They said I made it!
That's what I'm saying!
Running Madame's errands is my job?
You were last place.
At the recruitment.
Why did I get the job?
Isn't that the mystery?
A soypaste woman (materialistic beyond own means).
How much she'd like to pluck out, I wonder.
Hey, look here.
I'm merely a poor secretary who serves our Chairman.
Country accent?
Me? This Jean Thierry Cha?
I'm your dad, you punk!
Assa!
Crazy . . . looney.
What kind of a person is the madame?
Seo Yoon Joo?
Turns out she's become the madame of GN Fashion.
My mom's medical, hospital and medication costs.  Meet a man who lives well.  Please!
Hey, So In Chan really gave you this?!
Take this
and take this chance to break up completely.
How much?
$150,000 dollars, customer.
That diamond.
You tried it on, didn't you?
What?
It's your discernment that's shabby, Han Se Kyung.
Or blame it on 'circumstance'.
But that circumstance . . .
It's my parents.
And what my parents could do for me according to their circumstances.
Madame?
Episode 2
Oh.  Madame.
Stilettos.
Silk lace dress.
Cashmere coat.
Python clutch bag.
Everything's different.
From birth,
from the start.
Everything's different.
Hey, Han Se.
Seo Yoon Joo?
Seo Yoon Joo, you are . . . Madame?
How are you . . .
here?
That "Han Se Kyung
was you?
Subtitles brought to you by The Wonderland Team @ viki.com
Aren't you even ashamed?
You stole the boyfriend and had him draw for you, but you still lost to me.
Yup.  That's my skill.
Putting out his drawing with my name on it.
That's my ability, I said.
Han Se, why are you standing up and all.
Let's sit.
Yup.
How in the world?
How is it that you and I meet like this after 8 years?
I know.
Making me feel so bad.
And here, I didn't even know it was you.
Don't worry.
The warranty issue . . . I'll talk to the company.
Nah, no need.
I'll apologize.  This matter was definitely my mistake.
But actually . . .  I plan to hand in my resignation.
Resignation?
Why?
Is the company asking you to?
No, nothing like that.
It's your discernment that's shabby, Han Se Kyung.
Asst. Manager Shin is a bit difficult, isn't she?
Actually, she's my husband's sister.
I suffered a bit too in the beginning.
We were so different.
But she's not evil.
It's just that her own standards are so high.
No, it's not like that.
Just . . .
This doesn't seem like
a job I can do well.
That's why.
I get what you mean.
If it's really so uncomfortable for you, it can't be helped.
But my sister-in-law . . .
she is widely connected.
I know, because I've worked as a designer before too.
And this field is famous for how fast words travel.
If you quit over a matter like this, wouldn't there be talk of this and that?
Regarding . . .  your sense of responsibility.
Resignation letter
Han Se Kyung?
I heard the warranty issue will just be overlooked.
I apologize.
I heard you two were high school classmates.
Did you say you were going to hand in your resignation?
I've seen many people like you.
Your discernment is shabby andyou're not qualified to be a designer.
When being told that,
it's always the same response.
"I don't qualify
saying that and . . .
the resignation.
If you don't have a discerning eye,
shouldn't you at least have a backbone?
It seems you are having to attend to so many things lately.
When there isn't enough of you to focus solely on the meeting, as it is.
The meeting with Artemis that is coming up,
you're aware just how important it is, right?
Of course.  I know.
Don't worry, Sister-in-law.
I don't want to either.
Right.  You're not actually close friends, right?
What?
Han Se Kyung.
Nope . . .
we are close friends.
The madame of yours is Seo Yoon Joo?
That perpetual 2nd place from high school?
The one that even stole your boyfriend to have him draw for her to try to beat you?  That Seo Yoon Bal (foot)?
Wait.
Maybe Seo Yoon Foot hired you.
Since she's the Madame!
She's got the clout for it and if she knew the job application, she would have known that it was you.
No.
She looked like she was really shocked too.
Besides, why would she hire me?  There's no fond memory.
That's true.
But how can something like this happen?
Seo Yoon Joo as your madame?
How can that lackluster Seo Yoon Foot be the madame of GN Fashion?
The girl who got the nickname Seo Yoon Foot!
Maybe the man she was dating in France,
is your CEO?
France?
Remember, two years ago, how I dug around about everyone from our class?
To see how they're living?
Someone mentioned Seo Yoon Foot after seeing her in France.
She was living with some man there, you know.
And at a high luxury apartment, at that!
I guess that's when she and our CEO married.
How about it?
Want me to dig around in more detail?
I'm the "Internet Jeong Ah", aren't I?
Chief of internet?
Anything I want, I can dig it all out.
Ah Jeong . . . right now, I'm . . .
I know.
I know!
I'm so upset for you.
What are you going to do though?
Though . . . what else is there to do?
You guys fought like dogs.
How can you serve her as the madame?
Seo Yoon Joo.
Do you know what you look like right now?
What you're thinking right now.
That!
What?
You're going to continue working there?
Running Seo Yoon Foot's errands?
Se Kyung . . .
I know it was really hard to get the job,
and you do need to earn money,
and you'll have to marry too in the future as well.
It's true you can't continue living unemployed.
Yeah, you'll have to run Seo Yoon Foot's errands.
It's true.
You have to.
That's reality.
Well, work life is all like that anyway.
Right?
I'll have to earn money, right?
Of coursies.
Yup, and I need to marry too, right?
Yup and I have to quit living as an umemployed.
Right?
Stop, bitch.
You're pitiful.
You're not like this because I said to break up, right?
You better answer when I'm still talking nice, So In Chan.
Answer your phone!
Come to Pera Gallery in Cheongdamdong.
You're here.
Thanks so much for coming.
I'm in charge of this meeting alone, you see.
It's a very important matter.
You don't know how relieved I am because you're going to help me.
Not so, Madame. (formal speech)
What?
I am merely doing my work duty.
So funny.
Hey, why are you being awkward?  Relax.
This is more comfortable for me.
Please consider it.
Madame, if you went into work,
and the superior you're reporting to is your classmate.
So, could you treat her relaxed like a friend?
I see . . .  So you're going to treat me officially when we're meeting over work?
Alright.  I guess that makes sense too.
Actually, that is how work life is, isn't it?
Having to endure and do the tasks you don't want to.
And at times, having to put on forced smile as well.
Fine then.
Whatever makes you comfortable.
Should we begin the meeting preparations then?
Yes.
You'll have to be careful taking that off.
But there's a mark.
No, you'll have to fix that.
The furniture!  You have to mind the furniture too.
You're here?  Let's see.
They said this was the style favored by the Artemis President.
There's so little known about him.
I had to put some effort into finding it out.
Be careful of that.
Moreover, the Chairman I work for,
is precisely, merely, the one your side, GN Fashion, is bending over backwards to try to collaborate with.
It does look high class.
But must it be this extreme just to eat one meal?
What's known to the public,
is the name, Jean Thierry Cha. The youngest CEO of Artemis Korea ever.
Thanks to his work in the luxury market of Korea,
last year, Artemis Korea's yearly sales was over 40 million dollars.
This is a meeting to entertain someone of that caliber.
It's not just to eat one meal.
That's crooked.
How can you put that on the floor?
Bring it to me.
Clear this stuff off the floor.
Seo Yoon Foot, incredible!
Look.  I started from her and made this big turn,
and turned all the way to her and the answer came!
About what?
Living in France as "Yoon Joo, Cha" . . . !
Yoon Joo, CHA?  Not Yoon Joo, SEO?
This is it.  The reason Seo Yoon Joo lived as Cha Yoon Joo in France.
I found it on Gi Seon's homepage.
While traveling to France, she met CHA, Yoon Joo.
But why "Cha" as the last name?
In other countries, you take on your husband's last name after marriage.
Then this is her wedding photo?
Not officially.  A wedding just by themselves at the Catholic church.
But our CEO is a "Shin" as a last name.
That's the point that is incredible!
She met a guy in France and lived with him as Cha Yoon Joo, then she married your CEO.
Isn't it totally obvious seeing how it wasn't an official marriage?
She kicked her husband with the last name Cha to the curb, in order to marry a wealthier man with more abilities.
We've known her since high school,
but isn't she really so scary?
She struck a big blow to bite a better man.
She's venomous (coldhearted).
What duplicity.
Isn't she?
I mean you!  You!
You were so envious of her at Da Eun's wedding.
But why are you cussing Seo Yoon Joo now?
Hey, but that's . . .
She's the one who really made her dream come true.
She's the girl who claimed this was all her skill; her ability.
True.  She looked so pathetic back then.
But these days, this is ability too.
But what's going on with you and So In Chan?
What do you mean what?
So In Chan was absent without an excuse today.
Your call cannot be reached . . .
They're unable to get on the surgery schedule with the unpaid hospital bill still outstanding.
I'm in a bit of of a bind.
My bag . . . I still can't get a refund for it?
Customer, please come this way briefly.
Illegally distributed?
As you can see, there's a defective workmanship at the end of the thread stitch.
Our company retracts all defective merchandize and puts them through incineration.
We do not sell defective merchandize such as this, no matter what.
That can't be true.
They are confirming it at the headquarters.
So when that's done, we will contact you.
But I'm sure there isn't any issue with this.
This is definitely not one of those "illegally distributed" or what have you.
But anyway, please contact me as soon as that's confirmed.
"Omo, Royal Department Store is having a sale.  Grand Name-Brand Sale.
ID: Seungseung Jojo
Gotta go then!
Can a 50-day-old infant go to the department store?
But they don't really have many famous brands.
Royal doesn't carry Artemis.
Artemis is a 'no-sale' brand anyway. So annoyed.
Let's start a boycott campaign.
They need to wake up.
They're saying Artemis is going up by 10% in price.  The classic line.
Really? No way.
Going out to buy it now.
But I'm only getting paid next week.
Dearies, what about the campaign?
Mr. Chairman.
What is it?
It's your bag, right?
But you can't give me a refund, and you can't fix it?
This bag isn't an officially distributed merchandise.
Hey!
Then are you saying I bought it illegally?
Who's he now? The store manager?
Hey, you sold the likes of this bag and what now?
Illegal distribution?
I'm sorry, Customer, but where did you purchase this?
I didn't buy it at the store.
But this isn't a knock-off.  Check it.
You're right, Customer.
Regardless of where you bought it,
it is indeed our product.
Do you desire a refund or an exchange?
Exchange.  Switch for me.
With that.
Customer, the product price difference is three thousand two hundred . . .
Exchange what she wants for her.
What?
I apologize for the inconvenience to you.
And I hope you will make the purchase at an official store next time.
Customer, your mental health is more important than money, isn't it?
Convene a meeting.
Yes.
Cha Il Nam's video message.
Hey, heard you guys had a bag illegally distributed.
Hey, thanks.
For not putting Artemis into Royal Department Store.
Stuff like that is such a case of headache.
Hey, Cha Seong Jo.
No, Jean Thierry Cha.
Your grudge-bearing?  You take that after me.
Hey, but is your last name "Ssha" now?
Ssha ssi? Ssha ssi?
But why is your name Jean Thierry?
Why didn't you go with aluminum?
Aluminum Sshassi (punk).
Heck, you little rascal!
The products to be incinerated were distributed.
Who did it?
We're not sure.
But Deputy So In Chan of the Marketing Department has been on an unexcused absence since two days ago.
Is this how you've been working this whole time?
Haphazard with product inspection and you don't even know when someone snatch products out?
And have defective merchandize show up on the market?!
I bet some among you is thinking this right now.
Other brands sell their defective products at a discount.
People buy these expensive bags happily at a cheap price.
Yes, that's right!
Why don't we throw them all out on some family sale?  At unbelievable prices?
Then, whoever wants it,
be it a college student, or a mom, or granny,
it becomes something anyone can buy.
Is that the famous brand you all want?
Deputy So In Chan . . . find him!
Did In Chan show up?
So In Chan really caused huge trouble.
In Chan did an illegal distribution?
That's how it seems.
For 2 days, he's been out of contact.
The company wants to handle this quietly.
Before this becomes public, So In Chan should quickly come forward.
The company could have made a mistake during the product quality assuarance process.
That has not happened even once, yet.
The person you have called is not reachable at this time.  Please leave a message after the beep.
He has illegally distributed 5 defective bags.
In one month, we will be $2150 in the hole and in one year, it will become $25,800!
That kind of bag...if 5 of them...
It would be $30,000.
Subtitles brought to you by The Wonderland Team @viki.com
Oppa..
The number you have dialed is not available.  Please leave a message after the beep.
[Final Notice]
[Urgent Notice]
[So In Chan Profile]
Company loan, $40,000.
First financial debt, $21,800.
Second financial debt...
Geesh!
$150,000!
This crazy...
What is this?
Private financial debt, $69,300!
That's nauseatingly a lot.
How much is the debt?
For you...from this point, you don't know anything about this.
You don't even know a person by the name So In Chan.
What?
You should not put your foot in to a place you cannot be responsible to begin with.
There is no reason for you to be responsible for his debt.
That's right. I can't be responsible.
I don't have the ability as well.
But, are you telling me to give up on In Chan oppa in this situation?
Se Kyung.  I gurantee you.
He doesn't want you at his side.
You know he stole those bags.
If you were him, would you want to show yourself to him?
I'm going to pretend I don't know.
You better not say anything weird to him.
Is this something you can just pretend you don't know about?
This will pass. It's a situation that will go away.
It's not like a terminal illness to die from.
It's just money that needs to be repaid.
Money to be repaid, that's all.
Nowadays, poverty is the terminal disease!
Where are you going?
I have to go and find In Chan oppa.
[Urgent order from the madame:]
[EKNAFORA - opuscule, Fedon: vase, case, Balma: black shirts, Reeun: sleeveless top]
Gosh!
I'm leaving
You're here
Let me see...
Can you give that to me?
I'm sorry but can you put the rest in the dressing room?
Ah that's right, Se Kyung
Your boyfriend works for Artemis?
I heard from a manager at Artemis
that there has been some unsavory happening?
You'd better be careful.  It could negatively affect you.
And Se Kyung. That kind of man...
Shouldn't you cut him off quickly?
If you keep getting entangled with that sort of things, you could be held responsible as well.
So then, I will be leaving.
[speaking in formal/respectful speech]
Okay, Se Kyung.  I have so much to do so I won't be able to see you out.
Yes
At any rate, let's meet up next time to just hang out and chat.
I have no one to vent to.
Goodbye.
The president is coming up now.
Oh really?
Welcome back, president.
Yes.
Ah!
Ms. Han Se Kyung?
Yes.
I've heard alot about you from my wife.
You two went to art high school together?
Yes.
Please take good care of us.  I know it could be a bit uncomfortable to meet a friend at work.
No.  I don't think of the fact that we went to the same school at all.
Oh, that's right.
What was that saying?
What you said in French during the interview.
That saying left me a deep impression.
You said president is coming up. Hasn't he come in yet?
No, not yet.  He should have been up by now.
Ah, that's it.
Hard work will make who I am.
I really liked that.
At that time, I do not remember you being there.
At the interview?
Oh, I saw the video.  With my wife.
Excuse me?
Yoon Joo saw that?
She didn't tell you?  My wife gave you a high score.
How could such thing happen? How could we meet like this in 8 years?
Last place?
Then why did I get accepted?
That is a mystery.
From the get-go, you knew it?
Oh, I was in the middle of talking to Ms. Se Kyung.
To ask her to take care of us well.
Everything is ready.  Come on in now.
Is that so?... I'll see you later then
Se Kyung. Did you hear it?
What are you talking about, madame?
I have no idea what you are referring to.
[Using formal speech]
If you have nothing more to say, I will leave now.
Ah, it's not as fun as I thought it would be.  Your response.
Ha, I suppose, your current situation would be like that.  Isn't it?
You are still mean. You.
[Using informal speech]
So, you've been having fun so far.
Watching me running around like a chicken without a head, while running errands for you.
Se Kyung
Did you want to show me by being like this
that you've succeeded in your own way?
But what are you doing to do?
You think you've succeeded, right?
But not in my eyes.
You are exactly the same as before.
Seriously
Se Kyung! Why are you so serious?
It's not like what you think.
Do you know how you were during the interview?
You were...trembling.
You were so tense and it was obvious that you so desperately wanted to look good.
Hey, I really felt bad for you.
So how could it not hire you?
When you are putting so much effort into it.
Did I want to show it off to you how I live?
Not at all!  I simply gave you a job.
As it looked like you so desperated wanted it.
Of course, in your eyes, I could still be..."you know what".
But is that important?
What's important is...
thanks to a "you know what" person,
you got a job.
And, no matter how much of a "you know what",
I have acquired my position with my own effort and my own ability.
Good bye.
Subtitles brought to you by the Wonderland Team@viki.com.
Oh, that relieved my stress.
So how could I not pick you?
When you were trying so hard.
The important thing is, thanks to me, who's like you-know-what,
you got a job.
In Chan Oppa!
It's me.
Oppa, you're inside, right?
Open the door.
I said open the door!
Hey, So In Chan!
Open the door, open the door!
Open up!
[Next year, I won't make you toil! I love you.^^]
Oh, my arms are killing me.
It's almost over.  Let's just hang in there a bit longer.
Everyone's taking pictures and having a good time.
Please take just one picture for us.
What do kids eat and grow on nowadays to weigh so much?
I'll have a hefty bill for the pain relief patches.
Next year, I won't make you toil.
Truthfully?
Promise.
It came out nice and cute.
Yup.
How did you come up with this idea?
[Unlisted Caller]
Hello?
Is it you, Oppa?
Where are you?  I'll come pick you up.
I asked where you are.
I miss you.
I miss you, fool.
Perfect.
Can't you let me see Secretary Moon?
Does he know you're coming?
No, but . . .
It's that cry face again.
It's about So In Chan.
Please let me see Secretary Moon.  I've got to.
So In Chan?
He's not in.
So In Chan is your boyfriend?
Can't you call Secretary Moon for me?
Didn't I say I was the CEO's secretary?
You can speak to me.  What is it that you have to tell him?
Please tell him that Mr. So In Chan will return no matter what.
To wait for him just a bit longer.
He will return no matter what and explain and take any responsibility.
Did he say it himself, that he'd return?
That he'd be responsible for everything?
Did you see him?
This lady always makes me repeat myself.
I asked whether you saw him.
I talked to him on the phone.
Mr. So In Chan said so, on the phone?
For sure, it was a call from him.
And he will take responsibility.
What is this?  You haven't even spoken to him properly over the phone?
It's not that he said he'd be responsible?
Aigo, of course that's how they play.  The person himself doesn't even show up but sends a woman . . .
I'm not here because he sent me, but on my own.
Why?
-- Because I believe in him.
You believe in him?
I said I have faith in So In Chan.
He might have had a momentary lapse in judgment but he's not one to shirk his responsibility.
Even this lapse was due to his sense of responsibility.
How many years have you dated him?
6 years.
Do you know how much debt your 6-year-long boyfriend has?
Even though he may have some debt . . .
That he is officially declared delinquent?
I guess you didn't know.
Then, think about it very carefully from now on.
Then you'd be like, oops, why did I go there to see him?
Omo, I must've been crazy.  I must wake up to reality and get away from him as soon as possible!
That's what you'd think.
Because I know women better than women themselves,
I can offer you this advice.
What the . . . ?  Were you laughing at me just now?
Oh, seriously . . .
YOU are laughing at ME?
You, you may know women very well.
But you haven't loved, right?
Nor have been loved, right?
By the way, you, are you the CEO or something?
What?
You're not the CEO, but from the way you act and speak, it's as though you're the CEO, CEO!
You!  Stop costume-playing the CEO and just relay my message to the CEO.
That So In Chan will return for sure.
That I give my word.
Hey!
I've loved and been loved enough and that's where that life's insight comes from!
So speechless . . .
Umm, yes, I'm coming down now.
Have you brought it?
This works well, right?
Can it record even from inside my pocket?
I use it when I treat a lot of my patients.
OK.
But I'm asking you why, why are you borrowing a recorder all of a sudden?
You told me to heal myself.
Hey, hey, hurry and get out, get out.
Get out, I'm late.
Quickly, go!
You just wait, Seo Yoon Joo.
Here comes Edmond Dantes.
Why are you in such a good mood from earlier on?
Aren't you nervous?
I think I know now why people watch movies
like "The Count of Monte Cristo
and root for Edmond Dantes to take his revenge.
What?  Why do they root for him?
I think revenge is somehow beneficial to a person's health.
Sister-in-law, you're here?
The balance is not bad.
CEO Jean Thierry Cha has arrived.
I see.
Everything is ready, right?
Of course.
You are very pretty today.
Time to (take) revenge.
It's nice to meet you.  I'm Shin Min Hyuk.
Until we meet like this, information about you was so limited
that I was actually a bit nervous.
In France, I was just an Asian nobody
on the marketing team.
How can that be? Rumor has it that you came up with all the recent marketing strategies Artemis used in Korea.
Due to my personal experience,
I gave deep thoughts
to the Korean female psyche and they were the results.
In the end, the modern marketing strategy
is about how to quantify the human psyche and
how to translate it into sales.
Isn't that so?
Oh, is that so?
I . . .
don't know much about things like that.
Somehow, I thought Artemis's policy could not be explained away as a simple high price strategy.
May I say a psychological basis
that makes one's psyche vibrate.
You're overcomplimenting me.
At any rate, you're incredible.
I don't know what experience you had,
or how agonized you must have been
to gain enough insight to come up with all the marketing plans.
Well, about that, if we have time in the future . . .
Here!
Oh, shoot . . .
Honey, one more bottle of the same, please.
Ah . . . yes.
The house is very spacious.
Still . . .
such a loser you are.
What about you who has to kiss up to a loser
and your husband?
This time
you must shield me.
Still . . .
what an egotist you are.
Don't worry.
I simply came to return something.
Oh, thanks.
Oh, and you know
that I am also the CEO of Eclaire Korea.
I brought a small gift
for your wife.
Subtitles brought to you by The Wonderland Team @ viki.com
Oh, thank you.
Honey, hurry and open it.
Yes.
That was it!
Yoon Joo, why are you doing this?
I love you.
Enough to give up everything.
Why did you give up?
When the things you gave up
could have shielded me in such happiness.
Now, do you see?
To me, you were
just business.
What about you who has to kiss up to a loser
and your husband?
This is it!  Wow, the line is to die for!
What was I going to do if Seo Yoon Joo hadn't called me a loser?
Wow, this is terrific!
Got to hear it again.
What about you who have to kiss up to a loser and your husband?
That's right, yeah!
Wow, this is really healing me.
Oppa!
Oppa, you're inside, right?
Oppa, please open the door.  It's me, Se Kyung!
What are you doing here?
Hey, you crazy bastard.
You, jerk!
Where have you been?
Why did you do it, why?  When you've been holding up so well all this time?  Why?
To where did you wander so much, you fool.
I'm going to sort it out with the company, so you don't have to worry about it.
What are you going to do?
I'll probably be fired.
And again, I will find a way . . .
Umm, Oppa . . .
[I got into Artemis.]
I've said such schmaltzy things.
That's the message you wrote me,
after the junior year midterm exams.
And this is what I wrote you because you wallowed so much about not being able to get a job.
At that time, only you got a job and
I couldn't, that's why.
[Next year, I won't make you toil. I love you.^^]
Still,
this was the most fun time.
What are you doing?  Oppa!  Oppa!
Oppa, why are you doing this?
Oppa!
Now, stop all this!
You know too that this was all BS.
What?
Efforts make a difference?  Efforts are my force?
Okay, I also thought that way at the beginning.  So I tried.
I wanted to show you.
I wanted to prove to you that I could change, make progress.
Get married to you and
have kids, buy a house, buy a car . . .
But
no matter how hard I try, nothing changes.
What is getting better?  The more I try, the deeper grows my despair.
Of the myriad of apartments, there is no house I can buy.
No matter how much I work, I'm always in the red, I'll never be in the black.
And in such a state, I . . . get married to you?
Have kids?
The kids born to you and I
have to, under poor parents,
study, go to college,
and work.  What bad have they done? What bad have they done to deserve a life like mine?
The bags others buy so easily . . .
But my mom's life
can be saved or lost by a few of those.
So I ended up stealing them.
I got together the money for her operation.
Do you know the first thought I had, seeing mom coming out of the operation room?
When will I get the money together again?
Her hospital bills, chemotherapy, medicine bills, all I see is pitch black.
We don't know when it may recur, medical bills will continue to come.
They say the operation was a success and I'm not happy at all.
Yes, maybe, maybe I was disappointed.  Rather, had she passed away . . .
It's a rare cancer.
They say the insurance doesn't cover it.
Shit, a person doesn't pick and choose what cancer they get.
Is this a human being?
The So In Chan you used to know may have been a human, but now, I'm no human being.
And you, what are you doing right now next to me?
Why did you have to keep by my side and see me even like this, why?
Why?
Things will work out if we put in efforts,
let's work hard . . .
For always saying only those things,
I'm sorry.
But
I really thought
things would work out that way.
Because we worked so hard,
because, besides
working hard,
we had no other option.
So let's break up.
If you stay by my side, I think I'll really go crazy.
I'll really go crazy because I'll be such a loser and failure.
I'm sorry.
For making you say even these things.
For forcing you to say even these things.
I am really sorry, Oppa.
I'm sorry.
What about you, who has to please a loser?
And what about your husband?
This time, please protect me.
You're still as selfish as you were before.
Don't worry.  I only came here to return something.
S. J. Cha
Y. J. Cha
Se Kyung, don't worry.
Our house won't be foreclosed.
I'll repay our debts somehow.
How?
I'll have to work hard.  When haven't we worked hard?
Yes Dad.
Is there a time when we didn't try hard?
But, if it's true that
what you get out of something depends on how hard you try.
Why do we live like this?
There is no answer.
No matter how hard I try, there is no answer.
Who doesn't know that.
Even if you try, nothing will be different.
There is nothing to get better.
If you accept that, you can't live.
If you try, it will be okay.  Things will get better.
It is with at least that hope that we're able to live.
We aren't the only people who live like that.  Everyone in the world lives like that.
That's the only way.
No matter how hard I try, nothing changes.
What gets better if I try?  The only thing that gets bigger is my despair.
How could I not pick you?
You were trying so hard.
What's important is that thanks to someone like me, you got a job.
And no matter what I'm like, I earned my place through my work
and my abilities.
L'effort est ma force
My effort is what makes me.
Ma'am, you have a visitor.
A visitor?
I didn't give you any orders.
There was something I wanted to ask you.
You speak some French, right?
Yes.  But why?
Have you been to France before?
I have.  But why?
When you were in France, you were Cha Yoon Joo, right?
I saw it.  The photo.
It's this, right?
It's okay if you delete it.
What are you?
I can tell from your surprise that the president--your husband, doesn't know yet.
You said that
whatever you're like, you earned your place through your own work and abilities.
Did you really try hard?
What?
Did you really try hard to get to the place you are now?
Is it true?
Is it true that your efforts are what put you in this place?
Han Se Kyung.
What are you trying to do?
Do you think that you can steal this place that I've earned through my work with one photograph?
Are you trying to blackmail me and threaten to knock me out of my position?
Yes.  You're right.
I'm threatening you right now.
But I'm not saying I'll knock you out of your position.
Don't worry
What are you trying to do?
Tell me how.
What?
L'effort est ma force.
Tell me with what efforts you were able to get to your position.
Let me know as well.
Yes, the
abilities, the effort that made you what you are.
That secret.
Let me know it as well.
Subtitles brought to you by The Wonderland Team @ Viki.com
Cheongdam-dong Alice
Episode 3 Preview
You were able to.  Why can't I?
Just because I was able to
means that you can as well?
It tickles right here.
And my heart flutters.
Did you volunteer?
Rumors?
What rumors?
A woman?
A woman.
If my text messages make you uncomfortable, then tell me that they are.
He's definitely bad luck.
Figure out what their relationship is.
In life,
there are things that pass
and things that do not pass.
I'll do what I want to.
Isn't it crazy?
What's wrong? Why are you suddenly...
What's that?
Start right now.
Don't you know anything about your president?
There is love.