Why did I do it?
I didn't do it
out of greed or envy.
I did it because there was
nowhere left to go.
See, I'm nothing special.
I'm like everybody else..
getting by
day by day,
week by week,
dreaming about that one thing
that'll make everything all right.
That one thing.
JD Couriers. May I have
your account number, please?
- Another one?
- Yep.
Why are you bothering, kid?
You got a job for life here.
Yeah.
Well, it's all here. You've got
everything we're looking for.
Great. Thank you.
We should be able to let you know
sometime next week, so..
Can I ask you a question, sir?
I'm not gonna get this job, am I?
- I really need this job.
- I'm sorry.
A couple of years ago, you would
have walked straight in, but now..
I could start right away. I'd work for
free for a month if you needed me to.
I'm sorry, son.
Sorry?
Yeah, me too.
Are you done?
Yeah.
I'm done.
Yeah, I had dreams, but they're over..
because one day
you just gotta wake up.
- You just gotta wake up.
- Hi, Paul.
- Hi, Mom.
- How are ya?
- Pretty good.
How was your day?
Oh, you know..
same old, same old.
It'll come good.
I graduated two years ago.
I'm still living with my parents.
Well, do you hear us complaining?
Oh, I made you
some sandwiches.
You know, just to keep
that guilt thing going.
- Where's Dad?
- Working late.
You know,
you're pretty late yourself.
I guess if I keep on studying,
I can trick myself into believing
I'm getting somewhere.
- Why haven't you filled these?
- I'll get around to it.
Ma, you need to take
your medication.
They don't come free, Paul.
It's already wiped us out.
Don't worry.
I'll get better.
But in the end it wasn't about me.
It wasn't about me at all.
I'll get by.
It was about seeing pain and struggle
and knowing there was not one thing
you could do about it.
But not anymore.
Not anymore.
Hey, bro.
- Hey, how are you doing, man?
Have you ever done it
in a canoe before?
I thought a civilian snuck in.
You got a paddle?
Come on, take a risk for once.
Be more like your dad.
I'm good.
At least pretend you're cool.
What?
You didn't want it anyway.
- Fucking bitch.
- Aw, come on.
If you want a nice girl, there's plenty
to choose from out there.
I love this song.
What are you thinking about?
Paul: You.
I'm thinking about
how smart you are.
You get me.
Yeah.
I knew from the second
I saw you.
We're the same, aren't we?
Yeah.
We're the same.
It's so good to be with someone
who sees through all the bullshit,
- somebody with a vision.
I'm going to see
Dean again tomorrow.
Are you sure he can handle it?
- I mean, he can lose it big time.
- Yeah well,
we need him if we're gonna
go through with this.
When's that gonna be?
When I'm sure.
You wanna go out tonight?
No, tonight's not good.
Why don't we..
we'll do it some other time.
It's not good any night. You don't want
to be seen with me or something.
Is it so bad I want you all to myself?
No.
You know I love that.
I love you.
I gotta go.
And I love you too.
All right, on three.
One, two,
- three.
- Aw, fuck it.
Oh God, what is that,
like a double?
- Triple.
- Give me another.
No no no, finals week, remember?
- We gotta go, we gotta go.
- Oh, who cares? Come on.
Oh yeah, screw that. Don't forget
we've got a boys' night on Friday.
A boys' night..
yeah, I can't wait for that.
Come on, buddy.
We gotta keep the old fellas happy.
No, enough enough.
We've gotta go.
Oh, what is this?
Middle-age practice?
You know, you two would have
made such a good couple.
- Really, it's just..
- You're right, actually.
- I've just got too much fucking to do.
- Okay.
Let's go.
Oh, my bag.. gimme.
Oh, Nick, don't forget..
everybody sucks but us.
- Hi, Ma.
- Hey.
- What's going on?
- Nothing much.
I got you something.
Here.
Where did you get
the money for it? I mean..
- insurance won't pay for it.
- It obviously did.
I can't afford it.
The doctor said you gotta take
two of these pills a day.
Remember to do that, okay?
Ma?
No no, see, th-they can't.
They can't just do this.
Paul..
I'm so afraid.
Oh, Mom.
It's okay.
I'm so sorry.
I'll take care of this, okay?
A few days, the world's
gonna know who you are, Dean.
You ever think about that?
I have, yeah.
I can't do this on my own, Dean.
And we are all on our own.
Not anymore.
Tick-tock, tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick-tock,
tick..
Maybe she's right about you.
I thought she was just falling
for your blue eyes.
Listen, if you guys have
a thing going on,
- I don't want to get in the way.
- We're just friends. That's it.
You haven't called her
or anything, have you?
No, I haven't called her.
Why would I..
I lost my cell anyway.
Go figure.
Yeah.
Why don't you go
grab me a beer?
Yeah.
So tell me,
is that just a word?
I gotta do something
with my Friday nights, huh?
Okay, so that's
two tickets to Guadalajara
this Saturday the 27th.
That's it. You're all set.
Anything else
I can help you with, sir?
No, I've got everything I need.
Thank you.
Sorry.
I would have called, but..
No, I know..
no communication, no trace.
It's safer that way
until it goes down, right?
You mean..
Yeah.
When?
Tomorrow.
- I'll do anything you want.
- Yeah.
I know you will.
I know.
Now don't forget, Nick,
we're at Cliff's this year.
Dad, I won't forget, okay? Yeah,
I gotta go. See you tonight. Okay, bye.
What are you doing?
You won't be needing
those anymore.
I will if I don't pass.
Nick, we passed
the day we were born.
Accept it, man.
We don't live in the real world.
We don't have to.
It's for those dumbfucks over there.
You're such a people person,
you know that?
Hey, what's going on with Hailey?
This childhood sweethearts thing..
that's getting kinda old, man.
You're crazy about her, right?
God help me, yeah.
Yeah, I am.
Is she crazy about you?
Yeah. No.
Yeah yeah yeah, of course she is.
Then God help your AmEx.
You're actually gonna have to do
a day's work. That's funny.
That is really hilarious.
Well, when that happens,
I'll let you know what it feels like, pal.
Oh oh yeah!
Oh oh oh!
I hope you never get to hear this.
But if you do,
if this all goes wrong,
I want you to know that I did it
to make things right.
Just to make things right.
I love you.
Aren't we getting a little old
for these family vacations?
I mean, being out in the middle
of nowhere is fine when you're 12,
but the novelty's
kind of wearing off.
Well, you still have to have your little
poker night before the girls are even
- allowed in the door.
- Apart from our homecoming queen.
- Thank you.
- Hey, we're out of beer there, hotshot.
- This do instead?
- Yes.
- That does very well.
- Whoo-hoo!
Oh, there we go.
This is what you're gonna do.
Man:
It's a shitty color.
- What?
- This brown is like dark blue
or gray.. it's ugly.
- It's charcoal.
- No no no, it's not.
- It's charcoal?
- It's charcoal.
- Yeah.
But the best part is I can't see
your house from here.
- Well, Bob's late.
- He wouldn't be Bob if he was on time.
He's been that way since
fifth grade, you know that.
The kids are gonna get here
before him, you know?
At least we'll have
some time with them.
How's work going?
Safe, for now. You?
Well, you know.
It's work.
It's good.
Oooh, yikes. Look at that.
- What? It's a watch.
- Yeah.
Even in a shitstorm you come up
smelling like a rose.
What's your secret?
You bend the rules and I just
squeeze the shit out of them.
You win big, you lose big,
that's what I say.
What am I gonna tell you?
You know what? We're on vacation.
No more work talk.
- Good. Sure, don't bring it up again.
- All right.
I just heard a loon.
Bob's here?
What do you think you're doing?
Hey, are you deaf?
What are you doing?
I'm waiting for someone.
Waiting for somebody.
Okay, who are you waiting for?
You.
Where's your boat?
I didn't see the boat.
Hey, Avis, this is great.
I couldn't have done it
without Frank.
- Uh..
- Frank, look at you.
- You missed your calling.
- No, I'm very happy behind the wheel.
No, I can just see a nice floral apron.
It would suit you.
- Thanks.
- Avis, the kids are gonna love it.
Now get yourself home.
Oh, only if you're sure
that's all you need.
I'm sure. Home.
Okay. Good night.
Frank, I'm gonna need you
to hang around.
Bob can put them away, so we might
need you to give him a ride home later.
- Yes sir. Mm-hmm.
- Okay?
Go relax in the den, okay?
Why won't you let..
why doesn't he just stay here?
- He could, but he's not gonna.
- Why?
- That new blonde?
- Oh oh oh!
She reminds me of my second wife,
except I didn't have to buy her tits.
Badum-bum!
- Party time, my friend.
- Party time.
Fuck.
All right, on three we try..
try to grab my hand.
No, this is.. pull pull!
- Hailey: I can't.
- Fuck! Aw, fuck.
Shhh.
Please.
Jeff:
What do you want?
- Oh God.
- Don't you touch her!
- Nick: Let us go.
- Hailey: Please!
Nick: Just let us go.
We can help you.
We can get you anything you want.
Just please don't.. don't hurt her.
Please don't hurt her.
Answer me!
Please just..
Where the hell is Bob?
He's probably checking the tax
on his grocery bill.
That's why he's worth 10 times
more than us put together, right?
Except when it comes to Jeff.
Oh, Jeff, yeah right.
Now what do you suppose
he got him for graduation?
Probably socks from Switzerland.
- And aftershave.
- From Paris!
That better not be him.
Hey, why don't you ditch the suit?
Freshen up.
Are you hitting on me?
Hello.
- Mr. Jones?
- Yes?
- Mr. Clifford Jones?
- Yeah.
- You have a daughter named Hailey?
- Yes.
- That's right.
- No, actually that's wrong.
I have her.
I've also got Bob and Slick's boys.
- You want to talk to them?
- What is it?
Fuck.
- Don't fucking touch her!
- Tell us what you fucking want!
Don't fucking touch her.
Don't touch her.
- Just talk to us. Leave her alone.
- Fuck. Tell us!
All right.
So this is what's gonna happen..
What the hell's going on? If you so much
as touch a hair on my daughter's..
Why don't you cut the "if you touch her,
I'm gonna kill you"
fucking shtick,
you jackass, okay?
I'm gonna tell you what to do, you're
gonna do it and that's gonna be it.
It's as simple as that, okay?
Do you understand?
Okay.
Great.
I want a million dollars
from each and every one of you.
That's $3 million.
I want you to call your lawyers
and begin the bank arrangements.
There's gonna be no drop offs,
no suitcases full of money,
this is it.
I will call you in half an hour
with the bank accounts.
Do you have any questions?
I said any questions?
- No.
- And if you decide
to call the police, go right ahead.
All they're gonna do is clutter up
your house and delay our business.
And in that case..
save your money.
I'll say goodbye to your kids for you.
Were they scared?
- Yeah.
- Fucking pussies.
I love it. The one who was driving
makes me want to puke.
It'll all be over
in a couple of hours.
Well, I mean, it won't all be over.
Will it?
No, it won't.
Fuck! Voicemail again.
The one time we need him.
- Let's call the police.
- Okay, we call the police,
does that increase the chance of
catching this psycho? Yeah, it does.
Does it also increase the chance
of something happening to our kids?
Yeah, it does
and I don't like those odds.
- This is not a business deal.
- That's exactly what this is!
This is a business deal
and I'm doing risk assessment.
I'm not risking Nick's life because you
want to do what you think is the right..
Okay, then let's get out there and do
something to try and find them.
Well, Cliff, where do we start?
We're gone
and the guy calls, then what?
All right.
- We've gotta wait for Bob.
- Bob's not here.
Look, we don't have time
to make a debate about this.
All right, we need to stick together.
We can't afford to antagonize this guy.
All right, let's just do what he says.
Here.
Call your guy.
I'm going back downstairs.
Dean, you've got to stay up here.
No more than two people down there.
You know the rules.
Somebody has to be up here
to keep watch.
Yeah, so she can do it.
She can stay then.
No, Dean,
I need you for the big stuff.
Okay?
- Got it?
- Yeah.
- Everybody happy?
- Fuck you!
Oh yeah?
Why don't I just fuck you?
- What the fuck?
- Hmm?
Transfer arrangements
have been made?
- Yes.
- Good.
It should take a couple of hours
to work its way through the system
and then they'll be freed.
I want you to take this number down.
There's something you should know.
Bob Vincent hasn't arrived yet.
- Where is he?
- He's late.
- He's late?!
- What's going on?
It doesn't mean anything.
He'll be here any minute.
No, that's bullshit.
They're not gonna fucking pay us!
- They will!
- They'll pay whatever you want.
- Shut your fucking mouth!
- Just give me a second, all right?
- Which one's missing?
- Hey, you fucking cool it.
- Look at..
- Which.. which one is fucking missing?
The guy in the middle.
Hey, all right,
I'll give Mr. Vincent another
half an hour and that's it.
That's bullshit! Can't you see
they're fucking playing us?
Hey, just fucking cool it, okay?
Look at me. Cool it.
Okay?
All right? We're gonna
take what we can get.
Okay.
We'll take what we can get.
Okay, so I want you
to take this number down.
Fucking bitch.
If we're not gonna wait, we don't
really need this asshole, do we?
Jeff! Jeff!
- No!
- God.
What the fuck?
What is wrong with you?
We were gonna do it anyway.
Give me that.
Get the fuck out of here.
- No!
- Jeff!
You fucking bitch!
Fucking bitch!
- Listen to me..
- Dad!
That shouldn't
have happened, okay?
But if you don't want anything
like that to happen again,
- you'd better fucking listen to me.
- What the hell have you done?
- You killed an innocent boy?
- Just listen to me!
Bank of Lucerne,
- account number 0370995..
- You've got to say that again.
- Please, Dad!
- Account 0370-
- 995731.
- Dad!
- No! Fuck!
- Again.
5731.
You know the deal.. false names,
money there for five seconds and then out.
It'll take two months to track it down
and by then I'll be gone.
You've got till 3:00 a.m.
3:00 a.m.
Nick, what are they doing?
- Jeff.
- Fuck.
For unlimited celebrity sex videos visit
www.celebritysex.tk
I know the banks are closed.
What do you think, I'm a fucking moron?
Just.. use one
of the foreign accounts, Chuck!
I'll explain it to you another time.
I gave you the details,
now just fucking do it!
Are they giving you trouble?
I guess it's not every day that they're
asked to transfer a million bucks.
He called you Slick.
- What?
- The first time he phoned
he called you Slick.
Are you sure?
I haven't called you that
since college.
You're the only one who ever did.
What's going on, Rick?
If there's
anything else you need, I can..
Is something wrong?
Are you gonna stick
to the goddamn plan from now on?
- What's the big deal?
- The big deal is
you just fucking killed somebody.
- Is that an everyday occurrence for you?
- He deserved it, didn't he?
Anyway you're the one
who's been telling me for months
how we're gonna fuck them over.
Right?
Stick it to them, destroy their
perfect fucking little lives.
I thought you'd be.. I thought
that's what you fucking wanted.
It's not.
I'm sorry, okay?
I just want to make you happy.
That's all. I.. I love you.
I would do anything for you.
Well, then stick to the fucking plan.
You know,
why did she get to do that?
- Don't worry, you'll get your turn.
- Yeah, I'd better.
I didn't come out here
to just channel surf.
- I know.
- Good.
This place is covered in our prints.
Fibers and all that shit..
you know that too?
That's why we're gonna
burn it down after we're done.
You got it all figured out,
don't you?
Dean..
what's your problem?
I'm looking at it.
How's that?
- You just don't add up.
- Meaning?
Well, you say
you want to fuck them,
but really you want to be them.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Is that it?
- No.
No, this is just your little shortcut
into the club, isn't it?
- Isn't it?!
- Oh yeah.
You're right, Dean,
except for one little thing.
There isn't going to be
a club left,
is there?
Oh God, Nick!
Shh shh shh! It's okay.
- We're going to be okay. Okay?
Please don't touch her.
- Please don't touch her.
- Shut the fuck up.
She's gonna want to look her best,
like the little doll she is.
Please don't.
We'll get you the money.
I promise we will.
- This isn't about money.
- Why are you doing this?
- What the fuck is this about?
- This is about you.
You think you rule
the fucking world, huh?
Well, not tonight you don't.
Sit still.
There's a new show
in town tonight,
one night only.
What are you talking about?
My boyfriend's
a really clever guy.
- Mmm.
- Mm-hmm.
He planned the whole thing.
But he's a bit predictable.
So we thought: what's the best way
to end any show?
Hmm?
Well, it's obvious, isn't it?
With a bang.
- What what?
- But don't worry,
it's not for you.
It's for the folks back at home.
See, 3:00 a.m.
they'll be sitting there,
thinking they've done their duty,
and I guess you can say
we'll blow the fucking roof off.
Hey, have you ever
opened up a modem before?
- What?
- There's nothing there.
Just a circuit board
and a lot of empty space.
You really can
put anything in there.
Anything.
And if it's attached to a laptop
and it's programmed to detonate
like your daddy's is,
well, 3:00 a.m.
No.
Oh Jesus.
Oh man.
How long is this gonna take?
- Cliff, just take it easy, okay?
- How the hell do you remain so calm?
Because us panicking
isn't going to help our kids.
All right?
We'll get them home.
We have to.
- That's Bob.
- Okay.
So what are we gonna tell him?
Anything but the truth.
He'll go to the cops.
Anything but the fucking truth.
Cheers.
Coming!
Okay.
- Oh, Bob.
- Howdy, campers!
- You're late.
- Hey.
Guys, I don't blame you
for being pissed off.
Same old story, right?
Am I talking to myself here?
- No no.
- So I'm a couple of hours late.
What's the big fucking deal?
There's no harm done, is there?
Good seeing you.
I can guess who that is. Looks like
I'm not the only one who's late.
- Just get the phone.
- Yeah? You talk to him.
Yeah. Just get the phone.
Yeah?
Oh hi, sweetheart.
Hey yeah, no.
Everything's great.
Bob just got here.
No, she hasn't arrived yet either,
but you know how it is.
No, not tonight.
No, you'll see her tomorrow.
Yeah. Yeah yeah.
Yeah, good night, honey.
Jesus, you'd think they'd leave us alone
on our one night of freedom!
Hey, guys, listen,
I brought a great surprise for Jeff.
In fact I drove it here.
He's gonna love it!
- What?
- If I roll this, I think it..
I think it's loose.
Nick, Nick, hurry.
Oh God.
Fuck.
Okay okay.
Okay, all right, okay.
Wait a second, Hailey,
wait a second. Shh shh shh.
Shh-hhh.
It's okay. Be quiet.
Okay? Okay?
All right?
Hurry.
All right, all right.
Okay okay, you're okay.
Okay okay okay.
I don't believe this.
What?
We're at my dad's house.
Okay.
Well, you really did
think of everything.
Yeah, it's even better
than you promised.
To chaos.
To the American dream.
Something's wrong.
- Yeah, they should be here any minute.
- No, come on.
How long does it take to fix a flat?
You're not gonna get a signal
on that up here, Bob.
- Top you up?
- Yeah, thanks.
- Dick?
- Yeah.
It went right to voice-mail.
Hey, is Frank here?
- Yeah.
- So what are you waiting for?
Send him out to find them.
Th-there's no point.
- What's he gonna do?
- There's, um,
there's something
that we haven't told you.
- What is it?
- Dick.
No, it's all right, Cliff.
Jeff got pulled over for a DUl.
Oh, God damn it!
And made us promise
not to tell you, but I.. I'm sorry.
I knew there was something
going on between you two.
Shit!
I'd better get down there.
Where are they?
You'd just be wasting your time.
We called your lawyer.
He's gonna have them out
in a couple hours.
- I'm still going.
- No no, just..
you know what?
Let them sweat it out for once.
All right?
It'll teach them a lesson.
You know how they are.
Yeah.
You're right.
Champagne?
Cheers.
Jesus, I can't believe it.
Her father's place is
the only place within miles.
There's only two ways to get there..
they can take the road.
Nobody's gonna be around this time
of night so they're gonna take the forest.
Stay together, go due north. I've gotta
stay here and wait for the money.
They may just hole up
somewhere till daylight.
That's fine. As long as they're not there
to stop it, I don't give a fuck.
- They're not gonna wait till daylight.
- Why not?
- 'Cause I told them about our surprise.
- You what?!
- Why would you do that?
- You fucking dumb-ass!
- I don't know. Fuck.. fuck off.
- She fucked the whole thing up!
- Fuck you.
- Shut up, enough.
- I was afraid..
- I'm through taking orders.
You'll still find them.
Shut the fuck up.
I'm not going.
There's no point in going.
- Why'd you do that?
- I don't know.
- What's the fucking point?!
- The point is
you have a chance
to change something, okay?
You have a chance to convince
the world you're not the same
fucking loser you've been every other
goddamn day of your fucked-up life.
Okay?
That's the point!
You know what?
I'm getting kinda tired
of this place anyway.
Dean, I want them back alive.
Hey.
Go.
Fuck.
Are you sure we're going
in the right direction?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Nick!
Okay okay,
we'll stop just for a sec.
- We're never gonna make it.
- We still have three hours.
We'll make it.
I still can't believe we were
in your father's house.
- Yeah.
- I mean, this is seriously fucked up.
You know?
Yeah, I know.
All right, let's go.
- Hey, that's gotta be them now.
- I got it.
Hello?
Hey hi, Bill.
Oh really?
Hey, that's great news.
Yeah. Good good.
Okay thanks, buddy.
- Bye.
- Who was that?
My broker.
You know..
some deal he was working out.
- At 1:00 in the morning?
- That's what I pay him for.
Eh, you gotta give me his number.
- Your money's gone through?
- Yeah.
Well, I haven't heard anything.
This is taking way too fucking long.
- Get on it.
- I.. I..
I gotta go make a call.
- There's a phone right here.
- It's, uh, it's..
it's a personal call.
You mean a woman?
You got a little action going?
- I'll be right back.
- Then you're gonna share, right?
Yeah yeah yeah yeah.
Oh God.
I miss cassettes.
I could work cassettes.
- Oh yeah?
- Cliff?
- Come here for a minute?
- Yep.
I'm sorry, Bob.
This won't be long.
What the hell is up
with you two tonight?
- It's nothing. I'll explain it later.
- Okay.
- What's going on?
- I just talked to Chuck.
- Yeah, what?
- I don't have enough to cover it.
- What?
- Everything's..
it's tied up.
You're kidding me.
What are you gonna do?
Fuck.
- How much?
- $750,000.
What?
Oh, come on.
- Don't hold out on me, Cliff.
- That's a hell of a lot of money.
- For Nick's life?
- No, of course not.
Not for Nick's life.
I haven't got it.
What?
You think I'm lying to you?
This is our kids' lives
we're talking about..
- Exactly.
- You think I'm lying to you?
Okay, what the fuck is going on?
Tell me.
The kids have been abducted.
Wh.. what are you talking about?
- They've been kidnapped.
- Kidnapped?
Is this for real?
Yeah, it's for real.
Jesus Christ.
W-where are they?
Are they hurt?
- No.
- Is Jeff.. is Jeff okay?
Bob..
- I want you..
- Jeff's okay.
Fuck.
Are you okay?
- Are you okay?
- This is bullshit.
Why can't we just go to the road
and get some help?
There's no help, Hailey, okay?
It's the middle of the night
and we're in the middle of nowhere.
Now let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Stop!
Stop acting like you're in charge.
- We're going to the road!
- Look, I'm telling you that..
Come on, come on, come on.
I can't believe you didn't tell me
the minute I walked
through the fucking door.
- That was my idea. I'm sorry.
- Always playing an angle, aren't you?
Gimme that account number.
What are we doing?
We gotta tell him.
Nothing's changed.
He'll call the cops.
His kid's dead and we're letting him throw
away a million bucks?
It's the only way I can save my kid.
You couldn't fucking
help me, could you?
- Christ.
- Christ what?
And you would do some..
Done.
Hey, Ma, um..
I know you're sleeping, but, um..
look, I..
um, I.. I was just calling you
'cause I'm gonna..
I'm gonna be home
a little late tomorrow.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, we got it.
- Oh man, that's so awesome.
- Give that to me.
Give it to me, come on!
- What's going on?
- Let them go.
We don't need them anymore.
Just sit back, enjoy the fireworks.
Meet me at the gas station.
I'll be right there.
Wow. Well, if that's
what you really want.
You take the road.
- I'm going straight on.
- What'd he say?
Kill them.
It can't be much longer.
They can't be that far away.
How do we know?
They could be anywhere.
I don't know, I'm just assuming.
They were on their way here.
You know, I really admire
your confidence, Rick.
What do you mean?
Well, you seem to be
pretty sure that
this guy's gonna let them go.
Why is that?
Hailey, come on.
What the fuck
is the matter with you?
Oh, come on. Don't tell me
it hasn't crossed your mind, Nick.
That we just happened to be
in your father's place?
- That they knew it would be open?
- No no, it hadn't crossed my mind.
I mean, do you think it's that obvious?
Do you think it's that simple?
Yeah, maybe it is.
I'm his son, Hailey.
He's not gonna hurt me.
Well, you're not hurt,
are you, Nick?
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck
am I doing with you?
And you're a real catch, huh?
A hero?
Jeff is dead!
You didn't stop them!
- You didn't do anything!
- What the fuck was I supposed
- to do, Hailey?
Look, you'll get your money.
You don't have to do this.
- But I want to.
- Please, no. No, please!
Nick: Go go go!
Go!
Fuck you!
- I've got my money.
- Okay, what about our kids?
- You got what you wanted.
- You'll get them back in an hour.
This is the last time you'll be
speaking to me. In the meantime,
I don't want you to make or take
any phone calls. Do you understand?
- Yes.
- Good. And by the way,
tell your kids the show
has been canceled.
- What?
- They'll know what I'm talking about.
Okay, I need to know
our kids are safe.
They're safe.
He got the money.
He says he'll have them
back in an hour.
Excuse me, Mr. Jones,
can I call my wife?
- She panics if I'm..
- I'm sorry, not tonight.
Of course. I'm sorry.
Don't you ever get tired
of knowing your place, Frank?
- No sir.
- Don't call me sir.
- I'm not paying your goddamn wages.
- All right, that's enough.
Is it?
I think I can say exactly
what I want right now.
Okay, say exactly what
you want right now, Bob.
Well, you know what they say about
these things, don't you, Richard?
No, go on, tell us, Bob.
That they sometimes turn out
to be an inside job.
Am I right, Cliff?
- You're not serious?
- You're the one who needed the money.
Are you outta your fucking mind?
It's the truth, isn't it?
Well, how come you suddenly
have no money,
you come in here
like you're king of the hill?
You want the truth?
Here it is.
I got burned.. big time.
The party's over for me.
But who wants to hear that in
the land of milk and fucking honey?
I'm done!
Fucking happy?
Hey, Richard, just one question.
Is this one of your
pump-and-dump scams?
Bail out when the price
gets high enough?
- Wh.. where is this all coming from?
- I'm just asking.
What, are you two guys
the sons of the soil, huh?
I got news for you.. we all do
the same fucking thing.
We push numbers around
and we fuck everybody else
as long as we get ours.
End of story.
Only your numbers
don't always add up, do they?
And right now you decided
that that bothers you?
No, right now
you're the odd man out.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Not tonight, Bob.
That's you.
Oh, and how's that?
Tell me!
All right, I'm sorry.
Let's just cool it.
All right, we're saying shit
that we don't mean.
Let's just keep it together.
They killed Jeff.
Come on, we've got to get them
out of the house.
Don't don't don't.
- What?
- Come on.
Come on, come on,
pick up the fucking phone.
- We're too late.
- No, we're not too late.
Fuck 'em. Try the cops.
You killed my best friend, you bitch.
You fucking killed him!
No, fuck you!
Nick, stop!
Get..
Nick.
I recognize her. I've seen her
around campus and the other one.
All right?
Yeah.
I think you're right.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Here, Bob.
That could help.
Oh Christ.
It would have helped
if you'd saved my son.
Bob, there was nothing
that we could do.
We didn't have a chance
to save him, Bob.
I had to tell them
that you weren't here.
Why the hell did you
tell them I wasn't here?
- Why did they have to know that?
- Because I was stalling him.
I didn't know if we could get
the money together.
- Our kids' lives were at stake.
- No, my kid's life was at stake!
- My kid!
- Bob, you weren't here.
We couldn't have saved him.
Oh.
Well, you certainly
got your shit together
when it came to taking
my money, didn't you, Rich?
What else could I do?
Let them kill Nick too?
You'll get your money back, okay?
Every cent.
Fuck you!
All right, let's just say that
I accept everything you've said.
You don't seriously think
I'm going to sit here all night
while the psycho
who's got my money..
killed my son..
just walks away?
- We don't have any choice.
- Well, you might not have a choice,
but I do and I choose to do
something about it.
No, Bob, Bob, I'm not going
to let you do that.
- Gimme the phone!
- No!
- You're not calling the police.
- Maybe if you had
Jeff would still be alive.
No, if you were here,
he'd still be alive, Bob!
If you were fucking here!
- You fucker.
- No, God damn it.
- Let go.
- Come on.
Let go of me!
Fuck!
Where did they go?
I don't know.
Get up. Get up.
Get up! Which way?
Who cares?
Fucking asshole.
You're the fucking asshole!
You're the fucking asshole.
Get up!
Stupid motherfucker.
What's with this?
Where's mine, huh? That's not my car.
She was like that when I got here.
They must've..
Where did they go?
I don't know.
They're alive.
That's what you wanted, isn't it?
Hmm? Blanks!
Yeah, I knew you wouldn't be able
to control yourself, Dean.
Fucking smartass.
Well?
What are we waiting for?
Let's get out of here.
It's gonna blow any second.
Dean?
You were right.
You're all on your own.
I knew it.
I fucking knew it!
- How could I be so fucking dumb?
- See, Dean,
you're not dumb.
You're unstable.
You're antisocial and you have a grudge
against society like your friend here.
Okay? Two freaks fucking pissed off
at all those rich college kids
they see walking
across campus every day.
Nobody's gonna be surprised
that you tried a thing like this.
Nobody.
You won't get away with it.
Oh. No, see, I don't have
to "get away" with anything.
As far as they're concerned
there were only two people.
There's the girl.. who's dead..
and the guy on the phone.
That's yours, by the way.
It's a shame about the plane tickets
you bought with this credit card.
You're not going to be able
to use those.
I don't exist, you understand?
There's no trail, no evidence.
Nothing.
Oh, you're clever.
Yeah, but when the house blows,
they'll find something.. some trace.
They always do.
And you will go down.
You will fucking go down!
You will go down for it.
God, you really are stupid, Dean.
A bomb?
The transmitter,
the house blowing up?
Really? I just made that shit up
to turn you on, Dean.
See, I know everything about you.
Everything.
And soon they will too.
They're gonna know that you have
big highs and even bigger lows.
And that when the shit hit the fan,
you were always
gonna do that thing..
the thing that you've tried before.
The second time's a charm.
- Hailey!
- Daddy!
- Nick!
- Oh, thank Christ.
Hey, we gotta get out of here.
The whole place is about to blow.
- What do you mean?
- Your laptop, it's a detonator
and the modem's rigged with explosives.
It's a big finale.
- My laptop?
- It was supposed to go off
- like 10 minutes ago.
- I never bring my laptop here.
- What?
- Maybe that's what he meant.
The last thing he said to me
was to tell them
- the show's been canceled.
- Why would they even tell us that
- in the first place if..
- Probably just to mess with your heads.
- Oh fuck.
- Did you ever have anything
to do with these people before?
Because they seem to know us.
These two kids, we think we've
seen them before around campus.
- Nick: Yeah.
- All right, well, all that matters
- is that you're safe.
Nick, it's them.
No no, it can't be.
They've got the money.
- No, but they came after us.
- What do you mean they came after you?
We just escaped. What the hell
do you think we're doing here?
- I don't know him. Do you?
- No, it's not them.
Can I help you?
Paul.
- Dad.
- What happened to you?
There was this guy
at the gas station.
He had this girl
knocked out at his feet.
- That's the same people who got us.
- Anyway, I was gonna keep on driving,
but he pulls out a gun and tries
to pull me out of the goddamn car
and that's when.. anyway,
I managed to hit him and I got away,
but I think I got pretty lucky,
you know?
Well, come on in.
Thanks.
- So do we know who they are?
- Yeah.. well, we don't know them.
They, um, they held us ransom.
And they killed our best friend.
- You're kidding?
- Are you kidding, Hailey?
Mr. Vincent..
I am so sorry.
We loved Jeff.
But there was nothing we could do.
- I think it's time we called the cops.
- I already called them.
- They're on their way.
- Paul, what are you doing here?
Mom's worried sick.
You always call when
you're gonna be this late.
And I kept calling and calling
but there was no answer.
We heard it ringing, but they told us
not to answer the phone.
Listen, come on in,
come on in.
Hey.
Didn't Frank used to bring you
around when we were kids?
- Yeah, but then..
- You.. you had your own friends.
I just thought it was better
that we didn't impose.
Dad, it was in our house.
What?
Where they held us.
But you got away, right?
- Yeah.
- When?
I don't know.
Three, maybe four hours ago.
No, what he wants to know
is did you get away
before he paid up.
No, Bob, that's not what I meant.
There's just one thing, Nick.
Did you know your
big-shot daddy was broke?
- For God's sake.
- Bob: Now how about that?
But it's okay. I spotted him
a couple of bucks.
It's nothing, Nick.
Where are these cops?
We're a long way out of town, sir.
Yeah well, and in the meantime
these fuckers are getting away.
Where's my lighter?
We'll arrange for you to come down
and make a formal statement.
Any time, Officer.
I don't know what kind of country
we're living in anymore.
- What happened to our kids?
- I wish I knew.
It seems like
every day there's a..
That's just the way it is.
At least your son's okay.
You're both free to go.
Oh, and one more thing..
we're gonna need to check
your car for prints.
You can pick it up tomorrow.
Yeah, of course.
- There you go.
- Come on, we'll take mine.
Let's get out of here.
- Dick: And here we are.
- Yeah, that's about it.
Thanks.
Nick: Bob,
why don't you let us
give you a ride home?
You shouldn't be on your own.
- Good idea.
- I'll call you.
- Bye, Hailey.
- Okay.
Nick?
All those things I said..
sorry.
Cigarette?
All right.
Are you okay, son?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I can't go back there.
You don't have to.
Hey, Pop.
Everything's going to be okay.
Everything.
We played by the rules.
I wanted to play by the rules.
But that's the big lie.
It's not enough anymore.
So maybe,  just once
you've gotta break them.
Right?
SubText:
NoRMITA.326