Come on, baby. It's lunch time.
Up we go.
Good Morning. Costello Real Estate.
How may I help you?
Mr. Costello's offiice.
Good morning.
You are not gonna believe
what just came up.
Eeny, meeny, miney-- Lucy.
How day, race fans.
How's it hangin'?
It's hangin'just fine, thanks.
The boss wants a word. It seems we have
a little domesticon our hands.
Can you stall for me?
I'm a little busy.
That's all right.
I'll set it up on-line.
God for bid you actually have to come out
of your hole and talk like a human.
It make some wonder what you all did
before computers, Detective.
Anyway, it's all very hush-hush.
I'm going to lay my money on Hugo brat
shacking up with yet another bimbo.
Very embarrassing.
National disgrace.
Sono cops, got it?
Speak of the devil...
here's Hugo.
Okay, we're about to go live.
- Hilary.
- Mr. Hugo, one moment, please.
Putting you through now, sir.
You fat fuck.
You're on-line.
- Morning.
-Sir.
A personal problem has developed to me
that l'd like you to take a look at.
- Yes, sir.
- Nothing serious, really.
Nothing that a good kick
in the pants wouldn't sort out.
The pants in question being worn
by my 22-year- old son Paul.
I suspect he's been stealing money
from a trust account.
I want you to find out
what he's up to.
Yes, sir.
Thank you. Good morning.
Good morning.
Beauty is in the eye
of the beholder.
Hil?
He walks. He talks.
He's alive!
I'll call you from the trenches.
Here, I got you something.
" Portland, Oregon."
- It's the same one as Cincinnati.
- Nonsense.
- It's the same buildings.
- It's not.
- Is too.
Do you always park in front
of fire hydrants, sir?
Yes.
Are you gonna stop parking
in front of fire hydrants?
- No.
- And why's that?
My apologies, sir.
You have a nice day, now.
Who is he?
Some embassy brat,
forged Daddy's signature.
He's making a cash withdrawal
for someone.
- And who is she?
- I don't know. We've never seen her.
I bet she's pretty.
I bet she's not.
- Which one?
- There.
- This one?
- No.
No? Not this one?
- The other one.
- Yes?
The guy behind him.
Not the bum.
God bless America.
Can you spare any change?
Anyone.
You got a dollar for me, please?
Please.
Please, help me out.
One, three, three, four.
Why don't you take
any pictures of me, Daddy?
Sweetheart, I never go anywhere
without your picture. You know that.
I mean other pictures.
Sure, I used to take lots.
Do you remember Sea World?
The dolphins and the clowns on skis.
Do you remember?
You were just a baby at the time.
No. Where are they?
Your mother has them, along with
everything else with your name on it.
At least she was there
when I got home from school.
She didn't spend her whole life
staring at dumb computer screens.
Lucy!
Stephen, Stephen, Stephen.
- Where's the money, Paul?
- What?
- The money.
- It's in my bag, safe and sound.
Good. This is nice, hmm?
Do you like it?
No body can see us for a million miles.
Ever brought any women here?
- I have been known to on occasion.
- I didn't think so.
I brought you.
I'm not other women.
- Pass memy Gitanes.
- Your what?
- Gitanes. Cigarettes.
- Gitanes cigarettes.
- What is this? A shark? A fish?
- Oh, no. It's a pisces.
a pisces! How '70s.
What, you actually into that crap?
-As a matter in fact, l am.
- Well, I'm a Leo.
Hey, what do you think of that?
A shark and a lion.
So do you--
So tell me.
Do you swim around
all day eating plankton...
or do you bite the heads
off little fish?
Oh, pisces are broad-minded,
artistic...
and sensitive.
We're also extremely selfish...
manic-depressive substance abusers.
All depends on what side
of the bed l get up on.
Don't forget about
who's in bed with you, huh?
- Wait.
- Wait? What? What?
- Now we're going to play a game.
-A game?
Baby!
What are you doing?
- Get down now.
- Down, yes. How?
- Get down on your knees.
- You kinky little--
I-- Oh!
Oh, my.
Oh, yes.
Where'd you go?
Come here.
Merry Christmas, Daddy!
Merry Christmas.
Fuck in' phone.
Don't leave her, Daddy.
She's just a little girl.
Don't leave her alone.
Do you want your change?
- Where's the phone.
- Out back, past the cash registers.
Oh, come on.
Do you have another phone?
It's an emergency.
- Do you have another phone?
- Nah.
Cash registers kept smash in them
to pieces look in' for quarters.
- Here. I owe you ten bucks.
- Come on. Come on!
I want to come home.
It's Christmas, for Christ's sake.
You don't really have to come home
any more, dear, do you?
You can e-mail me, or we can talk
on this thing you've given me.
I gotta go, Mother.
I'll call you back.
Hilary--
- You're in the pool.
- Hi, Hil.
Well, well, well. Lucky legs.
Nice to see your smiling face.
Love your work, let's do lunch
and when ever you're ready.
The eye which is reflected
to the external world...
is also the mirror
to the soul within.
I didn't, if you please.
Beauty is in the eye of the beholder.
I'm a little out of my depth here.
We're gonna have to call a breach 3.
I got a breach 3.
What the hell
are you doing on hard-line?
My cell phone and GPS went down.
I had an accident.
I'm running a trace.
Pittsburgh, correct?
- Correct, train station.
- Okay, got it.
- What do you need?
- State police, federal, who ever's near.
Suspect's about to board
a train to New York City...
and may be traveling
under the alias of--
- Lucy.
- Under the alias of?.
- Lucy?
Talk to me, Lucky.
Lucky?
Under the alias of?.
- Lucky, what's going on?
- Don't tell, don't tell, don't tell.
Detective! Wilson, what the
hell's going on out there?
- Wait a minute.
- What's happening?
- Don't tell, don't tell, don't tell.
Look, you're wasting time here.
I'm sending in the troopers.
Don't leave her.
She's just a little girl.
- No, don't do that.
- Well, you have a breach 3.
Then suddenly you don't.
What's up? What's the matter?
Nothing, nothing.
I'll have to go. I'll call in.
- Lucky!
- Here we go again.
He's gotten a lot worse since
his wife and kid went away.
Well, why don'tyou stick your business
where the sun don't shine?
- How'd it go?
- Nothing.
No match, no fiingerprints.
Nothing.
- Is she real?
- She's real, all right. A real pro.
Acid wash would burn
her fiinger prints right off.
- Can I get you something to drink?
- Scotch, rocks with some bitters.
Thank you.
- Can I get you something to drink?
- I'll have a vodka and orange.
Happy New Year.
- Do you mind if l flirt with you?
- Seeing how timing is everything...
why don't you wait until
I'm done reading my stars?
Mickey Argyle.
- Dorothy Bishop.
- Pleasure.
Excuse me. I don't mean to interrupt,
but you're not from Cleveland, are you?
- No.
- Your name isn't Gail Fleming?
- No, it isn't.
- I'm sorry.
A friend from Cleveland used to go out
with a girl who looked just like--
But that was a while back.
I have never been to Cleveland,
and everybody looks like somebody else.
I'll drink to that, toots.
Excuse me.
May I please have my cognac?
I've been waiting 20 minutes.
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
Would you mind, please, sir?
The cognac?
So she says to me...
it's her or the jewels.
I chose to keep the jewels.
My jewels.
You know, you have beautiful eyes.
Unalloyed, unblemished black opal.
Almost perfect.
An expert. How fortunate.
Absolutely-tutely.
Voila.
Impressive.
Larry!
My mink was right here.
Oh, my God.
Somebody has taken my mink coat!
Very nice.
And this opal would retail
for approximately what?
- Five thousand.
- pisces.
- Could you give me possibly--
- It's all in the hands of the gods.
Maybe we should have a couple of kids.
What do you think?
Lay off me. Please?
Hey, lady, I think
it's time you went home.
Merry Christmas, Daddy.
Merry fucking Christmas.
I wish you bluebirds
In the spring
To give your heart a song to sing
- Lucy.
- And then a kiss
But more than this
I wish you love
And in July
A lemonade to cool you with
- Lucy, be quiet.
- Some leaf you glade
I wish you health
But more than wealth
I wish you love
- My breaking heart
- Stop sing--
And l agree
That you and l
Could never be
So with my best
My very best
I set you free
- I wish you--
- Lucy, be quiet!
I'm sorry.
I wish you health
But more than wealth
I wish you
I wish you bluebirds in the spring
Harry, can't you read the sign
that says "no pets"?
- This place doesn't allow gold fish.
- They don't make noise.
Debra.
A gentle reminder, darling.
Take out your own trash
on Tuesday and Thursday.
- Of course.
- And don't throw it in the street.
Throw it in a bin.
- Tell your boy friend to do the same.
- Which one?
The one who's been
following you around all week.
You know the one.
The one who waits outside for you...
and follows you around
like a lost dog.
- You know.
- Describe him.
Oh, so-so.
Average height.
Normal looking.
At my age,
they all look the same.
Have a nice day.
Yo, taxi!
Hey, hold up!
Yo, babe.
- Come on. Don't be so antisocial.
- You gotta give me some of that.
- Nuts!
- You ain't gettin' none of that.
How the fuck did you get in here?
Guy down stairs gave me the key.
Your name Debra Yates?
Detective Crocker, NYPD.
What can I do for you, Detective?
You, uh...
dropped your pisces.
- I've never seen it before.
- Oh, yes, you have.
The guy down stairs says
you're from SaltLake City.
That's right.
Isn't it against the law to walk away
from the scene of an accident...
in Salt Lake City?
It's against the law
here in New York.
What can I do for you, Detective?
Come again?
How much is this gonna cost me?
- Are you bribing me?
- Yes, I am.
How much?
Okay. A thousand dollars
and a shot of some of that...
whatever it is.
It's cognac.
- What do you do for a living?
- I'm a wigmaker.
I'm here drumming up some business.
You sure you got
a thousand dollars?
No.
But I'm sure we can come to
some kind of an arrangement.
I'm sure you're right.
Don't touch that.
Lady, can I get that for you?
Sir. Sir!
Taxi!
I'm tired, Daddy.
I want to go home.
Soon, sweetheart.
What are we doing here?
It's late.
I'm sorry, baby.
We can't go yet.
Not yet.
If l blink, I might lose her.
So?
So the last time I blinked,
I lost you...
I lost my wife
and I nearly lost my mind.
I can't lose her.
I'll be with you in a minute,
ma'am.
Sorry about the wait. Your brandy,
sir. That's six dollars, please.
Oh, thank you.
Here you are.
- I'm sorry, sir. That's a five.
- Pardon?
No, isn't.
It's a ten, you snake.
Oh, gosh, so it is.
Your drink, sir.
- And your change.
- Keep the change.
Thank you very much.
Happens all the time.
Waiters, taxi drivers, they all
try it on. I find it quite amusing.
You see, I can tell the difference
between a five and a ten.
- How?
- I fold them differently.
Short for a five
and long for a ten.
Cheers.
What are you reading?
Numerology.
Are you amateur or a professional?
Oh, I might be
professional someday.
- When were you born, Mr.--
- Leonard.
Alexander Leonard.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
Vincent, Charlotte.
How do you do?
So, the fox in the mink?
Cool as a cucumber.
She's gonna take the poor bastard
for everything he's got.
Well, that's my flight, Charlotte.
Thanks again.
It's my flight too.
- Oh.
- May I give you a hand?
You want to help me?
What's the procedure?
Very well.
I take your arm and you lead.
Your heart is beating so fast.
Why is that?
Oh, I was a little nervous...
that someone might
show up at the airport.
Oh, don't worry.
On the arms of a blind man...
is the safest place for
a beautiful woman to be.
Sir, sir!
You forgot this!
The eye which is reflected
to the external world...
is also the mirror
to the soul within.
- I didn't.
- Beauty is in the eye of the beholder.
Where the hell have you been?
You go shitting through a tea towel.
- You've got to speak to the boss.
- Stall for me.
Look, tell him Paul Hugo now goes
under the name of Barry Grible.
He spent a week in Montreal, and then
he went to Seattle with a girl.
He's on his way to Rome now. I'm on him,
but the plane's about to board.
I'm gonna send you a sample, Hil.
I want you to run
a fulI DNA test on it for me.
- It's a pubic hair.
- Not until you tell me what's going on.
Nothing's going on.
I'm close, that's all.
Don't do this. I'm not putting
my ass on the line again.
Look, this is not about the kid.
Hilary, look, this is legit.
Hil. Hilary.
- You son of a bitch.
- That's my girl.
So I'll send this to you today.
It should reach you by Thursday.
I have to go, Hil.
Well, well, what is this?
Mr. Leonard.
I tell you, it wasn't me.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Even so, it's lovely.
Step.
Here, let me feel it.
- Is that it? lt's a mere trinket.
- It's very sweet.
- I have a much bigger surprise for you.
- Oh, my.
An old friend passed away
leaving me with this eyesore...
and l've been scratching my head
wondering what to do with it.
And what do you
intend to do with it?
Do you want to bean
amateur all your life?
What can l say?
It's fantastic.
So do we consider
ourselves partners?
If you insist.
Like I said, if you like her so much,
why don't you talk to her?
- I don't talk to anyone.
- You talk to me.
- You're not real.
- Oops. Time.
He loves her...
and he's going to
take her away from you.
Not if she does him in first.
You're jealous, Daddy.
And you're not!
I here by declare Charlotte's den
of astrology and numerology...
offiicially open.
- Did I get it, darling?
- It was perfect.
Okay, this is it. This is the last
l can do. Then you fill the report.
So it looks like your
sweet little hair came through.
- What?
- The DNA test.
She's got a record.
- When did this come through?
- Yesterday.
- Yesterday?
- Hey, I'm on the line as it is.
- So cut the crap.
- I'm sorry.
Just pipe this one through.
I'll wrap it up and owe you my life.
Just name your price.
That's more like it.
Thank you.
Okay, so here comes.
- There. How'd you go?
- Oh, Hil, marry me.
I'll need everything you've got
on this probation report.
Was that aproposal that l heard
just pass through your lips?
Next of kin.
Joanna Eris.
- Charlotte.
- Good morning, Mr. Leonard.
- You're early as usual.
- Good morning to you, Miss Vincent.
Now are you ready to be dazzled
by my fine wines?
I can hardly wait.
Dazzle away.
You're leaving.
- I'll be back in a few days.
- No, you're not.
You're leaving me again,
just like last time.
I didn't leave anybody.
Your mother left me.
Then take me with you.
No, I can't.
It's too important.
You're running away again.
- I'm not running away.
- Me and Mommy, you hate us.
- Oh, for God's sake.
- You're abandoning me.
I didn't abandon anyone!
She took you away from me.
She took everything away from me.
If you don't take me with you,
I won't ever come back.
I have to go.
Dreams of striking gold.
But, of course, that didn't happen.
The fact was, he was a loser.
Probably the most adorable loser
to ever walk the face of the Earth.
So Mom left.
In December, a guy came and...
had the power shut off.
I was nine years old.
It was Christmas.
We went for a walk...
roaming the streets like
a couple of homeless people...
watching others shop,
looking at the lights.
He sang to me.
I wish you bluebirds in the spring
We sat some where
to rest for a while.
I wasn't stupid.
I knew l was gonna see Christmas...
from the back alley
of a shoe store.
But still, I was totally
caught up in spirit of things.
I wanted to get him something,
give him some thing special.
But when l got back...
he was gone.
It was Christmas Day.
I never saw my daddy again.
I never saw him again.
I'll always be here.
I love you.
I love you, Charlotte.
Don't leave her.
Don't leave her alone.
First we are processed.
They take everything away.
We lose our personal possessions.
Everything except our own shoes.
They want us to wear
our own shoes...
just to feel a little bit at home.
Then we make ourway
out into the yard...
where we will meet
our fellow in mates...
and the first thing
they're going to do?
They're going to take our shoes.
So, come on then.
Take off your shoes.
I mean it.
Take off your shoes!
- Dr. Brault.
- Can I help you?
You were in charge of the probation
exchange scheme during the early '80s?
If you would contact my offiice--
I'm investigating a former resident.
Could you spare me a few moments?
Who are you investigating?
Eris,Joanna.
- Cognac?
- Please.
She did fine with the foster homes.
The theft was nothing more than
a youthful dare-- there you go--
that certainly didn't amount
to 12 months' detention.
That's where the real damage
was done.
She tried to kill herself
several times.
Stuck her hand right through
a plate glass window...
and attempted to hack it off.
Did you know that?
Cigarette?
And after her release
she came straight to you.
They all came to me.
I was federal probation chief
at the time.
The whole exchange program
was my idea.
Remove the girls from
their familiar environments...
unearth them, probate them
where they had no roots.
Well, it didn't work.
It just didn't work.
After a couple of years
it became a very costly blur.
The girls were all unmanageable...
ignorant, demented female hoods.
All, that is, but...
Joanna, number 8773.
Joanna Eris.
She was unique. I had her
immediately transferred to Boston.
- For your own personal supervision.
- Mm-hmm.
Forgive me for asking,
Dr. Brault.
Are you wearing a wig?
Does she still wear wigs?
One of the little tricks
I taught her.
Never reveal yourself to any man
who doesn't need to know.
Now you need to know.
And what other little tricks
did you teach her?
I taught her to survive, to fight
and never let the mother fuckers in.
Survival of the fittest,Joanna.
Kill or be killed.
Was she ever
sexually molested by a man?
- Not to my knowledge.
- Were you?
All right. That's enough.
Get out.
- Detective, my ass. Who are you?
- Miss Eris is in a lot of trouble.
- I'm someone that's trying to help.
- What?
To find out where
the trouble started?
Now you think you've got
a pretty good idea, is that it?
Who the hell do you people
think you are?
This girl came to me a weak,
pathetic little field mouse.
You hand me the problems,
never the solutions. Get out.
-Jan?
- Yes. Come on in, girls.
God bless you for your time, Doctor.
Keep up the good work.
- Get out. What is it?
- Are you all right?
Of course.
Of course I'm all right.
pisces.
familiarity breeds contempt.
Time to end the holiday
and get back to work...
remembering to tie up all
loose ends before you move on.
Your search is far from over...
as your true companion still
waits patiently in the wings.
Oh, no, no, no.
Why don't you just take out
a fucking advertisement?
I've always wondered what it took to
contain a large family, and now I know.
Stamina.
- I'm exhausted.
- That's just one side of the family.
- Look!
- I never look. What is it?
It's a skunk. That's about the best
sign of good luck you'll ever have.
Only when the stars are right
and the moon is full.
How's the moon?
It's full as a bull, old-timer.
So how will we celebrate
our good fortune?
A simple ceremony...
here or St. Boniface.
Nothing too elaborate.
Quaint and charming...
for, say...
800 of your closest friends.
Now, call me old-fashioned, but...
isn't it I who should
pop that question?
Well, technically, yes.
But why would you think
a lovely young thing such as myself...
would want to tie the knot
with a blind old coot...
who's rapidly approaching
his "use by" date.
Not to mention the fact that
you're a Virgo, Mr. Leonard...
and I know you better
than you know yourself.
And ofcourse, there's always
your fortune that I'm after.
Why, Charlotte?
Why me?
Because you can't see
who I really am...
and I think it's in the stars.
Very well, Miss Vincent.
I do.
Until tomorrow, then, my darling.
I love you, Mr. Leonard.
You know, I never did
buy you that pendant.
Of course you didn't.
Take care of her, Roy.
I know you're there.
What do you want?
Open your eyes,
you stupid blind bastard!
She's gonna kill ya!
Come on!
I'm taking you away!
What are you doing here?
It's early.
Come on!
We're gonna get married!
- What?
- We're gonna get married!
Now?
Mr. Leonard, I think I have
something to tell you.
Congratulations.
You're kidding me.
That's fantastic.
I'm gonna be a father?
Congratulations, Daddy.
Stop.
Please stop.
Stop. Stop.
Please fucking stop.
Everybody stay back.
Back!
Let me go!
Get off me!
Get off of me!
Yea, though I walk through the valley
the shadow of death...
I will fear no evil...
for He is with me.
Looks like your cigarette lighter's
run out of gas, princess.
Hey, how are you?
- How are you?
- A little car trouble. Can you help me?
I sure think we can
take care of that.
I'm sure every man and his dog
has tried a line on you.
Has anyone ever told you
you have very sad eyes?
Yes, they have, Gary.
Has anyone ever told you
you need a shower?
That's a pretty mean-looking shark
you got there, princess.
It's a fiish. pisces.
Looks like a shark to me.
You like sharks?
I like the myths.
They have a limited memory.
Maybe only a minute or two.
Sounds like a pretty good life to me.
Ofcourse, the down side is...
they can never stop swimming.
Even when they're asleep...
they have to keep moving forward.
because if they stop
for even a moment...
they'll die.
- Fuck me dead.
- What?
Nothing. I was just--
I was just saying you could lay
your dentures on my bed side table...
any day of the week, princess.
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing.
Forget it.
Stupid bitch.
What are you doing
in there, princess?
You haven't started without me,
have you?
Princess is in the middle
of her ablutions.
Fuckwad.
I wish you bluebirds in the spring
A little surprise on the dresser
near your purse, princess.
Just for you.
A little dart action, you know?
You see, there's this bar just off
the one-five out of Baker...
where they have these
English dart champion ships.
And there's this guy.
And I bend over...
to pick up his girl friend
who's sprawled on the floor...
completely fucking smashed...
and the fucker hits me in the ass
with this yellow feather weight dart...
right between the cheeks.
Can you believe it?
So what do I do?
I nail him to the bar...
and use his head
for a fucking dart competition.
What's all this stuff?
That's just a little something
to get the evening started, darling.
Thanks. I'll pass.
No. No, don't.
It's just for fun.
I don't want to have to blast alone.
It's not my thing.
You go right ahead. I'll watch.
You'll fucking watch?
Ladies and gentlemen...
step right up
and watch the freak show...
and see for the first time
in this country the amazing pin cushion!
Treat yourself, folks.
treat yourself and watch
the bearded lady...
cut herself to ribbons.
Come on, baby.
Baby fell down.
That's a good baby.
Here we go.
Welcome to heaven, princess.
No milk today, thanks.
Thankyou!
Now piss off and mind
your own fucking business!
Yes?
Don't leave her.
She's just a little girl.
Don't leave her alone.
I'll never ever leave her.
Ever.
Cross my heart.
Hope to die?
Forever and ever.
Amen.
What the fuck is this?
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck?
Get me the fuck out of here.
Motherfucker!
Fuck it!
- The car! Where's the fucking car?
- Morning there, partner.
Sound like you had
a little fun last night.
Where is she?
I said, where is she?
She went north
about a half hour ago.
You gonna pay for them rooms?
- Hil, honey?
- Yeah.
We've got our lost dog.
Better late than never.
Christ.
I've got two guys in Boston
pulling the place apart.
What the hell are you doing
in Utah?
I've lost the Hugo kid, Hil,
and l need some help.
- Could you put an ASU out on all--
- We've been trying to tell you.
Hugo and his wife bought it
in a car accident a month ago.
So it's finished. It's over.
You're coming home.
The boss is dead.
Jesus, I've been worried sick.
How the hell are you surviving?
You know me. Lucky legs.
Could you put an ASU out
on all hospitals for me?
A woman may try to register
under the name--
For God's sake, listen to me.
Listen.
Hugo had ended the whole case
over to the Feds months ago.
So it's over. You're coming home,
and that's an order.
Will you do
one last thing for me?
I'm not authorized to.
Fuck authorization, Hil.
I'm in trouble here.
A woman may try and register into
hospital under the name Eris or Leonard.
This is an emergency, and the last thing
l need no ware the fucking Feds.
Will you help me, please?
Look, I can't fuck
this one up as well.
Please.
I'll see what I can do.
Hello, there.
Hello. Yoo-hoo.
Hello.
- Pardon?
- May I help you?
Yes.
I've just flown in to visit
a friend of mine, miss Joanna Eris.
Oh, good!
I'm so glad somebody came,
it being Christmas and everything.
She's down the hall in 36...
although she's probably
asleep by now.
You know she lost the baby, don'tyou?
Who was he?
He didn't say, dear.
But he asked for me by name?
He said Joanna Eris?
Yes.
He said he was a friend.
- What did he look like?
- Like a sales man.
They all look the same to me--
sales men, reporters, photographers.
They get your names from the registry
and come to sell baby products.
That's a roger.
Will wait till further notice.
Standing by.
Got any change?
Come on!
Fucking come on! Come on!
Buddy, you got a buck?
Miss Eris?
Federal police.
Would you mind coming
with us, please?
- Why?
- We'll explain in the car.
In the car, please.
Two, three.
Morning, Nellie.
- I'm ready when you are, darling.
- Get over it, pal.
It's not gonna happen.
I'd like the omelet
with herbs, please.
- The what?
- Omelet with herbs.
You shouldn't have to ask, Nell.
We're gonna install a bed here for him.
How are you, Frank?
- I'm good, Lizzie.
- Good.
So you come in a lot?
Last couple of weeks. You?
Have you been here long?
I don't know.
Couple months.
Side dishes?
- Taurus?
- Yeah.
- Do you believe in the stars?
- Not anymore.
pisces reads...
"It may seem you have reached
the end of your road...
but all is about to change.
The sacrifiice you are about to make
will become another's salvation."
And then it says,
"You will never be forgotten."
- Do you want some coffee?
- Yes, please.
I'm bust in at the seams, Frank.
You don't mind sharing, do you?
All done, gentlemen?
- Who gets the check?
- I got it.
Coffee?
- What do you think?
- Can't say for sure.
- Worth a try, though.
- Yeah.
Fucking cops.
What about them?
You can always spot them.
Didn't notice.
I don't know what time you're finished,
but I'm coming back later...
and I wondered if may be
you would want a drink.
I'm working a double.
Thanks.
Watch the alarm.
Raccoons keep setting them off...
and I sure ain't coming down here
at 4:00 a.m. to reason with them again.
Night-night.
Night, Frank.
I said, night, Frank.
Night, Lizzie.
I'm in real estate in the valley.
That's why I can help you
get a house.
Getting a house isn't a problem.
It's easy enough.
What do you do in a house...
when you wake up in it?
What do you do on Christmas...
in a house?
I'm supposed to be so...
young, and not have anything
to show for myself...
except a big sense of loss.
That hardly fills up a house.
What have you lost?
I've lost my childhood...
my youth...
my father...
my husband...
my daughter.
She wasn't any bigger than a minute.
Barely had a name.
Now my mind's going too.
It plays tricks on me.
And spookiest of all,
I lost my angel.
I had a guardian
who looked after me.
I think I miss him most.
My angel.
Maybe he'll come back someday.
Come back and bury me
in my favorite grave yard in Valdez.
It's not up to us, though.
Is it?
It's up to the gods.
The whole thing is.
What have you lost?
It's only fair.
This one's my daughter...
I think.
She was an embassy kid
and was relocated--
or dislocated is, I think,
the word that they used--
every ten months.
I simply came home one day
and she wasn't there anymore.
And seven years later,
I stopped looking for her.
The thing that gets me the most
is that she had no choice.
She simply woke up one morning...
and didn't have a father anymore.
So I'm just a daddy
who lost his little girl.
And I guess you're a little girl...
who lost her daddy.
And that's it.
End of story.
Romeo, we're real crowded today.
You're gonna have to share.
What can I get you?
Coffee.
That's it?
For the record, Lieutenant,
I think this is a very sick scenario.
Nobody's accusing
anybody yet, Doctor.
Just tell us what you see.
Okay. Here we go.
That's not Joanna Eris.
We have reason to believe it is.
Be very sure.
I'm telling you, it's not her.
I'd really like
a chance to try again.
And I wouldn't waste your time.
I'd make it worth your while.
It's not a waste of my time.
It's a waste of your time.
I don't know how much more
of this place I can take.
- I get off in two hours.
- I can't wait.
I could drive the car around the back
and we could go now.
I'll meet you out back
in fiive minutes.
Come on, come on, come on.
Have a seat.
What did you say you do?
Real estate.
It's a pretty tough business up here.
It's a pretty mean business.
Snow means money,
and I'm suspicious.
I think that's why
I spotted the police so quickly.
I think they had the place staked.
I wonder what for.
They're probably gonna arrest somebody.
Probably one of the regulars...
or one of the staff.
Would you like a drink?
I only have cognac.
I never touch the stuff.
I've seen you someplace before.
I don't think so.
I've been around
a long time, though.
Someplace else.
Have you ever been to Florida?
Couple of times.
Everybody looks like
somebody else, huh?
Mywife was born in L.A.--
What are you doing?
Don't do this to me.
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
I know who you are.
You took my picture...
at the museum.
I wish you love.