Many adults go into foster parenting
with the idea that love conquers all.
"They think," If I can
just love this child enough,
he or she will come around."
But this isn't always the case.
In this audiobook,
we will be dealing with how best to care
for a foster child
and guide you through the issues
you are likely to encounter
as a first-time foster parent.
- You go get up on that hill.
- All right.
A good way to establish a
bond with your foster child
is during the ritual of the family meal.
Dude, did you catch me
throw that sick whip?
Whoo! Ha!
Did you just jump over a bathtub?
Yeah, man.
Damn, dude, that was insane...
Yeah, hey, post that shit on my channel.
A major challenge with teen children is,
sometimes they've been touched by trauma
they neither acknowledge nor
know how to talk to you about.
Tony, where the hell is that tractor?
What's up, Helen? Just
pushing a car off 90.
Why the hell does everything
take forever around here?
Small town, boss...
- I figured you would be used to it by now.
- Light a fire under his ass.
- I'm gonna get a smoke.
- Yeah, make it quick.
Hey, let me borrow your phone.
- Why?
- Just a quick call.
You figure out what this is about?
Is it drug-related?
All I know is, Stig's
got someone in the trunk,
and we're going off turf to make a kill.
- Who? Who's in the trunk?
- I don't know.
It's some job for hire.
What if they want me to kill him?
Don't. Sit tight.
- I'll track you.
- No.
I'm not on my phone.
We're at a gas station near Tivoli...
Grey four-door, Maine plates.
Chris.
You find a glory hole? Come on.
Thanks, kid.
Uh... ugh.
Only one.
Don't drop it.
Nice.
Oh, come on.
Are you kidding me?
Thanks.
Damn.
Hey, how many hits I get?
Uh, 22... In less than five minutes.
That's not bad, actually.
No, damn, that's good.
Any comments?
Rose says that you're "dope."
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
You know that kid Tommy at school?
He has a DSLR. I'm gonna borrow it.
The resolution on it is so sick.
It's so much better than this.
I mean, sponsors are
gonna flip out over this.
Really? It's that good?
Yeah, yeah, it's amazing.
I never had footage this good.
I mean, it's... here.
I mean, you're amazing.
I mean, you're awesome.
What the hell you doing?
Nothing. I'm not...
Okay.
So, uh...
So I... I got a ton of
air on those jumps, huh?
Yeah, but...
you know, those whips aren't easy.
I didn't say they were.
I thought you were into motocross.
No, I'm not, actually, so...
Hey, now... hey, hey.
Hey, sit down. Sit down.
Wait.
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
What if someone sees us?
Yeah, like a squirrel?
No one's gonna know about this,
because you're never gonna tell them.
Hey.
Are you kidding me? I'm not doing that.
Sorry, I just...
everyone in the city carries one.
You've done this before?
Yeah. It's okay.
It's okay. It's fine.
Shit, it's my dad.
Chris, trunk. Check the area.
Check the area for what?
Shut your mouth and do what I say.
These guys are gonna shoot you...
I've got a gun in my belt...
- ... you with me?
- Yeah.
Chris, get him out of the trunk.
Come on.
- Who are those guys?
- I don't know.
Want a hand, or what?
Get under the bed, now!
Come on.
Set him down.
Get the door.
This ain't right.
We got to figure this out, man.
What? Relax.
Damn it, Stig, this ain't right.
We can't be doing this.
Jesus, Chris, I'll do it.
Move!
Dude, it's cool, man, all right?
I'm with the FBI.
Please...
Damn it, come on.
We got to go. Let's go!
Dude, get the bike, go. Get the bike!
What are you doing?
Listen to me. We can't
say anything to anyone.
Are you kidding me?
He was gonna kill us.
Who would blame you for killing him?
You don't get it! I'm not gay like you!
No one even knows we talk, got it?
It's him!
- Is that... is that a deer?
- It's a deer.
- We got to tell Helen.
- Tell her what?
We were in the cabin, naked?
No! Never gonna happen.
Okay, well, I won't say anything.
He was gonna kill me. If
you hadn't stopped him...
If you hadn't...
Let your little inner chimpanzee out.
Come on, me and you. Right now.
- Good?
- Yeah, very good.
Mmm.
Philip's sleeping inside.
Yeah, that's the best
thing about having a kid.
You get to sneak around.
- I should make him breakfast.
- Come on.
We can pick something
up on the way to school.
No, I want to.
Meals are supposed to be the best time
to bond with your kids, right?
Sorry.
Me too.
- Hey, babe.
- Yeah?
Don't be mad.
He's probably just
trying to make friends,
but it looks like Philip
snuck out last night.
Well, they warned us
he might not be ready.
He's only been here for six weeks.
We all need time to get adjusted.
Went straight to voicemail.
Mm, 'cause he's in the city with her.
What, you're tracking Philip's phone?
That's probably not the best
way to establish trust, babe.
Yeah, well, maybe not, but
he's our responsibility,
so we'll get him.
Slow down. He's with his mother.
Exactly.
Why don't we just wait and see
if he catches the bus back...
- in time for school?
- Why?
The court said no
visitation till she's clean.
Yeah, but look.
We're offering him a better life.
We can't make him forget about his mom.
There's some dead guys in my cabin.
What?
Who? How many?
I don't know. I mean, it's a mess.
- They're all shot up.
- Really? Okay.
Um, I'll... I'll come check it out.
You be careful, babe.
Yes, I will.
I'll call Tony.
- And you get Philip.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Philip, honey?
Honey. Hey.
Hey.
You can't be here.
- If the judge finds out...
- I'm done.
I can't go back.
I can't go back there.
It's okay.
I want to stay here with you, Mom.
Just a little... a
little bit longer, honey.
But I...
I'm getting better.
I swear it, baby.
You always say that.
Honey...
this time it's real.
But if the court finds
out that you've been here,
then they're never
gonna let you come home.
I know.
Um, I brought you a little something.
A little gift from the boonies.
I love you.
Love you.
Is it, um...
Gabe and Helen?
Are they treating you good?
Yeah, they're treating me good.
It's not them.
Tell me nice things... about you.
School, love life...
What?
Oh.
Oh, my God, you got to tell me.
What's her name?
Lukas.
Does he know that you like him?
He knows.
But he wants to keep it a secret.
It's real ugly over there.
Nothing I want you to see.
So for now, the quarry...
I don't want you riding
over there anymore.
Okay, Dad.
You're good, though, right?
Yeah. Yeah, Dad.
Step aside, please.
Kamilah Davis... FBI.
So what do these guys have to do
with your investigation?
They're Vescovi's.
They were making a play
to distribute heroin.
Chris Petronelli.
Does that ring a bell?
No, these guys are foot soldiers,
so not our priority.
I'm gonna need to log that wallet.
You got much trouble with
the Vescovi's in Tivoli?
No, I just hand them speeding tickets
when they're passing through.
Well, you might want
to keep it that way.
Well, I'm gonna need to
question them about this.
- Nope.
- Vescovi ring's off limits.
And how am I supposed to
investigate in the meantime?
There's nothing to investigate.
You know how to set up a perimeter?
Thanks.
Hey.
It's Chris.
Kamilah...
Chris knew what he was getting into.
- Now we need to bury this.
- I know.
The Bureau finds out that we let our
only informant get killed,
- I could get suspended.
- Oh, really?
Because if the Vescovi's find out...
that Chris was informing on them,
then my sister's dead.
- Look, asshole, social
services is gonna take my baby
unless I show 'em my
husband's pay stub by tomorrow.
I told you, Chris quit yesterday.
Rudy, slip two.
That's bullshit. I dropped him off.
A couple guys came to see him.
Next thing I know, he was gone.
- Hey.
- Hey!
- Were they Vescovi's?
- Yeah.
Hey.
- Hey!
- What?
Now you write me a pay
stub for Chris Petronelli
so I can keep a roof
over my kid's head.
- Do it.
- Okay.
Hey, you forgot this.
Uh...
- You okay?
- Yeah.
It was Anne's birthday.
Really?
Yeah, she's all alone,
you know, I didn't want to miss it.
Your mom always made such a big point
of telling me we're both Capricorns.
That's mostly in January.
She doesn't have anybody.
You guys got each other.
You don't really get it, you know...
I'm sorry, one second.
Sorry. Tony?
It's okay; it's just the way she is.
- Uh-huh.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Damn it, I have to go help
Tony with those three bodies.
Babe.
I'm sorry, Philip.
Um, what happened?
There was a shooting.
Um, where there, um... who died?
It was three gang members,
no one from around here.
Philip, you can't tell anyone anything
about Helen's work, okay?
What is it?
Nothing, it's just, um...
seeing a dead body sucks.
You've seen one before?
Uh, I got to go.
Bye, Philip.
So, Helen, are you okay?
You know, I was at the crime scene,
standing over the dead bodies,
and I...
I felt, for the first
time in a long time...
I don't know, since I moved here...
the sense of something...
of meaning and purpose,
and it just felt good.
Come on.
I didn't mean it like that.
Okay.
Hey, Philip, if you still
want to borrow my camera,
- I need some collateral.
- What?
I don't know, your jacket.
Oh, um, yeah.
- Cool, thanks.
- Okay, cool.
Hey, Helen said she found
three bodies in the cabin.
Wait, you told Helen?
Wait, what? No, no, no.
Listen to me.
There were four guys
in the cabin, right?
Yeah, so?
Yeah, so then why did Helen
only find three bodies?
Hey, who's your new friend?
Get out of here.
What if somebody survived?
Lukas,
listen to me, all right?
Okay.
Hey!
Okay, break it up!
Get off, bitch!
Get off! You're a goddamn freak!
Back! Back! Enough.
_
- Hey.
- Tony?
Big day, huh, Helen?
- Triple homicides and FBI...
- What is this?
It's our first murder board.
Uh, well, my first murder board.
I mean, you've...
You didn't have to do all this.
Hey, that's what partners do, right?
What exactly are we partnering on?
The case.
I kind of figured that you
might need back-up out there.
Listen, don't get excited.
The FBI want me to back off.
They say that there's
nothing to investigate.
- Are you serious?
- Mm-hmm.
Damn, I went all the way to Red Hook...
to get these thumb tacks, too.
We have thumb tacks.
Yeah, but they're white.
I wanted a color code, see?
Look, I even put, like,
different colors...
- for each victim.
- Okay, partner.
Did you fill out the homicide report?
I'll have to co-sign.
Um, okay, I couldn't find those.
We've never had
a murder here before.
Here you go.
Uh, I have never looked
in this drawer before.
Okay, you know what?
You know what I think?
No, don't think until
you fill out that report.
I think that the FBI folks
think that we're small-time.
That's because we are. Stop.
Give me that pen.
Sign it again.
Chris Petronelli had
calluses on his left hand.
Yeah, maybe 'cause he did construction.
Yeah, or maybe 'cause
he was left-handed.
Will you go get me those
traffic citations...
from the back of my Jeep? Thank you.
- What's up, Philip?
- Hey.
Hi, Philip.
I heard what happened at school.
I just, uh...
just got into a little
thing with this kid.
It's... it's fine.
Yeah, you okay?
Yeah, um, you busy?
No. No, sorry...
You don't want to see that.
What's going on?
Uh, I just...
I just wanted to tell you that, um...
that I didn't mean to
lie to you and Gabe.
About your mom?
- Mm-hmm.
- I know it's tough,
but sometimes there
are rules for a reason.
So you gonna send me back?
One minute.
I'm sorry, what?
Nothing, I'm just... I'm kidding.
Mind if we talk about
this tonight at dinner?
I'll cook.
Make you whatever you want.
Mmm, I like Chinese takeout.
You got it.
All right, what you got?
Shoot, this signature doesn't slant.
What you mean?
Well, I can't tell if he's left-handed.
Those guys are usually strapped.
I'm sure if Chris was left-handed,
he'd have a lefty holster.
Good call, Tony.
I'll go to his place... check it out.
Hey, uh, bad time, buddy...
Helen had to head out.
You, uh... you want a ride anywhere?
Back home or anything?
Chris, pick up the phone!
_
Pick up the phone.
Shh, it's okay. It's okay.
Yeah. It's okay.
Sheriff Helen Torrance. Can
you open the door, please?
Is this the home of Chris Petronelli?
No.
Then all these people
got the wrong address too?
Very sorry for your loss.
If I could just come in for a minute,
I have a couple questions for you.
I don't know anything.
Chris didn't mention any
plans the night he died?
Was he working for someone?
He's getting cold.
Is this... can I just ask,
is this Chris's hockey stick?
Was.
And he got pissed,
and he just started punching
me, so I had to defend myself.
- And, like, it wasn't...
- Doesn't matter who started it.
It doesn't matter, Philip.
It takes time to adjust to a new school.
And this isn't just new for you.
I mean, I've...
I've never done this
parenting thing before.
Why are you guys doing it now?
Well, Helen and I, uh,
wanted to give it a shot.
Together... a family.
You could have adopted...
like a cute, little,
chubby baby or something.
Gabe's family fostered teenagers...
when he was growing up.
And, um, did you still see them...
after they aged out?
I still see them now.
That's cool.
That's good.
Listen, Philip, I'm sorry I
left you in my office today.
But you more than made up for it.
You brought home Fang Chow.
Yeah, I did.
How many points do I get for that?
Um, food's hot... It's not burnt.
Excuse me?
I'd say it's a swish from half court.
Yeah, like Steve Kerr.
Uh, that was about 20 years ago, babe.
More like Steph Curry with the shot.
Okay.
Well, if it makes you feel any better,
I don't know who either
of those people are, so...
Sorry, guys. Hold on.
Yeah, Tony?
I found something on the surveillance
at the gas station.
That Vescovi guy, Chris...
Yeah, he was talking to some kid.
Looks like he borrowed his phone.
Great catch.
Find the kid, and get that number...
that Chris dialed for me that night.
Okay.
Wait, how did you think
to check the gas station?
It's the last place
to piss for 30 miles.
Thank you, Tony.
Well, that must've been important.
Sorry.
Philip, what were you gonna
tell me in my office earlier?
Um...
my mom... the judge...
He said that he might give us visits...
if she got into rehab.
You think she's ready for that?
Yeah. Yeah.
Great. Let's work on it.
Mm. Wow.
That was really nice.
Mmm.
What time do we have to be there?
Oh, we got time.
Shit, he's back.
Nice.
Hey.
Come back to bed.
_
Hello, this is Kamilah.
- Hello, Kamilah.
- Who gave you this number?
Hey, babe, remember we got our meeting
with Phil's principal this morning.
You want to ride together?
Nope, I just have to
stop by the station first.
I'll be right behind you.
Is that about the case?
No, I just have to
sign off on the budget,
but I'll see you there.
9:00.
Hello?
You know the old car wash on Route 9?
Yeah.
I'll see you there in an hour.
So what's to discuss?
Told you it was a one-off.
Yeah, you also told
me Chris Petronelli...
was a foot soldier you'd never met.
Yeah, that's right.
So you want to tell
me why he called you...
an hour before he was killed?
Someone walked away from that cabin.
Well, the FBI didn't
find any evidence of that.
Well, that's embarrassing,
because I did.
- Chris is a lefty.
- So?
So why is he holding his
gun in his righthand...
unless someone placed it there?
I think the killer is still out there.
If there is a killer out there,
are you gonna be the one to find him?
What is that supposed to mean?
Just figured you wouldn't
be up to the task...
you know, after Buffalo.
Dr. Caldwell?
Come on...
Sita, you pulled a gun on the foreman...
while you were holding your baby.
Don't! No, you can't take him!
No, please, don't! No, get off me!
No, no!
_
What the hell are you doing?
Oh, are you gonna hit me again, huh?
What the hell were you thinking
talking to me in front of everyone?
That doesn't matter anymore.
The guy... he was barefoot.
What?
One of the guys on the murder board...
he was barefoot.
That means he's dead.
Yeah, one of the other guys...
must've just lived and
then passed out, right?
Yeah, but the guy who saw us...
he's dead.
- He's dead?
- We're safe.
- Yeah, we're safe.
No. I can't.
What?
I can't believe what's happening.
You're into me. That's what's happening.
Just deal with it.
No, no, no. No one knows.
So what if they do? Who cares?
I care.
You don't get it.
I don't... I don't want to be that guy.
And my dad... he doesn't
want me to be that guy.
And Rose...
No one wants me to be that guy.
What if you are?
You don't know me.
I know that you're just some...
some spoiled-ass rich kid.
But you know everything
'cause your mom's a junkie?
Okay, you didn't have to say that.
Sorry.
Neither did you.
My dad's in Poughkeepsie tonight.
No. No.
- No, no, no, no.
- Huh?
- No!
- What?
No, no!
I'm not gonna be your little bitch.
- What?
- You got Rose for that.
You can't hit me in the face,
not want to be seen with
me like I'm some freak,
and then you want to fool around.
No, no.
No, you got to decide.
What's there to decide?
All right.
Flat.
Synced and corrected by louvette
www.addic7ed.com