- I caught Olga rummaging
through my papers. I was upset!
- Look at the shot.
It's amazing!
Borg had a serve
that was very good.
Watch the slow motion.
Of course it is good
We've gotta hurry if you don't want to
miss the beginning. Damien, away we go
Pierre?
- Yes?
- You are coming?
- Yes.
Olga!
Securely close it behind you
when you are leaving...
...OK?
Good evening!
Look at your sister!
You've seen it also?
There has been some progress!
- Yes!
- Bravo!
- Bravo! Bravo!
- I'm sure I left the car
open. I'll go check.
- Are you crazy! Hurry up!
*- The match between Borg and McEnroe
just ended.
* Borg won the match...
- It is still finite, Borg!
- Damn!
What are you doing in my car?
- Your back door was not closed.
- I was told that I would
find you in your car
- In French.
Look ahead.
It will appear more normal.
You never know.
How is Jacques?
- Good. Very good.
He told me to tell you...
...That the French Embassies in the
countries of Eastern Europe...
...are open,
to you and your family
- But I do not want to leave!
This is my country here.
Now, I have some important
things for you.
15 top leaders of
the West have...
been working for us...
for a longtime...
You see,
your classmates in the DST will love you.
- I don't work for the DST!
- You don't work for the secret service?
- Of course not...
I work here in Moscow,
for Thomsons.
Jacques is my boss.
He just asked me to tell you,
about the embassies.
- That's unbelievable!
They sent me an amateur.
It's very French...
Is that what you are saying...
- You really want to stay in Moscow?
- I will not flee like the others.
It's pathetic!
I'm not afraid to die.
My country needs me.
I can change the world.
Tell Jacques I don't want
to talk to anyone.
What I have done, should be worth
something to guys like you.
- I'm going to leave you, because my daughters
show is something else.
Lock the door before going out.
Good evening.
What a jerk!
They are nothings, those French!
Igor is back?
- In his room.
It has taken...
...A warning.
- Why?.
- He has treated Brezhnev old fart.
- What is
the story with Brezhnev?
- All right! It doesn't bother you.
- But not in public, you idiot!
There could be some trouble.
- Excuse me! I do not want
hurt your brilliant career.
- Don't speak to me in that tone of voice.
Go...
I have things to do...
- What are you hearing?
Western music!
Don't worry, go!
Your friends have closed the shop.
Bye bye, Queen!
- I heard about the job in
New York was about to be open.
- It will not be easy.
There's lots of people on the list.
But it's not...
...For now. Ah, here it is.
Pierre Froment..
...Our engineering student
stationed in Moscow.
Maurice Vallier, DST.
- How it happened...
...Moscow?
- I told him the truth, I
did it just to help you.
He wants to talk to a professional.
Your guy is a pathological liar,
who thinks he can change the world.
- This man..
...is a colonel.
Colonel Grigoriev.
He was born in Moldova,
he did his studies...
.. in Moscow, the KGB and used its
influence at the university.
He occupies a key position.
Everything goes through him.
He has become indispensable
in processing information.
Anyway... we didn't expect it.
And the list of names
he gave you...
.. Is unprecedented
since the beginning of the Cold War.
Voila. Anyway, thank you...
...for your help.
- How are you...
...do things, now?
You will contact him yourself?
- Certainly not!
The KGB had a file on me. It even has
Grigoriev, who was posted in Paris.
- Given the turn of events,
we will regain control, the...
Excuse me, I am tired.
Goodbye, gentlemen.
- Au revoir.
As expected...
...French elections
have had an upset.
Mitterrand was elected
with 51% of the vote.
Apparently he intends to take
Communist ministers...
...In his government.
- They are supposed...
...to be his allies.
Margaret Thatcher
is opposed.
- Never!
I will not let them do that.
We cannot count
on the French!
Our relations with Moscow
are very tense...
...and we must be losing an ally!
You were where? It has begun!
- In each store,
at the bottom of every court...
.. Behind a window,
there is a granny...
...One of our brave babushkas,
Simple and discreet...
...But note...
...that no one had seen.
Let's drink to our babushkas...
.. Our true sentinel...
...Against attacks..
...imperialists!
Applause
Let me introduce you to...
.. Our new rookie...
.. which is far from being a babushka...
Alina Samarova!
- Thank you!
- Girls, a little less chattering...
...and work more.
- who are happily marching together?
- Our column pioneers!
Gaily, gaily,
Always the right place.
Leninist Pioneers.
The Leninists come.
- Be ready!
- Always ready!
- Be brave!
- Always brave!
- Hay!
- I thought.
...it should work...
...together. Paris
sent someone to see me.
From the airport, we knew who came.
It will never work!
- Are you sick or what?
- There is no danger.
Nobody in the KGB is interested in you.
You are already in Moscow,
Your assignment folder is empty.
or almost.
You could avoid marrying...
...a former East German.
But hey!
She went to the West in '57.
She was 8 years old.
Have to go.
Make some copies of the documents
and bring them to me...
...to the Novoslobodskaya station.
on Thursday!
- No, but... wait! Wait!
No, but it's incredible!
- Shh!
The plans for the shuttle Columbia.
It's crazy!
Look, the notes
by the Russian researchers.
They believe that the fuselage
will not avoid overheating...
...when it starts the descent
in the atmosphere. Look!
The route of French nuclear submarines
for the next 6 months!
Damn!
- But why?
Why you?
- I know, me?
Maybe they mistook me
for someone else.
- We must get rid of all that,
fast! It is not possible.
- Wait, this is very serious.
- Be quiet!
- We will not throw...
documents we can only dream of...
agents of the West!
It's not your problem.
I married an engineer,
not James Bond.
- Perhaps I can ask
Jacques if...
- - What will Jacques get on the inside?
- He provided occasional services
to the DST
- What?
- I know that over the past three months...
- Your boss passed along messages for the
Secret Service, and by chance...
.. there was Russian tote in your car
with secret documents..
You are not telling me everything, Peter.
- You think we're all spies
here at Thomson?
Jacques does what he wants with the DST?
I see nothing in all this.
- I sure hope so, because we
in the lion's den, Moscow.
If you do not want
endanger your family...
.. burn it all and forget everything.
Forget it!
- OK, you're right.
Tomorrow, I will get rid of it all.
- What is the level of the source?
- Uh... Level One.
We believe that the source
will continue to be engaged.
We have planted
a cell within the DST.
- Why is the DST dealing with this matter?
- The source was stationed here in Paris...
...from 1965 to 1970.
and it was during this time
that we made the approach...
we sent a signal...
...there was three months.
If this case is assigned
to our colleagues operating abroad...
...we will lose contact.
The external espionage services
are infiltrated by the KGB.
The Russians have infiltrated...
the DST...
because it seemed unnecessary to them.
We do not have to intervene
outside the national territory.
- Glad to hear you say that,
Mr. Director.
Continue to follow this case...
...and report to me
personally...
because I agree with you on one point
the fewer people involved..
.. the Better.
I can provide a cover for you while I can
count on your loyalty...
.. and my respect.
- Mr. President, I have devoted my life
to the defense of the interests of France.
- You can go.
- Mr. President.
What did he put at the...
...top of the document?
One moment.
- The code name of the source...
..."Farewell", which means "farewell".
- And why not "Farewell?
- The Russians...
...think like the CIA, it will allow us
gain a little time.
- Come in.
- The United States cannot accept
Communist ministers...
...in Western Europe...
...Or in any free country.
- So I ask you,
in the interests of freedom...
...We meet...
.. To review the makeup of
your government.
- I was elected by a free people...
.. On the basis of a platform
I will implement...
...and I will fight...
...all forms of foreign interference
to guarantee to the people of France...
...the freedom to choose their own destiny.
Without interference...
...in American affairs,
I think...
...I'm a
sincere ally of the United States...
.. and I bring this to your attention.
A top-level source
sent us this list.
There are fifteen U.S. citizens
working with NASA, the CIA..
Pentagon...
and the White House.
Everything indicates that they have a
direct link with Moscow.
- Now, between the two of us
you know...
I was going to do a film with Ford..
it never happened, due
to a mix-up with the studio.
I can't remember any more
- Mr. President,
it's getting late...
- I do not trust Mitterrand.
He is just making waves
to buy some time with his Communist ministers.
This Farewell business.. This is bogus.
- I sincerely hope, sir.
If this proves to be true...
- The last two names on this list.
I want to know them before I get back
to Washington.
The last two names?
- Not a word to Feeney about this!
- If he found out
I was snooping behind his back...
He may be the CIA boss,
but I'm the boss of the United States.
- Ah The Pentagon!
It's good, eh?
I've put the...
.. plans...
...of Air Force One
It's funny.
- for your consideration.
How you doing?
For the documents, all that
they asked me was how much you want.
- you will become a little spy.
Suspicion.
- No, I can assure you the contact will
will find another solution in a while.
So, how much you want?
- Money, money!
What I can give you is priceless!
- I will tell them.
- Keep your money...
...And bring me some cognac and
champagne in Paris
They will all ask about the
bottles in my office.
That will be the day
there will no longer be...
birds chirping
- It is not easy to
speak in Russian?
- I like to speak French.
and who I can talk to...
...If not you?
- It would be more practical, anyway.
The next time
I'll bring the champagne.
- You French are chauvinists.
So are we.
I got my engineering degree here...
in 55.
And my son Igor will be...
...an engineer here also.
You are always in love...
...Your wife?
- Yes, of course
- We all love our women,
but in our own way.
You can return to Igor...
...Johnny Walkman?
- "Johnny Walkman"?
I don't know that.
Sony! A Sony walkman, no?
- Yes... Walkman.
- Yeah.
- Maybe Sony.
And the group...
Cassettes of the
American group "The Kin".
- "Kin"?
No, Queen! They are English.
Queen.
We will, we will rock you
- Perhaps, yes.
- You don't know?
- You like that?
- Yeah, that’s fine.
- Me, I love Ferré.
- Ferré, that’s good!
- What poetry!
And can you also bring me
some French poems?
And cassettes by Ferré?
- And a hundred balls
and a salad Nicoise, too?
Look, I'm not Fnac!
Your departure and arrival times...
...are written in a notebook
by the guys in the booth.
And then there are two men
in a Lada...
who followed you...
when you were driving.
- And the cleaning woman who searches
the apartment when no one is around
- But people who watch...
...are not amused.
If you're nice to them...
...They will like you a lot
and they will never suspect anything.
Next week
same line in the subway.
One last thing!
- What?
- The French residence...
...Is bugged.
You know that, I guess.
Yes, I know.
- Especially in the ceilings
So if a guy does not intend to be
with his wife in bed...
...he has a girl in his sights,
and there are possibilities, then...
...kiss his wife,
it is the only way to keep the peace.
Funny, eh?
- No, it’s not funny.
Pardon Me
I can't
because of Igor
and also because of Serge. I...
- You can't spend your life
sacrificing yourself for others
You're unhappy, Natasha.
- Enough, start!
Démarre,
We can't be seen here!
I'm tired of lies.
- Think of yourself first.
No,
we have no new name...
- ... But the source has provided us
with some very important documents.
What kind of documents?
*- They include air defense plans
of the United States.
* I am looking
all radar positions...
*... installed on your territory
since 1976...
*... your coded procedures
to trigger an attack...
*... in case of enemy air attack.
* In the margin, written in Russian...
*... he has the keys to engage
you at the same time.
* I also have the codes
to get into the White House...
*... schedules of companies
delivering food and clothes.
* as well as the Codes
used since 1959...
*... by your embassies
to communicate.
- I see.
Someone is coming
I thought
.. that you would not come.
- I think it is a mistake.
- Me too.
- Smile!
Remember your own wedding!
Shoot me with them! Voila!
- Of course, comrade
I am a professional photographer..
- Get closer.
A smile!
Thanks
- It's a good dream, communism.
- Yes, happiness flows
in your streets.
People are uplifted with joy.
- It's difficult to realize,
that dream.
You know what state
Russia was in '17?
The Middle Ages.
And after 40 years,
it was first...
...to send a man
space.
The first!
Today
the system is totally plugged up
We must blow up the system.
That's why I am giving you
all this information.
When the Soviet bloc will no longer exist
You loot, everything will fly...
...and there will be a new revolution.
I don't see that,
But Igor, my son...
...it will be alive in him.
That is it, my reward.
- Speaking of Igor, I have taken back
the things you asked me for.
A walkman.
with some cassettes...
...by Queen.
And a Léo Ferré for you.
- That's nice.
- For the book of poetry...
...I've taken
Lagarde and Michard one.
A school book...
...being used for the shelf.
It's the 19th.
You Baudelaire, Mallarme...
You'll be amused with that.
- I can't accept it.
It is a personal book, right?
- You're not serious.
It was thrown in a closet.
My wife would use it more.
- But she doesn't know...
...you gave it to me.
- If, of course.
- we quickly learn...
...a lie, eh?
I too am a lie.
And lonely. You, you should talk
Jacques has it all, has other...
But me...
Je n'ai que vous, Pierre.
You were on vacation?
- Yes, for 2 weeks.
With my parents in the Vercors.
- Oh.
- What is there?
- Holidays
were introduced in France...
...by a communist government.
- You are trying to piss me off?
- A little.
*- The little cat...
- The little cat...
*- Fled...
- Fled...
*- In the park!
- In the park!
What?
*- Will attack him!
- Will attack him!
*- Who left...
- Who left...
*- The door open?
- The door open?
- Well done!
- Let, let! Oh
It’s our fault!
No, but let me do it!
- Peter!
There's someone looking for you.
- Continue.
I'll have...
...a glass.
- I'm coming!
- You asked Jacques
to come here?
- There is something to clear up
on a file.
- A file on what?
- You're doing it again?
- I apologize.
I imagined a bunch of stuff.
- It's not serious.
Go! Where is it?
I would...
To thank...
again the CIA...
...in the person of Mr. Feeney,
its director...
...for this valuable collaboration.
If I may, Mr. President...
...I'll continue in French.
Thanks to the last
information from Farewell...
...We can see the global
Soviet espionage system.
The KGB is not the only
ones spying on us.
Every business in the East...
...Science Academies,
and even smaller...
participants in...
a trade show...
...are involved.
And all these networks send
routine information...
...that is centrally...
...reviewed by a body
we didn't know...
...even existed: The VPK.
- How many agents...
...Work in this agency?
Who's in charge it and since when?
- I don't have that reliable
information at my disposal...
...that would allow me to answer you.
- A long time ago, wee too heard about the...
VPK... for some time.
It's like the
Loch Ness monster!
- This is why you decided
we should never talk.
- Good, continue...
Mr. Director
- We have calculated...
...that the Russians spend more...
...For industrial espionage
than they do for their own research.
They take the risk of looking...
...But they want to
buy insurance...
they will find something
and it costs them dearly.
The looting is over 40%...
...of their overall budget
in the arms race.
- Well...
That's incredible.
Are you sure?
- Sure.
- 40%?
Can you imagine...
...the sums at stake?
It doesn't make any sense.
To feed the enemy good information
to hook them
...then dish out a lot of baloney...
...Is an old tactic.
But you know...
- Absolutely.
But Farewell is the finest
source of all time...
...Mr. President.
- I was given this to give to you.
There's a second...
...If the other fails.
- The Minox?
Is it from the CIA?
They're involved?
- No, not really.
but they know that the DST
has a source in Moscow.
They know your identity,
as well as mine.
- Why are they asking that?
So far it has been
going very well without them.
- Here are the detailed photos
taken under any conditions.
While photographing
documents on the spot...
...and no more lugging them away!
- Someone from the CIA
gave you these devices...
...So now they know
who you are, who I am!
- But no! It was Jacques who
discreetly passed them along in France.
And I've stashed them
in a little train for my son.
Voila! Okay?
I'll stop everything.
It became too much for me.
It's a big operation.
It already had a code name: "Farewell".
It was back on track
until Mitterrand and Reagan
I can't stand lying to my wife.
I am doing it more, it disgusts me.
Then we'll stop seeing each other.
Now, I know
what will happen. They will tell you
- You are arrogant,
pretentious and pathetic...
...You, the people of West!
It's me who decides how and to whom,
I give...
...what I want! Tell those idiots at
the DST they will change...
...Nothing!
Nothing!
Nobody buys me, never!
Enough!
- You are busting my balls!
Me too, I will decide!
It's over for me! I will not
throw away my life and my marriage...
...For reasons of state!
Good luck and so long!
- Not so fast!
Where are you off?
What were you doing in this car?
Your papers?
- Kind of stupid!
What a moron!
That's not possible!
Go! In the car!
This is my cousin from Leningrad!
It is dumb.
You're angry, I know.
But we will finish this story, Peter.
Both of us.
Soon, a large file
will come into the hands of the service.
The X list!
Bingo!
- What's the story?
- This is the X list.
This is the cream of creams.
The best agents at the Embassy / the Consulate.
You provide the X list...
It's killing the system.
You know the favorite poem
of your wife?
- I don't have the heart for poetry,
- "The Death of the Wolf. "
By Alfred de Vigny.
- What's the poem about?
- A couple of wolves with 2 little ones,
had been raised by the poet and his friends...
The pups were slowing them...
...And the hunters approached quickly.
So the male stopped...
...to wait for the hunter.
and the mother fled with the pups.
obviously, the hunters
killed the male wolf...
...who died in silence.
In silence.
You scared?
- Yeah, I'm afraid.
I am afraid for my children,
for my wife and for me.
Even with diplomatic protection.
- Diplomatic Protection?
To me, this will be the special treatment.
- And for you...
...It's a truck.
An unfortunate accident.
Watch the road.
- Drop me off at Smolenskaya station.
It will be easier for you.
- You will follow me?
- Not worth it.
I asked Jacques for your address...
...Your phone number, a photo
of your wife and your son.
Me too, I know a
lot about you.
When you finish this last case,
agree to stay in the West.
In time the dust will settle.
Then you will come back a hero.
- In their eyes, I'll always be a traitor.
I do the dirty work
nobody wants to do.
Until Thursday.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
Drop by.
The two women can talk.
- Hello Igor!
- It's a Good day?
- Are you interested in what I am doing,
now?
A super day!
We studied...
the benefits of the FYP
under Khrushchev...
Solved...
differential equations...
...discussed poverty in New York
and there were some potatoes at lunch.
Everything is great!
- Who's the lady with your mother?
She came to see the puppies,
after seeing the advertisement.
- Serge. Have you seen the book
on dog breeds?
Sergei!
- The book on dog breeds?
- I put it away the other night.
- Where?
- Look under the sofa.
"Who's the woman with mother?
For Shame!
- Listen Igor... with couples
there are times...
- Stop the bullshit...
...Agree?
You are lying to me...
...You lie to mom
you lie to everyone!
It is your nature!
A professional distortion!
Leave us outside
all your lies, okay?
It is the cowards...
...who lie!
And the traitors!
- Let me see!
Have you gone completely mad?
Sit down.
Don't touch me
Don't touch anything
- Don't worry, I will say nothing
But you can give me some more lessons.
Get out of my room.
Someone is coming.
- You're mad!
You don't know..
- I couldn't help it.
I had to find out where you live...
...It is how it is,
it’s how she talks to you
...it’s how you live...
together!
I couldn't resist it.
- Everything is going too fast.
Let’s take just a little time...
...to let things clear up.
- Serge. please forgive me.
- I don't understand.
- Forgive me for the awful thing
I've done.
Serge. I want to be with you always...
...whatever happens.
Super 8 Projector
- Hello.
What is the problem?
- Hello, Comrade Captain!
Yesterday, my wife and I
got home at 4 in the morning.
There was nobody here...
...to record our return
in your notebook!
Excuse me
but I think it's serious.
- Bring the book.
- What about the documents
while I'm away...
...While I'm here,
talking to you!
- Yesterday, we were short staffed
at the embassy level.
Exactly.
It won't happen again,
I assure you.
- I trust you, Captain.
Let’s forget it!
Wait!
Look! I bought the cognac
for an office party.
Drink to your health.
- Thank You.
- What are you doing?
It said it was in your car.
I've brought you what you wanted
for Christmas.
- I did something stupid, Peter.
I have a mistress.
My son knows and Natasha does too.
- It's not very serious. It happens.
There's ups and downs.
- My son hates me now.
It is very important to him
I'm taking risks here.
- Why didn't you tell him
the truth?
- He never listen to me.
More so now than ever!
- You have nothing for me?
The X list?
- Patience.
That will be very soon.
- In the library...
...there is nothing interesting.
In the room
my wife left at the side of her bed...
...the plans for the French Alliance
next month.
Show it to your leaders.
It will make a good impression.
Agree?
- Be careful, it's fragile.
- We have to be careful our whole life...
Careful
- The street is blocked
we can't say why
Ten years of memories
destroyed
It is what we want
Without having to choose
So sad
It's is a lost cat
believed to be found
It's a dog more
than world we know
It's a street name
Where will ever I'm on
So very sad
- Oh!
- When the cop yells
* And he doesn't know
that you are sick
and on the way home you
casually
Turn on the TV
And look distracted
A Zitrone hurry
To speak of tiercé
That you have not played
Melancholy
It is seeing a beggar
At the council room
It is to see two lovers
reading the newspaper
It is to see her mom
sick each time we meet
*Melancholy
This Garbo review
In "Queen Christina"
This Charlot review
back in Chaplin times
- What's up?
- I saw you in the park today
with a man.
You are pathetic.
Totally nuts.
You have been lying to me...
...right from the beginning.
And I can't take it.
I'm leaving.
I lost confidence.
And I must protect
our children from everything
No, leave me.
- Four times I have delivered
documents to the West.
I photographed them.
And I took the film to Paris,
like any tourist.
I never had a problem.
The photos are being studied
at the Elysée.
Then the White House.
For the first time, it is possible
things can really change.
But I told Jacques
it was over, that I was finished.
It makes me sick
that I have had to hide everything and lie to you.
I have an ulcer since summer.
I know, I should have explained it
but I couldn't do it without risk.
But I was a coward
I preferred to lie to you.
I completely screwed up.
I will love you always.
Let me be with you.
I will ask Jacques for a post
New York, that will be open in two months.
And I will get it, believe me!
I'll never have worry about
keeping anything hidden from you.
I promise you, never again!
- You don't even ask me
what I think of New York.
- You're the one who wanted to go
New York, from the start!
Look at me.
Viens.
- What are you doing?
Nothing
Anatoly was...
...who I made my report to...
...on French Arms.
You know...
...what he did with it?
- He released it to the meeting.
Weren't you there?
- Go to the meeting...
...it’s getting late in the morning.
- We haven't seen one another,
nor talked for a very long time, Serge. I...
- I have had a lot of work
now.
But let us do it Wednesday night.
We need to talk.
- What is wrong with you?
What is wrong with you?
- His father, during the war...
...commanded a division of the SS
Mine was a simple cook,
at the back.
But I'm better than him.
Right?
The other day
...they were all excited in my office...
...And he asked me, "Alina,
What is the meaning of "farewell"? "
I explained it
and he said:
..."I learned French
so I could have a cushy job...
..."And they got mixed up
with the English! "
- I will tell him the joke,
Anatoly was brave.
- What are you gonna do?
- On Wednesday?
- On Wednesday.
Ophélie! Ophélie!
- It's over, Peter.
The X list is...
...In your pocket.
We won.
When you return from Paris
we'll drink champagne.
- I never  listen to music much.
- watch out for the paranoid
They listen to
everyone, especially in Paris.
- Jacques, my wife
is a nervous wreck in Moscow.
She is cracking up because of all this.
We gotta go.
The position of New York will be open.
It will be New York.
- I am not deciding alone.
- We will listen.
The X list.
- Complete?
- Yes, complete.
I'll convince Grigoriev he
has to spend with his family in the West.
I just need to know
how it will happen.
- You are crazy!
New York, you see,
but to have it happen...
...it's a source in the West that Moscow
happens to like.
- Yes, exactly!
From the beginning, we
only to play by our skin.
So that's enough!
You must assure me of
my safety and that of Grigoriev.
Yes?
- Paname
Me me it is your eyes and your lips
That I want to kiss right
- Where you find
French songs?
- Leave me some secrets...
- Paname!
I'm going...
...to Leningrad
in two weeks.
They are looking for
an French interpreter.
You will never leave your wife
or your family.
I understood I was going home.
You're a little loose...
...Like all married men...
...Sergei...
Hold me in your arms...
...And then take me back to my house.
- Good...
Now, between the two eyes.
- Not bad...
...Eh?
- It makes you want to see the whole movie.
- I haven't had time
to arrange a screening...
...But I wanted to show you
this change...
...point of view.
It's a masterpiece.
Feeney came to see me this morning.
One of their moles in the KGB
identified Farewell..
- What?
- Don't worry.
They are only the only two
who know what the CIA has.
- Are the French aware?
- Well...
Feeney doesn't think we should tell them,
and I agree.
We know enough
to act without them.
- What will you and Feeney do?
- Wipe out their X List
then play poker!
It's more fun to bluff...
...When we know that the adversary has
a pathetic hand!
- You are completely right,
Mr. President.
It's a new game.
We'll have to strike hard.
- Ten, nine, eight...
...seven, six, five...
...four...
*- Mes chers compatriotes...
*... merci de partager ce moment
avec moi, ce soir.
*J'aimerais vous parler
de sécurité et de paix...
*... sujets aussi fondamentaux
que cruciaux.
* Avec nos alliés...
*... nous avons su contenir
une guerre nucléaire pendant 30 ans.
*Cette approche stable,
au moyen d'une menace offensive...
*... a bien fonctionné.
* After consultation
my advisors...
*... I think there is another way of
* countering the threat
Soviet nuclear missiles...
*... by defensive measures
placed in Earth orbit
*There are risks and the
results will take time.
*But I think
we can do it
* When this step...
*... I ask for your prayers
and to support me.
* Thank you, good night,
and God bless you!
Amen!
What do you know?, the KGB?,
these "defensive measures?...
"placed in Earth orbit?
- there have been leaks
in the American press.
They nicknamed this project...
..."Star Wars".
- Tell me.
- Unfortunately
we know nothing more.
We have lost almost
all our sources of information.
But it is only temporary!
I ordered an extensive investigation...
...Which is moving very quickly.
- To establish
our own "Star Wars"...
...How long will it take?
- 10 years. Minimum!
- Thank you,
...Comrades.
- Andropov asked to
go to Geneva.
He is not ready. I
will see Reagan.
I will try to convince
to renounce...
...this project, but...
he will go after...
...especially today.
Because it has been well known...
...we have no way
we can monitor them.
The country is
in a critical situation...
...particularly dangerous,
Comrade General
The country must
take a deep breath...
...find new energy,
otherwise it will sink...
...Into chaos.
For the country, more than ever...
...needs reforms.
Urgent reforms!
The door is closing.
*- What are you doing?
*- How?
*- Get out of here!
* You want a coffee?
*- Not after noon.
*- It has been dark for a while.
*- You told Natasha
I am in Moscow?
* How is she?
* In the last letter...
*... she wrote
it's very hard for her.
I am so stupid! You know all that!
You've been reading?
I think...
...we will find...
...she and I...
- they are clever, these Americans!
Take on an identity as lovers...
...of French culture.
Tell me...
...who was your contact
in the American Embassy...
...and what did you give him
Specifically...
...you can save yourself.
Tell me.
- "But the children of the wolf...
..."played in silence...
"... Not knowing that on two...
..."only half asleep...
The door opens.
"Behind the walls...
"their enemy. "
"But the children of the wolf
played in silence... "
- Coming back to the point.
You're here because your friends
betrayed you, Grigoriev.
You're all alone!
Think abou my suggestion...
- "He looks at us again
Then he lies down again...
..."While licking the blood
spread on his lips. "
- Goodbye!
- What did you do?
- Nothing.
They think I am someone who is...
*... working for the Americans...
* They will find out they are wrong.
Do not worry.
Igor didn't come?
- He is in school.
He'll spend the morning
- Don't cry...
...my dear.
And straighten up!
- If you tell them everything,
they will let you go home.
- Is that what he said?
- Forgive me, please.
Please, forgive me.
- You too
You really want
I come home?
Yes!
- Madame...
- Hey!
- I beg you.
I am a friend of your husband.
I'm French.
Where is he? He is suffering?
- My husband has nothing to do with you.
The dismal KGB traps!
Shame
- This is not a trap.
I can help you.
- Let us be!
- I am a French residence.
- Leave us be!
- Madame!
- Have you searched the parents room?
- Not yet, I'm going.
- You looked everywhere?
- Go check the sons room.
- Okay.
- Come here, please.
- Putain!
Is it an obsession with you?
- What?
- Never
- I must find out.
Tell me why my father...
...Finds himself in prison because
of the KGB, why these guys...
...dig into our affairs.
What the hell is going on?
- When was he arrested?
Why? How is he?
- Answer me.
- Putain!
- Answer my question!
- Igor...
You know nothing about your father.
- I want to show you something.
- The owner of the book
knows...
...That you can not
give it back soon.
Mlle Jessica Zimmermann.
An uneventful file.
Today Ms. Wheat was married...
...to Pierre Froment...
...two children, move into
the French Residence
- What...
...This story in poetry...
...in your handwriting...
In Russian and French?
What's this?
- I took this book these people had...
...during a literary evening
put on by the French Institute.
I liked this poem: "The death of the wolf".
I had an idea that, with these verses,
I could create...
...a code.
A brilliant new code.
- Are you kidding us!
- Want to save time, right?
I have lots of time.
You'll tell me everything!
- "The Covenant Cities...
...is the name I gave
to my syntax.
"Never enter into a
pact in the cities...
..."as man did...
..."in bonding with domestic animals. "
- At 8:15 this morning
he left on foot, alone.
His wife needed the car,
so he took the subway...
...and promised to return by 19h.
- You followed?
- All reports are formal,
there is nothing in the French.
- - And his wife?
- Around 9 am, she left
with children in the car.
She was buying clothes
for the children.
- Did you notice anyone following you?
- No.
We got rid of the Lada
because of no staff.
- Then voila!
The airport is your last chance.
You will see
if the French are leaving!
- They had called. The device
is in place. They won't fly it.
- He has promised
back at 19h.
- I am the skin...
...If they spin.
- "I'm skin... "
- Everything will be alright.
Don't worry. Where you going?
Come back!
Stay the in same lines.
don't move!
Never anything at the airport.
They are stashed somewhere.
They are playing hide and seek.
- By the road!
- What?
- They are heading
to the Finnish border!
- 800 km to the north?
Would you leave in mid-winter
with two children in the back?
- I don't have any children.
- Your papers.
- Good evening.
- Where are you going
and why?
- Alexe. i.!
- Don't move!
- Your license is not signed.
- It's true! I will do it.
What happened?
- Someone has been trying to
cross the border.
- Go ahead.
- Thank you, goodbye.
- Stop!
Thank you
- Go ahead.
The door opens.
The cubs have fled. Saved.
- Igor and Natasha knew nothing.
Absolutely nothing!
Anyway...
...Natasha had never accepted it.
She hates lying.
You know very well.
- Let's stick to facts.
- I do not want to die
like the others...
...shot in the neck.
- It is not for you to decide.
- Of course it does.
Nothing...
...As never before,
for a long night comes.
Without sacrifice
change is not possible.
The country needs change
to survive.
- The country will change
thanks to you, Serge.
Apart from your statue at the Kremlin
do you want anything else?
- Thank you for coming, Igor.
I think...
...All these times
when I wanted to chat with you...
...But you,
you locked yourself in your room.
- And now...
- Stop Daddy
What will happen,
now?
- Everything will change.
The world will change.
It will not be easy...
...but you are young, intelligent.
You'll find your place.
- Dad... for you.
What will happen to you?
We will make arrangements with Gorbachev...
...and others.
We found...
...a common ground.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Separate them!
- Get him out of here soon!
- Papa!
- My son!
Please.
- The free world owes you a lot,
Mr. Froment.
He doesn't know,
and he must...
...especially not learn that I...
For then, he would discover
that almost all...
Western strategic places...
Were known to the Russians,
for a long time.
People lose confidence
in their institutions.
No democracy can exist
without the confidence of its people
None.
- Trade Grigoriev and his family.
That's all I ask.
He won't say a word,
I know him well.
And he must...
...Much, no?
- Such an operation has no
chance of seeing the light of day.
- You're making fun of people.
You railed against
the Western democracies...
...But you let a man die
because it suits you.
I understand.
If Grigoriev speaks on this side of the wall
...You will be thrown out.
Grigoriev didn't try
to save himself.
He has a little more class.
- Come here.
Come.
This man called Shukhov.
Head of the KGB.
We then transferred the entries taken from
this NATO database.
He has been working for us since '78.
We approached him
when he was stationed in Ottawa.
He was disappointed with the Soviet system,
Brezhnev and his cronies.
The perfect profile.
Like Grigoriev...
...But with a Swiss bank account.
He taught us nothing
that was very interesting...
...But last Christmas,
everything changed.
On December 24,
He tried to resume his affair...
...With the wife of Grigoriev
at his place of work.
It failed. He was dejected...
...he left the military museum
and saw Grigoriev in the park.
with you, M. Froment.
From that moment on, we knew...
...What Farewell was.
how he operated,
disregarding...
...elementary rules of espionage.
It was so reckless...
...it was above suspicion.
We asked Shukhov to arrange for the  Russians
to find out who, Farewell was.
The KGB had started...
...An internal investigation that seriously
threatened all our sources...
...of information.
So, yes...
we gave them Grigoriev. It was
like throwing a dog a bone.
Adieu Farewell.
In that way, we could save...
...The entire network.
And we didn't forget you,
Mr. Froment.
The DST had no one the spot.
asked us to get you out.
On March 4, your cleaning lady...
...you gave a signal,
at the request of Lt. Colonel Shukhov.
...you managed to escape...
...having serious problems.
Try to forget this story.
It's better for you,
your marriage and your ulcer.
New York...
...is waiting for you with open arms.
East 72nd Street...
...A few steps from Central Park
and French school. You'll see...
...the earth, life is sweet...
...For young affluent couples,
without problems.