Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Nicole,
save some hot water for your dad!
- Mr. Walker.
- Larry.
I've eaten meaner dogs than you
for breakfast, you wimp!
- Did you get the tickets yesterday?
- Huh?
- The Pier? James Taylor?
- Oh, shit!
I'll have Eddie
get 'em today.
- What?
- Nothin'.
Dad, you're looking at me like you
didn't know who I was or something.
No, no, no. I was just thinking
that maybe you'd...
like Laura to take you
to buy new clothes.
What she's got on
is brand-new.
- This is new?
- Yeah. Why? What's wrong with it?
It looks like something you wore
when you were 12.
- Yeah, so?
- Look.
All I'm saying
is that it's... it's...
What? I'm not allowed
to have an opinion?
No, Dad, you're allowed to do
whatever you want to do.
I'm the one who has to ask
permission to breathe.
Can I go to school now, Father?
Have a nice day, Nicole.
Does that count
as quality time?
- Good boy, Kaiser.
- Drink all your juice, sweetheart.
- Congratulations. I heard you won your game last night.
- Spanked 'em.
- I bet that made your dad happy.
- He doesn't really watch the games.
He's too busy trying
to pick up chicks.
I gotta go.
Could you drop me off
at school?
The Mustang's way cooler
than Mom's car.
Please, Dad.
- Okay, hurry up. Get your stuff.
- All right!
He called me "Dad. "
- Morning, Eddie.
- Mm-hmm.
The Sweikert project
went to the bad guys last night.
- You're shittin' me.
- Wish I were.
We're on thin ice here, pal.
Vancouver or bust.
Show me the drafts we got.
I'll create the presentation myself.
- That's what I wanted to hear.
- We shouldn't be doing this.
We're just gonna have to turn around and
come back the second we get there.
Yes, but we can say we were there.
Factor in the residual coolness.
Sorry. Mr. Keheela had to stare
at my boobs for 10 minutes...
before he'd give me
an extension.
We should just get
something to go, guys.
Nicole, chill. What do you want
to remember five years from now?
Being on time for English Lit
or having a life?
Well, let me see.
English Lit, life.
- English Lit.
- Shut up, Gary.
Come along and take a ride
With the one
that's got a life
Just leave
your cares behind
Right now it's party time
Come along and take a ride
With the one
that's got a life
Just leave
your cares behind
- Right now it's party time
- Yo, get up, stand up Put your hands up
In the air like you just don't care
You can put down your gun
- Ooh la la!
- Yes?
- Smoked turkey and gouda on a roll.
- To go.
Ow-oo!
So pretty? Davey,
you see me hole that?
God, stop being so obvious.
What do you wanna eat?
Um, just some
chocolate cake, please.
- To go.
Swing and a miss. You're outta
here, buddy. Batter up, Davey.
Come along
and take a ride
With the one
that's got a life
Just leave
your cares behind
- Right now it's party time
- Ah-ha, whoo!
Winning is
a good thing, man.
This is what
we're gonna do
We'll leave the guns
and the knives at home
We'll only get busy on the microphone
with no static
- "King and Occidental"?
- I'm there.
- Down by the docks?
- Yeah. So?
- Better bring your Uzi.
- That's $8.75.
- I got it.
- Come with me.
I can't. I've got a family outing.
James Taylor at the Pier.
- Yikes! Isn't he bald?
- Probably.
Gotta go, guys.
Margo, come on.
All right, all right.
It won't stop
It won't ever quit
'Cause wild-ass kids
are for the bids
Sick and tired of
killin' one another
Each man teachin' one
that we'll all be brothers
- God, I'd bet it'd be a rush.
- You wouldn't really do it.
Why not?
Who wouldn't want millions
of guys fantasizing about them?
- It's power.
- It's nuts.
What, it doesn't
feel good to be wanted?
Hey, what about Jason Fuller?
He wants you bad.
He doesn't want me.
He just...
I don't really know
what he wants.
Every time I go out with him, I feel
like I should be paid for baby-sitting.
Come with me tonight. There's sure
to be something going on down there.
I told you, I gotta
do this family thing.
I'm leaving now. There's food in
the fridge and money on the counter.
If you need to reach me, I'll be at the
St. Francis under Vince's name, okay?
- Okay, Mom.
- Be good. Love you.
- Who's Vince?
- Some old coot in San Francisco...
with a potbelly
and a lotta dough.
He promised her a Mercedes.
Which means I get the Rabbit.
Don't you just love life?
Nicole?
Your father's here to pick you up.
Oh, yeah.
Life's just great.
- Dad?
- Daughter.
Is it absolutely mandatory
that I see James Taylor again?
When did you ever see
a James Taylor concert?
You, me, Mom,
summer of '85.
- Does that ring any bells?
- '85?
- You'd have been...
- Six.
That doesn't count.
I'm surprised you even remember it.
I don't think there's a thing
that's ever happened...
or not happened, for that matter...
that I don't remember.
You're the one
who blocks out the past.
Nicole, I don't
block out anything.
It just takes longer
to sort through 40 years of data...
than it does 16.
Maybe you oughta
consider upgrading to a faster chip.
You know, sometimes
you're pretty funny.
- I have my moments.
- It'll be fun tonight.
You, me, Laura. Toby.
Old memories, new adventures...
It'll be like real life.
Okay, my little sugar plum?
Okay, my little nectarine.
- Hey, Laura.
- Hey.
Want me to help
with anything?
Yeah. Uh, there's, uh,
fruit in the refrigerator.
- Why don't you get that out? Thanks.
- Okay.
- Mmm. Mmm!
- Mmm. Mmm.
- Mmm.
Get outta there!
I gotta change
and jump in the shower.
- Call Eddie first. He was looking for you.
- Whoops.
Come on. Not even a nice, schmoozy
conference call? Please.
All right.
What choice do I have?
I'll see you at the airport.
She's got this little chain she hooks
through it and wraps around her waist.
- What would Dad do if I got one?
- You know exactly what he would do.
- Bullet to the brain.
- Toby.
What?
I can't go to the concert.
I gotta go to Vancouver.
- Now?
- I have to meet the client for dinner in three hours.
Oh, Jesus, Steven.
We've been planning this for weeks.
- The whole thing was your idea.
- Honey, nobody wanted to go more than me.
- What would you like me to do about it?
- Keep your word to your family.
Oh, yeah? Then we can
just all starve to death.
- Spare me the melodrama. Nobody's starving.
- You were right, Dad.
It's just like real life.
Margo.
King and Occidental?
I'm with ya.
There's that guy
from Largo!
Let's go say hi.
Nah, I think I'll just be
over here, okay?
Hey.
Hi.
You're not dancing.
I know.
You aren't either.
- How come?
- How come what?
How come
you're not dancing?
Well, because
nobody's asked me.
Oh.
Come on!
Hey, come on.
Let's get outta here.
Logan!
Logan, come on!
Are you all right?
Yeah. How we
gonna get down?
I'll figure
somethin' out.
Hold on.
Come on.
I promise. It'll be okay.
It's safe. Come on.
Margo!
I'll see ya later!
Come on!
Go ahead.
Just let go.
It's safe. Come on.
Isn't this the car they stopped making 'cause
it, I don't know, blows up or something?
I guess that's why
I got her.
I saw her sittin' there all alone,
cold in the junkyard.
You know, it's not her fault
they didn't put her together right.
You just said that
like you really meant it.
I did.
I stayed with my real mom
in L.A. after my dad moved up here.
I was nine years old.
It was just the two of us,
all alone in this big house.
She was so sad most of the time that I
felt like I was the one taking care of her.
Must've been tough.
Yeah.
How 'bout your dad?
You get along with him okay?
I don't know. I only moved
up here about a year ago.
It's not like we even know
each other that well.
- Yeah.
- Hmm.
How 'bout you?
You have parents?
- I mean, that you see and stuff.
- Yeah.
They're back East,
but I talk to them all the time.
Are they still together?
They're weird, though.
I mean, they're totally cool,
totally together.
It's just that they've never had a
disagreement about anything more serious...
than whether it's gonna be
mashed or Stove-Top, or tea or coffee.
Kinda crazy.
- What?
- Nothing.
That was not "nothing" going on
behind those beautiful eyes of yours.
Tell me.
I was just thinking that,
you're not at all what I expected
you to be the first time I saw you.
How so?
I don't know.
You're just...
You're sweet.
What? You're the one
that's hiding something.
It's just that I was taught that if
something seems too good to be true,
then it probably isn't.
Yeah.
So far what I know about you
is you're beautiful...
and incredibly perceptive.
I just need to know like one flaw
so I can believe the rest.
- Got a week?
- Hmm. I got all the time in the world.
Oh. David.
I gotta go.
My curfew's at midnight.
All the time in the world.
David.
I'm sorry.
I guess
you found my flaw.
That's not a flaw.
That's one more perfect thing
for me to admire.
And respect.
And wait for.
The least you could have done
was call, Nicole.
I was sitting here for two hours
imagining God knows what.
Laura, I can't help it
if my watch broke.
I mean, how would I even notice unless
I was staring at it every second.
Go to bed, Nicole.
We'll deal with this tomorrow.
- Laura...
- I'm angry, Nicole. Just go to bed.
And take off your makeup.
You look like a slut.
- Mr. Walker.
- Larry.
So, 2:00 a. m.
Am I missin' somethin'?
Come on, Nicky.
Help me out.
Your were kidnapped
by aliens.
They tried to take you to their planet, but
you escaped and hitchhiked back from Pluto.
- So who's this guy you were with?
- Just a guy.
- Is he a good guy?
- He's good to his car.
You'd appreciate that.
Well, that's a start.
Maybe I should meet him.
I just met him. I don't know if
I'm gonna see him again.
Oh.
So?
Right.
All right, here's the deal.
Kitchen duty and yard work
for two weeks. No exceptions.
And no subcontracting out
to Tobias.
- Is that fair?
- Do I have a choice?
- No.
- I guess it's fair.
And... I want you
to apologize to Laura.
Yeah. I'll apologize to her when she
apologizes to me for calling me a slut.
You were too easy on her.
She should have been grounded.
She knows she screwed up.
It's all easy fixes
with you, Steve.
You give her whatever she wants, like
you're forever trying to make it up to her.
Please, Laura.
It's gonna blow up
in your face, Steve.
Everybody needs rules. She'd respect you more
if you laid it out and played it straight.
Straight, huh? Is that why
you called her a slut?
I said she looked like
a slut.
She had about two gallons of makeup on.
That's exactly what she looked like.
Shitty choice of words,
don't you think?
Maybe.
Love and hate
Get it wrong
Just cut me right back
down to size
Sleep through the day
Let it fade
Who was there
to take your place
No one knows
Never will
Mostly me
but mostly you
Do you say
Do you do
When it all comes down
'Cause I don't wanna come back
down from this cloud
It's taken me
all this time
To find out what I need
Yeah
I don't wanna come back down
from this cloud
It's taken me all this
all this time
You know, every part
of you tastes so good.
- Nicole?
- Yeah?
I wanna meet
your family.
- Really?
- Yeah. Will that be okay?
Yeah.
Dad, meet David McCall.
Mr. Walker.
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
Same here, David.
Hey, Toby, right?
What's up, big guy?
This must be
the savage beast Kaiser.
- Aah.
- That means he likes ya.
Yeah? Tell him
the feeling is mutual.
You know, you look bigger
than your sister described.
Or maybe you just grew
since yesterday. Which one?
So, David, you're not
in school with Nicole, are you?
Um, no, sir.
But maybe U-Doub in the fall.
I'm just kinda explorin'
my options, I guess.
Nicole, remember you gotta help me
plant these trees before you leave.
But I gotta get changed.
Well, you knew it was
one of your chores.
Excuse me.
It's Laura, right?
Hi, I'm David. I...
I don't wanna interfere, but it so
happens I work summers in a nursery.
- I'd be happy to give you a hand.
- Can I help too?
I couldn't do it
without you, partner.
Okay. Come on.
Grab the big one.
The main thing is the moisture content
of the soil when you first plant it.
These guys' roots are really sensitive
for about ten days.
Well, you certainly learned
a lot during your summer, didn't you?
Is there someplace
I can get cleaned up?
I don't know. Hard-earned dirt under
a man's fingernails can be attractive.
Maybe I shouldn't wash.
- It's in there, on your left.
- Thanks.
Oh, excuse me, Mr. Walker.
I was looking for the bathroom.
Uh, it's right in there.
- I'm not disturbing you, am I?
- No, no. Go ahead.
Thank you.
Did David come in here?
- I'll be right out.
- Margo.
Come on in.
Tell me about life.
Mr. Walker, I'm sure you know
a lot more about life than I do.
I wouldn't be so sure.
I get surprised at least once a day.
- That's the fun part, though, isn't it, Mr. Walker?
- Depends, David.
Kinda cuts both ways.
You just never know.
- Two minutes.
Those trash bags have to go out.
- You're not gettin' out of that.
- All right.
You should come with us
to the Orbit. It'd be fun.
- Nicole! Get me a Coke.
- Yeah?
Okay, I'll be right there.
Come on, Steve.
You could play pinball.
You could ride
the bumper cars.
You could do that thing where
you throw the ball at something...
and maybe win me a stuffed animal.
Or you could
just walk around,
eating cotton candy,
checking everybody out.
Hey, thank you.
You almost ready?
- Mm-hmm.
- I wanna get there before dark.
- We still gotta pick Logan up. Hurry, okay?
- Okay. Let me grab my jacket.
Okay.
David.
Nicole's curfew is 12:00,
not five after, all right?
All right.
Hello.
Yeah, Eddie.
Pleasure to meet you,
Mr. Walker. Take care.
No, I'm finishing them up
right now.
I'm gonna drop 'em off
at FedEx myself.
I'm not gonna miss it. It'll get there.
- Nicole!
- All right, Eddie. I'll see ya.
Nicole!
You let her leave?
- Steven.
- Why don't you get your helpmate to do it?
What, Eddie?
Childhood living
Is easy to do
The things
that you wanted
I bought them for you
Graceless lady
You know who I am
You know I can't let you
Just slide
through my hands
And wild horses
Couldn't drag me away
Wild horses
Faith has been broken
And tears must be cried
Let's do some living
Oh, after we die
Wild horses
Couldn't drag me away
Wild, wild horses
We'll ride them someday
Eddie, I'm sealin' the envelope,
I'm out the door.
What are you talkin' about?
The last pickup's not until 7:00.
I still got
half an hour. What?
Shit!
There you go, kid.
Take your best shot.
Bull's-eye will get you
anything on the wall.
- We got a winner.
- I'll take that peace pipe.
You look like a basketball player.
Take a shot.
I screwed up. I gotta
go back up to Vancouver.
Bye-bye.
I want you to come with me.
We could stay
in that same hotel.
Maybe even get
that same suite.
The number
of the hotel is by the phone.
So just rent some videos, call Domino's,
and try not to kill each other.
- I'll try and restrain myself.
- I'll sic Kaiser on you.
- Ooh-whoo.
- Ooh, I'm shaking.
Try and have a nice time, Nic.
Life is short.
Nobody in the house
but you and Toby.
- I hear you, Dad.
- Smile?
- Hello.
- David?
- Nicole, how are you?
- I'm good. Listen.
David, my parents went out
of town for a couple of days,
and I'm all alone
in my room.
- Nicole.
- Yes, David?
- I promised some friends I'd help 'em out with somethin' tonight.
- Oh.
- Um, okay. Whatever.
- But, Nicole.
- Yeah?
- I could come by afterwards.
- Would that be okay?
- Sure.
If it gets too late,
I might be in bed.
Okay? So just punch 1-4-3-2 into
the keypad and just come on in.
I'll be waiting.
Hey.
David.
Nicole.
I love you.
Please don't tell Margo.
Not that it's a secret or anything.
I just...
I don't know, it...
Are we talkin'
the "L" word here?
I don't know.
Whatever it is,
I definitely never felt it before.
Prince Charming
must be late.
- Do you want me to wait?
- No, that's all right. He'll be here.
David, what the hell
are you doing? Stop it!
Stop it!
What? Come on.
Go away!
Get away from me!
Just leave us alone.
Oh, my God. Oh, my...
- Who is it?
- Can I come in?
- Um...
- I, uh...
I thought of you when I saw
this in the hotel gift shop.
Oh, Nicole,
what happened?
I was in gym class. We were playing volleyball,
and I caught an elbow right in the eye.
Oh. Well...
Let's see
what we can do.
- Those are pretty shoes.
- Thank you.
Hey there. Doesn't your daughter look
exceptionally pretty today?
Uh-huh.
Oh, hey, yeah.
You look lovely, Nic.
Thanks, Dad.
I gotta go.
Can I get a kiss?
- Bye, Dad.
- Bye, Nic.
Thanks, Laura.
- What was that about?
- Woman stuff.
She got a black eye in gym class,
so I gave her a makeup lesson.
So she wouldn't
look like a slut.
Hey.
Talk to Travis Bickle yet?
I don't think I ever
wanna see him again.
Are you okay?
Did you see the look in his eye?
I can't get it out of my head.
Gave me goddamn nightmares.
I'm sorry, Gary.
I'm just so incredibly confused.
Hey, I'm a murderous
murder man
Comin' from a bad land
Real hard-core
Kickin' down
your front door
Let me get
what's comin' to me
'Cause if I can't use my mind
I'm gonna grab the...
Uh, we're here to see
a man about a dog.
- Does this look like a kennel?
- I, uh... W-We...
Woof, woof, woof.
All right, wait in here.
But don't be fooled. He's on red alert.
They're interested
in the dog.
Go tell David
we have to leave soon.
Holy smoke, Beaver!
Hey, man.
What the hell
you doin' in here?
- Not now, Knobby.
- Logan says we gotta leave soon.
Tell Logan I'm not goin'.
Oh, yeah? Well, he's gonna be pissed,
man. You've been bailin' a lot.
When his old man
gets back into town,
we're all gonna be
out on our ass.
You better start
thinkin' about that.
You're welcome.
Hey, Nicole.
You got a fan.
Thanks.
Never mind.
Steve, let me go?
Were the flowers
from him?
Yeah.
It's just like him,
you know?
He's always so polite
and considerate.
He never has to show off
the way other guys do.
Then all of a sudden
he turns into a monster.
I mean, Gary was down
on the ground, and David...
just kept on kicking him
and kicking him so hard!
Did he give you
the black eye too?
Did he?
Dad, I told you
how I got the black eye.
Steven, why don't you
let us finish up here?
Toss me the Kleenex?
Nicole, I want you to understand that whatever
you think I may have done to disappoint you...
is no reason for you
to go screw up your whole life.
What?
Dad, I don't know what
you're talking about.
That's what worries me.
Look, Dad, this may come
as a big shock to you,
but every move I make
does not have to do with you.
- Turns out I'm living my own life.
- Not yet you're not.
As long as you're living in my house,
you'll follow my rules.
That means when you wanna go out, I wanna
know where you're going and with who.
- And if I don't like it, you're not going.
- Don't be ridiculous, Dad.
- I'm not kidding, Nicole. This is gonna stop!
- What?
Why don't you just say it?
This is all about David.
- There's something wrong with him.
- That's your problem, not mine.
- He's not a good guy.
- Look, Dad.
David and I had
a disagreement.
Maybe we'll get past it,
maybe we won't.
But no matter what happens,
it'll be between us.
This doesn't have
anything to do with you.
Oh, God!
What the hell
was that about?
Oh, boy.
He hit her too, Laura.
I know he did.
You heard what she said.
I don't care what anybody says.
He hit her.
Fine.
But don't think you can bully her into
growing up, Steven. It doesn't work that way.
So he hit ya.
Sometimes that's just their asshole way
of showing they love you.
- He didn't mean to hit me. It was an accident.
- Fine.
- So then what's the problem?
- I don't know.
Do yourself a favor and don't think so
much. It gives you premature wrinkles.
My dad hates him,
that's for sure.
Well, that means that he knows
you're sleeping together.
You know, it's that usual
weirdo jealously trip.
How could he possibly know
we were sleeping together?
Caught ya, ya ho! You never told
me you were screwin' him!
Ach! Tch. You'll always
remember your first.
Not your second,
not your third.
Just your first.
- Party!
- Oh, shit!
No! No! Logan!
- Don't you dare!
- Goin' in.
Nicole. Nicole.
Just give me one minute?
I know you never
wanna see me again,
but I still
have to explain.
There's nothin' that I can say
that'll make what I did all right.
I know that, but I need you to know
that it came from someplace good.
It came from me feelin' like
I'd do anything to protect you.
- From Gary?
- I didn't know it was Gary.
I swear. All I saw was some guy
with his paws all over you.
I mean, knowin' how many
bad guys are out there...
guys that would take
advantage of somebody like you.
Guys that I would kill if they
ever did anything to hurt you.
I just lost it.
I want you to know...
that I'm very sorry about
what happened to Gary, I am.
But I can't be sorry
that I love you.
I learned from you,
Nicole, I really did.
I learned that I need people
more than I thought.
I've always been the one
takin' care of things.
And with you,
it's different.
And I want us to
take care of each other.
And I'll promise nothin' like that
will ever happen again.
I'm sorry.
I'm home.
Laura?
- No! No, no, no.
- Come here. Oh, yes, yes.
Hey there! Isn't this
Indian summer great?
- What's goin' on?
- Well, it's warm.
We're taking advantage.
You oughta jump in.
What's he doin' here?
What's he doin' here, Laura?
Steven, would you rather
she lied and snuck off to see him?
You made the rules.
I appreciate it.
Thank you very much.
- Hello.
- You remember that song and dance Nicole gave us...
about David growing up like Beaver Cleaver
in some perfect little town back East?
- Yeah, something like that.
- Well, guess again.
The kid bounced from foster home
to foster home to institution...
until he was finally kicked out
on his ass at 18.
Since then, no one knows.
He's got no family, no address,
no work record... nothin'.
All right. So the guy's embarrassed
about being an orphan.
Not his fault, by the way.
So he makes up a story about having
a happy childhood to impress a girl.
- What's the big deal?
- The big deal, Laura, is that the guy give me the creeps...
and the girl
is my daughter.
- Hello, David.
- Hi, Mr. Walker.
- You got a minute? I need to talk to you.
- I'm meeting Nicole.
This won't take long.
- All right.
- Follow me around the corner.
David, I don't want
to beat around the bush.
I came to tell you that
you're gonna stop seeing Nicole.
Now, either you're as smart as you think
you are and you'll just go away,
or else you're gonna make things harder
on yourself than they have to be.
You know, Steve,
you're really not a faggot.
- What?
- I'm serious.
Seem like a pretty solid guy.
You should lighten up on yourself.
- We're not talkin' about me. We're talkin' about...
- Yes, we are.
That's what this whole thing's
about, Steve. Your inadequacies.
- Your fears.
- You just wait a minute.
Listen to me. See, I'm hip
to your problems. All of 'em.
I know you abandoned Nicole when she needed
you most... 'cause I licked her sweet tears.
I know about things comin' apart at work.
Maybe you fuckin' lost it in that department.
I also know you ain't
keepin' up, so to speak,
your end of the bargain
with the missus.
'Cause if you were,
she wouldn't be all over my stick.
Relax, Steve.
We're friends.
We're practically family.
I want you to understand
something, pal.
If you don't disappear from my family's
life, I'm gonna rip your balls off...
and shove 'em so far up your ass
they'll come out your fuckin' mouth!
You got that, my friend?
Steve, what I'm saying is,
even if he's got a record and we can convince
a judge, this thing could still backfire.
You tell some kid that the state is
restraining him, you'll make him want it more.
We've gotta do something.
I'm not gonna just sit around.
Let me ask you something
as your friend.
Are you sure you're not just
fighting the inevitable here?
You didn't expect she
was gonna stay a virgin, did you?
Alex, the guy
is a psychopath.
Because he's hot
for your daughter?
Took a jealous swing at some guy,
talked trash to you?
- Are you gonna help me or not?
- Yeah, of course.
I'll make a couple of calls
for you, all right?
- Where's my father?
- He's in his workroom.
You know, Dad, I never expect you
to be perfect, 'cause I know I'm not.
But I never thought
you were a hypocrite until now.
Honey, calm down.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about you lecturing me
about what David did to Gary,
and then turning around and acting
a million times worse yourself.
- I don't know what he told you...
- He didn't have to tell me anything. I saw the bruises.
- What bruises?
- You're gonna tell me that you never touched him,
that you didn't hit him so hard in
the chest that he's sore and bruised?
- Look, I-I may have...
- Yeah, exactly, Dad.
You may have. But I'll tell you
what you definitely did.
You lost my respect.
Nicole, come back here!
Nicole!
Fuck!
She ran to the car, she got in, and she slammed
the door in my face, if you need to know.
What?
What are you talkin' about?
She's only 16.
So what if she wasn't kidnapped?
I still have the right to... Huh?
Fine, I'll call a lawyer!
Just you and me, Nicole.
Nobody else.
Mmm.
- Do you want me?
- Yes.
Tell me.
Tell me you want me.
- I want you, David.
- Yeah?
- David.
I love you.
And wild horses
Couldn't drag me away
- And wild horses
- Sure you won't change your mind and come home with me?
I can't.
My dad will kill me.
Okay. I love you.
- Bye.
I woke up wanting you
But you are rarely there
I howl a song
and I prowl at dawn
I growl but you don't care
Growl
I see you walking
around like that
With that animal
on your back
I woke up wanting you
- But you are rarely there - Get outta
here, you skinny-ass motherfucker!
I howl a song
and I prowl at dawn
I growl but you don't care
Growl
- Come on.
- Hey, fuck you. She's mine.
You want me?
Say it
so he can hear you.
Go ahead.
Tell him.
Tell him you want me.
Tell him! Now!
I want him!
Yeah, fuck it. Keep that
dirty little bitch. I don't want her.
What?
- Nic.
- Please, Dad. I don't wanna talk about it.
I just wanna be alone.
Okay.
The pain'll go away, honey.
I promise.
Is she okay?
I hope so.
I got you some anyway. I thought food
might zap you out of your zombie trip.
- Thanks. I'm just not hungry.
- Let me guess.
You're preparing a junk food defense before
you and your boyfriend go on a killing spree.
No. Definitely not.
Joke. Joke, Nicole.
As in "ha-ha. "
Remember?
Jesus, cane me in Singapore.
- Was Margo in bio? - Uh-uh.
She called and said she was sick.
- At least she's honest.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Speak of the devil.
- Guess who?
- Don't touch me!
Nicole, where are you going?
- Get away from me! Help!
- Get over here. Stop it!
- Somebody help me!
- What's the matter with you? Come here.
- Hey!
- Just stay away from me!
- No. Why?
- You heard her David. Just let her go!
All right? Okay?
All right.
Okay.
- Hey. They're in there.
- Hi. Thanks.
Why won't you
take my calls?
As you can see, I'm playing
with my little brother.
Okay. You don't have to
be so snotty about it.
Hey there, handsome. When you
gonna grow up so I can ravage you?
Margo, why don't you
leave Toby alone?
Jesus.
What's your problem?
What?
The fact that you can stand there and act
cool and fine as if nothing ever happened.
That's what scares me
the most about you, Margo.
It's like I don't know you, or... Maybe
I don't know anybody for that matter.
- Everybody says one thing and then does another.
- Nicole.
I... I'm sorry. I just... I have no idea
what you're talking about.
You know exactly
what I'm talking about.
Who told you?
Did David tell you?
Forget it. It doesn't matter.
You're not a friend of mine.
Nicole, I was high, okay?
He forced me. He made me do it!
Nicole, please don't do this.
Please don't do this. I need you.
You're my only friend!
Hey, pull over!
I gotta talk to you!
- What the fuck do ya think you're doin'?
- David, please leave me alone.
- Huh? What did you say to Nicole?
- Nothing.
You fuckin', lyin' fuckin' whore.
Get the fuck outta the car!
You lyin' fuckin' whore!
What did you say to her?
What the fuck did you say to her?
Nothing. I swear, David. I didn't tell
her. I don't know how she knows.
But she knows.
Let me tell you somethin'. You better
fix it. You better make it right.
Because if you don't,
I'm gonna hurt you.
Don't cry.
You fuckin' liked it.
Mr. Walker, sir, I believe I owe you,
Nicole and your entire family an apology.
Well, I was wonderin' if...
I was just wonderin' if you'd be so kind as
to let me come in and explain a few things?
I think you might
understand.
I'm not interested
in understanding you, David.
I'm only interested in
keeping you away from Nicole.
And I'll do whatever it takes
to accomplish that. Okay?
Whatever it takes.
Thanks, Dad.
Hello?
Oh, hey, Eddie.
Just hold on one second.
Yeah, Eddie?
I'm gonna work all night.
Please, don't panic.
I talked to the school.
Security knows about everything, so...
Don't worry, Dad.
It's over, okay?
- Love you.
Nicole! Wait up.
- Hi.
- Everything copacetic?
Yeah. You know, I never thanked you
for the other day.
No sweat.
Yes! You did it! This is great.
This is a work of art.
You think you can stay conscious long
enough to crunch out the new numbers?
I've been livin' on pure adrenalin
for 24 hours. Why stop now?
- Sure you don't want
to come to the mall?
Nah. I gotta finish
that story for the paper.
The Washington Post is gonna need to see
something before they make me editor.
- Hey, Laura. - Hey,
Gary. - Get in the back.
- Hey, Toby bear.
- Hi, Gary.
Okay, I'll see you later.
- Hey, Gary.
- David.
- Did you know I grew up in a lot of different places?
- Uh, no. Actually, Nicole told...
Oh, yeah. Bridgewater,
Spaford, Rikers, you name it.
- You know what they have in common?
- No.
Weak walls. Actually, that's why
they moved me around so much.
I'd pound on the wall,
it'd break.
They'd move me to the next one
and the next one...
until finally they got sick of
buildin' walls and showed me the door.
Pretty useful upbringing it turned out,
though, Gar. There's always walls.
Usually the moist, fleshy kind that try to get
in the way of me and it, whatever it may be.
Silly, silly people, though.
They're only to be knocked down.
Gary.
- We ready?
- We're ready?
I appreciate your efforts. I know how hard the
push has been on yourselves and your families.
Today is just another dog and pony show.
I'll kick it off, and then you're up, Steve.
Let's sell these guys.
How many tickets we got
for the Hawks Sunday?
- We got the four. Peterman kept the rest.
- That figures.
Holy shit!
Jesus, Steve.
What does it say?
Eddie, I need for you to give me the keys to
your car and for you to catch a ride with Harvey.
- Steve, we gotta...
- Please!
Okay.
Hello, Laura? Nicole?
Come on. Somebody pick up.
Shit!
Hello, Margo. This is Mr. Walker.
Is Nicole with you?
Do you know where
David McCall lives?
How are you?
I need to talk to you.
- Help!
- Shh!
Shh. You gotta listen to me, Nicole.
To me. The real me.
- You gotta use the one thing
you have that can hear the real me.
It's not here.
It's not what I say.
It's not the way
you see me acting.
It's here.
That's what it is, Nicole. You know it.
I know it. Your daddy knows it.
Everybody knows it.
That's why they're tryin' to keep
us apart. They're just jealous.
- We have somethin' that
everybody wants but nobody has.
- We can't let them
take that away from us, Nicole.
It belongs to me and you. Okay?
I love you.
Help!
Somebody help me.
It's your fucking fault!
Come on! Now somebody knows
who did this. Now who is it?
- I know who did it.
- Well, I'll fucking kill whoever did this!
- Yeah, who?
- Yeah, let's pay the dude a fuckin' visit, then!
All right.
Here.
Thanks.
I can't get over the feeling that I let
you down, Nic. I should've seen it coming.
- I'm sorry.
- It's not your fault, Laura.
Thanks, anyway.
I mean that, on top of the fact that
he assaulted her in a public bathroom,
and you're tellin' me that that's
not enough to haul him in?
Who gives a shit
about warrants?
They're runnin' their own cartel, and
you can't do a goddamn thing about it?
Well, look, I'm not worried about tonight,
but what about tomorrow and the next day?
She can't stay here
like she's a prisoner.
Pull in over there.
We'll cut through
the woods.
- An eye for an eye.
- A tooth for a fuckin' tooth!
Just remember,
Nicole ain't part of this game.
Ohh, Margo.
Ohh, what's wrong?
We...
Gary's dead.
They found his body in the woods
by school, beaten to death.
Kaiser. Kaiser.
Come here, boy.
Come here, Kaiser.
Good boy.
Okay, fine. You're right.
It's not an emergency.
Could I please talk to the people
that try and solve murders?
Jesus!
Come on.
That's a good boy.
- Come here, Toby.
- Yeah, yeah, um...
- Come here.
- My... My name is Steven... Hello?
Hello? Hello?
- The phone is dead.
- You're next, man!
No!
You don't know what's out there.
Here. Security'll come.
- There's no siren.
- Well, they'll still get the signal. Larry'll come.
No, it's disconnected. The system
works through the phone lines.
- Come here.
- It doesn't matter. No one is getting in here.
- You designed it, remember? Reinforced doors. No entry without the code.
- Dad?
David's got the code.
It all could've been different,
Mr. Walker.
You should've allowed nature
to take its course.
In the end it will anyway.
So let me in
the fuckin' house!
- Nicole, take Margo and Toby up to your room and stay there.
- Okay.
Laura, get the flashlight. Then
turn off every light in the house!
Go, Nicole!
And lock your door!
- Turn the flashlight off. I don't want
'em to know where anybody is.
- No one's gonna hurt
our family, honey. No one!
An eye for an eye,
eh, Mr. Walker, sir?
You fuck up my house,
I'll fuck up yours!
Steven?
Come on.
The refrigerator.
Oh, they're gonna kill us,
just like they did Gary.
Don't say that.
You need to calm down.
- I can't. I can't. I can't.
- You need to.
- Nicole.
- Noo-oo-oo!
Get out of the way!
Go check the kids. Go on.
Nicole, are you all right?
We're okay!
Steve!
You gotta do ol' dad
a favor before he kills you.
We're sorry. You've reached a number
that has been disconnected...
or is no longer in service.
- Steve!
- Laura!
Oh, fuck! Fuck!
I gotta get to a hospital, man.
I'm fucked!
- I'm fucked!
- This gig's tired.
Car comin', Logan.
Let's get outta here.
- Logan, you comin'?
- It's Larry.
- Gimme the fuckin' gun.
- It's gonna be all right.
Thank you, God.
Thank you.
- Stay here.
- Be careful, Steven.
Hands in the air, son.
- Sir, is there somethin' wrong?
- Hands on the hood real slow.
Sir, I think there's some confusion. I
just came back from visiting my girlfriend.
Is that right?
- Stay where you are!
- Larry!
- Mr. Walker, you okay?
- We're all right. We're safe.
- You know these jokers? Are there any more of them?
- I think the others ran away.
There's plenty of time. We're gonna take
this inside. Get the cuffs and the guns.
Laura, stay back!
Don't open the door.
- What? Steven, what's going on?
- Mrs. Walker?
Ma'am, we'd like you to see the
situation from a different point of view.
- Oh, God!
- Laura, no!
Yo, lady of the house, we're comin' in. You
gotta decide if he's comin' with us, and fast.
Say bye-bye.
Laura.
Laura, no!
I'm sorry.
Terry, go out there
and keep a watch.
If I could get to Laura's car phone...
I can fit through my bathroom window.
Log, cuff her.
Steven!
Logan, go find some tape.
I think I'll go check out
the rest of the house.
If you touch any
of those kids...
Calm down, Mr. Walker.
Everything's under control.
Stay away from me.
Stay away from me!
- Let go of me!
- Noo-oo-oo!
- Leave her alone! Don't you hurt her!
- Jealous bitch!
- No! No!
- Come on!
- Stop!
- No, get off me! No!
Stop hitting her,
you mother...
Toby!
Come on, Mr. Walker.
Time to give away the bride.
No! No!
It's time to go, Nicole.
- First, I want you to do the
right thing and say bye to Daddy.
- No!
- What?
You wanna go with me,
don't you?
- Yes.
- Well, all right then.
Come here and give your father a kiss good-bye.
It's not easy to give away your daughter.
David! Don't!
Please!
Nicole.
I know this is hard.
I'm sorry it has to be
like this, but it does.
It's not our fault.
It's his.
I tried so hard to be nice,
to get him to accept me.
Can't you see all he wants is for you
to be his little girl forever?
You don't want that,
do you?
It's okay.
All girls cry at their weddings.
Now, I know this is gonna be hard.
We'll get over it... together.
Just me and you.
Nobody else, remember?
Daddy.
You will forever hold your peace!
Now, you get out of here!
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org