♪ Do-do-do do-do-do ♪
♪ do-do-do do-do-do
do-do-do-do-do-do ♪
♪ do-do do-do-do ♪
♪ do-do-do do-do-do
do-do-do-do-do-do ♪
♪ do-do do-do-do ♪
♪ do-do-do do-do-do
do-do-do-do-do-do ♪
♪ what a wonderful world
we would live in ♪
♪ with hatred and love
reconciled ♪
♪ if we only showed each other ♪
♪ the faith in the heart
of a child ♪
♪ what a wonderful world
we could make it ♪
♪ what a wonderful place
it would be ♪
♪ if we had the faith
of a child to act ♪
♪ and the eyes of a child
to see ♪
♪ then trust
would replace suspicion ♪
♪ and hope
would replace despair ♪
♪ our tears would turn
to laughter ♪
♪ and wishing would turn
to prayer ♪
♪ what a wonderful world
we would live in ♪
♪ with hatred and love
reconciled ♪
♪ if you and I had
the simple faith ♪
♪ found in the heart ♪
♪ of a child ♪♪
We try, Mr. hilditch.
We do try.
I've told you before, Sidney,
it starts with the stock.
Don't rely on cubes.
What's for dessert?
Raspberry jam
steamed pudding.
I'd give it
a few minutes yet.
I'm afraid I've got a meeting.
I could bring it
to your office
when it's ready.
That would be
so kind of you, iris.
Thank you.
A pleasure.
Morning, Mr. hilditch.
Morning, Jimmy.
Morning.
Have you means
of identification?
Identification?
What's your name?
Felicia.
Do you have
a driver's license?
I can't drive.
Have you any form
of identification?
No, I can't think that I have.
No letter?
No documentation
of any kind?
Could you step aside?
Are you a resident
of the United Kingdom?
No, I'm from Ireland.
I'm here to see a friend.
May I look
through your bag
for a moment?
Every minute
I'll be thinking of you.
you'll be by my side.
The coach to london/victoria,
is departing from bay six.
Would the supervisor
please call maintenance.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Could you tell me where
the lawn mower factory is?
Lawn mower factory?
Sorry.
Yeah.
Okay, thanks.
Excuse me. Could you
tell me where the
lawn mower factory is?
Lawn mower factory, my dear?
No, sorry, can't help you.
Okay, thank you.
No, lysaght.
Johnny lysaght.
L-y-s-a-g-h-t.
Hello. Could you give me the
phone number for the lawn mower
factory in Birmingham?
No. A place that makes them,
doesn't sell them.
By installing food machines,
you could dispense
with the canteen staff.
The machines back directly
on to the kitchens
like this.
The prepared portions load
straight in.
And at a drop of a coin,
the dishes emerge when
and how they're required.
What do you mean,
"how they're required"?
Piping hot or chilled
or anything in between.
Come in.
Here you are,
Mr. hilditch.
Fresh from the oven.
It's better, iris.
It's better.
Good show.
Thank you, Mr. hilditch.
I'll let the others know.
It can serve drinks as well.
Just load the machine
with tea, coffee,
chocolate, softs.
No more than
ten minutes labor a day.
You can't lose.
But I would lose, Ted.
I would lose my staff.
I would lose the way iris
takes the bother...
To bring me up a dish of
raspberry jam steamed pudding.
Food must be served
by caring hands,
not by machines.
It keeps our spirits up.
It makes us feel...
Loved!
Can I keep this?
Morning.
Can I help you?
Is this where
they make lawn mowers?
I'm afraid not.
Lawn mowers? Why?
I have a friend who works
in a place that makes them.
The only thing is,
I'm not certain where it is.
You could try
the black barrow
industrial estate.
They've got
a garden center there.
They might know.
Go over the bridge,
turn right, and go
until you see the signs.
Okay?
Good luck.
Hello, sister.
Yes, I know Johnny lysaght.
And you went out
with him?
I did.
You hear certain remarks made
about that boy, Felicia.
I'm not saying it's gospel.
All I'm saying is there are
certain statements made.
What statements?
He joined
the British army.
But Johnny
went to england because
he couldn't get work here.
There's better boys than that
around here, Felicia.
Irish boys belong in Ireland.
Johnny's not in the army.
He works in a factory.
Lawn mower parts.
How about you? Would I know
your brothers or sisters?
No, just me.
Yeah.
No? Just you?
Just you and your father
and your mother?
My mother passed away
when I was four.
But there's my father
and my great-grandmother.
She must be
a ripe old age.
Yeah.
She's about a hundred now.
That's incredible.
But your mother passed away
when you were four?
I'm sorry to hear that.
♪ angel, angel ♪
♪ whoo-oo-oo-oo ♪
♪ you are my special angel ♪
♪ sent from up above ♪
♪ my fate smiled down on me ♪
♪ and sent an angel to love ♪
Sorry, there's no
lawn mower parts around here.
Best of luck anyway.
I hope you find it.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
♪ I know that you're an angel ♪
♪ heaven is in your eyes ♪
♪ a smile from your lips
brings the summer sunshine ♪
I'm sorry. There's no one
with that name on site.
Okay, thank you.
Good luck to you.
♪ I feel your touch
your warm embrace ♪
♪ and I'm in heaven again ♪
♪ you are my special angel ♪
♪ through eternity ♪
♪ I'll have my special angel ♪
♪ here to watch over me ♪♪
you didn't have any luck?
It's not there.
But a man gave me the name
of another town.
Yes, I thought
of Thompson's casting
five minutes after you left.
It's a bit of a distance.
You won't get a bus
in that direction tonight.
I'll stay here.
Have you got a place?
I'm just going
to look for a place.
Marshring.
There's a lot
of accommodation there.
And it's reasonable.
You're after somewhere
reasonable?
Yeah.
Right.
You go straight up the road,
take the second right,
turn left along the canal
and that's marshring.
I'd give you a lift.
I've just done me shopping.
Thanks.
You looked beautiful
the other day.
Has anyone ever
said that to you?
No.
I'm saying it now.
You look beautiful now.
♪ more than ever
more than ever ♪
♪ doo-do-do-do
more than ever ♪♪
bon. Let me give you
an important piece of advice...
About buying a good loin,
or about buying anything
for that matter.
The late
georges escoffier, one
of the greatest French chefs,
says in his important book,
le guide escoffier,
is a matter of provisions.
No matter what you buy...
The cheapest is always
the dearest in the end.
So, get your butcher...
To chop well down
between each bone.
And trim each chop
as for cutlets,
but do not separate.
Roll the joints in the form
of a crown...
With the meat inside.
Then attach them together.
Take this needle.
It's very scary, I know,
but it is so practical.
You tie them together.
It's really fun to do too.
There. Voila!
The crown roast of lamb...
May be filled with
ordinary poultry stuffing...
Or filled afterwards...
With mashed potatoes
sprinkled with parsley.
Or, and this is my favorite,
with pureed turnip and a pickle.
And what better way to puree
your turnip and a pickle...
Than by using
your new gala chef processor.
Let me tell you a few words
about your new processor.
It is amazing.
There are
all these possibilities.
To add the right ingredients,
you can fold...
This fresh Rosemary
will be the perfect garnish
for our lamb.
Let's go inside and see
if the roast is ready.
Isn't it perfect?
Last touches.
Now, let's put
these lovely little hats.
It makes it very festive,
you know.
But also, it's fun
with kids around the table.
Sometimes they can
pick it up and fight
over it, etcetera.
Here we go.
I think we should taste.
Let's have a taste...
And see how marvelous this is,
no question.
Delicieux.
No surprise.
Listen to me, Felicia.
You'll not live in our house...
And keep company
with a member
of the British army.
This family knows
where it stands,
and always has done.
Think of your
great-grandmother.
Her husband, your blood,
was executed
by the brits,
may, 1960.
Sacrifices have been made,
and they will be honored.
We have a duty to remember
these things.
Time will not allow us
to forget.
This fellow will be back,
Felicia.
But associate with him again,
and you will leave our house.
You're at the beginning
of things, Felicia.
One of these days,
there'll be work for you.
Felicia,
when you're a child,
you take advice.
But I'm not a child, dad.
Not anymore.
I've said what I have to say.
We can leave it.
You're goin' out, girl?
Morning.
My wife and I
were worried about you.
I was afraid you might
have left already.
It seems that Thompson's casting
would be a waste of time.
But I've tracked down the place
you're looking for.
It's about fifty Miles away.
A lot of people who live locally
make the journey every day.
No reason why
your friend wouldn't.
Ada's up there in the hospital.
We had that phone call
last night,
see, about you.
Ada's poorly.
You see?
But what I wanted to tell you is
I've got to drive up that way...
Tomorrow morning,
on account of ada.
What I'm saying is,
you'd be welcome to a seat
in our little jalopy.
I don't think I...
No, naturally you wouldn't.
You probably want
to get up there today.
Good luck.
Toodle-oo.
Could I have the lift?
Of course!
It's 6:30 sharp, though,
on account of ada.
But... I like to pop in
and catch her
before her morning tests.
6:30's all right.
I'll pick you up
outside your b & b.
All right?
See you tomorrow.
It won't be long
till you're back again?
No, it won't be long.
Can I write to you?
I'm not much of a one
for letters.
Come here, look.
Every minute, I'm gonna
be thinking about you.
And every minute,
you're gonna be
by my side, all right?
I haven't got your address.
How are you doing?
Nice to see you.
How are you?
Not too bad.
She's nice, isn't she?
Yeah, not a bad bike.
Were you involved
the other night?
Me friend Greg, broken nose.
Took some belt.
He did indeed.
How are you keeping?
Yeah, I'm good.
Good-lookin' belt.
I'm back off to england.
England, for what?
Just back there.
Gotta go back to work.
How long have you had this?
Three weeks now.
Don't kill yourself on it.
I won't.
Be careful.
Yeah.
I remember giving you a go
on a bike before.
Yeah, that's right.
See you.
He didn't see we wanted
to be alone.
You didn't tell him.
Your address.
I'll send it to you.
First thing
when I get there.
♪♪
I'm a friend of Johnny's,
Mrs. lysaght.
Yes?
I was wondering if you had
his address.
What do you want with Johnny?
Just to write him a letter,
Mrs. lysaght.
My son wouldn't want
his address given out
to all and sundry.
He wouldn't mind you giving me
his address.
He didn't give it
to you himself then?
No, he said he'd send it.
I was wondering
if he sent it to you
to give me.
All I want to do is contact him.
You've had enough contact
with him.
My wife and I
were worried about you.
It seems
that Thompson's casting
would be a waste of time.
But I've tracked down
the place
you're looking for.
It's about fifty Miles away.
A lot of people
who live locally
make the journey every day.
No reason why
your friend wouldn't.
Ada's up there in the hospital.
We had that phone call
last night, see,
about you.
Ada's poorly.
But what I wanted to tell you,
I've got to drive up
that way tomorrow morning
on account of ada.
Mrs. lysaght.
Mrs. lysaght?
Mrs....
Mrs. lysaght, please!
I imagine your eyes
as you read these words.
Your eyes are what fill
my heart,
and give me hope
in these confusing days.
Our days together
seem a long time ago.
I miss those days.
Are you receiving these letters,
Johnny?
Your mother said
she would send them on to you.
I need to see you
as soon as I can.
You seem like a nice person.
I'm all right
once you get to know me.
Are you married?
It doesn't matter.
I was just asking.
I'm not married, but I have
to look after my mother.
She's getting old now.
Is she?
Are you the only person
she's got?
You are a nice man, then.
You haven't told me
anything about you,
how you think, how you feel.
I don't even know
if you've ever been married
or you've got children.
You haven't told me
anything like that.
I'm not saying
what we had wasn't special,
'cause it was.
I probably
wouldn't be here now
if it weren't for you,
but you know,
things are different.
Morning.
Well, here we are.
Was it all right,
the b & b?
The what?
The bed and breakfast.
Yeah, it's fine.
I'm glad of that.
I wouldn't like to think
I'd misled you.
Has lysaght got you pregnant?
We're both responsible.
How long are you gone?
I've missed a few times.
How many?
There's no doubt about it.
Carrying the enemy within you.
Thank God your mother
isn't alive to see it.
You're a whore!
And you're worse than that!
Damn you to hell!
The first time
i met up with you...
I could see you were
in a bit of an upset.
You're fond of the boyfriend,
are you?
It's not difficult to believe
that he's fond of you.
I said,
it's not difficult to believe
that he's fond of you.
I'm having his baby.
What?
I'm pregnant.
You're going to be a mother.
We'll see everyone
who arrives
from here.
Going to get out
and look for him?
Yeah.
Go on then.
- May I help you?
- Is this where they make lawn mowers?
We make lots of things here.
Do you know if
Johnny lysaght works here?
I've not heard of that name.
He's about that tall.
He's got blond hair.
Let's just
check the register.
Okay.
This fresh Rosemary
will be the perfect garnish
for our lamb.
So let's go inside
and see if the roast is ready.
Cut!
Joey was in the shot again.
I know!
Go sit there.
Could we do
one more?
Yes, of course.
Next time, when you pick
the Rosemary, could you
really roll it in your hand?
No.
He doesn't work here.
He said he loved me.
That we'd be together forever.
Then he left
without giving me
his address.
I need to find him!
His mother's trying
to keep him away from me.
Mothers can be difficult.
I don't want
to bother you with it.
Another person's trouble
can lift the mind.
Do you understand me?
Don't be ashamed.
We understand exactly
how you feel.
Exactly!
We've had experience.
I'll drive you back...
After I visit the hospital.
I'll just pop in, dear.
Find out the state of play.
I'm sorry.
I've got to stand on my own two feet.
Surely you must see that.
I was weak before.
You've helped me
strengthen everything
about my personality,
and I feel like I'm ready
to go it alone.
I'll always remember
the conversations we've had,
and the way
you've helped me,
but... that's it now.
I'm not even a body,
I'm not even a person.
I'm just a part of a woman
that men want to use.
I've got nowhere to go.
Excuse me.
Could you tell me where
I might find the lavatory?
Down there
on the left.
Thank you.
You're fine.
You're not hurting.
You're the strong one.
Why do you need me?
Why do you need my stories?
I needed you.
You don't need anybody.
You've got your mum.
You've helped me back
to myself, I'm all right now.
That's why I wanna go.
I can't get attached
to people
in my profession.
You should be happier
for me.
Why aren't you?
You've been wonderful.
I can't explain.
And you've helped me get
to where I am now.
I've just got
this strength
and this spirit,
and I just want more.
I didn't want interviews.
I didn't want
all this crap.
"Who are you?
What's your name?
What did you do?
Who's your boyfriend?
How did you get
into this situation?"
Hi, my name's gaye,
and I'm a prostitute.
- My name's Sharon.
- Bobbi.
- My name's Beth.
- My name's jakki.
- Elsie.
You'll find other people
that you can relate to
the way you've related to me.
You'll find other people
that you can connect with
and talk to...
That are special to you.
I guess I'm just
another ordinary person.
There are lots of people
that would find
your personality endearing,
and they would love
to speak to you.
I'd give half my kingdom now.
No. Give me the head
of the baptist.
Stop it.
Please don't do that.
It's really scary.
I'd like to go back,
please.
Where are we now?
Please can I go?
Will you just stop the car?
Please will you just
stop the car?
I'd like to stop.
Don't just ignore me.
Will you say something?
What?
What is...
Wrong with you?
What's wrong with you?
Why don't you
just let me go?
I might see...
Just...
My God!
Get off me!
Help me!
Cut!
How was that?
Fine.
Should we do one with Joey?
Sure. We could have him
pluck some Rosemary,
then run to follow you inside.
Bon.
Is something wrong?
Ada's not so good.
They had to do
an emergency
at 5:00 this morning.
She's not so good.
I'm sorry.
I'll be all right in a minute.
You get a shock like this,
you don't want to be alone.
Both of us with a shock,
Felicia.
I'm glad you're going
to have a baby, Felicia.
It's a help to me, that.
A help?
Another life coming.
Ada going in
at this particular time,
and you here.
And ada concerned about you...
When I told her.
"Young Irish girl," I said.
She wanted to know
what you looked like.
I told her you were
going to be a mother.
I hope you don't mind.
I thought it might
give her a lift.
We never had kids of our own.
Yes, you told me.
A great disappointment.
A child is a blessing, Felicia.
Never forget that.
A blessing.
Are you thinking
of having the thing terminated,
Felicia?
What?
Do they have that over there?
Abortion?
Where?
Ireland.
There's difficulties.
Difficulties.
Of course.
We'll make our way back,
shall we?
My father...
Yes?
My father says...
Johnny joined the army
over here.
It can't be true.
Of course not.
Johnny wouldn't lie
to me.
No!
Johnny wouldn't lie to you.
He wouldn't join the army
over here.
Come inside.
We'll make some inquiries.
The girl I have at the office
is very good
at tracking things down.
I'm sorry.
I can't be a nuisance
at a time like this.
Never a nuisance, Felicia.
Never.
I don't want nothing.
Of course you don't.
Course not, honey.
Today I have brought
the Bible to you.
I don't want no Bible!
This is the paradise earth.
This is the promise
and the place
of the father lord.
You hear of the flood?
Noah and his ark?
You hear of that?
Yes, I have.
Child, we live
in a miracle!
Look here at this garden, honey.
The father lord
is gathering all things in.
I have to get a room
for the night.
I can offer you a room.
No charge made.
What I'm doing now
is pinching the Turkey...
So that I can loosen...
Who's making inquiries about this soldier?
I'm a friend of the family.
I'm afraid there's been
an emergency.
The young man's father's
had an accident.
What are you asking me?
Well, the family's uncertain...
Which barracks
the lad's stationed at,
owing to his father
being unconscious in hospital.
We're ringing round
all the barracks
in the area.
Name and rank?
Lysaght, j.
A squaddie, I would say.
A what?
A private.
We have a lysaght here.
Wonderful.
We'll pass the message on
after fatigues.
No.
It would be better
if the family
brought the news to him.
Now we know where he is,
we'll, contact him pronto.
Thank you.
Now, this fine young man...
Will help me demonstrate
a novel way...
Of stuffing your Turkey
without untrussing it...
And then trussing it
back together again.
No, no, no.
Too complicated.
I take the stuffing
and fit it into...
A nylon icing bag...
With no pipe affixed, of course.
Like this.
Fill it up.
Now, go in.
Et voila.
Now, Joey, why don't you
show everyone...
How easy this is.
You just squeeze it...
Until the bird is full.
Joey!
What a mess you made!
Here is a piece of liver
that managed to escape.
Open your mouth, Joey.
Joey!
Open your mouth!
It's very good for you,
the liver.
Liver is a delicacy.
Go get the towel
to help mama clean up.
What a mess,
Joey.
One, one, one, one.
Johnny!
It's quiet
in the gathering house
this time of day.
Each and every one
is out and about.
Do a lot of people
live here?
Black and white, child.
Young and old.
All that are called
to gather in.
You are not amongst us
by chance,
for there is nothing
that can happen...
But by the commandment
that began...
In the garden of pleasure.
Adam was taken
from out of the ground
of the paradise earth,
and the commandment...
Was drawn in the dust.
Look close.
See the serpent spit.
Where did you find this?
She was quite a sensation
back then, wasn't she?
Gave fannie craddock
a run for her money.
Not that I understood
a word she said.
What was the name
of her little boy?
Jimmy?
Does it say?
Here it is.
Joey.
What is it, child?
I've lost some money.
Money?
It was in my bag.
What you saying to me,
child?
I had money with my clothes.
It was hidden away in my bag
and it's been taken.
Not in this house.
Never that, child.
It's missing.
Stolen!
You're saying stolen.
No, not at all.
Only, I left the bag
when I first came in.
We provide you with shelter
and true belief,
and now there is accusation?
I didn't say it was stolen.
I just want it back.
I've no money now.
You're asking for money, child?
No. I'm sorry
to wake you. There's been
a terrible confusion.
The child has lost some money.
If one of you might
have seen it... maybe
I took it out by mistake,
or it slipped out
of the bag.
She says it has been stolen!
Are you working?
I say, are you working?
Give me a special price.
Are you working?
Suit yourself.
Nowhere to settle, dear?
Come.
Keep me company.
We meet again.
No luck with your searchings?
You're soaking wet.
Come in, come in.
Give me your bag.
Look at you.
Go through.
It's warm in there.
Yesterday, you said,
could you help me that day.
And I was wondering...
I was wondering
if you could lend me
the fare to go home.
You want to go back?
It was a mistake comin' here.
I shouldn't ever have come over.
What about your friend,
though? Sit down.
I'll never find him.
You can't give up, Felicia.
Not this easily.
If your friend knew
all this, he'd be doing
his nut with worry.
I've had experience of this.
If he knew what
you've been going through,
looking for him
in a country
that's so strange to you,
poor fellow would be
beside himself.
I want to find Johnny.
And that's what we'll do.
I'll ask the girl
at the office
to ring round,
like I suggested.
You remember
I suggested that, Felicia,
before you...
I'm so sorry.
I...
No, no. It's completely
understandable,
you scuttling off like that.
I passed that incident on
to ada...
When she had a bright moment.
She said it was understandable.
Hmph.
I only mention it...
'Cause I wouldn't
like you to think there
was any offense taken.
Is your wife getting better?
Ada died, dear.
God, I...
I'm sorry.
This morning.
I've just got home.
As a matter of fact,
we have to say
it was a blessed release.
We have to use
that expression, Felicia.
You need something to eat.
Come to the kitchen.
There's a place I've heard of...
Where the Irish boys
meet up of an evening.
It's called the barton arms.
Have you checked out
the barton arms at all?
It's a pub.
I have high hopes
of the barton arms.
I've a feeling in my bones.
Tell you the truth,
it'd give me a lift
to go out.
No go, dear?
No?
They aren't even Irish.
Happen the Irish lads
come in later.
We'll give it 20 minutes,
Come on, sit down.
Bear with me a minute,
Felicia.
It's just occurred to me,
I know a bloke
who employs Irish labor.
He's a manager
of a smelting works
about a mile off.
I'll give him a ring.
I'll get us some drinks
as well.
Did you want
a cup of tea?
Won't be a minute.
As many flowers
as are available.
As long as they can
be delivered immediately.
Yes, tonight.
Right. Yes. Well,
I'll leave the selection
up to you.
Yes, it's a funeral.
No dice.
Out for the evening seemingly.
We'll move on, shall we?
But...
We haven't had
our drinks yet.
I hope it's not
a presumption on my part,
Felicia,
but, have you considered
your condition at all?
It's only I'm thinking,
whatever the outcome
of tracking Johnny down is,
you don't want
to let yourself get caught.
"Don't let it go too far,"
was always ada's advice.
And my own as well.
Enough to say, you've lost it.
I don't want to do
a thing like that.
Now, now.
Drink some of that tea
while it's warm.
The goodness is
in the warmth, they say.
I only mention it because...
Ada mentioned it
before she went.
But you're right.
It's best left for now.
I'll get the girl
in my office
to make her inquiries...
First thing
in the morning.
She won't find him.
If anyone can find
your friend,
that girl can.
By tomorrow,
we'll have master Johnny
in our sights.
I'll come back in a few days.
A few days?
What are you talking about,
Felicia?
I forgot about the funeral.
Listen, dear.
Army life taught me
something very important.
You carry on.
Chin up, and march forward.
As far as Johnny
is concerned,
by tomorrow night...
We'll know the score.
I'll come back
tomorrow night, then.
Any time after dark.
You'll find
somewhere tonight,
will ya?
I'll manage.
You all right
in the toilet department
before you set off?
Yes, all right, thanks.
You're welcome, of course,
to lay your head down here.
I'll get you a blanket,
shall I?
Yes, please.
My favorite thing
was to run a bath,
you know,
like a bubble bath
and have scent.
Candles all around.
I'd walk around in her robe
while it was running.
And then I'd just sink away.
And then, when I'd finished,
if I had time
I'd go into their room...
And I'd dress up in her clothes.
Pretend that I was needed...
And wanted,
not just for my body...
But for me.
For who I was
and what I could do.
That was my little fantasy.
Morning.
Now, you will stay
in the house,
won't you, dear?
We don't want the neighbors
to get ideas
so soon after ada.
Well, you know.
No answering the door,
no phone calls.
I'll be back
around 6:00.
Bye.
I dreamt
that you met Johnny.
That you knew where he was.
With any luck, Felicia,
that dream might come true.
Let's see what my girl
turns up with,
I'll pray for her.
Who?
Your wife.
Thank you, Felicia.
Morning, Mr. hilditch.
Morning, Jimmy.
Better spot of weather,
Does your heart good,
Mr. hilditch. What do
we have for lunch today?
Rissoles in batter, or pork.
How was the COD
yesterday?
Tiptop.
I'm glad to hear it, Jimmy.
Morning, iris.
Good morning.
Smells champion, that pork.
Mr. hilditch?
What is it?
Double sausage roll.
Won't you try it?
Yes.
That's a beautiful tie
you're wearing, Mr. hilditch.
I've not seen you in black.
Did you not like...
Morning.
Morning!
Hello.
I had an abortion
six months ago.
I had to get rid of it.
And it had to be quick.
I couldn't think,
I couldn't breathe,
because every day
it was growing inside me,
and it was becoming...
It was becoming a person,
and I just...
It made me feel ill.
I didn't want it.
It reminded me of what I did.
What I do.
So I had to go private.
I looked in the phone book.
I found a clinic.
Nice place.
The gishford in sheffield.
The staff were really nice.
Friendly.
Didn't ask many questions.
An immediate
would be wonderful.
Yes!
Right. Thank you.
Thank you
for fitting her in.
Thank you.
Bye.
Johnny's different.
He'd want our baby.
And you came here
to ascertain that.
To make sure.
Is that right, Felicia?
But you never got an answer.
You have to look at it
like that.
If the girl in the office
had struck lucky today,
then it would've been
a different kettle of fish.
I'm not saying it wouldn't.
But she didn't.
And I'm definitely
of one mind with you now.
We won't find Johnny.
Johnny'll be over
St. Patrick's day,
or easter.
I was thinkin' about that
the entire day.
It'll be all right
when I'm there,
and we're together again.
There's no doubt
that Johnny loves you,
dear.
Nothing you've said to me
contradicts that.
No.
The point I'm trying
to make to you is...
The situation,
like you and Johnny are in,
could all too easily
be affected by misfortune.
Ada said that, Felicia.
Ada had a considerable insight
into matters of the heart.
The thing is, Felicia,
you're over here now.
This isn't Ireland.
And we have
certain facilities available.
What I'm saying to you...
Is what I'd say
to any daughter
ada and myself might have had.
I'm giving you the benefit
of long experience.
There isn't a doubt
in my mind, Felicia.
I've thought of nothing else
since I rested poor ada
in the ground.
There's some
would call it murder.
Murder?
We're not in this world
to cause pain, dear.
Of course,
you have to think
of yourself on occasion.
I'm not saying you don't.
But there are other people too,
which is something
you're daily more aware of
as you grow older.
What are you talking about?
No one's denying
you've been through it,
Felicia.
But so has your dad,
and your great gran.
Imagine them trying
to hold their heads up.
There's that to think about too.
We all have to do
terrible things, Felicia.
We have to find
the courage sometimes.
You're a young girl.
When you find Johnny again,
you can both make the choice...
To have a child.
But the circumstances
have to be right.
A child...
Needs to be surrounded
by all the love it can.
The love of the mother.
Of course he'll have that.
But the love of the father,
and the grandfather,
and the
great great-grandmother...
Why deprive this baby of that?
I've, um...
I've put by a little
that I'd gladly donate...
In order to do the decent thing
by your family.
Anything you lend me,
I'll send back.
Every penny.
I've no doubt, Felicia.
They can do an immediate
at the gishford.
A what?
It's a clinic.
They can do it at once.
I asked the girl
to put a call in to them.
You could be back
across the water by Monday.
Back a free spirit, Felicia,
with the whole thing...
Lifted from you.
It's what's right, Felicia,
believe me.
It's what's meant.
♪♪
Come on, then.
Put your coat on.
Yeah.
That's it.
Come on, let's get you home.
Thank you.
We're very much obliged.
See she keeps nice and warm.
We've a little journey,
they I'll tuck her up.
Just a minute.
Doctor said
she wasn't sleeping too well.
Thank you.
Come on, dear.
Take it easy.
We'll have you home in a jiffy.
I'll go in the morning.
Yes.
Forty-two pounds.
If I could borrow that.
I doubt if that's
sufficient, dear.
One little mishap...
It's terrible to be short.
You've had experience
yourself, of course.
I'll send every penny back.
And every penny it cost today.
Today was my treat, dear.
I was happy about today.
Ada would've liked today.
But you're in no state
to travel, of course.
I have to go.
You weren't at all well
in the car, dear.
You certainly can't set off
on a journey
in this condition.
I shouldn't have done it.
What's done is done, dear.
No one ever grew rich
on regrets.
What about the bright side,
For as long as
you want it, Felicia,
there's a welcome
at number three.
You have your own
little room now.
The sensible thing would be
if we took it day by day.
I had dreams.
The whole time it was happening,
I dreamt that I saw him,
Johnny and me...
Walking with our little boy.
A boy, was it?
I often remember being a boy.
Drink up your cocoa, dear.
I'm sorry if
I'm fatherly, Felicia.
I can't help being fatherly.
I've grown fond of you.
The first time I saw you,
you were there with your bag,
woebegone and bedraggled.
You were different
from the rest.
What rest?
The others.
Beth.
Elsie.
Sharon.
Gaye.
Bobbi.
Jakki.
Samantha.
All on their own journeys.
Lost girls.
I was the world to them.
In their time of need,
they counted on me.
But then they wanted to go.
Just like you.
But none of them
ever came into this house.
It was never that.
Then...
What was there?
A chat in the car.
I like the chats.
Then... sleep.
They were always asleep
when it happened, Felicia.
When I laid them
to rest.
No.
Shh.
I couldn't lay you
to rest, dear.
Not until you'd taken care
of your little one.
I couldn't do that
myself, Felicia.
♪ You are ♪
♪ my special angel ♪
♪ sent from up above ♪
♪ my fate ♪
♪ smiled down on me ♪
♪ and sent an angel to love ♪
♪ you are my special angel ♪
♪ right from paradise ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ that you're an angel ♪
♪ heaven ♪
♪ is in your eyes ♪♪
Good afternoon, sir.
Thank you for welcoming us.
Today we bring you the word
of our father lord.
I myself am from Jamaica,
and this is miss marcia tibbits.
May I inquire, sir,
if you are familiar
with the writings of the Bible?
I'm afraid I'm not interested.
If we could just step
inside your home,
my friend would offer you
her own experiences,
how she was gathered in.
Ten minutes of your day
is not much sacrifice
to make.
The father lord
gives us time eternal.
We live in a miracle, sir.
There is a future
for the one who dies.
Look at this garden, sir.
You see the fruits of the trees,
and the people of all nations?
Look. No iron bars
are needed, sir,
for all the animals
are at peace
with the happy people.
Look at these
brightly colored birds
as they flit here and there.
Imagine their beautiful song,
and the children's laughter...
Filling the air.
Look, sir, as the father lord...
Is gathering all things in.
Look here, I'm busy.
I've things to do.
An Irish girl
mentioned you, sir.
I remember that now
as we stand here.
"A good man," the girl said.
A helpmate to her.
"Duke of Wellington road,"
she said.
Big and bighearted
was maybe the description.
She said you seemed troubled.
Troubled?
I know no Irish people at all.
The girl make a song and dance
that she is stolen from.
Nothing better
than a common thief.
Soon, the folk will come
from all over...
For our prayer jubilee.
May I ask you, sir,
if you have rooms
going spare in your house?
Rooms?
What are you talking about?
Sir, the folk come to rejoice.
For the future is written
in the writing of certainty.
There will be fruit for all
heavy on the trees.
And the green hills
stretch to the horizon.
And the corn is lifted
from the land.
See the foxes, sir,
tamed in their holes,
and the geese happy
in the farmyard barn.
Hear the cries
of the children at play,
and the voices
raised in song
for the father lord.
That is the promise.
That is the future
for the one who dies.
None of us can flee
the one who dies,
for the one who dies
awaits us...
For when we, too,
have been cleansed,
and are ready
for the paradise earth.
There is a solace
for the troubled, sir.
What's she doing?
What's she writing down?
This is a private house,
you know.
What is written, sir,
is the address.
Three Duke of Wellington.
And the number of folk
you have room for when
the jubilee is at hand.
Sir, with the folk around you,
you will soon discover
a heartsease.
We understand
your troubles, sir.
- We have put two and two together.
- What two and two?
The Irish girl brought pain
to our people, sir,
as she has to you.
You helped that girl on her way.
You did not pass by
on the other side.
Sir, you are at one
with our church.
Sorry, I must get on.
This is not my kind of thing.
The girl was chattering.
It came out like that.
A confidence trickster,
it turns out.
Sh-she asked me
the way.
We would've shown her
the way, sir, as we
can show you right now!
Parthians, and medes...
And elamites!
Lord!
And the dwellers
in mesopotamia,
and in judea.
We hear them.
Some from their gardens.
Some from the deserts.
We give you thanks.
Get up from the ground.
We offer thanks!
For God's sake, get up!
Put that girl
out of your mind, sir.
The pain will wash away.
I'm not in pain.
I don't know what you mean
by pain.
The healing will commence.
I'm a catering manager.
I have lived in this house
all my days.
I'm a respectable man.
Hilditch I am called.
We have come to gather you,
Mr. hilditch,
as we come every day
to the houses
of the other folk.
Mr. hilditch, we are
concerned for you.
Why not kneel down with us, sir?
Why not permit us
to ask for guidance?
We mention the girl to you
only to compliment you
on your charity.
You are not yourself, sir.
I have seen that,
and have said it.
I took that girl's money.
To keep her by me.
I am the thief.
No.
No, no.
I am lonely sometimes...
In my house.
Often.
I am lonely.
You talked about me.
To others.
You told them...
I was troubled.
You said this
to complete strangers.
I'm sorry if I upset you.
I didn't mean to upset you.
No one's blaming you, dear.
Things... happen.
Things... take a turn.
We live in a miracle.
That's the promise.
That's the future.
The pain...
Will wash away.
The healing...
Will commence.
♪ what a wonderful world
we would live in ♪
♪ with hatred and love
reconciled ♪
♪ if we only showed each other ♪
♪ the faith in the heart
of a child ♪
♪ what a wonderful world
we could make it ♪
♪ what a wonderful place
it would be ♪
♪ if we had the faith
of a child to act ♪
♪ and the eyes of a child
to see ♪
♪ then trust
would replace suspicion ♪
♪ and hope
would replace despair ♪
♪ our tears would turn
to laughter ♪
♪ and wishing would turn
to prayer ♪
♪ what a wonderful world
we would live in ♪
♪ with hatred and love
reconciled ♪
♪ if you and I ♪
♪ had the simple faith ♪
♪ found in the heart ♪
♪ of a child ♪♪
Your grandchild
wasn't born, Mrs. lysaght.
Did you tell Johnny?
Did you give him
any of these letters?
Wherever Johnny is,
i want him to know
I'm all right.
The pain can wash away.
Healing can commence.
Lost within a man
who murdered...
There was a soul like any other.
Purity itself
it surely once had been.
I remember the names
of the ones he took away.
Elsie.
Beth.
Sharon.
Jakki.
Gaye.
Bobbi.
Samantha.
I remember these names
with every new face I meet.
May we all rest in peace.