Come on, boy- Come on, now!
Town boy, aren't you?
Brought up on a bloody bottle,
I suppose-
Everything out of a packet-
Never saw a cow till you got out here-
Want me to drag you behind me
in a bucket?
When I was your age,
I used to do 22 miles before breakfast-
You stay here-
I'll get up there
and I'll come back with a bus-
With all those women you had,
I suppose!
All those dirty doorways-
Come on, Pocket Billiards!
Want me to carry you?
I must be old enough to be your father-
You want to rest, don't you?
Want a bloody mattress?
Come on, get your hands up-
I can't get at them-
Come on, get them up-
We've got to keep going-
If I need your help, I'll ask for it-
Hey, boy... -
there's fresh water on the other side-
- How do you know?
- Smelled it-
They didn't teach you much
in that school of yours, did they?
How far do you think they are?
Ten years, the way you're going-
Sorry I forgot your toothpaste-
Not too much, boy-
You've got to help me, boy-
No-
All right, then-
Watch!
He didn't have a knife-
I shouldn't have had to do that
all by myself- That wasn't right-
Wouldn't have been so messy
if you'd helped me-
Hate a messy killing- That wasn't fair!
What are you crying for,
you sentimental, useless, bloody idiot?
Bloody hypocrite!
I was the one who had to do it!
He'd have died in his bloody bed
before Christmas-
If you aren't going to help me,
what did you come for?
Did you think this was going to be
a Boy Scout picnic?
Do you think they'll find him?
Got to get higher-
The sensible thing
is to find different clothes-
The sensible thing is to find a village
and wait for the dark-
Do you think
they'll try and take us back alive?
Don't you want to stop
and polish your boots?
I don't like it down there-
You can't go around-
It's too open-
Let's just walk down the road-
They'll think we're workers-
Bastard!
Bastards!
I'll kill you!
Kill you!
Playing with us-
Playing a game-
He can't have heard
about your goatherd yet-
Just waiting-
I didn't know he could do that-
I didn't know anybody could-
He could have taken my head off-
I could have been running around
like a bloody chicken... -
with my head bouncing
upon the ground in front of me-
I suppose he's calling them up
on his radio-
- What can we do, Ansell?
- Not much-
Wait for the dark, and then go fast-
Very fast-
If I could've got my bloody hands free,
I'd have pulled him right in on top of me-
I'd have rolled him right over-
Jumped up on those bloody skids
and I'd have ploughed him in-
- I might've tripped over it-
- What?
My head-
I could've kicked it-
I could've scored a bloody goal with it-
I'd like to kick my bloody head
right up into his Perspex-
Didn't that old man have
anything on him at all? Not anything?
If you stay here, I'll go and get a knife
and come straight back-
I'll bury that bastard pilot yet-
Let me go alone- Please-
Ansell, keep behind me- Twenty paces-
Ansell-
Quiet, old fellow- Quiet-
Quiet-
What happened to you?
Listen-
He had a picture of his grandchildren
and a piece of dried tobacco-
If you don't help me this time,
I'll kill you, too-
That's enough-
Watch while I drink-
Get down!
Got his best suit on, hasn't he?
Don't hurt her-
Don't touch anything in there-
You pig!
You stupid, half-witted,
half-brained, idiotic pig!
I wish he had taken your head off-
Stupid!
Stupid idiot-
Crazy, murdering pig-
He should have taken your head off... -
and put it into a bucket of vinegar
and sent it to a museum!
What a fool!
Do you have any plan at all?
She'd never have done anything
if you'd left that bread alone-
We're both going to be caught
tomorrow- You do know that, don't you?
All right, then,
you can damn well give me half of it!
Hang on-
Split up the food-
Why?
Only needed you
till my hands were untied-
You're quite sure?
- You can have the razor-
- I don't want the razor-
- I'm having the gun-
- I don't want the gun-
You can have half the tins, the blanket... -
suitcase, and the water-
Plenty of water up there-
Pockets big enough?
Hey! One for the road?
How are you going to open your tins,
country boy?
Bastard!
Bastard tin-
Blooming country boy-
All right, smarty-
How do I open it, then?
- What do you want for that?
- I want to come with you-
- I give the orders, then-
- Yes-
Give it to me-
Hey... -
you want some?
Hey!
Here-
Always keep neat and tidy, boy-
Be careful of your tender little face,
won't you?
And don't forget down below-
What?
Don't want to get the rot, do you?
- Are you serious?
- I've already done mine-
You've got something worth saving
down there, haven't you?
We'll have to eat at night
and drink in the middle of the day-
Right-
And any time you've got something
to say to me, I shall listen to you-
Thank you-
Sometimes I'm very stupid-
I am- I know that-
My wife has told me that-
Oh, yes?
Yes-
- You see the main ridge?
- Yes-
- You see that bit of rock like a fist?
That's our objective today- Right?
What's the matter now?
I'm just following you,
like you told me to-
If you kill me, there's no point-
I'd just be lying here like that old man-
And all you'll have is twice as many tins,
a suitcase, and a razor-
Look-
Later on, I might consider it-
Consider a parting, a going of ways,
I might-
But not now-
Because I'm lonely-
I'll consider it in the mountains-
I don't think that thing will fire anyway-
Funny if it had gone off backwards!
You married?
What chance did I have to get married?
Think I wanted to get into this mess?
A boy of your age ought to be married-
Responsibility,
that's what you boys need-
- That's all changed-
- What's all changed?
They don't want to get married now,
not since the pill-
You can have who you like,
you've only got to ask-
Models, wives, nurses,
secretaries, physiotherapists-
Think he saw us?
What he could be doing, you see-
Go up ahead, keep there-
He's coming back!
Go!
Right! Go!
Anybody can have a war now-
I mean, you just get a bit of equipment
and you start, don't you?
I bet he fancies himself-
Probably went to one of those schools-
One of those flying schools-
What do you think you can hit
with that thing?
Not too much-
Petrol tank is behind that cabin-
You've got to hit it from the side-
- Yes-
- You only get one chance-
He'd be off like a bloody bat-
But he doesn't know you've got it!
See what I mean?
My wife... -
she had to have her face built up-
Plastic jaw-
An Alsatian dog sprang
right across the bar at her... -
just as we were saying good night-
I'm sorry about that-
It was terrible-
Did you sue anybody?
Couldn't- It was her uncle-
Her uncle was the publican-
Couldn't sue her uncle-
I bet he's no bloody good on the ground-
Listen- This is what I'm going to do-
I'm going to twist, run, shout, act it up-
I'm going to go for that ridge-
He'll come over me,
playing his little game-
Then I'll bring him in to you, close-
Now, that's my plan- Understand?
Only go for the petrol tank-
That's the only important thing-
Stay here-
My leg!
I was lined right up on him!
I was lined... -
right up on his bloody head!
Hey, boy-
In the last minute...
- Off like a bloody bastard-
- What the hell do you mean?
That's why I missed him-
I won't miss him next time-
I'd never miss him again
if I got another chance, boy-
What about this?
Bloody Christmas present-
If I'd had this... -
I'd have wiped that bloody smile
right off his greasy face!
He was laughing at you, boy-
I hope this bastard is his brother-
But it was your job to get that tank,
not to worry about me, you stupid idiot!
No! He had something
in his hand, you see-
Something in his pocket-
Might've gone off, boy-
Might've been a bloody bomb-
Pity I missed him-
4:22-
July 17-
It's a good watch, boy- It's a Swiss-
Come on, boy-
If I had hit that tank... -
if I had, you might have gone up, too-
We didn't think of that, did we?
I'll tell you what, though, Mac-
There'll be no more games
from now on-
I'll tell you something, boy-
He's not going to come in so close,
now I've got this-
Maybe he's gone home for a coffin-
Like to have a smoke?
How many did he have on him?
Three-
Any photographs?
Yeah, a picture of his girl-
No money-
Got his lighter- And a watch-
I don't want to smoke-
You can have them-
I'm not having one if you aren't, Ansell-
All right-
You can have this other one
in the morning-
My hands are still shaking-
It's good, isn't it?
Yes-
What time is it, then?
It's not working-
You know what we'll have to do?
We'll have to put these tins in order-
- Why?
- So we know what they are in the dark-
We have to know that-
We must balance our diet-
Look, I've told you, I know what they are-
Come on-
You do?
There are only three kinds-
Big ones are beans-
Square ones are beef-
Medium, condensed milk-
How do you know that?
I smelled them-
- I don't believe you-
- Oh, yes-
I used to work in Fortnum & Mason,
you know-
Best store in London-
Only did it for the experience, of course-
And what I could pick up-
- What you could pick up?
- Yes-
Used to get a lot of Norwegian giris
in there... -
and Swedish-
I got this Australian girl once-
Took me to the Ritz- Paid for everything-
Father's a composer-
Lovely big baths they've got at the Ritz-
You can do anything in them-
I offered to pay- She wouldn't have it-
Got any daughters?
I'll bloody well keep my daughters
away from you-
Why?
I don't hold with all this-
With all what?
Hold with all what, Mac?
You give me that opener-
You say that these medium-size
are condensed milk?
I've told you that already-
Here-
Quite right, aren't you?
Why do you want to keep
your daughters away from me, Mac?
I'm a very good teacher-
How many are there?
Two-
They could do a lot worse, you know-
You must have given that bastard pilot
such a shock-
Ansell-
I'm not having you mess about
with any of my daughters-
Not flying so low now, is he?
I wish to hell he didn't know I had this-
He's all by himself-
Yes, and he wants us all for himself,
too, I'll tell you that-
Mac-
What's between us and the mountains?
Nothing-
What do you mean, nothing?
Villages-
No soldiers? No patrols?
Border patrol-
You don't know, do you?
No-
You don't know anything about it,
do you, Mac?
I know you're all right
once you get up in the snow-
Who's done it, Mac?
Who's ever done it before?
Why don't we just dig ourselves
a couple of graves and go to sleep?
Better cross over there
and get up the other side-
What?
Oh, Christ!
It's not funny, you know!
Oh, boy-
I've got to keep my shirttails out of this-
I know you're right,
but I hate that low ground-
I know, Mac, but we've got no choice-
Let's go fast-
I hope we're not too sore-
You were right
about that condensed milk-
He's a bloody field marshal now-
I lost my hat-
We'll never get through them,
not both of us-
Want to split?
We'd better get down here and lie up-
We've got to-
- I can't-
- We won't find a better...
I can't get down there
and let them walk right over me-
Come on!
Mac, get in there-
Last time we took your advice,
we got bayonets up our arse-
Whose fault's that?
If that black skeleton comes in over
the top, he'll drop mustard gas on us!
What would you suggest?
Why should I have to suggest anything?
You're the one
who makes the suggestions-
who goes in those stores... -
making suggestions to young giris-
You've got no right
to take advantage of them like that-
I think you're stark, raving mad-
Bloody sex maniac!
You ought to be in court-
One of those fathers
ought to have locked you up-
- I think you ought to be analysed-
- What?
They should never have invented
that bloody pill-
Right-
- Are you hurt?
- No-
Well, those idiots saw us come in here,
didn't they?
Come on, boy! Come on!
Get yourself through the middle-
Come on!
Through here, Ansell!
- Water!
- Wait! Wait till he can't see us-
Hey, don't wait for me!
Look what I've got-
I'll put it under his bastard pillow, boy!
One of your little school friends-
Be quiet, for God's sake-
Shut up, you maniac!
If I find that bastard pilot...
Hey, you bastard!
Ansell, that pilot's trying
to burn up everything-
I can't take him up in the snow-
I can't take him up there, boy-
Too cold up there- Go on, then- Go on!
Goodbye- He's gone-
Goodbye, you little sweetheart-
Where's your gun?
Can you hear me?
Get that mud out of your ears-
Get that muck out of your ears!
Can you hear me now?
- Yeah, I hear you-
- Where's your bloody gun?
It was the bloody farmers, wasn't it?
The farmers saved us, didn't they?
The poor old farmers-
My face hurts-
Yes... -
well, you better... -
put some mud on it-
Then the blisters can't...
See?
Put that mud on it!
You see him?
This time... -
you've got to do it-
I'll cover you with the gun-
All right?
Go on, boy!
That was your first-
Here-
It's here, boy, I tell you that-
What we need is food, Mac-
It's here, I know it-
Unbolt the door!
No bloody order- No bloody discipline-
They buggered it up for him, didn't they?
Wish I'd got him-
Want to go back?
Well, I got a drink out of it, anyway-
He's probably down there with that thing
at this very minute... -
crying over it-
I've got to sleep-
This'll keep the bastards in the holes
they were born in-
How far is the snow?
There isn't any snow- Snow's all melted-
Listen! I've got to sleep-
Well, you can't sleep here-
Come on, get up-
Give us your arm-
Wish I hadn't lost my hat-
I can see the bones in my fingers-
The tips are salty-
Don't look-
We smell like animals- Filthy!
Christ Jesus-
What have we done to ourselves?
All right, boy-
Not living- We're dead!
We should never have tried it!
We crawl along... -
slice with razors... -
blow our noses with our fingers-
Tear with our fingers!
Wipe ourselves with our fingers!
All right, boy, all right-
Oh, God! Oh, Jesus!
Oh, Christ!
We're worse than animals!
All right, boy, don't you worry-
My wife is five years older than me-
It's the face I always look for, Ansell-
The face, and then the legs-
She's got a pretty face,
but she hasn't got good legs-
Varicose veins-
That's because of the children-
She's always worrying about her legs,
she keeps shaving them-
The children haven't got good legs-
Not as pretty as their mother, either-
But they'll do all right,
because they've got her nature-
What happened was... -
she was always going out
with American soldiers-
I took my father's raincoat
and I put on my father's hat... -
and I went to a public telephone box
when I knew she was home-
I called her up,
put on an American accent... -
I lowered my voice... -
and I said, "Meet me in the park... -
"3:30, Sunday afternoon... -
"by the bandstand-"
Well, it was raining-
No band- But she came there-
I was 16-
She was 21-
Came there in a white mackintosh-
When she saw me
in my father's raincoat and hat... -
she laughed till she cried-
She went away-
I kept after her-
Then the Americans went away-
I had to join up myself-
And two years later,
I came home on leave... -
and I was drinking a lot-
And one night
she had to help me home-
I had to go out East-
She wrote to me... -
twice a week-
I was away for a long time-
When... -
she was... -
thirty-seven... -
yes, 37... -
and I was...
Well... -
anyway... -
we went back to the park... -
on a Sunday night... -
and... -
me and my wife, she...
Well, it was her idea-
I had her... -
underneath... -
bandstand-
How long have you been with your wife?
Years-
My children are all...
Children are all...
I've got old-
Yes, I've got old-
Come on, Pocket Billiards-
You see it?
Yes-
I never believed it-
Whose is it?
How do you mean?
I don't know whose it is-
Never did know-
Well, it's not theirs-
Come on-
- They won't shoot at us?
- No-
It's not theirs-
Come on, Mac!
We've made it!
Come on!
Maybe I could hold them back-
There's no need- Come on, Mac-
Do you know what? In all that time... -
all that war... -
she waited for me-
She never went out with anyone else-
Get up here, Mac! It's all over-
We're free!
Come on!
Get up here, Mac! Come on!
The day I was free... -
she knew it-
Nobody told her-
Thirty thousand miles away... -
she telephoned her mother-
Get up here, Mac!
Come on!
Childhood sweethearts-
Thin air-
Air's thin up here, you see-
"Thank God," she said to her mother-
Great, black bat-
Leave it, Mac- You've got no chance-
Hey!
Mac, what about me?
Come on, then-
Bastard!
Say your bloody prayers!