All new FBl agents
are required to recite
an oath as they graduate
from the academy at Quantico.
lt's not just a bunch of words,
it's the reason l joined.
l love America,
and believe it's worth defending
with my life.
ln 1983,
the FBl sent me to Taiwan
to assist in the murder investigation
of an United States citizen.
lt was there that l met Ming,
a man who had endured an injustice
that would force me
to reassess my Constitution,
my belief in the justice system
and the very foundation
of the government in the U.S.
FBl! He's with me.
Officer! Officer!
This American is with the
American lnstitute,
please take him away
and let me have a few minutes
with him
to discuss what just happened.
Don't worry, he's not dangerous.
Give us a few minutes, okay?
l just bought you some time.
You ok?
Here. Take that.
What the hell happened?
You start telling me
what is going on right now
or l am not going to be able
to protect you.
Oh come on!
You have no authority here.
This is Taiwan!
And in case you haven't noticed,
l'm the only thing connecting you
to your natural born rights.
Henry Wen's body had all the
earmarks of a mob style killing,
which is why l'm glad
they brought you guys in.
Hey hey! That's a first.
Personally, l think all this
whole rivalry
with the Feds is a bunch of bullshit.
l just want to catch the bad guys.
l'm with you.
Lisa, l like a straight forward gal.
That's Detective Gilbert,
Agent Braxton.
We discovered an abnormality
in the X-Ray.
His throat was scratched,
most of our examinations
are fairly straight forward.
This was an exception.
We pulled this from his trachea.
ls it Chinese?
Taiwanese actually.
l thought it might be a connection
to the lron Blood Patriots,
a Taiwanese gang with known
affiliates here in the U.S.
lron Blood Patriots?
Yeah.
And this was found here
at the crime scene.
These cigarettes are unavailable
for purchase here in the States.
l thought the evidence suggested
something somewhat
outside of my jurisdiction.
Could very well be Detective.
Henry Wen was a
professor of Economics.
This is what they're
teaching these days?
Not your run of the mill course study.
You find anything linking him
to the Taiwanese mob?
No, neither at the house.
And his widow was very helpful,
which is certainly not typical
of a mob related crime.
They killed him
because of his work.
There were spies,
watching him.
Any insight from the university?
We interviewed his fellow
professors and students.
He was well liked and respected,
he taught economics and apparently
he was writing a book.
What was the book about?
No one seems to know.
Or at least
that's what they're saying.
ln fact, we were just celebrating
Henry's tenure the night he was killed.
Coming into this country
as a young man,
an expert in number theory
and now being honored with tenure
in what l feel is record time.
To a man with great integrity,
may we look ahead to many
wonderful years.
Let's raise our glasses,
for Professor Henry Wen!
And when will we get to hear about
the wonderful new book Henry?
What book?
He was very well known in
the Chinese community,
their newspapers, etcetera.
Can you think of any reason why
someone might want to kill him?
Apparently, he was a very
outspoken critic
of the current
government in Taiwan.
l can't imagine Henry's
economic theories
provoking anything more than
esoteric argument.
But his wife suggested something?
She thought he was being spied on.
Well, maybe she was scared
shitless of this mob.
She was frightened.
Well, l'd say
that's understandable.
She did mention two
suspicious characters
who were hanging out across
from her house at the park,
and this was confirmed
by a neighbor.
l saw two guys in hooded
sweatshirts on bikes.
Anything more specific?
They looked Oriental.
l couldn't see them very well,
but they would sit on their bikes
right over there smoking cigarettes.
l saw them twice,
both times as l was going to
work in the morning.
lt just looks like the
work of amateurs.
Yeah, or made to look that way. What do
you think they were looking for?
And did they find it.
How are you getting along?
On some level,
l have been preparing for this
for many years.
But l am only now beginning to realize
that you cannot prepare
for something like this.
We knew each other our whole lives.
l attended a wedding at the
Ambassador many years ago.
l was a teenager.
lt was where l met my husband.
You might want to talk to the groom,
tell him l send my regards
and hope he is well.
Mrs. Wen was in the car when
the whole thing happened,
but she wasn't harmed.
They didn't touch her.
lt's awfully brazen.
They didn't seem to be concerned
with getting caught or identified.
The Wen's were the last ones to
leaving the building that evening.
Wen Ming Hwa?
Yes?
Ming Hwa! Ming Hwa!
Help me! Someone help me!
Ming Hwa? Ming Hwa?
No! No!
The meeting with Mrs.
Wen had stayed with me.
l can't imagine what that
must have been like.
lt's not often that a witness to
a murder is spared.
Why didn't they kill her?
l think this way of going about
it is the right way.
l think that is him, excuse me.
Agent Kelly?
Yes.
Susan Kane, l'm the
American liaison here,
how you doing?
Fine, how are you?
Please take them.
Let him take your bag.
So how was that flight?
-lt was good.
-Long huh?
We can get you settled into the hotel
and you can get some rest.
Agent Kelly, this is Mr. Kuo,
he's our liaison with
the government here.
Welcome to the Republic
of China Agent Kelly,
it's an honor to have you here
and the participation of the FBl.
lf there's anything l can do
to make your stay here
more productive,
please, do not hesitate to ask.
Thank you.
Superintendent Loh
of the police prefecture.
And Officer Chen of the
Taiwan Bureau of lnvestigation.
He's going to be your point person in
your assisting of the investigation.
We are looking forward
to your expertise
in finding the killers of Professor Wen.
-How dare you!
-Take him away!
All right gentlemen, shall we?
l'm sorry you had to see that.
Communist spy.
You can imagine all the problems
we have here.
Agent Kelly,
we have planned some
wonderful events for your visit.
At dinner tonight you will meet everyone
that is going to be
relying on your knowledge
and we have some excellent seats
to the ballet and orchestra.
Well, unfortunately,
l'm not here on vacation.
Well of course, work is important.
But this country has much to offer!
Whew, that's better.
l've been here four months and l'm
still not used to the humidity.
Never been through a
Chicago summer l take it.
Hey, l'm a California girl.
Ah, you need to pick your
assignments better.
Enjoy your stay Mr. Kelly.
Thank you.
You all set?
All set.
So, we'll send a car to pick you up
about 6:30 for the dinner,
and l'm going to recommend
that you take a nap.
l mean, these affairs tend to
be rather long
and believe me, its going to be hard
to leave early.
You know, l just need to
wash up for a bit
and then l'd love to get to
the Bureau office.
lf l may, we go to the dinner tonight,
have a couple of drinks,
get to know everybody a little bit.
You break through the formality here
and these doors just open .
When in Rome.
Exactly, when in Rome.
All right, thanks.
Get some rest!
Hello, National Palace Museum -
Yeah, l'm sorry,
do you speak English?
Yes.
Terrific, is this the
National Palace Museum?
Yes.
l'm calling to talk to
Dr. Huang Li Pei.
Dr. Huang is out.
Dr. Huang, sorry. Do you know
when he'll be back?
He's gone for the rest of the day,
would you like to leave a message?
No, that's all right, l will call him
back myself. Thank you very much.
Bye.
Taiwanese beer for you,
straight whiskey for me,
never even liked this stuff
before l got here.
When in Rome.
You know sometimes l think
this government
spends more of our money
on entertainment than defense.
Agent Kelly, Susan.
Did you find
time to see some of our city?
Unfortunately, l didn't
get out of the hotel.
As you can imagine,
l'm itching to get to work.
l think we're called to dinner.
l hope you guys are hungry!
Cheers!
Please drink!
Wow, l should be honored.
Oh, there's plenty more
where that came from.
Can't wait.
Hope you enjoyed your
evening Agent Kelly,
it was a great success.
Good night.
Thank you. Good night.
Taiwan lndependence!
We want murderer!
We want truth!
What's with the bags?
Bold fashion statement?
Or a political statement.
Or maybe they just
don't want to be identified.
Oh yeah, maybe they're the killers.
l mean, it's not like you can tell these
people apart anyway without the bags.
You are an asshole.
The bill they pulled from Wen's throat,
the Chinese mafia, when they make
a hit they leave a little bit of money
behind to pay off
the ghost of the victim.
That's very thoughtful.
l'm having a hard time seeing this
guy as some kind of gangster.
Well trust me, as you limp towards
retirement, it's gonna get easier.
We had a lot of calls come in,
we should go.
Now we're just wrapping up,
what about you? You find anything?
Just a monthly wire transfer
of $1000 bucks a pop.
You're kidding me.
Crime ain't funny Jake.
Well, why didn't you tell me this
from the start of the conversation?
Because the recipient is,
drum roll please,
the Presbyterian Church of Taipei.
Yeah, this mob connection thing,
you're right, it's a little thin.
Well, keep working it.
l appreciate and value
your years of experience.
lt's a good thing Braxton's not here,
he hates Chinese.
You gotta be kidding me.
How many calls have be gotten?
Hundreds, most of them worthless.
Any of them jump out at you?
Maybe. We got a call from
a convenience store owner,
he says two Asian guys come in and
as they're leaving, he's not sure,
but he thinks that they're driving
a brown Cutlass Sierra.
Okay, where was this?
-Brigmar and Ciscero.
-That's six blocks from the University.
Right.
So l do a little research
and l find out
the most commonly rented car
from O'Hare is a Cutlass Sierra.
By using the cigarette butts as a guide,
l make a short list of everybody
who arrives from Taiwan and China
who rents a Sierra.
Nice work.
Don't get too excited,
the list isn't that short.
So, what do we got?
Okay, so l just got a call
from a motel manager,
he says two Chinese guys
checked in the other day,
they don't speak very good English
and they're driving a Sierra.
-Wait, that's the motel?
-Right.
-That's the convenience store?
-Uh huh.
And that's the University?
Right off the expressway.
That's worth checking out.
Hi, l'm Detective Gilbert from
Chicago Police Department.
You called in about two Chinese man.
Oh, uh huh.
That's them.
David Wu. James Lee.
They're in room 36.
No Cutlass Sierra.
Clear.
Take a look around here.
l'll check back.
Lisa, there's two bikes back here.
Let's get some back up.
Lisa, do you copy?
Freeze police!
Stop! FBl!
lt's clear, it's clear.
This is Agent Kelly, FBl.
Shots fired, officer down.
4229 West Ciscero and 36th.
So, did you find anything?
lt doesn't hurt that much actually.
They're in Taipei!
The Cutlass Sierra was
found this morning
in an abandoned tire factory
on the south side.
She was right.
Who?
Lisa.
The car was rented from O'Hare two days
before Wen was killed, by James Lee.
The same James Lee bought a
ticket to Taipei, paid cash for it.
The second ticket was for David Wu.
So these guys flew out of O'Hare?
Passport Control had these sketches?
How the hell did they get out?
Anything from the locals?
Nothing, they believe that
these are false identities.
lnterpol?
Same.
And l've got the Senator
in charge of sub-committee
on Asian Affairs crawling
up my ass on this.
Seems he's making the
Professor his pet project.
Wants to turn this into
a god damed press event
because this murder
was of a U.S. citizen
and especially because
the suspects crossed the border.
Made in Taiwan.
Yeah.
But, seeing as how we don't have an
official relationship with them anymore,
we can't extradite anyway.
So State is telling me
that we are being
allowed one emissary to observe and
possibly assist in their investigation.
Why're you looking at me?
You're senior.
And when l left 'Nam l pissed out
the door of that chopper.
You can send me Europe.
So, how's your Chinese Kelly?
Um, nonexistent sir.
Well, tough, because you're up at bat.
Okay.
Now just remember, you're
being invited to assist.
What does that mean?
Don't be a cowboy.
Let them do their jobs.
Yes, sir.
Braxton.
Hey, it's Jake.
Hey, how's it going? Hey,
sick of the food yet?
Let's just say these people
like to drink.
l would too if l lived in a
fucking police state.
Yeah, me too.
But don't tell anybody.
So, what'd you find out.
Nothing. Going in to lD
some photos tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
These people don't seem
to view the case
with the same urgency we do.
l'll call you tomorrow after
l actually get to work.
Okay, don't forget. l worry about you.
Bye, Tom.
Bye.
They're going to take
Lee's body away
and the military police are going
to come back through that door
and they're going to throw
you ass in jail or worse.
So you tell me right now,
who gave you Lee?
Can you arrange
an unconditional release?
No.
There's nothing unconditional here.
Then all you're going to get from me
is name, rank and serial number.
Hello? How are you?
Hello, do you speak English?
Yes.
l'm calling to speak with
Dr. Huang Li Pei.
Who is calling?
This is Jake Kelly,
please tell him Mrs. Wen
suggested l call.
This is Huang.
Dr. Huang, this is Agent Jake Kelly
of the FBl.
l'm in Taipei assisting in the investigation
of the murder of Wen Ming Hwa.
A terrible tragedy.
Mrs. Wen asked me to
give you her regards.
Are you hungry, Agent Kelly?
Hungry?
You eat breakfast don't you?
l can recommend an
excellent restaurant.
Leave the hotel, walk 5 blocks.
The restaurant is on your right.
Thank you.
Dr. Huang?
Guess not.
What do you want to eat?
Uh, l.
What do you want to eat? Eat?
Um. l'm sorry, l don't,
do you speak English?
What do you want eat? Eat?
No, thank you.
You can't sit here
if you're not ...
Okay, coffee? Coffee. Coffee?
Don't.
lt isn't me! lt isn't me!
Help me! lt isn't me!
Please don't!
Hey, wait!
Hey!
You speak English?
Please, sir. Calm.
You know Dr. Huang?
He only ask you pay your bill.
First, we'll give you what we have on
known gang members here in Taiwan.
By the way you found Henry Wen
we believe he was assassinated by a
group called the lron Blood Patriots.
They are very well represented
in various U.S. cities,
facilitating stolen electronics
and drugs from the region.
And your Professor Wen,
he was a well known
boss of another gang,
the Bamboo Tigers.
Really?
Professor Wen was a
well respected academic.
We're having a tough time
picturing him as a mob boss.
As you can imagine, it's easier for us
to infiltrate these groups
than it would be for you.
Unless the Bureau is actively recruiting
native speakers of Taiwanese these days?
Please.
lf you got a good look at the assassin,
l assure you, you'll find him here.
Someone once said, be careful
for what you wish.
Well, right now l wish for
a pot of coffee.
Pour him a cup of coffee.
Well Agent Kelly,
what new information
do you have for us?
They're not here. No James Lee,
no David Wu.
That is impossible. This is the combined
work of 3 security agencies on the island.
Every gang member in Taiwan
would be in these books.
Sorry.
l think you've made an inaccurate lD.
He was as close to me
as you are right now.
And l'd have no trouble lDing you.
Agent Kelly!
How was your first day?
Mr. Kuo.
He says he didn't find the
suspect in any of our files.
Really?
Well, Agent Kelly must be right.
We'll cross check everything to make
sure no one has fallen through the cracks.
l'll go immediately now to get it done.
Yes, please go.
Now in the meantime Agent Kelly,
you've earned some serious R & R.
l know some place special
for me to take you.
Really special.
Come on.
Sounds good.
We have a private room for dinner,
then l'm going to introduce
to you some VlPs.
You're going to be in very
exclusive company Agent Kelly.
Very few people get to
see a party's inner sanctum.
Just me and the ClA spooks
there at the table, huh?
You guys are great.
You have some imagination
Agent Kelly.
l suppose in your line of work
it comes in handy. Come on.
So, who else would
rate to come in here?
Businessmen, representatives of your
Boeing or Lockheed perhaps.
You take good care of
my friend, okay?
lf you will excuse me, l'm going
to check the kitchen.
They make a very, very good
New York steak. Cheers.
Cheers.
Thank God for that guy, right?
You here on business?
Yeah.
Well, then you know what l mean.
Did you know
there's hundreds of missiles
being pointed at us right now
from China?
Ah, no l didn't.
And for what? Christ,
the Reds are already going to
get Hong Kong back.
With the Brits in charge,
that's for sure.
But that guy right there,
that guy right there is the only thing
keeping Taiwan safe for making money.
And democracy.
Yeah, that too.
That too buddy.
Cheers.
Yes, operator, l would like to
call the United States please.
Thank you.
Braxton.
lt's me.
Hey! How's it going,
you sound tired.
l am.
Yeah? Too much partying over there
or did they finally put you to work?
Yeah. Except it turns out their complete
records weren't exactly complete.
No kidding.
So, now what do you do?
Show up tomorrow,
they pull more files.
Sounds like fun.
What's that noise?
You got somebody coming up?
You got a girl coming up
over there or something?
Yeah, several. l'll call you tomorrow.
Hello.
May l help you?
l always wanted to meet an FBl agent.
Consider my friendship as a token
of our President's appreciation.
Please tell Mr. Kuo thank you
but, no thanks.
You don't find me attractive?
l find you very attractive.
l find you very sexy Agent.
Don't use your phone,
they're listening.
Who's listening?
Get angry. Throw me out.
Meet me in the alley in ten minutes.
Get out.
You don't like girls?
l don't like whores.
Get out!
How the hell did you think
you were going to
get a known felon in Taiwan
on a plane to the States?
That's why l called you!
l don't work for you and
l don't have unlimited powers.
-You wanna talk to the Ambassador
-Bullshit! Don't give me that!
you head across the Taiwan
Strait and go up to Beijing!
No, the government here
is highly dependent on ours!
No, the government here,
and ours l might add,
are only concerned with
making sure this island
doesn't become subject
to a Communist takeover.
And that's it.
Oh, come on! l don't buy for
one second that you believe that.
You're not stupid and you're not naive!
How does arresting me prevent
a Communist takeover, huh?
Where you going with this?
Were you followed?
No.
-Are you sure?
-Yes, l'm sure.
All right, it's dangerous here.
Who are you?
My name is Maysing.
Dr. Huang sent me,
okay? Let's go.
Maysing, who are you afraid of?
What's going on?
Did you enjoy your dinner tonight,
Agent Kelly?
Did they keep your drink full?
So, what're you saying?
They received a tip on Wu Da-Wei,
his name is David Wu in your country.
They know where he's hiding
and they are already making their move.
Come. We're close.
He's in the last room on the first floor.
FBl!
-FBl Agent!
-Stop!
What is he doing here?
Why wasn't l called about this?
Take him away!
-Away immediately!
-You can't do this!
Shit!
What were you thinking?
lt was a take down.
l thought l should at least be advising.
Christ. You could have
been shot on site
and then l'd really have a mess
on my hands, wouldn't l?
This morning they have no idea
who David Wu is.
Less than twenty four hours later
they're staging a major raid with half
the Taiwanese army to assassinate him.
This is not a conspiracy.
No.
No, its mob theory they keep
pushing down my throat.
The gangs here are very well connected
and unfortunately we have almost
no control over corruption.
Henry Wen was not a gangster.
We're outsiders here.
They do things differently
and they're not going to let us
in on the inside.
The military maintains an awfully
high profile here.
Well, they've been in a state of
martial law since '47.
l think it's very difficult for us to
understand constant threat of invasion.
The threat of a Communist
takeover. Very hard.
Front desk.
May l help you Mr. Kelly?
Mr. Kelly? Hello?
The phone's been ringing off the
hook for three hours.
Let me guess, Susan Kane?
Washington.
Washington?
Yeah, l mean, l didn't know
you had it in you
but you're apparently kicking
up a shit storm over there.
Tom, l'm telling you, they had 30 guys
between him and door and they shot him.
lt's their show!
Yeah, and they're taking me out to
dinner while the raids going down.
You're only there to assist.
How am l supposed to assist if
they're killing the suspects?
Tell you something bigger is going
on here. l'll know more soon, l think.
Yeah well, when you know,
be sure to let us know.
l gotta go.
Why am l not surprised?
l'm glad you do not dismiss
a lowly waiter, Agent Kelly.
l am Ming.
Dr. Huang is here?
l will take you to him.
So you knew Professor Wen?
No, l didn't know him.
Chicago's a big place.
And what did you know about him?
He seemed very well liked.
His wife was very nice.
There was a big demonstration
on campus protesting his death.
And this demonstration, what
was it trying to say?
lt was trying to connect his
death to your government.
Does that seem impossible to you?
Well, l know about his affiliation
with the Bamboo Tigers Gang.
You really must speak with
Dr. Huang.
How does arresting me prevent a
Communist takeover?
Where are you going with this?
Why were you meeting with
Dr. Huang? Hm?
Huang was Wen's mentor. Wen's
widow wanted me to say hi.
So you went all the way down
to Kaohsiung to say hi?
lf l tell you, can you get them to
release Ming to me?
l can talk to
the Minister of Foreign Affairs.
Not good enough.
You know what, let me
tell you something.
This isn't just some little investigation
you can control at your field office.
l don't think you understand
exactly what's going on here.
Yeah,
do you?
How is Mrs. Wen?
Under the circumstances, she
seems like a very strong woman.
When l last saw her, she was
a shy, beautiful bride.
Wen was very happy.
His was a terrible loss.
Are you close to finding his murderers?
Unfortunately, l seem to be
somewhat outside of the investigation.
They're not giving me much to go on.
This is very frustrating l'm sure.
So, who would want to
kill Henry Wen?
Are the police telling you
the mob is responsible?
Yes. And l don't think Henry Wen
had anything to do with the mob.
l'm proud of my student Henry Wen.
He did what l could not do.
What's that?
He made the ultimate sacrifice.
He left his country in order to
make it better for his people.
Being in your country, a free country,
he could speak freely.
What do you know of
our country's history?
Under Japanese occupation
until the end of World War ll.
Then when Chiang Kai-Shek and his army
were forced out of China by Mao Zedong
he established control here.
He's been protecting Taiwan
from the Communist invasion
from mainland China ever since.
l guess that information has been
approved by your State Department.
This island has been controlled
by foreigners for a long time.
To establish control Chiang Kai-Shek
imposed martial law.
lt didn't matter that people here
were harassed, arrested, tortured.
were forced to speak Mandarin.
We were fined for speaking our
own language, Taiwanese.
ln America, Wen was
able to write about all these things.
There are eighteen million native
Taiwanese on this island,
but about two million mainland
Chinese rule them.
And the minute your President Nixon
shook the hand of Chairman Mao,
the government saw their days were
numbered. They are desperate.
Desperate enough to kill an
American on America soil?
Kill the chicken, to scare the monkey.
Fear made us lose our awareness.
lt can turn us into cowards as well.
l do not wish to offend you
Agent Kelly.
But you might ask yourself why
your government sent you here.
You do not seem to be
an expert on Taiwan.
l was the only one who could
identify Wen's killer.
But they already know who
killed Professor Wen.
But what's important is we all can
say we did what was right.
And l owe this to Wen.
Taiwan lndependence!
We must finish Wen's work.
Come on.
Taiwan lndependence!
Today we are here for our Formosa
Our Taiwan. We are not afraid of...
Wen sent this to me. Now you
will reveal its contents.
You don't want to give that to me.
lf you were to give me evidence
l'd have to turn it in.
We all have to believe in
something, Agent Kelly.
l choose to believe, as did Henry,
in the ideals of the United States.
What about you?
Aren't you worried about what's
going to happen to you?
l am the chief curator of the greatest
collection of Chinese art in the world.
l am thus useful to the government.
lf l were not, l would not
have been here to meet you.
Finally, l too am doing the right thing.
Thank you Agent Kelly.
Thank you.
Ming.
Thank you very much, Dr. Huang.
Be careful.
Bye.
Taiwan lndependence!
All the fellow Taiwanese, the masters
of our Formosa, we stand up today...
They are speaking in Taiwanese,
not Chinese.
For democracy and
freedom of Taiwan,
With courage, we stand here today
What's two-two-eight?
February 28, 1947.
Chiang Kai-Shek's army killed twenty
thousand Taiwanese in one week.
lt's illegal to talk about.
What are they saying?
lndependence!
Taiwan lndependence!
Don't be panic.
Sit down! Everyone sit down.
Let's stay together.
You and Dr. Huang talked for
what twenty minutes apparently.
So you knew l was being followed.
This isn't the U.S. You're a visitor
going outside of your directives.
Well, you're not much of an agent if
you don't know you've been watched
since the moment you got here.
Who's side are you on?
l could as you the same question.
You're withholding evidence,
aiding a Communist spy.
What is this?
A government briefing now?
Military command briefed me
as a courtesy.
All right, let's cut through the bull then.
Why don't you tell me what you know.
All right, here's what l know,
an emissary of the United States was
seen at an anti-government rally.
That doesn't look too good.
This government ordered its army to
fire into a group of unarmed civilians
who were trying to stage a
peaceful protest.
How does that look?
l'm going to get back to the hotel.
lt's late. Please stay.
Oh, no it's...
Let me get some tea.
l can't believe the army could fire
on a crowd like that.
They were ordered to do so.
Why?
lt was a pro-democracy rally. The
government needs no publicity about 228.
They have done such a good job
that no one outside
this island knows about it.
That is why we suspect they
killed Henry Wen.
He was trying to expose it
to the rest of the world.
What happened?
After World War ll, the Japanese
left after fifty years.
We were very happy.
Then the Chinese Civil War started.
Chiang Kai Shek's army
began to lose against Mao Zedong's
army and the Communists.
Chiang's army started
coming to Taiwan.
At first, we were happy because most
of our ancestors are from the mainland.
But then, we began to realize why
they were losing the war.
lt was because they stole from
people on the mainland
in the same way they would
steal from us.
They came to Taiwan and saw
how rich we were.
And they acted
like they owned everything.
On February 28, 1947,
we native Taiwanese got together
and demanded for justice and order.
They responded by sending a
battalion to kill us.
They were very specific about
who they killed.
They killed politicians, businessmen,
journalists, intellectuals,
anybody who could create a government.
An entire generation of leaders.
My father was a civil engineer.
He was taken from my house
and dragged to the river
with five other unlucky men.
They were tied together,
they shot one of them in the head and he
dragged the four others down with him.
My father was the last to drown.
You should drink your tea,
it's a healing tea.
The Chinese say we are their brothers,
but if we are brothers,
why do they treat us like this?
Thank you.
Sweetie.
Come here, don't bother our guest.
No, no, no, it's okay.
We know there are agents sent
by the Chinese government
in every major university
in the United States.
Good morning.
Morning.
There's a shirt for you.
Thank you.
Pour him a cup of coffee.
How did Wen get that tape overseas to Dr.
Huang without the government getting it?
Even the government is not
organized enough
to deal with
the chaos of our mail system.
What's on the tape?
lt's a dictation of the major events
of Wen's book. lt's back up.
He sensed he was in danger.
What's the book about?
He was writing about
the Taiwanese's government's
systematic use of the Chinese mob.
The gangs sell drugs, and use
the money to buy arms
in other countries including
the United States.
They create fear by
spying on their own people.
Laundering money,
even killing political dissidents.
Open the door!
Open the door! Police!
Agent Kelly! You must come
with us immediately!
-Officer
-Susan!
Please wait a moment!
Keep moving!
Agent Kelly!
Where the hell have you been?
We've been looking
for you all morning.
Look, l don't know what's going on,
but l suggest you play this very cool,
let me do the talking.
And try not to say anything stupid.
Where's Kuo?
Good morning gentlemen.
Good morning. Thank you for coming.
l would like to take this opportunity
to reiterate the importance
the United States places
on finding Lee Shin-Shen.
We are aware of your concerns
Miss Kane.
And let me assure you, that we want
to find him as much as you do.
Thank you.
Do you want to find Lee or
do you want to assassinate him?
l saw how efficiently you
apprehended David Wu.
We can all appreciate l'm sure
Agent Kelly's frustration.
Please Ms. Kane,
Agent Kelly understands
what is occurring here.
We are eager to hear from him.
Well, perhaps you could tell us
what you were doing there.
l was doing what l was sent here to do.
l was observing.
Perhaps you'd like to tell me next time
when you're carrying out
a raid against one of my suspects.
The suspects are no longer your
suspects, it is our investigation
and if l tell you any information
regarding it, it will be out of courtesy.
l am quite certain, we all want
to find Lee Shin-Shen.
l am curious though,
how did you know where it was?
l was out for a stroll.
l saw some police activity
l decided to follow it.
Then, perhaps you could tell me
what you were doing at an illegal
protest in Kaohsiung yesterday.
Excuse me?
Surely, you weren't just
out for a stroll then.
No, l received a tip that Lee
was hiding in Kaohsiung.
And was he?
l don't know.
l was beaten over the head by
police before l could find out.
lndependently pursuing leads
can compromise our and
Officer Chen's investigations.
The last thing l want to do is
compromise this investigation.
And if l've somehow done that, l
apologize to you and Officer Chen.
Given the current state of unrest,
we fear it's not longer safe
for you to be here.
Your assistance is greatly appreciated,
but we will kindly request that
you leave the country no
later than tomorrow afternoon.
Ms. Kane.
Of course.
l trust that this will be enough time for
you to wrap up all your affairs here.
Thank you gentlemen.
Agent Kelly?
l can't leave yet!
My hands are absolutely tied.
We have no official relationship
with this country,
you're luck they didn't
throw you in jail!
Lee is the key to this whole thing.
He could blow it wide open,
which is why they want to get rid
of me and get to him first.
This is their investigation.
There's not going to be an investigation!
They're going to kill him.
What exactly are you driving at here?
l think the Taiwanese government
conspired to have Wen killed.
Listen, even if that was true, you'd
never be able to prove it.
No, not without Lee.
Stop. Show me your lD.
We are from the American lnstitute.
Go. Keep driving.
Listen to what you are saying.
You're thinking of indicting the
Taiwanese government
for murdering a U.S. citizen
on U.S. soil?
l'm really sorry it has come to this,
but you're going to have to let
this one go.
Don't leave the hotel
without calling me.
What's he doing?
Hello, operator.
Hello, operator. l'd like to call
the United States collect.
One moment please.
Hello?
Tom!
Jake! So, did you find out anything?
ls Daltry there?
What do you want to talk
to Daltry for? He's gone.
They're sending me home.
-What?
-lt seems l've overstayed my welcome.
This is bullshit.
Yeah well, shit see,
l told you to lay low.
lt's tough to lay low
when you're discovering the Taiwanese
government had Wen murdered.
What? What did you just tell to me?
lt makes sense the State
was calling Daltry.
Wait a minute, run that by me one more
time. What are you talking about?
Jake?
Jake!
Hey! Don't move!
Shit!
Where are you going!
Hey! Stop!
Jake?
Huang's dead!
-What?
-lt's not safe for you. We have to go!
They're coming after you next.
Come on!
Come on.
Come.
l see you have met my sister. She
has contacts at the security police.
Apparently.
Victims of torture.
From Kaohsiung?
Some perhaps.
This was made by blowtorch.
You see for yourself the words of Dr. Huang.
lt's good fortune you were
at the protest in Kaohsiung.
l believe they have started
something that cannot be stopped.
Brother, come here.
You tell him.
l'm sorry, but the security
police have information
that Lee Shin Shen
has fled to Hong Kong.
Leave quickly!
FBl! That man is with me!
He is under my custody!
Who are they? Who?
Give him a taste of blow torch.
No! l don't know!
lf you hold still, l will
remove your handcuffs.
You may remove your blindfold.
Don't worry, you are safe.
You are a lucky man Agent Kelly.
After your capture l lost track
of you for many hours.
Now l was afraid one of my subordinates
executed you under his own authority.
That would have been unfortunate.
You certainly aren't the push over
our government was expecting.
Where's Ming?
You will see him soon.
Change can come from anywhere.
Like my friend Huang,
some prefer to work from the inside.
Huang is dead.
Why should l trust you?
You have no reason to.
What if l told you
your suspect Wu Da Wei
and Lee Shin Shen
were members of an organization
called the lron Blood Patriots
and this organization was contracted
to assassinate Professor Wen.
You'd just be confirming something
l already suspected.
So the government was involved?
Yes.
Military command?
Of course.
But the order came from higher up.
The primary patron of the lron Blood
Patriots is the son of the President.
So they killed Wen to save face?
Yes.
But, why risk alienating the U.S.?
The decision was foolish. As are many
of the decisions l encounter these days.
Did you know about it?
Would you believe me if l said no?
l'd have my doubts.
As you should. This is tricky
business here Agent Kelly.
We must maintain sight of
the end game at all times.
Although they won't admit it, this
government feels backed into a corner.
So much so, that they are right now
finalizing a deal with
several American businessmen
to fund and train Nicaraguan Contras to
fight their pro-Communist government.
ln exchange for that, the U.S.
Administration will back an arms
deal to Taiwan exceeding
fifty million dollars.
When President Nixon decided to
back Communist China,
the mainland gained advantage.
The U.N. seat moved
from Taipei to Beijing,
but the biggest threat to our government
is not the Red Giant
from across the Strait,
it is here in Taiwan.
What the vast majority of Taiwanese
people want is a democratic government.
Separate and independent from China.
Sounds reasonable to
you as an American.
China needs Taiwan.
Taiwan does not need China.
This is a fact the United States and the
rest of the world have never understood.
Henry Wen was Taiwanese. He was
murdered, in short, by mainlanders.
Now that Wu Da Wei is dead,
Lee Shin Shen knows he is being
hunted by his employers
because we've made him
more dangerous
to the government than
Henry Wen ever was.
And now he's fled to Hong Kong.
Be careful of your intelligence
Agent Kelly.
We know exactly where he is.
You see, unlike Wu Da Wei,
Lee Shin Shen is a rather high
ranking member of the Patriots
and is therefore
afforded some protection.
We've managed to get to
a number of his Captains
and they've agreed to
a prize to hand him over to us.
We will move on him tonight.
And you want me to get to him
before they do?
How will l find him?
He's in a club run by the Patriots,
your friend Ming will know.
They've released him?
l have arranged a suspension
of your surveillance detail.
You do not want to miss the
last flight out, Agent Kelly.
And l wish you luck with
your last few hours in Taipei.
Ming!
Ming.
Are you okay?
Are you all right?
Ming.
l know where Lee is.
lf you help me find him,
l'll bring him in.
Who are you? Who are you?
Where is he? l know he's here.
Shoot the gun! Just shoot me!
He was my friend,
did you think you were going to
get away with it?
Honestly, l was waiting
for you to come for me.
What's he saying?
He says he's been waiting for us.
l know l have already been
sold out to the government.
l figure l might have better
luck in America.
He says, he knows his men have
made a deal with the Party.
That he would rather try his luck
with the American courts.
Ask him why he killed Wen.
Why did you want to kill
Professor Wen?
The government made me
a good deal to do it,
but only now am l realizing that they
are not good business partners.
He says the Party made him
a good deal at the time.
Now he realizes that they
are not good partners.
Who hired him?
Who instructed you to do it?
You tell him that until l am safely
out of Taiwan
he won't get one bit
of information from me!
He says, once he is in your custody and
off Taiwan he will tell you everything.
Let's go.
Where are you?
Headed to the airport.
There are two of us leaving tonight.
lmpossible.
Not impossible. l'm going to need
your help getting through security.
l don't have that kind of power.
You guys are great.
l know you have enough leverage to
broker a secret arms deal to Nicaragua.
l'll meet you at the security gate.
Right here, right here!
Stay safe my friend.
l'm coming with you!
No, Ming you need to get out of here.
lt's not safe for you.
l do not care anymore.
Do you know what's going to
happen if they find you here?
The only thing left for me now is
to see you get on that plane.
FBl! He's with me!
Stop! Stop!
Officer! Officer!
This American is with the
American lnstitute,
please take him away and let me
have a few minutes with him
to discuss what just happened.
You've been nothing
but a god damned cowboy
since the moment you arrived.
Reckless and arrogant
and that's going to cost the U.S. more
in political capital than you're worth.
l didn't come here to see the opera.
You don't need to throw out forty
years of foreign policy for one man.
You're not going to change anything!
lf you think justice for Wen is worth
taking down the last bastion
we have against Red China,
you're a traitor to this country.
Let me tell you something.
Wen was going to tell the truth
about what's going on here
and he was murdered
by the government.
lf that's the policy,
it deserves to be thrown out.
Just tell them you were
bringing Lee to me.
Please go outside for a moment.
Yes, of course.
God damn it!
What happened?
He wanted to wish me a good flight.
So, you don't call, you don't write.
l was a little busy.
Yeah, Daltry wants to hear all about it.
Every agent in this division
is being subpoenaed
to testify before a House committee
to explain how the
Federal Bureau of lnvestigation
helped one of its own agents
to violate international law.
l was sent to do a job, and l did
that job to the best of my ability.
You were sent to observe and report
Not to get our only suspect killed
while trying to smuggle him
illegally out of the country.
lf we wanted Elliot Ness,
we would have sent Elliot Ness!
l was the only one over there trying
to apprehend the suspect.
lt seems to me that the only
thing you did right
was turn over a known terrorist
to the Taiwanese government
and you did that by accident!
Ming was not a terrorist! l would
never have found Lee without him
and now we're leaving him for dead.
That's an internal matter for the
Taiwanese government.
They killed his family Daltry!
His daughter wasn't a terrorist!
lt's not our call!
lt's not our call! What about the truth?
Does that matter anymore?
What about finding Wen's killers?
They're not our people.
They're not our people?
Wen's an American citizen!
His widow is an American citizen!
Well, there's a lot of folks
who don't see it that way!
Who doesn't see it that way?
Do you have proof Wen was assassinated
by the Taiwanese government?
Because this is still the Federal Bureau
of lnvestigation and we deal in proof
and if you're going to create an
international incident,
you damn well better have something
more than just your word to go on!
And l am not about to jeopardize
the rest of my career
for a bunch of god damned
politics that l could care less about.
Hey!
The Taiwan Bureau of lnvestigation
is charging that you smuggled
out pertinent evidence.
What are they talking about?
Hell if l know.
lf l may remind you Agent, it is a
felony to withhold evidence.
You signed the same oath l did to uphold
the Constitution against all enemies,
-foreign and domestic.
-Don't you start with me.
l did not join the FBl to observe
people getting murdered!
You sure you wanna do this?
This isn't what l signed up for.
You know, it's just a job.
All right.
Make sure to turn in any
evidence you got.
ls that you or Daltry talking?
Hey,
Daltry.
You know l don't care
what you do with it.
You gotta be true to yourself, huh?
Do the right thing,
only you know what that is?
That's very Chinese of you Tom.
Yeah, coming from you
l take that as a compliment.
l'll see you around.
Yeah, so long. l'll miss you.
We know there are agents
sent by the Chinese government
in every major university
in the United States.
l, too, am being watched.
l've seen them photographing me
as l've left my office at night.
l know what l'm doing
puts me at risk,
to speak out and demand
change of all ways
that have put others at risk in history.
We are suffering enough now!
We cannot be silent any longer.