An hour ago, a bomb blew up the Kremlin
The President has initiated Ghost Protocol
The entire IMF has been disemboweled
Now I have been ordered to take you to Washington
where they will hang the Kremlin bombing on you and your team
Unless you were to escape after assualting Brandt and me
But if any one of your team is caught...
they will be branded terrorists, out to insight global nuclear war
So what happens now?
Your mission
should you choose to accept it
So...
whats the play?
Who are you really, Brandt?
We all have our secrets
Don't we Ethan?
Ok, now remember, blue is glue
And when its red?
Dead
You're not gonna make it!
You're not helpin
Comingsoon...
In The Tvshow.ir
Ali®eza@