MAN: When I was a lad,
a journey down
the rivers of England
was a truly blithe experience.
"Bliss was it in
that dawn to be alive,"
as Wordsworth has it.
Brooklime and flag iris,
plantain and marsh marigolds
rioted on the banks.
And kingfishers
swooped and darted about,
their shadows racing
over the brown trout.
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
I'm happy to be
able to tell you
that these ravishing sights
will be restored to us again
in the near future,
thanks to the diligent efforts
of your government and
your local authority.
All the water above this point
will soon be clear.
Clear of industrial effluent.
Clear of detergents.
Clear of the waste products
of our society,
with which for so long
we have poisoned
our rivers and canals.
Let us rejoice that
pollution will soon
be banished
from the waters
of this river,
and that there will
soon be no foreign...
Look!
What is it?
It's a woman!
What's that
'round her neck?
She's been strangled!
MAN 1: Looks like a tie.
MAN 2: Yes, it's a tie,
all right.
Another necktie murder.
Come on.
Move out of the way.
Please come away
from here, Sir George.
It's another
necktie murder.
What are the police
doing about it? That's
what I'd like to know.
Why can't they
find him?
He's a regular
Jack the Ripper.
Not on your life.
He used to carve 'em up.
Sent a bird's kidney
to Scotland Yard once,
wrapped in a bit of
violet writing paper.
That'll do, Herb.
I'm quite sure the lady
doesn't want to hear
any more about it.
Or was it
a bit of a liver?
I say, it's not
my club tie, is it?
FORSYTHE: Cheers,
Squadron Leader.
Chin chin.
Good morning.
Look, it may come
as something of
a surprise to you, Blaney,
but in this pub
we sell liquor,
we don't give it away.
Still less do we expect
our employees to steal it.
I was going to pay for it.
Oh, yeah,
I'm sure you were.
Well, that's the last drink
you're gettin' on this house.
Go on. Get out.
I told you I was
going to pay for it.
I always pay for my drinks.
Even for your
watered-down gin.
Now, don't come
the innocent with me,
you bastard!
My stocks have been
well down this past month.
Now, you watch
what you're saying!
What, to a thief?
What's going on?
Our friend here says that
I've been pinching his booze.
Ridiculous!
He always pays.
How would you know?
Well, I work
with him, don't I?
And what else?
What's that
supposed to mean?
Look, just keep out of this,
will you, Babs?
Come on, Blaney, outside.
FORSYTHE: You're fired.
BABS: You can't do that.
He never stole
nothing in his life.
He puts the money
in the till.
I've seen him.
A thief or a boozer,
it's all the same to me.
I don't need
either one as a barman,
quite apart from
the fact that half the time
he's pulling your tits
instead of pulling pints.
Now, look here...
He can't keep
his hands off you.
The customers are
always talking about it.
And what about you?
Always fingering me.
You keep your
lying mouth shut, Babs,
or you can get out as well.
I'm off.
Keep the change!
I'll send for
my things later.
Just a minute!
There's a little matter
of £10 I advanced you
on your salary.
Are you planning to
steal that as well?
There you are.
You know what
to do with them.
You shouldn't let him
talk to you like that.
I know.
What are you
gonna do, love?
I don't know.
Another pub perhaps.
Are you all right?
You just gave him back
the 10 quid you borrowed.
I had to.
He didn't think I had it.
Don't worry,
I've got a bit left.
Well, this is Covent Garden,
not the garden of love.
How 'bout starting work?
Oh, get stuffed.
Look after yourself.
I'll call you.
Thanks, guv.
Hello, Dick.
Hello, Bob.
I was just coming over
for a quick one.
Why aren't you back there
polishing the sausages
or watering the gin,
or whatever it is
you do there
before opening time?
I have just been
given the push.
What for?
You weren't pissing
in the beer again?
Forsythe and I had
a set-to.
Oh, him.
You duffed him up, I hope.
He's a bastard.
He was on my back
right from the start.
From squadron leader to barman
in one easy lesson!
He wouldn't leave it alone.
He's the boss'
brother-in-law,
isn't he?
Forsythe?
Yeah, I think so.
Brother-in-laws
are the worst.
Or should I say,
"Brothers-in-law"?
What are you gonna do now?
I haven't decided yet.
Well, if you're in schtuk,
you know where to come.
Thanks.
George!
That's the last one.
Thanks, Mr. Rusk.
Why don't you go
and have a chat
with your ex?
She's doin' all right,
isn't she?
I haven't seen her
for ages, as you know.
There's no use
opening all that up again.
No, I suppose not.
Well, as I say,
you can always rely on me.
You're all right
for a few quid?
Yes. Thanks all the same.
'Cause if you're not...
No, no. Really.
I just got paid.
Well...
Have some grapes.
Here you are.
I'll get you a box.
Finest muscats,
fresh in this morning.
Here you are.
Take one of these back
to your girlfriend, Babs.
Get her to peel you one.
"Beulah, peel me a grape."
That's what my
ol' mum used to say
when I was a kid.
Well, at least you
won't starve to death.
(CHUCKLES)
Are you sure
you don't need
a few bob?
No, I'm okay.
Well, you don't look okay.
Anything else the matter?
No. What should be?
I don't know.
Well, remember,
anything I can do,
anytime, it's a pleasure.
Ta.
It won't be the same
in the Old Globe now.
Well, Babs
is still there.
Yeah, that's true.
And she's
prettier than you.
A matter of opinion.
Bye, now.
Hey, wait a minute.
Here, give us your paper.
Here you are.
This will make you
a fortune.
This afternoon in the 3:00,
Coming Up.
Never been
out before, but very
well-fancied at home.
Now, this is
a four-horse race,
and the other three
have all won before.
So she'll start about
20-to-1, maybe more.
20-to-1?
Put your word on it.
She can't lose.
A little birdie told me,
and my little
birdies are reliable.
Well, thanks again, Bob.
Anytime.
Don't forget,
Bob's your uncle.
Good morning, Mr. Rusk.
Hello, Sergeant.
What's new?
Not much.
This necktie fellow's
giving them a bit of
a headache, though.
Can't seem to get
a line on him.
Have you tried
advertising?
Oh, very funny.
Look, you're one
for the birds.
Ask 'em all if they've
ever had a near miss
with a bloke like that,
would you?
Or if any of their
girlfriends have.
Sure.
Mind you,
half of them haven't got
their heads screwed on right,
let alone knowing
when they've been
screwed off.
Have you met
my friend Dick B...
Funny fella.
Well, don't worry, Sergeant.
I'll put the word about.
Thanks, Mr. Rusk.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
A large brandy.
What're you
gonna have, Doctor?
A pint and a morsel of
cheese'll do me fine.
Let me order us
a hot lunch.
We have plenty of time.
Hello, Mr. Usher.
What's good
today, Maisie?
Stick to the shepherd's.
I would.
Right. That's two
shepherd's pies,
then, please.
And two pints.
I see our
necktie murderer's
been up to it again.
I saw the newspaper
headlines as we
came away from the court.
Hmm.
I wouldn't envy
the lot of any medical man
giving evidence at that trial.
Why not?
Why, surely
it's easier in these days
of legally diminished
responsibility.
In many cases
you may be right.
But not here.
The man who's
killing these women
is a criminal,
sexual psychopath.
And the legal profession
has never really known
how to treat them.
I suppose you could
call them social misfits.
We were just talking about
the tie murderer, Maisie.
You better watch out.
He rapes 'em first,
doesn't he?
Yes, I believe he does.
Well, I suppose
it's nice to know
that every cloud
has a silver lining.
Oh.
On the surface,
in casual conversation,
they appear as ordinary,
likable adult fellows.
But emotionally
they remain as
dangerous children,
whose conduct may
revert to a primitive,
subhuman level at any moment.
Large brandy.
You mean they'll
kill at any time,
just as the mood
takes them?
Exactly.
And, being governed
by the pleasure principle,
they're particularly
dangerous
when their desires
are being frustrated.
Are you deaf?
I distinctly said
a large brandy.
There's scarcely enough
in that to cover the bottom.
Actually, you can
make it a triple.
I wonder if the police
have got any sort of
line on this fellow.
Oh, I shouldn't think so.
With psychopaths
there's usually
no linking motive.
Let's hope
he slips up soon.
In one way,
I rather hope he doesn't.
Well, we haven't had
a good, juicy series
of sex murders
since Christie.
And they're so good
for the tourist trade.
Foreigners somehow
expect the squares of
London to be fog-wreathed,
full of hansom cabs
and littered with ripped
whores, don't you think?
RUSK: Hey, Dick!
What about
Coming Up then?
No, I'm afraid
I haven't any time.
Thanks all the same.
No, Coming Up, the horse.
It won by a mile.
20-to-1!
What did I tell you?
Made a fortune.
Thanks a lot.
Anytime.
Hey, wait a minute!
This is my ma.
Ma, meet Dick Blaney,
the best pilot who ever
pulled a pint of beer.
Hello, Mrs. Rusk.
Pleased to meet you,
I'm sure.
She lives down in Kent,
in the Garden of England!
Still got the grapes then?
Oh, yeah. Keep 'em for later.
You tell her to
take the pips out.
They're bad for the appendix.
Ta-ta.
Bye. Thanks again for the tip.
I told you,
Bob's your uncle.
20-to-1!
20-to-bloody-1!
Christ! Damn it to hell!
BARLING:
Well, my dears,
I'm sure I can say
on behalf of Mrs. Blaney
as well as myself,
that it's moments
like this that make
all our little efforts
here so worthwhile.
You mean,
you just don't
do it for the money?
(LAUGHING)
Of course,
Mrs. Davisson,
this is a business,
and financial
considerations prevail.
But our ultimate satisfaction
is the making happy
of two lonely people.
Nice of you, Miss Barling.
Keep up the good work!
Well, it's up to us now,
I guess, eh?
Yeah. And good-bye,
Mr. Salt.
Bye, Miss Barling.
Thank you.
It's been our pleasure.
And I know you'll
both be very happy.
After all, I know you're
both mad about beekeeping.
And there's nothing
like a shared interest.
I'm sure we will be.
Come on, Neville.
Best foot forward.
SALT: I suppose
we should go straight
and get the marriage
license, my dear.
What's your rush?
Let's go to my place first.
Did you know, Neville,
that my late husband,
Mr. Davisson,
was up at 5:30 every
morning of his life?
And by the time
he brought me
my cup of tea,
which he did
punctually at 9: 15,
he would've
cleaned the whole house,
and he was so quiet about it,
that in 14 years,
he never woke me once.
Not once!
Oh, a neat man,
was he, then?
He liked a tidy place.
So do I,
come to that.
Dandruff.
We'll have to get you
something for that.
Afternoon.
You're new here,
aren't you?
I've been here
for over a year now.
What can I do for you, sir?
You can inform Mrs. Blaney
that one of her less
successful exercises
in matrimony has
come to see her.
And who shall
I say is calling?
Mr. Blaney.
Or if you preferred it,
ex-Squadron Leader Blaney,
late of the RAF and
Mrs. Blaney's
matrimonial bed.
I see. Is Mrs. Blaney
expecting you?
She must be.
Everybody expects
a bad penny to turn up
sooner or later.
Mrs. Blaney,
there's a Mr. Blaney
to see you.
BRENDA: (ON SPEAKER)
Mr. Blaney? Send him in,
will you please, Monica?
Hello, Brenda.
Hello, Richard.
What are you doing here?
I just thought
I'd call around.
Well, come in.
Take a seat.
Thanks.
It's good to see you.
You too. You look fine.
I'll be with you in a minute.
I've got to finish
writing up a few notes.
How is everything
then, Brenda?
You making a fortune?
Things are going very well.
Streets of London
thronged with lonely hearts
beating a path
to your door?
That's it.
I'm amazed that in an age
where practically everybody
considers marriage is hell
that you can find
any clients.
Okay, Richard,
if you've just come
around here to insult me,
I think, perhaps you...
I'm not insulting you,
for Christ's sake!
Will you please
lower your voice.
Why?
I don't care if
Vinegar Joe out there
does hear me.
Why don't you
get her married off,
by the way?
Preferably
to a 700-pound
Japanese wrestler.
That should iron out
some of her creases
a little.
Monica, dear,
it's nearly 4:30.
Why don't you take
the rest of the afternoon off?
I'm sure there's
some shopping
you'd like to do.
Well, thank you, Mrs. Blaney,
if you're sure
you don't need me.
I'm quite sure, thank you.
Good night.
BRENDA: Why do you
always come to see me
when you've had
too much to drink?
BLANEY: I don't always come
to see you when I've had
too much to drink.
As a matter of fact,
I don't always
come to see you.
I haven't seen you
for over a year.
You were half seas
over then, and violent.
I do hope we're not going
to have a repeat of that.
Me violent?
Don't be bloody ridiculous.
Would I raise a hand
to the goddess of love?
What Brenda Blaney
brings together
let no man put asunder!
I didn't say
you were violent to me.
But you certainly
acted the fool
and threw the furniture
about a bit.
Just look at
the state you're in.
Really!
Oh, leave me alone.
Bachelors are supposed
to be untidy, aren't they?
I thought tidiness
was most women's dowry,
or don't you preach that here?
Oh, we are bitter today.
What's the matter?
I'm sorry.
I had a bad day,
that's all.
I lost my job.
How?
Well, I got fired, that's how.
What do you think,
I mislaid it?
For pinching
a glass of brandy.
My employer thought
I wasn't going to put
the money in the till.
Till?
I was working,
until this morning
that is, as a barman.
And another thing.
I was given
a very good horse
by a great friend of mine,
one Bob Rusk.
And it came in at 20-to-1,
and I didn't have
enough cash on me
to back it.
I'm sorry.
Well, these things
always go in threes.
I wonder what the rest
of the day has in store.
Dinner with me, I hope.
Well, that, of course,
would be delightful, but...
I mean, of course, on me.
We'll go to my club.
But I must finish
these letters first.
Here's the address,
in case you've forgotten it.
How will it be
if we meet there
'round about 7:30?
Fine.
Thanks for a lovely evening.
It was great. I mean that.
Thanks for joining me.
It was a damn sight
better than
the leftovers at the Globe,
not that I'm in for
any more of those,
of course.
You ought to get
married again, Richard.
Oh, no.
You ought to know
I'm no good at it.
How long did we have?
Nine years, was it?
Ten.
Ah.
Ten years.
It was a good job
you got out when you did.
I don't know.
I suppose
I was lucky the agency
worked out for me.
What you mean is,
that you're lucky
you haven't had to rely on me
these past two years.
I didn't say that.
But you meant it.
Look, Richard,
I suppose some people
are good at organization
and others aren't.
That's all I meant.
And I'm not, I suppose.
Rubbish! You know
what filthy luck I had.
Was it my fault that
the roadhouse didn't go?
It was going fine
till they opened
the bloody motorway.
I know.
Was it my fault
the council tore down
the riding stables?
I know. I know life
can be very unfair.
But you never
used to be
sorry for yourself.
Where's the Richard Blaney
I married?
Richard Blaney, EFC.
Do you remember
the citation?
"For inspiring
leadership, skill,
and tenacity of purpose."
You divorced him.
That's what happened to him.
Now, you tell me,
what sort of skill
do you need to
deal with shopkeepers
and interfering bureaucrats?
(SHUSHING)
Everyone's listening.
Well, let them.
I'll bet they've
never had to tear down
their own livelihood
with their own hands.
It's all right for you.
You just go
and build it up
somewhere else.
You're like that.
You're good at business.
I'll bet they're all
good at business here.
I'll bet you're
making a fortune
out of that agency.
And why not? If you
can't make love, sell it.
The respectable kind,
of course.
The married kind!
Now look what you've done.
Oh, sir.
Let me help you.
Leave me alone!
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that.
Come on. We'd better go.
Will you be all right?
You did say you
hadn't enough money
to put on that horse.
Don't worry.
You've done
enough for one day.
You had a coat too,
didn't you?
Yeah. That one there.
Mine's the pink one.
No, no, no.
That's not allowed.
Rules of the club.
Thank you.
It's all right, Richard.
I've got it.
Here. Thank you.
So, this is it, huh?
Can I come in?
I'd like to see
where you live.
Go along now.
Run along home.
It's late.
You call this late?
It's late enough
for a working girl.
Come on, Brenda.
I won't be long,
I promise.
All right, but only
for a few minutes, mind.
Okay, thanks.
I won't need you.
(MAN 1 SNORING)
(MAN 2 COUGHING)
It just fell out of
your pocket, guvnor,
onto the floor.
And I was just
putting it back
when you were asleep.
It sort of jerked out,
like, on the floor.
I was putting 'em
in a bit quiet, like,
so as not to waken you.
You keep your hands
out of my pockets,
or I'll break your arms!
Honestly, there's
nothing I detest
more than someone
taking liberties
with a fine gentleman
like yourself.
Oh, it's you again,
Mr. Robinson.
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Well, I'm having
my lunch just now.
If you want
an appointment,
perhaps you'll be
good enough
to see my secretary.
By the way,
how did you get in?
Oh, no problem, really.
Just a question
of using your head.
I waited in the courtyard
till I saw her
go out to lunch.
It all seems
a bit elaborate.
Yeah, perhaps, but...
You're the one
I wanted to see.
I thought I'd already
explained to you that
we cannot help you.
Oh, come on now.
I know that you can be
most helpful when you try.
Look, Mr. Robinson,
you want women of
a specific type.
How shall I put it?
Certain peculiarities
appeal to you,
and you need women
to submit to them.
Here we have, I'm afraid,
a very normal clientele.
As I say,
we can do nothing for you.
And now if
you'll kindly let me
get on with my lunch.
I don't think
you're really trying
your best for me.
I mean, if you can fix up
a lot of idiots,
then why not me? Hmm?
I've explained.
You're different.
How so?
I have my good points.
I like flowers and...
Fruit.
People like me.
I've got things to give.
I'm sorry.
I thought matrimonial agencies
were supposed to
bring people together?
Not people like you.
Somehow I don't think
our clients would appreciate
your conception of
a loving relationship.
You're not the only
matrimonial agency,
you know.
Then go elsewhere.
Not that any
reputable agency
would service you.
I've been elsewhere.
But...
This one, for me, is the best,
because...
I like you.
You're my type of woman.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm serious.
I respect a woman like you,
and I know how to
treat you as well.
You know, in my trade...
We have a saying.
We put it on the fruit.
"Don't squeeze the goods
till they're yours."
Now, that's me.