What do you mean?
Why would His Highness discard
Your Majesty, the Queen?
What are you doing? Quickly ready the
sedan chair to go to the King's Quarters.
Mother, please take back
the words you just said.
You're clearly unwell.
What's the big deal about me being unwell?
Even if I'm throwing up blood,
I still need to go over.
Going there, I'll say everything
as the Crown Prince wishes.
Your Majesty! There will really be
big trouble if you keep at it like this.
All right.
Quickly prepare the sedan chair.
I need to accompany Her Majesty
to the King's Quarters to visit Father.
Your Highness.
Hyeongnim.
(Hyeongnim - respected older brother)
What Hyeongnim?
How can you address the Crown Prince
who is to become king in a private manner?
Do you wish to be discarded too?
Do you really want others to say
the Crown Prince discarded his brother?
Then let's go.
You mustn't, Hyeongnim.
Your Highness, you mustn't go.
Please stop quarrelling with Mother.
If Your Highness and Mother
quarrel like this,
what am I to do?
If she turns out to be that way,
His Majesty will truly be in grievous despair.
Your Highness.
The Eastern Palace has sent message
that there's an urgent matter.
He has really awaken, right?
Yes, Your Highness.
Indeed, this is how it is.
You dare trespass here?
The two of you should have been
taken care of long ago.
Like how you killed Do Saeng,
you're going to kill the two of us?
Why'd you do it? Why?
What exactly did Do Saeng do wrong?
Soon the whole world will know
you're the true killer.
So when you arrive at King Yama's,
earnestly beg for forgiveness from him.
His Highness will be here soon.
You may need to let me go before then,
if you wish to save your daughter's life.
She's called Rang?
She's quite unwell.
My Rang, how...
She came to my residence as a servant girl.
Wake up!
Your Highness.
If you don't believe it,
you can ask female physician Da In.
She's currently at my residence
treating your daughter.
How did she end up with you?
As a human being,
how could you do such a thing...
So, if you wish to save your daughter,
kill that fellow Deok Pal.
Are you all right?
Yes.
I heard that he woke up.
But...
Perhaps...
He hasn't stopped breathing yet.
If female physician Da In didn't alert us
ahead of time to strengthen the guard,
Choe Won and Deok Pal
would have long been killed.
They all appear to be
assassins from the Ming Empire.
To find out the instigators behind it,
I fear that it won't be easy.
Indeed it would.
Tonight's matters mustn't get out
of the Eastern Palace.
If matters relating to Choe Won
and Deok Pal were to get out,
not only I, it's even quite probable that
Father will be implicated too.
Do you understand?
- Yes, Your Highness.
Indeed it would be that way.
If the matter is escalated now,
his concealment of Choe Won
would also be uncovered.
Anyway,
since it's so difficult to kill this Deok Pal, we should
let it get out that Choe Won is in the Eastern Palace.
Before that happens,
Choe Won will kill Deok Pal.
Very well.
However, if you fail this time too,
the next secret order will have your name on it.
Today, once again, the innocent
have died because of me.
Back in the day when your grandfather passed,
I vowed not to let anyone
die because of me again.
It was also because of me that
Jubu Min suffered a ruthless murder.
I was also at fault for Jubu Min's death.
I'm sorry.
You suffered unjustly because of me.
Not only have I been unable
to help clear your name,
I had you carry the heavy burden
of having to save him.
But what else can be done?
Only by saving him,
am I able to live,
and you are able to live.
What are you saying?
If her high fever continues unabated,
her life will be in danger.
You must have her live.
I have no need for a dead body!
Just pretend you didn't see me here.
Kill Deok Pal within 2 days.
That way, I'll have you and your daughter
escape to Ming China to live.
You must save him.
It's not merely for you and me.
It will protect your dear Rang as well, isn't it?
I took Deok Pal's pulse yesterday.
His cun-guan-chi pulses are all weak.
(Cun-guan-chi - 3 locations along the wrist)
I fear that he doesn't have much more time.
How about telling His Highness
about this sooner?
That cannot be done.
It's better not to have His Highness
hang onto false hopes...
I will hold out until the end.
Anyway, could you have
Da In come see me?
That cannot be done.
I don't want Da In to be re-entangled
in these matters and exposed to such plight.
I know I'm being selfish,
but it concerns the life of my daughter.
I beg of you.
Why didn't you tell me?
That my Rang is at
Gim Chi Yong's residence.
How did you know?
I'm really sorry.
You're focused on treating Deok Pal ajussi.
(Ajussi - older man, uncle)
I feared that telling you would
bring harm to the matter at hand.
Does that make any sense?
Why it is that I'm like this,
don't you know better than anyone?
I didn't think it through very well.
But how did you know Rang is over there?
Last night, I met Gim Chi Yong.
He told me, if I don't kill Deok Pal
by tomorrow night,
he wouldn't let my Rang off unscathed.
How can a human being do such a thing?
My Lord, how did you respond?
What else could I have said?
However, My Lord...
Rang has been having a high fever.
A high fever?
Right now, the most important thing is to
rescue Rang from Gim Chi Yong's residence.
Quickly deliver this letter to Heukseokgok.
What on earth did Horse Thief write on here?
I'm dead curious!
You won't die from curiosity.
Hurry up and polish this.
What is this?
What on earth does it say?
What on earth are you
grumbling about, So Baek?
Father, how could you be
defecating for half the day?
This is from Horse Thief to you.
Is it?
The black is words.
The white is paper.
I can't bear to look.
Like Father, like daughter.
What ignorance.
You. All that time you use
talking about those two balls,
when you could be learning Hangeul.
Have I told you before, or not?
You have.
Aigoo, you just know a few words.
Such a show off.
(Aigoo - oh dear, oh my god)
You're so stingy,
I'm not listening.
How will that work?
This is Horse Thief's letter.
You have to listen.
Right? Even if she's so stingy
I still have to listen, huh?
- Here, here, here.
- Aigoo.
Everyone at Heukseokgok,
are you well?
I haven't yet repaid the debt from before.
Now, I have another matter to request of you.
I'm too ashamed to see you.
My daughter Rang is currently in dire straits.
She is currently in Right State Councillor,
Lord Gim Chi Yong's residence
being held...
Being held?
What?
That child is in danger?
Where is that place?
Gim whoever's residence, Granny?
No!
Oh my. You scared me!
Father, why did you shout?
It's not the Royal Investigation Bureau,
it's Gim whoever's residence.
To take a child out of that type of place,
it's a piece of cake.
That...
When I say you can't, then you can't.
I don't care.
Father, if you're like that,
then you aren't a friend.
If it wasn't for the Horse Thief,
you wouldn't be all safe like now.
Kkeok Jeong!
You can go.
- I want to go too.
- No.
Why aren't you letting me go?
It's a piece of cake.
I already said no.
Really!
Enemies often cross each other's path.
Do you really want to handle
Choe Won's daughter like that?
I've already bet my life on
this to Her Majesty, the Queen.
If I want Choe Won to get
rid of Deok Pal quickly,
letting him see his daughter dying
is considered is the safest method.
If it's not done properly,
and his daughter dies before Deok Pal does,
what are you going to do?
Your adopted daughter, Da In,
doesn't seem like she'll let her die.
My Lord, everything is prepared.
My Lord, look.
Isn't she Choe Won's daughter?
We're from Lord Gim Chi Yong's residence.
Go back and watch over the
Right State Councillor's residence.
Yes.
Didn't he say that he wanted to use
her as bait to catch Choe Won?
But why is she sent to the palace?
I'm the Royal Investigation Bureau's
Inspector Lee Jeong Hwan.
That palanquin that just went in...
Where is that kid who is sick?
She isn't here right now.
I know that she's here.
If you're going to trick me, you're dead.
I already said she isn't here.
His Lordship took her to the palace.
What? The palace?
Are you referring to the
palace where the king lives?
I secretly came out with father knowing.
Kkeok Jeong, can the places that you
go to not have me, So Baek?
What's so great about this place
that father didn't let me come here?
There's nothing.
Is Kkeok Jeong really going to take the
lead in stealing the tribute this time?
Chief, your right hand man is me!
What is it?
Let's go straight to the palace.
The palace isn't a place that anyone can go to.
I'm not anyone!
I'm Yangju's Iron Hammer's...
Father...
Father, that...
The Horse Thief's daughter is in the palace.
That Lord Gim whoever
brought her to the palace.
We were one step too late.
So...
you want to go to the palace?
If I don't do that,
the Horse Thief's daughter will be in danger.
If you're going into the palace,
what about you?
Won't you be in danger too?
There is a way that isn't really dangerous.
Rang isn't at your residence.
Didn't you leave Rang's treatment to me?
How could you move Rang
who is having such a high fever...
I was about to call for you.
If you want to keep treating that child,
you have to do one thing for me first.
His Lordship,
only wants me to bring him inside.
Rang.
Rang...
Before the hour of the Pig tomorrow night...
(9-11pm)
If by then,
Deok Pal has yet to turn into
a frigid corspe,
you'll see this child turn into
a frigid corpse.
Did you see Rang?
My Lord.
Please help me.
Who are you?
Can we really slip into the palace
by carrying these things?
Where are the goods from?
These are the tributes from Gangwon Province.
If I had those two balls as well,
it'll be just right.
Why didn't those things grow
at the bottom but at the top?
Isn't that right, guys?
Let me see your identification tag and pass.
Follow me.
Everything is here.
All of you may leave when it's unloaded.
- Yes.
I have something else to do in the palace...
You can go.
Wow, Kkeok Jeong.
You seem just like a real one.
You'll die if you say
the wrong things in here.
Where exactly is Rang?
I'm hungry.
I want to eat pig trotters.
- Quieten down.
- I want to eat pig trotters.
My legs...
Where exactly is Rang?
Why is this palace so big?
Seriously...
I can't harm you in order to
save my daughter's life.
But...
not being able to continue
giving you treatment... I'm sorry.
This is related to this child
and there's no time.
Please help me notify the Supervisor.
The cold wind keeps coming in through here,
so I want to move the child further back.
Can you give me a hand?
I got it.
He has already stopped breathing,
Your Highness.
What are you talking about?
That's not possible.
How can...
How can this be?
Where is Choe Won?
Where did he go?
Quickly take Rang.
This is something that Lord Gim Chi Yong did.
They are the ones who killed Deok Pal
and took Choe Won away too.
Royal Guard Seo, quickly go and
check on Gim Chi Yong.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
What am I going to say to father this time?
When His Majesty asked me
about Deok Pal's condition before,
I already said that he wouldn't recover so easily.
Although he looks very disappointed,
he's even more worried that Your Highness
is sad about this matter and
even causing harm to your body.
Father.
But...
His Majesty doesn't know that
Lord Bongsa Choe is treating Deok Pal,
so Your Highness must
keep concealing this point.
I wonder.
Even if I want to conceal it,
it'll be useless if Lord Gim Chi Yong
has captured Choe Won.
Is that true?
Is that fellow, Deok Pal, really dead?
Yes, that's correct.
So that's how it is?
My Lord, it's fine now.
A parent who has lost
their child is indeed scary.
Choe Won actually betrayed the Crown Prince
and listened to your orders.
But...
the matter of Choe Won disappearing,
His Highness is currently suspecting you.
What did you say?
Then... Choe Won that bastard,
he isn't with the Crown Prince
at the Eastern Palace right now?
My Lord. My Lord!
He shouldn't have gone far.
What are you doing?
Quickly go and capture him!
Yes.
Hey, stop right there.
Hold on a moment.
Why are you holding a child?
T-T-That...
She's a young palace maid.
Because she suddenly had a fever,
so we are sending her out of the palace.
Father...
What?
Father?
You really make people suspicious.
The both of you, follow me.
Horse Thief.
Why are you two here?
Didn't you beg me?
You told me to save your daughter.
Even so,
you enter the palace just like that?
My Lord, quickly get out of here
before anyone discovers you.
Will you be okay?
Don't worry about me.
What are you doing?
Quickly go.
Then I'll leave first.
That's right.
Now isn't the time to be eyeing each other.
Let's quickly get out.
I didn't have enough time to
say goodbye to the Crown Prince.
You must tell the Crown Prince the
reason that I can only do this.
You've worked hard.
Horse Thief, quickly come out.
Stop right there!
Quickly go.
Wait... this is...
Stop!
Your Highness, this is the Galhwa hangover soup.
(treats hangover and beneficial to the liver)
I'm really sorry.
You really wanted to clear
Choe Won of his injustice,
but because of my incompetence, Choe Won will
probably be framed just like Jubu Min.
Choe Won that person, if he still
hasn't shown his face to me,
he has probably been
caught by Lord Gim Chi Yong.
Your Highness.
Do I have to qualifications
to be called "Your Highness"?
After pushing a precious friend
towards death's door,
I'm only able to act like a drunk here.
This won't do.
I have to settle things with Lord Gim Chi Yong.
Your Highness.
Lord Bongsa Choe,
isn't in their hands right now.
What did you say?
His Lordship...
has probably safely left the palace now.
His Lordship told me that
I must let Your Highness know.
He apologizes that he's leaving without
saying goodbye to Your Highness,
and not being able
to save Deok Pal ajussi...
Is he really all right?
Yes, he's fine.
It is really fortunate.
It really is fortunate.
When I was following Lord Gim Chi Yong,
I discovered this at an abandoned
storehouse in the palace.
Lord Gim Chi Yong,
seems to have locked up
a child who is ill inside.
What?
It seems to be Choe Won's daughter.
Choe Won's daughter?
That's right.
This is the bag that Rang
uses to keep her medicine.
I left it there when I was
giving treatment to Rang.
Does this really belong to Rang?
Yes, Your Highness.
Omo, she's boiling.
(Omo - oh my)
Hey, kid.
Quickly bring down the fever
and open your eyes, okay?
No matter what medicine
I use it is of no help.
Sa Hyeol Chim was also ineffective.
That...
Are you going to use that to prick the child?
If there's a mistake in administering...
Is it because of me that you didn't put it in?
But Kkeok Jeong...
Why isn't Kkeok Jeong back yet?
Where did that bastard Choe Won run off to?
I won't tell you.
Well, if you don't tell me,
let's see how long you can hang on for.
Seriously, this...
You scoundrel,
who do you think you are acting wildly towards?
He definitely said that he
wanted to use that child as a bait,
to lure Choe Won to
His Lordship's residence.
But unexpectedly he brought
the child to the palace.
Inspector!
We saw Choe Won.
Choe Won?
Yes.
He was with his sick daughter that was here.
What?
Then why didn't you capture him?
That...
He sided with a group of bandits and escaped.
They are Yangju's Iron Hammer's bandits.
They are the people who launched a
surprised attack at the Royal Investigation Bureau
when they broke out of prison last time.
Yangju's Iron Hammer's bandits...
Yes.
One of them is a girl who is like a rash fellow,
and the other is a man
with a hairstyle like worms.
Then that means Choe Won is on
the same sides as those people
and took the child from the palace.
Then...
why did Lord Gim Chi Yong
bring that child to the palace...
So in other words,
the Right State Councillor's name doesn't need
to be written in the secret order anymore?
His Lordship has already
used Choe Won's daughter,
to order Choe Won to kill Deok Pal.
Then what about letting Choe Won escape?
He'll be caught very soon.
He definitely can't escape very far,
whilst taking his sick daughter along.
If that girl, Da In, didn't get involved...
If Merchant Jang adopted daughter
didn't cause trouble, this time we could have...
Da In?
Are you referring to the female physician
who attends to His Majesty's illness?
Yes.
She said that Choe Won is her savior,
so she even wagers her life to help Choe Won.
I really want to get rid of
her without anyone knowing,
but her adopted father is
His Lordship's right hand man
and our money tree.
Is that so?
She has some uses,
so I'm still observing her.
We'll be needing her in order
to catch Choe Won this time too.
Okay.
Then I'll keep an eye out for her too.
Anyway, our pitiful Crown Prince is
probably very sad right now.
He boastfully said that
he would stab me in the back.
In the end, didn't all of that fizzle?
That's right.
He could even be feeling light
headed and foaming in the mouth!
He's still the cornerstone of
this country right now,
how can he be showing his ugly side to people?
No.
We should quickly pull him down from
being the corner stone of this country.
Without you telling me, I've already
planned to stab the Crown Prince in the back.
I'm curious as to whether
that bait is doing well.
After all she is a weak child.
As expected the
Red Demon's intuition isn't ordinary.
That child isn't at my residence now.
Not here?
What do you mean by that...
I'm not sure how
His Highness knew about this.
He sent people to secretly take
that child back to the palace.
This is the order from His Highness who
is going to ascend the throne in the future,
how can I reject him?
So, then at the palace...
You already know everything.
So you also knew that
Choe Won was in the palace, right?
So the person who hid
Choe Won in the palace
is also the Crown Prince?
How can he shield a treasonous criminal?
He doesn't even think of how big of a crime it
is to hide a treasonous criminal in the palace.
Exactly.
This is an issue that
can't be let go so easily.
Have you found out anything?
I heard from the slaves talking that
that fellow with the worm-like hairstyle from
that group of bandits has been brought here.
Is that so?
We're unable to serve the Crown Prince
who is colluding with a traitor!
- Please observe clearly, Your Majesty.
Please take back the decree of abdicating for the
Crown Prince who believes in the traitor Jo Gwang Jo!
- Please take back the decree, Your Majesty!
With the unfilial matter of the Crown Prince attempting
to stab Her Majesty, the Queen in the back,
how can we respect him as
the cornerstone of the nation?
- Please observe clearly, Your Majesty.
Mother, please help hyeongnim...
Please help His Highness, the Crown Prince.
Grand Prince.
I have been abandoned by the Crown Prince
a long time ago, so what can I do?
Mother.
His Highness hasn't really abandoned you.
Otherwise he wouldn't have
listened to my request
to come and see you, Mother.
Grand Prince, you say that because
there's something that you don't know.
The Crown Prince wrote "The king of flowers"
on a Paulownia tree leaf to insult me.
Furthermore, he colluded with traitors
named Ravine patriots to attempt a rebellion.
No.
How can you say rebellion?
How can you say something so scary...
Grand Prince.
His Highness...
Hyeongnim is definitely not that type of person.
Hyeongnim is very filial and loyal,
as his brother I'm very clear on that.
Mother, in fact you know that
hyeongnim isn't that type of person.
So are you saying that
you're going to disobey me?
Mother, that's not what I mean...
Quiet!
I don't want to see you, so quickly leave.
Mother...
Do you want me to become those people
who have no tolerance and shout loudly?
No. I should live up to the expectation
of the status of the country's sovereign King.
So, you must be good and listen to me.
Isn't that right?
These are petitions that all the
Royal Court officials have submitted.
With one voice, they all plea that
you take back the abdication.
There are also petitions there, pleading
to take away the Crown Prince of his position.
Your Majesty, His Highness's filiality and conduct,
is something that all the people know.
Bad rumours are spreading now,
is because it's a scheme to corner His Highness.
- That's right, it's only a scheme.
How can it be said to be a scheme?
Then that letter that was found
in the Crown Prince's greenhouse...
that letter from colluding with the Ravine patriots,
what is the meaning of it?
Are you able to come up and refute the
matters mentioned in these petitions?
Listen carefully.
I admit that the thought of abdicating
to the Crown Prince is a bit hasty.
I'll take back the decree of abdicating.
- Your Majesty, please investigate thoroughly.
- Your grace is bountiful.
However Your Majesty, there are still
some bad rumours regarding His Highness.
Because this matter can't be let go easily,
so please forgive me for being bold.
There are rumours saying that His Highness
hid treasonous criminal Choe Won
at the Eastern Palace secretly.
Not only does he believe the
treasonous criminal Jo Gwang Jo,
he even hid a treasonous criminal in the palace.
Furthermore, it was at the Eastern Palace.
It's far from enough to just take back
the decree of abdicating alone on this matter.
That's correct.
Even if he is the cornerstone of the nation,
he should be severely punished
for disobeying the law.
As long as this matter ends smoothly...
What should we do about this matter?
Hasn't His Majesty already taken back
the decree to abdicate for the Crown Prince?
For fear of violent backlash on
the original plan for abdication,
in the end it became like this.
Since the only witness who can
destroy the Soyun faction has died,
the Soyun faction has waited for this chance,
to say His Highness has colluded with us,
Ravine patriots, to attempt a rebellion.
The matter of disposing the
Crown Prince is already being discussed,
so us being treated as traitors and
being killed is only a matter of time.
We have to think of a plan.
We should prevail.
If that is so,
then shouldn't we gather our strength
and help His Highness?
If His Majesty does dethrone the Crown Prince...
How could we know if this is
helping him or harming him?
Amongst the people who are
struggling against poverty
and are unable to use a sickle or pickaxe,
and can only take another person's life
to be able to live in this world.
His Highness should be able to turn this
crisis into an opportunity himself.
If he wants to become a wise king who really
cares for the people who are hungry and cold,
he must be able to accomplish
this kind of matter easily.
Bongcheon, Gangnyeong, Ungjindeung
and Hamgyeong Province,
how is the training going?
I heard that there is a lack
of weapons and food there.
Use this to replenish the stock.
Now is the time to train in
order to combat the enemy.
What to do...
The places that I go to,
Kkeok Jeong will definitely go too.
Why hasn't he come yet?
Could it be...
He is injured?
No, it can't be.
Kkeok Jeong is very skilled in fighting.
Then could it be...
He got caught?
No, no way.
Even if Kkeok Jeong was caught,
he can successfully escape.
Father...
Rang.
Oh my, she seems to
have said "Father" just then.
Kid, your father is here.
Quickly open your eyes.
That way you can see him.
Oh my, oh my.
Father...
I'm your father's friend.
Your father is here.
Rang.
Ajussi.
He isn't ajussi.
He is your father.
Please save my father.
Rang.
Why is she like that?
Has this child gone muddle-headed?
Rang, I can do it... Right?
That fellow's name is
really called Kkeok Jeong, right?
Yes.
I found out that he's called Im Kkeok Jeong.
Im Kkeok Jeong that fellow has been caught
by the Police Station a few times,
but he can always escape unnoticed.
This is something I can look forward to.
As long as my intuition is correct,
he'll escape from here by tonight.
Isn't that Inspector Im?
That's correct.
Inspector Im heard that you went
to Lord Gim Chi Yong's residence,
so he said he needed to go too.
Is that so?
Sir.
Secretly follow him.
Absolutely do not be discovered.
Yes.
Kkeok Jeong!
I've come.
What happened?
Who made you like this?
Lift up your head.
What I am going to ask you now,
you must answer with the truth.
Yes, Your Majesty.
How could I dare to lie to you?
The Crown Prince here...
did he really secretly hide treasonous
criminal Choe Won at the Eastern Palace?
In the future the position of
Chief Eunuch will be yours.
This concerns the fate of this country.
What are you doing, not quickly answering?
Quickly answer me.
Your Majesty, I deserve death!
Aigoo, this... wait...
What is the
Royal Investigation Bureau's Inspector doing here?
What is wrong with you?
We're all people who know the business.
We have to leave.
Please put me to death, Your Majesty.
In other words,
the Crown Prince really colluded
with a treasonous criminal
and even brought him to the Eastern Palace?
Father.
Just sit still.
Actually...
Let's separate first.
If this continues, all of us will be caught.
We'll meet up at the road
to the entrance of Yangju.
I'm relying on you.
Let's go!
What is this?
-=Next Episode Preview=-
Grand Prince, what conduct do you think
the cornerstone of this country should have?
The cornerstone of this country isn't me...
Will you not shut up?
So, what exactly do you want to say?
Where did the father of this child go,
that you're treating her here?
He seems to have been caught.
I already said no!
The real murderer of
Jubu Min is someone else.
-=Episode 9=-
-=Sa Hyeol Chim - bloodletting treatment=-
That's right, that's right.
Well done.
Open them a bit more.
- I already told you several times that it isn't me!
- Shut up!