(HORN BLARES)
DRIVER: Giddyap.
Whoa.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Come in, sir.
Am I late?
Where are the others?
Shh. They're in the study,
and I believe
the demonstration
has already begun.
Thank you.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
MAN: And so,
ladies and gentlemen,
we have brought you
together this evening
to witness a demonstration
of the remarkable,
life-giving powers
of galvanic electricity.
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
I am your host,
Professor Montgomery,
and this...
This is my assistant,
the very lovely Jennifer.
For two years,
we have been dead,
sustained in this
perfect condition,
only through the miracle of
the high-voltage electricity
which flows
through our bodies.
Electricity...
The force of eternity.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
You. Take this.
Oh! It tingles!
I thought it would hurt.
MAN: It's not that kind
of electricity, Baroness.
PAUL: Share it with us,
and live forever.
Ten thousand.
Twenty thousand.
Thirty thousand volts.
Ten thousand for each year
of our marriage.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
To Jennifer and Paul!
(LAUGHTER)
Happy third anniversary!
GUESTS: Happy anniversary!
Thanks.
(GUESTS EXCLAIM)
I'll drink to that!
MAN: I should have said,
"What a lovely couple."
And what a lovely kiss.
WOMAN: You're absolutely
insane, darling. You're mad.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(SIGHS) Well, you said
it was going to be an
unconventional party,
and you were
certainly right.
What was all that
electricity business?
Oh, some quack
cure-all machine from
their collection. (CHUCKLES)
Paul and Jennifer
make quite a job
of being unconventional.
(SIGHS) I can't say I quite
agree with his taste in art.
His taste?
He picks them,
she pays for them.
Ah, Nora.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
(DANCE BAND PLAYING)
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
(WHISTLING LONDON BRIDGE
IS FALLING DOWN)
Hello, Norman.
Got another blast
goin' on tonight, huh?
The usual weirdos,
no doubt?
Thank goodness
it's the last one
for a while.
And I'm taking off
on my vacation tomorrow.
Three whole weeks. Ah!
JENNIFER:
Oh, you're here, Norman.
Nora, there isn't any
champagne left. Will you
bring some up, please?
Yes, ma'am.
They got some kind
of orgy goin' on up there,
Mrs. Smedley?
You'd like to think so,
wouldn't you, Norman?
(CHUCKLES)
Uh-huh.
(BELL DINGING)
Did you read
Dr. Pamplemousse's
latest book?
He actually was
in a flying saucer!
MAN: No!
Hesse. Hermann Hesse.
H-e-s-s-e.
(GAME BELL DINGING)
WOMAN: Here it comes.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
So am I.
WOMAN: Closer.
There it is, head-on!
Ooh. There's three
innocent bystanders
just dying to be knocked off.
Closer. Closer.
(GAME SOUND EFFECTS)
Oh, how terribly gruesome.
Who ever thought up
this lovely game?
Terry did.
Why?
MAN: Why?
Mister, uh...
Harry Gordon.
You're Jennifer's lawyer,
aren't you, Harry?
Well, yes.
Most of our lives
are like... Pinball games.
Fantastically designed
machines that merely whir,
click and pay off,
at best,
in another free game.
The trivial things in life...
We take too seriously.
The serious things,
like death,
too trivially.
That's all I've tried
to say here.
(GAME BELL DINGING)
I won, I won, I won!
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
You see before you
the first known casualty
of too much
turnpike pinball.
Did you know that
Aimee Semple McPherson
was buried with
a phone at her side?
Why?
Just in case.
Nothin'. (CHUCKLES)
Mmm.
(GRUNTS)
It scratches.
Now, that's ridiculous.
Whole generations of women
lived with mustachioed men,
and there were
less divorces, too.
I say it scratches.
It scratches
just sticking it on.
(PAUL LAUGHS)
Mmm. What a nice scratch.
Once upon a time,
the evil queen of darkness
gave Sleeping Beauty
a poisoned apple.
Everybody thought
she was dead.
Mmm. With a phone
at her side just in case.
Except...
The handsome prince,
who knew just how
to wake her up.
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(HORN BLARES)
Mrs. Montgomery?
(GASPS) Yes?
Please forgive me for
appearing so unexpectedly,
but it seems to be
a habit of mine.
I was told
you'd be quite pretty,
but you far exceed
your description.
WOMAN: Morning, Jennifer.
Good morning,
Miss Beattie.
Valentino isn't
visiting you, is he?
No, I haven't seen him.
Oh, dear.
Valentino!
I can't imagine who's
been describing me to you.
Valentino!
(INHALES) How does the
name of Deirdre strike you?
Deirdre St. James?
Wolf Glade, '63?
Now of Madison,
Wisconsin.
Won't you come in?
Is she married yet?
Yes, yes.
Yes, two children,
a little boy,
a little girl.
She suggested
I drop by.
I am Lisa Schindler.
Won't you wait in there?
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Hmm?
Your breakfast is served.
All right. Okay, okay.
What a perfectly
lovely mirror.
In fact, everything you have
is absolutely fascinating.
You've lived here long?
Yes.
At first,
after my mother died,
I... Thought
about selling it.
And then I met Paul,
my husband,
and, uh...
Tell me, Miss...
Mrs... Mrs. Lisa Schindler.
Have you been a friend
of Deirdre's long?
Oh, I like to think
of myself as
a little more
than just a friend.
I was, uh...
How can I say it?
I was a consultant
to her as well.
I don't quite understand.
(CHUCKLES)
Could you, my dear,
come over here and sit
beside me for a moment?
Look.
I have known many
young women like Deirdre,
who tend to think
negatively about maturing.
I believe in
a beautiful woman,
the present, the past
and the future
are inseparable.
Of course, why,
we all know...
That it's
a woman's attitude
that keeps her
young forever.
We cannot deny,
more than did
the ancient Egyptians,
the importance
of certain aids
to beauty.
(SCOFFS)
You're a saleswoman!
In a sense.
So were Helen of Troy
and Madame du Barry.
It's rather amazing to me
their success considering
they did not know
the secret of
Countess Danielle's
magic foundation.
I don't believe
you know Deirdre at all,
unless you sold
her something.
You don't know her
at all, do you?
Well, do you?
No.
Quite honestly, I don't,
Mrs. Montgomery.
You see, we work
from... Yearbooks.
Wolf Glade, 1963.
"Jennifer Scott Taylor,
class cynic.
"Associate Editor, Yearbook.
"Voted most likely
not to have to worry
about succeeding."
That's nice.
And "President
of the Dramatic Society."
I would have thought
you would appreciate
a good performance
with that background.
(SIGHS)
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
I'm all right.
(SIGHS) I believe
it's the mind
which controls the body.
But my legs do not agree.
Your hand is very cold.
(SIGHS) Yeah.
Despite the good
vibration from yours.
I tend to be
too mystical
for my own good.
No. I think most people
are too practical.
Oh.
One must be practical
in order to survive.
Mustn't one?
I like this cologne,
you know?
Do you?
How could you
possibly tell? (CHUCKLES)
I've smelled it before.
Well, in that case,
you might like some
of our soaps, too.
They're quite expensive.
Three for $5,
but absolutely pure
and transparent.
Quite extravagant.
And also,
our body cream
and our bath oil.
All of the same desperately
exotic fragrance.
I'll take all of them.
Ah! But I can't leave
the samples with you.
I have to write down
the order.
It'll come with the mail
in one week or two.
Oh, don't get up,
please.
No, I must get up.
I must write the order.
I must get your full name
and complete address.
I... Must have
your signature to...
Please, please, please.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
No, no. I must get
these things down.
Oh, I must... I must...
Put down the order.
So... Cream. Body cream.
And I must get your money.
You know,
I have a quota to meet.
Each of us has
a quota to meet and
I must meet my quota.
Because, you know,
we work from a system which
is called the quota system.
When... When all
I really want...
Is...
Is to give them to you.
(BREATHING UNEVENLY)
Mrs. Schindler!
Paul!
More an attack of
heat prostration than
anything else.
She needs rest
and nourishment.
The B12 shot
won't do it alone.
A good rest now,
Mrs. Schindler,
you'll be back
on your feet in no time.
Thank you.
Jennifer.
Bye-bye.
(SIGHS) You have been
both so kind to me.
But I mustn't presume
on your hospitality.
Oh, no, you must feel
right at home here.
Mustn't she, Paul?
Oh, sure.
Oh, thank you.
If I could only
have one day.
We'll talk about it later.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Uh, well, you'll, uh,
have to excuse me,
Mrs... Uh, uh, Mrs...
Schindler.
Yes, Schindler.
Excuse me. I'm going
to the, uh, Winthrop Gallery
to see about
a couple paintings.
Excuse me.
Just a minute.
Uh... Do you, uh,
really want a stranger
in the house?
Do you mind terribly?
(EXHALES)
Well, you, uh...
You're the one
who has to wait on her.
Hmm?
(CHUCKLES)
I'll, uh, see you later.
Okay.
Mmm.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
How are you feeling?
Oh, better. Thank you.
Is your husband
an artist?
In a way.
Collecting is an art,
you know.
I would have thought
you'd be the artist
in the family.
Are you a Libra
by any chance?
Yes!
Then you believe in astrology,
mind reading,
communication
with the dead.
I don't know.
Should I?
Where I grew up,
there was never any question
about believing in them.
Where did you grow up?
It's a very long story.
Can it wait for a while?
I feel so tired.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Of course you must rest.
I have wonderful
old pictures
you could look at.
And marvelous clothes.
They're all buried
in my trunk.
Where you live?
Well, actually,
I had to let my apartment go.
My trunk is in storage.
Now, just exactly
where in storage is it?
It was in a place uptown.
It's odd, I had the ticket
in my hand yesterday.
(GASPS) Can you
get me my cape?
(SIGHS) Thank you.
Here it is.
"Fletcher Warehouse Company."
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(THUNDER CONTINUES)
(LAUGHING)
Oh, and now I'll change
so you can give your
husband his robe back.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
LISA: Here. Thank you.
Ah. It fits me better.
Oh!
They're my tarot cards.
A link between
the future and the past.
They never lie.
Sometimes
I wish they would.
JENNIFER: What is that?
Young lovers.
And this one?
Junon, the High Priestess.
It is not a very gay card.
Now, let's see what
we can find for you
to wear this evening.
What is that?
A memento from my
flamboyant past.
Oh! It's divine.
My dear, it's yours.
(EXHALES)
Thank you.
I'll see you
at supper.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(THUNDER CONTINUES)
(GAME BELL DINGS)
I must confess,
Mr. Montgomery,
your game room
confuses me.
In my country,
the men drink cognac
and smoke cigars
after supper.
Here, you do what?
Play pinball?
Well, not exactly. Uh...
These games symbolize
our American culture.
Oh, I can see how, uh,
our little collection
might seem strange
to a foreigner.
It does take
a rather special attitude
to appreciate it.
You Americans have it
so much easier
than most of us.
You are happy with
such simple amusements.
I'm afraid I'm used to
infinitely more exciting
and dangerous games.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
I have nothing but these
to give as an expression
of my deep gratitude
for your hospitality.
They are old
and quite valuable.
Well, they're...
They're beautiful.
Thank you.
They have
a rich history.
The rim of a hill...
At dawn.
Two figures...
Standing in a mist.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GUN CLICKS)
They were
two lovers of mine.
Stage-door Johnnies,
as you would say.
But they played
a real game,
Mr. Montgomery,
not a penny
arcade substitute.
It was Kurt who won.
I married him.
I would have married
either of them.
After all, a man who gives
his life for a woman's love
is irresistibly charming.
And do they still work?
Oh, I should think so.
A friend of mine used
one of them on the stage
not so long ago.
There are some blank
cartridges still mixed
with the others.
This one,
with the nick here
where it fell,
eventually took
my husband's life.
You see,
he became
uncommonly jealous,
forbade me to go
on the stage,
virtually imprisoned me,
and life became a nightmare.
The days
and the weeks
and months
passed by endlessly.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
One night,
each of us half-crazed
with our own
exhausting obsessions,
I placed a bullet
in this gun,
spun the chamber...
(CLICKING)
Held it to my head,
And pulled the trigger.
I offered it to him.
He took it.
Back and forth
it went,
this gun,
like slow motion,
for what seemed hours...
Until his last turn came.
(GASPS)
(SNIFFLES)
Do you think,
Mr. Montgomery,
I shall ever learn
to be impressed
with your pinball games?
Well, I play a much
more exciting game
every day of the week,
tricking my way into houses
to sell overpriced cosmetics.
Jennifer has been most
kind to protect me.
I've not come to expect
much protection.
Three times in my life
I've had to climb
barbed wire.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
And the last time,
even with the dogs
barking at my
heels in Berlin,
I found I had come
to somehow
enjoy it!
Need it.
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES)
When I see
the harmless games
you play,
Mr. Montgomery...
I'm simply bored.
(GUNSHOT)
(RATTLING)
(CHUCKLES)
Now, this,
Mr. Montgomery,
has been
what I call a real game.
Mmm. (EXHALES)
Good night.
Oh, yeah.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Uh, Jennifer?
In the, uh, future
we must make an effort
not to bore our
houseguest again.
(CHUCKLES)
(PIGEONS COOING)
PAUL: Jennifer!
What's this stuff
burning on the stove?
Huh? Can't you do
one thing at a time?
JENNIFER: It's not
exactly a tragedy.
PAUL: If you're going to
take care of the house,
why don't you do it?
I don't mind that woman,
but if she's gonna turn you
into a scatterbrain...
JENNIFER: It has nothing
to do with Lisa.
Oh, no?
It's a funny coincidence
then, that I feel left out
ever since she came.
Paul, please, not so loud.
(SLAPPING)
JENNIFER: Ow!
Don't you think,
Mr. Montgomery,
you should take
that out on me?
Well, now that you're here,
Mrs. Schindler,
there is something
I'd like to tell you.
Yes?
(SLAP)
Ow!
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Jennifer?
(JENNIFER LAUGHING)
(MAN LAUGHING)
JENNIFER: Shh. (CHUCKLES)
(MAN CHUCKLES)
JENNIFER: Hurry.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Jennifer.
JENNIFER: Shh.
(BANGS)
JENNIFER: Who is it?
"Who is it?"
Open the door.
Well.
I was resting.
I didn't think
you'd be back so soon.
Resting, huh?
Resting.
Where is Lisa? Well?
In the park.
What's this?
What is it?
(SIGHS)
Paul! Please!
Yes, Paul. Please.
After all, we guaranteed
Norman you'd understand.
(SCOFFS)
Just following instructions,
Mr. Montgomery.
(CHUCKLING) Yeah.
Pretending, you know.
(CHUCKLES)
Three against one,
that's pretty dirty.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(PLAYING DRAMATIC ORGAN MUSIC)
(ORGAN CONTINUES)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
J... Jennifer?
(ORGAN CONTINUES)
Jennifer?
You were going to sign
and return copies
of these last week, Jennifer.
It's, um...
It's not like you
to forget such simple
business matters.
Thank you.
I'm sorry to, uh,
intrude with such...
Conventional affairs.
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
PAUL: Here comes
the neighborhood animal.
I don't know who thought
up that little scheme
the other day,
but I don't think
he should get off free.
Paul, Lisa's waiting
for me at the museum.
Now, it, uh,
won't take long.
Just bait the trap.
You mean...
With a little cheesecake?
(WHISTLING LONDON BRIDGE
IS FALLING DOWN)
Morning, Mrs. Montgomery.
Come in.
You're just in time
to do me a favor.
What's that?
It's my zipper.
(LAUGHS)
It's stuck or something.
Oh?
Don't tell me, uh,
Mr. Montgomery
couldn't do this?
Oh, he's not at home.
Oh, yeah? (CHUCKLES)
Thank you.
Uh...
Anything else?
(CHUCKLES)
Huh.
Just pretendin' again,
huh, Norman?
PAUL: And you?
It's not what
you think, Paul.
PAUL: Uh-huh.
Hey, come on!
Okay, pally,
you've been
askin' for this.
You, uh...
You want a look, huh?
Look, 'cause it's
your last one.
Hey, man!
You've got it all wrong!
JENNIFER: No, Paul!
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(PANTING)
(CHUCKLES) Hello, Norman.
(LAUGHS) You, uh,
want to play games with us,
you're just gonna
have to learn
how to take it, huh.
(GUNSHOT)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
Oh, Paul!
Who touched this gun?
They were all blanks,
not two of them.
The real bullets were
in the one with the nick. I...
Oh, my God.
Paul. Paul.
He's not dead.
Paul, he's not dead!
He's not. Not really.
He's not!
He can't be! He's not!
(SOBS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(GASPS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
Jennifer?
It's Lisa.
Get her out of here.
Come on, Jennifer.
I... I want to call
the police.
Uh, we killed him.
Um, whether we meant it
or not... I mean...
You teased him,
and I killed him.
Honey, it's not
a case of self-defense.
Now, is it, huh?
Is it?
No.
Jennifer.
Um, come on.
Come on, get her
out of here.
Uh, what'll I say?
Um...
(SCREAMING) Ouch!
Sorry, honey.
Now go get her to fix it.
Jennifer, what is it?
Th... The coffee.
I spilled it!
Oh, it's really scalded.
There's a special lotion.
No, even better,
I'll get some butter
from the icebox.
No, Lisa, no!
Please, the lotion.
At the drugstore.
Please.
All right.
Now, you lie down.
I'll be right back.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(STAMMERS)
Th... There was no delivery.
He never came.
You understand?
Put these things away.
(GRUNTS)
When she comes back,
try and keep her out of here.
For God's sake,
keep her out
of the maid's room.
(PANTING)
(RATTLING)
(CASH COUNTER DINGS)
Just as long as it isn't
a third-degree burn,
I'm sure this'll make
Mrs. Montgomery
a lot more comfortable.
Okay, thank you.
Mrs. Schindler.
Oh, Dr. Edwards.
Something wrong
with Jennifer?
No, not really.
Just a minor burn.
My dear, there's no such thing
as a completely minor burn.
Come. I'm going
right past the house.
(DOOR OPENS)
LISA: Jennifer?
Uh, get her...
Out, huh?
Um, sleeping pills.
Give her some sherry
or something.
Give her a couple,
somehow.
Well, come on!
Come on.
Come on, come on!
I thought you were
gonna lie down.
I was straightening
up the kitchen...
To keep my mind off my wrist.
Oh, Jennifer.
There you are.
I ran into the doctor
in the pharmacy.
Let me see that wrist.
Mmm. Can't we get
a better light than this?
In the bathroom.
Good.
Now, if you'll
just sit there.
Perfect.
Mmm, that's not too bad,
except for the pain.
May I have that
ointment, please?
Thank you.
I remember once as a child
you burned yourself...
Trying to build a fire
in your doll's house.
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS)
Oh. I'm sorry.
What are you looking for?
A bandage. Some cotton.
No, not cotton.
Gauze or soft linen.
DOCTOR: There.
In another six hours
you can change the dressing
and put on some more.
Did you find anything?
An old sheet, a pillowcase,
anything like that?
Of course,
in the linen closet.
No!
It... It's all right.
Really. Please.
JENNIFER:
It's all right. Really.
DOCTOR: No, no.
It must be bandaged.
An old pillowcase
would be fine.
(SIGHS)
(LINEN TEARING)
There. If it throbs,
just hold it up.
Don't try to lift
anything heavy.
And don't go making any more
fires in your dollhouse.
Be right back.
(SIGHS)
LISA: Well, it was very lucky
running into you, Doctor.
DOCTOR: Not at all,
Mrs. Schindler. Not at all.
LISA: Good-bye.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS)
Hey, that's a good idea.
You know, I had a friend
who used to say that
alcohol was the
first real medicine.
He must have thought
he had a serious disease,
judging by the amount
of "medicine" he drank.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Yes?
I want to speak
to that boy Norman.
Ah, Miss Beattie,
I have no time.
I was watching out my window.
I'm sure
I saw him come in.
No, no.
That was yesterday.
Well, he promised to bring
Valentino's kitty litter.
Ah, look, Valentino...
He can play in our yard,
anyplace at all, okay. Huh?
Well, aren't you snappy?
(MEOWING)
Here's the kitty litter.
Oh.
Right here.
Well, he must have
forgot it yesterday.
This means you've got
a few of my trading stamps,
Mr. Montgomery.
Oh, yeah. Uh, here!
Mr. Montgomery!
(TITTERS)
Valentino, look.
Isn't he a nice man?
(CONTINUES TITTERING)
(MEOWS)
JENNIFER: Paul?
What did she want?
She, uh, thought she
saw him come in here,
but she's confused enough
to forget about it.
Where's Lisa?
Asleep on the couch.
Pills?
Thank God.
I don't know if, uh,
what she's told us about
herself is true or not,
but I know one thing.
If she ever found out
about this, she wouldn't
just turn us in.
She'd bleed us dry.
Then why don't we
get out of it?
Call Harry. He's a lawyer.
There must be
some way out.
Sure.
Five, 10 years in jail.
Suppose... Suppose
it were just two years
for you as an accomplice?
I'll call the police
right now.
And, uh, five for me.
That's the least I'd get.
(SIGHS)
Gotta get this
out of here.
Out of this part
of the city.
Take a ride to the
Statue of Liberty.
Now?
You take care of the gun,
and I'll take care
of the body.
We mustn't
waste any time.
I love you.
(MACHINE RUMBLING)
(SWISHING)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(UNEVEN BREATHING)
(MOANING)
(RUSTLING)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(SOFT THUD)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(PAUL PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
Norman?
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS) Norman.
Gettin' rid of a body,
that's one thing.
A statue,
that's quite different.
If Lisa should say anything,
tell her it's our
latest acquisition.
(HAIR DRYER WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING)
Hello?
Is this Martinson's Grocery?
Uh, this is, uh,
Paul Montgomery,
11 East 64th Street.
We ordered some groceries
late yesterday afternoon.
Well, we never got them.
Could you, uh,
check that order
and send them now?
Well, it certainly
isn't our mistake.
Thank you.
Do we have to do that?
We have to do
everything as though
nothing has happened.
Um, when that boy comes,
see if you can find out
what they think
has happened to Norman.
Where are you going?
I'm going to the club.
Try to catch
Sandy Peterson there.
He has a house in Maine,
on an island north
of Bar Harbor.
Well, he's been trying
to swap me something
for one of Terry's statues
for quite some time.
And I wouldn't be
surprised if,
on the way over there
in this little boat of his,
I had some sort
of unfortunate accident.
Want some more?
(DOORBELL RINGING)
I'll get it.
It's Norman
with the groceries.
(EXHALES)
Right here, Norman.
Oh, I'm Arthur, ma'am.
Uh, Norman's not
at the store today.
Where is he?
Vacation, I guess.
He said he was gonna go
next week, but...
Mr. Berwick swears
he sent these things
over yesterday.
I've been out of flour
for a week.
Yes, ma'am. Well,
have a nice weekend, ma'am.
LISA: Thank you.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
You know that last night
I could not sleep?
I heard voices.
Strange sounds.
(MATCH STRIKES)
The cards calling me.
And when I listened,
there were two voices.
Two very loud voices.
They came back constantly,
whether I asked about myself,
you or Paul.
(COUNTING IN GERMAN)
Now.
There's a tower...
Or a house.
It's been struck
by some catastrophe.
Now let's see
the other card.
Death.
(FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(SIGHS)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(GASPS)
Oh!
(LOCK CLICKING)
(PHONE WHIRRING)
(WATER FAUCET RUNNING)
(FAUCET STOPS)
This is Mrs. Montgomery.
Is my husband there?
Paul Montgomery, please.
(PHONE RINGING)
Mr. Montgomery.
(MACHINE RATTLING)
Thank you.
Hello?
Uh, you're gonna have
to talk louder, honey.
I can't hear you.
In the bathroom,
there's blood, Paul.
I'm afraid to speak louder.
What?
Blood.
Well, it's probably mine.
I nicked myself shaving
this morning.
You what?
Nicked!
Look, uh,
this is impossible.
I can't talk now.
I'll get home
as soon as I can.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(CLOCK STRIKING)
(FAUCET DRIPPING)
(STEADY TAPPING)
Lisa?
(BIRDS PEEPING)
(CRASHING)
(GASPS)
(MEOWS)
(MEOWING)
(ELEVATOR RUNNING)
Lisa?
(PHONE RINGS)
Jennifer.
Look, uh, what day
were you born on?
Lisa, where are you?
Oh, I'm in a simply
marvelous shop,
and I want to cast
your horoscope.
So I need some details.
Get the hour.
Did you hear that?
JENNIFER: Yes.
In the morning sometime.
(SIGHS)
Sunday, eight or nine.
I really can't remember
what my mother told me.
Lisa, come home, please.
Please!
What is it?
What's the matter?
It... It's nothing.
I'm sorry.
I'll see you later.
That's strange.
The idea of the horoscope
seemed to...
Upset her.
Oh!
Perhaps.
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(VALENTINO YOWLING)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(WHISPERS) Jennifer!
Come.
Do you feel it, too?
It's a spirit.
An uneasy spirit.
And I feel it most strongly
in certain places.
(RUSTLING, RATTLING)
(GAME BELL DINGING)
(BALL ROLLING)
Oh, spirit...
Restless wanderer,
uneasy...
Voyager in the limbo,
we heed thy presence...
And ask...
If we may intercede
on your behalf.
Speak to us...
Who wait in sympathy
for your restlessness.
Speak! Speak!
MAN: (SHOUTS) No!
(GASPS)
LISA: Again, spirit.
Again.
Your pain is heard.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, Paul!
What is it?
Uh, uh...
Just a dream.
(WHISPERS) Of what?
Uh...
Dark, uh, dark shadow.
For a moment,
I couldn't breathe.
He was holding me.
He was trying
to strangle me.
Who?
Um, I, uh...
A shadow. I couldn't say.
A dark shadow.
Close, spirit, close!
Ah, spirit.
You're with us now.
We hear you.
We hear you!
Speak to us.
No! No, stop it!
(SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
What is it?
Honey, there's nothing.
It's okay.
There's nothing.
(GASPING)
It's all right.
(BELL TOLLING)
(TOLLING CONTINUES)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(RATTLING)
PAUL: Jennifer.
Where's Lisa?
What?
Lisa! Is she safe?
Well, of course
she's safe. So are you.
You're, uh, sure
having this thing
makes you feel better, huh?
He's still
in the house.
Please. That's ridiculous.
You saw him.
No, I didn't.
He tried
to strangle you.
That was just a dream!
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
Oh, Mr. Bradley.
Thank you for calling back.
Yes, I know it's Sunday,
but I, uh...
I had to get that shipment
off to Maine a little earlier
than I thought.
Uh, today, if possible.
Tomorrow, huh?
No!
No, Mr. Bradley.
That won't do.
I have to be
in Maine tomorrow.
Well, I expect
to pay more.
Thank you, sir.
(SIGHS)
(SCOFFS)
(LOCK CLICKS)
4:00 this afternoon.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(SIGHS)
Well. That's it.
I've packed my trunk.
We... Never did
complete that order
to dear
Countess Danielle.
Did we?
You don't have to go.
Your husband and myself,
we talked it over
this morning.
And I'm afraid the influence
of a third person
in your marriage
is a little bit disturbing.
No. I think I was
a little stronger than that,
Mrs. Schindler.
Last night
you terrorized Jennifer.
She saw a...
What?
I saw nothing.
Well, neither did I.
Still, you had her
practically out of her mind.
I think that's carrying
those games you play
a little too far.
Mr. Montgomery, last night,
I was not playing your game.
I was just trying to help.
I'll come
for my trunk tomorrow.
Now I must get back
to work.
You know, we work
on a quota system,
and I have slipped
a little behind.
Good-bye. And thank you.
Well.
I'll, uh, call you tomorrow
when it's over, huh?
Please.
(LOCK CLICKING)
(STEAM HISSING)
(MEOWING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(MEOWS)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
(CLICKING)
(LOCK CLICKING)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(MEN WHOOPING ON TV, GUNSHOTS)
(CATTLE BAWLING)
(GUNSHOTS, WHOOPING)
(REMOTE CONTROL CLICKS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(TV TURNS OFF)
(GASPS)
(WHISTLING LONDON BRIDGE
IS FALLING DOWN)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GASPING)
Operator?
(WHISTLING LONDON BRIDGE
IS FALLING DOWN)
(GASPS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING, FLUTTERING)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SCREAMING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(CRACKLING STOPS)
(SWITCH CLICKS)
Jennifer?
(SIGHS)
(WHIRRING)
Operator? Get me
the police, please.
Hello? I, uh, want
to report a murder.
No, no, not me.
My wife.
(SIREN WAILING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
I've got a call
in to Wilson Kaiser
to handle the case.
He'll charge a small fortune,
but he's worth it.
And since she's clearly
in no condition to handle
her own affairs,
I'll see to it that
you're appointed
guardian immediately.
Paul. I just don't
want you to worry.
Harry, please?
God knows, Paul,
it's a sad way
to utilize a fortune,
but if it'll help Jennifer,
spend it for that purpose.
(SIREN WAILING)
Mr. Montgomery?
We'll need a statement
from you down at headquarters.
Two small Daumier lithographs,
one Cocteau poster.
Oh, and of course,
last but not least,
A Man in a Chair
by Terry Tower.
Mmm.
Um, 4,300 for that, huh?
Oh, yes.
It was all included in
yesterday's certified check.
(CHUCKLES) Quite a handsome
total for such an overnight
selling spree, Mr. Montgomery.
Oh, yes.
Uh, you know, uh,
I tried my hand
at one of those things
not too long ago.
Mmm.
$36 worth of plaster,
chicken wire and sand.
Sand?
Oh, yes.
Uh, two bags.
Two bags full, uh, inside.
I wanted it to have
a little more, uh, body.
(CHUCKLES)
Yes, indeed.
Good day, sir.
(WHISTLING LONDON BRIDGE
IS FALLING DOWN)
(CONTINUES WHISTLING)
Can the master
of the house
tear himself away
from his work?
I should, uh, do this kind
of work every day, huh?
(CHUCKLES)
Anyone who has got
enough sense to employ me
as a business partner
can expect
profitable operations.
A toast.
To, uh, to Switzerland,
land of untraceable,
anonymous bank accounts.
That's where
I met Jennifer.
Bumming around
a ski resort.
You can make
a lot of nice contacts
around a ski resort.
Oh, yes.
We should know about that,
shouldn't we?
Then, I thought
I'd go to Portugal.
(EXHALES)
Look up some friends.
There's this guy I knew
in the army.
Terribly rich.
Married a girl
I hated to lose.
Well, I guess you're dying
to know the final count, huh?
Or, uh, would you rather
count it yourself?
Oh, come on, Paul.
We're not back
one year ago in Vermont,
two strangers meeting
on a cable car,
striking up conversation.
It's done now.
Of course I trust you.
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
(SIGHS)
Ten percent of everything.
That's 43,900.
I made it an even 45.
I guess I'm just feeling
a little generous today.
I, uh, even sent
Norman's family
$1,500 for the funeral.
Fifteen?
But I thought
he was expecting 500.
Well, he was expecting blanks,
not bullets.
(CHUCKLES)
Frankly, I think he would
have done it for nothing.
You should have seen him
when he tried on that makeup.
"I, uh, guess I'm one
of your weirdos now,
huh, Mr. Montgomery?"
(IMITATING NORMAN'S CHUCKLE)
Mmm-hmm.
And I, uh, thought
for losing the game,
he deserved a little bonus.
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
Ah. Aw, poor Norman.
With all his fantasies.
Amateurs should not
play games
with professionals, huh?
I've always noticed
that professionals
have a way of dealing
with things
very simply,
very directly.
You wouldn't,
uh, call my scheme
exactly simple, would you?
(GROANS)
Precisely the point.
(BREATHING UNEVENLY)
(GLASS RESONATING)
No. (GRUNTS)
(GLASS RESONATING CONTINUES)
(PAUL GROANING)
(RESONATING STOPS)
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
So... Overcome by grief,
he took his life.
"We bought a new house.
We miss you.
"Love, Bob and Jane."
(WIND CHIMES TINKLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)