Events and characters that appear in this drama are fictional.
Aish. Pick up the call!!
Move! Let's talk later!!!
There..
Who is it?
Who is there? Come out quickly!
I'm calling the police now!
Why are you here?
I'm scared, someone's in the room.
You stay out.
Part 4 Remember Me In The Dark
You called the police because of this cellphone?
Yes.
Who broke the front door?
Him.
So he got hurt while fighting with the culprit?
No, it's not because of that.
Then why did you call for us?
Because of the cellphone.
I've been constantly receiving text messages from that phone lately.
But that hand phone was in my room.
Ah, then the person who broke the front door,
and the person who hit this man, are both not the culprit, right?
Then why did you contact us?
Look here. Someone that I don't even know
came inside my house and left their phone when I wasn't here.
This was burglary.
Pursuant to Penal Code Section 319,
the consequences are up to 3 years in jail or up to a 500,000 won fine.
It's a given that we find the culprit and make him pay the consequences!
She's totally crazy. This is going to be a pain.
We will definitely track the owner of this phone and notify you immediately.
Are you leaving just like that?
What, you're not going to stakeout here?
A patrol car makes rounds in this neighborhood nightly, so rest assured.
What is this?
Are they just leaving?
Excuse me, Officer.
What happened? Was there a thief inside?
No, it's nothing special.
What now!?
Ahjussi, I have something to tell you.
But don't you need to go to the hospital first?
I know the person to whom the cell phone belongs.
What?
Ah, why is it like this?
Door, listen to me!
Do you think that's going to fix it?
You need to pull harder.
Why are you quibbling again?
You never know what might happen today, so don't stay by yourself.
That guy might come back.
I don't think now is the time to worry about me.
Tell me. Why are you here? And what's wrong with your face?
It's nothing big.
Regardless, stay with a friend for the time being.
Don't stay here.
What are you doing? Hey, hey!
Hey Gum. Come to your senses.
Where's my phone? Phone, phone..
I'm going crazy. 911
Hey. Are you sleeping?
Soo Ha
From now on, you're going to be living with your uncle.
That's fine, right?
You'll be sharing a room with your cousins.
Brother-in-law, if you were going, you should have taken the boy with you.
Why did you go alone making it difficult for others?
It's already so difficult with 3, how am I going to raise another one.
Uncle!
Over here!
Please.. just disappear.
I can't immigrate with you along as well.
Is he hurt badly?
Stay still for now. You've got a fever.
Do I need to contact his parents?
They will be worrying.
But, why did he come to my house?
Why is he in this condition?
Gum.. is he a gangster?
I don't have any parents to worry about me.
I came because I had something to ask you. Also, I fell on the way here, that's why I look like this.
And I'm not a gangster.
Gum, do you look into someone else's mind 24/7?
Since the bus stopped running, you can sleep here tonight.
In the morning, go straight to the hospital.
Hospital, my butt.
- Oh yeah, what did you want to ask me?
- What?
You said you came because you had something to ask me.
Will she remember me?
My name... do you know it?
Name?
I don't know.
We won't be seeing each other again, so there isn't any need to know.
It's Soo Ha.
Park Soo Ha.
Park.. Soo Ha?
Your name is surprisingly normal considering your temper.
Piece of gum is a perfect fit for you. It's perfect.
Sleep.
Idiot.
There's no way she would remember. It's from ten years ago.
Park Soo Ha?
I feel like I heard it before..
Hey, Gum! Turn off the lights before sleeping.
Why is there so much on the breakfast table?
Today's Do Yeon's birthday.
I made a reservation at a restaurant for 7pm,
so make sure to come.
Yesterday, I met Chief Kong.
He said you cancelled your prosecution. What happened?
Oh, that. I heard the witness changed her testimony.
Do Yeon was totally backstabbed too.
I heard the defendant's lawyer was Hye Seong.
Yes.
Hye Seong? The one that lived at our place ten years ago, that Hye Seong?
Yes. She has become a public defender.
After ten years, you meet the daughter of the housekeeper who became a public defender
and you cancelled your prosecution in front of her?
I'm sorry.
Next time, I won't make that kind of mistake.
You're not eating? Where are you going?
I forgot that I have to go to a crime scene this morning.
I'm sorry.
If you keep doing this, rumours will start to spread.
What kind of rumours?
That you found Do Hyeon under a bridge.
(note: means she is not his legitimate daughter).
The joke is a bit much...
It's not a joke, you know that.
Well, even if I turn on my charm, it won't work on you.
So I don't have to look good in front of you, right?
It would seem that you don't have a Noona.
However, 99% of the women in the world look like this in the morning.
You should throw away useless fantasies and accept reality.
Do you want to drink?
No.
Okay!
Isn't this dog food?
Don't ask me for more after you eat it. Just eat.
How can you have only one spoon in this house?
I'm the only one living in this house. Would having one be normal or two?
Did you lose anything? It looks like the culprit made a mess trying to find something.
A mess?
The thief didn't do it.
If not the thief, then who...
You live like this?!!
Who is your first love?
She's pretty, to die for.
She's not just pretty.
She's nice and smart.
She's the most wonderful woman in the world.
99% of females in the world live like this.
In short, even Suzy and Girl's Generation live like this.
They probably all look like this at home too.
Eat or talk, just do one thing at a time!
He has left, my darling has left.
Toward the sun-lit green forest,
he is walking the short path away from me.
In this poem there are several interpretations of the "he" who has been lost.
I think "he" is someone's first love.
First love, you see, like this poem, makes people cry and is dazzlingly beautiful.
The hope that you'll meet your first love again makes your heart race.
Do you guys have that kind of first love?
No!
Damn.
How did you bring all of this? What about the store?
I left it in the care of Mr. Kim who works at the pizza place.
Yah, since you did that well on your first case, how much will they demand that you treat them.
If it fell on you only, because it would be left to me,
so I'm trying to help a little.
Oh, look.
This is seasoned and the other is fried.
You should hire people. Did you come all the way here since dawn just to give me this?
Would that be it?
Here.
Kirin Hotel at 7pm?
What's this?
He is my friend's son.
He is around your age and he also seems to be a good guy.
He's also a lawyer, so you two will get along.
Are you telling me to go on a blind date?
He's the son of a sauna house owner. He's super rich.
That all comes second though.
Mom, I have no intention of getting married.
Why? You wanted to get married early!
That was a month ago, but looking at the result of this case,
I'm the blue chip in my field.
Blue chip? You're spewing nonsense here.
If you'd seen me at the trial, you won't be calling me an ass.
I'm on a different level than other lawyers.
I was surprised at myself too.
To give up this talent for marriage is a huge disservice to the law.
So for now, just think that I'm married to the law.
Hey.
Your over-exaggeration is always the problem.
You've only won one trial.
Mom, be careful of my head!
With anything, if you want to do it for a long time,
you need to be humble, you understand?
I understand. I'll put this right back.
Oh! You aren't trying to stop me?
Whenever I look at your eyes, they are shining.
Working is better than marriage.
When water comes in, we should row the oars, shouldn't we?
Wait a little bit and eat lunch with me.
No, it's fine. I need to be getting back.
I told you to hire more people.
OK, I got it. Just go back in.
After she does her second trial, we'll die buried in chicken, it seems.
Lawyer Jang. Eat some chicken.
That's fine. Please eat to your fill.
Isn't this too fancy?
This is really expensive to do. If you do this at a shop, they'll probably charge you 20,000 won.
You have great talent. Anyways, consider yourself lucky.
There are many lawyers who just say a few lines and get a lot of money for it.
But look at me. I go to the school to investigate, I convince the witness. On top of that, I do all of it for free.
You should be grateful you met a lawyer like this.
I know it. I will tell myself that for the rest of my life.
OK. Write it here, and have it notarized before leaving.
At first, when I saw you, I thought I stepped on c***.
But then I changed my mind.
You trusted me when no one, my family, my teachers, trusted me.
Why did you trust me?
Yeah, uh, that is...
Well...I just got a feeling. You gave off the right feeling.
Thanks. Eonnie is the only person who-
Wait. Soo Ha also trusted me.
But why didn't Gum come with you?
He was going to come too. But he got a call and went somewhere else.
Where?
Who was the owner of the phone?
It was just a random ahjumma's phone. Are you happy?
But why is that in someone else's house? Did you check the fingerprints?
Nothing's coming up!
What about the person I asked about? Did you talk to Min Joon Gook?
He was living as a reliable, good man! He always volunteers.
Did you meet him? Where was he?
Aish, I can't tell you that. It's in our rulebook.
It's because he's a dangerous man.
It seems to me that you're the dangerous one, kid.
OK, OK. We'll keep monitoring him, so
put your attention on studying.
Is he living in the city of Yeon Joo?
Perhaps, is he living near the Justice Building?
Woah! He's like a ghost.
Did he just guess at random?
No! He's living somewhere far away.
Even if you keep asking, I won't answer.So, stop asking, punk!
Aigoo, regardless, you drank a lot of alcohol.
You can take that one. Yes, that one.
Have a nice meal.
I'm sorry. I'm just holding it for a while.
It's steamed sweet potatoes. So, if you put it in your pocket, it'll become mush.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy yourself.
He's still breathing! I should have just killed in one shot.
Dad!!
I told you I'd kill you! I will also kill all the people who listened to you!
Have a nice meal.
You look like a student. Did you come because you were hungry?
No, I was interested in volunteering. How can I start?
Really?
- Manager Kim.
- Yes!
There's
a brother that wants to volunteer here. What's your name?
It's Kim...Joong Ki.
Lawyer Jang,
your new case.
What kind of case has so many files?
Seo Do Yeon
It's Seo Do Yeon.
I heard you went to school together.
Yes.
Since high school, her effectiveness has dropped quite a lot.
I wonder if it's her style to use a whole bag of flour to make biscuits?
Seeing the records for the lawsuit, she sure did overdo it quite a lot again.
She doesn't seem to be overdoing it.
The point of contention is very peculiar.
Two brothers came into a convenience store and stole all the money.
What are you? What are you doing?!
They got caught by the owner. So, one of them stabbed the owner with a knife.
Let go!
The other tried to stop him.
It seems like a normal case.
The stabbing one should be charged for murder, and the other one should be charged for robbery.
Won't it be solved cleanly?
But, the prosecutor is charging both for murder.
Is Do Yeon in the right state of mind?
One of them definitely tried to stop his brother. It doesn't make sense to charge both.
Do Yeon is like that. Always overdoing things.
It seems like that...but she doesn't have a choice.
Who stabbed and who tried to stop it,
it's hard to tell.
Why can't you tell?
There should have been a CCTV installed, right?
Those two brothers are twins. Added to that, they are identical.
As well, both of them have confessed that he himself did the stabbing.
Well, how similar are they?
What in the world...
Am I defending the one that stabbed or the one that tried to stop it?
In the arraignment, it was recorded as the one who stabbed.
You're Jeong Pil Seung, right? Not Jeong Pil Ja.
Yes,
I'm Jeong Pil Seung. I'm the younger one.
I'm the lawyer in charge of your case.
Yes, I know.
You're Lawyer Jang Hye Seong, right?
I've heard a lot about you.
About me?
That you, from the very first case as a new appointee, crushed the prosecutor to a pulp.
The rumour has spread quite far.
They said I was lucky and everybody was jealous of me.
We'll have to get to the end of this trial to see if you're lucky or not.
You and your brother have both been
charged for robbery and murder.
Right?
It's not Hyung!
Hyung just followed me and is trying to take the blame.
I stabbed him.
You don't have any previous criminal record.
Yes,
but my brother does.
If he is charged for murder and since it's a repeat offense,
he might get a life sentence.
So you're going to take the blame, instead of him, because you don't have a prior record.
No, it's not like that.
I really stabbed him! Hyung is innocent.
Please argue like that.
Look, I'm your lawyer.
And, what's the mileage of a police record?
When you accumulate that, do you even know what you will get?
Get yourself together, Pil Seung!
This is a matter of rotting in jail for the rest of your life.
I know.
That is why I am begging you, Lawyer.
I took in a puppy a while ago.
I didn't know this would happen, and the puppy just started to walk.
Could you walk him for me?
Grand Prize Jeong Pil Seung
Sleep or type. Do one of them.
I can't.
Since the closing argument for Jo Yeong Sook's case is tomorrow,
I have to finish it today.
I'll do it.
You were up all night again yesterday, right?
This brain ought to be replaced by inserting a block of wood.
it's not working right now.
You're here?
You arrived?
What is that?
Ahhish, it's a puppy.
It is Mr. Pil Seung's puppy.
I said I'll take care of it until the case ends.
Until the case ends?
He's charged for robbery and murder, so he'll get like 10 years.
He didn't murder anyone.
The prosecution is wrong.
Again, the prosecution is wrong?
Yes.
I did it last time. Why would I not this time?
By the way, that case seemed to have been consolidated with his hyung's case.
Huh?
So the two brothers will be tried together?
Yes.
Perhaps this time you'll have to prepare to fight the other brother's lawyer more than the prosecutor.
He'll probably say his client is not the murderer too.
Who's the elder brother's lawyer?
He's a public defender too.
Public defender?
Is it Lawyer Shin?
No.
There. It is Lawyer Cha.
Lawyer Cha?
It's hard work, right? This much won't even last a week.
When did you start volunteering here?
It's almost been a month.
So you've lived in this church for a month?
Yes.
Why are you looking like that?
Do you, by chance, remember me? You look familiar.
No.
Where have I seen him?
I seem to have some impression.
You went to the courthouse a few days ago, right? Yeon Joo courthouse.
Did he see me there?
Right.
No.
I never went to court.
I think I've mistaken you for someone else.
Can I get a Green Grape Sparkling?
Yes.
I would like a grande iced tea, please.
Please charge hers on this card too.
Yes.
Get rid of any prejudice that old people drink only tea house coffee.
It's not that...What's up?
You never buy drinks for me.
So, you don't want it?
There's no need for that.
Do you have time for dinner today?
Our office is going to have dinner together.
I can go too?
You leave me out of dinners all the time.
Yeah...so you can't come?
No, well...
I'll check to see if I have time.
I'll go if I can.
Why are you here at court?
You don't have a trial today.
Lawyer Cha has a trial today.
I came to see if he's doing well.
Does it matter if the lawyer does well or not?
The defendant admitted to the crime.
Well, it's a simple case, isn't it?
Don't you want to know how he's going to argue about the sentence?
The defendant, Jo Yeong Sook, on March 16, 2012 at the Poong Jak Village Hat Salon,
stole 6,000,000 won in donations for the disabled, and
was arrested due to the Hat Salon director's police report.
When being arrested, the defendant waved a knife at the police.
Even if we consider that the defendant is speech-impaired,
the crime was planned ahead.
She didn't reflect upon lying in court.
Considering that the victim is requesting severe punishment,
applying Penal Code Section 331 Paragraph 2 Special Larceny
and Penal Code Article 136 Paragraph 1 and Section 144 Paragraph 2
Special Obstruction of a Government Officer Performing His Duty,
we are requesting two years of imprisonment.
Next.
The public defender can go now.
Yes.
It's not that folder. Go into the USB folder.
Yes. USB...
Did he bring the wrong information?
Why isn't this working?
Lawyer.
It's in the USB folder.
Yes. USB.
What?
Why is he doing that?
Why is this not working?
It's in the USB folder!
Yes.
Uh, this is...
Lawyer!
I said inside it. Did you not hear me?
I heard it well, Your Honor.
Your Honor,
you just experienced what it's like to be the defendant.
Like the defendant, no matter what you say,
other people don't hear you.
You got angry and banged the desk within 50 seconds.
If other people can't hear what I say,
I'll say it again louder.
But if they still can't hear,
then I'll speak even louder.
But if they still can't hear, then I get mad,
like the judge just did...
in 50 seconds.
But,
what if it wasn't for just 50 seconds,
but if they couldn't hear you for 50 years,
what would you have done?
You would have gotten angry a lot.
Instead of yelling and getting mad, the defendant
made donations.
She devoted herself to handicapped people like her.
She donated more than 30 million won.
When she couldn't repay her debts,
and went to the Hat Salon Director to ask for some money, she was turned away at the door and treated coldly.
Even though she was patient numerous times and begged, she wasn't listened to.
Of course, stealing money, out of anger, is definitely a crime.
She should have held it in, just like she has for 50 years.
But,
in that long time, was it so hard for even one person around the defendant
to listen to her voice?
Had they listened to the defendant's cries even once,
how might all this have turned out?
The person that has made the defendant come to stand here today,
may not be the defendant herself,
but we,
who are deaf.
In that long time, was it so hard for even one person around the defendant
to listen to her voice?
Had they listened to the defendant's cries even once,
how might have all this turned out?
The person that has made the defendant come to stand here today,
may not be the defendant herself,
but we,
who are deaf.
What are you doing here?
What about you?
Because that lawyer is going to take part in the twin case.
What is this?
You're out on a reconnaissance?
Yep.
This case makes me worry in various ways.
Of course it would,
there's going to be an evaluation soon.
With a public defender as counterpart, you withdrew the case.
If you can't handle this case well,
you'll have a lot to worry about.
I know, right?
The opposing lawyer is hard to deal with too.
Are you complimenting me?
No, not you.
Lawyer Cha.
You're probably worried too, after you saw that trial.
Isn't that right?
Not really.
- Joon Gook.
- Yes?
Do you know the high school volunteer's number?
I don't know his number, but I do know his name and school.
Is that so?
I forgot to give this to him while he was volunteering.
Proof of Volunteer Work
Is this important?
These days they need it to get into college.
Ah, what to do?
I'll go drop it off.
Ah, Kim Joong-
Student!
Can you call that student for me?
The one that's tall and playing catch.
Who? Park Soo Ha?
Park Soo Ha?
His name is Park Soo Ha? Not Kim Joong Ki.
No, it's not.
I'm Kim Joong Ki.
He's going around using my name?
Ah, no...
His name is Park Soo Ha?
Do you remember me?
Because you seem familiar.
Student.
Do you happen to know Park Soo Ha's phone number?
- Cheers!
Lawyer Jang, why don't you have a glass of wine too?
Today, it's all on Lawyer Shin.
I don't drink alcohol.
Then, should we order individually?
Why are you staring so intently?
Is something on my face?
No,
you're inviting me to dinner parties,
and you're letting me drop honorific terms.
It's weird.
You weren't like this before.
Usually,
I'm a bit harsh on people without talent.
Eh, so you're saying Lawyer Jang didn't have talent?
Of course she didn't.
But with Lawyer Cha, you dropped honorifics right away.
He's a talented guy.
You saw his trial just a while ago too.
Eh, Lawyer Shin.
Did you call me to the dinner for this?
To compare in each other's presence?
Why? Why don't you continue to use honorifics with me?
Why did you drop honorifics when I am this utterly without talent.
Don't worry,
you have your strengths too.
It's alright,
it's not even as if you're slapping my cheek, then humoring me.
What's my strength?
Your eyes.
My eyes?
Eyes that can tell
whether the defendant is lying or telling the truth.
No, but...
Other than that, what other strengths do I have?
Uh, other than that...
there aren't any other.
That doesn't make sense.
I even went to the defendant's school for that case.
That's because Lawyer Cha took you there.
Even in court when the prosecutor made a rebuttal, I made a game saving tackle . . .
You barely escaped only because I helped you.
Also!
What else is there?
Excuse me, can you please get me a glass of wine?
I thought you said you don't drink!
I said I won't, not that I can't!
Why do I only have one strength?
I asked why do I only have one strength?
You should have said she had 10 or something. What is this now?
Who knew she would whine this much?
Let's go.
Then, what about Lawyer Jang?
Lawyer Cha can take care of that.
Or you can.
Yes?
I'm sorry. Today's an ancestor's memorial, so I have to get going...
I have to be there as the first son, so I'll be leaving first.
Those eyes aren't mine.
I don't have eyes that can see through the defendant.
I don't see. I can't see.
Where did everyone go?
Lawyer Jang, where did everyone go?
I don't know. They must have all left without telling me.
Wow, her drunkenness is out there.
I don't see the truth.
Oh no!
Now, I really can't see.
What do I do? What should I do now?
Here.
Can you see now?
What should I do?
My eyes must be crazy.
Lawyer Cha has suddenly become a flower boy.
Oh my eyes have gone bad.
A flower boy.
That's right. I'm not a good judge of people.
So I need that piece of gum with me at all times.
Lawyer Jang, we'll look for that piece of gum another time. Let's find your home first instead.
Where is your house?
If he's not around, I can't go into a courtroom.
Why? Because my eyes have gone bad.
I can't see again.
Here.
There you go.
Excuse me, but where is your home?
Geez, I'm going crazy.
Why isn't she coming out?
Why isn't she answering her phone?
What is this?
What's the matter? Are you sick?
What a stench.
Hey, you were the one who came into our office, right?
Yes.
But what are you doing here?
I had something to say to Lawyer Jang.
As you can clearly see, she not in a state to listen to you.
Where does she live exactly?
I can't take her to my house either.
Should I take her back to the office?
It will be cold there at night.
I'll escort you to Lawyer Jang's house.
You know where she lives?
Yes, I've been there a few times.
Hand her to me and catch us a taxi.
Excuse me, but I'll take her by myself.
You can take her by yourself? She's heavier than she appears.
But for us to both take her home is a little excessive.
Is that so?
--Please take them safely.
--Yes.
Can I trust this rascal?
May I have one of your business cards, so that I can contact you after I get her home.
Sure.
If it's too difficult by yourself, contact me. I'll come right away.
That's alright. I'll be fine by myself.
Exactly how much
did you eat at the party,
that you're so heavy?
Damn.
It's still not fixed.
After what happened, you should be cautious.
♪ What made you finally appear?
♪ Where were you?
♪Even though it's a little late, still we've finally met.
This place is disgusting.
Gum.
Bring him here.
I need him at court.
What is she saying?
I need Gum...
He needs to be with me...
My eyes are rotten.
- Hello
- Hey, you little brat!
Pick up the phone properly!
Do you want to see blood and death?
Sober up, you wench!
Do you have to die in your mother's hands to get some sense?
Mom, talk softly. My ear is going to explode.
But what's wrong with your voice?
Are you hurt anywhere?
Yesterday, I had a dinner,
and drank some alcohol. I must have lost it.
But don't you hate alcohol?
Why did you drink it then?
Is there something wrong?
Mom, should I go meet that bathhouse son from last time?
Didn't you say you are forever married to the law?
The law and I had a falling out.
Why?
I don't know. I guess the law didn't want to be married to me.
How pathetic. You change your mind so easily.
I know, right. Why am I like this?
Hye Seong, do you even know how to do anything?
You're coming now?
Did you get home safely yesterday?
Do your insides feel alright?
Yes.
How do I look?
Do I still seem like a flower boy?
Wake up!
You seem to still be drunk!
I must have been crazy.
My eyes are really crazy.
I'm sober now,
but he still looks good even with those glasses.
Good morning.
Why are you looking at me that way?
Is something on my face?
Yesterday, did anything happen with Lawyer Jang?
Nothing really.
Ah! The high school student we saw before. Did he say he was Park Soo Ha?
That pal had come to get her.
That kid seems to escort her here and back everyday. Maybe he's a bodyguard?
Hey, Lawyer Cha.
Have you asked Lawyer Jang whether she knows that person named Min Joon Gook or whatever?
How do you, Lawyer Shin, know Min Joon Gook?
I was told he was a cell mate of someone I know.
Is he someone you know?
Yes.
That person, he was released a little while ago.
I was told he had inquired after you.
Released?
When did he get released?
It must have been about a month ago.
He had some debt to repay to you?
I'll be there
Could it be that person sent this too?
Sorry.
What are you doing here?
You didn't accept my calls, so I just came here.
The incident happened so long ago, and you still haven't fixed your lock?
Go.
I'll take care of it.
It's alright. I'm doing this in thanks for saving Seong Bin.
I told you go!
What's up? Is something wrong?
Get lost! Go!
Don't come here again!
I don't know if this rascal is with Min Joon Gook or not.
Hello?
It's me.
You remember my voice, right?
Ah, yes. You're Min Joon Gook, right?
How did you know my number?
I went to your school yesterday,
Park Soo Ha.
You didn't tell me your name, so I didn't recognize you.
I last saw you at court, ten years ago?
You... Where are you right now?
I didn't know what you liked, so I got this.
Eat.
You came, little one.
What are you thinking up?
You grew a lot, little one.
Your ability to read my thoughts that you had 10 years ago doesn't seemed to have changed
Speak up, and don't think them.
What are you worried about?
Why, you think I'm going to cause some trouble?
The cellphone is your doing, isn't it? You sent it.
Are you getting scared from just that? When I haven't even started...
What are you thinking.
Don't worry.
I don't have any hard feelings towards you.
10 years ago the target wasn't you, but your father.
This time too... it isn't you, but someone else.
If it's not me, who is it?
She became a lawyer, I've heard. That girl.
Let go of me!
Ahh! Save me!
Hello?
At the police station?
Ms. Jang Hye Seong! Hello.
What happened?
You know Park Soo Ha, the kid who was with you at the cell phone incident, right?
Yes.
Right now, that student beat up someone and is here.
A guardian has to sign him out, but he doesn't have parents and we can't contact his teacher.
So for now, I've called Lawyer Jang over.
What about the victim?
He left saying he doesn't want to charge for anything.
He just got released, so I guess he doesn't want to get involved in anything.
Released?
Yes. But the CCTV caught Park Soo Ha beating him up.
I can't give him bail unless someone can be liable for him.
What was the victim's name?
Yes, it's Min Joon Gook. He got released last month.
What?
Do you know this person?
May I see the CCTV?
Let's see...
Did Soo Ha say why he hit him?
I don't know. From what witnesses say, it was just a fit of rage.
There has to be a reason though.
Yeah, but there isn't any!
Min Joon Gook didn't say a word,
but then Park Soo Ha punched him!
I was there too. Min Joon Gook really didn't say anything.
Soo Ha was the only one talking.
Ah! Here it is! I found it!
This here.
What is Soo Ha saying?
What did he say?
Ah. He kept telling Min Joon Gook to speak up.
Not to think, but speak.
Say it, bastard!
Say what you're thinking!
I don't want to.
What are you doing? Let go and talk it out.
If that person wasn't there I would've died 10 years ago.
That's why think of my life as hers!
I'm going to protect her.
Get lost! I'm letting my life hang on the line to protect her.
Don't you dare do anything, because I'll kill you.
I'll kill you with my own hands.
If he bothers that woman, he announced he'd kill him.
I thought I was going to poop in my pants trying to hold him off.
He's totally crazy.
This punk, he even brought a hammer with him!
If he'd used this, this would've been a much bigger situation.
Listen to me carefully.
If she wasn't there 10 years ago, I would've been killed by you.
I... I...
will... protect you...
I wouldn't have lived if it weren't for her, so I'm going to protect her even if it kills me.
I'll risk my life to protect her.
I...
will... protect you...
What is this...
You know how to talk.
Kid.
What is your name?
Soo Ha...
Park Soo Ha.
I will be liable for him.
Where's Soo Ha?
Police
You let Min Joon Gook go!
Did you get his address? What about his phone number?
Hey, you seem to be misunderstanding something.
You were the one hitting. Min Joon Gook was the one getting hit.
You're the culprit. He's the victim. You got that?
Do know what he said? He's going to take revenge.
He's going to find the one who testified against him and kill her.
I believed you and asked all the witnesses at the restaurant.
There were no such words.
Min Joon Gook volunteers at
more than 6 places, such as soup kitchens and animal shelters.
He changed for the better. Yet you're accusing him without any evidence.
You should, at least, bring some evidence.
There's evidence.
What? What evidence?
I heard it. I can hear minds...
Stop it.
Don't say anything that's useless.
You'll just get treated like you did 10 years ago in court.
Park Soo Ha.
I remember your name now.