Did you get something?
They didn't have time to remove the chip.
Maybe
the blueprints are still in here somewhere.
What?
Maybe they had inside help.
Inside help?
Yes.
There wasn't enough time for them to
remove the chip.
I think they handed them over to someone
in the blind spot somewhere.
Father, Jiwan didn't do it.
I'm sure you think the same thing.
But I'm saying I did my part this time.
You're too loud I can't eat.
Mom, don't you think I earned some points?
That's all you think of these days, right?
You think your father doesn't know that?
He knows, but he's letting it pass.
Isn't that a good sign?
You think so?
But you need to learn that your father is
the scariest when he is not doing anything.
What scares me more are things you say.
Mr. Im,
Jiwan found out about the security chip.
Take care of it.
Okay.
Surprise!
Honey, I'm sorry.
I didn't know until Yeongju called me
that it's your birthday.
She was really mad.
She really cares about your birthday.
Why did you come alone? Where's Yeongju?
I thought you were coming home together.
Hello.
You wanted me gone, so why did you call?
What was that?
You said I was a fraud.
I'm very sorry about earlier.
Well...
When do you need the synopses?
Forget it. Writers are a dime a dozen.
I'm very sorry.
I have lots of ideas.
I'll write and work hard at it, too.
Should I send you one tomorrow?
Will you offer me a contract then?
I'll think about it after I read it.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Yeongju.
Did you eat?
I'm not hungry.
Mom, did you know about dad?
Yeongju.
You knew, and you've been doing that?
Yes, I made your dad stay there.
I knew it, but I couldn't tell him to quit.
No, I didn't.
Right.
I knew it.
I thought about it the whole time coming home.
Why did dad do it? Why did he have to do it?
Yes, I made a bad investment, so I've
I've been paying 1000s in interest per month.
So how could I tell him to quit?
We have no money for next month.
I had a hard time having the job I hate.
But dad's been hanging on
at a place where everyone wants him gone.
Imagine how he must have felt.
Stop it!
Knowing that,
how could you make him stay in that hell?
Meanwhile, you were having fun, taking yoga!
You're horrible!
How dare you!
How dare you talk to your mother like that!
How can you be that vicious to your mom!
You,
apologize to your mom.
Can't you hear me?
Apologize right now!
Honey, stop it.
Please don't do this.
You come back here!
This is what we get for spoiling you!
Honey, stop.
Why did you just listen to that, Minja?
You did all you can.
What is this?
You didn't do anything wrong.
Mom, what are you doing?
Oh?
Isn't that the purse Sugyeong gave you?
You're going somewhere?
Go away. Don't even think about it.
It's not like it'll wear out after one use.
Haengsuk.
How much do you think I can get for it?
Mom,
Seonhui doesn't give you any money?
Just ask her for some.
Why do you tiptoe around her? I'm upset.
It's because of you.
If it weren't for you, I'd have no trouble.
If the blueprints are in the building,
we still have hope.
Right.
Everything's going to be alright.
I asked Security to track the chip,
but he didn't get a signal in the building.
Then...
Why aren't things working out for us?
Those who took the blueprints
knew about the security chip.
How many employees would know that?
I'm not sure.
I didn't even think of it until you told me.
If they had inside help, it must have been
someone who knew about that.
Okay. I'll get the list of people.
Thanks, Hyeondo.
Now you're grateful?
It's great to have the owner's son as a friend.
But Ms. Seo is a bit...
We'll talk about it later.
Grandma, I can't stay in here anymore.
Hey,
it feels good in here.
Sweating will make your skin soft.
Stay a little longer.
I'll die of suffocation first, grandma.
Did you think
having soft skin was easy?
Mother, I should go to the hotter room.
I'm not sweating very much.
Hotter room?
Mom, I'll stay here.
Yes, the hotter one's a bit too much for me.
Grandma.
What is it?
What do you think about mom seeing someone?
Is she seeing someone?
No, she's not.
She's still young, and we're all grown up,
so I thought she might be lonely.
Don't even start.
I told her over and over again
not to worry about us and get married
if she met anyone nice.
But whenever I told her that, she would say
she couldn't do that to you two.
Oh, I'm sick and tired of that issue now.
What is it?
You want your mom to get married?
To be honest, I don't want her to date anyone.
You don't?
Don't you feel the same way?
Right?
You do, right?
I'm all sweated out.
I'm leaving, grandma.
This right here. Five times.
And then we'll get out.
I'm dying, grandma.
She insisted on coming by herself,
but she still isn't here.
Who? Aunt?
Speaking of the devil,
there she comes.
- Mom. / - I'm glad you're here.
Seonhui, Eunsu, you're here, too?
Hi, Haengsuk.
Aunt, you want eggs? Or sweet rice drink?
No, I'll have those eggs.
Don't get up.
Grandma, your porcelain skin
was a result of hard work.
Yes, look at my skin.
I don't look my age.
It's a result of perseverance and efforts.
That's right.
I'm glad only Jiwan takes after Sangjun.
If you were also as quiet as your father,
I would've died of frustration.
I'm sorry.
When does your daughter graduate?
She has one semester left.
You'll have to hang on for one more semester.
You have to do it, playing the Grim Reaper,
and I have to hang on, not to get fired.
We'll have to do it for one more semester.
I won't live that way.
Even when I'm old,
I'm not going to live that way.
What am I doing right now...
If I do what I want to do,
my dad has to keep doing that.
I'm being selfish.
I'm very selfish.
Let's drink together.
And you're not selfish.
That's not being selfish.
That's not.
Jiwan.
Jiwan!
It's Jiwan.
Hello.
Eunsu, are you all right?
Can we have another shot glass?
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeongju.
Let's drink together...
No, I'm fine.
Is something wrong?
Yeongju's dad...
You know what?
I thought my dad was the greatest.
But...
He was a reliable husband to my mom
and a loving dad for me.
But...
To see him treated that way at work,
I felt so sad for him.
Let me go to the restroom.
Where are you going? Listen to me first.
Restroom.
You're not drinking?
My dad was...
I went to my dad's workplace.
He was on his knees there.
And I got upset and screamed.
But my dad said he was okay.
He said he was okay and consoled me.
Yeongju, just a second.
Hi, Eunsu.
Where are you?
You're home?
Eunsu went home?
Yes, Yeongju. You're drunk.
Let's go.
Go where? Let's go for another drink.
I'll take you home.
Let go. I'm going out for another drink.
Get up.
Are you all right?
Yeongju.
Why do I always find things out late?
I found out about dad late.
I found out about my dream late.
I found out about the nice man I have late.
Get up. Let's go.
- Get up, Yeongju. / - Let go.
I said let go!
You really shouldn't be
doing things like this for me.
You're drunk.
Let go.
I'll go alone.
Oh, my,
you got here early.
I don't think I'm late.
You went to see Seonhui?
Have you been tailing me?
Why would you scare me like that?
I feel like I should prepare for the worst.
What did you say to her?
What do you think?
Isn't it obvious?
I was going to tell her how bold you are.
I only stole one bank account, but I felt
uncomfortable facing Seonhui's family.
But you stole their entire fortune,
and you're not scared of seeing them.
They hit poverty overnight because of you,
and your don't feel guilt in your conscience?
You're talking about conscience and guilt?
Fine.
What does your conscience want?
You failed at getting transaction records,
and you haven't told Seonhui anything.
That means you want something from me.
I've  never asked you for much.
Just one thing, that's all.
This is the bond from the loan sharks.
After this, I owe you nothing.
He didn't set this up
with the loan shark people, did he?
Wait, he stole a family's fortune,
and this is all he's going to offer me?
Taesu's become very petty.
Man...
Only the management level and above
in Security knew about it.
That's over 20 people.
This man was appointed relatively recently.
Mr. Im Hanseok. Do you know him?
No, I've never seen that name before.
You're right.
It happened after he was appointed.
And only his contact number's missing.
I'll check with the secretary's office.
Hello, Mr. Choi.
This is Jang Hyeondo.
The executive secretary,
the one who was just appointed.
Can I get his personal number?
What?
You don't have his number?
Okay.
Isn't it simpler to hand her over
to the loan sharks than to pay her debt off?
Even to you,
she didn't look like she'd go away quietly?
Why don't you hand her over?
If I call them right now...
The thing about people is that
they need hope or desire to be cautious.
Women like Lee Jeongae become
unpredictable if they are pushed too far.
If things go wrong after I hand her over to
the loan sharks, she'll come after me.
There's one thing I'm worried about.
Why did she need to take out a loan?
Should I find out?
Yes.
She loved spending money, but she wasn't
reckless enough to turn to loan sharks.
Kids, mommy's here.
Hello.
Hi.
These are for you.
Thank you.
- Thank you. / - Sure.
What brings you here?
I came to see you, mom.
Eunha is inside.
Okay.
You said you're broke, so stop bringing snacks.
I might be getting some money soon.
This is why people should have lots of kids.
What are you talking about?
It's nothing.
You have lots of kids, so you should see.
One of them might take care of you.
Unlike other mugs, I'm trying to
make the top part of the handle round.
And I want to put a flower motif on it.
Using graphics.
Is that possible?
Ma'am!
Yes?
Did you remove the invitations from here?
No.
Did I put them somewhere else?
What is it?
Do you need an invitation to get in?
No,
my face is all I need. I don't need one.
Let's go.
Okay. Take care of it,
and I'll talk to you on Monday.
I can't let Kim Jiwan stay at my company.
He's working at a place like this?
Oh, no!
He's the one who stole my invitations?
Okay. Bye.
Honey, if you're done, let's go and eat.
Honey!
I want to buy this painting!
This one?
The colors and the divided composition would
- look great in our living room... / - Whatever.
How much is it?
How many times must I tell you it's vulgar to
talk of price when it comes to masterpieces?
So you're saying
if I heard the price, I'd have a heart attack?
If you're not going to buy it, let's leave.
Thank you for letting me escape from here.
The food here is good. Let's come here often.
I only get invitations from nice places.
- He stole the invitation for here? / - What?
What did you say?
It's nothing. Keep eating, Mr. Jang Taesu.
There are no tables by the window?
What's that?
Isn't that Hyeondo's voice?
No, that isn't Hyeondo's voice.
You must be going deaf.
Have some more wine.
Here.
Go inside...
What are you doing?
I can't cut the steak.
Can you cut it for me?
Still, don't throw your steak at my plate.
Okay. Let's go.
Have lunch before you leave.
I have to leave, too, so clean up afterwards.
I'm not eating. You eat.
Fine. Just starve yourself.
It's your stomach, not mine.
They said it's now or never,
so I wanted to ask if I should review anything.
I was going to talk to you about Ohyeah Media.
I don't think that place is legit.
Something seems wrong.
What do you mean?
They steal up-and-coming writers' ideas.
I heard they turn you into their slave.
Anyway, their reputation isn't good.
If you sign a contract with them,
you might end up being in planning forever.
At least they'll pay me signing bonus.
They will, but it'll be pennies.
Anyway, read the contract carefully
and bring it to me. I'll ask around.
Director, we're ready.
Just a second.
Ms. Kang, the shooting's about to start,
so don't sign anything just yet, okay?
But what if,
like the guy said,
this is the best opportunity for me?
You might end up in some serious trouble.
But it could work out.
It could work out really well.
If I can get the money...
Are you doing this for money?
Then, you'll definitely end up big trouble!
They can sniff out writers in need of money!
They'll suck you dry!
No, Ms. Kang! Don't do it!
I'm sorry.
I have to go.
Ms. Kang!
You're going to read every line?
This society is based on trust.
Do you see $100,000 there?
You'll get it when the contract is finalized.
I'm a man of my words.
Sign there.
They can sniff out writers in need of money!
They'll suck you dry!
No, Ms. Kang! Don't do it!
When you're gone,
several lower positions can be spared.
Get a conscience!
You're not going to sign it?
What?
If you don't want to, forget it.
No!
I'm signing it right now.
Oh, my!
What the heck are you doing?
I'm her mom,
so I'm going to do something here.
Mom.
Mom, what are you doing?
You don't know anything, so just leave.
I don't know anything? How do you know?
I know more about contracts than you do.
I worked at a bank for 10 years, you know?
Let me see this.
Signing bonus, $100,000.
See? I knew it.
It says $100,000,
but what?
The signing bonus is 10%?
And the contract period is 10 years?
Your drama must air within the first year to get the signing bonus?
What?
Hey!
Who are you?
How dare you try to con my daughter?
You think my daughter's on idiot?
Are you mad?
You want me to call the police?
We must call the police!
I'll call them and tell them to arrest you!
Mom, what are you doing? It's embarrassing!
What the heck!
How dare you!
Let go! What are you doing to my mom!
Why you little!
Mom, nice! Good job, mom!
How dare you call this a contract!
Good job, mom.
Such an idiot.
You have no street smarts.
Even if you're desperate,
you should know what's good or bad.
How did you know?
That producer named Heo Seonggeun called.
Oh, he conned you, but he couldn't stand
watching you being conned by someone else.
Don't laugh.
You don't have to do this.
If your dad found out what you did,
he'll be even more miserable.
Mom,
I'm sorry about the other night.
I'm hot. Get away from me.
She never says anything nice.
Don't act rashly for your dad's sake.
I can't do anything for him anyway.
You don't need to do anything.
I'll take care of dad.
When I get involved, things just work out.
I raised an idiot like you into a decent woman,
so nothing's impossible for me.
I'm Oh Minja.
What's this?
Is it a gift or a bribe?
Gift or bribe, I'm not the least interested
in giving anything to you, mom,
but Eunsu is so nice.
She made this with her pretty hands
to give to you!
Why did I ever give birth to him?
I should tell Hyeongyu to come home soon!
This mug is one of a kind.
This design was inspired by you.
Not bad.
- What? / - Huh?
Have you gone deaf?
I'm old.
I can't be bothered.
So go ahead and date. I don't care.
- Do you mean it? / - Really?
Why do you keep asking me that?
You want me to take it back?
No...
No, mom!
We're just so happy, that's why, mom.
Don't be so happy.
My "Yes" means very little.
Mom...
Thank you.
But that's all.
Trying to break you up is a waste of energy.
That was hard on me, too.
I don't enjoy playing the bad guy, you know?
So keep dating.
Date as much as you want and break up.
But you handle your father. I can't.
You can't ask me that.
And please don't let your father catch you!
Don't show yourselves in front of him!
You're making me nervous!
Mom, see you at home.
Your father isn't happy about us?
My father?
My father's just...
Just give it to me straight.
You're not good at lying.
I can tell.
He's doing it because he's not happy with me.
He'll get over it soon.
My father really likes you and Jiwan.
Oh, they sure look happy.
What are they so happy about?
I can't watch them anymore.
How disgusting.
But that sure beats him moping around.
Really? Sugyeong?
You didn't make that up to assure me, did you?
Why would I lie to you?
You said yes, so why wouldn't they say yes?
Right. If Sugyeong's okay, Taesu would be, too.
Did Sugyeong do anything to you?
No, she was very classy.
Sugyeong?
She never once raised her voice.
Actually...
She did say something bad, but just once.
I knew it.
What about Taesu?
He's always nice.
I got all your favorites, father.
I'm a great son, don't you think?
It's obvious you want something.
What do you want to tell me?
I respect you very much.
Yes, using flattery before offering a deal,
that's very important.
No, I'm not trying to offer a deal.
I really do respect you.
You've been dedicated to mom all your life.
She's my mom, so I don't understand why,
but I respect your taste in women.
Anyway, thank you for staying with mom.
And I'm trying to date a woman like her.
I know I made a big mistake.
And I know you're very angry about that.
But it was my fault, not Eunsu's, father.
I want to know why it can't be Eunsu.
Do you have any respect for me?
Of course, I do.
The respect I have for you,
no words in this world can describe it.
The man you respect that much
told you to break up with her,
so why can't you accept it,
thinking, "Oh, there must be a valid reason."
Tell me the reason.
Every decision I make is to
protect everything I built.
My house, my company,
and most of all, my family.
So you think
Eunsu will ruin everything you built?
Why would you think such a thing?
Do you know the advantage of
someone who has accomplished so much?
You don't need others to understand you.
I just need to make orders,
and the others must follow them.
If they don't want to follow my orders,
they can leave from
my house, my company and my territory.
Father.
Father...
Mr. Yun.
What is it?
What's going on?
Jiwan,
you are to appear at the Personnel Committee.
Why are they holding it so fast?
They already finished the investigation?
How would I know!
Welcome.
Hello.
Sit over there, please.
Okay.
What brings you here?
Well,
I dropped by because of Eunsu.
Thank you for not telling your mother
about what happened the other day.
Why would you thank me for that?
How do you know about Eunsu when we didn't?
I knew Mr. Kim very well.
So I found out about Eunsu.
Mr. Kim asked me to look after Eunsu.
But that's so weird.
Sangjun had Taesu,
so why did he ask you?
That's not something I can tell you.
Anyway, thank you about Seonhui.
I always wanted to ask,
but you're not, right?
Seonhui and you...
I mean,
you're not in a relationship,
are you?
No, we're not.
Right?
Mr. Shin, I'm...
I...
I have feelings...
Seonhui and I aren't in a relationship.
And we could never be.
I have a feeling
she doesn't even know what I do for a living.
She's not interested in me at all.
Excuse me?
She's relying on me only because there's
no one else she can talk to about Eunsu.
If it weren't for her daughter,
she would never even talk to me.
That means...
You're...
Excuse me.
You're Mr. Im, aren't you?
What is this about?
About the blueprints that got leaked.
What about them?
There's a possibility they might still be here.
We're keeping that in mind.
And we're looking into possible inside help.
You're already investigating that?
You think we're amateurs?
You think the blueprints are
still in the building because of the chip?
Do you?
They might be.
But any decent industrial spy would
check whether or not there is an embedded
security chip.
Those chips are for average thieves.
They're not effective on industrial spies.
Stop playing a detective and start
preparing for the Personnel Committee.
How could you not find anything yet?
When I got you all those documents?
No wonder Mr. Jang was confident about them.
What about the stockholders?
Did you find the stockholders from the past?
Actually, we found something strange.
Strange?
There was a major investor when Best Global
was founded, but no one knows his identity.
He bought Taehu Industry at the verge of
bankruptcy and made a huge investment,
but he resigned after just one year,
and nobody knows where he is now.
We looked for him,
but his address and phone number were fake.
The president when the company was founded
might have been a president in name only.
So where did the investment come from?
I can't help feeling suspicious of Mr. Jang.
There seems to be a problem at Best Global.
They are trying to keep it under wraps,
but the new product blueprints were leaked.
The new product blueprints were leaked?
And the man they are suspecting
is the young man you were interested in.
You mean Jiwan?
We've had some issues lately.
Well...
Should I come see you?
I want to apologize.
It's okay, Seonhui. There's no need.
I still don't like them dating.
How about you?
You've changed your mind?
You sound nice, so maybe you have.
I guess I shouldn't object so firmly.
Listening to you being nice isn't so bad.
Sugyeong, the kids...
Whatever. I'm not going to care.
You shouldn't be worried about Eunsu now,
with what's happening with Jiwan and all.
With Jiwan?
What's happening?
You don't know?
He may not be your real son,
but you should pay more attention to him,
when there was such a huge incident at work.
What was it, Sugyeong?
What happened to Jiwan at work?
Jiwan is suspected of being an industrial spy.
My husband can only do so much.
He may be Sangjun's son, but he must
think of the other employees, too.
I'll be back.
Okay.
It's time to go to the investment presentation.
The Personnel Committee's today, too, right?
Yes.
He was a decent guy.
Should I tell them to go easy on him?
A normal company couldn't possibly
let an employee who leaked top secret stay.
Just let them decide on their own.
Yes, sir.
Yes.
Yes, I got it.
What happened?
Jiwan was sent to the Personnel Committee.
At this rate,
the outcome is obvious.
Hello, mother.
Did you eat lunch?
I haven't packed you lunch for a while.
It's okay.
Jiwan...
Mother, I have to be somewhere.
Jiwan.
Don't miss your meals.
Don't worry.
I never miss my meals.
Okay. That's good.
I have to go, mother.
Seonhui, where are you?
You said you'd be here by lunch, but it's 4!
I'm sorry, Haengsuk. I forgot.
- Minja. / - Yes?
I'm needed at home. Can you step in for me?
- I have to go. / - Don't worry about it.
I'm sorry. Thank you.
Oops.
Just don't do anything!
Why would you make a bigger mess?
What's wrong with you today?
You think this is too much work?
Look, if it weren't for Seonhui,
you couldn't live here.
Mom, you believe everything she tells you?
Man!
I can't take this from you anymore.
Do it all yourself!
Wait...
Mom!
How long are you going to tiptoe around Seonhui?
You didn't do anything wrong.
You were the one who always sided with her!
Why have you been so mean to Seonhui lately?
You're just making yourself look bad.
Be honest with me.
Isn't it because of Shin?
I knew it was because of Shin.
Stop barking up the wrong tree.
Even if he doesn't get Seonhui,
he would never even look at you.
Mom, you shouldn't trust Seonhui so much.
You're being horrible, so stop it.
Seonhui's personal life is clean.
I've lived with her for a long time.
Sangjun is the only man for her.
Look how she dotes on Eunsu.
She's doing it because she's Sangjun's child.
Eunsu and Sangjun aren't related.
She's not his blood.
I should go back to making pancakes.
It'll get dark soon.
Hey,
what did you...
What did you just say?
What do you mean?
Eunsu's what?
Eunsu's not Sangjun's child?
You said that, didn't you?
No, mom. I didn't.
You didn't?
No?
Look into my eyes and tell me.
I, I didn't mean it.
It was a slip of the tongue.
I'm serious, mom.
I knew you were acting strange lately.
You were being mean to Seonhui.
I figured it was because of Shin,
but it wasn't?
It wasn't?
Was it,
was it really because of Eunsu?
Mom...
Tell me!
Or I'll die of frustration!
If Eunsu isn't Sangjun's blood,
who is she?
Did she have her with another man and lied?
Who is it?
Is it Shin?
Was she with him before marrying Sangjun?
No, mom!
That's not true!
She's not Seonhui's child either.
She has nothing to do with Seonhui or Sangjun.
- Oh... / - Mom.
Oh, no...
Mother.
Mother, I'm late.
Is there any corrections you want to make
on your statement at the investigation
on the blueprint leakage on May 30th?
Is there?
There isn't.
I would like to thank all the domestic
and foreign investors for coming here.
For the past 23 years, Best Global has been
growing fast thanks to the transparent
and people-centric management.
Both customer satisfaction for our products
and employee satisfaction have been very high.
On top of that...
We've been focusing on innovation,
producing new products to lead the market.
We consider it an honor to be able to produce
a new protect that everyone likes this year.
We will use Mr. Kim Jiwan's statement
as the foundation of our judgment.
At the investigation by Audit,
you said you were responsible?
Yes, sir.
Is there anything else you'd like to add?
Leaking the blueprints was my fault.
But I didn't do it intentionally.
This company is my company.
This is the first company that hired me.
This is where I want to build my future.
How could I
do such a thing to a place like that?
I swear
I never did it intentionally.
I hope you would believe that.
We will take questions now.
Yes?
What is your prediction on overseas sales?
Yes.
To be honest,
we're entering new overseas markets,
so short-term sales won't be very high.
But in terms of market share,
we've been growing very quickly.
You have the printout of that on your table.
When the new product comes out,
that growth will be significantly higher.
Just a second.
I heard your new product blueprints were stolen.
If another country copies it,
the financial loss will be quite significant.
Shouldn't you have informed us on it?
Answer me, President Jang.
Is that true?
Let's say you didn't leak them intentionally.
Even if it was a mistake, the fact that
you caused damages doesn't change.
In your opinion, what do you think we should
do to an employee who made such a mistake?
Excuse me?
I'm sorry, Mr. Chair-person.
There's something I would like to say.
Mr. Kim Jiwan isn't the only one responsible.
I'm responsible for letting him go to such
an important contract meeting alone.
No, I'm the man to blame.
Mr. Kim Jiwan is a talented and devoted
employee who's worked harder than anyone.
Please show leniency.
We will address the issue of neglect
from the management at another time.
Today we will only deal with the leakage.
- But... / - Mr. Yun, be quiet!
You might be making things worse for him!
Answer me.
If it were you, what kind of
disciplinary action would you take against
an employee who made such a mistake?
I think he should be fired.
Jiwan!
Is there anything else you want to add?
No, sir.
We will decide on the disciplinary action.
What happened?
We have decided on the disciplinary action.
Mr. Kim Jiwan.
You're fired.
Should you have any objections...
Sir.
I object.