Play dumb.
That's right...
He likes Gon, so he'll bail us out.
Idiot!
Oh... Oops.
What is it?
You know someone here?
Ah! No...
It's that girl!
Oh? You know them, Shizuku?
Nope, never seen them before.
Huh?
Oh, I remember...
It's the arm wrestling kid.
Who was that?
Two days ago, you lost to
that kid at arm wrestling.
Lost? I lost?
That's a lie.
I would never lose to a kid.
Well, you were using your right hand...
Why? I'm left-handed.
Don't bother.
Once Shizuku's forgotten something,
she'll never remember.
Never mind... I was mistaken.
Thought so.
Oh?
You actually beat Shizuku?
Yeah.
Never would've imagined she
was a Troupe member.
Okay, I'll challenge you.
Ally x And x Sword
One more time.
Ready...
Go.
One more time.
Ready...
Go.
Hey...
When it comes to arm wrestling,
what's my rank among the spiders?
Seventh or eighth?
You're not weak, but you're
not strong, either.
And the strongest was this guy called Uvogin.
But apparently, he was
killed by the chain user.
We already said we don't know who that is!
Kid!
If you speak without permission again,
I'll kill you.
One more time.
Ready...
Go.
He was an Enhancer.
Simple-minded and straightforward,
he loved a good, all-out fight.
But he was fussy about time.
He'd get into fights
with Franklin and me when we were late.
He'd beat the crap out of me
in an unarmed brawl...
I've known him since before
the Troupe was founded.
I know him better than anyone.
He would never...
Uvo would never lose in a fight!
He must've been caught in some dirty trap!
I will make his killer pay.
I'll find him, no matter
how many I have to kill.
The chain user bears a
strong grudge against us.
The Mafia's Nostrade Family
hired him recently.
A grudge against the Troupe?
Recently hired...
You might not know him directly,
but you may have heard stories of him!
Think hard...
If you have any guesses, spill them!
I don't know anything.
But even if I did, I would never tell you!
I thought you were a bunch
of heartless monsters,
but you'll mourn the death
of one of your own?
Why couldn't you spare...
Spare a fraction of that grief...
for the people you've killed?!
You're getting too cocky.
Gon!
Another step, and I'll cut you up.
Answer the question.
Do you know who the chain user is?
I already said I have nothing to tell you!
Feitan...
Stop.
Stop what?
Stop what you're about to do.
You know what I'm about to do?
You're going to break his arm, right?
I'd start with a finger...
Peel off a nail.
Doesn't matter where you'd start.
Just stop!
Why are you giving me orders?
I have no reason to listen to you.
Hey, quit it, Nobunaga.
Have you forgotten the rules?
Troupe members aren't allowed
to start serious fights.
I know!
If there's a dispute, we flip a coin.
Tails.
Heads!
It's heads.
Let him go.
So, what do we do with them?
They haven't told us anything
about the chain user yet.
If they don't know anything,
we can let them go.
Well, Pakunoda?
I checked on the trip here.
They really don't know anything.
You're sure?
Yes.
They have no memories of the chain user.
Seems your instinct was off this time.
That's odd...
Well, if Pakunoda says so, it must be true.
Hey, Gon!
Did they do anything to you
on the way over here?
No, they just asked me a few questions.
Thought so...
Then they learned what they wanted
without our realizing.
What was it? And how?
Sounds like they really trust
Pakunoda's judgment.
She must possess a skill more
convincing than mere instinct.
They have no memories of the chain user.
Memories?
How about you?
Any guesses?
The power to scan someone's memory!
By touching them?
That would explain everything.
And we're in trouble.
When she scanned us before, I had
no idea who the chain user was.
But now, I have an image in my head.
If she checks again...
If they have nothing to do
with the chain user,
we can let them go?
Yeah, there's no point
in keeping them here.
No, we can't be sure they're
completely unrelated.
It's possible they're being used.
If the chain user typically conceals his chains,
they wouldn't realize he was the chain user.
We shouldn't release them until they
tell us who they're working for.
Assuming they're working for someone else,
it wouldn't be the chain user.
Because he operates alone.
Then you agree with Nobunaga.
Rather than use a couple of kids,
we can find the information we need
through the Nostrade Family.
Since we know the chain user's a member.
That's true.
Our target is the chain user.
We should ignore everyone else.
There you go.
You kids are lucky.
No, not yet.
I won't let him leave.
Kid...
Join the spiders.
Team up with me.
No way.
I'd rather die than join you guys!
He really hates us...
You're an Enhancer, right?
What if I am?!
I knew it!
Hey!
We're keeping them here
until the boss gets back.
I'm going to recommend we recruit them.
Are you serious?
The boss will never agree to that.
Well, it's your call.
But you have to watch them.
You can't blame us if they escape.
He reminds you of Uvo?
Yeah, he wears his emotions on his sleeve.
And when he's angry,
he forgets about consequences.
Most of all,
he's strongest when fighting
for someone else.
He did like to fight alone.
But he was strongest
when he'd team up with
Nobunaga to fight a horde.
Uvo never admitted it,
but he preferred having
someone to protect.
Then, he was stronger with
someone holding him back.
Well, I guess you could say that.
Shizuku is always so uncharitable...
On the other hand, Nobunaga's
skills are superior for duels.
You could even say that they're
really only effective one-on-one.
Whenever they had assignments to fight
together, they always complained.
But in truth, they seemed to enjoy it.
Okay,
that's enough reminiscing.
Let's get down to business.
Here's a list of Nostrade Family members
taken from the Hunter website.
These five are particularly important.
They serve as bodyguards for
the daughter of the boss.
And they're the ones who captured Uvo.
But Uvo said that the chain
user wasn't on this list.
Since we don't know the
chain user's appearance,
we'll have to find someone who does.
Oh, that's the guy I killed.
Cross out the top left guy.
Move around in pairs,
and search for the people on that list.
Then we'll meet back here
at 10 PM. That's all.
Wait.
Nobunaga's staying here, right?
What should I do?
You can team up with whoever's left.
Ow...
I was a fool.
If I'd made a move,
Hisoka wouldn't have hesitated to kill me.
That murderous aura...
I was frozen in place.
If Gon had suffered a lethal blow,
would I have been able to move?
That's impossible.
Your only concern when you meet someone
is whether you should kill them.
You're wrong...
"Never fight an enemy you can't beat."
I drilled that into you...
You're wrong!
Scary...
You look like you want to kill me.
Let me warn you first.
Step into range, and I'll cut you down.
Killua!
I stand no chance against him.
I have to think of a way to escape...
No windows.
One exit.
How can we get him to move away?
Is Leorio okay?
I hope he was able to find Zepile-san.
Killua, are you okay?
Yeah.
Hey,
Zepile-san taught us welding, exposing...
What else was there?
I forgot.
Side-stomping, maybe?
I don't think that was it...
Gon...
I'll act as a decoy.
Use that chance to escape.
What are you talking about?
Seriously.
Forget it.
You're smart enough to know
how much stronger I am.
There won't be any chances.
I already know that!
This room only has one exit
and nowhere to hide.
He can see everything we're doing.
We're facing someone who can watch
us without creating an opening.
He's probably an iaido master.
With his shodachi, his range
is at least two times mine.
If I take one step too close,
he'll strike a fatal blow.
But that's the point!
You can't do it.
Shut up!
I won't know until I try!
Killua, what are you thinking?
I'll stop his shodachi, even if it kills me.
Use that chance to run away!
Huh?
What was that for?!
Don't be so selfish!
Don't talk about dying like it's nothing!
What?!
You did the same thing earlier!
I'm allowed to do it!
But you aren't!
Huh?
You can't use logic against an Enhancer...
We can't escape unless we're
prepared to die, stupid!
You have no idea what I was thinking...
Who's the selfish one?!
Yes, I've no idea...
Because I'm stupid!
You kids are hilarious!
Hey, I'm not gonna hurt you or anything.
Just behave yourselves.
I know you're serious.
Don't throw your lives away.
Wait until the boss gets back.
If he won't give his approval, you can leave.
But if you try to escape, I'll kill you.
Don't make me draw my sword.
If I pull it out, you'll die...
I remember now!
It was side-stepping!
Welding, exposing...
And the last one was side-stepping!
Do you remember now?
Yeah, I sure do!
See?
How could we forget something so simple?
Huh?
Now that we've figured that out...
Let's go!
Are you serious?
You're going to die.
I'm not skilled or merciful enough
to control my strength.
Fools!
If the exit is blocked...
Make your own!
The wall...
Tsk, which one do I chase?
We're on the fifth floor.
The kid with slanted eyes
is already close to the stairs.
So the black-haired kid!
Now he has nowhere to run.
Am I an idiot?
They can break through walls to escape!
The slanted-eyed kid is below.
I'll have to follow the black-haired one.
Where is he?
The walls are intact...
So is the door.
Killua, are you there?
Yeah, I'm here!
That's it!
That last hole was a decoy!
He broke it before hiding in the nearby room,
waiting for me to pass,
before stepping into the hallway.
We can beat him together!
His presence disappeared... Zetsu?
Does the idiot want to fight me?
An advanced application of Ten and Ren.
En!
En
Normally, you shroud your body in aura
that extends a few
millimeters from your body.
But with En, you extend that
aura as far as necessary.
You can sense anyone who
steps inside your En.
Inside it, you can even count
the leaves as they fall.
You can conceal your presence and approach,
never making a sound.
But step within my En,
and I'll swing my sword.
Come to me.
Stupid.
Man, I wanted to beat him up.
That was impossible.
He'd have fought you off and killed you.
One hundred percent guaranteed?
We don't have a chance
only knowing the basics of Nen.
What is it?
You finally sound like yourself again.
It's my job to say crazy stuff.
Your job is to stay cool and stop me.
So I'm counting on you!
You're so selfish.
Well? What do we do next?
That depends on what you want to do.
I want to defeat those guys.
Well, that matches our original objective.
But we'll have to improve our Nen to do that.
Nen has the potential to give us the power
we'd need to stand a chance.
And the fastest way to learn more
would be to ask Kurapika.
Huh? Why?
Because Kurapika is the chain user
who defeated one of them.
Huh?
You didn't realize it?
Is that really true?
I'm pretty confident.
If it's true, we have a chance.
Because we learned Nen around
the same time Kurapika did.
We need to learn the techniques
appropriate to our abilities.
And most importantly,
we need the strength to fight the Troupe.
And Kurapika is the key to
finding those answers?
Yeah.
At the same time, a new storm brews
at the heart of Yorknew City.
Brush Your Teeth.
Unripe Fruit
Gon and Killua's Hunterpedia
Coming up, we have Gon
and Killua's
Hunterpedia!
It's Gon
and Killua's
Hunterpedia!
Gon and Killua's Hunterpedia
Today, we introduce Franklin,
A Phantom Troupe member.
a member of the Phantom Troupe.
He's an Emitter.
An Emitter.
His attack Double Machine Gun fires Nen bullets.
Transforms hands into
machine guns that fire
Nen bullets.
Retool your fingers for an extra punch!
Next time: A x Brutal x Battlefield.
Out.
Out?
Outfield!
Infield!