[♪♪♪]
So who'd you bring home last year?
Sheila-- What was her name?
I didn't go home last year.
What about the year before?
Mm-mm.
I'm not the first girl
you ever brought home, right?
Jackson. Oh, God.
Oh, no.
This makes it worse.
[CHUCKLES]
You never told me
it was like this.
It's a farm. There's a mortgage.
It's no big deal.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, my God.
HELEN: Some little
farmhouse you got here.
Watch your step on the ice.
Yes, dear.
HELEN:
Man.
Oh.
Come on.
Don't be impressed.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
[GASPS THEN CHUCKLES]
Shh.
You'll wake her up. rm Sorry
She's put you in the guest room.
HELEN:
Bummer. Where are you?
JACKSON:
Across the hall.
Well, it's her house.
It's a Catholic thing.
Come on.
No way.
I'll sneak you back before she knows.
No.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CREAKS]
[CHUCKLES]
[MOANS]
An angel in the kitchen
and a devil in the bedroom.
Now that's what I like in a man.
[GAS PS]
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh.
Oh, I am sorry.
I thought you were
in the other room.
I am in the other room.
I just came in here this morning
to, uh, say hello.
Well, I guess I'd better hurry up
and be embarrassed.
I thought you were Jackson.
Yes, I could tell. Heh.
Please forgive me.
Oh, God, no. I just-- I...
[HELEN MUMBLES
INDISTINCTLY]
Well, hi, I'm, uh, Helen.
Heh, heh. Of course you are.
And I'm Martha Baring.
Welcome to Kilronan.
Thank you. Thanks. Oh, boy.
And where is that son of mine?
I don't know, but I'd like to find him.
Yeah, so would I.
Well, so much for
first impressions.
You go ahead
and enjoy his breakfast,
and I'll look forward to seeing
a lot less of you downstairs.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
[♪♪♪]
MARTHA:
We can walk a bit.
You show a lot of promise
for a city girl.
HELEN: Thank you.
You're a terrific liar.
MARTHA:
Ha. Well...
[HELEN CHUCKLES]
JACKSON:
Mom, the place looks great.
MARTHA: Only because it's covered
with snow. It's been hard this fall.
But I don't wanna talk
about anything depressing.
Let's talk about our week.
I made some plans.
I hope you don't mind.
Well, we're not
staying the week.
We can't.
Of course you can.
JACKSON: No, we have to leave
right after Christmas. I'm sorry.
But, darling--
Mom, we have to leave
on Wednesday.
Well, of course, I mean,
if you have to go, you have to go.
I just thought maybe--
Well, heh, never mind.
Oh, look at the time.
We have to get back for church.
Go on. Go after her.
She misses me.
Heh,heh,heh.
Go.
[CLICKING TONGUE]
[JACKSON SIGHS]
I think I made a better impression
with my clothes off.
You look great. You look
beautiful.
Sure.
I love this house, Jackson.
There's something about it.
I suppose.
Maybe it's you.
How me?
I don't know, you.
You know, where you come from.
Who you are.
The architecture of a life.
Pretentious?
Just a little.
[LAUGHS]
What?
HELEN:
Now?
[CHOIR SINGING
"O COME, ALL YE FAITHFUL"
OVER SPEAKERS]
Well, heh, look at you.
You're putting me to shame.
Do you think this is too much
for church?
I checked with Jackson, but--
No, no. Not at all.
I envy your confidence.
Are you sure? I'm-- Actually, I
did bring another one, but--
No, I just worry you'll get cold
in that freezing old church. Ha.
Here.
Thanks.
Oh.
Oh, it's broken.
It's just-- It's an old catch.
Oh, I'll have it fixed.
Who are these people?
Are they your parents?
Yes.
And where are they
this Christmas?
Um...
They died a long time ago.
Oh. I am sorry, I didn't know.
Okay, you can stop
talking about me.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Let's go.
Oh. After you.
No, go ahead.
Please, go on.
Let's go.
[WHISPERING]
Nice scarf.
[ORGAN PLAYING]
MAN:
And the angel came to her and said:
"Hail, blessed one,
the Lord is with thee.
And you will conceive in your womb
and bear a son.
And the Lord God will give him
the throne of his father David,
and he shall reign
in the house forever.
And of his kingdom
there shall be no end."
ALL:
Amen.
PRIEST: Merry Christmas to you.
You're looking well.
Merry Christmas.
Thanks, Father.
Ah, the prodigal returns.
Welcome back, Jackson.
Thank you.
Baring and Son
finally back in business.
You've made your mother
a very happy woman.
Nonsense, Madge, I've been happy
since the day he was born.
PRIEST:
Merry Christmas to you.
Mom?
Does everyone think I'm moving in,
or is Madge just a trial balloon?
MARTHA: Let's see, with the flyers I
sent out and the ad in the paper...
Heh. I didn't really tell her that,
I guess my hopes were showing.
I know you want me to come back
but my work's in New York.
You never speak about that job
as if you loved it.
JACKSON:
Helen's in New York.
MARTHA: Now, that's mighty
inconsiderate of you,young lady.
Steal away my baby boy.
Heh. Well, now,
why can't you just be sensible?
Leave your life and your work
and your friends
and move in here
with a controlling old woman.
Learn how to bake bread
and shovel horse shit.
You're not that old.
[LAUGHING]
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
Let's not let Madge
spoil our Christmas.
Good night.
Night.
[♪♪♪]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[MUSIC PLAYING
ON MUSIC BOX]
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[GAS PS]
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
[♪♪♪]
HELEN:
Hello.
I'm sorry to disturb you there.
I think I'm lost.
I'm looking for Kilronan.
Oh, back that-a-ways.
Follow the tar road. Second left.
Second left, okay. Thank you.
You can tell Mrs. Baring
I'll bring the birds by later on.
HELEN:
Okay.
MAN:
Merry Christmas.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
HELEN:
Hi, baby.
Where have you been?
Please, I got so lost.
I'll tell you about it later.
You cleaned up?
I'm shocked.
No. It must have been my mother.
Old habits die hard.
She does all this
with no help?
The help never stays. She doesn't
give them anything to do.
By the way, I caved in. We're staying
for the New Year's Eve party.
ALL:
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six, five,
four, three, two, one.
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year.
[PEOPLE SINGING
"AULD LANG SYNE"]
Still love me?
Oh.
I'll love you, dear, I'll love you
Till China and Africa meet
And the river jumps
Over the mountain
BOTH".
And the salmon sing in the street
[LAUGHS]
Thank you.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
And there he was, he was
standing right beside her.
MARTHA: Did you have a good time?
HELEN: It was a great party.
I'd say it was a triumph.
Short lived, maybe,
but never mind.
Here's to you, my darlings.
Good night.
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
Happy New Year.
[CUP CLANGS]
HELEN: What are you--?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Jackson.
You're right. You do make a better
impression with your clothes off.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[BOTH MOANING]
HELEN: What are you--?
Oh, God! Ha-ha-ha.
JACKSON:
Shh.
[HELEN AND JACKSON MOANING]
[JACKSON CHUCKLES]
MARTHA:
All ready?
Think so.
Well...
Oh. I almost forgot.
I had it fixed.
Oh, my God.
You shouldn't have.
It's perfect.
[CHUCKLES]
Well...
[DOOR CLOSES]
Oh.
Oh. Just look at us.
I've gone and set you off.
I'm sorry, I'm just, ahem,
not so good with goodbyes.
Well, you go on, then.
Just go on.
Bye, Mom.
[♪♪♪]
Bye,baby.
Now, you take care out there.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
Last flight.
Ha-ha-ha.
[SWITCH CLICKS]
I know, I know. I haven't
fixed it yet, but I will.
You're so punished. No sex.
JACKSON:
Not again.
[SIGHS]
Oh, Well.
Be it ever so humble.
JACKSON:
Home, sweet home.
WOMAN:
So how was the vacation, huh?
HELEN: His mom was great.
He was a little bit weird.
WOMAN: They're always different
around their mothers.
HELEN: Really?
Excuse me.
The way I see it,
it's all about the breasts.
Within one mile of us, 100 men talking
to their shrinks about their mothers.
And women are talking to their
shrinks about their mothers-in-law.
Which are probably responsible
for over half the divorces, like mine.
You think I'm joking,
but just wait, you'll see.
HELEN: Now, wait, you marry the guy.
The mother is his problem.
God, I've heard
that one before.
HELEN: We've projected to complete
that phase within 16 months.
Now, this new Triple-E glass
is non-reflective,
which will make
the neighbors happy,
minimalizing the wrong kind
of visual impact,
and "optimalizing,"
heh,heh,heh, if that's a word,
energy conservation
for both heating
and cooling.
Ahem. The 60 percent glass--
[HELEN VOMITS THEN COUGHS]
[ALL MURMURING]
Oh.
MAN:
Maybe we should try...
[SIGHS]
[HELEN GROANS]
[♪♪♪]
You're home early.
You Okay?
HELEN:
I don't know.
What do you mean?
I'm pregnant.
Okay, now, this is where you're
supposed to go, "Are you sure?"
It seems that
my diaphragm is broken.
[HELEN SIGHS]
Marry me.
Oh, Jackson.
I think I lost my job today too.
I barfed on Gavin.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[SIGHS]
Look, you said there was
no other reason to get married
unless you were pregnant.
You're pregnant. It's settled.
I love you.
Marry me.
Hm?
Is that a yes?
Yeah?
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[PHONE RINGING]
MARTHA: Kilronan.
JACKSON: Are you sitting down?
Wait a minute.
Don't tell her I'm pregnant.
MARTHA".
What is it? Tell me.
Helen and I are getting married.
She's pregnant, isn't she?
JACKSON:
How'd you guess?
[LAUGHS]
Mothers know these things.
Where is she, is she there?
Hi, Martha.
MARTHA: Congratulations.
Isn't this the best news ever?
A baby.
And a wedding too,
I suppose.
When will it be? Well, we'd
better hurry, hadn't we?
We could have it here at Kilronan.
What do you think?
We were thinking something more
like city hall. Something like that.
We were?
[PACHELBEL'S
"CANON IN D" PLAYS]
PRIEST: May the Lord bless these
rings and those who wear them
as a sign of your fidelity and love.
What God hath joined together
let no man put asunder.
By the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
WOMAN 1:
You look lovely, Helen.
MAN 1: Good luck, Helen.
Hi.
Hi there.
You look great.
HELEN: Thank you.
Hi. Congratulations.
Thanks.
Hi.
Hey.
HELEN:Hey
Hey, Helen.
How you holding up?
[SIGHS]
I'm dying.
You're a beautiful bride.
WOMAN 2:
Helen.
Who's that?
Huh? I don't know.
Hang on.
Okay.
MAN 2:
She looks great, doesn't she?
What?
She got him back.
Who?
Your new mother-in-law.
You never showed for our lunch.
We were supposed to have lunch?
Whenever you could come visit with
me at the home for the near dead.
But your new mother-in-law said
you had bigger fish to fry.
Alice Baring.
I'm Jackson's grandmother.
Oh, my gosh. I'm sorry.
Hello. She never told me
we were supposed to have lunch.
She wouldn't, would she?
That's why you have to be
so careful of Martha.
I'm used to her folderol.
That's why I invited myself.
I'm the only one left
on his father's side.
Let's see the handcuff.
Looks familiar.
It belonged to Jackson's mother.
It's a family heirloom.
I know, I gave it to her.
Of course,
that was before I knew her better.
When are you due?
How did you know that?
Well, you can't be stupid
and breed horses.
Takes a lot of know-how
and control.
One man to help the stallion,
one to help the mare,
one to hold the tail,
and one to finesse the situation.
Now, Martha,
she can manage all that by herself.
Alice, what a surprise. I just
didn't think you could make it.
Yes, wasn't it lucky?
Two weeks of chasing every catering
truck in the county and I hit pay dirt.
Why don't you come with me?
Darling, they want a picture
of the happy couple.
Okay.
Take your damn hands off me.
MARTHA: Oh, Alice.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
Goddamn it, Jackson. God.
[KEYS THUD]
[GROANS]
[HELEN SCREAMS]
Shh.
[PANTING]
[GRUNTS]
[WHIMPERING]
One word
and I'll slice you wide open.
You got that, my pretty lady?
God, please don't hurt me.
BURGLAR:
My very pretty lady.
Please. Please. I'm pregnant.
[PANTING]
[IN SINGSONG VOICE]
I know where you live.
Don't you forget that.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
[sesame]
[♪♪♪]
[CHATTERING]
DOCTOR:
That was a very close call.
[SIGHS]
Pretty smart
telling him you were pregnant.
Most men run
when they hear that.
That's a bad joke. Bad joke.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Look, you take care
and get some rest, okay?
Okay.
Okay. Good night, Jackson.
I can't get his voice out of my head.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, my God. I can't go.
Look.
And I changed the locks.
JACKSON:
You okay?
HELEN: Mm.
JACKSON: You sure?
Mm-mm.
You're gonna be all right.
I'm fine.
MARTHA:
Surprise!
[GAS PS]
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
How did you get in here?
I didn't mean to frighten you.
HELEN: How did you get in here?
The super let me in.
Hello, darling.
HELEN: Hi.
Aw. Hi. Good to see you.
HELEN:
My heart.
MARTHA:
You're sure you're all right, darling?
Yes?
He took my locket.
Oh, no.
With the picture of your parents?
Oh, darling, I'm so sorry.
[♪♪♪]
Mom?
The land alone
is worth more than this.
Jackson, it's a developer.
You know, golf course and houses.
They're gonna have to tear out
all the barns, the paddocks,
turn the pastures into fairways.
Kilronan Country Club and Estates.
Can you imagine?
Huh. Tsk.
Two years ago, we were offered
three times this much.
Two years ago,
it was a going concern,
the oldest horse farm
in the county.
Where are you gonna go?
Well, I don't know.
I've never been anywhere else.
[♪♪♪]
Look,Jackson,
I can't run that place
all by myself anymore.
And if you can't help,
then you've got to let me sell it.
I'm gonna get the coffee.
If she really wants to sell it,
why does she need your permission?
Because it's mine. All of it.
It was left to me, not to Martha.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
Honey?
JACKSON: Yeah?
How long do you think it would take
to fix up Kilronan?
JACKSON:
Oh, I don't know.
The stables need renovating,
the stock's down to nothing.
Could make a good run in a year.
Make it attractive to a buyer?
Yeah, I could run
some projections for her.
Why don't we do it?
JACKSON: Okay, I will. First
thing tomorrow morning.
No, I mean-- Heh.
I mean, why don't we do it?
The whole thing.
What do you mean?
Honey, I think that this
could be a great opportunity.
You could do the horses,
I could do the house--
Talking a lot of money.
It's two mortgages.
But we could take out a loan.
With you down there, they'd fall all
over themselves giving you money.
What do you think?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
[SIGHS]
You never know, maybe we'd fall in
love with the place and wanna stay.
What about my morn?
What about your mom?
I like her.
What about the baby?
Oh, my God.
What was I thinking?
Deprive my child of the wholesome
environment and family values
of a New York City childhood.
The dirt, the noise.
Who could want more?
Let's talk.
I need to tell you something.
Okay.
JACKSON:
You know my father died.
What you don't know
is that it was my fault.
When he fell?
When he fell.
But, honey, you were 7 years old.
I was hiding under the stairs.
See, my parents were arguing.
They were fighting about this
woman my father was seeing,
this Robin Hayes,
he was leaving us to be with her.
My morn stormed out and I thought
my father was going after her,
so I charged in like I was
gonna save her or something.
I went straight into him.
He stumbled back
and lost his balance.
The doors were open
to the basement stairs.
And he went down.
[♪♪♪]
I started screaming
for my mom.
It seemed like forever
before she-- She heard me.
She'd been pulling the boards off this
old shed to make room for my kittens.
She came in and
she had this look on her face,
and she was still holding
this nail puller in one hand
and this tool basket in the other.
She dropped them
and they made this loud sound.
And then she hugged me tight.
And she told you
that it was just an accident.
She did.
Oh, baby.
You know,
I hated him for the affair,
the way he hurt her.
But I still...
Love him.
You've been living with
all these ghosts for so long.
You should go home.
We should.
Face all those ghosts.
Live in the home
that you loved.
With your mother.
And me.
And our daughter.
And our daughter?
Is there something
you're not telling me?
I guess my hopes are showing.
Runs in the family.
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Congratulations, Mr. Baring.
Thank you very much.
Now you've done it.
Whoo!
[CHATTERING]
Whatever you think is best.
Congratulations.
He's beautiful.
MARTHA". Dear God, thank you for
bringing my family home at last.
[CHATTERING]
[LAUGHING]
What happened to you?
Don't ask.
[LAUGHS]
Here.
Oh, God.
Honey, how do you really think
Helen is doing?
What do you mean?
Well, I don't know.
She just seems so delicate
and fragile. I worry about her.
Why?
I mean,
every woman is different, but...
Hell, I don't know how to say this.
[GAS PS]
But, you know,
sometimes during a pregnancy--
Turn around, hon.
Look-- Oh, God. Heh, heh.
I'll just say it.
Sometimes during a pregnancy,
making love
can be uncomfortable.
Physically. Emotionally too.
Did she say something to you?
I don't-- I just think maybe,
you know, you could keep your
distance a little. Know what I mean?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Mom, you mind
your own business.
Hey. Come here.
Aah! No!
Where are you?
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMS]
Aah!
Ugh. Oh, my God.
[WOOD CREAKING]
[SCREAMING]
[CROWBAR CLATTERS]
[DOOR OPENS]
MARTHA:
Are you all right?
Mm-hm.
Brought you some tea.
It's herbal. Lemon verbena.
Very relaxing.
It's almost like a drug.
I'm surprised it's legal. Here.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Oh, you gave us quite a scare.
Oh, my God,
there were so many of them.
It's the poison. They go
up into the rafters to die.
It makes them bleed to death.
It's painless,
but, heh, it does leave
a lot of bodies around.
God.
Well,
it's over now. You just relax.
I feel so strange. I don't
know what's wrong with me.
Oh, Helen, it's all right.
I know exactly how you feel.
Your muscles ache
and your skin is so sensitive,
and your mind, ha-ha,
it just goes haywire,
doesn't it? Heh.
Yeah.
Mm.
[SIGHS]
Oh, Helen.
You are a lovely,
lovely young woman.
And you just remember that.
No matter what Jackson
may say or do.
[♪♪♪]
You know, men can act strange
during a pregnancy.
Sexually, I mean.
My husband was devoted to me.
But while I was carrying Jackson...
I think we'll be fine.
I just think we need some time
to ourselves.
Of course.
And you will see Dr. Hill tomorrow.
Oh, Martha, please.
You know I don't want an amnio.
Helen,
Jackson was not
my first pregnancy.
You had a miscarriage?
No. We discovered
some abnormalities.
[SCOFFS]
It was the right thing to do.
But she would have been
just about your age now.
But I had to terminate
that pregnancy.
What abnormalities?
Well, never mind. You just go see Dr.
Hill. It's important.
Good night, darling.
Good night.
Would you send Jackson up,
please?
[♪♪♪]
How is she?
Oh, she's fine.
She just needs
a little time alone.
What's going on with her?
Oh, honey.
You just have to be patient.
Come on.
I'm gonna buy you a drink.
[SIGHS]
Ooh. Heh.
It seems like your husband
is the only one
getting any sleep
around here tonight.
[CHUCKLES]
I tried to wake him,
but he's out cold.
Farm work will do that to you.
It's more than that.
Oh, honey.
Now, you two aren't having
any problems, are you?
I don't know.
He's been different
since we've been down here.
I don't think he's ever gotten
over his father.
He's not the only one.
But then, Jackson and I have always
had each other to lean on, thank God.
Well, I don't have to tell you what
it's like to lose someone you love.
Well, I was very young, but I know.
Here's to accidents.
Fuck them.
[CHUCKLES]
Amen.
MAN 1: Turn this way, please.
MAN 2: Right here, folks.
[BOTH LAUGH]
MAN 3: One more.
Thank you.
[BUGLE PLAYING]
Good luck today, son.
He'll bring over 500,000
in stud fees alone.
Are you kidding?
Breeding is everything, my dear.
Speaking of which, Martha says
you've been very weak.
How are you doing?
Martha said what?
None of us want you
to lose that baby.
Oh, look, there's old Alice. I didn't
think she got out much anymore.
[LAUGHS]
MARTHA: Helen. Helen, darling.
Come join us.
I don't want you to feel left out.
Alice is here.
Really? I don't see anyone.
I'm gonna go say hello.
No, I forbid it. Ha-ha.
Excuse me?
It's just...
She's just a crazy old woman.
I don't think she deserves your
attention, darling. That's all.
Well, I don't think I've been forbidden
to do anything since I was 5 years old.
[♪♪♪]
Helen!
[NEIGHING]
MAN 1: Stand back.
MAN 2: Easy. Whoa.
MAN 1: Watch it.
MAN 2: Whoa!
Easy. That's okay.
Easy, now. Easy.
JACKSON:
What happened?
Are you all right?
HELEN: Yes.
MARTHA:
Oh, you gave me such a scare.
Why did you yell?
Young lady,
I have to have you leave this area.
God.
JACKSON:
Mom, what the hell happened?
MARTHA: Well, she walked right
in front of the horse, Jackson.
You all right?
I'm fine.
[SIGHS]
HELEN:
Oh, my God. I can't look.
Is it near the baby?
No, it's at the other end.
Now that I have your attention, there's
just one thing I wanna mention.
What's this I hear about you
wanting to have the baby at home?
What? I never said that.
HILL: It's a romantic idea,
Helen, but too much can go wrong.
Besides,
I can't have you young mothers
cutting into my income,
now can I, huh? Ha-ha-ha.
Dr. Hill, who told you that I wanted
to have the baby at home?
[♪♪♪]
Of course it was her.
Helen--
This is so invasive.
Let me ask you a question.
Is this my baby or is it hers?
She's lived here all her life,
she knows him socially.
All right, she knows him. Fine.
Why is she telling him
things that I didn't say?
She's just trying to be helpful.
Don't humor me, please.
Look, give her a break, for christ sakes.
It's for your own good.
Isn't it?
Yes, it's for my own good.
She's right and I'm always wrong.
Thank you.
ALICE:
What took you so long?
Go on, spit it out.
You didn't come here for the food.
[HELEN LAUGHS]
[SIGHS]
Can I ask you a question?
Please, please do.
At the wedding, you told me that
I had to be careful of Martha.
What did you mean by that?
You mustn't pay attention
to anything comes out of my mouth.
I'm incompetent.
Didn't she say that? Ha-ha.
And incontinent.
Sort of unreliable at both ends.
Here, girls.
I feed them the whole pharmacy.
Heartburn, ulcers, blood pressure.
They're immune to everything now.
The oldest living Confederates
in America.
There you are, girls.
Here's the thing.
I don't have anybody here to talk to.
I'm kind of busy now,
but I believe I could fit you in.
Come, let's sit over there.
All right.
Ever since
we moved back here,
Jackson is becoming more and
more, I don't know, distant.
Distant from you, closer to her.
Well, I think that--
You think you're losing
him to Martha.
That's what you think,
and you'd be right.
Why don't you say what you mean,
damn it?
Maybe I'm just being paranoid.
She was a stable girl.
She was?
Shoveling horseshit.
Not that I hold that against her.
No, no.
Mind, I admire her ambition.
She got herself pregnant.
She got herself a husband and son.
And a fine family name.
And now she's breeding herself
a grandson, isn't she?
[♪♪♪]
She never loved my son, Jack.
All she ever wanted was that baby.
After she had it,
she put my son out to pasture.
And she took Jackson and poisoned
his mind against his father.
And me.
She'll do the same to you.
[SIGHS]
I think she already has.
She made a beautiful widow,
Martha did.
So much more attractive
than a divorced woman.
Was Jack gonna leave Martha?
Nobody leaves Martha.
Believe me when I tell you that.
You bring Jackson to visit me,
and I'll tell him the truth
about his father.
I'm his blood.
And I love him.
You tell him that.
Hello, Dr. Hill,
this is Jackson Baring.
I know this may sound a little
strange, but have you seen Helen?
Yeah--
Where have you been?
We've been so worried.
Am I not allowed
to leave the property?
She just appeared, Dr. Hill.
Well, of course, darling.
It's just that I wish you'd tell us
when you were going somewhere
so we'd know where you are.
JACKSON: Bye now.
Good night, Martha.
[CHUCKLES]
Good night, dear.
HELEN: Honey, she's your
grandmother, she wants to see you.
Just come with me.
JACKSON:
Can we just go to sleep?
We'll talk about it in the morning.
HELEN: Okay.
[♪♪♪]
Mrs. Baring.
We haven't seen you for a while.
Alice will be so pleased.
Where is she?
She's still having a steam treatment.
You know Alice, always the last one.
Yes.
Go on in.
[ALICE SINGING
"OH, SUSAN NAH"]
Oh, Martha.
What a surprise.
Why don't you go to my room
and I'll be right with you.
Who pays your bills here, Alice?
Why, you do,
with the money Jack left you.
Is it cheap here?
I don't know. Cheap is something
you'd know more about than I would.
Is it cheap here?
I suppose not.
Heh.
Well, you suppose right.
And what is the only thing
I have ever asked of you in return?
What is it?
That you stay away
from my family.
That's all you have to do.
Oh, now, is that so much
for a mother to ask?
What did you tell her?
What dirty little lies
did you tell her, Alice?
Answer me.
[WATER DRAINING]
I am. You just can't see my finger.
[LAUGHS]
[GAS PS]
Oh.
Tsk.
Isn't time a terrible thing, Alice?
[♪♪♪]
Tick-took. Tick-took.
And look what happens.
Oh.
Are you gonna behave, Alice?
There's something
I've wanted to tell you,
ever since the first day
you came here.
You always smell of horseshit,
Martha.
Damn you, Martha.
Damn you.
Now, you stay away from my boy.
You understand?
[GASPING]
Well, I'll take that as a--
--Yes.
Goodbye, Alice.
MARTHA:
Oh, Sister.
She wants a little more time.
She says it helps her joints.
She's incorrigible.
I'll give her five more minutes.
Make it 10.
Come on.
[♪♪♪]
HELEN:
We can't go on like this.
Like what?
Look, I don't know
what has been going on between
you and me and your mother.
And I'm trying to be respectful of that,
but it's been very difficult, and you...
[SIGHS]
I just...
I love you.
I really love you, and we need
to be supportive of each other.
I understand that she's your mother,
but soon I'm gonna be a mother.
And I need you.
MARTHA:
I'm not sure I understand.
At this fee, with
a modest number of bookings,
we should get a positive cash-flow
increase sooner than we expected.
You mean we're ready to sell?
Mom, look...
I can see Helen's not happy here.
I wanna take her back to New York.
[CHUCKLES]
I'm not blaming you.
I'm not blaming anyone.
I love her. She's my wife.
I want her to be happy.
Things have been tense
between Helen and me.
But I want you to know
that it's been all my fault.
It's hard for two women
to share the same household.
I can see that my ways bother her
and I'm truly sorry about that.
But one thing
I do know that we both want
is that horse to win this weekend.
Helen and I will be packing.
And everything will be ready
for my little grandson.
Grandson, huh?
Listen, darling.
Your first responsibility is to her.
She's a wonderful, wonderful girl,
and I love her.
[♪♪♪]
What?
[LAUGHS]
Oh, are you surprised your old
mother can be a human being?
Well, yeah.
[LAUGHS]
But the truth?
I'm sorry to leave.
Don't be.
That wife of yours needs to go
where she belongs.
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Dr. Hill.
MARTHA:
Franklin?
Martha.
MARTHA: Do you know I was
just thinking about you?
HILL: Oh, no, were you?
MARTHA: Yes, I was.
HILL:
That's nice.
I know this is not
strictly by the books,
but do you think I could
talk to you about Helen?
What's the matter with her?
This girl is so filled with anxieties,
I don't know what to do.
It probably has something
to do with
all those books on pregnancy
she's reading.
Well, that'll do it.
She has got it in her mind
that first babies are always late.
I don't know what to tell her.
If she's a week or two late,
it's no problem.
Just tell her we can induce
right here, if she likes.
Oxytocin brings on contractions,
pfft, within 24 hours.
That's the same thing we use
for horses. Is that possible?
Yes, it is. Exactly the same.
Huh.
You tell her whatever it is,
we got the cure.
It's not like when you and I
had our babies, Martha.
Can you believe
I'm going to be a grandmother?
No, I can't.
[LAUGHS]
Yeah? Te" me.
Is it a boy or is it a girl?
You're gonna get me
into trouble, Martha.
I just wanna know what color for my
layette. You know I hate yellow.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
What color do you like?
Huh? Well,
blue was lucky for me
25 years ago.
Well, why don't you play
your hunch then?
[LAUGHS]
Bye, Martha.
Bye.
[♪♪♪]
JACKSON:
Come on, big boy, get in there.
MAN: Come on. Come on, boy, come on.
Tsk, tsk.
HELEN: Don't worry about me.
I'll just be here packing.
Sure you want me to go?
Yes, I want you to go,
and I want you to win,
and I want you to get your ass
back here as fast as you can.
It's more than three hours away and
you wanna get there before dinner.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[LAUGHS]
Come on, you lovebirds.
He's already in the van.
Goodbye, baby.
JACKSON: Bye.
MARTHA:
Good luck. Okay.
JACKSON: Now, you take care. Both of you.
I'll be back tomorrow night.
Bye.
[CHUCKLES]
Won't be long before this place
is everything it ever was.
Kilronan rises again.
It's kind of a shame, isn't it?
What is?
That we won't be here
to see it.
[♪♪♪]
Hey.
And the same "hey" to you, darling.
Oh. You're looking even lovelier.
[SIGHS]
I brought you something.
Kind of a head start
on baby pictures.
Oh.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, my-
This'll be a big hit around here.
These nuns love a fetus.
I came to say goodbye.
Hello and goodbye?
We're going back to New York.
Good for you.
You're well rid of that woman.
Why Jackson ever came back here
at all, I can't fathom.
That was my idea.
I just-- I thought he had to
come back and face all the ghosts.
He still blames himself
for his father's death.
No, he shouldn't. No.
His daddy fell on a farm tool
that was lying at the foot of the stairs.
[♪♪♪]
One of those things they use
to pull nails out of boards.
He landed on it just wrong
and it crushed his sternum.
It was in all the newspapers.
Doctors commenting, right and left.
A bizarre happening.
Jackson must accept that.
You better be careful
on your way out the door.
When Jack told her he was leaving,
she turned demonic.
I can see that.
She strikes me as the jealous type.
What possible reason could she
ever have to be jealous of Jack?
Well, didn't he ever tell you
about Robin Hayes?
Jack and Robin?
Walk me.
These old farts shock easily. Ha-ha.
What?
Oh, heh...
[CHUCKLES]
I was just remembering
when I had Jackson.
Oh.
I thought that pain was just
gonna rip me in half. Ha-ha.
Oh, no. Oh, how stupid I am.
Oh, honey...
Here.
Let me get you some dessert.
HELEN:
No, thank you. I'm really tired.
I'm gonna go upstairs.
But I made it especially
for you, Helen.
Come on, it's strawberries,
your very favorite.
Go on, take it.
Indulge yourself. Heh.
Go on. Take it. Heh.
You deserve it.
I think I'll just take it up to bed.
Yes. Heh. Go on. Heh-heh.
That baby needs all the rest
he can get.
Or she.
Yes, or she.
Good night, Martha.
Sweet dreams.
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Tender around that joint.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MARTHA: My God, I am heartily
sorry for having offended thee.
I detest my sins because I dread the
loss of heaven and the pains of hell,
but most of all,
because they offend thee, my God,
who sent me a daughter-in-law
from the land of the Moabites.
"And whither thou goest, I will go,"
she said.
"And your people shall be
my people."
And she went down
to the threshing floor,
and did exactly
as her mother-in-law instructed.
And she conceived a son.
And God said,
"He will be born and renew your life,
for he is born
of your daughter-in-law,
and is better than seven sons."
You understand, don't you?
This is all for him,
and the baby.
A precious baby who has no one,
no one to protect him from her.
Hey, are you kicking me again?
Is that nice, huh?
MARTHA: He is weak, my
son, I am his strength.
You hungry?
MARTHA:
And God said:
"Let the woman of emptiness
become full.
And you who are most worthy
shall take the child to your bosom
and become its mother.
And the women neighbors
will give him a name,
saying, 'A son is born to you."'
To you.
I firmly resolve,
with the help of thy grace,
to confess my sins, do penance,
and amend my life.
Amen.
[MOANS]
[GROANS]
Martha?
[GRUNTS THEN GASPS]
[HORSE NEIGHS IN DISTANCE]
HELEN:
Martha?
[MUSIC BOX PLAYING
IN DISTANCE]
[♪♪♪]
No,no,no.
MARTHA:
Helen.
[CHUCKLES]
You bad girl, you.
You found me out, didn't you? Heh.
I... I saw a light.
Well, there's just no stopping you,
is there? Heh.
Martha.
What is all of this?
What are you doing?
It was my surprise for you, honey.
Surprise? oh, Well.
I wanted to set it all up like this
for you to see,
and then I was gonna
ship it all up to you in New York.
[CHUCKLES]
But I just thought the presentation
would be so vivid.
[sesame]
I'm sorry.
It's all right, honey.
Really, it's all right.
Well, look, we can still
show it to Jackson. Heh.
Won't that be fun'?
Yes, yes.
Helen, are you all right?
Uh-- I'm just tired.
Well, come on, let me take you back
up to the house to bed. Come on.
What are you doing walking
around with no shoes on?
[PANTING]
[♪♪♪]
Wait.
[GROANS]
What is it?
Is it the baby?
HELEN:
Could I have some water?
We're almost to the house.
Now, come on.
No, I need-- I need some water.
[HELEN PANTING]
All right. All right, I'll be right back.
[♪♪♪]
Helen!
MAN:
Howdy.
What can I do you for today,
my pretty lady?
[GAS PS]
Pretty lady.
BURGLAR [IN SING-SONG VOICE]:
I know where you live.
Oh, my God.
Trying to be friendly, darling.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
Hey.
Goddamn!
[♪♪♪]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[♪♪♪]
[HORN HONKS]
[sesame]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
No.
What on earth are you doing?
You think you're some alley cat,
dropping your litter
by the side of the road?
[HELEN SCREAMING]
[HELEN SOBBING]
Oh, the pain is terrible, isn't it?
Darling, I can feel it myself.
I can feel what you're feeling.
Oh, my God, help me.
Oh. Oh, I wish I could.
Believe me,
I wish I could give you something,
but I can't.
You just have to go through it,
and feel it deeply.
[SCREAMING]
And then you will never, ever forget
what your child means to you.
[PANTING]
[♪♪♪]
I'm begging you.
[SCOFFS]
Well...
[SIGHS]
[BUGLE PLAYING FANFARE
OVER SPEAKERS]
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]: Contestants in the
Jefferson State Golden Horseshoe Pitch
will be gathering in the infield
for the $50,000 horseshoe pitch...
Hey. This is the big one, isn't it?
I put a couple C-notes on him myself.
Did you?
Hey, you know, I sent a buyer up
to Kilronan the other day
and Martha told him that you guys
had changed your minds.
She did?
[♪♪♪]
[sesame]
Now breathe. It's almost over.
Breathe, darling.
[PHONE RINGING]
It's okay. You're all right.
Breathe, Helen.
[PANTING]
[SCREAMS]
Hello?
Mother.
Jackson,
I was hoping it was you.
[PANTING AND GRUNTING]
Oh.
Well, of course everything's all right.
Good. Can I talk to her?
She's here.
You can talk to her in a minute.
JACKSON:
How's she doing?
MARTHA:
So how did the morning workout go?
HELEN:
Jackson!
JACKSON: Great. He's running the
best he's been. We're ready.
Did you draw your post position?
Yes.
Mom, look, the race is about
to begin, can I talk to Helen?
Oh, no. Jackson,
I'm losing you.
I'm so sorry, honey,
but I can't hear you anymore.
Jackson, can you hear me?
JACKSON: Mom?
[DIAL TONE HUMMING]
[sesame]
Let me go.
[LINE BEEPING]
Shit.
MARTHA:
There you go. You're doing good.
Come on, honey, push a little harder.
Push. Push, Helen, push!
I am pushing, you bitch! God.
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]:
They are at the post. The flag is up.
[BELL RINGS]
MARTHA:
One last time, now, push down.
Push, Helen. Push, push.
Come on, you can do it.
Give it to me. Come on, push.
Yes, I can see it. Keep pushing.
Oh, my God. Oh!
Yes, I see him coming.
Push, Helen.
[ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA]
Come on, go!
ANNOUNCER".
Across the line!
Yes. You've got him.
[♪♪♪]
Push, Helen.
Don't you quit now.
[GRUNTING]
Oh, my God.
It's a beautiful little boy. Oh. Ha.
He looks just like Jackson.
Sweet, sweet boy.
[♪♪♪]
What a beautiful boy.
Give him to me.
Mama's gonna get you
all cleaned up.
No, Martha, give me my baby.
Give me my baby.
MARTHA: I'll love you, dear
I'll love you
Till China and Africa meet
Till the river jumps
over the mountain
And the salmon sing in the street
Helen, you are losing
so much blood.
Look at the mess
you've made of my linens.
Oh.
I really wanted us to be
a family together, Helen.
Really, I did, but,
I don't know if that's
possible anymore, do you?
Oh, it's a pity.
But you were so weak
during your pregnancy.
Everybody knew that.
And you would insist on having
that baby right here at home.
But I did my best.
You know I did, Helen.
[SIGHS]
Of course, you won't remember it
that way, will you?
You'll tell them all sorts of things
about me, make up stories.
[♪♪♪]
You know, it's very dangerous
to take more than just a drop of this.
I want you to know
that Jackson and I
are gonna raise that baby
the way he deserves.
[TAPPING ARM]
Hey, I'm home.
You'd have been proud.
[GAS PS]
MARTHA:
No.
Mom?
Jackson, I'll be right there.
JACKSON:
Helen?
I've been calling and calling.
Hello.
It's a boy. You see, I knew.
Oh, he came so fast,
like a freight train.
I had no time to call anybody.
Oh, but your wife,
she was so brave and so strong.
Helen?
Shh.
She needs to sleep now, Jackson.
You have no idea what
she's been through today.
Jackson.
Don't you wanna hold your son?
Is she okay?
Helen's doing just great. Now,
come with me. I need your help.
We've gotta give this baby boy
his first bath.
She's fine.
She just needs to sleep.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
[♪♪♪]
[DOOR CREAKING]
[GAS PS]
Hey, Morn.
Oh, honey.
You can't get a good night's sleep
in this chair.
You go on off to bed
and I'll keep watch.
Thanks, Mom. Not a chance.
I wanna be here
when she wakes up.
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
No matter how many kinks
I get in my neck.
Your wife and baby are gonna
need you at full strength.
Believe me, you've got
a tough few months ahead of you.
Thanks for seeing her through this.
To bed now, young fella.
March.
I won't take no for an answer.
Shut up, Morn.
Quit while you're ahead.
Good night.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
JACKSON:
Hi, Mommy.
Wanna meet your little baby boy?
This is your mommy.
[BABY BABBLING]
How you feeling?
Okay.
Where's Martha?
I think she's asleep.
She said you really
went through it.
Thank God she was here.
Yeah.
Honey, can you do me a favor?
Ask her to make us
a little bit of breakfast.
You hungry? That's good.
Mm.
If you need anything,
I'll be downstairs.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[CHUCKLES]
Well, heh.
There you are, Daddy.
[LAUGHS]
Good morning.
JACKSON:
Hey, morning.
You been outside?
HELEN: Yeah, I was looking
for something in the barn.
Hey.
You ought to be in bed, young lady,
after what you've been through.
I feel wonderful, Martha,
I really do.
God, I slept so deeply. It's
like I was drugged or something.
Like 20 years passed
and I just don't remember a thing.
Oh, it has.
We just forgot to tell you.
HELEN:
Great.
What's in the bag?
Oh, it's just, um, this thing
I found in the barn.
[HELEN SNIFFING]
Mm.
Those eggs smell good.
What?
What yourself?
What's the mystery?
Oh, humor me, hon.
This is such a happy day,
I don't wanna bring everybody down.
Come on, baby. Heh.
Don't keep us all in suspense.
What's in the bag?
It's one of those things
that killed Jackson's daddy.
I had never seen one before.
[♪♪♪]
What are you talking about?
You know, I realized this morning
now that Jackson has a son
of his own,
he's gotta let go of all those
old ghosts so he can be free.
I just got obsessed
with finding one of these things
and burying it
so deep in the ground
that it can't ever harm anyone
in our family again.
[CHUCKLES]
I know that sounds hormonal, but--
There's no thing that killed my father.
He fell down the stairs.
Oh, but it wasn't the fall
that killed him.
I mean, your mama went downstairs after
you called her, just like you said.
And she found that he had fallen
on this thing in this freak way.
It was even in the newspapers.
He fell on something
at the bottom of the stairs?
[CHUCKLES]
Oh. Honey, I think Helen is right.
This is not the day that
we should be talking about this.
Yeah, he fell. He fell on this.
It's probably not the same one.
There must be lots of these
lying around a place like this.
What are you doing?
[SCOFFS]
Whatever do you mean?
That's how Jack died.
He fell with tragic,
almost inconceivable precision
on this thing,
and it crushed his sternum.
Just as surely as if someone
had smashed it into his body.
You were tearing boards
off that shed.
How could you remember that?
You were 7 years old.
You were scared to death.
I remember that you were holding
that thing when you hugged me.
When you dropped it,
it made this loud clanging sound.
Like this?
[CLANGS]
Why are you doing this?
You're trying to tear my family apart.
Just because you lost
your own parents.
Mom, she wasn't--
She's not fooling anybody
with that wide-eyed, innocent...
Do you know what she's implying?
Even if I did have one of those things
in my hands, that doesn't mean
there couldn't have been another
one at the bottom of the stairs.
You remember that day.
You remember the fall.
And that fall could have
killed anybody who--
Martha,
why, no one's implying
that you killed Jack.
My God, I mean, lots of wives have
affairs and don't kill their husbands
because he finds out
and is gonna leave.
My father was the one
having the affair.
Oh, no, no, you got that backwards.
Robin Hayes was a horse wrangler.
Martha was having an affair
with him.
Alice told you that, didn't she?
That's just the kind of twisted lie
Alice would invent
and your wife would try to
perpetuate to turn you against me.
Don't you see what she's doing,
Jackson?
--1841. I just talked to Robin Hayes
half an hour ago.
He's expecting a call.
Would you like to speak to him
for old time's sake?
No!
Robin Hayes died last year
of a heart attack.
There's one you didn't cause.
You just couldn't bear to let
a happy family be, could you?
We were so close to being happy,
Jackson.
We were so close to being happy.
Here's how close we were.
Your mother tried to kill me last night.
That's a lie.
Nobody leaves Martha.
Don't you see?
Your father was leaving,
that's why she killed him.
And what's worse, she made you,
her own child, think that he did it,
so she could bind you to her
for the rest of your life.
No! I want you to throw
this lying bitch out of my house!
Yeah, there's only room
for one of those.
You'll never prove anything.
She doesn't have to.
Oh, but, Jackson.
Jackson, you can't--
Shut up!
Everything about you is a lie.
This place and everything in it
will be sold.
You will never see me
or any member of my family again.
But I did it all for you.
You are not my mother.
No!
No.
You did this.
You tricked him. You trapped him.
You got yourself pregnant.
I know what you're after.
You want my farm,
my land, my boy.
You wanna take everything I have
and leave me with nothing.
Don't you see what she's doing?
She wants to be me. Heh.
[LAUGHS]
[GRUNTS]
So long, Martha.
No.
[♪♪♪]
[MARTHA SOBBING]
Grandma.
[♪♪♪]