Jump! Come on, red team. The same again. The whole team up!
And then the ball is in! Well! Good work!
We got a call about a possible homicide in Ekbackens sports.
2610 and 9220 taking fences and witnesses. Switch.
9220th It is understood.
Joona Linna, Rikskrim. Where should I go?
If you stick along the blue line is in order.
- Do we know who he is? - Yes. His name is Anders Ek.
47 years. He was obviously gym teacher here.
We've found more damage after a sharp weapon.
A knife or something similar.
Joona I get a call. It is not for us. Go home.
- Has his family been notified? - Yes, of officers. Go home and sleep.
I'm coming.
Good. Continuous progress report. End.
9022 here. We are murder victim Donald Ex house.
Send an ambulance and reinforcement. Insk_rsv_gen fifth It is urgent.
Got it. The ambulance is about 5-10 minutes. Switch.
- Did you alert? - Yes.
Joona Linna, Rikskrim. I was nearby. Is it here?
Are you okay? What is it that has happened?
I saw that there was something that did not vote ... It is quite sick.
The ambulance is on the way.
I go out and meet them.
What the hell ...?!
Knife Stabbed, unconscious, breathing, low blood pressure: 60
High pulse, no heartbeat on the left side.
- Who are you? - Joona Linna, police.
Wait here.
So, I'm ready for intubation. Connect Ringer's acetate.
Take BAS test and determine blood type.
Hi, Joseph. I'll light your eyes. It is not dangerous.
- We continue treatment. - Absolutely.
- You have to wait. - How is his condition?
- Serious. He is doing might not. - I must speak with him.
- He can not talk. - Let me try, will not you?
His entire family has been killed. Mother, father, sister.
Impossible. The boy can not communicate.
You can buy snacks if you want to wait. I'll take care of a patient.
Hey, Magdalena. I'm sorry to call so late, but it's crisis.
Yes, there is a witness. A boy, but he can not be heard ...
I do not even know if he survives.
In the end, we have technical evidence, but no witnesses.
Find out what you can and come. Okay?
- Maybe there's a way. - Moment. I have to finish. Yes?
Maybe there's a way.
Erik?
Erik. It rings.
Eric!
- I can talk to him. - Okay.
- Reply now. - Erik Maria Bark.
This is Deputy Police Inspector Joona Linna. I'm calling from Danderyd hospital.
- What is it about? - A badly injured patient.
- Who is the doctor on duty? - Daniella Richards.
Why ... why call her? One moment. We do like this ...
- I enter. - Okay. Great. Thank you.
Tell that to her.
- Who was that? - The ... A policeman.
- Policeman? - Deputy Police Commissioner of the EU.
What happened?
A boy who ... they wanted me to look at. A wounded boy.
I'm going in there. Damn!
I come afterwards.
Erik?
You forgot your phone.
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
Go back to bed.
- I'm sorry, honey. - What the hell are you doing?
Yeah, what the hell are we doing?
- Come to me, if anything. - And pain relief is the same?
- Hello. - Hello.
Thank you for coming.
Here's Joona Linna from the police.
- Well, you could make it. Coffee? - No thanks.
- Was it you who called? - Yes. So you're a specialist in. ..
Akuttrauma. Erik is the best in the area.
I had a patient that I should look at.
Come on.
It's okay. He is also a doctor.
Sorry.
- What's his name? - Joseph.
Joseph? My name is Erik.
If you feel my hand, then press it.
My rating is the same as Daniellas. There is no contact.
You said that there is ... other methods.
What other methods, Joona? What other methods?
Hypnosis.
He asked if there was any method.
- You know that I can not. Not? - Yes.
Erik?
Eric! Erik, wait!
- Hello, Magdalena. - Hello.
They stood in registered. The father was a compulsive gambler.
I give it to the Stockholm police.
They can look at his father's entourage.
- Who leads the feasibility study? - No idea.
I do not think it is an internal showdown.
They will kill a whole family, and our only witness can not communicate.
- There is also an older daughter. - What?
The social services were involved, when she was a teenager. She came into care.
- Has she got protection? - I think not.
I do not even have an address for her.
Wait, Erik! Wait!
Erik? Erik!
There's a sister. The family has a daughter.
Someone is out to get her and the boy probably know who it is.
- I can not help you. - Yes.
I know that you can get in touch with him.
- You can not. - Yes, it can. You can.
It does not work as you think. You reach only into his truth.
His own, subjective memories. There is a risk that I affect him.
He's a heck ability to get people to remember.
A little too well, was there anyone who did.
Can you feel my hand?
You can hear me.
There is absolutely nothing to be afraid of.
We can stop whenever you want.
You lie on a rock. It is quite warm.
You are looking at the clouds.
I sit in front of you.
I'm with you all the time.
We jump into the water.
We dive.
Now I count down from five -
- and for every number we sink deeper.
And feel a greater and greater peace.
Five ...
... four ...
... three ...
... two ...
... a.
Now we're at home.
What's going on?
sofa ...
sofa.
I'm sitting on the couch.
What happens on the sofa?
I read the letter.
What is this letter?
This is my letter.
Are you alone?
Lisa sitting next to me. The knocking on the door.
What do you do?
Joseph. Joseph, listen to me. It's alright.
I count up to five, and five wake you. One, two, three -
- four, five.
Quiet.
We must continue.
The boy must be constantly monitored.
- It's arranged. - And the sea ... Sorry.
- Hello? - We need to find the sister.
Did you take sleeping pills?
No.
I promised not to.
I know that you save them in aftershave bin. You have taken four.
I'm sorry.
Why do you keep?
- To be able to sleep. - Sofa from what?
Say what you will, but I think it's about gambling debts.
Hell, no. I think it is a planned series of murders.
You'll make it, so you can take action.
I was there, Carlos. I saw both crime scenes, right?
There was one that would kill the whole family. Planned, organized -
- and almost complete. The man in the sports hall was killed first.
First the man, then on to the town house, where he continued the family.
He managed almost. And there is one who tries to destroy the whole family -
- so he finds his daughter. Maybe it happened. Or the boy.
It is urgent. I know it's Christmas time, but we must take hold of this.
Stockholm police will even take care of it here.
They can go on with playing the debt, but let me examine the other track.
The man was killed first. The needle will agree with me when the autopsy is complete.
Yes, yes.
Okay. Until we have clarified the order, you must do as you will.
- So I start. Will I Magdalena? - Now you surprise me.
- Okay, but no more. - Fine.
I'm running Benjamin in school.
What happened to the bus?
I'll take him. I must nevertheless the road. Why?
Good.
I'll see you later.
Goodbye ...
Come on, Benjamin!
Why fight you and mom so much?
- Do you think we do it? - Yes.
We have to stop. That's not good.
- You're still single, what? - Yes, why?
As soon as I call, you of course. At any time of day.
- Every day, always. - But only when you call.
You were right. The man in the sports hall died first.
- Are you sending the report ...? - I have spoken with Carlos.
- I should say hello. The case is yours. - Thank you.
Well, see here. To push such a broad leaf through bone and muscle tissue -
- is difficult, even for a muscle mountain, but these connectors are not deep.
- And? - It's one that had to strain.
- What was the cop who called? - What?
- The policeman who called last night. - I can not remember.
What was his name? I do not know. Why?
- That you bother. - What?
- That you bother to go on. - What is it now?
A policeman rang, I ran into the hospital, there was a wounded boy.
Okay.
It says Daniella on display. Do you know that?
- Do you think it was Daniella? - It is of course on the display.
- He called from her phone. - Okay. Good.
Call. Here. Okay, he was calling from her phone. Talk.
- No. - Ask yourself.
I will not talk to him. Hold up. It does not matter.
- That means a lot. - I believe in you.
There's nothing with Daniella. That was two years ago. Let it go, move on.
She works at the hospital and I was there.
Okay. Okay.
This one sister can not just have disappeared. Or what?
Magdalena? Evelyn must have a phone that can be traced, a workplace -
- or a student. Friends who know her.
- Where is she last seen? - No traces. Not yet.
It's as if she does not want to be found.
Okay.
During the night knock on the door, and Joseph go out and shut up.
That we assume. Blow on, he said that under hypnosis. We are not in court.
A person puts the whole family down and walks away.
- And we have no DNA traces. - Technicians certain blood.
sister, mother and Joseph's home and the father of basketball hall.
No other DNA traces, no fingerprints, nothing.
Wait a minute ... Joseph said that he had read a letter.
- Is there found something like that? - I think not.
You can just hold for today. I have to do something.
See if your child can still recognize you.
- Police! - Police! Add the weapon!
- Lie down! - I lie down.
- I'm colleague ... - Look left!
I'm a cop. My id is located in the left pocket. Relax.
Joona Linna. Rikskrim? What the hell are you doing here?
What is it?
Who has packed it away? It's a mess.
- We had so fine ... - What?
I do not know how ... They are gone. You have packed it so sloppy together ...
- I've packed it sloppy? - Yes.
- It was me who packed all together? - Yes. It was indeed.
- Shut up. - It was indeed.
Let it now endangered. I said I was sorry. I'm sorry.
By that I discovered it?
It's two years ago. You just keep digging in it.
- It does not matter. - Of course it does.
It does not matter. You understand it really is not.
Every time it rings every time you get mail or letter, I get scared.
I've really tried. Every day I try.
Every day I try, but I do not have confidence.
I do not trust you.
- You know, the neighbors called the. - I had done exactly the same.
- Nice to meet you. - You too. Goodbye.
- Hello? - Magdalena? I found the letter.
- What letter? - The letter, Joseph talked about. Listen.
"""You are my flesh and blood, but the family will die."""
"""First, when it happens, it may be, as it should be."""
- What? I can not hear. - Were you afraid of Santa Claus?
- Joona, we must take it in the morning. - Okay, we'll rest tomorrow.
- Okay. Hey. - Hello.
- May I come in? - What does it mean if I say no?
It makes a lot. For me.
- Is it good, what ...? - It's funny.
- It does not look funny. - But that's it.
You look not so happy when you play.
I love you.
I do of course. You have to say it. Whatever it is, as you say it.
If something is difficult or there is something you are worried about.
- Anything. - Shut up.
Benjamin. Shall I give you the syringe tonight?
No, father to do it.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Hello.
- Good night. - Good night.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
There's something I have to tell you.
I can not bear more charges.
- I orcs not. - It's not accusations.
Well.
What is it?
I will take a break.
Break?
I will take a break ... from ...
- From what? Are you going to cry? - No.
- What do you take a break from? - From Us! From you and me.
- Pause? - Yes.
From us, from you and me.
A while.
- What do you pause? - Not now.
- What do you think? - Tomorrow.
- How many did you take? - Yes ... No ...
Go back to sleep on the couch. I can not stand to see you like that.
I will not see you like this. Lie on the couch.
- Erik? - Yes, yes ...
Erik?
Erik.
Eric!
Dad!
Hello? Hello?
Eric, there is one that ...
"""Dear child, I have long looked at you -"
"- and hate what you've become."""
"""Dear child,"" suggests suppose that it is one that is older. Not?"
"- It goes without saying. - ""I have long looked at you."""
Yes, as if someone has persecuted the child.
Something tells me that this is not the first contact.
At the same time they do not know each other.
And do not include themselves in the family.
"And ""for everything to be as it should be."" What does it mean?"
- psychopath ... - Moomintroll ...
- Now I'm getting tired of you! - What a nonsense.
So so. Petter, you have a moment? Come on.
- There was daddy. - Is the letter studied?
- Yes. - No fingerprints, in addition to Joseph.
What bothers me is that we have ...
We have two executions two different locations with respect to each other.
There are no fingerprints, no DNA. It works incredibly professional.
- But Needle says it is ... - Amateurish.
So we're back at the start.
We have to analyze the crime scene again, testing the letter a second time -
- contact relatives and try to find her sister.
Simone?
Simone? Simone! Simone!
An ambulance to Barn_ngsgatan 34th My wife has fainted.
- Well ... - What is it?
This is embarrassing, Joona. My goodness. Absolutely incredible.
"""Scandal Doctor in the police service."""
- It is urgent to get the boy to talk. - It does not hold up in court.
- That brings us perhaps beyond. - Has it done so far?
- Express rang. - What did you say to them?
I told them to go to hell. If this works for you, you are the man of -
- but it strikes mistake, banks Janne Josefsson at the door.
- They found her sister. - Good. We'll see.
"What do you mean by ""still not ...""?"
What do you mean that he is not in school?
Have ... Has not he been in. ..?
- Honey ... Beloved, hey. - Hello.
You're in the hospital. Relax. You are in the hospital.
It'll be all right. Take it easy, take it easy.
Hello. Simone?
Erik ... Erik, how ...?
Benjamin is with you, right?
- Benjamin is not in school. - Simone? Simone?
Where is Benjamin?
- Stay there. - I must go ...
- It's not me ... - Lie down. I'll fix it.
We have to wait to talk about it here.
They gave me an injection and took Benjamin! They have taken our little boy!
- Simone! - I have to help Benjamin!
- Where? When? Wait, wait. - While we slept! We must help our ...
Benjamin! Benjamin!
- Benjamin! - I'm going upstairs.
Benjamin!
No, no, no ... No! No! No!
No, not Benjamin.
He's not here. I must think.
Simone ...
You have to remember it. What is it that has happened?
I place you in the room 333rd
It's not luxury, but it is safe.
Hello. Rikskrim. Is this where Evelyn Ek ...?
Do you want something that banks simply on the door, and then we open for you. Okay?
Evelyn?
Hello. My name is Joona. I come from Rikskriminalen.
I'd like to talk with you.
Do you have any idea who might have done this?
Someone who has threatened you or something like that?
You can tell me. No one can reach you.
You know nothing. You do not know anything. You can not protect me.
He will find me.
Who? Who are you? Evelyn, who?
- I'm going back now. - Evelyn. Who?
He suffers from hemophilia. Haemophilia Disease.
- Okay. - So he gets syringes regularly.
And what happens if he does not get syringes?
Yes, because he suffers from haemophilia -
- so he risks getting bleeding which of course can ...
Simone, you do not remember anything, but you know that someone took Benjamin?
- Yes. - We can not get it to vote.
When I was asleep, there was one in and gave me a numbing spray.
- What We Believe. - I know.
I tried to wake Erik. I heard Benjamin try to call me -
- but I was so far away that I ...
We interrupt straight. You say that you tried to wake Erik?
Okay. Do you sleep poorly, Erik?
Yes. I have trouble sleeping. So I take ...
He's very strong sleeping pills. It was impossible to wake him.
What's the last thing you remember before you close your eyes?
That Benjamin tried to call me. It's as if ...
It's so hard to explain. It is like that which is in the head.
- How was the cry of Benjamin? - He was scared.
You heard the fear in his voice, and so did you react?
Yes. That's why I wanted to ...
It's so hard to sit and waffle. Can not we ...? Someone took Benjamin.
What do we know? We must look, right?
- We must lead, and not waffle. - It is not nonsense ...
We sit and logs. It is so strange to us because he is our child.
The phone.
- Bark. - Hello, Eric. It is Shulman.
Do you know where Simone is? She had to make some paintings.
- Hello? - Would not you stop by the gallery?
- Where are you? - Home.
How about Benjamin?
- Not something that ...? - No, it was a gallerist.
- My wife picturesque images. - Okay.
Benjamin is gone. It is such a nightmare.
There are police officers here who wants to talk to us, and ...
What do you say? What did you say something?
What is it that has happened?
Hello?
Simone!
NO MORE HYPNOSIS
- What happened here? - Rikskrim? What do you think?
- Talk to Erik. What happened? - A boy has been abducted.
Here?
Here. We have to eat something.
Want to order takeaway? Are you crazy?
- Just look at them. - Are you crazy?
Are you okay? Are you all right, Eric?
Good. I do not think that the family Ex killer has something to do with it here to do.
- It is on the wall. - You must not hypnotize.
It could be anyone. One who does not want you to start again.
Who could it be?
- No old enemies? Think about it. - I do not know.
Okay.
Let us assume that it is as you think.
That it has a direct connection to the murder of the family Ek.
So there's only one man who can give us information.
And we need your help. Can you ...?
Wait. What can I do? What is it that I can?
Talk to Joseph.
You want me to use hypnosis on Joseph?
You want me to solve your murder?
It's our only option. We are stuck in this investigation.
If I see that boy again ...
So would the killer know about it, and ...
- He is not out of it. - It is of course in the newspaper!
Journalists call me up in the middle of the night!
It was a mistake. It will not happen again.
- It's your fault! It's your fault. - Now we hold for today.
- Okay. I will contact you. - Goodbye.
Why do not you do something? What?
- Why do not you do something? - Right now we are waiting requirements.
The requirements are they on the wall in my studio. Can not you read?
- We are doing everything we can. - Okay. Well so.
So we're in good hands. Good.
- Do you want coffee? - Do you have tea?
What the hell ...? Should I sit here and drink tea?
Eric, dammit. They're a couple of idiots.
Shall I sit here and drink tea?! And read the newspaper?!
How's he doing without his medication?
He's strong.
Does he have pain?
He'll be fine. You know that.
Yes.
We must do something. We can not just sit here.
The police are doing what they can. They help us.
Nobody does anything. We sit here and do nothing. Nobody does anything.
They're working on it. They do.
The police ask a lot of questions. They might as well put it bluntly.
- What? - They think that we have done it.
- Do you have children? - No.
So you can not understand how it feels.
- You asked me if I had an enemy. - Yes.
There's one.
Hello. We are looking Evert Braun.
- Do you know where we can find him? - He's in the overhead crane.
Let me handle this. Wait here.
- Hello. - Hello.
- Are you Evert Braun? - Am I Evert Braun? Yes.
My name is Joona Linna and is from Rikskrim.
- I will ask you a few questions. - Rikskrim? Yes, sir. Like.
- Where were you the night to yesterday? - At work here as always. Why?
- All night? - Yes.
Shift work? Can you confirm any of this?
- Ask anyone in the workshop. - Did you take my son?
- Benjamin. Have you been ...? - Erik, now let me handle this!
What the hell is he doing here?
Have I taken your son from you? How dare you show up here?!
You've ruined my life, you fucking bitch!
Damn, damn pigs.
Are you aware of what a rumor can do? Can you believe it?
To Hell no.
So you come here and claim that I have taken your son!
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Okay. That's it.
I led a research project.
One of the subjects was Evert Braun.
He told about the abuse of children.
- Sexual assault. - Well, damn.
I told the police that initiated a feasibility study -
- and laid it on the grounds that I had planted evidence.
That I had given them images that were not theirs, to build memories.
That I had asked leading questions. I ...
So I was removed from my research -
- and the newspapers wrote about it, and it was ...
- Because of a mistake. - Yes.
I do not ... I destroyed a man's life.
It's not him. He knows nothing.
Nobody knows anything.
- A hard day? - Hello.
Yes. It could say that.
A doctor who smokes?
- As if you never go through a red light. - No, I have never ... No.
- Have you eaten? - No.
Come on. I give.
Hello.
Joseph? Can you hear me?
You speak so good Swedish.
- Thank you. You too. - Thank you.
- What is it? You look like ... - No ...
- Work. Never mind that. - Maybe it's just something you forgot?
I do not usually forget. I have a good memory.
What color are my eyes?
- You have blond hair. - Yes.
- And a white shirt, right? - Yes, that's right.
One gold jewelery. A heart and a small gold drop.
Your eyes are ... They are gray, but in bright light may appear blue.
Good.
And you have black leather boots on.
- Yes. - Is there anything else?
No, that's plenty.
Wait. His feet ...
His feet were dirty. There's something I need to check.
Sorry, Daniella. We'll see.
... two a.
Joseph? Breathe.
Shall we try again?
Now it's evening.
A piece away from you you see your home.
You will go inside.
Now we're at home.
What happens then?
I'm hiding in the dark.
- Is there someone else? - Lisa.
She comes running stairs.
- What do you do? - Jager Lisa up the stairs.
- What? - She cries.
- What did you say? - She cries.
Mother ... Mother must not hear it.
Mom can hear me.
I stick.
Mother ... She screams.
It's not ...
- What do you do? - Going into the bathroom.
- You met your father before? - Yes. Down in the sports hall.
I just did as she said.
As she said? Evelyn?
- I need to do as she says. - Who? Evelyn?
I'm sorry. Sorry. I just did as she said.
Joseph ... Said Evelyn, you should do it?
My sister.
Evelyn is my sister.
It's me, Eric. I'm in the hospital.
I think that it is Joseph who is the murderer.
- That must be the one who ... - I'm on my way there now.
- He has been up and walking around. - What?
I'll be there in a minute.
- I said it. - So, so.
He wanted me to say it.
Joona Linna here. Officer only in the hospital is not responding.
Little Friend, can I help you? Where are you going?
So. Can you stand alone? Arise.
That's it. Then we go back. There is not much. I'll get the other ...
Where is he? Where is the boy?!
Wait. Stop!
Where is the boy?
- How are they? - She operated now. It is critical.
Satan. Satan!
Listen. We are looking forward. The guy can not have gone far. He's wounded.
I think it's her sister. Evelyn.
- As made him do all this. - Meat and blood, what?
"Wait. ""You are my flesh and blood, but the family will die."""
Evelyn wanted Joseph to kill his own family.
Yes.
Do you know that? It is you who have written it.
Right?
"""You are my flesh and blood, but the family will die."" Josef is your flesh and blood."
You got him to kill your parents. And your little sister.
Was you with?
Kept you the knife?
I have not done anything.
We know that it was Joseph who did it. As killed them.
He ran away from the hospital last night.
He stabbed a nurse down. Her condition is critical.
Has he been in contact with you?
No.
I've always felt that there would be something terrible.
I've been afraid of him for life. I will not be afraid anymore.
You do not know what he is for a man.
He was always laughing when people get hurt.
He laughed when our last dog died.
And it was only worse.
- In what way? - Since the summer ...
He was even more insane. He beat us.
shouted that he hated us.
The mother and father had stolen him, and that they should give him back.
- I will not be afraid anymore. - Why do you think he said that?
I do not know.
How can you sit and eat? What? How can you sit and eat?
Are you thinking only about food? What?
Do you think ... Do you think that Benjamin is hungry?
Did he ...?
But that's no matter, you just sit there and eat like a pig!
You're the damn and stop food in his mouth like a pig!
He was even more insane. He beat us.
shouted that he hated us.
The mother and father had stolen him, and that they should give him back.
- Hello. I tried to call. - Well, something has happened? Come in.
- Josef is adopted. - Why do you think that?
Because Evelyn today said ...
- No, but what there is? - Mother!
Evelyn said Joseph accused his parents of having stolen him.
- Martin? - What the hell ...
What did you say?
It is clear that the letter was written from a parent to a child.
Joseph?
I think that the correct parent found him and contacted him.
That he is up for adoption, and so should the parent ...
... have come into contact with him. And have gotten him to do this.
- Yes. - We gotta go. We should be safe.
We must have an APB out. The person is now our prime suspect.
It might also have with Benjamin's disappearance to do.
- So we have to go now. - Yes.
I need to talk to Martin.
"A new message. ""Hypnotist must die."""
Joseph's biological mother named Lydia Evers.
We did not know much about her. She has long been socially isolated.
Thank you.
10 years ago was Lydia sentenced to psychiatric treatment.
And she was discharged six months ago.
Six months ago ... But you know what it says here?
Joseph was forcibly removed just before Lydia was hospitalized.
So he was adopted by the family Ek. Do we have a photo?
- Let's see what it says. - 99th It's 10 years old.
- She may look completely different. - Yes, but she's been gone a long time.
Hello. What is it that happens, Simone?
- Here's the picture. - Fine. But you must tell me about it.
"""I see you."""
I CAN SEE YOU AND YOUR whore. SOON IS DEAD.
Hello? There ... There is one that threatens my wife.
- If it right now? - Yes. It's happening right now.
And then the third there. But there must be ... There is one, right?
I've packed four into. I forgot it in the studio.
- I'll get it. - Let me.
Damn it! What the hell are you doing?
Are you mad?!
But ... What happens?
- Give space. - Well. Yes, yes ...
- What happened? - A completely insane person.
- He threw himself over me with a knife. - Simone. I heard it over the radio.
- It was a little child! - I know. Where's Eric?
- Where's Eric? - Who knows? Perhaps the hospital.
I know who took Benjamin. But do not know where she is.
- She? - I'll explain it later.
Joseph? Do you hear me?
Was that your real mother, who said that you should do this?
Was that it?
Lydia? Is this your real mother? What?
- Where is she now? - I love her.
- What did you say? - I love her.
Yes. Where is she? I must find her. Josef?
Damn!
Eric!
Hello! Are you okay?
- How long will it take? - Lydia has no credit cards.
No registered address, and the photo is both bad and old -
- so it will take time.
- Have you heard anything? - No. We are doing everything we can.
We'll find her and Benjamin. Try to get some sleep.
Yes, Erik, by the way. I checked him Evert Braun.
He stood in the register. Feasibility Study Material.
A few years ago they found evidence of child abuse.
Unfortunately, not enough to prosecute, according to the prosecutor.
But I think you should know.
Would you like a cup of coffee or something?
Why not?
Unfortunately, there are a lot of cases where no indictment -
- although the evidence is very strong.
We can not do much other than wait now. Sorry.
- You want more? - No thanks.
- I'm looking for Simone. - Yes. I will be sitting a little.
That I can not remember it ... It's so weird.
Why can not I remember?
- What? - Because you were stunned.
But it does look. Not?
I saw ... Do the ... I can ...
Think ... Imagine if I saw anything?
Erik? Help me.
I think I saw something.
- You must follow my instructions. - Okay.
You should try to trust me. You must dare to relinquish control.
- It stresses that you talk a lot. - Sit back.
I know that you have a lot of thoughts and anxiety, but try to just breathe.
Do not think so damn much. Okay?
- No. - Relax.
- I'm trying, Erik. - Here. Squeeze my hand in your hand.
Press to. Close everything out of this deal. Close all your opponent out.
Feel the pressure. Feel my hand, feel your hand.
So let the other be and breathe with me. Let yourself sink.
Relax. Sit back.
Breathe.
Close your eyes.
Breathe with me.
So. Stay here.
And now you rely only on me.
Does just me.
For peace of the whole body.
In a few moments, I lift your left hand.
You let me do it. Now.
In a moment I get rid your arm.
It falls heavily into your lap.
Now.
I want you to imagine a meadow.
There, a piece there, stands a house.
It is our house.
Erik?
Eric!
Do not sleep ...
I can not. It turns black. I can not stand on their feet ...
Listen to my voice. Go back to bed where you sleep -
- and everything is in order.
Now you lie in your bed ... and sleep.
You feel a twinge.
Is anyone there?
There is no.
I see her ...
- I see her in the mirror. - How does she look?
I see exactly what she looks like ...
I see exactly how she looks. Face.
Can you describe how she looks?
The one I have seen.
A nurse. She was in the hospital the first night, Joseph was hospitalized.
- Take a number and move it forward a little. - Okay.
There. Wait.
There she is. So we check. Take-General a little further along.
Take the left. Take the setter. And then another angle.
It is. And then run.
There.
Print it. So we must have a copy of the complete file of this sequence.
Do you have a USB port?
You want a break?
No.
- It sounded like that. - I understand that you thought it.
I had earned.
I do not even live up to my own expectations more.
Hold up.
If I had not taken all the pills ...
If only I could hear his voice ...
If I could just hear his voice.
Erik ... Sweet Erik ...
Call from 10th Person Wanted.
- It's Lydia Evers, born ... - Look! It's her.
- What do you think? - It is she who hire of B_rje.
It's damn her!
We go now. There's a plane in an hour.
She moved into B_rjes house by the lake and paid manifest cash.
- Has she been seen with the boy? - No, she keeps to herself.
- Yes. When will we gain? - A patrol will be here in half an hour.
1038 to 1442. Switch.
- from 1038 to 1442, change. - The 1442nd I listen. Switch.
- Where have you gone? - We're still at the station.
- How many do you have? - Two, so that ...
- We come in five to. - Hurry up.
- I do not wait. I'm leaving. - We go with you.
Okay.
We go and check it out. Stay here and wait for reinforcements.
We must go down.
Wait there.
Quiet. He sleeps.
Lydia?
- What are you doing here? - My name is Joona. I'm a cop.
I'm here to help Benjamin. He is sick.
- He needs medicine. - He is not sick. It is my son.
Lydia, he is sick and must be hospitalized.
- I know well, if he is sick. - He's not your son, Lydia.
Listen to me. Your son named Joseph.
- Look at me. Look at me, Lydia. - Where is Joseph?
- Josef is also sick. - Where is Joseph?
- He's in Stockholm. - What's he doing in Stockholm?
- We can get him here. - I want Joseph.
- They fly him here. - I just want to have my child.
I want Joseph brought here.
- No, no! - Listen to me. Look at me!
No, no, no. Where is Joseph? I want my baby!
- He should be here now! - Add the weapon from you now!
He was bad.
- Stop! - Help! Mom!
Shut up!
- Mom! - No ...
Come on!
Damn! Come, come, come!
Benjamin!
Lydia!
- Benjamin! - Benjamin!
- Stay with me! - Open the door!
Open the door!
- Let go of me! - Benjamin!
Benjamin, ran back! Running up!
- No! Benjamin! - Mother!
Benjamin!
No! No!
Well, Benjamin! Backwards!
- Benjamin! - No! No!
Benjamin!
No. Do not leave me!
Fight!
No!
Take my hand!
- Get Benjamin out! - Release taken in him!
Stop!
- Let go of him! - No!
We have to get out of here!
Benjamin! Here. Come! Spring!
Take my hand! Take my hand! The bus is sinking!
Take it! Lydia, take my hand! Lydia!
Joona! Here!
You, Benjamin ... Does it taste good?
Hot.
A message to our customers: Today, Christmas Eve, we close at. 15th
I'm working on getting hold of them. I need relief.
Hey, Magdalena. Merry Christmas.
I sit in the car and eat. Yes. Are you home?
I would get by with anything.
4912, you stand in line ...
- Hello. Merry Christmas. - Good July Sorry to interrupt.
- I just wanted to give it to the ropes. - No, but ...
- Mom! - However, little friend ...
I'm sorry. Were you scared? It was just a Christmas crown.
- Come on in, Joona. Come in. - I do not know ... Sorry.
I did not mean for you to be afraid.