[anticipatory music]
[phone dialing]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Hi Kit, this is
Libby Mannering.
Hi Lib.
What are you doing tonight?
Hmm, nothing, what
did you have in mind?
My mother and
father are going away.
How lucky can you get?
Overnight, they'll
be gone till tomorrow.
Are they leaving you alone?
Well no, they're getting
a babysitter for Tess,
my sister.
Don't they trust you?
Well sure they do, but
you know how parents are.
Listen can you come for dinner
and then spend the night?
I don't know about all night,
my father's awfully peculiar.
Oh, so is mine.
But I can handle him.
Try it Kit, we'll
have a lot of fun.
Okay, I'll ask him
and call you right back.
[frolicking music]
[phone dialing]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Lib?
Hi Kit, can you come?
Just for dinner, I
can't stay overnight.
Did you tell your
father my parents
were going away overnight?
Yeah I goofed.
That's why he said no.
Well maybe if I talked to him.
I'm very persuasive.
You don't know my father.
But at least I can
come for dinner.
He'll drive me over,
how do we get there?
You live out in the wilderness.
It's not that bad,
it's easy really.
You go about 15 miles
past the gas station
on Elm, then you turn
right on Tompkin Street,
you keep going right until
you pass the rail road tracks,
and then you turn left and
go for about six miles.
You come to a red
barn, and you pass...
[frolicking music]
[soothing music]
Tess, Tess!
Oh you little fool.
You're supposed to be sick.
You come in the house this
minute, do you hear me?
[dog barking]
How can you play outside with
the thermometer in your mouth?
You little idiot, wait until
I tell Mommy you went outside.
Don't tell her.
Stop talking.
You can't take
anybody's temperature
while they're running around.
Don't you know that
silly, now sit there.
If there's a fever,
it's mine, I'll read it.
Supposing you make a mistake?
I won't, you start at the top,
count back to the red line.
106, 105, 104.
103, 102, 101, 100.
99.
I'm normal, I'm a normal person.
Oh that's your opinion.
Mother? Mother?
Yes?
I checked Tess'
temperature and she's normal.
Did you hear,
Daddy? I'm normal.
Well, that's my girl.
She thinks she
should get a medal.
A medal, really? Well.
Oh have you kids seen
my tobacco pouch?
You know you could lose a
battleship in this place?
[giggling]
You really look cute, Daddy.
Cute?
Well, I'll buy that.
[giggling]
Libby.
Don't forget to tell
Mrs. Beale to give Tess
one of these before
dinner and one after.
And then she goes...
Goes straight to bed.
Big mouth!
Will you two please stop it?
Now here's the Wards' number,
Santa Barbara, 5930,
and Dr. Sweeney's
home number, okay?
Mm-hmm.
We're running late honey.
[phone ringing]
Oh I really think we should
wait until Mrs. Beale comes.
All right.
[car horn honking]
I'll get it.
[phone ringing]
Yes?
Ms. Mary this is Mrs. Beale.
Oh hello Mrs. Beale.
Hi Kit!
Hi Libby!
Hi.
How are you?
Fine, how are you?
Fine.
I want you to meet my father.
Hello Mr. Austin.
Hello dear.
Are you coming in
to meet my folks?
Well I'm sorry,
I haven't the time,
but please thank your mother
for having Kit over, okay?
Sure.
And I'll pick you up at 11:30.
Oh, Daddy couldn't
you make it 12?
Mmm-mm, 11:30's late enough.
You have to be up early
tomorrow, remember?
Yeah, I'll be ready.
Good night Libby.
Good night Mr. Austin.
[car engine revving]
When he says 11:30
he means 11:30.
Well come on then,
let's not waste any time.
David we can't go.
I'm sorry, but we'll just
have to call the Wards
and break the date.
Well for heaven's sake, why?
Mrs. Beale can't come.
Mother.
Daddy, this is Kit Austin.
Oh, hello.
Hello my name is Tess.
Hi Tess.
Hello Kit.
Oh Ms. Mannering,
it was so nice of you
to invite me to dinner.
Now what is all
this about Mrs. Beale
not coming?
Mrs. Beale is sick.
Ah...
Oh Mother, we'll
be all right alone.
Well it'll be pretty awkward
to break the date now honey,
it's business as well
as social you know,
couldn't we get somebody else?
But dear I tried to
get everybody before
I got Mrs. Beale.
Mother, when are
you gonna realize
I'm practically grown up.
[snorts]
Well you know she's
got a point there.
No, no, she's very responsible.
You remember how she
held down the fort
when your mother was ill
and that was two years ago.
Well I suppose we
could start back early.
Sure, we'd be back
at the crack of dawn.
Don't worry Daddy,
we'll be all right.
Countdown from the top,
see how normal I am.
[laughs]
I'm very normal.
I know you're just fine.
Good bye.
Goodbye Libby.
Oh you do have
those numbers now?
Yes Mother, the
Wards and Dr. Sweeney.
Okay.
Ellie come on.
Oh all right, goodbye Kit.
Bye bye, have a good time.
Thank you.
[frolicking music]
[car engine revving]
It's so different, from
our apartment I mean.
It's so big.
Come on, I wanna
show you my room.
Tess, you set the table.
Libby I wanna show her my room.
You can do that later,
set the table now.
Oh let her come,
Libby. Come on, Tess.
I wish I'd worn my jeans.
Oh I'll lend you
a pair of mine.
Do you have any
brothers or sisters?
No.
Are you spoiled?
Probably.
[soothing music]
[horse neighing]
[goat bleating]
Libby, what is that?
[laughs] That's Carmen.
Go ahead, pet her.
Well, we've got a pony and ducks.
[giggles] Even a tame raccoon.
My father's a frustrated
country squire, I think.
Come on.
[soothing music]
[horse neighing]
Lib, don't you ever
get lonely out here?
Ah, it's funny.
I never used to be.
Until I grew up, this
was just all there was.
You know, pets and
bicycles and a sandwich
and a glass of
milk after school.
But I was never lonely.
And now?
Well now it seems
like everything I want
is someplace else.
You know what I mean.
Parties, the movies, even
going to a friend's house
for dinner, they're
all someplace else.
Give your boys a road map?
It's not that bad.
But when I do have a date,
they have to drive
all the way out here,
pick me up, drive back to town
and drive me all
the way back here.
What's the sense of
making it so hard for 'em?
[door slamming shut]
What's the matter Lib?
Oh, Daddy was
supposed to fix this.
He probably did, but
nothing he ever fixes
stays fixed.
Come on Kit, help me.
I wouldn't just
be lonely out here,
I'd be scared stiff.
[foreboding music]
You wanna look
around some more?
There's a lot of things to see.
No, let's go back.
[frolicking music]
Kit, Kit, Kit!
Kit, it's for you, a phone call,
a boy.
Maybe it's Gary.
[frolicking music]
Tess, that's not funny.
[giggles]
Hello Gary?
Hello?
Hello?!
Hello!
There's nobody there.
He must've hung up.
Nobody called,
that's her idiot notion
of a joke.
I'm sorry.
We do it all the time,
call people for fun.
Yeah we do it all the time.
Wait till you hear
what they say.
Pick a name, Kit.
Go ahead, close your
eyes and pick a name.
Pick a name?
Any name!
Gimme the phone.
[frolicking music]
William Harrison.
One, four, one.
Nine, one.
Hello?
Hello, is Bill there?
Who is this?
This is Alice, I've
been waiting for him.
Almost an hour.
Waiting for him?
Yes, at the Green Garter Club.
He promised to be on time.
Well this is Mrs. Harrison.
I'll be sure to tell him.
[gasps] Oh, this is his wife?
Oh I'm sorry, I must
have the wrong number.
[giggling]
Okay it's your turn now Kit.
John Adams.
28061.
Six, one.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Hello, is John there?
Yes, he's here.
John, it's for you.
Yes?
Hello John?
This is Alice.
I've been waiting for
you, almost an hour.
Oh but I wanted
to meet you Alice.
Yes I did.
But you see I
already had a date.
With my wife, who also
wants to use the phone.
Oh whoops, I struck out.
Give it to me!
No, you'll just get
scared and hang up.
No I won't. Find
me a number Lib.
Okay.
Ah, two, three, two.
Two.
One.
Three.
Hello?
Mommy, is this Mommy?
No, this isn't
your mother, dear.
But I told Mommy
I'd call her so she
can pick me up at the movie
theater on Elm Street.
Well, why don't you try again
and dial very carefully honey.
But this is the wrong number,
and I spent my last dime.
Could you call my
mommy for me please
and tell her to come get me?
Of course darling,
what's her number?
Her number is OL4367.
I'll call her right
now, and you wait
right where you are.
I'll wait here, thank you.
Stupid.
But you gave her our number.
Well it's the
only number I know.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Your little girl
called my number
by mistake.
[giggling] [hushing]
She's waiting for you at
the theater on Elm Street.
Well it's so nice
of you to call.
Thank you.
I'm sure Nancy was upset.
I'll pick her up right away.
And thanks again.
Now let's see if
I remember Dave.
You like your coffee strong,
hot, and black, right?
Right.
Do you know that that
phone is still busy?
Thank you.
Do you think anything
could be wrong?
Oh honey I'd be worried if
they weren't on the phone,
so they're talking, so
everything's perfectly normal.
Of course.
You know how kids are.
[giggling]
Oh...
Steve Mara k.
Five, six.
Seven, nine, one.
[phone ringing]
Hello.
Hello, is Steve there?
Who is this?
Just a friend.
Look sweetie, are you sure
you got the right number?
Oh, well why would Steve
give me a wrong number?
Steve?
Steve!
Hold on.
Steve.
Look he's taking a
bath, call him later.
In the bathtub!
Tell her you've
gotta talk to him!
But it's terribly important.
Hold on.
Steve, will you rush it up?
I wanna get my things...
[sad music]
You ape!
You belong in a cage!
And you wanna know
why I'm leaving you!
You're not jealous,
you're not that normal!
You're insane!
[screaming]
[anticipatory music]
[glass shattering]
So he doesn't wanna
get out of the tub.
Well try again then!
What's his number?
Oh, I don't remember,
what was his name?
It started with an M.
Mannering?
That's our name, stupid.
Oh no it was a strange name.
Well how can we find it
now, you closed the book.
It started with an M.
Well, let him stay in the
tub, find me somebody else Kit.
[foreboding music]
Judith?
[glass ringing]
Steve?
[door knocking]
Steve.
Steve?
[door knocking]
What happened?
I stumbled, fell
against the shower door.
Are you all right?
It shook me up a little.
I thought Judith was leaving?
She left all right.
She didn't even finish packing.
We had another fight, a beaut.
I'll send her things after her.
She's gone for good.
I'm here Steve.
Don't let this hurt you.
She's not worth it.
You married a childish,
empty-headed, little tramp.
But now we can make
something wonderful together.
We have made it.
You know that.
Your hands are trembling.
I gotta get her things out
of here as soon as possible.
[ominous music]
I gotta get dressed.
Of course, go ahead.
I'll straighten up in here.
No!
What is it?
[ominous music]
Steve?
[moves into romantic music]
Later.
Will you promise
to come over later?
I tried to call you three times,
your line was busy.
Judy must've been
trying to call a cab.
I was kinda worried.
That's why I came over,
your back door was open.
You know it's kinda
nice being neighbors.
I can check up on you.
Your phone's off
the hook, Steve.
That's funny.
Good night Amy.
Later.
[frolicking music]
Is this Mr. John Hamburger?
Yes it is.
That's fine, would you
send over six with pickles
and onions?
Get lost nuisance burger!
[giggling]
What did he say?
He said, "Get lost
nuisance burger!"
[laughing]
You won't believe this
Libby, I swear you won't!
Donald Ileak!
Donald Ileak?
Is his brother the plumber?
[giggling]
[foreboding music]
[car engine revving]
I'm hungry!
Okay now I'll
show you something.
[phone dialing]
Hello?
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
Will you stop bothering people?
Oh, no sense of humor.
[phone dialing]
[romantic music]
[phone ringing]
Yes.
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
You did?
Nothing's sacred!
Operator.
Operator, I've been
getting a busy signal
at this number for
over two hours,
could you check and
see if there's anything
wrong with the line?
Yes Ma'am, that was OL4367?
Yes, that's right, thank you.
Hello?
Yes?
Yes Ma'am that number is busy.
I see, thank you.
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
[frolicking music]
[dog barking]
Slick, Slick where are you?
[dog growling]
Slick come here!
Slick!
[foreboding music]
Hey, hey, from
now on when you have
some business to attend
to, do it at the curb.
Don't wander off!
Hey come on let's go.
Next time it's your turn.
Hey what's wrong?
Nothing, nothing.
[car engine revving]
[sneaky music]
[dog whimpering]
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
[ominous music]
Eww!
You pig, you got
peanut butter and jelly
all over this page.
That's because I
put my sandwich on it.
I put it on the
man in the bathtub.
You what?
The man in the
bathtub remember?
He couldn't talk 'cause
he was taking a bath.
I put my sandwich down
then, on the phone book.
Steve, Steve Mara k!
Let's see if he's
still in the tub.
[phone dialing]
[phone ringing]
Maybe he drowned!
Hey, I'm hungry, are you?
[frolicking music]
[dog barking]
Steve.
Steve!
Steve?
I've been waiting for you.
Here, let me do that.
You shouldn't be alone,
especially tonight.
Come on in.
Your shoes are all muddy,
where have you been?
I had a flat, I
had to change it.
Well we're gonna get
those shoes right off.
Come on, let's sit down,
I'm gonna take care of you
whether you like or not.
Come on, take your shoes off.
I'm giving the orders now.
I know what you need.
But first, I'm gonna give
you a nice stiff drink.
I'm gonna have one too.
I'll show you what it is
to be taken care of.
Let's drink to that first
night we had together.
I never knew anything
could be so wonderful.
Now we can drink to a whole
lifetime of nights like that.
You know Judith
was wrong for you.
She was too young, too
young to be a wife,
a companion or, ugh, anything.
I want you to relax.
We're gonna have
a beautiful life.
Just being together, that's
all that really matters.
We can go away,
anywhere we want.
Oh I need you Steve.
[phone ringing]
Let it ring.
You need me.
Let it ring!
Yes?
I sot him!
Well talk to him!
Is this Steve?
Steve Mara k?
That's right, who's this?
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
[ominous music] [dog barking]
[mumbling]
What does he say?
He's playing along,
sounds exciting.
Yes, I know who you are,
and I saw what you did.
Who, who is this?
He wants to know who I am.
Oh make up a name,
make up a name.
Suzette.
Suzette?
Where are you calling from?
Where can I reach you?
What a swinger!
He wants a date?
Wouldn't you like to know?
Suzette?
[giggling]
Suzette!
Steve?
What is it?
What's wrong?
Just a business deal
I've been working on.
Look I may have to go out
later, you'd better go home.
No, Steve.
I'll wait, right here.
Please, Amy, I wanna be alone
till I can work this out.
Who is Suzette?
Get off my back, give
me room to breathe,
you don't own me yet.
I'm sorry Steve, truly I am.
I can't help worrying,
I just don't want to
see you hurt again.
There's nothing to worry about.
It's just a business deal
and Suzette's a part of it.
Darling if you're in
trouble, I wanna help
any way I can.
Amy please, go on
home, I'll be over later.
Look I have money, lots of it!
It's ours now, we
can go away together,
please, please let me help.
Amy, trust me.
We'll be together,
it'll work out that way,
I promise you, just trust me.
I trust you with all my heart.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Hello Steve?
Hello Suzette.
Why did you hang
up on me before?
I've got to see you.
As soon as possible.
See what I mean, sexy.
Hi Steve.
Suzette, I wanna meet you.
I wanna meet you too.
What a sex maniac!
He does want a date.
Anywhere you say.
Well, somewhere nice and quiet.
I know you realize
how important this is
to both of us.
It means everything to
me Suzette, everything.
I'll meet you anywhere,
at your home, at work.
I know you're smart, I know
you want the same things I do.
That's all that's
keeping me going,
nothing matters but seeing you.
You can trust me Suzette, I promise.
Suzette?
[foreboding music]
Oh my God.
You'll be hearing
from me, goodbye now.
Wait a minute, please.
I'll call you back, I promise.
Then you will meet me?
Promise?
Suzette, Suzette?
Where can I reach you?
Oh didn't he sound exciting?
Yeah and sexy.
Well Why'd you hang up then?
Oh I can't meet him
Kit, you know that.
So what's the use?
Oh call him once more, please.
No, game's over.
I wonder what he looks like.
We'll never know.
[rumbling]
That's Tess, she
fell outta bed again.
Libby, Libby!
Libby!
I had a bad dream, Libby.
Well, that's all
right, try to forget it.
I can't, it was horrible.
Try anyway, it
was just a dream.
All right, if you'll stay
here until I fall asleep.
Okay.
Libby?
What?
If you did meet him,
what would you do?
I don't know, go for
a ride or something
or just talk.
About what?
Well, whatever he wanted to.
His work, girls he's
known, where he's been.
But what would you talk about?
Boys, where I've been.
Libby you haven't
been anywhere.
Well I went to New
York with Daddy once.
I guess I'd lie a little bit.
Well, what if he
didn't wanna just talk?
I'm not exactly a baby Kit.
I can take care of myself.
Just by talking?
Suppose that he
wanted to kiss you?
Well, maybe I'd let him.
Just once, or as
much as he wanted?
Well, I don't
know, he sounds nice.
His voice was so
deep, so exciting.
It was like he was
running his hand
down my back.
Real slowly...
Was it cold?
That's a silly question.
I'll tell you what
would happen if you
really did meet him.
He'd take one look at you
and send you straight home.
Anyway he's probably married.
Oh Kit, you're so naive.
Just because a man's married...
I just wish I knew
what he looked like.
Kit, if we could find out.
Tess are you asleep?
Sure I'm asleep.
We could meet him Kit,
well see him I mean,
without him seeing us.
I don't know what you mean.
Well we know where he lives,
I could take Mommy's car.
I've got my learner's permit.
Libby Mannering!
You wouldn't dare!
I will if you will.
We could park near
his house and see him.
You're not leaving
me alone, Lib.
Ah, well I thought
you were asleep.
I was.
I can't leave Tess, Kit.
Well I'd stay with her.
No, she's my responsibility.
I just couldn't leave her.
Well our problem is
about the same, Tom,
trying to convert to
computers without violating
the union contracts.
Well I'm seeing Roy
Miller next week
to go over some of the figures.
David?
David there's no answer at home.
Well there must be.
But I've tried three
times in the last 10 minutes
the phone rings but
there's no answer.
And you're sure you've
got the right number?
Well of course I had
the operator check it.
Well maybe they've got
the TV turned way up.
The phone's in the same
room, they'd hear it if
they were there.
Now calm down honey,
maybe they're out
saying good night to Carmen.
That's our goat.
Or taking a look at the
moon or they're up
in their room playing records.
Now relax, what could be wrong?
I don't know, I just wish
we hadn't left them alone.
[frolicking music]
Number one, we don't
get out of the car.
Number two, we stay
just 10 minutes.
Well if that's
all we're gonna do,
what did you put on
your best dress for?
And all that make-up?
Just in case!
Suppose he doesn't come out?
It doesn't matter,
now remember,
nobody gets out of this
car, is that understood?
[frolicking music]
[giggling]
There it is Lib, stop!
Lib turn out the lights.
Be quiet!
It kinda looks like
him, doesn't it?
Like he sounds I mean.
Sort of mysterious.
Oh Lib there's no reason
for him to come out.
He's probably in bed by now.
Well, maybe he's got a dog.
He might have to
take it for a walk.
Oh this is silly Lib,
let's go home please.
We just got here.
He's probably
sitting there, reading,
or watching TV.
If I honk I bet he'd hear it!
Well don't!
Look we can come
back in the daytime,
let's go home now, please!
If we don't see him
tonight, we never will.
Oh Lib, you said you
wouldn't get out of the car.
I'm just gonna
walk past his house.
Oh Lib please don't go!
Lib, come back Lib!
Please, Libby!
Go get her Kit,
make her come back!
Oh that's all right Tess,
nothing to worry about.
[foreboding music]
[rumbling]
She's gone Kit,
I can't see her.
[foreboding music]
[screaming]
You little tramp!
Throwing yourself
at him, chasing him.
I don't even know him!
Get outta here!
You're a liar, I heard
you on the telephone.
Now get outta here!
Please, we didn't mean
to cause any trouble,
it was just a game.
I know what kind of a game,
with a man over twice your age.
Now get outta here!
Somebody's coming!
Mrs. Marak please,
you don't understand!
You little tramp!
They caught Libby,
get back Tess, quick!
Please, let me explain!
Get outta here, go!
Look, just a minute, if
you ever try to see him
or call him again...
I won't, I promise I won't!
You'd better promise,
now get in there!
Go on!
[foreboding music]
Oh no, no please
don't take that.
Go on home!
Look honey.
You're too young.
[door slamming shut]
Get out!
[car engine revving]
[frolicking music]
[doorbell buzzing]
I met your little
business deal, Steve.
Suzette.
What did she tell you?
She lied of course.
Another childish,
empty-headed, little tramp.
Your taste is sickening.
She even lied about her name.
Ellie Mannering.
Keep it, as a souvenir.
Just a reminder that this
is your last Suzette.
And it is your last one,
get that through your
head right now.
Look I don't need
you to plan my life
or to give me orders,
you wanna crack a whip,
get yourself a dog.
Oh but the orders
are just starting.
We're gonna get married, go away
and do exactly what
you said, be together.
You're crowding me again Amy.
I got things to do.
Sure you have things to do.
With Suzette.
I heard you on the
phone with her.
I listened in the bedroom.
I also know what
happened here tonight
to Judith.
It's a simple choice, Steve.
Life with me or no life at all.
You're blackmailing
me into marrying you.
You must want it awful
bad, the ring with
the Mrs. in front of your name.
But only with you.
What you're saying
is I have no choice.
None at all.
Very simple, all I have to do
is pick up the phone
and call the police.
Well Amy, maybe it'll work.
Who knows, you might
be just what I needed.
How about a drink
huh? I can use one.
It'll work.
Maybe not at first,
but it will work.
A little ice.
Steve.
Yeah?
Please try to understand.
I had to do it this way.
[foreboding music]
What'll we drink to?
How about uh, to us?
Okay, to us.
[glasses clinging]
[romantic music]
[sudden music]
[whimpering]
Steve...
Oh I told you we
shouldn't have come.
Who was she, Lib?
Mrs. Marak.
I've just got to
get it from her.
What Lib?
She took Mommy's
registration card.
Maybe if we went back,
but explained it was all a joke?
Oh we're in enough trouble.
If you go back I'm getting
out of this car now.
[phone ringing]
Hello, Sgt. Harris.
Oh Sgt. Harris, this
is David Mannering.
The Mr. Mannering
in Oakland Hills?
Yes that's right,
on Woodbridge Road.
I've been calling my
house for almost an hour
now my children are there
alone and there's no answer.
Well where are
you calling from?
Well I'm in Santa Barbara,
90 miles from the house.
Could the phone
be out of order?
No, no I had the
operator check the number.
I wonder if you could
send a car out there?
Well yes, but could
they just be asleep?
Well of course
they might be asleep
or playing outside, but
I'd certainly appreciate it
if you'd check.
I'll send a car out
right away, Mr. Mannering.
Oh thank you
Sergeant, thank you.
Yes we'll be at
Santa Barbara 5930.
And will you call us back here?
5930, yes sir.
Thank you very much.
David let's go home, now.
Well look honey,
everything's probably fine.
There's no point in leaving now,
not until we hear
from the police.
You're gonna catch it when
Mommy and Daddy get home!
Tess Mannering if you say
one word, just one word!
She won't have to, they'll
know we were out in the car.
Oh Libby what are we gonna do.
Oh I wish I knew.
You're gonna catch it!
I know one thing,
you're going to bed, now!
But suppose I have
another bad dream!
That's your problem.
You're gonna catch it anyway.
And you better take all that
stuff off your face too!
Oh Lib if my dad
finds out he'll never
let me come here again.
You know how strict he is.
If my parents find out,
that's the end of the car.
And I'll be grounded for years.
Libby you've got to get
it, you've just got to!
Well I wanted to go back,
but who chickened out?
Yeah but who got
us into this mess?
And remember, we'd
just stay five minutes,
and nobody gets out of the car.
Then you got out!
How did I know his
wife would be there?
I told you he was
probably married.
Shouldn't have gotten
out in the first place.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Is Mr. Mannering there?
No he's not.
Is Mrs. Mannering there?
Are you Mrs. Mannering?
No, she's gone too.
This is his daughter.
Well when will
your parents be back?
Not till tomorrow morning,
can I take a message?
No, just tell them
Mr. Jackson called,
it's a business matter.
Good night.
[foreboding music]
Tess, Tess?
Did you take that pill?
Libby?
What?
How are you gonna get
the registration card?
I don't know, maybe I can
call Mrs. Marak in the morning.
Get up before my
parents come home.
You've got to Libby!
I know, I know, stop worrying.
Tess?
Oh where is she?
[foreboding music]
Tess, are you hiding in there?
Kit, Tess is gone!
Gone where?
I don't know, come on,
we've gotta find her.
Oh Libby do we
have to go outside?
She's not in the house.
[dog barking]
Now he's gone.
Tess?
Tess!
Tess, are you out there?
Come in the house this minute.
Come on.
[dog barking]
Libby she wouldn't go this far.
That idiot would go anywhere.
Oh that little fool.
Oh when I get my hands on her.
[goat bleating]
Tess?
Tess!
Oh I bet she's in here.
[rumbling]
Tess.
Tess Mannering what
are you doing in here?
I couldn't sleep, I
had another bad dream.
Well why didn't you tell me.
It's my problem, you said so.
Anyway Gypsy couldn't
sleep either.
Oh Libby, let's go back.
Another thing, I was locked in,
couldn't open the door.
[door slamming shut]
Oh Libby!
[foreboding music]
[screaming]
Relax, relax, relax.
Well, no wonder your
folks couldn't find you,
have you been out
here all night?
No we went out in Mommy's car.
Yes, with Gypsy.
That's our pony.
Okay, come on, let's
get back to the house.
You're gonna have to
phone your parents,
they're worried
stiff, come on honey.
Come on.
Come on little lady, ah.
How long have you
been out there?
Okay honey, okay.
But you gave your
mother a very bad time.
Let me talk to her David.
Libby?
Hello mother.
I'm sorry you were worried.
We were just out back.
We didn't hear the phone.
Yes I know dear but you should
never have gone out.
How's Tess, did
she take her pills?
Yeah she's fine.
Well you get right
to bed, you understand?
Yes mother, we will.
Right away, I promise.
We'll see you tomorrow, okay?
Good night, dear.
Good bye.
They were upset.
I don't blame 'em.
Okay now.
No more wandering around
outside tonight huh?
As for you.
You get to bed.
Lib do you think
they believed you?
I mean about just
being out back?
Why shouldn't they?
[car engine humming]
Oh oh, that's my father.
I'm going to bed
like he told me to.
Lib we've got to
stick to our story.
But suppose I can't get
the registration back?
Whether you do or
not, we never left here.
I can't let my father
find out, you know that.
He won't, don't worry.
Promise Lib, never to tell?
Sure Kit.
Say it, say you promise.
[doorbell ringing]
Say it!
I promise!
[car engine revving]
Hello Lib.
Hello Mr. Austin.
I gather you two gave
Mr. and Ms. Mannering
quite a scare?
We were just out back, Daddy.
At this hour?
I don't think you used
very good judgment.
Come along, Kit.
And Lib I suggest you lock
up and tuck yourself in.
I will Mr. Austin.
Bye Lib, call you tomorrow.
Good night Mr.
Austin, bye Kit.
BYE bye.
Good night Lib.
[car engine revving]
Bye.
BYE bye.
[foreboding music]
Was Mr. Austin mad?
Well, not exactly mad.
Just kind of, well, grim.
Lib, when are Mommy
and Daddy coming home?
In the morning.
What?
What time?
Uh, about nine or 10.
Lib will you sleep
with me tonight?
Oh Tess, you're such a baby.
Please, I'll do
you a favor some day.
Okay.
What'd you say?
I said okay!
Goodie!
[calming music]
Can we leave the light on?
Tess, what are you afraid of?
I'll be right here.
Move over.
Move over!
[giggling]
[foreboding music]
And that winds up the late
scores, sports fans.
It's still anybody's pennant,
anybody's ballgame
you might say.
Uh just a moment
ladies and gentlemen.
Here is a special bulletin.
The body of an
unidentified woman
was found earlier tonight
in the wooded area
adjoining Oakland Hills.
That's not far from here.
The victim, described by police
as young and attractive,
was brutally,
sadistically murdered.
According to Chief of
Detectives John Halliday.
Police were directed
to the dead woman's
shallow grave by
Linda Carson, 22,
of Abaum Grove Township.
While searching for
her dog in the woods
near Oakland Hills, at
approximately 8:30 tonight,
Ms. Carson saw a man
lurking suspiciously
among the trees.
According to Chief
Halliday, Ms. Carson saw
what the man was doing.
Digging a shallow trench
in the rocky ground.
Prompted by what she
described as a hunch,
Ms. Carson reported the
incident to the police.
According to Ms.
Carson's description,
the murderer was
tall, dark-haired,
about 40 years of age.
To repeat.
What's the matter with you kid?
Oh that's horrible.
You've been shaking like a leaf
ever since we left
the Mannerings.
Might as well level with me kid.
What have you been
up to tonight?
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
What did you say?
Nothing Daddy.
[anticipatory music]
[soothing music]
[dog barking]
Lib, Lib!
You didn't let Spot in.
He's all right.
He doesn't mind
sleeping outside.
He isn't sleeping,
he's barking.
Well then you go to sleep.
[dog barking]
I can't, he's keeping me awake.
Well then let him in.
Okay.
[dog barking]
[frolicking music]
Spot?
Shot!
Spot, Spot!
Who are you?
Tess, Tess Mannering.
Where's Suzette?
You're Steve aren't you?
That's right, where's Suzette?
Come on in, she's upstairs.
She's sleeping?
Well she was till Spot woke us.
Wait, I'll get her.
Lib, wake up Lib!
He's downstairs.
Who, Spot?
No, Steve!
What do you mean?
I mean Steve, he's downstairs.
Tess, if this is a joke.
It's not, he's
downstairs waiting for you.
[giggles]
Suzette!
What do I tell him?
Don't ask me.
Thanks.
I wonder how he found us.
I don't know.
The registration.
I bet he got it from his wife.
He probably knew how
much trouble we'd be in
without it.
No, now you stay here.
Can't I look at him from
the top of the stairs?
Well, all right.
[foreboding music]
Steve?
Steve, are you in here?
Steve, where are you?
Mr. Marak are you out there?
[screaming] [sudden music]
You're not Suzette.
You're just a kid.
Where is she?
Mr. Marak, I
pretended to be Suzette.
I'm Libby Mannering.
You pretended?
It was a game, we called people
on the telephone just for fun.
Steve?
This is Suzette, I
saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
It was just a game.
You said you saw what
I did, what did you see?
Nothing, nothing.
That was just part of the game.
But you knew who I was,
knew my name, how
did you find that?
Well in the telephone book.
We just picked any name.
I put peanut butter
and jelly on it,
that's how we found it.
We called lots of
other people too.
We said the same
thing to all of them.
I'm really sorry Mr. Marak,
we shouldn't have done it.
But I tried to
explain to your wife
that it was just a joke.
Did she give you the
registration card?
You know what I should do?
Tell your parents.
Oh no, no please,
please don't do that.
You must want
this awful bad huh?
Oh I sure do.
You don't know what a mess
I'll be in if I don't get it.
My wife was pretty upset.
I'm really sorry.
It's all right,
I calmed her down.
Well there's no use
making a federal case
out of a silly prank, hmm?
Here.
Oh, just one thing,
don't use the phone for
fun and games anymore.
[phone ringing]
Good night, and thank you.
Hello?
Libby?
Kit, you'll never guess.
I told you everything
would be all right.
You see, all your
worrying was for nothing.
I hate to say I told you so.
I've got it, Mommy's
registration card.
No he brought it here.
Steve Marak was there?
Mm-hmm!
He didn't want us to
get in any trouble.
Oh thank goodness,
is he still there?
No he's gone, but
he sure had me scared.
I would've been scared too,
[sighs] what did he look like?
Well he was kinda tall.
He had brown hair.
He was older than we
thought, about 40.
Oh Libby this is real weird.
Wait till I tell you,
a woman was murdered tonight,
I heard it on the radio,
some girl saw the
man who did it,
she saw the murderer
Libby, and he was tall,
had dark hair and middle-aged.
I saw what you did,
and I know who you are.
And look it happened at 8:30,
just when we started
calling, isn't that
a weird coincidence?
I mean kooky!
Oh it's my clad, I
have to hang up.
Kit?
[foreboding music]
This is the operator.
Operator, give me
the police, okay?
[rumbling]
[screaming]
[anticipatory music]
[screaming] [glass shattering]
Tess, get UP!
Tess, where are you?
Tess!
[door closing]
[foreboding music]
Libby hide, he's
coming after you!
Tess, get out of the
house, run for help!
[screaming]
[foreboding music]
Oh Tess!
[dog barking]
Tess, where are you?
Tess, Tess?
[crying]
Here I am Libby...
The car!
Get to the car!
[car engine sputtering]
[weeping]
[screams]
[car engine sputtering]
[weeping]
[screaming]
[gun fires]
Libby, Libby, Libby...
[crying] [dog whimpering]
She's lucky you called
this in time Mr. Austin.
She's lucky my daughter
finally told me the truth.
I wasn't scared,
really scared I mean.
But Daddy's gonna be mad.
That man broke our window
and pulled out the telephone.
You're such an idiot.
They can fix the window.
But we're not gonna
be using the phone for
a long, long time.
[frolicking music] [laughing]
[cheerful frolicking music]
[rapid garbled speaking]
Sorry, you have reached
a disconnected number.
[cheerful frolicking music]