You're...
...from Baker?
Tell Baker that I told him
all that I know already.
Tell him I want to live in peace,
understand?
That it's no use
to go on tormenting me!
I know nothing at all
about that case of coins.
Now that gold has disappeared.
But if he'd listened to me,
we could have avoided this altogether.
I went to the Army court.
There were no witnesses.
They couldn't uncover any more.
I can't tell Baker
what happened to the money.
Go back and tell him that!
Word's around you had a visitor...
...and Baker knows it.
Name of Jackson.
Jackson was here...
...or Baker's got it all wrong.
He's not wrong.
Maybe Baker would like to know
just what you and Jackson had to say...
...about the cash box.
That's not what I'm being paid for.
I'm only interested in
what name Jackson's hiding under now!
Why do you think Jackson
may be assuming another name?
I would have found him already.
When I start off to find somebody,
I find them.
That's why they pay me.
What is Baker paying you?
That your family?
Yes.
Nice family.
What does he pay you for murdering me?
$500...
...to get the name!
The name!
Carson.
Bill Carson.
That's what he calls himself now.
Here's a lot of money: $1,000.
$1,000...
...and some in gold.
That's a tidy sum.
But when I'm paid...
...I always see the job through.
It's you.
Any information?
Too much.
He said quite a bit
that should interest you...
...and one or two things
that interested me.
Such as?
The name Jackson's hiding under is...
...Bill Carson.
That's your bit.
Keep talking.
He also mentioned somethin'
about a certain...
...cash box which just happened
to disappear.
That's my bit.
Anything else?
Not enough for you, huh?
Well, you don't have to worry.
He'll never say anything to anybody again!
Perfect.
Here you are.
Here, this is for you.
You did a good job for me.
Worth $500!
I almost forgot.
He gave me $1,000.
I think his idea was that I kill you.
But you know, the pity is,
when I'm paid...
...I always follow my job through.
You know that.
No pistol, amigo.
It won't do you any good.
There are three of us.
You know that you have a face
beautiful enough to be worth $2,000?
But you don't look like
the one who will collect it.
A couple of steps back.
Thank you.
How much you worth now?
How much?
$2,000!
That's right, $2,000.
Yeah, $2,000.
¡Hijo de puta que te parió!
You'll pay for this!
I hope you end up in a graveyard...
...with the cholera, and the rabies,
and the plague!
Cut me loose!
Cut me loose, you filthy bastard!
Put me down!
I hope your mother ends up
in a two-dollar whorehouse!
Cut me loose! Cut me loose!
You can still save yourself.
Let me go, and I'll pardon you.
Let me go!
I feel sick. The blood is rushing...
I'm dry.
Agua! Water!
You swine! You son of a bitch!
You're brave with a man who's tied up!
Come back!
Come back and fight!
You bastard!
Who the hell is that?
One bastard goes in, another comes out.
Cut it out! Cut it out!
I'm an honest farmer!
I'm innocent of any...
So, you're an honest farmer.
You recognize this man?
Yeah, it's you!
Who says so? You can't even read.
Roll it up. Roll it up!
I'll give you a good idea
where you can put it.
To hell with all you sheriffs and deputies
and all who gave birth to you!
Hey, everybody, look! Look!
He's giving him the filthy money!
Judas!
You've sold my hide!
But you won't enjoy any of that money,
not a penny.
If there's justice,
that money will go to the undertakers!
Every penny of it.
You know who you are?
You want to know whose son you are?
You don't, I do. Everybody does.
You're the son of a thousand fathers!
All bastards like you!
And your mother? Your mother...
You bastard!
Your mother, it's better not to talk of her.
I never hurt anybody!
...wanted in 14 counties of this state...
...the condemned is found guilty
of the crimes of murder, armed robbery...
...of citizens, state banks,
and post offices...
...the theft of sacred objects,
arson in a state prison...
...perjury, bigamy,
deserting his wife and children...
...inciting prostitution,
kidnapping, extortion...
...receiving stolen goods,
selling stolen goods...
...passing counterfeit money,
and contrary to the laws of this state...
...the condemned is guilty of using...
Therefore, according to
the powers vested in us...
...we sentence the accused
here before us...
...Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez...
...known as the "Rat"...
...and any other aliases he might have...
...to hang by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy on his soul.
Proceed!
Five for you.
One, two, three, four...
...five for me.
Five for you...
...and five for me.
Know how much you're worth now?
No, how much?
$3,000!
There are two kinds of people
in the world, my friend.
Those with a rope around their neck...
...and the people who have the job
of doing the cutting.
Listen, the neck at the end
of the rope is mine!
I run the risks.
So, the next time, I want more than half!
You may run the risks, my friend, but...
...I do the cutting.
If we cut down my percentage...
Cigar?
...it might interfere with my aim.
But if you miss,
you had better miss very well.
Whoever double-crosses me
and leaves me alive...
...he understands nothing about Tuco.
Nothing!
Wanted in 15 counties of this state...
...the condemned, standing before us...
sitting before us...
...Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez...
...has been found guilty
by the Third District Circuit Court...
...of the following crimes:
murder, assaulting a justice of the peace...
...raping a virgin of the white race...
...and statutory rape
of a minor of the black race...
...of derailing a train
in order to rob the passengers...
What'd you find out, Shorty?
If you ask me, it seems like a book!
An armed unit, escorting a cash box
of gold coins, meets a Yankee ambush...
...and only three of them are saved.
Stevens, Baker, and Jackson.
The thing that wasn't saved, though,
was the coins.
But then the Army decides, of course,
it ought to hold a hearing...
...and Jackson's acquitted.
He disappears, and becomes Bill Carson.
I know his name.
But you don't know
just who you're lookin' for, and I do!
And when he's found,
I'd be scared to be put in his shoes!
- Where is Carson?
- All I know is Carson re-enlisted.
The poor guy's minus an eye.
He lives with a girl called Maria,
who'll tell you.
She's a fresh young whore in the territory.
Where is she?
Now, what's the name of that town?
It's someplace very near...
Santa Ana.
Adiós, half-soldier.
Hand me down a whiskey!
Glad they got him.
A man guilty of all those crimes!
People with ropes around their necks
don't always hang.
What do you mean?
Even a filthy beggar like that
has a protecting angel.
A golden-haired angel watches over him.
Of all these crimes, the accused
has made a full, spontaneous confession.
Therefore, we condemn him
to be hung by the neck until dead.
May the Lord have mercy on his soul.
Proceed.
Let's get the hell out of here!
What are you saying?
Anybody can miss a shot?
Nobody misses
when I'm at the end of the rope!
You never had a rope around your neck.
Well, I'm going to tell you something.
When that rope starts to pull tight,
you can feel the devil bite your ass!
Yeah, you're right.
It's getting tougher.
The way I figure...
...there's really not too much future
with a sawed-off runt like you.
What do you mean?
'Cause I don't think you'll ever
be worth more than $3,000.
What do you mean?
I mean, our partnership is untied.
Oh no, not you.
You remain tied.
I'll keep the money,
and you can have the rope.
You filthy, double-crossing bastard!
Of all the stinking, dirty tricks...
The way back to town is only 70 miles.
If you save your breath,
I feel a man like you could manage it.
Adiós.
You filthy bastard! Come here!
Come here! Cut this rope off!
Get off that horse!
Get off that horse! You filthy coward!
If I ever catch you...
...I'll rip your heart out and eat it!
I'll skin you alive!
I'll hang you up by your tongue.
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Such ingratitude, after all the times
I've saved your life.
You wouldn't leave me here...
Come back!
Wait! Listen, Blondie!
¡Hijo de una gran puta!
You filthy rats!
Maria.
Is that you, Bill?
Who are you?
What do you want with me?
Go on talking about Bill Carson.
I don't know him.
You were calling to him in the dark!
Where is he?
What are you gonna do?
I'll ask the questions!
Where is he?
That's enough!
I don't know where he is.
He packed his things ten days ago,
and went away with his unit.
They all left.
Which company? Where'd he go?
Third Cavalry, General Sibley.
They left for Santa Fe.
That's all I know. I swear!
I'm very sorry, but the store is closing.
Revolvers?
Revolvers!
Here's where I keep the best ones.
Remington, Colt, Farroute...
...Smith Wesson, Colt, from the Navy...
Jocelyn, another Remington, and this...
That's enough.
Cartridges.
- You wanna try the pistol, just step...
- Let's go.
Cartridge.
How much?
$20.
$50.
How much?
$100.
$200. It's all I've got!
Come here!
This morning I heard the whole thing.
They say Colonel Canby's closing in
with his Northerners...
...and no later than tomorrow
that they'll be in the city.
That's why these Southerners
are getting out!
You see, as soon as these cowards hear
there are blue shirts around, they run.
- These rebels have no will to fight!
- Poor things.
They'll soon be finished.
We get rid of these bastards...
...then we begin making money
on those Yankees.
They carry gold, not paper dollars.
And they're going to beat the South.
Look, see that one with the white beard
sitting in the wagon?
General Sibley. He looks dead.
He's finally getting out of our hair.
Hooray for Dixie!
Hooray, hooray for Dixie!
Where's the owner of that horse?
Please, mister, sir...
...a bad heart condition...
- Where?
The war has frightened me already.
I'm looking for the owner of that horse.
He's tall, blond, he smokes a cigar,
and he's a pig!
Ad Maiorem Dei Gloriam
- AMDG777.blogspot.com -
THOMAS IRWAN KRISTANTO
- IrwanKristanto@Ymail.com -
COLOURFOOL
Because Life is not only BLACK and WHITE
The Good The Bad and The Ugly
+_+ Selamat Menikmati +_+
Where is he now?!
You leave him be! He doesn't know
who rides every horse!
You stay quiet, old hen!
Upstairs. Upstairs, in Room 4, señor.
Hear that?
You rotten criminals, how dare you?!
Your spurs.
There are two kinds of spurs, my friend.
Those that come in by the door...
...and those that come in by the window.
Take off that pistol belt.
It's empty.
Mine isn't.
Even when Judas hanged himself,
there was a storm, too.
That could be cannon fire.
Cannon fire or storm,
it's all the same to you!
You ever see this before, my friend?
Throw it over the roof beam.
That's it.
And get on that!
That's right.
Now, make sure the rope is tight!
It's got to hold the weight of a pig!
Now, put the rope around your neck!
Yes, very good.
It's too big for your neck?
We'll fix that right away.
I have another system.
A little different than yours.
I don't shoot the rope.
I shoot the legs off the stool!
Adiós.
...guilty of the following crimes:
horse theft...
And Shorty?
Sorry, Shorty!
Move, come on, let's go!
I don't know. As soon as I hit
the desert, I'm thirsty.
Burns, huh?
They say people with fair skin
can't take too much.
Like that, you won't
have to carry so much.
Where are we going?
Where?
Where I'm going, amigo.
Over that way.
Another 100 miles
of beautiful sunbaked sand.
Even the armies are afraid
to march through there.
Sibley's men are retreating up there.
Canby's men are coming here...
...but no one will set foot in this hell...
...except you and me.
One hundred miles. That's a nice walk.
What was it you told me the last time?
"If you save your breath,
I feel a man like you could manage it."
And if you won't manage it, you'll die.
Only slowly.
Very slowly, old friend.
After you, please. Start walking.
Taking a rest?
Come on, Blondie, we don't have
very far to go. Only 70 miles.
Only eight and a half hours more
before sunset.
That's not too bad.
Come on!
And so, Blondie...
...it's goodbye.
$200,000 in gold. It's yours.
Just get me water!
What's that you say?
Who the hell are you?
My name's Bill Carson now.
Surprise attack.
All dead.
My name is Jackson. Not Carson.
Yeah, yeah, glad to meet you, Carson.
I'm Lincoln's grandfather.
What was that you said about the dollars?
$200,000, all mine.
Was the Third Cavalry's.
Baker has nothing.
The gold...
I hid the gold. The gold is safe!
Where? Here?
Talk!
In the cemetery.
Which cemetery?
On Sad Hill.
There's a grave by the...
Which grave?
Have a name? Have a number?
Come on, you dummy, talk!
There's no number.
There's a name.
It's written.
Water!
You talk first, eh?
I'll give you the water later!
Sad Hill Cemetery, okay?
In a grave, okay.
But it must have
a name or a number on it.
There must be 1,000, 5,000, you!
Don't die.
Don't die! I'll get you water!
Stay there.
Don't move, I'll get you water.
Don't die until later!
Get away from there!
He's dead.
I'll kill you!
If you do that, you'll always be poor.
Just like the greasy rat that you are.
If I were you, I'd...
...keep me alive.
What did he tell you?
A name.
Name on a grave.
What name?
Blondie, don't die.
Don't die! I'm your friend.
Please don't die. Please! I'm your friend!
I'll help you. I'll help you!
Don't move. I'll be right back.
I'll get the water.
Don't die like that pig.
Water, Blondie?
Don't drink! It's no good for you.
Feel better?
Blondie, what's the matter?
Please don't die!
I've got a very sick man here.
But we have no more beds here.
Let him have yours!
- Where is Pablo Ramirez?
- Padre Ramirez.
He is away at the moment.
He should be back any day now.
It doesn't matter. For the moment,
we'll take very good care of my friend.
May God be praised.
In case you didn't know it...
...God is on our side, too.
Because he hates the Yanks.
Father, is he still breathing?
Yes, of course.
You're heavy.
All right, put a fresh bandage on him.
Put him in my cell.
Out, soldier. Out you go, come on.
Look out for him, please.
He's like a brother to me!
Father, did he speak?
Did he say anything?
Did he ask for me?
Did he speak about anything?
No, he hasn't spoken as yet.
But you mustn't worry.
He's both young and strong.
That's what's kept him going until now.
He should regain his strength
in a very short time.
Thank you, Father. You don't know
how much this boy's life means to me!
The old Father tells me
you'll be up and around in a few days.
You're very lucky to have me
so close when it happened.
Think, if you'd been on your own.
I mean, when...
...when one is ill...
...it's good to have somebody close by,
friends or relations.
Do you...
...you have parents, Blondie?
A mother?
Not even a mother.
No one.
You're all alone, huh? Like me, Blondie.
We're all alone in the world.
I have you, you have me.
Only for a little while, I mean.
It had to happen now.
What a dirty rotten trick of fate!
We could have all that money
in our hands.
I must tell you the truth, Blondie.
In my place, you would do the same thing.
It's all over for you now.
There's nothing anyone can do anymore.
It's my fault! Mine, mine!
I'll tell you one thing, Blondie.
If I knew that my last hour had come...
...I swear, in my place, in your place,
I would do the same thing.
I would tell about the gold.
Yes, yes I would!
I would tell the name on the grave.
After all, what good is the money to you
if you're dead?
I know the name of the cemetery.
But you know how many graves
there are there?
Please.
Please, have a little.
Coffee? Please tell me the name.
On the grave.
If I get my hands on the $200,000...
...I'll always honor your memory.
I swear it! I'll always honor your memory!
Come closer.
Tell me.
I'll sleep better...
...knowing my good friend...
...is by my side...
...to protect me.
"Tuco, water. Please, water."
But if I get that name from you,
I'll give you water!
All right, you dirty skunk,
get your ass off the bed!
Come on, come on, the party's over.
The wagon is all ready to go.
From the way the wounded
are pouring into this place...
...we better get the hell out of here
before we get caught up in the war.
Tuco, Father Ramirez is back.
This is something I have to look into.
It'll only take a minute. Get moving.
- Where? This way?
- Yes.
Hey, Pablo!
Don't you recognize me?
It's me, Tuco!
Let me embrace you.
I don't know the right thing!
I was just passing by here.
I said to myself...
...I wonder if my brother
remembers his brother.
Did I do wrong?
It doesn't matter. I'm very happy.
You've seen me, Tuco.
Yeah, well, I'm very glad I came.
Oh, my uniform. It's a long story.
Let's talk about you. It's more important.
You look very well.
A bit thin, perhaps, but...
...you always were thin, eh Pablito?
What about our parents?
Only now do you think of them?
To begin after nine years?
Nine years?
So it's nine years.
Our mother has been dead a long time.
Our father died only a few days ago.
That's why I was away.
He asked for you to be there.
But there was only me.
And you?
Outside of evil,
what else have you managed to do?
It seems to me
you once had a wife someplace.
Not one, lots of them!
One here, one there,
wherever I found them.
Go on, preach me a sermon, Pablo.
What good would that be?
Just keep on the way you're going.
Go away.
The Lord have mercy on your soul.
I'll go, I'll go. While I'm waiting
for the Lord to remember me...
...I., Tuco Ramirez,
brother of Brother Ramirez...
...will tell you something.
You think you're better than I am.
Where we came from,
if one did not want to die of poverty...
...one became a priest or a bandit!
You chose your way, I chose mine.
Mine was harder.
You talk of our mother and father.
You remember when you left
to become a priest.
I stayed behind!
I must have been ten, twelve.
I don't remember which, but I stayed.
I tried, but it was no good.
Now I am going to tell you something.
You became a priest because you were...
...too much of a coward to do what I do!
Please, forgive me, brother.
My belly's full.
Nice guy, my brother.
I didn't tell you
my brother was in charge here.
Everything, like the pope almost.
He's in charge in Rome.
My brother, he says to me:
"Stay, brother, don't go home.
"We never see each other.
"Here, there's plenty to eat and drink.
Bring your friend, too."
Whenever we see each other,
he never lets me go.
It's always the same story.
My brother, he's crazy about me.
That's so.
Even a tramp like me,
no matter what happens...
...I know there's a brother somewhere
who will never refuse me a bowl of soup.
Sure.
Well, after a meal,
there's nothing like a good cigar.
Wake up, you!
The troops are coming!
Blue or gray?
They're gray like us. Let's say "hello"
to them and then get going.
Hurrah for the Confederacy! Hurrah!
Down with General Grant!
Hurrah for General... what's his name?
Lee!
God is with us
because he hates the Yanks, too!
God is not on our side
'cause he hates idiots also.
Prisoners of war...
...forward...
...march!
Form a single file.
Robert Clark.
Present.
Sam Richmond.
Bill Carson.
I said Bill Carson!
Hey, Blondie, isn't that Angel Eyes?
All right, what's he doing? Sleeping?!
Yeah, and you better be Bill Carson.
That's me!
Please, Carson.
Answer, "Present"!
What are you, deaf?
Now, suppose you say "present," Carson.
I like big fat men like you.
When they fall, they make more noise.
And sometimes they never get up.
Wallace...
...that's enough.
Sergeant!
The captain wants to see you right away.
Be sure these two get good treatment.
Hey, Blondie, did you hear that?
Good treatment!
For the last time, sergeant...
...I'm telling you...
...I want the prisoners
treated as prisoners.
No more brutality!
There's hundreds of prisoners out there
and only a few men to guard them.
What am I supposed to do?
I have to have respect!
I think that you'll manage to gain
their respect by treating them better!
Are our men treated that well
in Andersonville Camp?
I don't give a goddamn
what they do in Andersonville!
While I'm in charge here,
the prisoners are not to be...
...tortured...
...or cheated...
...or murdered!
Is that an accusation?
Sergeant, gangrene is eating
my leg away...
...not my eyes.
I know the prisoners here are being
robbed systematically.
I know there's scum around,
or bivouacked near the camp, waiting...
...for someone to deliver this loot.
But as long as I'm commandant,
I won't permit any such trickery!
Am I clear?
Yes, sir.
Just as long as you're the commandant.
Yes, sergeant.
I know this leg means
I won't last very long...
...but I pray I can manage
to have enough time...
...to amass evidence and bring to a
court-martial all those who discredit...
...and dishonor the uniform...
...of the Union!
I wish you luck.
Ad Maiorem Dei Gloriam
- AMDG777.blogspot.com -
THOMAS IRWAN KRISTANTO
- IrwanKristanto@Ymail.com -
COLOURFOOL
Because Life is not only BLACK and WHITE
You and the others better lay low
for a few days.
I'll keep this. You go.
Wallace will let you know.
- Bring me Carson.
- Right.
Angel Eyes said for us
to lay low for a few days.
But we'll keep close enough
to keep an eye on things.
Come on, saddle your horses.
Come on in, Tuco.
Don't be bashful.
There's no formalities, here.
It's been a long time!
You're hungry.
Sit down. Eat!
I knew it, I knew it!
The minute I saw you, I said to myself:
"Look at that pig, Angel Eyes...
"...I'll bet he's got himself an easy job!
"And he never forgets a friend!"
I never forget old friends, Tuco.
It's good to see old friends again.
Especially when they come
from so far away...
...and have so much to talk about.