Hey.
Bathsheba Everdene.
Bathsheba.
The name has always sounded strange to me.
I don't like to hear it said out loud.
My parents died when I was very young
so there's no-one to ask where it came from.
I've grown accustomed
to being on my own.
Some say even too accustomed.
Too independent.
Miss!
My scarf.
I lost it.
You must be Farmer Oak.
Gabriel, yes.
My aunt's told me about you.
I'm working on her farm for the winter.
This is your land.
I'm trespassing.
You're welcome here.
Good afternoon, Farmer Oak.
Good afternoon, miss.
Come by, George.
George, away! Enough, George!
Enough!
Stand. Stand.
George, stand.
Away!
George, away!
He doesn't know when to stop,
Young George.
What's this one called?
Old George.
So you find me amusing, do you?
Goodness, it's Mr. Oak.
...and after that she was gonna be a governess.
But she was far too wild.
Always has been.
Miss Bathsheba Everdene.
I've brought you a lamb.
Ohh.
Thank you, Mr. Oak. He's such a dear thing.
He's come too soon
and won't last the winter...
...so I thought you'd like to rear it instead.
Thank you, that's very kind.
I'll make some tea.
-The lamb is not why I came.
-Go on.
Well, Miss Everdene, I wanted to ask...
...would you like to marry me?
I've never asked anyone before.
No.
I should hope not.
Well...
...perhaps I... I should...
-Perhaps I should leave.
-Mr. Oak, there are things to consider.
Is someone waiting for you?
No, but that doesn't mean I'll marry you.
Good day to you, then.
Mr. Oak!
Mr. Oak! Wait!
I didn't say I wouldn't marry you, either.
I haven't ever really thought about it.
I have 100 acres and 200 sheep.
If I pay off the money, the farm is ours.
You could have a piano in a year or two.
Flowers and birds
and a frame for cucumbers.
A baby or two.
-Mr. Oak...
-Or more.
I will always be there for you.
Mr. Oak, I don't want a husband.
I'd hate to be some man's property.
I shouldn't mind being a bride at a wedding
if I could be one without getting a husband.
That's stupid talk.
You are better-off than I, Mr. Oak.
I have an education and nothing more.
-You could do much, much better than me.
-That's not the reason.
I'm too independent for you.
If I were to marry, I'd want somebody to
tame me and you'd never be able to do it.
You'd grow to despise me.
I would not.
Ever.
Goodbye, Miss Everdene.
What is it, old boy?
Stay here.
Stay here, Old George. Stay here.
George!
No!
It's all yours.
We take no pleasure in this.
We wish you well, Mr. Oak.
Bathsheba.
What is it?
My love. It's your poor uncle's will.
What does it say?
Read it.
Read!
He's left you everything. It's all yours.
Oh, my goodness.
Take care, you hear.
Walk on.
Bye.
So who will join us, lads?
Which one of you fine boys
will put on the scarlet uniform...
...and proudly serve
his Queen and country?
See the world.
Form an orderly line, gentlemen,
at the front.
This gentleman in the straw hat,
step forward, sir.
That's my sweetheart, right there.
You, sir, next to the pretty lady.
There's a good strong figure of a man.
Join us, sir.
Go on. You'd make a fine soldier.
-Always room for a gentleman of your caliber.
-It's a roof over your head. Food.
Who wants a fine wage?
Excuse me.
You might try Weatherbury.
If you're looking for work...
...there's a farm there
needs all the help it can get.
I will. Thank you.
You should have a cloak for a day like this.
Francis will take care of me.
We are to be married soon.
Goodbye.
Come on, a decent wage.
Make your family proud.
Food, shelter. Who will join us?
Go and wake up the other farms!
Get them down here! We need more hands!
We need more men now! Wake them up!
Go and get the Smith brothers first.
Protect yourself, the fire's spreading!
Who's in charge here?
We're losing the ricks! The rick is lost.
We need to save the barn.
Come on, help me!
Come on, get some more water!
Get some more water!
-We need to push this out. Come on!
-Heave!
Heave!
Come on, push!
Everybody out! Everybody out!
Water! More over here!
The barn's going up!
Get the sacks out, the roof's about to go!
What's he doing up there?
We lose the barn, we lose everything.
Joseph, bring those brooms over
and let's get this sorted out.
Look sharp, men, the farmer's here.
Mr. Oak, is that you?
Perhaps you want a shepherd, ma'am?
I owe you an immense debt, Mr. Oak.
If I'd have lost all of this,
I'd have lost my farm.
Your farm?
My inheritance. My home, too,
for a while when my parents died.
When my uncle passed away,
he left it to me.
Of course, it's a little ragged now...
...but this once used to be
the finest farm for miles.
And I intend to make it so again.
Perhaps you find the idea preposterous.
I no longer have that luxury.
I'm truly sorry to hear of your loss,
Mr. Oak...
...but if our reversal of fortune
causes you any embarrassment...
Not at all-- ma'am.
Billy Smallbury? 9 and 8 pence.
Joseph Poorgrass?
-Go on, Joseph.
-Go on, lad.
Hat off.
-And what do you do, Joseph?
-I does general things.
And in spring I shoot the rooks
and help at pig killing, sir.
I mean ma'am.
7 and 9 pence.
And another 9 because I'm new.
Thank you, ma'am.
Now, Fanny Robbin?
Where is Fanny Robbin?
Where is she?
She's run away, ma'am.
She's gone off with a soldier, ma'am.
Not a soldier, a sergeant.
Bailiff Pennyways?
Here is 10 shillings and a further 10.
Why?
This ends our association.
You are dismissed.
I beg pardon, miss.
When my uncle was alive,
this was a fine, productive farm.
Since his death, it has fallen into ruin.
Now see here, miss.
You can't get rid of people like that.
I have resolved not to have a bailiff
and to manage everything.
Mr. Pennyways, if you'll listen to me
for a moment.
Mr. Pennyways, a fire threatened to destroy
the barn and you are nowhere to be found.
I have no use for a man like you,
Mr. Pennyways.
You are dismissed.
Get out while you can, if I were you.
Now you've all met our new shepherd
Mr. Oak.
You understand your duties, Mr. Oak?
If I don't, I'll ask, ma'am.
From now on you have a mistress,
not a master.
I don't yet know my talents in farming,
but I shall do my best.
Don't suppose, because I'm a woman,
I don't know the difference between
bad goings-on and good.
I shall be up before you're awake.
I shall be a-field before you are up.
It is my intention to astonish you all.
Back to work, please.
Perhaps I should wait here?
No.
Nonsense, Liddy. You're my companion.
-All of these?
-All of them.
Head high, Liddy.
If they stare, do not hesitate.
Remember, we have as much right
to be here as anyone.
Good morning.
-Liddy, if you lay things out.
-Yes, miss.
Gentlemen, shall we get back to business?
There you go, sir. If you feel it,
you can feel the quality.
-This is fine grain, miss.
-Thank you.
Perhaps we should leave, miss.
-But none of it as good as this lot.
-It's good stuff, I'll grant you that.
-Well, it's up to you. If you wanna go elsewhere...
-No, no, no...
Farmer Stone?
It's Miss Everdene.
Farmer Everdene's niece.
He talked about you
with such great admiration.
Of course, you're welcome to try elsewhere
but I think you'll find the grain as good
as it's ever been.
-Mr. Stone?
-How much?
-£5 a quarter.
-£3 10 shillings.
It's the same grain, Mr. Stone.
You paid my uncle £5.
£3.10.
This gentleman will pay me
the proper price.
Apparently not, no.
-£4.
-£4.10.
£4.05.
Perhaps I should move on.
-Liddy, would you help me with this gentleman?
-Of course.
Perhaps you'd like a sample?
-How much?
-£5 a quarter.
Very well.
£4.10.
He's rich, he's handsome.
He sends the local girls mad.
The Taylor sisters
worked on him for 2 years.
Jane Perkins spent £20 on new clothes...
...and might as well have
thrown the money out the window.
It's said, when he was young,
his sweetheart jilted him.
People always say that.
Women don't jilt men. Men jilt us.
Did someone jilt you, miss?
Certainly not.
A man did ask to marry me once.
Some time ago.
But I was too restless to be tied down.
What a luxury-- to have a choice.
"Kiss my foot, sir, my face
is for mouths of consequence."
It wasn't like that at all.
Why?
Did you love him?
No, but I rather liked him.
Anyway, it's impossible now.
Mr. Boldwood.
Don't shoot me, please.
I had no intention of shooting you.
It's Miss Everdene. Your neighbor.
Farmer Everdene's niece.
I'm managing the farm alone now.
Perhaps you've heard?
Yes, I'm sure you'll do very well.
In the circumstances.
Well-- as you say, we're neighbors.
Look what I've got here.
-What is it?
-Listen to this.
The rose is red
The violet blue
Carnation's sweet and so are you
It's a Valentine's card. I'm going to send it
to Joseph Poorgrass...
...just to see the look of panic
on his stupid face.
Poor boy. It's a little bit far-fetched, isn't it?
What about-- Mr. Oak, then?
No. Not Mr. Oak.
Imagine if we sent it to Mr. Boldwood.
Ignoring you like that, all high and mighty.
Mr. Boldwood?
Perhaps not.
Why not?
Because I don't think he'll see the humor.
Perhaps he wouldn't,
perhaps it's too much.
-Mr. Boldwood.
-You're right. Perhaps it is.
So we're gonna toss for it.
Liddy!
Come on.
-Open Joseph.
-No, Jan Coggan.
Open Jan Coggan.  Closed Boldwood.
-Sergeant Troy, 11:00.
-Yes, Sergeant Troy. And?
-Miss Fanny Robbin.
-Welcome. Step down the front.
-Where is she?
-I don't know.
Here she comes.
Sorry I'm late, old boy.
Not long now.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here
in the sight...
-I can only wait a few more minutes.
-She'll be here.
What do you think is happening?
I don't think she's coming, old boy.
Come on.  Go on, off you go.
That's it...go on.
-Morning, my love.
-Come on.
Bring them in, John.
Miss Everdene's here, you better do your
best work. I'm looking at you, Coggan.
Yeah, you keep quiet, Liddy.
What you doing?
Perhaps you'd care to lend a hand?
-You don't think I would?
-No, you wouldn't.
Come here.
There, she's getting in.
Well done, ma'am.
Gangway through.
Hey, Joseph. Joseph, look.
Good morning, Mr. Boldwood.
Miss Everdene. Mr. Boldwood wondered
if he might have a word with you.
Mr. Boldwood. Of course.
1,000 acres. A mix of arable and livestock.
Adjacent to Everdene.
An orchard. Glasshouse.
I have some interesting pigs.
Some other time, perhaps.
Thank you.
You have a very beautiful house.
Mr. Boldwood?
Miss Everdene.
I want...
...very much --more than anything...
...to have you as my wife.
Miss Everdene, marry me.
I...
...I feel...
...though I respect you very much...
...I do not feel what would justify me...
...in accepting your offer.
I have known disappointments before...
...but I would never have asked
in this instance had I not been, er...
...led to believe...
...unless, unless I am mistaken.
The Valentine.
No, you're not mistaken
but I should never have sent it.
Forgive me, it was thoughtless
to disturb your peace of mind.
So you meant it as a joke?
No. No, not as a joke.
Not exactly. It was-- impetuous.
I see.
Perhaps you think I am too old?
But I will care for you
more than anyone your own age.
-I'm sure you would...
-I will protect you.
You shall have dresses...
...a gig. A piano.
I amuse you.
No.
It's only...
...I have a piano.
And I have my own farm.
And I have no need for a husband--
no matter how honored I am by the offer.
I think I'd like to return home.
Yes, er... I'll, er...
...I'll get someone to drive you.
Mr. Boldwood, I've made you miserable.
It was very wicked of me.
Will you reconsider?
Let me think.
Yes.
Yes, I'll give you time.
I will wait.
You're working late, Mr. Oak.
Will you teach me?
Here.
Spin the wheel.
Incline it, like that.
And slide it gently. Spin the wheel.
Bit faster. Like that. Very good.
-Now slide it.
-I, it's...
...getting stuck.
I wanted to ask...
...did the men say anything today
about Mr. Boldwood?
-They did.
-What did they say?
That you'd be married
before the end of the year.
Come on.
Well, I'd like you to contradict it,
to the men.
-Well, Bathsheba...
-"Miss Everdene," please.
If Mr. Boldwood
did really speak of marriage...
...I'm not going to tell stories
just to please you.
I just wanted you to mention that it might
not be true I was going to marry him.
I could say that. But I could also give you
an opinion on what you've done.
I dare say,
but I don't want your opinion, Mr. Oak.
I suppose not.
Well, what is your opinion?
That you're greatly to blame for playing
pranks on a man like Mr. Boldwood.
Your actions were unworthy of you.
Unworthy? May I ask
where my unworthiness lies?
In rejecting you, perhaps?
I've long given up thinking of that.
Or wishing it, either.
But I will say this: leading on a man
you don't care for is beneath you.
I cannot allow a man to criticize
my private conduct.
You will please leave the farm
at the end of the week.
I'd prefer to go at once.
Then go.
I never want to see your face again.
Very well, Miss Everdene.
Whoa, there we are. There.
What's wrong with them?
They broke fence and ate the young clover.
Makes their stomachs swell.
-Well, what do we do now?
-Nothing. The whole flock is blasted.
You mean they're all going to die?
-Most probably.
-Another one gone here, ma'am.
Only one way of saving them.
You must pierce their side with a tool.
A hollow tube. Pricker inside.
Well, can you do it?
-This one's still alive.
-No.
-Can I?
-Oh good Lord, no.
One inch to the right or the left,
and you kill the ewe for sure.
Not even a shepherd can do it --as a rule.
Well who, then?
Gabriel.
Gabriel!
Gabriel Oak, wait!
Miss Everdene needs you.
Why are you alone? Did you find him?
Yes, miss.
So what did he say?
He said...
Joseph?
He said you're to go in person
and request him civilly in a proper manner.
Where does he get his airs?
I'll do no such thing.
He said you'd say that. He said to reply:
"Beggars can't be choosers."
Mr. Oak.
Gabriel.
Please don't desert me, Gabriel.
I need your help.
Make room for me.
-I wanna see.
-No, don't you start, Liddy, be quiet.
Find the spot.
Between the ribs.
-Oh Lord!
-No, no, no, no, no.
Now...
I can see his heart beating.
-Come on.
-Come on, girl.
Come on.
She'll be all right. She'll be all right.
You alright? Alright, Pixie!
Lay me low
Where no-one can see me
Where no-one can find me
Where no-one can hurt me
Please, quiet.
Oh early one morning
As I was a walking
The fields and the meadows
They looked so green and gay
The birds sang so sweetly
So pleasant and so charming
So early in the morning
At the break of day
Miss. Mr. Boldwood is here.
Thank you. Thank you, Jan. Jan, thank you.
Mr. Boldwood. What a pleasant surprise.
Will you join us?
Nice to have you, sir.
A song, ma'am.
I have no voice.
Come on, ma'am, you've got a lovely voice.
Come all you fair and tender girls
That flourish in your prime
Beware, beware, keep your garden fair
Let no man steal your thyme
For when your thyme it is past and gone
He'll care no more for you
And every place where your thyme was waste
Will all spread o'er with rue
The gardener's son was standing by
Three flowers he gave to me
The pink, the blue and the violet true
And the red, red rosy tree
But I refused the red rose bush
And gained the willow tree
That all the world may plainly see
How my love slighted me
-I thought we were rather good together.
-So did I.
We would make a fine duo.
I wanted to thank you for not approaching me
on that subject again.
Well, it has not been easy.
Do you wish me to...accompany you
back to the house?
No, I like to walk around the farm
every night to make sure all is safe.
Then I, I can walk...with you.
I've done it many times alone.
Goodnight, Mr. Boldwood. You've been
very kind. A pleasure to see you.
-Who are you?
-I'm sorry. I seem to be lost.
We're entangled. Are you hurt?
-No.
-I'm looking for Weatherbury.
-I hope I didn't startle you.
-We've got...hitched together somehow.
-Here, allow me.
-No. No. Please, let me do it myself.
If you lift your foot for a moment.
Please don't stare.
I don't think I've ever seen a face
as beautiful as yours.
You shouldn't be here.
Please let me have the lamp.
A mighty impressive harvest
this looks like.
Miss...
...look.
Who is he, Liddy?
Sergeant Francis Troy. Noble blood,
full of promise. Very sharp and trim.
Well-educated. There was good things
expected of him.
He threw it all in to be a soldier.
-Well, I won't have it.
-What are you doing, miss?
I'm going to tell him to leave.
Sergeant Troy, I must absolutely insist that
you leave at this very moment.
I can't.
Will you follow me, please?
What angers you, exactly?
Please.
What I said or the way I said it?
You must know.
There must be some man
who tells you that you're beautiful.
-Oh, not to my face, no...
-But there is someone who kisses you?
I've never been kissed.
Why couldn't you have just passed by
and said nothing?
Do you forgive me?
-I do not.
-Why?
Because the things you say...
I said that you were beautiful.
I wonder if you fight as well as you speak.
Better.
Meet me-- tomorrow.
I can't.
You don't want to?
Yes, but...
-Then you must.
-I mustn't.
Nobody would know.
Please go now.
Tomorrow.
8:00.
The hollow in the ferns.
Do you trust me?
I do.
I give you my word as a soldier,
I will not harm you.
The sword is blunt...
...but you must not flinch.
I'll try not to.
You cut my hair.
This sword could skin you alive.
-But you told me I was safe.
-And you were. Entirely safe.
I gave you my word.
Now I will take this.
Miss Everdene.
Perhaps I could walk with you?
I'm quite happy to walk by myself.
You should have nothing to do with him.
He's not good enough for you.
He's a perfectly decent man.
-That's not what I believe.
-Why? What have you heard?
You don't know him at all. It's all rumors.
-Prejudice simply because he's a soldier.
-I like soldiers. But not this one.
I believe him to have no conscience at all.
Stay clear. Don't listen to him.
Don't believe him.
Get rid of him.
And what is it to you?
I'm not such a fool as to imagine I might stand
a chance now that you are so above me.
But don't suppose I'm content to stay
a nobody all my life.
One day I will leave you.
You can be sure of that.
But for now, I care for you too much
to see you go to ruin because of him.
So if you don't mind, I'll...
...I'll stay by your side.
Good evening.
Mr. Boldwood...
...you have been a dear friend to me
these past months.
And it is because I value our friendship
so greatly that I am writing.
I am honored by your proposal
and have given it much thought...
...but I must tell you that,
to my own surprise...
...I have undergone what can only be
described as a change of heart...
...and I'm afraid I cannot accept your offer.
I wasn't sure you'd be here.
Where else would I be?
You ready?
Are you sure?
How does this sound?
Mrs. Bathsheba Troy.
All right?
Walk on.
Gentlemen. Ladies and gentlemen.
A short time ago I had the privilege...
...and the simple fortune
of meeting this angel.
Your mistress.
And now I stand before you her husband...
...your master...
...and the proudest man you will ever see.
So, please--charge your glasses...
...and sing out to my most beautiful wife...
...Mrs. Bathsheba Troy.
Miss Everdene...
there's going to be a storm.
Oak, you big lump. To me.
There's going to be a storm. We need to
protect the ricks or we'll lose the harvest.
I need 5 to 6 men for an hour, no more.
-Frank, perhaps we ought to...
-No. Darling, it's our wedding celebration.
It will not rain tonight. My wife forbids it.
Now if you'll excuse me.
Friends!
One more thing.
I may no longer be Sergeant Troy...
...but I remain a soldier in this one respect!
The finest bottles of French brandy...
...a triple strength dose for every man.
Cheers! To your health!
"Pretty Polly Pretty Polly
It's I've come a-woo-in'"
She says, "Creep and crawl through
the window then and...
"...then let's get doin'
And lay your leg over me, over me, do"
"Oh, me britches is tight
and I cannot undo 'em
and I cannot undo 'em"
"There's a knife on the window sill, love,
take it to 'em
"And lay your leg over me..."
About 40 weeks after,
the fine baby come bawlin'
Never regretted that creepin' and crawlin'
"Lay your leg over me, over me..."
Gabriel!
What can I do?
It's too dangerous!
I'm coming up!
Come on.
Hold it down.
Still no rain.
It'll come.
Come on, hold me! Come here. Come here.
Gabriel, I've been a fool.
I've always had contempt for silly girls...
...dazzled by flattery
in a scarlet uniform and...
...and now I've done
what I swore I would never do.
But he told me about another woman...
...a woman more beautiful that
he'd loved before and I couldn't bear it.
So somewhere between jealousy
and distraction, I married him.
I don't want an opinion
on the subject, I just...
In fact, I forbid it.
Go to bed.
I'll finish it on my own.
Gabriel...
...thank you.
Sir?
Mr. Boldwood, sir!
I wanted to ensure
your mistress' crops were safe.
Good work, Gabriel.
She's lucky to have you.
Wait a moment, sir.
You seem unwell, sir.
You should go home.
Yes--
Yes. I will.
Oak.
You know that things
have not gone well with me, lately.
I was going to get a little settled in life.
But, er...
...it was not to be.
I daresay I'm something of a...
...a joke about the parish.
But I do wanna make one thing clear.
There was no jilting on her part.
We were never engaged.
No matter what people say.
She promised me nothing.
And yet...
...Gabriel...
...I feel the most terrible grief.
Not a word to her.
We understand each other, yes?
Yes, sir.
Sit.
Stay. Now turn around.
-Can you spare a coin, please?
-No, no.
Hit him!
Come on!
Pay up, Mr. Troy.
Just take it.
Sir, excuse me.
Could you spare a coin, please?
No.
Fanny?
Hello, Frank.
Hello.
You're so pale.
-Oh, Frank.
-Darling, your hands are shaking.
I thought you said All Souls, not All Saints.
I went to the wrong church.
When I got there you'd gone.
And I don't blame you...
...but it's been very hard, Frank. I...
Not now.
My wife mustn't see you.
Your wife?
Mrs. Troy is very beautiful.
No more than you.
Frank, I must tell you,
I'm carrying your child.
What?
What if I told you that
I'd made a terrible mistake?
But that I will make amends.
I swear on my life I will find a home for you
and our baby.
-You've sworn before, Frank.
-No, this time... This time...
Go to Budmouth. Stay at the Union.
-The workhouse, Frank?
-Tonight, just tonight. One night.
And then meet me tomorrow at 10:00
on the bridge.
I'll bring you all the money I have
and I'll find a home for you.
You'll be safe, my darling.
And I promise you, I promise you...
...I will make amends.
Get back in the carriage.
Do you know who that woman is?
I do.
-Who is she?
-She's nothing.
Get back in the carriage.
Frank...
Could you let me have £20?
What for?
I need it.
If you continue to gamble,
we will lose the farm.
-It's not for gambling.
-What's it for?
Why should it matter what it's for?
It's my money.
I work for it, don't I?
No. You don't.
Not proper farm work.
Don't do something you'll regret.
The money is required for farm expenses.
No mistake, Mr. Oak.
This was Miss Robbin's last known abode.
Fanny was my uncle's servant
and we shall treat her with respect.
Perhaps we should take her to the church,
just for tonight.
No, bring her inside, please.
What did she die of, Liddy?
I don't know, miss.
There were rumors but...
Fanny had a sweetheart, didn't she?
Yes, miss.
A soldier.
Please, come and sit upstairs with me.
I seem to cry a great deal these days.
I never used to cry at all.
Goodnight, Liddy.
'Night, miss.
What?
Who is it?
-I can't stay...
-Stay, stay. Stay.
Don't kiss them, Frank.
I'm still your wife.
This woman, dead as she is...
...is more to me than you ever were, or are,
or can be.
You are nothing to me now.
Nothing.
Mrs. Troy?
I'm afraid...
I'm afraid your husband has drowned.
-That's a great responsibility, sir.
-Nonsense.
No reason why a man of your ability
shouldn't be able to superintend 2 farms.
And why shouldn't there be stronger links
between our establishments?
Think of it. 2,000 acres
under your sole charge.
A share of my profits.
-Miss Everdene needs me here.
-And her farm will have priority.
-I'd still need Miss Everdene's permission.
-But, of course.
Of course, I wouldn't dare do anything
without her blessing. And...
...if it'll help sway your decision...
...there's an old comrade of yours here.
Georgie.
Had to go all the way to Norcombe Hill
to find this old fella.
You pleased?
Yes, sir, very much.
And I'll have your decision soon, yes?
You will, sir.
Hey, Georgie.
Come on. Come on.
Gabriel, you're getting on in the world.
-Of course you must accept the offer.
-Only with your approval.
If I lose the farm, there may be no future
for any of us here.
You know where my loyalty lies.
You're a man of great talent.
It's only natural that you should rise.
I've no desire to hold you back.
Thank you.
Come on, Georgie.
Forgive me-- I understand there are debts.
Your late husband.
Perhaps,
perhaps we should change the subject.
Perhaps I can help.
Mr. Boldwood, that's a very kind offer...
...but I would never dream
of accepting any money.
I am a middle-aged man...
...willing to protect you
for the rest of your life.
You may run your farm, if you wish.
Without risk.
I'll pay your...
...departed husband's debts
and guarantee its financial stability.
It can be your pastime.
Of course, we'd...need to wait...
...for propriety's sake.
But when you're ready...
...I'm offering you shelter.
Comfort. A safe harbor.
As my wife.
You must at least admire my persistence.
I do.
-And like me?
-Yes.
And...respect me?
Yes. Very much.
Which is it? Like or respect?
It is difficult for a woman
to define her feelings...
...in a language chiefly
made by men to express theirs.
If you worry about a lack of passion
on your part, a lack of...
...desire...
...if you worry about marrying me
merely out of guilt...
...and, er...
...pity...and compromise, well...
...I don't mind.
When must you give your answer?
By Christmas.
It's a terrible responsibility.
I hold that man's future in my hands.
His sanity, too, perhaps.
-Could you care for him?
-You may suppose love is wanting.
But love's a worn-out, miserable thing
for me now.
Why are you asking me?
I need someone who's objective.
Indifferent.
Then I'm afraid
you're asking the wrong man.
Good evening, Mr. Oak.
Good evening.
-That's it.
-Mind.
I appreciate you coming along, Oak.
Yes, very good. Well done.
Just more, more things.
So what do you think?
I'm not in the habit of organizing parties.
Perhaps we should make it an annual event.
Every Christmas Eve.
I've invited the whole village.
Do you think they'll come?
-Do you think Miss Everdene will come?
-I'm sure she will.
And you'll come too, I hope.
I know Miss Everdene would like you
to be here.
Perhaps, for an hour or so.
Look, I'm shaking. I'm so nervous.
Gabriel, will you...
-As well as you can, please.
-I'll try.
Is there a knot
that's particularly fashionable?
You're asking the wrong man.
What about women?
Does a woman keep her promise?
She has promised?
An implied promise.
-Once again, I'm...
-Will she do what's right?
If it's not inconvenient to her.
Oak, you've become quite cynical lately.
She never promised that first time.
Therefore, she has never broken her promise.
She hasn't promised this time, either.
But she will. Tonight.
I know she will.
And when she does...
I wanted to tell you in advance, Gabriel...
...because I... I believe I know your secret.
I've seen you, together.
The way you speak to her.
And watch her.
And look after her.
And I know her...
...profound affection for you.
You've behaved like a man...
...and as the successful rival--
successful through your kindness...
...I wish to tell you...
...I am profoundly grateful.
The cook would like a word, sir.
-Kiss me. Joseph.
-No, please don't. Liddy, don't.
Would you excuse me?
I've come to say goodnight.
Go back and talk to the poor things.
You've broken their hearts.
I don't suit this kind of affair.
No. Nor do I.
I wish I could go, too.
-I must go.
-Not before you've danced. Both of you.
I insist.
Mr. Oak?
Thank you.
Tell me what to do.
Gabriel.
Do what is right.
Sorry, excuse me.
Frank.
Black suits you.
Although a little premature.
You're alive.
And here I am. Pulled from the sea.
Some fishermen found me
and brought me to shore.
Then I discovered I was dead
and found I preferred it.
For a while, anyway.
-Why have you come back?
-The strangest thing.
I missed you.
You don't seem very happy to see me.
You said I was nothing to you.
Did I?
Well, then-- honesty at all times.
I find myself in need of money.
I gave up my profession for you,
and it seems a little harsh...
...that you have a farm and a house
while I'm living off nothing.
-There is no money.
-Then sell the farm.
Come home.
No.
I said, come home.
I'm your husband and you'll obey me!
Oh, my God.
Let me see.
If it's any consolation,
his life will be spared.
Crime of passion.
Morning, Liddy.
It's a fine harvest, ma'am.
Best we've had in years.
Will we have it all over before the dew?
We will indeed, ma'am.
Luck's been on our side.
Come, Liddy, give me a hand.
I'm sorry I startled you.
I wanted to tidy up for them.
I haven't been here for so long.
Are you going in?
Rehearsals. I sing bass in the choir.
Yes, I've heard you.
Then I apologize.
I've been hoping to get a chance
to talk to you.
We, we've not spoken as much
as I'd have liked.
No.
I'm leaving England.
Leaving?
Going to America.
There's a boat leaving Bristol
in 4 days' time. I'll be on it.
Now that the farm is secure.
I understand I should give you notice.
No. You must go when you want.
I'll leave first thing tomorrow. No fuss.
I think that's best.
Gabriel.
Wait.
You'll think I'm strange but...
...I've been worried.
Have I offended you somehow?
No, not at all.
Is it money?
-I'll pay you whatever you want.
-I don't need money now.
-A formal partnership, then?
-Nor a partnership.
The farm belongs to you alone.
It's the finest farm for miles around.
-Then why else are you leaving?
-I said I'd leave you one day.
Well, you must not go.
-You forbid me?
-Yes, if you like.
I forbid you.
It's time for you to fight your own battles.
And win them, too.
So we should say goodbye, then?
I suppose so.
Gabriel, wait.
Thank you, Gabriel.
You've believed in me and fought for me...
...and stood by my side when
all the rest of the world is against me.
And we've been through so much together.
Wasn't I your first sweetheart?
Weren't you mine?
And now I'd have to go on without you.
If I knew...
If I knew that you would let me love you
and marry you...
But you will never know.
Why not?
Because you never ask!
Would you say no again?
I don't know.
Probably.
So why don't you?
Ask me.
Ask me, Gabriel.