Get the hell
out of my house!
Put that down.
What the hell's wrong with you?
Don't! Please!
No! For heaven's...
No. God, no! Please!
I'm gonna miss you.
I think you should canceI
your trip to LA.
I really do.
I will if you'll
canceI your triaI.
If I do, Mr. Murphy goes
to jaiI for 30 years.
He deserves it.
How could you defend
that son of a bitch, anyway?
Ever hear
of the Sixth Amendment?
He's entitled to the best
counseI he can buy...
I mean get.
You got it right
the first time, honey.
You have to
understand something.
Mr. Murphy doesn't see himself
as a son of a bitch.
He gives to charities.
He reads bedtime stories
to his kids.
You're breaking my heart, Matt.
Getting slow
in your old age, Gavin?
Thank you for inviting me.
It was Matt's idea.
It was?
He couldn't believe you never
went to a black-and-white ball.
I had other priorities.
Really?
Is everything Matt's idea?
You look beautifuI.
Thanks.
It's past your bedtime, David.
I love you, Trina.
Telephone call
for Mr. Corelli.
Mr. Corelli, there's a phone
call for you in the lounge.
Where's your phone?
Corelli.
What?
How?
OK. I'll be right there.
David, was it something I said?
Kyle Medford's dead.
What?!
Oh, my God.
I just saw him today.
You did?
Yes. We talked about the new
Matisse for the museum.
What happened?
He was murdered.
- It's a freak show.
- I'm not here.
- Who's in charge?
- Hargrove and Vasko.
- You on call?
- Yep.
You just hit the jackpot.
Hey.
We guess time of death
about four hours ago.
Want to look upstairs?
OK.
Get these people out.
They're stepping on evidence.
Black tie, Mr. Prosecutor?
Four separate cuts.
Two to the jugular.
Take a look
at this little goody.
Some kind of an African hatchet.
It's a fertility mask.
The maid says he collected them.
He was wearing it
when she found him.
The maid came back about eight
after seeing a movie.
She found him like this.
The weapon belongs to him.
It'll be tough
to show premeditation.
This is rage.
Make sure we get
some random blood samples.
Let's print the toilet.
Maybe he took a leak.
Or she.
Get anything in here?
I got some prints
off the tea set.
We'll wrap it.
It won't be a problem.
I'll send the ID tech guy
the prints.
The lab clear this room?
Yeah, they're done.
See if we can get
a hit this time.
Um... That bothers me.
See where he is with his work.
Karen?
Let's get these to the lab.
What are they?
Well, either he
collected pubic hair,
or he's auditioning
for a ClairoI ad.
We're all done.
Paramedics are finishing up.
- We're heading out.
- Right.
Don't log this untiI I say, OK?
- What is it?
- I'll tell you later.
Prints on the hatchet.
Perfect 14-pointers.
Do I get a warrant
on phone records?
His privacy's gone.
The media will make it
into a gangbang.
Everything goes through me.
You gotta be loving this shit.
I'm sorry?
Next year's an election year.
Good to see you.
Good to see you, too, Corelli.
Better bring Clifford
up to speed.
- What are you laughing at?
- I'm not.
Next year is an election year,
isn't it?
Is it? We'll talk later.
Yeah. See you.
- David, Mr. Wong.
- Mr. Wong.
Ask Mr. Wong
if he recognises this.
It was bought at his store.
It's good silver
from Chiang-Su in China.
Did he do the engraving?
No. It was done in Hong Kong.
For who?
It was made for a rich man here.
A gift from a beautifuI woman.
Ask him what this means.
It means jade.
Jade.
- Morning, HaI.
- Morning, Mr. Gavin.
Thank you.
Mmm...
See you in a couple of days.
OK. I'll call you.
Be good.
Always. You be carefuI.
- Morning, Mrs. Gavin.
- Morning.
Would you care for breakfast?
Er... just some coffee.
We're ready, Mrs. Gavin.
Father,
you are holy, indeed,
and all Creation
rightly gives you praise.
AII life, all holiness
comes from you,
through your son
Jesus Christ, our Lord,
by the working of
the Holy Spirit.
From age to age, you gather
people to yourself
so that from east to west,
an offering may be made
to the glory of your name.
And so, Father,
we bring you these gifts.
We ask you to make them holy
by the power of your spirit,
that they may become for us
the body and blood of your son
our Lord Jesus Christ...
What are you doing here?
I took Trina to the airport.
Free for lunch?
You see the papers?
It's the case you've been
dreaming about.
It will put your ambitious ass
into the big office.
You'll be the next DA
of San Francisco.
Where did she go?
- LA for a few days.
- Think she's coming back?
Maybe when we get a divorce,
you can marry her.
CooI.
She said you were
a terrible lover.
She lies
to protect your fraiI ego.
She said that's why
she chose me.
Everybody makes mistakes.
You finally admit that.
- You still playing?
- Sure.
- See you at 1:00?
- Take your best shot.
Medford had money problems.
Last year he lost $8 million
on the yen.
That's what he gets
for betting the yen.
And there's something else.
We've got a problem.
Only if we make it a problem.
We found a roll of film
in Medford's safe.
- This a gag?
- No gag.
Those pictures are not relevant
to this investigation.
Who's the girl?
Now, that
is a relevant question.
Let's find her.
We don't know anything
about her.
It's a waste of time.
We know one thing...
she's not a nun.
What about the, um... gentleman?
You want to bring him in?
I'm not making that call.
I'll take care of it, OK?
You've got pictures of the
governor with some hooker?
Keep that to yourself.
- What will you do?
- I'm seeing him tomorrow.
He could turn you
into road-kill.
No shit.
Why don't you come downtown?
As a partner?
Eventually.
What for?
Money. ReaI money.
I'm having fun doing what I do.
There's only three fun things
in life - money, sex and power.
Two out of three's not bad.
Be carefuI your dream case
don't blow your brains out.
What's this divorce stuff?
Oh, that.
I was just yanking your chain.
Oh?
You guys OK?
Yeah.
Don't look so disappointed,
David.
You're a cynicaI
son of a bitch, man.
Yeah, that's why we're friends.
Governor, Mr. Corelli.
Morning, sir.
David. Good to see you.
Always good
to see our rising stars,
even if they're plotting
headaches for my friends.
I like your boss.
Word is that you were thinking
about opposing him.
None of us ever run
for anything, do we?
We just allow the party faithfuI
to draft us.
You know my AA, Bill Barrett?
- Sit down.
- Thanks
I don't know how I can help
with Kyle. I liked him.
I've got a meeting
in 10 minutes.
I was hoping to see you alone.
I have no secrets from Bill.
He knows where all
the bodies are buried.
There's something
I need to show you.
Show me, but quickly.
Push the fucking meeting back
a half-hour.
Yes, sir.
I'd like to be alone
with David...
with the distinguished
Mr. Corelli.
Where did you get these?
Kyle Medford's safe.
Son of a bitch.
The miserable cock-sucking
son of a bitch.
Who knows about them?
The investigating officers.
My people.
And you, of course.
And me.
If you drag me into this, David,
if my name even shows up
on the periphery of this,
you better get the fuck
out of California
because you'll have as much
future as Jerry Brown.
Who's Jerry Brown?
Wouldn't it be an awfuI shame
if one little pussy
and a thimblefuI of sperm
were to affect the future
of this state?
Was Medford blackmailing you?
I don't get blackmailed,
Mr. Corelli.
I do the fucking.
I never get fucked.
I have my answer, then.
Thank you for your help.
Any time.
I enjoy dispensing advice
to those who care to listen.
Uh, the...
You have other copies,
I presume?
That's correct.
Then I'll just hold on to these.
Fine. Good to see you again.
Dr. Gavin
is a psychologist
who specialises
in the causes and treatment
of violence in the workplace.
Her work's been published in the
NationaI Review of Psychiatry
and in her two best-selling
works of non-fiction.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Dr. Katrina Gavin.
Good afternoon.
Today I'll examine situations
common to your company
and others
in the changing workplace.
It's important to distinguish
between someone having a bad day
that ends in a tantrum
and someone whose failure
to resist aggressive impulses
results in serious
destructive acts.
These people are in many ways
no different from you and me,
but they can no longer
controI their urges.
They disassociate themselves
from their actions,
often experiencing
an hystericaI blindness.
They're blind to the darkness
within themselves.
You have reached
the law offices
of Gavin, Terry, and Klorinda.
Office hours are 9am to 6pm.
After the beep,
please leave a message.
Hey, it's me.
I thought maybe you were
working late, but I guess not.
I'm so tired of these things,
honey.
I feel like I'm disassociating
myself from my own actions.
Maybe I'm reaching
hystericaI blindness.
Hey, be carefuI. I might give in
to an uncontrollable urge.
Anyway...
I miss you.
How does that
make you feel?
Be nice.
You don't give a shit
about anyone, do you?
That's none of your business.
Governor Edwards called me.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Are you out of
your fucking mind?
The next time you go there,
check with me first.
OK.
I want you off this case.
Cliff, I am onto something here.
I need a little more time.
I want you off the case.
You take me off this,
and I will go public.
I don't think the governor
would appreciate that.
Why don't you work it out
and try it yourself?
Maybe I will.
You haven't tried a case
in 10 years, Cliff.
Will there be anything else?
Here's the governor's
lady friend.
She's 17 here.
Had to get
into juvenile files for this.
Patrice Jacinto, 21.
Works for a beauty parlour
in Chinatown.
One arrest for solicitation
when she was a juvenile.
- You talk to her yet?
- No, not yet.
Her bank account shows
two $10,000 deposits
in the last six months.
Medford's had this place
a couple of years.
His investment company
leases it.
- Hi, John.
- Vasko.
I bet you can't wait
to see the bedroom.
- Corelli.
- Morning.
Deep-seated massage oiI.
And over here we have
a harmony pillow.
"This pillow allows
deeper penetration
"by positioning both partners
most advantageously.
"It raises the female hips,
facilitating male entry.
"You can inflate the pillow
"to varying degrees
of hardness or softness
"while enjoying the thrill
of floating action. "
Here in the nightstand,
we got about
three grams of coke...
Some poppers, some assorted
children's vitamins...
My best guess is ecstasy.
This is the room the governor
was photographed in.
Maybe it's his bridaI suite.
You look in here?
Yeah. It's been photographed.
Cristalle, Beluga,
Wolfgang Puck...
- It's a fuck-house.
- Not just a fuck-house.
He's got a nice
little camera over here...
and there's another one
up here...
low-light, high-density.
Neighbour saw
a lot of women come here.
Did you check out these jammin'
jellies and cliterrifics?
I was thinking about you.
Honey, I'd rip off
some of those butt plugs.
They're designed for
the perfect asshole.
Inspector Vasko.
Take a look at this.
You think the lab can do
anything with that?
- They can try recycling it.
- Great.
What about this neighbour?
Name's Guy Henderson. Claims
he never saw Medford here,
but saw women at the house.
Can he identify anybody?
I think he saw more
than he says.
His bedroom faces the house
and he's got a scope.
I didn't spy on them
or anything.
I'm sure you didn't,
Mr. Henderson.
A lot of women came up.
Men, too.
How many different women
you see over there?
I don't know.
Five or six, maybe.
Did you ever see any
of these women over there?
Yeah. Yeah, I, uh...
I think I saw her.
Patrice Jacinto.
She's been working in this
beauty parlour for six months.
Fifteen jobs in two years.
Waitress, actress...
You wonder how she put so much
dough in her account.
Ms. Jacinto?
Yes?
Could we talk to you?
Yeah. Just a second.
Ah, shit!
Patrice!
Watch it!
Watch out!
Patrice! Stop!
Patrice! God damn it!
God damn it, hold still!
God damn it!
Here. Here.
Shut up, sweetheart.
You're going downtown.
- Fuck!
- Come on, damn it!
My name is David Corelli.
I'm the assistant DA
in charge of homicide here.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Something to drink or smoke?
No. They said I couldn't
smoke in here.
They were wrong.
Let me tell you how this works.
I know, damn it!
I'm fucking calling my lawyer!
I can't believe
you did this shit!
Look at this!
Look at my face!
Sit down, Patrice.
Now, sit down.
You're right. Call your attorney
and say I have a witness
who'll identify you visiting
Kyle Medford's Pacifica house.
Sound familiar? I have pictures
of you fucking the governor
and those pictures will ruin
the governor's career.
And you know what's going to
happen then, Patrice?
Your attorney will tell you
to go fuck yourself and hang up.
The pay phone is
right out there in the hall.
Wait a minute.
I met Kyle at a party
and he knew I was broke,
so he offered me 500 a pop.
I mean, I fuck guys for less.
I'd go to the Pacifica house,
a guy would come
and we'd spend the night.
They wouldn't know me.
I didn't know them.
A couple of creeps
didn't even want me.
They wanted this other girl
they'd fucked before.
They called her Jade.
One of those guys
was the governor.
Jade must have rocked his world,
because he wanted me to
bend over and turn around,
but I don't take it that way.
He told me that Jade
took it any way.
She couldn't get enough.
She loved it.
I saw her once
leaving Kyle's house.
She had long, beautifuI hair
and great legs.
I think it was her.
I never met her.
I'd like to, though.
I'm into women, mostly.
Uhh!
Somebody sawed
through your brake line.
There was no fluid
in your wheeI cylinders.
His blood count's low.
He's lost consciousness,
could have a concussion.
We'll have to run some tests.
Somebody up there
loves you, Corelli.
They want to subpoena
my records.
They talked to my CEO.
He's pleading to two felony
counts and telling everything.
- What does he know?
- Everything.
You know Vince. He's my closest
friend - 20 years.
Who's representing him?
Lawton.
- Harry Lawton?
- Yeah.
Has he signed a plea agreement?
I don't know.
I know Harry.
Don't worry about it.
What do you mean?
He's a bullshit artist.
If it wasn't for me,
he would have been disbarred.
What am I going to do, Matt?
I've got four kids.
- A triaI will kill Sara.
- You will not go to triaI.
You will not do one day in jaiI.
You have my word.
Listen to me.
When they find out
I'm representing you,
this will all go away -
everything, OK?
We got prints on the hatchet.
Patrice?
No, but we got lucky.
An arrest in Palo Alto in 1980.
Some animaI rights protest
at Stanford.
No charges ever filed,
but the Sacramento computer
held prints.
Anna Katrina Maxwell.
We're trying to locate her
through the admissions office.
- You OK?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
Nice work.
I appreciate you doing this,
Mr. Henderson.
I want to show you
one more set of pictures.
OK. Anybody look familiar?
None of these are familiar.
Nobody from that set. OK.
One more group.
One, two... One more.
Yeah. I've seen her.
- The one in the middle?
- Yeah.
OK.
Paisan, get in here.
It's about time.
Tell Judge Licaldi
I'll ring him later.
Come on.
She told you
she saw Medford that day.
They were looking at a Matisse.
Matt, her prints
are on the hatchet.
I got to start at the beginning.
She probably looked at his
collection while she was there.
What are you saying?
To eliminate her,
I need to speak to her.
Fine. She'll be back
from LA tomorrow.
- Talk to her.
- Officially.
Come on, David... You know her.
You know her as well as I do.
You loved her.
- Still do.
- Cheap shot.
You think she'd take
a fucking hatchet to somebody?
No, I don't, which is why
I need to talk to her.
Fine. Come to the house,
have lunch, then talk to her.
Yes? Can I help you?
Inspector Vasko,
San Francisco Police Department.
- In the living room, please.
- Thank you.
- Hi, Maria.
- Mr. Corelli. Nice to see you.
Cosy little pad.
Yeah. Kind of like
Candlestick Park.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Hello.
- Inspector Vasko.
- Trina Gavin.
- Hi, Bob Hargrove.
- Hi.
- Matt said you had an accident.
- I'm fine.
Let's get something straight.
Mrs. Gavin is only talking to you
because she is not a suspect.
The investigation does not focus
on her at this time.
I think we can live with that.
What's your
relationship with Kyle Medford?
I'm on the board of the Pacific
Museum. Kyle was chairman.
He felt we were too conservative
in our acquisitions program.
I supported his efforts
to be more active.
Did you see him socially?
No, not really.
My husband and I saw him
at various functions.
Did you ever meet alone?
Yes. One time. The day he died.
He called me to talk about
acquiring a new Matisse.
I was leaving town, so I agreed
to meet him at his house.
That was last Saturday?
Yes.
What time did you get there?
I got there around 4:00.
We talked about the Matisse.
He gave me some tea.
He showed me his collection.
Was he alone?
Yes.
Did anyone see you there?
No. I don't think so.
What sort of things
did he show you?
He showed me this God-awfuI mask
from the Cameroon -
I think it was a fertility mask
- and a hatchet.
He said it was
over 100 years old.
Did you touch anything?
I touched the hatchet.
The mask, he held it up.
I can't remember
whether I touched it or not.
What did you do
after you left?
I went home.
Was your husband here?
- No.
- Was anyone here? Staff?
- Did you use the phone?
I had the machine on.
I was preparing a speech.
Look, I have no alibi
untiI 9:00,
when we went to the ball.
- Is that what you're asking?
- What else do you need?
Have you ever been
to Medford's beach house?
Only his house in the city.
I didn't know he had another.
Ever give Medford
a silver jewellery box?
I never gave any gift.
You never had sex with him?
What kind of question is that?
That's why they're here.
You don't have to answer that.
I said I had no sociaI contact
with him.
I do consider sex
to be a sociaI contact, David.
As you know, I'm married.
I think she did it.
Why?
No alibi. Prints on the hatchet.
- And she lied.
- TypicaI shrink.
They pull your strings.
She was pulling your strings
pretty good.
The guy almost
had them convinced...
Morning, Corelli.
Hey, Dave, how you doing?
Got something to show you.
How we doing?
Now this... is what you gave us.
We were able to enhance it
using software algorithms.
Let's see...
This is how it looked
when we got it.
Medford's beach house.
At least it's not
the governor again.
Or the president.
Thank God.
I can still believe in hope.
There's some jump cuts,
but we saved a few minutes.
You ever take it
like that, Corelli?
Is that an offer, Inspector?
You wish.
We cleaned it up
a lot more from here on.
Right.
Keep working on this,
you'll have a PG rating.
Boy, it's a wonderfuI
country, isn't it?
Freeze it right there.
Magnify it.
Jesus.
David?
Got a minute?
Yeah.
Miss Jacinto called. She wants
to meet you at 5:00 today.
Tell her Fior d'Italia,
Washington Square.
OK. She said it's about Jade.
Hey, you asshole!
Get away from her!
Call an ambulance.
Call 911. Code three. Do it!
Hey, you asshole!
Fuck! Fuck!
Shit!
Man, you fucked up!
MedicaI examiner's
case number 3209.
March 16, 1995.
Patrice Jacinto.
There are abrasions
to the chin.
The abrasions
are minimally haemorrhagic
and red to purple in colour.
The neck wound is
of a "Y" configuration -
the horizontaI line
being five inches long
and half an inch in width.
We don't have
a talking head any more.
Somebody knew
she was talking to us.
I didn't know
you knew the governor.
I don't.
I know Bill Barrett. Why?
- Want me to introduce you?
- Go fuck yourself.
- Glad you made her talk?
- What did you say?
You heard it.
What?
I am onto you! I am onto you!
Get off me, Petey!
I am onto you.
You want to tell me about that?
I can't yet.
What is it?
- It's a cuff link.
- Don't play with me.
I want to know what it means.
I don't know.
What if this comes
up in triaI, David?
There'll be questions asked...
I would never put
you up for grabs.
You are taking
a huge chance here.
- So are you.
- Yeah. No shit.
There was something between
you and Mrs. Gavin...
A long time ago.
And you're OK with that now?
I hope so.
People who commit these acts are
no different from you and me,
but they can no longer
controI their urges.
They disassociate themselves
from their actions,
often experiencing
an hystericaI blindness.
They're blind to
the darkness within themselves.
This is from a speech she made
in LA just a week ago.
We have her prints
on the hatchet.
We have her Iying to us
in her statement.
She was in Medford's house
just before he was killed.
- She's got no alibi.
- We don't have a motive.
What about blackmaiI?
The murder weapon wasn't hers.
No premeditation.
Matt Gavin's wife -
he'll eat us for breakfast.
It was her. She did it.
What make of car killed Patrice?
Black Thunderbird.
You didn't ID the plates?
No. No plates.
What does Mrs. Gavin drive?
Uh, they've got three cars.
A Jag, a Range Rover...
And a black Thunderbird, right?
All right, bring her in.
Just who I wanted to see.
Those photographs
you left in Sacramento,
I thought maybe now
that you won't need them,
you could help me
find the negatives.
Why don't you help him, Pat?
- Yeah, right.
- Excuse me.
Are you putting me on?
What do you need them for?
They're not relevant any more.
Beat it.
Aren't you going
to read me my rights?
You can leave any time.
I've told you about Kyle.
What else is there?
This is about Jade.
A couple of creeps
didn't even want me.
They wanted this girl
they'd fucked before.
They called her Jade.
One of those guys
was the governor.
Jade must have rocked
his world.
He wanted me to bend over
and turn around,
but I don't take it that way.
He said Jade took it any way.
She couldn't get enough of it. '
What does this have
to do with Katrina?
Could I have
that other tape, please?
Mrs. Gavin,
is that you?
That's not her!
- Mrs. Gavin?
- You don't have to answer.
I'm sorry, Matt.
Fuck you, David!
All right,
let's get on with it.
I met Jim at the museum.
I'd never cheated
on my husband before.
He took me to a house.
I spent the night with him.
Where?
Pacifica.
Some place on the beach.
Did you have sex with other men?
No.
I cheated on my husband.
I didn't know I'd be arrested.
You're not under arrest.
You never called yourself Jade
or used Medford's house?
Look, bring that girl in here.
She'll tell you
I'm not that person.
The girl is dead.
Excuse me.
Would it surprise you to know
that Medford owned
the Pacifica house?
Yes, it would.
What if a witness
saw you severaI times?
I'd say your witness
was mistaken.
Would you?
Where were you yesterday
between five and six pm?
In the city. I met Matt
for a drink around 5:00.
Then I went to my office.
I returned a few calls
and I got home around 7:45.
- What about Medford?
- What were you driving?
- I asked a question.
- I'll do the questions.
- What were you driving?
- My car.
- Black Thunderbird?
- Yes. Anything else?
Can you be
in a line-up tomorrow?
That's enough!
If you're charging her,
do it right now!
Well, I think she had
an uncontrollable urge,
coupled with
hystericaI blindness.
It's time you took yourself
out of this.
I don't
understand something.
How could you do this to me?
How could I do this to you?
- What did you expect?
- Expect?
I didn't expect to go downtown
and sit and watch a tape
of my wife fucking somebody!
You think I don't know
about you?
Know what?
I know everything.
I know their names.
I know about the Fairmont
Towers, sometimes your office.
I'm not stupid, Matt.
Is that why you did it?
We'll check if that's blood
on the tyres.
You'll get a comparison
with Patrice's?
Yeah, right.
What about this?
This looks like blood.
Could be paint transfer
from an impact.
This is the car, Petey.
This car was reported stolen
about a week ago.
Belongs to some
computer company executive.
Not Mrs. Gavin's car.
Maybe somebody wants us
to think it was.
This is the car, Petey.
This is the car.
What, did the tape
turn you on?
Don't ever talk
to me like that again!
Do you understand me?
What are you doing here?
I need to talk to you.
I can't. You know that.
I need your help, David.
I'm afraid.
Afraid of what?
Who am I speaking to?
Can I come in?
Come on in.
I didn't know Kyle
was taping any of it.
I knew they were powerfuI, but
I had no idea he was using them.
He told me they were
friends of his.
How many were there?
A lot. I don't know.
I lost track.
How could you let them do that?
They didn't do anything.
It was my choice. I liked it.
- And Matt?
- I don't fuck him that way.
That's not what I mean.
What did you tell him?
Nothing.
He only knows
about the man on the tape.
Who were the others?
Men with money...
reputations.
I didn't have to fall in love
with them, David.
It was safe.
At least, I thought it was.
David, I know too much.
One of them killed Kyle
and Patrice.
- I could be next.
- You should go.
I know too much!
I know you love me.
Don't do this. Don't do this.
Nothing's changed.
Everything's changed.
What?
You killed Medford.
Where are you going?
San Francisco DA.
All right.
No.
There's our last link to Jade.
Anyone who's ever
seen her is dead
or suffering
from penile amnesia.
Jade doesn't exist any more.
CarefuI. You nearly stood
on the murder weapon.
He was obviously
killed with that.
There doesn't appear
to be forced entry.
His brother came for dinner,
found the body...
The brother has a key.
He's still warm.
He's only been dead an hour.
- How long?
- An hour.
- Where's the phone?
- It's right up there.
Your friend Trina
sure gets around.
She couldn't have done this.
- Why not?
- She was with me.
Maria! Maria, it's Mr. Corelli.
Yes. Is Mrs. Gavin home?
No. OK. How about Mr. Gavin?
OK, would you tell Mr. Gavin
that I will be at my apartment?
Right. Thanks. Maria.
Where are you going?
A clouded dream
on an earthly night
Hangs upon the crescent moon
A voiceless song
in an ageless light
Sings at the coming dawn
Birds in flight
are calling there
Where the clouds
move the storms
It's there that
my heart is longing for
All for the love of you...
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
So it's there
my homage's due
Clutched by
the still of the night
Now I feel, feel you move
And every breath,
breath is full
So it's there
my homage's due
Hello? Hello? Hell...
You fucked her, didn't you?
Matt, where is she?
- Huh?
- Matt, she's in trouble.
Maria?
Maria, are you in your room?
Anybody here?
Matt?
Uh!
Oh!
This is Katrina Gavin,
1100 Hillsborough.
No. Hillsborough.
Talking to one
of your boyfriends?
David, watch it!
Trina.
Trina!
You like it like this,
don't you?
Let her go!
Who's there?
It's a tragedy for justice when
law enforcement people go bad.
They were cleaning up your shit.
They were just
two loyaI supporters...
Two supporters
who got carried away.
They wanted to see if she had
more pictures of the governor.
They acted on their own
out of misguided loyalty.
Kyle Medford was shaking
you down and was killed for it.
Patrice was in those pictures.
She was next,
then Henderson,
who could ID everybody.
That left Trina Gavin.
Why are you wasting
the governor's time?
Anything happens to Trina Gavin,
I have film
of you and a dead hooker.
And what if something
happens to you?
Leave her alone.
Get the fuck out of here.
Ready, darling?
We're going to be late.
Where did you get these?
Kyle Medford showed me
the day before I killed him.
You knew, and you killed him?
He was a scumbag.
He would have taken us
both down.
I told you...
I will never let
anyone hurt you.
But I don't remember any of it.
You know what I think it is?
HystericaI blindness.
Do me a favour, Trina.
Next time we make love,
you introduce me to Jade.
A clouded dream
on an earthly night
Hangs upon the crescent moon
A voiceless song
in an ageless light
Sings at the coming dawn
Birds in flight
are calling there
Where the heart
moves the stones
It's there that my heart
is longing for
All for the love of you
A painting hangs
on an ivy wall
Nestled in the emerald moss
Eyes declare a truce of trust
Then it draws me far away
Where deep
in the desert twilight
Sand melts in pools of the sky
Darkness lays
her crimson cloak
Your lamps will call,
call me home
So it's there my homage's due
Clutched by
the still of the night
Now I feel, feel you move
And every breath,
breath is full
So it's there my homage's due
Clutched by
the still of the night
Even the distance
feels so near
All for, for the love of you
A clouded dream
on an earthly night
Hangs upon the crescent moon
A voiceless song
in an ageless light
Sings at the coming dawn
Birds in flight
are calling there
Where the heart
moves the stones
It's there that my heart
is longing for
All for,
for the love of you