[Screaming]
[Crash]
[Car alarm blaring]
[Speaking foreign language]
[Shots firing]
Seven Wonders are in good hands.
ISRAELI PRIME MINISTER: [On TV]
Yes, Israel is moving ahead...
and we continue
to make every effort...
for a diplomatic solution
to this crisis.
Unfortunately, Dawn,
there are those who believe...
these talks should never happen.
They will remain steadfast
with this belief until Israel...
and all of its inhabitants
are eradicated forever.
Which leads us to the single
greatest threat facing mankind:
Rogue countries attempting to...
or already having
the capabilities...
to develop nuclear weapons.
The world's
most dangerous regimes...
with the world's most dangerous
terrorist proxies, could,
and we believe already have the
world's most dangerous weapons.
Israel, like America, reserves the right
to defend herself...
against such threats.
Israel wants peace.
America wants peace.
Our children need peace.
We'll resolve these differences...
Hey, Bry,
BRY: [On computer]
Hey, Shane.
Hey, I got the files
that you wanted.
I'm uploading them
to you right now.
Are you sure about this?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Three of our agents
have been killed
in the Middle East
in the last 6 months.
There's gotta be a leak somewhere
in the communication pipeline.
BRY: [On computer]
These aren't low-level agents
we're talking about here.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
BRY: [On computer]
The last time you tried
something like this,
it did not turn out so well.
I'm just saying, you lost a lot.
I just know how much
you two cared for each other.
Look, I'll see you in the office
tomorrow morning, all right?
BRY: [On computer]
All right, get some rest.
Yeah, you too, man.
[Phone ringing]
Daughtry
MAN: [On phone]
This is dispatch.
We have a call for you.
He refuses to speak with anyone else.
All right, punch it through.
This is Agent Daughtry.
MAN 2: [On phone]
Is this line secure?
You reached the FBI,
it's pretty secure.
Who's this?
I've got information for you.
SHANE:
All right, what's your name?
Last chance.
MAN 2: Malikov said you're the
only one that I could trust.
Malikov.
I need to know who this is.
What's your name?
It's...
it's Arlin.
Arlin Rockwell.
I need to tell you
about Seven Wonders.
We must meet tonight,
Mr. Daughtry.
There isn't much time.
[Phone ringing]
This is the fallen one.
MAN: [Distorted voice] Hello, my son.
Is there much to report?
The stork is delivered.
Seven Wonders is in good hands.
We're awaiting
the Decalogue from Mother.
MAN: [Distorted voice on phone]
Decalogue will be delivered soon.
Seven Wonders
will proceed as planned.
We have one other
order of business.
Yes.
MAN: [Distorted voice on phone]
We have a loose end.
I will send my brother.
SHANE: So rumor has
it, you're a smuggler,
Mr. Rockwell.
Importer-exporter.
Well, a significant amount
of money was recently wired
to an account linked to you.
There's good money in hate,
Mr. Daughtry.
I'm guessing this has something
to do with Seven Wonders.
MR. ROCKWELL: The world is
changing, Agent Daughtry.
You may wake up
one morning very soon
and find Iran has no enemies,
none capable
of interfering anyway.
How is it that Iran's hate
for America and Israel
is as great a threat
to democracy as Hitler's Nazis
and we do nothing?
This is all very
interesting but...
Please!
Please.
Please, sit down.
I'm not a bad man, Agent Daughtry.
I'm a specialist, you could say.
If there's something
that needs handling,
people come to me.
I don't ask questions.
I merely transport.
But there's some things
that I won't do,
could not do knowingly.
And I should have known
that the price was too high
for this to be just another job.
God forgive me, but...
I think I've imported...
a distraction.
I don't understand.
What kind of distraction?
MR. ROCKWELL: This is bigger than
anything you could possibly imagine.
Mr. Daughtry,
Seven Wonders.
[Shots firing]
[Glass shattering]
[Gunfire]
[Rapid gunfire]
[Explosion]
[Whispering] And when the
fourth seal was opened,
I heard the fourth beast
say, come and see.
And I looked and beheld
a pale horse
and his name
who sat on it was Death
and hell followed with him.
And so, there was
a great earthquake;
and the sun became
as black as sackcloth.
Speculative at best.
Shoddy research.
Hey.
Hey, how you doing?
Good.
Is everything OK?
Yeah, everything's great.
I marked some pages,
you know, for your research.
Ang, I gotta finish my article
on the peace talks.
Well, I know but I thought
maybe this could help.
Just...
I can do my own research,
and I really don't need anymore
of your hocus-pocus prophecy.
OK, Ang?
So here, take that.
Thank you.
You have a Nostradamus book
on your desk.
Hocus-pocus prophecies
like a unified Europe
or millions of Jews returning
to their homeland.
That hasn't happened before?
That's different, Angela.
No, it's not.
How is it different?
Islamic nations coming together
in a war against Israel.
That hasn't happened or
isn't happening again right now?
But if it doesn't make sense
to the great intellect
of Daniel Johnson,
then it just cannot be true.
OK, you know what?
So the whole Noah's Ark thing,
that's realistic to you?
Yeah, it is.
But you're a great swimmer,
so you ain't got nothing
to worry about, right?
Good night, Angela.
EVE: Hello, Jack.
How are you?
I'm doing quite well, Eve.
How's your father?
He's fine.
Look, we're concerned about
one of your field ops, Jack.
Eve, as you know
we typically handle matters
with our field operatives
internally.
Couple of his aliases
have been flagged on national
and international chatter
and it's not the first time.
JACK:
Dean.
We are the CIA.
What triggered your concern?
There have been several
financial transactions
and communications that have
made my superiors uneasy.
He's working on a mission
in the Middle East.
No, he isn't.
We are the FBI.
[Laughing]
All right, let me know
what you find out.
You know, it wouldn't hurt you
to smile once in a while,
sweetheart.
Hello, Eve.
EVE:
What are you doing here?
Are you having me followed?
Have you paid any attention
to the peace talks?
I love it how you seem to show
up to talk about your issues.
Well, there are other
pressing matters
that require my attention.
This is a pressing matter
for you, Eve,
much more than you know.
There's never been
an opportunity like this,
an offer of peace
from Saudi Arabia,
Syria, Lebanon, Egypt, Iraq?
Israel should just
carve up its homeland
and keep a few
choice cuts for herself?
Is that what you're recommending?
EVE: As much as you
might not like it,
Israel needs to reach
a peace agreement.
OK, the Americans,
the EU, the Russians
have all made it clear that
if Israel walks away from this,
then they're on their own.
MAN 3: In the mosques,
it is said that a true Muslim
must never recognize Israel.
Jerusalem will be
the price for peace.
Why are you in the States?
Because there are
Biblical prophecies coming true,
Eve, just as they
have in the past.
I want you to see that
your salvation is at stake,
and that Jesus is your
only path to heaven.
I really need to go.
MAN 3:
Eve.
What do you make of it?
[Whispering]
WOMAN: it's from the
Book of Revelation.
As in, The Good Book?
From my count,
it's his sixth time through it.
Impressive.
[Whispering]
[Whispering continues] And, so,
there was a great earthquake;
and the sun became
black as sackcloth of hair,
and the moon became as blood;
And the stars of heaven
fell unto the earth,
even as a fig tree
casteth her untimely figs,
when she is shaken
of a mighty wind.
Water?
All right, who do we have here?
John Doe, killing a man,
firing a gun at a federal agent,
several times.
Diving out a window.
Impressive for a ghost.
The question is,
you just a hit man?
I don't think so.
How do you know Rockwell?
He rip you off?
Was he gonna tell me something
you didn't want me to know?
Rockwell mentioned Seven Wonders.
You know anything
about that, mystery man?
And I saw a new heaven
and a new earth
for the first heaven
and the first earth
were passed away.
There is a revolution coming.
Revolution, huh?
A revolution of God.
Oh.
Well, I don't have
anything like that in my file.
Actually, Mr. Tanner,
I have a few questions
for you before you leave.
Hello, Shane.
Hey, Eve.
This day just keeps
getting better and better.
ISRAELI PRIME MINISTER: [On TV] Shalom
Aleichem, ladies and gentlemen.
It seems after 3 days
of negotiations,
the world cannot agree on
anything except that Israel
should give a part of her
land in exchange for peace.
We are very much back to where
we started many years ago.
Israel gave up land
for peace in 1948.
Israel gave land
for peace with Egypt
during the Reagan administration.
Israel gave Lebanon
for peace and got Hezbollah.
She gave Gaza for peace
and got the terrorist group,
Hamas.
Israel, the only nation created
by a direct and sovereign
act of God over 3,500 years ago
has no more land to give,
no more to give.
[Speaking foreign language]
WEATHERMAN: [On TV] The weather situation
is much worse across the country,
26 deaths are being
blamed on this cold snap
and it's expected to continue
for at least another 3 days.
WOMAN: [On TV] So has there been
enough concessions for the American
peace talks to go forward?
ISRAELI PRIME MINISTER: [On TV]
Yes, Israel is willing to move ahead.
Unfortunately, Dawn,
there are those who believe
that these talks
should never happen.
EVE: Nick Tanner, he's a spook.
Really?
When'd you get into town?
Didn't even know you were here.
Well, you're on
a need-to-know basis
and you didn't need to know.
SHANE: Counter-Intel's changed
you a little bit, huh?
Put a little fire your belly?
Good for you.
I've always had the fire, Shane.
I just choose to use logic
and evidence to make decisions
about my cases.
You know, one of us
had to make a move
and luckily I was still able to.
SHANE: Still angry about
our little mishap?
Our little mishap?
Are you kidding me?
You emptied 500 people
into the streets
in the middle
of a monsoon on a hunch.
You made me look
like a complete rookie
and you nearly ruined my career
so forgive me
if I'm still a little angry.
I can just come back
for those later, ma'am.
It was a good tip, Eve.
No, Shane, it was a bad tip
but mostly just a hunch.
And it's never your fault.
You know what?
Believe whatever you want.
No one could ever tell you
anything different anyway.
Right? You're perfect,
especially now
that you're sporting
a new logo on your badge.
Oh, you have some nerve, Shane.
You and your Counter-Intel
friends ever hear
of an operation
called Seven Wonders?
No.
What is it?
I'm not sure. I was about
to find out from Rockwell
when you friend here put him down.
You know who he's working for?
We have our suspicions.
You get anything out of him
before he, you know?
No.
No, just a bunch
of Biblical nonsense,
quote from the Book of Revelation.
Said something about
the revolution of God.
You know anything about that?
Heard of it, but nothing concrete.
Do you have any other
information or leads
to share with me before
I have a talk with him?
Maybe.
Why don't you let him
cool off for a little while.
Still like Russian food?
DANIEL:
Those are ammo crates.
How long have they been there?
Cream?
Agent Rearden.
You are much more beautiful
than he described.
You must stay
for my world-famous borscht.
How are you, my friend?
I received a call.
Arlin Rockwell.
SHANE:
Yeah.
How do you know him?
CHEF: Let us just say we have
mutual respect for one another.
How is he?
Dead.
Then this coffee should be vodka.
Why was he killed?
I cannot help you this time.
Can't or won't?
What's Seven Wonders?
We are capable
of greatness, Mr. Daughtry,
the music of Beethoven,
the words of Pushkin,
the brush strokes of Rembrandt,
but not all genius
ends up in beauty.
There is myth that Russia
has created nuclear bombs
that a single person
can deploy and detonate.
A Russian scientist
working with Iran
has created truth
out of this myth.
Are you telling me
that Rockwell smuggled
nuclear weapons
into the United States?
Seven of them.
Seven Wonders.
Suitcase nukes?
CHEF: Do you know what would
happen to city or cities
that are hit by these bombs?
Hundreds of thousands
of people will die instantly.
Their flesh will literally
melt off their bodies,
but the real strategic purpose
is the ultimate chaos
that will result from such attack.
SHANE: The attack itself
is not the sole purpose?
No, Mr. Daughtry.
The sole purpose is disruption
of American government
and financial institutions.
A distraction.
The America you know
will be part of history
and unable to protect its friends.
What friends?
Israel.
Do you know
that two Russian fleets
are steering for exercises
in the Persian gulf?
Is this Russian intelligence?
CHEF:
They cannot exactly say.
They are going to blockade
the Strait of Hormuz.
But they are moving
a muscle to do it.
Why is it that America
always thinks
that we are center of attention
when what we're dealing with
here is a new world order?
EVE: There's no information in our
files that this would be nukes.
What files?
How could that
have gotten passed us?
Tell me what's going on, Eve.
[Tires screeching]
All right, what are you
not telling me?
Get me up to speed now
or get out of my truck.
Matthew Dean is a CIA operative
we've been investigating.
Nick and Dean have been
in communication
for the last several weeks.
We believe that they are working
together on a major operation.
What, the nukes?
EVE: We have information that
the CIA has been investigating
certain Biblical
or apocalyptic events.
SHANE:
Whoa, whoa.
Are you kidding me?
EVE: I haven't been able to
wrap my head around it either
but apparently recent
world events have been
fitting right into what is known
as the Ezekiel war scenario.
SHANE: What is the
Ezekiel war scenario?
Eve?
According to the Hebrew
prophet, Ezekiel,
in the Last Days
the people of Persia,
which is, of course, Iran,
and the people of Gog or Rosh,
which many believe to be Russia,
form an alliance
whose main purpose
is to obliterate Israel.
I'm gonna go talk to your spook.
[Phone ringing]
Yes?
MAN: [Distorted voice on phone]
Your brother was picked up.
FBI Agent Shane Daughtry.
How would you like me to proceed?
MAN: [Distorted voice on phone]
Clean the house, starting
with the sister's bedroom.
You have company.
See that they are attended to.
Copy that.
[Phone ringing]
Agent Rearden.
MAN 3: Apparently your
assassin has a sister.
She's in Baltimore and she
may know about his cause:
Sheila.
You better not be interfering
with this investigation.
MAN 3: There are forces of work
here that you refuse to acknowledge
and continue to ignore.
Like it or not, Eve,
you need my help.
Send me the address.
Nick has a sister.
I have to go to Baltimore.
I'll handle things with Nick.
Nick, you didn't
tell us you had a sister.
Two agents are on their way
right now to pick her up.
[Knocking]
Sheila Tanner?
FBI.
Russ
RUSS: Looks like we're gonna
have to call it in, Evie.
SHANE:
Eleven, missed calls.
The only number not blocked.
Who've you been avoiding, Nick?
[Phone ringing]
Hello?
Eve?
You found her?
Shane, she's already...
[Shots firing]
SHANE: [On phone]
Eve?
If my brother's there,
they're already dead.
Russ
Russ!
Agent down! Agent down!
I need EMS and backup
immediately to our location.
Go get him, Evie.
Go get him, Eve.
Go get him.
[Shots firing]
Good morning.
Morning.
I'm sorry, Ang.
About what?
DANIEL: Not having a purpose
doesn't give me an excuse
to act like a jerk.
No, it doesn't.
And you do have a purpose.
Look, I know the last couple
of years have been tough.
Daniel, I just don't understand
why is it so difficult
for you to...
Sign up?
No.
Believe in something bigger
and better than just this life?
Here you go again
with the Christianese.
Look, we've been over this,
you know?
Year after year
we've been through this.
I just don't get it.
I mean you just woke up one
morning and you just believed
and now I'm supposed to
just follow you?
This hasn't been easy
on me either,
you know?
You've changed; you're a
completely different person.
And you disapprove?
No, it's not that I disapprove.
I just... I don't
get it, you know?
You've changed.
There's no doubt about it
you've changed for the better.
You're a better person for it.
It's just, I just can't seem
to wrap my brain around stuff
that you simply
have no problem with.
I don't know why...
Just listen.
You simply believe.
I just... I wish
I could do that too,
but I just...
I don't think that I can.
Baby.
It's a leap of faith either way.
I know it is.
Do you even believe
that Jesus existed?
Yes, Ang, of course.
There's overwhelming evidence, OK?
Billions of people celebrate
Christmas and Easter every year.
I get that.
I know that.
OK, then why did they crucify him?
What were they afraid of?
I just wish you would
open your heart
and ask God
to reveal himself to you,
'cause he would, he will.
I just... I'm gonna need
more time, OK?
Just give me more time.
OK.
SHANE: You know what?
She'll Full it out later.
Thanks
You all right?
No, I'm not.
I'm not all right.
Look, it's just part of the job.
You have to accept it and move on.
Well, that should be
very comforting
to his wife and children.
It's not your fault, Eve.
I should have known.
I knew he was there.
I just had this...
Hunch?
Yeah.
SHANE: He's good, Eve.
You couldn't have known.
EVE: You know, we have
seven nuclear weapons
floating around
within our borders,
a suspect that won't
give us an inch,
and we have two people
dead on our watch.
How are we supposed
to find these nukes?
SHANE: Well, not by sitting here.
We know almost nothing
about Matthew Dean.
The files the CIA gave us
were worthless.
We gotta get some answers.
EVE: What if we're supposed to fail?
What do you mean?
EVE: What if this
really is God's plan?
I don't think
nuclear weapons going off
killing hundreds of thousands
of people is God's plan.
So you do believe in God.
Ah, I don't know.
I guess I've always thought
there was something
bigger than us.
But that's about it.
You?
My family went through
an abrupt change
in our beliefs when I was 12.
And one night my father comes
in and tells me about Jesus.
You know, he told me that he
wouldn't force me to believe,
but you know he believed
that Jesus Christ
died for him on the cross.
You never told me this before.
I never told anyone.
It just never seemed
poignant until now.
Anyway, when I turned 18,
I moved out of my house
and I... I kept in contact
with my mother,
but I rarely spoke to my father.
It just seemed like
every time we talked
our conversations would
lead to talks about Jesus.
He would just keep telling me
that Jesus came down to earth
to die for me
on the cross so that...
so that I could be forgiven.
Do you believe that?
I don't know.
I guess I've always been more
of a believe-it-when-I-see-it
type of guy, you know?
Me too.
SHANE: What was he doing
in the Middle East, Jack?
JACK:
That's classified.
I gave you the files.
The files were useless
and you know it.
Anything that would have shed
light on this was deleted.
Now what's the revolution of God?
Classified.
We have an imminent
threat on our hands.
We're talking about
the destruction
of the United States of America.
Millions innocent people will die.
And you're passing off
the classified stamp?
What are you hiding, Jack?
What are you hiding, Jack?!
EVE:
Easy.
Take your hands off me, son.
Now.
Supposedly, the revolution of God
is a group of high-ranking
world leaders
with plans for a new world order.
We have not been able
to confirm or deny
the validity of their existence.
We can.
We have one of their
operatives in custody
so we know they exist.
We also have reason
to believe that he's been
in communication with Dean.
JACK: Dean is what we call
a nontraditional operative.
He's a covert
operations specialist.
He's a psychological
operations expert
in chaos theory
and unconventional warfare.
His real talent
is destabilizing governments.
And we trained this guy?
JACK: You better start thinking
a whole lot more like Dean
if you have any prayer
of catching him
and finding those nukes.
Yeah, we have our operatives
working on this, as well.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Let's go.
MAN 3: Eve, Agent Daughtry,
get in the car please.
MAN 3: A couple of years
back, a CIA analyst
began using prophecy in the Bible
to analyze events
in the Middle East.
There was some
interesting results.
Like what?
Israel recapturing
the western wall in Jerusalem
after the Six-Day war.
There was also a concern
about an event we'd refer to
as the Rapture.
EVE: Wait, so people
in the administration
were actually concerned
about the Rapture?
SHANE: Rapture meaning
everyone vanishes?
Well, there are many
interpretations about this,
but yes.
Losing a substantial
number of military
and key government personnel
to an apocalyptic event
such as this, could be
problematic at best.
Contingency plans were needed
so they sent Dean
into the field to investigate.
We intercepted
a number of phone calls
that may be of interest to you.
SHANE: Our sources claim
that Russia's Navy
is headed to the Strait of Hormuz.
Is that true?
We believe so.
So Russia and Iran are involved
in the revolution of God?
We believe that Rockwell
brought the bombs
in through the Great Lakes.
Simply put, their primary goal
is to wipe Israel
off the face of the earth.
Taking America out of the equation
is their first order of business.
And Dean is working for him?
We now believe that Dean
is their number-one
field lieutenant.
Essentially, their
boots-on-the-ground commander.
Plan the CIA.
We're talking about the end, Eve.
Agent Daughtry, my daughter's life
is in your hands
and so is Israel's.
The two of you have been chosen.
Put aside your differences.
Forget the past.
There's no longer
any need for that.
We have to succeed.
We have to find those bombs
and we have to find them now.
[Knocking]
Yes?
Hi, I was wondering
if you've seen my dog around?
No, I haven't.
He's just this little
Jack Russell,
a little black and white thing.
You want to take a look out back?
Yeah, that'd be
great if you don't mind.
No, no, please.
Yeah, oh, sure.
Excuse me, ma'am?
Sorry, we're closed
for the evening.
We're with the FBI.
We were hoping you could
hold the door open for us
for just a few minutes.
FBI, huh?
Just a few minutes.
Zeus, come here, boy.
Zeus?
DANIEL: Probably just out in
the street playing somewhere.
Thanks for your help, though.
I'll see you later.
Have a good evening, Daniel.
Well, at least the public library
still carries a Bible.
Nice.
OK, Ezekiel's war scenario.
You never mentioned your father
was a high-level agent.
You never asked.
Anyway, he considers himself
my guardian angel.
Plus if people knew,
including you,
I'd have been given
special treatment
and I didn't want it.
You knew.
You had your reasons
for keeping it quiet.
I can respect that.
I'm sorry for everything.
Yeah, me too.
I shouldn't have
left you like that.
You had every right to leave me.
I shouldn't have put you in that
situation in the first place.
I'm sorry.
So does your father really
believe this End-Times scenario?
He's been preaching it
for a long time now.
He and his people have been
paying close attention to it.
You believe it?
I believe we need
to find these nukes
or we're all gonna find out
the truth real soon.
Sorry, I didn't tell you
about my father.
You looking to buy a used Harley?
Only if it's
American-made.
Cash first.
Aren't you a little old
to be buying a fake ID?
EVE: OK, the audio
files were encrypted
Masad cleaned them.
MAN: [Recorded voice]
This is the fallen one.
MAN: [Distorted voice] Hello, my son.
Is there much to report?
MAN: [Recorded voice]
The stork is delivered.
Seven Wonders is in good hands.
We're waiting
the Decalogue from...
Wait, wait.
Just play it again
from the beginning.
MAN: [Recorded voice]
This is the fallen one.
MAN: [Distorted voice]
Hello, my son.
Is there much to report?
MAN: [Recorded voice]
The stork is delivered.
Seven Wonders is in good hands.
We're awaiting
the Decalogue from Mother.
MAN: [Recorded distorted voice]
Decalogue will be delivered soon.
Seven Wonders
will proceed as planned.
Stork?
Who's Stork?
Could that have...
could that have been Rockwell?
That would make sense
if he was the one
who smuggled the bombs
into the United States.
In good hands?
Stork delivered?
EVE:
What?
They're all in the same place,
the nukes.
They haven't gone anywhere yet.
This conversation was recorded
a couple days ago.
The bombs are still all together.
They were transported together.
We may still have a chance
at intercepting them all.
What's Decalogue?
LIBRARIAN: Decalogue,
the Ten Commandments,
the code by which
we are all to live.
You kids never read
the Bible anymore, do you?
Look it up, D for Decalogue.
All right, D.
She was right,
the Ten Commandments
or precepts given by God
to Moses at Mount Sinai
and originally written
on two tablets of stone.
SHANE: The code by which we
are all supposed to live.
The code.
Codes
They're waiting on the army codes.
From Mother.
They're waiting on Mother,
Mother Russia.
The codes are coming from Russia.
So this new loose end
must have been Rockwell.
Then he wasn't the stork.
I don't think so.
I mean the stork carries newborns.
Your father said that he thought
Rockwell carried the bombs
down through the Great Lakes.
So the stork must be a ship.
Are there any Russian
or eastern European names
on these lists?
I don't know,
there's 500 ships on this list.
What country of origin
do you think it came from?
Russia, Germany?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Germany.
A ship named Storch.
Chicago.
The bombs are in Chicago.
MATTHEW DEAN:
This is fallen leader.
Our timeline has been moved up.
Prepare for immediate deployment.
We're out of time, Nick.
You know what narcosynthesis is?
You should,
your friends came up with it
except they called it SB17.
That's gonna hurt.
Just relax.
Let it work.
The sting you feel
is a thiopental part
of a new and improved concoction.
Not like the truth serum
your old man used to use.
Is it working, Nick?
This makes lying more complex
than telling the truth.
It will help ensure
things go smoother,
quicker.
Where are the bombs, Nick?
Where are they?
It's too late for you
and your little girlfriend.
Bombs...
I had hoped that you
were smarter than most.
Yes, we're organized.
I know who you are, Shane.
Where are they?
NICK: You shouldn't be so
concerned with the suitcases.
America's been caught sleeping,
blinded by selfishness.
Where are the bombs?!
Blood will flow, starting with
your little Israeli friends,
we should cut off their head.
What Israeli friends?!
Cut off what head?!
I am but one, but we are many.
There are millions of us.
We're a tide that will not
be turned away.
We will wipe Israel
from the face of the earth.
As it is written,
the peace agreement
will never happen.
EVE: What about the peace agreement?
You smell that?
EVE: There's a plot aimed
at the peace agreement?
NICK: We will begin
with the little scene.
We shall cut off its head
beginning with the prime minister.
Where, Nick, where are
they gonna hit the delegation?
Conference of Jerusalem.
Do not weep for me,
but weep for yourselves
and your children.
The day that they will come
when they will say
blessed are the wombs
that never bore
and the breasts that never nursed.
[Screaming]
EVE:
Where, Nick, where?
The revolution of God.
The delegation
will board the plane
and my brother will deliver them
and they will be no more.
Dean.
He's gonna blow up
the prime minister's plane.
Take him back to holding!
You get to the delegation.
I'll call you when
I hit the ground in Chicago.
Shane.
I will be back for you.
I promise.
This is Agent Rearden.
Get me the head of the delegation
security detail immediately.
They're in imminent danger.
They've got ground
transportation waiting for us
on the tarmac in Chicago.
I want Jack Thompson on the
phone as soon as we take off.
EVE: I understand it's not protocol.
I believe the delegation
has been targeted.
The suspect is leading an operation
for a rogue organization.
MAN: [On radio] Fallen leader, we
are approaching insertion point.
We're in position.
[Grunts]
MAN: [On radio]
Two, one, Ere.
[Shots firing]
MAN: [On radio]
Target is neutralized.
Fallen leader,
the tarmac is clear.
Identification, sir.
Nypen, Corey.
Got your woolies on?
Cold one tonight, boys.
Yes, sir, stand by please.
This will just take a minute.
MAN 2: [On radio] Nypen,
Corey all clear.
SOLDIER: You're good to go, sir.
Carry on.
Dad, it's Eve.
Where are you?
Call me back immediately.
Sir, I'm gonna need you
to open up your tool bag there.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Here, let me help you out.
FBI, I need to see the delegation.
Matthew Dean!
FBI!
[Gunfire]
No!
[Explosion]
Hey, how you doin'?
Good, you?
Good, good, good.
So you locked yourself out, huh?
Yeah, yeah, work's been crazy
and just lost my keys so.
Lose your mind
if you're not careful.
That's what my mom always said.
Right, right.
Will this take long?
It will take as long as it takes.
OK.
You got some I.D.?
Yeah, yeah, sure, of course.
Here you go.
All right, let's see what we got.
OK.
Feel like such an idiot, you know,
locking myself out.
It's just that I have this
dinner party to get to
and so I'm really in a hurry to...
Man, you put a lot
of money into this lock.
Yeah, yeah, I did.
You can never be too careful.
I have to get another tool.
Really?
[Drill whirling]
Ah, great.
Home sweet home.
What do I owe you?
I'll send you a bill.
You're gonna send me a bill?
[Sirens]
[Phone ringing]
Eve.
EVE: Shane, I didn't make it.
We lost the delegation.
Masad is sending you
addresses right now.
I'm sorry, Shane.
Eve, we're gonna stop
those bombs, trust me.
I know this sounds
crazy coming from me,
but have faith.
[Daniel breathing heavily]
SHANE: I need all leads
in the Oak Park area
within the last 6 months.
I need every available
agent on this.
This is Daughtry.
I'm at the warehouse.
Going in.
[Phone ringing]
Yes?
MAN: [On phone]
Hello, my brother.
It is time.
MAN 2: [On phone]
Yes, brother.
[Speaking foreign language]
This is Daughtry,
scratch the warehouse address.
No activity.
DANIEL: [Breathing heavily]
[Speaking foreign language]
Come on, come on, come on.
FEMALE OPERATOR:
[Whispering]
Sir, you need to speak up.
Guns, lots of guns.
And they have bombs.
FEMALE OPERATOR: OK, stay where you are.
We're sending someone now.
[Whispering]
Please hurry, please.
MAN: [On phone]
Agent Daughtry.
SHANE:
Go ahead.
MAN: [On phone]
From a man trapped with gunmen.
He claims they have bombs.
You're about
Black and white units
are en route.
[Sirens]
[Phone vibrating]
[Speaking foreign language]
[Sirens]
Thirty-seven nineteen.
Thirty-seven...
[Shots firing]
ANGELA:
Daniel! Daniel!
[Speaking foreign language]
[Rapid gunfire]
[Shots firing]
God, please.
Please help me
get back to my wife.
[Yelling and grunting]
[Shots firing]
[Speaking foreign language]
[Yelling]
[Neck cracking]
Who are you?
I'm the neighbor,
from across the street.
Angie!
Angie, baby, where you?
Here.
I thought I'd lost you.
It's OK.
You OK?
Yeah, I heard people
screaming and gunshots.
I didn't know what was going on.
Look at me.
Will you pray with me?
Of course I'll pray with you.
Jesus,
I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
Forgive me for not
being a better husband.
Forgive me for my sins.
Come into my heart,
and I will make you
Lord of my life,
for all the rest of my days.
MATTHEW DEAN: Seven Wonders
has been compromised.
MAN: [Distorted voice on phone]
That's unacceptable.
There were circumstances,
you know this.
MAN: [Distorted voice on phone]
And there are consequences.
[Shots firing]
MAN: [Distorted voice] Hello, my son.
Is there much to report?
Brother has been called home.
Good.
I'll follow up
with further instructions.
[Explosion]
SHANE:
We got him, Eve.
We got him.
Are you all right?
EVE: I failed.
I couldn't save them.
I didn't make it in time.
It's not your fault.
You called the security detail
and they didn't listen.
You did everything you could, Eve.
We need to find Dean.
What in the world?
[Rumbling]
[Screaming]
[Crash]
[Car alarm blaring]
[Car alarm continues]
Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad.
Come on, come on, pick up.
Don't leave me.
[Phone ringing]
[Siren]
Eve?
EVE: All these years,
he was right, Shane.
My father was right.
I can't...
I can't breathe, Shane.
Stay where you are.
You have no idea
what we're in for.
Hurry, Shane.
SHANE:
Eve?
Eve, I'm coming for you.
I'm coming for you.
♪ Destruction is all around me
♪ The fear I face is all my eyes see
♪ The whole world is crashing in
♪ The days before are gone
♪ I can't see through this storm
♪ The dark has overcome our light
♪ Suffocating, hard to breathe
♪ But I believe that you can save me
♪ I have all my hope in you
♪ I know you hold the truth
♪ You can bring me back to life
♪ Help me fight this fight
♪ I have hope in you
♪ We've become so numb to all this
♪ In the blink of an eye
my life changed
♪ We have to stand up
and fight for his gain
♪ And I know that you will save me
♪ I have all my hope in you
♪ I know you hold the truth
♪ You can bring me back to life
♪ Help me fight this fight ♪♪
Sub source used: kvrle
Adaptation: miclar1