Hi.
Don't be late for judge Nicastro.
Are you kidding? I'm up, I'm ready, I'm...
- Good morning.
- This is ridiculous.
- We're seizing your boat.
What about due process?
Come on. I live here.
Not anymore.
You can't be serious.
Andrew.
I'm so glad that you called me.
Who are you?
My name is Kate Reed and I'm his lawyer.
Okay.
No one's setting foot today
on Mr. McKinnon's boat
but Mr. McKinnon.
Ms. Reed, your client is in violation...
He filed the wrong paperwork.
I didn't file any paperwork.
Which is still wrong.
But he's not a drug dealer.
He's an idiot.
Just didn't file the paperwork.
- Which is idiotic.
- The point is...
The point is this is America.
We don't board. We do not seize.
We're not pirates.
So go take down some bad guys
and make us proud.
Go on.
Let's go.
This matter needs to be resolved.
And resolved it will be.
Don't leave town.
Bad.
You know, if I knew a little customs
issue was the only thing...
No. . No time for flirting today.
Mm-mm-mm. I am almost late and I can't be.
You see, this judge, he totally hates me.
So call me at the office and
we'll discuss this later.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I didn't even know you're a lawyer.
I'm not. Well, I used to be.
- Then how you going to...
- Don't worry about it.
I got it covered.
All right.
Judge Nicastro's office called.
Well, did you tell him I'm here? I'm here.
If you're there, you can tell him yourself.
Judge, I'm here. I'm just saying.
You like football, Ms. Reed?
- Is that a trick question?
- Let's start again.
Um, yes, I love football.
No, I hate football.
Is that the right answer?
I'm not in contempt of anything, am I?
- Ms. Reed?
- Yes, sir?
There's a high school
football coach I know.
Old-school disciplinarian.
Strict. Tough.
Sounds familiar.
Ha. Well, anyway,
coach Gardner went after a kid in practice.
Quarterback. Really tore into him.
Somebody caught it on video
and the school has suspended the coach.
And, well, now a group of
parents, they're trying
to get him fired.
Any time a faculty member is suspended,
mediation is triggered automatically.
So I'm... I'm assigning the case to you.
- 'Cause I'm the best?
- 'Cause you love football.
Got it. Um, coach Gardner was your coach?
- No.
- Then he's your best friend?
- Uh, not exactly.
- Judge?
- Oh. Ha. Ah, my son.
- Oh, Bobby.
Yeah, Bobby.
Well, he's turned out
to be a fine young man,
but there was a time when that
was not a likely outcome.
Mm. When he was a teenager?
Teenagers rebel, judge.
I mean, that's just what they do.
And teenagers with strong fathers
rebel even harder.
Bobby was running full
speed down the wrong path.
And a lot of wrong paths.
- And then he found football?
- He found coach Gardner.
Mm.
The coach took all that
anger that Bobby had
and he made him put it
on the football field.
He learned respect for
the people around him.
Respect for himself.
Respect for old-school disciplinarians.
I very nearly lost my son.
Coach Gardner saved him.
I'm late for court.
Judge, sorry, just one more thing.
Mediators are impartial
so I'm just not sure...
I don't want to see him railroaded.
Just be fair.
- I can do that, sir.
- I'll be watching.
Closely.
That's comforting.
Sync by YYeTs.net
Corrected by Addic7ed.com
www.addic7ed.com
Hey, I don't want any
pissant excuses, Riley!
You're too stupid to look at your watch
and get here on time,
you're too stupid to play on my team,
you hear me?
Now, when you get your head out of your ass
and start acting like a
man, then you can play!
Till then, you sit down and shut up!
What are you looking at?
Let's go! Hustle up!
Okay. Who wants to go first?
I send my son now...
That was my son.
Could easily have been any one of ours.
This is a pattern of
behavior that has to stop.
We need to end this.
We need to fire that man.
I understand that you guys are upset.
But this...video tape does
not give us any context
in which to fire him.
Well, yes, it does.
Coach Gardner...
- I'll be right back.
- Yeah, he ran away.
- Coach Gardner.
- Whoa!
- Coach Gardner left.
- Oh, yeah. He took the stairs.
- Why didn't you stop him?
- 'Cause he's a football coach.
I couldn't even stop a guy
like that in a video game.
- Damn it.
- Is there anything I can do?
Yes, please. Reschedule for later on today.
- Great.
- Why is that great?
I thought you were going to ask me
to chase him down the stairs.
Kate.
You know what, I should get that.
- Kate.
- Yes. Hold on.
Wait. Don't move.
Kate Reed's office.
Justin, hi.
Oh. Yeah, sure. Hold on.
It's Justin for Leo.
That's weird, isn't it?
Mm. What happened with
the school mediation?
Why did the coach just leave?
Leo!
All good. Rescheduling.
They've all been rescheduled
for this afternoon.
See. Told you. Hey, it's Justin for you.
Kate, I am really concerned.
Oh, hold that thought. I should get that.
I want to hear what you got to say.
I just really got to get this.
Ah. Kate Reed's office. Andrew.
Yeah. Um, hold on one second.
Uh, it's a new client. Andrew McKinnon.
Yes.
I'm gonna be a while. So...
Yeah, um, you know what, I
haven't had a chance to yet.
But why don't you give me your number.
Okay, I'll call you later.
Yeah, promise. Bye.
What was that about?
Oh, it's just this... thing...
With my neighbor.
Mm. Thought he was a client.
- That too.
- So pro bono?
He got cited for a customs violation
and I'm just helping him out.
He's just a nice kid
from Australia, Lauren.
Oh, great. What's the issue?
Failure to declare funds over $10,000.
Well, did he file his paperwork
with customs and border protection?
No, he didn't.
But you know what? I'm actually...
I'm just starting to research all of that.
- I'll take it.
- What?
- Said I'll take it.
- Pro bono, Lauren.
For free.
What do you know about customs law?
That we have books about
it in the law library.
You mess up, we'll get sued.
Oh. Okay. It's a money thing.
All right. My world makes sense again.
Probably want to know why
Justin is calling me.
Actually, I don't.
Kind of fits in with the rest of my day.
Where are you going now?
To get the other half of my mediation back.
Oh!
- Oh, uh, excuse me.
- Yeah?
Sorry. Is coach Gardner around?
Yeah. I saw him in there. He'll be a while.
- Hi.
- Hey, man.
Whoa, lady, you're in
the wrong locker room.
No, no, I'm not.
The girls' locker room
is in full compliance
with all the codes and the regulations.
I wish I could say the same thing...
About the guys'.
And you're from the...
San Francisco Department
of Building Inspection, yes.
You don't look like a building inspector.
What does a building
inspector look like, hmm?
You know, I am old enough to be your...
Mother's very, very young sister.
I'm sorry, but I don't see you
carrying a tape measure or...
I don't need a tape measure to know...
That, uh...
These lockers...
these lockers right here...
Whoo.
Are in violation... of the code.
- Because they're too old?
- Small.
They're small, fellas.
I mean, they're okay for girls lockers.
But for guys...
I mean, you guys, um, you guys need, uh,
man-sized lockers.
Yeah.
Where are you going to put your man shirts
and your man pants?
And these teeny, tiny little things?
No. What about the sports
illustrated cutouts?
Yeah.
And the Victoria's secret models.
Those girls, they need
room in your lockers.
Oh! Oh! Oh, oh!
And right here,
I'm pretty sure...
there is supposed to be...
A jacuzzi.
That's right. Dreams can come true.
I just need one teeny, tiny little thing.
What?
The name of the person in charge.
Coach Gardner. Right down the hall.
Thank you.
Coach, it's not like that.
I will not stand by, you hear me?
- I will stand by...
- What's going on here?
- Are you Rick Riley?
- Yeah.
I'm Kate Reed.
I'm the mediator that's handling the case
between coach Gardner and the school.
Don't you have class?
Go.
- Well, that was interesting.
- Yeah. That was private.
No. We're past private, coach.
What's going on?
Why'd you leave the mediation this morning?
I need answers.
Look, those people don't
know the first thing
about what I do.
Those people are the
parents of your players.
Yeah. And they all want the same thing.
They want the results
without the hard work.
Okay. But they have the right
to question the behavior
of the person that they
entrust their children to.
- What, are you defending them?
- No.
I'm just saying that they have
the right to ask questions,
especially after seeing that
video, and they might have more
after I tell them what I just saw.
Now, if you don't like what they're saying,
then fine, say something back.
The school wants to hear your side.
Judge Nicastro wants to hear your side.
It doesn't matter what I say.
That's what's different now.
The parents run the school.
All right, well, if you want
to do something about that,
then I suggest you get your ass
to mediation this afternoon.
And this time, you keep it there.
Two o'clock.
So here's the thing, Mr. McKinnon...
- Andrew.
You have to declare large amounts of cash
on entering U.S. waters.
I know, annoying, but it's the law.
It's not for the Andrew
McKinnons of the world.
It's for the drug dealers
and the money launderers.
I'm entirely in favor of
having those guys arrested.
I mean, they spoil all
the fun for us, right?
Well, if you conduct a
transaction over $9,999,
the government tracks it.
You were flagged at the bank
when you got your cashier's check.
But I had to buy a new
mainsail for my boat.
Ten grand? Is it Mylar?
- You sail?
- Yeah.
My father taught me when we were kids.
Just dinghy sailing.
Do you still keep up with it?
Yeah. My... my late husband had a boat.
But now I'm just much too busy now.
Well, you're never too busy to sail.
I mean, work, sure,
just to make enough to fix your boat up.
Hmm.
So where are we with this thing?
Well, usually customs seizes
all undeclared currency.
Please tell me you're not serious.
That's how they pay for
those nifty jackets.
Look, don't you worry about it.
I'm not gonna let that happen to you.
We'll file the correct paperwork,
you'll pay a small fine,
and you and your very fancy mainsail
can be on your way back
to Australia in no time.
Puerto Vallarta, actually,
or San Juan Islands, or Vancouver.
- Oh.
- But I'm not leaving just yet.
Well, I will contact you
as soon as all the proper
paperwork has been filed,
Mr. McKinnon.
- Thanks. Andrew.
- Andrew.
- Yeah. Have a nice day.
- Yeah. Thanks.
You came.
I want to make a statement.
Thank you for coming back.
Now, in a mediation,
it's very important for
both sides to be heard.
- Um, am I missing something?
- 'Scuse me?
You saw the video.
There is only one side.
Mr. Riley, there's always another side.
You humiliated my son.
You benched him on the biggest game
of the season.
And you know how many
scouts were out there.
Oh!
Are you okay?
This doesn't make any sense to me.
The man you're describing is...
Not the man I knew.
Well, Joe Riley has not
pressed assault charges yet.
I got him to agree to a mediation
between the school and
the insurance company.
And then after that...
We're gonna talk about charges.
The coach has done a lifetime of good.
Now, I am not trying to make excuses
for the crap he did today.
I just... I don't want people losing sight
of all the wonderful
things he did yesterday.
Okay. I'll, uh, I'll see what I can do.
Shoot a little higher than that, okay?
Yes, judge.
You are one lucky moron.
Uh, Joe Riley's not
taking you to court yet.
We're gonna sit down with
the school's lawyer,
the insurance company,
and you better hope we
can work something out.
- Do I have to testify?
- No.
- Not unless it goes to court.
- Good.
Yeah, you'd be horrible on
the stand, wouldn't you?
You know, I don't get you.
You've got all this stuff, but
you're just destroying it.
They gave me till 4:00 P.M. to get out,
okay?
Oh. Well, let me help you out.
- I don't need any help.
- No, it's okay.
I don't mind.
I'm an excellent packer.
So, coach...
What are you gonna do
when you can't coach anymore?
Have you thought about that?
Are you gonna...
Be the host at a restaurant or something?
Don't... don't... don't touch those.
You have that kind of charm, you know?
You have a way you can just
make everybody feel welcome.
It's fast packing, right?
Come on. This stuff, it's all meaningless.
- Just stop.
- What are you gonna do?
You gonna punch me too?
Ah! Jeez!
Yeah. Oh, no, no, no. It's okay.
Don't worry about it.
Somebody will clean it up.
I don't need your help
or anybody else's, okay?
- Ah.
- Don't. Don't. Don't.
- Yeah. What?
- Give me that.
- What do you care?
- They're men now. Good men.
They've earned a right to be on that wall.
- How do you know?
- Because they call, okay?
They send me Christmas cards.
They come see me after homecoming.
They find me.
Adam Lee, he's a...
He's a banker in New York.
Ben Jones is a coach,
and Chad Harper's an artist in the mission.
Lou Tomacino, he's a...
He's a fifth grade math teacher.
- So you like the players.
- Course I do.
Why else would I do this?
Not for the money.
I got a car that's older than these kids.
Yeah, but you didn't like Rick Riley.
I don't know what you're talking about.
- Coach, I saw the video.
- Oh, you saw the video. Wow.
Makes you a freaking genius, doesn't it?
Evening.
Thanks for saving my ass this morning.
Everybody needs something to sit on.
I don't know what I would've done
if you hadn't introduced me
to that fantastic woman.
- And that would be?
- Lauren. She's amazing.
Lauren?
The blonde? The lawyer?
She's taking care of
everything at no charge.
- I'm in very good hands.
- Amazing? Really?
Yeah. And funny and interesting...
And stiff and icy and cold,
with the...The... Lauren Reed?
She's great.
Anyway, thanks, Kate. Night.
And I'll have the, uh,
New York strip medium
and the souffle for dessert.
Takes 20 minutes.
Uh, just the Caesar. Thanks.
So you're probably wondering
what this is all about.
- Not really, no.
- Not even curious?
- You need a favor.
- Um...
And it has something to do with Kate.
And I'm guessing since her
birthday's coming up...
Okay, all right, all right.
Stop. Okay, let me explain.
Because the fact that you
figured all that out
makes me seem extremely lame.
You have absolutely no
idea what to get her.
All right. Stop. Okay?
You figured me out.
Look, when we were married,
we had a strict no presents policy, right?
We would just do stuff together.
You know, maybe go out for the night.
Whatever. Just making time for each other.
It was great.
- Now we're not married.
- No, you're not.
Last month on my birthday,
Kate had this delivered.
That's nice.
And now I don't know what to do.
- You could return the jacket.
- No. Are you kidding me?
Not an option. No.
I want to get her something special.
You spend more time with
her than anybody I know.
Can you please help me with this?
What's in it for me?
Well, there's this little jaywalking ticket
that keeps bouncing its way
back to your old address.
Whoa, hey, know what, I
am here to help you.
Love that about you, Leo.
Yeah. Mmm!
Souffle, huh?
Joe Riley's here with his lawyer.
I put him in the conference room
with the insurance rep, a
lawyer from the school.
- Got it. Thanks.
- Hey, quick question.
Godzilla, Mothra, King Kong...
If you had to pick one.
First instinct. No wrong answer.
- Mothra.
- Hmm.
Would you describe Lauren as, um, amazing,
funny, or interesting?
- No.
- More like pinched.
Precise. Kind of annoying, right?
- That's more in the ballpark.
- That's what I thought.
All right, I'll be in the conference room.
Morning. I trust that
everyone's met one another.
Mr. Riley. His attorney Robert Kenton.
- Laurie Davidson.
- Ms. Reed.
Yes.
Before we begin,
please make it clear to Mr. Kenton
that coach Gardner was suspended
at the time of the incident
and, therefore, the school
cannot be held accountable.
Please inform Ms. Davidson that suspension
is not termination, and therefore...
Okay, suing a school
because a suspended member
of the faculty punched a
guy for egging him on
is not the home run case of the century.
Thank you.
However, coach Gardner, though suspended,
was still a member of the faculty
at the time the incident occurred.
And he did assault a parent
in front of witnesses.
So I'm sure that we can find
a reasonable middle ground.
No, come on, that's ridiculous.
- Joe...
- No. No. No. Come on.
Gardner berated my son, he benched him,
and then he assaulted me.
There's no middle ground.
Uh, Leo, we're in the middle of a meeting.
It's an emergency.
Your son collapsed in practice.
He's been rushed to the hospital.
Then I'd like to take him home
as soon as possible.
No, doctor, that is not an option.
No, not unless you're telling me...
We just walked in.
Okay, fine, I'll meet you there.
I gotta go meet the doctor in his office.
- Rick is in the recovery.
- I heard.
Probably giving him more fluids.
He was dehydrated.
Was that it?
Well, I think so.
Doctor's too busy covering his ass
to say anything more specific.
Listen, Kate, I really appreciate you
keeping me company on the way.
Oh, sure, sure,
I was more than happy to do that.
- Good. - And I guess I'll just reschedule
the mediation for when Rick is feeling better.
- No.
- Mr. Riley, we can make this work.
There's no reason
we have to go to court.
You know what,
I'm just gonna drop the whole thing.
The mediation, the assault charges,
everything.
Really?
Are you sure about that?
Obviously the stress with this thing
with the coach,
is the reason Rick's in the hospital.
I'm still ticked at that guy
for what he did to me and my son,
but I'm gonna suck it up.
Listen, I gotta go
find this doctor's office.
Get my son out of here before he catches
something actually horrible.
- Thanks again.
- You're welcome.
But I didn't really do anything.
- Kate.
- Yeah.
- How's the assault mediation?
- Um, good, good.
Everything's fine, you know.
The dad just decided to drop everything.
- Oh, wow.
- Yeah.
Why are you being nice to my friend?
I was better equipped to take the case
and I wanted to know if
your friend, McKinnon,
was related to another McKinnon,
the Australian billionaire.
- With a "b"?
- Yes.
Is he?
We do a small favor now,
maybe it pays off for the firm later.
I knew you weren't being nice.
Define "nice."
Watching you guys is like
watching those weird
rainforest bird territory dances.
Well, who has the better feathers?
Makes me so uncomfortable.
Why don't you watch shows
about humans, huh?
Touche.
Hey, is this video cued up?
Yeah.
Heat lamp, electric blanket,
or thermal underwear?
Electric blanket.
Leo, any more of these triptychs
and I'm gonna have to
ask for an explanation.
- I'll give you three.
- Cute!
You're too stupid to look at your watch
and get here on time,
you're too stupid to play
on my team, you hear me?
Now, when you get your head out of your ass
and start acting like a
man, then you can play!
Watch and get here on time,
you're too stupid to play
on my team, you hear me?
Now, when you get your head out of your ass
and start acting like a
man, then you can play!
- Hey, Leo.
- Yep?
Can you come in here for a second?
Does this kid seem scared to you?
You're too stupid to play
on my team, you hear me?
Not "there's an angry, muscular man
spitting in my face" kind of scared, no.
Till then, you sit down and shut up!
Hey, look, the kid says something.
Where?
It's after the coach stops talking.
Thanks, Leo.
Rick. Hi. Kate Reed.
- Remember me?
- Yeah.
- How are you?
- I guess I'm doing okay.
That's good.
Hey, listen, I rewatched that video
of coach Gardner benching you.
Look, um, my dad's just
filling out some forms.
He's gonna be back in here in a second.
Okay. I was just wondering
what was it that you said
after he stopped yelling at you?
I don't know. Nothing.
Really? Because it looked
like you said "thank you."
Kate, look, I really
don't feel like talking right now, okay?
Okay. Okay.
You know what doesn't make sense
in this situation?
That you would get reamed
in front of all of your football friends
and then say "thank you."
So man up. The truth, Rick.
What's going on with you and coach Gardner?
He caught me doing steroids.
It was just a stupid mistake.
But if anyone found out, I'd
get kicked out of school.
And there'd be no way that
I could get a scholarship
to college.
So I begged him not to turn me in.
And then the yelling,
that was... that was all just a show?
Yeah...I promised to stop
when he said that he'd just bench me
until the stuff left my system.
I don't want any pissant excuses, Riley!
If you're too stupid to look at your watch
and get here on time,
you're too stupid to play on my team!
Now, when you get your head out of your ass
and start acting like a man,
then you can come back on the team!
Till then, you sit down and shut up!
Thank you, coach.
Coach was just being nice.
Yeah. He was being awfully nice.
So is that it?
I don't know. Is it?
Nobody's making any sense, you know?
I just... it just doesn't
make any sense to me.
What doesn't make any sense?
The icing rules of hockey.
I just don't get it.
I mean, you've got the...
it was the blue line, right?
It's not really my... not my game.
So you're just hanging around the hospital?
I was just visiting a friend of mine
and I thought I'd see if
you guys were still here.
Yeah. Uh, I signed you out, bud.
Let's go.
- Bye, Rick.
- Kate.
You caused me a lot of trouble.
I didn't make you punch that guy.
- Honey, who is it?
- It's that mediator.
- Invite her in.
- Yes, please.
So why didn't you tell me
he was taking steroids?
He's a good kid.
He made one giant mistake.
I couldn't bring myself to ruin his future
by having that on his record.
Coach, with all due respect, you're lying.
You know, you and I,
we're never gonna see eye to eye on this.
We're not. We're not.
You went through the trouble
of screaming at him,
benching him, all so that
nobody would find out
he was taking steroids,
but then you get suspended
and you still don't say anything?
Last year, the basketball coach
turned a kid in.
He got kicked off the team.
Was never much of a student, that kid.
But without the structure of practice,
without the team, he fell apart.
Dropped out.
So you thought you could handle things
better than the system?
No, the team is the system. And it works.
We've been turning boys
into men for decades.
Yeah, but you can't do
that all by yourself.
I tried to call Rick's
father over and over,
but he wouldn't talk to me.
- So then you just decked him?
- I have good reason.
Here, I got something for you.
Keep 'em somewhere safe, all right?
- Give me that bottle.
- What?
- Coach, it's nothing.
What, are you kidding me? Come here.
You taking steroids is bad enough,
but your father dealing to you?
- Coach, it's not like that.
- Shut up, Rick!
I'm not going to stand by, you hear me?
I'm not going to stand by
and have this kind of...
What's going on here?
So by the time I found out
that Rick was getting
steroids from his father,
I'd already been suspended from coaching.
So that's why Joe was so eager
to get Rick out of the hospital.
He didn't want the doctors to find out
what he was giving to his son.
Have you called child services?
Not yet.
Look, they'd yank him out of his home.
I went to the hospital to find out
if he had any relatives he could stay with
while this thing was getting sorted out,
but it turns out, no,
they're all back east.
I feel like I let him down.
Poor kid's all alone.
No, he's not.
Okay, I asked Kate to choose
between Mothra, Godzilla, and Kong.
And she picked Mothra.
What are you talking about?
Her other answers were electric blanket,
corduroy, and plutonium.
Are you kidding me?
It all adds up to the perfect gift.
Which is what?
A monster with a radioactive blanket
that makes a noise when you rub against it?
- An iPad.
- Excuse me?
Kate's answers confirm what
we already know about her.
She's a woman with a million interests
and the attention span of a cocker spaniel.
Plus they're really cool
and everybody wants one.
I can't believe I let you
scam a meal from me.
Hey, if you got a better idea,
I invite you to go down in flames with it.
Well...
Didn't think so.
I'll tell you what, give
me your credit card
and I'll go pick one up.
And I'll wrap it too.
I'm one-stop shopping.
Fine.
Yeah. Come in.
Am I disturbing you?
Oh, Mr. McKinnon. Sorry, Andrew.
Yeah, no, please, please. Come in.
- These are for you.
- Oh.
They're lovely.
Uh, Mr. McKinnon... Andrew...
Just so we're clear,
as much as I enjoyed working
together the other day,
I'm in the middle of...
You wouldn't take any payment
for your services.
The flowers are my way of saying thanks.
Well, thank you.
I'll be seeing you, Lauren.
Yeah. Pleasure doing
business with you, Andrew.
Yeah.
Thank you again. They're really beautiful.
Mr. Riley. Hi.
Thanks so much for coming in.
Uh, we're gonna go right back
into the conference room.
Okay.
Not quite sure what we
have left to talk about.
You know, it's just some paperwork,
formalities, minor stuff.
You will be out of here in no time.
All right.
- After you, sir.
- Thank you.
Mr. Riley, I would like for
you to meet judge Nicastro.
Why is there a judge here?
Oh, he's just kind of an
agent of the court thing.
- Right, judge?
- Correct.
Have a seat.
Now, the beauty of a mediation
versus a court trial
is that in mediation, both
sides come out winners.
But in order to get those
really good outcomes,
you've got to make some concessions.
Concessions.
Here's what you're going to do.
You are going to write a letter
on behalf of the other parents
to the school district
insisting that coach Gardner be rehired.
And then...You're going to sign this.
Uh...You know what?
I'm not going to sit here...
You provided steroids to a minor,
Mr. Riley...
your son... in direct violation
of school policy and the law.
A felony. Open the envelope.
Your son will live with coach Gardner
and his wife for the remainder
of the school year.
He will be tested regularly
to make sure that he's clean.
You will enter a counseling program
of my choosing.
As long as you remain in that program,
you will have supervised
visitation with your son.
And you sign those documents
and you get a concession too.
And what's that?
We don't have you throw in jail.
Wow. Couldn't have be easy for Joe Riley
to give me temporary custody, huh?
Well, he liked it better
than his alternative.
Are you sure you're okay with him
coming to dinner every night?
Oh, yeah. I think it's good.
Boy needs to see his father
and Joe Riley needs to
learn to act like a man.
Little adult supervision
wouldn't hurt that.
No. I talked to Rick, you know,
and he seems pretty happy about it.
Yeah, he is.
- I think he's relieved.
- Yeah.
So how's your suspension coming along?
Oh, it's great.
Assistant coach is doing great.
It's relaxing, really, you know,
just to be an observer.
Yeah, I like it.
Come on, Clark! Pretend you're alive!
- It's like a vacation.
- Yeah.
Well, you finally got what you wanted.
Which is what?
You thought that the
parents were the problem,
and now you get to coach one of them too.
Whaley, come on!
You call that getting off the line?
Hi, Kate.
One day early? I am impressed.
Do you like it?
Justin, I love it. It's perfect.
Ah, you know, we've known
each other a long time.
Yeah, but still.
I mean, a boat toaster's a
little off the beaten path.
A boat toaster.
It might be the best present
you have ever given me.
Well, you know, I just, uh, had a feeling.
You know, I really like our new tradition.
What, you getting me something
beautiful like a coat,
and me getting you something
practical like a boat toaster?
No. Like, you put thought into it.
You know?
And we never used to try that hard.
Well, I'm glad you like it.
Listen, let me call you right back, okay?
Okay.
Kate Reed's office.
Where's my iPad, Leo?
She loves her toaster.
- Where's the iPad?
- It's my fee.
What are you talking about?
The boat toaster costs, like, ten bucks.
Yes, but she loves it.
How did you know she was gonna love it?
Well, Justin, Kate's a busy professional
with impeccable taste.
Plus she lives on a boat and loves toast.
Can't argue with that.
Good-bye, Leonardo.
Good-bye, Justin.
Hey, Leo, can you get me some bread?
Sync by YYeTs.net
Corrected by Addic7ed.com
www.addic7ed.com