It was all that damn kid.
I've always thought he
had no empathy at all...
but I never imagined this.
I can't believe it.
There must be some mistake.
There's no proof, is there?
I saw him.
He snuck out of the house that night.
But maybe he just went out.
Not just that night.
When Mr Kumagai died, too.
We can't just let this go.
It's just that he doesn't
understand the difference...
between right and wrong.
We can't have raised him right.
Don't punish him.
This has gone way beyond that.
He needs to be put away.
That would be cruel!
The boy's only 14!
LESSON OF THE EVIL
The rumors are true.
The marks in Year 1 Class 3
were very similar, and...
Yes, we know that.
So this term, how do
we stop this group cheating...
ls "cunning" the English word?
No, it's "cheating".
Oh...
And so?
Probably...
they're using cell phones.
So it's email?
They text without looking,
so from under a desk would be easy.
So I guess we ban cell phones.
We do that...
but we can't do body
searches and desk checks.
And it's not good policy to
openly distrust our students.
So what do we do?
Perhaps our Radio Club staff advisor...
could help us here.
Mr Tsurii?
This way we can shut down...
all the cell-phone cheating.
Excellent!
However...
However what, Mr Hasumi?
We may be in violation of the Radio Law.
You mean we'll be jamming phones?
We can adjust to stop it
going beyond the school grounds.
And limit it to exam times.
No one's likely to find out.
Yeah, but
breaking the law to stop cheating?
That's all mixed up.
Let's think of another way, then.
That's it for this morning's meeting.
Mr Hasumi?
Go for it.
I will.
I have high hopes.
Right.
Hasumin!
'Morning.
Good morning, Misaki & Ayane
Don't forget me!
Hey! Nice hair, Mayu
Questions so far?
Yes.
Yes, Toru
You always say "good" and "great".
What's the difference?
Good question.
Correct is "good", better is "great".
Even better is "excellent".
And there's more.
If it strikes you deep in your soul...
Mr. Watarai! It's your turn!
Magnificent
Is that right?
Excellent!
I'm trying to get into Todai University.
Magnificent
Let's repeat.
What does it mean?
Mr. Nagoshi! You'll up!
Sir?
Stand up, Please
All right, translate the title of
that comic book into English.
You can do it!
I'm sorry!
OK, it comes from "magnify".
It's an adjective.
On tests, remember
it means "beautiful", or "impressive".
Everyone! You've got a picture?
Yes.
OK. Next.
Grand, "majestic".
Related to "magnificent".
Magnificent?
A type of hymn, usually sung at evening.
Magnificent praises something
beyond normal understanding.
Keisuke! You're wasted
on science, you know.
Aw, shutout.
So how's your class going?
Are you used to Hasumi yet?
He's OK.
Anyway, word's getting around.
About what?
The cheating. You're doing it again, right?
You like raising shit.
What good does it do you?
Yeah. Why do you do it?
No reason.
Just to pass time.
It's a game to mess up
their marking scheme.
I won't get caught.
Yeah, you should be all right.
Sure!
After exams I'm taking off.
Where this time?
I don't know. Wherever I feel like then.
I haven't missed a school day
since 2nd year started.
You always say that!
There's no bullying here.
We're right on top of it.
Well, we've talked to her classmates again.
There's no evidence of bullying.
So Rina's lying?
I'm not saying that.
Maybe there's been some misunderstanding...
Misunderstanding?
You mean she just thinks
she's being bullied when she isn't?!
Do you think the ones doing it
don't know what'll happen...
if they own up to it?!
Calm down, please.
Calm down?!
Did you just tell me to calm down?!
Everything I do is for my daughter.
I'll kick your ass!
Try me!
I can fight, you know!
Inside.
Did you see that?
That was Miya, right?
Psychopathology Research
Hasumin! 'Morning!
Careful!
Who put gum in here!
Just leave it.
Then we can't lock it from inside.
Someone'll break in.
They'll just wreck it again.
Think of another way.
Hasumin...
What's up?
Um...
What's wrong?
Well...
Reika thinks maybe...
Miya is being sexually harassed.
Who by?
Are you OK?!
You're next.
Yes, sir.
Mr Shibahara found out...
I was shoplifting.
I won't tell anyone, he said.
Tell me why you did it.
I did...
and he recorded it...
then said put out or else.
Appalling
Really!
You, too.
Seat belt.
Send Shibahara this text.
I've apologized to the store, comma...
and it's OK now. Period.
However...
Wait...
However, comma...
I found out that for
lewd conduct with a minor, comma...
you are the one...
who will get charged. Period.
Is this OK?
Don't worry. He takes the
fall if this gets out.
Don't! Stop it!
You, too.
You stop it.
I'm going home.
See you tomorrow. Go straight home.
Starting with today's test,
we will collect cell phones.
I sympathize, but this
is a faculty decision.
Let's have 'em.
Thank you.
Give it here.
Where's yours?
I forgot it.
Oh, well...
No service
No service?
Maybe there's something
wrong with your phone.
With everyone's?
Now they're all working fine.
They were being jammed.
Jammed?
An interference signal.
It can be done.
Then why would they bother
confiscating the phones?
Someone else was doing it.
Jamming the phones?
Who?
My home-room teacher, I bet.
Tsurii?
Yeah.
He's staff advisor for the Radio Club.
He's a lurker.
You never know what he's thinking.
Since I have you here, I'll say two things.
One...
I will overlook this
latest cheating incident.
Learn from that.
And the second...
I wasn't jamming the phones.
But someone was.
Unless your phones and mine
went on the blink together...
it looks that way.
So?
Watch your step.
Masanobu Tsurii
The Weather Effect
Copycat Suicides
In Norse mythology, a pair of ravens
named Huginn and Muninn...
patrol the world as agents of Odin.
Their names mean thought and memory...
These two ravens fly over the Earth...
and bring tidings to
Odin, King of the Gods.
Watch your head. Feet first.
Whoa!
It's OK. Hang on.
Here he comes!
Go.
You OK?
Almost there. Take it slow!
I made it!
Confirm the victim is
conscious and breathing.
Finally, confirm pulse and breathing.
And that's it.
All right?
Who wants to try?
Me!
What if you defibrillate
his crotch by mistake?
Hey, wait!
It's OK! You might even like it.
Do me.
Three, two...
one, bam!
I never came that much before.
Yuck!
Whatever.
But don't forget...
it records everything
you say when it's in use.
Is that true?!
As data to improve treatment in the future.
And you're ugly!
Uh-oh...
Cut it out! Slow down!
Tade!
Ow! That hurts!
What a wimp!
Loser!
So you said there was
no bullying in Year 2 Class 4?
You didn't look very hard!
You didn't see that.
It's a message board one
of the girls started.
It's password-protected
so not everyone can get on.
There's a whole world out
there you don't see!
See? It's clear there's bullying going on.
This is Saori Yokota's site, Mr Kiyota.
There's lots like that.
I assume you're taking this
comment by "Tade" as bullying?
They're complaining about her!
All of them!
This "Tade"...
is a student named "Tadenuma".
He can be a bit aggressive...
but I wouldn't take
criticism on a site like this...
is anything more than letting off steam.
We all need that, don't we.
What?
I'm just here complaining
so I can let off steam?
Not at all.
You think you're pretty
smart, you son of a bitch!
Hasumin...
Yes, Miya?
Could I see you after school?
What's up?
I can't say here.
What?
Hey! What's going on?
I hate that.
Sorry.
Who's there?
Did you see?
What?
What are you doing?
Just sleeping.
It's wet.
Leave me alone.
It's OK.
Who was it?
Don't worry about it.
Where's Rina?
Hasn't she phoned?!
Kerosene?
Yes.
He had water bottles out
front to keep cats away.
But they'd been filled with kerosene.
We think the fire that killed him
started with a butt he'd thrown down.
A cigarette...
He smoked a lot, didn't he.
Oh?
He'd sit there and chain-smoke.
Here?
He'd come about his daughter.
Right?
Yes.
Well, at least Rina wasn't hurt.
That's the one good thing about it.
You're a detective, right?
And you are?
Tsurii. I teach physics here.
Mr Tsurii?
About Mr Hasumi, Rina's
home-room teacher...
He's a good teacher. Very enthusiastic.
And handsome.
What about him?
He started teaching at
this school last year.
Before that he was at
Kitahara Municipal High School.
Yes... and?
- So what?
- Goodbye.
What did you tell the cops?
That until the year before last,
Mr Hasumi taught at Kitahara High.
Kitahara High?
Cool!
What do you mean?!
Should I name names, Mr Kume?
All right. Masahiko Maejima.
You are involved with a student in
a homosexual relationship.
And so...
what do you want now?
I don't want this brought to light, either.
It could affect him emotionally.
Masahiko is sensitive.
And a bit conceited.
The combination could drive him to suicide.
He is also very attached to you, Mr Kume.
It's best for him if this is kept secret.
And for you as well.
You'd lose your teaching license.
Your family's prominent, too.
I'd like you to take more care.
This doesn't just involve you.
I'm sorry.
But how did you find out?
That doesn't matter.
What is important now is that you admit...
that you are an anti-social...
pervert.
Which means...
your life is in my hands.
I'm sure you understand.
Wow!
This is too much!
Tell me...
who's the friend who
lent you this place?
A smart gay, let's say.
Shall we shower?
You'd prefer alone?
I don't know...
What's that?
On your back.
A scar from an accident when I was a kid.
What happened?
Nothing worth talking about.
Weather effect?
The Sorrows of Young Weather,
the book by Goethe.
In the end he shoots himself.
A lot of people committed suicide
after it first came out.
So a wave of copycat suicides
is called the "Weather effect".
That happened at Kitahara?
There were four of them.
Two by hanging, one by jumping,
and one by carbon monoxide.
All at the school...
when Hasumi was there.
So?
Beats me.
How would I know?
Tsurii told the police...
Hasumi was at Kitahara
when the suicides happened.
He was involved?
No way!
Keisuke...
Drop this.
Why?
Just stop.
Somehow I feel...
you're in danger.
What?
Yeah, OK.
You piece of shit!
Stop it!
Don't!
Cut it out!
Where's Hasumin?
What's going on?
Yokota's site.
MT burned down RK's house
Tade burned down Rina's house?!
No, but someone posted this.
Who?!
Miya...
how many of those message boards
can you get onto?
Hey!
Tade!
Just between us.
Let's have a drink.
Huh?
You're a teacher.
I know you guys all drink.
You get a lot of things that piss you off.
We won't go anywhere, where we'll be seen.
I'm broke.
The grown-up pays, of course.
From his low salary. Don't tell anyone.
Let's see your hand.
It's fine.
Show me.
I'm fine.
And the shark, it has teeth
And it wears them in its face
And a knife has Mackie Messer
Of the knife one sees no trace
On a beautiful blue Sunday
Lies a dead man on the Strand
And a man goes round the corner
Mackie Messer they call that man
And Schmul Meier is missing
And many another rich man
And Mackie Messer has their money
They can't pin anything on him
Jenny Towler was found
With a knife in her chest
And on the wharf walks Mackie Messer
Who knows nothing about all this
And the great fire in Soho
Burnt to death were seven
children and an old man
In the crowd is Mackie Messer...
Hello, police? Help!
Who knows nothing, and whom you don't ask
And the young widow
Whose name everyone knows
Woke up with the dirty deed done
Mackie, what was your price?
It's just too weird.
Will you tell me what
you've found out about Mr Hasumi?
All I have is doubts, nothing more.
OK...
when did you first have doubts?
I'm a jerk, right?
Sorry?
When I meet someone outstanding...
I soon get feelings of inadequacy
that come bubbling up...
from deep down.
But I didn't feel any
of that when I met him.
On the surface...
he glitters.
But after a month, or even six months...
I still didn't hate myself.
There's something very strange about that.
So I went through
what I could find from his resume...
here at the school.
I found
it had strange gaps in it.
His father was a doctor,
and he was born here in Tokyo.
But then for 3rd year middle school...
he switched to Kyoto.
He stayed there, and got into Law
at Kyoto University...
but...
he dropped out after a month.
The next September he went abroad...
to Harvard!
What he studied had nothing to
do with becoming an English teacher.
He graduated, and took an MBA.
He then went to the North American
head office of Morgenstern.
Morgenstern?
A European investment bank.
But after two years he left...
and came back to Japan.
Then he suddenly changed fields,
and became a teacher.
At Kitahara.
So what's going on?
I started following other
lines of investigation.
His father's Clinic in Toshima Ward
had gone out of business.
Dr Hasumi and his wife
had been stabbed to death...
by an intruder.
His parents?
Yes.
He was stabbed in the
back and badly wounded.
That was in the winter of
2nd year middle school.
That made me very interested in
the suicides at Kitahara High.
Were they really suicides?
Or had there been other strange deaths
where he was around?
Before his parents died,
his middle-school home-room teacher...
a man named Kumagai,
had been killed in a car crash.
I only know about Tokyo.
What do you think, Mr Tsurii?
About Tade.
They say he ran away from home.
What do you think?
Good evening.
May I sit there?
Mr Tsurii made the sad choice...
to take his own life.
About this there is something
that must be said.
Which is that life itself is precious.
Here we go again, you may be thinking.
Whenever something like this happens,
our ears are numbed...
by talk of the importance of life
at school and in the media.
Where is it?!
Excellent!
Was it you?
Well done, Keisuke Hayami.
You're right. I bugged the room.
Did you kill him?
Keisuke?
Sir?
Sorry.
I didn't want anyone to see.
What's up?
Have you seen Keisuke?
Keisuke?
Keisuke Hayami?
No, I haven't. Why?
Nothing.
Soldering irons are great things, you know.
They can seal a wound shut
so you don't get the floor dirty.
Visually it's not great, though.
It leaves holes all over
the skin, like a beehive.
It's disgusting.
You know why I have this, right?
Nod for "yes", shake your head for "no".
Is that clear Mr. Hayami?
Bad, boy
First question.
The cheating...
which was very cunning...
You ran that.
Right?
Nod for "yes", shake your head for "no".
I see.
So you were the ringleader,
and these were your...
accomplices?
You may not want to tell on them,
but I won't do anything right away.
So relax.
This is so we can guide
our students better.
It's them, right?
Hey, Mr. Hayami, Yes or No?
Now...
to the big question.
Have you told anyone
what you heard from Mr Tsurii?
You were superb, Keisuke Hayami.
All those holes, and you wouldn't talk.
Or maybe you hadn't told anyone.
Anyway, as a teacher, I
am proud to have had...
a student like you.
Nice, that's "Mack The Knife".
Nope
Moritat.
Breech’s, The Threepenny Opera has... music
Yeah, I know.
Mack The Knife is the jazz
version of "Moritat".
Lyrics are little different.
But it's still a song about
a fucking killer too..
It's MY theme song.
You've killed a few, haven't you?
I spot people like you a mile away.
I'm right, aren't I?
Let's be partners.
It's over, CLAY.
You like killing for pleasure. Ha?
Not me.
You take the blame...
and a fucking burn.
Mr. Hasumi...
Vincent
has done an unfortunate thing.
As you can see
suicide.
There's even a will.
It's real.
You will testify. Because you get the
honor of being the first witness.
If I refuse?
You can't refuse.
Your name and fingerprints
will be on the
blacklist with the United
State immigration.
You'll never be able to
step foot into this country again.
Listen son
I plan on retiring quietly. Very quietly.
Don't ever come back.
You know...
this world is only for ambitious and
money-hungry criminals.
Not psychotic killers...
I could kill you anytime, Muninn.
You hardly ever answer
your cell phone, do you.
I don't?
I don't know what you
do when I'm not around.
Does it bother you?
Not really.
What is it?
Why...
do you have Tade's cell phone?
We went out drinking.
When?
The day of the fight.
He acts all grown-up, but
he can't hold his liquor.
He forgot his cell phone.
Tell me...
who do you think left that message?
About Tade putting kerosene
around Rina's house?
What do you think?
I don't know.
Final notice: I don't want to
be Shibahara's slave any more.
I am unclean in body and soul.
The only thing I can do
is leave this body. Miya.
Milk Bar
I want a crepe, but this is Chinese food.
Sweet-and-sour pork. That's what I want.
Work hard.
Sweet-and-sour.
This is the Year 2 Class 4 classroom.
Yay!
Hell.
Don't film me!
Whoa!
What do we have inside?
Hands growing out of the wall.
The 2-4 House of Horrors
is under construction.
Work is steadily falling behind schedule.
Will they be done in time?
Whoa!
That was a scare.
Ms Kashiwabara, how is work progressing?
Uh...
There's lots to do, but we're trying.
Yes!
Great! I got your "yes!"
Hisashi! Put that thing down and help!
This is the "making of' video!
For future generations
when the festival's over.
For what?
Yuck! That's disgusting!
Something's going on!
Let me see.
What do you think?
Rina?!
Rina!
Has Rina Kiyota returned?
You'll be here next term?
Yes.
Great!
Are you staying all night tonight?
Yes.
A comment, please.
Uh... no comment.
Hasumin! Rina's back.
I'm fine now.
You know what our class is making?
What?
Look.
A house of horrors!
She's lonely.
Yeah, you're right.
Settle down!
Who's here from Class 4?
Everyone, I think.
Except Tade.
Don't start trouble.
Is Shibahara...
still hitting on Miya?
I don't know.
He's the duty teacher.
He'll be here with us all night.
You think he'll try something again?
There she is.
He told her...
to come see him?!
Come on!
I'll stay here.
You're not worried?
Hasumin?
Lock it
Can we send Yuzuka that picture from
Tade's cell phone?
The one of them both.
When Rina showed up...
she said,
With Tade the whole class would be here...
and got all teary-eyed.
I don't think we should
show that to Yuzuka.
It might make things harder?
What's that?
What... are...
Giving Mr Shibahara a gift.
Hasun.
Min...
It's OK.
Whoa! Don't do that!
Hasumin?
Where's Miya?
Miya?
Kume speaking.
It's Hasumi. Where are you?
At home.
You can be here in 30 minutes.
Hurry.
There's trouble. It's Masahiko.
Masahiko
We're sorry, but your call
cannot be completed...
Here.
Thanks.
No service?
Satomi?
Do you have a minute?
I'd like to talk to you.
Talk to me?
Sure. What about?
Could we...
talk in the Club Room?
Can I finish this first?
Sure. There's no rush.
Holy shit!
Wow!
Mr Hasumi?
Over here.
Do you have service?
MY Phone?
No service. Why?
Jamming?
Hasumin.
What's going on?
Wow!
That's great, sir!
Play with us at the festival.
Who, me?
You're really good!
Buy some juice.
Yeah?
Thanks!
Is it true you guys and Hayami
were cheating with cell phones?
So what?
And all the phones said
"no service" then, too?
I had Shibahara all wrong.
Yeah!
He should play.
Will he?
We'll talk him into it.
You should hear Mr Shibahara!
All of you, stay where you are.
Uh, sir...
Wait... you're from Class 1.
Sir, is that a...
Hasumi?
What the fuck?!
Miya?
I heard a noise.
Move! Turn off the music!
Turn it off!
What's wrong?
Your attention, please.
There is an intruder in the school.
I repeat, we have an intruder.
He is dangerous. Do not
go to the 1st floor.
Do not panic. Remain calm.
Get to the top floor. The
intruder has a shotgun.
Go to the roof, lock the
door, and wait for help.
A shotgun?
No way!
Let's do what he said!
Wait a minute!
Something's weird.
Hasumin's on the 1st floor!
He could get hurt!
No!
Maybe we can't trust him!
Tell them!
Stay here!
How's that going to help?!
I'm trusting Hasumin.
Let go!
Go to the top floor. The
intruder has a shotgun.
Go to the roof, lock the
door, and wait for help.
We need to go!
United we stand, divided we fall.
Had I taught them that yet?
Come on!
What's wrong?!
Kakeru's downstairs.
Maybe he got shot.
Where?!
Satomi...
Quick!
Hurry!
Open it!
It's locked!
Wait!
Someone outside locked it!
Ayumi?
Is anyone out there?! Open up!
Miya!
What about trying a landline?
The pay phone?
Or in the staff room.
Let's split up.
Hurry!
If he gets Kakeru, we haven't got a chance!
Naoki...
Satomi!
It's OK.
Stay here.
Let's close the fire shutters
and build a barricade.
It's dead!
We can't call help!
Come on!
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
It's not very likely you'll
get two with one shot.
Why?!
Why are you doing this, Hasumin?!
This is Mr Kume's doing.
It's no good us all bunched up like this!
Split up and hide!
Suzuki!
Let him go!
But...
I'm going, too.
Miho!
Me, too!
You fool! What are you doing?!
Don't call me a fool.
Hey!
Quick! Move it!
Masahiko!
Miya Yasuhara
Hey, Partner!
Hey, partner!
How about a little more enthusiasm.
Mack The Knife
Who's there?
Hasumin...
Hasumin?
Madoka?
Hasumin!
We did what you told us, sir!
Why?
Hasumin!
Stop!
Hasumin! Why?
Why didn't you close the window, stupid!
It's your fault! It serves you right!
Taden.
Tade's dead, isn't he.
You killed him, didn't you!
Hey! Call the police!
Call the police!
What?!
There's a guy at the school...
with a shotgun!
That school?
Your student card...
Hurry!
OK, I'm calling!
Hang on!
Hello? Is this the police?
There's a man with a gun at
a high school near here.
A shotgun!
At Shinko Academy.
I'm taking...
Satomi...
with me.
Satomi!
He said the Club Room.
No way!
Way, maybe.
It might work.
She's the guinea pig?
Are you nuts?!
Satomi...
Don't! It'll never work!
Yukio?
Is that you?
Yes.
Satomi!
Kakeru!
Hey bro
Looks like we're out of time...
Oh, shit!
No, we're OK.
It's a fire shutter. That's what it's for.
That's right.
We'll get help before it's too late.
I know it.
We just have to hang in till then.
Why didn't anyone untie that?!
Why didn't you?!
Shut up!
Someone untie it!
Go on!
It's that stupid cow's fault
for going out that way!
You said it might work!
Fuck you!
Hasumin...
Stay back!
Keep away!
Out of my Way!
Reika!
Shit!
Sir...
I have to get into Todai University...
To die?
The chute.
Chute?
The emergency-escape chute.
He'd see it as soon as we put it down!
Wait...
That just might work.
Come on!
No time to think.
Shit!
Sorry, Tohru!
But I've got to do this!
Yuichiro?
Reika...
trust me.
Do what I say.
OK.
Whose shoes are these?
You're going to frame Mr Kume?
Great!
I warned him to keep his
hands off the students.
No matter...
how beautiful.
Mr Kume went crazy and,
taking all the students with him...
committed love-suicide with you.
That's a pretty wild story, though.
That's crazy...
That's everyone.
Happy graduation.
Mr Kume, the Art teacher,
was involved with a male student.
He entered the school with a shotgun,
attacked and handcuffed me...
and then...
shot the students,
the Gym teacher, and himself.
A girl the Gym teacher had harassed
also threw herself off the roof.
But it might be hard to
fit that into the story.
Anyway, there's no need to think too hard.
It's not me who has to
think up a simple explanation.
It's the police.
Here.
Thanks!
Two survivors!
You two...
I can't believe you managed
to live through that.
As your home-room teacher,
I'm proud of you.
You son of a bitch! Go
fuck yourself, Hasumi!
You did it! All of it!
Fuck you, Hasumi!
He's the one who did it!
You bastard!
Hasumi!
Cut it out!
Stay away from me, Hasumi!
You bastard!
Hasumi!
The proof was in...
the nurse's office.
Hey! Don't touch that!
Replayil'19-
It's not very likely you'll
get two with one shot.
Why?!
Why are you doing this, Hasumin?!
This is Mr Kume's doing.
Keisuke's alive, right?
He's alive, right?
Right?!
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
This was all the will of God.
He gave me orders.
I had to kill everyone,
all the demons in Class 4...
to save their souls...
Muninn.
Say hello to Odin for me.
God's will?
He's crazy.
The bastard's completely crazy!
No.
No?
He's just starting the next game.
Magnificent!
Let's go, partner.
No way we will be found responsible...
Hasumin...
Edited: Led Zepp
Hideaki Ito
Fumi Nikaido
Shota Sometani
Kento Hayashi
KodaiAsaka
Erina Mizuno
Takayuki Yamada
Takehiro Hira
Mitsuru Fukikoshi
Based on a novel by Yusuke Kishi
Written & Directed by Takashi Miike