[This drama is based on psychology.
All cases and treatments are fictitious.]
What color do you think these are?
Purple? No.
They're plum-colored.
And they signify eternal love.
I love you, Mr. Soo Hyun.
I'm different from your mother.
I'll never leave your side.
[Final Episode]
Mr. Soo Hyun, go to your office.
[Soo Hyun is a bit rough around
the edges, but he's handsome.]
[Mr. Soo Hyun can be a bit
salty at times but he's a great cook.]
[Mr. Soo Hyun is a romantic guy who
shows me romantic movies when I'm sad.]
[Mr. Soo Hyun is a terrible writer but
he makes up for it with his voice.]
[Mr. Soo Hyun is the man that I love.]
I came here to work on a project.
It's called the
Choi Soo Hyun Revitalization Project.
You'll help me out with it, right?
Do it for me, at least.
Please? Just eat a little bit.
You have an obligation to
repay me for my kindness.
I love you, Mr. Soo Hyun.
I won't ever leave your side.
You're going to give up
on your experiment?
Yes. I think it would prove difficult
to continue it at the moment.
I apologize.
You said something like
this before, too. Why-
What's the issue?
I'll take care of it for you.
It's not something that
you could help me with.
I think that there may be
an issue with my hypothesis.
The one that claims that women
aren't capable of true love?
Are you talking about that one?
Yes.
That would really overturn
the entire experiment!
What are we supposed to do now?
I've already budgeted out a
portion to invest into your research
and we've already begun
things with Marketing-
I'll do my best to offer my counsel as
a psychologist to the Marketing Team.
However, I'll have to put
a halt to the experiment for now.
There a really, really low chance that
Dr. Choi will cancel the experiment.
Why? We've invested so much
money into this, though!
I'm sorry, Chairman. But if he does that,
it'll be a breach of his contract, right?
How about dealing with the damage
control on a company-wide scale
and you give him a stiff talking-to?
For example, you can give him
a punishment, or something.
A punishment?
Just what have you planned?
What did you tell the Chairman?
What are you talking about?
I only got a call from him
asking me to counsel you
since you seem to be having issues.
That's my spot.
You're the patient, so sit over there.
How have you been feeling lately?
Just whatever.
Oh yeah. Something strange has happened.
I'm a psychologist, and the
the fortune teller from downstairs
says she's going to counsel me.
Isn't that amusing?
And have you been sleeping well?
Yes.
Liar. You can't sleep
or eat well, can you?
I can have a glass of milk, at least.
Also, the patient is allowed
to lie as much as they'd like.
The work of the psychologist
is to catch those lies
and to figure out where the
issue lies within that, as well as
what kind of psychological scars they
may have, and help them accordingly.
I'll take care of that myself.
You don't even shed any tears
as of late, do you?
I don't really have anything
to be sad about.
Your mother came back.
Isn't it more strange
to be crying like a kid when I'm 36?
She's a mother who abandoned you
when you were just 6 years old.
And because of that, you've lost
your memories prior to that
and you still experience pain when
you're hit by droplets of liquid.
Crying when you're sad
and getting angry when you're angry...
expressing your emotions like this
is what normal people do.
Wouldn't it be a natural response for
you to cry if you'd met your mother?
The quantity of those tears, per se,
varies from person to person.
Also, a defense mechanism
may be in place.
Not all defense mechanisms
are inherently bad, you know.
I've transcended that through
delving into my psychological studies.
That's quite a desirable defense
mechanism, wouldn't you say?
You don't really
understand what I'm saying
because I'm using
specialized terms, right?
Just ask me questions freely.
If there's something that you're having
a hard time with, I'll help you out.
Maybe it's because I was in a rush,
but there's a lot of things I forgot.
Like my charger,
underwear, and socks.
I didn't bring my Rubic's cube,
so my hands feel unoccupied.
Can't we just go to the store
and buy all of those things?
We have to scrimp and save!
How could we buy all that?
Also, I bought a new camera this month
so I don't have much credit left.
Damn it... forget my clothes,
I need my charger! What do I do?
Even if you don't take Hye Rim's calls
it'd be an issue if you
didn't take calls from work.
It's fine because I'm on vacation
right now, but still...
This won't do. I'll sneak in
and grab those things.
How?
- Oh, hello.
- Oh, um, hello.
What? She went into my place just now?
Got it. I'm going to go there and-
You can't. Do you think she'll tell you
if you catch her and ask where Ji Ho is?
She'll act all down for a day
and then run off again.
Yeah.
What should I do, then?
There's just one answer.
You have to tail her.
Here. Here, too.
Yoo Rim, the nape of your neck
is so pretty.
I heard you said that you fell
for my sister for the same reason.
No. Hers has nothing on yours.
Seriously!
Really? It's my first time hearing that
I'm prettier than Hye Rim.
Thanks, my baby!
Aw... are you two having fun
playing house?
Hye Rim, how did you know-
You like it? You like living blissfully
ignorant to the realities of life?
Geez!
Ji Ho. I got married when I was
exactly your age - 21.
But look. This is what's
in store for you two.
Do I look like I have a good life? Huh?
You did have a nice life. It's just
that your husband was a bastard.
It's partly my fault too
that my husband cheated on me.
We just got married because
we liked each other
but we didn't know each other
well at all.
So we fought about everything from the
way we squeeze toothpaste
to methods of cleaning
on the day after we got married-
We both squeeze the tube
from the bottom.
- Right, Ji Ho?
- Yes.
- But, as for cleaning...
- We can't do it every day.
Once every three days.
Okay?
Okay.
See?
What kind of life will you two live?
If you keep doing things your way
and Ji Ho eventually explodes-
I'm not a volcano.
I won't explode.
I've trained him well,
so don't worry.
Also, as you know, he's like a doormat.
I can just walk all over him.
Fine. Let's just say
that I let you guys get married.
How are you going to
get a place to live?
We'll just look for a place that
takes monthly rent.
Even the smallest apartments nowadays
go for about 700,000 won per month.
Can you handle that kind of rent?
More importantly, how are you
going to sleep in that small room?
We'll hold onto each other tight
and sleep like that!
Any other issues?
Bring them on!
Fine. Let's cut off contact
from now on, then.
What? Why are you
saying that all of a sudden?
I tried so hard to keep you
from suffering the same fate I did
but you're being like this,
so whatever.
Let's not see each other from now on.
From now on, you and I
are strangers. Bye bye. Okay?
I'm pregnant!
To tell you the truth,
I wasn't going to bring this up
but I have a kid inside me now.
So I have to marry him, ASAP.
Yoo Rim... really?
You'll congratulate me, right?
Are you out of your damn mind? Huh?
How could you be beating
a pregnant woman?
What the hell did you do, huh?
This young punk...
How dare you!
I'm sorry!
He didn't do anything wrong!
Hit me instead!
Yeah, have a fantastic life
on your own, both of you!
Hye Rim!
Yoo Rim, is that true?
Are you really pregnant with my-
Are you out of your mind?
That was a total lie.
Hye Rim!
Hye Rim! I'm sorry!
It's all my fault!
Don't run, you idiot!
What if you do something to the child?
Hye Rim, I promise we'll be happy.
Please don't be opposed to it, and-
First things first, come back home.
Let's talk when you come back.
Doctor.
Here are the materials.
Ah yes, thank you.
Doctor. My friend got a stomach ulcer.
But this friend really hates hospitals.
They ate healthy food and exercised
and when they got a check-up at
the hospital about a year later
everything apparently got better!
So you think that I'll
get better like that, too?
Do you think that ulcers and
cancer are on the same scale?
At any rate, they're both illnesses.
So Doctor, even if you won't get surgery,
please go get a check-up!
You've lived your life with
an optimistic mindset up until now
so there's a chance of the cancer
getting a bit better, too. Right?
All right. Let me personally
show you what my condition is like.
It's not good. According to this,
the cancer has spread to your liver.
What?
Radioactive treatment wouldn't
suffice at this point.
She'd have to undergo chemotherapy, too.
And of course, surgery would be a must.
What are the chances of her
making a complete recovery?
About 30 percent.
Doctor. Even so, you still have a better
chance of making a complete recovery
than you would have
with other types of cancers.
Please have the surgery and
undergo the treatment. Please?
Thyroid cancer treatments
usually take ten years or so.
I definitely won't be able to
complete my bucket list at that age.
I'm going to enjoy my life
while I still have the strength to do so
and complete my bucket list.
I don't want to waste away
in a hospital for ten years.
Don't tell the people at the center
about my condition, no matter what.
If there's even rumors about it floating
around, I'll go back to Jeju Island.
Seung Chan. I... wait, what's wrong?
Did something happen?
It's nothing.
What's up?
Is it okay if I
come over for a bit today?
Why?
I'm going to mimic Choi Soo Hyun.
You're sure that he's
coming home late today, right?
Yeah, he said that he was having
dinner with some professors.
But why?
What are you looking for?
Things like the photo of Mr. Soo Hyun
that you gave me last time.
If it's anything that'll shed light
on his psychological scars, it'll do.
Does he have any toys he used
to play with as a child, or an album?
I don't know. I think he threw those
all away when he moved here.
Wait, no. I think my mom
brought an album over here.
Why, should I ask her to
bring some over when she comes?
Your mother is coming here?
Yeah, with my father.
They're coming for a bit because
a relative is getting married.
Then, do you have anything else
besides albums?
I'm not sure. Something that will shed
light on the workings of his mind...
Maybe there's something here?
What, is anything helping?
Yeah. It's something in a different
direction than I'd expected
but I did find something.
[The Ethics and Symbols
of Shamanism]
[Between Frigidity and Passion]
[Credit Card Receipt
Purchased: Necklace]
[Past searches: "past loves,"
"Sociology," "Jerome Bruner"]
What's this?
It's a box, isn't it?
It's something that was inside
of your closet.
They're your things from when you
were an undergrad, right?
Did you go snooping around my room?
Just answer my question.
Why did you suddenly look through your
things from when you attended Stanford?
Were you thinking about
Clare, by any chance?
That's-
And what's this? You bought a necklace
at a luxury retail shop, right?
And that was when I was
away in Daejeon, too.
Why did you buy that?
Who was it for?
- Ms. Hye Rim.
- And these books, about past love!
And your searches, about past love!
Why are you thinking so much
about past loves, all of a sudden?
It's because of Clare, right?
She came back, which is why you're
looking at and reading these things!
Can I talk now?
Go ahead and try.
I'm sure they'll just be excuses.
It's true that I opened this box because
there was something I was looking for.
I wanted to make you
the omelet that you liked.
I had a recipe from a roommate who
was great at cooking, which was in here.
Don't believe me?
Shall I make you one exactly
according to that recipe right now?
Then what about that photo
that you took with Clare?
Clare's photo was in there? You
should've thrown it away. It's useless.
As for this necklace,
I did buy it to give to a woman.
And I already gave it to her.
Who, Clare?
- I gave it to Hye Rim.
- Are you messing with me?
Hye Rim, the Pomeranian that I have.
You said you went in my room
but you didn't see it?
She had a necklace on her.
As for this, I was reading it
because of a patient that I have.
I have a female patient
who's going through a hard time
because she was
dumped by her boyfriend
and she kept referencing this book
during our sessions
so I read it to try and get
a better understanding.
I guess you didn't see the book on
shamanism next to this one, though.
I was reading that book
because of you.
End of explanation. You're cleared
of your misunderstandings now, right?
Mr. Seung Chan,
please get me some plane tickets.
- Okay.
- You didn't ask where I was going.
- Where are you going?
- Alaska.
I'm going to leave in three weeks
to check that off my bucket list.
Oh... okay.
Wait. You don't have
anything else to ask me?
No, I don't.
Here's the itinerary.
Wait, it's this expensive?
Yes, since it's for two passengers.
I got tickets too,
so that I can come with you.
I can come with you, right?
Really? It'd be a big help
if you came with me.
But I did some research on Alaska.
This might be okay for me,
but I don't know about you.
Why?
Well firstly, you have to be
on the plane for 15 hours.
Will you be okay with that?
You have cancer, after all.
On top of that, we have to go to
Fairbanks if we want to see auroras.
But the sun barely ever rises
there in the wintertime.
It'll be night most of the time.
Also, the temperature can drop
to -24 degrees Celsius.
What are you trying to say?
On top of that, the weather
there is quite capricious.
There are windy storms, thunderstorms,
and even hail. It's seriously crazy.
Oh yeah. You said you wanted to see
Machu Picchu too, right?
But it's 2,400 meters
above sea level.
And yet, you have a hard time even
hiking up the hill right around here.
But there's a way you can
solve all of these problems.
I'm not getting surgery.
Doctor. There's a 30 percent chance
that you'll make a complete recovery!
It's not "just" 30 percent;
it's "30 whole percent!"
Why are you ignoring that?
It's my life.
It's my decision.
I don't want
to leave it up to statistics.
I'm going to Alaska in three weeks
to see the auroras, for sure.
Whether you come or not is up to you.
Please enjoy.
Come upstairs.
Drink it. It's tea that's good
for pregnant women's hormones.
Hye Rim, I'd like some water-
You can have some damn water
at your own damn house.
Also, why did you make Yoo Rim hold
the heavy luggage on the way in?
Don't you know how dangerous that
can be for a pregnant woman?
How many months along are you?
No, it probably hasn't been that long
yet. How many weeks along are you?
What do I do? When should I tell her
that I'm not actually pregnant?
I bought milk, anchovies, and cheese.
The baby's bone structure is
forming right around now
so you need to eat a lot of calcium.
Drink water often, and have lots
of fruits and vegetables, too.
And don't do any
strenuous exercising, okay?
It's almost time.
Let's go.
Go where?
I made an appointment for you
at the OB/GYN.
What?
We have to find out if the child
is in the right position
and doesn't have any
issues thus far!
- Let's go.
- Wait.
It's only the beginning of my
pregnancy, so I'm sure I'll be fine.
It's more dangerous because you're
at the beginning of your pregnancy!
You have to see if the child is doing
well, and if their heart is beating well!
What are you doing, as the father
of the child? Hurry and get her up!
Geez. Get over here!
- Let's go!
- Hye Rim!
- Hurry up.
- No, no!
- Hye Rim!
- Stop it!
Ow, my stomach.
Oh my gosh,
is the baby okay?
I was slightly jabbed there.
Hurry up and call an ambulance!
- Wait, you can't!
- This is 911, right?
Yes, we have a pregnant woman here,
and she fell down the stairs
- and hurt her stomach.
- I don't have one!
What don't you have?
A baby.
I'm not pregnant.
- What?
- I lied. I'm sorry.
What's with me?
I keep laughing.
What do I do?
I think she's gone crazy.
What's with your expression?
You're not happy to see your
father for the first time in a while?
Give us two of the A Courses,
and... what do you want to eat?
The B Course.
Is work going well? I heard you're
making him work, too.
You can't even take care of your younger
brother properly, as an older brother.
Isn't there a nicer place where
you can get him some work?
No, Father. I'm not ready
for something like that yet.
Since I spent all that money
to send you to study abroad
you should've done something greater.
But you're just some damn
counselor making pennies.
Is that what you should be doing?
You can't even answer me?
How frustrating.
It's probably because you
take after your damn mother.
What's with that smirk?
You're still the same, acting however
you please because you're old.
Soo Hyun!
You know that I can't eat oysters, and
yet you ordered an oyster dish for me?
Are you bragging about the fact that you
can't eat oysters, at your age?
You should act your age
and stop being so picky!
I know, right? I'm plenty old enough,
so why are you treating me like a child?
How dare you talk back to me!
A counselor, huh? Why the hell do you
care how I make a living?
Sending me to study abroad?
You never spent a single cent to help me.
Do you think you would've been able
to go if I hadn't allowed it?
I studied abroad with the
money that I earned on my own!
You didn't do anything
to contribute to it!
"You?"
Why are you talking to Father like that?
It's been so long, too!
One needs to have traits one can learn
from to be a qualified father.
All you do is treat everyone else
as if they're below you
and show off your status
because you're a bit wealthy.
A person who has biases and
does whatever he pleases all the time...
wants to be treated as if he's
actually my father now?
You bastard!
Do you know why I went
to go study abroad?
I wanted to get as far away from you
as I could.
I wasn't even laughing when I was
laughing. Why, you may ask?
Because I only did it
since you pressured me to.
Eat a lot of delicious
things for lunch.
You'll have to live a long time
if you're going to satiate that
incredible greed of yours.
What the hell are you doing?
Do you really want to be saying
those things to Father
who's getting weak in his old age?
This is between me and Father.
A guy like you, who was loved
throughout his childhood and
was allowed to do as he pleased
has no right to say this to me.
You're the one who pushed us away!
Father, sure. I don't know about him,
but Mom and I did our very best.
We tried so hard to see how we could
get along with you and be good to you.
But who was the one who pushed
Mom and me away regardless?
It was you!
The fact that our family
became like this is your fault.
It was all your fault.
Soo Hyun, I'm sorry for everything.
What can I do to be forgiven by you?
That's right.
And don't ever come back.
- Hello.
- Um, excuse me.
Is there any way you can tell me
where Ms. Seo Yeon Hui is staying?
Excuse me, but what's your
relationship with her?
Never mind.
I found her.
Hello?
Yes, my son.
I'm going to come back
after a couple of days.
Have you been eating well?
Geez, you can't just live off
of instant food!
Eat that soup I already made for you.
Make sure you eat all of that, okay?
Is your studying for your
upcoming exam going well?
Oh my. That's great! So you just have
to hear back from one more place, right?
Oh, that's great, my son!
You got into two of the schools
that you wanted to go to!
All you have to do now
is choose among them!
What should I do about Mr. Soo Hyun?
He's grumpy even if I'm good
to him, or try to cheer him up.
And if I try to get closer to him,
he wiggles out like a fish.
I don't know what else I can do for him.
I'm sure it will be difficult for you.
He's not your average guy,
and he's a psychologist too.
What he needs right now is a
reaffirmation of your affections.
A reaffirmation of my affections?
Yes. Dr. Choi is treating his situation
as if it's happening to someone else.
He's saying to himself,
"I know the story. I know how it ends."
And all the while,
he's analyzing the situation.
However, he won't reach an emotional
breakthrough with that kind of approach.
Then what can I do?
You have to drag Dr. Choi onto the stage
instead of letting him merely spectate.
As the main character.
Where are we going?
We'll be doing our
consultation outdoors today.
Don't you know that you're only supposed
to have consultations once per week?
Also, why outside-
A consultation with a
fortune teller is a bit different.
I'm going to do it where it feels right,
for as long as it takes.
Until I get something out of you.
I guess you did quite a lot
of research on me.
You even found the elementary school
I used to go to.
What kind of child were you
when you were attending school?
I was the same as all the other kids.
I ran around and ate well.
And played well.
What about around this time?
Soo Hyun. I wish you could
come and take me away.
I don't want to be here by myself.
All right.
One, two-
Choi Soo Hyun! What's with that
expression, when we're taking a photo?
Did you get yelled at by someone?
Smile!
I told you to smile!
All right.
One, two!
What's with your damn expression
when we're taking a photo?
Damn kid.
Soo Hyun, why aren't you coming?
Go on ahead. I want to play here
a bit longer before I go.
Why would you play outside
in the middle of winter?
Just hurry up and come, punk!
I... I really... I really
just want to play here.
- Soo Hyun.
- Do whatever you want!
He takes after his mother,
so he does whatever he wants!
Go and console him.
The only one who can console that
child right now is you, Mr. Soo Hyun.
Doctor. When you go to Alaska,
which bag do you want to use?
- This one.
- Okay. I'll order it.
But I don't know if your body
will be able to handle that...
Doctor. I think we'll have an easier
time seeing auroras if we go on a tour.
- Should I sign us up?
- Yes. Let's do that.
But it's such a long distance.
I'm not sure you'll be able to do it...
Doctor.
Since we're going to Alaska,
it'd be nice to see igloos.
Should we go on a tour for that, too?
You're just going to say
that we can't again, right?
Yes.
Why do you keep doing that?
It's because I want
to be with you for a long time.
You're my mentor.
Once a mentor, always a mentor!
Aren't I right?
You have to guide me
for 20 or 30 more years.
Just 6 months?
That's not enough time.
Please get the surgery, Doctor.
You can overcome it with chemo
and become healthy again,
and go see the auroras with me
and go to Peru, and dye your hair purple
and try all the beers in the world!
You can enjoy the rest
of your life like that!
Let's be together for a long time. Okay?
[10. Lying down in an igloo in
Alaska, and seeing auroras.]
Number 11.
Getting the surgery.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Hurry and get up!
First, we'll announce our
engagement at the cafe in a month.
Then we'll both save 40 percent of
our paychecks and put it away.
We'll get married in
three years, at the latest.
3 years?
But you'll still only be 24.
My age isn't important.
I just want her to wear a wedding
dress when she's young and pretty.
We'll have a small-scale wedding,
and we'll rent a tiny one-room apartment.
We'll pay back our debts within a year
and we'll get on the waiting list
for apartments.
You think that they accept just anybody?
What about your living expenses?
And what will you be doing
around that time?
Are you still going to be
working as an intern at the center?
I'm going to get my LCPC license
within three years.
She says that she won't
marry me otherwise.
As soon as we get married, we're going
to make four separate bank accounts
for income, expenses,
emergency funds, and investments.
And we're also getting some emergency
funds ready for when we can't work.
That's our ten-year plan for now.
Our last objective is to get a house.
Also, I'm going to support Yoo Rim
until she becomes a famous documentarian.
When will your parents be meeting?
That's the first step
in getting married.
Do you think that marriage
is just between you two?
Hye Rim! So you're finally
giving us your blessing?
Thanks so much, Hye Rim!
I promise that we'll be happy!
Oh, go away!
How's Dr. Bae?
She's a lot better than expected.
Hey, Soo Hyun.
I'm sorry about before.
I forgot how hard Father
used to be on you.
I'm sorry that I spoke to you like that.
Okay.
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, dear Soo Hyun,
happy birthday to you!
All right.
Speech, please!
- Thank you, everyone, and...
- He's getting nervous!
Anyway, thank you.
All right, then. Isn't it time
for me to get presents?
Oh yeah, presents! But before that,
there's something we have to do.
What is it?
Then I'll go for it too!
- Look here.
- Oh my gosh!
- Yoo Rim, go and wash up.
- Okay.
- Yes?
- Hello.
- It's me, Seo Yeon Hui.
- Oh, yes.
I'm leaving now.
Today's Soo Hyun's birthday, right?
Can you tell this to Soo Hyun for me?
That I love him.
I think that it became
ingrained inside my head.
That I'd done something wrong.
That she hadn't come back
even once for my birthday
because I'd spilled the ice cream.
You can't leave now, ma'am!
Excuse me?
Please hurry and come.
Mr. Soo Hyun is waiting-
Hello? Hello?
The person you are trying to reach
is in the middle of a call.
- Hello.
- I'd like to check out.
Understood.
The person you are trying to reach
is in the middle of a call.
It's okay!
No need to come out and meet me.
Yes, it's the 11 p.m. flight.
I'm heading there now.
Excuse me!
You have a guest
named Seo Yeon Hui, right?
Has she checked out yet?
Yes. Ten minutes ago.
I came back because I was curious
about what you said before.
I couldn't hear you clearly, but I
thought it was something about Soo Hyun.
Who is it?
I'm sorry, Soo Hyun, that I wasn't here.
How did you get here?
Happy birthday, Soo Hyun.
I came too late, didn't I?
So you remembered my birthday?
Yeah.
How could any mother
forget their child's birthday?
Then, what about you telling me
that you'd come back on my birthday?
Did you remember that?
About that, I-
Why couldn't you remember that?
Do you know how hard
it was for me because of that?
I thought that you'd left
because of me, and I was so...
I'm sorry. It's all my fault!
It's all my fault.
If you broke up with Dad, you should've
fought to take me with you!
How could you leave me
with such a terrible father?
Were you planning to have
a jolly old life on your own?
I was too weak.
I was kicked out,
so I didn't have anything.
But even so, I tried my best. But your
father's lawyer was too strong, so...
He blamed everything on me
and took away custody-
But you still should've come
to take me away!
My stepmom, dad, and younger brother
were all happy together
but I...
and then you started a new family!
I'm the only one who was left abandoned!
Soo Hyun.
Do you know what it feels like to have
nobody on your side and be all alone?
If only... if only from now on,
I'll always be by your side.
I'm sorry, Soo Hyun! I'm so sorry
for keeping you waiting for 30 years.
This is the first dose of chemotherapy.
You'll be getting this for a week.
Doctor. I downloaded some movies.
Want to watch some?
No, it's okay.
I have dramas, too! Korean ones,
American ones, and British ones.
It's okay.
Then, how about a performance?
It's Choi Seung Chan's live...
Oh, it's not live is it?
Well, anyway, a performance!
What kind of performance?
I was born to love you...
with every single beat of my heart.
Yes, I was born to take care of you
every single day!
Alright! Hey, hey!
I was born to love you
with every single beat of my heart.
Yes, I was born to take care of you
every single day of my life.
You are the one for me...
Hey, Ji Ho.
What's Mr. Soo Hyun doing?
Ms. Clare is here,
so they're working together.
- Clare is here again?
- Yes.
He said that they'll probably be up
all night because it's a lot of work.
Oh my. She won't eat dinner
with me anymore.
She's always having
dinner with that guy!
Even so, I heard
that the two of you got a lot closer.
But why are you dating a guy like him?
Excuse me?
I heard it through Secretary Lee.
You're dating Choi Soo Hyun?
Oh, um. yes.
Figures. I should've known from when
you told me to go get counseling.
But, do you two go well together?
He's kind of a jerk.
Is he kind and considerate to you?
Lately he's been too considerate,
which is its own problem.
I fixed him up with some counseling so
I guess he's confident that he can love
and is flirting with women
left and right!
Today, he brought this woman
named Clare again-
Who?
Chairman. When you were dating
your wife, you had a rival, right?
Huh? How did you know that?
I saw your letters from
when you were dat-
I mean, the spirit within me told me.
But how did you get rid of your rival?
Did you buy her gifts?
Or did you just cling on to her?
Goethe once said this:
"Love will find those who seek it."
Don't worry.
Love always finds a way.
Now eat up.
Thanks for helping me
out with work all this time.
You were a great help.
It was nothing. All I did was
give you advice on a few documents.
You're going back now? What about
your ride? Did you take a cab here?
Yeah. I'm heading straight
to the airport from here.
I don't think there are
any taxis around here.
Let's go.
I'll give you a ride to the airport.
Ms. Hye Rim, I'm going to drop her off.
She's going back to the States, so-
Did I ask?
What's that look on your face?
Did something happen?
Why do I always end up like this?
What are you talking about?
I feel like Mr. Soo Hyun is going
to leave me now, too.
I feel so uneasy.
[Third Task: Putting 100 colored
ribbons on a tree and confessing.]
Here, you'll need these
when you're driving.
Welcome.
Can you give me one of
these in the same design?
Yes, ma'am.
[Movie Title: Love Isn't
Something You Do Alone]
He's doing this crap again?
You think I'll fall for this again?
Are you crazy?
I'll never go!
Um, somebody is sitting here.
I don't think so.
This is G-26. My seat.
- Huh?
- What's going on?
Hello everyone.
Cellphone usage during the feature film
can cause other moviegoers to
feel despair and heartbreak.
Please turn off your phones
so that all of us
who live in an age of despair
and heartbreak, can have hope again.
Don't kick the seat in front of you,
and please throw trash in trash bins.
In the event of an emergency,
please use the exit on this side
and the bathrooms are around the corner
on the right, so please tread lightly.
Also...
to the woman sitting in G-25.
The woman sitting in G-25 is
more important to me than anyone else.
The one who healed my scars
is Ms. G-25
and the one who made me be
self-reflective is also Ms. G-25.
And the one who made
me feel that I should change
and become a cooler guy
is also Ms. G-25.
I love you, Ms. Hye Rim.
What was that?
Are you crazy?
Yes, I'm crazy.
How was my execution of Task 3?
What?
I just did Task 3
of the experiment for you.
A task that one must perform without
caring about what spectators think.
A task that only
a crazy person would do.
This is evidence that I've
completely fallen in love with you.
You're going on about this
experiment until the very end, huh?
I love you, Ms. Hye Rim.
[Madame Antoine]
I'm sorry, Director.
That, that... oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
Hey, hey you!
You can't do that!
Yoo Rim!
Oh no...
Just a moment.
That was awesome!
Thank you, everyone.
Then, I, too...
Oh my gosh, this is so embarrassing.
[Thank you to all of the viewers
who loved Madame Antoine.]