I'm in love with your brother
Yes, I am
But maybe I shouldn't
ask for his name
And you danced
Oh, what a dance
And you laughed
Oh, what a laugh...
What the fuck are you doing?
- Here.
- Oh, thanks.
Alicia, this is Brink.
Hi. Alicia, you made it.
Mmm. You smell like
American shampoo.
What? It's different
outside of the U.S.?
"Is it different?" you said.
This is Agustin's sister, Barbara.
This is Alicia. My baby
cousin from California.
Hi.
How was your trip?
It was good. It was long.
Is this your first
time in South America?
Um, it's my first time
outside of the U.S.
Oh.
You're kidding me?
Guys, we need to go. It's late.
No. She's been on a plane for hours.
She needs to take a shower.
Really?
This radio only plays CDs.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it. Come on.
Do we really have to
rush to the South?
Yeah. Trust me, you don't want
to stay in Santiago for long.
It's fucking boring.
Oh, is the South gonna be better?
How long does it take to get there?
Like 12 hours. You can get
a good sleep in the car.
Yeah. That's true.
Hey, I'm sorry my mom was so pushy
about me coming here.
I guess I just needed a break.
Oh, shut up. Don't be silly.
I'm so glad you're here.
Well, thank you.
So, what's with you and Agustin?
It's serious, right?
Uh, yeah. It's good.
We'll see what happens.
And who is that Brink guy?
He and Agustin met at
their gringo high school.
His dad is a diplomat or something.
Agustin brought him here
especially for you.
Yeah, he seems fun.
Sara?
I'll just be out here.
Don't be too long, okay?
Okay.
Okay. I'll just...
I'll keep calling her.
Alicia! We're gonna be
waiting in the car.
Agustin knows this guy.
Pedropiedra.
He is so fucking weird. Right?
English.
Speak English, please.
He pissed on the audience.
So gross.
How long have you been in Chile?
Longer than I expected.
Like two and a half years.
Yeah. We're gonna get
Sara to stay longer, too.
No. She has one
semester and that's it.
Yeah. I don't know. We'll see.
Can you turn the
music down a second?
Hola.
Uh...
One second. It's Paloma.
Okay. Um...
Barbara, can you please pull over?
Sara, what's going on?
It's okay. It's just school.
Fucking great timing.
What are we gonna tell them?
Can you tell her to tell
him that I'm on my way?
Guys, don't kill me.
I have to go back to Santiago.
I'm so sorry.
What? Yeah.
Today? Right now?
It's just gonna be you,
me, and Barbara, and her?
No. I'm going with her.
We're gonna get a bus
in Tijuana or something.
I'm not gonna take
care of your friends.
Barbara, it's fine.
I'll go by myself.
Don't worry about it,
Agustin. I'll be fine.
No, no, no, no. Are you crazy?
I'm coming with you.
No, no, you can't.
I'm just going for school.
I'll be back tomorrow. It's fine.
Sara, of course, I'm coming with you.
Are you kidding me?
I just got here.
I wanna be with you.
That's why I came out here.
Let's go!
Okay. We'll see, all right?
Let's go.
But you don't really have to go.
I just don't believe you.
It's an exam. Who cares?
Well, I care. I mean,
I've already failed one exam.
And I have to graduate at
some point. It's important.
Yeah, but you never cared before.
We're in Southern Chile.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna be gone
for, like, one day.
And they're really sweet.
Have fun with them.
Yeah, but, Sara, like, what's
the difference, you know?
If I come with you, then we
could just come back together.
You'll have so much more
fun if you stay here.
And you've been traveling for so long.
Just get there already.
No. I don't want to let
you go by yourself.
I'll be fine.
Agustin, what's going on?
This is stressing me out.
You're lucky. The next bus
is leaving very soon.
Yeah. I'm really lucky.
Hey, Agustin. Can you talk to her?
I don't think she should go on her own.
Okay, Alicia, enough.
Be nice to her, okay?
We'll be nice to her.
Agustin, we're gonna be so late.
What's keeping us?
Barbara, would you mind if we slowed
down just a little bit, please?
No, Melda's waiting for us.
Can we change this shit?
Come on. You pick one.
I don't really know
that much about music.
Be adventurous.
Just whatever you find.
Don't worry.
Agustin, stop reading this
stupid hypnosis book.
Here.
What does it say, anyway?
Put me in a trance.
Put me to sleep.
Shut up.
Come on, hypnotize me or something.
Seriously?
I like it.
This shit gives me the creeps.
Sorry.
What the fuck?
Just leave it. Great pick, Alicia.
I'm really sorry.
I'm kidding.
Don't worry.
This happened before.
It hasn't happened to me.
Well, not in a while.
Alicia, don't worry.
It happens all the time.
Folks, here's the story
'bout Minnie the Moocher
She was a red-hot
hootchie-cootcher
She was the roughest,
toughest frail
But Minnie had a heart
as big as a whale
Hi-de-hi-de-hi-di-hi
Hi-de-hi-de-hi-di-hi...
She messed around with
a bloke named Smoky.
Agustin, go look for Melda.
Go ask the guy over there.
I'm coming with you, Agustin.
I wanna meet a Mapuche.
These people must be
pretty exotic for you.
Yeah. It's really rustic.
It's not like they're
wearing feathers, you know.
Why are these sheep here?
Baby, sorry.
Yeah. She's all right, I guess.
What's it called again?
Mapuches.
White people in this country
have totally fucked them up.
You already paid for them?
Are you freaking out?
Is it gonna be enough?
Okay. I have to go. I'll call
you again later. Okay. Bye.
I need to pee. Cover.
What?
I need to pee. Can you keep cover?
Oh, my God.
What the fuck is that?
What? What happened?
Come and look.
Ew! It's two puppies.
God. That one's sick. Look, he's
got, like, warts all over his body.
We should rescue them.
It's got blisters. Look.
We have to save the sick one.
No. Barbara, if we're gonna take
one, let's take the good one.
You're such a bitch.
Take the sick one.
No. Just leave it there.
Come on, guys, seriously.
Aw... Poor things.
Ugh!
Hell, no, enough of this shit.
This is so fucking stupid!
Okay. You leave that stupid dog.
Barbara, chill out.
No. I'm not gonna chill out.
You want to leave the dog?
Leave the stupid dog.
You started this!
I'm not doing shit!
What are you guys doing?
So dramatic.
Folks, here's the story
'bout Minnie the Moocher
She was a red-hot
hootchie-cootcher
She was the roughest,
toughest frail
But Minnie had a heart
as big as a whale...
Hi. Thank you.
Thank you.
Shit!
I am so sorry. I am so sorry.
Oh, my God!
Is everything okay? Just...
Shit.
Alicia, don't worry.
Shut the fuck up.
Close the door behind you, please.
Alicia.
This is your room.
Okay.
Hey, I'm really sorry about
your bag. I really am.
Sure. It's okay.
Thank you.
English.
Oh, sorry, Alicia.
What a gentleman.
Brink? Mmm-hmm.
From 1 to 10,
how much do you like him?
I don't know.
We just met.
From 1 to 10, how
much do you like her?
6.4, 6.5.
No, I'm kidding.
10, 11. The most.
No. I can take a 6. It's okay.
Thank you.
Have you ever had a girlfriend?
Yeah. Um... Not in Chile.
We broke up, 'cause...
Has anyone talked to Sara?
I tried to call her today, but...
I talked to her.
She sat next to that screaming
baby the entire way.
Fuck that baby.
Well, she's coming tomorrow, right?
So, it's not that bad.
Yeah. True.
True.
Agustin.
Yeah, it should.
Uh... I think. Maybe there.
Hey.
Take a look at this video.
That video doesn't do
anything, Agustin.
Whatever. You should
try it, though.
Relax your eyes,
and stare at the center.
He's good.
He once cured this stomach
ache I had for 2 days.
That's disgusting, Barbara.
What's wrong with your body?
What's wrong with your face?
It's never worked for me,
so don't feel bad
if it doesn't work.
Can I look away now?
Agustin, stop it.
She's not liking it.
Why don't you finish
what you start, Alicia?
Okay, now...
Hey!
This.
Whoa. That's trippy.
Right? Mmm-hmm.
You want me to hypnotize
you for real now?
Okay.
I have to study, so keep it quiet.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay. Lay here.
No. I'm tired.
Oh. Maybe tomorrow.
Come on. Try new things. It's fun.
But I didn't really
sleep on the plane.
Yeah. That's cool. Good night.
Thank you. Good night, guys.
Sleep well. Good night.
Yeah, you, too.
Hey, let's watch a
movie or something?
Hey, fucker! Answer me.
I'm trying to do something here.
Hey, what's the weirdest place
you've ever had sex with Sara?
Or are you the conservative types?
It's so cold.
I wish Alicia was
here to keep me warm.
It's ready.
Go tell Alicia to come down.
Alicia! Alicia!
Breakfast, amiga.
Alicia.
That's disgusting.
Ew!
What were you dreaming about?
You don't wanna know.
Yes, I do.
What's so funny?
Hey, Alicia, how did you sleep?
I slept great. Thank you.
You look tired.
I love the South.
I always sleep like a pig.
Have you heard from Sara?
Not yet.
There's no reception here.
If you want me, I can
call Bernardo and ask.
Pass the coffee.
Bernardo?
Bernardo, can you hear me?
Bernardo. Copy, copy.
This is Barbara.
Look, he's not there.
He'll call me once she
gets here. Don't worry.
I'm not worried.
Alicia, there's no reception here.
No. I was just trying
to check my voicemail.
Well, we're going to the Fat Hill.
You can call from there.
You wanna come?
Do you think it's gonna rain?
Yeah, you never really know.
But we have raincoats here.
Go grab one.
Okay.
Hurry up.
Do you need a license to go
hunting here or something?
Is it legal?
What?
Yeah. Your turn is over.
Brink, wait.
Brink?
Hey?
Brink, please don't shoot.
Holy shit.
Is it dead?
I feel really stupid now.
You're upset.
I don't really care.
You can do whatever you want.
You guys wanna play tennis?
Yeah, sure. I could play tennis.
I'm not good, though.
Yeah, there are some roller skates.
You can do that and
skate like a faggot.
Hey, shut your mouth.
You're the faggot.
Whose tennis courts
are these, anyway?
It's everybody's.
We share them.
Wanna play roller tennis?
No.
I'm gonna go call Sara.
We said we were sorry.
Hey, baby, what's up?
Where are you?
Uh... I'm on my way to school.
I tried to call you this morning,
but there was no reception.
Hey, I have to stay until tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Yeah, I arrive in the morning.
Why didn't you tell me?
Well, I'm telling you right now.
I'm kind of trapped up here.
No. I'm trapped here.
What?
I just want to get
out of this place.
What? Alicia, what?
I can't hear you. Hello?
These people are sadists, Sara.
What? Alicia, those
people are my friend.
Hello?
Baby, I can't hear you.
Hey, can you...
Can you tell Agustin that
everything is going well,
and can you ask him to call...
What?
Hello? Hello?
Can you hear me?
I can hear you perfectly.
Hello?
Hello? Alicia, can you hear me?
I can't hear you, Sara.
Just call me back later, okay.
Hey, did you talk to her?
Who?
Sara, who else?
Who else what?
Did you talk to her?
What did she say?
Yeah, she'll be here
tomorrow morning.
What's with all the questions, man?
Come on, I dare you.
No, too close.
Hey, hey.
Hey, friend, hey.
Come here, come here.
What are you doing out here?
You should be working.
No? Lazy dog.
Ugh...
Stop it. Get off of me.
Get off me!
Oh, my God. No, no.
Sorry about that.
Oh, my God. So funny.
I'm done. I'm gonna call Sara.
Sara, Sara, always Sara.
Hi.
Oh...
This room is toasty,
toasty, toasty.
I'm not making lunch.
There's a lot of
things in the kitchen.
Take whatever you want.
Hey, sorry about that dog.
It's getting old and crazy.
Yeah, he thought you were a bitch,
but we told him you were
actually really nice.
Thank you.
Who am I kidding?
I'm, like, not even reading.
Sitting here just going...
Whoo.
You want a drink?
Sure.
Take mine.
Oh.
Wow, yum. What is that?
It's pisco with Coke.
Chilean people love drinking it.
I'm having one, too.
Hey, we're gonna visit
my cousins tonight.
And you are coming with us.
Sure.
Good.
I really like this.
It tastes like candy.
And you love candy?
Oh, Alicia, your
friend is calling me.
Shut up, Brink.
That's the house?
"That's the house?"
Why? Are you scared?
I don't talk like
that, you shit-fuck.
Agustin, what about
this one up above?
Yeah, let's try it. You go.
Yeah. Push me?
Okay, you have me?
Yeah.
It's open, yes.
Okay, okay, higher, higher.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, Brink, open this door.
Welcome to my horny abode.
Good job, man. Fuck yeah.
Alicia, give me whiskey?
Mmm, Alicia germs.
Look at this room.
Mmm.
Look at that thing.
Agustin wants the bottle.
Come get it.
Hey... Let's go to
my uncle's house.
Agustin, look.
No!
Brink, get off me.
Get off me, man.
What are you doing?
Hey... Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Man, what the fuck?
Relax, callate, I'm being the dog.
I'm that dog. I'm that dog.
No, no, no, no.
Hey! Let's go see the
tennis court upstairs!
I'm that dog. I'm that dog.
Stop it. Stop it!
Brink!
No!
Fucking shit.
Motherfucker! I'm bleeding.
Hey! What happened?
She kicked me in the face.
You stupid idiot!
You think you're so funny.
Well, you're not funny.
Oh, you're such a delight, Alicia.
You call me a bitch and then
you're touching me and...
Are you bleeding for real?
I don't even know you.
I don't know either of you.
Hey, hey, hey, relax.
Yeah, why don't you go lie down?
Oh, my God.
She obviously had
too much to drink.
She was wasted.
But that was the mood, that
was the mood of the night.
And she's the one who got violent.
You were fucking acting weird.
But I wasn't violent.
I wasn't violent, ever.
Come on, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Sara.
Pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone. Pick up.
Sara, please pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone.
Alicia.
Sara, finally!
Are you on your way here?
Have you taken that exam already?
Alicia, you know I'm not
here because of school.
What's going on, baby?
What? Where are you?
Sara, you have no idea
what has been going on.
This dog tried to hump me and
then I made Brink bleed.
Shit.
And it wasn't my fault,
I didn't mean to do it.
He fucking made me.
They killed a bird.
Brink killed the bird and
he just didn't care.
It was like...
Shh... Wait.
What is it? Oh, my God.
It's fucking Barbara.
She doesn't, like, let me make any
noise here. I can't even breathe.
She's fucking crazy.
I think she's just mad
because I dropped her
bag in the water.
It's not like I was
trying to fist fuck her.
Believe me, she would
know if I was.
No, no.
Alicia?
Alicia.
What are you doing?
I'm making some toast.
Huh.
Your cousin's here.
She's crossing the lake.
Okay.
I'm really sorry about all
the noise I made last night.
What?
It won't happen again, okay?
Hi, guys.
Hey, are you coming with us?
Yeah, you're going down? Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, I'll come.
Are you still bleeding?
Kind of.
No, he's not.
Yes, I was, Agustin.
You didn't see.
Um... Do you want some
snacks or something?
Yeah, bring some.
I'll bring some. We'll
be down by the pier.
Hi. Hi.
This weather's so shitty. I know.
Can you help me? Yeah.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Hey, I missed you.
I'm sorry, that took so
much longer than I thought.
Are you fluent in Spanish by now?
No.
Come on. Hey, where's this house?
Right there.
Sara.
What? No, nothing. Nothing.
I'm just really happy to have
somebody to speak English with.
Hey, let's go to those rocks.
What? You didn't speak
English with her?
Brink, are you serious?
I do speak English.
Chill out. I'm just used
to speaking Spanish.
You're not really though, are you?
'Cause you kind of sound
retarded when you do.
Here, take a photo of us.
Sure.
I guess I don't really
need to be in it, do I?
Come on.
Got it?
I'm freezing. Can we go inside?
Okay, let's go in.
Tell me, how do you feel?
Alicia, you're not even smiling.
Do one where you smile.
What the fuck is wrong with them?
Did you tell her?
No, are you insane?
They had such a big
fight last night.
They had a fight? What happened?
Don't worry. So, how was it?
It's fine. I'm fine.
Did it hurt a lot?
I don't want to talk about it.
What do you mean?
You have to talk about it.
It was my baby, too.
Shut up, it was not a baby.
Don't say that.
Hey, Agustin, can
I have my food, please?
What's up, bitch?
What's up, puppy killer?
I knew you were traumatized.
You're such a gringa.
No, I didn't tell anyone.
No, chill, Agustin told me.
I can't believe you just left
it on the side of the road.
That's really fucked up.
Oh, get over it. Did you get
your shit straightened out?
Yeah, I did my exam,
but I probably failed
it or something.
So I kinda don't
wanna talk about it.
Agustin. Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
Hey, go get your swimsuits.
We're going to the rock.
These people are fucking crazy.
I'm so sorry I hung
up on you last night.
Barbara has been making
my life impossible.
Why? What's she doing?
She won't let me move in my room.
So, what did you do in Santiago?
What? I told you. I had
to retake an exam.
No, that's not what you said
on the phone last night.
We didn't talk on the
phone last night.
Yes, we did, when
I told you about Brink.
We didn't talk about that.
Agustin just told me about the stupid
fight you guys had last night.
What?
Yes, we did.
No, we didn't.
No?
I mean...
On the hill.
Alicia?
I really don't think that
this room is that bad.
It's kind of depressing and ugly,
and there's probably like cum stains
all over the mattress. Ew.
But, I don't know, it's not
scary or anything. It's fine.
Yeah, well, thanks
for staying with me,
because you could have
stayed with Agustin, right?
No, are you crazy?
Of course I'm gonna stay with you.
I want to keep you company.
We're gonna have fun, okay?
I promise.
You okay?
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
You just had a nightmare
and you need to brush it off.
You'll be fine.
Sara, let's go. We're ready.
Okay, we're coming.
Ooh! It's freezing!
Are you gonna be okay
in that tiny wetsuit?
Do you want my sweater?
Oh, no. Thank you.
I'm okay. You sure?
It's really warm.
Alicia, he's being so nice to you.
Gold star, Brink.
Yeah, I like that
he's being nice now.
I'm always nice.
You want this towel?
Sure.
Here, you can take my hand.
Sara, I'm jumping after you.
No, no, no. Sara,
you're not jumping.
We all are. What, why?
I'm gonna sit here and take photos.
I don't feel great.
Sara... But you
should totally jump.
Alicia, we're jumping.
Yeah!
It looks cool doing it.
Jump in. Come on, ladies first.
After you.
Go, Alicia.
Sara, he's going first.
I'm so scared.
Go, bitch.
Don't call me that.
Okay, sayonara.
Oh, my God!
Is the bottom far down?
No, you can't even
see the bottom, go.
Okay, well, what if
I hit the rocks there?
Go!
You're fine.
Brink, move.
Just move, Brink, please.
Brink, just fucking move.
Jump!
Yeah. Go, Alicia!
We're going to count, okay?
1...
2...
No, no, no, wait, wait.
Wait, I can't do it.
Hand me my towel, please.
Wait, wait.
It's super safe. Do it!
You're gonna love it.
Will you just shut up?
I just need to concentrate, okay.
What does she need
to concentrate on?
Shut up.
Go, Alicia! 1!
2...
No, no, no, no.
We're gonna count again, okay?
No, no, no.
Come on.
Yes, you can. You promised.
Do it.
Sara.
Please come here. Please, I can't.
Okay, I'm coming.
No, no, are you crazy?
Agustin, just let her go.
Don't babysit her.
Sara.
Are we gonna be here all day?
You know it.
Oh, shit, it's really fucking high.
Agustin, come sit down here.
You can take better pictures.
Go!
Okay, I'm gonna do it.
Wait, wait.
Sara.
Yeah?
Why don't we jump together?
No, no, no.
There's not enough room.
Hey, watch out! Be careful.
Push her!
Okay, wait.
Sara!
Oh!
Baby, are you all right?
I'm okay.
You're one of us.
Oh! It's so fucking cold.
I'm gonna do it. Okay.
You should have pushed her.
Okay. Come on, watch me, okay?
One...
Two...
Three...
Okay.
Let's count down.
Three, two...
One.
Sara, give me your plate.
No, I don't want any more.
I'm fine.
Don't give me that
anorexia bullshit.
There's a lot of meat.
I have eaten, like, a whole
loaf of bread today, seriously.
Come on, baby. You have to eat.
I'm not hungry.
Alicia?
Oh, no, thank you. Okay.
Hey, Barbara. Um...
Do you think maybe we could take
Alicia to the doctor tomorrow?
'Cause she's not feeling very well.
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing. I just haven't
really been sleeping at all.
That's not true.
You always sleep a little.
You're sleeping, so you
forget you're sleeping.
Oh.
No, but she got,
like, vertigo today.
She kept us waiting on this
rock for, like, an hour.
Remember? "One, two, three..."
It's like the fucking
mantra in my head now.
I'll give you some sleeping pills.
You'll feel better tomorrow.
Okay.
I'll take one of those.
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
You know, I almost had to fuck
this prick. Look at that.
Am I supposed to take
that as a compliment?
Pose.
Don't be so boring. Agustin,
go on the table or something.
You guys look weird.
What?
Take these pills.
They're gonna make you relax.
Tomorrow, we can ask Bernardo
if he has some sleeping
pills for you.
Okay, this should work.
Thanks, Barbara.
Oh, fuck. You're not all right.
I'm fine. It's okay, it's normal.
This is what happens.
It will be over soon.
We're gonna take it
easy tonight, okay?
Okay.
Or are we having fun tonight?
What?
It's all black and infinite.
Gravity is pulling down
every cell in your body.
The sounds around you melt
together into one golden...
Okay, forget it.
No, keep going, please.
You laugh at everything I say.
It's the stupid voice that you do.
I can't help it.
Alicia, Alicia.
Let me get rid of that
unpleasant headache of yours.
No, I'm gonna be fine.
Your sister gave me these.
What is this shit?
Come on. Just try it.
You'll feel a lot better, come on.
Don't be so scared of everything.
Brink, stay away.
Come on. Lay down here.
Can you put the music down,
please? Just lean back.
Relax, close your eyes.
I'm going to the bathroom.
I'll be right back.
Breathe deeply.
You haven't slept in so long.
You really want to sleep.
Your eyes are tired.
Oh, great.
Feel the air coming in.
And out.
Feel your body resting.
Your mind is resting.
Alicia.
No.
Are you hypnotized?
Yes.
Tonight, you will rest.
When you go to bed, you
will have a great,
deep sleep, okay?
Yes.
You will now touch the
tip of your nose.
Okay, are you fucking with me?
Yes.
Alicia, dance to this song.
Okay, dance like a whore.
I'm in love with your brother
What's his name?
I thought I'd come by
To see him again
When you two danced
Oh, what a dance
When you two laughed
Oh, what a laugh
Has he mentioned my..
What? God, how many piscos
did you guys give her?
Whoa. Okay, Alicia, calm down.
Look how terrified Brink is.
Okay, now give Agustin a blowjob.
Oh, Brink, why don't you
just do it yourself?
Alicia, stop.
What the fuck? The fuck?
Whoa, whoa... Alicia!
What the fuck?
Hey, Alicia!
Are you serious?
Hit yourself in the face.
Yes!
Bullshit.
This is getting stupid.
Can we change the music?
Now put your face in the fire.
No way.
Whoa! Alicia, stop.
Fuck!
What the fuck?
Get some water or something.
It's okay.
Brink, stop fucking filming.
Look at my hand!
What the fuck, guys?
Can you keep quiet?
What the fuck, Barbara?
She really hurt herself.
She tripped and she
went in the fire.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, exactly.
Barbara.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, Alicia.
No, no, no, no. I have some medicine.
I have some medicine! Wait.
Is she all right?
No.
It's called craving attention.
Sara should be playing with
her more or something.
Hey, do all your girlfriends have
crazy relatives or just Sara?
I don't really care about
her social life, you know?
I'm gonna go check on Sara.
Good night, buddy.
Okay, Alicia, calm down.
Were you drunk?
Okay, now give Agustin a blowjob.
Oh, Brink, why don't you
just do it yourself?
Sara.
What is she doing?
Is she all right?
Yes, she took a couple
of those pills.
Thank God.
And I'm so tired of
you, and hearing you,
and drinking all the
booze in the house.
I am not gona buy morphine.
You hear that?
I just cannot deal with you guys.
It's not funny.
And everybody fucking with.
And I cannot deal with you guys.
It's not funny.
Sara?
Alicia?
Yeah?
Yeah.
What's going on?
Um...
My hand hurts and I can't sleep.
It's the room, I think.
What?
The room?
Did you take the pills I gave you?
No, I haven't yet.
Well, take them.
Yeah, I will. I will.
It's too bad Alicia is not here.
But it's probably for the best.
Wait, wait. Make up a word.
Okay, first word.
Alicia!
What? That sucks.
Alicia's not even a real word.
I'm just so glad Alicia's not here.
She's such a drag.
I wish she'd take those
pills more often.
What are you doing? What...
Please! Stop!
Please, no!
There's a dog's grave around here.
Fucking creeped me out
when I was a kid.
Oh, here it is.
Come on. Your turn.
No, I don't want a picture there.
Why? 'Cause it's weird.
What? Come on.
Can we do it now?
No, it's going to hurt.
Not now. Come on. Let's do it.
No, not now.
Let's do it the other way, then.
What? No!
Let's do it the other way.
I don't want to.
Hey.
What's with all the mirrors?
Weirdest place I've
had sex with Sara?
A dog's grave.
Come on. I don't
want to sing alone.
I don't want to sing.
I'm not in the mood.
Uh-oh.
Shut up.
Hey, Alicia.
Are you feeling okay?
I'm fine!
How's your hand?
It's okay.
I had a weird moment
with a horse here.
Talk about what?
You know what it's about.
Alicia!
Yeah?
Hey! What the fuck is your problem?
The next time you want
your pussy eaten out,
you can just ask me!
I like pussy!
What the fuck?
Shut up! You want them to know?
Really?
What are you talking about?
Shut up! You came into my room
and you rubbed your
pussy in my face.
Who told you to?
Why did you do that?
Get away from me! Sara!
Hey, baby!
This freak grabbed me!
He told me I rubbed
my pussy in his face!
She did! She did!
Whatever! She didn't, man.
She did! I swear she did!
She did not, okay?
Okay, she didn't.
Fucking asshole!
Alicia. I didn't. I didn't!
- She did.
- Okay.
I hate all of you!
You have to calm down.
I can't sleep. I can't sleep.
My phone doesn't even work.
Hey, you're okay. You're okay.
Alicia?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm just really...
I'm really tired.
I can't... I can't deal...
Alicia?
What's happening to me?
No.
Hey, Alicia. Hey!
Alicia, come back!
Alicia!
Alicia, stop!
Alicia.
Hey. Hey.
You okay?
You okay? It's okay.
Hey, let's go.
Let's go to her house.
She can help.
Come on, baby.
She's going to help you.
She's going to fix your hand.
Come on.
Come on, I got you.
Come on. You're okay.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean what
I said out there.
Huh?
You're feeling better?
Yeah, she put some herbal
ointment on my hand.
Hey, I'm making tea.
Do you want some?
Let's take you upstairs.
No, it's fine. I can go by myself.
Okay.
That girl is freaking me out.
Is she possessed, or what the fuck?
She's sick. She's,
like, mentally ill.
She needs to be
medicated, or something.
No, she just needs some sleep.
Maybe when I hypnotized her,
like, something got inside her.
Barbara, she's like a
pathological liar.
Last night, she came into my room...
No. Brink, shut up, okay?
She's not a bad person, you guys.
I know her, okay.
Then why don't you talk
some sense into her?
She just needs a doctor.
For her hand.
Yeah, right. "For her hand."
The nearest hospital
is 5 hours away.
And you're not taking the truck.
Hey, Alicia.
Hey, you want me to run you a bath?
I'm okay, guys.
I promise I'm not sick.
No, we know, baby.
Let's just make the tea
that that woman gave me.
I'm okay, really.
I believe you.
- Just make the tea.
- Okay.
Let's go upstairs.
Alicia?
Hey.
Were you asleep? I'm sorry.
Keep sleeping, baby.
That tea really worked.
That's good. Go back
to sleep. I'm sorry.
What are you doing in here?
Whatever. I'm looking
through Alicia's bag.
I found weird shit, Sara.
She has all these pills.
Do you know what these are for?
No. People take medication
for all kinds of shit.
Why don't you know
what she takes it for?
Come on. You're being
a drama queen.
Strange behavior.
Just be quiet. We don't want to wake
her up. We finally have some peace.
Does she get crazy on her
period or something?
Just be quiet, all right?
Why is it "gentle glide
for insertion comfort"?
What is she so afraid of?
Shut up!
Is your guy pretending to be happy?
Or smiling for real?
He's definitely
pretending to smile.
That's like half of them.
Does yours look like she's had
really bad plastic surgery?
No, it's not Susan.
Listen, it says here that
hypnosis is used sometimes
to treat mental illnesses.
But it doesn't trigger it.
Does she have any crazy
relatives, or something?
No. You're just being dramatic.
She's feeling much better now. Go.
Shouldn't someone be with
her in case she wakes up?
Barbara.
Okay, is yours using
their eyebrow muscles?
Wait a second.
I'm going to go check on her.
Bring back some of
those pills we found!
What pills?
It doesn't matter.
And some more ice!
Agustin.
She ate all of these
Barbara pills. Like 15!
Shit. Agustin, come here.
What the fuck is this?
Did you see this, man?
What the fuck?
The smiley face? Fuck.
Agustin, stop laughing.
This is really starting
to freak me out.
Did you guys look downstairs?
Yes, I looked everywhere.
Except for Barbara's room.
Yeah, let's keep Barbara
out of this, okay?
What the fuck!
Why is she doing this to me?
This is stupid! Why would
she come down to the beach?
Fuck! I don't know.
Do you have a better idea?
Yeah, maybe she's at the
neighbors' house, or something.
Alicia!
Don't you call out to her, Brink!
You're just going to
freak her out even more.
Come on, guys.
Hurry up! Help me here.
Don't fucking do that!
Alicia!
We'll find her, okay?
Bernardo?
Alicia!
Brink?
Brink, do you copy?
Hell yes, we're at
the tennis court!
Hey, come on. Let's go look
for her on the Fat Hill.
Come on. No. No.
Guys, dinner is ready.
1. 2.
3.
Alicia!
Hey!
Wait, did you hear that? Sara!
Alicia!
Sara, do you hear that?
Sara, I'm here! What?
No, it's coming from the water.
Alicia!
Sara!
Okay, guys, watch me.
I'm going to do it now.
What are you doing?
We found her. She's on the rock!
Hey. Come back up here.
What are you doing?
She's on the rock! She's jumping...
Alicia, you have to come back up.
Please. We're sorry.
Just come back up
and we'll go home,
and everything is going
to be fine, okay?
Please. We'll go back to California.
And you can forget about this place,
and it's going to be sunny...
Hey, where is she? Agustin!
Agustin!
Alicia, just walk back slowly, okay?
Don't yell at her.
I promise I'm going to do it. Okay?
No, no, no, no!
- 1, 2...
- Don't move!
- ...3!
- Alicia!
Is she fine? Is she fine?
Hey, just give her room.
Get out of the way, man!
There was a sheep and it fell.
What is she talking about?
Sara! Sara!
Bring my clothes!
Agustin, why aren't
we taking her home?
Melda!
Sara, where are you? Where are you?
It's me, Alicia.
It's okay. It's okay.
Agustin, tell them we need a doctor.
What are they giving her?
Just sleeping pills, tell her.
I don't want it.
Just give her 1!
3 is too many!
Wait, where are you going?
I'm gonna get the car keys.
See you at the dock.
Agustin?
Wait! Agustin!
I'm going to get the car keys.
Wait.
Alicia, it's Sara. It's me.
It's okay.
You're my friend.
Yeah. Yeah, it's okay.
Melda?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
It's not your fault. It's me.
Alicia, stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
What's wrong, baby? What's wrong?
Make it stop, Sara!
What's wrong? What's wrong?
Make it stop. Make it stop.
What do you need?
Please turn on the music!
Tell her to shut up!
What do you need?
You want the music?
Agustin, put the music on!
Put the fucking music on!
Okay. Okay.
Folks, here's the story
'bout Minnie the Moocher
She was the roughest,
toughest frail
But Minnie had a
heart as big as...
Agustin, where the fuck are we?
Where the fuck are we?
Sara, you're stressing me out!
We have to trust Melda!
She needs to go to a hospital.
No, not now! We can't go to a
hospital now. She'll just have to wait.
Relax. Everything is
going to be fine.
She needs to go to
a fucking hospital.
We can't go to a hospital now!
We're here!
- What is she saying?
- Shut up!
Ugh!
Agustin. Oh, my God. What is that?
Baby. I'm sorry.
What's wrong?
Alicia.
What's happening?
What's she saying?
What's happening, please?
She's dead!
No! No, she's not.
No, she's not.
She has done this before, okay?
She is alive.
Listen, her soul will
come back to her body.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Please come back, baby.
Come back. Please come back.