Ripped & Sync by: Etcohod
Timed by AccuSrt
Little Ricky, where are you baby?
Come on honey... it's dinner time.
It's your favourite flavour - Liver.
Where are you?
There you are. Hey. . what're you doing under there?
What you doing under there?
What's the matter?
Oh. . Ricky baby, what's the matter sweetheart?
We're ready for you doctor.
How is she?
- Still in the O. T. I haven't heard anything yet.
When did this happen?
- He was waiting for her at her place when she got home from class.
Forensics say it was the same man
who raped Cara Latham.
Did you really need a forensics expert to tell you that?
Andy.
Dana, when was the last time I asked your department to
beef up the security and cameras, right?
I mean not the first four times. It's the last time.
Don't get pissy with me professor.
I don't have the manpower to break up a fraternity party.
Suction
- Suction.
What's that pressure?
Less than 70. Sixty-nine.
She's sliding down pretty fast.
We're gonna lose her doctor.
- I would not bet my ranch on that.
David, drop 0. 2 ccs of epinephrine.
Tanya, give me the stitch please.
- 3,0 silk.
We've gone at 63. Epinephrine doctor?
- No, Not yet.
60.
Still think it's a phenobarbital reaction?
Epinephrine.
And. .
- At ease up on retraction pressure.
65 & going up.
- No doubt about that.
68.
- I don't believe that.
72.
- How about your scissors?
Metzenbaum.
- Beautiful.
80.
- She's out of the woods.
Great to practice medicine.
Irrigation please.
Dr. Robertson, would you please close the wound for me?
Nice going, people.
By the way, everybody:
it's great to be in Saint Agnes.
That was good work.
Dr. Robertson...
May I call you Matthew?
- Of course.
Matthew... .
I'm the new guy around here and I want to make friends, so... .
I'll say this to you and we'll start fresh.
If you don't like my jokes, don't laugh.
If you have a medical opinion, then please
speak up and speak up loud.
But if you ever again tell me or my surgical
staff that we're going to lose a patient,
... I'm going to take out your lungs
with a fuckin' ice cream scoop.
Do you understand me?
I'm not gonna like you, am I?
Don't be ridiculous.
Everybody likes me.
Dr. Hill!
- Ya.
I'm Andy Safian.
I'm Associate Dean at the college & I wondered. .
if you could tell me anything about Bridget Kelly's condition.
Well, she has a badly bruised liver but I
think she's gonna be just fine.
Great. Thanks to you.
Well, come to the midnight show, I love
to take the next of kin.
It's Jed Hill, right?
"Galloping" Jed Hill?
Excuse me.
We were at the high school together.
You're kidding me.
You went to Van Buren?
Yeah.
- Wow!
How long you've been in Westerly?
- Well, I've been here about nine hours now. Van Buren, huh?
Yeah, well, we weren't in the same... we didn't travel
in the same circles but...
Did I give you a hard time?
- No, you didn't know who the hell I was. So. .
Dr. Hill...
Hi Tanya!
I just wanted to say congratulations.
We're all very happy that you're here.
Well, thank you. It's. .
it's nice to be here.
Looks like you're again the popular man.
I hope to see you around.
- Yeah, me too.
Oh, that's wonderful, Michelle.
Hey, why don't we try painting on a paper
& not on your arm?
I am a monster.
- Teacher, teacher...
Hey, don't you ever play with plastic bags or
I'll tie you up and I'll feed you to little cape
monster, you got it?
I heard what happened.
- Can you come on lunch now?
in a minute.
Yeah, the guy got in when she was
at her class.
She's gonna be alright.
- Looks like it...
turns out that the hospital has a new surgeon,
this whizkid from Mass General did a great job.
So I went back to introduce myself, to thank him
& are you ready for this?
We were at the High School together.
- Oh, no kidding.
Speak of the Devil...
- And the Devil appears.
I was just recounting all your experts' here.
This is my wife, Tracy.
Tracy, this is Dr. Jed Hill.
A school friend of Andy.
This is Dr. Sullivan, Alan and Tracy Safian.
- Andy.
Andy works at the college.
- He's Associate Dean, Mr. Hill.
Fantastic.
- I don't leap tall buildings in a single bound.
But we are very proud of him.
- That's well. You should be.
Listen, we're having a small reception to welcome Jed
to Saint Agnes. Why don't you come along?
Oh, we'll have to go. We have a lunch appointment.
- Oh, maybe some other time.
Definitely.
Nice meeting you, Tracy.
- Yeah, nice to meet you.
Well, we got the estimate from the plumber this morning.
- And?
Are you ready for this?
- How much?
It's... 13,000 and change.
- How much change?
It's 14,000.
- Alright, forget it. I'm gonna do the work myself.
I got a better idea.
- No.
Well, just for a little while. It pays and goes,
we rent it to some visiting lecturer.
I don't want to rent out the third floor.
I don't want a stranger in our house.
Alright, suit yourself.
Would've been nice living in
a home with running water but...
I'm a simple girl.
Hey, I'm gonna pick you up after work.
- No, it's okay.
Forget it. I'm gonna pick you up.
There's a maniac who's in this town.
Helen can give me a ride.
- She can? Are you sure?
Make sure she waits until you're inside the house.
I'll have her provide air coverage if you want.
It's funny. I married a funny woman.
See ya.
- Nice.
You know in street clothes,
Helen looks positively masculine.
- What?
Helen. You said you were getting a
ride home from Helen.
Were you spying on me?
- No, no. Looking out my window.
Then you were looking at Dennis Riley, my mother's
lawyer. He had papers for me to sign.
What kind of papers?
Something about my mother's estate.
What is this?
Your mother's estate?
- Yes.
You told me she barely got by in
her social welfare check .
And now she's Lady Astor?
- Come on, Andy.
There was a small account for the
cemetery arrangements.
The money lacks about which Dennis
wanted to talk to me about.
And now what is it you want to
talk to me about?
Sorry.
Hey listen, would you think any less of
me if I use a fork?
I've been losing my strength here.
- I can't let that happen.
Lie back. Give it to me.
Lie back. That's right.
All the way back.
Technique, huh?
- The expert.
It's all in my hands, see?
Open. Open up.
Good boy.
Delicious, huh?
Delicious. More...
Look, I think your strength
is returning.
It's a miracle.
Andy.
What is it?
- He's there again.
So?
- He's looking at us.
Sounds like he's playing one of those electric keyboards.
- Jesus, it gives me the creeps.
Be nice.
His mother works as a night nurse.
Probably he is lonely.
We gotta get some curtains up here.
It's a priority.
Curtains are now the priority.
- Not until we decide what to paint.
There is no point in painting if we
are going to break the house for the plumbing.
So we are back to where we started.
Oh Jeez!... .
Front door was wide open.
- Oh...
You scared the hell out of me.
I should have knocked but...
- Oh, no, no.
Yeah... I have been working with a liquid paint remover.
Sometimes I get a headache from these odors.
Oh, you should be taking a B Complex.
- Say again?
Well, a loading dose of a B-12
would help to enhance the cerebral cap... .
Never mind.
- No, no. why did you stop? That sounded great.
Well, no it just occurred to me that I was suggesting you take a jar
of vitamins, you'd be smart not to leave the door open.
Look at that. I saved myself $ 5. 95.
I was in the neighbourhood looking at some houses
and I thought I would take you and your wife out
for the lunch as promised.
Well, Tracy is out to her class but I can get
cleaned up and we could go out ourselves.
Sounds good.
- Alright. Okay, I'll be right back.
So this is a real Victorian house, huh?
- Yeah, buried under a hundred years of paint.
It was part of the underground rails
during the civil war.
Lack of comfort makes up for the history.
You know anything about architecture??
- Architecture... oh architecture is my life.
If I hadn't been a doctor, I'd have been...
... It'd have been a building.
Is this a Degas?
Ya. I think it's original.
Tracy's father gave it to her.
She's been having these abdominal pains.
How often?
- Maybe once a week or all week days.
How long do they last?
- Half a minute, sometimes even longer.
Is she seeing someone?
- Yeah, a doctor in Boston named Lillianfield.
David Lillianfield. Do you know him?
- I've heard of him. Lillianfield is a good man.
The thing is, we really wanna have kids.
Tracy is nuts about it.
So am I.
- I'll tell you what.
Give it another couple of weeks and if there
is no change, have a come by and see me.
Alright.
Hey Stanley...
Hey Doc, it hurts when I do this.
Then don't do that. And get some
new jokes, Stanley.
So I told him 'why don't you come by and
look at ours and maybe we'd work out. '
You did what?
You're the one who wanted to rent it out.
I thought you'd be thrilled.
Do I look thrilled?
- You're not thrilled. I can see that now but. .
this is better than a visiting lecturer.
Jed is a friend.
He's not a friend. He didn't even
remember your name, Alan.
I mean, common the guy had just been
through twelve hours of surgery.
What is it Andy? You want to relive the Highschool,
be friends with the quarterback this time?
No, he was the running back.
And stop talking to me like I'm eleven.
What's your problem with this guy?
I mean he's smart, he's funny... .
... and he's a brilliant doctor.
- I know. I know he's brilliant Andy...
I can tell by the way the nurses seem to fall on
their knees when he walks down the hallway.
I mean, this guy doesn't have friends,
he has subjects.
Well... .
It's not too late, we
can call it off.
No, no. I'm leaving it up to you.
If you want to live with that, it's your decision.
- You're gonna get to like him. You really will.
And you know what else?
We could even ask him to recommend
another doctor for you.
Hello, what?
If for no other reason, then it's nonsense to drive two hours
to see Lillianfield in Boston when we could just easily...
Andy, please tell me you didn't say anything to Jed.
Please tell me you didn't share my problems with him.
It came up.
I apologise.
- Alright.
I will go along with this
for a few months...
Only because I want the sofa...
... combining with the stairs.
Oh my God, is he moving in tonight?
You're assuming it's Jed?
- Oh, I'm quite certain it's Jed. Open the door.
It could be anyone.
- The angels could dance on pins, but they do not. It's Jed.
What makes you so sure?
- You want to bet me?
No.
Because once money is involved,
you take me seriously, right?
Hello.
Dr. Hill. Please come in.
Andy just got through telling me,
we're gonna be roommates.
Well, that's why I stopped by.
I just wanted to make sure that it was really okay.
Don't be silly. I'm looking forward to it.
- She is. She is really looking forward to it.
Excellent.
The mid-term was at 8:30. I set my alarm for 7
& it didn't go off.
I mean if Professor Schmidt wants to give
me an incomplete, then I really don't care.
I can't control everything in this world.
My alarm didn't go off.
That's good.
That's very good, Paula.
That's so much better than locking your copy of
Beowulf in your friend's car.
Thank You.
Yeah.
Detective Harris wishes to see you.
- Really.
I'm amazed she could find the building.
We'll have to continue this next week if you don't mind.
- Fine.
Hang on, Paula. Hi Dana, go on in.
It will be just a second.
Mrs. Worthington, I want you to note all test and
exam times for Ms. Paula Bell.
She's to receive wake up calls from this office.
- Wake up calls?
She can't be expected to control the world, Mrs. Worthington.
Her alarm didn't go off.
I'll see you next week, Paula.
Sorry.
- Jesus!
She able to give any kind of description?
All she remembers is her cat crouching
under a chair...
... and an arm grabbing her from behind.
Is there any chance she'll remember more?
I don't think so.
So...
What do we do now?
- We?
'We' don't do anything Andy.
Only one of us is a police detective.
Maybe not even that many.
Oh... college wit.
Let me search my mind for a clever answer.
How about 'bite me'?
Touché.
We have ordered more ''Security Precautions'' pamphlets.
More pamphlets?
- That's right.
Do you know what I see when I come
to work every morning?
I see fathers loading trunks, suitcases, plants
and daughters in their station wagons.
Presumably to drive them off to school so that
they don't pose quite as high a death threat.
See, I don't think I'm being unreasonable
when I ask...
... what you and your crack-team of professionals are doing
other than distributing literature to repress this situation.
I need a list of anyone who had access to
the students' schedules.
Both victims were inside the class
when our guy got in.
So you have narrowed it down to a couple
of thousand people.
A list, Andy.
I need it, now.
Dana...
What do you think he does with the hair?
- The hair?
Yeah, he gets off all the hair.
What do you think he does with it?
Perhaps makes pillows. Who knows?
Billy, I want you in bed by 10,
you hear me?
You scared the shit out of me.
- I'm sorry about that.
What the hell are you doing here?
Are you alright?
- No, I'm not alright.
Anybody home?
Up here, honey.
This is ridiculous.
- Go to sleep.
Who the hell can sleep
with them doing that all night?
It's been like three hours.
I'll ask him to turn it down.
No, I don't want to make a big thing about it.
- No, if you can't fall asleep...
You think maybe he heard us?
- I hope so.
Where're you going?
- To the bathroom.
I know why guys like you become doctors.
It's not what you yhink.
I think it's to make a lot of money
& see a lot of naked women.
Oh. . well. .
Then it is what you think.
Hey, ease yourself.
I'm not done with you yet.
I am immune to alcohol.
- Yeah?
We'll see about that.
Tracy.
You alright?
Ya, I'll be right there.
You worried me for a second.
- No, I'm fine.
Come on, let's go to bed.
hey, how you there, old man?
Six miles a day keeps the doctor away.
Want some coffee?
- No, never touch in the morning.
You okay, Tracy?
- I'm fine.
Well, I'll grab quick shower, fly over to the
hospital. I'll catch you guys later.
Are you sure she didn't call to
cancel her appointment?
Yes, I'm sure that I called her
yesterday to remind her.
Did you try calling her again?
- Nobody's there, professor.
I keep getting her answering machine.
- She's there.
She's not answering it.
Paula?
I'm gonna need a statement.
Andy...
You wanna hear about the first time I
ever saw a corpse?
No.
It was my first year of medical
school, ghost anatomy.
The instructor begin cutting the corpse's head.
People were running out of the room.
Some fainted there.
I tell you, it really didn't bother me over that much though.
It's a great story Jed.
Of course, I'm not looking forward to
the same thing but... .
Hey, You'll get over it.
Hey Stanley, who the hell is that in the backfield?
Livelle or something. He's off the bench .
What happened to Krakowski?
- Funked the piss test.
That upsets me.
Guy can't stay off of cocaine even for one
million dollars.
Man, I'll give my right arm for
one million dollars.
We cannot afford plumbing for Christ's sake.
Would you really?
- What?
give your right arm for one million dollars?
You mean like, literally?
- Yeah.
Well, not even an arm.
Let's just say a finger.
One finger, for one milion dollars?
Oh god, this is a strange conversation.
What we're talking about is a surgical procedure just...
... to the joint.
Would you do it?
No.
Really?
Would you?
No.
I should be getting back
Jed let me... .
Hey, stay for one more drink with me.
- Tracy's gonna be home.
I'll see you.
- Yeah.
Stanley.
Would you please bring those two girls
a round of whatever it is they're drinking?
Bourbon.
- Bourbon it is.
Got a minute?
- Sure.
This... is the living room here.
Take a seat.
I just need you to clear up a few things for me.
- Like what?
Paula Bell came to see you 3 times, is that right?
- That's right.
It would have been four times only... .
- What is this?
Last night we matched the soil sample taken from
Paula Bell's carpet to a sample taken from your yard.
I went inside, I told you that.
We also matched it to a sample
taken from Bridget Kelly's room.
Bridget came by here to pick up a
letter of recommendation.
Am I a suspect, Dana?
Am I a fucking suspect?
All three victims had been in to see you
before they were attacked.
I found Paula, for Christ's sake.
What was it that made you go to her house?
- She missed her appointment.
So you went to her house?
- Yes, because she was a screw-up & I've a responsibility.
What's your blood type, Andy?
- O+ve.
See, as luck would have it, you have the same
blood type as the perpetrator.
Dana, this is crazy. In my entire life
I've never harmed anyone.
I believe you.
I don't think you're the guy.
Thank you.
I need you to do something for me. It's procedural,
I wouldn't be doing my job if I didn't ask you to do it.
Do what?
I need a sperm sample to test
against the one taken from the victims.
I don't believe this.
- It's a simple thing Andy. Maybe in an hour
... you'll be eliminated as a suspect.
What if I refuse?
Give the way to my handcuffs.
Damn.
- No, no. It's much better.
No, it's not.
- No, it is.
At least you did not hit the
innocent bystanders  again.
Beautiful.
Andy.
911 Emergency.
I'll show you the rotating muscle
if you don't mind, it's right in here okay...
... if it tears, you cannot comb hair, let
alone throw the ball.
That thing's been beeping all night.
Are you a drug dealer?
Yeah, you can say that.
Stanley.
Somebody, talk to me.
We've got massive haemorrhaging.
It's probably an ovary.
We'll have some more numbers in a few minutes.
Blood type.
- AB negative. We need more.
Tanya, get a hold of the Mass General, Boston, and
Mercy Hartford. If they're low, we're gonna need donors.
I'm sorry we had to put you through this, Andy.
You can go home now.
Andy.
Mr. Safian...
- Yeah.
Your wife's name came up on a 911.
It's a medical emergency.
David, what's the blood pressure?
- 93 above 57.
Heart rate?
- 86.
Capacity?
- 27.
Jed, did you see this?
Four to five weeks would be my guess.
She is pregnant?
- Not for long.
Her foetus got aborted from the trauma
of the procedure.
Whenever you're ready, doctor.
Dr. Hill...
Alright, let's begin.
Scalpel.
- Scalpel.
Mr. Safian.
- Yeah.
What happened to my wife?
- She's bleeding internally.
Dr. Hill will come and talk to you
soon as her condition is stabilized.
Is she conscious?
- I'm sorry Mr. Safian, that's all I know.
We're almost done. I just wanna have one last
look around. Check for rings and watches. Suction.
Suction.
Well, I think we've got it all.
It's amazing it didn't erupt so sooner.
Jed.
You got some pathology in the second ovary.
Let me have a look in here. Harrington.
- Harrington.
It was twisted when I unpacked it.
Think it's necrotic?
Alright I want to do a frozen section right away,
see if we still get a viable ovary here.
We can't.
- Why not?
The pathologist is not present.
- Then what do I do for frozen section?
We can call him in.
- How long would that take?
30-40 minutes.
Hell, then I'd get a microscope and do it myself.
It'll take at least a half an hour
for the processor to warm up.
What's the pressure?
- 78.
I don't have that kind of time.
- You got maybe fifteen minutes.
Alright. Irrigate and try to get the BP
back up. I'll be right back.
Come with me.
- What's going on?
I had to remove one of Tracy's ovaries.
It ruptured. A large cyst had developed in
that what was causing her pain.
I've to be direct with you
because we're little under the gun.
Is it under control?
- Not yet.
There is a problem with Tracy's second ovary.
We discovered it was torsed or twisted
around in its own blood supply.
If I remove it, I'm simply
removing a dead organ...
... and in all likely Tracy will lead a
normal healthy life.
But...
... she won't ever be able to have children.
If I close her up now, she could die of
toxic-shock in the middle of the night.
Do whatever you have to do.
- Tracy's gonna be fine.
Yeah.
But what?
- I'll tell you later.
No.
No, tell me now.
Tracy was pregnant.
Of four weeks.
Tracy is pregnant?
- No Andy. The foetus aborted .
She sustained a lot of trauma.
There was nothing that could be done.
I'm sorry about it.
Artery clamp.
Dr. Hill, I think this might be a mistake.
How do you know it's not still viable?
This is the wife of a friend.
I'll not take any chances. Scalpel.
You could be taking out a viable ovary.
It's necrotic. Scalpel.
- Without the histology, you can't be sure.
I'm sure.
Tanya, give me the scalpel.
Jed.
What you got there, George?
- It's from pathology.
Are they Histology report?
We took out a healthy ovary.
Only the surface was necrotic.
Jed, take this.
Look at it.
Then burn it.
That's a nice gesture, George.
Really.
The technician owes me a favour.
Lab won't be a problem.
It'll be a problem for me.
This hospital took out a healthy ovary.
I took out the ovary.
No one else.
It was a judgement call and
I stand by it.
Are you gonna be alright?
- I'll be fine.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I figured you probably hadn't eaten anything in a while.
- We should talk later, okay?
Well, Andy, I wanted to have a word with Tracy.
Maybe later, okay? Jed...
Hello, Mrs. Safian. You gave
us quite a scare.
Did I?
Tracy, I know you've been told
all about what's happened.
Yes.
I don't know if there's any point in telling
you how sorry I am.
I spoke with a lawyer this morning.
I want to make sure you don't
do this to someone else.
The legal statements will be in a week.
I think we can bring them down from
the 30 million in a settlement.
Let's not dick each other around here.
30 million, 25 million, what difference does it make?
You know anything over 10 million dollars
& I can't get insurance in this or any other state.
I say we go to a jury.
- I cannot recommend that.
Why not?
Let me tell you what a jury sees.
A jury sees a beautiful young woman
married to a mild-mannered teacher.
They buy an old house and dream of
filling it up with children.
Now that is a honey-sweet painting and you
have ripped it to shreds with your scalpel.
You're my lawyer.
Am I right here?
It's not my job to hold your hand, doctor.
It's not your job to be an asshole either counsellor
but that doesn't seem to be stopping here.
Maybe if we all calm down.
We could bring in a private investigator,
dig up something on her background.
Lester, she volunteered five days a week
in a children's ward.
And baked cookies for the staff.
Looks like you picked the
wrong patient to screw up on, doctor.
I didn't pick her, counsellor.
Physicians don't get to choose.
I'll need an ''expert''.
Who do you want to call?
What do you mean?
- An expert. Someone to make a statement.
A statement saying what?
- A statement saying that you're as good as you think you are.
Call Dr. Marvin Kessler.
Harvard Medical School.
Is that it Miss?
Yes.
How will I get in touch with you?
- You won't.
I don't want you to.
Tracy, why won't you let me help you
get through this?
This isn't a phase, Andy.
I can't have children. Ever.
He thought you were going to die.
Right about now he's wishing I did.
Tracy, I love you.
He took my insights out...
And you gave him permission.
Goodbye, Andy.
Dr. Kessler, would you describe your history
& relationship to Dr. Hill?
Dr. Hill was a student of mine at medical school.
From graduation I asked him to serve his
residency under my direction at Mass General.
And when he finished the residency,
I asked him to join our surgical staff.
Dr. Kessler, how long you've been teaching at Harvard Medical school?
- 21 years.
How long you've been chief of staff at Mass General?
- 14 years.
So you've been in a position to work with thousands of young doctors.
Am I correct?
-Yes.
I might add that the doctors are there a pleasure to teach
& work with are among the very best in the world.
And how would Dr. Hill rank in this group that
are among the very best in the world?
- There is no one any better.
Thank You.
Mr. Riley.
Dr. Kessler, your faith in Dr. Hill's surgical talent is obvious.
And completely deserved.
Dr. Kessler, seven months ago the position of Chief
of Surgery became available on Mass General.
Did you had Jed Hill seek this position?
- Yes, he did.
Did you give the position to Jed?
- Excuse me, my client's name is Dr. Hill.
Forgive me, did you award the position to Dr. Hill? - No.
Why not?
Well, he was certainly qualified...
- But you didn't give him the job.
There were many other candidates.
Surgeons more qualified?
- This isn't the trial, Mr. Riley.
Dr. Kessler, during Dr. Hill's residency in Mass General
you wrote several co-orderly valuations.
The valuations to be read and
reviewed by hospital administrators...
... department heads.
- Yes.
I'm looking at one... right now dated
June 15th, 1982 & bearing your signature.
It's coming up.
I'd like to read fom page 3, paragraph 4...
While Jed Hill consistently remains the
most skilled and the brightest of our residents...
... we should not ignore what the authorities of this
college observed that he suffers from "God Complex".
'God-Complex'. That's not a typo, was it?
It says 'God-Complex'.
That was read nearly a decade ago.
- What's a 'God-Complex'?
How did you get this information? This was priviledged...
- Dr. Kessler...
What's a 'God-Complex'?
It's a term that has no clinical meaning... at all.
Doctors throw it around...
Sir, with all due respect, but knock it off.
What did you mean in this evaluation when
you said Dr. Hill had a 'God-Complex'?
The power to heal can be an enormous thing,
an enormous thing...
to save a life. To get blood flowing into cells
and vital organs.
If a person can do that... And if one can do it
as exceptionally as Dr. Hill...
... it's not uncommon for a person like that
to begin to believe that he can do anything.
The power to heal can be like a drug.
'Like a drug', you're saying?
Would it've been uncommon for a person with a
'God-complex' to reject the advice of others?
No.
Would it've been uncommon for such a person to... .
proceed on a course that others might reject
if only out of a sense of a God like power?
Oh, now I think you're vastly overstating.
Is that why you didn't give Dr. Hill the job?
- There were a number of other factors.
Is that why you removed a healthy ovary
without any scientific diagnosis?
Don't you address my client, Mr. Riley.
- Do you have a 'God-complex'?
This is not acceptable.
- No, no. Let him address me.
Jed.
-No, No. It's about time I got to give some answers here.
Stop typing.
This is off the record.
The question is, do I have a 'God-complex'.
- Dr. Kessler says yes.
which makes me wonder if this lawyer has any idea...
... as to the kind of grades one has
to receive in college...
... to be accepted at a top medical school.
If you have the vaguest clue as to
how talented someone has to be...
... to lead a surgical team.
I have an M. D. from Harvard,
I am board certified in cardio-thoracic medicine
and trauma surgery,
I have been awarded citations from seven
different medical boards in New England,
and I am never, ever sick at sea.
So I ask you:
when someone goes into that chapel and they
fall on their knees and they pray to God...
... that their wife doesn't miscarry or that their
daughter doesn't bleed to death...
... or that their mother doesn't suffer acute
neural trauma from post-operative shock,
... who do you think they're praying to?
Now, go ahead and read your Bible, Dennis,
and you go to your church,
and, with any luck, you might win the annual raffle,
but if you're looking for God:
he was in operating room number two on November 17,
and he doesn't like to be second guessed.
You ask me if I have a 'God complex'.
Let me tell you something:
I am God.
This sideshow is over.
You got a winner here, Lester.
Call my office, in the morning
and we'll work out a settlement.
It gets better.
- What do you mean?
We talked to the bartender of a
place called Prince William Tavern.
Ask 'God' how many shots of bourbon he had before he cut me open.
The insurance company will be drafting
to my firm's account by sometime next week...
So if you sign right away, you should get
your money few days after that.
Listen there are some things we
should discuss now that can embroil a policy.
Dennis, this isn't such a good time for me.
- We're talking about 20 million dollars.
Dennis, I think about what I want for breakfast,
I start crying.
You could put the money in a coffee pot,
for all I care.
It's 8:30.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
You should go home.
Mrs. Worthington.
Mr. Leemus.
Christ!
You surprised me. Holy Shi...
I was working on the front.
I didn't know anybody else was here.
I saw the lights...
- It's my mother's hair.
She's not alive anymore.
That's her in the picture.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to get any of your things. I. .
- No, that's okay.
I came down to get a light,
I didn't realize...
You live down here?
- No, no. Just for a while.
My landlady asked me to leave.
I won't stay here long.
No, I promise Mr. Safian.
No, you stay here as long as you want.
I'll just take this and I'll go back up.
Good night, Mr. Safian.
- Good night, Earl.
Don't worry, it doesn't look as
bad as the other guy.
I could have killed him.
Junior, have you met the professor?
A very tough guy.
If you want something done, alright
goddamn it, you call a teacher.
Let me buy you a drink.
You know, there is one thing I
realized during all this.
Jed had just come out of the OR to
talk to me. He was covered in blood and
he was telling me what he was about to
do and then he needed my permission to do it.
And... there was a second, maybe a
second and a half... .
... between him telling me that Tracy
was pregnant and...
... then telling me that the foetus was
aborted during surgery.
That second,
that second and a half...
... that was the happiest time in my life.
That is a horrible story.
It's the worst story I've ever heard.
And I aprreciate your words of comfort.
- I mean it, Andy.
Like a fucking job,
shit just happens to you.
Have you had a lot of success talking
jumpers in from window ledges?
May I ask you something?
- Sure.
How well do you know Tracy?
- She's my wife. What do you mean?
My brothers, my friends and my ex-husband...
... have all accused me of wielding my sense
of honesty like a blunt instrument.
I don't want to hurt you anymore
than you've been but...
... I'm very sure I'm doing the right thing.
What are you talking about?
I want you to come back to the station with me.
I must show you something.
Sir, sir can I help you?
- I'm here to see Jed Hill.
What the hell happened to you?
- It wasn't my baby.
What?
It wasn't my baby.
Come inside.
What the hell happened to your face?
Doesn't matter.
You know what this is?
This is a police test.
A lab report.
I don't understand.
It's my sperm sample I left after
Paula Bell rape.
I'm sterile.
Can I have a look at that, please?
I can't have any children, so it
wasn't my baby.
You got to call your lawyer Jed.
You call your lawyer, you haven't tell the
insurance company to stop the presses because...
... this thing. No, it's not over yet.
Oh, Andy. This isn't about me.
It's about both of us, Jed.
She ruined both of us. It's too late for me
but it's not too late for you.
Andy, I don't mean to seem indelicate but
as far as my situation is concerned...
... it doesn't matter if Tracy was sleeping
with the Boston Celtics.
I took out her reproductive system.
It was a wrong call and the bill was
20 million dollars.
- No.
That's where you're wrong. See, the
20 million dollars is a big settlement, right?
That wasn't for the fuck-up.
That... that was for the victim.
The insurance company settled high and fast because
they thought they're up against Snow White.
What happens if Snow White is shacking up
with her lawyer Jed, huh?
You tell me.
Andy, you're hurt & you
want revenge.
& I can understand that, but I got
what I deserved.
and you know something,
as much as this pains you...
... no matter what Tracy was doing
behind your back...
she got a hell of a
lot worse than she deserved.
Did I?
Did you what?
- Did I get what I deserved?
Bad things happen to good people all the time,
Andy & for no reason.
Take my word for it.
I'll see you later.
What're you gotta do Andy?
I'm gonna go out and
get to know my wife.
Hi Dennis!
He doesn't have an appointment, Mr. Riley.
He just walked right on.
She tried to stop me, Dennis.
See, I can call him Dennis coz we're old friends.
We both slept with my wife.
Claudia, call security.
- Do that Claudia and then call the US Attorney's office...
... and see if conspiracy to commit insurance fraud
comes under their jurisdiction.
Forget security, Claudia. Just close the door
behind you. Thank you.
This... This is a nice office.
- What the hell happened to your face?
I beat the shit out of a deeply
disturbed serial rapist.
Hey, I want an explanation.
- An explanation for what?
For how my wife could have been pregnant
when her husband's sterile?
What was it - Immaculate Conception?
If that's the case, Dennis, I wouldn't have settled for
20 million if I were you.
Andy, I had no knowledge of this.
And I wasn't sleeping with your wife if
that's what you're suggesting.
Bullshit.
- Then what can I do for you, Andy?
You can tell me where Tracy is.
Telling you where Tracy is would break an Attorney-Client
privilege & I will not do that.
Now there is nothing more I can do.
Claudia'ill be happy to call the US Attorney for you.
Were you sleeping with her?
No.
Can you help me?
- Help you do what? What is it you want Andy?
I want to talk to Tracy.
I know I'm asking you a favour...
I've a professional obligation.
I've a legal obligation to my client.
Your problems, your questions,
cold as this may seem are not my business.
And I haven't got the answers you want.
Even if I did, I wouldn't be able to give them to you.
Talk to her friends, talk to her
mother & talk to other people.
What did you say?
- I'm saying this is a personal matter.
Did you say 'talk to her mother'?
- She certainly knows Tracy better than I do.
Her mother is dead.
When did she die?
- Twelve years ago.
You handled the estate.
No, I didn't.
- What're you saying to me?
I'm saying I didn't handle Mrs. Kennsinger's
estate and anything
else rather than framework of your
wife's lawsuit is not my...
I don't give a fuck about the lawsuit. I'm asking...
- Then we have nothing here to talk about.
Is her mother alive?
Where does she live?
Please understand...
- Fuck it. I'll find her myself.
Andy...
Scotch.
- What?
Bring her a bottle of scotch.
My name is Andy Safian.
- So what?
Did your daughter ever tell you
she had a husband?
Did your wife ever tell you
she had a mother?
- Yeah.
You're a liar.
She said you were dead.
- What do you want from me?
I... it's nothing. I just want...
- Nobody wants nothing.
I thought maybe we could
have a drink and talk.
She sure loved her daddy.
Second on the place of the best swindlers in Boston.
He taught her everything.
She was daddy's girl.
I wanted to ask you some questions.
She tried to do the smart thing,
I give you that.
The smart thing. What was that?
- Marry a rich fellow. What do you think?
Tracy was married before?
- I said she tried.
You got to pay attention.
One of Bill's old partners, a guy from Newport.
Millionaire with a heart problem.
He wouldn't marry her though.
Not even after she got pregnant.
Mrs. Kennsinger.
This is single malt scotch.
That was so classy Mister.
I haven't had single malt since '69.
I drink crap. Blended whisky is crap,
I don't give what colour the label is.
I need to find Tracy.
Tell me the part again where she was
working with children's ward.
I can tell you, she likes kids so she... .
What?
Did I say something funny?
She indeed found herself a dork .
Like shooting tuna fish in a barrel.
Big one too.
You're drunk.
- And you're stupid.
I can say that to you because
you're my son-in-law.
Want to see something?
- I want you to tell me where Tracy is.
I'm older, I'm smarter.
You can learn something from me.
I know she's been here.
Andy... is it Andy?
Yeah.
Andy...
It's a simple trick.
- The statue...
What?
This, the Degas.
- What about it?
It was in my house. It was Tracy's.
So I know she's been here.
Andy...
Believe me. You need to see this trick.
- Do you get that I'm serious?
I got it. Pick a card.
Look at it.
Put it back in the deck.
Shuffle the deck.
Mrs. Kennsinger, I don't want...
- You can call me 'Mom'.
I don't think so.
Shuffle the cards. And shuffle them good.
We used to give Tracy some money each week
so she could buy candy. Shuffle the cards!
She won't spend it though, not a penny.
Each week she put it under the mattress.
I swear I think there could
be $ 200 under the mattress.
I'll tell you something else about Tracy...
I don't think it bothered her a bit when her father
cleaned up the bank accounts and disappeared.
I think it bothered her when he took
the 200 dollars from under the mattress.
Jesus! what the hell kind of a family is this?
Want to bet?
- What?
200 bucks. You will give me 200 bucks if I guess
where your card is else I give you 200 bucks.
No.
Because once money is involved,
you take me seriously, right?
Look, you said there was a point here and I... .
Why do you give a Frenchman's fuck who
she was sleeping with?
Get into the game.
Go for the 20 million yourself.
Are you saying that Tracy set this up?
What the hell have I been telling you?
Am I talking to my shadow?
You think you're Sherlock Holmes with this statue?
You can buy them in any departmental store...
89, 95. Looks just like the real thing.
The whole thing was a setup?
You're crazy.
Yeah?
Then how come I have the Jack of Clubs
in my fucking pocket?
Look kid, I don't know what the game is.
But you got stung,
so did your friend, the surgeon.
Maybe, it's best to just take a medicine
like a good little boy and go home.
But do me a favour.
Leave me this scotch.
What happened to the baby? - What baby?
- The Newport millionaire, their baby.
She pocketed the money he
gave her for an abortion.
Went downtown to a clinic.
She ended up working for the doctor.
And there's a happy ending.
She disappeared with 80,000 dollars of
the clinic's money.
How much of that do you think I saw?
What was the name of the doctor?
How much you think I'm going to see
from this 20 million?
Was the name of the doctor David Lillianfield?
How much do you think she's gonna give her dead mother?
Was it?
- Was what what?
You think you can drink like this
and remember a name?
Was the name of the doctor David Lillianfield?
Welcome to the game.
CODE BLUE
ANSWERING SERVICE
Hello!
Excuse me.
Can I talk to your manager?
Mr. Hearn leaves at 5 o'clock.
You're gonna have to come back tomorrow.
I'm Dr. Lillianfield.
Mr. Hearn wanted me to come by to fill...
... out a change of address card for your billing.
Is that Lillianfield?
- Yeah. David.
Why don't you just write it on the back of the old
card and we'll take care of the rest tomorrow.
Thanks.
Where is the key?
I'm soaked.
God! I'm freezing.
It's cold in here.
We must do something about the latch.
Oh, this damn door is driving me crazy.
I am frozen through.
Warm me up, I'm freezing.
Take me upstairs and fuck me.
I should be heading back to town.
- We just got here.
I know, but it's broad daylight.
Relax. It's a done deal.
I'm getting the cheque on Monday.
What's wrong with you?
I got a letter today.
- From who?
Whom, from whom. From Dr. Kessler.
- What did he say?
He didn't say, Tracy. It was a letter.
He wrote.
Jed, take a drink, take a pill, do whatever it is
you have to, but lighten the fuck up.
What did he write?
That he was sorry.
That he was very sorry.
That was thoughtful of him.
What?
That was. The man put himself at the top.
I was in the room. The bartender was just icing. .
... but Kessler's  was the one who closed it.
Common, what more do you want from the man?
- I want him to know it.
I want him to know that I was holding the strings.
He's sorry? Let him say he was sorry
about Mass General.
When he says he was wrong, when he
says that I should have gotten the job then...
... you talk about bygones being bygones.
In the meantime, I think I'll send him a postcard.
- There, that's the spirit.
A picture of me sitting under a
palm tree with 10 million dollars in one hand...
... and a copy of his 'God-complex'
memo in the other.
With an inscription.
- What would it say?
It wouldn't say anything. It would read.
- Good going, Trace.
What would it read?
Never under-estimate a genius with
a 'chip on your shoulder'.
What the fuck was that?
Oh my God.
Where did that come from?
Andy.
- What?
Andy's been here.
- What are you talking about?
He knows.
- Then why aren't the police knocking on the door?
Because he's playing with us.
- Andy?
I don't believe it.
- Believe it.
How could he possibly...
- Well, let's think about that for a moment, shall we?.
What could we have done wrong?
Let's retrace the plan...
... and see if we can put our finger on a detail we
may have overlooked. One of us may have improvised.
One of us may have decided that to get
pregnant would double the money.
It did double the money. Now I don't want
to hear about it anymore. It is history.
Oh, no. . no. No kidding.
It's the present. It's the here and the now
and the needle in the haystack.
Let me ask you something.
Once he found out he was sterile,
how long do you think it took him...
... to figure out there was no Dr. Lillianfield?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
There wasn't supposed to be a baby.
I'll take care of Andy.
Don't get up.
What happened to your face?
I tripped.
I heard they caught the guy, the rapist.
- Yeah.
Well, that must be a load off your mind.
Yeah, it's great to finally have
things back to normal.
Andy...
They can be back to normal.
What's that?
Things.
Our life.
Remember me?
Tracy.
- What?
I think you dropped your shoe.
What can I get you?
- We'll have two glasses of house wine.
Is Chardonnay alright?
- It'll be fine.
Anything else?
- Some privacy.
Now I'm going to talk for a minute,
So it would be better if you don't interrupt me, okay?
I found a hypodermic needle in my bed.
I don't know who put it there,
it doesn't matter.
What matters, is that I didn't think it was funny.
And as you well know,
I've a healthy sense of humour.
So what I'm saying is this:
Whoever played that joke is playing in a league
that's just not ready for it.
Now I came here hoping we
could reach an understanding.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to hold grudge on this one, Trace.
- Oh, go to cops. They'll call you crazy.
While still we have another school, why don't you
try getting a teaching job? 'Happy Hunting', Andy.
Sit the fuck down.
- What?
I said, sit the fuck down.
I'm running the show now.
You're running it with an empty hypodermic needle?
I'm running it with trace amounts of Pergonal.
Here it is.
Mam, would you happen to know anything
about a drug called Pergonal?
I'm sorry.
Never mind.
That's alright.
It's a fertility drug, Andy.
I was trying to get pregnant.
A fertility drug.
That's exactly what the lab guys told me.
But it turns out that Pergonal,
when it's injected in like massive quantities... .
... can actually create ovarian cysts.
They gathered brilliant young surgeon around
Trace, coz you gave us all quite a scare.
It dissolved in the ovaries, so
you don't have clue how much I was taking.
That's right.
It's not like I had a witness.
I mean if I had a witness who saw
Jed giving you the injections...
... you bought, both of you would be spending
the rest of your sexually active years... .
... in a place where you'll work very good
such as prison laundry.
You're bluffing.
Tracy...
Right now, other than anything else in the world...
... don't you wish I had finally gotten
around putting up the curtains in the bedroom?
Shit!
Are you alright?
You should rinse your hands with some water.
- No, I'm fine.
Are you sure? Let me just...
- I said I'm fine.
You spilled your wine, Trace.
By the by, you should know in case some
bizarre active 'God' should happen to take my life...
... my will's been amended to direct the police
to the 10-year old son of our next door neighbour.
What do you want?
What does anybody want?
I want the Red Sox to win the World Series.
You haven't taken the kid to the police.
What do you want?
I had a chat with your mom.
Not bad looking for somebody who's
been dead for twelve years.
What do you want, Andy?
- I want to change my life, Tracy.
I don't think I'm overstating when I say
that she knows some pretty cold card tricks.
Cut the shit. What do you want?
I want half.
What the fuck do you think I want?
Give him the money.
What?
Give the man the money,
and let's get out of here.
Oh Jesus, Jed. . I need you to focus on this thing.
I'm telling you precisely what to do. Give the guy
the 10 bucks and we leave the country.
I'm supposed to split the money three ways?
I'm supposed to just accept this?
Welcome to the land where you
don't have a choice.
Don't fucking turn on me.
I earned this money.
This money is mine. He's not getting
a nickel. The cheque's in my name.
Not in the prison, I doubt.
Without the kid, he doesn't have anything.
Without the kid, Andy is just a guy
who cracked under the strain.
What?
Absolutely.
Do you know what you're saying?
- What's the big deal Jed?
You cut me open, stuck your hands
and twisted my ovaries so that I look all that dead.
Oh, excuse me, 'necrotic'. Now you develop
some enlightened sense of what's right and wrong?
He's a child.
No, he's a little fucking troll who deserves
to be put out of his misery...
... for fucking up my life.
Now if you don't have the balls to...
Don't talk about this again.
Anything happens to the kid and I'm
the State's star witness.
Give the man the money.
I'm sorry I hit you.
Put it down.
Which blood did you let
me lose before you saved me?
You waited an extra minute or two, didn't you?
You thought about going the other
way after you saw I was pregnant.
You thought for a second about
letting me die, didn't you?
I'm a doctor.
- You were a doctor.
Don't overestimate yourself, Tracy.
Give me the gun.
Come on.
It's me. I have the money.
Where are you?
- At Market Square.
Meet me in the northwest corner
in fifteen minutes.
Like shooting tuna in a barrel, huh?
I won't mind shooting you.
What took you so long?
We were waiting for Jed.
- Somehow, I don't think he's going to show.
Don't move. You need a doctor.
You hear that Trace?
We need a doctor.
You okay?
- I will be.
You're supposed to put ice on that.
- I don't want any ice.
You need ice.
Fine.
I'll have mine in a glass of some scotch.
Single malt. Nothing blended.
Blended whisky is crap.
Somebody told me that once.
Ripped & Sync by:
Etcohod