Someone from
Senator Eleanor Shaw's office called
and intervened on your behalf.
Major, you've reached the terminal end
of the Army's patience.
You're relieved of duty,
effective immediately.
Yes, sir.
Ben,
there is a young neurologist
at Walter Reed. His name is Zahn.
He's had real success
with Gulf War Syndrome.
You are instructed to get
your affairs in order
and report to him
first thing Monday morning.
I thought you said you lost it.
I bit a guy. I found another one.
These are not supposed to exist.
These are only theoretical.
So, what does it do?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
I don't know.
I don't wanna know.
You don't wanna know.
Look, it's out of you
and you are still alive.
That's the good news.
What's the bad news?
Maybe they know you're here.
You said the Army implants,
they were for
emergency medical data, right?
The ones they publicized were.
There was a parallel project
for all kinds of scary implantables.
The Clinton watchdogs finally
freaked out about it, closed down.
Parallel project?
How did you know about that?
Manchurian Global funded me
to make some of their scary shit.
Heard of them?
Lmagine not just
a corporation, Marco,
but a goddamn geopolitical
extension of policy
for every president since Nixon.
Cash is king, Marco.
Cash is king.
You sure you wanna do this?
Absolutely.
Because I don't.
I'll owe you one.
No.
I still owe you.
For getting me out of Albania.
Albania.
What are you doing?
In case I forget things
I wanna remember.
I'm putting you on a cocktail
of methohexitol to take the edge off.
The edge off of what?
Getting clarity.
Or whatever you wanna call it.
ECT not being
the precise science that, say,
leeching is.
You don't think
this is gonna work?
It's a desperation move, man.
But, hey, there is a school
of thought that says
a victim of induced abreaction...
Here it comes.
The night is clear.
Stars, but no moon.
The patrol is ambushed.
We were on a routine recon
inside Iraqi-controlled terrain,
assessing troop strength...
Captain Marco was
knocked unconscious.
In the ensuing firefight, Eddie Ingram
gets himself separated to the left.
Baker goes after him.
Hello, captain.
Before Sergeant Shaw
is able to locate...
Eddie Ingram gets himself
separated to the left.
Did you go blank on me again?
He said this would happen.
Who?
Your German friend.
Your friend.
Ben.
He said it'd be like
a computer system crash.
That your brain would shut down,
but it would reboot again
and you'd forget all your RAM.
Or most of your RAM.
Do you remember me?
Ben?
Eugenie.
How did I get here?
You called me.
Where am I?
- Planning a suicide bombing.
The Mile High City has suffered
a series of brutal attacks
during the past several months.
Senator Eleanor Prentiss Shaw,
does it bother you at all
that your son repudiates
so many of your more
- controversial policies?
- No. He's his own person.
Raymond and I may disagree
on certain issues,
but I think we share
the same fundamental vision
of what this country can be.
- Which is?
- Better.
Better and better.
Safer, braver, stronger.
A beacon of freedom
in a world troubled by shadows.
America must prevail.
The future and survival
of modern civilization,
democracy, freedom,
all depend upon it.
So your son, Congressman Shaw...
Rosie.
I was in the park on Friday?
We were in the park on Monday.
Monday?
- Yep.
- Monday.
We were flying low.
It's, like, over the ocean, and just...
A field hospital.
And they took us up to this place.
- Where? Military?
- I don't know. I don't know.
Just state-of-the-art stuff everywhere.
Stainless steel and wires
and tubes and monitors.
- Were you tortured?
- No. Yeah.
I mean, there was pain.
You know, it was like...
I don't know what they call it.
Invasive procedure.
For example?
Like what? What do you mean?
Invasive.
See, they were in my head...
...and they made me...
Well, Raymond Shaw,
they made him kill somebody.
Like it was nothing.
Private Robert Baker.
That's who it was, it was a private.
One of my soldiers.
I think they made me
kill somebody too.
A kid named Eddie Ingram.
Private Ingram, stand up.
Walk a few steps, please.
And if you could secure the door,
please, Chris.
Captain Marco.
Stand up.
- Raymond.
- Yes, sir.
There's a gun on the cupboard.
Would you please take it
and give it to Captain Marco.
Yes, sir.
Here.
Captain.
Captain Marco,
please shoot Private Ingram.
Now, Raymond,
suffocate Private Baker.
Kill him.
Keep going, Raymond.
I knew the...
A soldier knows the enemy.
I'm in command.
That's primary, I know.
I thought I knew...
...who the enemy was.
My men, they trusted me
with their lives, you know?
Don't.
Don't touch me.
Ben, the person that did this,
what was his name?
Can you remember?
Did he have a name?
Ben?
Smile if you like.
This will just take a minute.
I see you there all the time.
Bennett Marco.
Checks from First National Bank.
Romance novels, instant noodles,
NoDoz and tomatoes.
Old friend up there,
an old Army friend that...
Well, he's in politics now...
What else did we talk about?
What happened to you
after you were captured?
Black helicopters,
secret laboratories...
...mad scientist, mind drugs...
...shock torture
and Raymond Shaw.
- You don't believe any of it, do you?
- It's crazy.
- It sounds crazy, doesn't it?
- It sounds crazy.
That's what they wanted
me to think too.
It's exactly what they want
you to think.
What about the other guys
from your unit?
Where are they?
They're all gone.
So-called natural causes.
Owens died of cancer in '97.
Villalobos' car crashed.
Atkins committed suicide.
Jameson died 9/11, Pentagon.
- Ben?
- Yeah?
- Did he have a name?
- Who?
The person that did this, Ben.
What was his name?
Can you remember?
Ben.
- Yeah?
- Did he have a name?
You only have to look
at the enormous strides made
in the last decade
with the genetic reconfiguration
of the noble tomato.
What was happening was the tomato
was over-ripening in the process
and it was losing its flavor.
It's actually a very simple procedure
to deactivate the gene concerned.
And the same thing
can be applied to ourselves.
At a flick of a switch,
we can adjust character,
change personality.
And of course, more importantly...
...we can offset
the ravages of dementia
by implanting memory or adjusting
the synaptic connections.
We can free people
from the terrible burden
of an emotionally
compromised past.
- Watch where you're going!
- Sorry.
Watch where you're going!
Just back up! Just back up.
Watch it. Watch it. Shut up.
Take it easy, sir.
I called the Pentagon and they told me
he's on medical leave.
Secret Service, they got him on a
couple of their watch and observe lists.
I guess there's been some trouble
with this guy
involving Congressman Shaw.
Oh?
Among the shareholders
in Manchurian Global,
were they to ever publish a list,
which they won't,
you would find former presidents,
deposed kings,
trust fund terrorists,
fallen Communist dictators,
ayatollahs, African warlords
and retired prime ministers.
- See what I mean?
- I get it. They're big. They're huge.
They're... They're...
They're gigantic.
I can't touch them. I get it.
I don't want to.
And you bring me rumors
and conjecture.
I started with nightmares.
Rumors, conjectures,
that's a giant leap forward.
Nightmares that you've interpreted
using as primary resources
A, your spotty memory,
B, the Internet,
sacred sanctuary of idiots and nutters.
That's how they're gonna look at this.
And C, a crazy man's notebook,
along with evidence you chewed
out of a man's back.
All neatly stitched together
with a common thread
of a supremely powerful,
well-connected private equity fund,
who, if you ever get
anywhere near them,
will plead ignorance
and be shocked.
Shocked to learn
what some of their subsidiary
partners are engaged in.
I could give a rat's ass
about Manchurian Global, sir.
I could give a rat's ass about them.
That is not why I'm here.
I looked you up too, senator.
Oh?
You were in the Army.
I was drafted.
Didn't make much of a soldier,
I'm afraid. Let me see this.
That's not what I saw in the record.
That's not what the record says, sir.
And you know how it works.
Wars are fought
one battle at a time.
Battles, you win one bullet at a time.
And I'd be lying to you if I said
that I didn't factor in,
in a huge way,
the fact that you have
a vested, personal,
political and patriotic interest
in how all of this shakes out.
I'd be lying to you.
You're right, major.
I do.
A $5,000-a-plate dinner honoring
the CEO of Votron Incorporated,
the nation's third-largest producer of
the controversial touch-screen units
that will be used in the forthcoming
election, was disrupted last night,
when protestors disguised as
waiters and kitchen staff
unleashed a blizzard
of symbolic chants from above,
resulting in a momentary panic.
The supporters of presidential hopeful
Vice President Edward Nelson
fled to exits and dove under tables.
Security personnel quickly subdued
the protestors, one of whom...
The man is insane, Tom.
Full-blown schizophrenia.
He's been stalking Raymond,
the FBI is all over this already.
I've seen the files.
- Have you seen them?
- All over what?
Your bipolar war buddy
has been sharing his dreams
with Senator Jordan.
Hello, Raymond.
Hello, senator.
How's Jocelyn?
Have you fact-checked this
with anyone, Tom?
Raymond.
Do you recognize this man?
No.
His name is Atticus Noyle.
He's a South African scientist
and mercenary.
Someone our CIA turned to
for covert mind warfare
against the Soviets in Afghanistan.
Someone who has sold
his technology and services
to terrorists and rogue states.
And what does he
have to do with me?
Major Bennett Marco
claims that this man...
...brainwashed you.
In his dreams.
Contrived to have you win
the Medal of Honor.
And has you poised to be the first
privately owned and operated
vice president of the United States.
Sir, I've already spoken
with Ben Marco.
Unfortunately, he's not a well man.
He's delusional.
Nevertheless,
he's pulled from his mad hat
some remarkably lucid connections
between his dreams
of your exploits in Kuwait
and this Dr. Noyle
and the private equity fund
Manchurian Global,
your mother's primary political
benefactor for the past 15 years.
Oh, come on, Tom.
They contribute to half the Senate.
Both sides of the aisle.
What are you saying?
At the time of Desert Storm,
Dr. Atticus Noyle
was working under a research grant
from Manchurian Global,
developing deep implant
behavior modification.
Oh, my God.
Rogue scientists, mind control,
Manchurian Global.
- You.
- Tom.
Connect the dots, Raymond.
Where was your famous
Lost Patrol
for those three missing days?
Eluding capture in the desert?
Or somewhere else,
being microwaved
by this Atticus Noyle?
- Oh, Tom.
- I'm sorry, senator,
but what exactly
are you suggesting I do?
Bow out gracefully.
Personal reasons,
an obscure illness.
Yield your spot on the ticket
and go into seclusion.
Oh, that's what this is about.
And then surrender yourself
to federal authorities.
Help them trace this thing
to its source
and address whatever damage
may have been done to you.
And I'll be waiting
for your press announcement
first thing in the morning.
- And then we'll talk.
- Tom.
If there's any inkling of truth
in any of these charges,
if anyone has ever harmed
a hair on his head,
I will find out about it.
You have 12 hours, senator.
But if it's not true,
I will see you impeached
on the floor of the Senate
and bury you.
Good night.
It's preposterous.
Idiotic story.
Mother, there's something
I have to tell you.
What?
I've been having the dreams.
Ben said there were tests
they could run to see if...
No. Where are you going?
Sergeant Shaw.
What?
Sergeant Raymond Shaw.
Mother, I...
Raymond Prentiss Shaw.
Yes.
Listen.
Good morning to you all,
and welcome to Amtrak's
northbound Acela,
making station stops
at Baltimore, Philadelphia,
Newark, New York's
Penn Station
and Boston as the last stop...
Who's that?
It's Raymond, sir.
Oh, don't do that.
You're gonna get
soaking wet, Raymond.
Raymond.
I came to apologize, sir.
Raymond, what are you doing?
- I'm sorry.
- We'll get some help for you, son.
It's not your fault, Raymond.
It's not your fault.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- It's your mother...
Dad!
Help!
Oh, God. Daddy!
Raymond? What are you doing?!
What is going on?
What is happening?
Where's my father?
What are you doing?
Dad! Dad!
The five-term senator
and recent front-runner for his party's
vice presidential nomination
appears to have
accidentally drowned
when his kayak overturned near
his Chesapeake Bay weekend home.
Police say his daughter,
35-year-old Jocelyn,
may have been trying
to rescue Jordan
when she was herself overcome
by the icy water.
The bodies of Senator Jordan
and his daughter
were discovered this morning
by a crab fisherman
who spotted the capsized kayak
floating far offshore,
nearly a mile from
Senator Jordan's residence.
Neighbors say the senator was an
expert kayaker whose morning trips
were a familiar sight along
the western bank of the Bay.
Governor Arthur, do you have
any comment on this tragic event?
Senator Jordan was a statesman
of the highest integrity.
Tom Jordan was a friend.
A damn fine man.
Just a great American.
That's all for now. We'll have
something for you a little later.
They're the latest target of SEC
corruption probes,
but private equity fund
Manchurian Global confirmed today
it is continuing with plans to
finance privately owned combat units
to relieve beleaguered
U.S. Troop deployments worldwide.
It is a move that could save the
Defense Department billions of dollars.
How does Arthur die?
You know who I'm talking about,
the new president.
If he dies, Raymond Shaw becomes
the new president, doesn't he?
Chain of succession.
That's what you got in mind.
That's what you people wanna do.
You wanna really run the world,
don't you, Susie? Rosie?
Whatever the hell your name is. I got
my library card and I got your tapes.
I do my research too.
We're going to the feds,
we're going to the police,
the newspapers, whatever it takes.
I am the feds.
Now, get off me!
Get off of me!
We found...
...an implant device...
...in Al Melvin.
You found one in Melvin.
Just like you said.
I'm part of a shadow unit.
We've been watching you.
Trying to sort this thing out.
This isn't an election, this is a coup.
This is... In our own country,
a regime change, in our own country.
Ben, don't. Ben.
This is rich people, Manchurian Global
funding bad science
to put a sleeper in the White House,
and that's what's going on, Rosie.
- That's what's going on.
- I wanna believe you.
Well, then, believe me.
Help me. Help me.
Shoot me, then.
Help me or shoot me.
Make a decision.
I made a decision
when I met you, Ben.
Now, why don't you show me
what you have in your file.
- Sir!
- Congressman!
Sir, do you have a statement
for us tonight?
- Was exceptionally clear
and simple.
A stronger, safer,
more profitable world
through uncorruptible
top-level management.
We trust you with our technology
and suddenly you turn him
into a common hit man.
How fucking dare you.
I trusted you with my son.
You didn't even ask us...
Don't lecture me! You swore to me
that this was fail-safe.
No leaks, no glitches, no...
No dreams.
Not even a shadow of what was done
to Raymond...
You needed to ask before you acted.
This is not a...
Tom Jordan was going to destroy
my son and everything I've worked for,
and every one of us along with it.
And you wanted me to what?
- Call a meeting?
- Now, look, look, look.
In the larger course of history...
...there are key players...
...and role players, senator.
Bullshit! This is about my son
and the future of this country.
I thought we understood each other.
I think we do. I think we really do.
- Your god is money.
- Oh, wait, wait, and yours is...?
No, no. I'm a believer.
I am an optimist.
I believe in the future.
And people who do,
the ones who make history
instead of just sitting around
watching it,
no, they're willing to take
the big risks.
Yes, I made a decision.
Oh, God! Where are
all the men anymore?
My father, Tyler Prentiss,
never asked,
"Is this okay? Is this okay?"
You know what I'm saying, Mark?
He just did what needed to be done.
Come on, rise and shine, New York.
It's a big day in the Big Apple.
That's right. All polls indicate
that New Yorkers will be turning out
in record numbers today
across the five boroughs
to select a new president.
At least, that's how the billboard
says it's supposed to happen.
The polls open at 6 a.m.
And bars and taverns in Manhattan,
Brooklyn, Queens, the Bronx,
and Staten Island will be
opening shortly thereafter.
That's right, New Yorkers. We are
free to drink and vote all day today.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thanks for coming out.
Congressman, good luck.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Hey. Thank you very much.
- The next vice president, sir.
I hope so.
- Let's have a win.
- We're with you. We're with you.
Thank you, Tony, take care.
Thank you.
Take care. Goodbye.
Thanks very much.
It's clean.
It's all right, Evan.
How's your back?
I've been having the dreams, Ben.
Oh, that's good.
They're inside my head.
We'll get them out. I got the proof.
I know what they did to us.
I just don't know why.
I dream things, Ben.
Terrible things that can't
possibly have happened.
- I'm gone, Ben...
- No, you're not, you're right here.
Ben...
...there's something I want
you to have.
I don't deserve this.
Jocelyn's dead.
I know.
And the senator.
Yeah.
Did I...?
I think so, Raymond, yes.
I don't remember, Ben.
I don't remember.
Raymond...
...did they tell you what it is
they want you to do?
That's what I gotta find out.
We gotta find out what's gonna
happen, where it's gonna happen...
Are we friends, Ben?
I wanna believe we were friends.
We are connected and that's
something nobody can take from us.
You could've had me locked up,
but you didn't.
That's proof that there's something
deep inside.
There's a part that they can't get to.
And it's deep inside of us.
And that's where the truth is.
That's our only hope. That's what
you and me need to tap into,
and that's what you and I are gonna
use to take them out, Raymond.
We don't have much time. Please.
- I thought you were smarter than that.
- Raymond, please.
You don't think they saw this
coming, Ben?
You don't think they factored you in?
I am the enemy, Major Marco.
What are you talking about?
Yes, Mother.
Yes, he's right here.
- She wants you.
- Me?
Yes, senator.
- Is this Captain Marco?
- Yeah.
Captain Bennett Marco?
Yes.
Bennett Ezekiel Marco.
Listen.
Hurry up!
Major Marco?
Ben?
- People can get together whenever
they want and not get in trouble.
People should be allowed to say
what is on their mind...
The Bill of Rights gives people...
Thank you.
The candidates made ritual trips
to the voting booths today.
Governor Arthur,
casting his ballot in North Platte,
will spend election night in the Big Apple
with running mate Raymond Shaw
for their anticipated victory party.
The presidential rival,
incumbent Vice President Nelson
returned to his home
in Baton Rouge, Louisiana.
He attended special church services
this morning...
- All clear.
- Raymond...
- Clear.
...listen.
The bullet will strike Bob Arthur
the moment you step forward
and arrive on your star beside him.
Because the assassin...
...the deranged, obsessed...
...tragically paranoid lone gunman...
...is trying to kill you.
Major Marco's
an excellent marksman.
But you must stay very, very still
and stand right where you're
supposed to stand.
What happens to Ben?
The assassin always dies, baby.
It's necessary for
the national healing.
I'm sure you will never entirely
comprehend this, darling.
But I want you to know, Raymond...
...I did this for you.
So that you could have
what I couldn't.
What your father threw away.
The opportunity to lead this nation.
- I know, Mother.
- And so I let them take you
and change you a little bit.
Not so much that you would notice,
but just enough to bring you back
to who you really are.
And to what you will become.
Oh, and look at you.
Look at you.
Look what you've achieved,
look how far we've come.
It's working, Raymond.
And you're going to save
our country now.
In the hour of her greatest need.
Yes, Mother.
But...
But when you smile...
...oh, darling, when you smile,
that's what I live for.
When you smile.
Well, it's official.
CBS News now projects
Robert Arthur and Raymond Shaw
to be the next president
and vice president
of the United States.
With at least 270 electoral votes
and support of almost 70 percent
of votes tallied tonight.
Arthur and running mate
Raymond Shaw are leading
in all but one remaining race,
in the sitting vice president's
home state of Louisiana.
Wait, Jimmy. Jimmy, wait.
Wait. Go back.
Can you go back?
Yeah.
- Stop.
- Sure.
Now, can you zoom in on that guy?
Yep.
No, no, Jimmy, the other one. The one
in the back. The one in the shades.
- This one?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Never mind. Thanks, Jimmy.
Arthur! That's right!
Arthur! Arthur!
- We did it. Wow.
- Yeah!
All right! Yes!
- Yes.
- Hi.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Let's have a good show, people.
Let's have a really good show, okay?
Arthur! Arthur! Arthur! Arthur!
Cue screens.
Very good.
Stand by with the first music cue.
Now, music.
Okay.
Damn it.
Shaw missed his first position.
AOP! AOP!
Up there!
Ben!
All right. Bye.
The FBI has just released
security footage
of the assassin of Raymond
and Eleanor Prentiss Shaw
entering the hotel two hours
before the fatal shooting.
Authorities have identified
the gunman as Klaus Bachmann.
Bachmann was believed to have been
killed in a car bomb explosion
in Chechnya four years ago.
He was employed there as a
covert operation specialist
by Global Endeavors,
a U.K. Subsidiary of the equity fund
giant Manchurian Global.
A second former Manchurian Global
civilian contractor
was taken into custody
by federal agents
at Chicago's O'Hare Airport
early this morning.
Laurence Tokar made news
during the Gulf War
for his presence on Raymond Shaw's
famed Lost Patrol.
Tokar was missing in action after
the ambush that resulted in Shaw
being awarded the
Congressional Medal of Honor.
Authorities are exploring additional
connections between the two men.
Still reeling from the recent tragic loss
of Senator Thomas Jordan,
Congress has already announced
a far-reaching investigation
into Jordan's death,
in an effort to learn if it is in any way
related to the Shaw assassinations.
In a supercharged encounter
moments ago, president-elect Arthur...
I remember running.
I had to...
...get out...
...to where the sky was. And had to...
...get to the water.
Escape. Regroup.
Come back, get my men.
I thought that if I could just
get to the water...
...everything would be okay.
If I could just get to the water.
Now, when you're rescued
and returned with your patrol
to command headquarters,
what will be among the first
of your duties that you'll undertake?
I'll recommend Sergeant Shaw
for the Medal of Honor, sir.
He saved our lives.
He terminated the enemy.
Led us across the desert to safety.
Excellent. And there were casualties?
There's always casualties in war, sir.
Text Ripp & Fix
Killbear666