APPLAUSE
Gustave, that went quite well.
- I'm overwhelmed.
- Of course.
That old song brings back
so many memories.
But you were wonderful.
Thank you.
And now, Number 8.
And isn't she pretty?
Now, what's your name?
Emilie.
Show our friends how pretty you are.
She's so moved,
even a bit scared.
But don't be.
Our friends are so kind.
Now, what have you chosen?
- “White Hands''.
- A pretty song.
A shame it's been forgotten.
Move up to the microphone.
A wonderful choice.
I leave you now with Emilie
and her “White Hands."
Colette.
I'm awful there,
with that charming Emilie.
It's like I wanted
to look down at my watch.
I don't think so, sir.
It was a very sweet
and charming moment.
In fact, I think l did want
to look at my watch.
That would surprise me.
Mr. Wolf has arrived.
Mr. Wolf? Let him in, then.
This way, please.
Mr. Legagneur will see you now.
- Roland Wolf.
- Christian Legagneur.
Colette, Mr. Wolf is doing me
the honor of writing my biography.
On the contrary, sir.
You're giving me the pleasure.
Call me Christian
or we won't get anywhere.
He also writes detective novels.
Under what name, was it?
Well, Roland Wolf.
Of course. It all gets so confused
in my poor head.
I guess you won't be back
this week?
You bet.
My head's about to explode.
- And Wednesdays show?
- I'm sure you'll manage.
And if I need to contact you?
Call Colette at the number
I gave you.
Well, then, try to relax.
And you, try to work hard.
Tell me...
I was thinking.
I'm sure you were.
For your book,
the sooner, the better.
Definitely.
How long do you need
to operate on me?
Twenty hours, I'm afraid.
Here's what I propose:
The show is off this week
due to the soccer championship.
I'll take you to my house
in the country.
We'll be in paradise.
No phone calls, no pests.
Do you like the country?
I prefer traveling,
but the country's okay.
You can bring along
your girlfriend.
- I don't have one at the moment.
- What more could the people want?
How about a drink then?
I must say, I'd hoped
for something like this.
I thought so.
You could've put your bag
in the trunk.
I thought it was full.
Is that true, Max?
By the way, Max is mute.
A serious illness.
A sort of tongue cancer
with metastases in the ear.
But they stopped it in time,
right, Max?
Here we are. And welcome.
Max, show Mr. Wolf to his room.
See you in a few minutes.
What is all this crap?
I tell you, getting
the Clos Vougeot was no picnic.
Madeleine.
My dear Roland,
take a seat there, next to Patricia.
- Roland Wolf.
- Patricia Marquet.
Watch out.
She's got a strong grip.
She's a masseuse, and a good one.
An in-house masseuse.
What a luxury.
- Good to have someone new beside me.
- She reads cards as well.
- Only for those I'm fond of.
- You've never read them for me.
Cut the nonsense
and pour us some wine.
My husband, Manuel Marquet.
Yes, Manu. Pour us some wine.
He's an expert in the red stuff.
I ordered Clos Vougeot and Moults.
Do you want some Savigny too?
You know you have carte blanche here.
- You're in charge of the cellar?
- Christian was kind enough -
I'm not kind.
I just rely on experts.
- Good.
- Good?
Very good.
Full-bodied, rich color,
lingering taste.
Keep it under control.
I must say it's excellent.
It's quite good.
Terrine of pheasant.
I hope you like game.
- The season's open?
- One of Max's little secrets.
Best not to dig any deeper.
How do you like his chef's hat?
Isn't he handsome?
He loves wearing many hats.
Right, Max?
And Colette,
the best secretary I've ever had,
puts on her little apron
and serves at the table.
You seem surprised,
my dear Wolf.
- It's quite unusual.
- Indeed.
That's why they do it -
for the fun of it.
- Right, Colette?
- Absolutely, sir.
It's very amusing
to live several lives at once.
Here you are, darling.
I'm late.
Catherine, my godchild.
Allow me to introduce Roland Wolf.
He's the one writing the book
I told you about.
Hello, miss.
Forgive me for being late, sir.
- Please don't mention it.
- Help yourself.
You eat like a bird.
Be a good girl.
There.
- I put in the tablets.
- Very good.
Drink it while you eat.
- Is the medicine unpleasant?
- It's all right.
No point in restraining
your curiosity, Mr. Wolf.
My goddaughter's been ill
for several months.
All because of a blasted quack
who came to cure her
of simple food poisoning
and gave her such
a bizarre prescription
that she was left paralyzed
for several days.
Not paralyzed.
You couldn't use your legs, pet.
But things are going better,
thanks to a gentle
yet effective treatment
that Patricia helped me to perfect.
Using only herbs.
Unfortunately,
her eyes are still sensitive.
You know what?
I'll close the drapes.
I think my goose is cooked.
You're very good.
You're good too,
but your goose is indeed cooked.
No one's as good as you.
Don't smother me with compliments.
And put down that knitting.
Don't worry.
I'm hardly even aware of it.
You look tired, little girl.
I'm sleepy as well.
We're all sleepy.
One thing:
There are no hangers in my room.
Max will straighten that out.
Oh, that idiot has gone to bed.
You look after it.
You know where the hangers are.
I'll bring the hangers
to your room, sir.
Are these enough?
Oh, yes. I'm very neat,
but I don't have many clothes.
Well, then, good night.
Why did you do that?
Because I love you.
I love your eyes.
Kiss me...
and look right at me.
Don't say anything to my godfather.
He trusts me so much.
He's so afraid for me.
He's so kind.
Ah, my friend!
You slept well?
- Quite well.
- Sit down.
You're an early riser.
I like that.
It depends on the day.
Are you a tea or coffee person?
I take tea.
Tea then.
Would you like eggs or something?
- No, I'll just have some toast.
- Help yourself.
What would you say
to a half hour of jogging?
Frankly, it's not my cup of tea.
We'll get along just fine.
But you're wrong.
It feels great.
You get rid of all the filth inside.
It's almost a metaphysical exercise.
Yeah?
I must say I find it quite boring.
I'm more of a tennis person.
You're a snob.
But I'll put you to the test.
Here's what I propose:
May I speak informally with you?
I can't work any other way.
We'll work for a couple hours.
Then Max will take me to Paris
for a business lunch.
I'll look after some things
for next week's show.
And when I get back,
we'll play a set or two.
- Two hours isn't very long.
- We'll work more tomorrow.
Come on, let's get a move on.
From the start:
My father was a pharmacist.
He died when I was 12.
My mother was unable to work.
She'd never given it a thought.
She looked after the estate
as best she could,
which was not very well.
It was depleted very quickly.
How unpleasant it is
to slowly become poor,
to sink quietly into poverty.
But in the end, I found that people
were generally quite kind.
That's surprising.
Normally, people say the opposite.
If you lack the strength to fight,
others can't do a thing for you.
Very enlightening.
I'm not an intellectual, you know.
With me,
it's all about emotion.
I chose this career-
or it chose me, I don't know -
because I like people,
no matter who they are.
When they come on stage
with their timid looks,
their little bouquets,
their thin voices...
it wells up in me.
I almost feel like crying.
Sounds silly, right?
You'll write some nice line
about the strong protecting the weak.
I think I can manage that.
What's wrong, Frangois?
The poor old girl.
She was wearing a sort of
violet perfume. It was horrible.
It reeked like an Outhouse.
You're quite the actor, aren't you?
Why?
She was charming.
The fact is, I have allergies.
And not just to violets,
but to dust, mosquitoes, feathers.
Feathers are the worst.
Aren't allergies rather psychosomatic?
That's what they say.
But they also say the opposite.
Be careful about
the mosquitoes here.
Did you get bitten last night?
Last night? No.
Because mosquitoes are dreadful.
Mosquitoes come from
the same era as the diplodocus.
The diplodocus disappeared,
but the mosquito survived.
- A beautiful metaphor.
- I love metaphors.
They're the most subtle and powerful way
of expressing complex ideas.
That is, if you can decipher them -
if they are decipherable.
That's the problem.
Otherwise, they're just images, which is already not half bad.
You're here, darling.
We didn't hear you.
You crept in like a little mouse.
- A little mosquito.
- I didn't mean to intrude.
Did you sleep well?
I've been up for a while.
What's this?
I made it.
It's baked clay.
Baked? Where?
In the kitchen.
In the oven.
You could've burned yourself.
You need a special oven
that has safety devices.
That's crazy.
You worked so hard on it.
So what? You weren't happy with it.
But I was, Catherine.
The poor child.
I do everything I can
to help her recover.
She gets better for a few days,
then without warning she has a relapse.
I think it was just nerves.
She has no reason to be nervous!
I treat her like a daughter.
Her parents died when she was five
in a tragic car accident.
We can't even glue it back together.
They were my best friends.
They were killed instantly.
Since she had no family,
and I was her godfather,
I took her in.
Then I grew fond of her.
The love of children, you know.
It's crazy.
It eats you alive.
They're the real ogres.
Could you ring for Colette?
It's near the chimney.
Thanks.
She's like a daughter to me,
and she worries me.
I don't really know what to do.
- Why don't you call a doctor?
- No.
They're the ones
who put her in this state.
Colette, could you take this away?
Catherine made it
and then smashed it.
The poor girl.
I saw her run crying to her room.
Look after her.
Try to console her.
I have to go now.
Where's Max?
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Don't get too bored without me.
- I'll be transcribing.
- And when I get back-
Madeleine.
Rummaging, are we?
Mr. Legagneur challenged me
to a match.
If you accepted, you're crazy.
He'll beat you.
I play well, you know.
At least, not bad.
He beats everybody at every game.
He's a monster.
He didn't beat Madeleine, did he?
You know Madeleine?
Not at all.
He spoke of her to me.
She was a true champion.
But he must have beat her
a couple of times.
And what happened
to little Madeleine?
She left one day,just like that,
without fanfare.
She went to the Seychelles.
She left a note for Christian.
I think he was quite hurt.
But he's so kind,
he made excuses for her.
When'll you do my cards?
Whenever you want.
But I'd rather do
other things for you.
Come now, Patricia.
What are you thinking?
I'm a masseuse, before all else.
Here, my dear Wolf.
I bet you can't guess
the origin of this wine.
I wouldn't even dare.
There's just a little salad after this.
Will that be enough?
Certainly.
Light lunches are healthier.
That's debatable.
Look at you.
As fat as a monk.
Shall I serve you?
Please do.
And the wine, Mr. Wolf?
Excellent. But I couldn't tell you
where it's from.
Of course not.
It's from Australia.
Catherine isn't eating?
No, she's in her room.
Her godfather wants her to rest.
I'll bring her something later.
Mr. Wolf found Madeleine's racquet.
Little Madeleine.
Madeleine's racquet?
Do you know Madeleine?
Not at all. Who's she?
A young girl.
A friend of Catherine's.
Mr. Legagneur invited her here
for his godchild.
She wanted to be an actress.
She left one night
without a word.
She was a bit ﬂighty.
Didn't she have family?
I don't know.
You should ask Mr. Legagneur.
Some salad?
Please.
May I take over Mr. Legagneur's office
this afternoon?
Of course.
That's what we had in mind.
A little silly, right?
You'll write some nice line
about the strong protecting the weak.
I think I can manage that.
You like to play the cynic.
Young people like to be cynical.
But be careful:
In an interview like this, I can learn
as much about you as you do about me.
- Maybe. But I've got nothing to hide.
- Me neither.
And that's what
makes up my strength:
my sentiments, my emotions,
my naiveté even.
I accept all that.
I'm not ﬂattering myself
I'm just happy to be that way.
You're a happy man?
I feel good.
I feel well-balanced.
I'd like everyone around me
to feel the same.
You should jog, Roland.
You'd breathe deeply,
rid yourself of the filth inside.
You know St. Paul's epistles
to Timothy?
Hardly at all.
Actually,
I'm not the church-going type.
Catechism was a nightmare for me.
Even as kids,
we thought it was a bore.
But St. Paul is something else.
He's completely modern.
What he says about
understanding truth, for instance,
is extraordinary.
What I want you to understand,
because it's the key to everything...
COLLECTOR'S EDITION
PLEASE DO NOT CUT PAGES
is that I love my work passionately.
Don't worry I'm not saying
it'; a religion to me.
But frankly, ifs almost that.
I feel so strong.
St. Paul to Timothy.
“Let the woman remain in silence“ -
And they seem so weak to me.
I've taped all my shows.
I'll play one for you,
so you'll understand.
So, did you get some work done?
Yeah, a little.
I worked in your office.
Good move.
It's a comfortable room.
I like it a lot.
Are things starting to take shape?
Yes, things are taking shape.
Excuse me,
but may I have a word with you?
Go ahead, my dear friend.
It's confidential.
Well, then,
let's speak in confidence.
You did well.
Let her sleep.
I'll take care of it tonight.
And our match?
No backing out now.
- Damn it!
-30-40.
I'm going to lose.
But the match isn't even.
I was a real pig at lunch.
I think you're letting me win.
You guessed right.
You owe me another set.
I owe you nothing, but I accept.
I'm worn out.
You must be ranked,
you cagey devil.
You're not so bad yourself.
Oh, come on, I was terrible.
I was using Madeleine's racquet.
Madeleine?
“M.C."
Ah, right.
That's Madeleine's racquet.
I thought she took it with her.
- Who told you about her?
- Patricia.
We came here before lunch.
You're fooling around with her?
Be careful.
- She's a man-eater.
- So it would seem.
And just who is this Madeleine?
One of those girls
who want to get into showbiz.
She followed me around for a month
like a regular groupie.
I thought she'd make
a good friend for Catherine.
She was quite charming.
Pretty, even.
I invited her here for Easter,
and she ended up staying three months.
Shall we go in?
- Did she have no relatives?
- How should I know?
She never mentioned any.
And I never asked.
Why did she leave?
She left an odd note saying
she was going on a trip.
To the Seychelles, Patricia said.
My old-timers win trips there.
She must've dreamed about it, too.
- Catherine didn't say anything?
- She said nothing.
But why are you so interested?
I'm just intrigued
by young people's behavior.
Indeed.
- May I ask you how old you are?
- Twenty-seven.
I'm also intrigued
by young people's behavior.
Did you get him?
I can't stay long.
What did you do all day?
I slept.
Colette told me
he wanted me to sleep.
Were you tired?
I don't know.
My eyes and legs were sore.
I like you.
I wanted to see you,
but I was afraid I'd hurt him.
Fear the image of God.
It's a very common
and dangerous image.
I don't know what you mean.
Did you like Madeleine?
How do you know her?
I don't. I'm just asking.
I hated her.
She was mean and deceitful.
- She paid back good with evil.
- What do you mean?
I don't want to talk about her.
I was glad she left.
I have to go.
Another time.
May l?
Show me your knees.
Have you been
having problems walking?
It depends.
In the evening, sometimes.
Don't be so upset, my pet.
Colette will bring you your medicine.
Don't send me to the hospital.
Havel ever sent you there?
I know you like
that young man very much.
No, don't say a word.
I was young once myself.
I know that the feeling of love
is like a wave that's hard to stop.
But the problem is,
Wolf is just having his fun.
For him, women are just toys.
He takes up with one,
then another.
Toys are easily broken.
Especially by careless people.
Remember Madeleine.
You're not a toy.
I don't want you to get broken.
Is everything all right?
Just fine.
There now.
Sleep tight.
We'll look after you.
They mustn't see each other.
We can stop them during the day,
but at night?
Double her dose.
Why were those tires in my trunk?
It's scrap. Max is going to Aida
day after tomorrow.
Really bright.
You have to lay
your hands on the cards.
So, you've taken over my territory?
Are you going to be long?
I'd like Mr. Wolf and I
to work a bit.
- If you don't mind.
- Not at all.
- We'll continue later, Roland.
- Of course.
You call him by his first name now?
Mr. Wolf asked me to.
He knows how to talk to women,
this guy.
Roland, be kind and pass me a cigar.
There are none left.
Manu's work again, right, Patricia?
There must be some in my drawer.
Now you know
why I keep them locked up.
Will you give me a little massage?
- I'm sore.
- With pleasure.
No, the small gold one.
- Take one, if you want.
- No, thanks. Never in the morning.
I'll go get my recorder.
That feels good.
That's wonderful.
Thank you, dear.
That reminds me of my youth,
when I sang.
We had relaxation sessions
to clear our voices. Sit down.
There was an old Chinese masseur
with extraordinary hands.
- You sang?
- Years ago.
I don't have good memories of it.
But we must be honest, right?
Did you sleep well last night?
Not bad.
A few mosquitoes. And you?
I barricade myself in
with eyeshades and earplugs.
It takes a lot to wake me up.
Why did you stop singing?
Allergies.They're awful.
They destroy your voice
in two weeks. Horrible.
Just the thought of it
and I'm in a cold sweat. After 25 years.
Your singing career
was strangled, if you will.
- What a cruel way to put it.
- Sorry.
- I'd kill my sister for a well-turned phrase.
- How awful!
My dear Patricia,
be kind enough
to leave us to our work.
Your charm can only distract us.
Excuse me.
Isn't she amusing?
Turn that off for a couple minutes,
would you?
You didn't ask about Catherine.
Oh, how is she today?
Still tired.
Colette's looking after her.
Without meaning to,
I think you've upset her a bit.
I've upset her?
She's very fragile.
And she's lonely.
I know she went
to your room last night.
- It was all quite innocent.
-What did she want?
To see someone, I think.
To stretch her legs.
She only stayed two minutes, you know.
I must ask you not to to see her today.
I'm not trying to.
And keep your balcony door shut...
to keep the mosquitoes out.
No problem.
- Shall we begin?
- Of course.
By the way...
yesterday, Catherine spoke to me
about that girl, Madeleine.
What did she say?
She was very odd, really violent.
She told me she hated her.
That may be it.
They were inseparable
for three months.
- What're you doing here?
- They kicked me out.
It seems they're working.
You call that work?
I'm the one who's working here.
You're not complaining, are you?
I'm not. I'm not ungrateful.
But I'd like
that journalist to get lost.
I know.
Something doesn't feel right.
Seems like he's looking
for something.
Something specific.
Like what?
I don't know.
It's too specific.
“Miss Catherine Lecoeur“
“Miss Catherine Lecoeur
and Mr. Christian Legagneur.“
“Legagneur and Lecoeur.
joint account.“
“Deposit, Legagneur.“
“Withdrawal: 75,000 francs.“
“Withdrawal, Legagneur:
90,000 francs.“
“Inheritance from Mr. and Mrs. Lecoeur
to Catherine, minor.“
She's a minor.
“Mr. Christian Legagneur,
one oil painting by Claude Monet.
One oil painting by Monet.
One charcoal sketch
by Claude Monet.“
“Sale of The Blue Mimosas,
a retirement home,
to Mr. Christian Legagneur.“
A retirement home.
The bastard.
“Christian Legagneur,
Capellaci, Max,
and Chapiteau, Colette.“
“Company name:
AIDA Auto Demolition”
I get it now.
You scared me.
Sorry. I wanted some aspirin.
I've got a splitting headache.
Come along.
I'll get you some.
It's Bluebeard's den in here.
His repertory costumes.
Mr. Legagneur collects them.
- How many?
- Two.
A sleeping pill?
No, thanks. I don't take them.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Good night, Mr. Wolf.
Don't make a sound.
- I'm just returning your visit.
- Go away. I'm tired.
- Don't you love me anymore?
- Go away!
- I have something funny to tell you.
- I don't want to hear it. Let me sleep.
I intend to wake you up.
You didn't tell me you were rich.
And I mean “were,“
because you no longer are.
Your dear godfather
has robbed you blind.
Sometimes the truth
can make you dizzy.
He took you under his wing
for your money.
He took your funds
and bought companies in his name,
from a travel agency
to a scrapyard.
Even a retirement home.
A little soft shoe, then he robs them.
I don't believe you.
You have the eyes of a liar.
Let me sleep.
All this before you reach legal age,
of course.
He's been good
and generous all his life.
- You must stop taking that medicine.
- Shut up!
What are you doing here?
She fainted. Call a doctor.
Go and get Mr. Legagneur.
No, I'll go. You stay here.
- What's going on?
- We heard a scream.
It's nothing. Go back to bed.
Was that her screaming?
- Poor thing. Can we help?
- Call a doctor!
- I'll do it.
- No.
I'll have no doctor
in this house.
Sorry, but it was doctors
who put her in this state.
She's much better now,
thanks to Patricia and myself.
I will have no doctors here.
- I was trying to help.
- I know.
But things are more complicated
than you think.
It'll pass. This isn't
the first time, unfortunately.
- She should sniff vinegar.
- It's no use.
She's burning up.
You can all go back to bed.
I'll stay with Wolf.
- You don't mind, do you?
- Not at all.
- Call if you need anything.
- Thank you, my friends.
Catherine, wake up, my child.
My little pet.
How did you get in?
She let out a terrible scream.
I came in,
and she fainted in my arms.
She must've had a nightmare.
There she is.
Go to sleep now.
You can go now, Roland.
Thank you for your help.
Please. It's only natural.
Good night.
Will you sleep now?
And now, my dear friends,
we'll find out which
of our charming finalists
have won a wonderful trip
to Polynesia.
Two weeks in heavenly locations,
first class all the way.
An unforgettable vacation
that I'm so happy
to be able to offer you.
Watch now! The number of points
given to each couple
will now appear
on the board behind me.
Control room,
let's have it.
Couple number one:
56 points.
Couple number two: 54.
Couple number three: 51.
Couple number four: 62.
Couple number five: 55.
And, here we go,
couple number six...
Here we go.
59 points.
So, it's couple number four
who wins the trip to Polynesia.
I'll just ask Rosette and Maurice
to come join me.
This envelope contains your happiness.
- Who shall I hand it to?
Whey re so cute.
- She holds the purse strings.
- With my best wishes, Rosette.
Thank you, Christian.
Let me give you a kiss.
Excuse me.
He does that with such kindness.
You like him a lot, don't you?
I'd be ungracious not to.
He's so good to us.
I'm sure.
And for every couple,
a portable color television.
What a night.
So, shall we play the game?
Christian will interrupt us again.
No, he's with Catherine.
He's so worried about her.
You look much better.
You've got more color
than last night.
- Right, Colette?
- Without a doubt.
You faint too often, my dear.
You're much too emotional.
- I wasn't like this before.
- You must've had a nightmare.
Tell me about it.
I don't remember.
I hope the journalist hasn't planted
any ideas in your head.
Don't cry.
Come on now.
Don't cry, my child.
Men have lots of imagination,
you know.
Especially when it comes
to seducing girls.
I'd like to go out.
I must get up, wake myself up.
Of course.
You're not a prisoner.
I'll prepare your clothes.
You can take a walk.
You'll succeed in your undertakings,
but they won't earn you money.
What a waste of time.
However, there is money present.
You've reassured me.
But there will be problems.
You go from hot to cold, don't you?
That's strange.
Your cards are good,
but they're arranged
in an odd pattern.
I'll have to make the best of it.
But, if you want,
you could have an interesting affair.
It's not so bad after all.
It's up to you. But you'll have to
make the first move.
- Am I intruding?
- We just finished.
Did she promise you good things?
- Not bad.
- I'd say so-so.
I've got some news
I think will make you happy.
Catherine's much better this morning.
- You must be very glad.
- I must say I'm relieved.
Take a look out the window.
I suppose you want to work?
A resurrection, isn't it?
- You see, no need for a doctor.
- You're right.
Listen, I've got a bit of an appetite.
While I'm having brunch
as the Anglo-Saxons say,
why don't you go keep her company?
I'm sure she'll want to thank you
for last night.
I'll come get you when I'm done
so we can get to work.
And don't whisper sweet nothings
in her ear.
Thank you for last night.
Good. You've learned
your lesson by heart.
Your godfather sent me to you.
We're his puppets,
just like his old folks.
If you've come to torture me,
go away.
No, to open your eyes
and make you see the danger.
He's so sure of himself
that he thinks anything I say
will turn you more against me.
I'm just asking you to listen.
Don't be so familiar with me.
You approached me first.
Why did you start hating
Madeleine Chevalier?
You loved her,
then suddenly you hated her.
Did she say the same things as me?
She realized that
your godfather had a scheme,
that he was ﬂeecing you,
and that now he's after your life.
You didn't believe her, did you?
And you started hating her.
Is that it?
You told Legagneur.
He laughed his hearty laugh
and said Madeleine was crazy, bitter
and unbalanced.
And his proof? One day,
she left without even a good-bye.
She didn't leave.
He did away with her,
one way or another.
Just like he could do away with you.
He thought she had no family
to worry about her.
Roland Wolf isn't my name.
It's a pseudonym.
And the book on Legagneur is a pretext.
I came to find out about Madeleine.
I'm in your hands.
Do what you want.
Come on, old fellow.
Let's get to work.
There's not much time left.
Are you all right, Catherine?
You all right?
I'm all right.
I'm stealing Wolf from you.
- You're looking great.
- You too.
I came to get a piece of bread.
Hungry, huh?
Do you want some jam?
No, I don't like jam.
I saw you left the garden.
Are you throwing him out?
Don't you like him anymore?
I was afraid it would scare this one.
Are you crazy?
Please understand,
I can't stand feathers.
I'm allergic to them.
I almost lost my voice.
I almost died.
Look at me.
Allergies are very dangerous.
It was the bird or me.
Do you understand?
Understand?
Yes, I do.
I heard you come in.
I was waiting.
What's the matter?
- You woke me up.
- Really?
I'm sorry.
I was asleep for too long.
But your eyes entered mine.
I see clearly now.
He killed an injured bird,
just like its life meant nothing.
No more than any other life.
Do you believe me now?
Do you trust me?
Yes. Take me with you.
Let's go.
He's got every power to bring
you back, and he'd use it.
He'd call the police.
- Just tell them what you told me.
- There's no “just“ here.
His public status protects him.
Publicly, he's the best of men,
oozing goodness and charity.
I have no proof.
He'd laugh with a twinge of sadness
if confronted with such nastiness.
We'll find some other way.
You're the one who doesn't trust me.
- Why do you say that?
- I know it's true.
It's because
I didn't believe Madeleine.
You couldn't believe her.
You were blinded.
But still...
I feel guilty.
She was my friend.
She was so kind to me.
Suddenly I started hating her,
because I didn't want to believe her.
She might have had many faults,
but she never lied.
When I told my godfather, I was
so anguished I could hardly breathe.
- It's all my fault.
- No, it's not.
You were in darkness.
You couldn't see the light.
Think of yourself now.
Forget the past. Live in the present.
Tell me I'm not ugly.
Did he put that idea
in your head as well?
In his own way.
He'd say that I was pretty,
but that I shouldn't believe
those who said I wasn't.
He's really the most incredible
son-of-a-bitch!
It'll be a close game.
Are you up to it?
Ask me again.
Yes.
I want to be all yours.
You won't be mine, nor his.
You're your own person.
Then I'm giving myself to you.
Are you awake?
Did you sleep well?
Yes, thanks.
I feel great this morning.
Mr. Legagneur will be glad.
Drink while it's hot.
I'm hungry-
Hungry?
Will you get me some toast?
Certainly.
I I thought maybe you'd like a little jam.
No, thanks.
I don't like sugary things.
Some more tea?
No, thanks.
You're so kind to look after me.
- Happiness is a good appetite.
- Quite true.
I'll miss your breakfasts.
The weather's so fine
I went around the park.
ﬂogging?
- No, I took a stroll.
Tell me, old fellow.
Time's passed quickly, but tomorrow
it's back to the rat race.
I'm taping Happiness for Everyone.
You're cordially invited,
if you want.
I'd like to.
I'm very glad.
Usually, intellectuals despise
these kinds of shows.
Not in my case.
In any case, you've made me
understand their interest.
You'll write a good book, won't you?
You have everything you need.
I think I've got all I need.
And we've still got today.
Look who's coming.
My dear, be careful of your eyes.
It's very bright.
I've decided to get used to it.
I've decided to shake myself up.
You're very pretty.
May I ask you something?
Anything you want.
I'd like my checkbook.
I want to go shopping in Paris.
Are you sure you feel strong enough?
What do you think, Roland?
I don't want to interfere.
- Does that annoy you?
- Of course not.
I'm happy to see
you're feeling better.
I'm just afraid
you'll tire yourself out.
Well, all right.
I'll ask Max...
to get the car ready
and drive you there.
Don't get carried away.
Enjoy yourself.
Watch your coat.
What's going on?
The battery?
The ignition?
Go check.
This is ridiculous, Max.
I'm not at all happy.
Sorry, Catherine.
- You must be disappointed.
- It doesn't matter.
I'll go another time.
Get it fixed. And quickly.
This isn't good.
Come on, Catherine.
Put on your glasses, my girl.
The sun's so strong.
“The sun enlightens the sky,“
like the song says.
- You changed your mind?
- The car's broken down.
That great car? What bad luck.
You said it.
“Tomorrow, the motor will hum.
The lights will brighten up
the dark hillsides.“
My dear Roland,
your culture dazzles me.
Now, to work.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
There's one thing
you must emphasize:
how difficult it is
to move an audience.
That's important.
Catherine's transformed.
She's sunbathing.
Sunbathing?
She's not thinking.
She's mad.
What's come over her?
Excuse me for a moment.
Don't lie out in the sun like that.
It's not good for you.
It's even dangerous, I told you.
- But it feels healthy.
- Listen, my little girl,
I'm not used
to giving ultimatums.
But either go into the shade,
or go to your room.
It bothers you that I'm better.
Don't be silly,
but don't lie out like that.
I'm going in.
That's right, go inside.
For God's sake.
Mr. Legagneur isn't here?
He'll be back any minute.
Wonderful, isn't it?
Mr. Legagneur loves beautiful books.
He loves all beautiful things.
Here he is.
Be kind and accompany Catherine
to her room.
I can go alone.
The studio called. You're needed
there at 11:00 tomorrow.
As if I didn't know.
They're extraordinary.
So, on to the home stretch?
In a sense.
My keys, then.
Don't take a sip. It's bad.
Bring another bottle, then.
This is the first time it's happened.
You should've tried it.
He tries them enough as it is.
Vacation's over.
Tomorrow it's back to the rat race.
But you love it.
That's true, but these three days
have been very pleasant.
- This one's good.
- I'll get some other glasses.
The roast looks overcooked, Max.
Look at that.
It's like leather. inedible.
This isn't your day, Maxime.
- We should make shepherd's pie.
- That's an idea.
That will take three hours.
We can't wait three hours.
Make it for tonight.
Let's have sandwiches now.
Will that be all right with you?
Good idea. That's just fine.
Colette, go get Maxime.
- He's making the fruit salad.
- That can wait.
I want him now.
So, Wolfie,
feeling downhearted?
Well, I must say,
thanks to everyone here,
it hasn't felt much like work.
Your work has only just begun.
Mr. Max, it's my great pleasure
to raise a glass in your honor.
With this admirable shepherd's pie
made from a frightful roast,
you've given us a lesson
on turning defeat into victory.
Long live Maxime!
You're a brave little soldier.
I'm proud of you.
Why?
You've decided to fight your illness.
That's the best way to recover.
- Will you help me?
- Of course.
I'm going to bed. I'm tired.
I must get up early
to say good-bye to Mr. Wolf.
Say good-bye now
in case he leaves earlier.
- Right, that'd be smart.
- There are taxis at the station.
Well, in that case.
Good-bye, Mr. Wolf.
Glad to have met you.
Me, too. I hope you get well soon.
I'm on the way now.
If your godfather will allow me,
I'll give you a kiss.
Go right ahead, my old fellow.
A little formal, aren't we?
Good night, everyone.
Good night, dear.
I'll leave you with Manu
and Patricia for a moment,
in Patricia's capable hands.
I've something
to look after with Colette.
I'll join you in a minute
in the library.
Be kind enough to wait.
I've something to ask you.
Turn on the TV.
The soccer final's on tonight, alas.
I say “alas,“ but I'm actually
happy to go back.
Come with me to my room, Colette.
All my papers are there.
Manu, have one of my cigars.
It's getting tense.
That lousy bastard!
We took care of him, right?
I don't know.
Better to make certain.
We just have to do
the same thing as before.
- Impossible.
- I don't see why.
Tell him! He gets on my nerves!
Christian means that
this guy has ties.
It's different than a runaway
no one gives a damn about.
His disappearance
would create a fuss.
- Let's “suicide“ him.
- Too risky.
Catherine's just as dangerous.
- I can't control her.
- Me neither.
She's playing around with me.
It's hard to admit it,
but it's true.
Anyway, it had to happen.
She's the one we'll take care of.
You scared me.
Did I?
What's going on?
You're packing?
You want to leave me?
I suppose you want
to leave with Wolf.
Are you in love with him?
Look at that.
Her little chin is trembling.
You think I'm going to scold you?
You think I won't understand?
You love Wolf? All right.
Okay. It's the best I can say.
Want some money?
Here.
Buy a few dresses.
This bag's a bit of a mess.
Colette will help you with it.
Never mind.
You have to get to the station.
Colette will help.
And Max, too.
You already know the way.
You can't do this to me.
I'm not doing anything.
You're leaving on your own.
Take her down the back staircase.
Too bad you can't come with us.
We'll visit wine cellars.
They uncork
such extraordinary wines.
It'll last 15 days - 15 great days.
Leave him alone.
No, it's very interesting.
Did I take too long?
You didn't exactly take
the smallest one.
You're not watching the match?
Patricia didn't want to.
When France isn't playing,
it doesn't interest me.
I'd rather watch your show.
I never could stand watching myself.
- Everything okay?
- She's light as a feather.
Excuse me, but I've got
to be off early tomorrow.
I'll go too.
You always wake me in the morning.
- Are you coming?
- Please stay, Roland.
I've got something to ask you.
In case I don't see you tomorrow,
here's a kiss.
Good-bye, Patricia.
Thanks for telling my fortune.
If you change your mind,
I leave at 8:00.
Good-bye, Manu.
It's silly.
I wanted to suggest a game of chess.
For the pleasure of beating me.
I accept.
- But under one condition.
- Go ahead.
Tell me why you switch between
formal and informal address.
Good question.
The answer is simple:
informality comes from the heart,
formality from reason.
Informality is sentimental,
formality social.
- Is that good enough?
- Interesting.
- Right or left?
- Right.
You lose.
Black can win too.
Give me a hand.
Are you coming?
Shut up and drive.
I must confess something, Christian.
May I?
It won't disturb you?
“Wolf” is a pseudonym.
My real name is Roland Chevalier.
Madeleine was my little sister.
Well, what do you know?
Don't you believe me?
Impossible.
She always hated traveling.
She only wanted to be an actress.
She wouldn't waste her time
in the Seychelles.
Hollywood, perhaps.
She didn't mention
Hollywood in her note.
All I know is that she disappeared.
What do you want me to say?
Say, “How much?“
I don't get it.
You want me to say “How much“?
How much?
But Catherine's yours,
my old fellow.
Didn't you notice?
Catherine...
and the money.
Grooms are demanding these days.
I'd sell my soul
for the Impressionists.
Who's there?
It's me.
- Want a beer?
- No time.
Ask Totor to look after
the Cadillac in the morning.
The pink Cadillac? Okay.
SQ?
I thought I was on the right track.
Where did I make my mistake?
You didn't make any specific mistake.
You were just
a little too optimistic...
and you lost.
Good night, old fellow.
Sleep well.
My God!
Totor will crush it at dawn.
- Wake up, for God's sake!
- Are you nuts?
You must help me.
Catherine's going to be killed.
- How come?
- She's been kidnapped.
Do you know
the scrapyards address?
Manu, wake up.
Give him the scrapyards address.
Aida's scrapyard?
I took a bottle of
Chateau Neuf du Pape there one day.
17 Avenue Gabriel Peri.
- I'll come along.
- I can't wait.
You're both angels.
Not a word to anyone.
There are taxis at the station.
I know.
Totor!
Max came by last night.
The pink Cadillac goes first.
Sure, buddy.
Hi there.
- I work with Max. Was he here?
- Yeah, for the pink Cadillac.
Totor's on it with the crane.
Totor!
Change of plans!
Forget the Cadillac!
- Should I drop it?
- No!
Set it down.
Can't you make up your mind?
What the hell are you doing?
- Are you off your rocker?
- Help me open the trunk.
There's someone in there!
Help me!
Get the crowbar.
Call an ambulance.
Is she alive?
Yes.
Who's that chick?
My wife, I think.
Mrs. Lemonnier and Mr. Loury,
who may soon be
Mr. and Mrs. Loury.
- Remind us where you're from.
- From Pontoise.
I was a grocer
in Pontoise for 40 years.
Now I'm retired,
and I feel great.
I can understand.
And you, Simone?
- Simone, isn't it?
- Yes, Mr. Legagneur.
I'm a grandmother,
and even a great-grandmother.
I used to be a laundress.
A great-grandmother and a laundress.
Do you believe that?
How's it feel to be
a great-grandmother and engaged?
Her little chin is trembling.
But she told her children
and grandchildren
that she met a fiancé
thanks to this show.
I certainly did.
And they're very happy.
And I'm happy they're happy.
But I can tell you,
they'll be a little jealous
when they find out what you've won.
A trip.
My God! It can't be.
And not just any trip.
A trip around the world.
Yes, that's what you've won -
a trip around the world.
And now, a young couple will
present you with the tickets.
Be sure not to lose them.
A young couple
waiting at the back of the studio.
Our surprise guests.
No need to tell you
everything has an end.
Mr. Loury, I must confess
something to you.
I don't like old age.
- It frightens me.
- It shouldn't.
Same with the audience.
It disgusts me.
Deep down,
you know what I like? This.
So, my golden-age fiancés,
isn't that wonderful?
- Yes, it is.
- No, it's horrible!
It's a total fraud.
Because crimes of the heart
are the worst.
We make you believe
there's a little heart somewhere,
and you gobble it up!
Flaunting what should remain private -
isn't that a good definition
of obscenity?
You couldn't know.
Anyway, it's not important.
To think I've always loved
beautiful things.
Why do we always do
the opposite of what we want?
Maybe life forced you?
Yeah, right.
Life never forces anyone to do shit!
No, it's something else.
Something else.
I've always believed...
that life was a game.
And that I was the manager
of the toy department.
It seems we're having
problems backstage.
That's the risk of broadcasting live.
Gentlemen, allow me to finish
the show with a ﬂourish.
So.
Young wolf with a big appetite,
chevalier at another's table,
it turns out black can win after all.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have only one thing left to say,
from the bottom of my heart:
Get fucked!