Yo, y'all remember that nigga
Daniel from 16th Street?
Yeah.
- Fucking tough-ass nigga Daniel, yo.
That's my fucking word.
I see that nigga in jail, right?
Within a fucking week they had the nigga
wearing a fucking wedding dress.
I'm serious...
and carrying a fucking Bible.
I thought... that's my fucking word.
I swear to fucking God.
Like they fucking beat
his ass down mad fucking...
Fucking cocksucker-ass nigga.
So anyways, like I was telling you, right?
That's my word.
I fucking slapped that nigga's fucking face.
No.
Move it, before the flies lay eggs.
What the fuck are you looking at, boy?
Worse than my damn kids.
Man, that's fucked up.
Just shut up and pick 'em up,
sugar britches.
Bitch.
Motherfucker.
Why don't you turn up the frost?
They be getting hot back there.
Y'all cool now?
Fucking chillin', yeah.
...to endorse the emergency
bailout of Goldberg, Lesser...
...is claiming the Federal Bank
itself is on the verge of bankruptcy.
Fuck the banks, man.
G-man needs to give a serious
cash injection to this shithole.
That's what... that's what the fuck
needs to happen.
It's all about keeping
these monkeys in the zoo.
As long as their shit doesn't spill over...
...in their fancy backyards,
they could give a fuck.
Yeah, they pay us dumbasses
to clean up the fucking mess.
Damn right, brother.
And be thankful for the work.
Thankful my ass.
Make way for the man, fellows.
He got work to do.
Mm-hmm.
- We've been keeping him busy.
Shit. Yeah.
Listen, my friend,
I'll be seeing you later.
Yeah.
Fucking pussy.
See how he ran in there?
Shitting his pants.
City mayor slashed
the law enforcement budget...
...in the metropolitan area by 60%
as a last-ditch attempt...
...to stave off bankruptcy procedures.
This follows the closing...
...of an additional six inner-city schools...
...and the Greenborough Memorial Hospital.
Help. Help.
Oh hey, brother.
How's your day?
Fine.
I've got three in the back, execution,
covered with some pretty nasty shit.
Where's your porter?
Gone.
Jesus.
Where's the gurney?
Not here, please.
It was a pleasure, as always.
He gives me the fucking creeps, man.
He's a weird motherfucker, man.
You think he talks to the stiffs?
He's beautiful again.
It's as if he's reborn.
Thank you.
You have no conception of
how reconciled you've made me.
Shut the fuck up,
you little bastard.
Don't talk to him like that.
Then make him fucking stop.
Give him to me.
He's your son.
She always had class.
She was a proud,
discrete woman.
She would do anything for you.
I tried to take care of you myself,
but the state intervened.
She would do anything for you.
What the fuck did you say to me?
I do trust...
...you'll enjoy your time here.
Yeah, excuse the stench.
We do everything we can here,
but summer's upon us.
Hi.
Well,
this fabulous young man is Noah.
He's your replacement porter.
He's been gifted to us
by the ever-so-well-meaning...
...offenders rehabilitation service...
...gang member,
multiple gun violations,
yada-yada-yada.
But due to his parole officer's...
...acute sense of irony,
he has to complete his probation...
...wheeling in bodies for your delectation.
Well, I guess you two...
...should get along fabulously.
You'll find a lab coat in the locker room.
And please make sure
your hands are scrubbed.
A'ight, bro.
Please place that in the garbage pail.
Please, could you stop that?
It disturbs me.
You need to relax, man.
So, yeah, what is it exactly
I gotta do around here?
When a delivery is made,
I would like for you...
...to bring the bodies
through here for processing.
I would also like for you...
...not to disrupt my concentration as I work.
Now if there's nothing else,
please let me pass.
Oh, yes sir.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
You all right, bro?
She had to bring you up on her own.
She would do anything for you.
I tried to take care of you myself.
He's been crying all day.
Jesus, take care of him.
Can't you feed him something?
I ain't got nothing to give him.
Fuck. Shit.
You go get some food.
You're the big man around here.
Hey, sweetie, come up.
Get out of that rain.
Come on.
Oh, honey, you're soaked.
Poor baby.
Let's get you comfortable, honey.
Come on.
All right, honey,
just lay back.
Relax.
That's it.
Oh, honey,
you are always so cold.
You need some loving to warm you up.
...$137 million...
...from the metro public pension program.
This is the latest...
...in the series of corruption scandals...
...that has plagued the mayor's office.
The FBI...
Fasten your lab coat.
Yes sir, master sir.
I swear to God.
Fuck this bullshit.
I'll cut the motherfucker up.
Fucker. I'll fuck him up
for good this time, I swear.
How's about you keep your
eyes to yourself, man?
I mean there's a lot of shit
you don't need to know nothing about.
You feel me? So why don't you just
mind your own business?
Still locking that, huh?
You know anybody we want
in there, gets in there.
Say,
you seen a little kid...
...about yea high,
pretty like me?
No.
Are you sure about that?
Yes.
- Yes, you've seen him?
Or yes, you're sure you ain't seen him?
I haven't seen the boy.
Say you haven't.
Know this:
I've taken a liking to that boy.
So if you come across him,
you're obliged to tell me.
You get me?
That's it.
I'm out of here.
Hey kid, wait.
Wait.
This place gives me the creeps, man.
Yeah, well, you don't have to work here.
This is fucked up.
I'm telling you,
Carver ain't messing.
He wants the kid bad.
- Well, he ain't here.
Yeah, well, he's bound to
wind up here sooner or later.
Yo, my man, you seen the kid
around here, man?
What's his fucking problem?
The dude's straight up weird.
I want to come in.
It's not permitted.
Just let me in.
No, you're not allowed.
Please.
Why do you want to come in here anyway?
Just let me in.
I can't let you in.
Well, then fuck you.
Go on, fuck off.
Hey, kid, you need to calm down.
I hate you.
You're late.
- Yeah, I know.
All right, man,
so I'm late. Whatever.
I had some personal shit to take care of.
Delivery.
Porter?
Just get off me.
Porter.
The name's fucking Noah,
man, all right?
What was that all about?
- Mind your fucking business.
You have another 13 minutes
to work before you go.
What are you talking about, man?
It's 6:00.
You were 13 minutes late this morning.
You need to make it up.
Man, fuck that.
Man, I'm gone.
If you do not make up the time,
it will go reported.
With who?
Don't push me.
Whatever it is,
it can wait till tomorrow.
I'm over overtime, dude.
I'm over and out.
Come on, dude, just give me
the money, will you?
Where the fuck are you at, boy?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, man.
Good morning, Noah.
Here's where my joyful colleague...
...conducts his cheery work.
Hey.
This is Noah's parole officer Mr. Clinger.
I've got stuff to do.
So how's my boy getting on?
Behaving himself?
He's been satisfactory.
Really?
That's a surprise.
See, this brother here thinks...
...he's something of a hard man,
a gangster.
Ain't that right, Noah?
He's been satisfactory...
...and performs his duties adequately.
Well, you just let me know
if he steps out of line...
...if he curses you under his breath,
gives you any lip,
if he's late...
...by a single minute.
Because it would be my
absolute pleasure...
...to send this horrible little delinquent...
...right back to where he belongs.
I personally would like to ensure...
...that he rots there.
So you have anything
to say for yourself, laddy buck?
Huh.
That's too bad,
because I was hoping...
...that you would tell me to go fuck myself.
Well, if you don't mind,
Mr. Clinger,
Noah and I have work to attend to.
Well, go ahead.
I'm done here...
...for now.
Bye-bye, Noah.
I'll be seeing you very soon, I hope.
I don't need you to fight
my fucking war for me.
Porter.
Fucking trying to get away from me, Kane.
I'ma kick your fucking ass.
Fucking come here, come on.
I don't care.
- Stop fucking with me, man.
Don't fuck with me.
Come on.
No, I don't want to leave her.
Get off me.
- What are you gonna do, huh?
What the fuck are you gonna do? Walk.
Walk. I'ma rip your fucking arm...
...out of your fucking socket. Come on.
Walk walk.
Fuck you're looking at, man?
Mind your fucking business.
Stop it.
You fucking punk.
I could kill you myself right now, right here.
Fucking walk.
Hurry up.
Get the fuck out here.
Stop fucking around, come on.
Jesus.
- No.
Get inside.
Hey, get the fuck inside.
What's happening, iceman?
You see that kid yet?
Are you sure about that?
You ain't sure or you ain't seen him?
I... I haven't seen the kid.
Shame.
You ought to be careful out here
this time of night.
There's a lot of ill-minded motherfuckers...
...just ready to violate a fool.
Hey.
Oh, honey, come up.
It's cold out there.
I want you to go back.
Roll over.
That's it.
Just relax.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
You're so...
Jesus, baby, you've got knots...
...the size of baseballs.
Mm, there you go.
There you go.
Shh.
It's okay, honey.
You were just sleeping.
It's all right.
Thank you.
So long, honey.
I don't give a fuck who you lean on.
It's your obligation to find the kid.
I want the kid.
I ain't got the kid.
That irritates me.
Your incompetence...
...is an irritant.
I don't like to be irritated.
So find the fucking kid...
...and spare me the further irritation...
...of having to make an example of you.
You get me?
All right, come on,
get the fuck in here. Come on.
Get off me.
- Jesus Christ, get in there.
Come here.
You too, come on.
Yo, mister, you got a light?
No.
- You fucking say nothing.
You shut the fuck up.
- Get the fuck in here, man.
Stay the fuck still.
You're gonna stay the fuck right here,
or I'm gonna be the first one to make sure
you're back in that fucking mortuary...
...on a fucking slab, my nigga.
I'm freaking out, Noah.
I know. I know.
What are you doing here?
I was worried about you.
I was checking on you
to make sure you were okay.
So...
...are you okay?
I'm fine.
Thank you.
You know, you might want...
...to stop shrugging your shoulders.
You'll end up stooping like me.
Why have you been coming
to the mortuary?
I want to see my mama.
They won't let me see her.
What does your mama look like?
She's pretty.
She's got long dark hair
and big brown eyes.
She's got a little red ruby in her nose...
...and a tattoo...
...of some lady called Venus.
What's your name?
Kane.
Hello, Kane.
Would you like to sit down here...
...and tell me about your mama?
It's okay.
She smiles all the time,
even when she's sad.
She don't like me to know when she's sad.
So when I ask her why she's sad,
she just laughs and makes goofy jokes.
She sings me songs...
...when I go to sleep.
Sing me one of your mama's songs.
Can it be?
Do you hear?
A new freedom song
Is ringing
No more doubt
No more fear
There's a new song
That is ringing...
It's so far, it's so close
Almost near
Almost here.
You're freezing.
Wake up. I'm gonna
help you see your mama.
Come on.
What are you gonna do next?
Where the fuck is Kane?
Have you seen him?
Kane.
Kane. Kane.
Fucking shit.
Maria, they're fucking gone.
Okay.
Here here here.
Climb the wall.
Quick quick.
Motherfucker.
Fucking shit.
Here, cover your mouth.
Okay, let's go.
Argh.
Come here.
Get the fuck up.
Get over here.
Get over here. Come here.
Stop it.
Leave him alone.
Come here, my nigga.
Get the fuck over here.
Get the fuck down.
Fuck is wrong with you, man?
Leave him alone.
He's my friend.
Okay, I got you.
I got you. I got you.
Please don't hurt him.
He's only being nice.
You don't understand, all right?
Look, him being fucking nice...
...is gonna get us fucking killed.
- You understand that?
No.
- Get the fuck down, man.
Get the fuck down.
Come here, come here.
It's okay. Come here.
Maria, take him please.
Take him please.
You ain't going fucking nowhere.
- Noah, don't.
What the fuck, yo?
What the fuck?
Not in front of Kane.
What's going on, Noah?
Shit, mind your fucking
business, my nigga.
I swear to God,
mind your fucking business.
You made this my business.
- Excuse me?
If you don't tell me what's going on,
I'm taking Kane with me.
You're fucking going nowhere.
Get the fuck over here.
Get over here. I'm gonna fucking kill you.
- No. No.
What the fuck do you want from me, huh?
What the fuck more
do you guys want from me?
Noah, what's going on?
You have to tell me, Noah.
He's my fucking nephew,
dawg, all right?
Jenny Morales was my sister.
Carver thought he owned her.
Let me just check on him.
The kid's gonna have to learn to wait.
He's a sack of shit.
I swear I'm gonna give it to him
one day soon big time.
Listen, I don't like him.
He's an asshole. And he's a fool.
Why do you let him come in here then?
Why don't you just let him go
and stay out for good...
...instead of coming back up in here...
...and just jumping you
whenever he wants to?
Oh, grow up, Noah.
Having him come once
in a while to get some...
...is just enough to keep
the other hoodlums away.
It's bullshit.
- It's the way it is, so deal.
I'm gonna get us out of this place,
but until then,
it's just the way it is.
Can it be?
Do you hear?
Are you singing?
She was smarter than me.
She knew how things worked.
She knew what needed to be done.
I tried to protect them,
but I fucked up,
and I fucked up every fucking time.
I got sent upstate for
doing some stupid shit...
...enough stupid shit to land me
like a two-year bit.
What the fuck's going on?
He's been loaning her out to his crew.
Crew? Excuse me?
What does that mean?
Carver has been pimping
her out to his buddies.
Maria.
- I'm sorry.
She tried to leave,
so he beat her... look.
I can't even fucking deal
with this shit right now.
Where are you going?
Come on, let me go.
Oh God.
Hey.
You have to stay out of trouble.
I know.
Hey, kid.
You. You, come here.
You too, come here.
I couldn't bear to see her like that.
I knew I had to stand up
and take responsibility.
The prodigal son.
Sit down.
Be my guest.
You need to leave her alone.
She my baby mama.
I got rights.
No no, you ain't got no right
to raise your hands to her like that,
let alone let some other
niggas touch her, man.
You got balls coming here talking like that.
I'm telling you that you're a man, all right?
And I'm just asking you
to act like one. That's it.
You are asking me to act like a man?
No, dawg, I'm telling you to act like a man...
...and leave my sister alone.
Fuck that, Carver.
Whoo. Yeah. Ha.
That bitch going down.
Stop. Fucking stop.
Shit.
All right.
Brutal.
Carv, you fucked that bitch up for real.
Is that man enough for you?
Shh.
We need to get out of here.
I know someplace safe.
Hey, sweetie.
You can stay here as long as you need.
Carver won't look here.
I appreciate that.
- Thank you.
You'll be safe here for a while.
It was never meant to be like this.
I tried to step up and do right by my sister,
but each time it fell apart,
leaving Jenny to pick up the pieces.
You get to load it when you pay.
All right, that's 150, right?
Come on.
It should be 170,
but you look like a sweet guy.
All right.
Drop the gun, shithead.
Now.
Best you give that back
to me, don't you think?
You're a stupid fuck.
Yeah.
And, oh yeah...
...you're under arrest.
And with me back inside,
it got worse for Jenny.
She couldn't take it no more.
I don't want to know where you are...
...until you are safe,
you hear me?
Yeah.
Here.
Go go. Bye.
Come on, trouble man,
I'll race ya.
You're gonna lose.
He spotted them at the train terminal.
He dragged them back to his hideout.
Mama pushed me through
the bathroom window...
...and she told me to go to Maria.
But I waited for her.
Carver went psycho...
...when he found out
that Kane had escaped.
Jenny wouldn't tell him where he went.
So he beat her.
He raped her.
He shot her.
And he threw her in the canal.
Papa gonna get ya.
Let Kane see his mother.
He needs to make his own sense
out of all this.
Let him grieve.
Don't let the pain ferment.
It will entomb him...
...like it entombed me.
No, man, I can't do that.
Are you kidding me?
It's too dangerous for him.
Carver's already got a bounty on his head.
If we don't get him out of
here tonight, that's it...
All of us are as good as dead,
and that includes you.
I'm not going anywhere until I can see her.
Papi, you've already seen
what he can do to you.
We gotta get you out of here, man.
We gotta get you out of here now.
He'll never forgive you.
Please.
Stay with Kane.
All right, man, but hurry up.
We gotta get out of here.
So the kid's at the morgue.
Who else?
- Didn't see anyone.
Maybe the stiff guy's there.
That could be fun.
So it's good.
Should I get Rico and G?
Oh no,
I'll deal with this myself.
Too many people have seen
too much already.
So get the fuck out.
Yo, Carv,
you ought to take it easy
on that kid, all right?
I mean he's your blood.
He done being my blood...
...when his whore mother
turned him against me.
All right, Carv.
It's time.
All right, guys.
Well, ain't this some cozy-ass shit?
You have chance to be gone with the kid,
and you fucking stay?
I'm taking the kid now.
No. No.
You can't have him.
You're way out of your depth, boy.
I take what I want.
- That ain't gonna happen.
Fuck.
- No. No.
Motherfucker.
No. No.
Fuck.
No.
Noah.
It's over.
Hmm?
You're safe here.
Sleep.
Thank you.
How can I help you,
Mr. Bright Lights Big City?
I'm looking for someone
who might have known her.
There you go, handsome.
Careful, it's hot.
Hmm, she's beautiful.
My mother.
I was hoping
I'd find someone who remembered her.
Well, you enjoy your pie, okay?
Excuse me, sir.
My granddaughter mentioned...
...that you've been making
enquiries about a lady...
...who may have lived here a long time ago.
Yes. Please.
I knew her.
And I knew you too...
...when you were a little boy.
Your mother and I were very close.
I've written to you many times...
...and I always hoped you'd come.
Oh, my sweet boy.
Come with me.
We were very close.
Your mother and I
used to work here together.
You know, all I can really remember is...
...she would leave me each night,
and one night...
...she didn't come home.
She loved you...
...more than anything
in the whole wide world.
She would do anything for you.
When she couldn't make ends meet,
she began to...
...entertain gentlemen.
One of her clients became violent...
...and killed her.
That's why she never came back.
They never caught him,
never found out why.
They just dragged you away...
...and wouldn't even let you lay her to rest.
They wouldn't let you say goodbye.
Come on, Noah, run with us.
I am. I'm running backwards here.
Hey, Kane, are you tired or what, buddy?
Whoo.
- Touchdown.
Oh, fumble on the five-yard line.
Hey, come on, get it.
Relax. It's not like it's broken.
Thank you.
You're a kind man.
Run, get him.
Oh my God.
Enough to get you started.
I appreciate that, man.
You're a saint, you know that?
Go find a seat on the bus.
Take him.
Are you ready, Papi?
Go.
Thanks, man.
Alrighty, sir,
are you about ready?
You know, Ava, I must confess
I know nothing about you.
Do you have a family?
I do.
He's 13 now.
He lives in the country with my sister,
far away from this place.
I miss him.
He must love you very much.
Maybe we can visit him someday.
That would be nice.
Poor slob got fished out
of the canal this morning.
Ain't had a happy night.
Hmm, what a shame for him.
Hmm.