♪ Fixed & Synced by
bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick ♪
ANNOUNCER: Live from WZIL,
News '25 at noon starts now.
(NEWS THEME PLAYING)
NEWSCASTER: Colin Evans, convicted
of voluntary manslaughter
for one of the most brutal
murders in recent history,
is up for parole today.
Five years ago, Evans was one of
the most wanted men
in state history,
having emerged as
the prime suspect
in the disappearance
of five young women.
Evans was eventually
apprehended for the crimes,
only to escape and elude
authorities for several months,
until the night he was arrested
for the fatal barroom brawl
that would lead to
his manslaughter conviction.
The evidence necessary
to try Evans
for the abduction of the five
young women proved illusory.
The DA's office
decided to settle
for what it knew it could
prove in a court of law.
Hence, the lesser
manslaughter conviction.
No mention of Evans
being the primary suspect
in the disappearance and presumed
death of the five young women
was ever made at
his manslaughter trial.
But now, on a day when one
of the most feared men
in the annals of state
history might walk
after having served only five
years in prison for manslaughter,
the five families
are huddled together
outside the courthouse
hoping and praying
that the man they believe to be
nothing more than
a vicious animal,
is not set free.
DRIVER: I'm hoping you get
a fair shake today, Colin.
I prayed hard for it Sunday.
I appreciate that.
In my experience,
if you give a man
a second chance,
usually, they rise
to the occasion.
Well, except politicians.
I've never met one of them ever
learned from their mistakes.
What about you, Officer Reid?
Can I count on your support?
They pay me to guard
you, not to talk to you.
Don't mind him, Colin.
He's got woman troubles.
You know how that goes.
Yeah.
MAN: Colin Evans, currently
serving 10 to 15 years
for involuntary manslaughter.
Let the record show
you've requested
to address the parole board
in lieu of your attorney.
You may begin.
COLIN: Thank you, sir.
I'm not going to stand
here and lie to you,
because I'm not
very good at that.
When I was sentenced,
I was angry.
I told myself fights like this
get out of hand all the time.
Accidents happen
and I could have
easily been the man
that died that night.
But as time went by,
I realized I was wrong.
I shouldn't have been angry.
I should have been ashamed.
A man had died, and there was
no way I could bring him back.
But I could make
a change within myself.
And others, perhaps.
I started a teaching program,
teaching other prisoners
to read and write.
And the warden saw this,
and they're talking about taking my
program statewide to other prisons.
I feel like
that's an achievement.
I stand here right now
as a changed, humble man.
I've been in the prison correctional
system for five years now,
and that is exactly
what I am, corrected.
Rehabilitated.
I just want you to
give me a chance.
I won't let you down.
Thank you for your time.
Mr. Chairman, if I could
have just a moment?
CHAIRMAN: Go ahead.
You see, I did my
homework on this man.
And I can tell you
with confidence
that he's actually
quite a good liar.
That fight that got out of hand,
that was actually Mr. Evans
flying into a murderous rage
because of how the victim was
looking at his girlfriend.
And as a younger man, there
were other acts of violence,
frequently involving
the attentions of a woman.
Mr. Evans fits the criteria
of a malignant narcissist.
Charming, highly intelligent,
as you've witnessed,
but malignant narcissists are
compelled to prove their superiority.
Everything's a seduction,
and if they're rejected,
or things don't go their
way, they lose control.
Some other more well-known
malignant narcissists were
(DISTORTED ECHOING) Jeffrey
Dahmer, John Wayne Gacy...
Now, hold on.
No. Sir. Sir.
Mr. Evans, please,
just sit down.
Please sit down,
Mr. Evans.
I can tell you there's
violence in this man.
And his control over
himself is slender.
I'll let my fellow board members
make up their own minds,
but there are
five families outside
who are hoping and praying that
we do not set Colin Evans free.
Mr. Evans, as I'm sure
you're aware,
to be granted parole
in the State of Tennessee,
it must be a unanimous vote.
We'll take this up again in
five years, as mandated.
CHAIRMAN: Ladies and
gentlemen, that convenes
the State of Tennessee
parole hearing for today.
Madame Secretary, you can turn
off your recording devices.
Ladies and gentlemen, you are
free to go at this time.
I don't know what to say, Colin.
Why even waste your breath?
Uh, a little help.
My nose is bleeding.
Reid.
He'll be fine.
Give him a tissue or something.
Here.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Shit!
COLIN: No, no, put the gun down!
No!
Or you can watch him die
and I don't want that!
No!
You don't want that.
Put the gun down and you
both walk out of here!
Come on. I just want to
get out of here, that's all.
Colin, please.
You have my word.
Go on.
Come on.
Just put it down.
Just put it down!
(HEAD THUNKS ON FLOOR)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Yes, I'm still here.
(HORN BEEPING)
Yeah. Ryan, honey,
please don't do that.
Uh, yeah, can you please tell me
how long ago my husband left?
Ryan, stop it.
(BABY FUSSING)
Yeah. Javier,
one second.
Uh, yeah, well, if he checks in,
can you please have him call me?
Yeah. Thanks, Karen.
Okay. Bye-bye. What's up?
Uh, there's a storm coming.
Is everything gonna
be okay out there?
I covered the concrete
with plastic.
It will delay
the dry-time a little,
but nothing to worry about...
(HORN BEEPING)
Ryan, paint Mommy a picture.
Please, go make me a picture.
Go ahead.
Come on.
Go get your coloring book.
With the storm coming, there's
really not much we can do.
Hey, Javier. The house
is looking great.
It's getting there.
Have a good weekend.
You, too. Bye.
JAVIER: All right, let's go, guys.
Load it up!
Terry?
Hey!
When are they going to be done?
Uh, last month.
Ooh.
Maybe I should remodel.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Who's got the prettiest
goddaughter in the whole world?
You!
And, who's Meg's best friend?
Ryan.
And who's Ryan's best friend?
Meg.
And what's all the rest?
Bullshit!
TERRY: Meg. Yeah,
you're going to school
the first time she gets called to
the principal's office, not me.
What's he look like,
and is he single?
You are a mess,
but you look good.
Thanks. So do you.
Yeah, covered in spit-up
and carrying an extra
10 pounds, but thanks.
Do you know what I think?
I think you're not the reason
you feel bad about yourself.
I think that Jeffrey should be
making you feel appreciated
and he should...
Meg, Jeffrey makes me
feel appreciated, okay?
He appreciates me.
Thanks for your concern.
Lam just saying... Okay.
RYAN: Daddy! Daddy!
Hey, sweetheart.
Jeffrey's home early.
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
It's his dad's birthday, so,
he's taking him on a golf trip.
Okay. You know what? We're
going to have a girls' night.
I'm going to get some wine.
Mmm! Great.
My girl needs a girls' night.
We're going to get drunk!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
TERRY: I can't wait.
Oh! Hey, Jeffrey.
Hey, Meg
What are the two of you up to?
Oh, you know, just
braiding each other's hair
and talking about
the boys we like.
Ah, Meg stopped by on her run.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
Which I should probably get back
to, so, I'll see you tonight?
Yes, I can't wait.
Jeffrey, you're a lucky man.
Yes, lam.
See you later, Meg.
Bye, honey.
Hi.
Hello, darling.
Damn, baby.
I was feeding your children.
Can you try not to act
so grossed out?
I'm sorry.
It's just this Hopkins case
is turning into a nightmare.
The judge rejected
our plea today.
I am sorry to hear that.
JEFFREY: That's life, right?
I saw that Meg sold that
house down by the school.
She must be making a killing.
Meg has quite the life.
Here we go.
I'm home two minutes and
you're already being negative.
All I said was that Meg had the life.
And you don't?
Jeffrey, I...
JEFFREY: Babe, just remember it was
your idea to be a full-time mom.
This is what you wanted, not me.
Yes, it is what
I wanted, Jeffrey.
I hardly saw you all week
and I'm going to miss you.
I know. I'm sorry. Okay?
Let's get away.
Okay? Just you and me.
Without the kids. Somewhere
for a couple of days.
We need it.
It's been a long time.
Okay?
All right.
We can do that.
TERRY: I'm going to the store.
That way, you can spend some time
with the kids before you leave.
No, wait a minute.
No, no.
I'm already running late
and I still got to pack.
Jeffrey. That's why I asked
you to be home early.
It's my dad's birthday.
I'm going to go pack.
♪ ♪
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(FLICKS LIGHTER)
(STARTER GRINDS)
(CLICKS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
You're not taking
your big, warm coat?
It's going to be cold up there.
It's just two hours away.
I'll be fine.
They say the storm is
going to be really bad.
Are you sure you want to
drive all the way there?
Is all this worrying because
you need me to stay?
Of course, not. I know how
important this is for your father.
I better get going.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Tell your dad I said,
"Happy birthday."
I Will.
Make sure you use the alarm
when I'm gone, all right?
I know, I know, but just use
it for my peace of mind.
All right.
Do you remember the code? Yes.
(LAUGHS) I'll use it.
All right.
I'll miss you.
When I get back,
we'll plan that trip.
Maybe, we'll go back to that
little place on the vineyard.
How does that sound?
Great.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I love you.
I love you, too.
(SIGHS)
(PHONE CHIMES)
(PHONE BEEPS)
Hey, it's Renée. I hope
you're having a great day.
Listen, we should
catch up this weekend.
I have to tell you about the
horrible date I went on last week.
Ugh!
Anyway, give me a call and maybe we
can meet up for a movie or something?
Talk to you soon. Bye.
COLIN: Honey, I'm home.
Colin...
I just want to talk.
You know, I wanted
to tell you that, uh,
after what happened that night,
I don't blame you
for pulling away from me.
You know, moving out here.
The point is, I can't do
anything about that now.
When I was in prison,
I thought a lot about you.
What do you want from me?
I just want you to forgive me.
Give me a chance.
Hmm?
I know someone that
can make passports.
We can get two new names.
Travel, you know?
Go around the world, you and
me, like we talked about.
(INHALES)
Oh, shh.
Maybe get married.
Would you come with me?
I'm going to need
an answer, yes or no.
Yes.
Yes?
Do you still love me?
Yes.
Because I wrote you a lot of letters
and you didn't answer them.
(QUIET, ANXIOUS LAUGH)
But that's because
I didn't know what to say.
And there's no one else?
No.
That's right.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
Because you still love me.
Right?
(PHONE CHIMES)
ls that him?
Who?
(CHUCKUNG)
"Who?"
The guy I saw you talking
to at the coffee shop.
Nice looking fellow.
You and I are going to have
to have a chat later on.
He's my trainer. He wanted to
talk to me about his boyfriend.
His boyfriend?
Do you think I spent
five years in prison
for you to come
and lie to me now?
Where did you meet him?
You know, I found this
on your bed.
"Didn't want to wake you,
"'cause you look so
beautiful when you sleep."
Colin...
(STAMMERING)
I tried to wait.
No, you didn't.
I found these, too.
You didn't even
read any of these.
Didn't read that one.
Not one. Not one!
Hey!
Hey! No!
Hey...
(DOOR SLAMS)
Colin! You didn't
give me a chance!
Huh?
You murdered a man!
It's manslaughter in
the eyes of the law.
It's very, very different.
And those girls?
What about them?
Does he even know about me?
Who?
Huh?
Do you love him? Huh?
Do you love him?
Leave me alone. Just tell me.
Just tell me!
Leave me alone! Just
answer the question!
What? Did you have
sex in this bed?
You're just being ridiculous.
(STAMMERING) It's stupid.
That's what's going on?
While I'm in jail,
you're sitting here having sex
with this man. ls that right?
Why don't you just
tell me the truth?
Why don't you just tell me?
Yes! Yes, Colin!
(DISTORTED ECHOING) We do
it right here, in this bed.
All the time!
And it's great!
Is that what you want to hear?
Is that what I need to say to
get you to just leave me alone?
Just leave me alone.
(PANTING)
I'm sorry.
(WHISPERING) I'm sorry.
That's okay.
I just missed you.
It's okay.
I missed you so much.
I...
I am done!
(CRACK)
♪ ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(CAR ALARM CHIRPS)
(GRUNTING WITH EFFORT) Oh...
Shit. Okay.
(GROANS)
DR. ROSS: Mr. Evans fits the
criteria of a malignant narcissist.
Some other more well-known
malignant narcissists were
Jeffrey Dahmer, John Wayne Gacy...
(HORN BLARING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(BABY COOING)
(CLICKS TONGUE GENTLY)
♪ ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Cut those up.
Go ahead, cut it up
and put it on the plate.
That's very good. Big girl.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Okay, baby.
Finish that up, okay?
I'll be right back.
Okay, Mommy.
You are so early.
Oh.
Hello?
Oh, I'm sorry, I don't
mean to bother you.
You were the only house
with the lights on.
I just lost control of my car.
I skidded and, uh, wrecked it.
Are you all right?
I'm good.
I just have a scratch.
Oh, my God.
I'm all right. Do you think
I could use your phone?
I don't even need to come in.
I'll stand right here. You can
hand the phone and shut the door.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Okay. I'll be right back.
All right, thank you.
(LATCH CLICKS)
Okay, baby. I guess somebody
needs to use the phone.
Okay, finish cutting
that up, baby.
Put it on the plate, and
then come over here and eat,
because I want you in bed at
a decent hour tonight, okay?
Okay. All right.
I'll be right back.
Okay. Here.
(CLATTERING)
oh... oh...
Oh...
Uh...
I'll get that for you.
Oh, you don't have
to worry about that.
That's all right.
I really can get that later.
You know, the one time
I forget my cell phone...
Here.
Thank you.
Oh, boy.
Do you live around here?
Yeah, over on River Road.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
RYAN: Mommy!
Um...
I'm feeding my daughter.
I'm sorry. Go on.
Look, why don't you make the
call and I'll be right back?
Go on. I'll be fine.
Okay. All right.
Okay, Ryan.
Ryan. I need
your help, baby.
I'm trying to help a neighbor.
You have to clean that up.
(QUIETLY) Oh, Lord.
Just stay right there.
I'll be back, baby.
Oh, yeah, it's going
to need a tow.
Oh, it's totaled.
Um, hold on.
Is there anyone here that can
give me a ride to my car?
They want me to sign something
before they can tow me.
My husband's not home...
yet, uh, but he
should be home soon.
You know what?
Why don't you have them meet you
here just in case he's late?
Here?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
Yeah, it's fine.
Okay. Um, sir,
is there any way the driver can
meet me here where I am right now?
Great.
I'm at, uh...
17 Creston Lane.
17...
Creston...
Creston.
Lane.
Mmm-hmm.
All right.
Okay.
He said he doesn't know
how long it's going to take
because of the storm, but, uh...
They're on their way.
So, thank you again.
Yeah, sure. Mmm-hmm.
I appreciate it.
All right.
Okay.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CRASHES LOUDLY)
You know what?
You can come in.
I don't want to bother you.
No, it's no bother.
Just come on.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I can't leave you out in the
rain to bleed to death.
It's fine.
You're sure?
I'm positive.
Thank you. Ooh, that
cut's really bad.
No, it's not that bad.
Yeah, let me see if I
have something for that.
Stay right there.
All right.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
COLIN: It's really
nice of you...
(QUIETLY) Okay, there's this.
To, uh, look after a stranger
on your doorstep like this.
I mean, really, you
don't have to do this.
Like I said, I couldn't
leave you out in the rain
bleeding like that.
You can dry
yourself off with that.
You can come over here.
This is all I have, so,
hopefully, I can patch you up.
It's a beautiful house
you've got here.
Oh, thanks.
Let me get this for you.
Thank you.
Do you want me to
take that for you?
No, I'll just leave it here.
Okay.
Okay. Let's see.
Well, hello, little princess.
What's your name?
Hmm?
(TERRY CHUCKLES)
This is Ryan.
Ow.
I'm a superhero!
Ryan, no hitting.
That's a mean right hook
you have there.
Who taught you that your daddy?
I'm so sorry. I don't know where
she's learning this from.
Um, Ryan, do me a favor.
Go in the kitchen and get
Mommy a wet paper towel,
so I can clean up
his boo-boo.
She is so beautiful.
Thank you. (SIGHS)
ls that your only child?
Oh, no. Sam's in the
nursery, sleeping.
You lucked out.
It can be quite the zoo
around here sometimes.
And trust me,
I don't turn down an opportunity
to have some adult
interaction these days.
Oh, thank you, baby.
Finish cleaning up
your mess, okay?
All right, let's see here.
You must have thought I was your husband.
At the door?
Yeah, he'll be home shortly.
Yeah, you said.
So, I'm Colin.
Terry.
Terry?
Nice to meet you.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Okay. That should do it.
I don't think I'll put
a Band-Aid on it.
It looks like
it needs to breathe.
Okay, bugaboo.
What about Spy Dogs?
Spy Dogs!
Yeah!
Bye-bye.
Watch some Spy Dogs.
Spy Dogs. say,
"Bye-bye" (LAUGHS)
Spy Dogs, Spy Dogs.
Get you good and sleepy.
Okay. God, that should
keep her occupied.
You know what?
Why don't you come in here? I'll
see if I have a dry shirt for you.
You're soaking wet.
Here.
Oh, thank you. Hopefully,
the sizes are okay.
Thanks so much.
Oh, you're welcome.
So, uh, your husband
went to NYU'?
We both did, actually.
We met in law school.
Oh, so, you're both lawyers?
Uh, yeah. I was, um, a
prosecutor at the DA's office.
That's fascinating.
It was.
Well, most of my cases
were violence against women.
They're easier to make.
Why is that?
Well, it's almost always
someone close to the victim.
Husband, boyfriend.
They beat them?
They kill them.
I worked in
the homicide division.
Wow. I bet you were a force
to be reckoned with, though.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, that's the nicest thing anyone
has said to me in a long time.
Come here.
There you go. Got it.
Um, give me your shirt.
I can dry that for you.
Oh, right. Okay.
It helped that the men
made my job easy.
How come?
Unlike what you see on TV, most
killers aren't that smart or clever.
Actually,
they're pretty pathetic.
Pathetic?
Yeah, they're weak.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
Shit, that's going to wake Sam.
(CAR ALARM CONTINUES)
(CAR ALARM WAILING)
ls everything all right?
No. It's not working.
It does this sometimes.
Do you want me to take a look?
Do you mind?
Yeah, just grab that
coat right there. Oh...
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Thank you.
Yeah.
(CAR ALARM
CONTINUES WAILING)
Alarm. Alarm.
It's loud!
Yes!
It says there's a valet button
underneath the steering wheel.
Oh, wait. I think
I know where that is.
You know where it is?
That's not it.
What now?
We need to do something else.
(CAR ALARM STOPS)
What did you do?
I have no idea.
(TERRY PANTING)
That was bizarre.
I don't know.
Maybe it was a fuse.
Something's gone wrong.
Let me lock this.
(LATCH CLICKS)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Do you want some hot tea?
Sure.
Okay.
TERRY: Did you get lost?
No.
I'm just drying off.
Is this your husband? Oh, yeah.
Nice.
What about you?
Are you married?
(WOMAN GASPS, ECHOING)
Girlfriend?
(GASP ECHOING)
Ex-fiancée.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah. It just happened.
(WOMAN GROANING)
Sugar? Fresh lemon?
She was cheating on me.
Ouch. That's got to hurt.
The knowing is the tough part.
The act itself, well,
that's going to happen
whether you know
about it or not.
The only way to stop it
is to know more.
So, you want to know who he was,
what he was wearing,
what he was driving.
It sounds like torture.
(STAMMERING) No, it's worse.
It's like getting your heart
ripped out of your chest.
Yeah, but at least you know.
Isn't that better?
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
No.
We were going to get married.
(WHISTLING STOPS)
Well, I can tell you,
marriage is not all that.
Do you still love him?
Of course.
I guess I just miss my own fire.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
When we met, I was
(ECHOING) independent,
strong, and powerful.
(NORMAL VOICE) I just think
he sees me differently now.
(BANGING)
(CLATTERING)
He's just gone blind,
that's all.
(BANGING, CLATTERING STOPS)
Because you're still beautiful,
powerful,
fierce.
Yeah.
I'm going to go
put Ryan to sleep.
Can I use the restroom?
Oh, it's this Way.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Night-night, bugaboo.
Night-night.
Okay.
♪ ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
TERRY: You scared me.
Is everything okay?
I couldn't find the sugar.
I offered you sugar.
Are you looking
for your husband?
(LAUGHS)
I feel silly.
He's not coming home.
He's not what?
(DOORBELL RINGS)
The tow truck's here.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Hey!
Hey.
Did you walk?
It's just down the street.
I'm fine.
Crazy lady, give me that coat.
You're soaking wet.
(LAUGHS) I know.
Here. Sorry.
Give me the coat.
Um, look, I meant to call
you because, um, l have, uh.
What?
Hi.
Hi. And who are you?
I'm Colin.
That's why I wanted to call you.
Colin got into an accident
and I was the first house
that he stumbled upon,
and he needed to use the phone.
So, he called a tow truck and we're
just waiting for the tow truck.
We're waiting.
You don't have
your own cell phone?
I left it at home.
Oh.
(LAUGHS)
That cut's pretty nasty.
Are you all right?
No, I'm good. Terry's
been looking after me.
I'm sure she has.
Stop it.
She's a good little
nurse, isn't she?
Well, listen, l thought we were
going to have a girl's night,
but l suppose we can all share.
TERRY: Yeah, sure.
I'll get glasses.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MEG SIGHS)
Meg.
Meg. Colin.
So you said.
Right.
You know,
it's funny.
I thought I knew all the good
looking men in this town.
I bet you do.
Well, obviously not.
Now, where do you live?
River Road.
Hey, I just sold a house there.
I'm a realtor.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, 6267.
It's an old Georgian.
It was a horrible shade of brown.
The new owners just painted.
Do you know the one? Do you know
the one that I'm talking about?
The new owners just painted.
Nope.
No, I don't think
I've seen that one.
I know all the families
on that street.
What's your address?
Come on.
What is it?
My address?
Yeah, which house are you in?
Are you going to stalk me?
You should be so lucky.
(DISTANT) Yeah, I think
I should stalk you.
Now, seriously,
where do you live?
Um, I...
(TERRY SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
What happened?
Terry, are you okay?
God, that scared
the hell out of me.
Look at that. Do you
have garbage bags?
Duct tape?
Garbage bags?
Yeah, everything's in there.
Do you believe that? That
was such a freak accident.
No, I'm fine, but that
scared the shit out of me.
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
Jeffrey's not going to be happy.
TERRY: No, he's not.
It's just a broken branch.
There you go.
TERRY: I need a drink.
Jeffrey's not going
to like that.
(TERRY SIGHS)
Colin, you're so handy.
I've fixed a couple
of windows before.
Stop it.
MEG: Come on.
This is for you.
Thank you.
To Terry.
Me?
A great friend, a great mom,
(TERRY LAUGHS)
and a great wife...
Thank you.
Who Jeffrey doesn't deserve.
Meg.
To Terry.
MEG: Cheers.
You were thirsty.
Come on, let's go in the living room.
Bring the bottle.
Come on.
I'll give you some more.
TERRY: Meg.
COLIN: Exactly what I needed.
A definite step up
from tea, huh?
You guys were drinking tea?
Yeah. It's cold out.
Terry, a man that looks like
this shows up on your doorstep,
and you offer him tea.
(GROANS)
TERRY: You would have
plied him full of alcohol.
(LAUGHS) Yes.
I would have.
Would you have taken
advantage of me?
Where's your glass?
In every way possible.
Cheers.
Married women so quickly
forget what a sex drive is.
Meg.
Honey, I'm just kidding.
But I do think sex is
like going to the gym.
You should do it every day
and never use the same
equipment two days in a row.
Wow.
I guess you're not
the settling-down type.
The term "settling down," it
just seems redundant to me.
And marriage?
Hmm.
It's not really a goal for me
like it is for most women.
If I found the right guy,
but that's a big if.
The right guy has
to make me laugh
and be smarter than me.
Do you think love
follows all those rules?
You could get swept off
your feet, right?
Absolutely.
By an incredibly smart
and really funny guy.
(WOMEN LAUGH)
How did you two meet?
(SIGHS, LAUGHS) Uh,
(LAUGHS) where do we start?
College BFFs.
Yeah, we've known each other
and we go so far back.
(DISTORTED ECHOING) And don't
let this one fool you.
I wasn't always
the wild one of the pair.
(CONVERSATION FADES
AND DISTORTS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
It's true.
It's shocking, right?
(NORMAL VOICE) This one, the wild one.
It's surprising, right?
No, not really.
(TERRY CLEARS THROAT)
When, um...
(DISTORTED ECHOING) When Meg...
When I told her I was
moving back to Georgia,
she insisted on being
our real estate agent.
And I just happened to sell her the
house down the street from me.
Yay!
Which Jeffrey loved.
(VOICE ECHOES, DISTORTS)
(ECHOING LAUGHTER)
(NORMAL VOICE) I was talking
to Colin about where he lived,
but he wouldn't tell me
where he lived.
TERRY: Yeah, well,
I don't blame him.
Colin just broke up
with his fiancée.
It's been really tough for him.
Did you two know each
other before tonight?
No.
Yes.
(LAUGHS) oh.
(THUNDER CRASHES, RUMBLES)
Drink some more wine.
(SAM CRYING OVER MONITOR)
(SIGHS) oh, God.
A mother's work is never done.
You two behave yourselves.
I'll be right back.
MEG: Okay.
Are you going to
behave yourself?
I don't know, Colin.
(WHISPERS) Behave yourself.
(LAUGHS)
I Will.
Where can I smoke
without getting wet?
The garage should be good.
It's just, uh...
It's the door at
the end of the hall.
♪ ♪
MEG: Hey.
Can I get one of those?
Sure, there you go.
You can have that one.
Thank you.
So, what's the deal?
What do you mean?
She's happily married.
Well, I guess, that depends
on how you define happily.
Ha. What does that mean?
It means you just never know what's
going on behind closed doors.
Is there something
going on between you two?
(SIGHS)
ls there?
Are you serious?
You two are having an affair?
I can't believe
she didn't tell me.
You know, sometimes
you like someone...
I don't... What?
You feel close to them.
But they don't feel
the same way about you.
You know?
She hasn't told me because she doesn't
think we're very close anymore?
What are you saying?
You talked about this?
When I got here, I didn't
even know you were coming.
She didn't want you to find out.
Not this way.
I wrecked my car and the
first place I came was here.
Because I knew Jeffrey
wasn't going to be here.
Hey, Colin.
You're so full of shit.
What? I said, "You're
so full of shit."
Terry is my best friend.
I know everything about her
and she knows
everything about me.
So, there's no way she would ever
have an affair and not tell me.
It doesn't add up.
And, you know what else doesn't add up?
You don't add up.
And I'm going to find out
exactly what's going on.
Hey, Terry! Terry!
Hey!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
♪ ♪
Where's Meg?
She changed her mind.
About?
Staying-
She left?
Yeah.
Well, was she upset?
No. But I don't know her.
I'm going to call her.
So, you lied?
Excuse me?
About your husband.
You lied.
So, where is he?
He went on a golf trip
with his father.
A golf trip?
Yeah.
I'm going to get some water. Are
you thirsty? Do you want anything?
No.
Yeah, I'm going to call Meg and the
tow truck, see if they're coming.
Are you sure she wasn't
upset when she left?
COLIN: Yeah.
But like I said,
I don't know her.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CLATTERING)
(VOICE TREMBLING) Colin?
(THUNDER CRASHING, RUMBLING)
Colin?
(GASPS)
COLIN: Up again?
Here we go.
Put her down!
Hey, Mom.
Do it again.
Again? All right.
Let's do it. Let's go.
And up! Touch the sky!
Whoa!
(RYAN AND COLIN LAUGHING)
No, Ryan.
Ryan, baby, you have to go to bed, okay?
(QUIETLY) Please.
Ryan and I are just having
some fun, that's all.
Aren't we, Ryan?
No. Ryan,
come on, bugaboo.
It's past your bedtime,
sweetie. Okay?
Please.
Terry, is there something wrong?
Did I do something wrong?
Go to bed, sweetheart, okay?
What is this?
Who gave you this?
No. Give it to me.
Ryan and I are friends.
I wanted her
to have something
real special, that's all.
Keep it.
Baby, go to sleep, okay?
Mommy and her friend will be downstairs.
All right, sweetheart?
Okay, bugaboo.
BYE, Ryan.
(LAUGHS QUIETLY)
I'll see you later, okay?
Kids.
They know, you know?
They have a real sense
of who's good, who's bad.
And your daughter, she has...
Shh. Okay.
Come on.
Come on, get up.
(GASPING)
Put the baby back down.
Please.
Put the baby back.
It's okay, baby.
Just go back to sleep.
Everything's going
to be okay, okay?
Don't you do anything
stupid like that again.
Do you understand me?
Yes. Mmm-hmm.
You do?
Come on.
In the bathroom.
Let's go. Come on!
Go on.
In the bathroom.
Get in.
What?
Stay right there.
♪ ♪
(GASPS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(WHIMPERS QUIETLY)
Come on. Get out.
Turn the lights on.
Are these your clothes? Yes.
Right here?
Yeah.
Put those on.
I'm fine.
Hey. Hey.
Put those clothes on.
I'm not going to tell you again.
Go on.
Turn around.
Stand up straight.
Please. Please.
Please, what?
You don't have to do this.
Don't flatter yourself.
Put your clothes on.
Fuck you.
What did you say?
I said, "Fuck you."
I would be real careful
if I were you.
You're not going to kill me.
If you were going to kill me,
you would have
done that already.
Maybe, this is some sick fantasy
you're playing out
against your ex-girlfriend.
What was it, your fiancée?
(WRY LAUGH)
Or your sick mother.
I don't know.
I don't care.
Can we just move it along?
Because I'm really getting sick
and tired of your
sadistic bullshit.
Terry, I would have thought with
all those brains you've got, DA,
you would have figured out the
game we're playing by now.
(SCOFFS) This is a game?
Oh, it's all a game.
Yeah, well,
I don't play, asshole.
Well, we're just getting
to the fun part.
Yeah, well, I'm sure
the fun is long over.
(COLIN SHOUTS, GROANS)
(THUNDER CRASHES, RUMBLES)
(WHISPERING) Answer the phone.
Hello. Yes, there's
an intruder in my house.
There's a crazy man in my house.
He's trying to kill me.
17 Creston Lane.
Please hurry!
(SCREAMS)
Put that down!
(SCREAMS) Okay. Okay.
(COLIN YELLS, GROANS IN PAIN)
Hey!
Hey! Hey, Stop!
Please, Colin.
I will shoot you!
Okay.
Do you understand?
Yes! Okay.
I will shoot you!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
I called 911. The police
are on their way.
It's over, Colin. Okay?
So, just leave, okay? All you
have to do is just leave.
Look. If you leave now,
you haven't hurt me,
you haven't hurt my family.
I don't have a reason
to carry this on,
Colin, but you've
got to go. Just go!
Go get the kids.
What do you mean?
Oh, you're absolutely right.
We've got to go.
No. I will call
the operator right now.
Go get the kids.
No, please. Please let...
I'll go get them! No, I'll go!
I'll get them.
(TERRY SHUSHING)
(SAM CRYING)
It's okay, baby.
(GENTLY) Oh, I know.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Go that way.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
COLIN: Don't stop.
Keep moving.
Come on, let's go.
(TERRY SOBBING)
Keep moving.
RYAN: Mommy.
COLIN: Get up!
Come on, get in the car.
(SAM CRYING) Let's go.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Are you going to tell me
where we're going?
Just keep straight.
(COLLIN MOANS)
You don't look so good.
You lost a lot of blood. You
need to get to a hospital.
I need you to shut up.
Just keep driving straight.
Just keep driving.
Don't even think about it.
You know, when the cops
get to my house
and see signs of struggle,
your blood all over my kitchen,
and an empty house,
they'll run my tags.
It's not too late.
If not a hospital, I can take
you somewhere, anywhere,
but you can't stay in this car
because they'll eventually
spot my tags and pull me over.
I'm not going to warn you again.
I need you to shut the hell up.
(DEEP INHALE, EXHALE)
COLIN: Shit.
(SIREN WHOOPS)
Shit. God damn it.
(SIREN WAILS)
What do you want me to do?
Pull over.
Stay calm.
What are you doing?
Get off me.
No, no. Please. No.
Come on.
No.
It's just a little motivation
to keep your mouth shut.
I won't do anything, I promise.
Please put my baby back.
Just shut up!
(SAM FUSSING)
I hope my APB hasn't
crossed state lines.
Your what?
Just keep your mouth shut.
I have nothing to lose.
You stand to lose it all.
I won't do anything, I promise.
Please put him down.
Just be smart.
License and registration,
please.
RYAN: Mommy?
Okay.
Mommy.
Uh, everything's okay, baby.
Your baby needs
to be in a car seat.
Oh, he was, he was, but we took
him out just as we stopped.
He was crying.
He's gone to sleep now.
RYAN: Mommy.
What happened to your head?
What now?
Your head.
What happened to it?
Oh, I was, uh, fixing the windows
in the storm, but it fought back.
RYAN: Mommy.
(CHUCKLING)
Right back.
Is everything
all right, Officer?
Mommy, where is Daddy?
I want to go home.
Ma'am, could you step
out of the car, please?
Is everything all right, ma'am?
Yeah, everything's fine.
Were you trying to signal me
with your headlights back there?
You flashed your brights
at me back there.
Ma'am.
No, I, uh...
I, uh, was reaching
for the radio
and my hand must have slipped
and hit the brights.
Honestly, it wouldn't be the first time.
I'm really sorry.
Who's the man in
the car with you?
The man in the car?
Who is he?
Well, Officer, um...
(SIGHS ANXIOUSLY)
It's kind of embarrassing.
My husband,
he's out of town.
And you must think I'm awful.
Look, lady, it's
none of my business.
But you might do whatever you're
doing without the kids around.
Do you know what I'm saying?
TERRY: Yes, Officer.
I'm really sorry.
Are you sure
everything's all right?
You keep looking
back at the car.
Is there something
you need to tell me?
(WHISPERING) I can't
say anything right now.
All right, ma'am.
Have a nice night.
(WHISPERING) Don't move.
COLIN: Stay right there!
(TERRY SHRIEKING)
Get over here!
Right here.
(GUNSHOT)
He could have been alive
if it wasn't for you.
(SOBBING)
It's your fault!
I tell you to do
something, you do it.
Do you understand me?
I will kill you.
(SAM CRYING)
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Yes!
Go on and get in the car.
Get around there.
You're at my mercy.
Do you understand me?
You are going to do
exactly as you're told.
Get in the car.
Let's go.
(SAM CRYING)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Why are you doing this?
You'll see.
Pull in here.
This house right here.
Pull in.
There you go.
Pull straight in.
And I want you to back up
on the side right here.
Back it up a little bit.
(THUNDER CRACKS, RUMBLES)
That's right.
Keep going.
That's good.
Grab the kids, let's go.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Go on.
Put the kids in here.
TERRY: We're just going to have
a little sleepover, okay, baby?
Listen.
(KNOCKS ON BUREAU) Come on.
I love you.
Why are you doing this?
Shut up. Go on.
Through the door
right there. Come on.
I want you to go in
that bathroom over there.
Find a first aid kit.
Patch me up.
Come on.
I don't know where a first aid kit is.
Just keep looking.
There's something in there.
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Terry, meet Alexis.
Alexis, Terry.
You should have seen
the look on her face.
Life draining from her eyes.
And after all I did for her.
Come on, what have you got?
(THUNDER CRACKING, RUMBLING)
(CAR ALARM WAILING)
Give me the key.
Okay.
Give me the key. Come on! Okay.
(CAR ALARM
CONTINUES WAILING)
Shit!
Come here. Get on your knees.
Why?
On your knees. Take your coat off.
Take your coat off.
There you go. Put your
hands behind your back.
Now.
There you go.
Ow!
You stay right here.
Ow! (GASPS, GROANS)
I don't want you running around.
Right here.
Stay right there. Legs out. Ow!
(CAR ALARM
CONTINUES WAILING)
Please don't.
Shh.
Ow! Shut up. Just shut up.
(CAR ALARM
CONTINUES WAILING)
(SOBBING)
(ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
Hello? Hello?
JEFFREY: Finally, babe.
I'm at the hotel.
I've been here all night.
I left you, like, five messages.
Where are you?
Jeffrey?
Alexis.
Alexis?
COLIN:
"Didn't want to wake you,
"'cause you looked
so beautiful sleeping."
17...
TERRY: 17 Creston Lane
COLIN: Creston
TERRY: Lane.
COLIN: Lane.
Oh, my God.
(CAR ALARM CONTINUES
WAILING IN DISTANCE)
JEFFREY: Alexis?
I'm at the hotel.
She's dead, Jeffrey.
Your goddamn girlfriend is dead.
Terry.
Call the police.
Wait a minute.
Jeffrey, call
the goddamn police.
(PHONE LINE RINGING) (CAR
ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: You've reached
911 emergency response.
We are receiving a high
volume of calls in this area.
Ryan, baby.
Come on.
(CAR ALARM STOPS)
Shit!
♪ ♪
Shh.
Okay, Ryan. I need you to
stay right here, okay?
Be very quiet and wait for
Mommy to come back, okay?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
♪ ♪
(WIND WHOOSHING, GUSTING)
(KNIFE CLATTERS)
♪ ♪
(COLLIN GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
You bitch!
Jeffrey called!
What?
Jeffrey called.
He's on his way.
I know why you killed her.
The affair she was
having with my husband.
Where is he? This is about
getting revenge with Jeffrey.
Where is he?
Mommy.
(COLLIN GROANS)
Run, Ryan, run!
(COLIN YELLS)
(GUNSHOT)
Where are you going? Come here.
Get off of me.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(COLIN YELLS)
(TERRY SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOT)
(GROANS)
(TERRY YELLING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(COLIN YELLS)
(BODY THUDS)
(SIREN APPROACHING)
♪ ♪
(SIREN WAILING)
Excuse me.
What's your business?
I'm sorry, sir.
You can't go in there.
JEFFREY: That's my wife. Terry!
TERRY! OFFICER: Hold up.
Terry.
Baby, I'm sorry.
(SOBS)
Listen to me.
It's not what you think.
It didn't mean anything to me.
Baby.
Terry, it didn't mean...
(SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE)
♪ ♪
(MOVERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Great. That goes on
the first level. Thanks.
So, it looks like you'll
be right at home in there.
Oh, it's perfect.
If you have any questions,
you know how to reach me.
Oh, everything is
going to be great.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
WOMAN: Come on, Ryan.
TERRY: Are you taking
them to the park? Yeah.
Great. I'll walk over on
my way to the court house.
Come on, baby. How do you
like the house, bugaboo?
Yes.
Yay. (LAUGHS)
♪ Let us move on
♪ This is short
and it will pass
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ Every voice that is lifted
♪ River and some pain
♪ Show us now, and let
love not be chained
♪ We should feel what we
can stand, let us be alive
♪ Show enough, and
we've done all we can
♪ Let us that are frozen
get to see
♪ In all its glory
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ And let all that
is lost be forgotten
♪ And it will pass
♪ So let all that
is lost be forgotten
♪ Let us move on
♪ Like the waters
in the open sea
♪ When tribulation come
all we can say is hopefully
♪ And yesterday you could probably
say there's no hope for me
♪ But today
I'm overly dedicated
♪ I'm posed to be a testimony
for broken hearts in the city
♪ You're either crash landing
or planning on flyin' with me
♪ Misery love standing
behind its company
.l' Well, vividly I could see that
your feelings would like to dwell
♪ On our past encounters,
reaching over the counter
♪ Told me that it's appealing
to pop a pill that's a downer
♪ I heard emotions
burn deep
♪ I heard when you fall out
of love, the drop is steep
♪ I heard when you see a dove,
that's what you try to be
♪ Got these burdens under my
wings, but I'm still free
♪ Cause I can make the
decision to let it all go away
♪ Before I ever run astray, I
looked you in your eye and say
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ Let us move on
Let us move on
♪ For this is short
and it will pass
♪ And it will pass I
(MUSIC ENDS)
♪ [ENGLISH - US - SDH - BOZXPHD] ♪