radio announcer:
...WITH TRAFFIC BACKED UP
AT THE HOLLAND TUNNEL,
HEADING INTO LOWER MANHATTAN.
YOU'RE LISTENING
TO THE WAKE-UP CALL ON WXLM,
NEW JERSEY'S NUMBER ONE
TALK RADIO STATION.
MEMORIAL SERVICES
ARE BEING HELD TONIGHT
AT ST. ANTHONY'S CHURCH
IN JERSEY CITY
FOR REGGIE SUAREZ.
[helicopter thumping]
THE 22-YEAR-OLD NATIONAL
GUARDSMAN FROM HOBOKEN
WAS KILLED LAST WEEK BY
A ROADSIDE BOMB JUST OUTSIDE...
[helicopter drowns out radio]
[automatic gunfire]
- HONEY. HONEY?
I GOT YOU NEW UNDERPANTS.
OPRAH SAYS THAT MOST WOMEN
WEAR THEM TOO SMALL.
WHEN I HEARD THAT,
I THOUGHT OF YOU RIGHT AWAY.
- YOU GOT ME BIG GIRL UNDERWEAR.
- MIKE CALLED LAST NIGHT.
- CAN YOU GET
OUT OF MY ROOM?
- ARE YOU GONNA CALL HIM BACK?
- NO.
- OH, RONNIE, GROW UP.
HE'S A MAN. YOU WERE GONE.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MUCH YOUR FATHER
AND I SPENT ON THAT WEDDING?
[door slams]
-  I'M A LITTLE BIT ANXIOUS
I'M A LITTLE BIT SCARED
OF YOU HALF OF THE TIME
[tires screech, crash]
[car alarm blaring]
[woman screams]
- HELP ME, PLEASE, SOMEBODY!
DID SOMEBODY CALL 911?
I'M BLEEDING!
I NEED A DOCTOR NOW!
- I'M A DOCTOR.
- MY HEAD, IT HURTS.
IS IT GONNA SCAR?
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST APPLY PRESSURE.
- OH, MY--
- DAVID?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH HIM?
DAVID! WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING TO HIM?
- I THINK THAT HE MAY HAVE
A TENSION PNEUMOTHORAX.
YOU WANT TO JUMP IN HERE?
- GEE, YOU KNOW, I'M
JUST REALLY A DERMATOLOGIST.
I MOSTLY DO SKIN PEELS.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH HIM?
WAKE UP, BABY!
- HEY, DERMATOLOGIST,
I NEED YOU TO GET ME
A NEEDLE OR A KNIFE AND
SOMETHING TO STERILIZE WITH.
NOW!
- OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
- WHA--
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING TO HIM?
WHO ARE YOU?
- HEY, LADY, LISTEN.
YOUR BOYFRIEND--
- FIANCE!
- OKAY, FIANCE.
HIS CHEST
IS FILLING UP WITH AIR.
IF I DON'T RELIEVE THE PRESSURE
IN THE NEXT 30 SECONDS,
HE WILL GO INTO CARDIAC ARREST
AND DIE.
NOW HELP ME PULL HIS SHIRT UP.
- IT'S OKAY, BABY.
- DERMATOLOGIST, HOW WE COMING
WITH THAT KNIFE?
- YES. I'M HERE, I'M HERE.
- YOU'RE DOING GOOD.
- THEY'RE ON THEIR WAY.
- OKAY, WHAT NEXT?
- NOW I MAKE A HOLE
IN HIS FIFTH INTERCOSTAL SPACE.
WE'RE GONNA NEED A CHEST TUBE.
HAND ME THAT STRAW.
- WHAT? MAKE A HOLE?
AAH!
[air sputtering]
[deep breath]
[siren wailing]
- HE'S BREATHING.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN TO DO THAT?
- IRAQ.
- WHAT DO WE GOT?
- PATIENT HAD
A TENSION PNEUMOTHORAX.
I DID A NEEDLE DECOMPRESSION
AT THE SCENE.
GET HIM UP TO TRAUMA BAY.
HE NEEDS AN X-RAY.
- WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON HERE?
WHO ORDERED ALL THIS?
- ME.
- ON WHAT AUTHORITY?
YOU'RE A NURSE, OKAY?
A NURSE?
I'LL HANDLE IT.
- YOU'RE NOT A DOCTOR?
AFTER ALL THAT,
YOU'RE JUST SOME STUPID NURSE.
IF HE DIES, IF HE HAS
SO MUCH AS A SCAR,
I SWEAR TO GOD,
I WILL SUE YOU,
THE HOSPITAL, AND THE CITY!
[heart monitor beeping]
- SO I GUESS I SHOULD HAVE
JUST LET THE GUY DIE?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
- YEAH. THAT'S WHAT WE WANT
HERE AT MERCY HOSPITAL--
TO LET THE GUY DIE.
I BELIEVE THAT'S WHAT IT SAYS
ON THE BROCHURES.
CASE SHOULD HAVE BEEN
IMMEDIATELY TURNED OVER
TO DR. HARRIS.
- HARRIS.
PATIENT'S GOT A BENDY STRAW
STICKING OUT OF HIS CHEST
THAT'S KEEPING HIM ALIVE,
AND ALL THAT HE'S WORRIED ABOUT
IS HIS STUPID EGO.
- YOU MAKE THESE THINGS
PERSONAL, VERONICA.
- NO, I DON'T.
- WHAT ABOUT THE TIME
YOU CALLED HIM A TESTICLE HEAD?
- SCROTUM HEAD.
I CALLED HIM A SCROTUM HEAD.
AND I DIDN'T KNOW THAT
HE WAS STANDING RIGHT THERE.
- I WAS IN A WAR, TOO, YOU KNOW?
HAVE YOU EVER THOUGHT ABOUT
TALKING TO SOMEBODY ABOUT IT?
- I DON'T NEED TO TALK
TO ANYBODY ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE I'M ON DELICIOUS PAXIL.
- WORKING LIKE A CHARM,
I SEE.
[siren wailing]
- SPARE SOME CHANGE?
- OH.
ENERGY BAR?
[thud]
-  RIDING THROUGH THE CITY
ON MY BIKE ALL DAY
'CAUSE THE FILTH
TOOK AWAY MY LICENSE
IT DOESN'T GET ME DOWN,
AND I FEEL OKAY
- HEY, SONIA, YOU GET
THAT MIX C.D. I MADE FOR YOU?
-  EVERYTHING
SEEMS TO LOOK AS IT SHOULD
[cell phone rings]
BUT I WONDER
WHAT GOES ON BEHIND DOORS
- IS THAT THE LAWYER?
- MM-HMM.
- BUT YOU'RE NOT GONNA ANSWER.
- IT'S CALLED DISCIPLINE.
- YOU LEAVING THE LAWYER
HANGING?
- IT'S CALLED DISCIPLINE.
- I BROUGHT DOUGHNUTS.
LITTLE APPRECIATION FOR
THE BEST NURSES IN THE STATE.
- WOULD YOU LOOK
AT THIS SWEET BOY?
- OH, WHAT IN THE HOLY HELL?
- OF ALL THE SMOCKS
IN ALL THE WORLD,
AND SHE HAD TO WALK IN
WEARING THAT.
- HELLO, NURSES.
THIS IS CHLOE PAYNE.
SHE'S STARTING TODAY.
I KNOW YOU'LL TAKE
GOOD CARE OF HER.
[sniffs]
I HAVE TO LEAD ROUNDS.
[call button beeping]
- HI. UM, I JUST WANT TO SAY,
I'M REALLY, REALLY EXCITED
TO BE HERE.
I JUST GOT MY MASTER'S
FROM THE UNIVERSITY
OF PENNSYLVANIA,
AND I AM SO PSYCHED--
- HOLD THAT THOUGHT, FELICITY.
VERONICA, IT'S MRS. BORGHOUSE.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAG TEAM.
- I'LL GO WITH YOU.
- CAN I COME?
WHO'S MRS. BORGHOUSE?
- 60-YEAR-OLD WOMAN
WITH END-STAGE LIVER CANCER.
SHE'S BEEN CIRCLING
THE DRAIN FOR MONTHS,
BUT HER FAMILY
WON'T LET HER GIVE UP.
- AW.
POOR THING.
- MM.
- OH!
- AAH!
- I CAN'T EAT THIS FOOD.
I'M IN PAIN, AND I'M PRETTY SURE
I HAVE A BEDSORE.
- OH, NO, YOUR SMOCK.
- IT'S OKAY.
I BROUGHT EXTRAS.
- YOU NURSES, WHAT ARE YOU
GOOD FOR ANYWAY?
- WELL, WE DO TRY AND KEEP
THE DOCTORS FROM KILLING YOU.
- I HAVE TO GO
TO THE BATHROOM.
- OH.
- HAS SHE BEEN FEBRILE TODAY?
- NO, NO FEVER.
- HEY, WHAT ARE THESE DOING
IN SOME OLD GUY'S ROOM?
I BOUGHT THESE FOR YOU.
- YOU CAN'T COME
TO MY WORK ANYMORE.
- IT'S A HOSPITAL.
MAYBE I GOT THE FLU.
HEY, SON.
- HEY, MIKE.
- WOULD YOU LIKE SOME FLOWERS?
- LEAVE ME OUT OF THIS.
DO I REALLY HAVE TO LIE HERE
IN THE SAME ROOM
WITH THIS 12-YEAR-OLD
COVERED IN MY URINE?
- LET'S GET YOU CLEANED UP.
- YOU CAN'T BE HERE.
- [laughs]
YOU BELIEVE HER?
- IF I WERE YOU, I'D LOOK
FOR GREENER PASTURES.
- I KNOW, HUH?
I BEEN BARKING UP THIS TREE
SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING LATER?
- I THINK LATER
THEY'RE PUTTING IN A CATHETER.
BUT, SERIOUSLY,
HAVE YOU GOT A JOB?
- YES, MA'AM,
I'M A CONTRACTOR.
I DO ALL RIGHT, TOO.
- THIS IS A PICTURE
OF MY DAUGHTER.
SHE FILLS OUT A SWEATER BETTER
THAN THIS UNGRATEFUL JACKASS,
AND SHE WANTS KIDS.
- OH, OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
MIKE, WE'RE SEPARATED.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO BE MORE CLEAR.
YOU NEED TO LEAVE ME ALONE.
- OKAY, OKAY, I'M SORRY.
I'LL CALL YOU?
- FINE.
NO.
NO! NOT FINE!
WHAT--WHAT DID I JUST SAY?
- NORMALLY,
WE LIKE FOR NEW NURSES
TO HAVE MORE EXPERIENCE,
BUT YOU GRADUATED
TOP OF YOUR CLASS.
ALSO, WE'RE DESPERATE.
- OH, I WON'T DISAPPOINT.
- GOOD.
HERE'S A LITTLE JOB FOR YOU.
MR. WEINTRAUB.
HE'S DEAD.
TURN OFF ALL THE MACHINES.
[heart monitor beeping]
- BUT HE'S STILL ALIVE.
LOOK, HIS HEART IS BEATING.
- NO, HE'S GONE.
TURN OFF ALL THE MACHINES,
CALL THE MORGUE TO GET HIM,
THEN WE'LL FINISH
YOUR START PAPERWORK.
- THAT'S ENOUGH OF THIS!
- COME ON, YOU! COME ON!
I AIN'T DONE
WITH YOU YET!
I AIN'T DONE WITH YOU YET!
YOU'RE DEAD, BITCH!
- HEY, SHUT UP!
HEY, LEAVE THE KID ALONE!
- OKAY, COPS, WAIT OUT THERE.
- HOW'D YOU KNOW I'M A COP?
- IT WAS A LUCKY GUESS.
- HOW ABOUT WE SEPARATE THE GUYS
WHO JUST SHOT EACH OTHER?
- ACTUALLY, I WAS THE ONE
WHO SHOT HIM.
- WHERE'S MY DRIP?
LEG'S ON FIRE!
- SHUT UP, CRYBABY!
- KEEP RUNNING YOUR MOUTH!
- HEY.
DON'T CALL MY MOM, OKAY?
- HOW OLD ARE YOU?
- 15.
- 15. WHAT ARE YOU DOING
GETTING YOURSELF SHOT?
WE'RE GONNA CALL YOUR MOM.
SHE'LL WANT TO BE HERE
WHEN YOU GET OUT OF SURGERY.
IT'S GONNA BE OKAY.
- I'LL BE BACK AT YOU,
I SWEAR!
- SHUT UP!
- HEY.
HEY.
HEY, MY GUY'S CODING!
- WHERE'S DR. WHITTAKER?
- RIGHT HERE.
- ONE AND TWO AND THREE...
- CHARGE TO 360.
[defibrillator buzzing]
- AAH!
SON OF A--
- YOU FORGOT TO SAY "CLEAR."
- I GOT A PULSE.
- COME ON.
- THAT WHITTAKER GUY.
- OH, I KNOW.
WHY DO THE NICE ONES
ALWAYS HAVE TO SUCK?
SHOULD WE TELL HARRIS?
- NO. HARRIS ISN'T GONNA
LISTEN TO US.
JUST LET THE OTHER NURSES
KNOW TO WATCH HIM.
YOU WANT TO GET A DRINK?
- YEAH.
[heart monitor beeping]
- OH, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO, WE DON'T HAVE TO.
- WE HAVE TO.
- [whispering] WE CAN JUST GO.
WE CAN JUST START WALKING.
- HEY, WE'RE GONNA GO
GET A DRINK.
DO YOU WANT TO COME?
- OH, I'D LOVE TO, BUT, UM...
FIRST, I JUST HAVE TO KILL
MR. WEINTRAUB.
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
- [gasps]
- TIME OF DEATH, 1807.
- WANT TO GET THAT DRINK NOW?
-  I LIKE TO BREAK IT DOWN
FOR THE BOYS
- OH, MAN.
- 12:00.
- OH. WHY DON'T WE
JUST GO TALK TO HIM?
- BECAUSE, HE'S A UNICORN, OKAY?
HE'S A MAGICAL CREATURE.
- GIRL, HE'S FOR LOOKING AT,
NOT FOR TALKING TO.
[cell phone ringing]
- OH, MY GOD.
IS THAT THE LAWYER AGAIN?
YOU LIKE HIM.
ANSWER THE PHONE ALREADY.
- IS HE NICE?
- WELL, HIS SEVEN-FIGURE INCOME
IS NICE.
- THAT'S NOT WHY SHE LIKES HIM.
- OH, YES, IT IS.
I AM DONE WITH BROKE-ASS MEN.
DONE.
NO MORE GUYS
BEHIND ON THEIR CAR PAYMENTS,
NO MORE GOING DUTCH,
AND NO MORE LOSERS
WHO THINK YOU OWE THEM SEX
FOR DINNER AT BENNIGAN'S.
- WELL, YOU PROBABLY ORDERED
AN APPETIZER.
- I OWE A GUY SEX
IF I ORDER AN APPETIZER?
- HEY, I DIDN'T MAKE THE RULES.
- I DON'T KNOW
HOW YOU GUYS DO IT.
I MEAN, THAT WAS SO SAD TODAY
WITH MR. WEINTRAUB.
- OH, THAT'S NOT SAD.
- YES, IT WAS.
HE DIED ALONE.
- YOU WANT TO SEE SAD,
YOU GO DOWN
TO THE PEDIATRIC BURN UNIT.
YOU TREAT
A SIX-YEAR-OLD IRAQI KID
WHO GOT HIS ARMS BLOWN OFF
'CAUSE HE THOUGHT A BOMB
WAS A TOY.
OR HOW ABOUT THE SOLDIER
WHO LOST BOTH OF HIS ARMS
AND A LEG AND HAS TO WEAR
A COLOSTOMY BAG.
WE FIXED HIM UP, ALL RIGHT.
NOBODY KNOWS HOW A GUY
A GUY WITH NO ARMS
IS SUPPOSED TO MANAGE
A COLOSTOMY BAG,
BUT WE DID IT.
THAT'S SAD.
A 75-YEAR-OLD MAN
WITH CANCER?
THAT'S A TRIP TO CLUB MED.
I GOTTA GO.
- LIGHT UP A ROOM
AND LEAVE.
- SHE WAS IN IRAQ?
WOW.
[television playing]
- [snoring]
- [whispering]
DON'T--OH, BOBBY!
YOU SCARED ME.
- LEANNE KICKED ME OUT AGAIN.
- SHH. YOU'RE GONNA
WAKE UP DAD.
- YEAH, RIGHT.
[loudly] HEY, DAD!
THE HOUSE IS ON FIRE!
- [snoring]
- MOM FELL DOWN THE STAIRS!
VERONICA'S GOT A NEW BOYFRIEND,
AND HE'S BLACK!
- [grunts]
- MOM'S PASSED OUT UPSTAIRS.
DRANK LIKE HALF A GALLON
OF WINE.
- COUPLE OF SAD ALCOHOLICS.
HEY, YOU WANT A DRINK?
- GOD, YES.
WELL, THAT WON'T DO.
MM-MM. SHE KEEPS ANOTHER ONE
IN THE WASHER.
- SHE'S LIKE A SQUIRREL.
IT'S EMPTY.
- DAD'S WORKBENCH.
- OH, IT'S ON.
- HOW YOU DOING?
- I'M, UH...
I'M NOT SO GOOD, BOBBY.
I'M A LITTLE
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
AND MAYBE I HAVE
A DRINKING PROBLEM.
- [laughs]
SO GET BACK WITH MIKE.
- OH, MY GOD!
HE'S A CHEATER.
- PEOPLE IN GLASS HOUSES.
YOU TOLD ME ABOUT THAT GUY
IN IRAQ.
REMEMBER
AT MOM'S BIRTHDAY PARTY--
- SHUT UP. I ONLY TOLD YOU THAT
BECAUSE WE WERE WASTED,
AND I DIDN'T THINK
YOU WERE GONNA REMEMBER.
- WELL, I DO REMEMBER.
- WELL, SHUT UP ABOUT IT, OKAY?
HE CHEATED FIRST.
BESIDES, I WAS AT WAR.
I WAS FIGHTING
FOR MY COUNTRY.
I COULD HAVE DIED.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER SEEN M.A.S.H.?
WHY DO YOU HATE AMERICA?
- YOU'RE A HYPOCRITE.
YOU FOUGHT IN THE WAR.
IT DOESN'T GIVE YOU PERMISSION
TO BE A DICK.
- SHUT UP.
- IT'S TRUE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I TAKE IT BACK.
YOU DON'T DESERVE MIKE.
- I'M SERIOUS, BOBBY, STOP IT.
- I'M SERIOUS!
- HE SLEPT AROUND
WHILE YOU WERE GONE,
BUT HE NEVER FELL IN LOVE.
CAN YOU SAY THE SAME THING?
[bottle shatters]
- SO WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO FIRST?
- UM, MAKE SURE
HIS VITALS ARE STABLE.
- YEAH.
- I SCHEDULED ANOTHER SURGERY
TO REMOVE THE BULLET
FROM HIS HIP.
- UM, WHAT'S THIS RASH
ON HIS CHEST?
- WAS THAT THERE BEFORE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- HE GOT SHOT THROUGH THE HIP.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE WE SHOULD BE
WORRIED ABOUT A FAT EMBOLISM.
WE COULD GIVE HIM HEPARIN.
- HEPARIN?
HEPARIN'S A BLOOD THINNER.
THAT'S NO INDICATED
FOR F.E.S.
- WE USED IT
ON THE FRONT LINES.
THERE ARE STUDIES THAT SHOW
HEPARIN CAN HELP.
- TELL YOU WHAT,
I'LL LOOK INTO IT.
LET'S GIVE HIM
A COUPLE MORE HOURS,
THEN BRING HIM DOWN
TO THE FLOOR.
- ANGEL, CAN YOU HELP?
MR. EGGERTON GOT OUT OF BED.
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- YEAH, SURE.
- [moans]
MOM?
[gasps]
[gasping]
- HELP!
HELP!
HELP! HELP!
- [gasping]
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- HE CAN'T BREATHE!
- WHAT'S HE AT?
- 79 WHEN I GOT HERE.
- BLOOD PRESSURE?
[ventilator whooshing]
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU TOLD ME HE WAS STABLE.
- YOUR SON HAD AN EMBOLISM,
MS. WASHINGTON.
UM...
WE'VE DONE EVERYTHING
THAT WE CAN,
BUT HE'S BEEN DEPRIVED
OF OXYGEN FOR TOO LONG.
AND WE'VE RUN SOME TESTS,
AND HE'S JUST NOT RESPONDING.
I'M SO SORRY TO TELL YOU
THAT HE'S BRAIN DEAD.
- [crying] NO!
- I'M SO SORRY.
I'M SO SORRY.
- NO, HE'S NOT GONE.
PLEASE.
- I'M SO VERY SORRY.
- TELL ME HE'S NOT GONE.
- I'M SORRY, MRS. WASHINGTON.
- LOOK WHO IT IS.
HELLO.
HEY, YOU BETTER WATCH OUT
FOR THIS GUY.
LET ME KNOW
WHEN YOU COME IN HERE.
- HE'S UNCONSCIOUS
AND HANDCUFFED TO THE BED.
I THINK I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
- WHY ARE YOU SO MEAN?
MANY WOMEN ARE
INTO THE COP FANTASY.
- I'M SEEING SOMEBODY.
- COURSE YOU ARE.
WHAT'S HE DO?
- HE'S A LAWYER,
ABOUT TO BECOME PARTNER.
- BEDROCK OF SOCIETY.
- AT LEAST
HE DOESN'T CARRY A GUN.
OH, YOU THINK YOU'RE
SO DIFFERENT FROM THIS GUY.
YOU'RE ALL JUST LITTLE BOYS
RUNNING AROUND WITH GUNS,
AND NONE OF YOU
MAKE ENOUGH MONEY.
- WELL, NOW WE'RE
GETTING SOMEWHERE.
YOU NEED A DUDE WITH MONEY,
I'M NOT YOUR GUY,
'CAUSE I GOT CREDIT CARD BILLS
OUT THE ASS...
- I BET YOU DO.
- MY CAR'S PROBABLY
- GETTING REPO'D RIGHT NOW.
- I'M SURE IT IS.
- I WAS JUST GONNA ASK YOU
IF I COULD BORROW FIVE BUCKS.
LOOK AT THAT SMILE.
[cell phone chimes]
- OH, MY GOD.
I GOTTA GO. EXCUSE ME.
HEY, THE LAWYER
JUST INVITED ME
TO THE COSTUME INSTITUTE BALL
WITH HIM.
THAT IS A HOT TICKET!
- STOP IT. I TOLD YOU.
- HEY, DR. WHITTAKER.
MARCUS WASHINGTON
HAD AN EMBOLISM.
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
- YEAH, I HEARD.
- DID YOU TRY THE HEPARIN?
- THAT WAS A HAIL MARY,
AND WE BOTH KNOW IT.
WHAT WAS THAT FOR?
- NOW IS WHEN YOU THROW
THE HAIL MARY,
YOU UNBELIEVABLE MORON!
WHEN YOU ARE TRYING
TO SAVE A KID'S LIFE!
- THAT WOMAN IS GOING
TO SUE THIS HOSPITAL.
I WOULD IF I WERE HER.
- GOOD. THAT BOY IS DEAD
BECAUSE OF WHITTAKER.
- YOU HAVE NO IDEA
THAT'S TRUE.
- VERONICA, WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT YOU RIGHT NOW.
YOU TOOK A HORRIBLE SITUATION,
AND YOU MADE IT WORSE!
NOW, WHO DID YOU HELP
WITH YOUR LITTLE OUTBURST?
HMM?
YOU HAPPY?
YOU FEEL RIGHTEOUS?
- NO.
- YOU POINT FINGERS
AT EVERYBODY ELSE,
BUT YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO CAN'T CONTROL HERSELF.
I WILL FIRE YOU.
DON'T THINK I WON'T.
[upbeat guitar music]
- HEY, THERE SHE IS--
VERONICA.
- COME ON IN.
WE'RE HAVING GIN RICKEYS.
- YOU SHOULD HAVE ONE!
- COME ON, HAVE A GIN RICKEY.
- I DON'T WANT
A GIN RICKEY.
- WHEN DID YOU TURN
INTO SUCH A PILL?
- MOM!
- THAT IS SO WEIRD,
SAYING NO TO A GIN RICKEY.
- STOP SAYING GIN RICKEY.
- GIN RICKEY.
both: GIN RICKEY.
- COME ON, RONNIE.
VERONICA.
YOU WANT TO TAKE A RIDE?
- NO.
- GIN RICKEY!
- COME ON, HURRY UP.
- MIKE, I CAN'T SEE.
- [laughs]
THAT'S THE POINT, BABE.
- I WANT TO TAKE
THIS THING OFF.
- WHY? I MADE
A NICE SURPRISE FOR YOU.
- BECAUSE IT'S STUPID,
THAT'S WHY.
- CAN YOU JUST PLAY ALONG?
- WHERE WE GOING, A STRIP CLUB?
DO YOU HAVE TO HAVE
A PROBLEM WITH EVERYTHING?
- DO NOT MAKE IT LIKE I
HAVE A PROBLEM WITH EVERYTHING.
THE LAST TIME YOU DID THIS,
WE ENDED UP
WITH AN ABOVE-GROUND POOL.
- MIKE?
WHAT DID YOU DO?
OUR HOUSE.
- I BOUGHT THE LITTLE LOT
NEXT DOOR.
YOU REMEMBER
THAT NICE OLD LADY, MAE?
DEAD!
I WAS GONNA FIX IT UP
TO SELL IT,
BUT THEN I THOUGHT...
ADD A COUPLE MORE ROOMS,
MAYBE WE MIGHT NEED 'EM.
- ARE YOU DEAF?
THERE IS NO "US."
- OKAY, I GIVE UP!
FORGET IT.
- WHAT WAS THAT?
- YOUR ENGAGEMENT RING.
NICE REFLEXES.
- ARE YOU CRAZY?
WE'RE STILL PAYING
THAT THING OFF.
MIKE, YOU KNOW,
IT'S NOT THAT I'M NOT TOUCHED.
- I KNOW THE ARMY PAID
FOR YOUR EDUCATION,
AND YOU DIDN'T
HAVE ANY CHOICE,
BUT I TOOK IT PERSONALLY
WHEN YOU LEFT,
LIKE YOU COULDN'T WAIT
TO GET AWAY FROM ME.
- YOU NEVER TOLD ME THAT.
- I WAS STUPID AND INSECURE,
BUT I LOVE YOU.
I WANT TO BE WITH YOU,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE?
-  LONG WAYS DOWN
- I THINK YOU LOVE ME.
NOBODY KNOWS YOU
LIKE I KNOW YOU.
I'M THE GUY, OKAY?
- MIKE, I AM ALL MESSED UP
RIGHT NOW.
- NO MORE THAN ANYONE ELSE.
MAYBE THIS
IS WHAT MARRIAGE IS.
- TWO PEOPLE TORTURING
EACH OTHER UNTIL THEY DIE?
- YEAH, AND KIDS AND FRIENDS
AND GOING OUT TO DINNER
AND GREAT SEX.
WHAT'S SO BAD ABOUT THIS?
-  OH, THAT'S HOW IT FEELS
I WOULD UNDERSTAND
YOUR HEART
IF I COULD FEEL IT
- LET ME ASK YOU
ONE MORE TIME.
-  I WOULD UNDERSTAND
YOUR HEART
IF I COULD FEEL IT
- WILL YOU COME
BACK TO ME, RONNIE?
-  I WOULD UNDERSTAND
YOUR HEART
- YEAH.
YES, OKAY.
- THIS ONE.
- NO, THE BLUE ONE FOR SURE.
- REALLY?
- YEAH.
- OH, I LIKE THE RED ONE.
- IS THAT HELLO KITTY
ON YOUR SMOCK?
- YEAH. WHAT?
- I THINK THE BLUE.
- MM-HMM.
- WHAT IS THAT?
- MIKE AND I HAVE DECIDED
TO GET BACK TOGETHER.
IT'S GOOD.
MY PARENTS ARE THROWING US
A PARTY AT DELANEY'S.
YOU SHOULD ALL COME.
- OH, VERONICA. GOOD.
THIS IS DR. SANDS.
- HELLO.
- HE'S JUST JOINED OUR STAFF.
WE'RE VERY LUCKY
TO HAVE HIM.
HE WAS ON HIS WAY
TO SEE MS. BORGHOUSE.
MAYBE YOU COULD TAG ALONG?
- SURE.
- OKAY.
- HELLO. DR. SANDS.
I HEAR WE'RE PERFORMING
SOME SURGERY.
- MOM, DON'T YOU WANT
TO MEET THE DOCTOR?
- HAVEN'T I MET THEM ALL?
- WELL, NOW IS
THE TIME FOR QUESTIONS,
IF YOU HAVE ANY.
NO? OKAY, WELL...
- SOMETIMES PATIENTS
FIND IT HELPFUL
TO KNOW THE GOAL
OF A SURGERY LIKE THIS.
SINCE THE CANCER HAS SPREAD
TO HER OTHER ORGANS,
WHAT ARE WE HOPING
TO GAIN?
- HOPE.
HAVEN'T YOU HEARD OF HOPE?
- OH, IT'S A GOOD QUESTION,
UH...
WE ARE TRYING
TO BUY HER SOME MORE TIME.
- HOW MUCH TIME?
AND WHAT ABOUT RECOVERY?
AND WILL THERE BE
MORE CHEMO?
- YES. YOU MAY BE LOOKING
AT MORE CHEMO.
- FINE.
WE'LL TRY EVERYTHING.
- OKAY.
WE'LL SCHEDULE THE SURGERY
FOR EARLY NEXT WEEK.
YOU DON'T THINK THAT
SHE SHOULD HAVE THE SURGERY?
- HEY, I'M JUST THE NURSE.
- SHE WANTS TO TRY
ALL AVAILABLE TREATMENT.
- THAT'S HER KIDS TALKING.
- WELL, I HAVE TO TAKE HER
AT FACE VALUE.
SHE WANTS TO FIGHT,
I FIGHT.
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
I TREAT THE DISEASE.
- YEAH?
WELL, I TREAT THE PATIENT.
MAYBE SHE JUST NEEDS
PERMISSION TO GIVE UP.
- HEY.
[rock music]
I'M ON A MISSION,
A FOOLISH KIND
IT TOOK ME OVER
AND HAS NOT LET UP
I TRIED TO TELL YOU
I LIKE YOUR STYLE
- HI.
-  BUT I GOT NERVOUS
-  AND COULD NOT SPEAK
- HOW'S IT GOING?
- [laughs]
- IT'S GOING REALLY GOOD,
I THINK.
- WHAT ARE YOU--
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- LOOKING FOR YOU.
I JUST GOT OUT.
I KNOW I SHOULD HAVE
CALLED FIRST, BUT I THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE MORE ROMANTIC
IF I JUST SWOOPED IN,
TOLD YOU I LOVED YOU,
WE LIVED HAPPILY EVER AFTER.
- IF YOU HAD CALLED, I WOULD
HAVE TOLD YOU TO STAY AWAY.
- BESIDES, I WAS WORRIED
IF I CALLED,
YOU'D TELL ME TO STAY AWAY.
WHY?
- IT'S JUST, I'M...MARRIED.
- YOU TOLD ME
YOU WERE GETTING A DIVORCE.
- WE WERE, BUT THEN I THOUGHT
MAYBE WE SHOULD...
TRY AGAIN.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
WE BARELY
EVEN KNEW EACH OTHER.
- THAT'S NOT TRUE.
- IT IS TRUE,
AND THIS--THIS IS RUDE,
YOU JUST BARGING IN HERE
LIKE THIS,
TELLING A PERSON
THAT YOU LOVE THEM...
ON A TUESDAY,
WHEN THAT PERSON HAS
JUST RECOMMITTED
TO THEIR HORRIBLE MARRIAGE.
- YOUR HORRIBLE MARRIAGE?
WHOA, SOUNDS GOOD.
- IT IS. IT'S GREAT.
IT'S AMAZING.
THANK YOU FOR ASKING.
- UH-HUH.
- WHAT?
- NO, I'M JUST REMEMBERING
HOW MUCH YOU RELY ON SARCASM.
- OOH, THAT HURTS.
- WAIT, WAIT. WHOA.
HEY, WAIT.
- AND YOU'RE SELLING SNAKE OIL
TO MRS. BORGHOUSE,
AND WE BOTH KNOW IT.
- WAIT.
- SO YOU SLEPT WITH THIS GUY
WHILE YOU WERE IN IRAQ?
BUT I MEAN, LIKE, WHERE?
- WHAT?
- YOU WERE IN THE DESERT.
SO DID YOU JUST DO IT
OUTSIDE IN THE SAND?
- OKAY, I FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
FOCUSING ON THE WRONG THING.
- WELL, I'M JUST TRYING
TO VISUALIZE.
- WHY DO YOU NEED TO VISUALIZE?
IT WAS A HOSPITAL, OKAY?
WE STAYED IN A HOSPITAL.
- WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
- I DON'T KNOW.
ME AND MIKE HAVE BEEN
TOGETHER FOR SO LONG,
HE'S LIKE A...
A PART OF ME, YOU KNOW?
AND IT'S NOT NOTHING
WHAT WE HAVE.
- AND HOT DOCTOR GUY?
OH, YOU'RE IN LOVE WITH HIM.
- NO, I MEAN--
I MEAN, WE HAD
THIS REALLY INTENSE CONNECTION,
BUT I DON'T REALLY KNOW HIM.
I MEAN, HE'S DIFFERENT.
HE'S FUNNY...
AND HE'S QUIET...
AND HE MADE ME FEEL SAFE.
OH, MY GOD.
MY PARENTS ARE HAVING
THAT PARTY
FOR ME AND MIKE TONIGHT.
I AM THE WORST PERSON
IN THE WORLD.
- HONEY, GUILT'S
NOT GONNA HELP YOU.
AND, ANYWAY,
IF YOU NEED TO BLAME SOMEBODY,
BLAME THE TERRORISTS.
-  I TAKE IT IN STRIDE
ONE DAY AT A TIME
IF I ASK NO QUESTIONS,
I'LL HEAR NO LIES
HOW COME BLESSINGS
ONLY COME IN DISGUISE?
TRY THAT ON FOR SIZE
AS I VOCALIZE
AIN'T NOTHIN' GONNA GET
BETWEEN ME AND MY FLOW
AIN'T NOTHIN' GONNA
COME BETWEEN ME AND MY AFRO
MY MAN JUST LEFT ME,
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
EASY COME, EASY GO
- [moaning] NURSE!
NURSE!
[moaning]
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
OH!
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
WHOA!
- HEY, I'VE GOT HIM.
- LOOK AT ME. HEY, HEY, HEY!
LOOK AT ME!
LOOK AT ME, LOOK AT ME!
YOU OKAY?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- [panting]
[crash]
- [screams]
- HEY.
HEY, YOU OKAY?
- WHAT? YEAH.
IT'S, UH, TOTALLY GOOD.
- IT WAS, UH...
IT WAS JUST A DISH.
- I KNOW.
- YEAH.
WELL, SOMETIMES LOUD NOISES
CAN TRIGGER--
- I'M FINE. I'M OKAY.
I'M TOTALLY--I'M FINE.
I LIKE...
I LIKE YOUR SHOES.
- WHAT? OH.
THANKS.
THEY'RE NEW.
- COOL. SO I'M JUST GONNA--
I'M JUST GONNA TAKE
A BEAT HERE.
YOU CAN GO.
- BEEN TO THE CAFETERIA YET?
- NO.
- FROZEN YOGURT'S
DO-IT-YOURSELF.
NO LIMIT.
- OKAY.
- HEY, WHERE YOU GOING?
- I GOT A PARTY
TO GO TO.
CAN I HAVE MY PURSE, PLEASE?
- YEAH. YOU KNOW,
THAT EYE'S GONNA SWELL UP.
- OH, ARE YOU A DOCTOR?
YOU A DOCTOR COP?
- NO, I JUST--
HOLD ON A SECOND.
YOU JUST GOT ASSAULTED.
- WHEN GOD SEES ME HAPPY
FOR ONE SECOND--
- GOD HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
THAT WAS JUST SMALLS.
- NO, NO, NO.
IT'S THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
MAN, I'M NEVER GETTING
OUT OF HERE.
YOU KNOW MY BROTHER'S
IN A GANG?
BET YOU ARRESTED HIM BEFORE.
- THAT EXPLAINS
WHY YOU HATE COPS.
- I AM NOT LETTING THAT THUG
GET IN THE WAY OF MY PLANS,
ALL RIGHT?
- OKAY, BUT LOOK,
YOU'RE SHAKING.
TAKE A BREATH,
PULL YOURSELF TOGETHER.
- I'M TOGETHER.
DON'T I LOOK PRETTY?
- YEAH.
[elevator beeps]
- HEY, IT'S ME.
LISTEN,
I'M STILL AT THE HOSPITAL.
YEAH, THERE WAS
A REALLY BIG CAR ACCIDENT,
AND I JUST THINK
THAT BY THE TIME I GET DONE,
MANHATTAN'S GONNA BE
TOO FAR TO GO.
[Kings of Leon's Use Somebody
playing]
[laughter]
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
- HEY, LOOK AT YOU,
ALL DRESSED UP.
- STOP IT, GORILLA.
- THANK YOU FOR INVITING US
TO YOUR
NOT-GETTING-A-DIVORCE PARTY.
- HERE YOU ARE, PRINCESS.
- HEY, THERE'S MIKE.
HEY, MIKE!
-  YOU AND ALL YOU KNOW
AND HOW YOU SPEAK
all: OHH!
- COME ON, COME ON, COME ON.
- DRINK.
- COME ON, BIG BOY.
- OH, MY GOD.
- WHO IS THAT?
- OH, NO, NO, NO.
OFF LIMITS, GUYS.
SHE'S FROM LANCASTER.
SHE'S PRACTICALLY AMISH.
- RUMSPRINGA.
- JUST DON'T TELL HER
I'M MARRIED, OKAY?
- BUT HE'S TOO SKINNY.
- OBAMA COULD KICK
PUTIN'S ASS.
- ARE YOU HIGH?
PUTIN WAS K.G.B.
HE COULD KILL YOU
WITH HIS BARE HANDS.
UH...OH.
THIS CAN'T BE GOOD.
WE HAVE TO GO SEE
WHAT HAPPENED.
- OH, CAN I COME, TOO?
- WHAT DO YOU THINK
I MEANT BY "WE"?
- HEY, MIKE,
CAN I BUM ONE OF THOSE?
- THAT'S THE WORST THING
I'VE EVER HEARD.
YOU HAVE TO BE CRUSHED.
- LOOK, IT WAS NOT MY NIGHT.
I'M NOT GONNA CRY
OVER IT, OKAY?
- [sighs] OKAY.
- WHAT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER LET YOU
HAVE ANY WHISKEY.
- I COULDN'T EVEN LOOK
THAT KID'S MOTHER IN THE EYE.
- IT'S ONLY YOUR FIRST WEEK.
- [crying] I JUST...
I PICTURED MYSELF
SAVING PEOPLE.
HOW CAN I HELP ANYBODY
WHEN IT'S ALL SO SAD?
- IT'S A JOB, ALL RIGHT?
THAT'S ALL IT IS.
- [sniffling]
- YOU'RE THERE FOR PEOPLE DURING
THE WORST PART OF THEIR LIVES,
YOU FIND A WAY
TO MAKE IT BETTER, AND THEN--
AND THIS IS THE MOST
IMPORTANT PART, VERONICA--
YOU LET IT GO.
THAT'S HOW YOU
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF.
- WHAT?
I AM TAKING CARE OF ME.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
GETTING BACK TOGETHER
WITH MIKE IS ALL ABOUT?
HE'S A GOOD GUY, YOU KNOW?
- YOU GOT A PROBLEM?
- AND I REALLY THINK THIS IS
GONNA MAKE MY LIFE MORE STABLE.
- YEAH, UM, WELL,
ACTUALLY MIKE'S DOWN THERE
ABOUT TO GET HIS ASS KICKED.
- WHAT?
-  DO DO-DO-DO
DO-DO-DO
DO DO-DO DO-DO
DO DO-DO DO-DO DO
- GET OFF!
GET OFF OF HIM!
-  DO DO-DO DO
DO-DO DO DO-DO DO-DO DO
- COME ON!
DO DO-DO DO DO-DO DO
DO-DO
- YOU ARE TOO OLD TO BE
GETTING INTO FIGHTS, DUMMY.
- IT WAS HIS FAULT.
- DECIDED YOU DIDN'T NEED
A DOCTOR?
- WELL, I DIDN'T LIKE
ANYBODY ON DUTY.
MIKE, THIS IS DR. SANDS.
DR. SANDS,
THIS IS MY HUSBAND MIKE.
I WANT HIM
TO HAVE A CAT SCAN.
- BARELY EVEN HURTS.
- THAT'S BECAUSE YOU'RE DRUNK.
YOU HIT THE CEMENT
WITH YOUR HEAD.
YOU'RE GETTING A CAT SCAN.
- TELL HER
I DON'T NEED NO SCAN.
- WELL, LADY
SAYS YOU NEED A SCAN,
YOU NEED A SCAN.
COME ON,
WE'LL TAKE HIM UPSTAIRS.
YOU'RE A LUCKY MAN.
- I KNOW.
I KNOW. [groans]
SHE'S A BALL-BUSTER,
BUT I LOVE HER.
HEY, YOU SHOULD HAVE
SEEN HER IN HIGH SCHOOL
WHEN SHE WAS
IN HER GWEN STEFANI PHASE.
- YEAH, OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
- OOH, OOH, OOH.
- WHAT?
NEXT WEEK.
RIGHT. GOOD NIGHT.
BUDDY SYSTEM, BOYS.
[bell rings]
- LAST CALL!
- HEY, MAN,
GIVE ME A SECOND.
HEY, YOU.
MY BUDDY, RYAN, INVITED
ME TO THIS PARTY,
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE
I MISSED THE WHOLE THING.
- YOU WANT TO GET OUT OF HERE?
- YES.
-  UH-HUH, THERE'S NO PAPA
THAT CAN TREAT MY LIKE A LOVER
WHO MAKES ME FEEL
SO RIGHT
HIS LOVE IS SO TENDER,
IT MAKES ME SURRENDER
WHEN HE SQUEEZE
AND HOLD ME TIGHT
- YOU WANT A DRINK
OR SOMETHING?
- STOP TALKING.
-  THE WAY HE LOOKS
IN MY EYES
- HEY.
- HI.
- I, UH,
GOT YOUR HUSBAND'S SCANS HERE.
WANT TO COME TAKE A LOOK?
- YEAH.
- WELL, IT'S FINE.
THERE'S NO SWELLING.
- YEAH, WELL,
HE'S GOT A HARD HEAD.
- [laughs]
HEY, HOW YOU SLEEPING?
- BAD.
- YEAH. ME, TOO.
SO WEIRD BEING BACK.
- YEAH.
YEAH.
IT'S LIKE THERE'S THIS WALL
BETWEEN ME AND EVERYBODY ELSE,
AND THERE'S...
THERE'S ALL OF THIS STUFF
THAT I CAN'T GET
OUT OF MY HEAD.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF I'M A GOOD NURSE ANYMORE,
AND I FEEL LIKE I'M GONNA
BLOW UP ALL THE TIME.
AND THEN THERE'S YOU.
I FEEL LIKE I WOULD HAVE
GONE COMPLETELY CRAZY
IF IT HADN'T BEEN FOR YOU.
AND I FEEL LIKE I'VE...
SORT OF BEEN CARRYING YOU
AROUND WITH ME.
BUT I JUST--I...
I FEEL LIKE I HAVE TO DO
THE RESPONSIBLE THING.
- YEAH.
I GUESS IT WAS,
UH, PRETTY STUPID OF ME
TO COME RUNNING OUT HERE
FOR YOU.
IT'S JUST THAT
YOU WERE THE ONE THING
THAT MADE SENSE.
- WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO NOW?
- THERE'S NOTHING TO DO.
I SIGNED
A TWO-YEAR CONTRACT.
I'M STAYING.
YOU CAN TAKE YOUR HUSBAND HOME
ANYTIME YOU LIKE.
- I GUESS
WE'RE NOT HAVING BREAKFAST.
- OH, UM...
GOTTA GO TO WORK.
BUT I'LL CALL YOU.
- [knocks]
TIME FOR YOUR MEDS.
WHY IS YOUR HAIR
ON THE GROUND?
- MY HEAD'S HOT. LEAVE IT.
WHAT'S WITH YOU
AND THE SEXY SURGEON,
THE ONE WHO SQUEEZED
YOUR ARM LAST NIGHT?
- YOU LOOKED
LIKE YOU WERE ASLEEP.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
MY DAUGHTER'S ONLINE DATING,
AND YOU WITH TWO MEN
AFTER YOU.
- YEAH, WE WERE
IN THE WAR TOGETHER.
TAKE YOUR PILLS.
- WAR? HOW SWEEPING
AND ROMANTIC.
I HOPE YOU DON'T THINK
A MAN'S GONNA FIX
WHATEVER'S WRONG WITH YOU.
- JUST SWALLOW THE DRUGS,
LADY.
- YOU THINK I SHOULD
HAVE THIS SURGERY?
- YOU KNOW...
IF YOU WERE MY MOTHER...
- YOU'D HAVE A BETTER HAIRCUT.
- UM, IF YOU WERE MY MOTHER,
I WOULD SAY NO.
IT'S TOO RISKY,
AND IT PROBABLY WON'T WORK.
- I'M DYING.
- YEAH.
YEAH, YOU ARE.
THERE ARE A COUPLE OF THINGS
THAT SCARE ME
ABOUT THIS SURGERY.
YOU COULD DIE
ON THE OPERATING TABLE.
AT LEAST
THAT WOULD BE PAINLESS.
OR YOU COULD DIE
IN RECOVERY,
IN PAIN AND ON A VENTILATOR,
AND THAT SCARES ME.
I THINK THAT YOU NEED
TO DECIDE
ON THE QUALITY OF TIME
YOU HAVE LEFT.
AND I'M--I'M SCARING
THE HELL OUT OF YOU RIGHT NOW,
WHICH IS WHY IT'S BECOMING
VERY CLEAR TO ME
I AM IN THE WRONG LINE
OF WORK.
- NO.
YOU'RE THE ONLY PERSON
WHO'S BEEN HONEST WITH ME.
PEOPLE TREAT YOU LIKE
AN IMBECILE WHEN YOU'RE SICK.
- IF YOU WANT
TO STOP TREATMENT...
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS SAY SO.
YOUR KIDS WILL UNDERSTAND.
- I THINK I'D LIKE TO BE ALONE,
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
VERONICA,
YOU'RE A WONDERFUL NURSE.
DON'T DOUBT IT
FOR A SECOND.
- SHE'S BEEN HERE ALL NIGHT.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO KEEP
THE TRANSPLANT VULTURES AT BAY.
- DOES SHE HAVE ANY FAMILY
OR ANYTHING?
- I DON'T KNOW.
HAVEN'T SEEN ANYONE ELSE.
JUST HER.
[The Kills'
Goodnight Bad Morning]
-  SPEED'S WORKING,
I SEE IT
IN EVERYONE
LIKE A LOST IDEA
UNDER LIGHT BULB SUN
YOUR EYES,
READY FOR TAKEOFF
MELT IN YOUR HEAD
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL STATE
WE'RE IN
- SHE, UH, CANCELLED
HER SURGERY.
I'M TAKING IT
YOU ALREADY KNEW THAT.
ARE WE GONNA BE OKAY?
- WELL, I WAS THINKING,
MAYBE YOU COULD
BE MY FRIEND.
OKAY, YEAH.
I'M LEAVING NOW.
- I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
- YEAH.
FOR THE NEXT TWO YEARS.
I KNOW.
- TODAY IS THE FIRST DAY
THAT I DIDN'T
WANT TO KILL MYSELF.
- THAT IS SO WEIRD,
BECAUSE TODAY IS THE FIRST DAY
THAT I DIDN'T WANT TO KILL YOU.
- TODAY IS THE LAST DAY
I WALK THROUGH NEWARK
WITH MY PANTIES IN MY PURSE.
- BOY, IF I HAD A NICKEL...
[thud]
- WHAT? HEY!
[bottle shatters, shouting]
- GET HIM OUT!
- MAYBE WE SHOULD GO SEE?
- NO, WE'RE A HALF A BLOCK AWAY
FROM THE EMERGENCY ROOM.
- I'M NOT LEAVING THIS SEAT.
- OH, IT'S THE BARTENDER.
HIS ARM IS BLEEDING.
I'M GONNA GO SEE.
- THE UNICORN?
- HELL, NO,
SHE DOESN'T GET TO GO.
- HI.
- OH, YOU POOR THING.
- OH, I DON'T REALLY THINK
IT'S THAT BIG OF A DEAL.
- YOUR ARM.
- CHLOE, WHY DON'T YOU
GO FIND HIM A CLEAN BAR RAG?
- WHY DON'T YOU GO FIND HIM
A CLEAN BAR RAG?
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE YOU SHOULD
TAKE YOUR SHIRT OFF,
JUST TO BE SAFE
- DON'T WORRY.
WE'RE NURSES.
-  YOU ARE THE GIRL
THAT I'VE BEEN DREAMIN' OF
EVER SINCE
www.tvsubtitles.net