I know. I know.
Hey, man. It's been a while.
Land anywhere yet?
- No.
- Yeah, it's tough out there.
Well, they say it's coming back.
Not for me, it's not.
I'm sorry.
Put the gun down!
Somebody had to do something.
Don't do it!
The FDA has approved Denning
Pharmaceutical's new wonder drug.
Another blockbuster quarter
for Denning Pharmaceutical..
The news that the company's
new drug Prophidil,
is on the fast track
to FDA approval.
A major class action suit
against Denning Pharmaceutical
is gaining momentum on allegations
that the company had evidence that
its flagship drug, Prophidil,
has potentially fatal side effects.
No, I'm on my way
to the office now.
You can't put yourself in danger.
In danger? No, no,
I'm not in danger.
The news said he
worked for Denning,
isn't that the case you're on?
He killed seven people.
Yeah, including himself.
So, I think I'm safe.
Though I think he may have ruined any
chance of my getting a promotion.
- How come?
- He screwed me.
- What do you mean?
- 'Cause he was our key witness.
You don't have other witnesses?
Yeah, but without him,
the whole case is a bust.
I know, I'm not an expert, but
you wanna hear what I think?
Of course, I do. Talk to me.
I think you need a security detail.
Someone should make
sure that you're okay.
You're good.
- Interesting, interesting.
- Will you get reassigned?
I hope so, I wrote a memo on the
Gambizzi case I'm turning in today.
That's great.
Yeah, I should be on
Gambizzi by lunch.
Mom, I gotta go, I gotta go.
I'm running late.
- Love you.
- I love you too.
Excuse me, sorry.
I just gotta.. Sorry.
I need to get through.
Thank you. Okay.
Thanks.
Tom. It's Monday.
I knew that.
- Tom.
- Janine.
So what's going on in there?
The servers went down in
Kansas City last night.
- We lost all offsite backups.
- Oh.
You're gonna be making
copies all day long.
Yay, I love making copies.
- Really?
- Not really. Where's Emmerich?
Hmm, on the warpath.
- I gotta get this to Moyers.
- Got it.
Why don't you take
the scenic route?
- And don't let him see you.
- I love you, Janine.
- You're all set.
- I love you too, Barney.
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
Thank you.
- Ooh!
- Oh!
Jefe!
Donna, your lunch
appointment has arrived.
She's in the waiting area.
We need to update our
file on the Pamona case.
Per our conversation this morning,
I finally convinced Munson
to get off the dime.
He's agreed to extend
an offered settlement
to the amount of 1.5,
structured over three years.
First payment due at signing.
Tell him we'll agree to it. If he
tries to counter, shut him down.
I need the Amato file.
Here.
Give this to Murray and
get it back to me.
He's got to initial it by
noon today. Thank you.
You notice I'm never late.
And I've got two kids.
I wondered why you had all those
pictures of children on your desk.
Oh, shit.
Tom!
- Get this filed away.
- Yes, sir, right away.
I also need 20 copies of each of these
for the Harcourt presentation tomorrow.
Also.. Sorry, hi.
I went ahead and I included
Prophidil heart attack victims, uh,
along with the stroke patients
already in the class.
Case goes to trial tomorrow.
Our lead witness decided to
go on a suicidal rampage
at the defendant's
office on Tuesday.
So I don't have time
for innovation.
One motion, and it's done.
And defense won't mind 'cause
they're gonna be hearing from
- the heart attacks sooner or later anyway.
- Tom..
We work off a 40 cut of whatever
the court awards the plaintiffs.
Lifetime care cost of each
stroke victim is millions.
Burial cost of your heart
attack victim is 10,000 bucks.
Got it, got it.
You think you're doing
the right thing, Tom.
The one great aspect of
this justice system is that
there is a market for
all kinds of cases.
Large firms, like us, will take
care of the expensive victims.
Small ones can take care
of your heart attacks.
Psst! Tom!
I think he likes you.
It doesn't matter anyway.
The case is a bust after the
whistleblower went postal.
No case is a bust when you're billing
out a $12 an hour paralegal,
at $65 an hour.
Christ, Roger, they're only
paying you $12 an hour? Ouch!
Now we'll preview the
unredacted versions..
Jack, meet your client in
conference room B, please.
Your memo's on Moyers' desk.
Oh, you're my hero..
Heroine, heroine.
This is Tom.
Yes, sir, right away.
Looks like I'm gonna be joining
you on the Gambizzi case.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
I submitted a memo this morning.
Moyers wants to see
me in his office.
Hey, uh, speaking of heart attacks,
she is wearing the form fitted
gray thing that is just..
- You're so gross, Roger.
- ..unbelievable.
You gonna talk to her this time?
If you do, tell her I
want my boxers back.
He's ready for you.
- Tom?
- Yeah.
Shirt's untucked.
Come in.
You wanna see me, sir?
Yeah, Tom, hey! Thanks for
coming. Here, take a seat.
Thanks.
Never been in here before.
- Yeah, yeah.
- It's cool.
Yeah, it's nice, huh?
225 square feet.
- Nice.
- And fifth biggest office in the building.
Yeah.
So, Tom, this memo on Gambizzi..
It's all your own work? No one
helped you or advised you?
It's a fascinating case.
Yes.
I really feel like there's a spousal
privilege aspect to the case
that's been overlooked.
And so I hope the memo helps
shed some light on different..
I don't understand.
Tom, when you neglect the
cases that we assign you,
you neglect the client.
Without the client,
all of this, it disappears.
Gambizzi's small fry.
It's cases like Harcourt v. Denning
that keep the lights on.
- I understand.
- Do you?
Emmerich wants a follow-up
with you later.
Awesome. Thanks.
Yeah, anytime, Tom.
Mr. Ryan, please hold
for Miss Higgins.
So long, Harcourt.
- Oh, hey, Thomas.
- Oh, hey, Anna.
The Xerox machines in the copy room
were all occupied so I just..
Oh, well, I noticed some files out of place
the other day, so can I show you those?
Yeah, that's.. Yeah.
- You said you quit.
- Tough day.
Moyers didn't like the memo?
He shredded it, in front of me.
Thanks for the support.
How's that for support?
That's a little better.
The guy's a total loser.
You should seriously not
care what he thinks.
Yeah, I don't care what he thinks.
I do care what Emmerich thinks.
Now he wants to follow up
with me this afternoon.
Okay. Okay, here's what you do.
You apologize, you act sincere, and
then you forget it ever happened, okay?
- Don't take it personally.
- I know.
Listen, everyone's always gonna
have to answer to someone.
Emmerich doesn't.
- Ever met his wife?
- Well, that's true.
Good news is I get fired, we
can stop sneaking around.
You get fired, and I'm dumping you.
That wasn't funny.
So not funny, not
funny, not right now.
It's kind of.
Come on, babe, it's kind of funny.
Come here.
- You're so mean.
- Shh.
I gotta get that.
Hey, don't take it personally.
Chin up.
How many of those do they need?
Hey, hey!
I'm sorry.
Okay, everybody listen up.
RBE goes to trial against Denning
Pharmaceutical tomorrow.
I don't need to remind you what a big
day it's going to be for all of us.
I know how frustrating it's
been having the servers down.
There's not a lot more work
we can get done tonight.
I want everybody to go home.
- Tom.
- Yes, sir.
The memo you wrote on Gambizzi
references the witness list.
If I hadn't caught this before
all our discovery was filed,
it would have been submitted
to the district clerk.
That exhibit would have been
unsealed, allowing access
to the names and addresses of everyone
who's turning state's evidence
against the Gambizzi crime family.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
You're a paralegal.
There's a lot you don't know, but
I don't have a problem with that.
Hmm.
I do have a problem with
you acting like you do.
This is your last day at RBE, Tom.
Tom. I'm sorry.
Sorry.
- Hey, Mom.
- Babe, I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
Let's go get a drink tonight,
okay? Just you and me.
Okay.
I'm heading out now, but meet me
at Mahoney's at like 11:00, okay?
Bye.
- Moving back in with mom and dad?
- Something like that.
- Hey, Tom.
- Barney.
Sorry to hear what happened, man.
Appreciate it. I'll miss you, pal.
You'll always have
memories of the file room.
Pass card log.
She was never far behind you.
What was he talking about?
- I've maybe, possibly been seeing Anna.
- What?
For like, three months.
Oh, my God.
You're not serious.
Ugh!
I wanna get fired.
Oh, you know what?
I'll take the next one.
I gotta grab something on my desk.
- You want me to wait for you?
- No, no, go ahead.
- Go see your secret girlfriend.
- Ha..ha.
Hey.
Didn't waste any time.
Hey, Frank.
This isn't working.
Can you swipe me up?
- You got it, boss.
- I'll just leave this here for two seconds.
Hey, Jefe.
You didn't see a guy walking
around in a suit, did you?
Yeah.
What are you doing at my desk, pal?
They canceled my pass card.
- Hey!
- Hey, stupid pass card's not working.
Oh, okay.
- So you're still here?
- Yeah, yeah, I tried to leave but, uh..
I just had a lot of work
I had to catch up on.
Hey, you didn't see a lawyer
walking around here, did you?
No. Why?
What are you still doing here?
- Just wanted one more look at the place.
- Oh.
So what are you working on?
Oh, you know what, uh, Emmerich is
really invested in that Gambizzi case.
- So he's got me working here late.
- Right, right, right, right.
Argh!
Yep!
Tom!
Get this filed away.
All right.
I'm really gone this time.
Okay.
You want me to let you out?
No, I'll take the scenic
route, old time's sake.
All right.
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
Take care.
Yeah. Don't work too hard
on that Gambizzi case.
Can I help you with something?
I'm with contractor services.
They sent me up to fix a short.
You mean building maintenance?
That's it.
Oh, well, no one told
me anything about it.
Um, do you mind if
I see your badge?
I forgot it.
They called me up at last minute.
I just wanna get this
done and get out of here.
Oh, I'm gonna have to
call Jerry about this.
Let's not bother Jerry.
What did you say your name..
Come on you, let's go.
You're not helping, are you?
Come on, Tom.
Who's in there?
Hello. Excuse me?
Barney?
How you doing in there, Barney?
You wanna toss me your keys?
I promise to take good care of it.
Okay, I'll have these.
Thank you, Barney.
Stay there.
- Tom!
- Roger.
- What are you still doing here?
- Keep your voice down.
- Keep my voice down?
- There's a guy
on the floor, he just
killed Janine and Barney.
What are you talking about?
Roger, we gotta go.
We gotta get out of here.
Okay, well, what did he look like?
I don't know. Six foot,
180, he's wearing a suit.
That's everyone in this city.
It's dead.
Janine.
Shit!
Shit! We're trapped.
Look, he doesn't know we're here. Worst
case scenario, we hide out till he leaves.
Worst case scenario is he
finds us and kills us.
Get on a computer, see if you
can get online or something.
Okay.
- Tom, the Internet..
- Shut up!
Okay, here's the plan.
Take the long route around to
the far side of the bullpen.
Get to your desk, call the cops.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna find Emmerich.
No, listen to me.
Forget Emmerich. Forget doing
the right thing for once.
He wouldn't save us.
- God damn it..
- Roger, will you shut up and listen to me?
None of that matters now, okay?
You have kids at home,
keep it together.
Let's go.
Give me this.
Hey, hey, hey!
This isn't how I thought my
day was going to go, either.
So you're gonna take the one pass card
we have, you're gonna find a phone,
I'm gonna get Emmerich, and we're
gonna get out of here, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay?
Where'd you go?
Hi, honey.
- Sarah, hey. It's me, listen, honey..
- Excuse me, sir.
Honey, do you want me to
keep your dinner warm?
Hold on a second.
Yes?
I'm with building maintenance.
How long do you think
you're gonna be?
Okay, um.. Thanks
for letting me know.
- I'm just on the phone right now.
- I'll wait.
Guys, quiet.
I'm talking to your dad.
- Are you okay?
- Hey! No, I'm fine.
I'm.. I'm at the office and..
I'm with someone right now.
You got any idea how many other
people are working late tonight?
- Hey, honey..
- Sir?
Oh, Elaine and Mike invited us to
go to the lake again on Saturday.
What do you want me to say to them?
Need to make sure nobody's trapped.
I'm out of excuses.
Oh, your books from Amazon came
in today. They only sent two.
Tell her you've been held up late
in office. You'll be home late.
They didn't send the
restaurant guide.
Hey, I'm, uh..
I'm just stuck at the office,
I'm gonna be a little late.
Tell her everything's fine.
Kiss the kids night-night.
Are you sure everything's okay?
No, no. Everything's
fine. Uh, just..
Kiss the kids goodnight for me.
Okay, well..
Don't forget to tell
her you love her.
I love you, baby.
I love you too, honey.
Now hang up and put the
phone on the desk.
Oh, please. Please..
I didn't see anything. I..
Is anybody else
working late tonight?
No, no, it was.. It's just me.
Good. Good.
Roger?
Come on, come on, come on.
What the..
Ugh.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, goddamn iPhones.
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
I need to talk to you,
you have a problem.
Call me back.
Immediately.
Shit.
We have a situation.
Nobody was supposed to be up here.
Three.
And the one we spoke about.
I'll be in touch when it's done.
Tom?
Tom.
You think this is a big office,
Tom, but it's about to get really,
really small.
There's only one way out.
And I've got the key.
I will find you, Tom.
I'll find you.
If I have to burn this place to
the ground, I will find you.
Come on.
Hey.
Yes, come on, come on.
Pick up the phone, pick up the phone!
Call the cops.
Wait.
I got it, I got it.
There, look, "9-1-1 ."
I got it, yes.
Yes, I'm going to shoot
that kid in the face.
Yes, I am. Yes.
Come on.
Oh, come on.
Yes, yeah.
Come on, come on.
Yeah!
Got you.
Here goes nothing.
- Tom.
- Thank Christ.
Give me your cell phone.
- What.. what's going on?
- Excuse me, do you have a cell phone?
- Tom.
- We have to call the cops.
- Tom!
- There's a guy on the floor with a gun.
He killed three people. Can
you hurry up and call 9-1-1?
You said I'd be safe!
Shit.
- Alan Z. Emmerich?
- Oh, God!
Please, don't.
One of your employees, Tom,
reprogrammed the cards.
Please tell me there's another
card reader on this floor.
I don't believe so, no.
Oh..
This lawyer has started to seriously
affect my ability to do my job.
He's just a paralegal.
Let him go, he's nobody.
Do not leave this office.
Who is she?
Lorraine Gambizzi.
Gambizzi's wife?
She was testifying
against her husband?
That's why he's here.
He must be one of Gambizzi's guys.
But if she's dead,
why isn't he leaving?
Maybe he is.
Doesn't sound like it.
What is he doing?
What does he want in the file room?
Well, he's not gonna
get in there that way.
That's reinforced steel and bulletproof
glass. That's impenetrable.
So the one room where we're safe is
the room where we can't get into.
It stopped.
Shit.
Tom?
Tom!
Look who I got.
Fernando.
See?
Tom, I just want to talk.
That's all, see.
I'm an employee.
Just like you, I've been hired
to do a job, and my boss isn't the
kind of man who accepts failure.
Don't try and be a hero, Tom.
Nobody else has to die.
If you bring me the pass card,
I promise,
I won't hurt Fernando.
If you don't..
I will decorate that
wall with his brains.
What's his nickname?
What do I call him?
The janitor!
He's already dead.
It's been fun, Tom.
What's that?
He's turning the elevators back on.
He's trying to trick us.
Come on.
Stay here.
You heard it too?
Jesus Christ.
What is it?
It's my number.
Oh, shit!
Go, go, go!
Shit. Shit.
Oh, God.
This is gonna hurt.
You ready?
Nice phone.
You really should protect
your phone with a PIN.
You wouldn't want
just anyone using it.
No!
Hey, hey, hey, leave her out of this.
You already killed the other witness,
why are you doing it?
Why are you still here?
I'm gonna go let her in.
You got everything you wanted,
why are you doing this?
Not everything.
Hey! Hey, come back here!
Hey, come back here
and listen to me!
You touch her, I'm gonna kill you.
Get back here!
Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
- Don't go out there.
- I have to.
He's got Anna.
He'll kill you.
No, he won't.
I'm gonna give him
exactly what he wants.
Hi. I bet your name's Anna.
And who are you?
I'm the new guy,
and I'm having a
really bad first day.
What are you doing?
Give me your cell phone.
Please.
Thank you.
Let her go.
Oh, hello.
Let her go and I'll
give you what you want.
Tom!
Anna, baby, it's okay.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Just a friendly exchange.
Something you want for
something I want.
Aw, cute.
You've really thought this
through, haven't you?
Now, I don't like the way this is
going, all I gotta do is make a cut
and it's game over, you lose.
We both lose.
Except, one of us will be able
to live with the outcome,
and one of us will not.
I don't believe that's true.
Emmerich, what are
you doing? Emmerich.
- I'm taking a risk..
- Emmerich, I've got this.
as an act of good faith.
You've been trying to
get into our file room.
I think you have a job to do,
and you intend to see it through.
Am I right?
But I am confident that if you
were to put your gun down
then Tom would throw out that card.
Then both parties
would be confident in the good
faith of these negotiations.
Your turn.
Now, let her go.
That's not gonna work for me,
I want him to bring it to me.
- For God's sake, let's just get this done..
- No, Emmerich!
Emmerich, what are you doing?
Now, let her go.
Sorry, I'm renegotiating.
No!
Get up.
After you.
You shot me!
You might just live.
You're supposed to be the boss!
How hard is it to clear
out your own office?
Just get this done so I
can go to the hospital.
Come on.
Let him go, or I shoot.
You won't do that.
Yeah? Try me.
Anna, now!
What are you doing?
You can't go in there!
Go get that fire extinguisher.
- Oh, shit.
- Tom.
Yeah, give that to me. Stay back.
Tom!
Get off him!
Hey!
You got no clue who you're..
11-22.
Tom.
- You okay?
- Yeah, are you okay?
Yeah.
- I'll get the elevator started.
- Yeah.
I guess Harcourt's not
going to trial today, huh?
Holy shit.
This has nothing to
do with Gambizzi.
This is why he broke in the office.
Denning hired him
to destroy the Harcourt file.
- Tom..
- This is proof!
Denning knew that Prophidil could harm
people, and they released it anyway.
Tom, I need you to
call me an ambulance.
Okay.
11-22.
We have a situation.
Nobody was supposed to be up here.
Three, and the one we talked about.
It was you.
What, you were throwing
the case for Denning?
- The money was just a way out.
- A way out of what?
Think of this more as a settlement.
Oh, don't be so naive.
Every lawyer has a price, even you.
I'm not a lawyer.
You can be.
You can go wherever you want at
RBE, Tom. I will make sure of that.
Well, I want a raise. A big one!
And a corner office.
And then, I want to watch
when you tell Roger's wife and kids
that you had him murdered for money.
You fuck.
It was supposed to be an electrical fire!
No one was supposed to get hurt!
Then why did he have a gun?
Why did he call you and say "Three,
and the one we talked about"?
"The one we talked about"?
That was Roger, wasn't it?
Roger found this, brought this
to you and you had him killed.
No, I am not a killer.
No, you just pay other
people to do it for you.
It's easier.
Shred that file.
You think the Mafia is scary?
Wait till you see what a multi-billion
dollar corporation will do.
Denning has people
everywhere, in every firm,
every police precinct,
every governmental agency.
If you don't shred that file,
they will come for you.
Why would they?
You fired me.
Remember?
I clocked out at 9:00.
Thanks to you, I couldn't
even swipe back up again.
Go.
Reported gunshots
fired, 34th floor.
- Hey.
- Tom!
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Hi.
- Okay. We've gotta get out of here.
- Okay.
Hey, where's Emmerich?
Check the perimeter offices,
if you find anyone, detain them.
I'll get some backup.
What did you do with the file?
What I do best.
Morning, sir.
Morning, how are you doing today?
I'm gonna call in sick,
give me your cell phone.
If anybody asks,
- we were never here.
- Okay.
Yeah?
What does he look like?
Got him.
SubText: NoRMITA.326