ARE YOU STALKING ME?
Woman: NO, I'M JUST FILMING
FOR MY WEB BLOG.
WELL, WOULD YOU MIND
NOT FILMING ME?
OKAY.
THANKS.
NO PROBLEM.
WHY ARE YOU FOLLOWING ME?
I'M JUST HEADED
IN THE SAME DIRECTION.
I'M NOT FOLLOWING YOU.
NO, THAT'S NOT TRUE.
YOU'RE FOLLOWING ME.
WHERE YOU HEADED?
WELL, IF YOU
REALLY NEED TO KNOW,
I'M ON MY WAY TO IDENTIFY
MY GRANDMOTHER'S DEAD BODY.
OH, WOW.
NO, I'M JUST KIDDING.
NOPE, I'M NOT.
I'M SORRY, MAN.
OH, YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE.
I NEVER SAW MUCH OF HER.
SHE KEPT TO HERSELF.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO?
UM, WELL, ACTUALLY,
I, UH...
I WORK IN HOUSEWARES
AT ED'S BARGAIN BASEMENT
ON 14th STREET.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WORKING AT HOUSEWARES
WITH A COLLEGE DEGREE?
WELL, THE PROBLEM IS
I MAJORED IN SEMIOTICS.
THERE'S ABSOLUTELY
NO PRACTICAL USES
FOR MY DEGREE.
UH, SO IT'S BEEN NICE
BEING A PART OF YOUR BLOG,
BUT I'VE GOTTA GO I.D.
MY DEAD GRANNY NOW.
OH, MAN.
WELL, I'M SHARLEEN.
AND YOU SHOULD
CHECK OUT MY BLOG
BECAUSE YOU'RE ON IT.
SO...
(laughs)
WELL, I AM DANNY HILL,
AND YOU CAN FIND ME
AT ED'S BARGAIN BASEMENT...
IN HOUSEWARES...
IN THE BASEMENT.
OKAY. I'LL BE SEEING YOU,
DANNY HILL.
TAKE CARE.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
I'M LILY WAINWRIGHT'S
GRANDSON.
THE OLD LADY IN 1003.
THEY'RE REMOVING
HER BODY NOW.
I'LL TAKE YOU.
(elevator dings)
THANKS.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT LUTHER.
LUTHER'S LUTHER.
HE'S BEEN HERE 40 YEARS.
AND ME, I HAVE BEEN HERE
AS LONG AS I CAN REMEMBER.
IT'S GOOD BUILDING.
NO PROBLEM, NO MICE,
NO RATS, NO FUSS.
OH, THAT'S WEIRD.
WHAT?
I JUST COULD'VE SWORN
I SAW SOMETHING IN THE CORNER.
GOOD WATER PRESSURE.
WHEN THEY BUILT THIS,
THEY KNEW WHAT THEY WERE DOING,
NOT JUST LIKE NOW.
YOU NEXT OF KIN?
YEAH, I WAS HER GRANDSON.
CAN YOU IDENTIFY THE DECEASED?
YEAH, IT'S MY GRANDMOTHER--
LILY WAINWRIGHT.
WELL, YOUR GRANDMOTHER DIED OF
A MASSIVE CARDIAC INFARCTION--
HEART ATTACK.
I'M OKAY CERTIFYING THAT
SHE DIED OF NATURAL CAUSES.
OKAY?
YEAH.
JOE WILL HELP YOU.
OH, DANIEL, LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
LIVING ROOM, DINING ROOM,
THREE BEDROOM, THREE BATHROOM.
YOU GOT MAID ROOM,
EAT-IN KITCHEN,
LAUNDRY ROOM...
BIG PLACE.
3,500 SQUARE FEET.
COME SIT.
YOU WILL NEED LAWYER.
A LAWYER?
WHY AM I GONNA NEED A LAWYER?
WELL, THIS PLACE
IS RENT-CONTROLLED.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER
PAID VERY LOW RENT.
AND YOU, YOUR FAMILY,
YOU'RE ENTITLED
TO THE PLACE,
BUT YOU WILL NEED
HELP OF LAWYER.
BUT I NEVER LIVED HERE.
I MEAN, DON'T I NEED
TO HAVE LIVED WITH A RELATIVE
BEFORE THEY DIED IN ORDER--
DANNY, DANNY, DANNY...
WHY YOU DO THIS?
WHY YOU MAKE TROUBLE
FOR YOURSELF?
YOU LIVE HERE
WITH YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
BUT WHY WOULD THE LANDLORD
TAKE MY WORD FOR THAT?
HE WOULD TAKE
MY WORD FOR IT.
I'M DOORMAN--
THEY TRUST ME.
I HELP YOU,
YOU HELP JOE.
HOW MUCH WAS THE RENT?
$675.
ASHES TO ASHES,
DUST TO DUST...
YOU'VE GOTTA BE
DANIEL HILL.
YEAH.
I'M BERTRAM G. FEINBERG,
ATTORNEY-AT-LAW.
JOE SAID YOU HAD A LANDLORD
AND TENANT PROBLEM.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, LISTEN,
DANNY, LANDLORDS HATE ME
BECAUSE I ALWAYS WIN.
YOU SEE...
(chuckles)
YOU GOTTA REMEMBER THE COURTS
LEAN OVER BACKWARDS IN FAVOR
OF THE TENANT.
UH, ONE COFFEE,
EXTRA SUGAR, AND A PLATTER.
UH, BAGEL,
CREAM CHEESE, COFFEE.
IN YOUR CASE, YOU HAVE
A DIRECT FAMILY MEMBER
WHO PASSED ON.
I'M SO SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
YOU MOVED IN WITH HER
BECAUSE YOU WANTED
TO BE WITH HER
DURING THE FINAL STAGES
OF HER ILLNESS,
WHICH ENTITLES YOU
TO TAKE OVER THE LEASE
UNDER THE SAME TERMS
THAT SHE ENJOYED.
LOOK, SHE DIED UNEXPECTEDLY
OF A HEART ATTACK.
NO, YOU MOVED IN WITH HER
BECAUSE SHE COULDN'T COPE
FOR HERSELF--
AND THEN SHE HAD
THE HEART ATTACK.
I NEVER LIVED WITH HER.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT, LISTEN,
YOU MOVE INTO THE APARTMENT
TONIGHT, ALL RIGHT?
YOU CHANGE ALL THE LOCKS
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
DOUBLE--TRIPLE LOCKS.
HE'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
OH, UH...
TRIPLE LOCKS? WHY?
THE LANDLORD
PROBABLY HAS COPIES
OF THE EXISTING KEYS.
BUT IF I TAKE OVER
THE TENANCY, LEGITIMATELY,
WHAT COULD THE LANDLORD
DO TO ME?
DANNY, YOU'VE ENTERED THE WORLD
OF LANDLORD AND TENANT.
THE LANDLORD IS THE MONSTER,
THE GREAT BEELZEBUB,
YOUR WORST NIGHTMARE.
HE WILL DO ANYTHING
TO KEEP YOU FROM TAKING OVER
A RENT-CONTROLLED LEASE.
NOW, ON THE OPEN MARKET,
YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S APARTMENT
WOULD FETCH
$10,000 A MONTH, EASY.
HE'S GONNA LET YOU HAVE IT
FOR A LOUSY $675?
YEAH, BUT I DON'T WANT
TO LIVE UNDER THAT KIND
OF STRESS EVERY DAY.
NO ONE'S EVEN ASKING YOU TO.
I MEAN, FOR THE FIRST
COUPLE OF WEEKS,
YEAH,
YOU GOTTA BE ON YOUR GUARD.
BUT THAT'S AS LONG AS IT'LL
TAKE ME TO GET A COURT ORDER.
NO, TODAY'S MONDAY.
AH, THANK YOU.
UH, LET'S SEE, I COULD GET ONE
FOR A WEEK FROM FRIDAY.
THAT'S 12 DAYS.
A COURT ORDER?
A COURT ORDER OF PROTECTION,
GRANTING YOU A NEW LEASE
UNDER THE SAME TERMS
AS YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S.
HOW MUCH WOULD THIS
COURT ORDER COST?
IT'S 750, YOU KNOW.
WELL, I KNOW YOU'RE GRIEVING,
SO 500. 500?
HALF NOW, HALF WHEN
WE GET THE COURT ORDER.
NOW REMEMBER,
DON'T LEAVE THE APARTMENT UNTIL
THE COURT ORDER COMES THROUGH.
THIS IS ALL YOUR STUFF?
I LIVE AN UNCOMPLICATED LIFE.
I GOT GUY COMING
IN THE MORNING
TO CHANGE LOCKS
LIKE LAWYER SAID.
YOU ALWAYS DO
WHAT LAWYER SAY.
MANAGING AGENT COME BY TODAY.
I TOLD HIM YOU LIVE WITH YOUR
GRANDMOTHER FOR ONE MONTH.
HE WAS COOL WITH THAT?
WHY WOULD HE NOT BE
COOL WITH THAT?
(glass breaks)
(muffled yell)
DON'T WORRY ABOUT 1004.
GOOD PEOPLE, NO PROBLEM.
THANKS.
YOU NEED ANYTHING,
YOU CALL JOE.
YOU NEED ME TO GO TO MARKET,
JOE WILL GO FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
ANYTHING ELSE?
DON'T FORGET TO LOCK THE DOOR.
I WON'T.
(door locks)
ZIG!
IT'S OUR NEW HOME.
(chuckles)
COME ON, BUD.
COME ON.
(hisses)
OW!
ZIGGY...
COME ON.
HEY, HEY...
COME ON, COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU SO SCARED OF?
HEY, ZIG.
HEY. OH.
(Ziggy growls)
HEY, ZIG.
(meows)
A LOT BIGGER THAN
THE LAST ONE, HUH?
THERE'S NO SMELLY PHIL
TO DISTRACT YOU.
ZIG, YOU'RE GONNA
LOVE IT HERE, BUDDY.
COME ON, DON'T FREAK OUT.
(bang)
(banging)
OH, THESE DARN STEPS.
YOU WANT ANY HELP WITH THOSE?
JOE TOLD YOU
JOE WOULD GO TO MARKET FOR YOU.
WHY WOULD YOU LEAVE APARTMENT
WHEN LAWYER TELLS YOU
NOT TO MOVE
UNTIL HE GET COURT ORDER?
HEY...
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
OKAY, BABY, LIKE I TELL YOU,
YOU NEED ANYTHING, YOU TELL JOE.
HE GET AT
THE STORE FOR YOU, OKAY?
OKAY.
NOW THIS PLACE NEED
LITTLE BRIGHTENING UP.
IN THE MORNING,
I GET PAINT FOR YOU.
NICE, HAPPY COLOR.
OH, OKAY, THANKS.
I DO WANNA BE HAPPY HERE.
WILL YOU PROMISE JOE
YOU STAY IN APARTMENT?
DON'T LEAVE
UNTIL IT'S LEGAL.
OKAY. I PROMISE.
(static)
?
(gasps)
(growls)
OH!
(sighs)
JESUS!
ZIG?
(rings doorbell)
JOE GOT PAINT FOR YOU.
BERMUDA BURGUNDY.
YOU CANNOT GO WRONG WITH RED.
WELL, THANK YOU, BUT, LOOK,
I DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
I GOT IT FROM GUYS
WHO PAINT BUILDING.
LANDLORD PAYS.
YOU GO MAKE PLACE
LOOK NICE.
BUT IF YOU DO NEED MONEY,
JOE GO ATM FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
(bang)
ZIG?
HELLO?
WHO LET YOU IN HERE?
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT...
EXCUSE ME, EXCUSE ME...
WHO LET YOU IN?
(locks door)
"WHEN THE EVENING WAS COME,
THEY BROUGHT UNTO HIM
MANY THAT WERE POSSESSED
WITH DEVILS..."
NUT JOB.
(doorbell rings)
(doorbell ringing, knocking)
HI.
HOLA.
IT'S ME. YOU REMEMBER ME.
YEAH. WHO LET YOU UP?
UH, A DOORMAN.
ARE YOU GONNA LET ME IN?
HEY.
WHAT'S UP?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WELL, I STOPPED BY
ED'S BARGAIN BASEMENT,
AND THEY SAID YOU'D TAKEN
A COUPLE DAYS OFF.
SO I FIGURED WHAT THE HEY.
UM, I BROUGHT WHISKEY.
(laughs) SO...
THANKS.
CAN I COME IN?
YEAH, YEAH.
COOL. WOW.
ARE YOU LOCKING THE DOOR?
I HOPE YOU DON'T TURN OUT
TO BE CRAZY. (chuckles)
SO THE DOORMAN...
HE JUST LET YOU UP?
YEAH.
BUT I DID SAY I WAS YOUR
KID SISTER FROM NEBRASKA.
YEAH, YOU'RE TOTALLY
FROM NEBRASKA.
(both laugh)
? I SAW YOU WITH A MADMAN ?
? RUNNING DOWN THE STREET
WITH A HOLD OF YOUR HAND ?
? I SAW YOU TURNING THE CORNER ?
? WONDERING IF I'D
EVER SEE YOU AGAIN ?
? OH, COME ON, COME ON ?
? OH, DARLING, OH, DARLING ?
? THE EARTH
IS SPINNING SO FAST ?
? SLEEPING ON THE FLOOR
OF YOUR APARTMENT ?
? PRAYING THAT THESE STREETS
WILL LAST ?
? YOU WERE SAILING
ACROSS THE OCEAN ?
? WATCHING THE SKY
TURNING BLACK ?
YOUR GRANDMOTHER
MUST'VE BEEN STRANGE, DUDE.
WHY'D YOU SAY THAT?
WHY WOULD SHE WANNA HIDE
ALL HER OLD FAMILY PHOTOS
IN A DRAWER?
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
OH, THAT'S MY MOM.
SHE MUST'VE BEEN
ABOUT TEN THERE.
AND THAT'S MY GRANDMOTHER,
BUT I NEVER GOT TO KNOW HER.
HOW COME?
SHE SPLIT WITH MY GRANDFATHER
WHEN MY MOM WAS IN 6th GRADE,
AND HE TOOK MY MOM TO NEBRASKA,
WHERE HIS FAMILY'S FROM.
OH. FAMILIES ARE ALL
THE SAME, RIGHT?
SUPER COMPLICATED.
(chuckles)
WELL, THAT'S SMOKEY.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF GRANDMA'S DRESS?
CAN I HAVE IT?
IT'S ALL YOURS. IT'S ALL YOURS.
? ...ALL OF MY LOVE ?
? OH, COME ON, COME ON ?
? OH, DARLING, OH, DARLING ?
? DON'T LET MY DREAMS
COME TRUE ?
HMM?
(chuckles)
? I'LL LET YOU GET CLOSE TO ME ?
? IF YOU JUST LET ME
GET CLOSE TO YOU ?
(laughs)
(heavy breathing)
(yawns)
WHO ARE YOU, DANNY HILL?
WELL, APPARENTLY YOUR FAMILY
GOES TO THE WHITE HOUSE.
AND THEY HAVE AMAZING GENES.
LAUNDRY ROOM.
LUCKY GUY.
MAN, LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
BREAD? OH, MY GOD!
HOW DISGUSTING!
SALMON.
OH, MY GOD. THAT IS FAT.
DO YOU SEE THAT?
IT'S THE BEST THING
WE'VE EVER HAD ON STALK BLOG.
OH, MY GOD. HE DOESN'T PUT
THE CAP ON HIS STUFF.
THAT'S SO WEIRD.
(chuckles)
WHAT IS THAT?
"HELLO, I'M DANNY HILL. OH..."
UM, EXCELLENT.
WHAT?
UGH.
(GASPS)
(doorbell rings)
(knock at door)
SHARLEEN?
I'M WITH HILDEBRAND AND STEVENS.
WE MANAGE THE BUILDING.
OH, DO YOU?
I UNDERSTAND THE PREVIOUS
OCCUPANT, MRS. WAINWRIGHT,
RECENTLY PASSED ON.
UH, YEAH, YEAH,
THAT WAS MY GRANDMOTHER.
SHE DIED LAST TUESDAY.
OH, I'M SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
PLEASE ACCEPT MY CONDOLENCES.
THANKS.
SO AM I TO UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU MIGHT ARE INTERESTED
IN APPLYING FOR A NEW LEASE?
WELL, ACTUALLY, UH,
IT WAS MY IMPRESSION
THAT THE EXISTING LEASE
WOULD CONTINUE UNDER MY NAME.
THAT'S--NO, NO, NO.
THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
YOU SEE,
YOU ARE NOT THE LEASEHOLDER.
WHEN YOUR GRANDMOTHER DIED,
HER TENANCY ENDED
AND TECHNICALLY YOU HAVE
NO RIGHT TO BE HERE.
IN FACT, I'M GONNA HAVE
TO ASK YOU TO LEAVE.
WAIT, YOU'RE--
KICKING ME OUT?
TECHNICALLY,
YOU'RE TRESPASSING.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I KNOW MY RIGHTS, SO...
OKAY, WELL--
(door locks)
WELL, IF THAT'S HOW
YOU WANNA PLAY IT,
THEN THAT IS HOW
WE WILL PLAY IT.
SEE YOU SOON.
HE'S A MANAGING AGENT, DANNY.
HE'S NOT A LAWYER.
LOOK, I LOVE THIS APARTMENT,
MAN, AND I WANNA STAY HERE.
I COULD SEE MYSELF
LIVING HAPPILY HERE
FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE.
AND YOU WILL.
YEAH, BUT I NEED TO KNOW--
IS THERE ANY POSSIBILITY
THAT I'M GONNA GET KICKED OUT?
I MEAN,
IS THERE THE SLIGHTEST CHANCE?
LISTEN, DANNY,
I DON'T KNOW YOU THAT WELL,
AND YOU DON'T KNOW ME THAT WELL.
BUT I WOULD NEVER DREAM OF
GIVING A CLIENT FALSE HOPE.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
I'M ALREADY PAINTING THE PLACE.
SO I NEED TO KNOW THAT
NO ONE IS GONNA COME HERE
AND KICK ME OUT--NO ONE.
AND NO ONE WILL.
NO ONE?
LISTEN,
THEY WANT YOU OUT OF THERE.
NOW, UNTIL
I GET THE COURT ORDER,
YOU GOTTA BARRICADE YOURSELF
IN THERE.
LOCK YOURSELF IN,
LIKE I ALREADY TOLD YOU.
DON'T GO OUT FOR NOTHING.
NEVER.
YOU GOT THAT?
YEAH, I GOT THAT.
'CAUSE IF YOU GO OUT,
THAT'S IT. NO MORE APARTMENT.
THEY WON'T LET YOU
BACK IN THE BUILDING.
OKAY?
I GOTTA GO.
COFFEE, EXTRA SUGAR,
AND A PLATTER.
SHARLEEN?
(door unlocking)
WHAT ABOUT MY ATM CARD?
JOE KEEP IT.
YOU DON'T NEED RIGHT NOW.
OKAY.
UM, HEY, JOE...
WERE YOU ON DUTY
ALL NIGHT LAST NIGHT?
YOUR SISTER'S VERY NICE.
I LET HER UP BECAUSE
I KNEW IT'D MAKE YOU HAPPY.
SHE STAY WITH YOU?
YEAH. UH, NO, NO.
SHE, UH...
SHE HAD TO LEAVE.
BUT IT'S NICE
TO SEE FAMILY, NO?
YEAH, IT'S VERY NICE
TO SEE FAMILY.
BYE.
(locks door)
OH!
EVERYONE'S GOT A PASSWORD.
"THEY BROUGHT UNTO HIM
MANY THAT WERE POSSESSED
WITH DEVILS."
(bang)
(water dripping)
(rats squeaking)
SO NOW YOU'RE TELLING ME THAT
THERE COULD BE RATS UP HERE
ON THE 10th FLOOR?
I THOUGHT YOU TOLD ME THAT
THIS BUILDING DIDN'T HAVE RATS?
DANNY, TAKE IT EASY.
IT'S NEW YORK CITY.
OF COURSE
THERE'S THE ODD RAT,
WITH GARBAGE AND COOKING.
I'VE GOT MAN.
HE COMES EVERY MONDAY.
HE WILL TAKE CARE
OF PROBLEM.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HOW DO I KNOW THAT THE LANDLORD
HASN'T PAID YOU TO TRICK ME,
GET SOME GOON DISGUISED
AS A BUG GUY TO COME IN HERE
AND KICK ME OUT OF MY APARTMENT?
I MEAN, AFTER ALL, JOE,
YOU WORK FOR THEM--
YOU DON'T WORK FOR ME.
THAT IS WHAT YOU SAY TO JOE?
THAT IS WHAT YOU SAY TO ME?!
I THOUGHT WE WERE FRIENDS!
(sighs)
I ENCOURAGE YOU
TO LIVE IN MY BUILDING
BECAUSE I CARE ABOUT YOU.
BUT MAYBE--
MAYBE I'M WRONG.
MAYBE I LET YOU STEW IN THERE!
HAVE THEM KICK YOU OUT!
NO, NO, JOE, JOE,
LOOK, I'M...
I'M SORRY.
I JUST THINK I'M GETTING
A LITTLE PARANOID BEING
COOPED UP HERE ALL THE TIME.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU BRING THAT BUG GUY,
I'LL LET YOU BOTH IN, OKAY?
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S BETTER.
AND, UH, ACTUALLY...
I NEED YOU TO GO OUT
AND GET ME SOME GROCERIES
AND STUFF.
YOU NEED? NOW YOU NEED JOE?
YOU NEED YOUR BEST FRIEND JOE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME NOW?
YEAH, I SLID THE LIST
UNDER THE DOOR.
(sighs)
EIGHT SIX-PACK OF MODELO.
WHAT, YOU WANT TO KILL JOE?
NO, IT'S TOO HEAVY.
I BRING SIX SIX-PACK.
TWO GALLON OF MILK.
I BRING ONE.
I HAVE BAD BACK.
TWO PERCENT.
ALL RIGHT, RELAX!
NO PROBLEM.
FOUR PINT PHISH FOOD,
FOUR FROZEN TACO,
EIGHT FROZEN
ROAST BEEF DINNER.
THAT'S TOO MUCH BEEF, BUDDY.
I BRING BEEF AND CHICKEN,
50/50. BETTER FOR YOU. OKAY?
ALL RIGHT, JOE.
YOU'RE THE BOSS.
ALL RIGHT.
(rats squeaking)
(sighs)
Feinberg: THEY'VE TAKEN OUT
A COMPLAINT AGAINST YOU,
SEEKING AN ORDER FOR
IMMEDIATE POSSESSION,
AND IT'S TO BE
ENTIRELY EXPECTED.
BUT YOU ASSURED ME THAT
THE APARTMENT WAS MINE.
AND IT WILL BE.
I ALREADY GOT
A HEARING DATE
AT LANDLORD AND TENANT COURT
NEXT TUESDAY.
LOOK, MAN,
THAT IS A REALLY LONG TIME
TO BE HOLED UP IN HERE.
I'M STARTING TO GO
A LITTLE CRAZY, ALL RIGHT?
OKAY, JUST BE PATIENT.
YOU GOTTA REMAIN THERE
UNTIL YOU HEAR FROM ME.
IT'S GONNA BE WORTH IT.
YOU'RE GONNA THANK ME
LIKE YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE.
TRUST ME.
OKAY, I GOTTA GO.
CAN I HAVE A BITE?
Sharleen: DO YOU WANT ONE?
SURE, GO AHEAD.
IT'S SO GOOD.
IT'S BRILLIANT.
(humming)
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
UM, CAN I GET IN IT?
UH, DRIVE IT?
OH, SHIT.
I'M NOT THAT KIND OF GIRL.
BUT I CAN GET YOU
ON MY VIDEO BLOG.
CAN I HAVE A RIDE
ON YOUR VESPA?
GO DOWN THERE.
?
(laughs)
ARE YOU STALKING ME?
NO, I'M JUST FILMING
FOR MY WEB BLOG.
WELL, WOULD YOU MIND
NOT FILMING ME?
OKAY.
THANKS.
(heavy breathing)
(chuckles)
WHAT IS THAT?
"HELLO, I'M DANNY HILL. OH..."
(gasps)
(doorbell rings)
YEAH?
CABLE.
I DIDN'T ORDER ANY CABLE.
SAYS HERE YOU DID.
LOOK, I'M SURE
I DIDN'T ORDER ANY CABLE.
(doorbell rings)
NOW WHAT?
YEAH?
Man: PIZZA DELIVERY.
I DIDN'T ORDER ANY PIZZA.
WELL, I GOT A PEPPERONI
AND MUSHROOM HERE.
I DIDN'T ORDER A FUCKING PIZZA.
SO WHY DON'T YOU PEOPLE
LEAVE ME THE FUCK ALONE?
I KNOW YOU'RE TRYING
TO GET ME OUT OF HERE,
BUT IT'S NOT GONNA WORK.
YOU GUYS ARE NOT GONNA WIN,
OKAY?
PIZZA DELIVERY.
YOU JUST HAVE TO KEEP YOUR COOL.
YOU CAN DO THAT.
YOU KNOW YOU CAN.
AND THEN THIS BABY
IS GONNA BE ALL YOURS.
YOU JUST HAVE
A COUPLE MORE DAYS
AND THEN YOU CAN
GET OUT OF HERE.
NOBODY CAN STOP YOU
FROM COMING BACK IN...
BECAUSE THIS
WILL BE YOUR HOME.
OKAY?
YEAH.
THIS IS THE THIRD TIME
I'VE TRIED TO GET HOLD OF HIM.
Woman: I'M SORRY,
BUT MR. FEINBERG'S
AT WORK RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S--SEE, THAT'S WHAT YOU
TOLD ME YESTERDAY.
LOOK, JUST PUT ME THROUGH
TO ONE OF HIS PARTNERS.
MR. FEINBERG
DOESN'T HAVE PARTNERS.
MR. FEINBERG WORKS ALONE.
I CAN GIVE YOU
HIS VOICE MAIL.
NO, NO,
I DON'T WANT HIS VOICE MAIL!
(man screams)
(woman screams)
(people clamoring)
QUICK! GET SOME HELP!
(doorbell rings)
(knock at door)
JOE GOT YOUR STUFF FOR YOU.
BUT NOW I MUST GO
TALK TO THE POLICE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THE PAINTERS, THEY'RE GOOD,
BUT THEY DON'T PAY ATTENTION.
EXTERMINATOR
WILL BE HERE 9:00 AM.
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
WATCH WHERE YOU'RE SPRAYING
THAT NASTY SHIT.
ZIG?
(rats squeaking)
(grunts)
Joe: WHAT'S UP, JOHNNY BABY?
WHERE DO I START
THIS MORNING?
1003.
EXTERMINATOR.
HOW LONG ARE YOU GONNA BE?
DEPENDS.
YOU GOTTA A PRETTY BIG SPACE...
GIVE ME ABOUT AN HOUR.
(whistling)
(humming)
(Ziggy meows)
OH.
HEY, KITTY.
KITTY...
(chuckles)
(sprays)
(Ziggy growls)
DANNY BABY, IT'S JOE.
EXTERMINATOR STILL WITH YOU?
UH, I'LL CHECK
AND CALL YOU BACK.
HELLO?
(gasps)
OH! OH! OH! OH!
FUCK!
JOE?
YES, BABY?
HI, UH...
IT'S--IT'S DANNY
IN--IN 1003.
LISTEN, UM...
I JUST...
I JUST HAVE TO TELL YOU THAT...
THE EXTERMINATOR
LEFT A WHILE AGO.
DON'T WORRY, BABY.
JOHNNY MOVE THROUGH BUILDING
LIKE BURMESE PYTHON.
HE DO GOOD JOB FOR YOU, NO?
YES, HE DID A GOOD JOB.
HE DID A GREAT JOB.
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE.
BECAUSE IF YOU DO,
THE COPS WILL COME
AND THEN THE LANDLORD
AND THE MEDICAL EXAMINER.
AND WHILE THEY DRAG ME DOWN
TO THE PRECINCT,
THEY'RE GONNA BE IN HERE,
CHANGING LOCKS AND KICKING ME
OUT OF MY HOME!
NO...
YOU HAVE GOT TO GO.
(panting)
FUCK!
(grunting)
(elevator dings)
(panting)
(gasps)
WELL, HEY THERE AGAIN!
FANCY RUNNING INTO YOU
TWICE THE SAME DAY.
YOU DON'T RUN INTO NEIGHBORS
THAT OFTEN IN THIS BUILDING.
I'M SORRY...
WE MET BEFORE?
THIS MORNING
OF COURSE.
WE'VE BEEN AWAY.
MY DAD AND I JUST CAME BACK
FROM VISITING RELATIVES UPSTATE.
I ALWAYS LIKED
YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
NICE LADY.
NOW ISN'T THAT SMART?
THOSE GLOVES.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA PICK UP THESE DAYS.
YEAH. WELL, VERY NICE
MEETING YOU, NEIGHBOR...
TWICE IN ONE DAY.
IF YOU EVER NEED ANYTHING,
JUST LET US KNOW.
THAT'S WHAT
NEIGHBORS ARE FOR.
AHH.
(panting)
DANNY BABY,
YOU MISS EVERYTHING.
FIRST MY PAINTER...
AND NOW MY EXTERMINATOR.
THE FIND HIM DEAD
IN THE STAIRWELL.
MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
AWFUL.
YEAH.
THE PARAMEDICS,
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY FIND
IN HIS POCKET?
LITTLE BOTTLE OF PILLS
FOR BLOOD PRESSURE.
(mumbles)
WHAT?
ALL RIGHT, HE'S DEAD.
NOW I NEED TO GO.
FIND NEW EXTERMINATOR
TO DEAL WITH RATS IN BUILDING.
(mumbles)
THANK YOU.
(grunting)
OH.
(chuckles)
ZIG.
(sighs)
ZIG?
(snaps fingers)
ZIGGY?
COME ON, BUDDY.
(bell ringing)
(gasps)
ZIGGY?!
ZIGGY?! ZIGGY?!
(scratching sound)
ZIGGY?
(grunting)
(doorbell rings)
(doorbelling ringing
and knocking)
WHAT IN HELL
ARE YOU DOING IN THERE?
IMPROVEMENTS.
DO YOU HAVE
THE BUILDING'S APPROVAL?
UH...
I AM CALLING THE POLICE.
DAD, CALM DOWN!
I AM CALLING THE POLICE!
I AM NOT GONNA CALM DOWN
UNTIL HE STOPS THAT RACKET!
HELLO AGAIN.
NEED SOME HELP IN THERE?
WILL YOU SHUT UP?!
GET BACK IN THE APARTMENT!
IF YOU KEEP MAKING THAT NOISE,
I'M GOING TO HAVE YOU ARRESTED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE DOING IN THERE,
BUT THIS BUILDING HAS RULES!
THAT'S FUNNY.
YEAH, THAT'S FUCKING HILARIOUS.
YOU THINK YOU'RE GONNA WIN,
BUT NO.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA WIN.
JOE HERE.
YOU WANT WHAT?
WHATEVER YOU NEED, BABY.
WHATEVER YOU NEED.
(door unlocking)
YOU'RE IN LUCK, BABY.
RAZOR WIRE
AND RAZOR CUTTERS.
CAREFUL, VERY SHARP.
THEY CUT OFF MY POWER.
WHY YOU TALKING CRAZY?
CRAZY?
LOOK.
NO, NO, NO...
THEY ARE FUCKING
WITH MY HEAD, JOE.
THEY TOOK MY CAT!
POWER IS ON
AND YOUR CAT PROBABLY
HIDING IN THE APARTMENT.
NO, JOE, THEY CUT MY POWER.
I KNOW THEY DID!
I TELL YOU WHAT WE DO.
I TAKE ATM CARD,
GET YOU NICE DINNER
AND NICE BOTTLE OF WINE
SO YOU CAN RELAX.
I CAN'T RELAX!
WHY YOU HAVE ALL THIS STUFF?
TO KEEP THEM
FROM ENTERING MY APARTMENT.
THEM?
YES.
WHO'S THEM, DANNY?
NOT LANDLORD. DOOR'S LOCKED.
HE CANNOT GET IN.
WELL, THAT IS OBVIOUSLY
NOT STOPPING HIM, IS IT?
THEY ARE MESSING WITH ME, JOE.
THEY ARE TRYING TO DRIVE ME
OUT OF MY HOME!
WHAT DID LAWYER SAY?
HOW MANY DAYS BEFORE HE KNOWS?
THE DAY AFTER TOMORROW.
DAY AFTER TOMORROW, DANNY.
JOE?
WHAT?
I NEED YOU TO GET UP HERE
RIGHT NOW.
(doorbell rings)
Man: I'VE BEEN TOLD
TO ASK YOU TO LEAVE RIGHT NOW.
WHERE'S JOE?
HE WENT HOME.
I CALLED FOR JOE.
JOE IS SICK.
I'M FILLING IN FOR HIM.
YOU'RE FILLING IN FOR HIM?
UM...
ALL RIGHT, OKAY.
YOU KNOW...
WE CAN MAKE THIS WORK,
YOU AND ME.
UM... ALL RIGHT.
FIRST I NEED YOU
TO GO TO THE MARKET
AND GET ME SOME STUFF.
I'M PUTTING A NOTE
UNDER THE DOOR.
I'M UNDER STRICT INSTRUCTIONS
TO ASK YOU TO OPEN THE DOOR
AND LEAVE THE BUILDING
IMMEDIATELY, SIR.
WELL, ALL RIGHT...
WELL, FUCK YOU
AND YOUR FANCY NEW HAT,
BECAUSE THIS IS MY HOME
AND I'M ENTITLED TO BE HERE!
ONE MORE DAY.
ONE MORE DAY...
AND THIS PLACE WILL BE
ALL FUCKING MINE.
(echo) AND THIS PLACE WILL BE
(screaming)
(doorbell rings)
YEAH?
IS EVERYTHING OKAY
IN THERE, SIR?
YEAH, EVERYTHING'S FINE,
OFFICER.
MIND IF I TAKE
A LOOK FOR MYSELF?
Stanley: YOU SEE, I TOLD YOU
I'D CALL THE POLICE.
WE DON'T NEED PEOPLE LIKE YOU
IN THIS BUILDING.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
CAN I COME IN?
DO YOU HAVE A WARRANT?
NO.
NO? THEN YOU CAN'T COME IN.
YOU SEE?
WHAT DID I TELL YOU?
YOU'RE DEALING WITH
A COMPLETE WHACKO.
WHAT'S THAT SMELL?
DINNER.
I WORK...
ODD HOURS.
IT'S AFTER 10:00 PM.
KEEP THAT RACKET DOWN.
IF I GET ANOTHER COMPLAINT,
I'LL COME BACK HERE WITH
A WARRANT. YOU UNDERSTAND?
ZIGGY!
Woman: YOU HAVE REACHED
THE LAW OFFICES OF
BERTRAM G. FEINBERG.
MR. FEINBERG IS NOT AVAILABLE
TO TAKE YOUR CALL RIGHT NOW,
BUT PLEASE LEAVE YOUR NAME
AT THE BEEP.
(beep)
MR. FEINBERG,
THIS IS DANNY HILL.
MAIL BOX IS FULL.
(dial tone)
HELLO?
(grunting)
(knock at door)
MR. HILL?
CONGRATULATIONS.
LIKE I SAID ON THE PHONE,
YOU GOTTA TRUST ME.
I TOLD YOU THE COURT ORDER
WOULD COME THROUGH.
(knocks)
DANNY?
OPEN UP!
WELL, CONGRATULATIONS.
THE WHOLE PLACE IS YOURS--
EVERY SINGLE SQUARE FOOT.
GET OUT.
ENJOY YOUR FREEDOM.
(indistinct
radio transmissions)
(indistinct chatter)
Sharleen:
WHO ARE YOU, DANNY HILL?
OH, MY GOD. THAT'S FAT.
DO YOU SEE THAT?
(chuckles)
WHAT IS THAT?
"HELLO, I'M DANNY HILL. OH..."
EXCELLENT.