3 hours ago
One warm doner for 2 o'clock.
Room 607, The Westin Grand
What do you have to say about
the missile test results?
Korean NIS Surveillance vehicle
The estimates you gave us were
off by over two kilometers.
Yuri, Russian arms broker
Our technicians were not
present for the test.
Smaller arms and the older
missiles are not a problem.
We worry about the new missiles.
Hey, what just happened?
We lost audio.
Do something.
Korean National intelligence Agency Berlin
Office The Russian's opening his laptop.
- Fix the damn audio.
- Hang on a second.
- Are you getting audio?
- They're not closing the deal yet.
Who's that pretty boy?
I'm not getting anything.
Nothing on CIA, MI6
or Mossad database.
What the..?
A ghost?
I haven't seen one
of those in a while.
If you don't purchase
the new missiles,
we will not provide the
additional weapons.
Assim, Anti-imperialist
Arab League
And then
we run another test with
North Korean technicians.
What do you say?
Somebody fix the goddamn audio.
Let me call you back.
Surveillance department North
Korean embassy, Berlin
I don't make the decisions.
I only follow orders.
You have the new
young leader now.
You must be more
flexible comrade.
Flexible?
You claim to oppose imperialism, but you
negotiate with this imperialistic logic?
Our terms are non-negotiable.
Lee Hak-su, North Korea's
ambassador to Germany
Excuse me.
What's the problem between you?
You came to sign the
contract, not negotiate.
This is the most reasonable
deal I've seen in years.
You're both being stubborn.
You're slaves to your pride.
We cannot match his
price in dollars.
And what about Euros?
I can speak to him
about that, at least.
Get the helpers ready.
First, you sign the papers,
then you bet the money.
The transfer first.
Action.
Action!
Okay.
Abort! Abort!
The deal is off. Get
the hell out of there!
This is the Mossad!
Our cleanup squad's
here in ten minutes.
Dagan, Mossad (Israeli
secret service)
Don't make this any worse
than it already is.
We can end this here.
We've got no interest
in your weapons deal.
We're only here for the
Russian broker and the Arab.
You've got plenty of other
clients to do business with.
Target on rooftop.
Proceed to service corridor
on the opposite side.
Distance to target 150 meters.
Come quietly.
They train you to put
the gun on the temple?
I just need to know the terms
and confirm the goods.
I turn my head and the
bullet misses me.
Alright, let's go.
Your spectacular screw-up
could reverberate all the way
to the Presidential House.
This is an absolute
diplomatic nightmare.
And for what gain?
We got the deal on tape.
Did you get the conversation?
Or the actual goods on tape?
You've got nothing to
confirm the deal terms.
No recording of
the conversation.
Exactly what do you have?
He put a gun to my face.
What proof do we need?
And because of that commie,
one of our men sustained a
severe injury to the spine.
We still can't escape blame
under international law.
You opened fire based
on speculation,
- at a person whose identity..
- Don't dump your crap on us!
For fuck's sake.
You've got no information on this
supposed North Korean agent.
Are we even sure we're
dealing with North Koreans?
Who's going to clean
up this mess?
Who?
Fuck..
Berlin unit under Chief Kang.
Prepare to be disbanded.
Mr. Inspector,
disbanding the team isn't
going to solve the problem.
A third country party
intervened at the scene.
A third party?
Give me that.
It's not the weapons
trade we're after.
We're tracking down Kim Jong-il's
secret account worth 4 billion dollars
believed to have been moved from
Macau to Europe before his death.
If we find that account,
we get the upper hand in issues
regarding aid to North Korea.
It's unlike you to
make such mistake.
Yuri is an arms broker
wanted by the US government.
That explains how the South
Koreans knew about the deal.
But Assim is an
anti-American activist.
Why did Israelis show
up, not the Americans?
The leak must have come
from one of three parties.
Either the Russians sold the
information to the Israelis
or the Arab was a double agent
working for the Mossad..
Or it came from us.
Pyo Jong-seong.
Watch your mouth!
Jong-seong, listen
to me carefully.
Do you know who's on his
way from Pyongyang?
Dong Myung-su.
Why would they dispatch an
agent when you're out here?
They don't trust us.
Foreign offices are put under
scrutiny under the new leadership.
Even you, the Republic's
hero, need to be watched.
Take care where you tread..
Comrade Ambassador,
have you forgotten
what my job is?
I'm only saying..
I will not make an official
record of your statement.
Is that all I am to you?
An object of surveillance?
You're losing your focus.
These are all
speculations at best.
Where is intelligence?
Intelligence.
You gotta do better than this
to transfer to US office.
The agent in charge,
Jung Jin-su,
I heard he stirred up
trouble in Libya, too.
These old-timers hung up on
anti-communistic ideas are just burdens.
I prefer not to see his name on
your next report, understood?
I trust you'll take care of it.
Bring me results.
Man, I told you to stay clear
of Korean restaurants.
Are you pissed off at me
for not covering your ass?
It's my birthday today.
I felt like a bowl
of seaweed soup.
So, I came to this restaurant
where no Koreans come.
For a bowl of home-made soup.
I meant to give you a
heads-up about the account.
But I missed the timing.
That's your excuse? Timing?
Cut me some slack, man.
This is not some sloppy industrial
espionage job we're dealing with.
I have a political
position to consider.
Screw you.
What political
position with commies?
I don't even make left
turns at intersections.
Anyone in my position
in any organization,
prefers to work with someone
that listens to you.
Do you know what
your problem is?
You make people uncomfortable.
Why are you sitting with
someone so uncomfortable?
Fine, I'll get off your face.
What do you want from me?
You can get rid of me.
You can transfer
to the US office.
But our man who got busted
by the commie today,
he'll be confined to a wheelchair
for the rest of his life.
Just do your job.
I'll do mine.
We have a reservation under
the name, Ryun Jung-hee.
Upstairs, please.
He's already here.
He proposed this meeting.
So, he'll pick up the bill?
Didn't I tell you to take
off your wedding band?
It takes more than translation
skills to be a good interpreter.
There was a discussion at the bundestag
regarding North Korean diplomats
who got caught
smuggling cigarettes.
Caught smuggling cigarettes.
Why is German parliament concerned
with what happened in Austria?
Didn't we explain that it was
a simple misunderstanding?
If this becomes a pattern,
it's hard for them to help with
our medical supply issues.
They need to set a clear
position on the matter..
We payed him up out
of empty pockets.
And that's all he has to say?
22:00, Hackescher
Market tram stop
All I need is the grounds
to convince the parliament.
You know how things work.
Everything needs to be
recorded in Germany.
He is so shamelessly blatant
that it makes me blush.
Sick bastard.
Take a good care of him.
He wants a more
personal gesture.
They need to set a clear
position on the matter.
We payed him up out
of empty pockets.
And that's all he has to say?
All I need is something to..
Hey!
What brings you here?
Without calling me.
It's late.
Wash up and go to bed.
Take a good care of him.
Let me look at your wound.
It's not necessary.
Any news from Pyongyang?
What news?
We're way past due to return.
We don't make decisions.
We follow orders.
We can at least apply
for relocation.
When did the comrades at the embassy
last had their self-criticism?
Can't you just ask me
why I want to go back?
I guess I thought wrong.
I forgot that you're Republic's
hero before you're my husband.
Oh my God.
Help! Somebody!
There is a dead woman here!
Waitress commits
suicide by overdosing
Let's find a new way to meet up.
Kids these days
they try these fancy
new techniques
always end up gettin' their
asses handed to them.
And these guys like you and me,
two old dogs, with old tricks,
- but we're still kicking.
- Enough with the old dogs.
You really makes us sound old.
I hate yo break it to the
pal, but we are old.
So, what can uncle Marty
do for his favorite ally?
I need to know if that
guy's in your database.
A North Korean?
White or Black Ops?
A ghost.
You heard about the Westin
Hotel kidnapping two days ago,
didn't you?
He was there.
And You were there too?
Ah, fuck..
You knew my team was tracking
Asim and his network!
Way to bend me over
the barrel, pal!
I had no time.
If I got that fucking commie
I was gonna hand over the
others as my Present.
What the hell with your present.
You told me you'd leak any intel you
had about the North's weapons deals!
And now, you tell me
the shit hit the fan.
Hey! Shut up. Please.
I got you a very
special present.
special present..?
Look.
A guy named Sigmund,
who is the German
ODA vice-minister
had a meeting with the
North Korean ambassador.
At the end, the ambassador
told his female translator
to take good care of Sigmund.
I'm going home at the end
of the month, alright?
The only thing I want
on my plate right now,
- is my wife's home cooking.
- Hey. Hey, old dog!
Sorry.
Your Foreign Affairs
would love it.
What got you delayed?
I had to take care of
something upon my arrival.
I wasn't informed of your delay.
Watch this and
you'll understand.
Back then, orders never
contradicted each other.
They all had the same voice.
That's not how things work now.
The new Comrade Commander
doesn't like the old ways.
You recognize that woman?
Yes, it's my
favorite restaurant.
Germans like it, too.
So do the South Koreans.
They suspect you have a
leak in Berlin office.
It's not possible.
The most trustworthy is the one
to be watched most closely.
Comrade Stalin said that.
Did you inform the
Party about this?
I made a record of it.
Wouldn't it be better coming
from you than from me?
What if there is no evidence?
The Party says there is a
leak and you disagree?
That means the Party is wrong.
It makes the Party incompetent.
Say that again.
Who sold the information?
The woman..
The interpreter for the embassy
who made a reservation
under the name,
Ryun Jung-hee.
The waitress was an informant
for the South Koreans.
You know the
accusation is false.
Are you suggesting that Dong
fabricated the confession?
Whether it was fabricated
or not isn't important.
Your wife's name came
up in an inquiry
conducted by the
Security Department.
A name that Pyongyang
wanted to hear.
If you try to defend her when
the Party says she's guilty.
That makes you guilty, too.
There is no solid evidence
other than this confession.
Even you said that the leak
about the weapons deal
could have come from us.
For someone in my position, you
always have to have an answer
if not an alternative.
How much time do we have?
48 hours.
There's storm coming,
but no place to hide.
Are you sure it was this woman?
Yes.
How's work these days?
Same as always.
What you said the other
day about Pyongyang..
Do you want to go home?
Let's not talk about that.
I believe we can live
with our heads held high
even if we are poor.
Our facial recognition analysis found
three men showing over 85% match.
These two have plenty sources
for lD verification.
Bring up the travel agent.
But there is hardly any record
nor pictures of this man.
I only found one taken at a
culture promotion event.
Gotcha.
Ouch! Damn it.
Hey! Interested
in something hot?
What?
A North Korean official stationed
in Berlin just filed for defection.
To America?
No, he's asking for political asylum
through the UN to some third country.
When's next contact?
What brings you to
call me at this hour?
I have to drop by the embassy.
Did you have lunch?
I'm on my way to the
Parliament library.
I can't have lunch with you.
I'll see you at home, then.
Moran Peak 4639
requesting Comrade Ryun's
signing out record.
The next station is
Brandenburger Tor.
Negative.
Is the Parliament library
close to Brandenburger Tor?
It's at the Bundestag station.
Next to the Parliament building.
What's in Brandenburger
Tor area?
Embassies.
US and British embassies
are in the area.
This is a confidential
communication.
I'll report it myself.
Are you going out? You
didn't say anything to me.
US embassy
When is the next..
When is the next contact?
Long time, Comrade.
Still have two more days.
Did you put a tail on her?
I'm not here about your wife.
How can a perfectionist
like you.
Let this happen under your nose?
Something doesn't add up.
Is that an official statement?
We'll know soon enough.
I'm not accusing
you of anything.
The guilty will stand
for their crime.
Why are you really here?
It's a sticky situation.
And it's a matter
outside my authority.
One happy family.
There is a reactionary
seeking political asylum.
Someone from the embassy.
It's Comrade Ambassador.
Comrade Lee emptied out
the embassy's strong box.
This device will self
destruct after checking
Your password will be verbally
confirmed upon point of contact.
The agent key-phrase is,
It looks like it's
going to rain.
Your answer, verbatim, is,
But I've lost my
folding umbrella.
Your password will be verbally
confirmed upon point of contact.
The agent key-phrase is, it
looks like it's going to rain.
Your answer, verbatim,
is, But I've lost..
This is the time and
venue of rendezvous.
What's taking you so long?
What? What's taking so long?
You're the one that wanted some
private time with the guy.
We're gonna head to the U.S.
Embassy,
And enter the safe-house.
- You mean the laundromat?
- Excuse me. Do you speak English?
No.
We've got about the three hours
until the official time of contact,
so, factorin' in travel, I
can spare you about an hour.
We can say you work for the company
and that you're interrogating him.
That's as far as you
and I take this.
After that, it's every
old dog for himself.
And regardless of
what happens here,
the CIA has no affiliation
whatsoever with this operation.
There should be absolutely
no records, do you here me?
What's he offering you?
We're not sure yet,
But he mentioned a file,
some kind of shady account
they've been managing.
The Kim Jong-il account?
From Macau?
Oh sweet Jesus.
I wouldn't that make
everyone's fuckin' day?
You owe me pal big time.
3737 G406.
11 o'clock Target's
location confirmed.
Don't stand out
Blend in, idiots!
Did you tap my phone?
You're out of your mind to
interfere with CIA business.
How is North Korean
ambassador a CIA business?
It's ours.
Stand back if anything happens.
I'll take over.
Hey!
You, son of a..!
Target is getting away He's
heading to the subway.
Team A follow the subject.
Team B go across.
We gotta snatch the bastard
before anybody else.
Jong-seong.
Think about what you're doing.
We'll talk later.
Freeze!
Put the gun down.
This is our turf.
You don't want any
more trouble..
Motherfucker!
Take it easy, man.
Listen to me carefully now.
Go back to the headquarter.
Find everything you can on
the CIA agents out here.
- But it's CIA..
- Shut the hell up.
Another word from your mouth
and I'll chew your brain out.
Hi, Daddy. I love you.
Good bye.
No.
Come on, Cindy.
You knew my team was tracking
Asim and his network!
Way to bend me over
the barrel, pal!
Send me the address
of the travel agency.
Why did you do it?
I want you to think hard
why Dong Myung-su is here
why your wife is
being suspected.
You were planning to abandon your
family and defect to the West.
This is all part of a scheme
set by Dong Myung-su.. No,
his father Dong Jung-ho
to take over the Berlin office.
Dong's father wasn't an
ally with the new leader
and yet, he survived. How?
When Kim Jong-un's men pocketed
profit from illegal weapons trade.
The deal was handled
by Dong Jung-ho.
When the Americans tracked
down the Macau account.
Dongs had to clean up the mess
in order to stay in the game.
What did you get her to do?
But you don't believe
anything I say.
Questioning is in progress.
You can go in.
Jong-seong,
when you're blocked by the sea,
sing 'Arirang' a semitone down
and 'whistle' the chorus.
The Party wants to see
and hear for themselves.
Tell me what you want to hear.
I'll give an answer you want
in return for a quick death.
Your family is never your
concern even to the end.
There is nothing I
can do about them.
He talks as if
he's being framed.
Your name and position.
Lee Hak-su.
I'm an ambassador of Democratic
People's Republic of Korea
to Germany.
Why did you betray your country?
I just sent you the address
of the travel agency.
Frequent address changes
suggest it's a front company.
Shouldn't we notify Chief Kang?
I'll take care of it.
Hello.
There is a break-in
in my building.
The address is Einstenufer 9D.
It's the travel agency building.
What happened here?
Why did you lie to me
about where you were
going this afternoon?
Do you have anything
to say to me?
You knew about it all?
You weren't going to say
anything if I didn't?
I don't know where to begin.
I suppose I missed
the right time.
Tell me how it started.
It was an order from
Comrade Ambassador.
Not out of my will.
You're not giving me an answer.
Perhaps I don't
know what you want.
What have you been up to?
What am I supposed to do?
Entertaining guest was an order.
But I assure you.
This baby is ours.
This man was asking me about
an event at the square.
And this is where
my obstetrician is.
Why didn't you tell me?
I thought you wouldn't
believe it's ours.
What I think is not important.
Tell me the truth.
This is the truth.
Why didn't you say
anything earlier?
Did you ever listen?
Do you know what it's like to
endure this kind of filth?
Our first child
It's been two years
since we lost her
How much the little thing
must have suffered..
Have you ever
thought about that?
So what?
Were you going to
have an abortion?
How can you say such a thing?
We'll go to the hospital tomorrow.
If it turns out to be false..
You'll report me as a spy?
That will give you
a peace of mind.
That's what the Party
wants to hear.
Today,
Comrade Ambassador made an
attempt to defect to the West.
Write down all your whereabouts
in the last seven days.
Did you get her confession?
We still have time.
I must have interrupted
at an inconvenient time.
How did the interrogation go?
Successful, thanks to you.
His body will be
repatriated to Pyongyang.
Good work, Comrade.
I haven't found any evidence
tying Jung-hee to her charges.
Relax, man.
Congratulations.
You have passed
the loyalty test.
All this was necessary
because of Lee Hak-su.
After Comrade Chairman
Kim Jong-il passed away,
foreign funds coming into
Pyongyang dropped considerably.
While all focus was on ensuring
successful transition of power,
there was a suspicion
that Lee Hak-su
would smuggle his private
assets and defect.
And your name popped
up in the process.
A group of us including
myself insisted
that you would never
betray the Republic.
The Party's position, of
course, is not the same.
So, I suggested that
we test your loyalty.
How can we suspect the loyalty of a
man who will report his own wife
if there are suspicious
circumstances?
Agents from Security Department
will pay you a visit shortly.
You'll return to Pyongyang
and be promoted
in recognition of your loyalty.
Congratulations, Comrade.
You have saved me also.
How much did you hear?
You're a coward.
What the hell are you doing?
Once they find out what
you're doing to me,
you're a fucking dead man.
What do you think
will happen to you?
Today
a North Korean fucking commie blew
a hole through my friend's head.
At Brandenburg Gate?
My friend was CIA
tracking Asim's group.
If I report your lD
and tell them that
Israel is working with
the North Koreans who took Asim,
your fucking face will be on every CIA
watch-list in the world within 48 hours.
What now?
Do you want a cool diplomatic
dispute with America over this?
About a month ago,
Pyongyang contacted
Mossad Collections.
I'm not here about your wife
How can a perfectionist like you
let this happen under your nose?
The guilty will stand
for their crime.
They told us that if we
gave them the opportunity
to replace a few of their
people in Berlin..
Then they'd hand over the man
they do business with. Asim.
The weapons deal had to fail.
It was the opportunity
they needed.
Did someone on the
inside betray the North?
I only know what I need to know,
but.. I think
the North Korean agent at the
scene was double-crossed.
There is a sudden noise in the house.
Be careful.
Wiretapping
You have the phone
records from that time?
You want those?
I never mentioned
about reporting you
I have recorded everything
you've said here.
The word came out of your mouth
How can I have passed the test?
It's a trap We must run
Do you want it deleted?
Then you're gonna give me your
conversation with the fucking commie.
Did you finish packing?
We'll make some record
for reporting purposes.
Looking for this?
Idiots.. I warned
you to be careful.
Didn't I?
Allo..
Abdul!
Allo.
Sorry I'm late.
So.. what happened
to your brother?
The Mossad executed
him without trial.
I found the rat who gave your
brother Asim over to the Israelis..
If you get on it now, you
can still catch him.
Who is it?
It's someone we both know.
Pyo Jong-seong.
Take this.
A shooting incident was just
reported to the police.
A North Korean interpreter
lives at the address.
Hey.
Can you tap CIA satellite
communication network?
Put a surveillance on all
channels within 20km radius.
Are you out of your mind?
Just do as I say for once.
Tapping is your
expertise, isn't it?
See you again.
Watch your back.
You're going to run into
the Mossad again one day,
and it won't be pretty.
Man, you talk too much.
Do you have a room?
I prefer not to fill
out the register.
Are you alright?
We should treat
your wounds first.
Hey, policeman.
I'm from the consulate.
Here to lD the victim. OK?
Can you speak English?
- Nein.
- No?
We got a call from
a Korean student..
No problem. Just a moment.
An Asian from the
consulate is here.
A single precision shot
each to the head and chest.
These bastards are
not circumcised
and their dental work suggests
they're North Koreans.
I gotta get moving.
- Hey! Halt?
- Hi. I'll be right back.
Idiots.
Alright.
He killed all of our
comrades and escaped.
He's good, huh?
We'll get him.
Okay. First,
have your men search every
hotel within ten kilometers.
Their names will
not be on record.
So look for a couple who paid in cash
and checked-in in the last 10 minutes.
How certain are you of this?
It's what he taught me.
If you're being hunted, hide
right under the hound's nose.
Allo.
Hey. Allo.
This is a direct
order from the boss.
Search every hotel
within 10Km radius.
Look for a man and a woman
who paid cash and didn't
fill out the register.
I'm sending you their picture.
Sir, the keywords 'North
Korea, ' 'Abdul, '
and 'Assim' emerged on
CIA satellite network.
- Language used is Arabic.
- Arabic? What's the location?
It's concentrated in the 10Km
radius of the shooting scene.
Give us the traitor.
I'd like to,
but I need to get
them back as a set.
Hey, listen man.
If I become the
director of Berlin.
Then we can cut out the broker.
Everything will be
cheaper and faster.
We can pack up some super-notes
for you if you want.
Because no one better
dollars than we do.
But that's only after you drag out
this bastard's corpse, isn't' it?
Trust me.
Where are you?
It's a couple?
Jong-seong,
when you're blocked by the sea,
sing Arirang a semitone down
and whistle the chorus.
There was a suspicion
that Lee Hak-su
Arirang would smuggle his
private assets and defect.
When Kim Jong-un's men pocketed
profit from illegal weapons trade.
The deal was handled
by Dong Jung-ho.
And your name popped
up in the process.
The Whistle When the Americans
tracked down the Macau account.
Dongs had to clean up the mess
in order to stay in the game.
How can we suspect the loyalty of a
man who will report his own wife
if there are suspicious
circumstances?
I want you to think hard
why Dong Myung-su came here
and why your wife is
suspected of spying.
Listen to me carefully.
Dong Myung-su
is setting me up to make it appear
that I sold classified information.
He is trying to turn me and
Lee Hak-su into traitors
and take over the Berlin office.
If that's true, what
are we doing here?
Can we ever go
back to Pyongyang?
We'll go separate
ways from here.
Where will you go?
I can prove our innocence to the Party.
You must trust me.
The Party, the people, even the
fatherland can all suspect me.
But you..
you should have believed in me.
Will you defect or something?
How can you be so cruel?
Kill me whenever you want.
But now is not the time.
We're not here to kill you.
But if you continue to
resist, we have no choice.
You have ten seconds to decide.
One.
Two.
Three.
We're getting out
alive, all three of us.
Seven.
Eight.
That's all you
gotta think about.
Ten!
Hey!
You only got the woman?
You said there would be only two!
You gave us incorrect information!
There was another man there.
What? Another guy? A Yankee?
They said he looked like you.
It's a South Korean.
Welcome South Korean guy.
You've really gone too far.
This is getting interesting.
Let me get this straight.
My team breaks up
the arms deal Yuri set for Asim
and you'll hand both
of them over to us?
I don't believe you.
Take the wheel, if you
want to hear the rest.
It's been so long.
This is why I like you so much.
Why do you think the Mossad
let you go at the hotel?
From Macau to Berlin,
arms dealing, diplomatic office,
spying, assassination and defection.
How do they all link up?
The account that Lee Hak-su
held as a hidden card,
the 4 billion dollar fund that Kim
Jong-il left behind is the key.
After his death,
they had to transfer the
funds to the new leader
and change the people
that manage the account.
Neither Pyongyang nor Lee
Hak-su could trust each other.
As far as Pyongyang
is concerned,
the diplomatic offices' loyalty to
the new leader is questionable.
So, they decided to change
everyone with those they trust.
You've been discarded
in the process.
You're totally fucked.
You're wrong.
It's not the Republic
that betrayed me.
Do we use different Korean in
North and South these days?
You need to get the
facts straight.
This is all Dong Jung-ho's act.
Who?
The father of the assassin
that killed your CIA friend.
The secret account belongs to
Dong Jung-ho and his allies,
not to Comrade
Chairman Kim Jong-il.
Lee Hak-su was part of that
circle and got betrayed.
Where the hell is that bastard?
Think about who you
saw at the hotel.
Your husband has
crossed over to South.
It's over.
You can't be waiting for the scumbag who
abandoned his wife to save himself?
Think about it.
Testify on your husband's
double-crossing charges.
I'll take care of the rest.
Do you expect to live after
what you have done to us?
Who would know about it?
Who knows about this place?
The person who used to use it.
It's me.
All the sausages you ate
must have slowed you down.
What took you so long?
How are the South
Koreans treating you?
Let my wife go.
Wouldn't I need a witness
for a testimony?
After all, isn't it true that you're
collaborating with the South Koreans?
Put her on the phone.
Are you safe?
I'm fine.
Be strong and hang in there.
For now, do as
Myung-su tells you.
I'll come and get you soon.
What use is giving
her a false hope?
Watch it if you
want a clean death.
I'll die when I feel like it.
So, cut the crap and get
your ass over here now.
If you let me go, I'll
get you the account.
Pyo Jong-seong, do you
take me for a fool?
If I don't go,
you'll never find that account.
Nor can you find your wife.
An innocent woman will die.
Everyone dies.
She's carrying a baby.
It's not mine.
I'll convert.
Request for backup denied The
company denies all involvement
The backup's going
to be a little late.
Too many people can put the
safety of the hostage at risk.
I can do this alone
if you have my back.
If we get her out,
will she cross over with you?
She may refuse.
Let's just be honest
while we're at it.
You're willing to risk your life
for your wife who may not convert?
How am I supposed
to understand that?
It's harder for me to understand why
you're risking your life for this.
It's my job.
There is no reason for doing your job.
You just do it.
It's my wife.
There is no reason
for saving my wife.
Is he really coming?
It's going to be a while.
He won't be here till after 4AM.
Standard KGB attack time.
When humans are weakest.
Like that.
The sun will come up soon.
Have you had a sniper training?
I used to get reward vacations
for outstanding shooting skills.
Secure position.
Be careful.
On the perimeter,
two North Koreans and two Arabs.
Two Arabs by the center table.
One North Korean by the
window at 3 o'clock.
Hostage is..
on far left corner
tied to a chair.
She seems to be in..
good condition.
Hey!
Shake your head if
you can hear me.
Shake your head, damn it!
Son of a bitch.
You can't kill a man like that.
Revenge is a dish
best served cold.
What happened to your
South Korean buddies?
I can't bring in retards
to catch an idiot.
Bring the hostage over
and check the perimeter.
She made a few attempts
to escape while waiting.
Your family didn't
have to do this
to take control of
the Berlin office.
You can't have two
heads on one body.
You can endure hunger, but
can't endure headache.
Is that the kind
of trust you have
between Comrade Commander
and your father?
Comrade Commander
is a human, too.
Men betray.
I came here to be the
traitor you want.
If you let us go, we'll live in
hiding for the rest of our lives.
My confession to treason
is in that voice recorder.
The kind of things
you'll do to live.
It's an honor to hear the
confession of the Republic's hero.
Comrade Pyo betraying
the Republic.
This is so exciting.
Let's hear it, shall we?
Before we do that,
Let me ask you one thing.
Did you frame my
wife knowing that
her obstetrician was
near the US embassy?
Obstetrician?
That's right! Your wife is pregnant.
It was a lucky swing.
You're the one that
built up the story.
Isn't it your specialty?
Making a criminal out
of the innocent.
I, Pyo Jong-seong, a warrior of the
Democratic People's Republic of Korea
is having a
self-criticism session.
The party wants to replace
the Berlin branch.
But right now,
replacing the current
officials isn't justified.
Motherfucker!
Play the rest.
If we ambush the deal
Yuri is onto with Asim
then you will have the justified reason
to replace the current officials, right?
Right. So finally you Israelis
will have Yuri and Asim,
Like you've been wanting.
We can hand them over.
Explain yourself.
Didn't I always tell you?
You always get your temper
get the best of you.
You think you have it all?
Look at what you got yourself
into playing a hero.
I admit you were a good teacher.
Are you alright?
You must leave me if
you wish to live.
Don't be silly.
I know how you feel.
Then stick it out to the end.
Are you okay?
It's okay. I'm on your side.
Do you think you can move?
Go on.
Inject me.
You know killing me won't
put an end to this.
I'll put in a good word
for you to my father.
Let's just call it
a day here, eh?
Men betray.
What's your hometown?
It's okay.
Let's go.
Come on, Jung-hee.
We still have so
much to talk about.
Let's go now.
We can go anywhere we want.
I'm sorry.
Jung-hee,
wake up.
Please.
Jung-hee,
come on.
Come with me.
Where are we at
with the procedure?
Application for Defection
At the last stage.
He could convert to
our side if he wishes
or choose a third
country through the UN.
Good work, everyone.
Let's wrap up this
investigation here.
All documents regarding the
account or Pyo Jong-seong
must be destroyed living
only the minimum record
to be classified
as class 1 secret.
There are still a few
remaining procedures.
The President has announced
a new gas pipe project
during his visit to Russia.
We concluded our
negotiations with Pyongyang.
Their last condition was
for us to hand over
the account and Pyo
Jong-seong to them.
Will he be purged
along with Dong Jung-ho?
Why would Dong be purged?
He is the one that
set up this deal.
You know those types
don't go down easily.
Get off.
Get out of the car,
you goddamn commie!
I can't watch a commie like you
Live a trouble-free life.
Go.
You failed to protect your wife
and the baby that
she was carrying.
You even betrayed a man
who risked his life to help you.
You betrayed your country
and the people.
That's who you are.
Live in hiding all your life
Looking over your shoulder.
Live like that. Like a dirt.
Don't even think about letting
your heart out to anyone.
Don't think about revenge.
Just lay low breathing shallow.
Like the most common people.
It's me. How have you been?
Did you hope to live after
what you did to my son?
You're not going anywhere.
It's not just us
who's after you.
You don't have to find
me I'll come find you.
Make it fast.
I'll make you pant like a
dog begging me to kill you.
Vladivostok, one way.
SubText: MITA.326