I think this is employment fraud.
If you don't intend to hire but
give the impression that you will,
then of course all students
seeking employment will apply.
Because they're desperate.
There might be a different
company, a different contest,
and a better opportunity for them,
but they'll look at Hauline
and apply to the contest.
Ho Won.
- Let's talk about it later. Alone.
- Yes, do that.
Keep going.
I believe that the applicants
should know that...
we do not intend to hire them in
the second half open recruitment.
If you won't do that,
at least delete the false terms of...
employment.
We understand, so don't
make things complicated,
and sit down.
This is deception using one's
desperation, Mr. Park.
- My gosh.
- Chief Director Seo.
What did you say during your interview?
You said that you realized...
what you had to do after
seeing the three of us.
This is...
a mocker of the 600,000 people
who are looking for jobs.
Please remove the clause...
pertaining to employment.
Hauline must remain as an honest company.
Don't worry about it, sir.
I will talk to her.
Go back to work.
Yes, sir.
Goodbye.
Are you really that thoughtless?
What are you trying to do, saying
that in front of the chief director?
The chief director is the one who
put me in charge of the contest.
So why can't I tell him my opinion?
You could have talked to me, Mr. Heo,
or Mr. Seo first.
"Elimination of rank and position".
These are the things the chief
director said at the company dinner.
This is why he came in
to the meeting today.
Didn't he come to listen to
what the employees had to say?
Isn't it about time you are able to
adjust to the office atmosphere?
How much longer are you going to
say everything that you want to?
It's not what I want to say,
but what I believe should be said.
Ho Won.
You're no longer a contract employee
who is leaving in a couple months.
If you're a full-time employee of Hauline,
shouldn't you think about what
benefits the company first?
Ms. Cho.
I don't think that...
lying to desperate college students...
is a benefit to the company.
We can't change the
conditions of the contest.
Eun Ho Won.
Yes, Mr. Lee.
Do you think you're Yoo
Gwan Sun or Joan of Arc?
Why are you interfering...
with other people's work?
Mr. Lee, I was unemployed recently,
so I know how these students feel.
- I really think it's...
- No, no, no. Stop right there.
It's normal for people to
forget their earlier days.
And that's the right thing to do.
Ho Won, do you think about when
you used to crawl around...
at the age of one?
- It's not that.
- Stop.
Don't talk back to your superiors.
If a person's situation changes,
their behavior and mindset
should change too.
Just like me, an assistant manager.
I have class and manner that
is appropriate to my position.
Since you're a full-time employee,
you have to live and act like
a person worthy of Hauline.
It's going to get noisy
here because of you.
I'm sorry.
Here you go.
I think that the cooperation with...
the design team on the new
project is going well.
Ms. Cho has been doing a great job.
Far beyond my expectations.
The marketing team is
free these days, right?
Since there aren't many
additional promotions going on,
we've been checking on...
the online promotions
and existing projects.
It's hard not to have anything to do.
Also, when the outline for
the new products are set,
our team will have to participate in that.
I will go out now.
There will be an announcement about
restructuring the company soon.
I feel that...
the organization of the company is too lax.
If we continue this way,
don't you think it will be hard to
guarantee the future of the company?
I think it's time for a reformation
of the management of Hauline.
So what, then?
Do you intend to stabilize and reform...
the company by downsizing and
rearranging the people through...
an innovative restructuring of the company?
That's a good way to phrase it.
You should be in charge of the
plan for the restructuring.
It might sound good, but it just
means you're firing people.
If there is a need, we have to do it.
Restructuring without a reason...
will only bring opposition
from the employees.
Why do you think I don't have a reason?
I have performance records
and evaluation scores.
Chief Director Seo.
Our company is still all right.
If there is a problem, then it's too late.
I'm different from my father.
We have to take care of things in advance.
Why are you telling me this now?
Please compile a list of the
restructuring targets, Mr. Seo.
Why must I do that?
In an organization, if an order is given,
following it is your job, Mr. Seo.
Why do you keep asking questions?
I'm giving a task to the person who
is most qualified for the job.
I can't take my eyes off of you.
I never know when you're
going to cause trouble.
Mr. Seo.
I thought it was because you thought
you weren't going to live long.
Now you know you will, so is it all
right for you to act this way?
Are you prepared to deal with it?
We're not...
beggars who pick up and feed off...
false hope.
You don't know...
how desperate we are.
You all don't know how
much hope we lay on...
that kind of phrases and words.
You can't treat us like that
just because you don't know.
You can't walk all over us just because...
it's not your hope.
Are you done crying?
You probably don't know...
how it feels to smile
even when you're upset...
or how it feels not to
be able to protest...
even when things are unfair.
I've been having the same
feelings a lot these days.
Really?
Do you know why no one is
saying anything about...
the unfair requirement of the contest?
It's because they're desperate.
They know that if they make
an objection and lose favor,
the company will say,
"Don't apply then."
I know what you mean.
I know how it must feel,
but can't you let it go just this once?
There is a reason for it.
Please listen to me.
You said this...
when you were congratulating me for
getting the full-time position.
Authorization seems like a cool
thing where you sign your name,
but you're actually promising on
your name to take responsibility.
As a new employee of the marketing team,
please make your decisions carefully.
That's why I'm giving you this.
You see,
I'm using the desperateness...
and hopes of the job seekers as bait.
I'm basically in charge of deceiving them.
This is my first task as
a full-time employee.
Do you want me to deceive them in my name?
Just let it slide this once.
Just look the other way.
I thought you'd be different.
I thought you'd tell me...
to stick to my beliefs and speak up.
It's been a long time since
you came to see me first.
When I first met you,
I thought we'd make a good team.
I will do everything in my power...
to carry out the new project successfully.
Please reconsider the restructuring.
I beg of you.
This is unexpected.
I heard you were the most
meritocratic person.
Yes. I am a meritocratic person.
However, I can't evaluate each
employee's performance...
simply based on a rating scale.
Numbers don't lie, do they?
No, they don't.
But that's not all.
If you work together with the
employees in the office,
you'll see.
Someone's number...
doesn't come from their ability alone.
Did I pick the wrong person for the job?
I didn't know you were
such an emotional person.
Well... I'm sorry I can't
give you what you want.
Restructuring is inevitable,
but I'll look at the list
of people you make up...
and think about how many
employees we should let go.
(Performance review: Assistant
Manager Lee Yong Jae)
(Ha Ji Na)
(Assistant Manager Ha Ji Na)
(Evaluation)
Come in.
This is a review on the marketing
budget execution so far.
Well... Our advertisement on
the magazines ends this week.
We're not continuing the
advertisement, right?
As of now, we're not.
It'll be off-season soon,
but we've always had media exposure.
It feels a bit weird not to.
We're going to plan it soon.
Okay, sir.
Ms. Ha.
Yes, Mr. Seo.
Well... Is your father still working?
Pardon?
I'm just curious.
Do you have siblings?
Do they have jobs as well?
Do you have plans for marriage?
I have a younger brother. He's
serving in the army right now.
I do want to get married soon.
Why are you asking such
questions all of a sudden?
No reason.
You hardly ask personal questions,
so I'm a bit baffled right now.
Is that so?
Yes, but it still feels good.
It feels like you're
taking an interest in me.
All right then.
Goodness. I didn't know anything...
about the employees.
Ms. Ha. I've finished organizing it.
Really?
(Movie tickets)
Could you confirm these as well?
Oh, I think...
this seems fun and interesting.
Also,
you should take a look at this.
(Train tickets to Chuncheon)
I think it's good.
No.
I have something to tell you there.
Mr. Seo might see us. Stop.
You're being so ridiculous together.
What a nice thing to watch.
Don't mind me. Keep holding hands.
There should be a law
banning dating colleagues.
You neglect your duty, disturb
your co-worker's work,
and lose your will to work.
- Mr. Lee.
- What?
I did warn you, didn't I?
Don't forget...
your embarrassing history.
Stop.
What should I do? Should
I just tell everyone?
Don't. What's wrong with you?
Ms. Ha. You can...
keep doing your thing with Ki Taek.
Ki Taek. I support your relationship, sir!
Kiss, kiss, kiss.
How long should I wait while
dancing with my shoulders?
Darn it.
That jerk.
Listen. What's his embarrassing history?
Oh, that? You don't need to know.
That mean girl.
She doesn't know how I really feel.
No.
I still liked her as a colleague.
Don't be ridiculous.
I don't like skinny girls like her.
No. Don't do that.
You still liked her as a colleague.
Don't be absurd.
She's not even an attractive woman.
I really hate her.
No. What's wrong with you?
Snap out of it.
Calm down.
I'll get revenge.
Ji Na, I'll get revenge.
I don't know if it's the
weather, but I feel achy.
Me too.
You too?
I have no appetite and can't digest.
I don't do anything, but I'm tired.
Maybe it's an occupational illness.
Fatigue and indigestion.
I thought I saw you get up early and study.
Are you studying for the bar again?
- Are you really?
- No.
I'm waiting to tell Ji
Na this weekend, but...
I'm taking the test to become
a Korean cuisine chef.
Korean cuisine chef?
My parents run a restaurant.
It isn't big, but they had it for a
while, so they have many regulars.
Then will you be running a restaurant?
After seeing you guys
become permanent employees,
I thought a lot about what
I should do going forward.
Mr. Heo said they'd extend your contract...
and that you can try next time.
They aren't going to hire
in the second half anyway.
A contract extension is meaningless.
But more than that,
I thought about what I wanted to do.
My dream was to live an average life,
fall in love, and have kids.
What a pretty life.
However,
I realized I was chasing the job...
and happiness everyone else was after.
Everyone else lived like that,
so I felt like I should too.
You're right.
I often wonder if I wanted this...
or if my mom did.
- I get confused.
- That's why...
I'm going to chase what I want.
I like to cook.
Your food is really good.
That's right. Your instant noodles.
I think my dad's cooking
skills are within my DNA.
Why is cooking so much fun?
Ms. Ha is so lucky.
I want to get my license and help
my parents with their restaurant,
and then open my own.
You're so cool.
You guys will eat for free.
I don't think Ms. Ha would like that.
You have no idea.
Ji Na isn't selfish like that.
(Your submission for the Hauline
Design Contest has been received.)
(Mail sent)
(You have new mail!)
I'm a college student who applied
to Hauline's design contest.
Will the winner really be given employment?
May I ask when the employment would begin?
(Hello. We met...)
Ho Won.
Make three copies and file them, please.
Yes, sir.
Darn it.
Gosh.
Is something wrong?
No, Ms. Ha.
What is it?
Nothing.
Mr. Seo is acting weird too.
What's with everyone?
I have a favor to ask.
Would you pick up a cake
on your way in tomorrow?
Is it someone's birthday?
(Sales and Marketing Department
Employee Evaluations)
Just...
put my name on top of the list.
What do you mean?
It's hard putting together a list
of employees to cut, isn't it?
How did you know?
I've been at the company for years.
I told you that I have
eyes and ears everywhere.
I found out for the first time...
that Ms. Cho is a single mom
raising a girl alone...
and that Mr. Park sent his
kids to study abroad,
and lives alone half the year.
Also, that Mr. Lee has a lot
of debt because he paid...
for his siblings' tuition.
And...
That both of my parents
are in nursing homes...
with dementia?
I'm sorry.
I never considered the
employees' personal lives,
and cared only about work and results.
My evaluation from last
year was not that great.
An old, life-long manager is a burden...
to any department.
I've been ready. That's why
I wanted to talk to you.
I thought Chairman Seo
had made you a promise.
I don't trust promises
made by people high up.
You are wise.
The chief director seems...
determined to train you.
Even if it isn't you,
I knew I couldn't last once
the new chief director came.
Whatever the case may be,
I'm one of Chairman Seo's people.
What am I supposed to do going forward?
You have two options.
Do what he says. Do not do what he says.
The difference between the
two for a salaryman...
Cheers.
It will be seen in next month's paycheck.
Why is no one here? It's late.
- Happy birthday to you - Mr. Seo.
Happy birthday, Mr. Seo.
Happy birthday to you.
Blow out the candles.
You're supposed to put
frosting on the person's face,
but we can't since you're our boss.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Did you have seaweed soup for breakfast?
I'll have it for lunch.
Are you buying lunch?
- Sure.
- Yes!
- Happy birthday.
Thank you.
You're making him feel old.
I know. You're supposed to...
put frosting on their face
so that they feel young.
- Shall I?
- I'll pass.
Okay.
What's all the noise?
We're having a party! Mr.
Seo's birthday party!
I heard from Ms. Ha. You started already.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
I don't know if it is actually happy.
Life is torture.
Anyway, it's a good day.
Let's taste the cake.
- Okay.
- Let's go!
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday, Mr. Seo.
This is delicious. I haven't
had cake in a while.
It is.
- Do you want more?
- Sure, I'll take it.
Since you're all here, I
have something to say.
If it's about lunch,
there's a new restaurant
that just opened nearby.
Their sweet and sour pork is incredible.
That's right. You wanted seaweed soup.
I'm sorry.
Well...
The thing is...
What is it? Spit it out.
Our department...
is putting together a list of
employees for reorganization.
Reorganization?
What do you mean?
I never heard anything.
What reorganization?
Ms. Cho, did you know?
I did not.
Your acting improved a lot.
When did you find out?
I only recently found out.
Is it the chief director?
This is crazy.
That's why...
he told me...
not to do anything.
I concluded that it would be best...
to tell you the truth and
look for a solution together.
Rather than finding a solution,
I think you created more chaos.
If anyone wants to volunteer to resign,
please come to my office.
No, right?
It wouldn't affect managers and
assistant managers, would it?
What? Are you saying Mr. Seo has
been putting together a hit list?
Thank goodness I didn't
give him a frosting facial.
Don't worry too much.
They wouldn't cut young hires...
that just joined us.
People like me, who are
burdens, should worry.
Don't worry.
Right?
Why is he unloading this
on his own birthday?
General manager, entry-level scrub,
everyone like dropping bombs.
My head's about to explode.
Move, will you?
Darn it.
Who left this here?
To Mr. Seo Woo Jin.
When I first met you,
I wanted...
to impress you at all cost.
I'm...
good at refraining myself.
You are?
Then why don't you show us?
When I met you again, you were
still just as frightening,
but that time, I was bold.
Why did I apply? Like you don't know?
I applied so that I can eat.
What about you people?
Do you live for the company?
Sorry, but no.
And then, when I met you again,
you rejected me.
The sales team should take Ho Won.
You don't do well in marketing by
being good at refraining yourself.
And her wish is to be above others,
so it isn't like she would.
Plus, she's irresponsible on top of that.
But eventually, I ended
up learning a lot...
while working under you.
Working hard. Taking responsibility.
Above all else...
Will you do anything you are asked to do?
You must prove your own worth.
The fact that...
we must each prove our own wealth.
I will learn much more.
I think I can do well...
if you teach me.
Meeting you...
as my superior in my very first job...
was the luckiest thing...
that happened in my life.
Thank you, Mr. Seo. Happy birthday.
From Eun Ho Won.
Do you think we really will be safe?
It's one landmine after another.
Is this why we killed ourselves to
try to become permanent employees?
Does that mean...
Mr. Seo had been watching everyone,
trying to decide whom to cut?
That's not it.
He came clean because he
didn't want to do that.
He is so bold.
Ever since Dr. Seo became
the new chief director,
the company has become too cruel.
Just look at what he did to us.
He's not normal.
Ho Won, be careful.
I'm sure he isn't pleased
with you as it is.
Don't get in his way.
Mr. Seo told the employees...
that he's putting together a list
of people for reorganization?
Yes.
I just can't understand him at times.
In front of everyone and
on his birthday, too...
You must've been surprised.
No, not at all.
I assumed there was a reason...
for you to proceed quietly.
I appreciate that.
Not at all. Thank you.
It must've been too burdensome on Mr.
Seo to do it in secret.
I think he wanted to see if anyone
wanted to resign voluntarily.
The way he handles business...
is a bit out of line.
Well...
Okay. Cheers.
You've changed a lot, sir.
You had thought company
dinners were useless.
Who knows when we'll do it again?
Let's drink.
The reorganization...
How far up will it go?
Are we really safe?
Someone once told me that
as long as I'm happy today,
I can always be happy.
Let's worry about tomorrow tomorrow.
It's a Friday night. Aren't
you supposed to party?
You're changing too much.
I'm getting confused.
Really? Let's take it a step
further while we're at it.
Let's drink and only talk about
fun things tonight. Okay?
Okay.
Here. Cheers.
Mr. Seo. Is our company
struggling that much?
Why is a healthy company
talking about reorganization?
It's because of the chief
director, isn't it?
Ji Na, stop it.
You can curse anyone you
want when they aren't there.
Another beer, please!
Shouldn't you take her home?
It's fine.
Ji Na, when you get a new President,
the system changes as do the ministers.
Hang in there.
Mr. Seo. I really can't quit.
My installment savings account
won't mature for a while,
and I have to provide for this man.
Thank you, Ms. Ha, but please stop.
Is there a law that says the man
has to provide for the woman?
You keep house and be
the supportive spouse.
I'll work and make money.
I will take care...
of my man, got it?
What now?
I'm sorry, Mr. Seo, Mr. Heo.
I envy you.
Who will take care of me if I stop working?
Jealousy means defeat.
I hate to lose.
- You're so lucky.
- Right?
I told you to let me set you up.
- Like a blind date?
- Yes.
Yes. I have a friend who's
a really great guy.
He has looks, a great personality,
a great job, but no girlfriend.
Stop it.
Stop what? That's why I want
to introduce Ho Won to him.
He likes girls like her.
Cute with a great personality.
What great personality?
What do you mean? Ho Won
has a great personality.
You said you'd work hard if I taught you.
What's with the blind date?
Can I not go on blind dates?
Go ahead.
Not long ago, you confessed your love.
Now that you became a permanent employee,
just learn how to do your job.
Love comes before work, Mr. Seo.
In any situation. In any moment.
You do it for love.
So? Will you go on the blind date?
I do want to try it out.
Ki Taek. Beer.
Pour me some.
Okay. Here's your beer.
Where's my beer?
Excuse me. Beer, please.
Don't they dare cut me. I'll
set the office on fire.
You were so feminine before.
Why are you so violent now?
Goodness.
Good. Hold on tight just like that.
What? Can't poor people love?
I may be poor and pathetic now,
but my love will never change.
Put me down.
Weren't you sleeping?
There may be poor love,
but not pathetic ones.
Don't make me pathetic ever.
Mr. Seo.
You told me to stay still...
because of the reorganization, right?
You and the chief director
don't exactly get along.
I am worried,
but we won't touch low-level...
assistant managers or below.
What about the others?
That's right.
Thanks for the tie.
And for the letter too.
I'm sure everything looks good on you.
Even rubber shoes.
And the tie.
Probably.
So?
Will you go on the blind date?
I may.
Ki Taek said...
you're supposed to live for love.
So I should, right?
You said you'd just focus
on learning the job.
How fickle.
I'm saying I should work well, love well,
and do everything well.
I heard...
you make gimbap well, too.
Who said that?
Ki Taek said that earlier.
Well, I'm not bad.
If you have nothing else to do tomorrow,
why don't you make some?
That's not difficult, so
I'll do it if you want.
I owe you a lot anyway.
Kang Ho. You should go home.
Okay.
Aren't you going home?
No. I still have work to do.
You can go first.
Yes, ma'am.
How are things lately?
Are you getting used to
living independently?
Yes, of course.
It's great.
I'm glad. Go home.
Okay.
- Ms. Cho.
- Yes?
Here.
What's this?
I wanted...
to thank you for buying dinner
at the hotel and stuff,
so I wanted to give you something.
This is awkward.
It isn't expensive. I just
saw it while walking by...
and thought it was pretty.
See you tomorrow.
See you on Monday.
(Jang Kang Ho)
You're making gimbap often.
What is it today?
It's the weekend, so a date?
- It's not a date.
- It is.
It is not.
You're so transparent.
You don't have a poker face.
It really isn't a date.
Fine. Let's say it's a fake date.
If it is a date,
will you do something for me?
It's your date. Why should
I do something for you?
Half of these gimbap are yours.
- Really?
- Yes. Deal?
What do you want?
Well...
Remember that thing you
bought but won't wear...
because you don't like the color?
Can I borrow it?
It isn't a date,
but I need to wear something pretty today.
Please?
No wonder word got out.
Sorry?
It tastes good.
Mr. Seo, do you like gimbap?
I can make kimchi stew...
and beanpaste stew,
but I can't roll gimbap well.
Home-made gimbap tastes the best.
I like kimchi stew.
Then let's exchange.
I'll make kimchi stew. You make gimbap.
Exchange?
But...
what if people from the office see?
Since we came alone...
What if they see?
Is that bad?
No, it's not that it's bad.
- Still...
- Gosh.
You're so inconsistent.
Pardon? What did I do?
You say whatever you feel
like without a filter.
So why do you care what people will think?
That's not what I meant.
To be honest, you're the one
who cared what others thought.
You wouldn't even let me greet
you in the neighborhood.
You said to keep it a secret that
we lived in the same neighborhood.
That was because I didn't want
employees talking about us.
I was being considerate.
I didn't care at all.
Then now, you don't care
if people talk about you?
Well,
probably not.
Hang on tightly, or you'll fall.
Okay.
That's it.
That way, you won't fall.
Sang Man!
Sit down.
Why are you by the office on a weekend?
And why did you want to see me?
The spa by our office is the best.
It's not my office anymore.
Still, you came all the
way here to use the spa?
Seriously.
I bought a monthly pass.
If I come during the week...
and run into the kids, I'd look pathetic.
If you know you look pathetic... Gosh.
How are things at the company?
That chief director punk...
started reorganization.
Execution day will be here soon.
Goodness.
What about you? Do you like staying home?
Are you okay?
My wife took away all my credit cards.
She treated me like a human
being when I made money,
but now that I don't,
I get no respect either at home or outside.
That's how it is.
You're a problem too.
Are you thoughtless or bold?
How could you eat all three meals at home?
That's why you get cursed at.
That's why I thought of
a new business plan.
Hello, Park!
- Hi.
- Here are your beer and snacks.
When did you order this? So?
What about a convenience store like this?
You want to open a convenience store?
I think...
it's better than chicken.
The store by the office does well.
- What?
- It does.
No. That's ancient history.
It isn't profitable anymore.
Also, part-timers quit easily, but
it's not like I do without them.
Furthermore, I work until
dawn, so I'm always sick.
And at night? It's really scary here.
This isn't something that people should do.
He gets a bit excited, doesn't he?
Let me ask you something.
Why do you do it then?
Excuse me?
- Sang Man.
- What?
Let's do this.
Well, it's better than chicken.
Have a good time.
(Gwangheungchang Station)
He's late.
(Ki Taek)
(Ji Na)
(911 Emergency Rescue)
Mr. Seo.
The weather's very nice.
I have something to give you.
What is it?
Well... It's...
this.
This looks familiar.
Right?
My mom said she got it
at a very famous place.
Can you keep it?
It's a talisman that will help
you become a CEO in one try.
It seems like you don't know this, but...
if you try to do something in one
try, you can end up losing it all.
If you get promoted quickly, you
end up retiring quickly too.
That doesn't apply to you though.
Can you just hold on to it?
If not, it will go to waste.
Here you go. Why don't you try it?
Become the CEO in one try.
Why can't you?
Female manager, female general
manager, female executive,
until you become a female CEO.
Try to rewrite the history of our company.
Me?
Ms. Cho hasn't been able to do it.
How can I?
You can do it because you're Eun Ho Won.
Based off of everything you've
done, you can definitely do it.
Of course, you have to think
about your brother back home...
and think a little bit more carefully.
And hold back when you can.
Do you understand?
Mr. Seo.
You're saying this because of the
issue with the contest, right?
I know that this world is
filled with unjust things.
However,
it's not something that you
can change by yourself.
Then do you want to help me?
I can't help you either.
However, let's think about it together.
Alone, you're weak, but
together, we can be strong.
Instead of thinking, "As
long as I do well,"
if we contemplate it together,
it will get better...
little by little.
Yes, sir.
I threw...
too many tantrums, didn't I?
I'll really try my best from now on.
I might end up a CEO before you.
Be on your toes.
All right. Let's try working under CEO Eun.
What happened? Do you know
how many times I called you?
Why didn't you pick up?
Why didn't you come? What's wrong?
Ki Taek.
Is something wrong?
What is wrong? Tell me.
My friend is really sick.
I've know him since I was a kid.
Actually, since I was born,
and he's very sick.
Which friend? Is he someone I know?
You don't know him.
How sick is he?
A lot.
He's very sick.
He might die.
Poor him.
I'm so sorry, Ji Na. I'm so sorry.
I understand.
He's one of your closest friends.
No wonder you couldn't come.
I'm sorry.
You still should have picked up the phone.
I was worried about you.
Here.
We don't need to go far. I
feel like I'm on a vacation.
Good.
You were probably worried all day.
Eat a lot.
Even though I didn't make it.
Your face became hollow in one day.
Hurry up and eat.
You should've eaten something
even though I didn't come.
What did you do all day?
I just needed to wait a little
bit, and I could eat with you.
Why would I eat alone?
Let's eat.
Eat some anchovies too. Here.
- You should eat too.
- It's okay.
My mom sent me this.
You too.
Let's eat.
Eat slowly.
All right.
I was so hungry.
My gosh. This is delicious.
It is delicious.
Don't worry.
Did you have a good weekend?
We won't be seeing each
other for much longer now.
Whom are you talking to?
Good morning, my comrade, Jang Kang Ho.
You must have some good news.
Good news? Yes, I do.
All the people I love are here,
and if I go to work, I can see all of them.
What's better news than that?
You said you were going to go on a
trip with Ms. Ha over the weekend.
It must've been a lot of fun.
Yes, it was very fun.
We went on a very long trip.
Hello.
It seems like Ho Won is
the one with good news.
Your face is lit up. What did
you do over the weekend?
Me?
I did my laundry, cleaned
my house, and cooked.
What about you? Did you go home?
Yes, I made up with my dad and
had a drink with him too.
So you gained acknowledgement from him?
Did you forget what Mr. Seo said?
My worth is determined by myself.
He did say that.
- Let's go in.
- Okay.
Go in first. I want to stop
by the convenience store.
- Do you?
- We'll go first.
Let's go.
- I want to eat gimbap.
- What?
- Gimbap?
- Yes.
Let's eat it later.
Mr. Seo. You look great in that tie.
Do you have an important business today?
I can tell you're more
dressed up than usual.
Is that so?
Someone gave me this as a gift.
I guess that person has a good taste.
I'm sure you've had
trouble with your work...
because of our team's budget.
Aren't we going to have
additional promotion of Hauliz?
Not for a while, Ms. Ha.
Ho Won and Ki Taek,
we've been having a subcontractor
do the online promotion.
You should do it yourselves.
You worked together on the catalog before,
and you made a good team.
Yes, sir.
Ms. Ha.
You should come up with a
plan to raise Hauliz's sales.
- Yes, sir.
- Mr. Heo.
Please ask the sales team for assistance...
and plan our sale overseas.
Yes, sir. Your plan is to use two
nickels if you don't have a dime.
Yes. Please hang in there.
I believe in your ability.
All right. I'll go and get the
chief director's authorization.
He's inside, right?
He's been waiting for you.
Yes. Come in.
I'm thinking about laying
off two people from...
the sales and marketing department.
Have you chosen the people to dismiss?
There is no one to dismiss in our team.
Mr. Seo.
You can't say that. What about our team?
We only have four employees
including myself.
This is like wringing out a dry towel.
We can't reduce personnel anymore.
Is that why you told the
employees about it?
How long...
do you think I will put
up with the way you work?
Have you been putting up with me?
You made the employees anxious
and the atmosphere unsettling.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm working.
Mr. Seo.
- What's wrong with you?
- Mr. Seo.
Are you joking with me right now?
You have a bad sense of humor,
so it's not fun to joke with you.
I came to get your authorization.
What is this?
Should I have written it in Korean?
Can't you read?
It's my letter of resignation.