Just tell me when
you're rolling.
We're rolling.
A lot of people...
Have questioned what
really happened.
And when the novel
was first published,
it didn't take long
for there to be even
more questions asked.
It's always remained a mystery.
And that's why I
wanted to thank you
for coming in to meet with us.
To help shed some
light on the events.
Okay.
He dedicated the book to you.
Can you tell us how
much of his novel
was based on fact?
All of it.
It was 1969...
What can you tell us
about that summer?
Question? What was
the question?
What do you remember
about that summer 1969?
It was hot. It was real hot.
God must have been
sweating, it was so hot.
Tell me about the murder.
Hey, how much, how much I'm
getting paid for this?
Well, sheriff call was
this evil, nasty,
disgusting son of a gun.
Black people hated sheriff call
because he killed so many of us
during his two
terms in service.
Some of my family was included.
White people feared him too.
So somebody got fed up with
his fat ass, and killed him.
That's what happened
that summer.
They say he dragged
his intestines
for a mile before he died.
Crazy white people even
built a statue for him.
How did it come about
that you worked
for the jansens?
I was cleaning for
them part time,
right when his mamma ran off.
And ward and I, ward
was his brother,
he was in high
school at the time
and we raised him together.
Little Jackie was
five at the time.
Where was his father?
W.W. Was just
chasing girls, you know.
And running the
local newspaper.
The moat county tribune.
How's ward?
He's good, he's good.
Real busy.
Ward was a writer...
Uh... for the Miami times.
He used to write about, uh...
Well, he was kind of
famous, you know,
'cause he wrote about the
civil rights movement
and the poor and the
unjustly accused.
That's how come
that lady Charlotte
started writing letters to him.
Stuff like that.
Yeah.
And then Jack, like I
said, he was a swimmer.
And, uh...
Almost professional,
very close but then
he got kicked off
the swim team,
he got kicked out of college,
and he came back home to his papa's
house to deliver newspapers.
He didn't want to
come back home,
but he didn't have
nowhere else to go.
Yeah?
Mmm?
Jack, you better turn
that music down.
You know w.W. Gong
be mad at you.
Dang it, Anita, can
you please knock?
I could've been
jerking off in here.
Please, it ain't nothing
I ain't seen before.
What are you doing?
I'm picking up your stuff,
like I do every day.
Oh come on, not today.
It's too hot for that.
I'm just helping.
You're not helping me. You
don't have to help me.
Come on.
Get off the bed
so I can make it.
Go fix me some collard Greens.
It's my bed.
I know it's your bed. Really?
Because it's your bed, you
should fucking make it.
They canceled "the
smothers brothers."
Oh, no, that's your show.
Well, I love that show. I
love dick and I love Tommy.
Lay down. Let me be you for a second.
Oh, yeah, right. Get me in trouble.
You want to be me, I get to be you?
Okay.
Okay, I'll love this.
Jack, may I come in?
Oh, good, okay. Go away, go out.
Go back out.
Okay. I better start
jerking off first. Okay.
Jack, sorry to interrupt
your masturbation,
but I'm here to clean the bed!
I could've been jerking off!
I'm gonna clean everything!
I could have been jerking off!
Get out! Clean my shit up!
Get all that we have
received in return,
is just another smooth exercise
in political manipulation.
Good girl.
Deceit and deception,
callousness and indifference
to our individual problems,
and the disgusting playing
of divisive politics,
pitting the young
against the old,
labor against management,
north against South.
Did you want to see me?
Have you spoken to
ward this week?
No. Hello, Jack.
He didn't mention anything
to you about coming here?
I can't believe your father's
making me report on this.
I mean, look at her.
To open our society.
She plans to run for
president next.
They want to talk to
Hillary van wetter.
Don't you let that
pulitzer prize fool you.
He don't know everything yet.
Ain't no reason to come up here
stirring up shit
with that asshole.
I just wanted to say that
it is very important
for all Americans
to recognize...
Charlotte bless loved
her some dangerous men.
She wrote men in prison.
She finally fell
in love with one.
She was determined
to get him out.
Why y'all ain't got
no ice in here?
You want ice, go to your house.
Charlotte.
Oh, that's my show. What
you think, Charlotte?
I don't like it.
Make it looser.
That's that nigger
you've been writing?
No. This is my white man.
Oh.
What happened yesterday?
I missed it.
Listen to this. He
thinks I'm his angel.
His angel? Shh. Shut your face.
Bitch, how old is he?
Oh, my God.
He's a fine motherfucker
that's trying to fuck you.
"Ever there was an
angel in the world,
"my angel, it must be you,
but no angel would do the
things I dream that you want."
Your angel, his angel.
Mm-hm. That's hot.
He say, "if you truly exist, I
may become a religious man."
Ah!
"All my life, my heart has
tried to find a place
I cannot name... a home."
You need to find
yourself a young one.
He'll fuck you real good.
He says I'm his home. Hm.
Got a hundred different men
writing her from
the penitentiary.
That's her man.
Oh, no. This is my man.
This here's the one.
Mm-hm.
Ward came home to investigate
the conviction of
Hillary van wetter.
The town wasn't too
happy about it
and neither was his papa.
Oh, shit. Ugh.
Ward...
There's a horse in
the parking lot.
It's our ride home, yardley.
Uh, where is everybody?
It's Sunday.
People's either at
home or at church.
It's a shithole.
Hey, man.
Hey, you.
How you doing?
Jack, meet yardley ache man.
Hey.
My little brother, Jack.
The swimmer, right?
Yeah, he's our driver now.
Right, good.
Here, let me get these.
That's my typewriter.
You've gotten big, boy.
Just be careful with
the typewriter.
Got all pumped up. Is
that from swimming?
Not anymore.
No! No! No!
Yardley's real particular
about his suits
and his typewriter. Well,
it's very expensive.
Yes. Thank you.
How do I get in?
Watch your head.
Don't touch my head. Tell him
where you're from, yardley.
London.
Ah!
When I came here...
From New York,
I was interviewing
for the job...
And I was in advertising
in New York
and I mentioned that it was
simply different in New York.
So how'd you get
from New York City
to the Metropolis
of lately, Florida?
Jansen residence.
So I came down South and I
interviewed at the paper.
W.W., miss Roberta's
on the phone.
No, no, no.
We don't take phone calls.
Anita...
Who's miss Roberta?
No calls, Anita.
What part of London
you from, yardley?
Um, all over London.
Is there a good dry cleaning here?
Excuse me?
Dry cleaning.
Dry cleaning? Yes.
You ain't gonna eat that, are you?
Uh-uh.
How you gonna win those swimming
meets if you don't eat?
I'm retired.
Retired. Jack, you ain't even
tired enough to be retired.
How is it exactly you guys work?
I mean, like that boy
drowned at his initiation?
Well, yardley's the writer...
And I'd guess you'd say
ward is the nuts and bolts.
Yeah. When I was a reporter,
we had rewrite men who took
the stories over the phone.
No, no, no. I'm not
a rewrite man.
I'm the writer.
I'm the one who puts the
facts into perspective.
Oh!
Yes. It's a different
world now, Mr. Jansen.
Clearly.
Times have changed a bit, sir.
What interest does
"the Miami times"
have in Hillary van wetter?
He murdered somebody in jail?
Even if he was guilty...
It was a lynching, pure and simple...
he had certain rights.
And even if he was guilty...
Hillary has rights that the
process completely disregarded.
And that's why we're here.
I'm very sorry, everybody, but
I'm going to have to leave.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I have early evaluations
first thing in the morning.
Come here, sugar. I apologize.
All right, buddy.
Ward?
Good night, boys.
Seems mighty sure of
himself for a colored.
Ward said they need a driver.
A driver?
What you do out there?
So you meet anybody new
out there in Miami?
I met a few.
Oh, yeah. All types
down there, you know?
You stay away from
those rough ones.
Remember what happened
the last time.
How your kids?
You look beautiful, babe.
They're doing good. They're
doing really good.
As soon as I get out of here,
I'll go see them and make
dinner all over again.
You should come to
that dinner, too.
I'll come to that dinner.
I think Ellen is
maybe number four...
Since you left.
Yeah.
That's why I don't take
them bitches too seriously.
They come and they go and
they come and they go.
You know what I mean?
At last my dreams come true?
Today he said "I do "?
Friends said it
couldn't be done?
But all his love
I know I've won?
How you doing there, yard?
Oh, jeez.
That's where he placed
the wedding band?
Hey, close that door, boy.
I don't want your daddy
screaming about all the flies
getting in the house.
Hmm.
Who is that, Jack?
Uh...
I'm looking for the
office of Mr. Jansen.
Ward Jansen of
"the Miami times."
I said who is it? I
work for the times.
You do? Yeah.
Huh.
Well, I'm Charlotte bless.
I'm Jack Jansen.
Here, let me get that. Oh.
Hey. All my files.
The office is in the garage.
You look a little young
to be a journalist.
I'm really just the driver. Oh.
But I do write.
So do I. I write letters.
I'm pretty good.
Hey, guys!
This here is miss
Charlotte bless.
Oh, not for long.
Hillary and I are
engaged to be married.
Hello, miss bless. I'm ward.
Oh, Mr. ward, good
to finally meet you.
You didn't mention the engagement in your letters.
Go clean yourself up.
Well, it only just happened.
He just proposed.
Oh, that looks nasty.
Well, how did I do that?
Excuse me a second.
Get miss bless something to drink.
I'm yardley ache man.
We thought you and
Hillary hadn't met.
Well, only in pictures,
but we been writing
each other for months
and we understand
ourselves just perfect.
Ward, where should
I put her files?
Everything you need to
know about van wetter
that's been in the papers,
is here in these boxes.
Our exciting correspondence
is in that box.
In case you're interested.
My desk, Jackie boy.
Mr. Jansen, I really just
wanted to thank you.
I wanted to thank you for
returning my letters.
And for helping me get Hillary
out of that hellhole.
Well, I wouldn't go booking
the honeymoon just yet.
But we are going to
fight his sentence
and the way it came about.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Nobody deserves the death
penalty, miss bless.
Not even Hillary van wetter.
Um, excuse me. So, everything
is ordered alphabetically.
I was telling, um...
What's your name?
Yardley. Yardley.
Um, that all of the files,
um, everything that's
been in the papers,
is in the top box. This
is gonna be a great help.
He's an innocent man.
You're gonna find that out.
Wrongly convicted.
This is gonna get us
off to a great start.
I've done a lot of research.
I see that.
In the meantime, you need
to freshen up or anything?
Jack, show miss bless to the washroom.
I think I'll just stay here.
You might have some questions
that you need answered.
I can freshen up just here.
Cold beer for me, Jack.
You're adorable, Jack.
I will take an iced
tea if you have it.
You want anything, ward?
I'm good.
You'll see, uh...
It's an enormous amount of work...
what's with the boxes?
I don't know what to do here.
What's with the boxes?
Well, we're gonna start on it.
My Jack was in love
with Charlotte bless.
I could tell that
horny little boy
wanted to jump her
on first sight.
Everybody was confused why she was
engaged to Hillary van wetter.
Nasty, white trash swamp.
"All the killers who
have written me"
want to press their
mouths into my vagina
and some, even the
crack of my behind,
except Hillary van wetter.
He has no such desire.
He wants to be
sucked off himself.
"I consider this psychological
proof of his innocence."
She is one nasty
little nut job.
Think we've been taking her
a little too seriously.
You sure get bored quick.
No. Can tell I'm not going
to get laid anytime soon
in this floridian
shit pit, so...
Listen... hey, Kathy, it's me.
Hillary tells her
that the knife.
Yardley. And the bloodied shirt
that the deputies claim to
have found in his house
somehow got lost
before the trial.
Yeah, I miss you, too.
What?
Hello, Kathy.
Miss bless wanted to
look at the prison.
Jack's first assignment
was to take her there.
I bet he knows I'm here.
See, people who fall
in love outside...
Of a normal relationship,
they have these powers...
Telepathic powers.
Hillary and I have that kind
of connection, you dig?
Now why ain't you in college?
Huh?
Uh, I was a swimmer
when I was in school.
No kidding? Yeah.
I was a swimmer. You were?
Uh-huh. I'd swim like a mermaid
if it wasn't for my
damn curly hair.
I think straight
hair gives me class.
All right.
Good.
So?
Well, we was drunk one
night, and, uh...
I just...
I lost my temper and just...
Well, I emptied the pool.
At your college?
The university of Florida.
They called that
vandalism, I guess.
It's actually not as
easy to do as it sounds.
So you lose your temper often?
Mm.
This place is full of
boys just like you
who lost their temper one day.
I'm getting horny being
this close to him.
Oh, baby.
I bet he's horny for
me all the time.
Yeah.
Mmm.
Oh, I can feel him.
Can I help you folks?
Oh, no.
Yes, officer. Uh... hm.
We just wanted to sit in your
parking lot for a little while.
What for?
His daddy's in there and we wanted
to send him good vibrations.
Some good what?
Oh, these special things
called good vibrations.
Sorry, ma'am. Y'all
can't park here.
Oh.
Yes, officer.
The story that Hillary
told the deputies
was never investigated.
He simply told it once
from the witness stand
and was never asked
to elaborate,
not even by his own lawyers.
Good to see you again, ward.
Nice to see you.
Sir, this is my writing
partner, Mr. yardley ache man.
Of course.
I suppose the best
place to start
would be the beginning.
I was born in this county.
1897, to poor but
proud parents.
Mr. pine, could
we skip 65 years,
save everyone some time?
Hillary van wetter, 1965?
Oh, I can't agree to talk
to you about that matter.
Not without my
client's permission.
He's entitled to his privacy,
just like anybody else.
You have his permission.
He wrote you.
I'll have to check that out.
I'm sure the letters would
be in your files, Mr. pine.
That's what you say, but I
have a client to protect.
Look here.
If we have to get a lawyer
of our own down here
to sort this out,
then while he's here,
we're gonna have him look through every
aspect of Mr. van wetter's case.
Including the competency
of his defense.
There was nothing wrong with the defense
Hillary van wetter got in court!
Then you have nothing
to worry about from us.
We just want to talk to him.
Then we'll be out of your...
You don't know a thing
about this person!
You've been in this world
for five minutes, boy!
Now that's just not
necessary, Mr. pine.
Yes. I talk the way I
want in my office!
All right. Then you'll arrange
the meeting, will you?
Quick! We're gonna be late!
You get the marriage license?
I can't believe we
're doing this!
Fuck! Jack, go knock
on the door again.
There she is. Whoa, baby.
Well, I say... Good
morning, miss bless.
Look at Daisy mae.
Morning.
You look just fine.
Hope he likes it.
Uh...
Would you mind putting
up the windows?
It's gonna muss my hair.
Are you serious?
I'm sweating like a
pregnant nun back here.
Unbelievable!
Hi.
You got 15 minutes.
No physical contact
of any kind.
No tape recorders.
No object may be passed
to the prisoner.
I'll be right
outside this door.
Mr. van wetter,
my name is ward Jansen.
This is my associate, yardley ache man...
you look like your picture.
Mmm. I do?
Thank you.
These your paperboys?
Mm-hm.
What they gonna do for us?
They gonna save you.
They're gonna save us?
Mm-hm.
Shit. They can't even
save themselves.
Mr. van wetter, we
wanted to ask you
about the lost
evidence in your case.
Shut up. Can't you see I'm busy?
Will you do something
for me right now?
Oh. Oh, I wish I could.
Spread your legs
open a little bit.
Mmm. Yeah.
Now tear off them pantyhose.
Rip those off.
Yeah. Mm-hm.
Move your hands away. Mmm.
Yeah.
Now open up your mouth...
You picture what you wrote
me in your letters.
You bitch!
Oh, I love you.
What the hell's
going on in here?
You're a good girl. I warned y'all!
This visit's over!
I told y'all this visit was...
come on!
Come on, Hillary. No!
No! There's nothing going on!
Shit! No!
What the fuck? I didn't
touch that girl!
No! No!
What the fuck you
laughing about?
Come on now, miss bless.
Jack came home and
threw up after that.
He couldn't believe
he still loved her
after what he saw, but he did.
You're ward ward's boy? Mm-hm.
Most contrary man in
all of moat county.
What may I do for you
gentlemen today?
It's about the murder
of sheriff call.
I understand that there's
some physical evidence
relating to the
case that was lost?
Yes, sir. I believe there was.
Well, we was wondering
what sort of explanation
the department might have.
I wish I knew.
Mr. van wetter once cut
a deputy's thumb off.
Did you know that?
It was over a traffic
ticket, if I remember.
You can't do much
without your thumb.
It's what separates
us from the primates.
For a little thing like
holding your wife's titty.
You're not married, Mr. Jansen?
No.
A little thing like
that, you can't do it.
Maybe I'll just go
talk to the deputies
who was involved in the arrest.
You can talk to
whoever you want
as long as they'll talk to you.
But they won't.
And why is that?
They haven't forgotten what
Hillary did to one of theirs.
The judge allowed testimony
based on evidence that
he never even saw.
He took the officer's
word over Hillary's.
I can't say I blame him.
Nobody does.
You got me in the face there.
So you've got to ask him.
Where was he between
2:00 and 6: 00?
I'm gonna ask him about
some things he wrote,
some letters to Charlotte.
Here we go.
Hold.
Good morning, Mr. van wetter.
Hey.
Where's your dress?
You don't like me like this?
You know a prisoner
by the name of...
Ward, ward, ward.
You know a prisoner by the name
of Mr. Bobby Valentine?
Mr. van wetter?
Mr. Demarcus Williams,
Mr. Bobby hinton?
Another prisoner by the
name of Jimmy Edwards,
another one, Demarcus.
I think his name is curt.
I forgot his last name.
Anyway, you know what
they all have in common?
Hey, Martin Luther King.
You know what they all
had in common? What?
They all wear pants.
Every goddamned man
in here wears pants!
How am I supposed to tell
you apart from them?
Don't talk to her like that!
Sit down, Jack.
Sit the fuck down.
Mr. van wetter, we don't have
a lot of time, all right?
We got to move on.
You're gonna move on one
way or another, ward?
Ward's in charge!
He's gonna get his way...
Till he don't.
Maybe that's how he got
his scars on the face.
You mentioned in one of
your letters to miss bless
that you was working
turn around, bitch!
An Uncle tyree... yeah, yeah.
At the time of the murder.
What kind of work you doing?
Lawn work.
You wear a dress
in here next time
or you don't bother coming!
Bitch, look at me!
And stop bringing
that fucking nigger
think he muhammad Ali with you!
Mr. van wetter,
come have a seat.
Cassius Clay, nigger.
We can get a dress
here in five minutes.
Why don't you have a seat?
Go home, boy!
I don't know...
Charlotte, where does one get
pants like that from anyway?
Well, I think we got
the case licked.
This is a fucking circus!
In this town,
weldon pine helped get
sheriff call re-elected.
Tension was brewing
in the house.
Jack was getting jealous
of Hillary and Charlotte.
And he was getting jealous
of ward and yardley, too.
Ward wasn't somebody who attached
himself to just anybody.
Your dad's girlfriend,
what's her name?
Jack couldn't understand why he
was so attached to that yardley.
No, you didn't.
What is the hottest temperature
that you've ever been in?
125.
How about you?
Just put your hand out
and it burns off.
The hottest was when I lived in Florida.
How about you?
It doesn't bother me. I
never pay attention to it.
Cold and wet just goes fucking
through you like a knife
but... I don't know.
So how's Mr. van wetter today?
He still innocent?
I don't know. If he is...
He sure as hell didn't
have no help proving it,
not from that weldon
pine guy anyway.
Could I have a
fork or something?
The chicken legs, you eat
those with your hands.
Maybe at your house.
This is the South, sugar.
Anyway, you know how
I feel about that.
Do you eat your mashed potatoes with your hands?
Do you really want to...?
Bring me some chopsticks, Anita.
Do you really want
to take the shot...
On putting to death
a man or a woman
when maybe they're innocent?
I mean, I don't.
I don't want to try to
have to live with that.
On the other hand... are you
gonna eat that or torture it?
Told you, I'm not hungry.
That's 'cause you're in love.
I know who you're
sniffing around, too.
Anita, please don't
tease him at the table.
On the other hand, if
somebody's guilty,
well, you want to pay
their room and board 365?
Absolutely. Ah!
Whoops.
I'm so sorry.
Anyway, it's just iced tea.
It ain't even gonna stain.
You'da thought Jack would
had a girlfriend by now,
but all he did was jerk
off to the pictures
in those nude magazines
that was under his bed.
Now she was all he could
think of night and day.
Oh, yeah, he was
definitely in love.
He needed her.
What you reading?
You give it to me.
What is this shit? " Lolita."
Porno, I bet.
Oh.
You need a girlfriend.
Look at them girls over there.
Go on and introduce yourself.
Go on.
I'm just fine right here.
You want me to blow
you, don't you?
You don't have to answer.
I know it's true.
I'm not gonna blow
a friendship...
Over a stupid little blow job.
You hear me?
Look, why you talking
to me like that?
See that one in blue?
She'll blow you.
I don't want someone
like that blowing me.
It's a good thing
you're not in prison
because you wouldn't
have a choice there.
Fuck you.
Jack, come back here.
Well, well?
I passed the corner
where we first met?
Yes, I did?
Memories of our love
linger there yet?
Oh, I'm sitting on
top of the world?
Just to know that
you're my girl?
I'm just lucky?
I'm lucky, lucky,
lucky in love?
Our love is here...?
Lucky, lucky,
lucky in love...?
Oh, I'm sitting on
top of the world?
Just to know that
she's my girl?
That makes me lucky?
Oh my God. Pam.
I'm so lucky lucky
lucky in love?
Let me sing one more time?
What is that? Is he okay?
Is he having an
allergic reaction?
A jellyfish sting or something?
A fucking jellyfish did that.
You're supposed to piss
on a jellyfish sting.
We're gonna have to do
something embarrassing.
You got to hang in there. Hey!
Well, you're gonna...
You'll piss on him?
What are you doing to him?
Call an ambulance.
He's having a reaction!
Shut the fuck up!
Don't push me! You're
supposed to piss...
Get the fuck out of here!
I can see this.
I can see he's poisoned.
You don't pee on...
Don't push me! I
will slap your face.
Get the fuck out of here.
All right.
I said, I will kick your ass!
I'm going to call the police.
Move it! Fine.
If anyone's gonna piss on
him, it's gonna be me!
Fine, fuck you!
He don't like strangers
peeing on him!
Come on. Come on.
Come on, baby come on! Wake up!
Come on! Shit!
LA LA LA?
Zippeydoo da?
Come on.
Come on!
No matter what people say?
I know our love
is here to stay?
And I'm so lucky?
You're gonna be okay!
Lucky lucky in love?
I'm mister lucky?
I'm so lucky lucky
lucky in love?
Jack.
What are you doing here?
What do you think
I'm doing here?
Told you to knock on my door
before you come in my room.
Oh, hush up.
Here, I brought you something.
Take these pills.
I smell awful.
That's because that blond
lady peed all over your face.
Ugh. Here, drink this.
Does it hurt?
I'm cold, I'm cold, I'm cold.
Congratulations, Jack.
We're in the paper.
" Fast action saves
lately man at beach."
"Miss Charlotte bless
of mobile, Alabama"
apparently saved
Mr. Jansen's life
by urinating over the
areas of his body
where he was attacked.
"These included the victim's
arms, genitals and face."
Jack, I had no idea.
I had no idea that
your own father
would print something
like that.
It made the ap wire.
You're famous all
over the country.
" Home remedy." Good title.
What's dad trying to do to me?
It's called the newspaper
business, Jack.
Oh, shit.
Let him go, Jack!
You're gonna kill him.
Jack, let him go.
You put your hands on me again,
I will fuck you up! Yeah?
Fuck you, nigger!
He needs to get laid.
He needs a fucking
straitjacket.
He's sexually repressed.
Sexually repressed is
a 40-year-old woman
who's obsessed
with prison cock!
That's not nice. Calm down now.
No, fuck calm down!
I'm not having some
kid call me a nigger.
I want him out of here now!
Yardley?
Jack, let's go to the prison.
You two can stay here
and keep arguing.
This time I'm talking
to Hillary by myself.
Come on.
He's not even gonna look at you
if I'm not there
in a pretty dress.
Well, that's too bad for him.
Ward.
You'll see.
I knew Jack didn't
mean to say it.
But those were the times
we were living in
and it was what it was.
Yardley, on the
other hand, well...
Get out of the cold?
Take the night off?
Be your own boss?
When you're near me?
Can you hear me?
Or do I have to
shout in your ear?
Mmm?
Take the night off?
Turn the light on?
Forensic report says
that the sheriff
was stabbed between 2 and 3 am.
Yep. Like I told you,
I was with... my Uncle
tyree doing lawn work
in Ormond beach at the time.
Lawn work? Yes, sir.
You mean stealing? Yes, sir.
Stealing sod off a golf course.
A developer paid through
the teeth for that shit.
We sold it and we
didn't make it back
to the river till sunrise.
What kind of developers?
Condominiums, man.
You got a name? No, I don't.
Deputies say they found the
sheriff's body at 6 am...
But it was the way
he was killed.
That's what makes everybody
assume it was you.
What you think? You tell me.
I ain't the only one carrying
a machete around here.
True.
The deputies went
to Tyree's house,
he said he'd been
sleeping in bed all night
and had a whole bunch of family
members there to confirm it.
Then they go to your house...
Where they find the
bloodstained shirt and knife.
Yeah, all right. Listen to me.
Every knife and shirt that
I own is stained in blood.
It's what I do for a living.
I'm gutting alligators
for their skin.
Okay? I was a bachelor.
I didn't have nobody
to do my laundry.
You probably got somebody
to do your laundry.
What you think?
I bet you do.
They never matched the blood
to the sheriff's, did they?
Tell me how to find tyree.
The arms of mercy are so wide
they will accept any man,
but they will not accept
any man wearing pants.
Where is my woman?
Where's my woman?
The only one you need to talk
to right now is me, baby.
The only one I need to talk to?
I'm the only one.
I'm your mercy.
I'm your arms wide
open, I'm your pants.
Ward's in charge!
If you wanna go see tyree,
I'll give you directions,
but you got to make that choice
because he's a violent man.
Now stay with me now
because this is when
it gets tricky.
Ward called Charlotte
and told her to drive
yardley to Ormond beach.
He wanted to verify Hillary's
so-called golf course story.
The boys went on to
visit this Uncle tyree.
Man, this is stupid.
Where are we going?
No one lives out here. No
one could live out here.
You talk to Anita about your...
choice of words?
It was fucked up.
I know.
Goddamn it.
Sure you don't me
to watch the car?
Goddamn it! This stuff
ain't working, man.
It's like they like this shit.
Better than jellyfish, I bet.
Fuck! Oh, my God!
Watch it! You're way too close to him.
Ward! Ward!
You better jump him.
It's better in here where
we have to get lower.
Ward, you're sinking!
This whole place
is just floating.
You ever think about mama?
I wonder where she at.
She is in Tucson, Arizona.
You got a girlfriend?
Why?
You don't remember this, but
mom used to go on about, uh...
Don't make love to a woman until
you get married, right? Mm-hm.
I followed that until I was...
Oh, fuck that. We'll
talk about it later.
Let's go.
Mr. van wetter?
Good afternoon, sir.
My name is ward Jansen. I
work for "the Miami times."
We're here on behalf here
of your nephew, Hillary.
You lost a shoe.
You're lucky it
was just the one.
Snakes all around here.
We need to talk to you about
your nephew, Mr. van wetter.
Little late for that, isn't it?
He gonna be strapped to a
chair and electrocuted.
Well...
You come all the way up
here just to tell me that?
You could've saved
yourself a trip.
He tells me that
he was with you
the night sheriff
call was murdered,
stealing sod, which
you later sold.
Let's hope nobody believes him.
Stealing's against
the law, ain't it?
Now he's still got time.
I don't much care for you.
Come up here in my home...
And call me a thief.
I ain't up here about
thieving, Mr. van wetter.
I'm up here about whether a man's
life needs to be taken or not...
For the murder of sheriff call.
But if you was with
your nephew that night,
it's vital for Hillary
that you admit it.
I don't think he
likes you much.
I don't like him much either.
Where's the ice cream?
It's coming.
Keep that baby quiet.
What's wrong with that baby?
All right, well, sit on it.
Yeah.
You want...?
You want a little ice cream?
You don't want to
have any ice cream.
You take this chair
out here with me.
No sense you staying
over there.
Thank you.
Little man, get
yourself a chair there.
Get yourself a chair.
Was you with him?
Yeah.
Well, I...
I was with him.
Where?
Golf club.
Ormond beach.
Stole sod, sold it...
To this one condo developer.
Where's Hillary live from here?
We didn't get back till
the morning, sunrise.
He lives that way.
So why are you telling me now?
You seem like the only person
thinks Hillary's innocent.
No, sir, Mr. van wetter.
No, sir.
I didn't say that.
Your boy...
He's getting nervous
over there.
Let's go. I'm done
talking to you.
What you hiding? Ward?
I'm sick...
Of your questions.
Eugene?
Ward, remember the first day
when I was with Charlotte? Yeah?
We went and stopped
at the prison.
We didn't go in. I saw him.
Tyree? Yeah.
What you think? They was getting
their stories together?
I don't know.
I'll tell you this.
They ain't as dumb
as they look.
Oh, shit, man.
Fuck.
What the fuck, man?
Leave me at the fucking hotel?
Jesus!
In yardley's room, no less.
Fuck, man. Look at you.
You're becoming obsessed
with this case.
Wake me up.
Come on.
You look terrible, ward.
Those mosquitoes eat
you for breakfast?
Yardley found the golf course.
You found the golf course?
What's he doing in my clothes?
The car broke down.
We had to walk into town,
stopped by the motel
to freshen up.
Get out of my clothes now.
Come on.
Come on, Jack.
What are you doing?
Miss bless. Come on, stop it.
Jack!
On the morning of the murder
the grounds superintendent of
the ormond beach golf course
phoned the police department
to report that
four of his Greens
had been stripped in the night.
You talked to the superintendent?
No.
He died, but I found
another guy who remembered
that the club
called the governor
to ask him to declare
them a disaster area
so they could get federal funds
to replace the Greens.
It gets better.
I found the builder, too,
the guy who bought
the stolen Greens.
He remembered
Hillary and tyree.
They showed up at
6 am in a truck.
He took one look at
them and what they had
and thought they'd stolen
it from a cemetery.
But of course, he doesn't want to
be connected to this in any way.
And who was he?
Well, the only way
he'd talk to me
is if I promised to
keep him anonymous.
Come on now. What's his name?
No, no, no.
I've got to keep it anonymous.
I gave him my word.
He's got, well,
he's in a position
to get some work from
the state, so you know.
But good, huh?
Outstanding.
How'd you find him?
Building permits.
Damn building permit.
Time to get out of lately.
Did you sleep with yardley?
You know, people like
yardley, you just...
Got to get him on your side.
You know what I mean?
You fucked him for that?
Fucking a man is the most natural
thing in the world, Jack.
It is.
I kind of like it out here.
This was a good idea.
Ooh!
Come on! Let's dance.
Come on! No!
Come on, Jack. Got to have fun!
You wanna dance?
Yeah! I wanna dance with you!
Woo! You're good!
This is not me
apologizing, you dig?
I just don't like
to see you sad.
Yardley told their editor
about the new evidence
from ormond beach.
This was enough to show injustice
in the legal system of lately
and enough for a good story.
Yardley wanted to
get out of town
and ward knew it.
All these peanuts on the floor.
Pigs. Bunch of pigs
living around here.
Sick of this shit.
I can't find mama's ring.
Oh, well, a nigger
must have come
in the middle of the
night and stole it.
I'm sorry, Anita.
I didn't mean to say...
I didn't mean to say that.
And I'm really sorry.
You know, Jackie, you got
to watch your mouth.
Somebody'll cut your little
ass over some shit like that.
You understand me, boy?
Yes, ma'am.
And you miss your mother?
Sometimes.
It's a dis-damn grace
the way she left you.
And I been here.
Well, let's find
this ring, I guess.
No, that's all right.
I can find it.
Oh. Sorry.
All right.
Okay.
I'm really sorry. Okay.
All right, Jack.
What's makes this
story any different?
What makes your story different
than the others, John?
What makes this case so different
that you want to pull the plug now?
The facts. What's left to do?
You've been up there
a month and a half.
I want your ass back here.
Save that shit for
someone else.
I'm not comfortable with it
and you shouldn't be either.
I'm going to ormond
beach to get the facts.
I want to get some
alligator shoes.
You run this article,
this shit could hurt me.
I got advertisers to think of.
Advertisers? You want
me to be concerned
with the advertisers
for your newspaper?
Ward, you don't
know everything.
He knows what he's doing, pa.
Shut up! I'm not
talking to you.
He knows how to get stories,
but what he doesn't
fully appreciate
is that the stories go
out into a community.
They resonate.
Oh, like the jellyfish?
Like getting pissed on?
You notice Anita's been
acting mighty bossy recently?
She's always been that way.
Yeah.
Oh, shit.
Darling, let it go. Don't
get yourself hurt.
Sit down. I'll get Anita.
Anita!
Hey, I'll take care of it.
Anita will get it. Anita! Does she
have children? I can't remember.
She got two kids. Oh, yeah.
How you doing, baby doll?
Where you going?
Hoo. A baby shower.
Um, Anita, uh, before you go,
could you clean up this mess.
I said I got it. It's all right.
Anita's got it.
I got it.
We're going to ormond beach.
Oh, just come right
out and tell them.
I've named Ellen
editor-in-chief.
And...
We're getting married.
It's an antique.
I know it is.
This belonged to my mother.
It was a gift from me.
Give it back, Jack.
Just give it back to her.
It's all I got.
Ward never believed
yardley's story.
Building permits and
anonymous sources.
He took Charlotte and
Jack back to ormond beach
to get to the bottom of it.
Yardley went back
home to Miami.
That man is dangerous?
Loving him is dangerous?
What is that builder's
name, Charlotte?
What builder?
You know exactly what builder.
The one yardley says
bought the sod.
I don't know. He went alone.
I went to the hairdresser's.
Takes a lot to look like this.
Charlotte bless, you is a mess.
And you'd do anything
to get your man
out of jail... wouldn't you?
Thirsty, huh?
Oh, yeah.
That man is dangerous?
You keep staring like that,
we're gonna have a problem.
What really happened
down there, Charlotte?
After you went to the
hairdresser, what happened? Hm?
Jack, would you tell your brother
to get his hands off of me?
Come on, man. Let's go somewhere else.
Easy, little brother.
Just fucking relax, boy.
Miss bless ain't got
no answer, huh?
I didn't think so.
Your brother's acting strange.
Not used to drinking like this.
Is this love affair for real
or is it just one and done?
I'm telling you?
A little more than that.
Why is ward doing this?
We got 50 places
to be tomorrow.
What is that?
It's beautiful.
Don't turn it down.
No one's ever given me
something like this before.
Well, you just tell me when
you want it back, huh?
It's beautiful.
You want me to fuck you, Jack?
Then I'm gonna fuck
you any way you want.
Jack.
Jack!
I want to get some
alligator shoes.
Mmm, Jack.
You wanted your ass whipped.
Is that what you wanted?
Tell me what you want.
You're a dirty pig.
I'll fuck you any way you want.
Little white pig.
Jack? Jack! Jack!
Jack, wake up!
Something's going
on in ward's room.
Hey! Hey!
Stop it!
What the fuck?
Help! We need help!
Where's the fucking keys?
Where's the fucking keys,
you piece of shit?
Motherfucker, wake up!
Help!
Where are the fucking keys?
Ward, what's the plastic for?
What is the plastic?
What the fuck?
I've watched you so often.
You sit here, and I heard
that you play a little drum.
You didn't get up and do anything.
No.
I heard you could sing,
but with me you are
going to sing.
He's gonna be fine.
You don't have to sleep
all the way down there.
All right.
Just this once.
I can't fuck with this TV on.
Feels kind of awkward
to be talking
while you see this.
But it's kind of awkward that they're
doing it in the first place.
Most boys Jack's
age fall in love
with their high school
or college sweetheart,
but Jack never bothered
much with girls
after his mama left.
I guess you could say he
had abandonment issues.
With Charlotte, it was like
he was getting his mama,
his high school sweetheart,
and a oversexed Barbie doll
all rolled into one.
Any who, I think
y'all seen enough.
My hair looks like crap.
Don't even look at it.
Oh, shit.
I got to go to the hairdresser.
My wig ain't acting right.
I don't understand
what the fuck
you're doing with Hillary.
Oh.
Here we go.
You don't love him.
Really? Mm-hm.
You don't know that.
You don't know anything.
You're 20 years old. You're
not that much older.
I'm a lot older.
It ain't gonna happen.
Look at me.
It's not practical.
I'm not as practical
as the murderer?
He's not guilty, Jack.
That's the point.
That's not the point. Fuck this.
I knew it would happen.
What?
I give you some ass
and suddenly...
Look... Hillary ain't so bad.
And I'm not so good.
I've got another side.
I got a fucked-up side,
and it gets along just
fine with my man.
You can't split
yourself into sides.
Sure, you can. Just
ask your brother.
What the fuck does ward
have to do with this?
He has a dark side and I
don't mean him being a fag.
Now these boys lived
for each other.
Jack wasn't hurt by
ward being a homosexual
or the dark stuff
that he was into.
He was just hurt that
ward never told him.
Hi. Hey, there.
He's doing better. He's
gonna be all right. Good.
So, I gotta go.
Go where? Where you going?
I'm going back home.
You don't have to go anywhere.
It's just the way it works.
You shouldn't go anywhere
you don't want to go.
Who says I don't want to go?
Why do you have to go?
'Cause I do.
Take this ring back.
Yardley called the hotel.
Did you tell him?
I told him ward got mugged
and beaten on the beach.
Well, what'd he say?
Not much.
Wanted to know if he
was gonna make it.
When I told him it
wasn't serious,
he kind of just lost interest. He's
not gonna be much help for a while.
Didn't sound like he
needed much help.
He can't go write the
story alone, Charlotte.
Well, we'll just have to see. He
doesn't know enough about it.
This isn't about a
newspaper article, Jack.
I it's about a person's life.
That's the whole point
we're here, okay?
So it's about someone's life.
Baby, don't go.
You're starting to
screw with my head.
Look, you're a good
kid, all right?
You're...
You got your whole
life ahead of you,
and you want me?
Jack went down to
"the Miami times"
to try to stop yardley from
publishing the article.
He didn't want his
brother's name on it.
Jack.
Hi.
Hey. How's ward? How's
your brother doing?
Been trying to get a hold
of you since yesterday.
Good. He's obviously not
doing so badly then.
Sorry, I didn't want any distractions.
Come, sit, sit.
He wants to read
what you're writing.
As soon as I'm done, he'll be the
first to read it, as always.
Damn it! I'm so sick
of your shit, man!
His name is on that, too.
He wants to read it
before it's published.
Okay? That's it. Uh-huh.
He just wants to read it
before it's published.
You got to get those
facts straight.
You got to get all
the facts straight.
You're starting to sound
like your brother.
Look, we have a deadline here.
I've told you, this is
the newspaper business.
We don't have time to
get all the facts.
We both know the town of
lately set Hillary up.
We've got the story. It's
not the fucking truth!
You want to talk about
the motherfucking truth?
You thought I was from London?
Ain't no negro getting
a job up in this spot
unless he's a colored motherfucking
James Bond, you dig?
I got drunk once and
let ward suck my dick.
He got a taste for niggers
and now he hates himself.
That's the truth.
Go back to your brother, boy.
((British accent) I have
got a deadline to meet.
Hello?
Put ward on the phone.
Why'd you put his
byline on that article?
How could you sign
his name on that?
Tell him we got Hillary out.
The governor's
gonna pardon him.
Hillary's getting out.
"I've had some time to think
over the past few months"
about me, about you.
I'm not sure I found what
I want out of life yet.
All I know is that I don't
want to live it without you.
"Please take this ring back.
Love, Jack."
Get the door.
Get the fucking door, bitch!
Who the fuck are you?
I'm Hillary. What you want?
Get the fuck out!
I'm with Charlotte.
That bitch took my...
I'll call you later!
Charlotte, you want me
to call the police?
There she is.
I'm sorry.
I was gonna write
you a letter...
No, I don't need your letters.
Come here.
Uh...
Don't touch me.
Come on here. Don't touch you?
Don't touch you?
It's okay.
It's all right, baby.
You want to do
something for me?
Anything.
That's all right.
You told me you loved me
in your third letter.
Do you love me?
Yes!
You always fuck like this?
Like it was the last time?
Do you think I'm pretty?
You fuck those
niggers like this?
Gonna get all inside here!
Now pack your shit
and let's go.
I don't think I'm gonna
like living in a swamp.
I don't want to live in a swamp.
I like it here.
And that was their
declaration of love.
So Hillary took
Charlotte to the swamp.
So did you hear about
old man Henry? No.
He got drunk in his
back yard by the water,
and the alligators came out and
took a big chunk of his leg.
Ha. Just joking.
My daddy rooster, he got jumped
by three of his sons,
so I need to find a
home for three of them.
So he's in my house sitting,
so I need... I know
you only have hens.
That's why I was wondering, you
know, if you want to babysit,
you know, adopt three
of them for you.
But they'd be good though,
because you have hens. No.
You're my only hope. No!
I don't want any.
Come on, Charlotte.
I need you to do me a favor.
I need you to post
this thing for me.
It ain't got a stamp on it.
What's wrong with you today?
It's real important.
You think you can
do that for me?
You're not acting
yourself today.
Why's your door open, huh?
Smells like piss in here.
Ward ward said you
might show up.
Left him a note.
You stink.
I can smell you from over here.
Come here, boy. Come sit down.
What you doing back in Miami?
Yardley's gone.
He quit?
No.
He's in New York.
Signing some book deal.
Hero of the new journalism or
some kind of shit. I don't know.
W.W. Moved Ellen
into the house, huh?
Whatever.
Whatever makes him happy.
There wasn't no developer, Jack.
All right, let's move.
Come on, go shower, ward.
I'm tired.
Come on.
Jeez.
I keep thinking I
missed something, Jack.
Like I missed something
I was supposed to see
that was right in front of me.
Like what?
The point of it.
Doesn't matter.
Things got out of hand.
You got hurt,
yardley got his
fucking book deal.
Hillary got Charlotte
in the swamp.
The idea... is that...
You run the water
while you're in there with it.
Come on, man.
Hey.
What if we didn't
get it right, huh?
Makes no difference.
It makes no difference, Jack?
You don't know
what it feels like
to get it exactly right now.
To get it down just
the way it happened.
You're going back
to see Hillary.
Fuck yeah, I am.
Do you ever hear from her?
No.
Miss bless? No.
I wonder what she
thinks of him now, huh?
Can't see her sitting
on the porch stoop
holding a silver spoon
and waiting for the ice cream
carton to come her way, can you?
I dug around.
There wasn't no proof,
no how, nowhere
that they was ever
stealing sod that night.
They want me to
keep my mouth shut.
Don't want me to tell my story.
Well, fuck them.
I'm gonna tell my story.
I'm gonna write my story,
and they can publish it
wherever the fuck they want to.
Yeah, mama always
said you better be...
Right and be last before you gonna
be first and be wrong, boy.
Be right and be last before you
go gonna be first and be wrong...
Yeah, I know!
I heard... They said
things about...
Oh, yeah. It's all true.
Just kidding. You should
see the other guy.
Smile. Smile.
Thank you.
Everyone, please. We
're cutting the cake!
Where's the photographer?
Hey, Claire, can you hand me
that salt over there?
Thank you.
Hi.
You ain't supposed
to be in here.
You gonna get me in...
I got you a drink.
You know w. W. Fired me.
I'm gonna talk to your boss
and tell him you're a
friend of the family.
No, Jack. Yeah.
All I ever did was cook
and clean for you boys.
I wasn't never no family.
Anyway, go on back outside.
Well, ward's out there.
You gonna come see him?
Are you trying to get me fired?
I miss you.
I got something for you.
Wait a minute.
This came for you
about a month ago.
She told him to tell-
she told him not
to let you see it.
"Dear Jack, I can't believe"
I'm finally writing
you this letter
or if it will get to you
or whether you'll even read it.
Jack, I think I've really
messed up this time.
Don't misunderstand me.
Hillary loves me, in his way.
It's just me that isn't
made for this place,
for this lifestyle.
I hope I can make it to
your father's wedding
so I can hear you tell
me, 'I told you so.
"Take care for now.
Sweetly, your Charlotte."
Is that from blondie?
Thank you.
Where's your hat?
Oh, I forgot. Get
out of the kitchen.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me. I'm Jack Jansen.
I'm the groom's son.
My father wants to know what
exactly is taking dinner so long.
It'll be ready in a minute, sir.
Thank you.
Put the hair under the hat.
I don't want your black
hair in my food.
You can put your black
Cheers.
Bye, Anita.
Bye, Jack.
You wouldn't leave
without me, would you?
Drop you off at the motel.
I'm going somewhere.
Mind me asking where
you're going afterward?
Going to Charlotte's.
Well, it gotta be tonight?
I got to get her the
fuck out of there.
I got to get her out of there!
Charlotte's acting on
her own free will.
What do you want me to say?
Move.
I got to go to the
van wetters' anyway.
Come with me tomorrow morning.
We're going now. It
ain't the right time.
Get the fuck out my way. You
ain't driving drunk like this.
What the fuck are you
gonna do about it, huh?
What?
Charlotte must be a
good piece of ass.
You look like a pirate. I know.
Do this for me one time.
Go "aargh."
Uh-huh.
Hey, you're driving
all squirrelly, man.
Hey, Jack, sit on down. Hey.
You sure it's this way?
I'm sure it's this way.
Ain't a good time to be drinking
too much out here, Jack.
Yeah, you're one to talk.
Keeping your promise
to dad, did you?
Not to drink on his big day?
How you holding up?
Let's see your hands.
Are they shaking?
They shaking, ward, huh?
Don't drink.
Well, why do you take after
the worst of me, Jack?
'Cause you're my brother.
Wedding party, Charlotte?
I'm going to the wedding.
Don't be difficult.
I told you...
I don't want you to go.
No. I told you. I'm
going to the wedding.
Watch out.
God, it smells like shit.
Electric fence. You all right?
You all right?
Goddamn.
You let me lead.
I don't want to
quarrel with you.
You're my little pony.
I just want to climb up
on you one more time.
I can't believe
she'd live here.
Charlotte!
Charlotte?
What you want?
She not here.
She gone.
What is it you
want with my wife?
Huh?
What is it you
want with my wife?
Just wanted to say hello.
A quick hello and a quick
poke while you're at it?
How about you? What
you up to, ward?
I know what you came for.
I got what you want.
Where is she?
How should I know? I'm not
leaving until I see her.
She not here. She gone.
Let's go. Where?
How should I know?
Last night she told me
she was going to your
father's wedding!
You're a liar! We
just come from there!
And that's where you
should go back to, boy!
He's lying!
He's lying.
I got this. Go
back to the boat.
Where is she? Where is she?
Stop provoking me, boy,
and do what your
brother tells you!
I said I'm not leaving
until I see her!
Goddamn it, he killed her.
He killed her, ward.
You killed her!
You son of a bitch!
That's all you were good
for is killing her!
Huh?
Run, Jack!
Come on, boy. Show me.
I'm gonna fuck you up.
Come on!
Jack!
Ward!
Is this what you wanted?
Yeah.
You got what you come for.
Paperboy.
Where you going, paperboy?
Ain't no way out of this one.
Fuck you!
Hillary van wetter was
tried and convicted
in the murders of Charlotte
bless and ward Jansen.
He died in the electric chair
at the Florida state prison.
Nobody ever found out who
murdered sheriff call.
My little Jack finally saw his
mama again at ward's funeral.
He became a writer
of some renown.
He never did get over
his first true love.