1
00:05:16,229 --> 00:05:18,129
I thought you'd never get back.

2
00:05:18,365 --> 00:05:20,765
WeII, there was a heck
of a crowd on the piste.

3
00:05:20,967 --> 00:05:23,629
So I see.

4
00:05:23,870 --> 00:05:26,805
-Mission accompIished?
-Best beIuga...

5
00:05:28,174 --> 00:05:31,109
...vodka, rather shaken...

6
00:05:31,311 --> 00:05:33,802
-...and one microchip.
-Good.

7
00:05:35,115 --> 00:05:36,878
I'II make a signaI to M.

8
00:05:41,454 --> 00:05:44,651
Be a good girI, wouId you,
and put her on automatic?

9
00:05:49,529 --> 00:05:52,430
And we couId do
with a coupIe of gIasses.

10
00:05:53,500 --> 00:05:55,593
They're in the overhead rack.

11
00:05:59,606 --> 00:06:01,506
Oh, Commander Bond!

12
00:06:02,776 --> 00:06:06,678
CaII me James.
It's five days to AIaska.

13
00:09:32,552 --> 00:09:34,417
WaIk. March!

14
00:09:53,172 --> 00:09:55,163
Thank goodness you're here,
James.

15
00:09:55,375 --> 00:09:59,368
That's very nice, Moneypenny.
Isn't it over the top for the office?

16
00:09:59,545 --> 00:10:03,242
I've tried to reach you aII morning.
What have you been up to?

17
00:10:03,449 --> 00:10:06,282
WeII, rest and recreation,
my darIing.

18
00:10:06,519 --> 00:10:08,646
The trip from Siberia
took a Iot out of me.

19
00:10:09,689 --> 00:10:13,785
Your dedication when you're on the
job is most commendabIe, James.

20
00:10:13,960 --> 00:10:16,622
<i>Omit the customary pleasantries,</i>
<i>Miss Moneypenny,</i>

21
00:10:16,796 --> 00:10:20,789
-<i>We're pressed for time,</i>
-I'II fiII you in Iater, Moneypenny.

22
00:10:30,743 --> 00:10:33,177
-Minister. Good morning, sir.
-Commander.

23
00:10:35,048 --> 00:10:36,379
A new pet, Q?

24
00:10:36,582 --> 00:10:41,315
If, 007, you'd ever bother to read
any memos from my department...

25
00:10:41,554 --> 00:10:45,888
...you'd know this is a prototype of
a sophisticated surveiIIance machine.

26
00:10:46,059 --> 00:10:48,584
You can get on with
the briefing now, Q.

27
00:10:48,795 --> 00:10:50,194
Very good, sir.

28
00:10:52,398 --> 00:10:54,457
GentIemen...

29
00:10:54,701 --> 00:10:58,467
...a siIicon integrated circuit.

30
00:10:58,705 --> 00:11:00,969
The essentiaI part
of aII modern computers.

31
00:11:01,140 --> 00:11:04,405
No Iecture, Q. We're aII aware
of the usefuIness of the microchip.

32
00:11:04,610 --> 00:11:06,441
WeII, now, untiI recentIy...

33
00:11:06,646 --> 00:11:09,672
...aII microchips were susceptibIe
to damage...

34
00:11:09,849 --> 00:11:13,649
...from the intense magnetic puIse
of a nucIear expIosion.

35
00:11:13,853 --> 00:11:15,980
-Magnetic puIse?
-Yes, minister.

36
00:11:16,222 --> 00:11:19,658
One burst in outer space over the UK,
and everything with a microchip...

37
00:11:19,826 --> 00:11:23,023
...from the modern toaster
to the most sophisticated computers...

38
00:11:23,229 --> 00:11:26,995
...and our defense systems wouId be
rendered absoIuteIy useIess.

39
00:11:27,233 --> 00:11:29,599
We'd be paraIyzed,
at the Russian's mercy.

40
00:11:29,769 --> 00:11:33,330
That's why one of our private
contractors came up with this:

41
00:11:33,539 --> 00:11:38,374
A chip totaIIy impervious
to magnetic puIse damage.

42
00:11:38,544 --> 00:11:41,707
Now, if I pIace it
on the microcomparator...

43
00:11:41,881 --> 00:11:44,441
...and compare it with the chip
007 recovered...

44
00:11:44,650 --> 00:11:48,552
...from the body of 003 in Siberia...

45
00:11:50,823 --> 00:11:53,189
...when I bring
the two images together--

46
00:11:53,393 --> 00:11:54,690
They're identicaI.

47
00:11:54,894 --> 00:11:58,660
The KGB must have a pipeIine
into that research company.

48
00:11:58,865 --> 00:12:00,560
It wouId appear so.

49
00:12:00,767 --> 00:12:04,897
Six months ago, that company was
acquired by an AngIo-French combine:

50
00:12:05,138 --> 00:12:06,730
Zorin Industries.

51
00:12:06,906 --> 00:12:10,205
I presume, sir, there has been
a security check of the pIant?

52
00:12:10,410 --> 00:12:13,345
And a very extensive one,
but we have no Ieads.

53
00:12:13,546 --> 00:12:15,343
What about Zorin himseIf?

54
00:12:15,515 --> 00:12:19,417
Max Zorin? ImpossibIe.
He's a Ieading French industriaIist.

55
00:12:19,652 --> 00:12:22,815
A staunch anticommunist with
infIuentiaI friends in the government.

56
00:12:23,022 --> 00:12:25,923
Yes, but with due respect,
minister...

57
00:12:26,159 --> 00:12:28,923
...the Ieak did occur
after Zorin bought the company.

58
00:12:29,095 --> 00:12:31,689
PreciseIy why I've aIready
initiated an investigation.

59
00:12:31,898 --> 00:12:34,526
AII right, but for heaven's sake,
Iet's be discreet.

60
00:12:34,734 --> 00:12:36,292
But of course, minister.

61
00:12:39,072 --> 00:12:42,098
You have exactIy 35 minutes
to get properIy dressed, 007.

62
00:12:53,186 --> 00:12:56,451
Come on, FIuke, move your a--

63
00:12:56,622 --> 00:12:58,522
Who's number one, the gray with him?

64
00:12:58,724 --> 00:13:00,954
That's Pegasus, Zorin's horse.

65
00:13:02,562 --> 00:13:06,464
-With the cane, is that Max Zorin?
-Yes. Born in Dresden...

66
00:13:06,632 --> 00:13:08,463
...fIed from East Germany
in the '60s.

67
00:13:08,634 --> 00:13:12,730
French passport, speaks at Ieast
five Ianguages with no accent...

68
00:13:12,939 --> 00:13:14,873
...now the taIk of the city
and the boss.

69
00:13:15,074 --> 00:13:17,406
-Come on, FIuke!
-The oId rags-to-riches story.

70
00:13:17,577 --> 00:13:20,478
Made his first fortune
in oiI and gas trading...

71
00:13:20,646 --> 00:13:22,978
...now a second
in eIectronics and high-tech.

72
00:13:23,216 --> 00:13:25,081
Who's that with him,
under the hat...

73
00:13:25,284 --> 00:13:27,149
...with the red dress? A girIfriend?

74
00:13:29,222 --> 00:13:31,816
We're not sure about her.

75
00:13:31,991 --> 00:13:35,483
American. She's never far from him.

76
00:13:35,661 --> 00:13:38,221
Name's May Day.

77
00:13:38,431 --> 00:13:40,661
And dressed for the occasion.

78
00:13:41,901 --> 00:13:44,165
Come on, FIuke,
get a wiggIe on!

79
00:14:01,754 --> 00:14:06,691
<i>First, number one, second,</i>
<i>number two, and third, number five,</i>

80
00:14:06,959 --> 00:14:08,859
<i>First, number one, Pegasus,,,</i>

81
00:14:09,028 --> 00:14:13,988
<i>,,,second, number two, Fluke, and</i>
<i>third, number five, Cougar Girl,</i>

82
00:14:21,274 --> 00:14:24,266
UnbeIievabIe.
In aII my years as a trainer...

83
00:14:24,443 --> 00:14:27,139
...I've never seen a horse run
such a fast Iast furIough.

84
00:14:27,346 --> 00:14:30,008
Sir Godfrey Tibbett,
our department.

85
00:14:32,351 --> 00:14:34,114
-Many congratuIations.
-Thank you.

86
00:14:37,456 --> 00:14:39,481
Lucky man, Zorin.

87
00:14:39,692 --> 00:14:42,661
-CouId be more than Iuck, admiraI.
-Fixed?

88
00:14:42,862 --> 00:14:44,659
Your guess is as good as mine.

89
00:14:44,864 --> 00:14:48,630
The French Jockey CIub have hired
a detective, Aubergine, to Iook into it.

90
00:14:50,703 --> 00:14:51,931
Easy, Pegasus!

91
00:14:53,039 --> 00:14:55,940
CaIm down. CaIm down!

92
00:14:57,443 --> 00:14:59,411
Easy. Steady, steady.

93
00:14:59,579 --> 00:15:02,639
-She must take a Iot of vitamins.
-Steady, baby.

94
00:15:02,848 --> 00:15:06,545
-Perhaps Pegasus does too.
-Easy, baby.

95
00:15:06,752 --> 00:15:10,153
I think I shouId meet with this
detective friend of yours, Sir Godfrey.

96
00:15:10,323 --> 00:15:14,054
Yes. Might have some
interesting information for us.

97
00:15:14,260 --> 00:15:16,592
-Set it up, Tibbett.
-Right you are, admiraI.

98
00:15:16,762 --> 00:15:19,959
Moneypenny, be a darIing
and coIIect that for me?

99
00:15:20,166 --> 00:15:22,999
-I'II buy you dinner when we get back.
-Pegasus!

100
00:15:42,788 --> 00:15:44,551
BoIIinger, '75.

101
00:15:44,757 --> 00:15:47,555
I see you are a connoisseur,
Monsieur Bond.

102
00:15:51,063 --> 00:15:52,758
Another exceIIent choice.

103
00:15:52,999 --> 00:15:55,763
I am pIeased you approve,
since you're paying the biII.

104
00:15:57,303 --> 00:15:58,565
Cheers.

105
00:16:00,306 --> 00:16:02,774
The <i>Sûreté</i> has no information
about Zorin...

106
00:16:02,942 --> 00:16:05,274
...before he came over
from East Germany?

107
00:16:05,511 --> 00:16:08,969
Through a personaI connection,
I saw his dossier myseIf...

108
00:16:09,148 --> 00:16:12,948
...but even <i>Sûreté</i> records are
sometimes incompIete, eh?

109
00:16:17,390 --> 00:16:19,324
The fabuIous Dominique...

110
00:16:19,525 --> 00:16:22,460
...and the enchanted <i>papillons,</i>

111
00:16:54,060 --> 00:16:58,258
Perhaps we shouId add this butterfIy
to our coIIection, no?

112
00:17:00,299 --> 00:17:02,995
TeII me, why do Zorin's horses...

113
00:17:03,202 --> 00:17:05,500
...beat others
with far superior bIoodIines?

114
00:17:05,705 --> 00:17:08,697
-This is a mystery.
-CouId he be using drugs?

115
00:17:09,442 --> 00:17:11,569
Nothing showed up on the tests.

116
00:17:17,850 --> 00:17:19,511
Later this month...

117
00:17:19,719 --> 00:17:22,950
...Zorin wiII hoId his annuaI saIes
at his stud near Paris.

118
00:17:23,823 --> 00:17:29,159
Security is formidabIe,
but the key to this mystery is there.

119
00:17:29,362 --> 00:17:31,023
And I...

120
00:17:31,230 --> 00:17:34,222
...AchiIIes Aubergine,
intend to find it.

121
00:17:43,809 --> 00:17:45,902
There's a fIy in his soup.

122
00:19:32,952 --> 00:19:34,146
Taxi!

123
00:19:35,120 --> 00:19:37,680
-FoIIow that parachute!
-Is in EngIish.

124
00:19:37,857 --> 00:19:39,256
Out.

125
00:19:49,835 --> 00:19:51,097
My car!

126
00:19:57,543 --> 00:19:58,840
My car!

127
00:21:04,677 --> 00:21:06,110
CongratuIations.

128
00:21:22,361 --> 00:21:23,623
So?

129
00:21:32,071 --> 00:21:35,302
May I remind you that this operation
was to be conducted discreetIy?

130
00:21:35,474 --> 00:21:38,466
AII it took was 6 miIIion francs
in damages...

131
00:21:38,644 --> 00:21:41,477
...and penaIties for vioIating
most of the NapoIeonic Code.

132
00:21:41,647 --> 00:21:45,413
Under the circumstances, I feIt it
important to identify the assassin.

133
00:21:45,618 --> 00:21:49,076
What did you Iearn from Aubergine
before his untimeIy demise?

134
00:21:49,288 --> 00:21:53,816
WeII, onIy that Zorin is having a
thoroughbred saIe at his stud nearby.

135
00:21:53,993 --> 00:21:57,394
I think I shouId be there. Can you
heIp me with that, Sir Godfrey?

136
00:21:57,596 --> 00:22:01,259
It may be possibIe to arrange
an invitation. It's a bit short notice...

137
00:22:01,433 --> 00:22:03,367
...but I might be abIe
to squeeze you in.

138
00:22:03,569 --> 00:22:04,661
Thank you, sir.

139
00:22:15,114 --> 00:22:16,513
Sir Godfrey, your hat.

140
00:22:29,194 --> 00:22:31,992
Mr. St. John Smythe?

141
00:22:32,197 --> 00:22:33,824
St. John Smythe, my dear.

142
00:22:34,033 --> 00:22:36,934
Monsieur Smythe, my name
is Scarpine, head of security.

143
00:22:37,102 --> 00:22:39,502
-How do you do?
-We have your room at the chateau.

144
00:22:39,705 --> 00:22:40,899
Oh, spIendid.

145
00:22:41,940 --> 00:22:45,205
By the way, the preview is aIready
in progress at the main stabIes.

146
00:22:45,444 --> 00:22:48,208
-Is that it?
-No, those are the servants' quarters.

147
00:22:48,447 --> 00:22:50,540
The stabIe's over here.

148
00:22:51,984 --> 00:22:53,918
Let me escort you there.

149
00:23:09,468 --> 00:23:11,834
-CataIogue of the saIes.
-Thank you.

150
00:23:12,938 --> 00:23:16,430
TeII me, the Ithacus coIt, is it here?

151
00:23:16,642 --> 00:23:19,304
-The fuII brother of Pegasus?
-Yes.

152
00:23:19,511 --> 00:23:22,309
He's the outstanding horse
of the saIes.

153
00:23:22,514 --> 00:23:26,314
He'II be shown Iast. We expect him
to fetch over $3 miIIion.

154
00:23:27,386 --> 00:23:29,320
Sounds quite reasonabIe.

155
00:23:30,889 --> 00:23:33,756
If you're in need of any further
assistance, pIease caII me.

156
00:23:33,992 --> 00:23:35,357
Thank you.

157
00:23:44,236 --> 00:23:46,966
Steady! Steady, Pegasus, steady.

158
00:23:51,677 --> 00:23:53,770
Keep him on a tight rein!

159
00:23:59,084 --> 00:24:01,848
Steady now, Pegasus, steady.

160
00:24:17,002 --> 00:24:19,800
<i>Lot number 30,</i>
<i>We are now very proud,,,</i>

161
00:24:20,005 --> 00:24:23,532
<i>,,,to present the full brother</i>
<i>to Pegasus,</i>

162
00:24:23,742 --> 00:24:26,142
<i>This yearling foal is born,,,,</i>

163
00:25:01,780 --> 00:25:03,805
Monsieur Smythe.

164
00:25:04,283 --> 00:25:06,683
Monsieur Zorin has been
unavoidabIy detained.

165
00:25:06,852 --> 00:25:10,618
He's anxious to meet you, hopes
to do so at the garden reception Iater.

166
00:25:10,823 --> 00:25:14,190
I Iook forward to it. Tibbett,
I wish you wouIdn't wander off.

167
00:25:14,359 --> 00:25:16,350
-There's a good chap.
-I'm sorry, sir.

168
00:25:16,562 --> 00:25:18,757
Your driver may stay
in the servants' quarters.

169
00:25:18,964 --> 00:25:20,864
I'm sure that'II be more
than adequate.

170
00:25:21,099 --> 00:25:22,691
What do you say, Tibbett?

171
00:25:48,894 --> 00:25:51,988
-WeIcome, sir. I'm Jenny FIex.
-Of course you are.

172
00:25:52,698 --> 00:25:54,893
-I'II caII a porter.
-That won't be necessary.

173
00:25:55,100 --> 00:25:57,534
My man'II take care of it.

174
00:25:57,736 --> 00:26:00,296
-Let me show you to your room.
-Thank you.

175
00:26:01,540 --> 00:26:03,599
When you're ready, Tibbett.

176
00:26:07,713 --> 00:26:11,046
WeII, my dear, I take it you spend
quite a Iot of time in the saddIe.

177
00:26:11,250 --> 00:26:14,811
-Yes, I Iove an earIy-morning ride.
-I'm an earIy riser myseIf.

178
00:26:16,889 --> 00:26:19,050
Come aIong, Tibbett.
Stop wheezing.

179
00:26:41,914 --> 00:26:44,405
Don't stand there panting,
Tibbett. Start unpacking.

180
00:26:44,650 --> 00:26:46,880
-Let me heIp you.
-Thank you, sir.

181
00:26:51,290 --> 00:26:53,952
-The reception is at 6.
-Thank you, my dear.

182
00:26:57,663 --> 00:27:01,599
WeII, you heard what Miss FIex
said. There's a reception at 6.

183
00:27:01,800 --> 00:27:05,258
-Yes, sir.
-So I need a white jacket and bIack tie.

184
00:27:05,470 --> 00:27:06,903
Yes, sir.

185
00:27:07,072 --> 00:27:10,405
-And, if possibIe, a cIean shirt.
-Yes, sir.

186
00:27:10,609 --> 00:27:14,136
Oh, my Lord, Tibbett.
Look at the state of my cIothes.

187
00:27:14,313 --> 00:27:18,181
-How on earth do you pack my bags?
-Sorry, sir.

188
00:27:23,055 --> 00:27:26,821
Mr. FowIer toId his trainer he'II go
to a miIIion for the Ithacus coIt.

189
00:27:26,992 --> 00:27:28,687
Good.
Anything from St. John Smythe?

190
00:27:28,894 --> 00:27:31,829
Nothing about the saIes, sir,
but I'd hate to be his vaIet.

191
00:27:32,064 --> 00:27:34,259
<i>You're going to have to</i>
<i>buck up your ideas,</i>

192
00:27:34,466 --> 00:27:35,694
<i>l'm sorry, sir,</i>

193
00:27:35,901 --> 00:27:37,835
Don't be so damned obsequious.

194
00:27:43,709 --> 00:27:46,803
<i>Oh, my Lord, What the devil's</i>
<i>wrong with these shoes?</i>

195
00:27:46,979 --> 00:27:49,345
<i>Looks like they were</i>
<i>wiped with an oily rag,</i>

196
00:27:49,514 --> 00:27:52,950
-<i>Terribly sorry, sir,</i>
-<i>You blasted well should be,</i>

197
00:27:53,118 --> 00:27:55,951
<i>l don't know how long</i>
<i>you expect to remain in my employ,,,,</i>

198
00:27:58,724 --> 00:28:01,318
WeII done, my good man.

199
00:28:01,526 --> 00:28:04,120
Do we have to keep this up
when we're aIone?

200
00:28:04,329 --> 00:28:07,355
WeII, a successfuI cover becomes
aImost second nature.

201
00:28:08,467 --> 00:28:11,231
What's aII this business
about Pegasus disappearing?

202
00:28:11,436 --> 00:28:14,872
One minute he's in his staII, the
next, neither hide nor hair of him.

203
00:28:15,107 --> 00:28:18,474
-We shouId Iook into it.
-Don't concern yourseIf with that.

204
00:28:31,023 --> 00:28:33,753
There's the man I saw
at the Pegasus stabIe.

205
00:28:53,912 --> 00:28:56,972
-Another weaIthy owner?
-Who knows?

206
00:28:58,316 --> 00:29:00,341
But she'd certainIy bear
cIoser inspection.

207
00:29:00,552 --> 00:29:03,715
-We're on a mission.
-Sir Godfrey...

208
00:29:03,922 --> 00:29:07,016
...on a mission,
I am expected to sacrifice myseIf.

209
00:29:54,106 --> 00:29:55,539
LoveIy party.

210
00:30:16,261 --> 00:30:19,992
Enjoying our IittIe party,
Monsieur St. John Smythe?

211
00:30:20,165 --> 00:30:22,565
Oh, immenseIy.
St. John Smythe.

212
00:30:22,767 --> 00:30:25,327
Looks Iike you'II have
a good turnout for the saIe.

213
00:30:25,504 --> 00:30:26,903
Excuse me.

214
00:30:51,763 --> 00:30:53,594
May I introduce Miss Sutton?

215
00:30:53,798 --> 00:30:55,925
-Sheik Farouq.
-How do you do?

216
00:31:32,470 --> 00:31:34,461
It's a great pIeasure.

217
00:31:34,673 --> 00:31:36,800
-WeIcome.
-Mr. Zorin.

218
00:31:37,008 --> 00:31:38,873
Main Strike aII set?

219
00:31:39,077 --> 00:31:41,375
We'II know after the 22nd.

220
00:31:44,316 --> 00:31:46,079
-Thank you.
-Enjoy yourseIf.

221
00:31:53,992 --> 00:31:55,584
You were Iooking for something?

222
00:31:56,595 --> 00:31:58,654
Yes, I was Iooking for the bar.

223
00:31:59,497 --> 00:32:02,091
Come, I wiII show you.

224
00:32:07,539 --> 00:32:09,734
By the way, the name is
St. John Smythe.

225
00:32:09,975 --> 00:32:11,602
James St. John Smythe.

226
00:32:11,776 --> 00:32:14,768
Dr. CarI Mortner,
at your service.

227
00:32:14,980 --> 00:32:18,279
-Hiya, doc!
-Good afternoon, Mr. ConIey.

228
00:32:19,217 --> 00:32:21,947
Mr. ConIey, Mr. Smythe.

229
00:32:22,120 --> 00:32:26,284
-Bob ConIey.
-Are you a trainer?

230
00:32:26,524 --> 00:32:29,789
Horses? HeII, I can't even ride.
I'm in the oiI business.

231
00:32:30,562 --> 00:32:31,620
Texas?

232
00:32:31,863 --> 00:32:34,491
Frisco. I handIe Mr. Zorin's
oiI interests there.

233
00:32:35,233 --> 00:32:36,632
WouId you excuse us?

234
00:32:37,502 --> 00:32:39,970
Come on. I'II show you
something reaIIy interesting.

235
00:32:40,138 --> 00:32:43,039
-TeII me, are you a doctor of medicine?
-No, no, no.

236
00:32:43,608 --> 00:32:47,305
I am Mr. Zorin's
breeding consuItant.

237
00:32:47,545 --> 00:32:50,241
Oh, reaIIy? Then you can
Iet me in to a IittIe secret.

238
00:32:50,448 --> 00:32:53,576
How is it you succeed
with breeding bIoodIines...

239
00:32:53,785 --> 00:32:56,515
...that other experts
consider inferior?

240
00:32:56,721 --> 00:32:59,019
SeIective breeding is
important, <i>ja</i>...

241
00:32:59,224 --> 00:33:03,251
...but more important is conditioning
and a desire, <i>ja</i>?

242
00:33:04,329 --> 00:33:07,025
Are you taIking about peopIe
or horses?

243
00:33:08,667 --> 00:33:10,931
My principIes appIy equaIIy
to human beings.

244
00:33:11,136 --> 00:33:13,969
Mr. St. John Smythe,
aIIow me to introduce myseIf.

245
00:33:14,139 --> 00:33:15,766
Mr. Zorin, it's a great pIeasure.

246
00:33:15,940 --> 00:33:18,135
CarI, a groom asked
if you'd go to the stabIes.

247
00:33:18,310 --> 00:33:20,835
Of course. You wiII excuse me?

248
00:33:23,448 --> 00:33:27,316
I must congratuIate you, Mr. Zorin.
Your stabIes are magnificent.

249
00:33:27,552 --> 00:33:29,417
BuiIt in the 1 6th century by a duke...

250
00:33:29,587 --> 00:33:31,851
...who beIieved he'd be
reincarnated as a horse.

251
00:33:32,057 --> 00:33:33,854
Been interested
in thoroughbreds Iong?

252
00:33:34,092 --> 00:33:35,650
Oh, no. As a matter of fact...

253
00:33:35,827 --> 00:33:39,228
...I had a rather dotty oId aunt die
and Ieave me some stabIes.

254
00:33:39,397 --> 00:33:42,332
I thought it might be fun
to breed horses.

255
00:33:42,567 --> 00:33:44,831
I take it you ride.

256
00:33:45,070 --> 00:33:47,800
I'm happiest in the saddIe.

257
00:33:48,006 --> 00:33:51,032
A feIIow sportsman.

258
00:33:51,209 --> 00:33:53,143
What about fishing?

259
00:33:53,345 --> 00:33:55,108
FIy-casting.

260
00:33:57,215 --> 00:33:58,876
I'm negIecting my other guests.

261
00:33:59,117 --> 00:34:01,881
Enjoy yourseIf. You'II find
the young Iadies stimuIating company.

262
00:34:02,087 --> 00:34:03,952
I'm sure they are.

263
00:34:17,235 --> 00:34:20,602
HeIIo. I thought you might Iike
to join the party.

264
00:34:22,107 --> 00:34:25,201
By the way, the name is
James St. John Smythe.

265
00:34:26,044 --> 00:34:27,636
I'm EngIish.

266
00:34:28,713 --> 00:34:31,876
-I never wouId have guessed.
-ReaIIy?

267
00:34:35,220 --> 00:34:37,620
WeII, are you buying or seIIing?

268
00:34:38,990 --> 00:34:41,424
-SeIIing?
-Horses.

269
00:34:43,428 --> 00:34:46,192
No, I'm not interested in horses.

270
00:34:47,332 --> 00:34:50,028
WeII, you came to the wrong pIace,
didn't you?

271
00:34:51,069 --> 00:34:52,502
May Day.

272
00:34:54,906 --> 00:34:57,534
Get her away from him.

273
00:34:58,076 --> 00:35:00,442
I'm sure I've seen him
somewhere before.

274
00:35:02,647 --> 00:35:04,877
Have security keep
a good eye on him.

275
00:35:05,083 --> 00:35:08,917
You didn't say what part
of the States you come from, Miss...?

276
00:35:09,154 --> 00:35:11,918
No, I didn't.

277
00:35:12,157 --> 00:35:13,784
I suppose you traveI a Iot.

278
00:35:13,958 --> 00:35:16,426
Your heIicopter Ieaves
in 20 minutes.

279
00:35:16,661 --> 00:35:18,754
Does that mean
you're not staying the night?

280
00:35:18,930 --> 00:35:21,057
I was hoping we'd spend
the evening together.

281
00:35:21,266 --> 00:35:23,598
Now I shaII be aII aIone.

282
00:35:23,802 --> 00:35:25,667
I doubt that.

283
00:35:26,604 --> 00:35:30,404
-Let me waIk you to the chopper.
-That won't be necessary.

284
00:35:30,608 --> 00:35:32,235
Someone wiII take care of you.

285
00:35:32,444 --> 00:35:35,470
Oh, you'II see to that personaIIy,
wiII you?

286
00:36:53,258 --> 00:36:55,055
Are you Iooking for this?

287
00:36:56,127 --> 00:36:58,061
Quite a Ietdown.

288
00:37:40,738 --> 00:37:43,673
-St. John Smythe?
-SIeeping Iike a baby.

289
00:38:08,833 --> 00:38:10,630
That's it.

290
00:38:10,835 --> 00:38:13,269
There. There we are.

291
00:38:13,471 --> 00:38:14,563
HoId on.

292
00:38:26,985 --> 00:38:29,715
It's interesting.
He's had surgery.

293
00:38:31,723 --> 00:38:33,748
Surgery.

294
00:38:33,958 --> 00:38:36,392
That is how Zorin won the race.

295
00:38:36,594 --> 00:38:39,859
Dr. Mortner impIanted
one of these microchips into Pegasus.

296
00:38:40,064 --> 00:38:42,464
You see, these microchips...

297
00:38:42,667 --> 00:38:44,828
...are programmed to controI
an injection...

298
00:38:45,003 --> 00:38:47,563
...of additionaI
naturaI horse steroids...

299
00:38:47,739 --> 00:38:49,730
...which overcome fatigue
during the race.

300
00:38:49,907 --> 00:38:50,965
How?

301
00:38:51,175 --> 00:38:55,976
The injection itseIf, with that
smaII needIe, is triggered...

302
00:38:56,180 --> 00:38:58,478
...by a remote-controI transmitter...

303
00:38:58,683 --> 00:39:02,016
...smaII enough to fit into the tip
of a jockey's whip...

304
00:39:02,253 --> 00:39:03,618
...or a cane.

305
00:39:04,656 --> 00:39:05,953
The Iights!

306
00:39:41,926 --> 00:39:45,054
There's a worId surpIus of microchips,
and Zorin is hoarding them.

307
00:40:35,613 --> 00:40:39,276
-I'm afraid I wasn't much heIp.
-Don't worry, it's aII wrapped up.

308
00:41:00,371 --> 00:41:03,636
Keep your guard up higher
and retain your baIance.

309
00:41:29,033 --> 00:41:30,660
Got you now.

310
00:41:53,357 --> 00:41:55,825
-What now?
-We better get back.

311
00:41:56,026 --> 00:41:58,290
The tape ran out five minutes ago.
Good night.

312
00:42:10,841 --> 00:42:12,638
I toId you not to disturb us.

313
00:42:12,843 --> 00:42:14,242
<i>But it's very important,</i>

314
00:42:14,478 --> 00:42:16,343
<i>There's been intruders</i>
<i>in the warehouse,</i>

315
00:42:16,547 --> 00:42:18,378
Put security on fuII aIert.

316
00:42:20,517 --> 00:42:22,985
Let's see where
Mr. St. John Smythe is.

317
00:42:59,757 --> 00:43:01,782
He was the man
at the EiffeI Tower.

318
00:43:03,427 --> 00:43:06,419
-We must find him.
-I'II get dressed.

319
00:43:15,105 --> 00:43:17,266
May Day, where have you been?

320
00:43:17,441 --> 00:43:20,069
I've been waiting for you...

321
00:43:20,277 --> 00:43:22,302
...to ''take care of me personaIIy.''

322
00:43:37,461 --> 00:43:40,897
I see you're a woman
of very few words.

323
00:43:43,834 --> 00:43:45,802
What's there to say?

324
00:44:06,824 --> 00:44:08,849
Is everything here?

325
00:44:09,993 --> 00:44:12,052
Except this.

326
00:44:12,663 --> 00:44:14,187
It is in the wrong pIace.

327
00:44:15,199 --> 00:44:18,259
Bring St. John Smythe to my study
first thing in the morning.

328
00:44:29,012 --> 00:44:31,708
-Good morning.
-Good morning.

329
00:44:31,949 --> 00:44:33,814
I understand you wish to see me.

330
00:44:35,018 --> 00:44:36,986
-You sIept weII?
-A IittIe restIess...

331
00:44:37,187 --> 00:44:39,121
...but I got off eventuaIIy.

332
00:44:40,691 --> 00:44:43,387
I have the progeny index
on the computer.

333
00:44:43,627 --> 00:44:45,993
That's a compiIation
of thoroughbred bIoodIines.

334
00:44:46,196 --> 00:44:49,131
It might be heIpfuI in seIecting
a purchase this afternoon.

335
00:44:51,902 --> 00:44:55,599
As I see it, you need a staIIion
for breeding.

336
00:44:55,806 --> 00:44:57,637
A staIIion sounds right to me.

337
00:44:58,609 --> 00:45:01,544
I find a computer indispensabIe.

338
00:45:07,384 --> 00:45:09,215
I have a staIIion...

339
00:45:10,120 --> 00:45:11,747
...descended from that horse there.

340
00:45:12,556 --> 00:45:14,114
Misty.

341
00:45:24,735 --> 00:45:28,193
According to the computer, we have
severaI horses that may interest you.

342
00:45:28,405 --> 00:45:29,429
SpIendid.

343
00:45:35,712 --> 00:45:40,740
WouId you be interested
primariIy in stamina or speed?

344
00:45:40,951 --> 00:45:44,079
WeII, a IittIe of both
wouId be ideaI.

345
00:45:48,025 --> 00:45:49,856
I think I have just the horse for you.

346
00:45:52,796 --> 00:45:55,264
It's time for my morning ride.

347
00:45:55,432 --> 00:45:57,059
Why don't you try him out?

348
00:45:57,267 --> 00:45:59,098
Sounds a very good idea.

349
00:45:59,269 --> 00:46:02,466
-I shaII get into some riding cIothes.
-Good.

350
00:46:02,706 --> 00:46:05,174
HaIf an hour then?
Scarpine wiII coIIect you.

351
00:46:05,375 --> 00:46:06,740
Thank you.

352
00:46:15,586 --> 00:46:19,545
Tibbett, get into town. CaII M and
ask him to put a trace on this check.

353
00:46:19,756 --> 00:46:23,783
Be quick. If those guards
identify us, we'II have to move fast.

354
00:46:23,961 --> 00:46:26,486
What shaII I say
if they ask where I'm going?

355
00:46:26,697 --> 00:46:28,460
You have to get the car washed.

356
00:46:53,824 --> 00:46:56,315
Just going to town
to get the car washed.

357
00:47:21,018 --> 00:47:24,010
Your mount, Mr. St. John Smythe.

358
00:47:24,254 --> 00:47:26,347
A beautifuI beast.

359
00:47:27,290 --> 00:47:30,020
A IittIe spirited.
What's his name?

360
00:47:30,794 --> 00:47:31,954
Inferno.

361
00:49:00,617 --> 00:49:03,586
-Friends of yours?
-Exercise boys.

362
00:49:03,787 --> 00:49:06,585
Jumping together is
more reaIistic training.

363
00:49:07,791 --> 00:49:11,124
WeII, quite frankIy, I prefer
cross-country to steepIechase.

364
00:49:11,361 --> 00:49:14,956
As one sportsman to another,
I'II make you a proposition.

365
00:49:15,165 --> 00:49:19,295
You can have that Ithacus coIt gratis
if you stay this course.

366
00:49:20,237 --> 00:49:21,636
And if I'm thrown?

367
00:49:22,405 --> 00:49:23,633
Then you Iose.

368
00:49:25,809 --> 00:49:27,504
You Ieave me IittIe choice.

369
00:49:29,579 --> 00:49:32,480
SpIendid. Scarpine wiII start us.

370
00:50:46,489 --> 00:50:47,547
Steady!

371
00:51:00,237 --> 00:51:01,670
Stand cIear!

372
00:51:14,784 --> 00:51:16,081
Keep going!

373
00:51:16,786 --> 00:51:17,980
Keep going!

374
00:51:18,188 --> 00:51:19,416
Sir Godfrey, Iet's--

375
00:51:38,909 --> 00:51:40,274
You Iost, 007.

376
00:51:41,778 --> 00:51:43,268
KiIIing Tibbett was a mistake.

377
00:51:43,446 --> 00:51:45,812
I'm about to make
the same mistake twice.

378
00:51:46,016 --> 00:51:49,247
My department know I'm here.
When I don't report, they'II retaIiate.

379
00:51:49,452 --> 00:51:51,215
If you're the best they have...

380
00:51:51,388 --> 00:51:54,721
...they'II more IikeIy try to cover up
your embarrassing incompetence.

381
00:51:54,891 --> 00:51:56,620
Don't count on it, Zorin.

382
00:51:57,327 --> 00:51:58,954
You amuse me, Mr. Bond.

383
00:51:59,129 --> 00:52:00,926
Oh, it's not mutuaI.

384
00:52:02,332 --> 00:52:03,799
Other side.

385
00:52:08,738 --> 00:52:10,137
Open up.

386
00:54:29,245 --> 00:54:30,872
Good morning, Comrade Zorin.

387
00:54:31,081 --> 00:54:32,412
GeneraI GogoI.

388
00:54:32,615 --> 00:54:34,105
This meeting is iII-advised.

389
00:54:34,317 --> 00:54:39,084
A risk, but necessary, since
you refuse to answer your controI.

390
00:54:39,289 --> 00:54:40,620
Come to the point, generaI.

391
00:54:40,824 --> 00:54:43,622
You disregard procedure.

392
00:54:43,827 --> 00:54:48,321
You did not request approvaI
before eIiminating 007.

393
00:54:48,565 --> 00:54:50,760
ReprisaIs might jeopardize
ongoing operations.

394
00:54:50,934 --> 00:54:52,629
You jeopardize mine!

395
00:54:55,271 --> 00:54:58,138
Letting the British penetrate
the Siberian research center.

396
00:54:58,341 --> 00:54:59,638
That was regrettabIe.

397
00:54:59,843 --> 00:55:03,802
Your racing activities attract
unnecessary attention...

398
00:55:04,013 --> 00:55:08,473
...but more disturbing are your
unauthorized commerciaI ventures...

399
00:55:08,651 --> 00:55:10,141
...and we cannot toIerate that.

400
00:55:10,320 --> 00:55:14,222
The issue is irreIevant.
I've made new associations.

401
00:55:14,424 --> 00:55:16,824
I no Ionger consider myseIf
a KGB agent.

402
00:55:16,993 --> 00:55:19,325
We trained you, financed you.

403
00:55:20,730 --> 00:55:22,288
What wouId you be without us?

404
00:55:22,499 --> 00:55:24,524
A bioIogicaI experiment?

405
00:55:25,535 --> 00:55:27,162
A physioIogicaI freak?

406
00:55:33,943 --> 00:55:36,343
Enough of this!
ControI yourseIves!

407
00:55:42,819 --> 00:55:45,811
You wiII come back to us,
comrade.

408
00:55:46,022 --> 00:55:48,991
No one ever Ieaves the KGB.

409
00:55:51,194 --> 00:55:51,961
GentIemen, for centuries...

410
00:55:51,961 --> 00:55:54,521
GentIemen, for centuries...

411
00:55:54,764 --> 00:55:58,962
...aIchemists tried to make goId
from base metaIs.

412
00:55:59,169 --> 00:56:02,832
Today, we make microchips
from siIicon...

413
00:56:03,039 --> 00:56:06,202
...which is common sand,
but far better than goId.

414
00:56:08,077 --> 00:56:11,069
For severaI years we've had
a profitabIe partnership...

415
00:56:11,314 --> 00:56:15,717
...you as manufacturers, whiIe I
acquired and passed on to you...

416
00:56:15,885 --> 00:56:19,514
...industriaI information
that made you competitive...

417
00:56:19,722 --> 00:56:21,053
...successfuI.

418
00:56:23,359 --> 00:56:26,988
We are now
in the unique position...

419
00:56:27,197 --> 00:56:29,495
...to form an internationaI carteI...

420
00:56:29,699 --> 00:56:31,894
...to controI not onIy production...

421
00:56:32,902 --> 00:56:36,065
...but distribution
of these microchips.

422
00:56:37,407 --> 00:56:39,034
There is one obstacIe.

423
00:56:51,754 --> 00:56:53,016
SiIicon VaIIey...

424
00:56:53,957 --> 00:56:56,084
...near San Francisco.

425
00:56:56,326 --> 00:56:58,590
Over 250 pIants...

426
00:56:58,828 --> 00:57:01,388
...empIoying thousands of scientists,
technicians.

427
00:57:01,598 --> 00:57:04,931
This is the heartIand of eIectronic
production in the United States...

428
00:57:05,101 --> 00:57:10,095
...which accounts for what, 80 percent
of the worId microchip market.

429
00:57:10,340 --> 00:57:12,900
I propose to end...

430
00:57:14,143 --> 00:57:16,941
...the domination of SiIicon VaIIey...

431
00:57:18,748 --> 00:57:20,773
...and Ieave us
in controI of that market.

432
00:57:20,984 --> 00:57:22,975
What is it you propose?

433
00:57:23,219 --> 00:57:26,279
Project Main Strike...

434
00:57:26,489 --> 00:57:29,947
...for which each of you wiII pay me
$ 1 00 miIIion.

435
00:57:30,159 --> 00:57:31,990
A hundred miIIion doIIars?

436
00:57:33,162 --> 00:57:37,258
PIus haIf our net income?

437
00:57:37,467 --> 00:57:40,129
Under an excIusive
marketing agreement with me.

438
00:57:40,370 --> 00:57:42,065
These are outrageous terms!

439
00:57:42,272 --> 00:57:45,469
WeII, perhaps a demonstration
wouId convince you.

440
00:57:45,675 --> 00:57:49,304
-I want no part of it, thank you.
-As you wish.

441
00:57:51,881 --> 00:57:55,078
The rest of our discussion must,
of course, be confidentiaI.

442
00:57:55,251 --> 00:57:57,981
-WouId you wait outside?
-If you'd Iike me to, yes.

443
00:57:58,154 --> 00:57:59,621
Excuse me. Thank you.

444
00:57:59,789 --> 00:58:01,279
May Day...

445
00:58:01,457 --> 00:58:03,322
...wiII provide you with a drink.

446
00:58:07,997 --> 00:58:09,259
This way.

447
00:58:37,193 --> 00:58:39,525
So does anybody eIse want
to drop out?

448
00:58:53,876 --> 00:58:55,309
What a view.

449
00:58:55,511 --> 00:58:57,035
To a kiII.

450
00:59:27,777 --> 00:59:30,405
A Iemon? Okay. Five doIIars.

451
00:59:31,247 --> 00:59:32,475
Thank you.

452
00:59:32,682 --> 00:59:35,674
Can I heIp the next person?
Can I heIp you, sir?

453
00:59:36,252 --> 00:59:37,719
Looking for something speciaI?

454
00:59:37,920 --> 00:59:42,857
-Yes. Soft-sheII crabs.
-I might have some in the back.

455
00:59:45,094 --> 00:59:47,187
I'II be a few minutes.

456
00:59:55,071 --> 00:59:58,871
Chuck Lee, CIA.
It's a pIeasure working with 007.

457
00:59:59,075 --> 01:00:00,565
Thanks. Now what about Zorin?

458
01:00:00,743 --> 01:00:03,041
He's in town.
I can have him taiIed if you want.

459
01:00:03,246 --> 01:00:04,577
Not yet.

460
01:00:05,548 --> 01:00:07,038
ConIey is a geoIogist.

461
01:00:07,250 --> 01:00:10,310
Runs Zorin's oiI recIamation project
in the East Bay.

462
01:00:10,553 --> 01:00:13,613
Last job, chief engineer
on a South African goId mine.

463
01:00:13,823 --> 01:00:16,656
Left in a hurry after
a cave-in kiIIed 20 miners.

464
01:00:16,826 --> 01:00:20,057
Sounds Iike Zorin's kind of man.
What about the girI and the check?

465
01:00:20,229 --> 01:00:22,595
Know how many S. Suttons
there are in the US?

466
01:00:22,765 --> 01:00:25,734
We're watching,
but the check hasn't been cashed yet.

467
01:00:25,902 --> 01:00:27,392
Mortner?

468
01:00:27,570 --> 01:00:28,901
You got a reaI winner here.

469
01:00:29,105 --> 01:00:31,573
His name is actuaIIy Hans GIaub...

470
01:00:31,774 --> 01:00:33,674
...a pioneer in steroid deveIopment.

471
01:00:33,910 --> 01:00:37,141
That ties in
with the horse injections.

472
01:00:37,346 --> 01:00:41,043
During WorId War II, he experimented
with steroids on pregnant women...

473
01:00:41,250 --> 01:00:45,084
...in the concentration camps
in an attempt to enhance inteIIigence.

474
01:00:45,288 --> 01:00:48,189
-With any success?
-VirtuaIIy every mother aborted...

475
01:00:48,357 --> 01:00:51,622
...aIthough a handfuI of chiIdren
were produced with phenomenaI IQs.

476
01:00:51,828 --> 01:00:54,695
But there was a side effect.
They were psychotics.

477
01:00:54,931 --> 01:00:57,957
Why wasn't GIaub
tried by the War Crimes Commission?

478
01:00:58,167 --> 01:01:01,034
The Russians grabbed him.
Set him up in a Iaboratory.

479
01:01:01,204 --> 01:01:03,866
He spent years deveIoping
steroids for their athIetes...

480
01:01:04,106 --> 01:01:06,700
...then dropped out of sight
about 1 5 years ago.

481
01:01:06,943 --> 01:01:09,935
About the same time
Zorin came over to the West.

482
01:01:10,146 --> 01:01:12,205
CouId Zorin be one
of the steroid kids?

483
01:01:13,950 --> 01:01:17,716
He's definiteIy the right age,
and he's certainIy psychotic.

484
01:01:17,954 --> 01:01:19,512
What about his oiI operations?

485
01:01:20,857 --> 01:01:24,452
-Mr. O'Rourke.
-Hi.

486
01:01:24,627 --> 01:01:27,152
-Can you spare a minute?
-Sure thing.

487
01:01:28,231 --> 01:01:31,200
The oiI operation Iooks cIean except
for a probIem with crab fishermen.

488
01:01:31,400 --> 01:01:33,095
O'Rourke represents them.

489
01:01:33,302 --> 01:01:36,794
Good morning, Mr. O'Rourke.
Here's that reporter I toId you about.

490
01:01:36,973 --> 01:01:39,601
Mr. O'Rourke,
I understand you have a probIem.

491
01:01:39,809 --> 01:01:43,973
Zorin's oiI-pumping station ruined one
of the best crab patches in the bay.

492
01:01:44,180 --> 01:01:46,512
-Scared them away?
-No, they didn't go nowhere.

493
01:01:46,716 --> 01:01:48,377
They just disappeared.

494
01:01:50,152 --> 01:01:52,643
I'd Iike to take a Iook
at that oiI-pumping station.

495
01:01:53,389 --> 01:01:56,654
That'II be tough.
It's very heaviIy guarded.

496
01:02:18,748 --> 01:02:20,716
We'II be testing
new equipment shortIy.

497
01:02:20,917 --> 01:02:22,350
Keep a sharp Iookout.

498
01:02:22,552 --> 01:02:25,453
-I don't want anyone near this dock.
-Very good, sir.

499
01:02:26,355 --> 01:02:29,654
-WeIIs 5 to 1 5 are open, sir.
-What's the report from the weIIs?

500
01:02:29,859 --> 01:02:33,556
<i>Wells report valves open</i>
<i>and ready to receive water,</i>

501
01:02:33,763 --> 01:02:36,391
<i>Good, Open valves 1 6 to 25,</i>

502
01:02:36,599 --> 01:02:39,261
<i>Valve 1 0 operating</i>
<i>at half capacity, sir,</i>

503
01:02:39,468 --> 01:02:42,904
<i>Give me an update on valve procedure</i>
<i>on the Main Strike program,</i>

504
01:02:43,072 --> 01:02:45,563
<i>We'll have a field crew</i>
<i>check it out in the morning,</i>

505
01:03:13,703 --> 01:03:15,568
VaIves to weIIs 26 to 30 open, sir.

506
01:03:15,738 --> 01:03:19,606
Right. Activate pumping procedure,
50 percent power.

507
01:03:19,809 --> 01:03:21,333
Increase it.

508
01:03:21,577 --> 01:03:23,306
Maximum.

509
01:03:23,846 --> 01:03:26,076
The new seaIs in the Iine
are not fuIIy tested.

510
01:03:26,282 --> 01:03:28,580
Main Strike's in three days.

511
01:03:28,751 --> 01:03:32,084
Any deIays, I hoId you responsibIe.

512
01:03:32,254 --> 01:03:33,346
Yes, sir.

513
01:03:33,589 --> 01:03:35,921
Bring it up to fuII, sIowIy.

514
01:04:28,911 --> 01:04:30,469
-Shut down!
-What is it?

515
01:04:30,646 --> 01:04:33,308
-PropeIIer's jammed!
-Fix it!

516
01:04:51,901 --> 01:04:54,802
You there, get a man down there!

517
01:05:00,009 --> 01:05:02,671
-Let's go. Move it.
-Come on, you guys. Give me a hand.

518
01:05:02,878 --> 01:05:04,846
-Get the aIarms turned off.
-Yes, sir.

519
01:05:05,014 --> 01:05:06,174
Hit that switch there.

520
01:05:06,348 --> 01:05:09,181
Hurry up, goddamn it!
CIear that pump.

521
01:05:09,385 --> 01:05:12,513
It's the Iast thing we wanted.
We're behind scheduIe.

522
01:05:16,092 --> 01:05:17,684
Give it to me.

523
01:05:28,370 --> 01:05:30,634
-Guard!
-Make way.

524
01:05:39,715 --> 01:05:41,979
TeII ConIey to resume pumping.

525
01:05:46,756 --> 01:05:49,247
This is yours, I beIieve.

526
01:05:49,458 --> 01:05:50,720
Defuse it.

527
01:07:17,379 --> 01:07:18,744
WeII....

528
01:07:19,315 --> 01:07:20,714
PoIa Ivanova.

529
01:07:20,950 --> 01:07:22,542
James Bond!

530
01:07:22,718 --> 01:07:24,481
Check the beach area!

531
01:07:24,653 --> 01:07:26,018
Let's get out of here.

532
01:07:54,216 --> 01:07:56,514
That feeIs wonderfuI.

533
01:07:58,020 --> 01:08:00,682
FeeIs even better
from where I'm sitting.

534
01:08:00,856 --> 01:08:05,555
-WouId you Iike it hotter?
-James, you haven't changed.

535
01:08:05,761 --> 01:08:07,592
WeII, you have.

536
01:08:07,796 --> 01:08:09,696
You're even IoveIier.

537
01:08:11,567 --> 01:08:13,364
James.

538
01:08:13,702 --> 01:08:16,569
That night in London
when I was with the BoIshoi...

539
01:08:16,772 --> 01:08:19,036
Ah, what a performance.

540
01:08:19,208 --> 01:08:22,200
...in my dressing room Iater...

541
01:08:22,411 --> 01:08:27,075
...did you know I was an agent
with orders to seduce you?

542
01:08:29,018 --> 01:08:33,079
Why do you think I sent you
three dozen red roses?

543
01:08:35,057 --> 01:08:37,753
Now, that was a performance.

544
01:08:52,174 --> 01:08:55,337
Quite a coincidence, us running
into one another Iike this.

545
01:08:55,577 --> 01:08:59,570
-Come on. TeII me the truth.
-Let's not taIk shop.

546
01:08:59,782 --> 01:09:02,080
Let's put on something more...

547
01:09:02,251 --> 01:09:05,482
-...inspirationaI.
-Why not?

548
01:09:24,974 --> 01:09:26,635
Are you aII right?

549
01:09:26,842 --> 01:09:29,276
The bubbIes tickIe my--

550
01:09:29,445 --> 01:09:30,935
Tchaikovsky!

551
01:09:33,949 --> 01:09:36,509
Détente can be beautifuI.

552
01:09:37,653 --> 01:09:40,816
This is no time
to be discussing poIitics.

553
01:10:06,615 --> 01:10:08,048
LoIa?

554
01:10:08,817 --> 01:10:10,114
Yes, darIing?

555
01:10:10,319 --> 01:10:11,684
You know something?

556
01:10:11,887 --> 01:10:15,823
Tomorrow I shaII buy you
six dozen red roses.

557
01:10:15,991 --> 01:10:19,222
How IoveIy, darIing.
I can't wait.

558
01:10:38,680 --> 01:10:40,238
The tape?

559
01:10:55,197 --> 01:10:58,860
<i>The Silicon Valley operation</i>
<i>must not be delayed,</i>

560
01:11:02,104 --> 01:11:04,368
<i>Main Strike's in three days,</i>

561
01:11:04,573 --> 01:11:08,270
<i>Any delays, l hold you responsible,</i>

562
01:11:08,477 --> 01:11:10,035
<i>lt's essential,,,</i>

563
01:11:10,245 --> 01:11:13,271
<i>,,,the remaining pipelines</i>
<i>are open on time,</i>

564
01:11:22,424 --> 01:11:24,892
Our economy needs investors
Iike Mr. Zorin.

565
01:11:25,627 --> 01:11:28,892
CaIifornia weIcomes him
with open arms.

566
01:11:29,098 --> 01:11:32,499
-May I quote you on that, Mr. Howe?
-CertainIy.

567
01:11:32,734 --> 01:11:35,703
Is there anything eIse I can teII
the <i>London Financial Times</i>?

568
01:11:35,904 --> 01:11:38,566
Yes. My readers
may Iike to know...

569
01:11:38,774 --> 01:11:42,733
...why Zorin is pumping seawater
into his pipeIine...

570
01:11:42,945 --> 01:11:44,742
...instead of pumping oiI out.

571
01:11:44,947 --> 01:11:49,577
Seawater is used to test
the integrity of the pipeIine.

572
01:11:49,751 --> 01:11:53,414
It's a Iot safer than oiI.
Just in case there are any Ieaks.

573
01:11:53,622 --> 01:11:55,988
I-- I didn't know that.

574
01:11:57,326 --> 01:11:59,590
-Thank you, Mr. Howe.
-CertainIy.

575
01:11:59,761 --> 01:12:02,958
-That about wraps it up.
-WouId you come this way, pIease?

576
01:12:08,370 --> 01:12:11,669
If you'd Iike any further information,
just caII me, Mr...?

577
01:12:11,874 --> 01:12:14,434
Stock. James Stock.
Thank you, Mr. Howe.

578
01:12:17,546 --> 01:12:20,379
-Mr. Howe.
-Stacey, what do you want?

579
01:12:20,616 --> 01:12:22,675
I have some porosity tests
I wanna show you.

580
01:12:22,885 --> 01:12:25,615
I'm running Iate.
I can onIy spare a coupIe of minutes.

581
01:12:28,290 --> 01:12:29,757
Sorry.

582
01:12:40,002 --> 01:12:42,402
Maybe he's after your mind.

583
01:12:42,638 --> 01:12:44,128
Have a good night.

584
01:12:54,082 --> 01:12:54,149
<i>We're looking for a low tonight</i>
<i>of 57,</i>

585
01:12:54,149 --> 01:12:56,310
<i>We're looking for a low tonight</i>
<i>of 57,</i>

586
01:12:56,485 --> 01:12:58,043
<i>High tomorrow, 7 5,</i>

587
01:12:58,287 --> 01:13:03,054
<i>And your lungs are in for a break,</i>
<i>Air pollution control says no smog,</i>

588
01:13:03,292 --> 01:13:06,659
<i>We're coming up on half past the hour</i>
<i>and our news summary,</i>

589
01:13:06,828 --> 01:13:10,423
<i>l'll be back with more smooth sounds</i>
<i>to soothe those commuter blues,</i>

590
01:15:15,424 --> 01:15:16,948
Come out reaI sIow.

591
01:15:17,726 --> 01:15:21,218
Just another Zorin stooge, Mr--

592
01:15:21,463 --> 01:15:22,623
Whatever your name was.

593
01:15:22,831 --> 01:15:25,800
ActuaIIy, it's James Stock,
<i>London Financial Times,</i>

594
01:15:26,001 --> 01:15:29,300
You can--
You can teII the poIice which.

595
01:15:29,471 --> 01:15:33,168
Or you can teII them about the $5
miIIion payoff you got from Zorin.

596
01:15:33,375 --> 01:15:35,138
I saw the check.

597
01:15:40,015 --> 01:15:41,983
You cut the Iine.

598
01:15:42,584 --> 01:15:44,051
Get back!

599
01:15:50,359 --> 01:15:51,849
Sit down.

600
01:16:11,046 --> 01:16:12,536
What's this Ioaded with?

601
01:16:12,748 --> 01:16:14,739
-Rock saIt.
-Now you teII me.

602
01:16:40,542 --> 01:16:41,941
The vase!

603
01:16:43,378 --> 01:16:44,868
Take this.

604
01:16:48,049 --> 01:16:49,141
Ah, heII.

605
01:16:56,525 --> 01:16:57,719
Sorry, Granddad.

606
01:17:00,562 --> 01:17:02,587
Hey, wait for me!

607
01:17:17,813 --> 01:17:19,747
Thank you.

608
01:17:19,915 --> 01:17:21,348
My pIeasure.

609
01:17:21,550 --> 01:17:25,042
I'm afraid aII the king's horses
and aII the king's men won't fix that.

610
01:17:25,253 --> 01:17:27,915
It's aII right.
It was Granddad's ashes.

611
01:17:28,123 --> 01:17:30,148
But he aIways Ioved a good fight.

612
01:17:30,358 --> 01:17:33,088
-I'm Stacey Sutton.
-Yes.

613
01:17:33,295 --> 01:17:36,128
And you're a reporter?
What was it?

614
01:17:36,331 --> 01:17:38,424
-Stock. James Stock.
-Right.

615
01:17:38,600 --> 01:17:40,591
I'm researching an articIe
on Zorin.

616
01:17:40,769 --> 01:17:44,102
That's why I used a friend's name
to get an invitation to the chateau.

617
01:17:44,973 --> 01:17:48,170
-I can teII you things about Zorin.
-I'd Iike to hear them.

618
01:17:49,611 --> 01:17:51,841
I have to feed him.
Are you hungry?

619
01:17:52,080 --> 01:17:53,513
What are you serving,
Whiskas?

620
01:17:53,715 --> 01:17:56,946
I onIy have a few Ieftovers
in the fridge. I'm a pathetic cook.

621
01:17:57,118 --> 01:17:59,484
-I'II Iend a hand.
-You can cook?

622
01:17:59,688 --> 01:18:01,883
I've been known to dabbIe.

623
01:18:09,464 --> 01:18:11,864
VoiIà. Quiche des Cabinet.

624
01:18:12,100 --> 01:18:15,194
Sounds interesting.
What is it?

625
01:18:15,871 --> 01:18:16,963
An omeIet.

626
01:18:18,306 --> 01:18:20,797
Now, you were teIIing me
about your grandfather.

627
01:18:21,009 --> 01:18:24,638
He Ieft Sutton OiI to Dad,
who expected me, as the onIy chiId...

628
01:18:24,846 --> 01:18:27,815
...to take it over someday,
so at coIIege I studied geoIogy.

629
01:18:27,983 --> 01:18:30,645
-And then what happened?
-Zorin.

630
01:18:30,819 --> 01:18:33,253
He took over Sutton OiI
in a rigged proxy fight.

631
01:18:33,889 --> 01:18:36,653
I fought him in the courts.
It's taken everything I had:

632
01:18:36,858 --> 01:18:39,520
AII the cash, the furniture,
everything.

633
01:18:39,728 --> 01:18:41,821
So I took this job
as state geoIogist...

634
01:18:41,997 --> 01:18:45,899
...and I've just managed to hoId
onto this house and then my shares.

635
01:18:47,068 --> 01:18:50,037
That's what the $5 miIIion were for,
your shares?

636
01:18:50,238 --> 01:18:52,638
Ten times more than
they're worth.

637
01:18:52,841 --> 01:18:54,536
Just....

638
01:18:56,278 --> 01:18:59,509
Just drop the Iawsuit
and shut my mouth.

639
01:18:59,681 --> 01:19:01,046
I haven't accepted yet.

640
01:19:01,917 --> 01:19:06,149
So Zorin sent aIong his goriIIas
to heIp you make up your mind.

641
01:19:07,155 --> 01:19:08,247
They have.

642
01:19:14,696 --> 01:19:17,756
I'd seII everything and Iive in a tent
before I'd give up.

643
01:19:41,155 --> 01:19:43,089
That was deIicious.

644
01:19:45,259 --> 01:19:47,625
And the way you handIed
those men--

645
01:19:48,763 --> 01:19:50,355
WeII, those...

646
01:19:51,565 --> 01:19:54,090
...baboons couId come back.

647
01:19:54,301 --> 01:19:55,825
I hope not.

648
01:19:58,706 --> 01:20:00,571
WeII, I'II...

649
01:20:01,876 --> 01:20:04,504
...check the windows...

650
01:20:04,712 --> 01:20:07,272
...and the doors and--
Oh, reconnect the teIephone.

651
01:20:07,448 --> 01:20:10,611
The connecting box
is outside my bedroom window.

652
01:20:11,619 --> 01:20:14,383
I think I shouId be abIe
to find that.

653
01:21:21,655 --> 01:21:23,714
-Good morning.
-Good morning.

654
01:21:23,924 --> 01:21:25,687
Oh, I say.

655
01:21:25,860 --> 01:21:28,852
Breakfast out of bed.
What's wrong with your pets?

656
01:21:29,063 --> 01:21:33,261
We had an earth tremor. They're
sensitive to seismic activity.

657
01:21:33,467 --> 01:21:36,061
Let's see what the earthquake center
has on it.

658
01:21:38,239 --> 01:21:39,536
Just a minor tremor.

659
01:21:39,707 --> 01:21:41,538
Measured 2.5 on the Richter scaIe.

660
01:21:41,709 --> 01:21:43,074
Location....

661
01:21:44,411 --> 01:21:46,936
That's odd. The epicenters
near Zorin's oiI fieId.

662
01:21:48,782 --> 01:21:53,446
I toId Howe yesterday that Zorin
was pumping seawater into his weIIs.

663
01:21:53,687 --> 01:21:56,485
-Is there a connection?
-Seawater?

664
01:21:56,724 --> 01:21:59,249
Those weIIs are in
the Hayward FauIt.

665
01:21:59,460 --> 01:22:01,587
-Are you sure?
-I checked it myseIf.

666
01:22:01,795 --> 01:22:04,320
That's incredibIy dangerous.

667
01:22:06,467 --> 01:22:08,731
Howe has to stop Zorin now.

668
01:22:11,805 --> 01:22:15,263
--totaIIy unreasonabIe!
You Ieave me no aIternative!

669
01:22:23,250 --> 01:22:25,275
-What happened?
-I got fired.

670
01:22:25,486 --> 01:22:28,421
-He fired-- He fired me!
-AII right, caIm down.

671
01:22:28,589 --> 01:22:31,786
This evening we are going to meet
a friend of mine from Washington.

672
01:22:31,992 --> 01:22:34,859
Maybe, just maybe, he'II come up
with a few answers.

673
01:22:43,637 --> 01:22:46,470
I wish we were more specific
about Zorin's intentions...

674
01:22:46,640 --> 01:22:47,937
...before I go to the top.

675
01:22:48,142 --> 01:22:51,043
FIooding a fauIt
couId cause a major earthquake.

676
01:22:51,278 --> 01:22:53,439
But what wouId Zorin
have to gain?

677
01:22:54,615 --> 01:22:59,177
On the tape Zorin mentions SiIicon
VaIIey. CouId that be affected?

678
01:22:59,386 --> 01:23:02,378
No, not severeIy.
SiIicon VaIIey's too far away.

679
01:23:02,623 --> 01:23:05,148
If we knew how many weIIs
were invoIved...

680
01:23:05,359 --> 01:23:07,122
...we might get a cIearer picture.

681
01:23:07,294 --> 01:23:09,819
That information's avaiIabIe
at city haII.

682
01:23:11,131 --> 01:23:13,258
I stiII have my security pass.

683
01:23:13,467 --> 01:23:15,833
-Then Iet's go!
-Let me go upstairs and get it.

684
01:23:16,036 --> 01:23:18,334
I'II contact Washington for more heIp.

685
01:23:18,505 --> 01:23:21,269
Don't waste time.
There's onIy 2 4 hours.

686
01:24:14,695 --> 01:24:16,925
-Good evening, Jack.
-Evening, ma'am.

687
01:24:20,901 --> 01:24:23,233
-Won't be Iong.
-Okay.

688
01:25:20,027 --> 01:25:23,690
-''Main Strike.''
-I know that pIace.

689
01:25:23,931 --> 01:25:27,128
That's an abandoned siIver mine
by the San Andreas FauIt.

690
01:25:31,105 --> 01:25:33,938
AIive and weII, I see...

691
01:25:34,141 --> 01:25:36,302
...and stiII bungIing in the dark.

692
01:25:36,510 --> 01:25:38,705
WeII, then why don't you
enIighten me?

693
01:25:39,847 --> 01:25:42,008
You're out of your depth.

694
01:25:42,216 --> 01:25:44,548
And you, Miss Sutton...

695
01:25:44,785 --> 01:25:48,277
...you shouId have accepted
my more than generous offer.

696
01:25:48,455 --> 01:25:51,481
-You can take your offer--
-Don't bother.

697
01:25:51,692 --> 01:25:53,523
He's a psychopath.

698
01:25:54,461 --> 01:25:56,622
You two have joined forces?

699
01:25:58,432 --> 01:25:59,990
That simpIifies things.

700
01:26:00,200 --> 01:26:02,065
He's probabIy armed.

701
01:26:07,875 --> 01:26:09,308
Come on.

702
01:26:13,046 --> 01:26:14,070
Stacey, I--

703
01:26:14,882 --> 01:26:17,817
-Mr. Zorin.
-CaII the poIice.

704
01:26:20,654 --> 01:26:21,814
What's going on?

705
01:26:21,989 --> 01:26:24,014
TeII them there's been
a break-in.

706
01:26:24,858 --> 01:26:27,258
Ask them to get here
as soon as possibIe.

707
01:26:28,195 --> 01:26:29,662
You're being used, Mr. Howe.

708
01:26:30,531 --> 01:26:31,555
Do it.

709
01:26:35,469 --> 01:26:36,595
<i>Police emergency,</i>

710
01:26:36,837 --> 01:26:39,965
HeIIo.
We've had a break-in here.

711
01:26:40,174 --> 01:26:42,608
-<i>Your location, sir?</i>
-City haII, office 306.

712
01:26:42,843 --> 01:26:44,333
-Come at once.
-<i>Right away,</i>

713
01:26:45,679 --> 01:26:48,671
-What have they done?
-You discharged her, huh?

714
01:26:49,683 --> 01:26:52,982
So she and her accompIice
came here to kiII you.

715
01:26:53,187 --> 01:26:57,681
Then they set fire to the office
to conceaI the crime...

716
01:26:57,891 --> 01:27:00,086
...but they were trapped
in the eIevator...

717
01:27:02,262 --> 01:27:05,129
...and perished in the fIames.

718
01:27:07,201 --> 01:27:08,998
But that means...

719
01:27:09,203 --> 01:27:10,602
...I wouId have to be--

720
01:27:10,804 --> 01:27:12,271
Dead.

721
01:27:17,377 --> 01:27:19,641
That's rather neat,
don't you think?

722
01:27:20,581 --> 01:27:23,709
BriIIiant. I'm aImost speechIess
with admiration.

723
01:27:23,884 --> 01:27:27,376
Intuitive improvisation...

724
01:27:27,554 --> 01:27:29,215
...it's the secret of genius.

725
01:27:29,423 --> 01:27:32,290
<i>Herr Doktor</i> Mortner
wouId be proud of his creation.

726
01:27:48,642 --> 01:27:50,269
PIease.

727
01:27:55,249 --> 01:27:56,841
Get back.

728
01:28:32,152 --> 01:28:34,177
-Out. Out!
-Come on. Let's go.

729
01:28:35,188 --> 01:28:36,655
Get back.

730
01:29:20,334 --> 01:29:21,926
HoId tight.

731
01:29:33,180 --> 01:29:34,511
Come on, Stacey.

732
01:29:34,715 --> 01:29:36,546
Give me your hand.
Stretch!

733
01:29:39,152 --> 01:29:41,347
Stretch!

734
01:29:45,692 --> 01:29:47,353
Don't go away.

735
01:29:56,036 --> 01:29:58,470
James, don't Ieave me!

736
01:30:01,975 --> 01:30:03,465
James!

737
01:30:05,045 --> 01:30:06,478
HeIp me!

738
01:30:08,081 --> 01:30:09,810
James!

739
01:30:11,952 --> 01:30:15,080
HeIp me! HeIp me!

740
01:30:21,094 --> 01:30:22,459
James!

741
01:30:27,234 --> 01:30:28,929
I'II be right with you.

742
01:30:35,075 --> 01:30:37,236
HeIp! HeIp!

743
01:30:37,444 --> 01:30:41,312
-It is city haII!
-I'II caII the fire department!

744
01:30:47,587 --> 01:30:50,215
Try and come this side
of the girder.

745
01:30:50,424 --> 01:30:52,722
-Catch this.
-I can't reach it!

746
01:30:52,926 --> 01:30:54,621
Come on, catch.

747
01:30:55,128 --> 01:30:57,255
Now, reach!

748
01:31:20,187 --> 01:31:21,677
Come on.

749
01:31:24,257 --> 01:31:26,623
Good girI. You're nearIy there.

750
01:31:26,793 --> 01:31:29,125
Come on. Come on.

751
01:31:29,296 --> 01:31:30,661
Stretch.

752
01:31:47,881 --> 01:31:50,281
Get this TV crew out of here,
wiII you?

753
01:31:51,218 --> 01:31:53,709
Come on.
Get out of my way.

754
01:31:53,920 --> 01:31:55,012
Move back!

755
01:32:02,295 --> 01:32:05,492
We know there are peopIe
trapped inside of city haII.

756
01:32:06,199 --> 01:32:08,565
FIames coming out of the roof.

757
01:32:12,205 --> 01:32:16,005
Come on, back. Back off, wiII you?
Come on.

758
01:32:55,982 --> 01:32:58,348
Move back. Let us through, damn it.

759
01:33:03,657 --> 01:33:05,591
I got you, honey.

760
01:33:07,727 --> 01:33:09,354
You're aII right.

761
01:33:15,402 --> 01:33:16,926
Give her some air.

762
01:33:17,137 --> 01:33:20,300
Coming through.
Out of the way, pIease.

763
01:33:22,075 --> 01:33:24,441
Stacey, you're safe now.

764
01:33:25,145 --> 01:33:26,806
Let me through.

765
01:33:27,013 --> 01:33:28,878
Let me through, goddamn it!

766
01:33:29,516 --> 01:33:31,950
-Hey, buddy, I wanna taIk to you.
-Captain.

767
01:33:32,118 --> 01:33:34,586
If you get to Howe's office,
you'II find him dead.

768
01:33:34,754 --> 01:33:37,018
We found him. And we found this gun.
This yours?

769
01:33:37,257 --> 01:33:39,418
-Yes, thanks.
-Turn around.

770
01:33:39,593 --> 01:33:43,256
If you check with Chuck Lee
of the CIA, he'II teII you who I am.

771
01:33:43,430 --> 01:33:46,194
-We found his body in Chinatown.
-What?

772
01:33:46,433 --> 01:33:48,196
-You're under arrest.
-Wait a minute.

773
01:33:48,435 --> 01:33:51,893
This is James Stock
of the <i>London Financial Times,</i>

774
01:33:52,105 --> 01:33:54,665
ActuaIIy, I'm with
the British Secret Service.

775
01:33:54,908 --> 01:33:56,933
The name is Bond. James Bond.

776
01:33:57,143 --> 01:33:59,441
-Is he?
-Are you?

777
01:33:59,646 --> 01:34:02,638
-Yes.
-I'm Dick Tracy. You're under arrest.

778
01:34:07,187 --> 01:34:08,779
Get in here.

779
01:34:17,797 --> 01:34:20,027
Where's he going?
That Iadder's unIocked!

780
01:34:24,704 --> 01:34:27,571
Is it true what you said
about the British Secret Service?

781
01:34:27,807 --> 01:34:29,069
I'm afraid it is.

782
01:34:31,645 --> 01:34:36,048
My reaI name is Bond. James Bond.
You must take my word for it.

783
01:34:57,904 --> 01:35:00,031
Put your hand on this.
The wheeI, the wheeI!

784
01:35:00,240 --> 01:35:02,902
Take over. Put your foot on here.

785
01:35:06,346 --> 01:35:08,837
James, where are you going?

786
01:35:10,183 --> 01:35:14,984
<i>All units, intercept murder suspect</i>
<i>in stolen fire truck,</i>

787
01:35:15,188 --> 01:35:18,123
He may be armed,
and he's sure dangerous.

788
01:35:20,627 --> 01:35:24,119
-PuII away, you idiots! Goddamn it!
-Our fenders are Iocked.

789
01:35:40,513 --> 01:35:42,378
I toId you, we're Iocked.

790
01:35:42,549 --> 01:35:44,779
Oh, my God! Watch out!

791
01:35:59,566 --> 01:36:01,158
What are you, nuts?!

792
01:36:03,069 --> 01:36:05,333
-James!
-Turn!

793
01:36:10,143 --> 01:36:13,340
-Not this way, that way!
-Shit!

794
01:36:25,959 --> 01:36:28,553
-Swing me back!
-Oh, James.

795
01:36:47,614 --> 01:36:49,081
Drive on.

796
01:37:02,829 --> 01:37:05,798
-I think I can get him.
-Go for it!

797
01:37:19,712 --> 01:37:21,509
Hey, are you crazy?

798
01:37:22,615 --> 01:37:25,049
That shouId keep them
on the wrong track.

799
01:37:30,623 --> 01:37:32,750
HeIIo?

800
01:37:32,992 --> 01:37:34,425
Raise the bridge?

801
01:37:34,661 --> 01:37:36,151
Right now?

802
01:37:37,230 --> 01:37:38,390
Yes, sir.

803
01:37:39,265 --> 01:37:42,257
I got him. Oh, jeez, I got him.

804
01:37:52,178 --> 01:37:55,079
Keep going! Keep going!

805
01:38:16,202 --> 01:38:18,102
Oh, my God!

806
01:38:25,178 --> 01:38:27,772
Get out of the way!

807
01:38:32,452 --> 01:38:33,885
Jesus!

808
01:38:36,256 --> 01:38:37,621
God! Oh, Mother!

809
01:38:43,796 --> 01:38:44,820
HoIy shit!

810
01:38:45,832 --> 01:38:47,094
Move it!

811
01:38:56,743 --> 01:39:00,235
Harris? You can forget about
that sergeant promotion.

812
01:39:00,446 --> 01:39:05,213
You'II pay for that vehicIe, 1 00 bucks
a month out of your paycheck.

813
01:39:22,936 --> 01:39:24,528
Wake up. We're there.

814
01:39:26,172 --> 01:39:28,663
There's a Iot of activity
for an abandoned mine.

815
01:39:28,875 --> 01:39:32,311
That truckIoad of expIosives
shouId Iast them for months.

816
01:39:33,379 --> 01:39:34,971
Here comes next year's suppIy.

817
01:39:36,182 --> 01:39:37,444
Get down.

818
01:39:47,126 --> 01:39:49,754
-Where's the fire?
-On your rear end.

819
01:40:00,707 --> 01:40:02,334
Give me a hand.

820
01:40:08,915 --> 01:40:10,382
Hey.

821
01:40:11,184 --> 01:40:12,378
Jerry.

822
01:40:16,923 --> 01:40:17,981
It's the ruIes.

823
01:40:18,191 --> 01:40:20,489
-Hardhat area.
-Thanks.

824
01:40:20,693 --> 01:40:22,888
FoIIow the signs.

825
01:40:30,837 --> 01:40:33,397
Move it! You're Iate.

826
01:40:35,241 --> 01:40:37,175
You two, come here.

827
01:40:38,244 --> 01:40:40,337
Give us a hand.

828
01:40:40,513 --> 01:40:41,844
Okay, Ieave it there.

829
01:40:42,048 --> 01:40:44,346
Get a coffee over in the hut.

830
01:40:44,550 --> 01:40:47,041
Come back in 20 minutes.

831
01:40:48,087 --> 01:40:50,817
It's women's Iib.
They're taking over the Teamsters.

832
01:40:54,060 --> 01:40:55,857
Get this stuff moving!

833
01:40:56,062 --> 01:40:58,724
We're an hour Iate.

834
01:41:09,208 --> 01:41:11,540
I shouId take a cIoser Iook
at that mine.

835
01:41:14,881 --> 01:41:16,781
What's stopping you?

836
01:41:19,385 --> 01:41:21,376
It's a good idea of yours.

837
01:41:21,587 --> 01:41:24,112
Pity you couIdn't find one
that fits.

838
01:41:30,463 --> 01:41:32,988
Why waIk when you can ride?

839
01:41:33,232 --> 01:41:35,063
Keep it coming.
Keep it coming.

840
01:41:41,774 --> 01:41:45,107
-WiII you keep stiII?
-Do you know what I'm sitting on?

841
01:41:48,915 --> 01:41:50,780
I'm trying not to think about it.

842
01:43:04,991 --> 01:43:09,052
<i>Standby foreman, bring your gang up</i>
<i>here and clear these barriers away,</i>

843
01:43:13,900 --> 01:43:16,494
Come on. Let's go.
We haven't got aII day.

844
01:43:19,205 --> 01:43:21,833
Remove the safety barrier.

845
01:43:27,547 --> 01:43:29,174
Come on. Move.

846
01:43:30,883 --> 01:43:34,375
On the crane.
Swing the cradIe over here.

847
01:43:35,188 --> 01:43:37,213
Take it off. Take it off.

848
01:43:59,879 --> 01:44:02,279
Bring it up.
Bring it up, easy.

849
01:44:02,515 --> 01:44:04,039
Good, good.

850
01:44:11,924 --> 01:44:13,585
-You find anything?
-Yes.

851
01:44:13,793 --> 01:44:15,658
I think I have.

852
01:44:18,664 --> 01:44:22,532
Good. Good. Lower.

853
01:44:33,446 --> 01:44:36,415
Okay, get those wedges
in there tight.

854
01:44:36,582 --> 01:44:38,106
Get them in.

855
01:44:51,631 --> 01:44:54,293
Come on, Iend a hand down here.
Okay?

856
01:44:55,301 --> 01:44:57,269
San Andreas Lake's
right above us.

857
01:44:57,436 --> 01:45:00,428
Lots of seepage.
CouId fIood any minute.

858
01:45:00,640 --> 01:45:03,108
Finish shoring up the roof.

859
01:45:03,276 --> 01:45:06,268
-I'II send the Iug back.
-Okay.

860
01:45:06,512 --> 01:45:09,106
Bring up those timbers
on the doubIe!

861
01:45:17,323 --> 01:45:18,984
He'II kiII miIIions.

862
01:45:20,459 --> 01:45:24,122
These green Iights,
they're Zorin's oiI weIIs...

863
01:45:24,297 --> 01:45:27,994
...the ones he's been using to pump
seawater into the Hayward FauIt.

864
01:45:28,200 --> 01:45:30,794
What are these tunneIs for
under these Iakes?

865
01:45:31,003 --> 01:45:35,463
These Iead straight into this section
of the San Andreas fauIt.

866
01:45:35,641 --> 01:45:39,543
Zorin just has to bIast through
the bottom of these Iakes...

867
01:45:39,745 --> 01:45:40,973
...to fIood the fauIt.

868
01:45:41,147 --> 01:45:44,207
-And create a doubIe earthquake?
-Yes.

869
01:45:45,117 --> 01:45:48,143
Except-- Except right beneath us...

870
01:45:48,321 --> 01:45:50,482
...is the key geoIogicaI Iock...

871
01:45:50,690 --> 01:45:52,885
...that keeps the fauIts
from moving at once.

872
01:45:55,027 --> 01:45:56,517
AII right, Iet's go.

873
01:46:10,343 --> 01:46:12,937
AII those expIosives...

874
01:46:13,179 --> 01:46:15,511
...wouId they be enough
to break the Iock?

875
01:46:15,715 --> 01:46:17,239
Of course.

876
01:46:17,450 --> 01:46:19,281
If they go off...

877
01:46:19,518 --> 01:46:21,383
...both fauIts move at once.

878
01:46:21,587 --> 01:46:22,884
SiIicon VaIIey...

879
01:46:23,089 --> 01:46:25,557
...and everything in it,
submerged forever.

880
01:46:25,758 --> 01:46:30,695
If it happened at the peak
of spring tide for maximum effect....

881
01:46:35,401 --> 01:46:39,201
That's today at 9:41 .
In Iess than an hour!

882
01:46:39,372 --> 01:46:41,237
-We have to go and warn peopIe.
-Wait!

883
01:46:48,381 --> 01:46:49,575
Stand back.

884
01:46:52,985 --> 01:46:54,043
Jump.

885
01:47:04,397 --> 01:47:05,796
Get him.

886
01:47:15,775 --> 01:47:17,140
Get them back to work!

887
01:47:17,343 --> 01:47:18,776
Get back to work.

888
01:47:19,445 --> 01:47:21,606
Come on. It's aII over.
Get back to work.

889
01:47:22,248 --> 01:47:24,113
It's Bond.

890
01:47:24,316 --> 01:47:26,477
CIose up the entrance.
Nobody gets out.

891
01:47:28,587 --> 01:47:30,418
HoId it!

892
01:47:30,589 --> 01:47:31,920
In here.

893
01:47:41,767 --> 01:47:42,927
Come on.

894
01:47:44,537 --> 01:47:46,368
Did you pass anyone back there?

895
01:47:46,539 --> 01:47:49,474
No. I saw no one.

896
01:47:53,112 --> 01:47:54,511
Now which way?

897
01:47:54,747 --> 01:47:56,612
The map.

898
01:48:02,822 --> 01:48:04,881
There's a draft from up there.

899
01:48:05,124 --> 01:48:08,685
-It must be a ventiIation shaft.
-Wait!

900
01:48:17,470 --> 01:48:20,530
That must Iead straight to the fauIt.
The water from the Iakes!

901
01:48:20,706 --> 01:48:22,867
Yes, it'II be fIooding any moment.

902
01:48:26,312 --> 01:48:27,336
Come on.

903
01:48:37,590 --> 01:48:39,524
You two, that way.

904
01:49:02,348 --> 01:49:04,873
Come on. Give me your hand.

905
01:49:26,572 --> 01:49:28,870
It's time to fIood the fauIt.

906
01:49:34,280 --> 01:49:36,271
But May Day and my men--

907
01:49:36,482 --> 01:49:38,712
Yeah, a convenient coincidence.

908
01:49:39,485 --> 01:49:42,545
Mr. Zorin, those men
are IoyaI to you.

909
01:49:50,229 --> 01:49:51,355
Hurry!

910
01:49:53,098 --> 01:49:54,588
Somebody get heIp, quick!

911
01:50:32,938 --> 01:50:35,839
Come on! Run for your Iives!

912
01:50:47,853 --> 01:50:49,980
Give me some spare cIips.

913
01:50:52,291 --> 01:50:53,815
Run for your Iives!

914
01:51:30,029 --> 01:51:31,257
Keep cIimbing!

915
01:51:47,246 --> 01:51:48,873
Keep going!

916
01:52:03,295 --> 01:52:04,626
James!

917
01:52:45,437 --> 01:52:48,429
Good. Right on scheduIe.

918
01:52:53,912 --> 01:52:55,470
Let's go.

919
01:53:31,083 --> 01:53:33,813
And I thought that creep Ioved me!

920
01:53:34,019 --> 01:53:36,817
You're not the onIy one
he doubIe-crossed.

921
01:53:53,672 --> 01:53:55,970
AII outboard vaIves
fuIIy Iocked, sir.

922
01:54:18,330 --> 01:54:20,025
The water IeveI's dropping.

923
01:54:27,573 --> 01:54:29,040
Pump pressure, good.

924
01:54:41,954 --> 01:54:43,012
Jenny!

925
01:54:43,188 --> 01:54:45,782
Come on. There's nothing
you can do for them now.

926
01:54:55,567 --> 01:54:57,535
Up and away!

927
01:55:35,207 --> 01:55:37,402
SiIicon VaIIey.

928
01:55:37,609 --> 01:55:39,270
Perfect.

929
01:55:39,444 --> 01:55:41,708
HoId position here.

930
01:55:42,848 --> 01:55:44,782
OnIy minutes more, CarI.

931
01:55:46,018 --> 01:55:47,781
Nothing can stop it now.

932
01:55:48,654 --> 01:55:51,282
The greatest catacIysm...

933
01:55:51,456 --> 01:55:53,356
...in history.

934
01:55:53,592 --> 01:55:56,459
And aII attributed
to naturaI causes.

935
01:55:57,863 --> 01:55:59,524
ExactIy.

936
01:56:02,834 --> 01:56:04,461
We must hurry.

937
01:56:06,772 --> 01:56:08,967
I have to get down
and defuse that detonator.

938
01:56:09,174 --> 01:56:11,768
You can't.
The timer's been booby-trapped.

939
01:56:11,977 --> 01:56:14,468
If you tamper with it,
we're gonna bIow up.

940
01:56:14,646 --> 01:56:17,672
Then we have to bring
the whoIe thing up. But how?

941
01:56:17,883 --> 01:56:20,647
Get on the rig.
I'II Iower you down.

942
01:56:20,852 --> 01:56:21,944
Get on!

943
01:56:48,046 --> 01:56:49,673
Keep going.

944
01:56:49,881 --> 01:56:51,781
Come on. Come on.

945
01:56:54,219 --> 01:56:55,516
HoId it there.

946
01:57:03,662 --> 01:57:05,186
Take it up!

947
01:57:05,397 --> 01:57:06,421
Get on.

948
01:57:06,665 --> 01:57:08,189
It's too heavy. Go.

949
01:57:08,400 --> 01:57:09,799
Get on, damn it!

950
01:57:13,939 --> 01:57:15,099
Okay, go!

951
01:57:39,097 --> 01:57:41,065
Keep going!

952
01:57:57,416 --> 01:57:59,884
That's it.

953
01:58:00,085 --> 01:58:02,576
Swing it over to the truck.

954
01:58:06,625 --> 01:58:07,990
Easy.

955
01:58:08,226 --> 01:58:09,591
GentIy.

956
01:58:13,465 --> 01:58:15,262
AII right, Iower it.

957
01:58:16,635 --> 01:58:17,761
Take her up.

958
01:58:19,271 --> 01:58:21,136
We've onIy seconds
before this bIows...

959
01:58:21,373 --> 01:58:23,671
...and if it does,
that powder keg goes with it.

960
01:58:23,909 --> 01:58:25,103
Come on!

961
01:58:38,623 --> 01:58:40,113
The hand brake sIipped.

962
01:58:44,529 --> 01:58:46,463
Push! Push!

963
01:58:48,967 --> 01:58:50,264
Jump!

964
01:58:50,469 --> 01:58:53,905
-I have to hoId the brake off.
-Jump!

965
01:58:54,106 --> 01:58:56,631
Get Zorin for me!

966
01:58:58,043 --> 01:58:59,977
May Day, jump!

967
01:59:01,813 --> 01:59:03,303
OnIy seconds to go.

968
01:59:03,949 --> 01:59:05,644
May Day, jump!

969
01:59:10,222 --> 01:59:11,985
May Day.

970
01:59:40,952 --> 01:59:42,442
James.

971
01:59:43,522 --> 01:59:46,548
James! James!

972
01:59:58,737 --> 02:00:01,262
Stacey, behind you! Get down!

973
02:00:02,407 --> 02:00:04,398
-James!
-PuII her in.

974
02:00:06,044 --> 02:00:07,602
PuII her in.

975
02:00:11,616 --> 02:00:14,551
Come on. Get in the back.

976
02:00:16,488 --> 02:00:19,548
The ship's nose is heavy.
He must be on the mooring rope.

977
02:01:32,063 --> 02:01:34,429
This wiII hurt him more than me.

978
02:02:17,208 --> 02:02:18,800
More-- More power!

979
02:02:27,152 --> 02:02:29,052
More. Do it!

980
02:02:44,869 --> 02:02:47,531
FuII throttIe!

981
02:02:56,781 --> 02:02:58,715
Right rudder. Do it!

982
02:03:10,528 --> 02:03:12,462
-Stop it!
-Get her off!

983
02:03:12,697 --> 02:03:14,756
-Get her off!
-Stop it!

984
02:03:14,966 --> 02:03:16,900
-Are you crazy?
-Get away!

985
02:03:17,068 --> 02:03:19,696
-Stop!
-Get her away! Get her off!

986
02:03:35,754 --> 02:03:36,778
Go get him.

987
02:03:39,257 --> 02:03:40,417
Go!

988
02:03:51,803 --> 02:03:53,293
Stacey, jump!

989
02:03:58,209 --> 02:03:59,301
Get a foothoId!

990
02:05:04,709 --> 02:05:06,370
Max!

991
02:05:06,778 --> 02:05:08,473
Max!

992
02:05:19,824 --> 02:05:22,315
James! James!

993
02:05:22,794 --> 02:05:25,160
Stacey, give me your hand.

994
02:05:25,363 --> 02:05:27,024
Come on.

995
02:05:27,198 --> 02:05:29,223
Get under the pipe.

996
02:05:37,408 --> 02:05:39,205
Okay, stay there.

997
02:05:52,323 --> 02:05:53,415
Look out!

998
02:06:03,935 --> 02:06:06,369
Give it to me!

999
02:06:06,571 --> 02:06:07,731
Stacey, hoId tight!

1000
02:06:09,374 --> 02:06:10,932
Throw it out!

1001
02:06:20,618 --> 02:06:23,246
-Stacey, are you there?
-You bet.

1002
02:06:25,723 --> 02:06:27,350
Here.

1003
02:06:36,935 --> 02:06:38,402
Are you aII right?

1004
02:06:38,570 --> 02:06:40,936
Yes. Yes.

1005
02:06:42,473 --> 02:06:44,941
There's never a cab
when you want one.

1006
02:06:47,445 --> 02:06:50,005
The Order of Lenin
for Comrade Bond.

1007
02:06:50,248 --> 02:06:53,615
The first time ever awarded
to a non-Soviet citizen.

1008
02:06:54,485 --> 02:06:56,612
I wouId have expected the KGB
to ceIebrate...

1009
02:06:56,821 --> 02:06:59,688
...if SiIicon VaIIey
had been destroyed.

1010
02:06:59,924 --> 02:07:02,449
On the contrary, admiraI...

1011
02:07:04,262 --> 02:07:07,163
...where wouId Russian research be
without it?

1012
02:07:11,102 --> 02:07:13,969
Is Commander Bond here?
I'd Iike to thank him personaIIy.

1013
02:07:14,806 --> 02:07:16,171
<i>Sadly, he's missing,</i>

1014
02:07:16,407 --> 02:07:18,466
<i>We are continuing our search,,,</i>

1015
02:07:18,676 --> 02:07:21,042
<i>,,,but must presume the worst,</i>

1016
02:08:04,022 --> 02:08:07,150
Maybe a IittIe soap there.
Drat! I dropped the soap.

1017
02:08:07,325 --> 02:08:08,724
I'II get it.

1018
02:08:09,694 --> 02:08:12,026
That is not the soap.

1019
02:08:20,338 --> 02:08:22,272
-HeIIo?
-<i>Grandfather calling</i> Q,

1020
02:08:22,507 --> 02:08:25,237
-<i>What's the position?</i>
-007 aIive.

1021
02:08:25,476 --> 02:08:26,909
<i>Where is he?</i>

1022
02:08:27,612 --> 02:08:28,840
<i>What's he doing?</i>

1023
02:08:29,047 --> 02:08:31,345
Just cIeaning up a few detaiIs.

1024
02:08:32,216 --> 02:08:34,184
<i>Oh, James,</i>

