WOMAN: (WHISPERING)
I'm doing this
because I love you.
You know what happened.
This is what
you'll turn into.
(IN A GRUFF VOICE)
Don't talk to anyone.
(STERNLY) I warn you.
Don't move a muscle
unless I tell you to.
(STERNLY)
Don't talk to anyone.
(YELLING) Why would you
keep things from me?
(STERNLY) John!
Look at me. Look at me, John.
Look at me.
Don't look at me
unless I tell you to.
(AGITATEDLY) Don't talk to
anyone. Don't talk to
anyone. John, why would you...
(VOICES OVERLAPPING)
(CHILD CRYING AGITATEDLY)
WOMAN: (QUIETLY)
I don't love you anymore.
(TRAIN RATTLING)
TED: (ON RADIO)
How many times do
the people of Nebraska
have to be
embarrassed by the man
that represents it?
NEWSREADER: That was
challenger Ted Johnson
responding to
the latest scandal
to rock the highly
contested Senate race
between he and
incumbent senator
Jackson Wyatt.
Wyatt has been photographed
with yet another woman
that is not his wife.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(VOICES CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE)
(BUS DRIVES AWAY)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(SIGHING)
Good morning,
Mr. French.
Good morning
.
Thank you, sir.
John, Mr. Crill's election
celebration's today.
I've taken
the liberty of cutting
some flowers from my garden
.
for all the men to
wear on their lapels
Mmm-hmm.
.
Have all this
finished by 3:00
You're probably
going to have
to skip lunch.
Okay?
Paycheck for you
.
Oh. Hmm.
I don't know why she didn't
make one of her girls
make this.
I know. It's ridiculous.
Fanny's just
promoting her shelter.
I can't believe
she's throwing
him another party.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: Girls, once you're
done with that thing...
.
And keep the
candy in a..
A separate bag, John?
Mmm-hmm.
Baseball cards, too?
Yes. Yes, please.
Five packs.
(CASH REGISTER DINGS)
LOUISE: Hello, John.
Hello.
It's always nice to see a friendly face.
Hello, Mrs. Sternberg.
Louise. Call me Louise.
Okay, Mrs. Sternberg.
Must get lonely
in that house.
You should come
over to dinner.
I make a wonderful
pot roast.
Well, excuse me.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHING)
(TRAIN CONTINUES RATTLING)
(LOUD CRASHING)
(MUFFLED VOICES)
Ron, should someone
call Dr. Elkins?
Can you move your
fingers and toes?
No, no, no.
I'll stay right here.
We thought
you were a goner.
MAN: You're lucky to be alive.
RON: Can everyone please step back?
MAN 1: Who is she?
MAN 2: I didn't know John had a wife.
You afraid?
Kyle, why don't you run inside
to the kitchen?
I don't mean to be rude,
but how do you know John?
Are you family?
I live here.
(VOICES CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
John! John!
You okay?
Another 10 feet, your house
would've been a goner.
Is your lady
friend okay?
My breakfast
is getting cold.
John?
Hey, John.
JOHN: Officer.
We just heard
about the train.
Is everything...
I'm... I'm supposed
to go to work now.
John, I heard
about the train.
Good morning
, Mr. French.
Was there
a woman there?
Thank you.
Was there a woman
in your house? I mean...
I heard about the train.
I really need to
get this work done.
There he is, John Skillpa.
Talk of the town.
Morning, Mr. Crill.
Good morning, Doris.
So a train bucks the rail,
winds up in your backyard
and you still come to work?
Yes, sir.
Well, I had to.
?
I've never seen
anything like that.
So what can I do for you
Day off? Remember,
we're all family here,
so take advantage.
Hello, sir.
These need to get done.
Thank you.
I don't care about the work.
And I don't think
Edmund does, either.
Of course not.
I suggested he
take the day off
as soon as he
came into work
this morning.
John, go home.
I'll just get
this one work done,
and then I'll
go home for lunch,
if that's okay
with you, sir.
Please.
Sure.
Ladies.
John, these
need to be done.
Thanks.
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
(VOICES CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE)
There you are.
Officer.
This morning on your bike,
you acted like you've
never seen me before.
John...
BOY: Superman!
Hey, kids.
Go on, get down
from there. Go on.
I knocked on your door
this morning to check
on the young lady
you got staying
with you.
Nobody answered.
Mmm-hmm.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Some of the women
tell me
she's your wife.
Nobody knew
you got married.
Congratulations.
John, I'm really
happy for you.
I just need everything back
to how it was before.
Have you even
called anybody?
Umm. No, sir.
All right.
Listen here.
When your mother died,
I showed you what to do,
who to call, what papers
need to be filled out,
and you did it.
Mmm-hmm.
That's exactly what
you got to do now.
Yes, sir.
There's no one here
to help you anymore,
you understand?
You need to call
the train company
and tell them
exactly what you want.
Okay?
Yes, sir.
CLAPP: Mr. Skillpa,
first I want to apologize
for any inconvenience.
I've spoken to Mayor Crill.
Well, thank you, Mr. Clapp.
Can you come
and get your train
out of my backyard?
We're working on that,
as we speak.
The inspectors and engineers
are on their way,
but, as I said,
these things take time.
Well, I just want it gone
as soon as possible.
Officer McGonigle
told me to call.
How about tomorrow?
I could come home early
and I could get
a half day at work.
Tomorrow would
be good for me.
Listen, we're
probably gonna have to send
a team of welders down there.
Our head engineer,
Mark Huggins will have
to take a look at it.
He can't get down
there until Friday.
No sooner
than Friday?
Sir, like I said,
Mark Huggins will
be there on Friday.
Mmm-hmm.
?
You looking for this
(GASPS)
Oh, my.
I got it.
CONNOR: Come on, birdie.
FANNY: Connor, it's over there.
JOHN: (AS WOMAN) You have to
get out now. Please.
CONNOR: Come on.
Come on, birdie.
Please leave.
Connor, get ready
to close the door.
(FANNY SIGHS)
(LAUGHING)
.
I'm Connor Black
I'm senior political advisor to
Senator Jackson Wyatt.
And we're here
to see Mr. Skillpa.
Fanny Crill.
Such a pleasure to
meet you, Mrs. Skillpa.
Well, I must say,
there could be less
odd circumstances
to get acquainted.
John's not here.
Fanny.
We're here because
of that monstrosity
in your backyard.
We want to do a rally
in your backyard
using the train as a backdrop.
What?
CONNOR: That train was
part of Senator Wyatt's
Whistle Stop campaign.
The challenger, Ted Johnson,
is a real mudslinger.
He wants to use
the train as a metaphor
for my boss' political career.
To be blunt,
I need you and
your husband's help.
Have you seen this picture?
CONNOR: Ted Johnson's
gonna use this photo
to hurt our campaign.
We're only three weeks
from election day,
and we can't let him
get away with it this time.
And Connor has
been kind enough
to allow me to
organize the event.
All of Peacock will be here.
Marching band, food.
What a very
special day it will be.
You and your husband
together with the Senator.
(SIGHS)
Connor, why don't you take that outside?
You don't mind if I
have a moment alone
with Mrs. Skillpa?
Sure, sure.
I don't have
anything better to do.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHING)
I knew I should've
come alone.
You know,
I have always been so
curious about this house.
Well, have a seat.
(SIGHING)
How do you know John?
Well, my husband
owns the bank.
He's John's boss.
Ray's been
the Mayor of Peacock
for three terms now.
I guess this must all be just a
tad overwhelming, Mrs. Skillpa.
Why don't you let me explain?
I run the county
shelter for women.
We mold the modern woman.
The woman who votes.
And Wyatt is viewed
as someone who's,
well, a little insensitive
to women's needs.
And so Connor had the idea
that we would get
a bunch of my girls
together with
the Senator and take a photo
and I've agreed to it.
But that oaf has no idea
that I plan to use the rally to raise
money for my shelter.
Mrs. Crill, I need
to go upstairs.
Come on now.
Life doesn't begin
and end with housework,
and please call me Fanny.
Mrs. Skillpa,
this photo will help us
get donors for the shelter.
I don't know.
I know that the Skillpas
have a long history
of keeping to themselves.
But you're your own woman.
Remember that.
Oh. Okay, well,
it was a pleasure meeting you
and if you need anything,
just come out back
and we'll only
stay a few minutes.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(DOOR OPENING)
I have to tell Wanda.
CONNOR:
What have you
got there?
Mrs. Skillpa,
how're you feeling?
You look so much better.
.
FANNY: That is so lovely
CONNOR: Careful.
Watch yourself.
.
FANNY: John should
really fix that step
Fanny?
FANNY: Yes?
When is the shelter
clothing drive this year?
It's closer
to Christmas.
Mrs. Skillpa,
I'm sure you know all about
Fanny's work at the shelter
with displaced
women and children.
Displaced children?
Well, we've been known
to help in
the adoption process.
Find good homes
for children.
.
Well, you should
come and meet some
of my girls sometime
So, where are your kids?
Well, Mr. Black,
I don't know how you
folks do it in Lincoln,
but in Peacock,
we don't pry.
I'd love to hear you
say yes to this rally.
If it's John,
only you know the
best way to get through
to your husband.
So get through.
Understand?
It's moments like this
modern women
take advantage of,
because it's
moments like this
that put us on the map.
We ladies have
to stick together,
Mrs. Skillpa.
Oh. Emma. Please
call me Emma.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Yes, Mr. French.
.
I'm so sorry, but John
is running a little late
Yes, I'll have him
off to work in no time.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Johnny, man of the hour.
Did I do something wrong?
No, no, no, no.
Come on. Connor, this
is our guy.
John Skillpa,
meet Connor Black.
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
Hey, how about this?
That's really something,
isn't it, Johnny?
I loved meeting
your wife.
Who?
FANNY: Emma.
She's wonderful
and that house,
I can see
why your family
loved it so much.
God, you were in my house?
Connor, why don't you
explain to John
our plan for the rally?
What we'd like to do is
hold a political rally
in your backyard
using the train
as a backdrop.
The whole town
will be there.
p
Well, the train's
gonna be gone on Friday
'cause I spoke to Mr. Clap
and he said...
RAY: John.
John, hear
Mr. Black out.
Yes, sir.
Emma loved
the idea of the rally.
Your wife made us
lemonade and cookies.
She was so hospitable...
Well, she's not
the boss of me!
.
Don't speak to
my wife that way
I...
You don't know
what you're doing.
Everything just
needs to get back
to how it was before.
Mr. Clapp promised the train
would be gone on Friday,
and that's what
needs to happen.
John, I spoke
to Albert Clapp
this morning.
The train's gonna be
there a while longer.
Well, it's my house.
And I don't know
what she told you.
.
I don't know
what she told you,
but she's not the boss of me
I make the decisions
, not Emma.
.
I'm the man of the house
We know you're
the man of the
house, John.
Now, Mark Huggins
is coming to take that
train away on Friday,
and that's that.
Connor, why don't
you and I go
to Ray's office
and let him
speak to John alone?
RAY: John.
John, I wanna run
for Senate someday.
Now this could
really get me in
with the big guys, hmm?
I don't understand
how your wife can see
how big this is,
and you don't.
No one understands, sir.
John, I don't wanna hear
another word out of you.
You need to sit here
and think about this.
I can't let her do this.
MAGGIE: John?
It's me.
Jake! Come back
to Mama right now.
Is anyone home?
What do you want?
There just isn't
any easy way
to say this, John.
Jake and me, we...
We're getting
out of this town.
I need your help.
What kind of help?
Money help.
It's been almost
a year now.
I've doubled up shifts
just to keep my place.
I don't know
what else to do.
I mean, I've been
planning on getting out
of here for a while now.
You know, saving and all.
Look, I know you've got...
Why are you
asking me for money?
The checks.
I haven't got a check
in a year now.
If I could just...
What checks?
(LAUGHS)
I wasn't sending
you any checks.
Your... Your mother was.
My mother died a year ago.
I didn't know that.
What were the checks for?
.
He's two now
I... I honestly
thought you knew.
Your mama was
sending me checks as
long as I stayed away.
John, please.
John, where are
you going?
I have my own money.
Don't go.
John, I really think...
Come here, honey.
I'm so sorry.
.
I didn't realize
anyone else was home
We better be going.
I'm so sorry.
What's his name?
Jake.
Who are you?
I'm Maggie.
.
Just an old friend of John's
Why are you here?
I read in the paper
about the train and all.
I just wanted to stop by
and make sure
everything was okay.
I better be going.
I'm Emma. John's wife.
Nice to meet you.
Good night.
EMMA: Maggie.
Where's your car?
.
I let a friend borrow it
Her aunt's real sick
in Lincoln,
so Jake and I
just been doing
a lot of walking.
You don't really
own a car, do you?
I don't mean
to pry or be rude,
but where's his bed?
Why don't you let me
drive you home?
That'd be real nice.
I'm sorry,
where's John?
Oh, he's sleeping.
You ready?
Do you...
Do you drive much?
You caught me.
You don't drive?
No.
Okay. You just
use one foot.
Don't put one on the gas
and one on the brake.
Just use one foot
to go back and forth.
All right.
Just like that.
Just easy.
All right.
I think you're
ready for the open road.
Thanks for
driving me
way out here.
I'm sorry if I
caused you any trouble.
You didn't,
you didn't.
Don't be silly.
Let me help you
into the house.
Have a seat.
I'll be right out.
Here you go, sweetie.
Good night, Jakey.
Would you like a drink?
Just a little something would
be nice.
Do you like it here?
It's all I can
afford right now.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Excuse me.
I got a few bucks,
if you got a few minutes.
MAGGIE:
Not now, cupcake.
I got company.
Oh.
Okay.
Well, you know
where to find me.
Is that how you met John?
Emma, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
It's okay, Maggie.
I just want... I just want
what's better for Jake.
You know what,
I went...
I went as long as I could
without that money.
What money?
Was John sending
you money?
His mother was.
Emma, it's bad.
It's really bad.
Please, I need to know.
I won't judge you.
Please believe me
when I say that.
Um,
I met his mother
three years ago in a bar
, and she paid me.
She said it was
just to meet John.
She brought me to that house.
and she brought me...
She brought me
up those stairs,
and I thought you were her.
She was wearing this o
ld blue and white dress.
And the creaking
of that bed.
John didn't
wanna do any of it.
I swear, Emma.
r.
But I couldn't stop he
And she just
stayed in the room
the whole time.
And then I was
forced to stay.
I was so scared.
She made him do...
She made him do
horrible things.
And I'm the worst
person in the world.
(SNIFFLING)
It's okay, Maggie.
I'm sorry.
Us ladies have to
stick together, right?
(BED CREAKS)
Um, what if we
wanted to adopt Jake?
MAN: Well, you'd have to
come down for an interview
and fill out the forms.
So, John and I
would both have to
come in together?
?
Yes. Is that a problem
Well, it's just that
with John's
work schedule and all...
I understand.
You also need references.
Yes.
Could Fanny Crill
help with that?
Are they staying
at her shelter?
No. Why?
.
Well, the shelter's
very effective in
facilitating adoptions
I didn't know that.
Well, let me know
what you'd
like me to do.
Thank you.
.
"'Perhaps you
could play with me,'
Wendy said hopefully
"'I'd love to,'
sighed the wind,
bending the grasses..."
.
Good morning.
Good morning
CHILDREN: Hello.
Hello.
"The socks and the shirts,
the sheets and the petticoats,
"and Wendy's pal
e pink party dress
"
"all jiggled on
the clothesline.
FANNY:
That's the U-joint,
right there.
So that's where everything
tends to get clogged,
so what you want to
do is open that up
and drain it.
Here, Karen,
why don't you try?
Thanks, Fanny.
Well, look who
we have here.
Emma Skillpa.
Don't you look
beautiful today.
I want to do the rally.
Excuse me, girls , for a second.
I'd like to talk to Emma alone.
Maybe you could go
to the typing room
and try your hand at
that again. Thanks.
I'm so happy to see you.
Here, have some lemonade.
No, I can't.
I have to be home by 8:15.
I just really
needed to tell you
that I want to do the rally.
And I have a question
about the shelter.
What about John?
He put up quite a stink at the bank.
I don't understand.
You spoke to John?
Yesterday, and he
would have none of it.
We came to an agreement.
What changed his mind?
I did.
Terrific. This is
going to be huge news.
You have to tell Connor.
No, I can't do that.
I have to be going.
Yes, you can.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Mrs. Skillpa.
My favorite peacock.
What can I do for you?
The rally.
We'll do it.
Emma? Emma Skillpa?
You know, in a town
of only 800 people,
you're one of the
hardest people to find.
Um...
Tom McGonigle. I stopped
by the house this morning.
e.
I'm gonna need you
and John to fill out
the accident report with m
I can come by tonight.
What's a good time?
Fanny Crill, the Mayor's wife,
is waiting for me. Excuse me.
Hi, Fanny.
Morning, Mary.
Thanks for noticing.
,
You know, these gals
, they wave and they
invite me to parties
but not one of them
has ever volunteered
at my shelter.
And look at this.
Oh, my gosh,
I've got to get my
girls to paint this.
Fanny, I don't mean to
be rude, but I really
should be getting
back to the house now.
I got it.
Did you ever
meet John's mother?
No.
I don't think
many people did.
G)
(FANNY LAUGHIN
Do you have children, Fanny?
I'd rather not
talk about it.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to...
I have a son. James.
He passed away 14 years ago.
I don't know what to say.
It's okay.
Ray and I tried
for a long time,
and it finally happened
and it was wonderful.
All John and I ever wanted
was a little boy
running around our house.
Kids give you so much.
I have to get going.
Fanny, how does someone
come to stay here?
(CAR APPROACHING)
(DOOR OPENING)
MAGGIE: Emma.
You getting comfortable
driving that old car?
What are you
doing out here?
I had something I wanted to
discuss with you
if you had a moment.
Sure.
(PLATE BREAKING)
What the hell's going on?
Stupid kid!
MAGGIE: Damn it, Wade.
(JAKE CRYING)
MAGGIE: It's okay, sweetie.
You never ever
threaten a mother's
child.
WADE: Maggie,
there's dishes to do.
God, I hate all this.
You don't have
to stay here.
I know Fanny Crill.
The Mayor's wife.
You know the Mayor's wife?
She's wonderful.
And she runs
the most amazing
women's shelter.
No. No, I got
no time for that.
I mean, those places
are for people
without ambition.
I'm letting Fanny do
this rally at my house.
So she owes me.
And besides, I think
it would be good
for you and for Jake.
do
For Jake?
What good does it
putting him in a place with a bunch of
unambitious women?
Maggie, you're family.
And we need to stay close.
That's sweet of you to say that,
but I just want to get out of here.
I want a job where I
can hold my head high,
and I don't think I'm gonna find
that in Peacock.
The shelter can
help you with that.
I owe $300 in rent
on a trailer.
And Jake's
growing like a weed.
New shoes...
It's free rent and clothes
and they can help you
find a better job.
I can get you
over there tonight.
I just want a better life.
John's money
could really help me.
Maggie, you don't
need his money.
John doesn't understand
the importance of family.
Okay.
I'll try.
But if John
offers me help,
I'll take it.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
John. Hello.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm sorry I didn't
call ahead of time.
What's this?
I just wanted
to say thank you
to you and Emma for,
well, everything
you're doing.
Is she home?
I'd love to say hi.
(CAR HONKING)
Evening, John.
Don't worry about
work today.
Be sure to tell Emma
I said thank you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
All right, I don't
want to leave Ray
waiting in the car,
so just say hi
to Emma for me.
(SLAMS DOOR)
What is she doing?
(VOICES CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE)
John, will you bring your wife out?
I need the both of you
to go over everything.
Yeah, and we need to make sure
the caboose is stable enough
for the platform.
TOM: John, this has to get
filled out and signed
before you can do the rally.
You're not helping me.
Good morning, John.
We're just setting
up the grandstand.
No. No! I said no rally!
But Emma told me
yesterday it was okay.
Emma?
Get out! Get out, all of you!
Skillpa...
John, you've got to control yourself.
Just shut up!
MAN: Okay, fellas.
Let's take a break.
Okay, okay.
Get out.
You just take
a minute
and cool off.
Just calm down and fix this.
I'll swing by later.
(TRAIN RATTLING)
(MECHANICAL BUZZING)
Excuse me.
What can I do for you?
I have a caboose
in my backyard.
I have money.
How much to come
pick the train up
and get it out?
Listen, buddy.
That's private property.
The train company'll
have our hides.
I know it's illegal.
But I have money and I'll pay.
Eight hundred cash,
and I start tomorrow.
Okay.
EDMUND: John Skillpa, you're late.
Where were you yesterday?
You weren't at work all day.
Do you need help?
Did Officer McGonigle
get a hold of you?
Because he was looking for you.
I called your house several times.
Several times, John.
I know you have a lot going on,
but you or your wife
could pick up the phone.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Okay, well,
look, train or no train,
this cannot happen again.
WOMAN: Peacock State Bank.
You're going to have to skip lunch today.
WOMAN: Okay, sure.
Just one second.
EDMUND: Sit down
WOMAN: You have a phone call.
EDMUND: Who is it?
It's not for you, sir.
It's for John.
I think it's
your wife Emma.
Hello?
John, it's Maggie.
Why are you calling?
I really need to talk to you.
Where are you?
I'm at the women's shelter.
Women's shelter?
Emma brought me here.
John, I really need
to talk to you.
You met Emma?
Yes, I...
You stay right there.
I'll come to you.
May I help you?
I want to
donate these, please.
And can you get
Maggie for me,
please?
Come on in.
Just toss them o
n the chair there.
.
Maggie, you
have a guest
John?
When did she do this?
Do what?
Bring you here.
Yesterday.
(STAMPING FOOT)
No. I...
John. John, what's wrong?
I met Emma the night
I came to your house.
She gave Jake and me
a ride home.
I can't let her do this.
Maggie, you need to
stay away from Emma.
Emma's just trying
to help me and Jake.
I'll give you
the money
so you can leave.
Are you serious?
Yes. I need to
get you and Jake
out of Peacock.
It's not safe here for Jake.
.
Maggie, I can't go
back to that place
I'll give you
all the money,
all of it.
.
I've got $1,409.16
Emma doesn't know I have it.
It's at work.
But what do you mean?
What place?
You don't understand.
I can't go back home.
John, I know you've
been through a lot
in that house,
but you gotta go home.
To Emma.
o?
Where do you want to g
o.
o? I'll take you
wherever you want to g
I'll take you.
I've got family
in Madison, but...
I'll take you there.
I'll give you the money
and I'll take you to Madison
I'll take you and Jake.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm sorry if I caused trouble
for you and Emma.
She's not my wife.
John?
John, are you okay?
Please don't make me go.
I can't go home.
Are you hurt?
No.
Did you hurt somebody?
.
No, I swear I didn't
(STONE SPLASHES)
She held my head underwater.
Emma?
No. When I was a kid.
Your mother?
She's not taking
care of me anymore.
And she would
have liked Emma.
Of course.
Yeah.
I met Emma
the day Mom died.
.
John. She's gone
You know that.
Your mom is gone
Okay, buddy.
I don't want
what happened to me
to happen to anyone else.
Okay, buddy, look.
We gotta get you
home, okay?
.
John, let's
get you home
I can't go.
Well, you can't
stay out here.
(DOOR OPENING)
JOHN: No.
(CRASHING)
(RINGING DOORBELL)
Yeah
?
I need a room.
How long?
I don't know.
No, you can't do
this to me, Emma.
You can't do this to me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Good morning, ma'am. Is the man
of the house here?
Who're you?
I'm here about the train
What about it?
Your husband
hired me to remove it.
Did he?
You see your husband's name
at the bottom
of this contract?
0?
Yes.
Do you see the $80
Well, as I said before,
my husband is not
here right now...
Is Maggie with you?
No. Why?
I'm gonna be back
here tomorrow, ma'am,
at 8:30 and you
better have that $800,
or you'll be
meeting my attorney.
What is that about?
Is everything all right?
Yes, everything's
fine. Why?
Glenda called me at home
and she said that.
John took Maggie and Jake
yesterday
and they haven't come back.
Do you know anything about it?
No, I don't.
Well, one of the girls
said that
she seemed a little strange
like maybe she's lying.
I'll call Maggie at the trailer.
You don't mind?
No, I insist.
Why weren't you at the shelter
last night?
Emma, please don't be mad at me.
I just want to know
what's going on.
John came by the shelter
and he said he'd give me
what I asked for.
The money?
And he'll drive to
my aunt's in Madison.
Well, he never
discussed this with me.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to come between
you and John.
I always said
I'd take his help
if he offered it.
(SIGHS)
And I had some
good news for you.
What?
I just spoke to Fanny Crill
about getting you
a job at the bank.
And it's a very
respectable position,
and obviously the pay
is a step in
the right direction.
And we can all stay together
and be here in Peacock.
I don't know, Emma.
Emma?
(DOOR SHUTS)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello?
JOHN: Hello,
is Maggie there?
Hey, Miss Popular,
phone's for you.
Hello.
Maggie?
John?
I'm going to the bank
and then we're
going to meet tonight.
e?
You still gonna help m
Yes.
John, thank you so much.
It's important that no one knows
what's going on,
especially Emma.
Okay.
Meet me at the Husker Mote
Room 9, 11:00 sharp.
The motel?
Why the motel?
If Emma finds out about this
you'll never get the money.
Understand?
Yeah, yeah,
I understand.
11:00 sharp.
If you're one minute early
or one minute late,
you don't get the money.
Okay.
Well, hello, John.
Louise, hi.
Hi.
Excuse me, Mrs. Sternberg.
Good afternoon, John.
Why did you come
in the front door?
Emma told me how
neighborly you've been.
She's a bit frazzled
and not herself.
Not every day
a train lands
in your backyard.
John, the inbox is
rather full today.
I won't keep you,
but how about
you and Emma
taking us up on
that dinner offer?
That'd be great.
I'm sure it will be.
John, could you
follow me, please?
I have a stack
of papers for you.
Goodbye, John.
Bye.
Mr. French, what would
you do without me?
Find someone
more reliable.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
Where're you
from, cupcake?
All over, ma'am.
Not really rooted
anywhere.
My name's Cal.
My name's Maggie.
Fire!
John! John!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Emma?
Yes?
May we come in?
TOM: Maggie was there.
She confirmed it was him.
The fire chief
said it was probably
caused by John
smoking in bed.
I know John was
having a rough
time of it.
John didn't do
anything wrong.
Emma, can I help you?
Emma?
She needs to be alone.
Let's say a prayer and go.
PRIEST: Heavenly Father,
have mercy on Emma.
We pray for your strength,
that she will come to accept
that her earthly loss
is the beginning of
life ever after for John,
whom she loved.
In your mercy and love,
forgive whatever sins
John may have committed
through human weakness,
and live forever
with your saints.
In your name, we pray. Amen.
TOM: Amen.
FANNY: Amen.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
And now we
should take a moment
and honor Mrs. Skillpa.
From myself and
everyone in Peacock,
we want to thank you
for offering us your home
during such a difficult time.
Where is she?
I haven't seen her.
YOUNG JOHN: Mommy! Mommy!
Everybody at that
bank is so nice.
Maggie, come with me.
Emma, is everything okay?
Emma, what's going on?
What are you doing?
EMMA: I don't want
what happened to John
to ever happen again.
I'll give you
all the money.
All of it.
Go to Madison and
get out of Peacock.
?
Did I do something wrong
I thought I was
gonna take John's job
at the bank...
John shouldn't be dead.
He shouldn't be dead.
I should never
have left the house.
He's not safe here.
I don't understand you.
You're scaring me.
It's what John
would have wanted.
e.
Now, go. Pleas
Please.
(DOOR LOCKS)
(PEOPLE CLAPPING)
WYATT: Looks like all of
Peacock is here.
Thank you for having me.
Emma? It's almost
time to take the picture.
My good friend, Mayor Crill,
would like to
thank Emma Skillpa...
FANNY: The Senator
is leaving soon.
I'll try to
represent the best interests
of the people of Nebraska.
Emma, Emma, it's Fanny!
And I believe we're
making progress...
(FANNY CONTINUES KNOCKING)
Emma?
Where's Maggie, Emma?
Is she with you?
(FANNY CONTINUES KNOCKING)
It's wonderful out here.
You're missing it.
Emma?
}}