Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org.
PHANTOM
BASED ON THE NOVEL THAT APPEARED UNDER THE
SAME NAME IN THE ILLUSTRATED BERLIN NEWSPAPER.
"WHAT WERE YOU JUST
THINKING ABOUT, LORENZ?"
"ABOUT MY FORMER LIFE..."
"WRITE THE STORY OF YOUR LIFE IN THIS
BOOK, WHICH FATHER GAVE TO YOU."
"DO YOU THINK THE MEMORY WILL
BECOME LESS PAINFUL THEN?"
Hereby, I, ex-convist Lorenz Lubota, write down at my beloved
wife Marie's urging, the story of my crimes and my atonement...
"MELANIE DOESN'T SEEM TO
HAVE TIME FOR THIS, DOES SHE?"
"CALL LORENZ!"
"YOU WITH YOUR BOOKS, LORENZ...!"
"LORD KNOWS YOU DON'T EARN
ENOUGH MONEY TO AFFORD THEM!"
"LET ME BE WITH MY BOOKS, MOTHER."
"THEY LET ONE AT LEAST DREAM ABOUT ALL THE
THINGS ONE WOULD NEVER EXPERIENCE..."
"ISN'T IT TIME FOR
ART SCHOOL, HUGO?"
"I'LL BE A BIT LATE
COMING HOME TODAY."
"I WANT TO HELP AUNT SCHWABE
WITH SOME ACCOUNTS."
"I DON'T WANT YOU TO HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH HER... THAT... PROFITEERING WITCH!"
"SHE'S GOTTEN RICH OFF HER CUTTHROAT BUSINESS!
AND I'VE WORKED LIKE A HORSE MY ENTIRE LIFE..."
THE NEIGHBORS
"LORENZ SHOULD BE HERE SOON."
"IT SEEMS MY CHILD THAT YOU SEPARATE YOUR DAY
BETWEEN THE COMINGS AND GOING OF LORENZ!"
"DOES LORENZ KNOW?"
"HOLD ON TO YOUR HEART, MARIE!"
"AS SOON AS LORENZ WAKES UP
FROM HIS DREAM WORLD..."
"HERE ARE A COUPLE OF POEMS
THAT I'VE WRITTEN, MR. STARKE."
"I'D LIKE TO HEAR
YOUR OPINION ON THEM."
"BOY O BOY! NOW EVEN
YOU WANT TO BECOME A POET!"
"PLEASE, DON'T HOLD ME UP!!
I HAVE TO GO TO WORK!"
"WHAT KIND OF WORK
DO YOU DO ANYWAY, YOU...?"
"WHERE DID YOU GET THOSE SILKY RAGS?! WHERE HAVE
YOU BEEN RUNNING AROUND NIGHT AFTER NIGHT?!"
"CALM DOWN, MOTHER!
YOU'RE RID MOF ME NOW!"
"I HAVE NO DESIRE TO WITHER AWAY
AND ROT IN THIS MISERABLE HOLE!"
"I CAN STAND ON MY OWN TWO FEET!
I DON'T NEED ANYBODY'S HELP!"
"MISERY, HUNGER, POVERTY... EVERYTHING'S
COMING DOWN ON ME! AND NOW THIS DISGRACE!"
"CAN'T LORENZ LUBOTA
EVER GET TO WORK ON TIME?"
"WHEN THE GOOD LORD WAS ANGRY,
HE MADE LORENZ LUBOTA THE CITY CLERK!"
"WELL THEN, FAREWELL MOTHER!"
"MELANIE... WHERE YOU'RE HEADED TO...
THERE'S NO WAY BACK..."
"WHAT DO YOU WANT HERE?"
"WHY ARE YOU CHASING AFTER
OUR YOUNG LADY?"
"SO, MARIE, I'M TELLING YOU... LORENZ, WHO WOULD HAVE
THOUGHT! THIS IS MORE THAN TALENT... THIS IS GENIUS!"
"HEY, MR. LUBOTA!"
"OLD MAN STARKE DOESN'T BACK JUST ANYONE,
PROFESSOR, BUT THAT LORENZ IS A GENIUS!"
"ARE YOU THE ONE, OH MUSE,
WHO ENLISTS ME IN HER SERVICES..."
"AND LIKE THE SPHINX TEARS THE SONG
FROM MY BREAST WITH HER CLAWS?"
"LORENZ! ARE YOU SICK?"
"HAVE YOU HEARD ABOUT IT ALREADY?"
"FROM YOUR SISTER?"
"HOW AWFUL...!
HOW TERRIBLY AWFUL IT ALL IS...!"
"I WANT TO GO AND GET SOME FRESH AIR.
MAYBE THEN I'LL FEEL MORE AT EASE."
"HEY BOY! YOU'RE A GENIUS!"
"I GAVE YOUR POEMS TO A MAN WHO WOULD
CONSIDER IT AN HONOR TO BE YOUR MENTOR."
"ONE FINE DAY AT THE TOWN HALL
WHERE YOU WERE ONCE A MEAGER CLERK..."
"YOU'LL BE MADE
AN HONORARY CITIZEN OF OUR CITY!"
"DO YOU REALLY BELIEVE... THAT I'M A POET?
THAT I COULD BECOME A FAMOUS MAN?"
"I BELIEVE THAT NOW THE BOY REALIZES
HE'S A POET, HE'S LOSING HOS HEAD!"
"WHAT'S THE NAME OF
THE DAUGHTER OF THE HOUSE?"
"VERONIKA!"
"I CAN'T GIVE YOU MORE, CHILD...
I DON'T HAVE ANYTHING MYSELF."
"IT'S EITHER THE MONEY OR THE PAWN TICKET...
THERE HAS TO BE SOME ORDER IN THIS WORLD!"
"THIS MUST BE YOUR FIRST TIME WITH SCHWABE 'CAUSE YOU
THINK YOU CAN PERSUADE THE OLD BAG BY PLEADING."
"YOU KNOW MR. WIGOTTSCHINSKI,
RIGHT LORENZ?"
"PRETEND I'M NOT HERE;
ACT LIKE YOU'RE AT HOME."
"I GAVE A NUMBER OF POEMS
THAT I COMPOSED IN MY SPARE TIME..."
"TO AN EXCELLENT JUDGE OF LITERATURE...
A CERTAIN MR. STARK."
"NOW HE WANTS TO INTRODUCE ME TO A FAMOUS
PUBLISHER WHO IS SUPPOSED TO PRINT MY POEMS..."
"OH BOY, YOU MIGHT BECOME
QUITE A FAMOUS MAN."
"HOW COULD AN OLD PRO LIKE YOU
BE SO FAR OFF THE MARK IN YOUR JUDGEMENT?!"
"THE POEMS ARE QUITE NICE... BUT THEY ARE
DEFINITELY NOT PUBLISHING MATERIAL!"
"NOW I DON'T DARE TO GO TO THE PUBLISHER...
WITH MY SHABBY SUIT..."
"CONSIDERING YOUR IMPENDING FAME,
YOU REALLY DO LOOK PRETTY SCRUFFY..."
"WE'LL JUST HAVE TO FIX THAT FOR YOU..."
"THE OLD BAG SEEMS
TO HAVE TAKEN A FANCY TO YOU..."
"SHE USUALLY ISN'T
DECEIVED THAT EASILY."
"I THINK I'LL ACCOMPANY MY WRITER FRIEND
TO PICK OUT SOME NEW CLOTHES..."
"I'M SOMEWHAT OF AN EXPERT
IN THAT FIELD."
"ARE YOU COMING BACK AGAIN?"
"THIS SO-CALLED PROFESSOR CLAIMS
THAT LORENZ'S POEMS ARE WORTHLESS."
"YES, BUT...
WHAT WILL LORENZ SAY TO THAT?"
"NO, NO, MY GOOD MAN...
WE MUST DRINK TO THE VERY PROMISING..."
"BEGINNING OF
THIS LITERARY CAREER!"
"WHERE IS LORENZ?"
"AND WHY ISN'T MELANIE HERE YET?"
"FIRST OF ALL, SOME CHAMPAGNE!"
"EVEN IF WE BURN
THROUGH ALL THE MONEY..."
"THE OLD BAG HAS MORE
IN THE CASHBOX, RIGHT?"
"CHEERS, POET!"
"I'LL LOOK AT WHOMEVER I PLEASE!"
"YOU'VE MADE A CONQUEST, LUBOTA!"
"BUT HE'S MY BROTHER!!!"
"HAVE YOU HEARD, THE OLD HARLAN WANTS TO HAVE HIS
DAUGHTER VERONIKA ENGAGED TO THE RICH WIEDENBERG!"
"IS THAT TRUE... WHAT YOU'VE JUST SAID
ABOUT THE ENGAGEMENT OF VERONICA HARLAN?"
"SAY THERE, LITTLE ONE, YOUR BROTHER LORENZ
IS IN GOOD WITH OLD SCHWABE, ISN'T HE?"
"MY BROTHER LORENZ IS THE MOST
HONEST MAN IN THE WORLD..."
"AND THE ONLY ONE MY AUNT SCHWABE
DOESN'T THINK IS A SCOUNDREL!"
"WE WOULD LIKE TO INQUIRE
AS TO WHY THE CITY CLERK LUBOTA..."
"HAS BEEN AWAY FROM WORK
WITHOUT AN EXCUSED ABSENCE?"
"MY SON IS ILL..."
"WE HAVE RECEIVED COMPLAINTS AGAINST THE
"INDISPOSED" MR. LUBOTA WHO HAS BEEN..."
"GALLIVANTING AROUND IN BARS AND CAUSING
A SCANDAL IN FRONT OF THE HARLAN HOUSE."
"ACCORDING TO THE COACHMAN, YOU'VE ALREADY
FOLLOWED MISS VERONIKA AROUND ONCE..."
"CITY CLERK YOU USED TO BE, MR. LUBOTA!"
"DO YOU KNOW WHERE
LORENZ IS TODAY, FATHER?"
"I'M IN NO HURRY TO TELL LORENZ
HOW UNSUCCESSFUL HIS POEMS ARE."
"WELL, FOR HEAVEN'S SAKE LORENZ,
WHAT'S GOING ON WITH YOU AND THE HARLANS?"
"MOTHER... LAST NIGHT..."
"THE WORLD FELL DOWN AROUND ME!"
"IF YOU LOVE ME, MOTHER, DON'T ASK ME!
I HAVE NO TO LOSE! ..."
"I HAVE TO GO THE HARLANS!"
"IF I ONLY KNEW HOW I COULD GET YOUR BROTHER
TO REALLY TAKE THE OLD BAG TO THE CLEANERS."
"I'VE ALREADY TOLD YOU ONCE! LEAVE MY BROTHER
OUT OF THIS! HE'S TOO GOOD FOR THIS!"
"DEAR MADAM... IS IT TRUE... THAT YOU WISH
TO ENGAGE YOUR DAUGTER TO MR. WEIDENBERG?"
"I KNOW I HAVE NO RIGHT IN THIS MATTER! NEVERTHELESS,
FOR GOD'S SAKE... HAVE PITY! ANSWER ME!"
"CALL MY HUSBAND!"
"DEAR MADAM...
I'VE ONLY SEEN YOUR DAUGHTER ONCE..."
"BUT I CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT
THE HOPE OF WINNING HER FOR MYSELF!"
"DON'T THINK I'M A FOOL, DEAR MADAM!
THIS LOVE OVERTOOK ME LIKE FATE! ..."
"TO GIVE UP ON IT WOULD BE
LIKE ME GIVING UP ON GOD!"
"WON'T YOU SHARE YOUR WORRIES WITH ME,
MOTHER LUBOTA? IS LORENZ SICK?"
"I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S WRONG WITH HIM!
HE ISN'T MY LORENZ ANYMORE! ..."
"HE'S A STRANGER... SOMEONE I
DON'T KNOW... WHO DOESN'T KNOW ME!"
"HOW CAN ONE HAVE DOUBTS ABOUT LORENZ...
EVEN FOR A MINUTE, MOTHER?!"
"I CAN'T LEAVE, MR. HARLAN, UNTIL I'M ASSURED THAT
YOU WILL SUPPORT MY COURTING YOUR DAUGHTER..."
"IT WOULD BE AN HONOR, MR. LUBOTA,
SHALL WE SAY IN A WHILE...?"
"TO THE BEST TAVERN IN THE CITY!"
"FORGIVE ME... PLEASE...
AN ALMOST UNBELIEVABLE SIMILARITY..."
"YOU MAY STAY... IF YOU LIKE.
WE WERE JUST ABOUT TO LEAVE ANYWAY."
"CHAMPAGNE! I'D LIKE TO DRINK CHAMPAGNE!"
"TELL ME, MARIE,
DO YOU THINK IT'S POSSIBLE..."
"NO, FATHER!"
"WHAT I WANTED TO SAY... LORENZ LUBOTA
IS DEVELOPING HIS POETIC GENIUS..."
"HE'S ONLY TRAVELING
IN THE BEST CIRCLES NOW."
"WHAT THAT BOY COULD BECOME...
IF ONLY HE HAD MONEY!"
"HE WOULD ONLY HAVE TO HAVE MONEY...
JUST MONEY!"
"NO...! NO...! DON'T RUN
AWAY FROM ME! NOT YOU TOO!"
"WHO ARE YOU?"
"I'M... A CITY CLERK
DRIVEN FROM HIS JOB!"
"DON'T TELL THIS JOKE IN FRONT OF
MY MOTHER, OR SHE'LL THROW YOU OUT!"
"TELL ME, WHO ARE YOU!"
"I... AM A POET... A MAN WITH NO LUCK...
WHO CHASES A SHADOW... A PHANTOM!"
"I WANT TO KNOW... WHAT DROVE YOU
TO ME, LIKE A SLEEPWALKER..."
"I WANT TO KNOW, WHO DO YOU
IMAGES KISSING WHEN YOU KISS ME?"
"UNFORTUNATELY, MY DAUGHTER AND I ARE TOTALLY
DESTITUTE... YOU UNDERSTAND ME, DON'T YOU? ..."
"MELITTA LET SLIP THAT YOU'RE A FAMOUS POET...
I HOPE YOUR INCOME CORRESPONDS TO YOUR FAME!"
"YOU'RE RIGHT... ONE HAS TO PAY...
THERE'S A PRICE FOR EVERYTHING!"
"MY SON IS NOT AT HOME..."
"HE NEEDN'T BOTHER TO COME
TO CITY HALL ANY MORE..."
"HE'S FREE OF THAT CONCERN!"
"LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT, BROTHER-IN-LOW!
YOU SHOULD UNDERSTAND!"
"CHILDREN, IF WE STUCK TOGETHER AND HAD THE RIGHT
CLOTHES... WE COULD SET UP A SPLENDID BUSINESS!"
"I... NEED MONEY!"
"MY DEAR CHILD, I DON'T CONCERN MYSELF WITH YOU LOVE
AFFAIRS... SO PLEASE DON'T INTERFERE IN MY BUSINESS AFFAIRS!!"
"THE ONLY PERSON WE CAN HIT UP FOR MONEY
IS OLD SCHWABE, THAT'S FOR SURE! ..."
"HOW ABOUT IF LORENZ OFFERED HER
HIS POET'S ROYALTIES?"
"WELL, MY BOY, PASSING ONESELF OFF A POET HAS CONSEQUENCES...
OR ELSE DO WITHOUT THE SUPPORT OF A GULLIBLE AUNT."
"YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN HELP ME, AUNT SCHWABE! ..."
"THE WORLD IS CLOSED TO THOSE
WHO ARRIVE WITH EMPTY HANDS!"
"PEOPLE ARE SCOUNDRELS, LORENZ... ALL OF THEM!
THERE'S ONLY ONE I TRUST... THAT'S YOU!"
"THIS BOY HERE... HE WOULDN'T GET A PENNY FROM
ME! BUT YOU... YOU SHALL HAVE THE MONEY!"
"I CAN'T STAND IT...! I DON'T WANT
THIS...!! I'M NO SCOUNDREL!!"
"THEN EXPOSE THE WHOLE LIE
AND BE A NOTHING..."
"AND HUNGRY FOR THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE!"
"AND... HER?"
THE PRACTICAL APPLICATION
"I WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK WITH LORENZ!"
"YOU'RE TALKING TO THE WRONG PERSON! I
HAVEN'T KNOWN WHERE LORENZ IS FOR DAYS NOW."
"AND NOW SHOPPING!
BUY A HUNDRED THOUSAND THINGS...!"
"YOU DON'T SEEM WELL... I WOULD THINK THAT
LORENZ WOULD HAVE TAKEN BETTER CARE OF YOU."
To Mr. Lorenz Lubota: It is a fact
that you have been away from work...
without an excused absence, that you have frequented
and behaved scandalously in questionable taverns...
and further, that you have harassed
highly esteemed citizens of the community.
Moreover, your unqualified behaviour
towards city clerk Hermann Schraat...
is considered a serious offense
against a public administrator.
In view of the above, you are desmissed
immediately from your employment with the City...
and are without claim
to any further wages.
"WHAT DO YOU ACTUALLY WANT?
WHY ARE YOU SPYING ON ME? ..."
"YOU'VE NEVER ONCE SHOWN
ANY CONCERN FOR ME... WHY SUDDENLY NOW?"
"WHAT DO I WANT HERE? I LENT 60,000 MARKS TO LORENZ...
AND NOW I'D LIKE TO KNOW WHAT HE'S USING IT FOR."
"MY LORENZ IS AN HONEST MAN!!
HE CAN ANSWER FOR HIS ACTIONS! ..."
"REMEMBER THAT AND LEAVE ME ALONE!"
"I WANT TO KNOW WHERE I STAND!
I SHALL MAKE INQUIRIES..."
"IN ANY CASE, YOU CAN TELL LORENZ
THAT I EXPECT HIM AT MY PLACE TODAY!"
"I LIKE BUY THIS FABRIC
FOR MY MOTHER."
"THE FOUNDING OF THE WIGOTTSCHINSKY-LUBOTA
FIRM CALLS FOR A CELEBRATION!"
"I BROUGHT SOMETHING FOR YOU, MOTHER."
"DID YOU BUY THAT WITH
THE MONEY FROM AUNT SCHWABE?"
"SHE WAS HERE... SHE ASKED ABOUT YOU...
YOU SHOULD GO TO HER TODAY..."
"WHY DID YOU WISH
TO SPEAK TO ME, AUNT?"
"LORENZ, YOU'RE THE BIGGEST SCOUNDREL
I'VE EVER ENCOUNTERED IN MY LIFE!"
"I'VE MADE SOME INQUIRIES...
AND NOW I KNOW WHERE I STAND WITH YOU! ..."
"I DEMAND THE MONEY BACK
THAT YOU SWINDLED FROM ME!"
"AND IF YOU DON'T HAVE THE MONEY ANYMORE,
AS YOU CLAIM... WHAT DID YOU DO WITH IT?"
"I DON'T OWE AN AXPLANATION
ABOUT HOW AND WHERE I SPEND MY MONEY."
"YOUR MONEY? HOW DARE YOU
TALK ABOUT YOUR MONEY!..."
"WHAT'S COME OVER YOU? ARE YOU ALL
SUDDENLY POSSESSED BY THE DEVIL?!"
"YOU EITHER GIVE ME BACK THE MONEY... OR I'LL HAVE NO QUALMS
ABOUT HANDING YOU AND YOUR FINE FRIEND OVER TO THE POLICE!"
"I'LL GIVE YOU THREE DAYS TO CLEAR THE
MATTER UP COMPLETELY, NOT AN HOUR MORE..."
"I'LL TURN THE MATTER OVER TO THE
POLICE IF YOU HAVEN'T DONE IT BY THEN!"
"SHE HAS UNCOVERED THE FRAUD...
SHE WENT TO SEE MOTHER..."
"THE OLD BEAST KNOWS NO PITY WHEN SHE
THINKS HER MONEY IS IN DANGER! ..."
"SHE'LL BREAK YOUR NECK
WITHOUT MERCY!"
"YOU'LL JUST HAVE TO TAKE THE OLD BAG TO THE
CLEANERS A SECOND TIME... WITH FORCE IF NECESSARY!"
"I'D RATHER STAND IN THE TOWN SQUARE AND
PUBLICLY ADMIT MY MISTAKES AND DO PENANCE!"
"DO YOU THINK DOING THAT
WILL GET THE MONEY BACK?"
"I WANT TO PAY THE MONEY BACK!
I WANT TO PAY BACK EVERY NICKEL AND DIME!"
"FROM WHAT? FROM YOUR INCOME AS A DISCHARGED
CLERK... OR FROM YOUR POET'S ROYALTIES?"
"I CAN'T BREAK AWAY FROM HER!
I CAN'T BREAK AWAY FROM HER!"
"CAN'T YOU SEE THAT I'M ON THE BRINK OF INSANITY?
SO PLEASE HELP ME! WHY DON'T YOU HELP ME...?"
"IF I COULD HELP YOU... IF I COULD RELEASE
YOU... THEN I WOULDN'T LOVE YOU ANYMORE..."
"MOTHER IS VERY ILL... I MUST
GO TO THE PHARMACY QUICKLY!"
"MOTHER... MOTHER!
I'VE COME TO YOU... HELP ME!"
"MY SON IS OUT THERE!"
"YOUR MOTHER IS VERY SICK, LORENZ... WE
HAVE TO KEEP HER AWAY FROM ANY EXCITEMENT!"
"I'LL GIVE YOU THREE DAY...
NOT ONE HOUR MORE!!"
"MARIE... I HAVE TO
ASK YOU SOMETHING..."
"MARIE... WHAT WOULD YOU SAY... IF SOMEONE WERE TELL
YOU... THAT I'VE BECOME A GOOD FOR NOTHING...?"
"I WOULD LAUGH AT HIM, LORENZ!"
"BUT IF HE WERE RIGHT, MARIE?"
THE LAST ATTEMPT
"I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU, AUNT..."
"AUNT... I BEG YOU... HAVE MERCY...
I CAN'T GIVE YOU BACK THE MONEY YET..."
"AND I CAN'T TELL YOU
WHERE IT WENT!"
"THEN THE POLICE WILL HAVE TO
CONCERN THEMSELVES WITH THIS MATTER."
"YOU CAN ASK THE GENTLEMAN WHO DISCOVERED YOUR TALENT TO POST BAIL
FOR YOU... OR YOU CAN SIGN OVER YOUR FUTURE ROYALTIES TO ME..."
"BUT NONE OF IT IS TRUE!
IT'S ALL FABRICATION! ..."
"NO ONE WOULD EVEN GIVE ME
50 MARKS FOR MY TEN MISERABLE POEMS!"
"YES!! I LIED TO YOU! BUT I DON'T
WANT TO LIE ANY MORE... NEVER AGAIN!"
"YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN BATTER OFF
IF YOU HAD KEPT ON LYING, YOU FOOL! ..."
"MAYBY THEN I WOULD HAVE GRANTED YOU A DEFERMENT TO
PAY BACK YOUR DEBT! BUT NOW... TO WHAT END...?!"
"I CAN WELL IMAGINE WHAT KIND
OF WOMAN YOU THREW MY GOOD MONEY AT..."
"BUT I'LL HAVE THE POLICE AS MUCH ON
THAT WOMAN'S THROAT AS THEY ARE ON YOURS!"
"WHERE IS LORENZ?"
"I DON'T KNOW, MOTHER...
BUT HE'LL BE BACK!"
"NOW YOU HAVE NO CHOICE!!
WHEN THE WHOLE STORY COMES TO LIGHT..."
"YOU'LL GO TO JAIL AND IT WILL BE
THE DEATH OF YOUR MOTHER!"
"WELL THEN, AGREED...
TOMORROW EVENING..."
"DO YOU HAVE THE MONEY?!"
"I DON'T WANT TO HEAR ABOUT ANY BUSINESS NOW,
I JUST WANT TO HAVE A NICE DINNER WITH YOU."
"CHEERS, HERE'S TO A LONG LIFE!"
"WHO IS WALKING BACK
AND FORTH SO RESTLESSLY?"
"DON'T YOU WANT TO GO TO SLEEP TOO,
LORENZ, IT'S ALMOST 2 A.M.!"
"WE'RE LOST... WE'RE BOTH LOST...
WE'VE GONE TO THE DOGS!"
"CAN YOU TELL ME WHERE THE ADDRESSEE LIVES?
THE HOUSE NUMBER IS WRONG."
"DAMMIT!
THE OLD BAG'S NIGHT BELL!"
"NO! NO! DON'T!!"
"YOU DON'T NEED TO TIE ME UP...
I'LL GO WITH YOU VOLUNTARILY."
"DON'T ASK ANY QUESTIONS,
BE GOOD TO MOTHER! FAREWELL!"
THE PENANCE...
AND THE REDEMPTION
"WE'VE BEEN WAITING FOR YOU,
LORENZ, TO BRING YOU HOME!"
"LOOK, LORENZ... YOUR NEW HOME!"
But I have the consolation that my good Mother
died in the firm belief that I was ill.
"DID FATHER'S BOOK DO JUSTICE?"
"YES, MARIE!..."
THE END
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org