Subtitles by DramaFever
Chief.
Yes?
I'm quitting the ST.
What?
You're quitting ST? What does that mean?
What are you doing?
I'm not obligated to tell you.
Yes you are. Of course you are.
I'm your chief!
Gross.
I can confirm that she has submitted
a transfer request.
Did you coerce her into doing that?
What do you mean?
You want to separate Midori-san
from ST don't you?
- I didn't say anything.
- I heard it from Ikeda.
Hey, wait.
I have not given her
any instructions.
But obviously she's not the type
to take direction anyway.
You're right.
Since she submitted a request, I'm
recommending her to the FBI liaison.
It's good timing for me to notify the
other members of my plan.
Akagi Samon. Tokyo University,
Forensics Medicine Department.
Aoyama Sho will be sent as a researcher
to the Police Force Science Institute.
Kurosaki Yuji will be sent to the Police
Department, Security, Second Unit.
Yamabuki Saezo will be transferred to the
Kanto Police Academy as an instructor.
You're trying to disband the ST?
All that's left is you.
Lieutenant Yurine.
I'm staying in ST.
Yuki Midori, without question
but Akagi Samon, Aoyama Sho, Kurosaki Yuji
and Yamabuki Saezo - all of them
In order for all their talents to be
maximized within the police force
I will not allow ST to be disbanded.
If only that were the opinion
of everyone in ST.
That was lame.
[Toto Music University Recital Hall
4:42PM]
The Vienna International Violin Competition
is the world's most prominent competition.
The winner, Yuzuki Kyoko, was someone
I followed very closely.
I'm so grateful to you for inviting me to
such a special event.
Don't thank me, thank the higher-ups.
I just got the invitation from them.
I'm a lucky man, for you to extend the
invitation to the investigation team.
That's why I thought it only appropriate
on such an occasion to bring a date, right?
She'll be playing a Stradivarius on
loan from the university tonight.
What happened?
Stay where you are.
I'll be right there.
What happened?
Akagi-san, don't you
think anything of it?
Of what?
Midori-san is leaving and she
won't even tell me why!
And what did she mean
by 'gross'?
Midori-san thinks you're
gross, Chief.
But what does that mean?
I don't understand.
Oh you don't?
Aoyama-san, don't you care
that Midori-san is quitting?
Can I go home now?
What? What? What?
Akagi-san, won't you say something?
Akagi-san, are you fine with all this?
- This text is from Midori.
- Huh?
Someone's dead at Toto Music University.
Hey, wait!
[ST: Scientific Task Force]
[Toto Music University Recital Hall
7:11PM Crime scene]
The victim is Komatsu Sadao, age 45.
He was an instructor at the University and
he is Yuzuki Kyoko's former teacher.
The cause of death is likely...
Brain injury. Definitely. If you can only
equivocate, don't speak at all.
Akagi-san!
Besides, what is this room?
It's the display room for the
Stradivarius.
The temperature and humidity is carefully
regulated 24 hours a day, 365 days a year.
It is such a delicate instrument.
The acoustics in here are perfect
for practicing on the instrument.
[University staff: Karashima Akihito
Violinist: Fukushima Reiko]
[Music producer: Ono Shinichiro
Violinist: Yuzuki Kyoko]
This is the dressing room.
Who are you?
I'm on staff here.
My name is Karashima.
This green room includes the waiting,
the dressing and display rooms.
It's normally locked and certain
people are allowed to access it.
'Normally'?
Yuzuki Kyoko-san is a very
special guest!
She had the key so she could practice
freely for this rare Stradivarius concert.
Yuzuki Kyoko.
Who's that?
Shut up! You don't know?
Yuzuki Kyoko was the winner of the Vienna
I am she.
I discovered Professor Komatsu's body.
Can you describe what happened
in great detail?
The door to this room locks automatically.
Yuzuki-san left her key in the room.
I'm so sorry I left the
key inside.
- It's not a problem.
- Thank you.
When the security guard opened the
door the chain was on.
Is somebody inside?
Open up.
- The guard called out but got no response.
- Excuse me.
- Please wait here.
- All right.
They had no choice but to
cut the chain.
There, Professor Komatsu was
on the floor.
A panicked Yuzuki-san
contacted Karashima-san.
And they all ran here.
Professor Komatsu!
The security guard corroborates
Yuzuki-san's story.
Which means, in other words...
a locked-room murder.
Please, don't say those words.
'Those words'?
You mean 'locked-room'?
I know you're claustrophobic but
even just saying those words?
'Locked-room murder'?
This guy put the chain on himself.
Then he tripped on the carpet and hit
his head right here.
There certainly seems to be a possibility
of it being an accident.
Not a possibility of an accident,
it was an accident!
The door was chained from the inside.
Idiot. Look closely.
If he had hit his head on the display case
there would've been circular drops of blood.
This spray of blood proves
he had been struck.
The evidence here is all an attempt
to make it look like an accident.
Ah, I see.
The door was chained from the inside.
Nevertheless you concluded that this
was a murder, not an accident.
- That's right.
- Based solely on the drops of blood.
I see you've finally begun
to understand this case.
Um, Akagi-san is taking the evidence into
consideration and will conduct a thorough
For example, any of you could
be the perpetrators.
Why was Komatsu Sadao here?
I don't know.
You don't know?
You mean Komatsu made his way into the
green room without your knowing?
How did he open the door?
I don't know.
All right.
Ask a locksmith about the key.
You sound as if these are
somebody else's problems.
Based on the attempts to disguise the
crime the criminal is not very intelligent.
This is boring.
I'm going home.
Akagi-san.
That's fine.
We will continue our investigation
without the aid of ST.
Hold on a minute.
There's one person dead.
It brings the police down to have an
investigator who claims this is boring.
What better way is there for the police
to gain trust except to solve crimes?
Is there something better than
arresting the criminal?
Akagi-san is right. ST will arrest the
perpetrator and serve justice.
Then what if you can't find the criminal?
Or you determine this was an accident?
You can disband ST immediately.
Understood.
That's a promise.
Why did I say something like that?
Why did I put the future of
ST on the line?
My mouth just said it before I could
think! This stupid mouth!
We have to solve the case or else it'll
be my fault that ST is disbanded!
Oh yeah, it's all your fault, Chief.
What? Are you saying it's my fault?
No, it's the Chief's fault.
Chief, hurry up and organize the
facts of the case.
Roger.
After hearing Yuzuki Kyoko's story
at 9 AM, she was visited by a former
classmate and substitute instructor
Fukushima Reiko-san, in the green room.
Coming.
Oh hi. Come on in.
[10:04 AM Rehearsal]
After that, around 10AM, she
rehearsed for about two hours.
Shortly after 12PM, Yuzuki
Kyoko-san returned to the green room
From 1PM to 2PM, she was visited
by music producer Ono Shinichiro-san.
From 2:30PM to after 3PM,
a former schoolmate and current University
employee Karashima-san visited her.
After that, Yuzuki Kyoko went outside to
get some fresh air before her concert.
She left her key inside the room so
a security guard had to open it for her.
The door was chained closed and inside,
Komatsu Sadao-san was dead.
How did the perpetrator enter and
exit the green room?
Why did the perp go out of his way
to kill Komatsu-san in the green room?
And why was Komatsu-san in the
green room to begin with?
Midori, was there anything that caught your
attention during Yuzuki Kyoko's testimony?
She was lying.
I see. That was a lie.
Why was Komatsu Sadao here?
I don't know.
That was a lie. Her voice changed pitch.
Proof that she's hiding something.
I see. Who benefits from Komatsu's death?
His family might cash in life insurance
but that's no reason
to be in the green room.
So the people who were hurt
by this incident are
Yuzuki Kyoko.
Her concert was canceled. Her
reputation as star violinist was marred.
I get it. So the perpetrator was trying
to damage Yuzuki Kyoko!
We have to interrogate these three!
Calm down. Nothing good
comes of panicking.
I don't want ST to be disbanded.
I've decided in my heart.
I want to create a home for you.
That's why I must win the approval
of the Director.
I don't really want her approval.
See, this is exactly the problem.
ST has to try to gain approval!
Akagi-san, your spiteful tongue!
Aoyama-san, the state of your desk!
It's too filthy!
Midori-san and Yamabuki-san,
your wardrobes need improvement.
Kurosaki-san, you too.
Can't you try to at least utter a greeting?
I'm going out to question
some people.
I haven't said anything untrue.
I know you're right.
I just want you all to live a bit
more intelligently.
What are you talking about?
I am intelligent.
That's not what I mean.
[Ono Music Office]
Following the rehearsal
you visited Yuzuki-san in the green room
without a prior appointment, didn't you?
Yes, I'd heard she might be rehearsing in
there so I thought I'd catch her there.
Why did you want to see her?
I wanted to release a CD of her music
and needed to discuss it with her.
Of course I also wanted to
hear her play again.
[1:06 PM - Ono Shinichiro]
Bravo, bravo!
Your playing the Stradivarius is
really the best.
Yuzuki-san, I came here
with a contract today.
Trust me, I will make
it a huge hit!
No thank you.
No matter how many times you
come, the answer will always be no.
I had pushed her too far,
I'm afraid I acted disgracefully.
I left without even
saying goodbye.
Why did she turn down your offer
to produce her debut CD?
Ask her yourself.
I know without asking.
It's because you actually have
absolutely no interest in classical music.
Look at this.
Doesn't look like you opened
these books even once.
Do you know the difference between
a violin and a viola?
Huh?
You wanted to produce Yuzuki Kyoko's CD
only because she won a prestigious contest.
- Now wait a--
- I don't care.
All I want to know is whether her mentor
Professor Komatsu was there with her.
Komatsu disapproved of your plan,
so you murdered him.
Wrong!
I did no such thing!
I was speaking to Yuzuki-san alone.
Anyway Komatsu wasn't the kind of person
who looked after his student's well-being.
You all are fooled by his
title of professor.
Komatsu-san was pursuing a
physical relationship with Yuzuki-san.
If you think I'm lying
do some asking around.
Do you think what Ono-san
said is true?
He panicked when we accused him of murder
but he regained his calm quickly.
It's not necessarily just a story.
There are two people left.
Let's go.
[Toto Music University]
Fukushima-san, why were you
in the green room?
I was on my way to work and
walked by the room.
I thought I'd pop in to
congratulate her.
Come in.
Kyoko-san.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Wow. You really have this
whole suite to yourself?
You can practice all you want
on the Stradivarius.
I guess this is the difference between
a substitute instructor
and the winner of the Vienna
International Violin Competition.
I'll make some tea.
I'm not staying for tea, after all.
What?
I wouldn't want a violinist like you,
the pride of Japan, to risk getting a burn.
Don't forget, trends change quickly.
Anything could happen to your
music career at any moment.
Are you saying I held a grudge
against Kyoko-san?
Grudge. Jealousy. So resentful
you can't sleep at night.
What?
You wanted to destroy Yuzuki Kyoko,
so in the green room...
you killed her mentor
Komatsu Sadao.
Please don't make such
wild accusations.
How did you get in and out of the
green room?
This guy is crazy.
Calm down.
Do the police always try
to put words in peoples' mouths?
Excuse us.
Fukushima-san was once the center of
the media as a beautiful violinist.
But the media gets bored quickly.
That's why Fukushima-san told Yuzuki-san
to do her best regardless of the media.
Sure, there are times one might
feel jealous over another's success.
However do you really think that is reason
enough to kill Professor Komatsu?
- I don't.
- Huh?
However when you said 'anything could
happen to your music career at any moment'
that wasn't just a nasty remark, it
was a warning about something.
And when something did happen,
you were going to smirk
and laugh at Yuzuki Kyoko.
What were you planning?
- Stop making accusations.
- There's no hiding your love triangle.
What? Love triangle?
Yuzuki Kyoko and Karashima
are lovers.
However, they grew apart, probably
when she went to study abroad.
He started seeing
Fukushima Reiko and still is.
That much was clear from where you sat
and the way you looked at each other.
You wanted to show off
your relationship to Kyoko.
Yuzuki Kyoko still has feeling for him.
For the moment you're winning in love,
but losing in your career.
A violinist deemed too beautiful who
is now a substitute instructor
can't compete with the winner of the
Vienna International Violin Competition.
So you staged a sensational murder
to tarnish Yuzuki Kyoko's career.
No.
I'll sue you for slander.
We'll find out soon enough.
So?
Why were you in the green room?
You were troubled by Komatsu's advances
so you asked for Karashima's help. Right?
- How did you...
- Karashima-san told us.
Did Komatsu-san perhaps come to the
green room, looking for you?
Yes.
After Karashima-san left,
Professor Komatsu came.
He forcibly pushed me down.
But I didn't kill him.
I was desperate so I just ran away.
That's all.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you before.
I was scared of being a suspect.
When you pushed him away,
did Komatsu-san hit his head?
If so that would legitimately
be self-defense.
No. When he attacked me,
we were in the waiting room.
Not the display room.
There was no evidence that
the body had been dragged.
I confirmed through Komatsu-san's emails
that he was stalking Yuzuki Kyoko-san.
So to summarize, Yuzuki Kyoko was
being physically harassed
Ono Shinichiro had been rejected on
his plan to produce her CD
Fukushima Reiko harbored jealousy
and Karashima Akihito was sincerely
trying to help Kyoko.
They all had reasonable motives to
murder Komatsu.
So the investigation is
back to square one?
We've discovered a few new details
about the people involved.
What are they?
Ono, the music producer's office is on the
verge of going bust with a lot of debt.
Karashima, on staff at university,
was on bad terms with Komatsu.
Some have even said that he was
bullied by Komatsu.
Thank you very much.
But...
none of these are a
knockout punch.
- I'm sorry.
- You're supposed to say thank you.
I may not be able to protect ST.
The investigation is going nowhere.
Unless something changes,
ST will really be disbanded.
Nobody took it seriously when
Midori-san said she was quitting.
- You too, Akagi-san.
- I'm focusing on the case.
Don't you care if all the members
of ST get separated?
I am focusing on the case.
- Let me focus.
- You said it was boring.
Is it because you don't want
ST to break up?
Shut up!
You do your thing.
And I'll worry about the other stuff.
I know someone who can help you
with your worries. I'll call.
Huh? Who is it?
Director Matsudo.
What?
I have no doubt she would
answer your questions.
Long time no see.
I think we saw each other
just yesterday.
I meant I haven't seen you
here in a while.
It's been seven years.
Seven years ago?
Matsudo was a detective and Yuki-kun
was a newbie in the crime lab.
They met working on a murder case.
Yuki-kun was outstanding.
Nobody could follow her
analysis and problem-solving.
The other officers disregarded her
as a newbie.
Director Matsudo alone believed in her
and solved the case.
Back in the day when I got stuck on a case,
I would meet you here to ask your opinion.
After the case was closed, Director
Matsudo evaluated Yuki-kun highly.
She recommended her for
numerous posts.
But Yuki-kun never once accepted
an offer.
To work in the FBI Lab would of course
mean having to get on a plane.
Have you gotten your claustrophobia
under control? Can you get on a plane?
I wonder.
It has nothing to do with space.
Wherever I think is closed space
is where I feel claustrophobic.
Why did you want to quit ST?
Do I have to tell you?
You feel bound.
You think that ST is now a closed space.
But Lieutenant Yurine isn't binding you.
He just believes in you and
the other members of ST.
As I did in the past.
What? Is that what you came
here to say?
You just want to run away
from his belief in you.
Do you want me to stay with
ST or quit? Which is it?
You won't listen to me either way.
You should reconsider whether ST is
really the closed space you think it is.
Sorry I'm late.
I've been waiting for you.
- Something bitter.
- You just ate something sweet, huh?
Director, do you know why Midori-san
suddenly wanted to quit ST?
It's because of you.
Is that right?
I knew it.
But I still think she belongs in ST.
I'm not just talking about Midori-san,
but everyone belongs there.
Chief.
Does ST exist only for us?
ST is composed of people who were
the best in their field
and was created to support investigations
from a scientific angle.
It was created for investigations.
ST exists to solve crimes.
I've failed as the chief of ST.
What should I do?
Think. Think!
Director, do you regret not being able
to create the right place for Midori-san?
I admit I failed to do so.
But I have no regrets.
I have no time for regret.
That's because you are strong, Director.
I can't do it.
What I can do is...
only one thing.
And if there's only one thing
I can do...
I just have to do it, right?
Thank you very much.
Wherever I think is closed space,
is where I feel claustrophobic.
You think that ST now is a closed space.
But Lieutenant Yurine isn't binding you.
He just believes in you and
the other members of ST.
Won't you tell me what you're
really thinking?
How are they doing?
I can't keep my eyes off of them.
They're all over the place.
I'm sorry.
But...
I didn't expect Akagi Samon
to say what he did.
You mean asking whether ST
existed for them?
That surprised me too.
That's why I can't keep my eyes
off of them.
Is it Yurine-kun's influence?
Perhaps it is.
But he'd better understand that
self-awareness can lead to a fatal mistake.
Person to person relationships
can be very tricky.
Because there's no right answer.
There's something I wanted to check.
Is it okay if I close the door?
Yes.
A closed room.
Not even a window.
My breath.
My breath is...
not strained.
No way!
- Thanks for your cooperation.
- Good evening.
What is the chief doing?
One. Stay at ST and maximize the power
of this group as I have done.
Two. Go work at the FBI Lab and learn the
most cutting-edge techniques in the field.
Was he trying to outline all the
possible outcomes for your situation?
Looks like he came up
with a hundred possibilities.
You're right.
He must have stayed up all night.
That's not what you think!
What do you mean?
Don't misunderstand.
I'm not trying to hold you back.
I was simply...
using these one hundred possibilities
to help you think about your next steps.
Oh, I would like to help all of you
think about your futures.
Chief, you really are stupid.
You are stupid.
Stupid.
You guys are horrible.
Calling me stupid.
Chief, you are really stupid.
My next steps don't matter now.
We're in the middle of an investigation.
Midori-san.
Clear up this mountain of memos.
Keep them at my desk.
I'll read them after the investigation.
I'm going over the case from the
beginning, Chief Stupid.
Akagi-san!
Call Kikukawa-san here.
There's something that's bothering me.
Roger.
[Stradivarius Yuzuki Kyoko]
So this is Yuzuki Kyoko
playing the Stradivarius?
The University loaned me this because I
was disappointed the concert was canceled.
What is it that's bothering you?
Last night I heard Yuzuki Kyoko
playing the violin.
She wasn't treating that violin as if it
were the precious Stradivarius.
And what of it?
If this sound is the Stradivarius
then what she was playing last night
was not the Stradivarius.
You can hear the difference?
Harmonic overtones produced by different
violins are not precisely the same.
In other words, each violin is unique, and
Midori-san is able to hear the difference.
Don't you have any other
recordings?
I have one more.
It's from the rehearsal on the
morning of the concert.
This isn't the Stradivarius.
She ought to have been using the
same instrument as the concert.
Why wasn't she playing the Stradivarius?
Stradivarius violins are extremely
expensive, aren't they?
In auctions they've gone for tens to
hundreds of thousands of yen.
Hmm, a price that'd make someone
want to steal it.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
What if, somebody stole the Stradivarius
and in order to delay the
discovery of the theft
they left a substitute violin instead.
He's saying that perhaps
Yuzuki Kyoko hasn't noticed the switch.
She's a professional! There's no way
she wouldn't notice a different instrument.
If that's the case, why is Yuzuki Kyoko
hiding the fact that it was stolen?
Maybe Yuzuki Kyoko herself
switched out the violins!
Yuzuki Kyoko would have been
the first to be accused of doing that.
I find it implausible that
she'd be the perpetrator.
Then, who?
There must have been someone,
perhaps even very close to her
who was trying to frame her.
Yuzuki Kyoko isn't the only one
who has been hiding this.
He should have realized at the rehearsal
that she wasn't playing the Stradivarius.
- 'He'?
- Who is it?
Karashima Akihito.
He has a good ear.
As good as mine.
If he had noticed but
remained silent...
Karashima seems suspect.
I can understand how Yuzuki Kyoko would
remain silent in order to protect him.
She's still in love with him.
But where is the real Stradivarius?
Contact the University and ask them if they've
noticed anything strange the past few days.
I am going to hear a Stradivarius
in person.
I'll do anything to make that happen.
I'll focus on Yuzuki Kyoko.
The question is, how is the missing Stradivarius
related to Komatsu-san's murder?
Or perhaps they're not related at all.
The more important question
is the closed room.
How did the perpetrator enter and exit
the room that was chained from within?
True. Unless we can solve the closed-room
mystery, we can't prove this was murder.
Kikukawa-san, don't scare us like that!
What are you doing still here?
You just left.
How'd you get back in?
Don't talk to me
like I'm mosquito larva!
I left the important CD in Akagi's player.
I don't want it to get scratched.
Akagi-san will get mad at you if you
go into his cubicle without him.
I see. I see it now.
Unfortunately
thanks to Kikukawa, the mystery
has been solved.
I can't believe I didn't notice it before.
That was stupid of me.
Idiot! Idiot!
Stop it! If you've solved the mystery,
tell me!
I will tell you more than everything
you need. Follow me.
[Karashima Akihito] [Ono Shinichiro]
[Fukushima Reiko]
To my dear supporters,
I've decided to return to Germany.
Before I go, I'm determined to have you
listen to my playing
so I can properly express
my gratitude.
Tomorrow I will play the
Stradivarius as planned.
I think you will enjoy it.
I look forward to seeing you.
Yuzuki Kyoko
[August 12 1:04 PM
The day of the concert]
- Thank you for coming.
- We were looking forward to it.
Where are you going?
The concert hasn't begun yet.
Ono-san.
It's a very rare chance to hear
a Stradivarius.
I have an emergency to attend to.
Excuse me.
What is this? Please clear the way.
Sorry. I'm not a security guard,
I'm with the police.
Hey, wait a second.
What are you doing?
- What's this?
- That's uh...
I bought it for my daughter
to practice on.
If you can't distinguish a violin from a
viola, how did you choose this?
Wait, please, stop that.
No, don't, stop!
The Stradivarius!
Take a closer look.
That's a fake.
Couldn't you tell?
Fake?
Since the murder, the Stradivarius has
been switched out with a fake.
A very well-made fake that could fool
the general population in sight and sound.
There are two people
who noticed that is was fake.
The first is of course, the performer
herself, Yuzuki-san.
The other person was Karashima-san.
Your keen sense of hearing
should have caught the difference.
But you kept quiet
to protect the perpetrator.
Because the violin thief was none other
than your lover Fukushima Reiko-san.
What you said to me that day...
You killed her mentor
Komatsu Sadao.
The muscles around your eyes twitched
creating creases in your skin.
It was an expression of relief.
You were relieved because we didn't know
anything about the Stradivarius.
You can't cast us as your perpetrators.
I found a letter of admission addressed to
the media on your university computer.
[Yuzuki Kyoko has the audacity to try to
fool her audience with a fake Stradivarius.]
The only person who could have written this
is the person who stole the Stradivarius.
You left your violin case in the waiting
room and went into the display room.
You purposely insulted her there.
I guess this is the difference between
a substitute instructor and
the winner of the Vienna International
Violin Competition.
I'll make some tea.
While Yuzuki Kyoko was out of the room
you replaced the Stradivarius with
the fake you had kept in your bag.
By leaving your violin case
in the waiting room
you avoided suspicion from Yuzuki Kyoko
later when she'd discovered the switch.
Reiko, that was you?
You had thought it was
Karashima who replaced the violin.
We found your fingerprints on a
flowerpot in the hall.
That's where you were hiding
the room key.
You wanted to talk to Karashima alone so
you asked him to meet you there.
You assumed Karashima, who knew of the
hidden key, could have switched violins.
You also assumed that he was the only one
who could have killed Komatsu-san.
That's why you also hid the fact that
you'd been attacked by Komatsu-san.
You worked so hard to protect Karashima-san
but he had nothing to say in return.
You got fed up and took it out
on your violin. Am I wrong?
The violin wasn't the only thing
that had been replaced.
Our awareness had also been
switched out.
The perpetrator did not kill Komatsu-san
in order to frame Yuzuki Kyoko.
He killed Komatsu-san because
he wanted the Stradivarius.
The perpetrator is
you.
You're wrong.
You would steal and sell the Stradivarius
and use the money to pay off your loans.
I said you're wrong!
When the body was discovered
there was a chain on the door.
Nobody could enter or exit so the murderer
must have been inside the green room.
That day after Yuzuki Kyoko
refused your contract
you pretended to leave while
hiding yourself in the dressing room.
You were waiting for your chance
to steal the Stradivarius.
But then, Karashima showed up.
I got this email from Professor Komatsu
and I don't know what to do.
After Karashima left, Komatsu showed up.
- Kyoko!
- Stop it!
- Kyoko.
- Help! What are you doing?
You thought you were finally alone.
Ono-san, what are you...
Hey, we both have things we'd
like to hide now, don't we?
Let's calm down and have a talk.
Let's calm down and talk, okay?
Come on.
What should I do?
I know.
In that sound-proofed display room
you killed Komatsu and made it look
like an accident.
You tried to steal the Stradivarius
and escape but...
- I'm sorry I left the key inside.
- It's not a problem.
Is somebody in here? Open up.
Excuse me?
- Please wait here.
- All right.
And when everyone was focused
on the dead body
you saw everyone in the display room and
joined them like you'd come from outside.
Only you, who was in the display room with
Yuzuki Kyoko could have done this.
If Yuzuki Kyoko had been in the waiting
room, you couldn't have hidden.
Because the door to the green room
was chained shut
it created the illusion that the crime
had been a closed room mystery.
An enclosed space is so only because
you believe it is.
A closed room is so only because
No, no I didn't do it!
Shut up. Stop repeating yourself
you idiot.
How else could you have known that Komatsu
was making sexual advances on Yuzuki Kyoko?
The fact that you knew is proof that
you were hiding in the dressing room.
You need more evidence?
We have proof that you were looking for
buyers for the violin on the black market.
Stand up.
You are wanted for questioning in the case
of the murder of Komatsu Sadao.
Fukushima Reiko-san, you are wanted for
questioning in a case of larceny.
We will be taking testimonies
from all of you.
We couldn't have solved this case
without you, Midori-san.
The person who's saved ST
from being disbanded is
you, Midori-san.
Chief, you're just...
Never mind.
What? Please say what you were going to
say. I won't be able to sleep.
Perfect. Aren't you going to stay up
thinking of everyone's 100 possibilities?
Saving ST and thinking of everyone's
futures are two separate things.
Isn't anyone going to clean up
this violin?
Akagi-san?
That's the end of your report.
Good work.
Um, about the future of ST...
Never mind.
Excuse me.
Wait a second.
Yurine.
Look at this.
Director Matsudo's report on where each
member of ST should be transferred to.
She told me to toss it because
she wasn't going to be using it.
- Amazing.
- Yeah.
It is amazing.
A lot happened but everything
seems to have turned out well.
We were able to avoid
disbandment.
Hey have you thought of my
one hundred possibilities?
Not yet. I'm still working on
Aoyama-san's one hundred.
Are you sulking because I haven't gotten
to you? Maybe you're jealous?
Who are you talking to?
You don't have to get embarrassed.
- I'm not embarrassed.
- Yes you are.
Thank you.
- Tell me Aoyama's one hundred options.
- What?
- Tell me.
- Why should I tell you?
I'll do yours after I get through hers.
You'll just have to wait.
Subtitles by DramaFever