It's Thursday,
December 29th.
We left the hotel
about an hour ago
and everyone's sleeping.
But I... I can't...
I can't sleep because...
See that?
Surprise.
Ah... That's your daddy.
That's the best daddy.
Look at him.
Say, "Hi, Daddy".
- The van.
- Hmm?
Stop the van!
Yeah. Let it go!
Whoa! Yeah, bro!
Oh, get it all out!
Get it all out.
You okay?
- That is disgusting.
- I'm fine.
It's making my eyes water.
It smells like straight
whiskey.
Some nice greasy
hangover food will
be good for you.
Come on.
Yeah, let's get
some hangover food.
Mmm-mmm-mmm...
Oh! Round two!
This is all
my fault.
Well done.
Shut up!
Oh, yeah, man.
Eat them beans.
Beans and rice
mixing together...
Are you serious?
...having a party
in that stomach.
Are you serious?
Are you kidding me?
Make a web series out of this.
Just stop, man.
"Cole Pukes.
The Untold Story."
Mark, cut it out.
Why?
Give me a little spirit.
Why not?
Would you stop?
What? It's...
It's annoying.
You're being obnoxious.
Stop filming!
You're looking over
our little dossier?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm actually...
- Evil awaits us, huh?
Turn off the fucking
camera, Mark!
Dude, chill.
And your eyes are beautiful.
Give me the camera!
Give me the camera.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
Dude! Dude,
you'll hurt the camera!
Sorry, I just gotta tell ya,
my wife and I are such
big fans of your show.
- Huge fans.
- Thank you very much.
We have your entire
first season on DVD.
I don't know how you guys,
you know, go into all those
places and spend the night.
I get scared in the dark!
I don't mean to be nosy,
but what are you guys
doing here?
Are you going up
to Hillcrest?
Look at you, baby.
Baby, where are you?
There you are.
Hi.
Hmm...
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
So, how'd it go
with Mark?
Oh, I think
we're all good.
Yeah, it went okay?
Yeah.
Good. That's good.
I don't care. If we
don't get anything,
we don't get anything.
If they cancel the show,
that's no big deal.
I just want it to be...
I want to be real.
You gotta
stop worrying about it.
Okay?
All right.
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm not, just...
Just what?
Just 100 episodes
into a hit television show?
Oh, I'm so worried,
so worried.
It's amazing.
Hey, oh! A big part of...
You look so stupid!
He does not!
You're like a chipmunk!
Well, he says
whatever he wants.
He looks like an asshole.
Oh, my God,
he's gonna choke.
This is where you
start getting stuck.
Thank you very much.
Oh, my God!
Oh, no!
Seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one!
No! Open your mouth.
Open your mouth.
Open it, open it, open it.
Oh, my God!
All right.
Whoo!
That deserves
a nice handshake.
Wow!
Hey, either way,
the pretzels were delicious.
Yeah, okay, I don't want to
pay for anything tonight.
Well, come on,
you're $100 richer.
Yeah. Another round.
Barkeep!
Barkeep! Barkeep!
You can't say that.
Ready?
Why would you be
able to twist your arm
all the way around?
Oh, my God!
Ew! Ew! Ew!
You got this, Cole?
You got that? Yeah!
Nope, nope, nope.
Humans shouldn't
have to do that.
Guys, I can do...
Oh, my God!
Oh, no, no,
no, no, no!
Who wants to kiss me?
There we go.
Bare skin.
Oh,
there's the Wolfman!
Ow! That hurts so good!
All right, you're
eating that pretzel.
I'll give you $75 to
eat that pretzel.
I'm sorry I called
you a barkeep.
This is  GhostTrackers,
episode 100,
Hillcrest Sanatorium.
Camera A. Camera B.
All right, I'm rolling.
Hey, Ty.
Yeah.
As you can see,
we are packing up
for what is sure to be
one of the most
exciting investigations
we have ever done.
The location we're
going to is shrouded
with so much
secrecy and lore
that we're pretty sure
we're in store for
one heck of a night.
Yeah! We're the lucky bastards
that get to go in first!
Oh, shit!
All right,
let's watch it, guys.
God, I wanna get there.
Did we
pass a Stoney...
- A Stoney Hill... Lane?
- A Stoney Hill...
Stoney Hill Lane?
They're all stony hill lanes.
The phone
fucking keeps
freezing, man.
Man,
it's all our phones.
Okay, so, Sam, why don't
you tell us and our viewers
what's going on?
Well, what's going on is
we are currently lost,
which is a little embarrassing
as we are obviously
a van full of people
who can find the paranormal,
but no one can read
a fricking map!
It happens even to us.
Sometimes we get lost,
but these places are
in the middle of nowhere.
All right,
so can you tell us
why we're still lost?
What's going on right now?
Lost.
Sometimes you have to let
a spirit guide you.
I don't know, I think the
scariest places should be
the most difficult to find.
That's how I feel
personally, so...
Guys!
What?
I found it.
Got it?
Let's go!
Come on.
Spirit probably told her.
It's fucking cold.
Let's go!
Probably came in... Okay.
Found it. That's done.
Yeah, I know.
We got that.
Wow!
Oh, boy.
All right, that's it.
It looks...
...pretty creepy,
like we thought it would.
This is a big one for us.
- This is like our Super Bowl.
- This place is famous.
Oh, my God.
Do you see it's
all boarded up?
That's Irwin.
That's Irwin, the guy
who set this all up for us.
Oh, my God,
it's amazing.
Irwin?
Yeah, I'm Irwin.
Hey,
we're the GhostTrackers.
I know who you guys are.
I watched your show.
I watched just
the beginning of it.
You're Tyler, right?
That's me.
Hey, I'm Irwin.
How are ya?
Hey, thanks so much.
Samantha.
Sam, you know me
from the phone.
Yes. Cole. How are ya?
What's cooking?
Sir. Really good.
Hey. Mark, crack him up.
Oh, man, pleasure.
Hey, yeah. Oh, thanks, man.
How are you? The one
with the jokes and the
wisecracks, yeah.
Oh, Bridge, how are you?
How are you?
Good.
Always with the equipment
and stuff like that.
Great to meet you.
Welcome, you guys.
This is, like,
a part of the show?
Yeah. Yeah,
you're on camera right now.
Hey, Irwin, we're real
excited to get inside
the Sanatorium, so...
Sanatorium, technically,
it's now the Hillcrest
Nursing Home.
The Sanatorium closed down
years and years ago.
Then it was abandoned
for a couple years.
Uh-huh.
Then, around 1974,
some people came in.
They renovated the inside
and they made it
a nursing home.
It's the
Hillcrest Nursing Home,
so technically,
you're looking
at the abandoned
Hillcrest Nursing Home.
Well, you think we
can get inside,
take a quick look or...
Front door's locked.
There's a padlock.
I can't find the key.
We can't get in today.
I got a guy coming tomorrow
with one of those hydraulic
power bolt cutter things.
We can cut
the bolt on the door.
So we can get in tomorrow.
What if we get,
like, a state trooper
or something
just to, like,
shotgun it open?
No, no, no, no, no.
- Look around today.
- I appreciate it, man.
- Don't break nothing.
- I'm not...
If you break something,
I'm a ghost, 'cause
I'm dead meat.
All right. Yeah.
Yeah.
No, man,
I don't want you
haunting me, Irwin.
What? Oh, my God,
it's happening.
You're the man.
You're the man. Okay.
All right.
You're the strong man.
Okay?
I am big.
Yeah. Yeah.
All right,
yep, and in...
And there we go.
What are you...
What are you zooming in on?
The window.
It's a scary window.
I know it's the...
No, it's not scary.
It's the same shot
we always get, man.
It's a pretty
scary window, man.
You're doing what we
normally do. I want to
do something different.
- Oh, shit.
- You got it.
The sky's the limit, man.
We can go anywhere with this.
We're gonna... Why can't we
have 10 million viewers?
But that's what I'm saying.
You have 1,800.
I have 150,000.
You need to step up
your game, dude.
Great, it's our 100th
episode, that's 100...
That means 100 fucking
episodes of the same thing.
Episode.
Watch the DVD,
you're gonna see
the same shit.
Right.
Two more.
What the fuck was that?
Did you hear that?
Nursing home came and
went before I started, uh,
taking care of the property.
That was '74, or '76.
Before your time.
Yeah, before I started
taking care of the place.
Didn't those two boys
go missing a couple
years ago?
Nobody wants to talk about it.
Between you and me
and the grand piano,
I don't think anything
happened to them in there.
I think they were just playing
around somewhere,
and some pedophile freak was
passing through the area,
scooped them up.
If they were playing
around this property,
I would have known.
This place is huge.
I mean, you're only one man.
You only have two eyes.
I'm in charge of this place.
I'm in charge of everything
that comes and goes.
I see what
goes on here, okay?
It's my job.
Irwin, do you believe
in ghosts?
Do I believe in ghosts?
Yeah.
I believe in ghosts.
As far as this place, nah.
This is just
a dumpy old,
scary old building.
It's scary looking.
You'll see what it's like.
It's just a bunch of rooms.
Let's check out this, uh...
I saw this window here.
What the hell?
Oh, hey, man.
No, no, no, no.
Irwin's over there,
so just keep it cool.
All right.
All right?
- You getting this?
- Yeah.
All right,
ladies and gentlemen.
You're gonna get
a little preview here.
So, uh...
Watch the glass.
I know.
All right,
go, go, go.
Oh! Jesus Christ!
Mark, you weren't trying to
go in there, were you?
No, man.
Okay, deal's a deal.
No, I got you, dude.
Okay. You go in today,
I lose my job.
I got you, man.
We were just
taking a peek, that's all.
All right. I will.
Okay. You're the man.
Fucking asshole.
Jesus Christ.
"For our 100th episode,
we will investigate
claims of apparitions,
"disembodied voices,
and the apparent abductions
that have happened here."
How's that? Good?
I think that was perfect.
All right, action.
Just behind me is the
infamous Hillcrest Sanatorium.
Built in 1908...
- It's all right. Relax.
- Let's do it again.
Just behind me
is the infamous
Hillcrest Sanatorium.
Oh, fuck me!
With the discovery
of antibio... Um...
And, uh...
Many died
and went insane.
Griz... Grizzly...
I'm guessing it's
for the little kids or
something like that,
but we could
probably spin it.
Right? About the patients
that stayed here?
Yeah, that makes sense.
Does that make sense?
Cool.
So, uh, Cole and I
discovered these flowers
left by family members
of the poor souls that
lost their lives here in
this gruesome sanatorium.
I think tonight,
during our investigation,
I'm going to be dedicating
everything I can to...
Hey, man. Wait, wait.
Wait. Hold on, man.
What? What?
There was something
in the window.
What?
There was something
in that window.
It looked like a...
It looked like a little kid.
There was something...
There's a little kid
in the window?
There was something
in the window. There was
a kid in that window, man.
Okay. Get this.
Get this then.
Hey, little kid!
If you're in the window,
show yourself!
Dude...
No, man. Check the tape.
Dude,
you're doing good, man.
You don't have to
ham it up here.
I'm serious, man,
there was a kid in there!
Okay.
...dedicating everything
I can to...
Wait, wait, wait...
Hold on, man.
Right there,
right in the window,
then it goes away.
I see it.
No!
I think there's
something there.
It could be a shadow,
but there's...
There is something.
There's definitely something.
No, do it again.
I didn't see anything.
...dedicating everything
I can to...
Hey, man. Wait, wait, wait.
Wait. Hold on, man.
What?
A little boy?
Yeah!
Say you saw
a monster or something.
Well, maybe it was a monster.
We'll find out when
we get there, right?
I was there,
I didn't see anything.
Either way, it's definitely
worth checking out.
When we go inside,
we'll have to...
I don't know.
Take a good look
around that room.
Maybe see what
we can draw out.
Haven't even gone inside
and we're already,
maybe seeing things.
Maybe it's our emotions
getting the best of us.
Either way,
it's pretty exciting.
All right, so it's 4:30 a.m.
and I'm trying to stay up.
We're all trying to stay up
as long as possible.
You know, so tomorrow night
no one's slacking around
or anything like that.
But my buddy Cole
is sleeping.
Might need a little drink
to wake him up. Hunh?
A little wake up call. Hmm?
Hello, oh, hello.
Hey!
Man, you're so...
Really?
Dude, don't break
the camera, man.
Jesus Christ, man.
What the fuck?
Oh...
Only one person who that
could be at 4:30 a.m.
Someone's getting ass...
Hi!
Why are you guys filming?
Someone left something on,
like, Tyler and Sam's door,
It has to do with Hillcrest.
We're in their room now.
Okay...
You guys want info
on Hillcrest? Here it is.
- What the fuck?
- Yeah.
And here he is.
Richard Howl.
- Holy shit.
- What?
Wait, let me get this.
Oh, my God,
this is great.
Wait. Hold up, Ty.
This was taken on
New Year's Day?
Holy shit!
Richard Howl murdered
three children
on New Year's Eve, 1955.
He brutally murders
the three kids
and then hangs himself.
- Oh, my God.
- Yup.
So, holiday party
right before
it all happened,
three of these kids, dead.
How old were they?
11...
The youngest one was 8.
11, 11 and 8.
Just little ones.
- Is that the police report?
- Can I get that?
Some of his ribs
were removed.
What?
And it's actually
like this.
It's that way?
Part of this lung is gone.
What the...
Wait.
Why did they do that?
He had TB and he was
getting experimented on.
What?
Yes,
Hillcrest was kind of...
From here it says
that they would do...
Yeah, exactly, Cole.
Experiments.
It was like the patient
had nothing to live for.
Fourteen people
in a room? Jesus.
I'm just really scared.
I don't want to
go tomorrow.
Well, it's just gonna
get scarier.
I think it's really scary.
I didn't know the kids
were so young.
This is what we do.
I didn't think it was
real, guys. I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
I'll be there.
You guys are in
for such a treat.
I cannot wait for tomorrow.
Is it tomorrow yet?
Technically, it is tomorrow.
Technically,
we're about to go!
Whoo!
And, uh...
It's on the anniversary
that he hung himself.
- Wow.
- There it is. Yes.
The Hillcrest Sanatorium.
Oh, come on.
He's wearing different
clothes than yesterday.
Great.
The last thing
I said to him,
I specifically said,
"Please wear
the same clothes".
Awesome.
I kinda plowed earlier
before you guys came.
A little bit, not plowed,
but I kinda stomped it down.
I'm ready to go in,
you ready to go in?
Let's do it.
Okay.
You all over 18, right?
Most of us. Yeah.
Okay. Ready?
Here we go.
Might be a couple of rats,
but don't worry.
Okay, there's a lot
of water here.
Might be some ice.
Now, the Sanatorium
was built in 1908
as just a wellness center
for people
in the countryside.
It was supposed to have
about 30 patients.
Then, when the
white plague hit,
there was well over 500 people
in here at any given time.
Just squeezed in every nook
and cranny in the facility.
It was a very,
very sad place.
People from all over were
trying to get in here.
So, how many people
were still stuck here?
About 1,000 people
died in here.
What?
1,000 people
died here in five years.
During the height of
the plague, this was
the draining room.
When somebody would die
from their tuberculosis
and at the peak
of the plague,
that was happening,
like, every day,
they would take
the dead bodies and
there were poles here,
and they would hang
the bodies by their neck.
but just, you know,
keep them up from here.
And they would make
an incision from the sternum
all the way down
to the groin
so that all the fluids
in the body would drain out.
Back then they didn't know
and they thought
by removing the fluids
before they shipped the
bodies out for disposal,
they could contain
the infection to
the facility. Okay?
Bridget?
Yes.
We should set up
a static camera right here.
All right.
I want to get full
coverage of this room.
- Okay.
- Oh, guys. Guys.
Ooh...
I feel a lot of
static energy right here.
Right here.
It's pulling me in.
- Irwin, come here.
- What?
Feel this.
Put your hands here.
You feel that?
Nah, man.
What are you talking about?
It's right here.
Nah, nothing there.
This is its origin, here.
Right here.
During the
nursing home period,
this was...
As you might be able to tell,
this was the kitchen.
You know, stoves,
ovens, sinks.
But before that,
this exact same room,
back in the Sanatorium days,
was the autopsy room
in the morgue.
What?
Yeah.
So we're talking
a lot of bodies
in this room.
A lot of people who went
through probably horribly
traumatic deaths.
And this is where
they were stored.
This is where
they were dissected.
Tyler! Come in here.
Feel this.
It's like 20 degrees colder
in here than in there.
It's freezing in here.
Cole, get in here!
It's definitely...
It's noticeably colder
in this room.
This place is evil.
Anybody else's limbs
hurt right now?
Like my limbs, like my elbows
and all my joints, right?
Yeah.
Between you and me,
I think it's just cold
'cause it's winter.
You know?
Yeah.
Watch out for hoses here.
There's a lot of...
Whoa!
Jesus Christ! Fuck me!
It's all right.
It's just something fell.
What'd you see, Mark?
Oh! I don't know.
What fell?
Let's get the fuck
out of here.
This doesn't feel safe, guys.
So he was right up there?
Yeah. Right up there where
the plaster's missing.
That crazy light
wasn't there back then,
but they came in
and found him dangling right
from that spot there.
I know you can hear us,
Richard Howl.
I know you're
watching us right now.
I can feel you.
You did that
to those kids, Richard?
to those kids?
Try that on me.
Try that on me!
Okay. Uh...
- I think we can cut?
- Let's do it.
- Dick Howl.
- Real tough, Mark.
All right.
Action!
This is the room where
the infamous patient
Richard Howl lived.
Richard suffered
from a severe strain
of tuberculosis
which slowly consumed
him from within.
He unfortunately
volunteered for many
experimental surgeries.
These surgeries would later
drive him completely mad.
He had eight rib cage bones
removed from his chest
and one of
his lungs collapsed.
It was in this room
on New Year's Eve,
December 31st, 1955,
that Richard
took his own life
after brutally bludgeoning
three children to death
while they were
sleeping in their beds.
This is where
they were killed.
Irwin.
Don't sneak up
on me like that.
Sorry.
The three kids,
viciously beaten
in this room.
What happened in here
creeps me out
when I'm by myself.
This is definitely a room
that we gotta stay in.
I want you guys
to be extra careful.
It is really, really
dark down here.
That is what was called
"The Passage to Paradise".
Dead bodies on gurneys were
rolled through this maze
for waiting hearses.
The doctors were thinking
it would stop the spread
of infection.
It also would have
relieve the patients
from seeing death.
This is a sad place.
It is really dark
down here.
Actually,
let's turn off our lights
to show you guys
just how dark it really is.
Get 'em all off.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is what we see
when the lights go out.
And we can only see the LCD
screens on these cameras.
Infrared.
No infrared.
- That's pretty dark.
- Told ya.
That concludes the tour.
Sorry. No gift shop.
- We can't thank you enough.
- Yeah, thanks, Irwin.
- It's been amazing.
- We appreciate it.
Anything for you guys.
Just put that thing as
far away as possible.
I don't want to hear it.
So, these are
motion detectors.
If any mass or energy passes
through, an alarm will sound.
Okay.
Hmm?
Hillcrest Sanatorium.
Everything's getting set up.
The sun's about to go down
and things are
about to get wild.
Oh, fuck!
I feel like
I just got tripped.
There's nothing around that
could have tripped me.
Maybe it was myself.
I don't know.
Could have been.
But I don't think so.
Anybody here
trying to freak me out?
Trying to scare me
out of here?
You're gonna have to do
better than that.
I'm all alone here.
Nobody else is here.
There's nothing here.
But I ate it pretty hard.
Gonna be sore tomorrow.
What is that?
Guys?
Hello?
Fuck!
Found a bowling ball.
Fucking asshole.
Why would you do that?
It's New Year's Eve night.
56 years since Richard Howl's
brutal rampage.
We're here at the
Hillcrest Sanatorium,
about to enter, record
and document some of
the strange phenomena
that has been reported here.
Any last words for us?
Happy New Year's.
- Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year, Irwin.
Thank you. Thank you.
All right.
So our cameras
are all set up.
We've got this
whole place covered.
We've got the kitchen.
We've got every hallway,
the children's wing.
We've got outside in front.
We've also got
motion detectors
in Howl's room,
the children's wing,
and there's also one
right behind me
so that Mark doesn't pull
a single thing.
Thank you, Bridget.
We've got a great
opportunity here
to capture some really good
activity in this building.
Let's break up into teams.
Sam and I are
gonna be one team.
And of course,
Mark and Cole another.
Bridget's gonna stay here
and monitor all our activity.
Let's do this, guys.
One, two, three...
Lights out!
Let's go!
Okay.
Night vision on, guys.
Oh, careful!
Damn it.
Watch your step, okay?
A lot of boards with
nails in 'em. Watch out.
All right.
Copy that.
Set.
This is an EMF detector.
Ghosts, spirits,
they're said to give off
electromagnetic energy.
If one gets close to me,
this is gonna spike.
Any people who were
tortured in here,
we're not gonna hurt you.
Just come close to us.
We don't try to
just spice things up.
If I'm not picking
up anything,
there's nothing in here.
Sometimes that happens.
I'm Mark, this is Cole.
We're about to descend down
to the Passage to Paradise.
Start our investigation.
Here we go.
Oh, dude,
it smells so bad.
This is gross.
There's
water on the ground.
That's nice.
What's going on in here?
Yeah, this is...
I'd live here.
Jesus.
Dude!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Dude, dude, dude!
Shut up! Come on.
Over here.
Jesus!
What the fuck?
What is this?
Look at the wall.
What the fuck is that?
There's just drawings.
They're people
on the wall.
Looks like a dragon
about to attack a devil
holding a baby.
Look at that.
Look at the dragon.
Right.
Oh, look at
the baby flying out.
Holy shit!
That is that.
It's fucking...
There's just
one singular bathroom.
Gross.
What the fuck?
What is that?
What did we just see?
Look at it.
Go down, go down.
Ready? And, hello.
Oh...
This is Tyler and Samantha.
We're in the dining room
headed towards the kitchen.
Do you hear that?
No, what?
I thought...
Nothing, forget about it.
It's nothing.
- Dude, dude!
- What? What?
Shit! Shit! Shit!
What?
There's a big spider!
Spider up... Spider!
There's a spider over here?
Dude, there's a spider on...
Get it off my face.
Get it off my face!
You don't have
a spider on your face.
There you go. Got it.
You okay? You okay?
Yeah.
Can you make it?
Fuck you, dude!
All right.
Oh, what the...
Shit!
You all right?
There's all
sorts of stuff here.
Whoa.
What? Oh, nice.
Why?
Yes!
Got to do
something with that.
So, I, uh...
So, I found this gurney.
I don't know who put it
here, but it's here.
I'm gonna lay down on it.
Maybe feel some
spirits go through me.
Maybe just listen for them.
They're coming.
Oh, yeah!
Just listen.
Whoa! Oh, shit!
Hey, what do you want to do?
You want to move on?
Shh! I heard something.
What?
Footsteps right over here.
I'm gonna call Bridge, okay?
Samantha to Bridget.
Hey, can you roll
back the kitchen feed
about a minute or so,
and tell us if you
see or hear anything?
You got it.
Copy, thanks.
Hey, what do you
want to do?
You want to move on?
Shh! I heard something.
What?
Footsteps right over here.
Hey, what do you
want to do?
You want to move on?
Shh! I heard something.
What?
Footsteps right over here.
Hey,
what do you want to do?
You want to move on?
Shh! I heard...
Shh!
You want to move on?
Hey, guys.
So I reviewed the footage
a couple of times,
and, Tyler, when you
approached the piping
in the center of the room,
there's definitely
something interesting
in front of you.
I can't say for sure
what it is until I analyze
the footage more, but...
I think we might have
a possible orb.
A possible orb?
I knew it.
I knew we had
something right over here.
We just heard it.
If you're still with us,
please let us know!
Give us some kind of sign,
some kind of signal.
Anything, any kind of noise.
Don't be afraid.
This is a digital recorder.
We use it because
the microphone can
pick up things
that the human ear
can't hear.
Hello?
If there's someone in here,
you can say something
into the little red light.
If you have anything to say,
we'll be able to hear you.
That thing just fell.
I was just
laying on the gurney
for 30 minutes,
nothing going on.
Gurney just fell
out of nowhere.
No explanation,
just fell, just lost all...
Something doesn't
want us here.
Something's saying,
"Get out".
"Not in my house.
"You're not laying
in my room."
There's paranormal activity
going on right here,
something's paranormal.
We have to go,
we have to move on,
we're going up to
the freezer room
right now.
Hello?
Mark?
Sam and Tyler,
Mark and Cole,
can I get a quick location
check from you guys?
Hey, Bridge,
Tyler and I are just
outside the medical wing.
Yeah, me and Cole are on
our way into the freezer room.
Hello?
Is someone there?
We're filming in here
so it's...
-  Bridget.
Is everything okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
You scared the shit
out of me.
All right, set that.
You good?
Yeah, that'll work.
All right.
But this...
People that perished from
the tuberculosis were
brought down to this room.
They were strung up by
their necks and sliced,
from their sternums
down to their groins,
releasing all
bodily fluids.
They didn't know how
to control the disease.
You want to get
some promo stills?
I got my camera here.
Yeah.
All right.
Good idea.
All right, hold on.
There you are.
Give me more face.
All right.
Dude, dude, dude!
What? What?
Cole! Dude!
Are you all right, man?
Cole!
Dude, come on, man.
I can't see shit.
Cole.
Dude,
what are you doing, man?
All right, good stuff, dude.
Can't see.
Christ!
God...
Dude, the camera's
on the ground?
Good job, asshole!
Goddamn it!
All right.
Funny, dude.
Great job.
Cole!
Dude, come on, man.
I don't have time
for this shit.
Seriously, man.
What the fuck?
Dude, what are you doing?
You want to break
the fucking camera?
Careful.
Cole!
Dude, what are you doing?
What... Dude!
Dude.
What the fuck, man?
What do you mean, what?
You're such an asshole.
What is...
Did we get it?
Did we...
Kiss my ass, man!
You wanna break the camera?
You wanna break our things?
Don't be an asshole, man.
This is Tyler and Sam.
We're in the medical
wing in the building.
People who entered
this room were
extremely brave.
This is where the most
drastic measures were taken.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
I heard something.
Shh.
Tyler to Mark, come in.
Tyler to Mark.
Yes. What's up, Tyler?
Hey, man,
how's the medical wing?
I don't care if
you don't believe me,
all right?
My heart's
pounding right now.
Is it music?
Yeah, that's what I think.
Let's try this way.
So weird,
it was right here.
It was coming
from right here.
I think it's coming
from upstairs now.
It's crazy, right?
Like it keeps changing.
Whoa!
What? What? What?
The curtain just moved.
What do you mean
the curtain just moved?
I mean,
the curtain moved, Sam.
It's just the wind.
No, no, wait, wait,
wait, wait, no, wait.
Why?
I don't know.
I feel weird.
I'm nervous.
Don't be nervous.
Come on.
Where'd it go?
- Fuck! It's a radio.
- What?
Fucking Mark
hid the radio.
Calm down. Calm down.
You don't know if it was Mark.
This is the exact
kind of shit he pulls.
I'm done dealing
with this guy.
Oh, come on.
What?
How many times
have you said that?
I mean, I work so
hard for this show.
He does nothing
except fuck around.
Look at this.
Let me see it.
Hey, babe,
how did Mark
make a radio work
with no batteries
and not plugged in?
Well.
He could have
rigged something up.
There's a million places
where he could have...
Don't get
overexcited, okay? Just...
I'm not overexcited!
Yes, you are!
Just... I just wish
that you'd calm down.
Come on!
I know. I know you
care about the show.
I know you're only looking
out for the show.
Nobody knows that
more than me, baby.
I'm sick of dealing
with this guy.
Wait, what time is it?
Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
Whoo!
Hey! Happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
100 shows! 100 shows!
Where are you, Bridge?
Happy New Year!
Now it's my turn!
Oh, I love you.
Happy New Year!
Reality. This year, this
clothing that you can wear,
just looks like a black
shirt on regular light.
When infrared light
hits it, it's a totally
different ballgame.
There's patterns and, like,
a maze of mystery on it.
And, I don't know.
I think that could sell.
I think it'd sell a lot.
Make coats, make pants.
Surprise!
Aw, yeah.
GhostTrackers,
we're all playing with,
like...
Um... Hey, guys.
I'm sorry, I don't mean to
interrupt. I just...
Yeah, we have some big news.
- I'm pregnant! I'm pregnant!
- What?
Oh, my God!
I knew it!
I totally knew it!
Did you know?
Oh, no, that
I wasn't pregnant.
We've been...
I'm in shock still. I...
I know, I just told him,
like, literally a second ago,
and I don't know if
you guys knew this...
for a really long time.
Uncle Mark says hi.
Wow, that's so...
I didn't think this episode
would get any better,
but it just did.
That's really great,
you guys.
You're all fucking uptight,
you're having a kid,
it's New Years, just relax!
Yeah,
I know those things.
Yeah, okay, well...
And I also know
you put a fucking radio
in the bathroom.
I didn't put a fucking...
Why would I put a fucking
radio in the bathroom?
Why would I put a radio
in the bathroom?
And for our 100th episode,
we got something new.
Sam, tell us what we got.
Oh! Well, actually,
Bridget's the expert.
I just call it
the Sam-Cam.
It's the Sam-Cam,
but really
it's just a body cam.
Um, and it records audio,
it's got a flash drive.
And it's just a tiny thing
so she can be handsfree
while she does
the investigation.
Yes, so from now on
in the sanatorium,
whatever I see,
you will see.
We're here inside
Richard Howl's room,
and we set up
some motion detectors.
That'll give us an
audio alarm if anything
breaks that barrier
and comes in
around that doorway.
I also set up this chair,
right underneath where
Richard Howl killed himself.
I'm gonna sit here
and hopefully gather
some evidence for
our investigation.
Richard, are you here?
I know you suffered a lot
while you lived here.
You had a hard life.
But what you did
to those kids,
that was unacceptable.
What are you doing?
Just trying to
provoke him a little bit.
All right, Mark.
If you're here,
just give us a sign.
We just want to know
if you're still here.
If you're here,
touch my arm, Richard.
Come on.
I'm gonna wait here
all night.
I know this is where
you killed yourself.
I don't care
how long it takes.
All right,
now can we
try it my way?
Sitting quietly in the dark.
I'm so done
with this, man.
What is up Tyler's ass?
It's just like...
Just trying to make this
show better. That's it.
I know, man.
He doesn't get that.
It's his thing, man.
Wait, do you feel that?
What?
It's right here.
Dude, what are you?
Getting possessed again?
What are you doing?
Don't steal my
goose bump line, man.
I'm not stealing your
fucking goose bump line.
It's a heat.
Dude, you're freaking
me out, man.
There's a heat. Shut up.
It is warm over here.
It's warm.
What is that?
It's here.
Yeah.
Whoa. It's hot.
You feel okay?
Yeah.
I don't feel good.
What?
I don't feel good, man.
Dude. You gonna throw up?
No, it's...
Dude, you're
freaking me out.
I know. Oh, God, it's...
Dude!
Oh, God. No, no, no.
Bro, chill.
Dude, give me a second.
Dude, you're
freaking me out.
It's too hot.
What is that?
What the fuck?
Dude, that sounded
like a little girl, man.
Are you the little girl
that was hurt in this room?
We're your friends.
We won't hurt you or anything.
We just...
Why don't you
show yourself?
Dude, what the...
What's that?
What was that?
Guys, get down to
the children's ward now!
Now!
We got real
fucking activity.
Real activity.
Class A EVPs.
Right now.
Get down here.
Dude, oh my God.
Dude, that was real.
That was...
That's the first time in
nine years, that's a real...
You want to go
check it out?
Go for it.
I mean, of course,
I want to check it out.
You don't want to go?
Something could
happen here.
I feel like
I should stick around.
All right.
I've waited here
long enough.
Are you sure?
Nervous, yes?
I think something
could happen here too.
Okay. Well,
good luck with that.
I'm going,
if you're sure.
Yeah.
Okay. I love you.
I love you too.
Bye.
Oh, fuck.
Ty, my battery just died.
Oh, shit! Fuck.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I got a dead brick.
Do you have a flashlight?
Yes.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hello?
Is somebody here?
Ow!
Ow! Oh! Ow!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Ah!
Oh, fuck. Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Oh, no.
Oh, please, no.
Oh!
Oh, shit, Samantha,
fucking klutz.
Shit.
Goddamn it.
Yeah, don't step on this.
There's some advice.
Guys,   I'm freaking out right now.
Where are you?
There is little kids up here.
This little ghost ki...
No thank you, please.
Again, do it again.
No, thank you, please.
Whoa.
It's a little girl.
That's a little girl.
It's clearly a little girl.
That is a little girl.
You heard it with your ears.
You heard this
with your ears?
We heard this with our ears,
believe me.
Give it to me.
No, thank you, please.
God.
"No, thank you..."
"No, thank you, please."
That's an EVP,
a disembodied voice
in this room.
Yup.
In the children's wing.
No, thank you, please.
Did you listen to this
all the way through?
I think so.
Come here, come here.
Tell me what you hear.
-  No, thank you, please.
There.
Did you hear that?
Play it again.
-  No, thank you, please.
"Go away."
No, thank you, please.
Go away.
You hear that, right?
Yeah.
That's two...
Two disembodied
voices recorded.
Jesus Christ.
GhostTrackers,
100 episodes...
I didn't hear that.
Hillcrest Sanatorium.
We have evidence
of the paranormal.
Tyler is going to
shit in his pants.
You didn't hear that,
right, Cole?
No.
Cole, listen, listen, listen.
Did you hear, like, "Go away?"
You didn't hear that part
with your ears?
No, I didn't.
This is amazing.
One more time.
Listen again.
No, thank you, please.
Go away.
"Go away."
Sometimes we
like to use trigger objects
to try to coax
any spirits in the room
to interact with us.
In this case, Mark and Cole
successfully recorded
the disembodied voice
of a little girl,
so we're using candy canes
as a trigger object.
We've also lowered ourselves
down to her level
to make her feel
more comfortable.
You're recording?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Hello?
Is there anybody here?
Is there a little girl
here with us?
I know you're here,
we heard you.
We'd love to
hear you again.
We brought you some candy.
Do you see this candy?
You can have all
the candy you want.
You can touch it,
you can take it.
My name is Samantha.
What's your name?
Can you tell me
your name?
Be quiet.
I told you.
I told you!
I told...
I fucking told you.
Did you hear that?
Richard, are you in here?
I'm here on the
anniversary of the night
you killed those kids.
You want to do something?
Do something to me.
Come on, Richard.
Hello?
Samantha to Tyler.
Tyler, come in.
Tyler, come in! Come on,
you got to get up here.
You're missing everything.
Tyler, what are you doing?
Come on.
Samantha to Tyler.
Tyler, go. Tyler.
Sam, the Howl feed just
went dead for some reason.
It's working now.
Tyler isn't in the room.
I think you guys
should go check on him
and make sure he's okay.
Okay.
Okay, copy, yeah.
I'm going back.
Tyler!
Ty!
This stupid thing.
All right,
I left him right here.
Come on.
Tyler, baby,
where'd you go?
- Tyler?
- What the fuck?
Come on, Tyler!
if you see Tyler
anywhere in the building?
He's not in
Richard Howl's room.
None of them?
Check again.
Whoa!
- What the fuck?
- What?
Guys, check this out.
What the fuck was that?
Wow.
The fucking chair just
flies across the room?
The chair
just moved.
I was here a second ago,
and it just moved.
And the...
The alarm went off.
Come on,
he set this shit up.
What is he doing?
Dude, if he's fucking
with me right now,
he's winning,
I'll tell you that.
There's nobody here.
This room is hot.
And the temperature's
going way up.
This whole area
is red hot.
Look, he's shaking.
Tyler!
- What? Come on!
- Tyler!
Come on!
Are you fucking
with me right now?
Tyler!
Come on!
Call the police.
Call the what?
I said, "Call the police."
How am I supposed to call?
There's no fucking
service here!
How am I supposed
to call the police?
We'll go get...
No, go get them.
Go get the police.
Come on! Is he fucking
with me? Sam, is he fucking
with me right now?
Is he fucking with you?
Yeah, is he fucking
with me right now?
Did you see what was
on that video cam?
Is he trying to get back
at me for all the bullshit?
It's such bullshit!
Would you just
shut up for once?
What do you want?
What are you talking about?
I don't know
what I just saw.
Mark,
shut the fuck up, man.
I don't know what I just
saw on that camera...
What the fuck was that?
All right,
we gotta get back.
We gotta get...
You go to a place outside.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Tyler!
What the fuck
was that?
Tyler!
What the fuck was that there?
Tyler, it's me!
Where are you?
Don't fuck with me, Tyler!
Don't...
Tyler!
- Tyler?
- Tyler!
- Tyler.
Tyler.
Hang on.
Fuck. Fuck.
Tyler?
Tyler!
Shit!
- Guys.
- What?
All the doors are open.
Fuck.
Are you kidding me?
All these doors are
open now? Come on!
Tyler?
Tyler.
Bridget to Samantha.
Take the camera.
Go for Samantha.
Go for Samantha, Bridget!
Motion sensors
just went off
in the children's wing.
Copy that.
- Children's wing.
- Fucking shit.
- Fuck this place!
- Tyler!
- Come on, Tyler!
Tyler!
- Tyler!
- Fuck.
Come on, Tyler.
Fuck.
Tyler, are you up here?
Dude.
It's warm here.
- Dude, your jacket.
- What's happening?
Dude.
Cole.
Cole! Cole! Cole!
What is it?
Cole! Cole!
Cole!
Shit!
Cole, where are you going?
What the fuck is
wrong with you, man?
Where are you going?
Why are you running, Cole?
Cole, stop running!
Cole, why are you running?
Just stop! Why?
What are you running from?
Cole, just come back
to home base!
Ow!
I don't know where he went!
Mark, where are you going?
Mark, no!
Please don't leave me!
Please don't!
I'm not!
Where did you go?
Calm down, calm down.
I'm not...
Why have you...
You calm down!
I don't know what to do!
I don't have my husband!
What do you want me to do?
I don't know,
I don't know, I don't know.
We'll get out of here.
We'll find them and we'll
get out of here. I swear.
Okay.
Just breathe.
Just breathe, okay?
All right?
Okay.
Let's go, come on.
Come on, come on.
Okay.
Bridg!
Bridget!
Mark, where is she?
Fuck me.
Fucking... Bridget!
Bridget!
Bridget, what happened?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Her neck.
What? Oh, you're bleeding.
There's blood on her neck.
What happened?
Fuck!
What happened, Bridget?
Here, here.
Just put this on it, honey.
What the fuck?
What the fuck is going on?
We're gonna help you.
Please answer.
Cole. Come on, Cole.
Come on.
Where are you, buddy?
Come on, buddy.
There he is! There he is!
He's in the freezer room!
Quit...
What the fuck?
Come on, guys.
Come on, we got to
go to the freezer room.
Come on.
- This isn't good.
- Cole!
This isn't good, Mark!
Where are you, buddy?
Don't worry.
This one?
This one? You're sure?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We're close.
He's not here.
How did... Wait...
Wait a sec. Wait.
Get out of the way.
What is that?
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my...
- Oh, my God! Bridget!
- Help me!
That was Cole.
Bridget!
- That was Cole! Go! Go!
- Cole!
Bridget. Bridget,
come on, we've got to go.
Come on, Cole.
Help me!
What's going on?
- Wh...
- Help!
- Cole? Cole!
- Cole! Cole!
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
What the fuck?
- Help!
- Fuck. What the fuck?
- Cole!
- Help me!
Cole. Cole,
stay where you are, man.
We're coming for you, dude.
Let me see. Fuck.
It's open.
Help me!
It's coming
from here. It's this way.
Help!
Cole!
Oh, my God!
Mark, what the fuck
is that?
- Cole!
- Mark?
- Help!
- Cole!
- Cole! Cole!
What the fuck?
Cole!
What the fuck? Cole!
This room is empty.
Bro, where are you?
Shut the fuck...
It was coming from in here.
Where the fuck is Bridget?
She was right behind me.
Where's...
What the fuck?
Jesus fuck!
Bridget!
Bridget! Bridget!
Where the fuck is she?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, shit! Shit!
Bridget!
Are you in there?
Watch out, watch out!
Bridget! Bridget!
Open the door, Mark.
Open the fucking door!
I'm trying!
Bridget!
That's it, that's it!
We gotta go!
We gotta go now! Run!
Just run! Run!
No, we can't leave...
Just run! Go!
Bridget!
Run!
Come.
Don't!
I'm scared.
No! Mark...
Shit.
Oh, shit. Fuck.
Go, go, go.
Mark...
We can't leave...
Go. Oh, shit!
Fuck!
Go! Go!
We're gonna go
to the police
and we're gonna go back.
I don't give a shit! Go!
Don't fucking tell me!
Just go!
That's my husband,
and I can't just leave him!
What are you doing?
I don't know!
Go!
I don't know what to do!
I don't give a shit! Go!
I'm trying. Oh, my God.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
Wait, Tyler!
Tyler!
That's my husband.
That's my husband! Tyler!
Sam, no! No, Sam!
Sam, don't!
Babe!
Sam!
Please don't go back in!
- Tyler!
- Sam!
No! No!
No...
Tyler! Tyler!
Mark? No, no.
No. Please, no!
No, no! No, Mark!
No!  No!
No!
I know you're here.
What do you want?
Tyler!
Tyler, we have
to get out of here.
Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
Tyler!
Tyler, where are you?
Help me! Help me!
Please, someone help me!
Someone!
Someone please help me!
Please!
God damn it!
Somebody please!
Shut up!
Oh, my God! Help! Help!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
No! No! No!
No, no! Please!
So Cole and I are walking
around the perimeter,
just scouting things out,
and then we discover
our boy Irwin over here.
I thought he was
taking a piss.
He's just
talking to no one.
Absolutely no one.
Or, maybe he's
talking to a demon.
Dude, seriously,
this guy's out of his mind.
He's crazy, man.
What's he doing?
No, no, no, no, no.