♪ If you've got a friend ♪
♪ that you want messed up ♪
♪ Just meet me on the corner ♪
♪ by the Tail of the Pup ♪
♪ I'll be there soon ♪
♪ if you'll wait a while ♪
♪ It'll be just one punch ♪
♪ for my patience ♪
♪ And a drawer full ♪
♪ of dirty shirts ♪
♪ We'll find out ♪
♪ just who hurts 'cause ♪
♪ Bing can't walk ♪
♪ Bob broke both his legs ♪
♪ You're the one ♪
♪ that I'll remember ♪
♪ Most of all tonight ♪
♪ Someone let go of my string ♪
♪ I'm fallin' down ♪
♪ like a broken kite ♪
♪ Who's to say, ♪
♪ and who's to know ♪
♪ They don't know what I know ♪
♪ There's something ♪
♪ out there floatin' free ♪
♪ Anything I had is tangled up ♪
♪ In the branches ♪
♪ of a hangman's tree ♪
♪ Bing can't walk ♪
♪ Bob broke both his legs ♪
Great tune.
That was a request from
my mom back in England.
And this is Richard Blaine
on KSLM.
Let's go to the phones again
here on the Blaine Line.
Give us a call with
your personal problems,
predictions, and political beefs.
Hello, you're on the air.
Uh, we'll get back to you.
Now, let's go to our next
caller here at KSLM.
Hello, you're on the air.
It's Cletus, man.
I'm in trouble again.
Oh, no, not you Cletus.
What's wrong now?
Man, I'm in the county jail.
So, what happened, Cletus?
There was this chick, all right.
She was unbelievable. She was
on the corner at Sunset.
So, what is it you need, Cletus?
Give me some advice, Blaine.
I need someone to get
me out of here, man.
Cletus, you're a lucky man.
Because I got this friend who plays
a mean guitar and he's studying law
and right now he's in county jail.
So, look for Pete, Cell 47.
He can get anyone out.
Wait, what's his name?
I'm sorry, Cletus,
we're out of time.
This is my only call, man.
Next caller, please.
Hello, you're on the air.
Hello?
Hold it, hold it, this isn't me.
Did I fool you? This is
an answering machine.
Pretty nifty, huh?
So, if you'll wait for the tone
I'll be happy to
pass it along to Drood
whenever he comes home or
wakes up or whatever he does.
Are you ready?
Drood, pick up the phone.
I know you're there.
Pick up the phone, Drood.
Shit!
Helen.
Look, how many times do I
ask you to do me a favor?
I'm out the door.
No, no, forget it, forget it.
I took her to school already.
Jeez, listen,
I was up all night.
I don't even want
to hear about this.
This is exactly the kind of
thing I talked to you about.
I know.
And I was late.
I don't know what
to say. I gotta go.
Helen, I...
Hello.
Drood, this is Wilson.
Where is Drood's World?
Hold it, this isn't me.
It's my answering machine.
Shit!
Did I fool you?
Drood is unable to come
to the phone right now,
but if you'd like to leave
a nice little message,
just wait for the tone.
It's deadline time.
Pick up the phone.
I've got better things to do
than chase after you
all the time.
Drood...
Drood, if it isn't in my
hands by 4:00, you're fired.
Asshole.
Hi.
You sold it?
I can't believe it.
You're very hot in certain
circles right now, young man.
Thanks to me.
Jimbo, this is $500.
Whoa! Stop!
Whoo! This is
a silk shirt.
And a great tie. Who?
Look, the guy...
Who?
The guy was real tasteful, okay?
He had dark glasses
and a white stick.
What do you care,
I sold it, didn't I?
Hey, Bean!
Hi, Daddy.
Hi, baby.
Listen, I'm sorry
about this morning.
Are you taking me to your house?
No, honey, I just stopped
by to say hello.
Listen, what were you
doing over there?
Beating up a boy. Feel my muscle.
Let's see.
That is excellent.
Hello.
May I help you?
I was just saying hello
to the kid.
I'm her father.
My name is Charles Drood.
We haven't met.
I'm Margaret Bell,
Elizabeth's teacher.
Who? Oh, oh, Elizabeth, right.
We call her Bean.
Drood, show her your teeth.
You must be new here.
Do the teeth thing,
Daddy, please.
Aw, honey, I don't think Miss
Bell really wants to be bothered.
Missus.
Huh?
Mrs. Bell.
And, actually, I'd like
to see this teeth thing.
I lost them in a fight.
Your back teeth?
Daddy likes to tell stories.
Mommy says he tells
stories all the time.
Blaine Line,
let's go to our next call.
Hello, you're on the air.
You've got to help me.
I'm calling from a pit
where my house used to be.
Um, excuse me.
What's your name, sir?
My name's Ethan
and you got to help me.
This UFO thing, look
like a big Buick hubcap,
come down, sucked up
my furniture with,
I don't know, some sort
of hose or something.
Sucked up everything.
I went to get
the bowling trophies,
you know, it's important for me
to get the bowling trophies,
and you're not
going to believe it,
I come back
and my family was gone.
What?
Bad move, Ethan.
Sucked up the hose.
Hi, Drood!
Oh, my God!
Drood!
That didn't hurt.
Arrest that kid.
Would you grow up.
Children, please.
How do you do it?
Do what?
Well, you walk in and
everything falls apart.
Helen, I got hit in the nuts
with a fucking rubber chicken.
Right, laugh.
I'm sorry.
I gotta sit down.
Oh, come on.
What are you doing here, Drood?
I just...
Helen, what do you think about
you and I getting back together?
Yeah, I need...
I need a hand, yeah.
So, which hand
would you like, sir.
Listen, now, don't fool around.
I'm trying to make a chicken.
So, you're...
You're into chickens?
No, no.
Oh, you're cooking, I'm sorry.
Is this chicken fully dressed?
I don't know,
if feathers count as a...
God!
Mr. Drood?
My card.
Come here.
It's okay.
Where is it,
Mr. Drood?
Where's what?
You got to tell us, okay?
Okay?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Aw!
Where is it?
You got the wrong guy here.
She gave you something.
Who?
- Who?
Fuck this.
Let me get back there.
It'll be just a few minutes, Mr.
Drood.
Thank you.
Anybody tell you to move?
I'm not...
Sit over here.
Look, I think...
Listen, I'm not
supposed to be...
No one is.
Look, I just...
You're making a big mistake.
I'm going to kill every
fucking guy in here.
You fuck my wife?
What's her name?
Oh, no.
Oh, please, no, don't.
Hold it.
Wait a second.
Hey, hey.
Hey!
Which one of you guys
is Charles Drood?
I am.
So, you never saw either one
of these men before, huh?
Nope.
And if you saw them again do you
think you could identify them?
Yeah, maybe.
Listen, I don't know.
They didn't take
anything, right?
Nope, nothing.
And you don't know
what they were after.
That it?
Not quite, Mr. Drood.
You see, your kidnapping
may be connected to a case
that we're investigating here
in which you may be
considered a suspect.
A suspect for what?
Well, I have to advise you
that you have a right
to remain silent
and have the services
of a lawyer
but if you haven't
done anything wrong,
you've got nothing
to worry about,
and I can get you out of
here a hell of a lot sooner.
I don't need a lawyer.
All right.
What can you tell me about a
girl named Yolanda Caldwell?
Nothing.
We just found her body today, Mr.
Drood.
You're supposed to say
you love me now.
"I would characterize
the relationship
"as primarily sexual
as I knew...
"...as I never knew very
much about her private life
"outside of our relationship.
"Her marital status, place of
birth, friends, etcetera."
Right.
Weren't you curious?
She wouldn't tell me.
"The last time I saw her
"we had agreed to
go away together."
No, I said that I would
meet her there, I...
I didn't exactly say
that I would go away with her.
"I never went
to the station."
And why not?
I don't know.
I didn't go. I got a
wife, I've got a kid.
I just didn't go, okay?
Okay, okay.
Let's go over it again.
Frank.
"I met Yolanda Caldwell
at a party
"in a West Hollywood dance club
"run by a friend
named James Campbell."
Hello there, darling,
fancy a little dance?
Yes.
Excuse me.
Is that one of
those trick lighters?
No.
Is that a wedding ring?
You ask a lot of questions.
I never met a woman
with a gun before.
Were you in love
with her Mr. Drood?
You still haven't
answered me, Mr. Drood.
Did you love her?
I don't know.
I don't know what that means.
Ah!
Mr. Drood!
Yeah.
Listen, Mrs. Raines.
I'm probably
gonna be moving from here.
What?
Where's your hearing aid?
I'll talk to you later.
Oh, Mr. Drood!
What?
Your envelope!
I've written
a letter of complaint
to the postal service
in Washington, D.C.
I didn't want to send it
locally because I'm sure that
our mailman's superiors are part
and parcel of the conspiracy.
I can't go back.
What conspiracy?
Mr. Drood,
you look terrible.
What conspiracy?
To lose our mail.
Haven't you noticed
anything missing?
Okay.
Go to the window.
Go to the window!
Turn around.
Close the blinds.
Get down on your knees.
Come on.
You don't have to do this.
I promise you...
Shut up.
She thought you were so smart.
Okay, let's see
how smart you are.
Okay?
Right.
You got an envelope
like this? Yes?
Go get it.
Go get it!
Fast, quick!
Come on!
Put it down on the table.
Put that inside.
Don't look at it.
Just put it inside.
That's very good.
You just forget this.
I'm doing you a big favor here.
Hey! Hey!
What, are you crazy?
What!
Give me the lighter. Give me...
Give me the lighter!
You are nuts.
Why can't you say it?
Give me the lighter.
So damn guarded.
Me? What about you?
I have to be.
Why?
What could be so terrible?
You'll be there?
I said I would.
You'll really be there?
I'll be there.
Daddy!
Hmm.
Am I going high?
Real high, baby.
Come on, let's
go play in the sand.
Let's go play in the sand.
Okay.
Drood?
You all right?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah, I'm...
You're sure? Was off some place.
Yeah.
Good.
I talked to Jim this morning.
Yeah?
Yeah.
He said your place
got broken into.
I told him not to
tell you anything.
Come on, he just knew I'd
be concerned, that's all.
It was nothing.
What do you mean
it's nothing, hon?
Somebody breaks
into your apartment,
and you're going to try to
tell me it's nothing now?
What is that?
It was nothing.
Really.
They didn't even take anything.
Is that for me?
Yes.
Ketchup only.
Thank you.
I've been thinking about, um,
what we were talking
about the other day.
What?
About us getting back together.
And?
I don't think it's such
a good idea right now.
Yeah.
I don't think anything
has changed with you.
I don't know.
Up you go.
You don't have to eat all of it.
Just what you can.
Here you go.
Mr. Drood.
I know.
That's a new lock.
This is a new lock here.
Is it?
Listen, Mrs. Raines...
I don't have a key for that.
I made you a key.
If there should be
a fire or something...
Fuck!
I made you this key!
Do you have one for me?
Oh, God.
Tequila.
What?
Shot of tequila.
Five bucks.
I'm a friend of Jim's.
A friend of Jim's?
Yeah.
Five bucks.
Five tequilas then.
What are you doing?
Not doing anything.
I'm doing what you said.
Nothing.
Is that what I said?
What do you want?
Huh?
She loved you.
Somebody kills her
and you just blow it off.
Isn't that what you wanted?
You put a fucking gun
to my head.
Is that what's stopping you?
Is it the gun?
Who do you think you're fooling?
It ain't the gun that stops us.
We're just chicken shit.
See?
The lights are on
but nobody's home.
Am I right?
Mr. Drood.
There's just the two.
There's this one.
And the follow up on page three.
Oh, God.
So, what do you think?
I think we got a guy
with a wife and a kid.
And he's been cheating on her.
I wanted to be different
for a long time.
But I was the same.
I was always the same.
I can't go back.
Back to what?
Van Gogh's pizza,
teriyaki chicken
and burrito, too.
You want to make an order?
Hello.
Hold it, this isn't me...
Zeta Temporary Office Services.
What are you doing here,
Mr. Drood?
This is a crime scene, you're interfering
with a police investigation.
What the hell
are you doing here?
I didn't kill her.
Who's there?
What's the matter?
Jesus.
You scared the shit out of me.
How did you get in here?
Mrs. Raines let me in.
Nice.
What's all this then?
It is this that Yolanda
girl, isn't it?
Yeah.
You've been walking the same
cage for too long, my friend.
Listen, Jim, what do
you know about her?
She's dead. That's
what I know about her.
Dead and gone.
Here, I heard a terrific
joke at the club tonight.
Yeah, yeah, I met her
that night at your club.
What night was that?
That reception for that
congressman asshole.
Oh, yeah.
Who did she come with?
Don't know.
She must have come
with somebody.
How should I know?
Look, have a drink.
Well, do you want to
hear this joke or not?
Yeah.
Right.
How many surrealist painters
does it take to screw
in a light bulb?
How many?
The fish.
Oh, come on.
All right, all right, right.
All right. Bloke goes into
an army surplus store
he says, "Excuse me, have you
got any camouflage trousers?"
The bloke says, "Yeah,
but we can't find them."
What?
He says, "Yeah, but
we can't find them."
The body.
All right, Sherlock,
you tell one.
The body.
The body?
Yeah, yeah, the body?
What's that? Some kind of
minimalist joke then or what?
Yolanda Caldwell.
No, she's still here.
Nobody picked her up?
Nope.
Did you contact her husband?
There wasn't any husband.
You know something
about a husband?
No, I...
I just thought, you
know, she was married.
What is your name?
A friend.
I need your name.
Nix...
...son. Nixon.
Richard Nixon.
It's with an "X".
Wanna see God?
You're fucking falling
apart on me, Buddy.
You didn't get
that envelope, right?
Right.
I told you.
He don't know nothing.
Then what is he doing
down at the morgue
asking about her husband?
Nancy Barron.
Nye. Bobby Nye.
Oh, God.
Hey, Smiley, how you doing?
Hi, John.
How ya doin'? Okay.
So, what are you doing here?
I got to talk to you
about this Drood case.
What's on your mind?
Let's walk, okay?
Sure.
The kid's innocent, John.
The guy is sick.
Be straight with me, John.
You're framing him to protect
yourself, aren't you?
No.
I'm protecting you, Smiley.
Zeta Temp, remember?
Took you to a party, John.
I got you laid.
Hey!
What the fuck
are you doin', huh?
Yeah, you.
I'm talkin' to you.
Like a bird on a wire.
You think this is a joke, huh?
I'm sick of it, man.
I want you to leave me
the fuck alone.
Zeta Temporary Office Services.
Yeah.
Do you know a Yolanda Caldwell?
Miss Caldwell is
no longer with us.
I have Miss Schell available.
She was trained
by Miss Caldwell.
She was trained by...
Um... Could I make an
appointment with her?
Mr. Charles?
Brought your typewriter
and everything.
Just in case.
Can I get you something?
Some water?
Uh, no, thank you.
You're an artist?
Yeah, listen, Miss...
Miss Schell.
Look, would you
like to get started?
Mmm?
Yeah. Yeah. Are you sure?
I can't get you something?
Some coffee, tea?
Okay, you fix some tea
and I'll get set up.
Listen, maybe I just ought...
You're kidding right?
No.
I ain't Santa Claus.
Wait a second.
Just relax.
Look, do you want
to get it on or not?
Not! Not!
That's Nancy Barron.
What did you say?
Listen, I don't...
I don't know nothin'.
What did you say?
Oh, God.
Nancy what? Nancy what?
Oh, please.
What is her name?
What is her name!
It's Yolanda.
It's Yolanda Caldwell.
You said another name, Nancy something.
Nancy what? Nancy Barron?
I won! I won!
Hi.
Oh, shit.
Helen, this isn't what it is.
What is it?
Just give me a second.
Would you excuse us,
please? Helen.
She's a model right?
No. She's a secretary.
You are unbelievable.
Helen, I swear to God.
Unbelievable...
Oh, Jesus!
Helen!
Helen, wait.
Listen...
Fuck you.
I can explain, just slow down.
You're going to kill me here.
You're sick, Drood.
You really need help.
Helen, please, I swear to you,
it's not what it seems like.
Helen!
Oh, right!
Oh, fuck!
Mrs. Raines.
I need that key back.
Hey, hey, hey!
What else did you take
out of the envelope?
What?
What else did you take?
Oh, I don't have any?
You took these things.
What else did you take
out of the envelope? Huh?
What else?
Tell me what you saw?
What did you see?
Don't hurt me.
What else did you see?
Please.
What else?
Please don't hurt me.
Please. Oh!
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
God!
You the one who wanted
to see Smiley?
Come on.
Hey, Smiley,
you going fishing tomorrow?
You got me for two more weeks.
Okay, a toast to
Smiley, a hardnosed cop.
To Smiles!
Come on. Come on.
Move it! Move!
Helen.
It's me.
Oh, God!
Let me in.
Look, I don't want you here.
Helen, listen to me.
Helen, open the door.
No!
Helen, you've got
the phone off the hook.
Yeah, that's right.
Helen, open the door. No!
I am in trouble here.
I'm in real trouble.
I'm in real trouble. No, I'm
not listening to any of this!
So just get away from my house!
Damn you.
Drood.
Helen, I'm sorry.
What is this?
What's this all about?
I'm sorry.
What the hell...
You can't just come in here
like this anymore. I'm sorry.
It's just...
You've got to listen to me.
You got to.
There was this woman...
Another woman? Wait a minute, wait
a minute. I don't know how...
You're gonna tell me you came here tonight
to talk to me about another woman.
- Helen, you've gotta listen to the whole story.
- Helen.
You've got to listen, it's the whole thing.
I swear to...
I'm gonna throw up.
Drood, I want you to leave.
Drood.
I want to see Bean.
You look through all these?
Not yet.
Uh-huh, yep.
Excuse me,
are you Mrs. Drood?
Yes, sir.
Well, I'm sorry to bother
you at work here but...
You're from the police.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm Detective Smiley.
Benjamin Smiley.
Here's my card. Do you
mind if I sit down?
No. No, not at all.
I'd just like to ask you
a couple of questions...
Excuse me.
Vinewood Nursery School.
Helen, it's me.
Mrs. Hernandez, uh, yes.
Could you call back later? Yes,
I'm in a meeting right now.
Helen, please don't hang up.
Uh-huh.
Listen, I've got to talk to you.
Thank you very much. Bye-bye.
Helen. Helen, no please...
...the death of Yolanda
Caldwell is the murder of Adrienne Schell,
who was found shot
through the head
in the apartment of newspaper cartoonist,
C.C. Drood, earlier this morning.
Drood, previously
questioned in the case,
is now the prime suspect
in the investigation.
Police have issued an all-points
bulletin for his arrest.
He is described as a 30 year old
white male, 5'11", 180 pounds,
thought to be driving a...
Scoot over.
It's not just you and me.
There's a lot of people
involved in this, big people,
anyone who went to a party.
Drood has got to go down
on this or we all go down.
♪ Got high hopes ♪
Hi, Jim, have you talked
to Drood today at all?
No. Oh, damn it.
♪ Singin' Got high hopes ♪
♪ High hope, high hope ♪
Drood had a book, it was a
little red appointment book.
And he used to write down
all his important things.
I think he kept it in here. Now have you
seen that? Did you find that in here?
Oh, he was always
such a nice man.
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace ♪
♪ Give me, give me ♪
♪ Got high hopes ♪
♪ Give me help ♪
♪ Give me strength ♪
♪ Give me, give me strength ♪
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace Got high hopes ♪
We're not open yet, pal.
Okay, Don, I want this
bar ready by 9:30.
Oh, Christ.
Come on.
What are you going to do?
You got something to drink?
I'm afraid to go into
a fucking liquor store.
Drood, you're making
the front page, man.
You're on television.
Helen's going crazy and Bean's
having trouble at school.
Are you going to
listen to me or not?
No! You're a selfish fuck.
I'm calling the police.
I'll tell them you
wanna turn yourself...
Now, come on, Drood, stop now.
I need your car.
My car?
Yeah.
Forget it.
Give me the keys.
No.
Give me the fucking keys!
"Bobby Nye..."
"Nancy Barron,
aide to Bobby Nye."
Gee.
Never mind, never mind.
No, no, no.
Don't bother yourself.
George.
Would you get this
gentleman another drink?
Here, let me introduce
you to a few people.
No. I...
This is Councilman Hancock
and his wife Dorothy,
Supervisor Clealand, Mr. McGrath
and Patricia Menninger.
And this is Mr. Drood,
isn't it?
Mr. Drood
is an artist.
I'm afraid I'm not familiar
with your work, Mr. Drood.
Oh, you will be, Pat.
Excuse me, more champagne?
May I get you anything
else, Miss Nye?
Bobby Nye.
You're Bobby Nye.
Let me show you
around. Come on.
What do you think,
Mr. Drood?
I overpaid a bit for that.
But I think its value
is about to skyrocket.
That's what usually happens
when an artist dies.
You killed her.
That depends.
I prefer to think
that you killed her.
She betrayed me.
Over what?
Some pictures?
Some photographs?
You don't know what love is?
Do you?
What a fucking joke.
Let me tell you something.
She was nice to me.
She was very nice to me.
But Miss Nye told me to hit her.
And I did.
And she fell.
She hit her fucking head
on a coffee table.
She broke her neck.
Isn't that somethin'?
The whole thing is
a fucking accident.
Well...
Please.
I'm sorry, Mr. Drood.
No!
No.
- Hello?
- Helen.
Drood.
Are you alone?
No, no, not exactly.
I need your help.
Yes, yes I know.
Do you remember
our second honeymoon?
Do... What?
Do you remember the room?
Honey, I don't see
what this has to...
Now, it's okay,
just listen, please.
Do you remember the room?
Yes. Do you remember
the room number?
Yes, of course,
I do. It's...
Don't say it. Just...
Do you remember it?
Yes.
Okay.
Drood, are you...
I'm okay.
Where have you been?
I've been looking
everywhere for you, Drood.
What do you want me to do?
I need your help.
Okay. I'm listening.
I need some money,
and a change of clothes.
Okay.
I will be there
as soon as I can.
Jim, will you watch
Bean for me, please?
You're going then?
Helen, he's off his bloody head.
Hello.
Detective Smiley, please.
This is he.
Detective, this is Helen Drood.
I know where my husband is.
Helen, this is
completely insane.
My keys.
Helen!
Jim, please let me go.
♪ I love you ♪
♪ For sentimental reasons ♪
♪ I hope you do believe me ♪
♪ I'll give you my heart ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ And you alone were meant to be ♪
♪ Please give your ♪
♪ loving heart to me ♪
♪ And say we'll never part ♪
♪ I think of you every morning ♪
♪ And I dream of you every night ♪
♪ Darling, I'm never lonely ♪
♪ Whenever you're in sight ♪
Come in.
What?
What are you doing?
Thank you.
It's Bean's. I thought
you might need a hat.
What's wrong?
I'm just imagining myself
on the run in this hat.
Drood, stop it.
Fugitive elf.
No, Drood, Drood, Drood.
It's Smiley.
What?
I called Detective Smiley.
You what?
All you have to do is
talk to him, that's all.
Helen. Helen,
are you crazy?
No, just talk to him.
No!
Drood, no!
Don't, Helen, don't open the door.
Helen!
He's got a gun.
Mr. Drood.
Can you hear me,
Mr. Drood?
I just want to talk you.
Helen, get out of there.
Look...
Get...
Mr. Drood, I'm gonna show
you my hands, all right.
Okay, I'm gonna come into
the room now, Mr. Drood.
No!
Drood.
I'm on your side,
Mr. Drood.
Drood, just listen to him, okay.
He's lying. He's in on it. All
you have to do is listen to him.
I really want to
help you, Mr. Drood.
I know you didn't kill anybody.
Put it down.
What the hell
are you doing here, John?
Put it down.
Kick it over here.
I told you to stay out of this.
It's over, John.
Give me the gun.
Give me the...
Smiley, don't.
Don't make me do this.
Give me the gun, John.
Give me the...
No!
- Come on.
- What do we do?
Get the stuff.
What are we going to do?
Come on.
No.
We gotta get out of here. No.
Go, go, go!
Would you please...
I told him you
couldn't kill anybody.
I wasn't trying. If I was
trying, I would've missed.
Oh, God!
Drood, what are we going to do?
Fuck!
Now I'm a cop killer.
I am dead. I'm...
Drood.
I'm dead.
Drood, you're scaring me.
I'm a dead man, Helen.
Where's the toolbox?
I got it. I got it.
Go, go, go!
Drood, I'm going. I'm going.
What are you doing?
Turn up here.
No, right.
Oh, Drood.
I'm going to kill myself.
What?
Drood, just say something
that makes sense, all right?
Tell them I forced
you to drive me up here,
that I said that
I had to meet somebody.
You picked me up
outside the hotel.
You weren't in the room, okay?
What do I tell Bean?
Tell her that I'll be there.
Okay?
There.
Take care of yourself.
I love you.
The lights are on
but nobody's home.
My head with oil,
my cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy shall
follow me all the days of my life.
And I will dwell in the
house of the Lord forever.
Helen.
Drop dead.
♪ Got high hopes ♪
♪ Monday morning ♪
♪ runs to Sunday night ♪
♪ Screaming slow me down ♪
♪ before the new year dies ♪
♪ It won't take much ♪
♪ to kill a lovin' smile ♪
♪ Says every mother with a baby ♪
♪ cryin' in her arms singin' ♪
♪ Give me help ♪
♪ Give me strength ♪
♪ Give a soul a night ♪
♪ of fearless sleep ♪
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace ♪
♪ Well, don't you know these ♪
♪ days you pay for everything ♪
♪ Comin' from the cities ♪
♪ Comin' from the wild ♪
♪ I see a breathless army ♪
♪ breaking like a cloud ♪
♪ It's gonna smother love ♪
♪ It's gonna shoot your hopes ♪
♪ Before the meek inherit ♪
♪ They'll learn to ♪
♪ hate themselves singin' ♪
♪ Give me help ♪
♪ Give me strength ♪
♪ Give a soul a night ♪
♪ of fearless sleep ♪
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace ♪
♪ Well, don't you know these ♪
♪ days you pay for everything ♪
♪ Got high hopes ♪
♪ So, tell me someone ♪
♪ now, what's the price ♪
♪ I wanna buy some time ♪
♪ and maybe live my life ♪
♪ I wanna have a wife ♪
♪ I wanna have some kids ♪
♪ I want to look in their eyes ♪
♪ And know they're gonna ♪
♪ stand a chance, singin' ♪
♪ Give me help ♪
♪ Give me strength ♪
♪ Give a soul a night ♪
♪ of fearless sleep ♪
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace ♪
♪ Well, don't you know ♪
♪ these days you pay for ♪
♪ Got high hopes ♪
♪ Singin' Got high hopes ♪
♪ High hope, high hope, ♪
♪ high hope ♪
♪ Got high hopes ♪
♪ High hopes ♪
♪ Give me help ♪
♪ Give me strength ♪
♪ Give me hope ♪
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace ♪
♪ Give me, give me ♪
♪ Got high hopes ♪
♪ Give me help ♪
♪ Give me strength ♪
♪ Give me, give me strength ♪
♪ Give me love ♪
♪ Give me peace Got high hopes ♪