In what looks to be another battle
in the ongoing drug wars
that have plagued the region
in the recent months including
the murder of three US ambassadors
in Ciudad Juárez
and the shocking disappearance of
California's very own drug czar, Millard Hanson.
How long has it been since
you last confession?
I can't remember.
What would you like to confess?
I wanna make a donation.
Please, we have a poor box
outside of this booth.
Right.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
There's no need to be sorry.
Will you do something for me, father?
What is it, my son?
Forgive me.
No!
You're so good, yeah.
Good boy.
Yeah.
- Happy birthday, baby.
- Hi.
So, what do you wanna do?
Don't worry about it.
Something's planned for you.
Yes?
Oh my, that dog is huge.
Oh wait, I got a little surprise
for you in the parking lot.
So I gotta cover those playboy eyes.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Alright, watch your step
Don't wind up hurting yourself.
Almost there.
What?
You got us new bikes?
Yeah, and a bike rack installed
by yours truly.
Ah, I can see that that is
your handiwork.
Yeah, it's just a loose screw,
I can fix it later.
Thank you.
Now, it's time for gift number two.
- There's another one?
- Yeah.
It's not in there, silly.
- Gotta go for a little drive.
- Oh, a drive thing?
- Give me a hint.
- No. Get in the car.
You can take it.
No, I...
I promised no work tonight.
Here.
Adios. No more calls.
No more calls.
Why are we stopping?
Open it.
What?
What is this?
It's a fingerprint key.
It's the latest in home security.
David, whose house is this?
It's ours.
What?
Now it's your turn.
That's weird.
We'll have to get you your own.
Just went into foreclosure.
It's not even on the market yet.
I pulled a few strings at the bank.
And we are getting this place at
an absolute steal.
Of course, I didn't sign the final
paperwork yet.
I was kind of hoping we could
do that tonight.
Together.
Morgan, Morgan's and Loan he's the one
that hooked me up with a keypad.
I couldn't get the power on.
Don't have any connections to
the power company.
I had a couple guys come in
and pack up what the previous
owner left behind.
You know what, wait till you see
the pool out back.
And if you like any of the art
it's ours.
Comes with the house.
I have no idea why there's a stove
in here but...
I know you love antiques.
Oh, and they're also building a school
three blocks away from here.
Baby, this is the house we've always
dreamed about.
Babe, I...
I can tear this up right now.
I love it.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Pen.
- Okay.
We... are officially... homeowners.
- Hey, you wanna see something really cool?
- Yes.
Talk about your own security systems, huh?
- What?
- Yeah, check it out.
We got a custom designed system
that covers 360 degrees of the premises.
How is this running without any power?
Oh, the system has its own power line.
It also comes with a fully automatic MTS.
MTS?
Movement Tracking System.
What?
Is that Trish's car?
What is she doing here?
No idea.
Love the place!
What are you doing here?
Well, the front door was wide open.
And David showed me pictures
yesterday of the house
and I found the perfect
housewarming gift.
Oh wait, it's official, right?
You're taking the house?
Yeah.
I'm so happy for you.
Thank you.
Oh, that is the latest piece of this hot
new artist showing at my gallery.
This is a far cry from that shit box you guys
were held onto on the north side, huh?
I know.
Oh, and I expect a jacuzzi and
a wet bar out here very soon.
Deal.
- Bye!
- Wait, why you leaving so early?
I'm sure you guys have some
celebrating to do
and I have drinks and clients
and then a hot date
with "Michelangelo".
Oh, god.
- I love you, girl.
- Love you.
David, great job.
Thank you.
That girl's crazy.
I know she is.
Oh, poor thing. They left you
all alone out there.
We're gonna pick up some bird feeder
in the morning.
Trish.
- Ah, she got timing.
- I know.
Hi.
Hello.
I saw your SUV out in front.
I came to check in.
Can I help you, folks?
David Nash.
This is my wife.
- Amy.
- Ray.
So, you guys thinking of
buying the place or...
We are.
Well, we just did.
Welcome to the neighborhood.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
You know, I always wanted to see
the inside of this place.
Do you mind if I just...
- Oh, go for it.
- Thank you.
- Wow, this is nice... exposed brick.
- Yeah, we like it.
So you're a Buckeye?
Yeah.
How did you know?
Sticker. Ohio sticker on the windshield.
Ah, of course.
So that's where you met?
Yeah, freshman year.
Co-ed dorms.
What line of work you in, David?
I'm over at Nitrom Trust.
Oh, what do you do there?
I specialize in city redevelopment
You know turning porch hounging
neighborhoods into...
- One like this one? Right, right?
- Exactly.
Alright well, I better get going.
- Nice to meet you.
- And you.
You know it's always... nice to have
good people devoted to the block.
Thanks.
You guys take care.
- You as well.
- Yeah.
Make a wish.
- What did you wish for?
- I can't tell.
Happy birthday!
Thank you.
It's really sweet.
I just want you to be happy, baby.
It's so peaceful and quiet here.
That's the idea.
Now we can spend more time together.
I've heard that before.
A little bit different now, you'll see.
I want a tape recorder.
I want to get this on a record.
You think you got jokes?
Yes.
What is that?
I don't know, it was probably a
little mouse or
I don't know.
What the hell is that?
Fine.
Check this out.
It seems like we might have a little
mouse issue up in here.
Yeah, you know what, I'll call
the exterminator tomorrow.
and get this place bug gone
before we move in.
It looks like we have a busy day tomorrow.
We should probably get going.
Hold up.
I can think of at least one thing
we could do.
Really?
It's too bad we don't have any furniture.
Luckily
I came prepared.
I doubt there's any luck involved with that.
A scratch.
It's awful how dirty this is.
What do you think of his nurse sinks?
Oh my god!
What is this?
I think it's heroin.
Hey!
Mr. and mrs. Nash.
- Richard?
- Ray.
- Ray, sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
Is everything okay?
No. We found something in the house.
Really?
What did you find?
We need to call the cops.
I was...
I was really hoping you weren't
goin' to say that, David.
See, I bet somebody twenty dollars
that you two wouldn't find that
stash tonight.
I guess I lost.
Hey, you can just take it.
We don't need to go back in there.
It's all yours.
Really?
So, you guys gonna wait upfront?
With your eyes closed?
Count to a thousand for me?
Get inside!
Let's go!
Fuck!
Shit!
- The back door! Back door!
- Shit!
- Get a knife or something!
- Okay.
There's nothing in here.
No!
How did you do this?
I hit the switch.
Oh my god, David!
Oh my god!
Okay, good.
I'm okay.
I just need my breath.
What is this place?
They dropped the barricade.
What do we do now?
Hey, what the hell is wrong with you?
Without a keypad we can't get in there.
We need the kid alive.
What are you doing?
Things have escalated here.
It's your first day.
Hey, go ahead.
Hit the panic button.
Call it in.
It's gonna look bad on both of us.
Let's just finish our business here.
And then you and I can stab each other
in the backs later. Okay?
It looks like it stopped bleeding.
You should be fine.
Couldn't you pick us a house with
a white picket fence?
Good line.
They knew...
Knew what?
When we walked out that front door
they knew we were calling the cops.
- How did they know we were leaving?
- I have no idea.
Unless...
You know, I've always wanted to see...
the inside of this place, do you mind if I just...
This is nice...
exposed brick.
They've been listening to us all night.
Oh my god!
There goes our bug.
I think we're safe as long as
we stay in the house.
Safe?
They have automatic weapons.
You see that?
Walls, windows or doors...
they're all bulletproof.
This whole place...
is fortified.
Drug dealers have the tendency
to get paranoid about the competition
looking out their stash.
How do you know that?
Five seasons of "The Wire".
It doesn't make sense, why would drug dealers
foreclose on a stash house?
No clue.
What are you looking for?
Can you hold that?
Maybe...
they haven't shut off...
the phone line.
Anything?
- They got the junction box.
- What?
They destroyed the junction box!
What?
Oh my god!
Okay, okay.
We have to stay calm.
Tell me, what are we gonna do?
Listen to me!
You gotta calm down.
Hey, look at me...
look at me, calm down.
This is what I do, baby... crisis management.
I solve problems everyday.
I'm gonna get us out of here.
This is not an accounting error.
There are men out there trying to kill us!
There is a way out of here.
There has to be.
You just... You just have to let me think.
Okay, baby?
Okay.
They're here for the stash so we just
give them what they want.
Then after this?
They leave.
Something on your mind?
The stash.
All of it!
Come on.
Dammit.
There's some good stuff in here.
Please go!
- I think it's what they want.
- Really?
What are they doing?
What gave you the impression
I came here for that poison?
Just tell me what you want.
I'll get it for you.
Never negotiate with something
you can't deliver.
They're not gonna leave.
Amy!
They're gonna find a way in here.
No babe, look at me.
If they knew a way in
they would've found it by now.
Okay.
I won't let anything happen to you.
It's gonna be okay.
Two bags.
It's not a lot of product for a stash house.
This was more like a weed station.
For monthly loads,
not a lot of traffic.
Off the radar.
That's why they kept the package here.
It's been a while though.
Any chance they could find it?
It doesn't matter at this point.
What's so funny?
Oh nothing. Just something a friend south
of the border calls you, that's all.
Let's hear it.
Dijo de puta.
They say anything else?
Just that after ten years in the field,
you still bet a thousand.
Which I guess...
makes you worth the trouble.
Keep an eye on them.
Where you going?
Fishing.
We need to make a run for it.
No way.
I can make it over that fence.
You forget about their guns?
You can't outrun a bullet.
I can make it.
It's too risky!
Twenty seconds, that's all I need.
I'm fast.
- They'll hear you as soon as you hit that fence.
- Then you'll distract them with noise in the front.
Amy...
These guys... they're professionals.
Our best bet is to stay here
and just try to ride it out.
Twenty seconds.
If they make a move stall them.
- I can't stop you from doing this, can I?
- No way.
- Twenty seconds.
- No, stop!
Come on!
No!
Shit... shit!
No, no!
He's coming!
Don't make this worse.
Hey!
Are you listening in there?
Open this door now and your
husband lives.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
My partner is gonna shoot to kill,
unless you open this door.
This is one of those true die moments.
Don't let us kill your husband.
David!
Fuck!
I wonder where David could be.
You...
David!
Amy!
Oh my god!
You okay?
Yeah, baby.
- I thought you were dead.
- I'm very much alive, baby.
Your hand...
- Oh my god, David!
- It's alright, baby.
What was that?
What is that?
Where is that coming from?
He's climbing.
Where are you going?
He's trying to get into the chimney.
Maybe he's looking for a way to slide down.
You hear that?
Sounds like he's drilling into the roof.
Doesn't sound like drilling.
- What does it sound like then?
- I don't know.
Probably the chimney cap?
Get back!
Come on!
Adios, amigo.
Get down!
Stupid son of a bitch!
Are you hurt?
- Are you hurt?
- I don't know.
You smell like chimney.
Okay.
Stay here.
Do you think the neighbors
heard something?
Not through these walls.
You son of a bitch!
I think I got one of them.
I don't hear anything.
You bitch!
I'll kill you!
You piece of shit!
Where is he going?
I'm sorry.
What for?
Everything.
Tonight.
Bringing you here.
I should've said no.
For the house?
Before...
I should've never left Ohio.
This is an opportunity for us
to build a better life.
No, David.
This was an opportunity for you
to build your career.
That's it.
We were so happy.
Whatever they want,
is hidden in this house.
Where are you going?
To find what they're looking for.
Ah... son of a bitch got me in the neck.
It was a lucky shot.
It won't happen again.
You're done here!
Calling Khulia Khan?
I wouldn't do that.
I'm doing it!
Making that call only shortens
your life by a couple of hours.
Yeah.
Near retirement?
I'm sorry to say, it's been rejected.
What do you know about that?
Only what our friends down south told me.
There's too many company secrets
in that big fat head of yours.
Go ahead, make the call and
you know what...
Call the Juárez cartel while you're at it.
The decision's been made
across the border, amigo.
You... won't live to see the sunrise.
Everyone...
has an expiration date.
Go ahead! Get it over with!
It's tempting.
But...
there are a couple colombians...
waiting outside your house.
That have been paid handsomely,
for that privilege.
Now...
I've got a proposition for you.
You help me retrieve that package
and I'll let you walk out of here with the H.
We've got a deal?
Try behind there.
There's something behind this wall.
This' part of the basement?
No, it's off the property now.
Payables.
Receivables.
And this is...
this is all accounting figures.
I think this is a counting room.
Mini Corp.
What do you think that is?
I don't know.
They have contract work for these guys.
Paid once a month, like clockwork.
Close for... at least three years.
You know...
I read this article
about these ex-special forces types that were...
working with cartels.
The kind of guys who would have
access to weapons and grenades.
You hear that?
The scratching sound's back.
What is that?
I don't know.
It's definitely not a mouse.
It's locked or stuck or something.
Do you have your USB key with you?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh my gosh.
What is this?
Maybe it's what they're looking for.
There's something in there.
What the hell is that?
It's a man.
What?
Yeah, it's a man in there.
Oh my gosh!
Turn around, turn around.
On three. One, two, three!
How long do you think he's been in there?
I don't know.
For a while.
He looks familiar.
Hold on, wait here.
Listen, something's come up.
Yes.
Yes, remember that place we talked about?
You need to meet me there, tonight.
Yeah.
Everything's gonna be okay.
I love you too.
I found this.
Let's bring it up to slice.
- What?
- That's him.
Millard Hanson.
He's some kind of...
state drug czar.
We can't hand him over to them, okay?
Yeah, I know.
Where's your partner?
Licks his wounds.
You made things interesting with
that firework show.
What do you want?
At this point...
I'm just trying to get home to my wife.
Yeah?
'She know what you do?
Does yours?
I don't hide things from my wife.
Really?
Then she knows the truth, how you happen
to stumble upon this house.
Previous owner here worked
for a drug cartel.
He was a housekeeper.
It's an easy gig.
Requires just a signature on the deed
and two phone calls a month
to his employers.
But yesterday, the housekeeper
missed his call.
The housekeeper never misses a call.
It turned out...
he decorated the inside of a
confessional booth with his brain matter.
Now, you work for the bank David.
You have no doubt heard
about the suicide.
Question is...
Did you tell the wife?
We all have our secrets, David.
Your lives aren't the only ones in the line
here tonight.
My old man...
went out in a barcalounger,
way before his time.
That's not gonna be me.
David.
Just open the door and we can
all go home.
Go ahead, just open the door.
Bitch!
I can't find them.
Take care of business first.
And worry about the couple later.
So what's the story with the package?
We're looking for somebody with
a ransom.
- How much did they ask?
- Nothing.
They wanted to trade him for a couple
cartel bosses up in San Quentin.
They're cutting into the floor bars.
They're looking for him.
They never build this place they didn't
wanna be able to see out, right?
There's gotta be something
hidden in here.
What?
I can see them! They're cutting into the hedge.
It's not gonna take too long to figure out
he's not in there
and then they'll come looking for us.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
I can see their shotgun.
I'm gonna go for it.
While they're still working,
Even if you get it,
you don't know how to use it.
We don't have a choice!
When they'll find out that he's not there,
they will find us and
they will kill us.
I gotta try.
Wait!
I'm sorry.
For everything.
I only did this because I thought
it would help us.
I love you.
Where am I?
Please.
Stop, just stop it, stop!
Who are you?
If you say one more word
they're gonna kill us all.
Fuck!
Come on!
Piece of shit is stuck!
I don't hear anything.
He's there!
One of two possible scenarios.
That voice...
I know that voice.
It's empty.
That was the other one.
That's the man who brought me here.
They're still in the house.
All three of them.
Don't move!
Cops?
Your neck.
My weapon.
What for?
To cover your ass.
Sorry to bother you, sir.
Oh, it's no problem. What's up?
What's going on?
Well, someone discharged a flare
about an hour ago in this neighborhood.
A flare? Really, wow.
Could you open the door, please?
Yeah, yeah. One second.
You know, I...
I didn't see or hear anything.
I crashed on the couch, hours ago.
I've been out like a rock.
- Sorry to bother you again, sir.
- Ah, no problem.
You know what, it's probably some of these
neighborhood kids trying to have a laugh.
Look out!
- Drop your weapon!
- This is my home.
- Put it down, sir!
They broke in, okay?
They're trying to kill us!
I don't give a damn!
Put your weapon down!
You don't understand!
- I do understand!
- No, you don't!
They've been after me and my wife all night.
They're trying to kill us!
- Please, don't make me do this!
- Godammit, listen to me!
I will shoot you where you stand!
Put the weapon down, drop it!
No!
That was for the flare gun.
I'm gonna take it easy on you, David.
But I can't say the same thing
about your little wife.
I've got some real payback waiting
for that bitch.
Oh, man!
What a night!
Hello?
Whose car is that, outside?
- Trish!
- Michelangelo broke up with me
and I went to you guys apartment
and noone was there...
I need to talk to Amy.
Get out of here!
Oh my god!
No! Get out of here!
No!
Come on, man!
Why?
On your feet.
Back to business.
Better work on that poker face.
Let's go!
We have 15 minutes before police show up,
looking for officer Friendly.
The keypad.
Where is it?
Give me your thumb!
Fuck you!
Hey!
Come on!
The front door! The front door, this way.
No! Stop!
I don't know how to disarm this.
The back door.
Emergency, what's the problem?
Cops are on their way.
Fuck, shit!
There's no way out.
Over here!
We need something
to pry this open with.
Come on!
- Fuck this!
- No, wait.
Come on, come on!
Come on!
Ah, the cops are here.
You can take us hostage to scare them.
I'll have to put in on this.
Hostage scenario is out the window.
So, we're gonna have to improvise.
Adapt.
I'm the good guy,
you're the bad guy.
If the catch me before I drive out of here,
Amy dies.
If they catch you alive,
Got it?
Don't let them find you here.
Put your arms around me
and don't let go.
If you make a move or
get me cornered
I will kill you.
Two intruders.
They came for the drugs,
heroin I think.
And when did the second intruder go?
He escaped, two minutes
before you got here.
Jesus... we're lucky to be alive.
I can't believe they killed her.
I'm sorry, honey.
You know the victim, ma'am?
Ma'am?
She was my friend.
And you are, sir?
I'm her father.
Don't say a word!
And what else can you tell us about
the second intruder, mr. Cobb?
He was...
He was about 5'11", 180...
Listen to me.
The guy in the other room,
he's got my wife.
If you call for help,
he's gonna kill her.
Okay?
I need you to believe me.
Alright, just... just calm down.
- Put the gun down.
- Sorry!
Man down!
Dark hair, short, above ears.
Sir, you're gonna be alright.
Look, detective...
I'm not spending another second
in this house.
My daughter and I've been
through enough already.
I understand. Why don't you step
right this way.
You'll be under police protection
for the next 48 hours.
That won't be necessary.
Sorry, sir... but that's
standard procedure.
Police! Stop!
It's right over here.
It's not too much...
Yeah! Right here...
What did you say your name
was again, sir?
Louis.
Louis Cobb.
Cobb, that's right!
Two B's.
Stop, right now!
Dammit!
We need an exit... he's getting away.
Turn around!
You in real estate, sir?
- Mr. Cobb.
- Excuse me?
Are you in real estate, mr. Cobb?
Yeah.
Do you mind if I talk to your daughter
in private for just one moment?
Just one second. Please.
Sure.
Calm down, baby!
Shoot him!
You sit, shut up!
Stand, sir!
Drop it!
I thought you weren't gonna
open that, David.
There's a lot of people
looking for you.
And you just killed a cop.
Take your shot at me and
they're gonna put you down.
And you're gonna ask yourself...
Is killing me worth killing yourself?
David, put the gun down.
He's got a weapon!
Drop the gun!
Is my life really worth yours, David?
No.
- Drop the gun!
- Let me see your hands!
Do it now! Do it now!
Everybody says...
No!
Next time, you pick the house.
Amy!
No!
He's got a gun!
Drop the gun!
Wait, wait!
That's my husband.
What did they do to you?
You okay?
I'm fine, baby.
As long as you're alright.
Okay.
What happened to him?
He's gone.
What did he say to you?
He said...
Next time I should pick the house.
I agree.