STEREO
Now that we have some insight,
into the concept of experiential space
we may consider interaction among
the experiential space continua
of a highly unique group of individuals.
In general, a study of the varying
dimensions of human experience
in the context of man in his society
is known as human social cybernetics.
In our experiment,
eight Category-A subjects
underwent pattern brain surgery
whose program was developed within the
academy's organic computer dialectic system.
The object of surgery was
to extend by a process called
biochemical induction.
The natural, electro-chemical
network of the human brain.
This extension would provide each
subject with telepathic capabilites.
A telepathist is one who can
communicate with other minds
by means which do not involve
perception by the senses.
Thus, telepathy is a form
of extra-sensory perception
or ESP.
Our subjects were to be kept in isolation
at the institute for three months.
Where they were to prepare for
their first meeting as a group.
This meeting was to take place at the academy
sanitorium in the Ontario north woods.
Telepathic dependency
is an extreme form of psychic addiction.
It is essentially an
electro-chemical addiction.
The dependent, surrending the
autonomy of his own nervous system
to that of the onject of his dependency.
And altering his patterns of
electro-chemical discharge
to mimic those of his object.
When the object of dependency is telepathically
unavailable for long periods of time
the new nervous patterns
find themselves suddenly
without a constant source
of electro-morphological reinforcement...
and, severe psychic disorientation
begins to manifest itself in the dependent.
At its most intense level
a frustrated dependency can result in the
irreversible destruction
of critical brain tissue.
In as much as the establishment of
a partial telepathic dependency
of the subject upon his researcher
is an unavoidable part
of the parapsychological
experimental gestalt.
The means to maintain this
dependency at a controllable level
must be considered an organic element
forming that experimental gestalt.
During the institute phase of
the induced telepathy series...
our subject
possessed of a statistically excessive,
dependency susceptability quotient,
wounded himself in the
forehead, with a hand drill.
The wound, a hole about
one-half an inch in diameter,
completely penetrated the subject's skull
and seemed to afford him the relief
of imagined cranial pressures.
Temporary euphoria,
and electro-chemical dissociation, which he sought.
It will perhaps clarify these matters
if we consider the specific configuration
of the Category-A subject.
Category-A is a classification
which finds its meaning within
the scientific metaphysics
of the aphrodisiast and theorist
Luther Stringfellow.
It is not what is usually considered
an objective classification.
Based for example, upon physical
or psychological characteristics.
Category-A, is rather a certain
field reaction of the researcher
to an intensive period of personal interaction
with each of his potential subjects.
There is also, therefore, the element
of an aesthetics of human form.
in the Category-A system
of subject classification.
Dr. Stringfellow made his name, as an
exponent of the existential organic approach
to the sciences, long before his work
in the socio-chemistry of the erotic
achieved its present
international eminence.
A Category-A classification
is the existential organic
methodology put into practice.
Dr. Stringfellow
has repeatedly stressed
the vital necessity for
the use of this approach.
Particularly,
in the new social sciences.
where variables are infinite
and complexity is of the
highest possible order.
The nature of erotic research
requires that the sexual emotional
involvement of the researcher
with each subject be taken
to its farthest possible extreme.
It is only in this way that the researcher
in whose consciousness, a total mosaic
of his particular research project exists
can divine in each of his subjects
a color, a texture, and a shape.
And so assign to that subject,
his proper place in the research mosaic.
It was hoped that many important questions
would be clarified, if not answered,
during the course of our experiment
with induced telepathy.
Two of the eight subjects consented to
having portions of their larynx removed.
Making it physically
impossible for them to speak.
In addition
large portions of the speech centers of the
brains of these subjects were obliterated
so that the psychological faculty of
speech itself would be impaired
Would the maturing and strengthening
of the telepathic capicity in
these speechless subjects
surpass that of the subjects who
still retained the ability to speak?
It was anticipated
that the telepathic experience would be much
more than simply reading another's mind.
One telepathist would perhaps
be able to apprehend
not only verbal patterns,
as they arose in the mind of another,
but would also encounter simultaneously
the germinative layers of memory,
learning, emotional response,
and psycho-physiological impulse, which
actually generate thought and language.
How dependent upon language is thought?
Is abstract logical thought even
possible without language?
The essence of the telepathic bond
is the dominance
of one of the particles forming
the telepathic conglomerate.
Whether the conglomerate consists
of two telepathists or of a large
socially cohesive group
the principle of psychic
dominance remains constant.
The dominant personality
is responsible for the
suppression of the heterogeneous
elements which the
conglomerate comprises.
The homogeneous elements which remain
are then driven together
to form the conglomerate
by the laws of telepathic bonding
implicit in the Stringfellow Hypothesis.
The principle of dominance thus
provides the agglutinizing impetus
which induces the initial
conglomerative motion.
As Stringfellow notes in defining
the nature of dominance
the will of the newly formed
conglomerate must necessarily
be a function of the will of
the dominant personality.
Only after an indefinite period of
symbiotic telepathic cohesion
can the dominant personality abnegate
its agglutinative role and encourage
the emergence of a truly synthetic
conglomerate personality.
Stringfellow's behavior
as parapsychologists
suggests that perhaps that his foremost
post-operative research objective
was to intuit which among his Category-A subjects
was the one most capable of assuming
the role of psychic dominant.
This subject was then provided
indirectly with certain
historical and interpretive data
concerning his fellow subjects.
This data would naturally assure the immediate
social dominance of the chosen subject
within the context of the experimental,
socially isolate gestalt
The function of the dominant would be
then to select from his fellow subjects
the one psychically most vulnerable.
And by the application of subtle, social intimidations
followed by a careful series
of potent symbolic gestures
draw the subject into the field of his
psycho-telepathic dominance.
Once a true conglomerate
exhibiting complete telepathic
bonding has been established
between this primary couple
the progression towards a larger and
more complex conglomerate may begin.
In psychic research
the emotional distance between
the researcher and his subject
is inevitably diminished until it is no more
than the distance between any two persons.
The acquiescence of the subject
of the demands of the researcher
comes nothing more nor less,
than an individual act of faith of love.
If there can be no love between
researcher and subject
there can be no experimentation.
In conventional theories
of scientific methodology
an experiment proves its validity
when it can be universally
repeated in every aspect.
In psychic research, such an
approach is completely untenable.
The existential circumstances of
any experiment in parapsychology
are inextricably mixed with the individuals
and the phenomological sets involved
in that particular experiment
and cannot be abstracted
from those individuals
or phenomological sets.
The conditions of experiments
in parapsychology are unique,
non-uniform and non-repeatable.
A completely non-scientific burden
is therefore place upon the researcher
for if the peronal relationship between
researcher and subject deteriorates
the experiment cannot continue
along its natural course.
The sensitivity of the experimental
parapsychological plexus
demands new methods
to help maintain the emotional
momentum in certain experiments.
Proving notice
that the motto of the Canadian
Academy for Erotic Inquiry
has immediate relevance for the Stringfellow induced telepathy series.
"Amor vincit omnia."
Or: "Love conquers all."
We understand that the unique way
in which an individual perceives
and reacts to his environment
is a funstion of his own
experiential space continuum.
When object events enter the experiential
space continuum of that individual
they become an integral
organic part of that space.
They are actually changed,
qualitatively modified
in accordance with the
creative nature of that space.
But we are now dealing with telepathists.
In theory
the experiential space continua of
two or more telepathists can merge,
can blend together to an extent far beyond
the range of normal human experience.
What would be the organic nature
of communal experiential space
shared among eight psychosomatic entities?
Would one person, one mode
of perception and reaction,
one experiential space continuum
dominate this oversoul?
Or, would each mind participate
in the synthesis of a uniform
newly created emergent space,
unlike any of its constituents?
How would the physical and social functioning
of members of this group be altered?
Or, could they function in
recognisable modes at all?
There is some evidence to suggest
the potential telepathic intensity
varies indirectly as the square of the
distance between two telepathists.
An increase in physical distance may
therefore be used by one telepathist
as an effective defence against telepathic
intrusion on the part of another telepathist.
A far more sophisticated
intrusion avoidance device
known as schizophonetic partition
was evolved by one of the female subjects
during the group isolation sanitorium phase.
In order to subvert attempts
by fellow subjects to establish
potentially intrusive telepathic rapport
she completely separated her
telepathic, non-verbal self
from her oral verbal self.
The telepathic self functioned
as a false self
diverting fellow telepathists
from the real or true self
which manifested itself only in occasional,
deliberately confused, verbal utterances.
She thus protected her true
self from telepathic intrusion
by abandoning her telepathic
faculty to a false self.
Not surprisingly, repeated telepathic
probes undertaken by other subjects
could not discover the true nature of
her experiential space continuum.
The danger inherent in
schizophonetic partition
as a telepathic intrusion avoidance device
is that the false telepathic self
tends to become increasingly parasitic
on the true oral/verbal self.
The true self begins to suffocate
in as much as it is starved
of contact with the outside.
And the false self gradually
becomes the only self
to interact with other selves.
In the instance of our
female schizophonetic subject
the true self began to express
its moribond existence
through the telepathic emission
of violent images of decay
vampirisim, disentegation and necrophilia.
Which sporadically interrupted the
functioning of the telepathic false self.
The intensity and frequency of this
emission of morbid, telepathic images
rapidly increased until it began to
create the same depressed mode
in those close to her.
Another important function
of our experiment
was to be the practical testing
of the Stringfellow hypothesis.
The Stringfellow hypothesis takes
the form of the following equation:
The rate of telepathic flow
between two minds,
is directly proportional
to the intensity of the relationship
between the two minds.
The units used to measure flow and intensity
are taken from psycho-chemistry.
In less mathematical terms, we may say
that this hypothesis indicates that
even between mature telepathists
there can be no telepathic communication
until some sort of existential
emotional relationship
has been established in
conventional sensory ways.
Thus, among complete strangers
there would exist only a kind of noise,
a short wave static
The Stringfellow hypothesis
also suggests that here
the potency of human eroticism
would play an important role.
A strong sexual attraction
would be a substantial basis
for the establishing of a geometerically
increasing rate of telepathic flow.
The politics of experience
on the level of individuals
is a correlative of the
politics of social groups.
The politics of telepathic experience
may be studied as a projection of the
power struggles among individuals
into the extremities of psychic
potency and complexity,
a projection that is, into the
future of human social evolution.
The role of the induced telepathy series,
in the total Canadian social experiment,
is theoretically secure.
That role emerges out of
Dr. Stringfellow's concept
the telepathic commune.
A group characterized by the blending
of experiential space continua
and the constant instantaneous
exchange of data
among the nervous systems
forming the commune.
Stringfellow indicates that at
the most basic structural level
the telepathic unit,
which empasizes acts of faith and love,
seems the most plausible replacement
of the obsolescent family unit.
The communal telepathic experience
translated into the larger
social national context
would preumably carry with it intrinsic
qualities of willing reciprocal dependency
and a mutual experiential creativity.
The social responsibility
of telepathic prototypes
is therefore of the utmost gravity.
For it is only by their individual efforts
that the creation of the first and most
critical telepathic communes can be realized.
For those of exponentially and
maturing telepathic capacities
the question of phenomenological
refinement must inevitably become one
with the problem of the
internalization of the sensory.
The telepathist faces the
obsolescence of the
senses and the possible atrophy
of the human sensorium
in all but its most mundane operations.
During a certain phase in
the telepathist's evolution
the sensory will attempt to
internalize to avoid its extinction
on the level of intellectuality and emotion.
This avoidance could take two forms.
One would be the forced psychic injestion
of the entire universe is conveyed
in terms of sensory information.
This would partially manifest itself in
in the instantaneous translation
into the vocabulary of the sensory
of all purely psychic abstract
or extrasensory phenomena.
Second form of avoidance would
be the reification of the psychic,
the abstract or the extrasensory, and its
subsequent externalization or projection.
The process begun by the subjectification
and displacement of the nonsensory
would find a point of
equilibrium and complete
itself only with the indescriminate
return or internalization
of both the projective nonsensory information
and its sensory screen,
the passive external world as perceived by the senses.
In both instances, the distinction between
the sensory and the nonsensory,
the concrete and the abstract,
the psychic and the physical,
would be lost utterly.
These opposite poles of human sexuality
are traditionally held to be
hetrosexuality and homosexuality.
Yet this same bipolar structure
of sexuality is ignored
when the question of normaility
and deviation arises.
The norm is taken to be hetrosexuality
and both bisexuality
and homosexuality
are considered deviations from that norm.
The primary justification for normality
of hetrosexuality is reproduction.
Only a hetrosexual relationship can,
as yet, result in regeneration.
This argument colapses however
once it is demonstrated
that the sexuality involved in reproduction
represents only a very small,
almost accidental segment of
the total human sexual spectrum.
Academy research has established that
both hetrosexuality and homosexuality
are equally, what might
be termed perversions,
relative to the potential
human sexual field.
In this context, the true norm is
an expanded form of bisexuality
which we term omnisexuality.
As an aphrodisiast, Dr. Stringfellow
proposes the use of synthetic
aphrodisiac drugs
to assist those who wish to attain
a fully three dimensional sexuality.
The proper use of psychic aphrodisiacs
such as those being
developed by Dr. Stringfellow
at the Canadian Academy for Erotic Inquiry
is not to increase sexual
potency or fertility
but to demolish the walls of psychological
restraint and social inhibition
which restrict persons to a monosexuality
or to a stunted bisexual
form of omnisexuality.
A telepathist then, by virtue
of the omnisexual nature,
of his experiential space continuum,
may readily be seen to be the possible
prototype of three dimensional man.
Certain unexpected result however,
threw the future of the project into doubt.
When preliminary confrontations between
any two subjects were arranged
the subjects not only reported no
instances of telepathic communication
but quite emphatically avoided even the
most casual sensory contact with each other.
At the same time,
electroencephalographic probes
indicated that such telepathic
communication as was denied by the subjects
was in fact taking place, and at
a remarkably high rate of flow.
How could such flow exist among strangers?
In an emergency program modification
five of our eight subjects were
combined in an enforced community study.
These five subjects, although psychochemically
the least volatile of the group
almost immediately retreated
into a state of false incapsulation.
Refusing to communicate in any way
with either researchers or each other.
Before further investigations could be made
two of the five subjects committed suicide
in their residences at the institute.
Another, pierced his skull
with an electric drill,
an act of considerable symbolic significance.
Careful separation of the remaining
subjects was maintained.
The study of human erotic morphology
deals more directly with this question.
Morphology is the study
of form and structure.
Erotic morphology is the study of those
forms which evoke an
erotic or sexual response
when they are perceived or
otherwise communicated.
Not only the shape of objects or body
parts, but also the morphology of motion,
of movement in certain patterns,
can convey erotic signals
of a very complex nature.
Finally, the combination of shape plus
motion can attain an erotic significance
which is contained in neither shape
nor motion when taken separately.
But, the telepathist does not
have to perceive a breast or thigh
or sexual motion directly.
He can apprehend the thought of
a breast, thigh, or erotic motion
in the mind of another telepathist.
And this thought is received
with greater impact
than the perception of the actual breast,
thigh, or erotic motion
would itself have been.
Thus, although both telepathists in our
hypothetical confrontation are male
they have made an erotic
morphological communication
which is essentially hetrosexual,
or male-female.
We can begin to see why
the telepathic experience is
essentially omnisexual in nature.
Why the male-female bisexual
categories can no longer apply.
In the sanitorium phase of
the induced telepathy series
measures were introduced to
prevent further instances
of interuption caused by
frustrated telepathic dependency.
A single compact electromagnetic
receiver transmitter
was provided for the subjects
undergoing primary group isolation.
The receiver transmitter
was to feed the subjects
reproductions
of a variety of patterns of
electrochemical discharge
unique to Dr. Stringfellow,
the group's common researcher.
The prupose of these transmissions
from the institute
was to ease the difficult transition from the
inevitable telepathic dependency
established individually between
Stringfellow and each subject
to a group telepathic cohesion
and a group telepathic autonomy.
The necessity of sharing the
transmitted electrochemical patterns
either through the sharing of
the receiver transmitter itself
or the telepathic sharing of the
experience of receiving the poatterns
would provide a basis for the
formation of a telepathic commune,
which did not depend upon
Stringfellow as a psychic cluster nucleus.
Dr, Stringfellow indicated that he himself
entered a severly depressive psychological
mode upon separation from
the induced telepathy group.
An event,
suggesting that to some extent
telepathic dependency
functions reciprocally.
Even between telepathists
and non-paranormals.
Five intensive months of work
with the remaining subjects
revealed ways to gradually increase the
tolerance among them, or group exposure.
It was found that the telepathic experience
was likely to be an overwhelming
and extremely exhausting one
verging on pain and hallucination.
The most crucial problem for
the telepathist apparently
was to develop within himself
the means to control and modulate
the rate and quality of telepathic
flow between himself and another.
The inexperienced telepathist
simply cannot cope
with the complexity and effort involved
in the social telepathic situation.
The first meeting of all the subjects as a
group took place at the Academy sanitorium
somewhat later than originally planned.
The sixth subject arrived
two weeks after the others
when it was certain that he had fully
recovered from his self inflicted violence.
It will be sometime before
the data on this period
accumulated through electroencephalographic
information retrieval
can fully evaluated.