- Is that for us?
- No, it's for you.
- What is that?
- A mantrap.
They used to use it
for catching poachers.
Hello, Amy.
- Hello, Charlie.
- Where do we put it, Mr. Sumner?
- Oh. Here in the back.
- Oh, it's heavy, Mr. Sumner.
I'm surprised
you still remember me.
Where do we put it, Amy?
Anywhere you want.
It's your birthday present.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- Don't scratch it.
- Why are you surprised?
- How long has it been, Charlie?
- Three summer holidays in six years.
David, this is an old
friend of mine, Charlie Venner.
My husband, David Sumner.
- Mr. Venner.
- Please call me Charlie.
You work around here?
Sometimes.
- Will you give me a hand, please?
- Yeah.
- David's a mathematician.
- What are you going to catch?
- Peace and quiet.
- Oh, an arithmetic teacher.
- Well, uh--
- No.
He's writing a book...
on the computer analysis
of the celestial--
Good try. Here, why don't you
put this in the trunk, Amy.
Let me.
Maybe, um, Charlie could
help us with the garage, David.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
This fellow Norman, uh--
- Scutt.
- Yes.
- He's, uh, taking forever.
- Me and Bobby'll do it
for you, Mr. Sumner.
Me and my cousin Bertie will be out
tomorrow. We'll get it up for you.
Yes? How much?
- Oh, reasonable.
- Okay, thank you.
- We're at--
- Back at Trencher's farm.
We'll be there, sir.
Good. Good.
Where are you going?
David?
- Where are you going?
- Cigarettes.
Okay.
Uh, a couple of packs of
any American cigarettes, please.
Time, gentlemen, please.
Finish your drinkin', gentlemen.
Let me have your glasses.
Henry Niles.
I thought he was to be put away.
Oh, we can take care
of our own here. Usually do.
Remember when
I took care of you, Amy?
But you didn't.
Remember?
There was once a time,
Mrs. Sumner...
when you were ready
to beg me for it.
Take your hands off me.
Come on, gentlemen. Drink up.
Let me have your glasses, please.
Bloody early, Harry.
Harry...
I think I should have another pint.
Sorry about my uncle, Harry.
I think he's a bit taken with drink.
Oh.
I do beg your pardon,
Mr. Harry Ware.
- I'll pay for
the American gentlemen's cigarettes.
- Oh, no, that's okay, I--
That's all right.
I got it, sir.
Garage coming along?
Norman fixing it up all right?
Yeah.
And I'll pay for the glass.
And I'll even pay for the little bit of
plaster to put on your bleedin' finger.
But I do think I should have
another pint to take me home.
The bar's closed, Tom.
- Come on, Tom.
- Oh.
It is, is it?
We'll see about that.!
- Take it easy, old man!
- Old man, you say?
All right, Tom.
You've had your fun.
Pay the man and leave.
Ah.
Oh.
I do beg your pardon,
Mr. Magistrate.
But what I am, I am.
What's the damage, Harry?
Call it a quid, Tom.
Let's call it, uh...
30 bob.
Will that do then, eh, Major?
Go home, Tom, will you...
or you'll be up before me
on a fresh charge.
Come on, lads.
Work to be done.
- See you tonight, Harry.
- All right, Tom.
I showed him, eh, lads?
Uh, they're paid for, sir.
They are now.
- Stupid cow!
- Get off!.
What was that about?
Who was that big guy
with the beard?
Why?
Is he any relation
to your friend Charlie?
Yes.
How well do you know
this fellow Venner?
Stop teasing.
- Did you ever go out with him?
-Stop.
- Hmm?
- Leave me alone! Stop it!
Stop.
- Tell me.
- I'll stop the car.
I just want to know.
Tell me.
Stop. I'm telling you.
- You asked for it.
- Okay.
All right, drive the car-- Ooh!
Ooh! Ooh!
You asked for it!
Chicken!
- You're nuts!
- You're terrible! You're wicked!
Oh, by the way--
- Yeah?
- Venner did try to get fresh once.
Yeah? So?
Nothing happened.!
- Ba-bum
Ba-ba-bah-bum
Ba-ba, ba-bum
Hi.
You'll have some help tomorrow.
Charles Venner and his cousin
are coming to help finish the garage.
We'll have the garage finished
before Chris gets the rats out.
- Hello, miss.
- Chris?
Yeah, Chris.
Oh,yes. Mr. Cawsey.
The rat man.
- Want help with this, sir?
- Yes.
It's a real antique, sir.
- Rare, they are.
- My wife is a collector.
But I end up with them.
I find it's a bit large
for my prey, sir.
- Won't do at all.
- Don't count on it.
- Do you like it here, sir?
- Very much.
- I hear it's pretty rough
in the States, sir.
Have you seen some of it, sir?
Bombin', riotin', snipin',
shootin' the blacks?
Can't walk down the streets, they say.
Was you involved in it, sir?
I mean, did you take part?
See anybody get knifed?
Just between commercials.
Wanna put that down there?
No, I'm just glad I'm here
where it's, uh, quiet...
and you can breathe fresh air
and drink water that doesn't
have to come out of a bottle.
It isn't water that I drink
out of a bottle, sir.
Those two fellows will be up
to help you tomorrow.
Kitty.!
- You gonna have a crack at her, Norman?
- No.
Ten months inside
is enough for me.
- They got anything worth taking?
- Nope.
Except, uh...
these.
- You bloody fool.
- It was nothing.
She's got a dozen or more.
Full of perfume.
You like my trophy?
Bugger your trophy.
I want what was in 'em.
I could do with
some of that too, Normie.
Charlie Venner.
He had some of it years ago...
when she was here with her father.
Venner's a bloody liar...
and so are you.
Tell her, smell her
Lock her in the cellar
Kitty, kitty.
Where are you?
Kitty.
Kitty, kitty.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Want a drink?
I can't find the cat.
Doesn't answer my call.
Do I?
You'd better.
Why did you hire
Charlie Venner?
I didn't. You did.
Kitty.
If she's in my study,
I'll kill her.
What?
Nothing.
That your daddy's chair?
Every chair is my daddy's chair.
I'm glad we came.
- What are you doing?
- Kiss me.
Mmm.
- You're an animal.
- Mm-mmm.
Why'd you take my heater
out of the study?
Because it's going upstairs.
What happened?
It's not going upstairs.
It's freezing in there.
Hello.
I can see you're working at top speed.
Is he in there studying?
You'd better do something.
- My husband will think
all Englishmen are lazy.
- Let me help.
Hey!
Yeah, come on over here. This way.
Watch your fingers, Chris.
What was so funny with them?
They just think
you're strange.
Why, because I'm American?
Mmm, no. No.
Just strange.
Do you think I'm strange?
Occasionally.
You act like you're 1 4.
I am.
Wanna try for 1 2?
How about eight?
I freak out for eight-year-olds.
- David?
- Huh?
Will you please
get some lettuce?
Okay.
Oh, and fix
the damned toaster.
What does she think
I'm doing here, playing games?
What is this,
grammar school?
Jesus Christ.
Uh, we're leavin' now,
Mr. Sumner.
- Mr. Riddaway be givin' us a lift.
- Fine.
Oh, I was just sayin'
to your missus...
that in a funny sort of way I feel
closer to rats than I do to people.
Even though I kill 'em for a living.
Their dying is my living.
Smell a rat, see a rat, kill a rat.
That's me, Chris Cawsey.
I'd be lost without 'em.
It's true. I tell you straight.
Cleverest thing you ever see
around these parts is a rat.
Rats is life!
Shove up,
you overgrown bastard.
How's your day been?
Been up in a fat sheep, have ya?
Oh, you fluffy fleecy darlings
You with the dark brown eyes
David?
David.!
Dinner's ready.!
Did you hear me?
- Hello, Major.
- Evening, Major.
- Evening.
- Will you be having a pint
with me then, Major?
Not tonight.
I'll buy my own.
Otherwise
we'd never get out of here.
You know that.
Yes, I do know that.
Thanks, Harry.
Excellent.
-John.
- Evening, sir.
- Fancy a game?
- Aye.
- Evening, Harry.
- Evening.
John Niles, come here to me.
- Is this for a drink, Tom?
- No, this is for the truth.
Your brother.
Been hangin' around
the girls again.
You'd better keep a closer watch,
or we'll be puttin' him away.
It's all right, Pa.
He's only throwing the ball
to 'em a little.
A little's too much
for that sod.
Watch your tongue, Norman.
I'll watch nothin'
except my own ways.
You watch your brother,
or I'll do it for you.
If he ever makes
a mistake again in any way...
I'll be the first
to have him put away.
David.! You've been at it for hours.!
Aah!
- Gave me a fright, you did.
- You watching him, are you?
Just lookin'.
Do you fancy him?
He's sweet, I think.
Want anything?
Want a tomato?
No, thanks.
Want a grapefruit?
- Hey, hey.
- Your move.
Okay.
Check.
- No, thank you.
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
"This move now...
"puts black into
a desperate plight...
"with no possibility of mobilizing
his disorganized pieces.
"Therefore, he begins
to return material...
"to make progress
in developing at any price.
Two pawns down,
white can conveniently--"
Hey, I bet I can undress,
do my exercises and get into bed
before you make your next move.
- Is it a deal?
- You're on.
- Ah! No cheating.
- I'm not cheating.
Shh, David.
Aha! I have it.
No, no, no, David,
just a minute.
You're supposed to do a hundred.
I did a hundred. I counted
by binary numbers. Make your move.
- Binary numbers.
- Make your move.
- Wait a minute.
- Come on.
- What about that one there?
- No.
- Uh--
- It's difficult, isn't it?
Terribly.
Just a minute.
I think I have it.
Um--
Ooh.
That puts you in.
-Jesus!
- What are you doing?
I gotta get my watch off.
You're an animal.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
I'm just setting the alarm.
Are you finished?
- Wait a minute.
- Oh, no. What now?
David.
David, what are you
doing down there?
- Looking for a chess piece.
- What are you doing?
Take a look.
- Whoa. Did you find it?
- No, not that.
Wait a minute.
Let me give you a hand.
Aah.!
David, no.!
- No, wait! Wait a minute!
- You see it? Huh?
- No, I didn't find it.
- I think it's a rook.
No.! Aah.! No.!
Mmm.! I love you.!
I never cheat.
Look, Amy,
don't play games with me.
I've got a lot on my mind.
You're not being fair.
I'm just trying to help.
If you want to help,
then get your friends to finish.
Get the garage makers and the
rat catchers-- Get them all to finish!
- Oh.
- A-And fix the toilet
and clean up the kitchen.
That would be a terrific help!
I love you, Amy,
but I want you to leave me alone.
Okay.
I'll leave you alone
with your blackboard.
Don't play games with me.
No.
Don't do it, Amy.
They were practically licking my body.
Who was practically
licking your body?
Venner and Scutt.
I congratulate them on their taste.
Damn rat catcher staring at me.
Why don't you wear a bra?
Why should I?
You shouldn't go around without one
and not expect that type to stare.
Look...
if you could hammer a nail, Venner
and Scutt wouldn't be out there.
Listen, Amy, uh...
fixing the toaster
and getting the garage built...
is not exactly the reason
I came here in the first place.
Are you saying
you'd be happier if we hadn't left?
We left because
I got a grant to do work...
which I haven't found
the time to do.
You left because...
you didn't want
to take a stand, commit.
Commit to what?
Huh?
I was involved with my work.
You want something out of me
that is not right to deliver.
That's not what I was there for.
But I know why you're here.
Why?
Could it be because there's
no place else to hide?
I'm here because you once said...
y-you thought
we could be happier here.
Remember?
I'm sorry.
Are you sorry sorry,
or just sorry?
Sorry sorry.
Then come here.
I'm gonna take a bath.
Why?
You don't need one.
I think I do.
Hey.
By the way, I never claimed to be
one of the, uh, "involved."
Don't forget
to draw the curtains.!
- Hello.
- Hi.
Thinking?
Mm-hmm.
- Don't want to come
for a walk, do you?
- Sure.
When?
In a little while.
Hey, hey, come on.
Come on.
Hello.
Good evening.
Kitty.! Kitty.!
Kitty, kitty.
David, I can't find the cat.!
Can you forget the cat
and let me work for a minute!
Kitty.!
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Kitty? Kitty, kitty?
" Kitty, kitty.
Kitty, kitty, kitty."
- Shit.
- Here, kitty, kitty.
Other side, sir.
Hang on. Hang on.
- Hold it, hold it.
- Wait for him for a minute.
Where be the blackbird
Oh!
- Hey, let him pass!
Let's see how good he is!
Whoo!
You're out of your mind.!
- Hello, Henry.
- Hello,Janice.
Henry! Come here!
Oh, he's all right.
Aren't you, Henry?
Henry, how many times
I gotta tell you, boy?
You don't listen.
Come on.
Come on, Henry.
We're going home.
What do you want?
You'd have known for sure what
she was after 20 years ago, eh, Tom?
Now, now, that'll do.
- They still down at the hall bingoin'?
- Yeah.
Tell her I'm behavin' meself.
I'll be along soon.
Bobby.!
Run along now.
- Hello, David.
- Hi.
Bobby!
Take care of your sister, mind.
I will, Dad.
- Bye, Mr. Sumner.
- Good-bye.
I'd like a scotch, double...
with ice.
Cheers.
Evening, Major.
- Evening, Major.
- Mr. Sumner?
- Yes?
I was about to call up to your farm to
welcome you into our little community.
I've just been welcomed.
-I'm John Scott.
- Hello.
I saw your car outside. I thought
perhaps we could drive up together.
I wanted to have
the good Reverend and Mrs. Hood...
talk you into joining us at the
church social this coming Thursday.
The vicar will run me home.
Can I buy you a drink, Major,
before you go?
No, thank you, Tom.
We're in a hurry.
Buy 'em all one.
- Good night, Major.
Watch out for sheep.!
- You got your
Wellington boots on, Major?
Now, some men
goes for women
And some men
goes for boys
But my love's
warm and beautiful
And makes
a baa-in' noise
Amy, nice to see you.
- Major, why haven't you
been out to see us before?
- Shearing time. My apologies.
- I see you brought
my drunken husband home.
- Come on, I'm not drunk yet.
Certainly not my fault.
- Hi. I'm David Sumner.
- I just brought him home.
- Barny Hood.
- Reverend.
- My wife.
- Mrs. Hood.
- Hello.
- Well, well. Please sit down.
- Barny. Louise.
- Hello, Major.
What are you drinking, Reverend?
Scotch.
The reverend and his wife...
came to invite us to a party
at the church hall next week, David.
Oh.
Well, it's, uh, going to be more than
an invitation, Reverend, isn't it?
Major, you gave away
our secret plan.
- Who said anything about money?
- I was thinking of about five--
I'll take it.
Thank you very much.
And I expect to see you both
at the social and at the church...
when you can spare the time.
Time is a little difficult to find
these days. Uh, so are cats.
By the way, Amy, did you find
your, uh, kitty, kitty, kitty?
No.
At least give us some hope
about your coming to church.
- Yes. After all, hope is your business,
Barny, isn't it?
- Yes, and faith.
And charity.
- Thanks.
- Amy's been telling us
why you came to Wakely.
- To write, to meditate.
- Why did you come?
I was drafted.
- Well, tell us what you do.
- Okay.
I'm a, uh,
astral mathematician.
Oh. Never heard of it.
That's because I just made it up.
I'll get you another drink.
I have a grant to study, uh...
possible structures
in stellar interiors...
and the implications regarding
their radiation characteristics.
-Am I boring anyone?
- Radiation-- That's
an unfortunate dispensation.
It surely is.
Yes, indeed.
As long as it's not
another bomb.
You're a scientist.
Can you deny the responsibility?
Can you?
After all, there's never been
a kingdom given to so much bloodshed...
as that of Christ.
- That's Montesquieu, isn't it?
- Oh, really?
Who's he?
Somebody well worth reading.
We'd better leave
these good people.
Yes, well, you won't let me
walk home, will you, Barny?
Mrs. Hood,
you're very lovely.
- I'll get your coat.
- Does God bore you, Amy?
In the areas of boredom, Mrs. Hood,
God is not my problem.
- Your wife tells me you play
an interesting game of chess.
- Yeah, I guess I do.
You were... awful
to the reverend.
No, no, no, no.
I wasn't.
He's all right.
I like him.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
His wife is very attractive.
Oh.
Yes, she is, isn't she?
- Here, I think I--
I think you need some help.
- David.
- Hmm?
What's a binary number?
Uh, zeroes or ones...
plus or minus.
In sequences of twos.
Hey, that's right.
You're a bright lady.
You're not so dumb.
Sometimes I need help.
When?
Like, um, now, maybe.
You got it.
What's the matter?
Scutt or Cawsey.
I've locked all the doors
and windows downstairs.
Let's keep them locked
from now on. All right?
Great.
Did you hear me?
What?
Scutt or Cawsey.
- Why?
- To prove to you they could
get into your bedroom.
I don't believe that.
Well, who else
is around all the time?
Amy, uh...
we've left all...
the doors unlocked.
I mean, it could have
been anybody passing.
"Anybody passing"?
David, a complete stranger
comes into our house...
and decides to strangle our cat
and hang her in the wardrobe?
Somebody passing?
Cawsey or Scutt.
Here, Charlie.
It's bloody heavy.
Lousy way to make a livin', though.
You gonna look at them all day?
Would you feel better
if I went out and talked to them?
Not necessarily.
Perhaps we could just pack up and leave.
Nobody's leaving.
Why? Because we paid for a year?
Look, Amy,
I'm not going to...
just go out there
and blatantly accuse them.
You don't have to accuse them.
You could start by mentioning that our
cat was strangled and see what happens.
You can believe in the possibility,
can't you?
Okay. Okay.
I'll go out and mention to them
that the cat is missing...
and I'll ask them
if they've seen her.
All right,
let's see what it's good for.
- You don't think that's enough, do you?
- Not quite.
Perhaps you'd like to write them
a note on your blackboard.
Well, I thought he might enjoy it.
- How are you?
- Fine, thank you, sir.
- How's it, uh, going up there?
- It's all right, sir.
Yeah. Want a smoke?
I like the smell of those
American cigarettes, Mr. Sumner.
Can you give me a hand with that
mantrap? Just wanna get it in the house.
Uh, right through here.
Right here by the fireplace.
Thanks.
Amy, listen.
I'm gonna catch them off guard.
- When?
- Right now.
Open or closed, Mr. Sumner?
Uh, gee, I don't know.
Uh, open it.
If you can.
Sorry, Charlie.
Bite, sir.
I can appreciate that.
Be careful.
Watch that hand
on the spring.
Pretty dangerous thing, sir.
- This is the, uh, safety lock, sir.
- Right.
Where would you like it, sir?
Uh, put it right over
the fireplace there.
You fellows like some beer?
- Very nice.
- Oh, very welcome.
Thank you.
Cheers.
Uh, cheers, miss.
- Mr. Sumner.
- Huh?
Would you like to
shoot with us sometime?
Oh, I've, uh--
I never hunted much.
Oh, but you've, uh,
shot, Mr. Sumner?
Just once or twice,
but that was--
Be easy then.
You should try it, sir.
Living here at Trencher's, with good
shootin'outside the door. Eh, Norman?
Right. Right, sir.
When?
How about tomorrow, sir?
Okay. Thank you.
That m-- That might be... fun.
I'd like that.
Thank you.
What about the garage?
It can wait.
We'll meet at Wakely
at about half past 8:00.
- You know the pub?
- Yes, I do.
Well, we'd better
get back to work, sir.
Thank you for putting that up.
That's all right, sir.
Oh, I, uh,
I don't have a gun.
But, uh--
will this do?
Ah.
There'll be plenty extra, sir.
Good.
- Thank you for the drink, sir.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Thanks for the drink, sir.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
Break it, Mr. Sumner.
- Why? It's not loaded.
- Break it.
Now you're sure.
Uh, this'll be you
right over here, Mr. Sumner.
Right.
Now, here's your sack.
We'll beat the ducks
right to ya.
- Small, they are.
- Yeah.
We don't want it broken up
with shot unless you have to.
But, uh, if--
if you can't catch 'em...
shoot 'em.
They might come
right down here, sir.
- Or they might come
from behind as well, sir.
- But I don't move?
Stay as still
as you can be, sir.
Now, we'll be spread about.
If you need us,just call.
You do that.
Here's your sack, Norman.
- You drive 'em to me, Charlie.
- I will.
Uh, good luck, sir.
Might be a little while, sir.
I'll be here.
Who is it?
Is David all right?
He's fine.
Enjoying himself.
May I come in?
All right.
- Would you like a drink?
- I'd love one.
Would you like me to go?
I will, you know.
No.
Stay and have your drink.
I'd like to know
what you think of cats.
I do fancy cats.
Please leave me.
No.
Get out!
Don't tease me, Amy.
Please.
Aah! Aah!
No!
Aah!
No.
Please, Charlie.
Amy.
I don't want to reave you, but I will.
No.
No. No.
No! No!
No!
No.
Amy!
N-No.
Easy.
I'm sorry, Amy.
I'm sorry.
Hold me.
No.
No.! No.! No.!
Why didn't you open the closet?
We don't have any more cats.
I'm firing Venner
and Scutt tomorrow.
Hooray for you, tiger.
What for?
Because they stuck it to me
on the moor today.
They also serve
who sit at home and wait.
What?
Nothing. If you'd have said
something to them ages ago...
-about the cat, this would
never have happened.
- Easy.
- None of it.
- Easy, easy.
I was going to say something
until you pulled that childish stunt...
and ruined any chance
I had of finding out.
- David, I didn't--
- I didn't finish.
- You pushed me, and you don't do
any good by pushing.
- I didn't.
When are you ever gonna
learn about growing up, huh?
I'm trying to.
Well, you're a little late.
Why didn't you ask him
instead of making me look like
an idiot with that bowl of milk?
You're a coward.
- No, I'm not.
-And I'm a coward.
Plain and simple.
No, I'm not.
I don't blame you
for hiding in your study.
I don't--
I don't want to
hide there with you.
I-- I can't anymore.
Okay.
Easy, easy, easy.
- You're fired, all of you.
- I beg your pardon, sir?
I've noted the hours
that you've worked...
and I've deducted...
the-the time wasted.
- Here. It's all here.
- Why, sir? Why are we fired?
We may not work the way
you like to work, sir--
- Listen to me.
- Sir, I mean, why?
You're fired because I don't want you
around. I want you to leave. Right now.
- Is that clear?
- We've been working all the time, sir.
Clear enough, sir.
- Norman.
- Huh?
That's a nice way
to treat people.
We're due at the church hall at 8:00.
I'd like you
to meet Amy and David Sumner.
- Hello. Nice to meet you. My husband.
- Hello, Mr. Sumner.
Hello, Amy.
Nice of you to come.
I'll show you to your seats.
Hello, Reverend.
How have you been?
- Please sit here.
- Thank you.
- I think she'll be able
to see okay from here.
- That's fine.
Would you care for a drink?
All right. Thank you.
I hope you enjoy the show.
Thank you.
Be brave.
Evening, ladies and gentlemen...
and welcome to our
annual social gathering.
It's nice to see again
all the old familiar faces.
And the not-so-old,
indeed, as well.
To begin the evening, we have
our very own Reverend Barnard Hood.
Your vicar,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for my famous newspaper trick.
Tore it up last year, Barny!
Yes, and I might well
next year, too, Tom.
Here we are, ladies and gentlemen--
a very simple trick.
I simply tear a piece
of newspaper down the center so.
Tear it again.
Fold it towards me.
Music, please.
Open it up very carefully.
Tear it again.
There we are.
Roll it towards me again.
- You enjoy this, Mrs.Johnson?
- Yes, Vicar.
It is a good trick, isn't it? I do it
in front of the mirror every night.
And we begin to open up.
- I always enjoy doing this.
It gives me a chance to...
- Hello, David.
catch up with my reading.
Hi.
You want a smoke?
And I find that
it hasn't been torn at all.
- No.
- What?
- Don't smoke in here.
And you'll also find that
that one isn't torn either.
Sorry about that, ladies and gentlemen.
But I think
you'll probably find that...
it hasn't been torn at all.
- Hello, Henry.
- Hello.
I'd like to go for a walk.
- Will you take my arm?
- Now, ladies and gentlemen...
for my piece de resistance...
I now present to you an empty glass.
I am now going to fill
this glass with milk.
Would it work better
with whiskey, vicar?
- Nothing works better with whiskey.
- I do.
You've never worked
in your life, Tom.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
I take the lid off my cocoa tin.
And very carefully now,
I place the glass...
into the tin
and replace the lid.
I take up my wand
and I utter the magic words--
What do we find in the tin...
but one complete...
glass of milk.
- Yea.!
- Good old Barny!
If I could convert you
to this, Tom, that would be a miracle.
Thank you very much.
Thank you. Major.
The next item on this evening's
program, ladies and gentlemen...
- You want to go?
- Yeah.
...who will sing for you the aria
Caranome from the opera Rigoletto.
Dad?
It's Janice.
She made off to the yard.
Then she went walking with Henry Niles.
He was holding her, Dad.
Touching her.
John Niles.
What's the matter, Tom?
Come with me.
All over her, he was.
Touching her.
Had his hands all over her.
Don't be afraid, Henry.
- I'll find him.
- No.
Let the boys find Janice.
The rest can wait.
Have you ever kissed
anyone, Henry?
No.
Get your mates to find her. I'll be
waiting in the pub. Get all of them!
Would you like to kiss me?
Go on. Find him!
Would you now all please stand?
As these lights are
extinguished in our eyes...
and also in the presence of God,
the Blessed Virgin...
and all the saints--
Deliver unto the devil
a punishment with eternal fire.
Dwell without him...
unless ye repent.
-Janice?
-Janice.!
- Amen.
- I have to go.
- No. No, they might hurt you.
-Janice.!
- Come here.!
- Where are you,Janice?
- Henry.!
Janice.!
We don't know where she is.
We looked the whole town!
- Keep looking.
- The fog's coming down.
Did you try the lorries and such,
parked outside the meeting house?
- Then do it!
- I'll go with him, Pa.
-Janice?
-Janice.!
Janice.!
We're almost home now.
Can I help?
David!
Jesus! I couldn't stop.
- Oh, God, David.!
- Easy.
Okay. Get the keys.
Easy. Easy.
David,you know it's Henry Niles?
I don't want him here.
He's hurt.
I don't want him in my house.
Fine. You get upstairs.
You go to bed.
Take a bath.
You just get out of here.
He'll stay until the doctor comes.
What do you mean,
you don't want him in your house?
- David, did you get anyone?
- No.!
I tried the doctor. He's not home,
and the consul's not either.
Nobody answers.
I'm calling the pub.
- Wakely Arms.
- Hello, this is David Sumner.
No. No, he ain't.
Oh. Well, when he comes in,
tell him to call Trencher's Farm.
I've got Henry Niles here.
Right.
It was the American,
looking for Allsopp.
He hit Henry Niles with his car.
He's got him up at Trencher's.
Bottle.
And another.
Let Norman and me go in, Tom.
We know the American.
- I want to know where myJanice is.
- We'll find out, Tom.
Riddaway will stay with you, Tom.
That I will.
- You have Henry Niles in there?
- Wait a minute. Is the doctor with you?
- We want to see Niles.
- Why? What's the matter?
Wake up!
- Wake up!
- Don't try to kid us
you're sleeping. Come on.!
- Hey, wait a minute, now.
- Come on! Come on!
He's hurt.
He could have a broken rib.
Oh. Sorry, sir.
He'll have more than a broken rib if he
doesn't tell us whereJanice Hedden is.
- What aboutJanice Hedden?
- Took her, he did.
What have you done with Janice Hedden,
you dirty pervert?
Lookee here. He played
his filthy tricks on Janice Hedden.
He took her, and he was seen
with his hands on her body.
She run, he run after her,
and now she's missing.
- Look, I understand your concern--
- You--
Don't touch him!
Don't do that.
Don't lay your hands on me!
It's none of your business,
and it never has been.
That's fine.
But you can't hit him.
Listen, Mr. Sumner...
we come to get
this bloody freak.
And we're gonna get him...
with your cooperation or without it.
David, stop it.!
Hey, listen.
Listen, Henry, did you see
Janice Hedden tonight?
Of course he did. Ain't you listenin'
to me? He did his dirty numbers on her.
Just take it easy.
Henry, listen to me.
Did you takeJanice Hedden out
of the meeting house tonight? Huh?
Listen to me. Please.
Gentlemen, he's helpless.
Look at him. He couldn't hurt a fly.
You'd be better off looking for
Janice Hedden than standing around here.
You know?
All right. We go find Janice,
you go find the doctor.
I'm not leaving him here
with my wife.
- Thought you said he was helpless.
- Yeah.
You wouldn't leave him alone with your
wife or your kid, if you had one.
Oh, that's different, huh?
Look-- Look, fella.
He's staying here with me until
the doctor and the police arrive.
- He's my responsibility.
- Your responsibility?
- That's right.
- Why?
This is my house.
Okay, come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
The police'll be here soon.
What did the bastard say?
Didn't talk.
Well, why didn't you make him?
That's what you went in there for!
-Uh, David--
-Why don't you just go make some coffee?
I want that Niles.!
I'm goin'in.
- Please, David. Stop them.
- Don't worry.
Solid. They can't break in.
I know how they feel.
I'd feel the same way if it was
my kid that was missing.
Amy, go to bed, huh? Go on.
I can handle this.
You give me that Niles!
Hey! Hey, cut it out!
Listen to me. If you don't stop now,
so help me God I'll press charges!
Okay, you've had your fun.
I'll give you one more chance.
And if you don't clear out now,
there'll be real trouble. I mean it.
- Chris.!
- Come on. They're gonna cooperate now.
Just go on upstairs.
Don't worry.
- Where are you going?
- I'm just gonna fix the window.
- Do you think we ought to
clear off, Norman?
- Why?
We'll get that Niles.
I tell you we will.
Well, why stop then?
He's got no right to live,
an animal like that.
Tom, I'll run 'round,
I'll slip in the window...
and get that Niles out
quick as a flash.
Uh, the rest of you, kick up a row.
Hey.!
What the hell is wrong
with you people?
It's that snipe
we're after, Mr. Sumner.
- I said stay down!
- I want the lavvy.
Come on.
Look, you stupid Yank.
Let's have Niles
before someone gets hurt!
Come on. Up you go.
I've had to put up
with a lot in my time.
You can't leave him in there.
But I draw the line at this place.
No.!
I'll have an answer,
or I'll have blood!
Where are you going?
Give Niles to them.
That's what they want.
They just want him.
Give them Niles, David!
- They'll beat him to death.
- I don't care.
You send him out,
or your whole house will be--
Get him out!
You really don't care, do you?
No, I don't.
Cawsey.!
Come here.!
There's more whiskey
in the lorry.!
No. I care.
This is where I live.
This is me.
I will not allow violence
against this house.
Don't worry.
Go on upstairs.
- Beautiful.!
- Please don't leave me.
Just do as you're told.
Get out of there!
David? It's me, Major Scott.
- Come on.
- Thank you.
I see you finally got
through the enemy lines.
Don't worry about that.
I'll tell them to clear off.
Sorry I didn't get here earlier.
Yeah, I am too.
They're breaking all my windows.
David,Janice Hedden is missing.
Tom is out of his mind with worry.
They're drunk out there.
I know that,
but you're the law here.
Oh, where can he be
I don'tjust kill 'em,
you know. I breed 'em as well.
I'll deal with them.
- David!
- Lots more where they came from.
Well, Tom,you're being
a bit stupid, aren't you?
Chucking things through people's
windows. You ought to have more sense.
You tell him I want that Niles
or I'll come in and get him!
You give me that bloody gun and get
the hell out of here. That's an order.
What about myJanice?
It weren't one of yours.
- He took myJanice.
- Listen, Tom.
We don't want any trouble
here, do we?
There wouldn't have been any trouble
if you'd put Henry Niles away.
You wanted to put my Emma
away soon enough!
Damn you, Hedden.
Give me that gun.
Damn you, Major.
Let go!
- David!
- Bastards!
Bastards.!
You bastards!
David, phone! Phone anybody!
Please, phone somebody!
David!
Phone!
- No calls tonight.
- It's dead.
Get the lights. Go on.
I didn't reckon on nobody
gettin' killed, Norman.
Yeah, well, that's too bad.
We're all in it now.
- Accessories, we are.
- That's the law.
Henry Niles!
David, give them Niles.
That's what they want.
I'm gonna keep them
out of this house.
Please! Listen to me!
- Come on!
- Shut your mouth. Shut it.
I can hold them off. Don't worry.
Someone will show up.
- David!
- Cut it out!
Like Major Scott?
David, how are you
gonna keep them out?
- I can keep them out.
- How? There are five men out there.
- I know that.
- They have a gun!
I know they have.
- Honey, I know what I'm doing.
- Goddamn you, David!
- If you don't give them Niles, I will!
- Oh, no, you don't.
We're gonna blast your windows.!
This is my affair.
The lights.
Go upstairs and turn on
all the lights.
They won't be able to see me,
but I'll be able to see them. Go ahead.
No.
No, I won't.
Go.
Goddamn you! Move!
Move!
Yee-hee-hee-hoo!
Oh, he's running it
into the glass house.!
Norman.!
Charlie.! In the glass house.!
What are you gonna do on your own?
Do we have any rope? Huh?
I'm talking to you.
Do we have any rope?
No.
I suggest...
you get out of the way
of the windows.
I also suggest that you turn
the rest of the lights on upstairs.
- Do we have any wire?
- I told you, I won't help you.
I see.
Why don't you entertain Niles?
Norman! Chris!
Who is it?
Where are ya?
- Yaa-ha!
- Aah!
Oh, I fell!
You're damned right, ya jerk!
I'll wrap this bike
'round your neck!
- See ya at the bottom!
- Yee!
Let me in the door.!
I want Niles.!
David, they're everywhere.
What are we gonna do?
- David! Aah!
- Amy.
Amy. Amy.
Open the door,
and let's have Niles.
I won't let them hurt you.
Please, love.
Wait there.
I'm coming, Charlie.
Wait. Wait, Tom.
No, David!
Easy, Tom. Come on, Tom! Wait a minute.
Let me out, David!
David, I'm sick of it.
If you don't let them have
what they want, then I'm going.
Let me go.
Go. Go.
Go on.
No! Aah!
Stay there and do
as you're told.
If you don't,
I'll break your neck.
You've got more cartridges, Tom.
Enough for all of them.!
- It's just Niles.
- Listen--
He can't shoot
through that door.
Ya dirty Yank bastard.!
Listen to me.
You know what happens if they
get in now? They'll kill us all.
They've gone too far
to back down now.
You understand that?
We're dead if they get in.
Thank you, sweetheart. Stay.
- Cawsey, come here.!
- Where are ya?
- Can you get in?
- Yeah, I think so.
They'll be hiding from the gun.
Get in and slip along and open the door.
Hey. Make bloody sure
Tom don't fire at me.
He won't. I'll be there.
Mrs. Sumner, I've got
something for you here. Look.
Aah!
See him down there?
- Get out! Get out!
-Aah.! Hee hee.!
Let go.
Make one move, you son of a bitch,
and I'll slit your throat.
Give me your other hand.
Come on.
This wasn't any of my doing, sir.
It was Venner and Hedden.
Been after your wife,yes.
Am I hurting you, Mr. Scutt?
- My neck's on the glass.
- Good.
Hope you slit your throat.
Come out here.!
Amy, come here.
Get me out ofhere.!
Tom.!
- Wait. Fine.
- Watch my head.
Hold it still.
That's it.
Get upstairs.
There we are.
David.! David.! No.!
No! Aah!
David! No! Aah!
Open the attic door. Come on.
Come on.
Tom!
Open the door,
or I'll blow you to pieces.!
- You bastard.
- Okay. Okay, take it easy.
Where is he?
I can't see him.
Open the door.!
More water!
Norman, Tom.! Come in here.!
- I got him!
- It'll hold. Where's the pole?
Go on. Yell out if you see them
come around the front.
Charlie, come over here.
Here we go again.!
Keep goin', Norman.!
Do it again.!
Hee-hee.!
- Tom!
- To your right a bit.
Watch this one.
He's playing music.
- Give me the gun.
- Out of the way. I'm goin' in.
Keep the gun pointed,
and he won't get near you.
I've got ya, Tom!
What's the matter, Tom?
You're dead!
I'll kill ya!
Don't come in.
You don't come in here.
Evenin', Mr. Sumner.
Come on.!
Come on!
Gun's empty.
Is it, now?
Why don't you pull it
and show me?
I've got plenty of time,
Mr. Sumner.
David, I need you.!
Charlie.!
No! Get away!
No.! Aaah.!
No.! No.!
Take him downstairs, Charlie.
You put him to sleep.
I'll call you when I'm ready.
Just do it, Charlie.
No, Charlie!
Jesus.
I got 'em all.
Amy? Get-- Get the gun.
Amy--
Use the gun, Amy.
Okay. Okay?
You okay?
Hmm?
I don't know my way home.
It's okay.
I don't either.