I wanna come home,
Claire. Let me come home.
Please.
Just get out.
Get out!
Don't tell me Dad's not
coming back. Don't tell me that.
Kevin, wait. Kevin?
Claire.
I love you like a sister,
but you have got to
get those divorce
papers signed
and move on.
It's been nine months.
What? Are you having
second thoughts?
I'm having dinner.
With Garrett?
Oh, you pussy!
It's for Kevin's birthday.
Honestly, Vicky, sometimes I
think you're rooting against us.
Who's "us"?
You and me,
or you and him,
because I kinda
thought that was done.
He's the father of my kid.
Who cheats
with the secretary
every time he goes
to the home office.
Brings a whole new meaning
to "the San Francisco Treat. "
Not funny.
He said she smelt like chocolate
chip cookies.
Goodbye. I'm just quoting his email.
You don't have to! Okay?
Because it's
burned in my mind.
Forever.
And for your information, he
doesn't go to San Francisco anymore.
So, stop bringing it up.
It's not fair.
Ta-da!
Make a wish.
Happy birthday!
You made that?
Of course!
Come on. I've been
waiting all day.
I want you to see this.
Okay.
I'll help you.
One, two, three!
Ta-da!
Oh, my God! Dad!
Huh?
It's like a high-powered
gaming tower
with an arctic cooler.
And you made this?
Three weekends in a row.
Triple processor.
Dad, thank you so much.
Let's do cake.
What are you guys
doing for Labor Day?
I don't know. Why?
I thought we'd go camping
like the old days.
Mom, too? GARRETT: Yeah, of
course. That's what I was thinking.
Oh, it will be a lot of fun.
We could catch fish,
and, Mom,
you could cook it.
Yeah, that sounds
like a lot of fun.
Please?
Look at you, you got schmutz
everywhere. Go clean up.
Okay. All right,
be right back.
Come on, what do you say?
Um...
When were you
thinking of going?
I get back from
a business trip
the Thursday
before Labor Day.
Business trip?
Yep. Get back
Thursday night,
we'll leave, three days.
Where?
That old cabin we used
to go to at Mammoth Lakes.
That sounds great!
No, I meant where
is your business trip?
Let me guess. San Francisco?
It's work.
It's not what you think.
Does she still work there?
Claire, it doesn't matter.
No, I guess
it doesn't matter.
Mom?
Yeah?
So, you coming or not?
Mmm. You know what?
That's the weekend
before school starts.
So, you know, you guys should
just keep it a guy trip.
You'll have a blast.
Okay.
Kevin!
Honey, we gotta go.
I know.
Mom, the door is jammed.
Mom, look,
can we just forget it?
Because I don't wanna
see another doctor, okay?
He's not gonna tell you
anything any different.
He is the best allergist
in the Valley, okay?
We're going.
You know what?
I'll lift the door,
you pull the cord.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, you ready, Mom?
Just pull it up! It's
too heavy.
It's too heavy.
Pull it up, baby.
I got it.
I can fix that
for you if you want.
And you are?
My nephew.
Oh, hey, Mr. Sandborn.
Noah. I'm staying
next door with my uncle.
Claire.
He's here to help me
when I get the, uh,
bone marrow transport.
Right.
"Transplant," Uncle Bob.
"Transplant. "
Oh, yeah.
He's got a real knack
for fixing things.
I can, uh, take a
look at this real quick.
Hey, how you doing?
I'm Noah.
Kevin. Yeah. Um...
I don't know
what the issue is.
It might be
off the track, but...
Nah. Actually,
it's the clutch.
We can get another one at the
hardware store if you want.
You wanna go? Come on.
Well, you know, we actually
had somewhere to be,
but now that
we're gonna be late...
Mom?
Okay.
Go ahead.
Cool.
All right. It was nice
meeting you. You, too.
Uncle Bob?
Are you gonna be okay?
Yeah, sure, I'm fine.
Look at me.
Hey. Love you.
Love you, too.
His parents died last year.
I'm all he's got now
in the way of family.
He seems like a nice boy.
Yeah, he is.
You up for some coffee?
Yeah, sure. Sure.
Come on.
So, the entire time,
it was the clutch.
Mm-hmm.
How old are you,
anyway?
Almost 20.
But you're not
from around here.
No. San Bernardino.
My uncle, actually,
my great-uncle, uh,
he needed help,
I needed a change,
so I figured I'd go
back to school here.
You mean college?
There was this, uh...
Accident.
So, I lost some time.
So, I'm gonna finish up
at Monroe High.
That's where I go. My mom
teaches there, actually.
She seems way too cool
to be a teacher.
She is cool.
For a mom.
Okay. We got everything.
Good to go?
Yeah, let's go.
Okay.
Here you go, sir.
Thank you.
Whoa.
Can you, uh, pay for this?
What?
Uh...
Look,
that's Allie Callahan, okay?
She's the most
beautiful girl in school
and I just can't think when I'm
around her. So, just, can you...
I don't know.
I hate to tell you this,
but she's already seen you.
Just go on
and talk to her.
And say what?
Just tell her,
"Here are some garage parts. How much?"
Go!
Wow. Very funny. Yeah.
Come on.
Thank you.
You want me to fail.
Hi.
Hi, Kevin.
Hi, Allie. Um, I didn't
know you worked here.
My dad's making
my brother and me
do split shifts
to earn gas money.
It could be worse.
If you didn't have a brother,
you'd be working full time.
Noah Sandborn.
Allie. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
I'm friends
with Kevin here.
I'm gonna go look around.
Okay, sure.
So, you're having
a good day?
Yeah.
Great.
How about you?
Actually...
Hey, check it out.
Look who it is! Whiz!
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Okay, okay!
Jason! Guys!
Did you pee-pee?
Oh, what is this, huh? Come on.
Is this your EpiPen?
Your little
penis purse?
You guys, stop it!
Get out of the store!
The kid still pisses the bed.
All three of you, get out!
Okay, all right,
fine, fine.
See you later, Whizzy. Stay away
from liquids.
Hey, Noah,
are you ready to go?
Uh, Allie, how much
is this gonna be?
I'll ring it up.
Clutch is in.
We're all good.
You thirsty?
Yeah.
Thanks for fixing the door.
And for including him.
Hey, there was this kid
at the hardware store
giving him a hard time.
Jason Zimmer?
Um, skater kid, red hair,
permanently dumb look
on his face?
That would be the one. Kept
on calling him "The Whiz. "
He actually had an incident
a couple of years ago
on a playground
where he got stung by a bee,
and his throat swelled up
and he panicked
and lost control.
Whiz.
Oh, man.
Kids can be cruel. Especially
kids like Jason Zimmer.
But, please,
don't tell him I told you.
He'd be mortified.
You can trust me.
Anyways, uh, you're all set.
This is very exciting. Very
exciting moment.
It works!
Thank you.
I'm gonna take off
this cover real quick.
Put it over there.
On the ground?
Uh, wherever. Just set
it down, doesn't matter.
Set it down?
Yeah.
All right, now this
bad boy right here
is the alternator.
You know what this does?
No.
It charges the battery.
So, I'm gonna
do one piece of it,
you're gonna do the other,
all right? All right.
All right?
Yeah.
You're actually
going the opposite way.
Yeah.
All right, we're gonna
check out the alternator.
You're loosening it up
rather than tightening it.
How's that?
It's in there. You wanna
finish it off, Noah?
I'll just do it in there.
Okay.
Yeah, this one
needs two...
Make sure it's
actually in there.
To the right?
Okay,
I'm changing the subject.
Um, how long will your
uncle be in the hospital?
Um, I don't know.
It's all about
the transplant taking.
Well, until he's better, you
can come over for dinner here
anytime, okay?
I don't want you eating
by yourself. I mean it.
Thanks, but I don't
wanna impose.
Oh, I do. Especially if
she's making the guacamole.
You are not an imposition.
Are you saying I am?
Mmm.
Well, in that case,
I wouldn't mind
imposing on your
literature class.
Oh, no, dude,
you don't wanna do that.
They call her
"The Crusher. "
Is that what they call me?
Yes.
Yeah.
You know what? Carry
your own plate.
Clean up all the dishes.
Now he's really
worried about it.
Strange kid.
Why?
Can't put my finger on it.
Don't try so hard.
Okay. He's interested
in literature?
In the classics.
Back in San Bernardino,
we were studying the Odyssey.
You want me to help
you out with that?
Sure. Here you go.
You know, I'm teaching
Homer next semester.
Really? He's my favorite.
You're kidding, right?
Second that.
Dude, you gotta
read the lliad.
Achilles is this
total badass.
Hot-tempered, full of pride,
completely consumed
by his emotions.
You know what he
called Agamemnon?
Who?
"A pitiful excuse
for a king. "
To his face.
He killed this guy, Hector.
But instead of hiding out
like a pussy, he...
Dragged his dead body around
for everybody to see.
Yes! He stood by his
actions, right or wrong.
Well, because to him
they were justified.
Do you have any idea
what they're talking about?
No.
Homer's a genius,
my man.
Just like Shakespeare,
Byron, Zeppelin, Dylan.
Ugh.
Poets.
I'll have him
back Sunday afternoon!
Bye, Mom, I love you!
Oh, hey, Noah,
come on in.
You know,
Kevin already left.
Actually, I, uh, picked
something up for you.
Oh, my God,
this is a first edition?
I can't accept this, this
must have cost a fortune!
It was a buck at a garage
sale. One man's trash...
Noah, I can't.
Honestly...
Claire, please!
I've been eating here
every single night.
It would mean a lot to me.
Thank you.
Those yours?
Oh, no.
They were a gift from Vicky. Good.
Why?
Those kind of shoes are
for women trying to be sexy.
You don't need to try.
I'm sorry,
I shouldn't have, uh...
No. No, it's okay.
Where are you?
Almost there.
Well, hurry up!
Vicky, I can't do this!
I haven't had a date
in 18 years,
I don't even know
what to do anymore!
Three yhings.
One, laugh a lot.
Two, take off
your wedding ring.
Three, give him head.
What?
Kidding!
Just get here, pronto!
And yhe closer
I get to this car,
the smell is getting stronger
and stronger.
And I walk up to
the guy's window,
rolls down the window,
I look and on
the passenger seat is
his dead dog!
You did not tell me that.
So, Ethan tells me you teach.
English, is it?
The classics.
Wow.
What does that mean?
Oh. No, he just
means as a compliment,
like, "Wow, you teach
the classics. "
It's fancy.
I mean, I don't know
how many kids nowadays
are going to use
what they learn
from classics.
No offense.
Oh, none taken.
I am a vice principal
and I just want to see
these kids employed.
Shall we order?
Silly me,
I just want them educated.
I'm fine with education,
but we gotta
get them working.
Practical skills.
That's where the money is.
Ah! Money!
That's the goal, then.
Oh. Ethan,
how's your mom?
Gallstones.
Oh, gallstones.
Mm-hmm.
Are those the ones you
pass? Or are those the other stones?
Yeah,
she's getting better.
You know, money's fine, except
when it's motivated by greed.
You're a little firecracker when
you get riled up, aren't you?
I think it stopped raining.
Firecracker?
Is that how you regard
women with an opinion?
Only when they
disagree with mine.
Pleasure to meet you, Benny.
No, Claire,
stay, stay!
J. K. Rowling.
I'm sorry?
Billionaire.
Classics major.
She's a lot of laughs.
You gotta get to know her.
Hello?
Quesyion.
I tried to defrost
a chicken in the microwave.
And some of it's
kind of cooked,
some of it's kind of not.
Do you think
it's still cool to
eat the cooked part?
No! Do not eat that!
Then, please, come over
and bail me out. Um...
Um... Uh...
Okay.
Perfect. Okay.
Yes.
See you soon.
Okay.
I mean,
that date was awful.
Like that chicken.
I'm sorry I couldn't salvage
it more, but... You did fine.
The damage was done.
Yeah. I'm glad
I had you next door.
What?
God, you're beautiful.
You know that?
Oh, no, I'm...
Amazing.
And sweet,
natural and sexy.
So sexy.
Noah!
Kiss me, Claire.
Just...
I can't.
Just once.
Please.
I have to go.
Tonight, in the window...
You were watching me.
I can't do this!
Noah!
I want to watch you now.
This can't happen.
We can't.
It's wrong!
It doesn't feel wrong,
does it?
Wait.
It feels so...
Oh, my God, stop.
...nice.
Soft.
Please, please stop.
Noah, please!
Stop.
No judgments.
No rules.
Just us.
Oh, my God.
A woman like you
should be cherished.
Loved.
Let me love you, Claire.
You are perfect
in every way.
Oh, my God!
Hey! Where are you going?
Home.
I gotta get home.
No, you don't.
Kevin doesn't get home till
later. Have some coffee.
I can't. This...
Was incredible.
Hey, you're having second
thoughts, it's normal.
This isn't normal, okay?
Nothing about this
is normal.
Where's my coat?
Would you just stop
for one minute?
Look, Noah,
I don't want you to think
that any of this
was your fault, okay?
I'm the adult, I'm the
one that should've known...
Stop, stop! Just stop!
What we did wasn't wrong.
No matter what you say,
it wasn't wrong!
I wasn't thinking
clearly, okay?
I got swept up in the
moment. I was vulnerable
and you're very sweet.
No.
And it was flattering, but I... No.
It was more than that.
God damn it!
Noah, look,
it wasn't more
than that, okay.
I was feeling vulnerable.
How can you say that?
Last night was so perfect.
Because it's true.
And in time, you're
going to see it, too.
Just leave.
Are you okay?
Go!
Mom, we caught seven trout.
Wow!
Yeah, he was, uh,
pretty amazing.
Uh, Mom, can Dad
stay for dinner?
Um...
Please?
Dad?
Sure.
I saw this video
on YouTube,
where this, just like,
big, you know, mountain dude
who lives all alone in
this old shack in Montana.
And he cooks all
his food on a shovel.
No, you didn't.
We did.
I mean, we wrap it up
in tinfoil first...
And eat off the shovel?
Yeah, well, the
foil-covered shovel.
It was a great meal.
It was delicious.
Yeah, it was, like, one of
the best meals I've ever had.
Oh! Thank you!
No. No offense, Mom.
You know what I mean.
I don't mean it like that.
This was great.
What do you
think she made?
I bet you it's cookies.
I'll get it.
You want any coffee?
Yeah,
I'll have some if you are!
Noah! What's up?
Hey, man,
you're back.
How was the trip?
Hey, Dad,
this is, uh, Noah.
Remember, I've been
talking about him a lot?
Hey, nice to meet you!
I feel like I know you,
he talks about you so much.
Told me about the alternator
you put in the truck.
Oh, actually,
Kevin helped out, too, so...
Yeah?
Yeah, I did.
Yeah. It was so cool.
I had no idea
you could do that yourself.
That's what
friends are for.
Hey, Mrs. Peterson.
Hey, Noah.
Wow, looks perfect.
You tell them what
happened this weekend?
What happened?
Oh, there was a big
thunderstorm up here.
You guys didn't
get it up there?
No, beautiful,
dry as a bone at the lake.
Well, it got
pretty wet here.
Wow.
You know what, big day
tomorrow. First day of school.
It's getting kind of late.
But it's, like, 8:30.
No, no, no. Actually, I gotta get
going. It's a big day tomorrow.
I'll walk out with you,
Mr. Peterson.
Oh, I'm going to stay
around awhile, thanks.
Well, you know, I'll
walk out with you, Noah.
Yeah, come on.
Uh, do you want to take
a cookie for the road?
I love your
mother's cookies.
They're great, right?
Nice to meet you.
Yeah. You, too, pal.
Nice kid.
You know, we need
to figure out
what we're doing here,
Garrett.
What do you mean?
I mean, we're in limbo here
and maybe, you know,
it's just time to move on.
I'm not seeing her
anymore.
But you might as well be, because
I'm always going to think you are
and I don't want
to live that way.
And you shouldn't want
to live that way, either.
Hey, it wasn't about her.
It was about us.
Okay? We were broken.
We both checked out.
I'm not saying what I
did was right, it wasn't.
It was...
It was stupid.
Smart people do dumb
things. They make mistakes.
Haven't you ever
made a mistake?
Don't throw
our marriage away
because I made a mistake.
Don't file. Not yet.
Just take...
Take some time.
All right.
Come on.
Welcome, everybody,
to the start of
a brand-new year.
This year,
we are studying
Homer's lliad
and its themes.
The first one we'll be studying
is the wrath of Achilles.
Mrs. Peterson.
Principal Warren,
what a nice surprise.
Good news.
I've approved your request
for Noah Sandborn
to join your class.
"No man or woman born,
coward or brave,
"can shun his destiny!"
I think it was Achilles
who said that, right?
Wait!
Ed?
Wait a second.
This is a class
for AP juniors,
Noah Sandborn
is a transfer senior, so...
I'm confused.
Your transfer request
said, yeah,
that he'd be an asset
to the class.
This was your email.
That's right. Thank you.
Have a great year.
Hey!
Stop following me!
I'm not following you, Claire.
I live next door.
Kevin!
Yeah?
Did you send an email
from my account
to Principal Warren?
No, why?
Because somebody did.
It sounds like
you've been hacked.
You should really
change your password.
You know, I'd be happy to help
you out with that, if you want.
No, thanks.
Hey, you ready to go?
Yeah!
Kevin!
Noah, can you give us
a second, please?
You can wait
for him outside.
Yeah, I'll be
down in a minute.
Oh, sure, yeah.
Mom, that was really rude.
Why'd you do that?
He's here way too much.
You're the one who
told him he could be
and he's coming
to dinner tonight.
No, your dad's
coming to dinner tonight.
So, why can't
he come, too?
I want it to just be
the three of us, okay?
Okay, yeah.
Okay.
All right.
I'll see you later, then.
My Uncle Bob was
a tail gunner in Korea,
and a sergeant in Vietnam.
Tough old dude.
Now he's laying
in Valley Memorial,
hoping the transplant takes.
Here, you got that?
Thanks.
Your dad seems to be
around a lot now, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
Like a dinner
and a camping trip
can just make you forget
about how he walked out on you.
Yeah, it's so predictable.
A guy hits middle age,
and suddenly
staring death in the face.
You know,
tire around the waist,
hair in the drain,
cock that just
won't stand up anymore.
He wants to
feel alive again.
feel that rush,
you know, he felt
when he was our age.
So, he picks up
a younger woman and poof!
Whole new life.
Go ahead and aim.
Almost.
Little better, right?
Yeah. Here,
switch with me real quick.
Then the guilt sets in.
Because he basically just
left the first kid in the dust.
So, he tries to bribe him.
With things.
Like computers.
Wow.
You follow me?
So, what's up?
How's school?
It is what it is.
Tell him about
your computer class.
He's learning how to
write his own software.
Like father, like son.
That's cool. We can
do some stuff together.
I dropped it.
What?
It was boring.
Going out for boxing now.
You're going out for boxing?
You don't like boxing!
How would you know?
Seriously, how would you know
what I like and what I don't like?
Am I missing something here?
Yeah!
Okay. You've been missing it
for nine months, Dad!
You just can't
come back in here
and expect to pick up,
like nothing happened!
All right, Kevin,
that's enough!
No! Mom, he's gotta
hear this! Okay.
Life's been happening, Dad.
You know what, Mom,
I got homework to do.
Kevin, wait. At least
finish your dinner!
Let him go.
He just probably
needs some space.
Here we go.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, uh, how was
dinner with your dad?
Let's just take a break,
all right?
No, keep going!
Come on, talk to me.
Dinner?
God, I was a jerk, okay?
I feel really bad about it.
No! No! Dude, that's good.
It means he knows
you're onto his bullshit.
We just have to hope that
your mom doesn't fall for it.
Can't let her, uh,
be his meantime girl.
What's that?
You know, someone he
screws in the meantime.
Hey, uh, come on.
Someone he screws
in the meantime?
Yeah. Put your body
into it, there we go!
Kev! Take it easy, Kev!
Calm down!
Easy, easy! Kev!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Kev! Kev!
What do I do?
God damn it!
Where's your pen?
Shit!
Kev. Kev, I got it!
What do I do with it?
Oh, my God!
Where do I put this?
Shove it in the leg!
Is it working?
You good?
Oh, my...
Are you all right?
Oh, my God.
You're not dying
on me today, okay.
God! Get over here!
Garrett's coming on
a little strong,
don't you think?
What makes you think they're
from Garrett?
Did you read my card?
Would I read your card?
"Please give me
another chance. "
What? It's a thin envelope.
Ugh.
Tell me you're not going to.
I'm thinking about it.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
Oh, I know! I know.
Let's tell him
to take his cookies
and shove 'em
right up his ass.
You know what? Enough
with the cookie jokes.
We've all done things in our lives
that we wish we wouldn't have.
You know what?
Maybe you should start
worrying about yourself
for a change.
It's way more fun
worrying about you.
Make him grovel
just a little bit, I swear...
Hey!
Um...
Uh, did I catch you
at a bad time?
No, never. They're beautiful, Garrett.
What is?
The flowers!
Flowers? What flowers?
Claire? Hello?
You know what, I'm
going to call you back.
I need to talk to you.
I'm busy with
physical education.
I believe you're familiar
with that subject, right?
Noah!
Those flowers?
What were you thinking?
They were
a peace offering.
Do you know what
that looks like?
A student sending
a teacher flowers?
That's why I didn't
sign the card.
And you hacked my email?
You said I could be
in your class.
And you're trying to turn
Kevin against his father!
You can't blame me
for the trouble your cheating
ex-husband has brought upon himself.
Stop it!
You're welcome, by the
way. For saving your son?
Thank you.
You know what,
you're right,
I should have thanked you.
Everything okay,
Claire?
Yes, Mike.
Everything's fine.
Thanks.
Look, I just want us
to start over, Noah, okay?
Can we do that, please?
Yeah. I can if you can.
So, deal?
You can trust me, Claire.
Okay?
Okay.
Allie? Hey.
Hi, Kev.
Need something?
Yeah, um, I need four three-eighth
hex head bolts, nuts and washers.
And I need an air filter
for a 2012 Silverado Z71.
And I need you to go
to a movie with me.
I'm kind of busy with work.
And now that school's started... Um...
Okay.
Um...
Well, I guess
I'll see you around, then.
But I don't have
a date to the Fall Fling.
Uh, me neither.
That'd be really great.
Like, really, really, um...
Great?
Yeah, great.
Great.
Okay. Well, um,
I'll see you around.
Okay, cool.
Okay.
I think I like
the first one better.
You do?
Yeah.
Then the soldier says, "No, no,
buddy, she didn't have a head. "
Oh, God.
It's stupid.
It is stupid.
I'm not ready.
What?
There's someone else?
No! But we were apart.
Hey, no, no. I don't wanna
know. Look, it was nothing.
It just made me
realize how lost I was.
Me too, Claire.
We gotta...
Listen, we gotta
have a clean slate.
Okay.
But until I get
my head straight,
I'm not ready to
just jump back in,
and I need you
to know that.
All right.
It's honest. Okay?
No guarantees, I get it.
Okay.
Um...
I think I had one too many.
Can I crash on the couch?
Okay.
I just want you to know,
I'm not giving up on us.
Well, I want you know
that I'm not asking you to.
Kevin! Let's go!
What a fucking whore
you are!
"Deal," you said.
"Let's make a deal. "
You trying to
play me, Claire?
Is that what this is?
Of course not.
Bullshit!
What?
Why are you doing this?
Because you're a fucking liar!
What is wrong with you?
I'm seeing things
clearly now.
You have to stop! Hey,
Noah, what's going on?
Game on.
Mom, what just happened?
Honey, I need you to
stay away from Noah, okay?
He's a bad influence.
What're you talking about?
You're just going to have
to trust me on this one.
No, I'm not going
to trust you! Okay.
'Cause you're not taking away
the one good friend I have.
He is not your friend!
Bullshit!
Mom, he's my friend!
Excuse me? Watch your
mouth and get in the car!
You know, he said you'd do this. What?
He said you'd do this,
and if you did,
then it was Dad
talking and not you.
He's been right all along!
This is crazy!
Noah, wait!
Kevin! I'm asking you
to get in the car.
See you at school.
Hey! Whoa!
Excuse me.
Hello.
Move! Move!
Hey, Peterson!
Your movie was on Turner
Classics last night.
The Wiz.
It's like the black version
of The Wizard of Oz.
The Wizards of Waverly Place
are on tomorrow.
Fuck you, Zimmer!
Want some of this?
Yeah, fuck you!
Stop it! Noah, stop it! Stop it!
Get off!
Get up! Get the fuck up!
Noah, stop!
Fuck you!
So, I was looking
at your files.
Why?
I'm a vice principal.
It's my job.
Whatever.
So, what a surprise
I found when we didn't
have your transcripts
from your old school,
so I called them.
Know what they told me?
To mind your own business?
No!
That you were kicked out
for disorderly conduct.
Jason Zimmer's skull is fractured.
You could have killed him!
Okay.
I'm not done.
I am.
I'm not! Sit down!
I said sit down!
You know what I see?
I see a pattern of disturbing
behavior. Poor impulse control.
You know what I see?
A pathetic old woman
who's trying to look
and act like
something she's not.
Something she'll never be.
Because all she really is
is a dried up,
dirty, fucking cunt.
You're gone,
you're expelled!
Kevin, you don't want
to keep her waiting.
Come on,
you're going to be late!
Mom, we're going
to get there too early,
nobody's even
going to be there.
Okay, how do I look?
Like the handsomest man
on Earth.
Mom, come on,
please, stop.
Seriously, come on,
tonight has gotta be
perfect, all right?
Because Allie Callahan's the
most beautiful girl in school
and I just never thought
she'd actually go out with me.
Okay, please, stop.
Well, she obviously knows
quality when she sees it.
Mmm.
She'll love it! Come on!
Hey!
Hi, Kev.
You look amazing.
Thanks, Allie. Uh, you
look really great, too.
Thanks.
Uh, this is...
That's for you.
Thank you.
Mrs. Peterson?
Yes?
Um, some of the guys
said there's water
running out of
the boys' bathroom.
Oh, okay. Um...
You guys go. Have fun.
Okay.
I'll check it out.
So, do you like the flower? Yeah.
I love it, thank you so much.
Anybody in there?
Ugh.
We need to talk.
Your behavior has been
completely unacceptable.
My behavior?
And I'm not going
to stand for it.
Just let me go.
So, what, your shit-head
husband comes crawling back
and you're just
done with me?
Suddenly,
I'm nothing to you?
Like what we had
never even happened.
It was one night, and it was
a mistake! We had nothing!
Hey, hey! Yes, we did.
And you loved it.
Just like this.
No.
Don't.
You think you can scare me
with some graffiti
on the wall?
Think again!
It's going to be
your word against mine!
And who do you think
they're going to believe?
Stay away from me!
And stay away from my son!
Sorry, guys.
Good morning!
Um...
Give me one second, okay?
What's going on?
She locked us out.
Mrs. Peterson.
Mrs. Peterson,
open this door!
Mrs. Peterson!
Open this door now!
Mrs. Peterson,
I'm coming in!
Come on in.
What the devil's going on?
The bell rang
five minutes ago.
Oh, I'm sorry, Ed.
Take a seat. Come on.
Why was your
door locked, Claire?
Oh, I just had
a personal call.
You guys take
your seat, okay?
All right.
You know what, give Mrs.
Peterson and I a second.
I'm concerned, Claire.
Very concerned.
Your behavior lately has
raised a lot of eyebrows.
Mike Avenido
reported an incident
in the gym with you
and Noah Sandborn.
Oh. Yeah, I remember that.
That was when I was reprimanding
him for skipping class.
Mike said that you
got physical with him,
that you put
your hands on him.
Now, you know what
our policy is regarding
the use of physical force
on students.
Well, I would hardly say
I was using physical force!
I'm not questioning
your integrity here, okay?
But I'm questioning
your behavior.
Get it together.
Please.
Hey, Kev!
What?
I told your mom
I'd pick you up today.
Because I think it's time
for you to drive this bad boy.
I'm not used to you driving.
Yeah, well,
I've been doing it awhile.
I guess.
Come on, buddy,
slow down.
You like to drive fast,
isn't that right?
I mean, why else
get a car like this?
Unless you're trying
to be something
that you're just
completely not.
Kevin, slow down!
Do you have any idea
what that was like
when you were gone?
You didn't
see her, Dad, okay.
She wasn't Mom anymore.
She was just
completely torn apart,
and I had to
sit back and watch
and there was nothing
that I could do about it!
Kevin!
Slow this car down!
Oh, no!
Oh.
What's wrong?
What's going on?
It's not braking!
Hit the brakes! It's not working!
Downshift!
Downshift, downshift!
There's no clutch! What do
you mean there's no clutch?
Look out!
Here comes a car!
Look out! Watch out!
Oh, fuck!
Okay. All right, here goes.
Straight, straight.
Here comes another one,
Kevin. Stay right here!
Kevin, look out!
Look out!
Nothing's working, Dad!
We gotta get off the road!
Emergency brake, punch it!
Punch it!
Oh, shit!
I'm so sorry!
Are you all right? It's okay.
It's okay, son.
It's okay.
Kevin!
Garrett?
Hey, we're in here
watching TV.
What happened to your car?
Oh, nothing. I had a
little fender bender.
We're all right.
Yeah.
They look, uh,
fine to me.
Hey, Mrs. Peterson.
We're watching
the Detroit Grand Prix.
Come on in
and get a slice.
Yeah, there's
plenty of room.
I gotta unpack
the groceries.
I'm gonna get something
else to munch on.
Look at these clowns.
Do you have any chips?
You took pictures!
A video, actually.
Capture the moment.
Come over tonight.
After they're asleep.
Say, 2:00?
Go fuck yourself!
I'd rather fuck you.
You're fucking crazy!
Who should I
show it to first?
Garrett?
Or maybe... Kevin!
No!
Yeah?
Do you want a soda?
That sounds good.
Thanks!
Hey, I'll take another
cold one, please!
Yeah, anything
for you, Garrett.
I'll leave the light on.
Noah?
Hey, you're early.
Where's the damn video?
Why are you so angry?
What you did in my
classroom today?
You've been avoiding me.
What do you think? This is some
kind of game we're playing here?
This is real life!
That is my home!
Okay. You're doing things
in front of my kid,
in front of my husband?
Your husband. Your fucking
cheating, lying husband?
Okay. What's your plan?
What do you think? What do
you think, we're going to date?
We're going to go on
family vacations together?
What do you think
is going to happen here?
Here? Nothing.
But it's a big world
out there, Claire.
Oh, my God, this is crazy!
No, no, no,
wait, wait, wait!
Wait.
You see that video,
and the proof of our love
as a threat to this life,
but I see it as a promise.
For a better one.
And none of this will
ever see the light of day.
If you let me show you
what's possible.
Because, Claire,
I will never
ever gonna let you go.
Fucking crazy!
Oh, Claire.
Okay,
why didn't you tell me?
I thought that
I could handle it.
I thought that it was gonna
just blow over, I don't know.
I didn't think he was going
to turn into a stalker!
Okay, okay. Look, we can look
at this picture and we see,
we know that
he's a psychopath,
but it's not the way the rest
of the world's going to see it.
And there's a video.
What?
There's a video,
and if it gets out,
you know I'm going to
lose my son,
my husband,
my job, my life.
Everything that I've ever worked
for. Okay, Claire, listen to me.
Claire, that's not going
to happen. Do you know why?
I'm not gonna let that
happen, and neither are you.
No one is going
to see that video.
It won't see
the light of day.
What? VICKY OVER PHONE:
Claire, he saw me.
Get the hell out of there,
he's coming back there!
Wait. I haven't even found
the video or the files yet.
Get the hell out of there,
you got five minutes max!
Mrs. Peterson!
Mr. Sandborn!
You scared the living
daylights out of me. I'm sorry.
What in the world
are you doing here?
Sorry.
Tell me that you're home,
and that all the doors
are locked.
Yes.
And I found the computer
and I deleted all the files.
Good. Good.
But I found something else
even creepier.
I'm not surprised.
He's a freak!
Does Ethan know any cops
in San Bernardino?
Oh, I'm sure he does.
If we're not having
dinner with his mother,
we're having dinner
with cops.
Why?
Just a hunch.
I might have to go
there later. I'll call him.
He went to Laughlin
with his mother
for her birthday.
Welcome to my world.
But listen...
Whay?
He's here!
Get out of there! Run!
Claire! Claire!
I'm gonna call the cops!
Talk to me, Claire! I'm dying!
He's trying to force the lock.
Whay?
Oh, God!
Run, hide!
Hey, Mom,
what's with the knife?
It's Kevin.
Oh, my God!
Oh.
I'm going crazy.
You guys have to spend the
night with me, out here, okay?
Oh, God.
I love you very much.
I'll talk to you later.
Ethan, uh, said you wanted to
take a look at the Sandborn case.
Yes.
Sad. I remember it.
They were on a back road
outside San Bernardino.
Tire marks indicated the driver
had lost control of the car.
The crash killed both
passengers instantly.
And it was ruled
an accident?
Bodies were destroyed,
so there was no toxicology.
But we assumed
the driver was drunk.
Why was that?
Well, he had
a long history of DUl's.
Or his brakes went out. I mean,
they could have been tampered with.
Well, Mrs. Peterson,
even if his brakes went out,
there was no indication
of malfeasance.
Sometimes,
breaks malfunction.
Sometimes, people drive
while intoxicated.
This is the Sandborn car.
If you don't need
anything else...
One more question,
Detective. Um...
Was this a 2006 minivan?
Well, yeah.
That's exactly what it is.
Is there something else I
need to know, Mrs. Peterson?
No.
Thank you.
Hey, Noah.
Are you home?
Yeah, what's up?
You got plans tonight?
Well, I'm supposed to go
to that car show with my dad.
Well, I'm over here
working on Vicky's tractor.
You're at Vicky's?
Yeah, I'm at her ranch.
You know where it's at?
Yeah, no, I think
I know where that is.
Is everything all right?
Can you and your dad swing by
and give me a hand?
Yeah, okay. Let me ask.
Just get over here.
Okay, catch you later. Bye.
Let me just start off
by saying I'm sorry.
No, really, I am very,
very sorry,
Vice Principal Lansing.
See,
I've got a bit of a temper.
There's no denying that.
And sometimes,
it gets the best of me.
Like, when I feel
like I'm being bullied.
And no one likes
to be bullied, Vicky.
Can I call you Vicky?
I mean, given that
I'm in your house,
and it's after hours,
calling you Vice Principal
just feels,
I don't know, wrong.
See, my guess, Vicky,
is that, uh, you don't
like to be bullied.
I mean, who would?
But that's what you were
doing to me today.
You and Claire.
Now, the two of you,
with your little secrets.
You were playing a joke.
A silly little game.
Trying to make me think
that you were her,
so she could do what?
Something sneaky?
Something...
She's hiding from me?
What was it, Vicky?
No, no, no.
Let me.
Vicky!
Listen, I am pretty sure
that Noah tampered with the
brakes on his parents' car
and that's why they crashed.
And I'm pretty sure he did
the same thing to Garrett's.
Claire, I need you.
I need to talk.
Can you come over?
Vicky?
Vicky! Are you upstairs?
Vicky.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
911. What's your emergency?
Out!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
You killed Vicky!
For you. For you, okay? She
wasn't your friend, Claire!
Hey, hey, hey!
When I love somebody,
I protect them.
That's what heroes do.
No heroes kill their
mothers and fathers!
I would never ever
hurt my mother.
I loved my mother,
but she killed herself.
My cheating father
and his whore
got what they deserved.
But, hey.
I protect people I love.
This is all for you.
Okay?
No!
Now, let's go.
Garrett!
Oh, my God!
What did you do to him?
Well, he ran into
a 14-inch crescent wrench.
Mom!
Kevin!
Noah, you hurt my mom,
I swear to God...
Really, Kevin?
I would never
hurt your mother.
I love your mother.
Just steady your breathing,
baby!
And honestly,
I'd hoped you'd see me
as a mentor
who cared about you
more than your
cheating father ever did.
Tell him, Claire.
Do you need your shot?
Mom.
You know,
it's destiny, Claire.
And you can't
interfere with destiny.
Mom.
We're meant to be.
And Garrett
needs to know that.
Wake up! Hey, wake up!
It's gonna be okay.
You know, I was going
to take Kevin with us.
Seems like he's got too
much of his father in him.
No, he needs to go.
No! No, no, no.
No, he's not like
his father at all.
Noah, you've taught him.
You've changed him.
All right.
All right, then, uh...
He'll come with us.
Yes.
Form our own family.
Mom! Mom!
Please, Noah!
Please, just stop this!
Let me help you.
There's still time.
There's no time.
This is our time!
You'll never be lovelier
than you are right now!
We will never be here again!
What are you doing?
Building a funeral pyre.
What does it look like?
You can't do this!
No!
Stop!
I'm sick and tired
of everyone
going back and forth!
So, it's time to
make a choice, my love!
You either live with me
or you die with them.
No! No!
Take Kev
and get out of here!
Ahhh!
No! No!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
Stay with me, Garrett!
Garrett, stay with me!
Stay with me!
All right.
Let's go, Claire.
You'll see.
You and me. Off-grid.
There is nothing
I wouldn't do for you.
You can trust me.
But, Noah,
you can't trust me!
Die, you piece of fucking shit! No!
Ahhh!
Sorry, buddy,
but sometimes even heroes
have to make tough choices.
Noah!
Noah! Noah!
You're no hero!
I'm here.
I'm right here.
All right, guys, lift
on three. One, two, three.
Me and Kevin
are right here, sweetie.
We got him now, ma'am.
Don't you worry.
He's gonna be fine.
Just hang in there.
Hang in there.
You're gonna be okay.
You're going to be okay.
And then we're
gonna go home.
You hear me?
We're going home.