The_Intruders
Translated_By
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha
Please, no, please.
Yeah, no, it wasn't too bad.
We didn't even hit any bad weather
until the Midwest.
I'm excited, it was competitive,
but they got my design.
We're incredibly lucky. We got a nice house.
So, like it?
I like our old house.
Why is this furniture here?
Previous owners left it behind.
We're going to get rid of it
once our stuff arrives.
It's only temporary.
I always wanted to restore an old house.
Come here, I want to show you something.
These are the original plans.
This thing was built in 1912.
I thought that maybe
that would be your bedroom,
second door on the right.
Like, they added this wall here
to house the central air duct
for a completely inefficient use of space.
I thought we'd open it up and restore it
to its original layout, what do you think?
You couldn't find a crappy
remodel closerto home?
Come on.
A change of scenery is a good thing.
Not always.
Okay, don't judge the kitchen!
I've got someone working
on the water damage.
And then we're gonna gut this stuff.
We're gonna get new countertops, cabinets,
but I'm gonna wait for stuff
to settle down at work first.
Which will be never.
Speak of the devil.
Yeah, hey, it's Jerry.
Would my princess care to lick the spoon?
I sure would.
No, don't even think about it.
All right, enough, you two.
What would you guys do without me?
We'd probably kill each other.
Hey.
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
We just moved in across the street.
I'm Rose.
Leila.
Hey, Leila.
Are you all right?
My dad is, like, unreal, I can't even tell you.
Me and my dad, we argue all the time.
I mean,
obviously I don't know your situation.
But I'm sure it's gonna be okay.
See, that's the thing, it's not gonna be okay.
Yeah, he can't erase everything he did.
She's gone
and she's not coming back.
Ever.
What's your deal anyway?
Nothing, like I said, we just moved here.
Honestly, how can you live in that house?
Honey, let's get in the house now, okay?
Come on.
She said she doesn't understand
how we could live here.
- What do you mean?
- In this house.
Why would she say that?
Did something happen here?
No, nothing happened here.
This is a great house, give it time,
it'll be home before you know it.
I had your prescription
transferred over to the local pharmacy,
so let me know when it's time for a refill.
I don't want to be on medication any more.
Rose, we've been over this.
So, I thought maybe this week
we could take a cruise,
check out some local campuses,
University of Chicago, Northwestern...
I'm going back to Stanford.
Your mom loved this city,
she talked about it all the time.
She loved the people, the music.
She loved everything about the place.
The lakefront, the
museums, she hated
baseball but loved
Wrigley Field,
Buckingham Fountain all lit up at night.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, I remember the pictures.
Tomorrow why don't we check it out?
Would you like that?
Damn, looks like
I have to go into work tomorrow.
Shocker.
Don't come near me!
Christ, whoa. Time out, Jesus.
Who the hell are you
and what are you doing in my house?
I'm Noah, Noah Henry,
I'm part of the construction crew.
We were hired to work on your house,
that's why I have keys.
We left a bunch of tools downstairs,
somebody must've moved them.
There was a scraping sound.
What was that, was it you?
That was the guys outside
pulling off the gutters.
Sounded like the walls were caving in.
Well they wrap around the entire house
and they're filled with ice and snow,
dead leaves, all kinds of gnarly stuff.
That's why you're getting
this water damage inside.
Why is it so quiet now?
Maybe they got the first side down already?
God, I'm so sorry. Let me get you some ice.
My dad didn't tell me you were coming today.
Yeah. No, the contractors weren't ready
for us on anotherjob so we swung by here.
We didn't think anybody was home.
Here.
Thanks.
Does it hurt?
Only when I breathe.
I'm kidding. Kind of, sort of. Not really.
So, are you going to be here all day?
I wish.
Got a few more houses we need to hit up.
- Well, I should probably...
- Absolutely.
Only, I didn't catch your name?
It's Rose.
All right, well, don't forget to lock up
before you leave.
All right, Rosy Rose.
Just Rose.
Sorry again for the intrusion.
What the hell?
- Hello?
- Hey.
How's it going?
I just have a few things to finish up
and then I'll be heading home.
When?
I'm just asking 'cause I'm making dinner.
That sounds good. I'm not sure.
Not long, I'll call you from the car.
Okay, hurry home.
Your mom burnt plenty of dinners
when she first started cooking.
I turned it off, I told you.
Maybe you turned it up by accident instead.
Yeah, or maybe
if you didn't stay at work all night
we could actually eat when dinner's ready.
I'm sorry, I'll call next time. I promise.
Do what you want,
I'm not even supposed to be here.
I should be away at school.
Rose, the administration suggested strongly
that you take a leave of absence.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Is Leila home?
You two seem about the same age,
I hope that's where the similarities stop.
You seem like a very smart girl.
I should be going home.
Stay out of trouble, you hear?
Rose, have you seen
those blueprints for the house?
The ones I showed you?
- What?
-For the house?
No, I haven't seen 'em.
That is so weird,
things don't just go missing.
Will you keep an eye out?
I have to submit 'em to the city.
What's that?
I found it in the neighbours' driveway
across the street.
What were you doing in their driveway?
I haven't seen his daughter
since he caught us talking.
What if... I don't know,
what if something happened to her?
Just forget it.
Is the modem hooked up?
No, it's not working, but I'll call tomorrow.
Help me.
Let me out!
Please help me,
let me out!
Help me!
...the building, it's elegant, it's simple,
it's really sound.
Just a simple beam construction.
What you don't see are the caissons.
Go down 180 feet into the ground so...
Will you excuse me for a second?
Would you mind waiting in my office
forjust a minute? Thank you.
Hey.
Rose, what are you doing here?
- Something's happening in the house.
- What are you talking about?
Something. I don't know,
strange things keep happening.
How did you get all the way down here?
I flagged a cab in the street.
All the way here? How did you pay?
I didn't, you took my credit card,
I don't have anything.
He's waiting downstairs.
Oh, my God, look at you.
You must be freezing.
What are you thinking? This isn't California.
Where's yourjacket?
All right look, when this meeting is done
I'll take the rest of the day off.
Here, give this to the cab driver.
Actually, on second thought,
just stay here, don't move,
I'll be right back. I'll take care of it, okay?
The last person to see Rachel
was Howard Markby,
a neighbour of Mrs Garrison.
Howard Markby, formerly a prime suspect
in the disappearance
of 20-year-old Rachel Winacott,
has been vindicated by police.
Winacott was a
houseguest staying
with Cheri Garrison
of 340 Laura...
It was right here.
I found a doll head in my room.
Rachel wanted me to go up there.
That's why she knocked over
Mom's recipe box.
She wanted me to go upstairs
and see what Howard Markby was doing.
And then today
I found my phone in the drawer
'cause she wanted me to find the doll head.
Look.
I don't understand,
it was easier to read before.
But, here's the R and the A.
Here's the W.
Do you see it?
"Rachel was here."
To be honest, I don't.
But even if I could,
didn't a girl named Rachel live here?
- Wouldn't it make sense if she...
- Something bad happened to her.
What about the door slamming shut?
I couldn't get out.
It's an old house.
It has quirks.
Why couldn't I get out then?
It was like someone was
pushing on it from the other side.
It's stuck a little.
It happens with wood, expands, contracts.
Don't look at me like that.
The necklace.
Howard Markby
was the main suspect for a reason.
Yeah, the police ended the investigation,
but why was he a suspect in the first place?
Did you call about the Internet?
Yes, they sent someone by earlier today.
It should be working.
Is that what you were
looking for downstairs?
There.
There, now do you see?
How did this get back up here?
Explain that to me!
Rose.
No, I can't stay in this house.
I want to stay at a hotel.
- That's not gonna happen.
- I feel like I'm a prisoner here!
I don't know anyone,
I'm 20 years old and I can't even access
my own bank account without your consent!
- I'm just doing what's best for you!
- No, you're doing what's best for you.
I'm doing what's best for us!
This is not my imagination!
I'm not some crazy person,
it's not my emotions running wild!
- I'm not Mom!
- That is enough! That's enough!
I want you to be honest with me.
Are you taking your meds?
Yes.
I think we should call Dr Turner,
get a referral for someone local,
someone good.
I don't need a psychiatrist!
I just... I'm tired.
I haven't been sleeping well.
Plus the stress of moving.
You were right, I overreacted to everything.
But I'm fine now.
Really.
I swear.
Hey, where are you off to?
Coffee shop.
On foot? It's like three miles to town.
You don't have a car?
Or a winter coat?
Yeah, I'm still getting used to
this whole winter thing.
I should probably run back inside.
You mind if I wash my hands?
We were using this nasty epoxy stuff.
Yeah, come on.
So, how's the eye?
I'm hanging in there, thanks.
Stanford, huh?
Oh, yeah, I'm just...
I'm taking a semester off to figure things out.
How 'bout you?
Me? I'm working my way through school,
taking art classes in the city.
That's cool.
So, how's your boyfriend
coping with your absence?
No boyfriend.
Do you know Leila across the street?
Leila? Yeah, kind of.
We went to high school together,
she's a few years younger.
Her dad was accused of kidnapping
that girl who used to live here.
Yeah, it was big news for a minute
until the truth came out
about her moving away.
How do they know
that's what actually happened?
I guess there was an email saying she left,
not exactly sure.
Here's something I do know, you and me,
we should hang out.
Isn't that what we're doing?
No, I mean, like when I'm off the clock.
You should see me
out of these work clothes,
I'm a completely different person.
I bet.
Do you know why she was living here?
Rachel Winacott?
I guess Cheri Garrison
was trying to help her out,
she's always taking people in
and organising charity events,
that sort of thing.
She's like the saintly figure in our town.
She still lives here?
No, I heard she moved away.
Wonder why.
I'm gonna go grab a warmerjacket.
Great idea.
Think about what I said,
you and me hanging out.
Noah?
Is that you?
- Dad!
- Rose!
- What's the matter?
I saw someone in the basement.
There's someone down there.
They're in the closet, I swear!
In the closet.
He's 'm the comer 'gust standing there.
I know what I saw.
I'm not making it up.
Look, I thought the change of environment
might be a good thing,
but obviously the move
has triggered something.
This isn't about Mom!
Howard Markby is hiding something,
he sent his daughter away the day after
he caught us talking. Why is that?
Rose, he did not send her away.
You're right, God only knows
what he did to her.
I just saw them together outside!
No. Where are you...
Rose, do not go out there!
Leila! Leila, we need to talk!
Rachel Winacott didn't move away.
He did something to her, didn't he?
Why was he a suspect?
What did he do to her?
He didn't do anything.
Rachel spent some time at our house,
so my dad was brought in for questioning.
A few days later Cheri got an email
from her son saying they ran off together.
No. That day you were out here crying,
you said that he caused a lot of pain,
that she was never coming back.
I was talking about my mom.
They separated and now she wants a divorce.
That's it, case closed, mystery solved.
- I'm so sorry, she's not well.
- No.
Where did you get that?
This necklace belonged to Rachel.
Yeah, she gave it to me for my birthday.
My dad and I got in a fight
because he thought it was from Kyle.
I got mad and I threw the necklace at him.
You saw it happen?
What, were you spying on us
from your window?
I saw you that night in the driveway,
with the garbage bag and the shovel.
Yeah. So?
So?
I had a bag of gravel in the basement,
I brought it up and put it in my truck
with a shovel to gain some traction.
So don't come over here acting like
you know something about it,
'cause you don't.
I'm sorry.
- We're terribly sorry, we're sorry.
- Sorry.
- Come on.
- I'm sorry.
See? lt'sjust in your mind.
It's like what the doctors say.
You find these things and you run with it.
They seem real, but...
Rose, the workers are here,
but they're in the basement,
I told 'em to keep it down.
I know this last year has been
really hard on you.
You have to try to move forward.
I won't be gone long.
Call if you need me, okay?
I sure would.
No, don't even think about it.
All right, enough, you two.
What would you guys do without me?
We'd probably kill each other.
Would my princess care to lick the spoon?
I sure would.
No, don't even think about it.
All right, enough, you two.
What would you guys do without me?
We'd probably kill each other.
You saw everything,
I must've looked like a total crazy person.
No, not at all.
Maybe my dad was right,
maybe the stress
from the move triggered something,
caused me to imagine things
that weren't really happening.
Are your folks split up?
Mine divorced a few years ago.
I'm staying with my dad for now
until I get my own place.
My parents aren't divorced.
My mom died nine months ago.
Oh, Jesus. I'm sorry.
You know, after she died I kind of fell apart.
Well, yeah, of course.
It was bad. It was really bad.
My mom was diagnosed with schizophrenia
around the time I was born.
You know, when she was feeling good,
she was the best mom in the world.
She was so smart and funny.
She was an amazing cook.
But the medication, it changed her.
It just completely wiped her out.
I used to sit with her after school,
and I'd read to her, and we'd talk.
I did most of the talking,
but she always listened.
I mean, I get it.
I can see why she didn't like taking her pills,
they just make you feel so numb
and disconnected from everything.
But to do what she did.
And not leave a note or anything.
That's something I'll never understand.
I was so mad at my dad
when he said we were moving.
I mean, all the memories
that we had in that house.
That's all we had left.
I'm never like this.
Why is it so easy to talk to you?
I've been told I'm a good listener.
We have orange juice, apple juice.
Water's fine.
Glad I went with water.
I know it's gross,
but I'm the only one who drinks it.
I was kidding, kind of, sort of.
Not really?
So, I asked my dad about Cheri Garrison.
Yeah, what did he say?
Hey.
I just wanted to apologise
for freaking you out.
No, I'm sorry, it was totally me.
Anyway, I was gonna say
we should be friends, but...
I see you already found someone.
We were just talking about Cheri Garrison.
What do you want to know?
The other day you said you didn't know
how we could live here.
What'd you mean by that exactly?
Hello, this place is beyond creepy.
Cheri left without saying a word to anyone.
No one even knew she was gone
for the longest time.
All her stuff was here,
and she had just disappeared... Like that.
And also, a few days before you moved in,
I heard yelling from in here.
I called 911, the cops came,
searched the entire house,
but there was nothing.
Well, how do you know
it was coming from in here?
Kyle heard it too, we were both
right outside on the stairs.
It definitely came from in here.
You got to wonder about somebody
who just skips out like that.
What was Cheri Garrison running from?
Yeah, or trying to hide.
Before you guys moved in,
your dad had us do some quick fixes.
In one of the bedrooms, the windows
were completely boarded up from the inside.
Here, I'll show you.
It was so effed up,
I had to take a picture of it.
The glass wasn't broken or anything.
Why go through the trouble
of boarding it up?
Which room was that?
The second door on the right.
And, on the outside of the door,
was a heavy-duty padlock.
Whatever was inside that room
wasn't supposed to get out.
That doesn't prove anything.
I came over here to see Rachel,
she was so pale and anorexic looking.
Cheri said she was
going through withdrawal,
that's why she locked her up probably,
for her own good.
It's what they do with addicts sometimes,
till the symptoms pass.
Rachel was basically homeless,
Cheri gave her food and a place to stay.
Cheri Garrison is a good person.
I don't really know about her son, Marcus,
he was kind of quiet, shy.
I gotta grab something from the van.
Be right back.
So, are you two a thing?
What? No, we're just friends.
Come on, you two are beyond smitten.
It's so painfully obvious.
So, how old is Cheri's son?
A few years older than us, I guess.
He was home schooled, didn't get out of
the house much except for church.
Total choir boy. Like, literally.
That's why I was so surprised
when they ran off together.
Rachel and Marcus?
Yeah, what can I say? The girl has issues.
Anyway, I should probably get going,
I'm staying with my grandparents tonight.
I want to ask you something.
You know the blueprints
for the house are missing.
You think I took them.
I'm just asking.
You don't believe anything I say any more.
I have a question.
When you bought this house
did you know that the windows
in my room were boarded up
and that the door had a padlock on it?
What else do you know about this house
that you're not telling me?
"The bitch finally let me out.
"It's so dark and cold down there,
no food, no water.
"I have to find a way to leave
but she's always watching.
"My whole body aches, I feel so weak."
"Cheri, Marcus and Rachel."
"Marcus stood up for me today,
he clearly has feelings for me
"but it's only making things worse
for both of us.
"I wonder how long
she'll keep him locked up."
Help me!
You're gonna have a really hard time
convincing people, that's all.
Nobody's gonna believe
she did the things you're saying.
Well, once they realise it was all a lie.
It's like her charity was a way to cover up
what was actually happening in this house.
That's why she disappeared overnight,
she didn't want to get caught.
So, my friend Charlie's
having a hotel party tonight.
There's a great indoor pool,
guaranteed good times, you should come.
In fact, I insist.
You need to get out of the house,
meet some new people.
I'll pick you up at 8:00?
Great.
Only thing is I'm not supposed to
use the work van after hours,
I don't want your dad to see me driving it.
So is it cool if I pick you up
around the corner?
Yeah, I'll see you in 20 minutes.
I'm gonna bring a friend.
She's cool, she just moved here.
Rose?
Would my princess care to lick the spoon?
I sure would.
No, don't even think about it.
All right, enough, you two.
What would you guys do without me?
We'd probably kill each other.
Would my princess care to lick the spoon?
Rose'?
-l sure would.
No, don't even think about it.
All right, enough, you two.
What would you guys do without me?
Hey, sorry I'm late. Did you get my text?
No, I couldn't find my phone.
No way.
You've been out here this whole time?
I'm so sorry,
I got stuck at home helping my mom.
She wouldn't let me leave.
Didn't you say you lived with your dad?
Oh, yeah. No, no.
I stopped by my mom's for dinner.
You look pretty, by the way.
Thanks.
Here you go.
I'm glad you came tonight.
So, I was wondering.
You said you kind of
fell apart after your mom.
What happened exactly?
If you're comfortable telling me.
Let down your wall, girl.
Remember when I said I'm taking
some time off to figure things out?
Well, I didn't really have a say in the matter.
Truth is, after my mom died,
I wound up in the hospital.
My dad probably thinks I'm exactly like her.
My doctor even said the episode I had
was brought on by stress.
Not mental illness or anything like that.
Why do you want to know all this stuff?
'Cause I like you.
People, this is a party.
If you're not adding value, you're out, huh?
Yeah!
Can we do this?
Yeah, let's do it.
Sorry, I haven't.
Rose! Have you seen Leila?
Not since the other day.
She said she was going
to her grandparents' house.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
Hello?
Is everything all right?
I haven't heard from her since last night,
and she's not answering her phone, so...
If you hear from her
would you let me know, please?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Okay.
This is very helpful.
Yeah. Thank you, Dr Turner.
Okay, I will.
Okay.
Why were you talking to her?
She was giving me your referral.
Something's happening in this house
whether you choose to believe it or not.
Rose, I can't do this right now.
Do you see this?
I have a huge presentation, I have to focus.
You never have time for anything but work.
- That's not true.
- Yes, it is!
When Mom got really sick,
I was the one nearby her bedside every night
while you stayed at work late.
That's how you handle anything
involving actual human emotion.
I felt so alone after she killed herself,
I had nobody.
Did you ever stop to think about that?
Did you ever stop to think about this?
You're not the only one who lost somebody.
Yeah, just keep popping your pills
to numb the pain.
I'll be fine on my own.
Rose, is that you?
I'm so sorry I said what I said to you.
Oh, my God.
I came in here and it was like this.
I didn't do this.
- Just get out, please. Just go.
- Dad, I swear.
Go!
Get out!
Maybe you were so upset
you don't remember doing it.
No, that's not what happened.
Something in this house
is trying to communicate with me.
It's absolutely happening.
And now Leila is missing.
She's probably off with Kyle somewhere.
Kind of like Rachel and Marcus?
Marcus was trying to protect Rachel,
and things went too far.
Cheri did something awful to them,
that's why she left town.
Rose, you can't bring her back.
No, but I can at least try to figure out
what happened to her.
That's not who I'm talking about.
You suffered a major loss, it's your mom.
There's nothing worse than that.
Your pain, it's starting
to come out in other ways.
Don't you see?
You sound just like my dad.
Why, 'cause I'm worried about you?
Where are you going?
Look, just 'cause we kissed
doesn't mean we're together, okay?
You're not my boyfriend.
So, is this your thing?
Someone gets too close, you shut 'em out?
- Give me the keys.
- What?
Now!
I don't want you coming
in and out as you please!
- Now get out!
- Rose, I have a job...
Out!
Can we please talk about this?
There's nothing to talk about.
You're right, I'm not well.
Let's just leave it at that.
Hi, the lady upstairs directed me to you.
I'm looking for the original blueprints
to our house.
We don't usually get
too many young people down here.
Yeah, my dad misplaced his copy,
so I'm just trying to help him out.
Well, blueprints are generally filed
with the corresponding building permit.
Can you give me the name
of the previous owner?
- Yeah, Garrison.
- Just a second.
Garrison, Garrison.
Watch your step.
Cheri Garrison, 340 Laura.
Got it.
Dad?
Hello?
My phone's about to die, can you hold on?
I need to get my phone charger. Hello?
Shit.
Rose! Rose!
Rose? Rose?
Rose?
Breathing's back to normal,
heart rate is good.
Right now she just needs some rest.
Are any prescription pain medications
kept in the house?
Like hydrocodone, oxycodone?
Yeah. I'm on pain meds,
I had back surgery last year.
I'm asking you this
because your daughter's symptoms
are consistent with this type of misuse.
Hey.
How do you feel?
What are you doing?
I made you some soup.
When was the last time
you took one of these?
Why didn't you tell me that you ran out?
I forgot.
Are you trying to hurt yourself?
How many of my pills did you take?
I never touched your pills.
Rose, the paramedic said
your symptoms were consistent
with an overdose of hydrocodone.
That's impossible.
And you believe them?
I left some water for you right there.
Do you want anything? Juice? Tea?
Wait, yesterday when I came home
I had some juice.
I remember it tasted funny.
Right afterwards
that's when I started feeling dizzy.
Are you saying you were drugged?
I don't know what I'm saying.
Hey, it's Jerry.
Just call me back
as soon as you get this, please.
Stop, stop, I don't want to hurt you.
I don't want to hurt you, but I will.
So don't make me.
What do you want from me?
I want you to put on the dress.
My dad's gonna be home any minute.
We both know that isn't true.
Don't lie.
No!
Stop crying!
People get hurt when they cry.
Why are you doing this?
'Cause it's so much fun!
Just kidding.
It's been you the whole time.
I get to keep you.
You should be glad, Rachel wasn't so lucky.
My mother didn't agree with our relationship.
She made me do it.
She made me do all kinds of things.
God's good intention.
She said,
the almighty hand of the Lord!
Put on the dress!
I never hurt my mother
or fought with her before Rachel.
You and me, we're the same.
We both lost our mothers,
and that's what brought us together.
That was Rachel's dress.
I'm so glad that you
wanted to know what happened to her.
Rachel's the reason.
The reason that I ended up
in this house all by myself.
I don't want to hide any more.
You're even more beautiful
than I ever imagined.
It's okay.
I'm nervous too.
No!
I like this game.
I like this game so much.
He'll hear you.
- He'll hear you.
- Where are you, Rosy Rose?
Where are you, my sweet?
Rosy Rose.
Okay.
Rosy Rose?
Have I found my true one?
Have I?
You're being awfully quiet!
I'll come back for you.
Dad!
No!
It's not supposed to be like this, Rose!
Stop, you're not like the others.
Stop it!
Rose, Rose!
Are you okay? Rose. Rose, are you okay?
Rose.
No, stop!
No!
Marcus, stop!
Like I said...
You're prettier than I imagined.
Dad!
Help me.
Well, it's not much,
but at least our stuff has arrived.
Anything's better
than that hotel for another month.
Well, maybe not anything.
But, this is exactly what I wanted.
No musty basement, no creepy attic.
We're getting new appliances next week.
It already feels like a home.
Thanks again for helping out.
Glad I could be of service.
So, your first day of school tomorrow.
It's not Stanford,
but Northwestern ain't too shabby either.
You nervous?
No.
Maybe there will be
some cute guys in my classes.
Be careful, your boyfriend might get jealous.
- He's got nothing to worry about.
- Really?
Come on.
The_Intruders
Translated_By
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha