As a child, I had visions.
Sometimes they would come true.
As I got older I started to dismiss them.
Then my sister was murdered in Germany
and the visions started again.
So I left the States for Germany
hoping to find some answers,
But what I found was far beyond
anything I ever expected.
I saw people die.
Please! Forgive me...
I'm sorry... I'm so sorry.
Please... please...
Why couldn't I stop thinking about that?
Shit. Shit happens sometimes...
Couldn't I?
No.
...none of my business.
...the corpse was his job.
Nothing can happen to me...
Or it could?
I don't wanna go to jail again.
Nobody would have known...
NOBODY!
And Kathrine? I don't know...
she's not important to me.
Hello.
Donnie who?
Hey Sarah. What's up?
When are you leaving?
Well, why don't I go with you?
Yeah, I've got friends there
that might be able to help.
They are paranormal investigators
Okay, great. See you then. Bye.
God, I really hate nature ghosts man.
They're too damn fucking clever.
Not that clever, only smarter than you are!
Year after year we go out there
and let him fuck with us...
I mean aren't you a
little tired of this?
No.
Aunt Rose!
Hello. Yes he's here.
Hi, Aunt Rose.
No... I don't think your
new puppy is a werewolf.
Uhm... miniature werewolf!
A lycanthro-doodle!
No, I'm here. Yes. Sam is here too.
- Hello!
Yes, oh wow.
Pie with dinner tonight? WOW.
Uhm no, we gotta go.
Yes, chase more ghosts.
Yes, so it's a big case, okay?!
Ok, we love you. All right. Bye.
Lycanthro-doodle?!?!
Oh yes yes yes
A "Lycanthrodoodle"...
it's a cross between a werewolf and
a poodle. A LY-CAN-THRO-DOODLE...
It's cool... isn't it?
Yes. It's the best one you ever made up.
So, umm...
Are you are ready to call it a night?
Oh, no. I'll work a little longer.
Five against one...
Man, I don't know.
What's up tomorrow?
Umm, Donnie is flying in.
-Oh!
Didn't I tell you?
- No.
That could be really nice...
It's been about five years since he moved...
and...
he's bringing a friend.
Aha... who?
- A friend.
Who?
- A friend?
- WHO?!
- A woman friend.
Who?!?!...Umm... Sa... Sar...
Are you a fucking owl?
So, anyways... All right
man. I'll go to bed.
- Have a good one.
- Yes.
Good night.
- Enjoy your arm wrestling.
- Yeah, wet dreams baby.
What happened?
Tell me now!
For the last time,
I have no idea what happened to Mike!
I'm done talking about Mike!
You killed him, didn't you?!
What are you gonna do?
Call the police?
Is there something you're not telling me?
- No, God damn it!
Leave me alone!
Calm down!
- You're a fucking asshole, Chris!
Kath, I swear I don't
know what happened to Mike,
or who's responsible!
Believe me...
Believe me.
If you didn't do anything,
then why not go to the police?
Because they'll think I killed him.
You might as well just kiss
my ass goodbye after that.
I don't know.
Hello.
- Same place, same time. No, I'm still there.
No traces yet.
We're asking the neighborhood.
I can't talk any more.
Who was it?
Tell me.
I'm gonna go take a shower.
What's up, bro?!
- Man!
Donnie.
- Hey Sam.
- Howdy.
Sam, this is Sarah. She is
a little bit tired and yes...
She's American.
- Of course she is.
Nice to meet you.
My name is Sam, but
you can call me Sammy.
And I am the good looking half of the...
- C'mon guys, cut the crap.
Sit down.
- Hi Sammy
- Hi Sarah.
This isn't purely a social call.
Do you recognize the
name Tanja Campbell?
Campbell... Campbell, wait...
Yeah, wasn't she the girl
who was raped and murdered...
Yeah, I remember seeing
her stuff all over the news.
Yes, but slow down. She was her sister.
- Ooh. Bullseye.
You know, Sarah and I met in
Chicago and became friends.
I showed her some photos from the
fatherland just the other day and...
Don't keep us in suspense "Mr. Medium"
- She recognized someone.
And you've never been in Germany?
- No.
- Right!
She's seen him in her
dreams and she's convinced
that this is the guy
who killed her sister.
This is the guy whose in your dreams?
-Yes.
I hate to break it to
you, but this dude is dead.
He was slaughtered in his home.
Just a few days ago.
Damn.
- I mean ripped to shreds.
He was Tanja's boyfriend,
and she was pregnant
with their baby
when she was killed.
I have a friend at
the police station.
He sent me some crime scene
photos from this murder.
I have them on my laptop.
Maybe we can find something in there.
Sammy. Laptop!
Mr. President!
- Thank you.
Look. I can see something!
It's the cursor... It's the cursor!
You said this guys were close.
Is that the best you can do?
Guys...
Well, it definitely seems to be spectral
anomaly. It's ectoplasmic in nature...
It is not a fucking orb... this guy...
body after the murder...
No. It looks female...
You can tell from that?
It just looks like a blur to me.
Can I see the screen?
That's Tanja.
- Guys, let's get back to reality!
Do you know a guy named, umm...
Christian Van DerStraaten?
Yeah, sure.
That is this guy's buddy.
Umm, well... Sarah thinks
her dreams are a sign...
A sign from her dead sister.
I feel that she's telling me
that until her murder is resolved,
she can't rest in peace.
Yes, how can we help?
I need you help me
find that Christian guy.
I think he and Mike
murdered my sister.
And I'm not gonna rest until I find him
and put him to justice.
Whatever it takes.
We're not talking about
anything illegal, are we?
I am really tired, you guys.
I have very bad jet-lag.
Okay, since you're
a guest in our house,
you can have my bed
and I'll take the sofa.
No! My bed is much better! So...
- She can have my bed!
She can have MY bed! Use my bed...
- My bed is nice!
You know what?
I just gonna take the sofa.
I don't wanna put you out.
It's fine and...
No!
- Yes!
- I'll go back to the hotel...
I'm dead on my feet and...
No! This is great.
There are two free beds here...
...why don't you stay with me?
- NO! NO! NO!
- No!
No!
- He's dead tired.
- I'll pay for the hotel
- Yes!
- I can cancel my room!
No! No! Yes...
- We'll pay for the hotel.
Company Business...
- Yes!
You stay here!
You stay here! You can use my bed.
- You'll call me in the morning?
I will, yes.
- Thank you.
Guys! See ya!
- Bye, Donnie. Bye.
- See you, man.
Good night.
Okay. I can find it by myself.
What? She's hot, huh?
Shut up!
- Ey! She is hot!
Stop.
-She's not hot?
- What the fuck?!
You have to believe me.
I didn't have anything
to do with Mike's murder!
That's all you've got for me?
I don't know anything!
I could arrest you!
I know.
But you don't wanna do that.
I have to know who killed him!
Don't waste my time!
I have no idea what happened to him,
or who killed him!
Hey, I like you.
And if you were an idiot,
I wouldn't like you.
All right, man.
Please, just don't hurt me here.
- I won't hurt you.
I'm only here to help.
Don't forget.
Every one of us is a criminal.
I'll go my way and you go your's.
And don't ask Kathrine anything.
She knows nothing.
Tell her I said hi.
Hey. Good morning.
- Hey, I made you some coffee.
- Thanks.
It's good.
Everything okay?
Yes. Yes it's okay.
I was thinking about my dad.
You wanna talk about?
He used to be in the army
here in Germany and... uhh...
...he blames me for telling Tanja...
I mean yeah, I told her to come...
...here so she could follow her dreams.
Live your own life.
Do what you wanna do.
I mean she wasn't having
any luck in the States so... why not?
And what was her dream?
She wanted to be a model.
When she died, my dad blamed me.
He said when she died, he died.
And I'm not his punching bag.
- Ya know...
Sometimes, when someone dies,
family members like to
place the blame on others.
I felt guilty.
I thought I was guilty.
But I know it's not my fault.
I came here because I need to find out.
I wanna know.
And knowing is half the battle.
Come in.
Hey.
- Hey.
I thought you were tired.
- I am. I'm exhausted.
And every time I lay down,
I see that bastard's face.
It really makes me sick.
Yeah... I have nights like that too.
You wanna talk about?
I just wanna calm down, ya know?
I just want to relax and
get some rest tonight.
You know what I mean?
So, tell me about Sarah.
Sarah? Okay.
Let's see. I was
born in New Jersey.
My mother died when
I was three years old.
So my father raised
Tanja and I by himself.
He later moved to Frankfurt...
Got another wife...
...and I went to Chicago. I studied.
I was a history major.
And I never left. That's about it
How about you?
- This is it.
Hooked up with Sammy...
started the company.
You know... the better looking half of the...
German...
Is that my file?
- Uh, yes.
There's an "H" in Sarah.
- Yes, I know... Good eye on that.
So what you think?
- Uh, it's coming along.
We, uhh... I think we might have something.
- Thanks.
Thanks for the coffee.
Fuck you.
They're both for me.
What's up?
It's Kathrin. I'm afraid she's
going to talk... about everything.
Buy something for her.
Money makes the world go 'round.
Simple. Communicate with her.
This is hardcore, man...
and I don't wanna meet you in public
again where everybody can see us.
You're still paying me off.
How long will we do this?
The question isn't how long.
It's how far.
Tom. Can you call the detective?
I could. But they're not gonna show you her file.
And they don't have any information
that we don't already have.
Please. Call him.
Yes. My name is Tom Snyder.
Can I speak to Detective Teppert please?
Sorry. Mein name ist Tom Snyder. Kann ich mit
Commisar Teppert sprechen?
Thanks. Yeah.
Thanks a lot, Detective Teppert. Bye.
Well?!
Okay. He's gonna meet
with you in ten minutes.
Down the street there is a parking lot
where he's gonna meet you.
You don't wanna go?
- No he wants to meet you alone.
I'll stay here... milking the goats.
Milking the goats?
Thanks.
Teppert?
- Yes.
Look.
I need to know what happened to my sister.
We don't know anything.
We can't help you.
This is incredibly ridiculous.
A woman was killed.
You don't have finger prints,
trace evidence? Nothing?!
No fingerprints, no traces evidence.
Nothing.
This is insane! Look. I've been
having visions of her murder.
I think somebody
murdered my sister.
Visions?
We're not psychics. We are police!
Fine. I'll do it myself then.
You'd better not.
- Why?
I'm sorry. We can't do anything...
And neither can you.
Visions don't help you.
- We'll see about that.
You know what?
If you'd just do your fucking job I
wouldn't be in this position right now.
You know what I mean?!
Just do your fucking job.
Listen! Go back to the States.
We don't want you here!
Who is we?
Get a cab, buy a plane
ticket, and leave Germany. Now.
That's the best you can do.
You know what?
This is a really good police
force here. Thanks a lot.
Right! And you have to leave.
The earlier the better.
Tell her she has to leave,
if she's a friend of your's.
And whose speaking?
- ME!
Fuck you.
-What?!
Thank you. Thank you.
You okay?
I think I'm gonna puke.
Kath, are you alright?
You need to stop mixing all
that shit together or it'll kill you.
I swear that's never happened to me before.
Donnie. What's up man?
We're just working on Sarah's file.
- I see.
Speaking of Sarah...
So, she sees Christian in her dreams?
Now, is this the first time
she's had these visions or
is she just recreating something
that she's seen in the past?
No, she is not recreating.
She made those sketches of his face...
...and saw the photos, like,
three weeks later.
So maybe Tanja's soul is restless.
Do you think she had something
to do with Mike's murder?
Sarah?
- No, her sister!
I think the question is "why".
Mike was a damn good
friend of Chris', so...
Well, if she were a revenge
spirit, yes. That would be it.
But then we'd be dealing with
more victims, wouldn't we?
Yes. Maybe she's trying to
reach out to the astral plane...
and give Sarah a message?
Yes, that's what I think.
- Well, yeah...
...everyone related to the
murder will be killed...
but they'd have to be directly related,
either in the murder or covering it up.
Okay. So, as an entity,
she can't leave the confined
areas of the victims.
Which means she can't
leave the area she knows.
But if she IS a revenge
spirit... what then?
She has free will and
can go wherever she wants.
Donnie. Who is Sarah... really?
She was calling me, trying
to make an appointment.
Uhm, but she stood me up
for the first few times.
And all of a sudden she was
standing at my front door.
That's how it all started.
Sarah. We need to help Sarah.
What do you want me to do?
Uhm, Tom... But
she's not dangerous,
if that was what you
were wondering about.
Okay.
And we need to help Sarah.
- Okay, see you guys later.
Pizza?
Hello?! Don't call this number!
Fuck...
What the fuck?! No...
but maybe the American woman is
a bigger problem than I thought.
Do whatever you want...
I'm erasing some important stuff...
Maybe you should take off, too.
Didn't I tell you to dump it!?
Why didn't you listen to me!? Huh?!
- Leave me alone! NOW!
Maybe I should bury you too, huh?
- Do it, God damn it!
Blow my brains out! Violence...
that's your solution for everything!
I can't trust you anymore.
Why do you still have it? Huh?!
No. Don't do this.
- What?! Huh? Don't do what?!
Please. You can trust me Chris...
Why do you still have it? Huh?!
I'm wondering now if
maybe you didn't kill Mike.
The paper said he was shot with a pistol,
and here you are with one.
A shotgun!
The newspaper said he
was killed with a shotgun!
Hmm... I guess you're right. It said Shotgun, huh?
And this here is a pistol, right?
Christian, I love you... please don't do this!
So, what do you think I should do?
Hey, hey. Calm down.
Put the gun down.
Do you know where he lives, Tom?
Sarah, don't. That'd be a big mistake.
But you have his address, don't you?
Yes. But I'm not gonna give it to you.
- Great.
Why not?!
- What do you wanna do?
Go over there and kick open his
door and say, "Hi, I'm Sarah.
You raped and murdered my sister?!"
No, I'm not gonna do that,
but I've gotta go over there.
C'mon, take me to him.
I really need your help, Tom. Please.
Your aim still sucks.
Shut up, you bastard.
You make me sick.
Everything has to be
done your way, doesn't it?
You think you're the only one
who knows how to do anything.
You really make me sick!
Well, what's keeping you here then?
Leave if you want.
I'm not gonna stop you.
Go away! Now!
-We both know what'll happen if I do that.
What'll happen then? Huh?!
C'mon. Please.
Bullshit!
I want to be able to
take it all back...
forget it all happened.
Forget about Tanja!
She's always with me.
Whenever I close my eyes,
I dream about her.
When I'm awake, I can't
stop thinking about her.
It drives me insane!
Dwelling on the past isn't
going to do you any good.
What's done is done. You need
to suck it up and move on.
Chris... I was pregnant.
- What?!
Was... was it mine?
What happened?
Why are you telling me this now?
An abortion...
- What?!
You did what?!
- I had an abortion!
It was my baby too!
- Your baby?!
And you murdered it,
just like you murdered Tanja!
You know why I did it!
Don't pretend I'm the
only guilty one here.
You fucked her...
you and Mike both did!
I did what I had to to protect you.
So now you're the hero,
and Mike and I are the villains?
I don't think so, sweetie.
You and I are up to our
necks in the same shit.
Why couldn't we just keep our mouths
closed and forget it ever happened?
Just like that, huh?
We don't talk about it
and everything's okay?
So what you gotta do when we get there?
- Nothing.
You think this is easy for me?
I'm the one that pulled
the trigger, remember?
Her blood is all over MY hands.
I can't forget it.
No! I can't forget it.
Then let's go to the police,
put an end to this shit once and for all.
Do whatever you think is right.
Kathrin, I don't want
one of us to do something
we're going to regret
for the rest of our lives.
It's too late. We've already done it!
I'd turn back the clock if I could.
Make it so none of this happened...
but it doesn't work that way.
Thinking about it all
the time is killing me.
I don't think I can
take it any more.
That's bullshit!
What was that sound?!
- There's nothing here.
I heard something...
- There's nothing here!
Look... there is nothing here!
- Shut up, Kathrin, okay?
I swear to God that I heard something!
I heard something.
Get in the car!
That's not my sister! That's not her!
- Sarah!
Get in the car!
What the fuck was that?!
I thought we'd be dealing with Tanja's spirit.
Well, yeah... sometimes when a person has
been brutally murdered or wronged in anyway,
their soul can call back an...
an avenging spirit.
What the fuck is avenging spirit?
It's, it is...
It's used to lash out to those who
wronged or hurt the person.
And, and, and?!
- And she is pretty fucking pissed!
Yes, no shit!
And she's not gonna stop killing
until she finds everyone who
is involved in Tanja's murder!
I gotta call Sam.
- Just wait a minute!
Okay. Mike's already dead.
I need you to tell me who is
involved in Tanja's murder.
I need the information right now!
Sam! Yes... we're not
dealing with Sarah's sister.
It's a revenge spirit.
Yes, that's what I thought.
All right. We'll meet you there.
What, what?!
We'll meet Sam and
Donnie in fifteen minutes.
Holy shit! Who the fuck are you?!
This is fucking
Christian's girlfriend!
Are you out of your fucking mind?
- What the fuck?!
What was I supposed to do?!
What did you do to get that
revenge bitch to fucking chase you?!
And what do you know
about Tanja Campbell?!
You fucking tell me now!
Sarah!
Shut up!
- Sarah!!!
Get your hands off from me!
Sarah!
- WHAT?!
Sit down!
It was an accident...
- What was a fucking accident?!
Tell us!
- Mike and I used to be lovers...
I do everything for
him... All right!
Get to fucking Tanja
right now... just...
You don't fucking touch me!
You don't fucking know!
He cheated on me with Tanja.
There was a party at the lake.
...Tanja was there.
And I told Chris I wanted to scare her.
We got the gun out of
his car and waited for her.
Who do you think you are?!
Dirty bitch!
Who do you think YOU are?!
Dirty slut... you little piece of shit!
What should we do with you now?
She got away...
Do something! NOW!
Are you nuts?!
Is she dead?
The bitch was pregnant.
- You fucked her!
I thought my life was over!
Guys, haha... Is she dead?
Holy shit!
You just saved my life!
No one talks about it and everything's okay.
- Perfect!
Are you nuts?!
Anyways... it's daddy's turn now...
- Are you crazy? Kath killed her!
She's history now... It's daddy's job now...
- Damn.
I'll call him.
- Hey dad. It's me.
We really need your help here...
Okay, see you soon.
He's coming.
He'll take care of this.
You guys can go home now.
It's not your problem anymore.
Damn. Thanks.
Thanks a lot. Let's get a beer... now!
Hey, it's me. Change your plans.
We just found out where Tanja's body is.
Yeah. You know the old cabin by the lake?
Yeah, that's exactly what I thought.
Yes. We'll meet you there in twenty minutes.
And Sam... bring the salt.
I have a really bad feeling about this.
Sam...
I never should have brought Sarah to Germany.
This is much bigger than we thought.
Sam. Kathrin. Girlfriend of
Christian, who, by the way,
just got ripped apart
by that revenge bitch.
I think Teppert and the others
are in some really big trouble,
if they're not already dead.
What difference will four more make, huh?!
I'm ready to burn in hell!
Why did I confess all of that to you?
It was none of your business.
Kathrin...
- Why couldn't I take my own advice...
...and keep my stupid mouth shut?!
Kathrin... just give me the gun.
You don't wanna kill anybody.
Just give me the gun!
Kathrin...
You don't wanna kill anybody. Just...
I didn't want to kill Tanja either,
but I did... didn't I?
I couldn't tell you the whole story...
because I didn't know it all...
...until now. There was someone else.
What?
Are you saying there's
someone else involved?
Just run away Kathrin.
We won't tell anyone what happened.
Kathrin. Just put the gun down.
I know you don't
wanna shoot anybody.
I can't.
- Just put it down!
You're confused.
We just wanna help you.
I can't!
- Just put it down.
I CAN'T!
Holy shit!
- Fuck!
Salt!
It was all Kathrin's fault!
Sarah! Get away from him!
Follow her to the States,
become friends with her,
and then bring her to
Germany... at any price!
She sent a sketch of Christian
via fax to my police station.
I have to know what she knows!
I've got a really bad feeling about this.
Do what I want...
or I'll blame her death on you.
I didn't do anything!
That's none of my business!
You gave me a call and said
that her death was an accident!
And now you know the truth.
So please... do what I want.
Get away from him.
Don't you wanna know who
really killed your sister?
I already know who
fucking killed my sister.
There's more to that story.
Teppert paid me.
I didn't wanna hurt anybody.
- Fucking bitch!
I just realized what I got myself into.
Frank!
I thought it was an accident... not murder.
-You're a fucking liar!
What have you done?!
- Something I'll pay you to help me out of.
I... I can't believe this!
You're the police!
And I want to stay a policeman.
Mike is Teppert's...
...son!
Liar!
- I didn't wanna hurt anybody...
I just realized what I got myself into!
Man... my knees won't stop shaking.
It's just your knees... pussy.
Good job, fuckface.
- Yeah, shitball. What did you do?
Sarah.
Oh fuck...
It's okay. It's all over now.
You're all right?
- Yes, I am.
Let's go.
Fuck you... Fuck you!
Fuck that shit!
Subtitles by LeapinLar