♪ Candy says ♪
♪ I've come to hate my body ♪
♪ And all that it requires ♪
♪ In this world ♪
♪ Candy says ♪
♪ I'd like to know completely ♪
♪ What others so discreetly ♪
♪ Talk about ♪
♪ I'm gonna watch ♪
♪ Blue birds fly ♪
♪ Over my shoulder ♪
We are at
an evolutionary moment.
One that pushes us
to confront
how we define ourselves
and know one another.
We've outgrown categories
and definitions
that once held us.
Man, woman, boy, girl.
Masculine and feminine
no longer reflect us all.
We've made way
for something new:
cis and trans, non-binary
and gender queer.
The singular "they."
We've seen
an Olympian sprint away
from her heroic past
to declare herself anew.
A black child
from Mobile, Alabama, reach
unimaginable stardom
on our screens.
An Army sergeant break rank
to defend his right to serve
our country openly.
These stories of triumph
do not outweigh the tragedy
facing many Trans-Americans
who struggle
with limited access
to shelter, healthcare,
education, and employment.
Susceptible to HIV,
criminalization,
suicide, and violence.
Despite the vitriol,
despite the backlash,
despite the discriminatory laws,
we fight to be seen
as we see ourselves and live
our truth without compromise.
We are a constellation
of experiences,
expressions, and identities.
Ours is a mesmerizing
constellation,
so vast, it can't be contained,
so plentiful,
it can't be denied
so brilliant, it shines
through the dark.
This is "The Trans List."
I grew up
in a very rural community,
which really still
is close to my heart,
in the middle of Missouri,
called Fayette, Missouri.
Population hee-haw.
One flashing red light
in the middle of town.
We're called "the buckle
of the Bible Belt."
I remember coming home
every day after school
and having private time
with myself praying.
I prayed for unity
of my body, mind, and spirit.
Now obviously, I didn't have
those exact words as a child,
but I knew
that my body and--
and my mind didn't conform.
I wanted God to
change me, to fix me,
because I knew
something was wrong.
I was masculine.
Always masculine.
Uber-macsuline.
I was never mistaken
as a girl most times,
and if I dressed up
as a girl,
it looked like
I was in drag.
Well, I would try
to pretend to be a girl,
and that would last for,
like, two days at school,
and I just
couldn't stand it.
I'm like,
"This seems so... gay."
My parents were
children of slaves.
They loved me unconditionally,
no matter who I was or am.
My father drove trucks.
I'd go on runs with him
on my spring break,
when I could be
with him all week.
People would always say,
"Oh, you brought
your son with you."
He just never blinked an eye
and kept it moving.
Well, he was just
always my cover guy.
He just innately got
who I was.
A child that looked like me
going to school had
a very hard time
with the skin color.
I'd lived as a high yellow
and had taken a lot of hate
from that as a child.
I got locked
in the coat closet
by the teacher
for doing nothing,
and luckily,
my dad did truck deliveries
and happened to walk
into the school one day
and saw
what was happening.
He dropped a delivery
and walked
to the principal's face,
and he said,
"Don't you ever do that
to my child again."
I think Mother had more designs
on who I should be
and what I should
be looking like.
I turned 18,
my mother put
her hand on my shoulder
and looked me in the eye.
She's like,
"You know you're a girl, right?"
I described myself
as nothing, literally,
and would just,
like, avoid the question.
Then finally,
I began to use the "L" word.
It was like,
"Uh, l-- l--"
Because my attraction
was towards women,
I must be a lesbian.
But I was never at home
in any of the spaces.
You listen to certain music,
you read certain books.
I'm like, "Well, gee,
this music isn't for me."
For a black person
walking around
looking like a dude going,
"Hey, man. What's going on?
How you doin', man?"
Uh, they just didn't
like that very much.
It wasn't until
I found an article
about Billy Tipton,
who was a musician.
He hadn't sought
medical treatment
and he died of simply
a-- a bleeding ulcer
because he'd been hiding
his identity for so long.
I'd hide that in our house
every day to read after school,
and it let me know
I wasn't crazy.
I would always
play Perry Mason
on my little twin bed.
In my room
was my desk
and I'd have
everything laid out.
What I had decided was
that I would become
a corporate lawyer.
It was horrifying.
Skirt suits, hose, and heels.
I couldn't wait to
get to the parking lot
to get in my car.
I was like Superman.
As soon as I got in the car,
I was ripping everything off.
And I started
dressing like this.
It's just innately me.
I had had a vision
that one day I would do
testimony before Congress,
and I remember
thinking that as a kid
playing Perry Mason
on my little bed.
And then that happened.
It was very emotional.
It took me back
to the experiences
that I had had
of being treated
as a non-human being
just for being trans.
But I wanted to tell
everybody's story
through my story.
We need clear,
explicit protection
for trans people
throughout this country
so there is no doubt
that somebody can't kill me
just because I'm trans.
And if they do,
then they suffer
the consequence.
Today it's not
such a big deal.
25, 30 years ago,
it was a big deal.
Getting through
the '60s and '70s transgender,
it wasn't-- wasn't fun.
Back then,
you just blended in.
Is there a certain way that
you're supposed to be or look?
We come in all
shapes and sizes.
God blessed me
with my looks
to be able to work
as a model,
but it's also--
that's caused me
the greatest deal of problems.
I think it would have
gone to my grave.
I don't think
I would have ever been
open enough
to say, you know,
"This is me. So what?"
It was just forced upon me
and then having to deal with it.
After I was outed
by "News of the World,"
I felt desperate, suicidal.
It really wasn't
anyone's business,
and it should have
been left to me
if I wanted to talk about it.
I had all these tabloids
ringing and-- and saying,
"You know, just--
"let-- let's see
your birth certificate.
Let's see some documentation."
I was devastated.
I mean, it was
very personal to me
and private.
I thank the Lord
that I did have my family.
That just gave me
strength to fight.
The rights and recognition
and, um, to be accepted.
It wasn't until
I had sexual awareness
that I realized, you know,
"There's something
wrong with me."
I just assumed
I must be gay,
because I was attracted
to boys and not girls.
I just needed
to get away from home
and find myself.
Grow my hair...
tid a bit and look
sort of girly.
I moved to London
and I wasn't accepted
in gay clubs,
in the gay circles.
They said, "Oh, you know,
we don't allow drag queens."
And it's like,
"Drag queens?
I-- I'm not a drag queen."
I was totally lost.
I had an evening job
in a West End show
selling programs,
ice creams.
Quite a famous choreographer
came up to me and said,
"Have you ever thought
about being a showgirl?"
and I said,
"Showgirl?"
And he said,
"Well, you're beautiful.
You're tall. You're slim."
I said,
"Well, um, I'm a boy."
And he said,
"Well, I know that,
but in Paris,
"lots of the beautiful showgirls
are all transgender
and what have you."
And he said, "I'm auditioning
and I'd like you to come along."
And I was like, "Okay."
So, I went along
for the audition
and got the job
and it was like,
"Oh, my gosh."
And it changed my life.
I was working in Paris.
This one particular person
kept sending champagne
and I met him
after the show
and he was very handsome.
I confided
and, uh, he--
he thought it was fascinating.
He said, "You're beautiful,
you're unusual,
"you should never have surgery.
You're unique."
He gave me
a beautiful penthouse,
jewelry, clothes, love.
I had everything
a girl would look for
in a relationship.
But I just--
I weren't happy.
Without getting
into the nitty-gritty
of the sexual side of things,
I mean, he never
touched me down there.
Obviously he was aware of it
'cause he could see it.
It wasn't something
I was comfortable with.
Um, you know, it was
just a part of my body
that I detested.
I couldn't be active.
I wanted to be passive.
I tried being passive
as the gay role, but...
that just wasn't
comfortable for me.
He said, "Well, you know,
I'll give you the world,
but I'm not gonna pay
for your surgery."
I said,
"Well, that's okay."
You know, so, um,
I made my way home.
I've never
regretted my surgery.
It was important for me.
I do know
and have heard of people
where, "It's gonna
make me a woman."
You know, "I can't wait."
And it's like no,
it'll help you function,
but it's never gonna
make you a complete woman.
That's just a small part
of the whole picture.
And I did the Wella ad
for a perm,
and that was a big campaign.
Bras for Playtex.
I'd also been part
of the Smirnoff Vodka campaign.
I was behind the Loch Ness
Monster, waterskiing.
And it was a great campaign.
It was all in--
all the magazines
and billboards.
And nobody knew.
It just--
it wasn't questioned.
But everything crashed down
with the Bond film.
I can honestly say that
I loved being successful
as a model full-stop,
not transsexual
Tula the model.
There's a lot of bigoted,
ignorant people out there
that still give people
like myself a hard time.
Odd character that say,
"No matter what you do,
you'll always be
a mutilated man."
Very unfair
because we're not criminals.
You know,
we were born this way
and we just really try
to make the most of life.
I just...
pray for them.
It's all I can say,
because they have
more problems
than I do.
I'm just me
and I hate labels
and boxes, so...
As a kid,
I loved boy bands,
and I still do.
I also loved Pee-wee Herman.
I loved "Pee-wee's Playhouse."
His gender was
so strange to me.
He was so otherworldly.
I also loved
the movie "Stand by Me."
Watched it obsessively.
Had it memorized
by seven.
It felt like
a raw connection.
Four young male friends
in the '50s--
there was something there.
An experience
that I was longing for.
I remember walking
outside with my mother
at the age of five
and telling her
I should have been
born a boy.
It was a very
simple conversation.
Like, "No, you don't.
Don't say that again."
And then I don't think
I did say that again
for a long time.
I had long brown hair
and bangs, and it was
always pulled back.
I feel like I look the same.
Honestly.
With a few minor adjustments.
Shopping for clothes was always
a nightmare growing up.
The girls' section of Kmart,
that's where I would--
you know,
those were my options,
so it was, like,
the most masculine stuff
that I could find
in those sections.
Clothing was the one thing
where I felt like
I had some control over
how the world was seeing me.
Well, anything that
would hide my body--
large, giant pieces
of clothing.
I-- I really loved
any kind of, like,
oversized, hooded sweatshirts.
I didn't want anybody
to see... anything,
so I covered it up.
I really don't know
what I was waiting for
for so long.
It just felt it was
no longer an option
for my sanity
or for my health.
I was trying to make it through
without transitioning,
and I couldn't.
I had to stop
spending so much time
covering up my emotions
and my problems,
and I had to deal
with myself.
My drinking was
a coping mechanism...
to not deal with gender,
to not deal with the way
that I was existing
in the world
at the time.
And I know that
if I had kept drinking,
I never would have
done anything.
I had started
taking photographs
of trans men
in San Francisco.
I met my friend, Rocco.
During his photoshoot,
I was telling him
I wanted to make
all of these photographs
and just put them
into a zine.
And we ended up
partnering up
and making it into,
this quarterly-printed magazine.
There wasn't
really much trans
experiences
in the media
at all.
I wanted to see
myself reflected,
and from there it grew.
The models
and the people
being featured
were speaking
for themselves
as trans people.
They weren't just
being photographed
and put in a magazine,
they weren't just having
an article written about them.
They were talking,
they were telling us
their story,
posing the way
that they wanted to pose.
They were-- everything was
very much like, you know,
self-styled,
and... that--
I felt like
needed to happen.
Naming it "Original Plumbing"
was like throwing it
in people's faces
who are always asking, you know,
"What's in your pants?"
Finding out that you're trans
and just immediately
thinking about genitals.
It's just acknowledging
that that's a question
that's asked constantly
Passing is when
you're not being
"seen" as a trans person.
I think I noticed
that I was really,
um, "passing" when,
um, men would
say things if I made
eye contact for too long.
I remember smiling at
a young man and his young son,
they were on a bicycle,
and just, like, smiling at them,
and he was like,
"What the fuck are
you looking at? Fucking faggot."
I just would love
to tell my younger self
that there are more experiences
than just male and female.
You will be an adult.
You will not be shopping
in the women's section of Kmart.
You will become yourself.
The very first time
that I dressed up,
it was one of the greatest
moments of my life.
I felt enlightened.
I just felt... me.
It was a white dress,
strapless, and short to my--
down to my knees
and it was flare.
I would say
I felt like Cinderella.
The little mousies came
and just gave me the magic wand,
and I was just transform.
I am a very proud
Trans-Latina immigrant.
Some people may think
that I'm a troublemaker,
but our time is now.
Our time to resist,
our time to organize,
it's now.
Oftentimes, the LGB community
is not supportive of the issues
happening with us.
Where the trans community
is in comparison
to the LGB community,
we are about 40 years behind--
legislatively, economically,
academically, you name it.
There was a very significant
event that changed my life.
The murder of Gwen Araujo.
That sparked my anger.
That unleashed the deer in me.
Ever since then,
I've been, like, nonstop,
doing whatever I need to
in order to not only make
the voices of my community heard
but disrupting whoever.
And when I came
to Los Angeles,
I found my community here.
1988.
There were a gang of girls,
20, 30, in one corner.
Those who have
a little more experience
or that were
a little more seasoned
would take us
under their wing.
How to do my makeup,
how to do a body.
They give you tips and tricks.
I needed to go
every single night
to the street
to get money.
That was my only
source of money.
Drugs were my refuge.
Drugs was a way
for me to cope
with everything that was
going on in my life.
Sleeping on the street,
coping with the fact
that I had just been raped.
Drugs did that.
Gave me the strength
to continue to survive.
There were major crimes
that I committed.
The crimes that I committed
were generated
because of my drug addiction.
I was in a prison
of about 3,000 men.
There was this individual who,
every time
he would see me,
he would say,
"You need to stop it.
You need to stop it."
He came with a big two-by-four.
Out of nowhere,
he just started hitting me.
I ended up
in the infirmary.
But then after,
when I got out,
I seen him and...
I did what I needed to do.
One of the proudest moments
that I continue to feel
is when I see
the transformation
of a young person.
Seeing them build up.
Seeing them
transform themselves.
I felt like a--
like a proud mama.
I think I need a moment.
I always refer to myself
as "Yo soy un milagro,"
which means that
I am a miracle.
There was a reason
why I didn't...
get killed
when I was
on the streets.
There was a reason why
when I overdosed
in an alley,
the paramedics came
and got me.
There was a reason
why I didn't get killed
when I was in prison.
I'm supposed to be here
doing what...
I'm supposed to be doing.
Testosterone is a powerful hormone.
It changed
the way I think,
it changed the way
I interact in the world,
it gave me confidence,
and it also gave me confidence
around my sexuality.
Loving your own body
can change your life.
I decided I'm gonna make
my own idea of what a man is,
and for me,
my idea of a man
doesn't necessarily
include a penis.
So I'm a man without a penis.
What does that say
to the world?
It says that you can be any type
of man that you want to be.
My ideal man was G.I. Joe.
Since I was a kid,
G.I. Joe was
this guy that
I wanted to be.
I wanted to have
that masculine body
and I wanted
to have muscles
and I wanted to take
my shirt off.
And I know it just seems
very... shallow in a sense,
but I think
for trans people,
our outer selves are
very important to us.
They're very important to
the way we present to the world
because it's the way
the world comes back to us.
My first suicide attempt
was at 16.
There was no future.
All I thought about
was killing myself.
That was the only option
I ever felt that I had.
It is that thing that
in a way kept me going.
I always knew that I had
this "option," right?
This option to just check out.
I started going to therapy.
None of my therapists
had the tools, right?
In the '80s and '90s,
nobody really talked
about a transgender man.
When I said I felt
like a man, they all said,
"Well, you're a very
male-identified female,"
which still, to this day,
I don't really understand.
"Basically, you're a lesbian
and just deal with it."
But I knew that wasn't true.
Eventually, one day I found
this amazing therapist.
And she would say,
"Whenever you're ready
to say something,
it's okay, I'm here."
She knew I needed
to say something,
and every week, I would just
sit there for 45 minutes,
'til one day I walked in,
I just started crying,
and I said,
"I feel like a man."
And she said,
"I believe you.
I believe you.
What can we do?"
She saved my life.
There was
no Internet back then,
which is, like, such
a crazy thing to say now.
There's no cell phones
or Internet, right?
There was no Internet,
and I had to go to bookstores.
I found like a very homemade,
punk rock, stapled-together book
that I still have.
Resource guide
for male-to-female
transsexuals.
I knew that was me,
but the opposite.
And in that,
I found a hormone doctor.
He never dealt
with a person like me.
He only dealt with
male-to-female transsexuals,
but he knew when he heard
the urgency in my voice.
He said actually these words:
"You will be my guinea pig,
"because I have no idea
what I'm doing.
Are you prepared for that?"
And I was prepared for it.
I didn't have a choice.
When I decided to get
into making pornography,
they had chicks with dicks,
and I was like,
"That's interesting.
I could be the man
with a pussy."
It didn't exist in the whole
pornography world.
Who's gonna be my audience?
Who's gonna be the people
who are gonna be my customers?
Who? Who? Who knows?
Surprisingly so,
it was gay men.
I got emails that said,
"I've always fantasized,
always fantasized,
about a man with a vagina."
I was like,
"What?"
Nobody acknowledged
my work in my industry.
Nobody acknowledged my work,
and then all of a sudden
I won the "Oscar"
of the porn business.
What I learned from my work
and what I really believe
about sexuality and desire
is that it is
a human thing.
People are attracted to people.
I've pretty much had sex
with pretty much every type
of human being there is.
And it's because I was
attracted to them as a person.
Becoming connected
to your sexuality
and your body sexually
is a huge part
of becoming yourself
and understanding
and loving your body.
It changes everything.
It's difficult.
Because my life did get better
and I feel so blessed
in so many ways,
but when I look back
and I see that little--
I see that little kid, and I...
and I know how
that little kid feels,
that little kid doesn't see
the light at the end
of the tunnel.
And I know you can
say it to that kid.
I could say it
to him right now.
There is a light.
There is a light,
believe me.
But I know
how deep it hurts.
But what I could say
to that... kid is,
"You can be G.I. Joe. You can."
Miss Major:
I don't need your acceptance.
I just need your respect.
Read your Bible,
go back to the Pharaoh,
and pick any eunuch
that you can think of,
see if it had a first name,
which was probably Bob,
and what they
call it now, Loretta.
Oh, that's a transgender person.
Well, shit. Oh, dear.
We've been around
since time began.
Duh.
The '60s were a moment
of everybody trying
to self-identify, everybody
trying to be who they are
and get recognized
for that and appreciated.
My family told me that...
Chicago was not big enough
for the both of us.
Went to New York and got
my world turned upside down.
It was vibrant and young,
and people were
dressing up to go out,
and the clubs were sparkling
and everybody was
doing their own thing.
No matter what you were into,
you could find it there
at any time.
It was absolutely fabulous.
Stonewall was
a meeting place
in the Village
in New York
for transgender,
nonconforming people
to meet and socialize
and hang out.
When you were through
hookin', you know,
you could run in
and have a quick drink
before you went home,
chat with your friends,
see who made
the most amount of money,
make plans
for the next day,
and then hit it.
You had to step away
from another person
of the same gender.
You had to have three articles
of male clothing
over or under your dress
or they would arrest you
for fraud.
And when that
Stonewall incident happened,
it just became a thing of...
the shit just finally
hit the fan.
I was there
when the fighting started.
I got knocked out.
Thank God, or they would have
continued to beat me
until I couldn't have walked.
And it went on for days.
Did it change things?
It did for the gay
and lesbian community.
Did it change things
for my transgender community?
It really didn't.
We're the third or fourth letter
in that alphabet soup
thing that they have, GLBT.
Well, to me,
"T" should have been first.
We were there doing
most of the fighting,
so let's start there,
and then let's get
the gay and lesbian and bi.
We were unemployable.
I gotta eat.
I'm hungry.
And like
Scarlett O'Hara says,
"Child, I will never
be fuckin' hungry again."
So it was a matter of doing
what you needed to do
to survive.
I hooked up with some girls
who hooked a lot.
I learned how to boost
and rob johns
without them knowing it.
I got arrested
for getting in a fight
with a cop
and knocking him out.
He tore my silk
organza dress, girl.
That is not
a thing to do.
Took me too long to find
that dress at my size.
You want me?
Catch me.
So, he caught me,
and I wound up going to jail.
While you're in there,
you were suffering
the same abuses
that you were suffering
while you were outside
the prison wall.
And the assaults
are not just physical.
They're mental,
spiritual, and emotional,
so it was hard.
It was very--
it was-- it was hard.
We're not safe.
We are running around
with targets on our back.
We have to constantly
be on our guard.
Constantly watching what anyone
and everyone is doing around us.
I got gray worrying
about all that stuff
all the time.
I want to make sure
that every young girl has
an opportunity to get
to this point safely
with the least amount
of bullshit happening to her
and knocking her on her ass
and trying to keep her down.
I want us to get a chance to
appreciate smelling a rose,
walking through the park
without your shoes on
to feel the grass
on your toes.
Go to Monterey
and walk on the white sand.
Oh!
And those are things that
we don't get a chance to do.
What would I like
my legacy to be?
She came, she cared, she left.
What else would there be?
Bathrooms is sort of
like the focal point
of trans issues?
Ooh, the bathroom.
What do we do
about the bathroom?
It does start to...
collapse that structure
of two-gender
that has been here
for so long.
Just bathrooms.
We all gotta use 'em.
Doesn't have to
be so protected.
Not the Pentagon,
just a bathroom.
In the fifth grade,
they have actual,
like, multi-stall bathrooms.
That was the year where
I started going by Nicole
and I started wearing skirts
and had my ears pierced
and everything.
That was really what marked
transition for me.
We'd worked with the school
and they said,
"We think that it'd be best
if she have her own space
away from the other students."
I had a staff member
six feet behind me at all times.
If I wanted to get up
and go to the bathroom
in the middle of class,
I had to wait
for the staff member
to come with me
to make sure that I didn't go
into the girls' bathroom.
And it really made me feel
like I was an outsider
and that I wasn't fit
to be with the other kids.
Like there was
something wrong with me.
This is very,
very common
among trans youth everywhere.
Someone's gotta say
somethin' about it.
A year after middle school,
we had filed a lawsuit
for wrongful discrimination
based off of my gender,
which was protected
under Title IX.
It took a while.
I think it was
six years it took. Wow.
When the Susan Doe
versus RSU 26 case was decided,
I was in the lunchroom,
you know, doin' my business,
I think I was
eating waffle fries,
and I got a text
from my mom.
It was just, you know,
all capital letters,
lots of exclamation points,
"We won!"
You know, I was running around
telling everybody.
This case is really
a landmark case,
'cause this is the first time
a court has ruled
in favor of a trans youth.
This is what happened in Maine,
now we can make it
happen other places.
The dreaded bathrooms
aren't gonna be
something that we're all
so afraid of anymore.
We can just pee in peace.
I'm an identical twin.
I have a twin brother, Jonas.
I'm older by 10 minutes.
Growing up with somebody
who was an exact mirror
of what I could have been
was scary to me
when I was little.
He was always what society
sort of expected of me.
I started hormone blockers
right before I started puberty.
We totally cut off testosterone,
and it worked amazing.
I can't stress enough
how I dodged a bullet.
Our journey was a family one.
My dad struggled
for a while and said,
"You're not a girl."
"Yes, I am."
"No, you're not."
"Yes, I am.
"Dad, you've gotta face it.
"You've got a son,
you've got a daughter.
There's nothing
you can do about it."
Well, I think
it was really my mom
that helped
my dad come around.
She left Jennifer Boylan's book
"She's Not There"
on the coffee table.
She didn't tell him to read it.
She just sort of left it there.
And it didn't work
on the coffee table,
so she did
the next best thing.
She put it in the bathroom.
Couple days later,
the book wasn't
in the bathroom anymore.
When he got on-board...
he got on-board.
He's just totally become
this figure in the community
and it's amazing to watch
his transformation
as well as mine.
To a young person whose parents
aren't necessarily on-board,
I'd say you gotta
advocate for you.
That's what I did
with my parents.
You know,
they wouldn't have known
if I really wasn't as vocal.
Advocate for yourself.
Do not take no for an answer.
Do not settle for less.
This is your life.
Just save yourself.
Slay your own dragon.
You can do it.
The United States Military
is a hypermasculine
environment.
There's only
three percent female,
so the United States
Marine Corps is alpha male,
straight forward,
hooah-hooah, hardcore, oorah,
you know,
badass motherfuckers.
They don't have time
to be worrying about,
like, who's peeing in a ditch
and who's peeing standing up.
They're just wanting
to get the mission done.
My performance standard
was so high
that nobody really
gave a shit.
It was like,
"That dude's awesome at his job.
That dude's a chick. All right."
It's just gonna
fall off the table.
And they just let it go.
No one's just gonna
come and square off.
I mean, now I'm bigger,
but even then I was
a badass motherfucker.
I was just, you know,
140 pounds versus 180 pounds.
The first time I went to Iraq,
I was only 18.
Two weeks in, I saw
a woman get stoned,
I watched one
of my best friends get
his legs blown off.
It's everything
you can imagine.
It smells bad,
it's hot, it's sandy.
There's a lot of chaos,
a lotta high anxiety,
a lotta high-stress moments.
That first deployment
to Fallujah,
more than a third
of our Marines
were killed in action
or wounded.
My particular platoon
only had 30 people,
and when we came back,
we only had
12 of the original people
we'd deployed with.
It was really hard
to deal with.
I'm still dealing with it.
I learned about discrimination
from a very young age.
I grew up
on reservation land.
My great-grandmother
and-- and my grandmother are
both 100% First Nation Cherokee.
I lived with
my great-grandmother
off and on during the summers
during my childhood.
I always heard her stories
of what it was like to be,
you know, an indigenous
person in America.
My family's people
were originally settlers
in the Virginia area,
and they got pushed to Kentucky.
So, I had
first-person accounts
of what it was
to face adversity.
When I went in
the United States Marine Corps,
it was still under
"Don't ask, don't tell."
I think that my recruiter
thought I was a lesbian,
and so like, he made me sign
that waiver that says, like,
I'm not a homosexual
or whatever,
but he gave me this odd look
while I was signing it.
I definitely felt
the oppression
as far as it applies
to sexuality.
I identify as queer
or pansexual.
For me, it was kind of
like a sense of panic.
It's like a witch hunt.
Somebody's gonna,
like, jump out of the woods
and be like,
"Ah, gotcha!"
Legally speaking,
for the last five years,
I am male.
My military passport,
my official red military
passport says "male."
With the Department
of Social Security, I'm male.
But the entry system
which holds the data
for every service member,
male, five-six, blah-blah-blah,
that hasn't changed for me.
I still have to be
addressed by members
of my senior command
as female.
I'm not allowed
to correct people,
because it's military law.
Uh, I can't be like,
"Hey, you're using
the wrong pronoun,"
because technically speaking,
they're in the right.
Being listed as a female
but being seen as male
with your peers,
probably one of the largest
reasons why my anxiety level
is really high.
I never know which bathroom
to use at work,
so I just conveniently
always, like, use the bathroom
when somebody else
is not there.
But I usually use
the men's bathroom
because it's really
inappropriate to, like,
walk in-- in a female.
It's just always
a really weird situation.
I was going
to the Pentagon
and they wanted me to wear
a female dress uniform.
To do that was
incredibly humiliating.
Like, the civilians there
were interacting,
but they were like, "Sir,
that's a woman's uniform,"
and I'm like,
"I know."
The United States Military
uses a medical code
based on the "DSM-IV,"
which is very, very outdated.
If you're transgendered,
it says it's
a psychosexual condition,
which is-- also lines up
with bedwetting, dementia.
Everything is still
as it was before.
You have to pretend to be
this other person
that you're not.
There's been
no accommodations
made for anyone.
I've always just
been this guy
that always just kinda
wanted to help people.
I saw that no one was
advocating for military rights
for trans military people,
and I felt that
people needed to see,
"Hey, I'm an American soldier,
I can do this job,
and I do it well."
Martin Luther King says,
"If not me, then who?"
You know,
"If not now, then when?"
So, I had to do something.
I swore to serve and protect
the people of the United States
against all enemies,
foreign and domestic.
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna
protect them, right?
What is normal?
Let's be honest,
everybody has their stuff.
This happens to be my stuff.
This is what I dealt with
all my life, secretively,
behind closed doors.
I just couldn't
do it any longer.
I'm just so lucky in life.
I'm this white,
privileged older guy,
ya know, financially all set
and this and that.
"Oh, it's a different
story for you."
Every journey
has its struggle.
Mine...
I had to do it publicly
in front of literally
billions of people
with their perception
of, "Oh, my God, Bruce Jenner,
'Mr. Male Athlete
of the World,' is really trans."
Going from a very positive
masculine figure
to what a lot of people perceive
as a feminine, weak figure...
publicly, not easy to do.
I'm comfortable
in my womanhood.
But what does
that really mean?
What is this thing "female"?
I still struggle with that.
It's more than hair
and makeup.
It's more than
the pitch of your voice.
I didn't grow up
having my first period.
on my first date.
I didn't have
all of these things
that all women experience.
I am a trans woman.
My experience is different
and I think I am different
than other women,
and I never want to disrespect
women from that standpoint,
but I'm much more comfortable
over on that side,
and that's the first time
in my life I can ever say that.
All of a sudden now, I am...
like this spokesperson
for the trans community.
Not even close.
I am an expert on my story.
Nobody else's.
I would love to show
other stories through the media,
and yes, I do have
a platform here,
and that platform
is very important.
I can't go out
and help anybody else
or talk about this issue
if I'm not so clear
in my soul
about who I am
as a person,
and this is who I am.
For the first time in my life,
I wake up in the morning
and I don't have any more
secrets stored up
in my soul.
Growing up,
I was a dyslexic kid.
Suffered from terrible
low self-esteem.
I had gender issues
all the time.
My outlet
to prove my masculinity
was to play sports.
'Cause that was all of me.
That was the little trans kid,
that was
the little dyslexic kid,
that was a person
with great drive.
When the games were over with,
I got up the next morning,
I put the gold medal
around my neck
and I looked in the mirror,
not a stitch of clothes on,
and I said,
"Oh, my God,
now what do I do?"
You know,
now I look back on it,
"Go, Bruce!"
But we've moved on.
A sense of humor
is extremely important.
This is pretty funny.
Ya know, me of all people,
the big Bruce Jenner,
ya know, dealing
with these issues.
That in itself is a sketch
on "Saturday Night Live."
For Halloween,
they were coming up
with a Caitlyn Jenner
Halloween costume,
the bustier I wore
on the cover of "Vanity Fair."
I think it's
pretty funny, ya know?
And boy, some people
in the community go,
"How can you do that?
How disparaging."
You know, "You're putting
trans people down,"
and stuff like--
and I said,
"No, I'm thinkin'
I like to go through life
with a sense of humor."
And to me, that was--
yeah, that was funny.
I feel so blessed
that I did transition
later on in life
'cause I loved raising my kids.
I loved carpooling my kids.
They were just great.
They said,
"Can we still
call you Daddy?"
I said,
"Of course you can
still call me Daddy.
"I'm gonna be your dad
until the last day I'm here
on Earth, okay?
I'm always going to
be your father."
My daughter-in-law
just had a little girl.
She will only grow up
knowing Caitlyn.
I thought,
"Isn't that so cool?"
So of course we're trying
to come up with a name.
I don't know
if we're gonna go with it,
but they came up with...
Boom-Boom.
Why Boom-Boom?
I don't know,
but it seemed to stick
with all my kids in the room
to call me Boom-Boom.
And I've been called worse.
Yeah, I've been called worse.
Yeah.
Ah.
Remember, keep
your sense of humor.
Gender is an essence.
Personality.
The power of gender is precisely
that it can never be defined.
I don't think
that gender is fixed.
I think that gender can actually
change every single day.
Myself is many selves.
One day I might
feel really masculine,
one day I might
feel really feminine.
The next day,
I might feel neither,
and every single day,
I should have the autonomy
to self-determine
who I want to be.
I identify as non-binary,
which means I don't identify
as either a man or a woman,
but I identify as femme,
and I understand femininity
to not be the same thing
as womanhood.
I think femininity exists
outside of bodies and outside
of one type of gender.
My femme identity is part
of a long ancestral lineage
of all the feminine people
in my life who have done
so much profound emotional
and social work,
but have been
completely discredited.
Like caretaking,
helping people process trauma,
grief, or depression,
cooking for people.
These are all things
that are substantive
and real and powerful,
but we're taught
from our society that
they're insignificant and wrong.
For me, identifying
as femme is about saying,
"No thank you, patriarchy.
"My strength comes
from my femininity,
and my femininity is not
confined to just my body."
So much of what Western culture
is obsessed with is the body.
We live in a culture that's
routinely fat-shaming people,
policing people's skin tones,
holding up certain bodies
to be more desirable
than other bodies.
Why are we so fixated
on people's physicality?
We literally have
a women's movement today
that says being a woman
means having a vagina.
That's the most
misogynist equation
I've ever heard
in my entire life.
Patriarchal society
has taught us that
women are just vaginas,
that women are just mothers,
that women are just
reproductive agents.
Feminism should be about
complicating that narrative.
Constantly,
people will tell me,
"You're just a man
because of how you look,"
and I have to step back
and be like,
"Let's check a lot of those
assumptions you're making there.
"One, you're assuming that
just because a doctor
"told my mother
when I was born
"that I was a boy
that that should be my fate
for the rest of my life."
I'm fighting for a world
where people can actually have
the self-determination
to choose who they are.
There's no one way
to look like a woman,
there's no one way to look
like a man or a femme.
There's just a way
to look like yourself.
I think that there have
always been people like me.
Learning that is so important.
In India, there's
a long ancestral tradition
of gender nonconformity.
We have gods
who changed genders,
and in large parts
of South Asia, you can be
represented as the third gender
on your identity document.
When the British colonized us,
they created the first types
of colonial legislation
which defined trans
people as "eunuchs,"
a.k.a. defined trans people
as men without penises.
and it became a fixation
on our genitalia.
They criminalized us and taught
our own people to hate us
even though
for thousands of years,
my cultures had found
ways to understand gender
as a relationship
with our land,
our relationship
with our families,
to caretaking.
All of those infinite ways
of understanding gender
were lost and made
into genitalia.
And that has everything do
with the history of colonialism.
Liberation looks
like every single person
being able to
self-determine their identity
without fear
of persecution or violence.
I shouldn't have to modify
my body in order to be safe
and I should not
be victim-blamed
for being who I am.
I should be able to wear
a skirt, a dress, a beard,
interchangeably all the above,
with no fear.
I grew up in a world
that taught me that
I should be
confined by my body,
but I refuse
to accept that.
And that is a lesson
that I think everyone
could learn from.
You are so much more
tremendous and incredible
than something so simple
as what you look like.
I've always known that
I wanted to be a performer.
In the black church,
there was this whole thing
about being made over,
about being sort of,
you know, transformed
by the spirit or something.
And I think that
very early on,
I wanted to be
sort of transformed
by art and by television
and by the theater.
As a kid
in Mobile, Alabama,
my environment
was not necessarily
the most affirming place,
but in my imagination,
I could go anywhere,
and my imagination saved me.
The first time
I saw Leontyne Price
was when I was five
or six years old.
"Evening at Pops,"
Boston Pops,
which they used to
do on PBS.
And she was this
regal black woman
with big,
full lips like me,
and high cheekbones,
and she had so much dignity.
And she was singing
"Un bel di vedremo"
from "Madama Butterfly,"
and it was sort of just
this big, huge,
rich, smoky voice
coming from this elegant woman.
And it was just--
I was like,
"I wanna be like that."
I started begging my mother
to put me into dance classes
when I was five,
and I danced around everywhere.
There was a lot
of gender policing
from people at church
and my teachers,
particularly in
elementary school.
A teacher would say,
"You need to take
"that child out
of those dance classes.
"Those dance classes are
making them gay,
or gonna make--
turn them gay,"
and, "You're acting
like a girl."
My mom said,
"No, no, no.
I will let my child
do what they want to do."
I had a dance scholarship
to Indiana University
and then to Marymount.
I got to travel
all over the country
'cause of art.
Art has consistently been
this thing that has
saved my life, and it sort of
rescued me from darkness.
As a black trans woman,
it is difficult to get a job.
I mean, like three years ago,
I was barely paying my rent.
Like I was literally
in housing court,
you know,
trying to avoid eviction.
Working at Lucky Cheng's,
a restaurant that dubbed itself
the "drag queen capital
of the world,"
as a trans woman
was deeply challenging.
The clientele at Lucky Cheng's
came for a spectacle,
came for the spectacle
of what they perceived
to be men in dresses.
My identity as a trans woman
is not a joke.
However, I'm a performer
and I'm an actress,
and I was there
doing a job.
I am not sure
I would have had a job
if it were not
for Lucky Cheng's.
The trans women
and the queens
that I worked with are
some of the best people
that I've ever known.
I would not be here if it
were not for that sisterhood.
For years,
I would audition
for agents
and casting directors,
and they would say,
"You know, uh, maybe
you should move to L.A.
"There's not really work
for you trans people.
"There's stuff here and there.
I don't know
what to do with you."
And there was just,
like, people telling me
that I probably wouldn't
be able to do this.
The morning I found out I was
nominated for an Emmy,
I was in my tiny
studio apartment in New York.
It was like a...
It was incredible.
And I think it meant a lot to
a lot of trans people out there
who thought
that a trans person
will never have
this kind of moment.
I've always been
in this place with my looks
where it's not enough.
I'm tall,
I have broad shoulders,
I have big hands,
I have a deep voice,
I have big feet.
I'm recognizably trans.
For many years, I would
sort of like sort of cower
and sort of try
to make myself disappear
so people
wouldn't notice that.
I can't make myself disappear.
I'm a--
I'm a big presence,
and so I had to start
owning this trans thing.
This is it.
Yes, I'm trans.
It's wonderful, it's beautiful,
I'm gonna own this.
I'm starting to believe
in my own power.
My voice matters.
My truth matters.
We live in a world
that tells so many people
that they're not enough.
I'm here to tell you that you are.
You-- you're enough
just as who you are.
♪ I've been set free ♪
♪ And... I've been bound ♪
♪ To the memories ♪
♪ Of yesterday's clouds ♪
♪ I've been set free ♪
♪ And... I've been bound ♪
♪ And now ♪
♪ I'm set free ♪
♪ I'm set free to find ♪
♪ A new illusion ♪
♪ I've been blinded ♪
♪ But... now I can see ♪
♪ What in the world ♪
♪ Has happened to me ♪
♪ The prince of stories ♪
♪ Who walks right by me ♪
♪ And now ♪
♪ I'm set free ♪
♪ I'm set free to find ♪
♪ A new illusion ♪
♪ ♪