It's occupied.
One thousand drachmas.
Come on, seven hundred.
Okay.
Well done.
He's old enough to be her father.
- What has he done?
- He just has to get out of the country.
Yes, but why?
Can you bring the passports
to one of the islands?
I don't know. How much trouble is he in?
Niko, he'll pay us.
We can make a lot of money.
Are you joking?
This guy hasn't got a clue.
This is bullshit.
I'm not getting involved.
Police are investigating the death
of an American national
at the Grand Hotel in Athens.
The man, in his 50s, was discovered
by hotel staff yesterday morning.
Police are yet to name any suspects,
but it is believed
they are focussing
their search in Athens
and the border crossings
with Yugoslavia and Albania.
Stop! Stop it!
Can't you see he's drunk?
What's going on here?
Nothing.
How soon can you get
the passports to Iráklion?
Tomorrow morning.
I'll see you at Café Astir at eight.
I'll be there.
You didn't tell me
he's wanted for murder.
He's got plenty of money.
I can't wait for you.
Sorry!
The girl doesn't feel well.
How far is it to Iráklion?
Five kilometres.
Past the ruins at Knossos.
Are you all right?
I had too much to drink.
You should be careful in this weather.
You could slip and fall overboard.
Okay, I'll be careful.
Where are you from?
- Crete, sir.
- Documents?
Did you visit Knossos?
No, why?
We're looking for someone
seen at the ruins.
Go and speak to my colleague, please.
Could you go and speak
to my colleague, please?
Just over there, please.
Were you travelling alone in Crete?
No, I was visiting my mother.
Did you visit Knossos?
Why would I go there?
I was born in Crete.
Where do you live now?
Athens.
What's your occupation?
Musician.
Reports indicate the victim was robbed
as no valuables
or identification were found on her.
A man in his 20s,
believed to be a Greek national
was seen leaving the site
by a group of students.
Attention, please!
Passengers for Flight 180 to Istanbul
should proceed to the boarding gate.
We lost him on Aynicilar Street.
He must be heading for Rustam Square.