Hey, Don. It's Daniel.
Listen. Don't put the boiler in
until I get back.
The framing inspection
isn't before a couple of weeks,
So we got plenty of time.
I'll check in with you guys
in a couple of days, ok?
Take care. Bye.
First thing I will do is try
to find another producer.
There's gotta to be somebody else
in town who could help us out.
Just for the pre-game.
Hold on just a second, Cal.
Hey, just one second.
I gotta go.
Call me back if you need me. Good luck!
Ok, bye.
Hey, I'm so sorry.
What's up?
I got stuck in the phone with Cal.
The crew hasn't even made it to the arena yet.
That's not good.
I don't know what they gonna do.
Are all the lights out?
No. They're all on.
Just checking.
Are you sure you want
to load that thing with you?
I don't even think we can get online there.
Oh, we can. I checked.
All set?
Let's just try to remember...
It's Cal.
Hey, just a second.
This is supposed to be a vacation.
I know. And boy, do we need one.
Hey, what's up?
Well, that could work.
Hey.
We're all set for the morning.
We have to be at the dock at 8:30.
Did you have a little shower?
Yes.
Great.
I'm so glad I made you bring this.
There's gotta be thundershowers
tomorrow night late.
Looks like it's gonna be crowded
in the boat tomorrow.
I hope it's not a cattle boat.
We'll just do our own thing. Did you ask?
No. They seem pretty relaxed.
Why is it so hot here?
Air conditioner is blasted.
Figures.
- We didn't come for the room.
- That's for sure.
Considering how much time we had
to put this whole thing together,
I'm amazed if we got anything.
I'm not complaining.
Yes, you are.
Alright, I'm done.
Want to check your email?
No. I'm on vacation, remember?
Right.
That tasted good.
His face!
You too.
Yeah. It's different. I'm a girl.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
So how are you?
Fine.
A little stressed. Still I guess.
It's about work?
Yeah, work, life.
Maybe I can get you
to think of something else.
You ok?
I might not be in the mood.
Just thought like
you might be a second ago.
Could go either way, I guess.
Maybe I need to give you a little nudge.
Yeah, I'm not in the mood.
That wasn't the direction
I was trying to nudge you in.
Sorry. I'm just tired.
It's been a long day.
We can talk.
Nah, you are right.
We should get some sleep.
I'm wiped.
Very funny.
All right, ladies and gentlemen...
Welcome aboard the
world famous "Reef Explorer".
My name's Davis.
I'm going to be one of the guides
on board our vessel today.
Also driving your boat
with, huh, Linda
and Junior. Junior is gonna be
the next guide on board our vessel.
We are going to be knocked
to a dive site called "Magic Kingdom".
Now things you want to look for
down there on this dive:
spotted eels, spotted morays,
enough of stingrays in the sand,
there's angelfish, parrot fish,
tropical fish, barbed beauties...
Is there any big fish
like sharks or anything?
Yeah. We're going out
to the open ocean,
so chances are you probably
might see a shark or three.
But, you know, like I tell
everybody who see a shark,
if you don't want to see it, close your eyes.
No problem.
Sharks over here are not
very aggressive towards human beings,
so therefore you don't really
have to worry about sharks.
Ok.
Ok, that's enough guys.
Enjoy the ride out.
Ok, guys. I need to have
your attention for just a few minutes.
We are going to be entering
the water in a minute.
Once that everybody has entered their gear,
what we want you to do is
a buddy system to enter the water first.
Once that buddy systems are in the water,
we are going to have guided divers,
and myself, Linda, and Junior,
is gonna help you guys get into water.
Linda is on surface support, so
if you surface in a distance away from the boat,
You want to let her know that you are OK.
You start to let her know you are OK
by giving her a big "O" over your head.
If you are not Ok, you do
the international distress signal.
The international
distress signal is simple,
very easy to do. It's like this:
"Help!"
Ok? All right?
Very easy, very simple.
Once everybody's in the water,
I want you to make your way
to the white float ball.
The white float ball
is at the stern of the boat.
- We want you to huh...
- May I sit there?
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry. Go ahead. I'm sorry.
Is that your mask?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- You didn't bring your mask?
- I brought it. I don't know what happened.
It was supposed to be here.
Sorry, sorry everybody.
I'm just, you know...
Anxious to dive. I don't wanna...
Do you have extra masks on the...
- Linda, did you bring an extra mask?
- You have an extra mask, Linda?
No, I don't have an extra mask.
- Junior?
- Anyone?
Does anyone have an extra mask?
No.
You can't dive without a mask.
Yeah, I understand that.
Thank you, Travis.
Davis, Davis.
I'm sorry guys. Go on.
Alright guys. The dive is going to be
at a maximum drop of 60 feet, so...
Therefore, we are going to be
down there for about 35 minutes.
You are ready?
Yeah.
- Are you ok?
- Yeah, I'm ok.
I can't equalize my ears.
Ok. Are you going
to report to the guardian,
trying to get equalized?
I don't think I can go down.
Alright, do me a favor.
Inflate your BC,
put the regulator in your mouth
and swim back towards the platform.
Ok.
Up, stand up, stretch your knees up.
- How was it down there?
- I didn't get down.
You didn't. Why not?
What happened?
I can't get my ears equalized.
You feel all right?
Yeah, I'm good. Thanks.
You mind if I borrow this? Is it ok?
I'll bring it right back.
Save some time. Yeah?
- Sure.
- Thank you. God bless you. I Love you.
Are you going down now?
Yeah, Linda, I'm going down.
Hallelujah.
The only problem I have is
you don't have a buddy right now.
I don't need a buddy.
I've dived all my life.
Unfortunately you do
if you're on our boat, sir.
Your boat.
Give me a break.
Find a buddy for me.
Someone down there's
coming back up.
Can you dive with me?
Unfortunately, if I don't find you
a buddy, I can't let you go, sir.
I love high water.
I'm diving in the finest. Help me.
Come on, dive.
- What's your name?
- Brian.
Are you ready to go, Brian?
We're set. See? I got a buddy.
All set.
- Sir, your regulator.
- Regulator.
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah, got one of those.
Have a good time.
Thank you.
There's a place
in Heaven for you.
I love you. Thank you.
It was great, man.
- Yeah, I'm good. You good?
- Yeah.
Thanks buddy. I appreciated.
Thanks a lot.
You are an angel. I needed that.
- Did you see that shark down there?
- Yeah.
Did everybody enjoy their dive?
Yeah.
That's good.
Have we got everybody?
Daniel, where is the boat?
It's a good question.
I guess it's one of those.
You gotta be kidding me.
It better be one of those.
But which one do you think?
I don't know.
- Did you get us lost?
- No.
So we are in the right spot?
Yes. I'm 90% sure.
90%? Why only 90%?
'cause the boat is not here.
There is a coral head
exactly 42 feet below us.
I marked it on the way down.
Yeah. I can still see the stocks.
The stocks?
Yeah, there's three prawn,
like a forked thing
right below us.
You are unbelievable.
You can still find some of
those little coral formation
in the middle of the ocean, but
you get lost going to my mother's.
I need an incentive.
You love my mother.
They obviously cannot see us.
You think it's time to swim?
Swim where?
I don't know. I think...
That one is the closest.
Honey, it's a bad idea.
Why?
Because we are not sure
that's our boat.
And if it's not our boat,
That means we could swim
farther from our boat.
Besides, you know how far away that is?
It's really far.
It's farther than that.
And if it's not our boat,
they can pull away at anytime.
And our fucking boat,
wherever the hell it is,
will have a hell of time
trying to find us.
You're going somewhere?
Just my face.
I hate to tell you this, but,
I didn't see anything that looks like
any kind of coral formation.
Could you just show me?
I'd just feel better. Sure?
See it? Cause I don't see anything.
- Shit!
- What?
You don't see it, because it's not there.
So does that mean...
...that since we've surfaced,
we're drifting.
Oh, shit. But what does
that mean? Should we swim?
Goddam it. We wasted all this time.
Honey I hate to tell you this,
but swim or not,
we're going
where this current decides.
Are they moving?
Hey! Yes.
Oh God.
Please let this be them.
- It's gotta be, right?
- Yes.
- They're coming right this way.
- Yep.
You realize that's a distress signal.
We are in distress.
Daniel, did you just pee?
Yep.
You're so disgusting.
You said you are a little cold.
Daniel, was that a shark?
Maybe, or a dolphin.
If it was a dolphin, you'd be on your way
over there to play with it,
so you obviously think it was a shark.
- That's all we need right now.
- That's ok.
You were patting a shark
less than an hour ago.
Please, that was nothing
but a big old catfish.
It was more than two hours ago.
You know, now I'm starting
to really get cold.
It's ok.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
I thought he said they
never come that close.
They also said the boat would be here.
It's gone.
It was probably just curious.
A couple of bodies floating up
in the middle of nowhere,
I'm sure it's not
something it sees everyday.
Oh, Daniel.
Where the hell are they?
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
It makes me feel better.
But what do we do if it comes back?
I don't know.
Do we splash? Do we stay still?
You are the one who watches "Shark Week".
First of all, we should be in a cage.
No, we should be on land.
- Sharks are attracted to wounded fish.
- Ok.
So I guess you just
not splash around too much.
- Just sort of...
- Stay still?
Try to stay still.
Oh, God.
Ok. I can't stand
not knowing if it's under me.
- I'm just gonna look, ok?
- Ok.
Okay.
Katharine Hepburn
and Nick Nolte in "Grace Quigley"
and Nick Nolte and
John Malkovich in "Mulholland Falls".
How's that for a quick.
Always quick.
All right. It's your turn.
I, hum...
You know, I really
don't feel like playing.
Okay.
Feel hungry?
Of course.
I'm starving.
- Ouch! Shit!
- What?
Something just bit me here...
What? Where?
I don't know.
It's right down by my ankle.
Oh, God. It kills.
Goddam it! It burns!
I don't see anything.
- Did it get you?
- Yes!
- What is it?
- I don't know,
but the fucker really
stung me. It hurts.
- Let's get the hell out of here.
- Okay.
- I think we are away from them.
- Is that far enough?
Anything?
You got anything?
No.
Damn, those fuckers stung.
I know.
Where did it get you?
On my ankle, on my leg.
Through your wet suit?
I don't know. I guess so.
So are you ok?
No. I'm not ok.
Are you ok?
We find our boat, we'll be ok.
Oh, come on, honey.
I know, I know, I know.
I'm sorry.
It really sucks,
but we're going
to get through this, ok?
Ok.
I know I know.
God, okay.
I've just never heard of anything
so fucked up in my entire life.
Who's ever heard of
two people getting
left in the middle of the ocean before?
I have actually.
- You have?
- Yeah.
Where?
Dive magazines.
It's a lot more common than you think.
Well, thanks for telling me
when we got certified.
Over there.
Oh, my God. Oh, Daniel.
Oh, God. Please, please,
please, let just be them.
Oh, God. I don't even care
if it's not them.
Just please see us and pick us up.
I don't think they can see us.
Wish we had more sun.
- They can't see us.
- I know.
They are leaving.
Yeah.
Stay close.
What if they don't know we're missing?
There's no way.
They took a head count
on the boat. I saw it.
Our stuff is on board.
We have their tanks.
And we know we've drifted.
It may take them a while,
but they will find us.
I hate to tell you, but
I think my dramamine is running off.
- You're getting nauseous?
- Yeah.
- Honey, I could kill those fuckers.
- I know.
It's just all this going
up and down of the weights, I think.
You're probably getting dehydrated.
Yeah? But we can't drink the water, right?
No. I should've told you that before.
You didn't, did you?
A little.
Honey, stop.
It will give you diarrhea, and
make you even more dehydrated.
Great. "Shark Week"?
"Disasters At Sea", History Channel.
I guess this means
I have to stop complaining
about you watching
so much television.
But I didn't know
I might get something out of this.
I'm really, really not feeling well.
Oh, man.
You think maybe
if I took my weights out.
then it wouldn't
pull on me so much?
Just keep the belt, drop the weights.
You'll see'em try
to charge us for those.
Oh, hey. We should put our gloves on.
How are your stings?
Still there.
They're the one thing I think
the salt water is actually helping.
This glove isn't helping them.
I don't feel very good.
Why don't you
lay back for a little bit?
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Just lay back.
- I'm sorry.
- It's ok. I got you.
- Just relax.
- Ok.
- There you go.
Just for a few minutes.
Just relax.
Close your eyes.
Daniel, I have to pee.
Ok.
It's gonna be warm for a minute.
Thanks.
Daniel!
Oh, God. Daniel!
Susanne!
Daniel, I'm over here.
Oh, thank God.
It's ok. I got you.
- Oh, my God. What happened?
- I don't know.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine. You ok?
What happened?
Where did you go?
I must have fallen asleep
and we drifted apart.
- Jesus.
- I'm sorry.
You scared the hell out of me.
I'm so sorry.
It's ok. I'm glad you are here.
Oh, my God.
It's ok.
How long are we sleeping?
God, I'm so out of it.
Jesus, we've been
in the water for 7 hours.
Daniel, I feel something on my leg.
What?
I don't know. It hurts.
It's your sting?
The wrong leg.
Oh, my God. it really hurts.
We just try to keep...
I don't see anything.
I can't either. It's on the back.
I just can't tell.
Hurt all over the whole thing.
Just leave it alone. Ok? Don't tap it.
I'm not touching it.
Well, something is touching it.
It's not me, honey. I'm not here.
My hands are all here.
- Something is tapping on it.
- I will take a look.
Jesus.
Oh, God. I feel sick.
I'm sorry, honey. I threw up.
Fish gotta eat too.
Speaking of which,
the thing patting at your leg,
is just a little cleaner fish.
What about my leg?
A little cut.
- How could it get cut?
- I don't know.
Maybe you rub it against my knife
over sleeping, or something.
Oh, come on. It wasn't a shark, was it?
- No, honey.
- Are you sure?
No. If it was a shark,
your leg would be gone.
Great.
And most, it was a teeny little barracuda
just checking to see if you tasted good.
Oh, God. Is it deep?
No, it's not deep.
- Let's swim out this puke.
- Ok.
Come on.
That's far enough, you think?
Yeah.
Oh, baby. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Rinse your mouth a little bit.
Yeah.
Just don't swallow any, ok?
Spit it back out.
Can still feel that tapping.
- What, the fish?
- Yeah.
Try not to focus on this. Relax.
Here you go.
What is it? Are you ok?
It's leg cramp.
Can I help you?
Is there anything I can do?
I got it. Ouch!
We are really
falling apart, aren't we?
Oh, God. Oh, Honey. Oh, God.
They're gone. They're gone.
Jesus, Daniel. What kind are they?
The big ones.
I'm serious. Are they the bad kind?
I have no idea.
Oh, my God.
No, no, no. Be still.
Don't splash around.
Oh, my God. This can't be normal.
Honey, oh, honey.
I don't know what is worse,
seeing them or not seeing them.
Seeing them.
Unbelievable.
This is truly un-fucking believable.
The best part is that we paid to do this.
We paid to be out here.
We paid those incompetent fuckers
to drop us out
in the middle of the fucking ocean.
We wanted an ocean view.
Boy, did we get it?
You feel better?
I wouldn't exactly call it better.
You finished yelling?
That could be.
Oh, good. You're not the only one
stuck out here, you know.
What? Are you mad at me?
No.
Why? Because I was yelling?
Fine. You be mad.
It's a great vacation, honey, isn't it?
So now we entered no talking phase, uh?
Could you maybe
answer one last question?
Has this somehow over the hours
become my fault?
Let's just drop it.
Of course.
You believe what you want to believe.
But I know for certain that
we were in the right spot.
It's not just a matter
of being in the right spot.
It's being there on time.
We were on time.
We were early. He said 10:30.
Do we always have to get it so close?
For God's sake,
Why don't we stay with the group?
We always have to do things
different than everybody else.
We shouldn't have spent so much time
with that god damn eel.
Well, that's a nice touch, adding "we".
Especially since you wanted have
nothing to do with that fucking eel.
Do you honestly, seriously, honey,
Do you honestly think
that we got left behind
because we were late?
I'm serious.
Do you have any idea
how idiotic that sounds?
Oh, so now I'm an idiot.
We are where we are, aren't we?
Yes, fine, because of me.
You refused to swim.
My God. There were boats all around us.
You refused, and now, look, look around us.
We are stuck in the middle of the ocean.
With nobody.
Even if we had been swimming
for the last five hours,
We would not be any closer
to a boat than we are now.
The only reason we are even
out here in the first place,
is because of your fucking job.
- What?
- If it were not for your job,
We would not have thrown out
our plan out of the window,
Rush around the last minute, and
Settled on this fucking trip.
We would be at home,
in the middle of our hectic lives,
which right now sounds like heaven to me.
And in a month's time,
as we planned seven, seven months ago,
we would be where we were
supposed to be in the first place,
and paying less than
we are now to be shark bait.
Oh, damn it.
I can't even believe you
bring all that up right now.
You were the one that picked the dates.
Yeah, out of my whopping two choices,
this was the better date.
I wanted to go skiing.
Oh, God.
I can't believe how far we've drifted.
You think the current
will take us over there?
Hopefully.
How's your leg?
It's ok.
You know, hurts a little bit, but it...
it's ok.
All right, let's go for it.
- I love you.
We are gonna be fine.
Other people going to vacations,
they spend their days
just laying around,
eating and drinking.
That sounds pretty good right now.
Actually that could.
This'll be the story we'll be telling
for the rest of our lives.
- Daniel.
- What?
Look. Wait.
Oh, my God.
Wait. They are five of them.
Look. Hold on.
Where those comes from?
You know how dry my mouth gets
when I'm diving,
I wanted put them in the dive's bag
but you had it,
so I stuffed them in here
at the last minute.
Oh. Never thought anything
could taste so good.
Just hold me for a second, ok?
I gotta make sure
we don't lose these ones.
I got you.
Ok.
- You're done?
- Yeah.
What is it?
You are all right?
Oh, my God.
- I don't see it.
- Are you ok?
I don't know.
I'm bit.
Oh, my God, honey.
The fucker bit me.
Ok, Hold on.
I'm gonna look.
Oh, God. It fucking hurts.
Daniel, breathe, ok?
Stay right here.
I'm gonna look. Ok?
I'm gonna go look.
You keep breathing.
Daniel, listen to me.
- I'm going to go look. You breathe.
- I'm breathing.
Ok. Stay where you are.
I can't see.
My leg is still there, right?
I can feel it.
Ok.
It's all right, honey.
You gotta put something on it.
Ok. It's bleeding.
It's bad, isn't it? It's bad.
No. It's not that bad.
Ok, I'm going to tie something around it.
Just keep breathing for me, ok?
I'm breathing.
God, it fucking hurts.
I'll put my weight belt
tethering around it. You wait.
This can't be happening.
How could this be happening.
I got bitten by a shark.
We could actually be
eaten alive by shark out here.
We don't know anybody
who's ever been bitten by a shark.
There are always three or four guys
there on the shark show.
Hey, it's all right. It's not that bad.
It's going to be fine, ok?
You are going to have
a nice scar to show your friends
and that's it.
Ok? Look at me.
Look at me, baby.
That's right. You are fine.
You are not that bad.
Just hurts right now.
The salt water will make it get better
It's ok. Just hold on.
Just breathe.
It's ok that it hurts.
Oh, God. Something
is trying to get to my foot.
It's a big one.
I love you.
Stay still. Stay where you are.
It's gonna be ok. You hold on.
You hold on, Daniel.
You don't leave me out here, by myself.
You promise me you'll hold on.
- My leg!
- Daniel!
Hello? Hello?
It's the manager. Hello?
- So what's the final weight on it?
- 2.13
Give me a knife.
How's that?
Good?
That's what it ate.
Check it out.
Man, they really do eat anything.
I wonder if it works.