Previously on "The Whispers"...
Sean was not a perfect husband.
I was not a perfect wife.
Do you love him?
No.
But you had to think about it.
We found Sean's plane
thousands of miles away
from where it was supposed
to have disappeared.
- Peter: What is that thing?
- Wes: Fulgurite.
Drill says he can help
you get what you want
if you help him get what he wants.
Don't you want to know where your dad is?
He's experiencing some kind of memory loss.
Each of your tattoos,
they represent a place?
I don't know until I get there.
- What happens when you do?
- Nothing good.
Sean is trying to cause a meltdown?
Flood the reactor.
Oh, my God, Henry. Henry? Henry?!
Henry: Daddy!
[Rumbling]
[Grunts]
Can someone tell me
what the hell I just saw?
Three people just walked
out of that facility.
They're clean. Whole area is.
Can you hear me?
It was supposed to be a secret
between me and... Drill.
Henry.
[Clicking]
You okay?
It's okay.
I'm right here, baby.
I'm scared, mommy.
It's okay.
It's okay. I got you. Hold on.
It's okay. I got you. Just look at me.
Everything's gonna be okay. I love you.
It's okay, baby.
- No, no, no.
- Mommy!
No, no, no, where are
you taking him?! Henry!
- Mommy! Mommy!
- Henry!
Henry!
Frommer: Someone explain this to me.
Why would anyone want to
undo a nuclear meltdown?
Not undo, sir... contain.
Imagine this possibility.
Somehow, through technology
we're not yet familiar with,
you're able to contain...
trap, if you will...
the energy of that meltdown.
We're talking the equivalent
of four Hiroshimas.
To be used without the
launch of a nuclear device.
The ultimate chemical attack.
Frommer: We need to know who's behind this,
and we need to know now.
There's only one man
who can answer all of our questions.
Sean Bennigan was there
on someone's direct orders.
Question him, break him,
and we'll get our answers.
[Machinery whirring]
[Buzzing]
Claire: Where's my son?
Kest: They should be bringing him in now.
Mrs. Bennigan, we ran a
thorough series of tests
on you and your son.
There is absolutely no evidence
of any radiation exposure.
You should both be dead
right now. Instead...
Instead, my son is hearing again,
which we were told was not possible.
So how is all this happening?
I don't know.
But we're looking at a miracle.
Sorry, Doctor.
I don't believe in miracles.
Henry: Mommy?
Hi.
Mommy, are we dying?
No.
We are okay.
Henry, what you did,
- going into that place, that...
- Drill told me to trust him.
He said it would be
okay, and... He was right.
Drill...
You can't see him, can you?
No, he's just in my head.
And he helped you get into the reactor?
He said it was a game.
He said I would get a prize if I won,
and I did.
I found daddy.
Do you know how he made
the explosion go away?
I don't know.
I guess the same way he
gave me back my hearing.
How is that?
Magic.
Are you a captain in the
United States Air Force?
I don't know.
[Beeping]
On the night of May 1st,
did your plane crash in the Sahara desert?
I don't know.
Frommer: So far, your hope in Bennigan
having all the answers is coming up short.
That's because he's not
asking the right questions.
- How did you gain entry into the nuclear power plant?
- [Door opens, closes]
I don't know.
Everything just opened.
Wes: I'll take it from here.
Thank you.
Hello, Sean.
Do I know you?
This whole amnesia thing, it's very smart.
You think I'm faking it?
Why would I fake something like this?
Because maybe there are some things
you don't want to come home to.
Why don't you tell me
how we know each other?
Henry and Minx.
Did you choose them just to punish us?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I saved that boy.
If it wasn't for me, he'd
have been washed away.
If it wasn't for you, that meltdown
would never have happened, Sean.
- Are you saying I caused a meltdown?
- When you sealed off the pipe,
you blocked the water
from cooling the reactor.
- No, that's not...
- Sean, who's Drill? Is it a person?
A government organization?
Are they state-sponsored?
- I don't...
- Who are they, Sean?
I don't know.
How many times do I have
to say it? I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know!
Okay.
Look at me.
I have nothing.
No memories...
No past...
Barely a present.
And the future?
The mere notion of a future
scares the hell out of me.
My shadow knows more than I do.
Okay.
Okay, Sean.
Why don't you tell me what you do remember?
The first thing I remember is the pain.
I had just woken up...
somewhere in the desert.
I had this huge piece of...
Rock lodged into my back.
Now, I don't how long it had been there
or how long I had been there, but I knew...
I knew that if I didn't get this thing
out of me, that I was gonna die.
So I had a choice to make.
Give up, die with no name,
or take it upon myself to live...
Live to find my answers.
And now here I am,
sitting across the table from you.
It's pretty clear you and I
weren't friends before, were we?
No.
I think that's fair to say.
There is one thing I can tell you.
Whoever's doing this,
whatever this is,
I feel it.
What?
This isn't over.
[Beeping]
[Electricity crackles]
[Whispering]
Don't worry, Drill.
It'll be done soon.
[Whispering]
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[Birds chirping]
[Door opens]
Oh, thank God.
You got the wrong guy.
Yeah, I know.
That's why you and Minx are leaving.
What are you talking about?
- You're going to your parents.
- Wait.
- What about you?
- I can't.
Whatever's happening, I have
to stay here and stop it.
Wes, we're not leaving without you.
Minx was not chosen at random.
She was chosen because
of my job, because of me.
So we'll protect her.
We can't even keep her in our own house.
She does exactly what
this "Drill" thing wants.
Henry, Minx, they all do.
So until this is over, you
will go to your mother's.
You can't just send us away.
Lena.
No, this is my home. You are my home.
If anything happened to you...
Wes, I'm not as helpless as you think I am.
That's not what I'm saying.
Yes, it is. And I get it.
I haven't always been...
But that's over.
We're not leaving.
[Birds chirping]
[Claire sighs]
Hey. You are supposed to tell me when...
when you go out.
What are those men doing here?
I'm sorry.
I'm still getting used to
hearing your voice again.
Those men are here to help keep us safe.
We'll have alarms and
cameras. No one can hurt us.
You want to watch me,
make sure I don't play with Drill.
No, that is not why, Henry.
Drill's the one who brought daddy home.
Aren't you happy?
Of course I'm happy.
I want to see him.
I...
Daddy can't come home right now
'cause he's a little confused.
People are trying to help him.
Can't we help him?
He needs experts first.
But then he's back for good, right?
Everything goes back to normal?
[Car door opens, closes]
That's my partner.
I have to talk to him
for just a little, okay?
But I promise you,
we will talk about this more later.
Okay.
Psst.
Go long!
Keep going! [Chuckles]
How you doing, Claire?
[Breathes deeply] Do
you really want to know,
or are you just being polite?
I really want to know.
They say we're fine. No radiation.
I'm really glad to hear that.
It's a brave thing you did.
What's happening at the office?
- You know I can't talk...
- Oh, come on. You're kidding me?
Come on, Bennigan.
You know you can't stay on this case.
[Sighs]
They sent me here to collect your files.
And you get a new partner.
Hey, I didn't ask for this.
I heard what you did.
Buying me time in the
reactor to get to Henry.
Not according to my report.
Thank you.
I'll get you those files.
Just keep me in the loop.
He's my husband, Jessup.
Have you seen him yet?
D.O.D. hasn't cleared me.
Well, you have a pretty good
friend there, don't you?
I'm sure it can be arranged.
Okay.
What?
What is it?
[Sighs]
Just thinking about how my wish came true.
Yeah, what did you wish for?
For Drill to make you and
daddy love each other again.
Just let me know if you need anything.
There you are.
I told Mrs. Bennigan
you'd be here any minute.
Thanks, Renee.
No, leave it open.
I need to see him.
He's still being debriefed.
There are a lot of unanswered questions.
Yes, I know, Wes, but...
But what?
Drill.
I don't think we're dealing with a "who."
I think we're dealing with a "what."
It's the only way it makes sense.
Henry says that he... he can't see Drill,
he just hears him in his
head. How else can you explain
an invisible friend that makes our kids
do things that...
They would never do on their own?
So, then, what is it?
I'm not sure yet,
but that's why I have to talk to Sean.
Claire, he's not the same person.
He is.
He's just forgotten.
You're not just some FBI agent, are you?
My name is Claire Bennigan.
I'm your wife.
You don't remember anything...
About us?
I brought something...
That...
Maybe can help.
We look happy.
Were we?
We were married.
I know you're in there, Sean...
Somewhere.
Sir, we've been going over the readings
from Bennigan's polygraph.
What does it show us?
That's just it.
We're not sure.
What's happening here?
Looks like a malfunction, right?
But the machine, the recording equipment,
- they all check out.
- It makes no sense.
What is it, sir?
It's exactly the same.
How did we meet?
My father.
He set us up.
He'd drove his car into a ditch
trying to avoid... hitting a deer,
and it was dark out.
His phone wasn't getting
any service, and...
Just when he thought he
would have to spend the night
sleeping in his car...
There you were.
On leave from training, in your uniform.
He said you looked like some...
Damn superhero.
Mm.
He had you over to the house
for dinner later that week.
I knew...
I knew exactly what he was doing.
And I was determined to hate you.
- But you didn't.
- No, I did.
[Chuckling] I did...
At first.
I never saw myself as a military wife.
But I swept you off your feet.
Yeah.
Yeah, something like that.
I like that story.
I sound like a good guy.
You are, Sean.
I'm sorry. I don't remember.
[Children shouting]
Man: Welcome to the fun sphere.
Let's celebrate Jenny's birthday!
[Shouting continues]
[Up-tempo music plays]
How can such little people
create so much noise?
[Chuckles]
Oh, Minx looks like she's having fun.
Yeah.
Yeah, unfortunately,
I don't think we've solved our problem.
Thank you for recommending Dr. Rosen.
Wait. You didn't hear?
Hear what?
He was killed the other night.
Apparently some kind of freak accident.
I don't know all the details,
but something about a kid
jumping out in front of him
just right on the street.
Dr. Rosen's bike slammed into a car.
A little kid?
Came out of nowhere.
Wait, d-d-did you see where she went?
Heather, where's Minx?
I don't know.
She said she needed to talk to a friend.
[Whispering]
It's got to be a coincidence.
You think that's a coincidence?
Well, I just...
- The machine clearly malfunctioned.
- And what if it didn't?
Sorry. I'm not following, sir.
Sean Bennigan's subconscious.
I mean, what if the machine
was picking up something there?
That's not how this works.
I understand that, but...
so far, everything about
this entire operation has not
gone the way it was planned.
We need to start looking
at everything differently.
[Telephone rings]
Renee: Hello?
Honey, I think the problem with the volcano
is what's underneath.
[Chuckles] Well, your friend's right.
It's the heat underneath the volcano
that causes the eruption.
That's what pushes the lava up.
I'll stop on my way home
and get a bigger battery.
It's underneath.
What?
Like lava formations... they're caused
by the volcano erupting
from the heat underneath.
The... the fulgurite. It's caused by heat.
It's not the crash site that's important.
It's what's underneath it.
- [Children shouting]
- Minx?
Minx, stop it! Stop talking to him!
What are you doing? You're embarrassing me.
[Cellphone ringing]
[Beep]
Wes.
I have to go back.
What? Where?
Mali.
To the desert, back where it all started.
You're leaving us?
I have to.
The answers that we need,
they're... they're there.
I know it.
Wes...
Lena, are you... All right?
Did something happen?
No. Nothing's wrong.
Just, um, be safe, okay?
I love you.
I love you, too.
You want to know what happened?
This was the first one.
As I was waiting in a cave,
not sure if I was gonna make it,
I kept seeing this image,
and I knew that it was important,
and I couldn't forget.
After that, more images kept coming.
Some of them... told me things.
Some of them... brought me places.
These visions,
you said that they led you to places.
Seville.
There was a train accident,
some strange power outage, two people dead.
I couldn't save them.
Sean.
I had to... I-I had to keep going, though.
A dam in Bordeaux... more casualties.
And that's when I knew.
These visions,
they were giving me a
roadmap to destruction.
And for some reason, I was
being asked to follow it.
And then...
Harper's tree house.
Nuclear plant.
A blackout.
A dam. A nuclear reactor.
All things...
Related to an energy source.
Energy.
What is that, that one?
"A.S. 33"?
I don't know.
I haven't solved that one yet.
Arsenic... atomic number 33,
the only tattoo on Sean's body
that he hasn't been able to solve.
And all the other ones?
Have led to some kind of disaster.
A.S. 33.
So, we're talking about a mass poisoning?
Worse.
You dose a nuclear weapon
with arsenic, and you get...
A salted bomb.
Larger radioactive
fallout, longer half-life.
The reactor wasn't the end game.
It was just the beginning.
No sign of any arsenic?
No missing inventory from
any medical or research labs.
I'll move on to chemical warehouses.
I'm getting nada from the universities.
You're sure?
Nothing.
Well, there's got to be.
Expand the search beyond U.S. borders.
Sir?
Do it.
Lena: I shouldn't have taken her
to that party today.
With everything that's
going on, it was too much.
You thought she was missing, you panicked.
I would have done the same thing.
Well, that's just it, I
didn't think she was missing.
I thought she was...
You thought she was what?
She and Noah had a playdate last week.
Did he mention anything about her?
No. Why?
What about the other moms?
I know they like to gossip.
Lena, talk to me.
She's changing, Callie.
Minx... she's talking back,
sneaking out of the
house, doing things that...
What if she's turning
into one of those kids?
You know, the ones we whisper about,
the ones you make up excuses
to keep your kid away from.
Do you remember why I asked
for that therapist's number?
The imaginary-friend thing.
Well, it turns out he isn't so imaginary.
What? Have you met this friend?
Not yet. It's complicated.
Look, Lena,
when it comes to protecting your family,
there's no such thing as "complicated."
You do what you have to do.
Sorry, Claire, but without
any concrete results...
Well, I know. It's just...
- I really thought...
- We'll keep digging.
I'll let you know if anything pops up.
[Birds chirping]
Oh, my God.
"A's."
Man: There's the thermal imagery.
As you can see, there's nothing underneath.
We've used gravity
meters and magnetometers.
There's no evidence there's anything more
to the site than what's visible.
But there's no way to be
absolutely sure until we dig.
Digging takes money and equipment.
Given the information that
we have, there's no rush.
We need time to evaluate the surface...
I don't think you understand.
I'm not asking you. I'm telling you.
Tangara: You will get
your request, Mr. Lawrence,
but... Whatever it is you expect to find...
You may study...
But you may not remove.
It belongs to my country, not yours.
Claire: I need to talk to Ethan.
It's important.
I don't know. I... I
need to ask his mother.
So call her.
Now.
But in the meantime, I
need to prevent an attack
that's about to happen on U.S. soil.
So where is he?
[Indistinct shouting in distance]
Claire: Ethan...
Do you know someone named Drill?
[Sighs] Are you one of his friends?
It's okay.
You can talk to her.
Ethan, what are you building?
It's a volcano.
See, it's a mountain on top,
but there's a battery.
So when I push this, it'll explode.
Can I ask you a question about Drill?
How do you know Drill?
He doesn't like grown-ups.
My son, Henry,
he's a friend of Drill's.
Drill told me there were others.
Did he tell you how many?
Ethan...
[Sighs]
Did Drill ask you to build this?
Yes, he said I needed to make it...
And to call my mom if it didn't work.
I needed to call her at a certain time,
and then she solved it.
I just needed a bigger battery.
I don't want anyone questioning my son
without me present.
Mrs. Bennigan, what are you doing here?
Renee.
Renee...
Where's Wes?
- [Clang]
- [Groans]
[Gasps]
[Grunts]
- [Clanging]
- Stop!
We hit something!
[Indistinct shouting]
[Breathing heavily]
They found it.
[Indistinct conversations]
But it's impossible.
Our scans would have picked it up.
Everyone, please, step back.
Please.
Dig it out.
Claire: Come on, Wes. Pick up.
Damn it.
[Clatter]
[Dog barking in distance]
[Crickets chirping]
[Clang]
[Barking continues]
- [Telephone ringing]
- [Gasps]
[Beep] Hello?
Claire: Lena...
It's Claire Bennigan.
I'm sorry to be calling.
I know... I know this is...
But it's about Wes.
Has he called you?
Why? What's going on?
I know that he's in Africa,
and I've been trying to reach him.
There's another child
being manipulated by Drill,
like Henry and Minx.
I think that it has
something to do with Wes.
What?
I think he's a target.
I think that Drill wanted
Wes to go to Africa.
I haven't been able to reach him,
and neither has Renee,
and I just... I-I thought that...
I thought that you should know,
in case he calls.
Uh, I-if he calls I'll... I'll tell him.
Lena...
Thank you for calling.
[Beep]
Wes, it's me.
If you get this, call me,
please, as soon as you can.
It's important.
[Beep]
[Cellphone thuds]
[Beeping]
Jessup: Looks like she's
in bed for the night.
Frommer: Let me know if that
partner of yours goes anywhere.
Of course. I'll keep you posted.
Thank you, Agent Rollins.
Sir, I wanted to ask you something.
With all due respect,
sir... what's this all about?
Does this have to do with
what happened at the reactor?
Do you think that Agent Bennigan
had something to do with it?
If I thought Claire
Bennigan was responsible,
you'd be doing more than following her.
Then why?
Do you watch the news, Agent Rollins?
I prefer to get mine
from the papers, but...
I hear people say they hate
watching the news on television.
It scares them, seeing all
the madness in the world.
It's not the things I
can see that scare me.
It's the things I can't
see, Agent Rollins...
The unknown.
That's what this is about.
[Warbling]
[Electricity crackling]
[Indistinct shouting]
Up.
Take it.
Whatever it is, it's yours.
Just take it.
[Warbling]
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -