R
Re
Re-
Re-S
Re-Sy
Re-Syn
Re-Sync
Re-Sync &
Re-Sync & E
Re-Sync & Ed
Re-Sync & Edi
Re-Sync & Edit
h
ht
Re-Sync & Edit
htt
http
Re-Sync & Edit
http:
http:/
Re-Sync & Edit
http://
http://w
Re-Sync & Edit
http://ww
http://www
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.
http://www.f
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.fa
http://www.fac
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.face
http://www.faceb
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebo
http://www.faceboo
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook
http://www.facebook.
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.c
http://www.facebook.co
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com
http://www.facebook.com/
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/t
http://www.facebook.com/th
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tha
http://www.facebook.com/thar
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/thari
http://www.facebook.com/tharin
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharind
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.j
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.je
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jee
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeew
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewa
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewan
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewant
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewanth
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
Re-Sync & Edit
(
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(w
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(ww
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-m
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-me
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-med
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-medi
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-media
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-medias
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasi
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasin
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinh
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinha
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhal
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhala
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalas
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasu
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasub
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubt
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubti
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtit
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitl
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.b
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.bl
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blo
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blog
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogs
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogsp
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspo
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot.
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot.c
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot.co
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot.com
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot.com)
If I had known how everything was going to happen
I would have done everything differently.
I would have stayed invisible.
A nobody.
But I'm no longer a nobody.
I'm one of the most wanted hackers in the word.
Who am I?
I am Benjamin.
And this is my story.
He's learned his lesson.
He claims he's done with hacking.
He said he can lead us to
Fr13nds and Russian cyber mafia
He wants to talk only to you.
And you are...who am I?
There's a reason why you're here.
A reason I'm here for.
So?
Everything is somehow connected.
Everything that has a beginning has an end.
It's a mix of everything
And I'm in the middle.
I always wanted to be a superhero
with a superpower
I wanted to do things that nobody thought possible.
In reality I already had a superpower
I was invisible.
And I also had a superhero costume.
Paradise Pizza : the end of the rainbow
Every superhero needs a tragic family story:
Spiderman's parents
Dead.
Batman's parents
Killed.
Superman's parents
Exploded.
I actually had the best requirements
My dad ran away to France when I was born.
I've never met him.
A similarity that I share with my grandma.
Her father died in the Second World War
The only memory she has from him
are three bullet casings his comrade
brought from foreign countries
My mom took her own life when I was 8
The best material for a hero story.
My grandma took care of me
and later I took care of her.
I'm not a psychologist.
I don't care about your dreams.
What do you know about CLAY?
About your alliance with the Fr13nds?
Everything you want to know.
But every detail is important.
Hacking is like magic
They're both about deceiving the others.
Since I was 14 I spent my time in front of the PC.
I learned programming languages
Hacked my first system.
A universe of infinite possibilities.
For the first time I felt like I was good at something.
In real life I was a zero among ones.
An outsider.
A loser.
A freak.
But on the Internet I felt a sense of belonging.
A refuge for people like me.
Everyone who wasted their time on the World-Wide-Web
met here in the so-called "darknet"
The Internet within the Internet
Here I could be whoever I wanted.
I spent days and nights on the PC.
Then I slept in the real world.
But there was an antidote
I got the idea from my biggest idol.
There are a lot of great hackers out there.
There was only one true hero for me
He called himself "MRX"
He is from nowhere
No one knew who he was.
He could hack into any system.
He was a real star
One of his most famous hacks
was a social network attack
He didn't take anything or anyone seriously.
He was the superhero among all hackers.
I wanted to be like him.
He had an exploit used to manipulate an online pharmacy
to get Ritalin
The hacker's watchman
MRX had 3 rules:
3rd: Have fun in cyberspace and meatspace
In other words, don't limit your fun, don't
enjoy things only in the virtual world
But the real reason I sit here now
why everything happened this way
is Marie.
Hey! Just resting hasn't helped anyone so far.
Hope is the rainbow over the waterfall of our life.
Do you still want to pass the exam?
Try with learning!
Or do you hope someone will steal
the exam questions for you?
I called Superman but he had no time.
Retard!
What kind of weirdo bird are you?
Paradise Pizza
The end of the rain-...
-bow.
During the school time I was
desperately in love with Marie.
But after ten years no one still
remembers the freak from the last row.
That'll be 34.28
I said without anchovy
I'm not paying for this!
Don't be an ass, Oscar!
The rest is for you.
What? Are you crazy?
Mr. Anchovy gives you a hundred
more if you get the exam questions.
Bachelor of Laws
The world doesn't need a savior
but everyday I hear people crying for one.
What?
That's Superman
It's okay.
Thanks.
You're such a jerk!
I finally wanted to be a superhero.
Marie had a problem
and I could solve it.
I just had to get her the exam questions.
She'll remember me.
We'll fall in love
get married
have kids
be happy together
Bingo.
The bachelor exam questions were stored on
the central server of the university
All I needed was access.
It was way too easy.
Most of the hackers only pass through
They appear in the system without changing a thing
Others leave a hint
and many take a souvenir.
I was Superman, Spiderman, Batman
What are you doing there?
I was an idiot.
No entries, no previous conviction
50 hours of community service
Do something with your life!
It's up to you!
My 50 hours of community service meant
cleaning a city I didn't care about
It couldn't be any worse.
Not even the ritalin worked anymore.
But everything had to change in one fell swoop.
And? why are you here?
Can't you speak or what?
Then no.
Let me guess...
you're one of those guys who
thinks life's unfair for them
who feels like only passing by
invisible
just as the rest of society
In school you weren't even beaten up
because nobody gave a damn about you
That's all really really sad.
Do you know what I think?
it's all just a scam.
Computer stuff.
And you?
This and that
What kind of things? huh?
DDoS attacks?
Botnets?
Phishing?
Or are you just a script kiddie?
I hacked the University's server.
How did you manage to gain access?
Using a 0Day Exploit.
You know how to read machine language?
Simply as that?
Mhm
I am Max.
Benjamin.
Any plans for today?
I keep wondering if there's a moment
that pulls all strings together
That moment which changes everything
The later the evening gets, the
more drunk the guests become
How do you like my modest temple?
I don't even know half of these people.
All shit suckers!
Max was the total opposite of me
Self-confident, charismatic
A winner
Close the door!
Let me introduce you
This is Benjamin.
Stefan
Benjamin
Benjamin Engel.
Stefan was the software master
He could find a bug in any application
He's always been completely insane.
He loved the thrill
craziness
and so on
No last name.
Paul was the hardware freak
Give him a paper clip and a motherboard
and he'll build anything you want.
Like me, he lost his mother early.
His rich father left him at an orphanage
so he could focus on the important things.
Don't worry! His smile muscles were removed at birth.
Max said that you can read machine language
Machine language?
Anyone can say that!
It's not something that's easy to prove!
Prove it!
Or you won't leave alive.
Angel
Paul
Benjamin
Just Benjamin
The fun begins now!
Don't worry!
We're not the swindlers
What? Did you think that I live here?
Come on!
Come on! Go!
Make way!
You're the pizza bird!
Do you know each other?
It's his party!
What the fuck?
No last name.
I always stopped at warnings
never asked myself again after that
I can't anymore
I can't go any further
See ya after!
Now I remember you!
Benjamin! Benjamin Engel!
Our teacher forgot about you
and then you had to take the train back home!
It was interesting...
..the evening
Bye!
Bye.
We all knew that this day will come.
Your grandma needs professional help.
You must let go!
She's on really good hands.
My grandma was diagnosticated
with Alzheimer 4 years ago.
Since then it's like an invisible
eraser deletes her borders.
Tickets, please!
I thought the cops have caught you!
It wasn't a good idea in the very
first week to close the exit.
What's wrong?
You'll feel better.
Come on! I show you something!
Come on!
I should have stayed there sitting
But it was like between us was an invisible rope.
He told me how he started with hacking
I was all ears.
There are people out there, they think they're safe
They have no idea what's going on.
Security. Everyone wants security.
Security doesn't exist!
Once you understand this, you know
it's like you have the world served on a plate.
You only have to get it!
Even though we were so different,
we had something in common.
First: Don't enjoy your actions
only in the virtual world
Second: aim for the impossible
3rd: No system is safe
MRX!
Never hide behind your computer.
MRX already knows this.
The main vulnerability isn't in applications or servers
Man is the main security flaw.
You hack people?
Exactly.
The most effective of all hacking
methods, the great art of deceiving:
Social engineering
Man is by default trusting and confiding
Social engineering uses these two components
so that you can get anything you want:
Passwords, secret information, login data
Hungry?
Hold this!
How many chocodonuts do I get for this?
It's a new sales pitch? huh?
Pay for 10, get 8!
For those with chocolate it wasn't available.
What would I stand here for?
Who required this?
That blonde from there!
Come on! I'm hungry and got things to do!
There you go!
Have a good evening!
All good!
You must be bold enough!
Then the world is at your feet
Oh! Already late!
Are you ready?
Come on let's go.
But...
Where are we going?
Come on!
Go!
Why did you bring him?
You don't know if we can trust him!
You already saw what he can.
You can drive.
Don't make a big deal out of this! We'll bring it back!
Looking like this, you'll never get in!
Why does he come?
I thought I come with you!
What are you up to?
Not "you", "we" !
Come on! Get dressed!
Chop-chop!
This wasn't part of the plan!
Let's go!
Good luck!
Don't you come with us?
I'd rather not!
Let's go, my young boy!
The identification card was a
small simple piece of paper
Five minutes of Photoshop
Two minutes for printing
Any idiot could do that.
Identity card?
Without despatch!
Fellow of the Danish Federation.
Without
Without despatch.
One of the guest speakers!
Danish people's front!
What has this to do with hacking?
The presentation's laptop
must be connected to another wifi network
This is your job!
Don't forget! Aim for the impossible!
Shit! Shit!
Which?
What other network?
I don't trust the small one!
You don't trust anyone not even yourself!
Listen! They're sick of this!
The Federal Intelligence Service has people everywhere!
They're between us! OK?
They have this kid that never said a lie.
I'm invisible!
You assholes!
Time for a bit of blasphemy!
Dear fellows,
we're presenting you now our new wallspot!
A small flame that will burn in german's hearts!
Quiet!
Cut! Cut!
The lamers are coming!
Stefan! the keys!
I don't have them!
That was our first action together
The birth of something real big.
And I was a part of it.
How do I know that what you're telling me, is for real?
17-04-73 6212
What did you say?
Your insurance number.
Born in Friedrich
studies in Germany
Graduated as the best of the year
Investigator at the European Cybercrime Center in Hague
Two bank accounts: one at Densk Bank
other at Holland Direct Bank
During the study period, you had a problem
Since then you couldn't have kids anymore.
Because of an uterus disease
Your colleagues consider you cold
I consider you lonely.
We needed a place for hacking
My grandma's house was the perfect place.
This reminds me of the old times.
Having a computer crib or something.
1 million views!
We need a name!
We must become a brand! We must become famous!
All what attention generates is counterproductive.
We're staying off the radar.
Fuck the radar!
Brand is awesome!
Like Anonymous or Lizardsec!
Like MRX!
Are you all completely nuts?
Max had an idea
If Max had an idea, nothing could stop him
I no longer do this shit with you!
Take the surprise from chocolate!
Take it!
Sure! No problem!
I follow the polls!
Who is "for" ?
We still need a name.
How about "CLAY" ?
as in "Clowns laughing at you"
because it's all about fun and because of the mask
Nominated with 4 votes.
For CLAY
CLAY's next move was a small
greeting to the financial world
We had taken a liking to this.
Our next target was a big pharma company.
Max was right
The bolder you were, the more you could achieve.
We hacked everything we got our hands on.
The ritalin kept us awake
We didn't take anything and anyone seriously.
Who hides behind this mask?
Is it a criminal organization
or just a group of rebel teenagers?
Hi!
What are you doing?
Me? Nope.
You?
I'm looking for the man of the rainbow.
Marie? Are you coming?
We must stop meeting in secret!
and also leave our covers!
You're such a fiasco!
You...for you it's easy!
You're...you're different! people are listening to you!
You're cool!
Maybe you're right!
When life gives you lemons, ask for salt and tequila.
Max was marching on
but his mood could change in seconds.
For weeks he tried to get from
MRX a reaction about CLAY.
He wanted appreciation from his biggest idol
We are fucking losers!
But MRX didn't give a fuck about us
Abroad there was another player.
Around this time she entered the game.
Now I call on Hanne Lindberg, lead
cybercrime investigator of Europol
Yesterday night, was a cyberattack on
the European Central Bank of Frankfurt
We found out that the same hackers are involved
which are also behind the attacks
on the German Army's servers.
they call themselves "Fr13nds".
Fr13nds is part of the Russian cyber mafia
They hacked as in the past years
many international targets.
The group has 4 nicknames to locate
3 of them are:
The last one is still unknown.
The data they got was sold on the so-called "darknet"
and consumed by the Russian cyber mafia.
According to our newest
investigations, at least one
of the Fr13nds members seems
to operate from Berlin.
Our commission joins the Europol investigations.
Nobody knows the Fr13nds and their past
actions better than Hanne Lindberg
Is it true that you're tracking the Fr13nds for 3 years
without success?
Yes!
OK. Any other questions?
Good.
Hanne!
I just wanted to say...
Glad to see you!
I hope you don't have any problems with this
No!
No. I'm glad to work with you!
Good.
One more thing...
The fact that we were together, no one must know it.
People are talking. Must lose the information!
While she was hunting the Fr13nds,
Max tried to get rid of the frustration caused by MRX.
Wanna take a ride?
Max and Stefan borrowed one of Paul's toys
and tampered the transmission line
of a radio's prize competition
They interrupted all the lines but one
so that Max could be put through.
Hello!
My name is Benjamin Engel.
The correct answer is B: Ottmar Hitzfeld.
Are you crazy?
What has this to do with CLAY?
What kind of fucking message
is behind stealing a Porsche?
It's not like that!
It's not like a shitty Renault!
Superheros need a superhero car!
Exactly!
Moreover it's not stolen, it's won!
Forget it!
Here!
Excuse me, girls!
We were a bit late!
These guys are like Windows: it
takes a while till they boot up.
Cheers!
You can be whoever you want!
Check this out!
Be open minded!
You achieved everything when you
completed your ultimate challenge
So can Benjamin, for example, he has a
huge potential, but he doesn't use it!
He hides behind the others. He doesn't open his mouth!
If someone must always pull you
then you'll never go far!
Most of the people can only follow rules!
It wasn't enough!
Max was right. I had to finally change something
I passed the exam!
What are you up to now?
Do you know how I made it?
Nope.
I've intentionally answered wrong the questions.
Why?
There are so many possibilities outside.
I had the feeling that is not carved
in stone that I pass the exam.
Like all the doors shut forever.
But now I've decided on a door.
Why are you driving a Porsche?
I'm the employee of the month.
Or maybe I'm also a superhero
and this is my superhero car
Yeah...maybe
Come on! believe in yourself!
Be like Max
Aim for the impossible!
I'd better go out
It fits to Porsche
Oh look who's here!
The pizza bird!
Get your hands off Marie!
Nothing has changed.
Everything's alright?
Don't ask.
MRX sent a message!
MRX hasn't missed a single word about CLAY
until this moment.
In front of us we had the
confidential cybercrime
investigation document
they sent to Europol
It was a marked paragraph about CLAY
The packet's purpose was only one:
He wanted make this clear to us
CLAY in his eyes wasn't more
than whining babies.
We'll finish the fucker!
Let's do an attack that tops all!
We could hack a big bank!
Yes! the money of a famous company!
Bullshit!
We need an attack on something real huge!
Something able to reach the Olympus!
The Federal Intelligence Service.
What?
BND!
The king class.
The German Secret Service.
Bullshit! It's unhackable!
No system is safe.
And aim for the impossible!
The BND action must be the most complex we ever did.
Here you go, you pussy!
With the right bait
you can catch any fish.
Without knowing, Gerdi granted us access.
But from her system we still
couldn't access the main server.
Gerdi was the jackpot, though.
Gerdi was responsible for the card cloning
and for distribution of the entry-cards to BND.
Accepted by password or address?
It was the all time biggest breaking cliché.
Idiots!
Many tried to hack the BND before.
But you can't do this only by hiding behind your desk.
Ready?
Where's Benjamin?
No idea
Where have you been?
We really made it.
That was the Olympus
We haven't just climbed it, we
also have put a flag on its peak.
As for BND, the employees will get the
next day the shock of their lives.
That was my night
Leave me alone!
Let us in!
Don't act like a kid!
And you like an asshole!
You're nothing without us!
A nobody!
It's enough
Nobody.
Nobody
Without the others knowing it
I stole secret data from BND server.
First he has manipulated the printers over
the communication protocol
then he bypassed the security firewall
and stole data.
Our unhackable system
has been hacked in 2 minutes 23
You're saying this like you were excited about it.
Whoever did this is a genius.
We should have had recordings
They deleted all the video files and left something.
But everything has a consequence
Every single fly flap.
That was found about his body.
He was found in the woods.
Moritz Lauer, better known as Krypton.
Morning!
Get out!
Get lost!
What the fuck? you need us!
What?
I need you?
Or maybe you need me!
Do you know what?
You're nothing! you're nothing
more than a shitty impostor!
All you can do is using people and manipulate them!
Stop! Stop!
Be quiet!
Quiet!
This morning was found the dead body of the hacker
which has the pseudonym "Krypton"
His dead and the German Secret
Service hack of the last night
confront the BND with something that might be
the biggest scandal of its history.
Near to the dead body, was
found the stolen data from BND
A secret employees list
proving that Krypton worked for the BND.
It seems that Krypton belongs
to the hackers group Fr13nds
Financed by the BND to collect
information about hackers
At this time, the hackers group CLAY
seems responsible for the BND breaking.
You were the only one in the server room!
What have you done there?
We said that we don't touch anything,
take anything and turn on only the printers!
Did you leave any data?
I've found a hidden partition on the BND server
I have...I've cracked the password
and then downloaded some kind of employees list
I don't know...
I sent it to MRX.
Are you crazy?
I wanted to prove him!
I wanted to prove you!
You thought I'm a nobody!
Sometimes we hold so tight a
photograph we got from someone.
It was like I couldn't recognize myself anymore.
Everyone sees what they want
Suddenly, it was crystal clear
MRX has sold the stolen data to the Russian cyber mafia
MRX belongs to the Fr13nds
When he found out that Krypton worked
for the BND, he eliminated him!
Now everyone thinks that we did it!
It's only his fault!
Austrian product.
Krypton has been admitted to the
government agency and was eliminated.
What has this to do with CLAY?
I don't know.
We could fail.
I received a call from Hague.
They wanted me to make an evaluation
of you.
Your work
I didn't know that your chair isn't stable
Why didn't you tell me?
Where are you going?
To find some fun. This isn't fun anymore!
Krypton is dead, Max, dead!
And we'll get fucking blamed for all this scandal!
Benjamin could hand himself over to the police
and tell them how he built alone his shit CLAY!
Do you want sacrifice one of us?
You always wanted to run away!
I don't fuckin' care what you're doing, I'm out!
Stefan! Wait!
This is all my fault!
I must find MRX!
And then what?
It's not about us! it's about MRX
the Fr13nds
they are the target!
Benjamin is right. Running away doesn't solve this
There are so many tracks left there
It's just a matter of time till they catch us!
We deliver them MRX and the Fr13nds
and we'll become invisible again.
Exactly.
When I said "we" I didn't mean "you" too!
Oh my god! what happened to you?
I'm fine.
What do you want?
...last night you suddenly disappeared and...
and I thought that...
You came here for Max.
Max? No!
It's better that you go now.
Are you building there a bomb or what?
Anything else?
What's wrong with you?
You're completely weird
Exactly
That's all you can see, right?
the freak weirdo
Do you know what?
I wish I had never met you!
We had to find MRX
I was the decoy
We were lately so paranoic that
we could use only public networks
Oh! here are you!
Come on fast!
He tried to contact MRX
His IP address is spoofed
he uses 100 different servers in Europe
He's changing his location at every 3 seconds!
I think I got something!
The server he uses more often points to this IP address
In Berlin!
Get as much information as you can, Katja
He gave me access to his private channel.
What are you waiting for?
We're running out of time!
I almost have it.
They're here!
Did you get it?
Let's get outta here!
Now.
We'll meet downstairs!
Nothing! as if the earth had swallowed him up!
I am suspended.
They're looking for someone else from Hague!
I'm sorry
What did MRX ask for?
He wanted us to send a Trojan to the Europol system
If someone has access to Europol,
can track investigations
and tamper
What was your plan?
We wanted to know who is MRX
His identity in exchange for our freedom
We wanted to prove that he's behind Krypton's death
We wanted to disappear from the
1st position of the wanted list
We only wanted to be...invisible again
To get access to MRX's computer
we had to reach deeply into our bag of tricks
Stefan called the application
"the pregnant horse"
It was a Trojan horse inside of a Trojan horse.
The second when MRX would log on to
the Europol server using our backdoor
we could be able to access his computer.
And MRX's mask would fall.
But before we had to destroy all the evidence
I want to apologise...
for the blue-eyed
like Marie.
You knew all the time what she means to me
and you didn't give a fuck
What can I say? I'm an asshole.
The statement is true.
I'm an impostor! I could never do what you can
I'm just a fucking script kiddie
I can't do more than copy/paste!
I don't even know how to program!
I didn't know that
Do you like this?
Love birdies!
We were on the way to Hague
to Europol
We had to get in the lion's den
but the road was long.
We tried several methods
No success.
Our old phishing methods
We even tried to get in across the canalization.
It's the only entrance.
What are you doing there?
A fucking nail!
Take it out!
We had to admit that it was
impossible to enter the Europol.
What are you looking at?
It was my fault.
I've dragged us in this
I also had to get us out.
Man is by default trustful and confiding
Social engineering.
Come on! Believe in yourself!
With Paul's box I could access a network
and then a second one, in
parallel, a so called "evil twin"
If someone had logged in from one
of the offices in that network
I could access their laptop
and then the server
MRX gave us an access key to a darknet channel
where we could find the instructions.
I only had to give MRX the manipulated Trojan
As soon as he would log in in the Europol server
his mask would fall
But MRX foiled our trick
MRX won the game
and I lost everything
Max, Paul, Stefan
they're all dead.
I want to be Benjamin again
I want to be invisible again
This is Anne! Call me as soon as you wake up!
You must come here immediately!
Finally no one else
You came...
Yeah, I came.
Oscar said that someone hacked the
University's server some months ago
and stole the questions for the Bachelor exam
and got caught
You once said that
you must find out who you are
..and that there are a lot of opportunities outside
but you can be whoever you want
you can be anything
Do you understand?
I can be the federation!
You're a weirdo!
Do you come with me?
I already said that you're crazy!
Where?
Wherever you want.
Copenhagen?
You can go anywhere and want to go to Copenhagen?
Why not?
Yeah...
Why not.
What else do you know about me?
Do you know that I'm suspended?
You want to be invisible again!
But the Fr13nds know who you are!
You want a new identity
you want in the witness protection program!
that's all you always wanted!
For this I give you MRX, the Fr13nds
It's not that easy!
The Federal Criminal Police Office will be successful
politics and media, pleased
You are rehabilitated.
Let's say I agree.
How will you get MRX?
Using a magic trick
There are holes in his story as big as the Death Star!
He's nothing
A no one!
He played with fire and got burned
but he can lead us to MRX!
If we have him we will also get the Fr13nds!
You're suspended!
The promise of the witness protection program must end.
I need you for this!
How should work this magic trick?
We will attack MRX's weakest point
his pride!
We got him!
What's his real name?
19 years old
from New York
You should be the last one too
so that you're not alone
That's from Superman!
In a few hours you're a freeman!
New name, new city
There are holes in his story as big as the Death Star!
I'd like to ask you some questions.
Do you know this person?
No.
He said you were in the same class.
The freak!
Have you seen Benjamin lately?
No.
Excuse me.
What's this all about?
Benjamin is under the BKA's attention.
He declared that in the last months you met often
We did what?
He's completely crazy!
I'd never like to meet such a guy!
Thank you for having time for me!
It's about Engel
Or better said "your angel"
You know him?
Since he was young.
I have curated his mother.
What can you tell me about him?
He's uncommunicative
outsider
No wonders in his story.
His mother took her own life
Benjamin has grown up in unclear circumstances
His mother had an identity problem
Schizophrenia?
Multiple personality disorder
She had multiple personalities
thinking they're all herself
The medication kept her at bay.
In the end she couldn't endure anymore.
Is it inheritable?
Possible.
What is it caused by?
It can be caused by a
predisposition to other substances
Some medicines can make the symptoms even stronger
There are several triggers.
Ritalin?
Ritalin is one of them.
But what it's all about?
Is everything alright with Benjamin?
The laboratory results are here!
Let me guess! The bullets are from the 2nd World War!
Yes.
How did you get this wound?
what did hurt you?
Why were the car keys at you?
It is supposed that Stefan has driven the car!
What did you tell me about Paul? about his mother?
She died when he was young
That's you!
They're all you!
No. They're dead!
There are no dead bodies! No evidence!
In any damn hotel in Hague!
What you saw in the hotel room
doesn't exist!
You made them up in your imagination!
CLAY - that's you alone!
You are Max
What? Did you think that I live here?
You are Stefan!
You are Paul!
Every action, it was you!
Alone!
I don't even know one half of the people!
All shit suckers!
We need a name!
We must become a brand! We must become famous!
All what attention generates is counterproductive
We're staying off the radar!
Nothing off the radar! Brand is awesome!
Like Anonymous or Lizardsec!
Like MRX!
fucking nail!
I'm not like my mom!
I know who I am
That means that our agreement
disqualifies you for the witness protection program
No! You said we have a deal
a caution!
I get the witness protection
program, that's what you said!
I'm sorry!
They killed Krypton
I betrayed MRX. They'll find me!
Do you understand?
We had a deal! I get the witness protection program!
That's what you promised me!
I'm sorry.
You're sick!
I'm not like my mom!
I'm sorry!
The Fr13nds will kill me like they killed Krypton!
I want witness protection program!
You promised me!
Congrats!
The collaboration between the Europol and BKA
(Federal Criminal Police Office)
has been from the start a composite of
efficiency, professionality and certain
Responsible for this is Hanne Lindberg
an exceptional fighter against the cyber mafia
The Internet is not a legal black hole
its doors aren't invisible!
Anyone can be traced.
I asked them to bring you to the court.
I'm sorry for hacking you!
It wasn't fair
The witness protection program is literally a program
You have 5 minutes
What will you tell them?
That you're on the way to the courthouse
Won't you be fired again?
They wanted MRX, the Fr13nds. You're a nobody to them!
You're invisible to them!
Promise me that you're done with hacking
I promise!
No magic tricks anymore
Wait!
Just one more thing
How do you make this trick?
If you know how's working, it's less deceiving
Everyone sees what they wanna see
Take care!
She swallowed it hook, line and sinker.
The all time greatest social engineering trick
Not even the Europol knows now who you are.
What name did you pick?
No name
OK. Who am I?
I'm Benjamin.
I'm a hacker.
and this is my story.
Hacking is like magic
They're both about deceiving the others.
Where have you been?
They have my computer!
They know who am I, we all gotta get outta here!
What happened?
I was at Europol
How did you get in there?
I pretended to be one of the students from a group
it doesn't fuckin' matter!
The task.. was a failure!
They got.. they have all my personal details!
Everything! Do you understand?
We gotta get outta here! Immediately!
Come on! What are you waiting for?
You're one of us!
We don't forsake you!
Now what?
No system is unhackable.
Excluded from the witness protection program
are persons having psychic diseases
Once again
Give her very detailed information
this works only if you trust yourself
And if she doesn't feel mainpulated!
You can do it!
Only this is left
Ready?
We're all invisible!
What if she checked?
Don't worry!
She has checked.
But she has what she wants
No more magic tricks.
Re-Sync & Edit
http://www.facebook.com/tharindu.jeewantha.3
(www.t-mediasinhalasubtitle.blogspot.com)