Don't try and stop me this time.
Who's trying to stop you?
I wish you a safe journey
and a good time travelling.
I'm going to L.A.
and find people who love me.
And those people will find me a job
that will make me a lot of money.
Please, Ellie! Don't go!
Say goodbye to Ellie, Lena.
She's going to L.A.
Oh, wow. Bye, Ellie!
Oh. I'll get the phone.
Have a pleasant trip.
I'm leaving!
Were you really gonna run away?
I always mean to run away.
But when I walk out that
door, I think of Dad.
Can you imagine what he
would do if I left?
No, I can't.
Inger! He would freak out.
He would no longer
have a reason to live.
Jeez, really?
Yes.
I mean, if I left, it would mean
he'd be totally alone with Mom.
-And me!
-Right. And you.
God, I hate school.
Hey, Sasquatch!
-Leave her alone.
-Oh, yeah?
Just ignore them, okay?
What will you do, dinger?
Leon, I'm having a really
shitty day today. So get lost, okay?
It's not until I get this close...
...that I realize what a big,
ugly bitch that you really are.
Back off, all of you,
or I'll pull his hair out.
Do it!
Farther, you fuckers!
Oh, shit!
What's the problem?
You don't give me
the benefit of the fucking doubt.
Karen, please--
Ben, if I say that she's
acting up again...
...l expect you to believe me
and help me deal with it.
You know, Mom, we love you too.
And what about this attempted
murder charge at the bus stop?
Not guilty.
Well, I'm starving.
I'm gonna see what's for dinner.
Wait up.
What you doing?
Cover me. I'm going in.
Hi, Bobby. Ellie's inside the truck.
Oh, hi, Ellie.
Oh, hi, Bobby.
You guys are moving?
Mom and I are leaving because
Dad can't pay his bills.
Your dad's not coming with you?
No.
Want to get out of my truck?
Come on, get out of here.
-Bobby said I could.
-Did not.
-Did too.
-Brat.
Lena, could you come upstairs?
I need you to run some errands.
I'll be right there.
-Hey!
-The keys.
You'll miss me, pookie.
Enjoy the show?
-Lawson, wait.
-Let's do it in his house.
No, no.
I'm getting out of this place,
immediately.
That's fantastic.
That's the best news.
I'm ready to go right now.
Let's get out.
Look...
...it'll just be me and the girls.
What do you mean?
We had plans.
I know it's difficult.
-You can't leave now.
-Control yourself.
You fucking bitch!
Oh, baby.
Oh, baby, I'm sorry.
What was that?
There's nothing there.
God, Jesus. I'm gonna miss this.
Lena, could you stop?
I want to speak to you.
Is something wrong?
I have to let you go.
Look, you've been really great, but
we just won't be needing you here.
Here's two weeks' wages. You'll also
find a very nice recommendation.
Excuse me.
What's going on here?
You're being fired.
Ellie, lnger! I'm home!
Hi, Dad.
There you go.
And what did you get me?
It's a makeup kit.
I don't know what's in there...
...but the lady at the store said
it was a starter set for girls.
Thanks, Dad.
You're welcome, honey.
Lena didn't say what kind of
personal emergency?
No, she didn't.
Not a word?
I'm not as interested in her
personal life as you are.
What's that supposed to mean?
You fired her because you
felt like it!
No, I fired her because I know you
want to fuck her!
-If you haven't already.
-That's really rich, Karen....
It's only a 40 minute drive
to and from work.
It doesn't matter, Ben,
because I've had it.
I'm taking my children
and getting out.
What do you mean, "your" children?
How about "our" children?
You think I'll let you take them?
There's nothing you can do about it.
-We'll see what a lawyer has to say.
-Yes, we will.
Oh, that's just great, Karen, great.
Good night!
Dad, is that you?
I just thought it would be better....
Hey.
You look great.
Thanks.
Couldn't sleep?
No.
You're wearing that ring
I got you last month.
Yeah, I never take it off.
I even sleep in it.
Hadn't you noticed?
Yeah.
You love me, don't you?
-Yeah, sure.
-No, I'm serious.
Don't be silly.
You really mean it?
Ellie, come on.
Look, I'm gonna tell you a story...
...and I'm only telling you this
because you seem a little down.
You promise you won't get
a big head about it?
I was talking to Lawson and he asked
me which one of you I loved more.
And I said I loved both you
and lnger equally, and he said:
" Bullshit. You always feel
differently about each of them."
But I didn't want to tell him
how I felt.
I didn't tell him how
you were my favourite.
Dad.
Really?
-What is that you have on?
-Dad's makeup.
You're not going to school
like that, young lady.
Oh, yes, I am.
You're gonna take it off now.
You're just jealous.
-Ellie, you are just--
-Stop!
Don't you push me!
You're ruining it!
-I'll just put it back on.
-No, you won't.
I'm putting it right back on!
Over my dead body!
Let go of me!
Hi, Karen. I was wondering
if you would be able--
Karen, what's wrong?
It's been one of those mornings.
Ellie, it's time to go to school!
I would really appreciate it,
thank you. Oh, hi, Ellie.
Goodbye, Mrs. Potter.
She's a moody one.
Hi, you've reached the home of the
Christiansons. Just leave a message.
Hello?
What's going on?
I heard someone got snuffed.
Ellie's gonna be home soon.
What's going on?
Ellie?
Could you come up here?
I have something important
to tell you.
Your mother's dead.
I loved her, Ellie.
I can never love anyone
llke I loved her.
I can never marry again.
-Hey!
-Hi, sir.
-What are you doing?
-Shooting overalls, sir.
Boland...
...what are you doing here?
Well, Ritchie...
...a white woman got knocked dead
in her own home...
...inside a gated community.
Don't you think they'd call me?
-I see.
-What do you got?
Burglar broke in the back door...
...not counting on the presence
of Karen Christianson.
Surprise, struggle, and there she is.
Burglar? Anything taken?
Her diamond wedding ring.
Really?
Mr. Christianson?
Yes?
I need to talk to you,
whenever you're ready.
Notice anything missing?
Besides the ring?
No, not yet, anyway.
When I was down in your dining room,
I noticed a Greek drama mask.
They usually come in pairs,
you know: Tragedy, Comedy.
I only saw Comedy.
I don't know where the other one is.
We had two.
Anything unusual or strange going
on between you two?
Arguments, or...
...fistfights?
-No.
-Really?
No.
Nothing important, that is.
Our marriage was great.
-You have no idea who did this?
-No.
No suspicions?
No.
Well, that'll be all for now.
I'll be in touch.
I knew her pretty well.
She'd always help out with
my things for Casa Del Norte.
Did you llke her?
Oh, yes. Very much.
Well, somebody didn't.
What's your name?
Amaryllis Potter.
Amaryllis?
Like the flower?
Yeah. Like the flower.
My wife left me.
Well, it sure looks that way.
What can you tell me about
the Christiansons?
Not much. Not much.
-You weren't friendly with them?
-I wasn't very close with them.
They llve about 1 00 feet from you.
Well, so what?
I'd call that close, wouldn't you?
-Lay off.
-Why are you upset?
Of course I'm upset.
Christ, Karen's dead.
" Karen"?
You mean Mrs. Christianson.
Yes, Mrs. Christianson.
You have an affair
with Mrs. Christianson?
All right, llsten.
You can screw around...
...and stIll not have killed her.
A lot of people screw around.
I used to screw around.
Does the husband know?
No murder weapon. No ring.
So he's not a total moron,
he could've stashed it away.
-It doesn't mean a thing.
-You really think it's him?
Him...
...or somebody else.
--an entrance into the land
of llght and joy...
...in the fellowship of thy sense.
Through Jesus Christ, Our Lord. Amen.
Your mommy loves you.
You're my number one girl.
You're the special one.
I love you, baby.
Wait for me in the car, okay?
Lena.
Oh, hi, Ben.
Oh, baby.
I was worried.
Where have you been?
At a hotel.
Pollce went through the place...
...and we didn't want to
go back right away.
-Sorry I didn't call.
-No, no. I'm sorry, I understand.
I need some time, Lena.
Just wait a couple of weeks
before we see each other.
We'll talk later.
Yeah. I'll call you.
-I'll call you.
-Okay.
Dad!
Let me just say hi to the girls.
Hi, Ellie.
Mr. Christianson, are you okay?
Mr. Christianson?
What's for dinner?
Dad?
Can we move away from here?
Of course, but not right away.
Why not?
Well, we have to sell
the house first.
-It's the middle of a school year--
-Dad, I'm scared.
Oh, honey.
Mrs. Potter installed an alarm system.
We're okay.
Hey, I have an idea.
What if we all slept in here tonight?
Can we, Dad?
Good morning, Lawson.
Hi, Ben. How's everything?
I'm hanging in there.
How about yourself?
No complaints.
Except for this maintenance increase
that Mrs. Potter gave me.
Oh, that. Right.
We discussed that last Tuesday.
You weren't there.
No, no. I'm thinking of moving out.
-I never go to those fucking meetings.
-Right. Those fucking meetings.
They're boring.
Yeah, those fucking meetings.
-Anyway, I just saw the pollce leave.
-That's right.
Right. So they questioned you?
Yes, they did.
-And now you are.
-You seem on edge.
-I'm sleeping fine at night.
-Let's just calm down.
-I'm calm. Are you calm?
-I think we're both calm.
Good.
Why don't we just let the pollce
do their jobs?
If you have a problem,
take it up with them.
What did you just say to--?
Shit.
Where do you think you're going?
You have to vacuum the llving room.
But I just did the upstairs.
And it's not even dirty.
It's fllthy. I wIll not
have Dad see the house this way.
Do it!
Jeez. Who died and made you boss?
Okay.
Shit!
Take a picture, Lawson.
It'll last longer.
Inger, I thought I told you
to vacuum in here.
What are you doing?
Put that mask down!
-I'm just looking at it.
-Give it to me.
Now, who could that be?
You pest!
Give it to me, lnger!
Give me that mask, you llttle brat!
I'll kill you!
Give me that mask!
Girls?
Girls, it's me! I've got some food.
Let go!
Oh, my God!
Girls, what are you doing? Stop it!
Ellie, stop it!
Listen, kids fight.
Oh, I know. I mean,
I have a sister, and we fought.
I mean, belleve me,
we fought llke hell.
But, I mean, we pulled hair,
or pinched or kicked.
I mean, we didn't strangle.
Aren't you making too much of this?
Strangllng. Serial killers strangle,
not sibllngs.
I mean, they're girls.
All alone, unattended here.
Ben, I really know what it's llke
to be a single parent.
When I was a kid, I hit my brother
over the head with a hammer.
If I'd killed him, my llfe
would be very different.
Ben, it's a very big house
and you need somebody here.
We're doing fine.
I'm around the corner.
Call if you need me.
I wIll, I promise.
-Okay. All right.
-Good night.
Ellie?
-My God.
-What happened?
Just sit down.
I'll be out in a minute.
-Ellie? You look--
-Like Mom.
And that's Mom's dress.
Is it? Well, I'm surprised
how good it looks on you.
Would you llke some wine?
Wine? Oh, yeah.
-I want wine.
-You look a llttle underage to me.
Very funny. Ha, ha.
Karen.
-Karen.
-Dad?
Wait! You forgot your lunch.
-Thanks.
-What do you want for dinner tonight?
I don't know.
Mrs. Potter can get us
some steaks or something.
WIll you please go back inside?
Right now.
Ellie, come on! Jesus.
Is your name Ben Christianson?
Yes.
Do you llve in Europe?
No.
Are you employed by Matrix Systems?
Yes.
Did you kill your wife?
No.
Are you a college graduate?
Yes.
Are you employed by Matrix Systems?
Is your name Ben Christianson?
Yes.
Did you bludgeon your wife to death?
No.
I gotta tell you, I was nervous.
Very nervous.
The machine supposedly
takes that into account.
There's something else.
I didn't kill my wife.
I may have wanted her dead,
but I didn't do it.
I didn't kill her.
We're not accusing you.
Wait in the hallway.
I'll be out in a minute.
Relax.
He's telling the truth.
According to Poly here.
-What?
-Yeah, well....
-You're stIll getting over your mom.
-What do you want?
I'm a llttle concerned about
what I see going on around here.
It's not right to leave
you girls all alone.
Thank you,
but it's not your business.
I llve right over there
if you need anything.
What could I possibly want from you?
Ellie, who's there?
Just Loser-- I mean, Lawson.
He was saying good night.
Night.
Why did you say you would marry me?
When did I say that?
You said if it wasn't for Karen,
you'd marry me.
-I know, and I wIll, but not now.
-When?
-When this whole thing blows over.
-And when does it blow over?
If I don't get my green card,
I have to leave.
Can't you see how it would look?
Fine. Fuck you!
Another one, please.
Where were you? I was worried sick.
I was out. Out and about.
You didn't call. I didn't know
if I should call the pollce.
Well, I'm okay, okay?
-I smell llquor. You been drinking?
-Yeah, what of it?
I'll ask you one more time!
Where were you?
I'm tired and I want to go to bed.
-I waited up all night for you.
-Get off my ass!
Having a hard time sleeping?
Are you trying to get away from me?
You were really mean to me tonight.
Well, you were really mean to me too.
-What about this morning?
-You were in that skimpy thing.
I mean, fuck you!
What do you want from me? Do I
have to do everything around here?
Do we have to argue llke this?
I don't know.
I was talking to Mrs. Potter today
about the new alarm system.
-Dad!
-What?
I just don't know what goes on
inside your head sometimes.
It's just been a tough period.
Same here.
I was really worried
about you tonight.
Yeah, maybe I should have called.
It's only because I care about you.
I care about you too.
Remember when I was llttle,
you'd kiss me llke I was a movie star?
Gee, that was a whlle ago.
-I remember it.
-You must have been 4 or 5.
I'd lean back and you'd kiss me
llke Rudolph Valentino.
Kiss me.
I'll make the coffee.
Sure.
Hey! Wait up!
Your lunch?
Well. Thanks.
I missed you last night.
-I should've called.
-You'll be home tonight?
Of course.
-Tell Ellie we'll have a dinner guest.
-Who?
-Let's make it a surprise, okay?
-Okay.
Bye, sweetie.
It's probably somebody very important,
llke a coworker or something.
-What kind of coworker?
-Somebody very important.
You know, Dad might be up
for a promotion.
If he doesn't get it,
it won't be because of this meal.
Inger! Ellie! I'm home!
Here, let me take your coat.
It's not a coworker, it's Lena.
-Lena!
-Hi!
Ellie? Do I smell smoke?
-Isn't this just dellcious?
-It's wonderful.
You cook this yourself, Ellie?
Yes, I did.
You look lovely. You look
more llke your mother every day.
No, everybody says
I look llke my father.
-I look nothing llke my mother.
-She's wearing Mom's dress.
I thought I recognized that dress.
Oh, that's so cute.
When I was llttle,
I used to play dress-up too.
-It's not dress-up. It fits.
-I know, dear.
Wait, hold on. You applled
a llttle too much blush there.
There. That's much better.
-What's going on?
-Can't I have Lena over for dinner?
Yes, but not as a guest.
What are you thinking?
Is this a problem?
If it isn't a problem, why did you
spring her on me llke that?
-I'm so tired. I'll call a cab.
-I'll drive you.
-I have a cab company's number.
-It's okay. I'll call a cab.
-That won't be necessary.
I'll be back in a bit.
-Aren't you coming to bed?
-I'm just waiting for Dad to get home.
Okay. Good night.
Good night.
-Dad?
-Ellie? Are you still up?
Where are you?
I'm over at Lena's.
I had some car trouble...
...so I'm gonna have to stay over
here tonight. Honey?
-Ellie?
-The Audi was fine this morning.
I know. Funny, isn't it?
Yeah. A real fucking riot.
Please, don't use language like that.
Lena?
I just picked up
the other extension...
... to say how happy I was
to see you tonight.
I didn't hear you pick up.
-And the meal was scrumptious.
-So lock up and go to bed.
-Be back tomorrow. Good night.
-But--
I haven't gotten to the good part yet.
-What?
-Sam McGee was from Tennessee.
Oh, tell me that story
when you were in school.
-The one in the kitchen.
-We were in a restaurant.
That dessert was great, honey.
Expecting more car trouble tonight?
-What's that supposed to mean?
-Just cut the crap, okay?
Inger, could you come in here, please?
Lena and I are going
to stay up for a whlle.
It'd be best if you two slept
in your own beds tonight.
-Is that okay with you?
-Sure.
-He didn't ask me if it was okay.
-You're old enough to sleep alone.
Hi, Lena.
Hi.
-Thirsty?
-That's right. I came down for water.
Want mine?
No, thanks.
Why not? You're thirsty.
You want it, so take it.
Thanks.
Drink it.
Oh, if you insist.
It's not as if
I poisoned it or anything.
But you're looking at me, expecting
me to drop dead, aren't you?
Relax, Ellie. I'm just joking.
Let's turn the llght on the situation.
Look, I know how you feel
about your father.
I understand, because I felt
the same way about my father.
I even dreamed about marrying him.
Of course, that's not possible.
Look, Ellie. One day you'll find
someone you'll be attracted to...
...and you'll have sex with him
and maybe even fall in love.
-Oh, really?
-Yes. Just llke your father and l.
-Lena?
-In here, sweetheart!
What are you two doing up?
Just quenching our thirst,
and enjoying a llttle girl talk.
After you're done, get to bed.
You've got school tomorrow.
Good night, Ellie.
-You're looking good today, Sasquatch.
-Thanks.
Ellie was in school
the day her mother died.
-How do you know?
-The attendance records.
-And the rest of the day?
-I could check with each teacher.
Would you? I'd appreciate it.
Here's my number.
Just call me. Thank you.
Now that Lena's been over a few times,
we were both wondering...
...what do you guys think?
About Lena and I seeing each other,
and her coming over?
-You guys are getting married?
-I told you that's what they'd think.
We want you to know
that nobody is marrying anybody.
-That's right.
-But you are getting married?
Ben, speak to her.
We're not rushing into anything.
Sometimes grownups
need other grownups.
Your father loved
your mother very much.
-We're not thinking of marriage now.
-What are we thinking?
We're just spending
some time together.
Do you, Ben Christianson,
take Lena Anderson...
...to be your lawful wedded wife?
To have and to hold,
to love and to cherish...
...in sickness and in health,
for richer, for poorer....
I didn't tell him how
you were my favourite.
You were my favourite....
Favourite....
TIll death do you part.
I do.
-Detective Boland.
-Why don't you call me James?
-You sure sing pretty, Amaryllis.
-Thank you.
-Are you off duty or on duty?
-I'm looking for Ellie. You seen her?
The Blue Hawallans
wish Ben and Lena the best...
...on their wedding day.
Let's go, boys.
Hey! You all right?
-Jesus! You all right?
-Lawson? What the hell?
Usually when I come out here,
it's totally quiet.
Shit. Tonight,
there's nothing but noise.
You should go. There's free beer.
You're wasted.
I had one drink for the toast.
Stand up.
Close your eyes.
Why? Do you want to kiss me?
Just close your eyes.
You sure she's here?
She's here. You know, I did
see her drinking earller.
-Maybe she's in the ladies' room.
-Can you check it out for me?
-Yeah. Sure.
-Thanks.
-I'm hopping!
-Now recite the alphabet backwards.
Z. It starts with "Z." Come on!
Z...
...Y....
-Wait a minute.
-Just one drink? Right.
I think that I have to go
wash up somewhere.
We can go to my place.
Can we run away?
We can leave right now.
-Ellie!
-Ellie?
Let's look in Ellie's room.
I'll check in the back.
Whoa.
We don't have a lot of money, right?
So we just llve off the land.
Use the National Parks.
Sleep under the stars.
I'm good with my hands.
I could be a day labourer.
I'll make just enough to get us
to the next place.
I don't know.
If we go, I don't want to be a gypsy.
We should settle down.
-Where?
-How about up north? Like Portland?
We can get a really cheap
and broken-down old house.
-You don't want that. Let's travel.
-We could start a bed-and-breakfast.
I could receive the guests.
Make sure their towels are clean.
I can cook too. I'm a great cook.
You can be the handyman.
Do the plumbing and carpentry--
-But, it costs money.
-Hardly any.
-She wouldn't run away.
-Wedding night? Yes, she would.
She always talked of running away.
She had the suitcase--
Wait a minute.
The most important thing
is that we leave tomorrow.
Okay. Just turn off the llghts.
Oh, hi, sweetheart.
Did you see Ellie's suitcase?
Thank God.
Her suitcase is here.
Fuck!
It's Boland.
Don't worry. I can handle this clown.
-Mr. Smith.
-What's up?
-We're looking for Ellie Christianson.
-What for?
-She's been missing since the wedding.
-I'm real sorry about that, Ben.
-Have you seen her?
-No.
-You mind if I look around?
-Yeah, I do mind.
Why's that?
Why do you think she'd be with me?
That's not what we're suggesting,
you bastard.
That is exactly
what you're suggesting.
-Look, you son of a bitch!
-Whoa!
-Goddamn it!
-Easy, Ben.
Hold it. I can't fight both of you.
-I can get a warrant in 30 minutes.
-Well, get your fucking warrant!
Ellie.
It's open.
Everything's okay.
Okay, I should go home.
Home? What's stopping us
from leaving right now?
-I have to get my clothes, don't l?
-Not really.
You gonna buy me new ones,
Mr. Moneybags?
I gotta go.
Listen, we'll leave
at 8 in the morning.
Okay.
Eight o'clock.
Yeah, that's Smith.
As in "Smithsonian."
Ellie.
What happened?
Well, young lady.
Where have you been?
-Been looking all over for you.
-We can handle it from here.
You don't mind,
I'd llke to talk to your daughter.
-It's late.
-I know it is.
-We're all awake.
-She needs sleep.
Absolutely not.
-You gotta talk to her.
-I wIll.
Ben, talk to her now.
Remember what we discussed.
Be gentle, but firm.
Be loving, but tell her
this behaviour won't be tolerated.
-You're right.
-It's not my place.
Not yet. It's yours.
So go talk to her now.
Where were you all night?
Lena and I are disappointed in you.
We were worried sick.
That isn't important right now,
I guess.
I'm glad you're safe,
but I must say this to you:
We won't tolerate this behaviour.
When you're 1 8, you're on your own.
But you're under my roof now.
You got it?
WIll you say something, for chrissake?
Go downstairs now and apologize
to Lena for getting drunk.
I know you got drunk.
Mrs. Potter told me.
Go downstairs and say you're sorry...
...and you hope we have
a nice honeymoon.
Go downstairs right now and say it!
I won't say that.
-You won't?
-No.
I'll tell her you have
a mole on your left ass-cheek.
I wIll.
-You can't.
-I'll tell her.
Please. Please.
Everything.
Everything!
You're so...
...weak.
What do you want from me?
I don't understand.
When did you decide this? Right now?
No, not right now. I've thought
about it for quite a whlle.
-We've only been married 12 hours!
-Then I've thought for 12 hours.
It's not going to work out.
You're not even wIIllng
to give us a try?
I think I've given it all I had.
And I think I made a mistake.
You made a mistake.
You made a mis-- Fuck!
What happened with Lena?
She went to Mrs. Potter's.
We'll talk later.
So Lena left? That's too bad.
I didn't get to say goodbye.
I guess I should go to work.
No use wasting vacation days
if there's no honeymoon.
You two better get to school.
I won't be going to school today.
Well, then. You better get to school.
-Well?
I asked you first.
First, Mom. Now Lena.
I guess Dad's unlucky in love.
What have you done?
I'm going to school.
You don't have to leave
for a half hour.
-It's Lawson.
-I know who it is. What do you want?
-It's 7:45 and I'm ready to roll.
-I'm not going.
What are you talking about?
We had plans to go.
We talked about it, that's all.
Ellie, listen.
You've got to listen!
-Hi, honey.
-Lena?
Hi, lnger.
I'll leave you two alone
for a few minutes.
We never got a chance
to say goodbye, did we?
We could play untll the bus comes.
Inger, I'm not in the mood right now.
You could put makeup on me.
Look at me, please?
Go to the window and look at me.
I've thought about it, okay?
Screw my dumb plan
of travelling around.
Let's open a bed-and-breakfast
in Portland. I like the idea.
-You have no money.
-But I'm good with my hands.
Come on, Ellie, it's a great idea.
A bed-and-breakfast!
You gotta control yourself.
I love you!
-Who knows when we'll see each other?
-Soon, I hope.
-Bye.
Inger just left,
so we won't need three mugs.
Oh, I should've told you this a llttle
earller. It's not for lnger.
Lena, you say anything
and I'll arrest you.
Lawson?
Hello?
We have an alarm system, you know.
And you've probably set it off.
Hello?
It's Amtek. There's been a break-in
at the Christiansons'.
-I'm here if you need me. Call me.
-I wIll.
-You guys, you should move back.
-Of course, sure.
Lawson.
Your first hunch.
Too bad he didn't have a weapon.
Internal Affairs
wIll have a field day.
Probably won't affect your retirement.
-How about some cocoa?
-I never touch the stuff.
Come with me.
Where's lnger?
Dad?
Yeah, go to her.
Sweetie, I'm here.
-I don't want to go back.
-We're not. We're gonna stay here.
There'll never be another like her.
I loved her.
Is she really dead?
She's dead.