Subtitle edited By iMR aka imxpress
Oh god!
Help!
Losing my fucking mind.
Fuck you!
Come one.
Ah, fuck!
Fuck it, fuck it, fuck!
Fucking shit!
Fuck it!
God!
Come on!
Come on.
Are we friends, George?
What the hell are we doing here?
Shit!
Here!
Hi! Hi!
I can't believe it!
Come here. Oh, god!
Oh, god!
Hey...
Hey, come here.
Thank... thank you.
So warm... so warm... so warm...,
Get the...
Wait, wait, wait. Calm down,
I'll get you out of here.
Calm down.
Get this open, please.
Water, water.
Water.
Are you hungry?
Do you want this?
It's ok.
Hey, it's ok.
Everything's gonna be alright now.
I promise.
What the fuck?
Get away from him!
You hear me?
Get out of there!
Get out of there! I'm warning you!
You stop that! You st..,.
That's right.
I told him.
I warned him.
What the fuck is this?
Fuck it!
Let me out of here!
Oh, god!
Fuck this!
Come!
Fuck, open! Fuck!
Fuck!
You son of a bitch!
Oh, fuck me!
Oh, god!
Help!
I'm here!
I'm here.
Help me!
Help, fuck!
Who's Raymond Plazzy?
You.
Raymond.
Hello.
My name is Raymond.
Police have identified three men
wanted in connection with Friday's
robbery of an Abbotsford bank.
Eric Stapleton, George Weaver
and Raymond Plazzy are wanted...
...deaths of a female teller
and security guard.
Suspects have been since seen
in a silver chevrolet.
They are to be considered armed
and extremely dangerous.
Even if you do get out of here
you're fucked.
God! Oh, god!
Fuck!
Damn! Fuck! Fuck!
Oh, fuck!
Help me.
Help me!
Who the fuck are you?
My leg.
Please.
Fuck!
Hey! Hey, wait! Hey!
Oh, god!
Hey, dog.
Come here, boy!
What are you doing out here?
You're a good dog?
You're a bad dog?
I hate mint!
I had a dog when I was a kid.
He had a name.
Duke.
Oh, god!
Can't stop now.
Come up, boy!
...and demanded money...
...three suspects...
...two men entered the bank...
...Raymond Plazzy...
...deaths of a female teller...
Help!
Stop!
Fuck!
Shit!
Anybody out there, boy?
Ha?
Oh, fuck!
Oh, god!
Shit!
Here, come.
Little, little, yeah.
Little, little, quick.
Yeah.
Fuck you!
You're a crazy dog.
Go get it.
Good boy!
Bring it here.
Oh, good boy! Oh, good boy!
Good boy! Oh, good boy!
Where is the stick?
Ah, get it!
Get it!
Chicken!
You chicken!
Come on! Come on, chicken!
Come here!
You're a chicken.
You're a good boy.
Good boy.
Hello?
Come and get me!
I don't care!
What?
What do you want?
Go!
What is it?
No! What?
What?
No!
No, no.
Fuck you.
Move the fuck away from me!
Move the fuck away!
I know what you're trying to do.
I don't want you here!
I know.
You did this!
You didn't think I would do it?
Well I did.
I did.
No.
There's no road.
Stupid.
Yeah, I told you it was a stupid idea.
Fucking stupid.
Keep talking, yeah.
Keep talking.
Shut the fuck up!
That's what I thought.
Cause we've had this conversation already.
- Why? Yeah, I know we've had.
We've had that conversation like...
- Oh, god! Well you just get...
What do you want?
You gotta do things like that, I mean...
Absolutely not.
Let's go!
- Out of the fucking way!
Let's go, guys!
Gotta go! Come on! Let's go!
- What? What are you doing?
No!
- Oh, my god!
Shit! What the fuck is this?
Who the fuck is this?
Come on, go!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Go!
Oh, my god! Simon!
Left here! Go left!
I got it, I got it!
This wasn't fucking planned!
You shot the fucking guy!
Calm down, guys!
The dog.
- What?
My dog.
There's no dog.
You ok?