God's Gift - 14 Days
I have a special treasure
that can not be exchanged to anything in this world.
Give me a kiss.
The child that I love.
During the live broadcast, that all the citizens were watching,
my child was kidnapped.
The child that was lost...
came back as a cold dead body.
In that cold, deep, dark ground,
my child is in there.
How cold would it be?
How scary would it be?
So, I'm...
going back to my child right now.
Ah, really!
Episode 3
Ahjumma!
Please call the police!
Ahjumma, save me!
Ahjumma, over here!
Dong Chan!
Mother!
Please save me!
Save me!
Wait, wait.
I can't swim!
I am telling you I can't swim!
Save me!
The first execution will take place.
Mom!
My daughter
Hello?
Mom, where are you?
Are you Saet Byul?
Yeah.
I'm hungry.
Hurry up and make me some food.
Saet Byul is alive.
Our Saet Byul?
[ 14 days before the incident ]
She's not here.
Surprise!
Happy Birthday, to my mom!
Your mom must be really surprised.
Are you surprised?
I prepared this so I can make a surprise party with Dad.
Blow the candle, Mom.
Are you really Saet Byul?
Are you really our Saet Byul?
What's wrong with you?
Did something happen to you?
Saet Byul!
Mom, the candle, the candle!
Are you alright?
Are you hurt anywhere?
God!
Mom!
I can't breathe.
What's wrong with you?
Saet Byul, get ready to go to school.
Are you alright?
Where did you go early in the morning?
Did you go to the broadcasting station?
Honey, what happened to our Saet Byul?
What?
She died.
She died for sure.
We did the cremation and the funeral.
What are you talking about?
Saet Byul died?
Did you dream it?
Dream?
What kind of dream is this?
Get back to your senses.
Is this all a dream?
She didn't iron my white shirt.
Something is wrong.
What is?
It's 2 weeks before.
2 weeks before?
Yeah.
Today is my birthday, so
before this day, it is exactly two weeks before.
This day, our Saet Byul died.
I remember it clearly.
What do you mean by she died?
Why would our Saet Byul die?
You keep on saying unlucky stuff in the morning.
It's true.
I don't even know what's going on.
You should sleep first.
Let's talk later.
Honey...
Why did you come out?
I told you to rest.
Mom, have you seen my journal?
It's over there.
Ah!
No, Saet Byul!
Are you alright?
Saet Byul, get some cold water.
Oh my!
Ow...
Saet Byul!
Is your hand okay?
-Are you alright?
-It's bleeding.
It's so distracting.
It's distracting, right?
It's okay. Listen to it.
No.
Mom, a birthday present.
A present?
Yeah.
It looks just like regular pen, right?
If you press it a super laser comes out.
Shoot!
If you press this in the back,
it shoots a super laser!
It's repeating.
Mom...
In the alley in Gangnam,
a woman was murdered, cruelly.
Today, at 6:00 AM,
the body of a dead woman was found near the Han river...
What's wrong, Mom?
No.
It can't be.
What is this?
How is it?
Do you like the surprise present?
You said you wanted a bag from there.
Thank you, Honey.
What's wrong, Mom?
Mom...
No.
No, no...
Mom,
what's wrong?
It's Eun Joo.
It's a dog.
Welcome.
I think you're misunderstanding this cafe to another cafe.
But this cafe is the only cafe in this area.
It's weird.
This is the place for sure.
What happened?
Unni.
Saet Byul.
I'm sorry.
Today is your resting day,
but I can't get in touch with that person.
You're the only one I can leave her with.
What is it, Unni?
I'll explain everything later.
Just look after my Saet Byeol.
Don't go out until I come back, okay?
You can't go in. Stay behind the police tape...
Excuse me, the woman who died here,
was she wearing it?
That... that leopard printed dress!
her hair came up to her shoulders, and...
That's right!
There was a stab wound on her face.
Was it below her right side of her jaw?
Like this.
Was she laying down like this?
Are you a witness?
Am I right?
It's not that...
What's wrong?
Let go!
Let go of me!
Let me go!
I'm telling you the truth.
Tomorrow, that guy, wait...
Tonight, he'll kill a woman again.
So, listen to me and catch him immediately.
You have to catch him for my daughter to be safe.
So, the criminal for this case,
will kill two more women tomorrow,
and then your daughter?
Yes.
-I see.
How do you know the events that'll happen so well?
I'm being serious. Think about it.
If it's not so, how did I
know what clothes that woman
was wearing and how she died?
That's why, how did you know?
Something that the reporters don't even know.
Unless you're the criminal...
The criminal?
-Yes.
There isn't any other way to explain this, right?
Pretend to be fooled and
just listen to what I'm saying...
If you find out where the R Club is and hide there,
you'll know if I'm right or not.
-Ah, really!
If you keep saying this,
you may be arrested for being the real criminal.
-What?
Even if we take everything you've said into account, it's more than enough to arrest you.
You would have to come stay here for a few days.
And if you get sent to the prosecutor,
it's really complicated!
Just believe me!
I'm going crazy, seriously!
These people! They really tried to kill me by throwing me in the lake!
Not just that, they tied a rock this big on me and dropped me into the water!
If this isn't attempted murder, what is it?
Ah, I'm going to go crazy.
I mean... at first meeting, why would we?!
For what reason would we drop you into the water?!
Our first meeting? Look at these guys. That jerk who cheated.
Your boss said it.
To completely drop me into the water... you said I was
waterproof!
Cheat?
The two of us?
Hey, these guys could
clean up at the Academy Awards for their acting.
Hey, Huh Goo, why aren't you looking at... ?
Ahjumma.
You're alive!
Oh...
You're here, Ahjumma.
You disappeared so suddenly,
so I thought you went into the lake again.
I'm glad to see you again.
Now that we met again and you're alive,
I'm even more glad.
Ahjumma, don't you remember me?
I saved you.
I'm pretty upset that you don't recognize me.
I went to call 119 (911), and it that time you had disappeared and weren't there.
Oh yeah,
you beggar like bastards.
You can't get out of this one.
This woman is a witness.
Hey, Huh Goo, hurry up and take those two gangsters statements.
Is that true?
Ahjumeoni,
tell it how you saw it, okay?
I don't know what you're on about.
Ahjumma, why... ?
I've never been to that lake that you're talking about, and
I've never seen those guys before, either.
Why are you being like this?
I pulled you out, who had jumped into the water to commit suicide with my own two hands, now what are you saying?
Why would I kill myself?
It seems you saw a person wrong.
Wow, look at this woman's nerve pretending not to know me.
You can't do this to your life's savior.
This woman won't do, this ahjumma.
Sir, how long do we have to continue
listening to a crazy psycho?
Are you going to arrest these
innocent citizens?
Right, you can go back.
Hey, what are you doing?
You can't just let them go! They're
guilty of attempted murder!
Hey, you! According to whom,
are you just letting them go, huh?
They all have an alibi for today.
They were all in Seoul today.
Hey, tell me honestly,
you were bribed by them, right?
How much did you get paid?
What?
You're going too far!
I let go of you because you're a sunbae!
What, you bastard?
Sunbae?
Why am I your Sunbae, when I'm
not even a police officer anymore?
Were you really a policeman!
- Let me go! Are you not going to let me go!
Wow...
How did that bastard become like that?
He was one of the greatest homicide police officers in Seoul.
Really?
That person?
Of course.
Ki Dong Chan was one of the legends in Seoul.
He was a true legend.
He's better at fighting than the gangsters.
He's smarter than the criminals and is usually one step ahead of them.
There's probably no on like Ki Dong Chan here.
Where is that woman?
She is waiting because she wants to talk to Team Leader.
It's been about 10 years, right?
I thought that once in a lifetime, I might meet you.
I saw a few times your name coming out in broadcast.
It felt great.
You became a writer.
The atmosphere changed a lot.
Where did that gangster looking student go?
I like that better.
I liked that better.
It hasn't been 10 years.
What?
We've met in the broadcasting station before.
And that place, the words you just spoke,
you said the same thing.
What are you talking about?
You won't be able to understand
the words I am telling you, even if I explain it.
I will tell you in detail later.
So, please believe everything I'm telling.
Please.
So, you're back two weeks before you daughter died, right?
So, you knew the murder cases were going to happen.
Is that what you're saying?
You haven't changed at all.
10 years and now.
Rubbing your hands with your nose,
is the habit that happens when you're trying to believe what I'm saying when I am lying.
Who would believe what I say, when even my husband doesn't believe me?
Please let me out.
Ahjumma, lower it.
This...
Ahjumma, please take me to the subway nearby.
It's bothering to have a fight in front of the police station.
I'm getting in.
Thanks.
You wretch!
Leaving me here to die like this.
You bastard!
Come on now guys.
Catch him!
You bastard!
Hey!
Stay right there!
They're so disgusting!
I'm going, bye!
You're making such a dirty fuss with just this one newspaper!
Why is the news like this today?
Let's look.
Today's luck is?
Today is...
an important day that will make you meet a person who will change your destiny.
A person who will change my destiny?
Who is it?
What is this?
It's a newspaper that is one month old.
Citizen's union on criminal safety. Demand on executions!!!
They're going to do an execution.
Dong Ho hyung is going to be executed today.
My brother is a prison guard.
I took a peek at the list.
It's total of 5 people.
The last person in the list is Dong Ho hyung.
Did Grandma...
say anything?
What?
About your dad?
Dad?
Grandma is a liar.
She always says that I can meet my dad after sleeping 10 nights.
Maybe Dad forgot Young Gyu.
Young Gyu misses Dad.
Uncle, are you crying?
Are you crying because you want to see Dad, too?
No.
It's because this is spicy.
Even the smell is spicy.
It's not really spicy.
Pack only the things you really need right away.
Later, I will ask Dad to bring them.
Are we really going to Hawaii?
What about school?
I told the school already.
Hurry up and pack your things.
Hey!
Can you eat jjajangmyun after working like that?
What's wrong?
Hey, that woman,
didn't you check that her husband was the boss of a gang?
If we get a client, I told you to do a background check on the client, you jerk!
I almost died because of that adulteress!
When did we get a request about adultery?
We haven't had a single customer for a month! Not even a single fly!
You guys are both trying to play a joke on me?
Hey, the day when we were eating jjajjangmyun,
did a lady wearing a blue clothing and a black miniskirt come in?
That she was committing adultery, she looked just
like this...Oh my!
Why are you here?
Why, again?
Oh, welcome!
Have a seat.
What do you mean 'have a seat'?
How can you come back here?
I'm really going to die.
What are you saying?
Do you want some tea?
Jenny, get her some Earl Grey.
Ahjumma... no, ma'am,
why did you...
say those things to your husband?
What would become of me?
That day, I only...
I don't even remember that day.
The day I gave you the pictures.
I ate the first meal and after the day was over...
You bastard, didn't I tell you rip off last month's calender?
What are you talking about?
There's nothing wrong with the calendar.
Are you joking around?
That's this month's calendar?
[ March 10th, 2014, Monday ]
Jenny,
today is really...
March 10th?
No way, it can't be.
No way, it is.
What's wrong with you?
Today, let's get to the point,
Is today perhaps...
the first time you're coming here?
Yes.
Is this my first time meeting you?
Of course.
Do you know me?
Then the reason you came here is
to catch your husband cheating?
How do you know that?
Is your husband right now...
living as boss of a gang?
Oh my!
Is this a fortune telling place, not an errand center?
Hey, this is not a joke right?
Hyung, what are you?
Are you possessed by a spirit?
Please hurry up and leave!
Go away!
Can you be like this to a customer?
I can't accept the work so go!
Hurry up and leave!
Hey, Hyung Tae,
is today really March 10th?
Why do you keep on asking?
What is this?
What happened?
Perhaps...
No, it can't be!
It doesn't make sense.
Hello?
You bastard, there's no more rice!
Hurry up and buy some rice and make some food.
Buy some meat, too! Korean beef!
After eating only rice,
the sound of a cow keeps coming out of my mouth.
This grandpa.
Keep acting up like that!
That grandpa died...
What are you doing?
It's real.
This is real!
I'm getting goosebumps!
If this grandpa is alive,
then I get my 10 billion KW.
(10 million dollars)
This is 10 billion KW!
Ah, 10 billion KW!
It's 10 billion KW!
It's finished now.
Do you want some ice cream?
Yes.
Wow!
Wow, Grandpa!
Move aside!
Are you crazy?
Why are you all of a sudden like this?
Wait a minute.
Grandpa, this...
is grande size of caramel macchiato with a lot of whip cream.
And this is... do you see the marbling?
This is top grade Korean beef with great marbling.
You... did you eat something bad?
Grandpa,
these past days,
I've made you very sad, right?
Please forget everything.
Forget everything and
live comfortably thinking this place is your home.
I thought about it and
in that short period of time, I have such deep sentiment towards you, Gramps.
Even though we don't look alike,
you seem like my father.
Why are you like this all of a sudden?
So, from today on,
I am quitting the Supporter thingy.
I'm going to live as a good person from now on?
I am going to do some volunteer work.
I'm going to attend the church now.
Now, I'm going to become a new person.
Would you please watch over me?
Are you sick anywhere?
No, I'm fine.
So,
our grandpa,
do you have anything to say
to me?
What?
Think about it.
You have something to tell me.
I do.
You do?
Yes, you do.
Say it comfortably.
I will listen to it.
Go to the hospital.
I think you are mentally ill.
I'm fine!
What's wrong, Grandpa?
Are you sick anywhere?
I need to poop.
Right, go poop. Relieve yourself.
Don't put in too much strength.
He'll probably say it tomorrow.
I'll be patient for one day.
The honorable CEO Choo Byeong Woo died of a chronic heart problem.
Right... heart failure.
Wait a minute.
He died on this day.
Ah, what should I do?
Give this to me.
What are you doing?
There's no taking back.
Give that back.
Do you know how bad coffee is for your heart?
This is poison!
Saet Byul!
Passenger, are you alright?
Did you feed her something?
Yes, I gave her some ice cream.
What kind of ice cream?
It was nut ice cream.
She has a nut allergy.
I think it's anaphylactic shock.
We need to go to the hospital quickly.
What?
Saet Byul..
Saet Byul...
This is the pilot speaking.
We have an emergency patient in this airplane
so we have to go back to Incheon airport.
This is the captain speaking.
This plane is returning to Incheon airport.
Every situation is repeating.
Me getting a burn,
your white shirt getting a hole,
the vase... No, it's a glass cup...
Our Saet Byul getting cut.
And the present you and Saet Byul gave,
almost hitting a bicycle, the murder,
they are all happening.
Honey.
I have proof.
Look at this.
It's the picture I told you about before.
For sure, this is the picture me and Saet Byul took.
But, look.
Saet Byul is the only one not here.
Think about it!
If Saet Byul is only one who disappeared in this picture,
means that in two weeks...
She's going to die?
So you tried to run away to a foreign country?
Yeah.
If she's here,
she's going to be kidnapped and murdered by that murderer.
It's not two weeks, but
today that Saet Byul almost died!
It was because of you.
No matter how much you try to run away and step on it,
destiny follows you know matter what.
It's no use in running away from it.
So instead of running away from it,
fight it.
Okay, let's face it.
It's no use in running away from it.
I will find that person myself
and I will change Saet Byul's fate.
Saet Byul...
I will save you for sure.
For sure.
The second woman victim.
She wore a skull tee with flowers.
The witness' statement,
about in the mid 20s?
In a Gangnam night club, during 9:00-10:00 PM,
witnessed in the club.
A skull tee
Where are you going again?
I'm protecting Saet Byul.
Where are you going when the child is sick?
I don't care if you think of me as crazy.
I'm not letting Saet Byul go, a second time.
Ki Dong Chan...
used to be a legend in Seoul in the police.
He can fight better than gangsters,
using his head,
he was always on top of the criminals' heads.
In this field,
there weren't any other cops better than him.
I..
I didn't play with Saet Byul.
It's a problem if you don't recycle.
I heard that you're a human rights attorney.
Let me tell you something,
the basis of human rights start with correct public behavior.
What is it?
Aunt!
Yes?
Did you throw this away?
No!
These are all new!
Did Saet Byul's mom throw this away?
Do you like that?
Wear these shoes
and when someone tries to take Saet Byul away,
you have to run and stop them.
Okay?
Okay.
Let's make a promise.
I promise!
Young Gyu,
I'm sorry.
Ah, this Hyung!
Hyung!
Are you really quitting?
How about our overdue monthly rent?
What are you going to do if you quit this?
Volunteer work.
What?
Byeong Tae,
from now on,
I'm not going to the scenes of people committing adultery,
or collecting money from people.
I'm going to live a new life.
Good.
A new life. That's good.
That's all good,
but volunteer work...
Oh! Hello!
We're closed for business.
Hyung! Why are you like this?
Ki Dong Chan...
Hey, Byeong Tae,
throw some salt here.
Because of you, I've drank tons of water and almost died. I saved your life yet you treated me like that and now you call me,
"Ki Dong Chan?"
I'm sorry, I wasn't in my right mind then.
It wasn't that you weren't in your right mind,
but it's that you're rude.
Go before I do something harmful to you!
Go...
Ahjussi,
please help me.
What do you mean help? I quit!
Can't you see?
You know...
that my child is dead, right?
You know that my child was kidnapped.
It's impossible that you don't know since it was broadcasted live.
I don't know. What is this woman talking about?
I don't know! I don't watch news.
You came back, too.
I heard from the police station.
We came back 2 weeks before my child was found from the lake.
2 weeks later... No,
before that, my child will die.
So,
please help me so we can catch him.
Why should I?
Why would I catch that murderer who killed 3 women...
Yes. The murderer who killed 3 women!
He'll kill my daughter.
So please help me.
You're the only one who can help me.
My husband, the police... they all don't believe me.
I don't want to.
Why would I meddle in someone else's business?
What if I get hurt? I only have one body.
I'll pay you as much as you want.
Hey, where are you showing off your money?
I don't need this little money,
so don't try to do any funny business and get away!
Are you crazy?
Yes.. that...
So your daughter will die... No,
it'll happen to her, right?
How worried are you?
I don't know what's going on, but if you..
Take it.
Take it and go. Go away.
Go away!
Get out. Get out.
Hey, Ki Dong Chan!
Ki Dong Chan, please!
Just give up.
My hyung, once he says no,
he'll never go back on it.
He's got a stubborn personality.
Excuse me,
please tell him to contact me if he changes his mind..
Please.
-Okay.
Hey,
do you know
where the gun store is?
Gun store...Wait. Gun?
Ahjussi! Just wait a little!
I'll save you!
Soon,
the first death penalty will be carried out.
Dong Ho Hyung...was sentenced to death this morning.
Young Gyu!
Shut up, you bastards!
If you come even one step closer!
I won't let this child go!
Young Gyu!
She said Dad will come if I wait 10 days..
But I guess he forgot about me.
I miss him, though.
If this child lives,
Hyung doesn't die.
Wang Byeon Tae
Why aren't you answering your phone?
What is this?
Just something...
to take care of your body.
I'm rich with meat, rich!
Where did you get the money to buy this?
There's something.
Hyung,
you don't have to move your stuff out anymore.
I met the owner
and took care of the rent in advance.
What did you say?
Why would you pay for the rent, I'm moving!
And also,
with what money did you do it?
Hey, you bastard, where'd you get the money?
Where'd you get it?
Huh?
Hey, you gambled again, didn't you!
Tell me the truth! Did you gamble?
No, that ahjumma earlier!
What ahjumma?
I helped the ahjumma a little.
Helped her?
About what?
Club Rage
Buy me some coffee.
When it's raining, you have to drink cappuccino.
Hurry up!
Put a lot of cinnamon in it.
You're so fickle.
You made all that fuss this afternoon.
Hey, you bastard,
a young guy like you sleeps in the early evening?
I gave her all the list of all clubs beginning with 'R' in Gangnam.
Hyung, but it looks like that ahjumma
is going to make some big trouble.
She asked me where the gun store was.
It's the place where they buy guns, right?
Gun?
That ahjumma with no fear.
Aish, I don't know!
RaRaRa Nonhyeon 804-35
Normal Trash
District 3
What the heck? What's going on?
What's happening?
Turn on the lights!
Are you crazy?
Do you know how big it is to kill someone?
Do you know how painful that feels?
Who is going to kill someone?
Let go of this.
This.
Move aside.
I understand, so stay still.
I just have to catch that person, right?
So what's the use of coming here?
While waiting near that trash can,
when that bastard comes, you can just beat him up.
It's not the place where he killed her, but it's the place where she was thrown away.
I don't know where he killed her.
If we wait there,
we might find the culprit, but the woman would be dead already.
We have the save the person first.
Let's do it.
Let's save the person, first.
Why did you change your mind?
You said you'll give me money.
Let's sign the contract after we finish the work.
This ahjumma, has a quick character than I thought.
The time is not yet right.
Jenny! Byeon Tae!
How was it?
I came at the perfect timing right?
You're time was perfect.
This woman would've been caught if the
lights had turned off even a little bit late.
Hey, don't stay here
and stay at the entrance and, then
if you feel like something has happened inside, call us
You understand?
And Jenny...
Where did she go?
Jenny is over there!
Hey, where are you going! Come here!
You! Really...
These guys are so into it.
Come down!
Come down, you wench!
Ouch.
Come on, let us play a bit.
Let go of me and talk!
Stop!
Where did Ahjumma go?
Damn it! Go find Ahjumma!
What the hell?
Excuse me? Anyone? There's a murderer here!
There's a murderer here!
Murderer?
So what you're saying is that you tried to
get her number by taking her phone out, right?
I mean, can't young men and women
exchange their phone numbers?
You do this to me just because I tried to get her number?
You better be prepared,
I'll send you to prison for assault charges.
I'm sorry.
Do you think this can be resolved by you just saying sorry?
Hey! Do whatever you want!
Why don't you try to press charges on her?
You look like you're a married man.
Should I call your wife?
And tell her that her husband
tried to get another woman's number
and got smacked on the back of his head?
So, your wife's phone number is...
I'm letting this go because I'm a good person.
Hey, and you...
manage your wife properly.
You disgust me.
What did you say?
How on earth do I look married to this Ahjumma?
I'm going through such crap when it's already a unlucky day.
Please don't go.
You will die if you go by yourself.
Why are you doing this?
Let go of me! Please catch that woman!
Hurry and catch that woman!
Is there a rubbish bin around here?
It's over there.
Thank you.
(Calling Ki Dong Chan)
Normal Trash
District 3
Are you okay?
Excuse me?
So who takes away these beverage boxes?
Does the cleaner take them away?
No. If we leave them here,
the alcohol company takes them away.
When?
Tomorrow afternoon, when the alcohol
gets delivered before opening hours,
they collect the empty boxes.
Tomorrow afternoon?
So will they stay here before then?
Yes.
Okay.
I'm sure these boxes weren't here before.
This used to be an empty spot.
It's not this rubbish bin.
I went to all the clubs starting with "R"...
It's not a 'P'...It's an 'R'...
It must be somewhere else..
What should I do?
Ki Dong Chan
It's scary.
That cross necklace...
Someone saw her drinking at a 'R' club before she died.
She was apparently really drunk.
It wasn't that woman. It was her!
Wang Byeon Tae
Excuse me, don't go!
You'll die if you go, please!
What the..
Aren't you leaving?
All of you are going to get screwed up.
What are you doing?
Why are you flirting with my girlfriend?
Huh?
He's on the phone, heh?
Yeah, Ahjumma.
Ki Dong Chan! It wasn't that woman!
Here...
Ahjumma!
Ahjumma Ahjumma!
Where are you, Ahjumma?
So where are you, Ajhumma?