Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
So the games
of the 20th Olympiad...
...begin with the voices of children.
Beautiful, innocent, serene.
The setting much more Hansel
and Gretel than Hitler and Göring.
The day is perfect here
in Munich, Germany.
Just nine miles and 30 years
from Dachau.
The Olympic Games designed
to heal old wounds.
To show history that men and nations
can change for the better.
Come on. Let's go.
How are you?
- Hello.
- He's back.
- Hey.
- Hello.
Hi.
- Hello, Spitzer.
- Just got in from Holland.
- How's the wife?
- Fine. She's still there with the baby.
She'll be coming on in a few days.
Why are you limping, Yossef?
I ruptured my knee during
the clean and jerk on the 430.
I'm flying home for an operation
tomorrow.
Did you hear about Gaddie here?
He placed 12th
in freestyle wrestling.
Twelfth out of 50.
Maybe in four years,
a medal in Montreal.
Oh, yes. Go get some rest.
- Good night.
Yes, Ankie.
Yes.
It's wonderful here,
but I miss you terribly.
Come two days earlier.
Kiss Anouk for me.
Moshe? Is that you?
Arabs!
Terrorists!
Get out, buddy!
Everybody, get out!
- Don't shoot him.
- Hands up.
Help. Help us.
Arabs with guns. Help us.
Arabs with guns.
31 Connollystrasse.
Come on.
Keep going. Keep going!
- You. Against the wall.
- Send in their guide.
Get over here, get over here.
You too. You too.
Put your hands up.
None of your friends
can hear you here.
Now...
...if you lead me to the rest
of your delegation...
...and announce yourself at the door,
I will let you go.
Where is Lalkin?
Weinberger?
Get up against the wall.
Hands up.
Help! Somebody!
Better call the police.
Any Israelis in there?
Then who's in there?
Uruguays. South Americans.
How many Israelis in there?
David.
- Did you hear that?
- What?
Get up.
Move.
Hands on your head.
- Did you hear that?
- Sounded like automatic fire.
Go on!
Hey!
Stop!
Go back.
Schreiber.
My God.
How many hostages?
Well, send a man over there
and find out.
Not from the Olympic Village.
One of my men.
Also, send 20 men and seal off
all the access routes to Building 31.
Surround it without the terrorists
seeing you.
You will tell your superiors that any
attempt to interfere with our mission...
...will bring about the immediate
liquidation of all Zionist prisoners.
How do we know
what prisoners you have?
Dr. Schreiber, our men
have surrounded Building 31...
...but the East German delegation
refuses to move.
Go over there. Remind them
that they're in West Germany...
...and tell them to get out.
- Right.
"The revolutionary organization
Black September...
...demands that by 9 a.m.,
the Israeli military regime...
...free 236 revolutionary prisoners...
...whose names are listed herewith."
They're also asking Bonn
for three long-distance planes...
...to carry them and their hostages
to a country of their choice.
"If the deadline is not met...
...the Zionist prisoners
will be executed forthwith."
The Olympics.
Six years we have worked
for this dream here in Munich...
...and now this.
Mayor Troger, it's not just Munich.
It's our whole country.
Six million ghosts
have come back to haunt us.
Gentlemen...
...the problem is that we have
several heavily armed men...
...holding as many as 10 hostages...
...in a highly populated area
of the Olympic Village.
They've already killed
at least one man.
And our job is to see
that they kill no more.
It seems to me that only the Israeli
government can prevent that.
Minister Merk...
...the crime is occurring here.
It's our responsibility.
It is obvious they picked the Olympics
in order to draw maximum attention...
...to their political grievances
over Palestine.
This is the same organization
that slaughtered all those people...
...at Lod Airport last May.
The International Olympics
Committee must be informed...
...of any decisions we make.
- All right. Let's get them here.
Brundage, Daume, all the others.
But I'll tell you, the only way
to defuse a situation like this...
...is to start talking to the terrorists
right now.
But who will talk to them?
Well, at the moment, none of us.
Not even a policeman,
because the uniform...
...would put them on the defensive.
I think it should be a member
of the Olympic security forces.
And preferably a woman.
Now do you believe us?
We'll kill them all.
Starting at 9:00.
And then we throw their bodies
in the street.
Do you understand?
Hello.
What do you think
you're doing here?
Come down. I want to talk to you.
Yeah, that's right, you.
- What do you want?
- Don't point that thing at me.
I have no gun.
I mean, it might go off, you know,
and then what?
Who are you?
Fräulein Graes, of the Women's
Olympic Security Service.
We have no women in here.
Think you can charm your way
in because you're a woman?
Well, you're speaking to me,
aren't you?
There's nothing wrong in that,
is there?
How many hostages do you have?
What are their names?
What's the difference?
- You know we have them.
- Yeah.
But Israel will want to know
who they're bargaining for.
I mean, maybe you've killed
them already.
No. We did not come here
to shed blood.
We came here to take them
all alive.
To show the world that the fedayeen
are not cruel warriors.
Our only mission is to free
our comrades from Israeli jails.
But this is not Israel.
Your comrades are not here...
...and you don't have
236 hostages in there.
You seek justice in numbers?
What about the millions of
Palestinians evicted by the Jews?
But why bring your holy war here?
The world cannot stay blind
to the tragedy of Palestine...
...here at the Olympics.
We've been dead and forgotten
for years now.
Well, you know, we can do nothing
about freeing political prisoners...
...in another country.
We can only transmit your terms.
Why not give us conditions
that are possible to meet?
I have.
Free them all if you don't want
the hostages to die.
Good day, fräulein.
Move.
This is still the Olympics,
gentlemen.
They've gone on for nearly
3000 years...
...and no petty political hoodlums
are going to stop them now.
I am placing all the security forces
in the Village...
...under Dr. Schreiber's
police command.
And I am here to give the full support
and aid of the federal government.
Thank you, Minister Genscher.
I need all the help I can get.
You've contained those Arabs
over on Connollystrasse?
We have the building surrounded.
We're still waiting word from Israel.
Until then, we're only working
with one hand.
Just so long as it's a firm hand.
Some gentlemen want to talk to you.
Talk means nothing.
You said you didn't want to kill.
You didn't say
you didn't want to talk.
Who are they?
Dr. Schreiber
of the Munich police...
...Bavarian Interior Minister Merk
and a gentleman from Egypt...
...a member of
the International Olympic Committee.
Okay.
Stop right there.
We haven't an answer for you yet.
In 10 minutes, if I don't have
an affirmative response...
...I will kill a hostage
right where you're standing.
Look. You've got to believe us.
We are doing everything we can.
To show our good faith, the three
of us are willing, right now...
...to take the place of the hostages.
You are not my enemies.
Brother, Israel has
just received the list.
It is a very long list indeed.
Be reasonable.
Give them time to study it
before you take any action.
They have had already
reasonable time.
Now each hour
will cost them one hostage.
That's not reasonable.
It's plain murder.
If you do that, your hostages
are no longer hostages.
They're just people
you were going to kill anyway.
And the whole world will know it.
- How much time?
- Six hours.
That's ridiculous.
Five hours, then. Please.
Three.
Twelve o'clock noon, then.
It's the prime minister.
Madam Prime Minister.
Yes. We've managed
to extend the deadline...
...three more hours till 12:00 noon.
Thank God for that.
I'll do everything in my power
to free the Israeli athletes.
But may I suggest that...
That you make some offer.
A partial promise.
For example, if they will free
the hostages...
...Israel will agree to turn loose...
...a portion of the Arab prisoners in...
In a few days.
Mr. Chancellor, my position
is a clear one.
Israel will, under no conditions...
...make the slightest concession
to terrorist blackmail.
My government is completely
behind me on this.
These men are murderers.
They have proven this
over and over again.
If we should give in...
...no Israeli anywhere in the world
can feel safe.
I am concerned only with the lives
of the Israeli hostages in Munich...
...at this moment.
Munich is a German city.
The murder of Mr. Moshe Weinberger,
and the taking hostage...
...of 10 athletes and officials...
...are domestic German crimes.
I know that Germany would never
abandon to terrorists...
...guests taken hostage
in its territory.
That is correct. But, please,
I urge you to submit my suggestion...
...to your cabinet.
I beg of you, Mr. Chancellor,
do not abandon our children.
Fräulein!
Tell your friend Schreiber
to get these men off the roofs...
...or I shoot a hostage.
I give him 15 minutes.
They have run into some telex trouble
with Israel.
Atmospheric conditions
are very poor today.
Well, let's hope for the sake
of the hostages they quickly improve.
How are the hostages?
I'm only asking in case
someone needs a doctor.
No one needs a doctor any longer.
Then there are more dead in there.
Yes, one.
Who is he?
Tell me that much.
Someone called Romano.
A weightlifter.
Why don't you stop all this killing?
Look, we didn't mean to kill
those two men, but we had no choice.
We did not come here to kill anyone,
especially Jews in Germany.
- You know what the world will say.
- They are saying it already.
I just want to get my brothers
out of jail.
Your brothers?
You mean, your comrades.
No, two of my own brothers.
In a word, the Israeli government
is refusing to release...
...a single political prisoner.
That is correct.
Mr. Ambassador,
do you know what this means?
Unless the terrorists collapse...
...the only way to save your people
now is by force.
Are you willing to take that risk?
Dr. Schreiber, what you plan
to do now is entirely up to you.
Dr. Schreiber would like
to speak with you.
Another last-minute appeal,
Herr Doctor?
Listen to me.
Israel still hasn't had time
to complete the files...
...on the 200 and some-odd...
Then in nine minutes,
we start shooting the hostages.
- I asked you to listen...
- Don't come any closer.
If what you wanna do
is murder Israelis...
...we can't do anything to stop you...
...any more than we can make
a decision for another country.
But have no illusions.
If you kill them, we kill you.
We are not afraid to die.
In that case,
you'll find us most obliging.
Who is the new visitor?
Mohammed Khadif
of the Arab League.
Paulo.
Now, when we finish talk
in good faith...
...I will return to the second floor
where I've entrusted...
...the safety device of this weapon
to my comrade.
All right? Is that clear?
We have not come here
to trick you.
We are all looking for a solution.
There is only one solution:
The liberation
of all fedayeen prisoners...
...from the jails of occupied Palestine.
You must understand.
We are in the midst...
...of extremely delicate negotiations
with Israel.
Mohammed Khadif,
have you, too, come to trick me?
Brother, I speak to you as an Arab.
I, too, wish to see our comrades
released from Israeli prisons...
...but I don't want to see you
hurt your own cause.
Give the German more time to
bargain with Israel for a final answer.
Always more time.
I give them an hour, they take two.
I give them 20...
They are doing everything they can.
They don't want more Jews
to die here.
That's what will happen.
And it will be on their heads...
...for all the world to see.
- No, it will be on our heads.
Show the world
that we are human beings.
You will never have
a better opportunity.
The West German authorities
have authorized me...
...to offer you any amount of money
you want...
...and safe conduct
out of the country...
...if you will release the hostages.
That kind of money would be very
valuable to your organization.
No, brother.
You mean well, but why bother me
with such useless proposals?
We don't want money.
And we don't want to hurt anyone.
We just want to get our comrades
out of jail.
- And we are prepared to die for it.
- Then give them the time to do it.
Give them until 5:00 at least.
They have given me their word
that nothing will be tried against you.
Otherwise, I would not have come.
All right. But if by 5:00
Israel has not answered yes...
...to all our demands, the executions
will begin punctually. No more talking.
Suspend the games? For how long?
Until the crisis is resolved,
Mr. Brundage.
Well, I wouldn't oppose
a temporary suspension.
As a policeman, I'm against
cancellation for a very simple reason.
Tens of thousands of people
are attending these games...
...and if they're cancelled, most will
descend on Connollystrasse...
...making my job next to impossible.
I'll have to divert hundreds of police
in order to keep the crowds back.
May I suggest a temporary suspension
toward the end of the afternoon...
...when there is a normal break
in the games anyway.
All right. But then...
...what do we do now?
I think we keep talking
and hope they make a mistake.
Your two brothers in prison,
when did you last see them?
Two years ago. A family reunion.
Your parents as well?
Yes.
They are separated now.
But my mother still lives
in Nazareth.
But Nazareth, it is in Israel, no?
Galilee.
My mother is a Jew,
as a matter of fact.
Why do you look so surprised?
You know, I was born in Nazareth...
...Iong before it was occupied
by the Zionists.
My father is Jordanian.
What does he do?
He's a merchant.
He does very well.
It's been a very good life.
Always plenty of money,
plenty of women.
I've traveled and studied abroad.
But all that means nothing now.
There are five entrances
to the apartment.
The upper and lower windows,
front and back. And the lobby door...
...which can be reached
from underground and front.
Minister Merk, a frontal assault
like that would result in a massacre.
We don't know how many hostages
there are, where they are...
...or if they're together.
And most frustrating, we don't know
how many terrorists there are.
What we do know is that
they control an armed fortress.
We've got to get inside
and see where they are.
Stop there.
Put down the boxes.
Now you can tell your policemen
to go back and change their clothes.
We can manage from here.
- Who are they?
- From the international youth camp.
The radio broadcasts have been
telling us for the last two hours...
...that Israel long ago
rejected our demands...
...thereby sentencing
their countrymen to death.
Every radio station in the world is
speculating as to what might happen.
It doesn't matter.
You've played around with us too long.
We have decided to leave Germany
with the hostages.
In one hour, I want
the three planes and crews...
...which we requested this morning.
We shall fly to Egypt. When we land,
we want to find waiting for us...
...at Cairo Airport every
one of the prisoners...
...whose release we demanded.
If they're not there,
before leaving the plane...
...we will execute all the hostages.
Without exception.
A moment, please.
What he is saying is that he does not
wish to kill the hostages here.
We certainly have no intention
of letting them leave the country.
Yes, but we can't let them know that.
I warn you that trying
to get three planes...
...in one hour is absolutely impossible.
It will be hard enough to get one.
All right. One will do.
Good. But to find a long-range plane,
service it, work out the transfer...
...all that could never be done
in one hour.
We would need at least three.
Seven o'clock. No later.
Just a minute.
How do we know the Israelis
are still alive?
Before we fulfill our end of the bargain,
I insist that we see them.
Get a Jew.
Bring him to the window.
That one. Untie his legs.
Come.
Up!
- Good day, gentlemen.
- Good day, dear sir.
I am Bruno Merk,
minister of the interior...
...for the free state of Bavaria.
I am Andre Spitzer...
...fencing master and coach
of the Israeli Olympic team.
We want you to know that we are
doing everything humanly possible...
...to get you released.
- I thank you, sir...
...in the name of all my comrades.
- How many of you are still alive?
- No, don't answer that.
- Ask only what we agreed on.
- Listen, you animal.
No blackmail in the world
can make us accept the word...
...of a single Israeli
with a gun in his back.
We're not doing a damn thing for you
until we've seen every hostage alive.
And what's more, we are not letting
a single hostage go anywhere...
...unless he agrees to it.
One moment.
They're scared. They know Israel
won't deal with them.
They wanna get out of here.
- Has Chancellor Brandt arrived yet?
- He has just arrived in the Village.
Go and transmit
their new demands to him.
All right.
To show you our humanity
and goodwill...
...I will grant this favor
to only two of you.
Dr. Schreiber and you, Mr. Genscher.
Take off your coats.
He doesn't like you very much.
He might simply add us
to his collection.
Maybe. Maybe not.
Gentlemen, I'm Manfred Schreiber
of the Munich police...
...and this is Mr. Genscher
of the federal government.
- Hello.
You have all been told
of the commander's decision...
...to fly all of you to Cairo?
- Yes, we have.
I want to make our position clear.
We cannot allow this unless
each and every one of you...
...agrees to leave
the Olympic Village.
Dr. Schreiber, whether we leave
the Olympic Village or not...
...we know we are dead men.
There are nine hostages.
Altogether on the second floor
rear bedroom.
Could you identify their pictures?
Yes. Was there a terrorist
on the balcony when we were inside?
No. He went in when you did. There
was just the one outside with us.
How many did you see inside?
- Four, including the leader.
- Then there are only five.
I don't know. The doors to the back
bedroom were closed downstairs...
...and then there's the front room
upstairs.
Might have been more.
Herr Schreiber?
General Zamir is here.
- Manfred Schreiber, how do you do?
- How do you do, sir?
They say President Sadat
has still not returned to the capital.
Then tell them I wish to speak
to Prime Minister Sedki.
- David Marc Berger, the American.
- American?
Yeah, dual citizenship.
He's engaged to an Israeli girl.
He was badly beaten.
He has a bandage on his shoulder.
Ze'ev Friedman,
our bambino weightlifter.
- Yossef Gutfreund.
- He's been beaten around the face.
None of them complained.
Eliezer Halfin, wrestler.
This must be the dead one.
I didn't see his face.
Romano.
Do you know that this big bruiser
was a window dresser?
He went out yesterday to look
at the window displays in Munich.
Young Mark Slavin.
He only left Russia four months ago.
Amitzur Shapira, our track coach.
Kehat Shorr.
Spitzer, of course.
Yacov Springer.
Poor Moshe.
Excuse me.
May I ask...
...Dr. Schreiber, what is preventing
an immediate assault on Building 31?
General, the latest demands
have been telexed to Jerusalem.
And Chancellor Brandt
is still trying to get through to Cairo.
Now whether these diplomatic efforts
succeed or not...
...we're still going through with
the plan to transfer the terrorists...
...and the nine hostages
to the airport.
You mean that you're going to...?
We have no intention of letting them
leave Germany.
Good evening, Mr. Prime Minister.
I can't hear you very clearly.
I said, good evening,
Mr. Prime Minister.
To what do I owe the honor
of this call?
The perpetrators
of the Connollystrasse attack...
...have announced they want to go
to Cairo with their hostages, sir.
The final ultimatum expires in...
Heinz?
In one hour and 40 minutes.
We would be willing
to let them go...
...if you will agree to intervene the
moment the plane lands in Cairo...
...to ensure that the fedayeen
do not kill the hostages.
And that the plane will immediately
be able to continue safely...
...on to Israel
with the nine athletes.
I do not believe your plan
a valid solution.
At any rate, it is unworkable.
This is not an Egyptian matter.
Mr. Prime Minister, I am asking you
to join in a plan to save human lives.
I fail to see how or why Egypt
should be involved...
...in what is taking place in Munich.
Because, sir, the fedayeen
plan to fly to Egypt.
Good night, Mr. Chancellor.
The Riem Airport
is too close to town.
It's much too large to contain.
They could take more hostages there,
or even another plane.
And we'd never convince the terrorists
to make that short a helicopter trip.
A helicopter?
I don't wanna transport them
by car or by bus...
...because they'd commandeer it
right to the aircraft steps.
I've got to get them
to walk out in the open.
Fürstenfeldbruck.
Stand by your cars, please.
You'll be getting instructions soon.
All right?
In my opinion, gentlemen...
...the longer you negotiate, the more
important you make them feel.
As long as we keep them talking,
there will be no more killings.
A blitzkrieg now would only
lose more hostages.
Some may die, yes,
but others may be saved.
Your parleying may end
in having them all killed.
Would you wait here, general?
Is our plane ready?
- It won't be ready before 8.
- You said 7.
The simple fact is we are having
trouble getting a crew to volunteer.
Have you heard from Israel?
- Frankly, no.
- I've had enough.
I told you, we're not going to let you
play around with us any longer!
You can kill all of us
right here, right now...
...that still won't get you your plane.
We need a few more hours.
At 9:00, I want two buses
waiting for us...
...at the underground door
to Building 31.
You hear those people out there?
They're just itching
to get their hands on you.
If we drove you out of here, a million
of them would tear you apart.
Come on, doctor. Riem is only
8 kilometers from here.
If only you could give us
a motorcycle escort.
They'd brush aside the escort
and hang you.
Crowds are beginning to gather
at Riem Airport.
They are ready to fight with their
bare hands to save the Israelis.
Your German guilt runs deep.
You, sir...
...you don't know
the meaning of guilt.
We're flying you to Fürstenfeldbruck
by helicopter at 9:00.
Have your hostages ready.
We will have a controlled situation
out here.
The field is completely fenced in...
...to keep out crowds
and prevent any escape.
That's where the plane will be.
A hundred police have already sealed
off the base around the tower...
...and they're backed by
200 more around the fence.
We've assembled two squads
of motorized police...
...and six armored cars.
And also a shock commando group
of 23 men...
...with bulletproof vests,
in case they're needed.
Now, the first helicopter
will land just about here.
Herr Feldhaus is my deputy chief.
He's in charge of the entire operation
here at the airport.
These men here, they are the finest
marksmen in the Bavarian police.
You mean they're not
Bundeswehr soldiers?
I can assure you, the Bundeswehr
has no sharper eyes...
...nor steadier hands
than our own Bavarian police.
Here, let me show you the five
sniping points we have selected.
The other helicopter will
go down right about there...
...forming a line with the 737...
...which will be standing
approximately 80 meters away...
...right over there.
There will be three marksmen
up here.
One down below
and one behind the hut.
That whole area down there
will be too dark.
We're putting in more lights.
Don't worry, it will be as clear as day.
Make sure.
Excuse me, but why are there
only five sniping positions?
According to the number
of known terrorists.
But you can't be sure
there are not more than five.
You're right, general.
We have nine other marksmen
in reserve.
What do you think, general?
The layout here...
...disturbs me.
Really disturbs me.
I think the attack should take place
in the Village...
...before the hostages
even reach the helicopter.
If it's possible...
...we'll try the Village first.
Gentlemen, Cairo refuses
to intervene.
The terrorists promise
to kill the hostages...
...if Israel refuses to negotiate.
We must draw the line.
An honorable nation
does not get rid of its guests...
...by shipping them outside
of its borders...
...tied up like packages
of unregistered freight.
Nor can we stand with arms crossed
while our guests are murdered.
I see no helicopters.
The pilots couldn't land
between these buildings.
They're parked on the lawn outside
of the administration building.
- How do we get there?
- We go through the underground.
It comes up outside G1.
- I want to see the route first.
- All right, let's go.
How long will it take?
There and back?
- Four minutes.
- lf in four minutes I'm not back...
...my comrades will begin shooting
hostages. One a minute.
Now, don't hold me to that.
I don't know how fast you walk or
how many questions you might ask...
...or how many stops we might
have to make for security reasons.
How far is it?
Through the underground,
I'd say about 300 meters.
Six minutes.
Wait.
The torch.
You, that side. You, next to me.
You, behind me.
If anyone makes a false move,
I will drop this grenade, understand?
Why are they so far apart?
Look, the Air Ministry requires that
they be that far apart. That's all.
You've already used
three and a half minutes.
Salah, it's okay. We are back.
Tell Tony.
The route is no good.
I cannot see your men down here,
Schreiber.
I can smell them all over the place.
So I have decided that we
should go to the helicopters by bus.
This is ridiculous.
How long do you think
you can go on?
As long as I hold the hostages.
I want a large bus here, in front
of this door, in 15 minutes.
Thirty minutes.
All right, 30 minutes.
But no booby traps.
You must first give me your word...
...that no German citizen who aids in
transportation from this building...
...to your final destination shall be
in any way harmed or taken hostage.
You have my word on that.
Damn him.
I already told you,
no more deadlines.
No, it's just me.
I'm out of cigarettes.
- I was thinking.
- What?
You say if Israel doesn't concede...
...you're going to kill the hostages.
- Yes.
Whether here or in Cairo,
kill them nonetheless?
Yes.
Even if maybe you don't want to?
You never would have done this
unless you thought...
...there was a good chance
Israel would negotiate.
But now, you...
You're dangling from
your own ultimatum.
What if you simply walked away
from it?
Just left, right now.
They've promised you safe conduct.
Listen to me.
Millions of people are
watching you right now.
Watching you and me
talking in front of this door.
It's so crazy.
They're afraid of you.
They're afraid for you too.
Imagine what the world would feel...
...if you suddenly spared
those nine men in there.
They're not only Israelis anymore,
they're men.
Sons and husbands,
people we've come to know.
Fräulein, you're asking me
to show the world that I'm a coward.
Is that it, then?
They're going to die
because of your vanity?
It is vanity when you ask me
to walk away...
...so the world will think
I'm not a bad man after all.
No. I'm asking you
to stop the killing.
I only want my brothers out of jail.
I still believe we should hit
them in the underground.
That would have been fine
until they asked for the bus.
There will still be at least 10 meters
between the bus and the metal door.
Look, we agreed not to shoot...
...until at least half of the hostages
were present.
The others are almost certain to die.
They will be killed anyway
if you do not strike...
...at the first opportunity,
getting on the bus.
But certainly before
getting on the helicopter.
It is simply too great a risk
to stage a shooting match...
...in front of the
administration building.
They would spray the area
with automatic fire.
That's the whole point
of the airport ambush.
They have to walk in the open.
But you told me, sir...
...that you had serious doubts
about the layout...
...about the lighting
at Fürstenfeldbruck.
I still have.
But at least we've got
a controlled situation.
The bus is just arriving.
Dr. Schreiber.
I have a request.
That I be allowed to go along
with the Arabs and the hostages.
Why?
The man listens to me, you see.
As long as I'm there, I don't think
he will shoot anybody.
There will be other Germans
on that plane as well.
Anneliese, the plane,
if they ever get to it...
...will never get off the ground.
Eight. My God,
there are eight of them.
We were right not to have tried
anything during the transfer.
Faster.
Jan, call Deputy Feldhaus at
Fürstenfeldbruck.
Tell him the action
is going to be there.
Tell him I'm sending his men back...
...and that there are
eight terrorists. Eight.
Look up there.
Closer. Close together.
Captains Arbes and Vacano.
When you land at Fürstenfeldbruck,
open your doors...
...and get away from your copters as
quickly as possible without running.
But do not head for the 737.
Understood?
Roger.
There are five of them.
Five Arabs...
...out in the open.
Not a chance.
They're packed too close together.
You are isolated out here,
and so you men are on your own.
If you can't find good positions
for clear shots...
...get off the plane
as fast as you can.
They're going to cruise north
before turning west.
We'll head straight for
Fürstenfeldbruck.
We ought to beat them by
about eight minutes, huh?
God be with you.
- Did you get your men back?
- Four minutes ago.
They're all in position now.
Where do you think you're taking us?
We're supposed to be there by now.
If this copter is not down in five
minutes, I'm shooting one of you.
Pirole Two, this is Pirole One, over.
Pirole Two here. Go ahead.
They're threatening us.
They know we're circling.
I'm heading straight to
Fürstenfeldbruck, full speed.
I'll call the tower.
How's it going with you? Over.
White hat here is getting real nervous.
I was about to call you.
Move it! Move it!
We brought in all the lamps
we could find.
I've checked each position,
all the men can see clearly.
And I have eight armed men
on the plane.
But you can't do anything
with only a few men 100 yards away.
You've got to hit them
from all sides at once.
Get out in the open
and fire at close range.
- Where are the backup troops?
- They're not yet here.
The press leaked the word.
All of Munich is on its way.
There are huge bottlenecks
on Routes 2 and 471.
That's all we need.
This is ridiculous.
There isn't enough room. I mean,
what can we do in here anyway?
We're laying an ambush.
Try to find a better position.
There's no place to hide here.
He's right, we can't
do any good here.
Let's get out of here
and take positions outside.
Turn out the lights.
Halt! Get your hands up.
What the hell are they doing?
They are Arab terrorists.
They are breaking their word.
That makes 11 hostages.
Thirteen.
They're gonna check it out.
Radio the cockpit, tell them
two Arabs are coming aboard.
Sir, there's no one on the plane.
- What do you mean?
- The men have left the plane, sir.
For God's sakes, man, get down there
and help the sharpshooters.
Be ready with automatic fire
when they get off that plane.
Yes, sir.
Who decides when
to start shooting?
Feldhaus. When he starts to shoot,
the others follow suit.
We've been tricked, comrade.
Damn it.
Fire when you're ready.
Damn, he's still up!
What the hell are we waiting for?
Why don't we return the fire?
Not while there are still hostages
on those helicopters.
There he goes again!
Come on, come on!
Come on.
Where are those armored vehicles?
How will you use armor
in a situation like this?
This is Manfred Schreiber.
Throw down your weapons
and surrender.
I promise your lives will be spared.
You're completely surrounded.
There's no chance for escape.
I repeat:
Throw down your weapons
and step out on the runway...
...with your hands on your heads.
Out!
Oh, my God.
Eleven days ago, I declared
the Olympic Games of 1972...
...to be opened. Yesterday,
the abominable attack...
...on Connollystrasse shattered
the serenity and saddened the world.
Who bears the responsibility
for this crime?
First of all, the terrorist organization
that thinks hatred and murder...
...can be methods
of a political struggle.
But in addition, there are countries
that do not stop these men...
...from perpetrating such acts.
The Olympic idea lives on.
Our commitment to it
is more powerful than ever.
In the name of the
German Federal Republic...
...I address this appeal
to all the peoples of the world.
Help us overcome hatred.
Help us pave the way
for reconciliation.
Help us.
Fifty-three days later,
the three surviving Arab terrorists...
...were released from a Munich jail
in exchange for 17 passengers...
...on a German airliner
hijacked by members...
...of the Black September
organization.
On their arrival in Tripoli, they were
accorded a hero's welcome.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org