- Now you are a man.
- Now I am a man.
Now you are a man.
- Now you are a man.
- Now I am a man.
My dick feels like he bit it off.
Shut up and relax, Huku.
You have to wait until it heals.
You'll be someone totally new.
We all will.
Got a smoke?
- Hi.
- What are you carrying?
Just a shipment of rape seeds.
To Yawlou.
Show me.
Okay.
Take it out.
Careful!
Rape seeds?
Yeah.
I shouldn't open it then --
- or they'll spill all over the place.
- Yeah.
- Just make a couple of peepholes--
- Wait!
Now I'm thinking maybe
we should open it after all.
Die! Die! Die!
Die!
Anybody else?
No thank you.
So-- who do you work for?
Who do you sell to?
You're illegally running blood.
You need to give me a reason
not to lock you away forever.
There's a pressing need
for blood products here and abroad.
Gamma globulin, clotting factor
and other medicines...
...are necessary for even the simplest surgeries.
And sick people rely
on these products every day.
The Provincial Health Office
has urged everyone to give.
To reward the selfless act
of giving...
...the company will compensate
you each with five dollars.
People can give at the same time.
The blood is taken by sterile needle.
We can fit four samples
in a centrifuge.
The centrifuge spins the blood
and separates plasma
from red blood cells.
The combined red cells
which the company doesn't need-
-are split up
and returned to the donors.
I'm Tong Sam. Hi.
My wife.
My daughter- Qi.
Too young. She needs to be twelve.
Fine, I'm twelve-and-a-half.
We can't take you either.
I've been waiting for hours.
Come on, cut me a break.
Sorry. You're obviously not healthy.
It's not up to me, its policy.
For safety.
People who get your blood
could get sick.
It's just a cough.
You'll buy Huoang's blood
but not mine?
His is fifty-percent booze. People
who get his blood will get drunk.
Look, I just hired your neighbor
Zaohao as a collector.
Come back in a few weeks.
Hello.
How are you?
I'm alive.
I've reduced the afternoon meal
to 20 minutes...
and reinstated the 15 hour day.
You bastard.
Recover quickly.
Or I'll take away all the perks
you've won in the last 8 years.
Sweets?
No. Marijuana.
Stay well, friend.
Why am I paying you?
You're not to come
to work if you're sick.
I'm telling you it will pass.
This girl
must have been lying to you.
Careful!
She probably sleeps around a lot
and that's why you're sick.
Times have changed, Bongile.
they all found Christ...
...and now you can't trust a woman
to be honest about her virtue.
Who's winning?
I need a new job.
You got the best job in the world,
buddy.
Ah, I told your mother
not to raise you catholic.
We have some kind of problem.
Your blood sample today.
OUTBREAK!
Is that the Mother?
I'm surprised she would show
her face in church.
None of them have any shame.
they've really gone
to town this year.
Everyone else has money to spend.
I feel fine now.
the lady you work for told me
to come back when I felt better.
Well, I have no protocol
for changing your status.
When Miss Jin comes back,
I'll ask her.
When's that?
Definitely within 6 months.
No longer.
Everybody in town is making money
from you except me!
Give me a break, Zaohao...
it's New Year.
I need to clear my debts.
Sorry, Sam.
Fine. Do her then.
She's not old enough.
She's twelve.
Since when?
Since she was eleven.
Why isn't she in junior high?
she's not very bright.
How do you feel?
Good.
- Not dizzy?
- Nope.
Here. You get 10 percent.
It's my blood!
You can spend that.
the rest you invest in our field.
We'll go back every ten days.
Soon can afford seed and fertilizer.
Maybe an ox.
What if I want the money for myself?
then I'll tell them you're only ten.
the ox is mine.
Fine.
Don't tell your mother, okay?
That baby was born too early.
Now he's always going
to be impatient.
she caught your cold.
I'll go to the herbalist.
Hi.
Beautiful day.
Yes. I thought I'd take advantage.
I think my wife caught your flu.
My kid's in bed too.
That's why I needed the walk.
Hi.
You wanna buy a bike?
For fever, hatchet needles
pressed with honey.
Ok.
Just a sec.
All sold out.
Well what do you actually have?
I have a bit of orange seed
Echinacea left.
I'll give you what I've got.
This tastes like crap!
If it tastes good it doesn't work.
How did this happen to you?
It's one of the plantation workers,
... they have the virus.
And one sure way to get rid of it
is to pass it on to a virgin.
Who was the man, Undilewe?
Frankly, I have no beliefs to impose.
You exhume their wealth and
resources and leave them for dead.
I'll be here with them long after
your mission's gone home, Father.
Wow...this must be
the best year, ever.
This girl annoys me.
Just do what she wants
and she'll quit nagging you.
I thought nuns were supposed
to be different than other girls.
You gotta be kidding.
Is she rating?
I'm right here.
Why are you asking him?
He doesn't feed me, my mother does.
she seems tired today.
she's fine.
she likes coming to see you.
she gets to buy herself things.
she has her own little job.
I'm right here!
Better seed. Fertilizer.
It's going to be a good season,
thanks to you.
Good. I'm thinking of retiring soon.
It seems there's a way for you
to make money after all.
You'll buy my blood?
I need to transport the shipment
every couple of days.
To Longhu.
I'm too busy at the house.
I thought of you first.
To Longhu?
That's two hours with a cart!
And now you've got a water buffalo.
Two hundred yuan every time.
What do you want?
My father is outside.
Where's my cut?
Sorry, this is MY job.
But you're using MY buffalo.
Let mommy work.
You have to disguise it better.
Here. Look at this.
they peel right off
when they get there.
SPlCY RED SAUCE
You better hurry up.
I couldn't make an appointment.
It's an emergency.
It costs money to see a doctor.
How can you be sure you're sick?
the father. He's sick.
Sick how?
like a skeleton.
I can't give you medication
without a test first.
I'm having contractions.
How far apart?
Six hours, four hours. I don't know.
It started last night.
You can't tell anyone
where you got it.
You take it now...
You give some to the baby afterward.
You can't breast feed.
Okay.
Where are you having this baby?
I need to stay here a few days.
Don't worry about the money.
You'll work it off later.
You selling these?
Tell me -
Are these the baskets
by the old woman on the hill?
they are.
All of them?
How much for the lot?
One-thousand, five-hundred.
Ay, ay, ay.
I would give you one thousand.
I'll take them all.
Ok, wrap them up.
Huku!
Yes, Granny?
It's time for you to became a man.
Granny?
she never woke up since you left.
I've come an awfully long way...
walking for days with these children
...to find our uncle.
- What's his name?
- Philisande.
Oh, I know Philisande.
He hasn't been around here in years.
Mr. Tong?
You must be in shock.
I don't know why they died.
Was there no doctor?
It happened very quickly.
If your family is dead and buried...
...what would you like
this office to do?
Don't you want to know
what happened to them?
Mr. Tong, I am curious,
to be honest.
It could have been dozens
of infections.
But curiosity isn't a reason
to disturb the dead.
You won't do anything?
I don't know what to do.
Mr. Tong?
I really am very sorry.
You're made a lot of people happy,
Zaohao.
You're our employee of the month.
I like to help out.
But there have been
some problems with the blood.
I need to have the equipment
repaired.
I've taken really good care of it!
I clean it every week.
When will it be back?
As soon as we've had it serviced.
Two days?
Two weeks?
I'll be in touch.
Pack up your things.
It's happened again.
What are you doing?
I packed up the van for you.
I want you to drop us off
in Shanghai.
I can't do this anymore.
You're imagining things.
No, we're making people sick.
This is the third time.
- Look at yourself.
- I give a pint a day! That's why.
these people give too often,
that's all.
It's greed, because they're poor
and they're all in debt.
like you are to me.
Just find a new village to set up,
and we'll meet up with you.
We have to leave now.
Before they figure it out.
Come on.
He'll ride with me.
I just spoke
with your provincial rep.
- He remembered your visit.
- He didn't know what to do.
What is your complaint?
My family died.
then your complaint is with Buddha.
Mr. Tong,
why have you come alI this way?
they asked me to. My neighbors.
they should let you get on
with your lift.
they're sick.
Your neighbors?
the people in my village.
- How many?
-All of them.
When the Health Officials
have made an assessment...
... they will implement a strategy
for all of you to follow.
It was like half my time.
Half my time spent worrying
about it.
I got so freaked out,
I'd go get drunk.
I would get so drunk, you know--
--that I'd wake up with
a businessman
or bus driver in my bed.
And I wouldn't see a condom
anywhere.
And I'd get paranoid that I got it.
So I stop having sex and I go
for a test and I DON'T have it,
and then I start worrying
about getting it again.
And the whole thing
starts over again.
It felt like-inevitable.
So I went out and I got it.
I went into chat rooms.
I found guys who would...
give it to me.
On purpose.
And it worked.
I got it.
You have a guest.
Thank you. You can go.
I'm sorry.
Hold him a few weeks.
No one will be pressing charges.
Image my surprise
when this boy Huku...
asks me for my teenage daughter,
to marry.
And what does he offer for
compensation for such a big surprise?
Such a great, bulky,
cumbersome surprise?
A hog and her piglets, Sister.
Which I suspect he stole.
I would not let such a cherished
girl go for less than 10 cows.
Absolutely not.
He has no mother, no father.
they tell me you nuns
take care of him.
Tell your neighbors
you're recovering.
Tell them we're helping you.
Why did you rush the barrier?
You wanted to see the people
from the ministry?
You shouldn't touch them.
It's going to be all right.
We're here to figure it out.
then we'll be able to help you.
This blood collection business...
...do you know who set it up here?
A lady in a white van.
You have to stay inside.
It's called House Arrest,
not Front Porch Arrest.
You have a beautiful field.
the weather's been petty good.
We should go back to the house.
You could get in deep shit.
Don't you have enough problems
without your crop going to seed?
It's probably too late.
On duty.
I'll help you tomorrow...
...in your paddy.
Just let it go!
I planted too much.
Testing costs ten dollars.
the whole thing's a scam.
He only paid me five dollars
when he gave me this disease.
- Don't I know you?
- I don't think so.
DVD subtitles:  CNST, Montreal