I don't remember anything...
Not even my name.
But I remember the day I came
here.
And I remember good the year
they say I turned 6.
I was angry that day.
But then I met you.
"Dear Mei Mei, my name is"
Dean Randall.
I'm from Australia, and I'm
"your sponsor."
"Sponsor... financial donor"
"or godparent in a baptism."
Yes, a parent from god.
"I work as a park ranger",
taking care of wildlife...
Animals and birds.
My wife, Jenny, looks after the
kids, Aiden and Maggie.
"And we live in Sydney."
"I want much seeing Sydney."
I want much meeting you.
"Yours truly, Mei Mei."
[ Children talking excitedly,
[ cheering ]
* once a jolly swagman camped
by a billabong *
* under the shade of a
coolibah tree *
* and he sang as he watched
and waited till his... *
it's all right.
* and he sang as he watched
and waited till his Billy
boiled *
hi.
I want... I want to go to this
place.
Yeah.
You know?
Yep. No, you're right.
So, okay...
> Hi. This place, this bus?
Yeah.
Hey! What are you doing?!
Back of the line!
Australian money only.
You can change it at the bank.
Hurry up!
Come on! Get a move on!
Please. Wait.
I-I have no time. Please...
no, no, sorry. It's got to...
here. I got it.
"Dear Mei Mei, we went to a"
Christmas concert at the beach
last week.
And because it's summer here,
it was really hot.
But it was a lot of fun.
I thought about you and
imagined you singing Carols
"with our children."
"Winter in China... sky"
always gray.
I like see blue sky, white bird
"in your picture cards."
"Our house is by the beach."
It's really beautiful.
On the weekends, we swim or
bushwalk or just stay at home
and play with the kids in the
"garden."
You are Mei Mei.
Wake up, miss.
Miss?
Mr. Randall?
Who wants to know?
How you do, Mr. Randall?
What are you, red cross or
salvos or something?
You sponsor me... send money.
I'm Mei Mei.
Right.
I'm... I'm Gary Randall.
You actually want my brother
Dean.
Where Mr. Dean Randall?
At beach?
Beach?
Please, I need see.
Mr. Randall and his family.
Please. Please wait!
Please?
Carl.
G'day, Gary.
Cashish time already, is it?
Come on, Gary.
You must own a calendar by now.
Sorry.
Please, wait.
Wait!
Please!
Look, look, I big trouble later.
My last chance was Mr. Randall.
I-I go Canberra tomorrow, but no.
Mr. Randall... just
brother Randall.
What?
I need to see Mr. Randall...
Not that one, the other one.
Mr. de Randall.
Y-you know?
Yeah, I know where he is.
Please take me. Please.
Hop on.
All right.
Now hold on tight.
Lean the way I do!
All right, well. Here we are.
Hey, how about... how about you
call me?
My name's Carl.
"Cow."
No, no.
No, not... no. "Carl."
Yes, yes... "cow."
I call "Mei Mei."
"Mei Mei"?
Okay. All right.
Well, you'll call me? Yeah?
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Hey!
That's it. Come on.
Let's go!
Come on.
You too. Let's go.
Not again.
Get out of the way.
Okay, first-timers.
We regroup at 4:00 sharp.
We bring back only what we take
out, all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, of course, boss.
All right?!
Yes!
What are you looking at?
I-I'm gonna sit there.
Bugger off.
Okay!
Address.
"Dress"?
No I.D.?
Driver's license.
You ask Mr. Randall.
He work here. He want to see me.
I don't think so.
Please? Mister, help me.
I need to see him.
Please, help me.
Can I help?
Mr. Randall... you know him?
What's the nature of your
relationship?
"Nature"?
Yes... trees, birds, the
beach.
No, sorry.
How do you know Mr. Randall?
He sponsor... parent from god.
He send me money.
I go school.
Please, help me.
Okay.
I look after Dean Randall.
His m.I.N. Number is 256904.
I'll sign her in.
I'll put my extension number
here for future reference.
Thank you. Thank you.
Can you sign your name in
here?
Okay.
How you do, Mr. Randall?
I Mei Mei.
I am Mei Mei.
Yeah, I know you are.
I want to say thank you,
Mr. Randall... for school,
for write me.
It was... it was nothing.
It... everything... for me.
I learn english.
I can read... read your life.
And your picture cards.
Yeah, the postcards, yeah.
I bring gift for you, but...
They take it.
Yeah, the... the screws would
take it.
No... the guard.
Yeah, the screws
security-check everything.
Did they... Secure each of
my letters, too?
How'd you get here?
Motor bicycle. Very fast.
But...
"Cow." Honda.
H-h-how'd you know I was
here?
Your brother... uncle Gary.
Right. "Uncle Gary."
So, what do you want?
Want?
Yeah.
I-I...
I-I don't understand.
Nothing seem like your words.
Nothing looks same... no like
picture cards.
What do you want?
I want to see you.
I want to see Mrs. Jenny, Aiden,
Maggie.
They aren't real, okay?
Wh... what this mean?
It means they don't exist.
Why?
You really shouldn't have
come here, you know?
Sorry, miss. Visit's over.
Visiting a prison can be a
very confronting experience.
Everything is wrong.
I ask stupid questions.
It's probably not your
fault.
Mr. Randall doesn't get many
visitors.
Everything
is wrong.
My car is over there.
Well, technically, she's got
to be missing for 48 hours
before she's considered missing.
But she is missing!
Not technically.
Hey, mate. How'd you go?
Hey, good, mate.
Fletch is in the office.
Thanks.
How'd you go?
Yeah, good.
Mrs. macneil lost her job, so
she missed a payment, but she
said she could pay next week, at
the latest.
Stupid woman.
She'll get her husband killed if
she's not careful.
Hey, Brian.
Good. Good.
Dad, she said she could pay
next week.
Can't you tell the guys to leave
him alone...
yeah.
No, cool.
Just one... macneil.
Yeah.
You are not gonna let them
bug you... do you understand?
Get back to your cell.
Tommy.
Ta-ta.
You sprung?
It's macneil's wife.
Hands up, macneil.
It's your warning.
Please, no!
You know the rules.
Get him up, Dwight.
Now, you listen to me, all
right?
You tell wifey on the outside
that she respects my timetable,
and then I'll respect you.
You understand?
Then we won't have all this
nonsense.
You didn't see anything,
okay?
Hey!
He asked you a question.
Leave him alone, Brian.
He's okay.
His brother always pays on time.
How many years have you known.
Mr. Randall?
Many years.
We talk in letters...
And picture card.
Nice.
And did he ask you to come to
Australia to visit him?
No. I come with orphanage.
Orphanage?
We sing for choir festival.
Right.
I love music.
My daughter plays the piano
really beautifully.
Unfortunately, she's... she's
given it up.
Thank you.
That's okay.
She has disobeyed the
regulations.
All meeting with sponsors should
be organized through our
orphanage.
It's a waste of our time.
I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
There's no evidence that my
client was involved in macneil's
beating.
I'm aware of that.
This protection-money racket,
cashish... is this the head guy,
Tommy fields?
Would help your chances at your
parole hearing.
We'd look after you.
Very well, then.
If you change your mind, contact.
Mrs. crenaugh.
Make sure Mr. Randall
participates in outdoor
activities and weekly
excursions.
I'd like the parole board to
consider the fact that my client
has been sponsoring a child for
many years.
Haven't you? In China?
I've met her. She's a nice kid.
If you want to see more of
her, I would consider the deputy
director...
she won't be coming back.
Mr. Randall?
Can I call you "Dean"?
What happened on the bus
this morning?
It's in the doctor's report.
Yeah, I read it...
"self-sabotage."
You know, Dean, it's not
uncommon for you to be feeling
anxious about your parole.
It's a big change in your life.
Do you want to make an
appointment, and we can have a
chat, or I can arrange some
counseling for you?
You didn't have to mention
the girl.
Well, should I mention you're
a park ranger, then?
She left this in my car.
10 years, you've been writing
to her and sending her money,
she told me.
So?!
Why?
I don't know.
It's just something to do.
"There's a family of eagles"
nesting in the bush near where
we live.
I love watching them fly.
They do kill to survive, but
they also play.
They certainly know how to
protect their young.
If you ever come to visit, I'd
love to show you our beach and
where the animals come to
"feed."
"the animals come to"
You'd like it here.
"You'd like it here."
And you can bring the other
children, too.
We'd love to hear you sing.
"We'd love to hear you sing."
* liang zhi Lao hu
* pao de kuã¡I
* yi zhi mã©I you er duo
* yi zhi mã©I you wei ba
* zhen qã­ guã I *
right, you lot.
Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Out. It's an order.
Get out there now.
Come on.
Throw it up here, mate.
Oi. Hey.
I heard they, they got you
into a little talk.
Anything I should know?
Are you deaf, Dean?
Tommy! Tommy!
Are we playing or what?
Go ahead. I'll be there.
Mei Mei!
* happiness is just a little
thing *
* humans mostly are too large
for it *
* if you cannot feel the joy of
spring *
* shrink yourself, and maybe
then you'll fit *
* happiness is just...
Make the beamers a priority.
Keep your eyes open for the
other ones?
Beamer. Right-o.
Be good.
Yeah.
Yeah?
G'day, mate. How are you?
Make sure that it's straight.
Yep.
Hold it.
Hold on to the wheel.
Grab the brace.
Okay.
Good.
They want to know if I can
still stay with you when I...
When I get out.
Is that okay?
Yeah, of course.
Where else would you stay?
I don't know.
Come on. Time.
They've got those halfway
houses and...
I haven't seen you for ages.
Yeah, sorry.
That place freaks me out.
I've been, you know... busy.
Yeah, you must have been.
It's been, like, eight months.
Hey, look, I have been
busting a gut trying to organize
things for you.
Yeah, all right.
Hey, I need you to come in
today, if you can, and sign
something for my welfare
officer.
What, you... what, you want
me to just drop everything?
It's for the parole hearing.
Yeah, all right. All right.
I'll...
I can do it after lunch.
Okay. Thanks.
I'll let her know.
Get off, mate.
Right-o.
Yeah?
I want to see cow.
Cow?
Cow? Like a... like a moo cow?
Like a... "Moo"?
Moo-moo!
Moooooo!
Oi!
Hello, cow.
"Cow."
back off, Dave.
This is Dave.
Don't worry about him.
I'm gonna break for lunch.
Yeah, sure you are.
Hungry?
Yeah?
You want to grab something to
eat, or...?
I want see Mr. Randall.
What... right now?
Yeah, look, I don't know how
they do things in China, but...
I'm not a taxi service.
Hey.
You just want to put your arms
around me again, don't you?
Sorry.
After you.
I tried calling your brother.
He's not answering.
I meant to say the other day,
it's really admirable what
you've done... sending donations
to that child for so long.
Might tell my other clients
about it.
I don't reckon Gary's gonna
show up.
Because many of my clients
need my help to rebuild their
lives after parole... form
connections again.
Why don't you go down to the
workshop?
I'll page you if your brother
turns up.
Yeah, good job.
Yeah.
Yeah, turned out well.
Yeah!
M.i.n. number is 256904, report
to the visitors hall.
M.i.n. number 256904.
Hey, visitor?
Christmas, is it?
You're up.
You coming?
Hey!
Screw bring gift?
Yeah. Yep. Thanks.
Panda bring you good luck.
And the cd is our choir, but
about five year old already.
I didn't think I'd... See you
here again.
I stay here.
Where?
Here... Australia.
What for?
You are alone. Me too.
Now we no more alone.
Yeah, but... but...
W-w-where you gonna live?
Who's gonna look after you?
You look after me already...
Many years.
Now I can look you.
No, no. I mean...
How are you gonna cope?
You no want me stay?
You don't know anybody.
I know uncle Gary and his
friend.
Uncle Gary doesn't have any
friends, okay?
All right? He...
He has alibis.
Do you know what that means?
That means you'll end up like
me, in a place like this.
Why are you in place like
this?
You never said anything to me
about y-y-your parents in any of
your letters and what happened
to them.
What... what happened to them?
Don't know. Don't care.
They don't want me.
I don't want them. Okay?
Would you shut up?!
Dad, I want to go!
All right.
I've always liked the name.
"Mei Mei."
It's... it's good.
It's... it's a cute little name.
"Mei Mei" mean "little
sister."
Not even real name, you know.
I big now.
I can find a stronger name
myself.
"Mimi."
That's right.
"Mimi" is a bigger name.
I no more crying "little"
"sister," like that one.
Hey, I told you... shut up!
No!
Hey, leave her alone, will
you?
Both of you, sit down!
Or what, bigmouth?
You two... outside, or the
visit's over.
Hey! Hands off!
She's just trying to help,
okay?
You don't like outside?
Children cry.
No one listens.
That father no good.
He no listen her cry.
Yeah.
Look.
Like your picture card.
Can I come tomorrow?
For the buses, okay?
A-and tell them my m.I.N.
Number, which is 256..
904.
Yeah.
Why... why you always go
first?
Hoo!
Well, they've already left
for Canberra, but they said
they'll be back on Sunday for
the Sydney concert, so...
Do you miss them?
Your friends?
Yeah?
Well, it can't be all that bad.
I mean, you like our beaches,
right?
Yes.
I've never been to beach before.
How old are you, Mimi?
I old enough.
You know, you shouldn't be so
trusting of everyone.
You shouldn't even trust me.
Who's coming in the water?
But definitely don't trust
these idiots.
You're going in the water!
No!
Water!
Put her down, Dave!
No! Carl!
Hey! Put her down!
Let me down!
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
Hoo!
All right.
Come on. Open the door, babe.
Open the door. I got to pee.
Yeah, this is it.
This is our place.
Open the door, babe.
I'm going! I'm going!
Hurry! I got to pee!
Don't do it. Don't do it.
Shut up!
Let's go!
And we're home sweet ho...
easy.
That's Dave and Ruby's room.
And this...
this is our room.
Dave.
Or you can sleep on the
couch.
That's cool, too.
Wait a minute.
Get these out...
Dave's left his junk everywhere.
You can watch TV if you
want.
Got some videos and DVDs.
Ruby's?
No.
Actually... that's mine.
Y-you cook?
Yeah.
Yeah...
Yes.
"Hello, Mr. Randall."
I 6 years old.
One tooth go bye-bye, and other
wanting to go, too.
I learn abcs.
I learn good because I want to
read your words and see your
face.
Mr. Randall, I tell you
everything...
Things I no tell others.
You always there... hear my
words.
Friends come, friends go with
new parents.
I no see them no more...
But I see you.
Miss chen, she says maybe I was
born in the year of the fire
dragon.
"Yours truly, Mei Mei."
* happiness is just a little
thing *
* humans mostly are too large
for it *
Anna, I've already paid for
it, and you can't even thank me.
There is nothing wrong with this
model.
Mine's still working, and it's
been two years.
Calm down.
It is just a mobile phone.
"Controlling"?
He said that?
Well, you can tell your father
that that is because I know...
God.
Anna?
Mr. Randall.
Can I... how can I help you?
To be honest, I have no
idea whether you can legally
sponsor a child to stay here.
Yes, there would be legal
restrictions, but, yeah, I can
check.
Okay.
Hey, Dean.
Burned Robert yesterday.
I didn't say anything.
You didn't say anything about
what?
About anything.
Hold yourself up.
Hey. Hey. Listen to me.
This is just a warning, all
right?
'Cause I care about you.
I do.
You stay quiet.
[ Joy enriquez's "all eyes on"
"[ me" plays ]
Okay.
Now...
We do clothes!
* decked out driving in my
red corvette *
* I got my hair in a ponytail
on top of my head *
* a fresh pair of blue jeans
with my white vanity *
* my shades on, and I'm ready to
roar *
* hit the town for the night,
everything's on me *
* shout out to all my girls,
are you ready, ready?" *
* all eyes on me,
are you ready, ready? *
yes!
You are so cool!
What you think?
I don't... I don't know.
Ruby think I hot, then
sometimes she say I cool.
What happened to face?
It's nothing.
Don't worry about it.
That no good.
You must look after yourself.
Yeah.
You sound like my mum did.
Well, except with a funny
accent.
Got some more money for
you.
No, no, no.
No need to give me money.
I work already.
You work already?
Doing what?
Wash car.
I clean inside, outside.
I clean good.
Yeah. I bet you do.
Y-you sing pretty good, too.
I, listened to that cd.
It's good.
Old songs. I sing no more.
My voice not the same.
You said in one of your letters
that, miss fong told you...
I think when you were about
14... that you were too old to
sing anymore, right?
And... and that you want to be a
conductor now.
Yeah?
Well, that...
That sounds good.
My job!
I come sometime tomorrow.
Yep.
So, you're the first one to
leave today?
We going?
You call the hostel again,
please?
Yeah, I already called
them.
They just said the same thing...
Sunday.
No, but, hey. Hey. Hey.
Don't worry about them.
Worry about yourself.
Dad.
What?
About that course I was... I
was talking to you about...
I already said no, didn't I?
Well, I could still do the
collection rounds for you, and I
get a student allowance, so I
wouldn't need any money.
Where's that course gonna get
you?
Well, chefs make good money,
dad.
Hey.
Come here.
Have a look at this.
You walk straight into it.
It's all yours if you want it.
Dave.
Do you like girls, Carl?
No, no. Don't touch that!
What?
What did you say?
Quit mucking around, Dave.
Get the car painted.
Yeah, we're on it, mate.
Change it... metallic silver.
Yeah, got it.
[ Jacqui hunt's "calisthenics"
[ plays ]
Good. Higher up.
What are you doing?
Take it off!
I'm changing the plate.
No, no.
We're spraying the car first.
You told me to change the
plate... I changed the plate.
No, no, no.
I come all the way down here to
help you out.
I don't want to touch stolen
cars...
no. Ruby, Ruby.
I don't want to touch them in
the first place.
Take a seat. Thanks.
So, what was that all about?
What do you mean?
Parole hearings can be
quite...
no. Not that.
What was that crap about you
testifying against Tommy?
Don't worry.
It's not gonna happen.
Then why were they asking?
'Cause they...
Gary... Gary, you were an
asset in there.
Now the parole board knows that
your brother has somewhere to
stay and that someone's gonna be
looking after him.
Hey, any more news about the
immigration lawyer?
Yeah.
You can't sponsor her because
of your record, but he can
organize a visa for her and look
for a foster family.
All right.
But it's not cheap.
It's $2,000.
Shut up, will you? Shut up.
All right, well, tell him to do
it.
He'd need an establishing fee
of $500.
That's okay.
And, as I said, you can't be
seen to be sponsoring her.
It would have to be anonymous.
Yeah, that's fine.
That's good.
Mrs. crenaugh, can you come
here for a moment?
Immigration?
The Chinese chick?
Listen, can you take
500 bucks out of my money?
Your money?
Yeah.
Mate, your money ran out six
months ago.
Why?
You keep stuffing up your
parole.
What are you talking...
there is no money there,
okay?
I am the one who has been
paying... overheads in here.
Yeah, but...
do you understand?
After all I've done for you.
What you've done for me?
I took the rap for both of us,
okay?
I'm the one keeping you alive
in here.
It's 500 bucks.
Can you do it or not?
Not if I have to pay Tommy,
as well.
Don't worry about that.
I'll sort that out.
Just make sure you get the money
to her.
You are lucky fletch has got
a big job coming up.
W-why are you still doing stuff
with him?
You're an idiot.
Where do you think I'm gonna
get the money from?
Jesus, Dean, grow up.
You can come in now.
Thank you for waiting,
Mr. Randall.
The board has reached a
decision.
Parole is granted.
You'll be released two weeks
from today.
Well, I'll tell you what I am
concerned about.
I'm concerned about fletch
taking more money than we've
agreed upon.
You're the one on the phone
talking to him.
If the phone's tapped, it won't
be m going down.
It'll be you.
I know, Tommy.
So this is your problem...
Not min all right?
All right.
Tommy?
Yes, Dean?
Man, I have to be a bit late
with the next cashish, I think.
Maybe... tuesday, if that's all
right?
Is he for real?
I mean, are you for real?
I just heard you're getting out
soon, Dean.
And now you're trying to wiggle
out of your last payment.
Don't do it.
Toddle off, Dean. Away you go.
For the beamer.
Thanks.
You good for Tuesday night?
Yeah. What is it?
Two this time.
Sweet.
How's your brother?
Yeah, he... good. Good.
Gets out in a couple weeks.
Fast pair of hands, your
brother.
Business expanding... be a real
asset.
I'll tell him you said hi.
Don't take all bloody day on
that thing.
Okay, Mr. fletch.
We do quick.
Hey.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Is that your daughter?
Yeah, that's right.
I've...
Got the...$500.
Terrific.
Thank you. I'll pass that on.
Count it if you want.
No, that's okay.
Thanks.
You all right?
Yep. Good night.
'Night.
Hello-o-o-o-o.
All right.
Hey.
Hi.
Come up.
N-no.
Come on, Mimi.
Got to learn to ride sooner or
later.
Hop up.
Right.
What you want to do is put both
your hands on the handlebars.
Yep? All right.
And what you got to do is when I
turn, you lean.
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
So when I turn, you lean.
Ready?
Lean.
Nice.
All right. Gonna go left.
Ready?
Lean.
Good!
And turn...
got to lean a little bit.
Okay?
Aa-aa-aa!
Is she okay?
Yeah.
Nice work, Carl.
Paint job's not bad, either.
All right, kiddies, it's just
like Christmas.
Hey!
Pizza!
There you go.
Thank you, fletch.
Now, Ruby.
Dave.
Thanks, mate.
And Mimi.
No, no, no.
You keep that.
That's yours.
But... look.
That's a lot of money,
Mei Mei.
Who are you working for?
Rich man. Nice.
Lots of cars.
He take our business.
What kind of business is it?
Is it legit?
Put that away, will you?
Is it legal?
I work hard.
Money's for us.
I not break a law.
Yeah, how do you know?
You sure?
Put it away!
You not believe me.
Well, just seems a bit suss,
that kind of money.
Why you no believe me?
I always tell you everything in
letters.
No lie. Always tell truths.
But you?
Picture cards all wrong... no.
Mrs. Jenny, no Megan, no Aiden.
And here?
You don't tell me why you're
here.
Why?
You want to know why I'm
here?
You want me to tell you?
Because I killed someone, okay?
Now, all we had to do was burn
down a print shop, and we were
gonna make a lot of money.
That's what Gary's mate
reckoned.
I'm sorry.
You know, the whole time, I
had a bad feeling about it.
But I just wanted that money.
So, you know, I just pretended
everything was all right.
There wasn't gonna be anyone
in that building, they reckoned.
Mr. Randall.
He died, Mei Mei, that old
man.
It was my fault.
Yes.
But you have paid.
I don't know about that.
And you have give me a good
life.
Well, you've got to live a
good life.
And not be doing things that
make you feel bad.
I don't feel bad.
Look, Mrs. crenaugh's gonna
try and help you, okay?
It's complicated, but s-she's
gonna try and find you a family,
and we're gonna take care of
you.
A family?
Yeah.
But... you are my family.
You don't want me?
No, no, no. It's not that.
You see, legally, I...
What I'm trying to say is,
you're gonna be taken care of.
All right?
When I get out of here, I'm
gonna come and see you.
All right?
I'm gonna get out of here in two
weeks.
Two weeks?
Yep.
So happy!
I will go to work.
You will see.
I can make money.
I will help you.
In two weeks, you will see.
That... t-that's him!
Yes! That's him!
That's him!
Nope.
Can't you help us out?
You have to calm down.
Hey, Gary.
So, my place, 8:00, yeah?
Two items.
Two different locations.
Yeah. Right.
Done.
Dad, I want to do one.
Seriously?
You reckon you're up to it?
I'm not doing it for free,
though.
Exploiting your old man, are
you?
Don't worry, kid.
You'll get your cut, you do a
good job.
You saving up for a new bike?
No.
I'm gonna go do that... that
course I was telling you about.
Did you get the money to my
welfare officer?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. She got it.
How'd you go with the... The
other thing?
You know... Tommy?
Good. Yeah.
Spoke to him, and, you know,
it's fine.
He'll wait.
All right.
Well, I don't... I don't
think you'll have to wait long.
Got a big job tonight.
I don't want to know about
it.
Thought you were all right
with fletch now.
Why would you think that?
Well, the Chinese chick...
Didn't you set her up with him?
What are you talking about?
Yeah, well, that's where
she's working... helping fletch
with the cars.
All right. Got to go.
Here you go.
What's the urgency?
I want to testify.
Against Tommy fields?
Yep.
Good.
That's good.
Why did you change your
mind?
What difference does it make?
I mean, that's what you want,
isn't it?
Well...
I'm glad.
I'll... I'll let the
deputy director know.
The thing is, I-i have to
get out today, okay?
I don't think that
that's possible.
Come on.
I mean, he can make it happen
if he wants.
You people are doing deals all
the time, right?
Okay. I'll try.
I am here to help you.
Nice!
All right, wait.
If you lift up the black thingy
and then scrub right
underneath...
hey.
Hey.
Mimi, want to come on a
joyride with us tonight?
Joyride?
This will be fun.
Okay.
Good girl.
I want you to check through
the transcript of your statement
for accuracy.
My client will need a
decree of protection before he's
released.
You did the right thing.
Thank you, Mr. Randall.
I didn't do it for you, mate.
Well, I didn't.
Bring it back.
Got you covered.
No, you've got to get over it
and like that.
See?
Tommy.
You-know-who has been talking.
Open up!
Open up, will you?!
Hurry up!
Paperwork?
Here.
I'll be seeing you later,
Randall.
Did you hear that?
Mimi?
What is she doing here?
We get her hands dirty, she's
part of the team.
She's part of us. Understand?
This was not part of our
deal, dad!
Deal?
Which particular position are
you deali from, Carl?
You wanted to come.
You're in or you're out.
Uncle Gary!
What's going on?
You know her?
How you do, uncle Gary?
That's... that's Dean's
kid.
The... the kid he sponsors.
You knew this?
What's going on?
What's she doing here?
Let's go.
You all right?
Yes.
Well... good luck.
Okay.
Who wants to do the honors?
Here, I'll...
I'll do it.
You up for it?
Come on.
No, it'll be all right.
Carl, what's this?
You... what are you doing?
It's got nothing to do with
you, Mimi.
You want to steal that car?
It'll be okay.
No.
It'll be all right.
That's wrong.
You no can do that.
That is... this is bad.
Hey, Mimi. Mimi.
Shut up and let him do his work,
yeah?
No, that's wrong!
It'll be okay!
It'll be all right!
Shut up!
You gonna do it?
Mate, come on.
Let's just call this off.
We should not have brought the
kids.
Hey, there's nothing wrong
with my kid, mate.
Just leave it.
You will be like Mr. Randall.
You will be inside...
you don't understand!
Just stay in the Van.
Don't go.
Are you gonna do it?
Yeah.
No! Don't!
Don't!
Stay in the Van.
This feel no good.
No good?
"Feel no good"?
Come on.
What's that supposed to
mean... "no good"?
You bad father!
Come on, mate.
Seriously, mate.
Fletch!
I said shut up!
Come here!
Just had it!
Uncle Gary!
Right! Come here! Come on!
No! No!
Uncle Gary!
I told you to shut up in
there!
No!
In the back! Go on.
No, no.
Stay there!
Get in! Get in the back!
Uncle Gary!
Shut up!
Uncle Gary, you help me!
Mr. fletch! This is wrong!
Get me out!
Hey! I'll punch your lights
out if you don't shut up.
Just ignore her.
Blue beamer, right?
Yeah... the automatic.
Get on with it.
Dave?
Where's Mei Mei?
Who the hell are you?
I'm Gary's brother.
Where is she?
She's with my
dad at the car yard.
Okay, well, you got to take
me there.
I can't, man. The car's hot.
I don't care!
She's in trouble, all right?!
Come on!
That should be down in the
garage!
Dean.
Where is she?
I don't know what you're
talking about.
I'm here!
Where is she?!
What are you doing?!
Just tell me where she is!
You'll bloody ruin
everything!
I don't know!
I told your brother!
Come on, fletch!
I don't want to hear...
Gary!
Hey, Gary!
Bring it back in now!
I just want Mei Mei!
You're gonna ruin it!
Where are you?!
Security 1 to base.
I need the police.
Roger that, security 1.
Dad! Dad, get off of him!
Where is Mei Mei?!
You shouldn't have brought
him here!
You're gonna bugger everything
up as usual, you bloody idiot!
No!
No! I'm here!
Mei Mei?
Mei Mei?!
Where is Mei Mei?
Mei Mei, just wait!
I'll get you out!
Mr. Randall!
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
Stop! Let her go!
Just wait, Mei Mei.
Dad! Dad! Dad!
Let go of me!
Stop!
All right, it's over!
Just stop!
Let go of me!
It's over!
You're an idiot!
Hey!
Hands behind your back.
All right.
Run!
Go!
No!
Stop! Not him!
Stop! Stop!
All right, hands behind your
back.
You're under arrest.
No!
Stealing cars?
I didn't steal anything.
I got you out of here this
morning, and now you are
straight back in here!
You don't understand.
Mei Mei was in trouble.
I was just trying to help her!
This is so disappointing.
Do you realize that the lawyer
has almost finalized Mei Mei's
temporary visa?
Where is she?
Is she here?
No!
She is locked up, thanks to you.
But that's all right.
We can sort that out.
We'll find her a foster family,
andcan look after her until
then.
Is she all right?
Can I see her?
She can't have anything more
to do with you.
Why not?
Or with this place.
Do something right for once and
let her go.
What she needs now is a nice
home and a responsible guardian
and someone with financial and
social stability.
And that's you, is it?
You don't even know her!
But what I know is that she
needs help.
"Mr. Randall, I tell you"
everything...
Things I no tell others.
You always there... hear my
"words."
She was brought in last
night.
I have authority to take her
into my care.
Mei Mei.
I have an interim order here
granting Mei Mei temporary
protection status.
Mei Mei, this is what you want.
You can stay here in Australia.
You can stay with me while we
find you a foster family.
I go back to China.
But...
No, but, Mei Mei, you can stay
here.
You can start a whole new
life... a nice house, good
school.
No.
Thank you.
* happiness is just a little
thing *
* humans mostly are too large
for it *
* if you cannot feel the joy of
spring *
* shrink yourself, and maybe
then you'll fit *
* happiness is just a little
thing *
* humans mostly too...
Always you appear real to me.
Please stay real.
Please.
For me.
Thank you.
D-don't move.
You're hurt... hurt bad.
You need to rest, Mr. Randall.
I'm sorry, Mr. Randall, but I
have something to tell you.
Children need me...
and I miss them.
So you...
You won't be here?
Yes. I will.
In letters.
And you will be with me, like
before...
But different.
Different.
Real?
I have a name for you.
May.
Mei?
That... that already my name.
May... may's spring in China.
And Autumn... here, it's Autumn.
So...
So you can be "may" in both
places.
It's a real name.
It's a big girl's name.
But, you know, in China, only
parents can give name to child.
May.
How are you feeling?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Where are you going?
To speak to the deputy director.
You don't need to speak
to the deputy director.
Yes, I do.
We had a deal, and he didn't
live up to it.
You didn't let me finish.
I've made all the arrangements.
They realize that they can't
fight any lawsuit you'd bring,
so you're free to go.
And joining the
Sydney children's choir today
is the dong ying choir.
Put your hands together and
give them a warm welcome.
This is the final performance of
their Australian tour.
* it's because I love you
* not because we're far apart
* and because you're near my
heart *
* oo-oo-oo-
* do what you wanna do
* be what you wanna be, yeah
* ooooooooooh
* do what you wanna do
* be what you wanna be, yeah
* be what you wanna be
* ooooooooooh
* do what you wanna do
* be what you wanna be, yeah
"dear Mr. Randall..."
Two new little Mei meis come
stay in orphanage last week.
I teach them sing.
Their voices are small, but
will be stronger next year for
when you come to see us.
Love, may.
* ooooooooooh
* do what you wanna do
* be what you wanna be, yeah
* ooooooooooh
* do what you wanna do
* be what you wanna be,
ye-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-a-a-a-*