Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
♪ (ROCKABILLY MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
WOMAN: Mario!
Hey, Mario! Hey, hey!
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
- Great party, Mario.
- (MARIO CHUCKLING)
♪ (SINGING) ♪
ESCARLETTE: Lobos!
Pass me the ball!
MARIO: Okay,
Escarlette, Escarlette!
Right here, on the left!
Come on!
ESCARLETTE: Lobos, over here!
Over here, over here!
- Yeah!
- (ALL CHEERING)
MARIO: Well done, Escarlette!
That's my baby,
that's my baby.
- (GASPS)
- (DISHES CLATTERING)
Mario!
I love your bottom, Katty.
Did I ever tell you that?
You have the best bottom
in Copiapo.
You're crazy!
- Hey, Mario.
- Hey, Manuel.
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
Come on, Copiapo!
Lucho.
Tomorrow is
my free day, but...
I would like to work.
I'm kind of short of money.
Tomorrow?
I know there is
a lot of people
asking you for
the same thing, but...
You got it.
That's it? You're not going
to fight me or anything?
I'm not going to fight you.
Thank you very much, Copiapo!
DON JOSE: Hola, Jessi.
Hello, Don Jose.
Alex, I found a job for you.
Rodrigo's going to be looking
for some help
in the body shop.
We talked about this
last time.
What's he going to pay, Dad?
50 a week?
You love birds
get the sonogram yet?
- ALEX: It's a boy.
- JESSICA: It's a girl.
- It's a boy.
- It's a girl.
It's a boy. It's a boy.
JESSICA: Alex, talk to him.
Okay.
Rodrigo, how are you, man?
- You talked to your old man?
- Yeah.
- How much you going to pay?
- 50 a week.
- You're going to have a baby.
Get your ass out of that mine.
DON LUCHO: Someone fill
this old man's glass.
Mario Gomez!
Congratulations
on your retirement.
45 years a miner.
- The bravest man I ever met.
- WOMAN: Gomez!
46!
DON LUCHO: 46.
MARIA: Empanadas!
Cheese, chicken, pino meat!
Empanadas!
- MAN: Good morning, Maria.
- Empanadas!
Dario.
I know you're not sleeping,
little brother.
I don't care if you don't eat them.
I'll always be here.
They're still warm.
Cheese, chicken, pino meat!
Empanadas!
Yonni, the bus is here!
What's she doing here, Yonni?
You live with me now.
I'm his wife, you bitch.
Why do you do this
to yourself?
- I made your breakfast.
- I know.
You made him breakfast?
She made breakfast,
that's what she does.
Marta, I didn't say
I didn't want it.
Guys, guys!
Here comes Don Giovanni.
Check this out. All right.
We have to find
a solution to this.
MARIO: Oh! (LAUGHING)
Okay, okay!
(ALL LAUGHING)
- Andale.
- Okay!
Hey, Mario.
You couldn't find a mistress
who lives on
the other side of town?
Admit it, you're jealous.
Uh... Believe me, I am not.
Nah.
I love you!
♪ (UPBEAT LATIN
FOLK MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Not dead yet, Segovia?
Not yet, Pastor.
Getting there.
Bolivian!
(BLOWS AIR)
Loser!
(COUGHING)
(ACTORS SPEAKING SPANISH
ON TV)
I found this on level three.
So?
We put these mirrors
in the cracks
so we know when
the mountain shifts.
She's an old mine.
The mountain
is going to shift.
The mirrors
are going to break.
I think we should get
a health check on the ramp.
- We may be looking at...
- The ramp is a good rock.
The mine's got another
20 years left in her.
We may be looking at
a weakness in the mountain's
internal structure.
Marco.
It's my job
to keep these men safe.
Correction.
Your job, Lucho,
is to keep these men
pulling out 250 tons a day.
250?
Your quota has gone up.
There's only so much gold
in the mountain.
Dario.
DON LUCHO: All right, guys,
we're working
rock bottom today.
Where is Carlos Mamani?
- Here.
- Everyone!
Say hello to Mamani,
our new boy from Bolivia.
He's a tin digger.
What does a tin digger
from Bolivia
know about mining for gold?
Elvis, not today, huh?
I got him.
Retirement papers, Gomez!
Two weeks,
and you're a free man!
Sign them
and get them back to me.
Bravo, Gomez!
DON LUCHO: Lobos, let's go!
Is that the only way in?
The only way in,
the only way out.
(MAN SHOUTING)
(MINERS CHUCKLING)
YONNI: You know Elvis didn't
write his own lyrics, right?
That's blasphemy.
Next you're going to tell me
he didn't do his own dancing.
(GASPING AND GULPING)
MAMANI: How much longer?
About an hour.
ALL: Whoa.
YONNI: Easy, Lobos.
Okay, huevones.
You know what to do.
DON LUCHO: You should
get it together. Dario.
Yonni, what's that?
Bolivia! Hey, Bolivia!
Kananni, Kachani...
What's your name?
Mamani.
Whatever, come over here.
I know, I know.
That's crazy Elvis.
He's just always
looking for trouble.
He actually thinks he's Elvis.
(SHATTERING)
ALEX: Rodrigo has offered me
a job in his body shop.
50 a week.
What do you think about that?
50 a week?
That's a joke, right?
And you're going
to be a father?
That's the problem.
You know what?
You're asking the wrong man.
And I have
a terrible hangover.
I don't know,
it's the same thing
- over and over with my dad.
- (RUMBLING)
What was that?
This is why we're here.
Yeah, I can taste it.
Copper and gold.
1,200 an ounce.
Take it. Take it. Yeah.
Cholo, you going to stick that
in your pocket for your mama?
What did you say?
Everyone knows that Bolivians
are a bunch of thieves.
He's stupid, you know that?
Chile stole this land.
After the War of 1881.
Who are the thieves?
That was...
1881, you know?
(CRACKING)
Run now! Run!
What the hell?
Oh! (SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING AND COUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
Dario!
DARIO: Alex, pull me up!
Pull me up!
Alex, don't let me fall!
- Alex, don't let me fall!
- Hang on, Dario.
Pull me up!
Collapse! Collapse!
Lobos! The carrier!
Gomez, come on!
Get on, get on!
Hurry up! Let's go!
(DARIO SCREAMING)
Come on, man!
Dario! Climb, Dario!
(YELLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
DARIO: Run!
Go!
Move it, move it!
Out! Out!
Let's go, everyone!
Come on, Henriquez, let's go!
Come on!
Get on! Get on!
Come on, get up!
Everyone hold on!
Lobos!
Come on, let's go!
Come on, come on!
- Go up!
- No, don't go up!
No, it's coming from above!
Head down to the refuge!
Head down!
HENRIQUEZ:
Head to the pick-up!
DARIO: Hey! Wait for us!
Yonni!
- Come on!
- HENRIQUEZ: Hurry! Let's go!
- Everyone in?
- Start it!
Up, up, let's go up!
Drive! Out, out, out!
Run, come on!
Go!
- Wait! Lucho!
- Hold on!
Hey!
Lobos! Slow down, slow down!
- Mario!
- Lucho!
DON LUCHO: Mario, get on!
- Help him up!
- Mario, go!
Get on, Elvis!
Bolivian!
They're in! Go, go!
ELVIS: Come on, man!
The Bolivian fell down!
- Stop!
- MINERS: Lobos, stop!
Lucho! Stop! Stop!
What is that?
Bolivian, come on!
- Come on!
- Mario!
Come on!
Run, run, run!
Come on! Run, damn it!
I got you!
(BOOMING)
Oh, shit.
Go!
Are we past it?
I hope so.
YONNI: It's okay. It's okay.
We're going to be okay, guys.
(HORN HONKING)
Go back!
It's coming from above!
ELVIS: The wrong way!
Go to the refuge!
Head down!
Yonni! Turn around!
DON LUCHO: Look out!
Stop! Stop!
No, no!
Go, go, go!
(MARIO GROANING QUIETLY)
(COUGHING)
(MAN COUGHING IN DISTANCE)
Gomez.
(GOMEZ WHEEZING AND COUGHING)
Gomez!
(COUGHING IN DISTANCE)
Alex!
MARIO: Alex!
You all right?
Come here.
Help me out. Quick.
Stay with him.
- ALEX: You okay, Gomez?
- Yeah.
- Let's get you up.
- DON LUCHO: Pastor?
Where's the pastor?
Henriquez.
Okay.
Pull!
(ELVIS GROANING)
Elvis.
You okay, man?
Guys.
You have to see this.
Oh, my God.
That's a big rock.
That's not a rock.
That's the heart
of the mountain.
She finally broke.
CASTILLO: Yes, sir.
Yes.
I got my people
checking it out now, yes.
We'll keep it contained.
I'll make sure no one leaves.
Come on!
Let's go!
Hey, Jose, there's been
a collapse in the mine.
They're locking us down.
I'm calling the news.
MAN: Nobody out!
Wait, Don Jose!
Stay here.
I'll call you later.
No! I'm coming with you! No!
KATTY: Hello?
What?
A serious accident
just occurred
at the San Jose Mine
40 minutes outside Copiapo.
The number of miners
trapped inside
has yet to be determined,
but the company estimates that
30 men were working below.
DON LUCHO: 29...
30...
31, 32...
33.
We're all here.
I thank God for that.
The refuge is built for 30.
So... we're okay.
What do you mean?
What do you mean "we're okay"?
The ramp is blocked, Mario.
There's no road.
We have no way out.
What about the chimneys?
There's ladders there.
Too dangerous.
I am not ready to sit
down there in the refuge
and wait for help.
Mario.
My job is simple.
I have a duty to the safety
of these men.
At this moment, the refuge
is the safest place.
There's a radio.
There's food.
Some of these guys
need patching up.
You know me, Lucho.
There is no way out
until there is no way out.
I'm going to check out
those ladders.
Don Luis. Excuse me.
I'm coming with you.
All right, come on. Bolivian!
We should make a lot of noise.
Burn tires, bang on pipes.
Make a big racket.
You never know.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING QUIETLY)
WOMAN 1: What are they doing?
WOMAN 2: We have to wait.
WOMAN 3: It's okay.
Hey, talk to us!
Five hours we've been here!
GUARD: We told you already.
The company has the situation
under control.
KATTY: Get Castillo here!
Get off your bony ass...
Okay!
Everybody, shut up!
Or I'll have you removed!
Now, go home
and wait to be contacted!
(CROWD SHOUTING ANGRILY)
Who threw that?
I did.
What are you going to do?
Shoot me?
GUARD 2: Get off the property!
And you, too!
All of you! Go!
Get out of here!
Go home!
Come on!
Hey, where are you all going?
Come back.
No, please.
We have to stand our ground.
We have to stay put.
What do you want us
to do, Maria?
They have not
told us anything!
That's because
they're hiding something.
And there's a reason for that!
We have to stand our ground.
We have to stay put.
Where are the rescue teams?
Huh?
Where are the drills?
Why isn't anybody
doing anything?
My brother is down there!
We're not going anywhere.
We have to stay here.
- ESCARLETTE: She's right!
- We want to stay!
Hey! Put that down!
Put that down!
- Get used to it!
- Stop that!
MARIA: We're not
going anywhere!
PINERA: This is
a private mine?
GOLBORNE: Yes, sir.
Bohn and Kemeny.
Chilean nationals.
33 men trapped underground.
And we don't even know
if they're alive?
PEREIRA: The responsibility
rests with Bohn and Kemeny.
The government has no
obligation to take a position.
We should have
no position on this.
- What are they doing about it?
- Nothing.
They don't have
the capability.
I think the government
should show its face.
I'd like to go up there
and take a look at it, sir.
You've never set foot
in a mine, Laurence.
What makes you think you
can make any difference?
You've been in the job
for what? 4 months.
If we don't react,
if we bury our heads
we look like we don't care.
That's bad for the industry
and that's bad for Chile.
With all due respect, sir,
it's not about us.
I believe we have
a moral responsibility.
33 lives is
a lot of dead people.
MARIO: Keep going.
Stop!
Come on, Alex.
MAN: Someone has to hear.
DARIO: Lobos.
You're wasting your time.
No one is going to hear us.
No one is going to help us.
Hello, this is Luis Urzua.
HENRIQUEZ:
I'll check first aid.
Hello, this is Luis Urzua.
Can you hear me?
- (YELLS)
- (THUDDING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Shit.
ALEX: What?
MARIO: There's no more ladder.
What do you mean
"there's no more ladder"?
I'm telling you,
it's not here.
ALEX: No, no.
No. No.
Moving on.
Alex.
Let's go back.
Okay.
Damn it.
MARIO: No! Alex!
(ALEX SCREAMING)
Hold on!
ALEX: I can't hold on!
- Mario!
- Hold on!
HENRIQUEZ: Our Father,
who art in Heaven...
Lord Jesus Christ...
You, who are
the son of our Creator...
We ask you to grant us
strength and fortitude
in our tribulation.
We ask you today
to protect our families.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
It's the government. Hurry up.
Can you please let me through?
We want answers.
GOLBORNE: That's why
I'm here, madam.
But I can't give you answers
unless you let me in.
Or I can have them remove you.
Go ahead and try it.
If you want a little riot
on TV tonight.
You're from
the government, right?
Laurence Golborne.
Minister of Mining.
There are a lot of unhappy
people out here, Laurence.
It's been two days, and no one
has told us anything!
We all know how this goes.
The government shows up,
some good-looking
guy in a suit
tells us how much they care.
How much they're going to stop
at nothing to save them,
and they do nothing!
We're not going to stand
for it, Laurence.
I want you to promise me
you'll do something.
I can promise you we're going
to do everything we can.
Okay?
Okay, go ahead.
- Move, let them through.
- GOLBORNE: Thank you.
ALL: We want answers!
We want answers!
Let's say they are alive.
How long do they have?
CASTILLO: Assuming
they're alive and they make it
to the refuge
there's enough food and water
for three days.
And what attempts have been
made to reach them?
I sent a crew of my men down.
A couple of them
were almost killed.
(SIGHS)
So what can we do next,
Mr. Castillo?
Nothing.
Well, what's protocol, then?
Protocol?
This mountain is still moving.
I've been a miner
for 25 years!
I've seen 5 collapses!
You know how many
men we saved?
No one!
JESSICA: Minister, can you
tell us anything?
Yes.
The government is
assessing the situation.
KATTY: Are they alive?
Do you know?
MAN: What did they tell you?
The mine is
extremely unstable.
And dangerous for rescuers.
Therefore,
we have to suspend
any further rescue attempts
for the moment.
You promised!
GUARD: Grab the Minister!
You liar!
Close the gates!
WOMAN: It's not right!
MARIA: You're abandoning us!
Stand over here, sir.
You promised!
- Please! He's my dad!
- My husband's down there!
(SOBBING)
GUARD: Please step back.
Help us!
Lunchtime.
I think we should
wait for everyone.
Why?
- I'm hungry.
- YONNI: Dario.
This food is for an emergency.
So, what is this, Yonni?
A picnic?
Take it easy.
I'm going to eat, Yonni.
Come on.
- Dario... Use your head.
- I want you to move.
- Dario! Hey!
- Move!
Come on!
Look at this crap.
Works for me.
You knew, didn't you?
You knew they never
finished the ladders.
You knew this place
was a deathtrap
but you let us come down
anyway, Lucho.
Listen.
I asked Castillo
about the ladders.
I asked him again and again.
He had the certification!
YONNI: Don Lucho!
What is going on there?
Don Lucho!
(MINERS CLAMORING)
MAN: Give it back!
Don Lucho! Look at this!
Give me the key.
Give me the key!
You took the food!
What are you doing, Dario?
- Having lunch.
- Oh, having lunch?
You're having lunch?
- This is my food.
- Relax! Stop it!
Back off!
Stop it! Stop it!
Calm down!
It's just some cookies.
What's the big deal?
"What's the big deal?"
Let me tell you.
- There is no ladders to climb.
- Yeah.
ALEX: And the chimneys
just caved in.
MAN: What?
And there is a huge rock
blocking our only
way out of here.
Guys.
We are buried alive.
That is the big deal.
This is all the food we have
left to keep us alive.
We have to
ration it carefully!
If we plan on surviving down
here until we are rescued!
Rescued?
Do you hear any drills?
That's because
they're not drilling for us.
We're too far down.
It took 100 years for them
to dig this deep.
How long do you think
that's going to take?
Do you think
the owners are going
to spend that kind of money?
They didn't even
finish the ladders!
They'll wait three days,
then close the mine
and put up the gravestones.
MARIO: No.
No, no, no, no!
I don't believe that!
They'll dig us out!
And if they don't,
our families will!
With their bare hands,
if it's necessary!
I believe we'll make it
out of here
because I choose
to believe it!
All 33 of us.
You, Lucho, you believe
whatever you want.
It's your problem.
Yep.
Yeah. That's the way.
That rescue better
get here pretty quick.
Yep. Give me.
There's 18 cans of tuna.
165 grams a can.
33 men,
that's 90 grams a man.
That's half a can.
A little more
for the rest of your lives.
Anybody else?
Thank you. Come on.
Hey.
Thank you.
- Mario.
- Give me.
GOLBORNE: Early today, the
mining company's rescue team
made an attempt
to enter the mine.
Through the
ventilation chimneys.
But, a secondary collapse
blocked off
any possible access to it.
The mining company has now
relinquished control.
Are you watching this?
The Chilean government is
taking over this operation.
SOUGARRET: Of course.
I need you up there,
Sougarret.
As soon as possible.
Golborne is going
to need help.
Everyone I speak to says
you're the best
in the business.
Thank you, Mr. President.
I appreciate that.
And you appreciate
that we can't afford
to fall on our asses
in front of the whole country.
Which one of you is
Laurence Golborne?
Can I help you?
Sougarret. Andre Sougarret.
I'm your new chief engineer.
Says who?
The President.
Now, assuming they're alive,
we got 33 men down there.
They are running out
of food and water.
But there is adequate air.
We know that they can survive
for a period of time if
they are relatively healthy,
but we don't know that.
Some of them could be injured.
Some of them are in the early
or later stages of silicosis.
Miner's lung disease.
What I do know, is that if we
don't get them up fast,
we're going to be
bringing up 33 corpses.
Here's what we know.
The men were working
in the lower half of the mine
when it collapsed.
That puts them here,
at the refuge.
A 5 meter-wide space
200 stories down.
My readings indicate
that a massive rock
displaced itself here.
We're talking about
700,000 tons of diorite.
Or twice the mass
of the Empire State Building.
Obviously,
we can't go in through the
front door, so to speak.
So we're going
to have to drill.
Best case scenario,
we reach them in eight days.
Eight days?
They're too far down,
too deep.
Eight days?
But that's not
the biggest problem.
It's the deviation factor.
Look. Here's the refuge.
If you run these drills
24 hours a day
at full speed,
the drill is going
to deviate, like this.
Or like this.
In fact, it can bend
20 different ways.
And even if everything goes
according to plan,
the odds are still
going to be against us.
What exactly are you saying?
What I'm saying, Minister,
is that there's a less than
1% chance of finding them.
I need every drill that you
can get your hands on.
And I want them here
as soon as possible.
- Mario.
- Yeah.
This one has less.
- Which one?
- This one.
- Is everybody happy?
- Yeah.
All right, ladies.
Next meal in 24 hours.
How are we supposed
to survive on this?
If we get hungry, we can
always eat the Bolivian.
(MINERS CHUCKLING)
I heard Bolivians
taste like chicken.
WOMAN: Look! Look!
- MAN: They're bringing drills!
- (CROWD APPLAUDING)
WOMAN: The drills are here!
MARIA: We did it.
ELVIS: Okay.
Twist it. Twist all those
wires together.
There will be light.
You cannot live without light.
MARIO: Tell me, Alex...
Why do you think having a boy
is so much better
than having a girl?
Yonni, what is it
about a guy like you?
Face like a horse's ass,
nappy hair, bad breath,
you fart in your sleep.
How come the ladies
love you so much?
There's 33 guys down here
and I'm the only one
who has a little something
going on, on the side?
No, not in the house
across the street, man!
At least close the curtains!
(ALL LAUGHING)
She doesn't have curtains!
(ALL CHEERING)
Elvis is in the building.
Shh!
(SHUSHING)
You hear that?
(FAINT HUMMING)
It's a drill.
They're looking for us.
Is that not the sweetest sound
you've ever heard?
SOUGARRET: The job
is so much more
complicated than I thought.
I really want to be there
for Ivy's birthday.
Tell the girls
I miss them so much.
HURTADO: Stop, stop!
Look, I've got to
call you back.
What happened?
Sougarret! What happened?
You see this diorite?
Twice as hard as granite.
This is the problem.
We're going to need
new drills.
Okay, I can get you
more drills, but
- we're running out of time.
- I know.
Why are you burning
through them so quickly?
Listen, I don't have 6 months
to explain to you
the complex geology
of the Atacama Desert...
- That's not what I asked...
- You want to be a miner?
Get a book, read the basics.
Start with orogenesis.
I got 33 men down there
I've got to worry about.
You do what you need to do.
Be a suit,
go talk to the media.
Let me do my job.
Why is it taking so much time?
I know you're all
growing restless.
I know you want answers.
But I'm here to assure you
that we are doing everything
we possibly can
to make contact
with your loved ones.
We need to know
if they're alive.
I don't have a definitive
answer right now.
That's the truth.
We have 10 drills
working 24 hours a day.
Look, I know
how you must feel.
I'm going to expand
accommodations
for your families.
I'm setting up a commissary,
a medical facility,
and a temporary school
for your children.
- That's all for now.
- (CROWD CLAMORING)
REPORTER: Minister!
We know the mine
is very dangerous.
It can collapse in any moment.
Minister!
MARIA:
Hey, Minister of Mining.
Don't look at me like that.
I'm not going to slap you.
I'm not saying
I'm never going to slap you.
You kept your word.
What's your name?
Maria Segovia.
Dario's wife.
Sister.
He's my kid brother.
I'm not leaving without him.
(GASPING)
They're everywhere!
Please get them off me!
Get them off me!
They're everywhere!
I need a drink! Oh, God!
HENRIQUEZ: Dario.
I'm dying. I'm dying.
We're all dying.
We're all going to die.
It's okay.
There's a lot worse things
in life than death.
How come you have time for me?
Huh?
Why don't you hate me
like everybody else?
Why? Why?
Hate
is for children.
If we can just
be good to each other,
we might find
a way out of here.
We can say a prayer together,
if you like.
I don't know the words.
God doesn't care.
HENRIQUEZ: Merciful Father.
DARIO: Merciful Father.
Take
this boy.
Open his eyes.
So he can see.
I'm sorry.
(SOBBING)
It's okay.
- It's okay.
- I'm so sorry.
DRIVER: Maria, where to?
This way, please.
- Yes, Mayor.
- Good, good, good.
Okay, we're going to school.
Single-file, please.
File in behind me, please.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
That one.
- Thank you, Susi.
- Enjoy. Nice to see you.
OFFICER: Excuse me.
What's your name?
What's she been saying?
What are you doing, Marta?
Her name is Susana Valenzuela.
- Don't do this. Marta!
- She's my husband's mistress.
Sorry, Susana,
but only family members
are permitted
inside the fence.
No putas allowed, sorry.
But I am his family.
I love him,
and he loves me too!
He loves you?
(WOMEN SHOUTING)
- Take her stuff.
- You can throw me out,
but I'll be back.
And when Yonni comes up,
and he will come up,
we'll see who he loves best!
What is this?
Food and water is low.
We have to make it last.
One tablespoon of tuna
every other day,
and a shot of water
once a day.
That's it.
ALEX: I ran it through
a filter I made.
It sucks, but it's just
about drinkable, okay?
Alex.
Do yourself a favor.
Yeah?
If we get out of here,
find yourself
a new line of work.
Shut up, Gomez.
Shut up!
We're getting close.
Adding the last pipe section.
How many sections?
MAN: We got five left.
- SOUGARRET: Okay.
- We need to set it.
It's a little tight.
We're getting
extremely close, sir.
Six!
We're down to
the last 6 meters.
Five meters!
Four!
(RUMBLING)
- Yeah!
- (MINERS CHEERING)
We need to mark it!
Yonni! Get some paint!
When the drill comes through,
we all have to make
a lot of noise!
- Write a note!
- I've got it!
What?
What happened? Mario?
It's below us.
The thing's below us.
At least they are looking
in the right place.
You still don't
get it yet, do you?
It took them this long
to get that close!
They're not going to look
for us forever, Mario.
We're starving, Mario!
When they get back,
we will be dead!
- Alex.
- (GRUNTING)
Alex!
Hey!
(ALEX SOBBING)
I've been a miner all my life.
I let you down!
I let myself down.
I knew this place
was dangerous!
We all knew about this place!
Nobody's blaming you!
You want to blame somebody?
Blame Castillo,
blame the owners!
Where is Alex?
Nothing.
SOUGARRET:
It's the deviation, Laurence.
We can't figure it out.
We missed by 10 meters.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
MARIO: That's 100 years
of piss and shit
down there.
Alex!
If you really want to do this,
don't do it alone.
- Are you crazy?
- No, let's do it together.
Yes, I am crazy! I am crazy!
I am completely
out of my mind.
But you know what?
I have a daughter.
And a wife.
And you have a wife
with a baby on the way,
and they're counting
on you, Alex.
My baby.
We need you, man.
I need you.
SOUGARRET: We've already
burnt through nine drills.
This...
This is becoming
an impossible situation.
Sometimes
impossible situations
can take a little longer.
Laurence, our guys are already
in acute starvation.
If they are even alive.
I think we've got to start
asking ourselves
the really tough questions.
How long do you think
we can keep this up?
Hmm?
SOUGARRET:
What's going on here?
They know the rule.
No families allowed.
It's Don Francisco.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SIGHING)
(SCREAMS) Shit!
God damn it, Mamani!
You scared the shit out of me.
What are you doing here?
The same as you.
What's with the knife?
Are you going to
cut me up and eat me?
They say Chileans
taste like chicken.
(CHUCKLING)
Maybe you've noticed...
I don't have a lot
of friends down here.
Where's your head lamp?
I never got one.
Here.
Listen, Mamani...
Nobody is eating anybody
while I am here.
Did you get that?
I'm so scared.
I don't want her growing up
without a father.
Tell me it's going to be okay.
- Just say it...
- I can't.
Just tell me that
it's going to be okay.
Jessi, stop it.
You know it as well as I do
that it's not gonna be okay.
I have been wanting
to say something.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry that I have
stolen from you guys.
I just hope that one day
you can forgive me.
I have been
saving these for you.
I just wish I had a box
of them to give you.
Thank you, Dario.
Thank you from all of us.
What I wouldn't do for
one of your sister's
empanadas right now.
♪ (HYMN PLAYING) ♪
Bless this food. Amen.
Mmm.
(CHUCKLES)
Jessi.
Oh, my God.
Baby.
MARIO: Katty.
(SNIFFLING)
KATTY: It's gonna be okay.
Mom, what are you doing here?
Look how skinny you are.
Yonni, eat.
Charquican.
Your favorite.
Excuse me.
(COWBELL RINGING)
Fresh milk.
Anyone?
(ALL LAUGHING AND CHEERING)
I just...
I just want you to know
that...
I couldn't be
prouder than I am
to share with you
this last meal.
With all of you.
If that is the case,
if this is our last supper,
I am officially handing in
my retirement papers.
I quit!
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
You called it off.
It wasn't my decision.
And this?
A memorial?
A poem for the gravestones,
a few words by Pablo Neruda.
That has nothing
to do with me.
This is bullshit. Look.
Those people out there are
counting on us.
On you and me.
33 men underground.
300 mothers, fathers,
brothers, sisters,
and we are their only hope.
Snap out of it, Laurence.
It's a false hope.
- And you're giving up!
- Three days' food?
That's all they had.
They are down there
for 16 days.
You are giving these families
false hope.
They can survive
40 days without food.
Not under those
conditions, Laurence.
It's 100 degrees down there.
Do you know what that's like?
It's a tomb!
I understand how you feel.
I feel the same.
I know that your heart is
in the right place.
And where's yours?
It's not about you!
It's over!
It's over, Laurence.
♪ (ACOUSTIC GUITAR PLAYING) ♪
♪ (JESSICA SINGING
IN SPANISH) ♪
(CROWD CHANTING)
♪ (SINGING CONTINUES) ♪
I have something for you.
Hi.
MARIA: It's the best
empanada in town.
Mmm.
I mean well.
I do.
I say everything I think.
That's my trouble.
I aim to please.
Somehow I...
I always find a way to miss.
Not by miles,
but I can't seem to learn
from my mistakes.
You have to sleep.
Thank you.
We heard the news, Minister.
I'm sorry.
Don't be. No one is dead yet.
Restart the drill.
You got it.
You have the azimuth?
Who?
The azimuth.
The angle, Minister.
SOUGARRET: Hey, Laurence.
You need some help?
What's on your mind?
GOLBORNE: Ground.
Refuge.
Drill.
Look at the direction.
Look how I drew it.
Yes, but I don't
get your point.
We learn from our mistakes.
Let the toughness
of the rock be the guide.
Your drill is facing
in the wrong direction.
Exactly.
This doesn't make any sense.
Only if you aim to...
Miss.
Are you crazy?
You'll bring the mountain down
on top of these men.
Stop trying to think
like you're some kind of...
Why, yes.
We use the deviational
measurement
from our last miss.
And we already know where
the rock is at its most dense.
It's so simple.
Learn from your mistakes.
Aim to miss.
(CHUCKLES)
Now you're thinking
like a miner.
HURTADO: Keep it going!
20-degree inclination.
- HURTADO: Keep going!
- More.
That's it!
MAN: 35!
Perfect!
ALEX: If I have a girl,
I'm gonna call her Esperanza.
Jessi would like that.
DARIO: Come on, Pastor.
Drink.
Stay with me, Pastor.
Our Father,
who art in Heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Forgive me, my Lord.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses,
as we forgive
those who trespass against us.
And lead us not
into temptation
but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
(RUMBLING)
Drill.
Drill!
Hey!
Come here! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Drill!
It's here!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
Look, look! Look.
Look. Hey! Hey, guys!
ALL: Hey!
(ALL CLAMORING)
We're here! We're here!
(WORKERS CONVERSING)
Shh! I hear something.
Someone's alive.
Shut down the generators.
Could be rock fall.
Stethoscope.
Here.
(CLANGING THROUGH STETHOSCOPE)
(ALL SHOUTING)
I have the note.
I have the note!
(ALL CHEERING)
HURTADO: Okay, stop!
It's been painted.
You sure it wasn't
there before?
- Definitely not, sir.
- There's something there.
Where?
- HURTADO: Oh, my God.
- (LAUGHING)
HURTADO: Oh, my God!
This message comes to us
from the depths of the earth.
From the very hands
of our miners.
"We are all well
in the refuge.
- "The 33."
- (GASPING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Viva Chile, mierda!
Susi!
Marta!
He's alive!
PINERA: They're safe!
They're all safe!
I knew you could do it.
We found them.
Now we got to get them out.
Nobody has ever done
anything like this before.
(ALL CHEERING)
PINERA: God bless our miners!
God bless them!
GOLBORNE: It's Luis Urzua,
the supervisor.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I can hear you.
This is Laurence Golborne,
the Minister of Mining.
How are you?
17 days is a long time,
and after 17 days,
you wouldn't have blamed
rescuers for losing hope.
Until they got the sign,
that is,
that 33 miners, all of them,
2,000 feet down,
were okay.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
The families today
get a chance
to do what they do
once a week.
They get to meet
via video conference
with their loved ones
down below
for about 8 minutes.
Three platforms
are now in place,
specialized in deep drilling.
The Australian drill, Plan A,
is going directly into the
miners' emergency shelter
which is 2,300 feet
below the surface.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Down here is Plan B.
Now, this is a T-130 drill.
That is going to be manned
by the U.S. engineer
Jeff Hart.
It's a pretty
blunt instrument.
It's like a huge jackhammer.
But it could get through
the ground very quickly.
One guy has a drug problem,
another suffers
from depression,
another guy is bipolar.
These men are going to start
killing each other
if they're down there
for much longer.
And this is going to go on
for 3 months at least.
Three months?
- Are you recording?
- ALEX: Yeah.
Uh...
My name is Mario Sepulveda.
Welcome to the
San Jose Mine Resort Hilton.
We'll take a look around.
YONNI: Guys,
more palomas coming in!
Nikes.
And iPods for everyone!
YONNI: Hey, Gomez!
Here are your dirty magazines.
- KATTY: Mario?
- ESCARLETTE: Hi, Dad.
- Can you hear us?
- Can you hear, Dad?
Yeah. Yeah.
How are you?
Other than skinny.
- Katty.
- You're so skinny.
Escarlette.
It's okay, Dad.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(JESSICA CHUCKLING)
Here it is.
I couldn't see if it was a boy
or a girl.
Let it be a surprise, Alex.
I don't want to know.
As long as you two are good.
That's all that matters.
Dad...
Alex.
I've missed you.
MARIO: Another one of us.
No, don't, don't...
People don't need to see that.
And the fact that I was
in the military for a while
allowed me just to know
how to organize people.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
You are famous, Mario.
Don Francisco was here.
He said last night
that you were the most
famous man in Chile.
Don Francisco said that?
We will get you out.
And to see your families
by Christmas.
We'll be waiting for you.
Goodbye, and God bless.
- All right, he's gone.
- Christmas?
- Listen, listen.
- That's 3 months!
(ALL SHOUTING)
No, listen! Listen to me!
Disappointing news from Chile.
The Canadian drill, Plan C,
has been shut down
indefinitely
due to unexpected
technical difficulties.
The drill and its team,
which the families had
high hopes for,
are now headed home.
(DARIO BREATHING SHAKILY)
Have your husband sign them.
And please,
if you have any questions,
call me, okay?
I'm going to read them
and talk to Mario.
We're talking about
a lot of money.
Katty,
keep it to yourself.
- WOMAN: Farkas!
- Look, it's Farkas!
How are you, how are you?
I'm going to give you
enough money
so your husbands don't have
to work for a year.
I'm going to give you
each $10,000.
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
Dario.
The huge slab of rock,
the so-called "megastone,"
twice the size of the
Empire State Building,
is believed to have shifted
in the last few hours.
It has added yet more urgency
to the rescue effort here,
on the surface.
We hit steel.
Most likely
a horizontal support.
A beam or something.
Anyway, we busted the bit.
Bitch is stuck down in that
borehole like a dummy.
Let's replace the bit.
No, the piece of bit
is 1,420 feet down there.
We're not drilling until we
get that piece out of there.
However that is.
I'm calling
my contacts in Brazil,
get us some big old magnets.
Mario, there's no drills.
They're not drilling.
Are you listening to me?
Okay, that's good.
ELVIS: Hey, Yonni,
listen to this.
"Marta,
"the wife of miner
Yonni Barrios,
"had Yonni's mistress
removed from Camp Hope
"for the third time."
(ALL LAUGHING)
"Susi, Yonni's mistress,
"is happy being
a home wrecker."
Now the whole world thinks
that Susi is a whore
and that
I'm a two-timing scumbag.
Well... (CHUCKLES)
That's not right.
YONNI: I don't believe this.
Our fearless leader,
Super Mario,
who will tell anyone
who is willing to listen
that he is the one solely
responsible for our survival,
has been offered
a book deal for
"an undisclosed sum."
Undisclosed sum, huh?
What's the sum, Mario?
Were you planning on
having any of us
in this book deal?
- Did you do it?
- YONNI: Of course he did it.
You know what,
"Fearless Leader"?
We're going to get along
just fine without you.
You really think I need you?
Any of you?
You know, the leader
makes sure you don't starve.
The leader keeps
the lights on.
No, you had some help
with the lights on.
Yes, me.
What are you doing?
- We don't need you!
- You did this, Mario!
LOBOS: We've had enough.
Get out of here!
The leader never gives up.
You know,
you wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for me.
I never asked for this.
You gave it to me.
You listen to me, Golborne.
None of your drills
are working.
That is unacceptable!
We spent millions of dollars
bringing them down here.
We made no secret of that.
Now you tell me
the American drill is down?
The drill bit fractured
in the borehole,
but we have magnets
coming in from Brazil.
Heavy-duty magnets...
I don't want to hear
about your magnets!
The mine is crumbling!
We're running
out of time, Golborne.
There's talk of lawsuits
and criminal charges
from the families.
I don't have to tell you
the miners occupy
a privileged position
in the affections
of the Chilean people.
The last thing we need
is these men dying
with the whole world watching!
I don't think it's going
too far to say
that the future
of this administration
depends on the outcome.
Mr. President, I can...
(PHONE BEEPS)
MARIO: Dario.
You want to say
something to me?
You know Maria,
my sister, right?
Yeah.
I have been mad at her
all of my life.
She abandoned me
when I was just a kid.
I mean, she was a kid also,
and had already raised
my other five siblings.
She just needed her own life.
I couldn't see that before.
I know she's up there,
I know she's waiting for me,
but what am I supposed to say?
What am I supposed to do
when we get out?
If we get out.
You hug her
and you cry like a baby.
Forgive her for everything
that she has ever done.
You pray to God
that she forgives you.
She's your family.
Maria is all the family
you've got.
Family...
Family is all we have.
♪ (ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING QUIETLY) ♪
That's my iPod.
You're a thieving
Bolivian Indian.
- We all got iPods.
- It's my iPod.
- It's not yours.
- Give me my iPod.
- It's not yours!
- Give me my iPod!
It's not yours, Elvis!
MARIO: Mamani.
Stop!
Kid, look at me!
Look at me!
That's the Devil
guiding your hand.
Give me that.
You were going to kill a man
over this piece of shit?
For what?
Because some fat cat says
he's gonna give us some money?
Because some whore
writes some gossip
about your family life?
Come over here.
So what?
So some people
wanna break your balls
because you are a Bolivian?
You are a Bolivian.
So, what is that,
what is that?
Come on.
What about me?
Calling myself
the leader down here.
Throwing my weight around,
thinking, you know,
that I did everything
on my own.
No.
No, this is not me.
This is not us.
We all know what is up there.
It's a circus.
So let's not get too far ahead
of ourselves.
No, let's don't do that,
because we are not going
to get anything out of this.
Anything.
We walked in miners
and we will walk out
miners.
I didn't sign the book deal.
Was I going to?
Yes.
Did I want to provide for
my family and for my kid?
Yeah. But I didn't.
I didn't. Why?
Because of you.
Because you're my brothers,
and if we want
to stay brothers,
we got to pull together
to get out of here.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
ALEX: Welcome back, Mario.
Welcome back.
JEFF: Here it comes!
I knew it!
Yes!
Back to work!
Vicente! Hey!
Come on, get up.
Let's get ourselves
some miners.
SOUGARRET: We got it out.
We're gonna restart.
JEFF: I figure about 20-40
we're gonna hit 'em.
Hey, Vicente!
Hey. Okay, guys.
Come on, let's go.
Arriba.
Get some coffee over here.
Come on, son!
Lieutenant.
Take down the fence.
All of it.
Yes, sir.
(CROWD CHEERING)
GOLBORNE: Come in. Everyone.
Please.
You're coming in too close
to some iron support beams.
If she hits those beams,
that drill is a goner.
We're going to have to clear
it ourselves from down here.
How?
A controlled explosion.
No, no, no, Don Lucho.
That's a negative.
The mountain is
completely unstable.
You need another option.
We know.
We know it's unstable,
but it's the only way.
We're all ready
to get out of here.
Or die trying.
DON LUCHO: Alex! Mario!
We're going to
bolster the beam
with these timbers, here.
The charges will be placed
here, correlating to this.
(GROANING)
Jessi.
I'll take you to the hospital.
No, I'm staying right here,
Don Jose.
I'm not leaving Alex.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Susi.
From Yonni.
He wrote me.
Oh, my God.
He spoke to the Minister.
You belong at
Camp Hope with us.
- I get to come in?
- Yes.
Marta, why are you leaving us?
I decided to leave him.
He doesn't deserve
a woman like me.
Besides,
he farts in his sleep.
Excuse me.
Okay, okay.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Okay.
Carlos Mamani.
Okay?
YONNI: Are you ladies ready?
Hell of a first day,
eh, Bolivian?
Make sure you put in
for some overtime.
Come on, baby.
3... 2... 1!
Look!
Here she comes!
(ALL LAUGHING AND CHEERING)
JEFF: All right, we're in.
You did it!
Thank you, Jeff.
You're Chile's
new national hero.
WILLCOX: Decked out in the
colors of the national flag,
this is Fenix 1,
the rescue capsule that
Chilean authorities,
along with most of the world,
are now pinning
their hopes on.
The metal cage is
designed to haul
the 33 miners, one by one,
from 700 meters below ground
to the sunlight they haven't
seen now for 62 days.
GUARD: Open it up.
Okay.
It's sinking.
How fast?
Too fast.
You see this green line?
We marked this
stone yesterday.
You see how far
it has come down?
I guess the explosion
has done its job.
700,000 tons of rock
sitting just directly
over their heads.
It's not a question of
if it falls, but when.
Okay, guys,
here's the situation.
We just don't have time
to reinforce the shaft.
If anything happens
to the Fenix capsule,
if its mechanism fails or the
walls of the shaft collapse,
I have to tell you
that there is
a real possibility
we can't get you guys out.
The guy who goes first
will be in
the greatest danger.
But could also be the only one
to make it out.
You decide who
that man will be.
Fenix.
Sir?
We're ready for initiation.
- Yeah.
- Go, Alex!
See you old men
up there.
Okay?
Okay.
Get in there.
We are ready.
Sir, they're good to go.
All right.
On the count of 3,
begin the ascent.
Beginning ascent
in 3, 2...
Come on!
(ALL CHEERING)
700 meters.
Mr. Vega is looking good.
The capsule is holding steady,
500 meters.
500-meter mark.
Look, his heart rate
is all over the place.
He's nervous.
Who wouldn't be?
The mountain is stable.
Everything looks good.
Rate of ascent is within
normal parameters.
400 meters.
300 meters.
GOLBORNE: Ignacio,
what happened?
The capsule is trapped
in the borehole
and we lost biometrics.
There's a problem.
ALEX: Hey!
Hey!
- Stand by.
- It's not moving.
We don't have
a visual down here.
I'm gonna try and reverse it.
Don Lucho.
The capsule is stuck.
They're reversing the Fenix.
What happened?
Here we go.
Okay, beginning descent.
Is he breathing?
We have no way of knowing
what his oxygen supply is.
Oh, man.
Hey!
- Shine it down there.
- Anything?
I'm gonna try again.
The wheel has stopped.
Okay, it's moving.
The capsule is moving.
What happened?
We lost the feed,
we lost Alex.
They've lost contact.
(CROWD CHEERING)
He made it?
- He made it!
- (ALL CHEERING)
Dad.
DON JOSE: Mijo.
This is your baby girl.
Esperanza.
Oh, my God.
YONNI: Mario.
MAN: Good luck, Mario.
See you soon.
(LAUGHS)
Goodbye, huevones!
I love you!
Yeah, baby! Come on!
I'm coming, Katty!
Minister. Finally I meet you.
- Call me Laurence, Mario.
- Laurence.
REPORTER: Mario! Over here!
CROWD: Mario! Mario!
Hey, my brothers, thank you!
Thank you for everything!
- Let's go for a "Chi!"
- CROWD: Chi!
- Let's go for a "le!"
- CROWD: Le!
CROWD: Chi, Chi, Chi!
Le, le, le!
(CHEERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- (HORN HONKING)
- (GIRL SHOUTING)
Viva Chile!
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Thank you for never
giving up on us!
Thank you for never giving up!
I love you, Copiapo!
CROWD: Elvis, Elvis!
Yonni! Yonni!
- Susi.
- I love you!
MARIA: Dario, Dario.
My sister, Maria Segovia.
Do you know her?
Right there. Right there.
Come.
PHOTOGRAPHER: Dario, Dario.
Where?
Maria?
DARIO: Thank you.
Thank you.
(SNIFFLING)
(LAUGHING)
(PULLEY WHIRRING)
♪ (UPBEAT LATIN FOLK
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com