The history of man is defined by war.
And war by the men who fight it.
What if we could create a better man?
Someone did.
The Agent program was
initiated in August of 1967...
by a man named Peter Aaron Litvenko.
It's purpose was to create
the perfect killing machine.
Human beings without emotion,
or fear, or remorse.
The resulting subjects were called Agents.
The Program was a success.
But the price of creating men without
humanity, was Litvenko's conscience.
Applying his brilliant mind
to his flight, he vanished.
Fearing that it would be exposed,
the Govt shut down the Program.
And surviving Agents drifted
into shadows.
Realizing it's potential, many
tried to re-start the Program.
All failed.
So they focused their efforts
on finding the one man who could.
The task fell to
Dr. Albert Delriego.
A ruthless, and efficient man.
Bu Litvenko had disappeared
and even he couldn't find him.
Then, 6 years into his search...
Delriego made an unexpected discovery.
A single photograph, which would
become the key to finding Litvenko.
No-one had ever imagined,
that in the end...
it would come down
to one, little .. girl.
SALZBURG - AUSTRIA
SYNDICATE INTERNATIONAL
- RESEARCH FACILITY
Sir, we have a match in Germany.
Verifying database.
REMOTE ACCESS
- UPLOAD VIRUS
ATTENTION, EVACUATE THE BUILDLING
- SECURITY ALERT
Lock all files and evacuate.
Sir, we have to leave now.
- What the hell is going on?
- I don't know, sir.
REMOTE TRACKING
- ACTIVATED
I want to know who's doing this.
I need answers.
Give me an update.
I said give me an update!
I said!
I supposed I should be flattered.
I didn't think I merited a contract.
You don't.
You know? I hunted an Agent once.
For four weeks.
Most rewarding catch
of my career.
Your employers are attempting
to re-start the Agent Program.
And you're here to stop them?
You're too late.
We already have Litvenko.
He's currently working
on next-generation units.
He's not.
Because you haven't found him.
Where is Katia van Dees?
I have a chip implanted, here.
If my heart stops beating, my security
detail will come through that door.
You need me.
No. I only need pieces of you.
The information I require
is in two places.
Your secure database...
And inside your head.
Berlín, they found her in Berlín.
That's all I know.
Okay, okay.
File 5-1-7.
Acess code:
G21-12-57.
Thank you.
But you won't find her.
She's a ghost.
I will.
HITMAN AGENT 47
SINGAPORE
Delriego is dead.
What happened?
We think it may have been an Agent.
Delriego was close to
finding the girl.
Get to her before he does.
BERLIN - GERMANY
He lived in Berlín between
1989 and 1990.
There must be taxes paid,
rental records, or something.
You know his name?
I don't have a name.
Look, he would've been 49, 50.
Blonde hair, 1.74 metros,
75 kilogramos.
Like this.
Sorry.
Without a name or an address...
Nothing I can do for you.
If he is missing...
May I suggest you try the police?
The police won't help me.
Why do you think I'm here?
And all you're doing is telling me
what you cannot do.
You have to realize that millions
of people have lived in Berlín...
over the past 25 years.
I can't be expected to sort through everyone
of them for your mystery man, can I?
It's 19,467,000 population
That's 62.2% Slavik origin.
And 49.2% male.
1.2% between the ages
of 49 to 50.
That's 71,291.
That's something, isn't it?
There's nothing I can do
to help you, Miss.
Okay.
Who is he?
This man you have to find.
What is he to you?
I don't know.
To or From?
Everybody who comes here
is running.
Either to something, or from it.
I see a lot like you.
Runners.
They come to me thinking a new
passport, means a new life
This is not good.
- It's perfect.
- The date strip's been demagnetized.
- The ony place this gets me is holding cell.
- If you want better you pay more.
Or I put a word out that
Tobias sells bad paper.
Be careful, little girl.
This world is a dangerous place.
MATCH FOUND
100% MATCH
47, it's Diana.
You have company.
- Who is he?
- A Syndicate asset.
Name, unknown.
Technical capacities, unknown.
He found her.
- Means he's good.
- You're better.
I'm sure you can handle him.
You have 48 hours
to terminate both targets.
Sorry.
You do know that stealing's a crime,
don't you, Katia?
That is your name, isn't it?
Katia Van Dees?
- My german's not...
- Are you some kind of cop?
- No.
- How do you know my name?
I'm John.
John Smith.
- I'd like to buy you a cup of coffee.
- Not interested.
How about in living?
Are you interested in that?
Walk away or I'll scream.
He won't care.
He's here to kill you, Katia.
And I'm here to stop him.
I know you don't have any reason to trust
me but look at him. Look at how he moves.
Look at the shadows on his coat. Look at
his eyes, and tell me that I'm lying.
Why would anyone want to kill me?
For the same reason you're trying to look
for someone you can't find.
The man I'm looking for,
Do you know where he is?
No, but you do.
Waht do I have to do?
There's a maintenance door.
The north end of the driveway.
It's been unlocked for us.
We're going to head there now.
Go through the corridor, up the stairs.
To a car will be waiting for us.
Run!
Move.
Franco, we're coming your way.
Hurry! Hurry!
Where's the Agent?
He's right behind us!
Move, move!
- Katia, are you hit?
- Who the fuck are you people?
Come down, Katia!
You're safe.
We've been sent to protect...
I work for a corporation called,
Syndicate International...
- And I'm here to protect you.
- From who?
His name is 47.
And he's an Agent.
And right now the only thing standing
between you and him, is me.
If you don't do everything I
say, everything...
He will kill you.
Let's go!
We'll be safe here.
EMBASSY OF
THE UNITED STATES OF AMÉRICA
Identificatión, please.
Purses open and in plain sight,
please.
Put down your weapon!
On the ground!
Hands where we can see them!
- Don't move!
- Cuff them!
You're coming with me.
Grab the pack.
Move!
Miss Van Dees, is it?
You mind telling me why you're here?
Because your friend in there wouldn't talk.
He's not my friend.
I don't know who he is.
Alright.
Maybe we can start with why he discharged
a firearm in from of my embassy.
Soemone was trying...
I think that someone
was trying to kill me.
John was trying to .. help me.
Does this someone have a name?
Something wrong, Miss van Dees?
Miss van Dees.
He's coming.
Shit.
Freeze!
Hands in the air!
Sanders.
Blaser R93 LRS2 rifle.
Custom configured right hand twist.
4-24x50 sniper scope, and...
hair trigger.
Very nice.
Come here.
Almost as the nice as 45s...
and these very special knives
you walked in here with.
You like riddles?
Yeah, me neither.
I hate them actually.
But you, my friend,
are a riddle to me.
Because I've run your face and prints
through every database we have.
And you know what we found?
Nothing.
So...
Why don't we start with your name?
47.
That's not a name.
No...
But it is mine.
Okay.
Alright, Mr. 47.
What exactly are you?
An assassin.
An assassin, okay.
And you're here to kill who, exactly?
You have a girl here.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Do you love your family?
My family?
Yes, your wife...
two small children.
You love them?
We're not talking about me,
we're talking about you.
No, we're talking about life.
And death.
Do .. you .. love them?
Alright.
- Maybe we should start over.
- I believe you do.
That's why, you should let me go.
Now you listen to me very carefully
Mr 47, or whatever the fuck your name is.
There's a lot of ways that this
can end and that's entirely up to you
But you can be goddamn certain
that it's not gonna end the way you
Because the last time I checked...
You're locked in here with me,
and I'm the one with a gun.
No, Mr. Sanders.
You are locked in here with me...
And you just brought me mine.
Do you love your children
enough to die for them?
Freeze!
Let's go.
Let me help you.
Two suspects
one male one female...
Broke out of
Interrogation rooms 1 and 2.
They're armed and dangerous.
Proceed with caution.
Sargent.
Is everything alright, sir?
Sir?
Hurry! Hurry!
Get out!
Move!
You want to tell me
what's happening now?
What the fuck is happening?
The man you're looking for,
his name is Peter Aaron Litvenko.
Who is he?
Your father.
Tell me about him.
I don't know much.
Only that he's a genecist,
an expert on human biogenetics...
who spearheaded a
program of experimentation.
What kind of experiments?
The kind that created killers.
The engineered human beings
by targeting specific genes.
The resulting subjects were faster, stronger,
more intelligent than normal people.
They programmed out pain, fear,.
Even love.
They called them Agents.
And your father was one of the
lead scientists of the Program.
You can't be serious.
What does this have anything to
do with me?
And why do they want to kill me?
Kriton Technologies
has re-started the Agent Program.
They're building Agents right now.
Like 47, maybe worse.
They belive that you're the
key to finding your father.
I don't understand.
Your father knows their weakness.
He knows how to stop them.
Katia!
You okay?
No.
Is your name really John Smith?
It's Brian.
Well, at least you didn't
say I was Agent 46.
No, that's someone else.
Come here. let me help you.
You're going to be alright.
No lie?
I'm sorry.
For what?
For having to tell you
who your father is.
Well, you told me the truth.
That's more than anyone ever has.
Why is it that they think
I can find him, John?
Doesn't matter now.
But it does.
Tell me what you know.
I know that you're in danger.
The best thing you could do
right now is hide.
I've been hiding my entire life.
Please...
tell me what you know.
I'm authorized to protect you...
Katia, not find your father.
Don't do this.
I have to.
Okay.
When we were researching your
father, we found a file.
It mentiined you. It said that...
Said what?
It said that he changed you.
Changed me, how?
It said that he had enhanced
your survival skills.
It's why we think you've been
hiding...
Why you've been able to stay
off the radar, been to stay alive.
- That's why I was always afraid.
- Yes.
Jesus!
They think I know how to
find my father.
What is this?
It's my father's life.
What else do you know about him?
Just what I told you.
You must have something.
How old is he?
Seventy two.
Where was he born?
Ukraine.
Medical conditions?
He was diagnosed with rheumatroid
arthritis in his 40s.
Somewhere warm, then.
What else?
Lung cancer.
Last known sighting was
in a hospital Seúl, Korea in 2011.
He was engaged in some clinical trials...
in something called nanomolecular
inhalation therapy
He was stage 3 then.
So, travel will be difficult.
Does he have money?
I think so.
Somewhere warm with advanced
medical facilities.
A city.
Hobbies?
What does he love to do?
Orchids.
He was an expert in orchids.
What languages did he speak, John?
English, Russian, Mandarín and Tamil.
Why Tamil?
Because your mother was from Sri Lanka.
You know where he is, don't you?
Katia.
YOu told me you wanted to do this,
and I told you I would do it with you...
but if you want my help, you
have to tell me where he is.
We've lost the girl.
You told me that your John Smith
would be adequate.
We underestimated this Agent.
Find Litvenko,
whatever it takes.
And, Garad, better this girl dead...
Than this Agent finding Litvenko
before we do.
Katia.
Do you know why you're still alive?
Because I chose not to kill you.
But they will.
After they use you
to find your father.
What do you know about my father?
As much as you do.
Everything will be alright.
No!
Time to make a choice, Katia.
Them or me.
Why should I trust you?
You don't have to.
Just trust you memories.
Take my hand.
You remember the day you ran away, Katia?
Peter, we have to go!
Your father's lab?
The car rides?
Easy.
The last time you saw your mother?
No! No, no, no, no!
You were there.
Yes.
Yes, we were part of the same Program.
We have to go.
Quickly!
Run! Quickly!
Good, get down there.
Get down, please!
Papá!
Live.
He left me.
Why?
Find him.
You can ask him yourself.
Untie me.
You have a lot to learn, Katia.
We don't have a lot of time.
Untie yourself.
That took you too long.
I didn't know that was a test.
Everything is a test.
Keep taking these, you'll fail.
Hey, I need them.
What you need is a clear head.
Stop fighting what you are.
And what am I?
Keep asking questions,
you'll probably be dead.
What am I?
You're the same as me, only better.
Bullshit!
I'm just Katia van Dess.
You speak French, Spanish, Mandarín.
Where did you learn them?
HOw did you free yourself from the rope?
You've been programmed.
And your name isn't Katia van Dees.
It's "quatre-vingt-dix".
French for "90".
So I'm 43 versions better than you?
So they know?
If they knew,
you'd be the target.
Come on, let's go.
If you need my help to find
my father, Why did you shoot me?
I didn't shoot you, I marked you.
There is so many.
If I shoot one, the rest will converge.
So what do we do, Katia?
Avoid them.
NO, suppress your fear.
And face the threat.
YOur father programmed you to see and hear
everything at extremely hightend levels.
You process that information
to anticipate a threat.
So anticipate it.
Katia.
There.
Area Four, all...
Katia.
Now.
I need you to step out there.
Why?
To draw them toward you.
They're going to shoot me!
They're not going to shoot you.
You want to see your father again?
Trust me.
I ahve a visual target lock.
Moving in.
Hello, Katia.
I'm only going to ask you once.
Where is your father?
I want you to know, I'm a
big fan of your work, 47.
It's an honor to meet a legend.
I thought you could only
be a legend after you are dead.
Oh, but you are.
You just don't know it yet.
Feeling pretty good for
a dead man, John.
- Almost as good as you.
- Yeah?
Well, the thing is I'm special.
Let's see.
Pretty crazy, huh?
I'm better. Say it!
Say it!
You're not.
You missed.
No she didn't.
You made a mistake.
He had a gun to your head.
And he didn't pull the trigger.
He wanted me to know he beat me.
Well, what the fuck is he?
People just don't walk away from
four bullets. They just don't.
Subdermal titanium body armour.
Injected under the skin
in liquid form
It's flexible, extremely strong
He had his nervous system heightened.
Wired for speed.
I've heard of these Syndicate experiments..
If they can do this with him...
Now, will you tell me
where Litvenko is?
Swear to me that you're not
going to hurt him.
Swear it.
Alright, I swear it.
Diana, did you hear that?
I did. Send me the link to the asset.
If you lie to me, I will kill you.
I'm not that easy to kill.
He's in Singapore.
Syndicate headquarters are
in Singapore.
He's hiding in plain sight.
- Yes?
- It's Diana.
I need you in Singapore
as soon as possible.
I'm on my way.
Singapore
Yes?
Litvenko's in Singapore.
They're on their way.
Thy're coming. Scan the
re-entry points.
Yes, sir.
The Syndicate ties into those
cameras, isn't it?
They're tied to everything.
Will you hold this, please?
Thanks.
How do you fight against that?
By playing the odds,
doing the unexpected.
Take nothing for granted.
Everything you do has a reason.
What does that mean?
Jacket. Give me your bag.
Right now,
it means avoid those cameras.
Okay.
08/14
I know, that took me too long.
Ask you a question?
Am I going to end up like you?
Bombs?
Moths.
Italian wool, they love it.
TARGET LOCATED
Did it hurt?
Yes.
You all...?
The barcode is given to
us when we are born.
The number?
When we become Agents.
He'll be there in the morning,
at about 9:00.
It's when the orchids
are in full bloom.
You know he's dying?
Lung cancer.
He needs an inhaler
now to breathe.
Are you human?
Is just that John said you're incapable
of feeling fear or remorse
It's all been suppressed.
Is that true?
Yes.
What about love?
I am what I need to be.
What does that mean?
In this job, sometimes
it's better not to feel anything
I'm not talking about the job
I think you're lying
I don't believe you can just
turn off fear or love
I don't believe anyone can.
You're either a person or something
else. Which is it?
Are you asking me, or yourself?
You can't fight who you are, Katia.
You'll lose.
Is that what happened to you?
You fought who you are, and you lost?
People can change.
Don't put your faith in me.
You'll be disappointed.
I still have a job to do.
Which is?
Right now, I need to sleep.
When I get anxious, and I can't sleep,
I take things apart.
I'm sorry.
Don't ever do that again.
Were they Syndicate?
No, free-lance.
Friends of yours?
So, the Syndicate doesn't
know we're here?
There's a open contract out on
us. What do you think?
Here, try not to take this apart.
- Smells bad.
- Robert, please!
- How did they find us so quick?
- You tell me.
- No games.
- What makes you think this is a game?
The cameras in the Terminal
didn't see me.
But the one outside, near the
exit, did.
Getting pretty good at this,
aren't I?
No, you're sloppy.
But, I'm going to have an attack.
Bee a good boy.
Here, take your inhalor.
It'll be alrght.
Excuse me.
- Where did you get that?
- I traded it.
- For what?
- Your knife.
Bring Litvenko
and the girl to me.
You shouldn't have come.
You know who I am?
You are your mother's daughter.
Why did you leave me?
I wanted you to have
no part of what I was.
I wanted you to live.
You had no right.
To walk away from you?
To turn me into this isolated,
afraid thing that I am.
You had no right!
Walk with me, Katia.
I loved your mother very much.
She was a light...
In a very dark world.
And more than anything else..
She wanted a child.
But she was unable.
So, we broke every rule we had...
and we made you.
We knew that if you were discovered...
They would take you from us,
so we gave you...
the tools to be free.
This isn't freedom.
No, perhaps not, Katia.
But it is necessary
for your survival.
NOw, I don't expect you to understand...
But I do ask that you
find it in yourself...
to forgive an old man's selfishness.
And if I can't?
You will, because you are the
reflection of the woman I loved.
I'm ready.
Get it over with.
Do it now.
He's not going to kill you...
father.
Yes he will.
It's inevitable.
Killing is what he is programmed to do,
and who he is.
Isn't that right, 47?
You're wrong.
We determine who we are
by what we do.
You believe...?
You have a choice?
I believe that's
what makes us human.
Then it seems...
that you and your brother...
have a lot to teach
this old man.
I guess I gave you
family, after all.
Move!
I got you.
Seal the building.
Go!
- What do they want?
- More of me.
Why would anyone
want more of you?
One and Two stay on him,
Three and Four cut him off.
Cut him off.
They're boxed in,
they've got nowhere else to go.
Right or left, Katia?
Straight ahead.
Trust me.
Holy shit!
I want this building sealed!
Perhaps you should consider shooting him.
Subdermal body armour.
What, they actually got that to work?
Yup.
Drive the fucken car faster.
Faster! faster!
We won't be able to make it.
Trust me.
I want all units on station.
We'll take them in the city.
- This is never going to end, is it?
- I'm afraid not.
He will never stop.
Who?
Antoine Le Clerq.
He's the Syndicate chairman.
What if we kill this Le Clerq?
Will it end then?
We can't.
Maybe not, but you can.
Nobody ever gets close enough
to LeClerk to kill him.
He nver leaves his protected offce.
Nobody ever goes in.
He's surrounded at all times
by security.
Fourteen.
That's how many Agents
have tried.
All are dead.
Help me! Help me!
- Get up!
- I can't walk!
Come on! You can do it!
Get up.
- Sorry.
- I'll get help.
Take her away from me!
- Take her! Come on!
- Take here! Please!
Come on!
Please! Get her out of here!
No! No!
Take her!
Hello, doctor.
What the hell did you do?
We have to go back!
He was all I had.
- I have to help him.
- You can't.
Damn you, you piece of shit!
- I should kill you.
- Yes, but you won't, because you're weak.
You're nothing more than a scared little
girl, who's only real gift is running.
Damn you.
DNA sequences, Doctor?
Adaptive mutated bacteria fissures
The epistasis rings?
Transfer RNA?
Come on, Doc.
I don't want to do this.
Believe me, you don't want
me to do this either.
So tell me what I need to know.
Tell me...
how to make an Agent.
This is just experimental, Doc.
I've seen it work...
And believe me when I tell
you don't want to be the one.
You're a bastard.
I know.
No. you don't.
You're a result of
inferior techonologies.
A failed experiment.
An Agent's advantage is not
his body, John Smith.
It's his mind.
You will never be as good as him.
Inject him.
For fuck's sake Doctor,
give me what I need.
Shit.
Mr. Chairman.
Are you alright?
No, I am not.
I need the Chairman's detail.
The Chairman is out.
911.
Emergecny Services, please.
Can I have your location, please.
Dose him again.
You could kill him.
Do it.
Oh, fuck it!
It's the Chairman.
What's happening?
What's he doing out of his office?
It's quite enough, John.
You can wait outside,
all of you.
It's okay, John.
Petya.
Can you hear me?
I am going to be completely
honest with you.
I admire you.
YOu have created something unique.
A better human being,
and I want it.
I have bet my wealth,
my company, my reputation...
Everyting on the success of this program.
You understand?
Good thing I sold your stock, then.
You and I are so very different.
You know this.
You're wrong.
People can change.
No.
No, not people like us.
What you did...
When you chose to play God,
can never be undone.
You can't run from what you are.
So I should...?
Embrace it?
Re-start the Program
with you as it's head?
Yes.
You always were a small man, Antoine.
A derivitive thinker, at best.
This desperation suits you.
The key to everything...
is in your mind,
and you're going to give it to me.
Tell me how to build an Agent.
You don't want an Agent.
Then, What do I want?
An Army.
And I won't give it to you.
Then you're going to die.
I'm already dead.
Yes, what about your daughter?
You don't have her.
No, but I will...
eventually.
Give me what I want
and I'll leave her in peace.
I give you what you want
there won't be no peace.
Mr. Chairman.
Where is he?
How did he get into our system?
I don't know, Mr. Chairman.
I'm assuming by your reaction,
that you know who I am
What do you want?
To make a deal.
- You have nothing I need.
- You're wrong.
You want what's inside
Litvenko's head...
But he won't give it to you.
I can.
How?
Window.
You want the next
generation of Agents...
but you've been
looking in the wrong place.
You thought the girl was
the only way to find Litvenko.
A means to an end.
The truth is...
She is the end.
That's right, everything you need.
The strength, the speed...
the intelligence, is right there.
Locked inside her DNA.
So you want to trade him for her?
Why?
Because I always
close my contracts.
Fuck you.
There's a helipad on the roof.
Get him someplace secure.
- Heading up to the Safe Room.
- I want all teams to Floor 40.
That's not going to be enough, John.
No. You stay with me,
protect me!
So many choices.
And only one right answer.
What's it gonna be?
Emotion or duty?
It was too quick.
Fire Dept was here too quick.
- Someone called them before the crash.
- What does that mean?
It means he was never
in that helicopter.
Get them out.
What was your mistake?
I don't make mistakes.
You needed me to know
that you were better than me.
Where is he?
On the roof.
When this is done, I will kill you.
Your mother would be proud of you.
What?
Nothing.
I doubt you'd understand.
Doesn't matter.
We'll find her.
I believe you will.
Confirm target termination.
Target...
Le Clerq, Antoine...
terminated.
And the other?
Second target?
47?
47!
Second target?.
Le Clerq.
He was your target the whole time?
Everything that you told me,
was you'd have a diversion?
It was necessary.
What? to kill a single man?
No.
To put a stop to the Agent Program,
once and for all.
And to set you free.
Your father loved you, Katia.
He understood that LeClerk would not
rest once he knew who you were.
That he would hunt you down.
So he did what any parent would.
He died to save his children.
This is your mission, isn't it?
We determine who we are,
by what we do.
There is a building full of
highly-trained operatives...
who will be on their way up here now.
You're wrong..
There's just one.
Diana says Hello.