On 23.11.93, Maximilian B.,
a 19-year-old student,
shot three people in a Viennese bank
and killed himself
with a shot in the head
shortly afterwards.
Day and night,
Ghamsakhurdia's supporters
attack the city with tracer fire.
Holding handkerchiefs aloft
as white flags
refugees walk through the firing lines.
More than 100,000 people
are still fleeing from the war.
Peace efforts in Somalia
have suffered a setback.
The leaders of the two rebel groups,
Aideed and Ali Mahti,
have rejected the peace conference
in Addis Ababa
because they were not consulted.
For the first time since
the truce was agreed
Aideed's supporters have again attacked
UN positions in Mogadishu.
From the air,
US forces attempt to bring home
President Clinton's confused policy
to the Somali population.
Aircraft thundering overhead, bombs,
machine gun fire, threatening gestures.
And psychological warfare:
Americans and Somalis shaking hands
in a gesture of peace.
On the reverse it says:
The only obstacle to peace
is rebel leader Aideed.
The Somalis find this
difficult to believe in view
of the heavily-armed US soldiers,
tanks and combat helicopters.
Ali Mahti, Aideed's rival,
is demanding
a clear statement of policy from Clinton
If he doesn't disarm the clans, Somalia
will sink back into anarchy and chaos,
he said.
However, the Americans are determined
to withdraw from the country in 6 months.
The Caribbean state of Haiti is becoming
a new crisis point for the UN.
A total of 1,600 military advisers,
police instructors,
and administrative experts
are at hand to help the country
return to democracy.
But, as in Somalia,
resistance is growing
to the American and Canadian soldiers,
who form the advance troops.
Ralf Hoogestraat sends us this report:
The American ship Harland County
is still at anchor
off the coast by Port-au-Prince.
Armed gangs have occupied the harbour
and are protesting against the
- as they call it - foreign invasion.
In a carefully-staged action by Haiti's
rulers, diplomats and journalists É
71 FRAGMENTS
OF A CHRONOLOGY OF CHANCE
How is she?
102.8¡
And by direct manipulation.
- What does that mean?
With the mouse instead of commands.
How long've you got for it?
End of term.
Talking of time,
your minute was up ages ago.
Ok, show me then.
Not so simple, is it?
So, that'll be 20 schillings, mate.
- Ok, ok.
Betting debts are debts of honour.
Which one is she, then?
The one in the green jersey, isn't she?
Shall we go in?
Yes, of course.
This is Mr. and Mrs. Brunner.
They'd like to meet Anni.
Anni, are you coming?
Hi there, Anni.
Hallo, Anni.
Look, we've brought you something.
Here É
Look, Anni É
Don't you like it?
Can I have it?
- No, Petra, the lady brought it É
You'll have to be patient.
It's a completely normal reaction.
Are you my new foster mummy?
'Morning.
Mrs. Thomek, countersignature, please.
Busy today, aren't you?
- It's always like this on pension day.
'Morning. How are things?
Fine, thanks.
Good-bye.
Could I use the phone?
Yes, go ahead.
Excuse me.
One, two, three, four.
Good-bye. Thank you.
Hello.
Here É
How are you?
Thanks for asking. Fine.
Fine.
Pardon?
- Pardon what?
I'm sorry, I didn't catch what you said.
You don't need to say sorry.
I said: Thanks for asking. Fine.
Nine thousand,
three hundred and seventy-two schillings
and forty groschen.
I don't have time just now, Dad. Call me
this evening and we'll talk then, ok?
All right.
I'm sorry to have troubled you, Miss.
'Bye.
I'll call you.
Good morning.
É to finish building the power station.
In fact, around 4,000 workers
are directly or indirectly
employed in its construction.
By the middle of 1997,
the first turbines should be supplying
electricity to the network
if everything runs according to plan.
We mustn't have a hard winter
or flooding,
the Christmas spate must come between
24th December and 6th January
and not like last year in November,
which was in fact atypical.
If we're delayed by a hard winter
then we'll have to increase
efforts to catch up.
Work is now proceeding
on the left bank of the Danube.
This is where the barrage weir
will be built over the next two years.
This island in the Danube
is the first part of the dam
which will keep the water back from
the excavations for the barrage weir.
Shipping on this stretch is confined
to single line traffic.
This is what the power station
will look like when finished.
This photomontage shows a bird's eye
view of the Vienna barrage weir.
From 1998, the power station
should be supplying enough electricity
for over 270,000 households.
Computer fans gather over the next
few days at Vienna's Trade Fair Centre,
where the 3rd PC Expo
was opened this morning.
We take a look at the newest trends
on the computer market.
Frenetic images and fantasy worlds
are still market leaders.
Computer games reign supreme.
The ideas of the computer manufacturers
seem inexhaustible
in the quest for new markets.
This manager has just lost
all his appointments.
But this little electronic gadget
is much handier.
It converts handwritten input
into computer data,
processes the information
and then transfers it to a computer.
The Engl É
'Evening. Vehicle inspection.
When did you leave barracks?
This morning at 7. Why?
Armoury's been broken into.
Were you inspected when you left?
No. It was for the medical unit. Orders.
It's full of medical supplies.
Did you have any private
belongings with you?
Thanks.
Same to you.
Shut up!
Claire!
If we don't get out now, I can't É
No! Wait a second!
Claire! Come here!
Anything happened?
We can't take anybody else!
Wait, damn you!
Claire, come on!
'Night.
A cross?
- Yes.
A hundred schillings?
One minute?
- Yes.
Off you go.
But there are more bits now.
Too easy otherwise.
Thirty seconds.
Thirty-five.
- Shut your face, OK?
É and sixty!
And how much time
d'you need to do it now?
Sorry.
I no understand. What you wanting?
É saw them running away.
The attack is an act of revenge
by the radical Ulster Volunteer Force
for the IRA bomb attack
which killed 10 Protestants on Sunday É
according to a statement made
by the UVF to a local radio station.
This morning,
just a few hours before the shooting,
a 70-year-old Catholic was killed
by the Ulster Volunteer Force.
The trial of strength between
the French government
and Air France employees continues.
The strike by ground personnel
has now been joined by the pilots.
Yet again,
several thousand Air France employees
demonstrated at the airport in Paris,
joined this time by their colleagues
of Air Inter.
As a result,
half the flights were cancelled.
Only foreign airlines
flew into Paris today.
The striking employees are demanding
a written guarantee
that the programme of economy
measures will be withdrawn.
The government had originally planned
to rationalize several thousand jobs
but then capitulated
in the face of the strike.
The guerilla war being waged
by the Kurdish Workers' Party PKK
is claiming more and more
victims on both sides.
In the past two days,
42 civilians have been killed
in PKK attacks, among them children.
In a massacre in eastern Anatolia
alone 38 young men lost their lives.
Screams of pain, full of impotent rage.
This man is trying to retrieve
his dead brother's shoe
from the bloodstained floor
of the village cafŽ.
The police are dragging him away
from the scene of the bloodbath.
In Javi, near the town of Cat,
5 PKK guerillas disguised as soldiers
stormed into the bar and opened fire.
The victims are aged between 15 and 25.
A further 10 men were injured,
some of them critically.
This young woman
has lost her husband in a struggle
which he, like the other victims É
Dear God, give the little one a long
life and good health
and give me a long life and good health
and help Maria to be a happier person
and help me to be a better
and happier person
and don't let me have any
serious illnesses
and don't let there be a third world war
or a nuclear disaster
not in this generation or the next.
And help all suffering people
in the world
and I thank thee for everything,
dear God. Amen.
When'll you be back?
- After six.
Punctual as clockwork! Hello, Anni.
Good afternoon.
Come in, don't be shy.
- Hello there, Anni.
Hello.
Do come on in.
Put your things there.
Did you find it all right?
- Oh, yes. No problem.
Can I take your jacket?
Your colleague from the Youth Office
had problems finding it.
Do you like it?
I'm so pleased you wore it today.
Come on, Anni. Take your jacket off
or you'll be too hot.
That's nice of you. Thank you.
I promise I'll give it back
to you afterwards.
So, do come on in.
It's this way.
Do have a seat.
I hope you like the cake.
Do sit down.
- Thanks.
Are you coming to me?
Come here, Anni. Sit down here.
What is it?
What did you say? I didn't understand.
She wants to see her room.
I'm sorry?
She'd like to see the room
you'll be giving her.
Oh É of course.
But it's not quite ready yet.
Here you are, young lady!
Well, d'you like it?
You wouldn't have these problems
if you kept to the diet.
But I don't like it.
What do you suggest, then?
D'you prefer the pain?
Get back!
Get back from the edge of the platform!
If you bet that He exists,
you win everything.
If He doesn't exist,
you don't lose anything.
The other one says:
But why do I have to bet anything?
The first one says: You have no choice.
You're in the boat.
That's just an assertion.
If I don't want to, I don't have to.
Why? If you say you're not betting,
you're saying He doesn't exist.
You can't say it's not a political act
not to vote É
Great É now I don't need
to lug this around all the time.
You'll get the money tomorrow.
And why did you muck that one up?
- I was É
You weren't paying attention, were you?
So, just look at that.
Look, you're standing right,
your weight's right,
your feet are right.
Look, your basic position's OK.
Now just look at this!
Look where you're standing,
much too near the table!
And your feet are pointing
in the wrong direction!
Why don't you move back from the table?
And now it's too late.
And where's the ball? Much too far back.
And your balance? Up shit creek!
You can't go for the ball
when it gets you so far back.
Just look at the way you're twisting.
The energy's going to the left
- all wrong.
I was É
You were half asleep!
Stop making excuses!
Just slamming the ball isn't enough.
Open your eyes and look at your opponent.
You're not playing by yourself.
And what's that?
Don't bother getting annoyed.
Stop annoying me and concentrate,
will you?
But he kept É
And stop making excuses for yourself!
- I'm not making excuses!
You never stop making excuses!
You were too far forward,
the rest's irrelevant!
You have to follow the ball;
it won't follow you.
I know, I know É
Well, if that's what you think É
You don't need to tell me,
I know I'm a burden on you É
No, it doesn't matter.
You don't need to bother
pretending I'm not.
I expect you'd be a burden on me
if I were in your place É
All right, all right É
Why?
Oh, come off it É
that's just a waste
of telephone money É
No, I'm very busy É
Shall I tell you what I do all day?
Well, then É
yes É
so do I É
All right, then É
Hey! I nearly forgot É
what happened about
Gebhard's promotion?
Now that I really don't understand É
then how long will it take?
Perhaps he should É
Ok, ok, all right É
I know É
I won't say another word É
yes É
just meaning well doesn't count,
does it?
Yes, the old idiot's resentful,
I know É
otherwise nothing'd be right
with the world, would it?
Well, let him fall on his face then É
it's not my job É
ok, ok, I'm sorry É
but it's true É
yes, all right É
forget it!
What am I meant to say?
If I don't say anything,
you think I'm not interested É
if I do say something
then it's interfering.
So what am I supposed to do É
I'm sorry for existing É
Sorry É
All right,
let's stop É
Hey!
I wanted to tell you,
Mrs. Wawrik, you know,
the one next door with the dog,
she's moved out É
gone to live with her children,
'cos she couldn't manage any more,
cooking and cleaning,
and all that - you know.
And now the children
have got her with them,
'cos she É
she said if she had to go into a home
she'd do away with herself.
I didn't believe a word of it,
but it worked É
No, that's all, really,
can't think of anything else É
Say hello to Gebhard and give Sissi
a kiss from me É
I'm longing to see her É
you don't know what you've got in her.
Rubbish É
come on É
can't you take a joke?
I meant it nicely.
Yes, of course É
all right É kisses É
stupid expression É
I'll never get used to it É
"Kisses"
Used to get on my nerves
with your mother, too: "Kisses."
between grown-up people É
It probably doesn't matter É
What?
Well, it's my phone bill, isn't it?
What else am I supposed to talk about
if not myself?
It's the only thing
a decent person can talk about.
What?
If it's too much for you, then hang up.
But you'll only have a bad conscience.
See how well I know you É
Just as if I'd made you É
Yeah, you're right É
when you're bored É
you talk a load of rubbish.
All right, then É
'night.
Hey!
Let me speak to Sissi again É
Ok.
'Bye.
Hi, sweetie-pie É
sleep well É
sweet dreams É
No É
I don't know É
what did you dream yesterday, then?
No! Fancy that É
Good!
And what did he do then?
I know,
that's just what I'd have done, too É
Listen,
tonight it'll be different É
when you É
What did Mum say?
Let me speak to her again É
Come on É
sometimes I ask myself, I really do É
What?
Oh, really?
You're a really spiteful person,
did you know that?
What does it do for you?
Are you trying to hurt me É
or É
My god É just calm down and listen É
stop interrupting and screeching at me.
Well hang up, then É
I told you to before, anyway.
Oh, really?
That's just fine!
You'll see what it's like É
What are you trying
to get your own back for anyway?
What?
What are you trying
to get your own back for?
You can't really be that nasty É
I'd like to see you in my situation É
Yes, that's right É
it's the same for everyone É
Exactly!
Just you wait!
'Bye.
Let me speak to Sissi again É
Just for a second É
so your family life isn't
disturbed too much.
Sweetie-pie É
I love you.
What's the matter?
Are you drunk, or what?
Yes, why?
Not very É
I mean, what are you getting at?
You don't say "I love you" out
of the blue. And certainly not you.
So, what d'you want?
I thought it would be helpful.
- For what?
Old High German.
Yes É it's a bit strange,
more like a foreign language sometimes,
but I can't say I don't enjoy it.
Before Christmas.
But I've heard it's not a very difficult
exam. It's relatively harmless.
The only problem is that training
takes up so much time.
And how are things your end?
Have the Gauweilers finished converting
their house yet?
Really?
It'll be interesting to see it.
And Dad?
Yes, me too. Say hello from me.
Nothing much else to tell you, really.
I'm fine.
"How are you - I'm fine!"
Ciao, Mum, I'll be in touch.
Come in!
What's the matter?
Well, come on - what's up?
When can I start sleeping there?
É I bribed the driver.
Where did you get the money from?
I begged and stole sometimes.
He wanted a lot of money - $200.
And then he said he would only
take me as far as the Austrian border.
It was too risky for him
to take me across the border.
How long did it take you
to get the money together?
A few months. I had to eat, too.
I'm not on the game.
You said you crossed the border
over two weeks ago.
Why didn't you go to the police
or somebody else earlier?
The driver said if they caught me
and I couldn't speak German
they'd send me back straight away.
What did you live from, all that time?
People are very careless here.
It's very easy to steal.
Where did you sleep?
In empty houses.
- Wasn't that cold?
Yes, it was sometimes.
I've got this jacket.
It's been cold the last few days.
That's why I went to the police.
Can you tell us how you got the idea
of running away to Austria?
I heard that people are nice
to children here.
Who did you hear that from?
From a girlfriend of mine.
And where did she hear that?
She's on the game,
so she talks to a lot of people.
How old is she?
About the same age as me.
What was your life like in Bucharest?
Don't you have parents?
No.
I ran away from a home two years ago.
There was a group of us at the station
- older children, too.
They were my family.
It was all right at first,
but then it got harder and harder.
Two of my friends died.
I didn't want to stay after that.
Isn't that incredible?
What do you think
will happen to you now?
He doesn't seem real.
He's like an adult.
I want to stay here.
And where would you like
to live in Austria?
I don't know exactly. But É
they said I'd probably have
to go back anyway.
But even if they do send me back,
I'll be back here again in a few months.
Whether Marian Radu can stay in Austria
depends on the discretionary powers
of the immigration authorities.
The legal situation is as follows:
Foreigners who enter Austria illegally
and who could have sought asylum
in a so-called secure state
are not eligible for asylum here.
All of Austria's neighbouring states
are considered secure states.
In addition É
Can't you sleep?
No.
Are you thinking about that boy?
Yes.
And the little girl.
Me too.
Well?
I don't know.
How can we explain it to her?
É against the Gaza-Jericho accord.
They shouted
"Death to Israel and America."
The supporters of the pro-Iranian
Hezbollah organisation were also grieving
for one of their fighters
who was killed in an Israeli attack.
In a retaliatory strike,
the Israeli air force
yesterday bombarded Hezbollah positions.
Previously, Hezbollah fighters
had attacked barracks
used by the Israeli-supported
South Lebanon Army.
They attacked the army base
with machine guns and mortar fire.
Later, Hezbollah fighters É
captured 12 soldiers
of the South Lebanon Army.
Today in the Hague the judges were sworn
in on the UN war crimes tribunal
for former Yugoslavia.
The list of alleged war criminals
includes Croats and Serbs,
among others the Bosnian
Serb leader Karadžić
and Serbian president Milošević.
However, proceedings will be difficult
since the tribunal is dependent
on the accused being extradited
by the Serbian or Croatian authorities.
For two years now,
pictures of the atrocities
in ex- Yugoslavia have shocked the world.
The concept
of so-called ethnic cleansing,
now part of everyday language,
has revived horrifying images
from the Second World War.
New massacres are reported
with horrifying regularity.
On both sides,
soldiers and self-appointed militias
kill at random.
Neither women,
children nor old people are spared.
Thousands vegetate in prisons
and concentration camps,
in constant fear of death.
There seem to be no limits
to the cruelty in this war.
Mass rape is constantly used by Serbian
soldiers to break the resistance
and will of the enemy.
The survivors of these atrocities
have hoped in vain until now
that those guilty of these crimes É
Click it on with the left-hand button.
Rotate it with the right-hand button.
Exactly É
now stick it on.
It fits.
You can do the same with the rest.
That's really clever É
it looks really good, too.
No, that doesn't fit there É
When they go together
they change colour.
That's right.
Here, give us the mouse.
So you set the number
of puzzle pieces here
and here you set the time limit,
and there you've got the different
symbols you can make.
Let me have a go again.
I think I've nearly got it.
It always gets easier near the end É
Well, two minutes wasn't that difficult.
If you go over the time,
it falls apart again.
That's the last piece É
Finished É
Great.
And what does your professor
say about it?
Are you going to market it, or É?
- No way É
it's just a child's game,
there's masses of stuff
that's much more sophisticated.
But next year É
the Massachusetts Institute
is lending us É
the Data Glove.
It's a sort of electronic glove -
you've probably seen it on TV.
You put it on
and then you can move around
in the computer in three dimensions.
Hey! D'you know Mikado?
From years ago.
This is É
skill against chance.
Soon the Data Glove'll be on the market.
There'll be a new software sector
and you have to start
programming for it now.
D'you know how to play?
More or less.
That's the Mikado É
when you get that,
you can use it to help you.
That's right.
Let's start.
Go ahead.
What are we playing for?
- Nothing.
Nothing's nothing.
Well?
Haven't a clue.
Come on!
What d'you mean, come on?
- What are we playing for?
Come off it.
It moved É
No, seriously!
OK, what d'you want to play for?
Your revolver?
And what are you betting?
What d'you want, then?
Haven't a clue.
Here, your turn.
Your watch?
My parents gave me that
when I finished school.
We don't have to play for anything.
It was your idea.
It moved!
He looks even younger than on TV.
Does he know it's only for a while?
- Yes.
He knows the legal situation.
Shall we go in?
Come on then.
É a peaceful Christmas É
is what most people in Sarajevo
dream about.
Like seven-year-old Dalida
and her friend Boris.
While they decorate the Christmas tree,
hundreds of grenades fall on the city.
People run,
trying to dodge the snipers' bullets.
In Sarajevo nearly all
the black market stands are empty.
Only a few Christmas wreaths
are for sale.
"But they're much too expensive",
says this young woman.
"We're just glad to have enough food
for a small Christmas dinner, at least."
But many people are desperate,
like this mother.
This afternoon she took
her baby to hospital.
Her little boy had been hit
in the leg by shell splinters.
Is Michael Jackson telling the truth,
or was he putting on an act?
That's what his fans are asking
after the superstar's appearance
on TV yesterday evening.
After weeks of silence while undergoing
withdrawal treatment,
in a live TV broadcast
from his ranch in California
he denied all charges of child abuse.
Ralf Hoogestraat reports:
"Don't treat me like a criminal,
"I'm innocent."
says a tearful Michael Jackson,
broadcasting from the privacy
of his Neverland ranch.
Visibly moved, he described how police
had examined his genitals.
Supposedly, some of the descriptions
given by the boy allegedly abused É
É call 0 45 92 99.
The call costs 13.33 schillings
per minute during the day,
and 8.67at night and on weekends.
I'm off.
When'll you be back?
- After six.
It's nearly all melted here.
How about with you?
No skiing, then.
Oh, well, we'll have to see.
Hey, I'll have to get on. I've got to pick
something up for my trainer with his car.
It's too complicated É
I'll tell you this evening
I'll have to hurry, or I'll be too late.
What?
The timetable says it leaves at 13.30.
Yes, so it should arrive
between five and six.
Well,
then call the station to make sure.
Star.
Christmas star.
Exactly. Like in the sky.
D'you understand?
At night - stars everywhere.
Human beings.
You - human being.
Me - human being.
Those - human beings.
É and strong winds in the mountains
of40 kph,
increasing during the evening.
Vehicle 7 approaching.
É costs 79 schillings,
and 86 schillings for mussels in broth.
This is served with a 'baguette',
French white bread.
About 20 metres further west
I come upon a stand É
that has all the charm of a beach hut.
You can see through the window É
and watch the Asiatic chef
arranging portions of sushi É
- that's raw fish as eaten in Japan.
A young man
is just coming out of the door É
and I'm going to ask him
what he's just had:
É I had salmon sushi,
they're great.
It's raw fish with rice
and underneath there's a green paste
which is made of horse-radish, I think.
It's really good, fantastic.
How much was it?
I'm ashamed to admit it,
but I ate two large servings.
Normally you're full
after one large helping,
it cost 290,
I mean two times 145,
that'll do me for the whole day.
Culinary excursions to foreign parts É
aren't always so expensive,
I was assured by a student
from the Technical University nearby.
He had a Korean soup,
then moved on to a Greek restaurant
where he had a spinach strudel É
and for dessert he bought an Israeli
orange from a Turkish grocer's.
42 schillings all in all.
Now we're going to the bank
to get the money for our holiday.
Bank!
Exactly.
To get the money.
Come on.
God, it's crowded.
We'll have to queue here.
D'you take cheque cards?
I don't have enough cash.
There's a machine over the way.
Where?
Use your eyes!
Out of order
I've got the car outside.
I just need 300 schillings.
Please join the queue.
The machine's out of order!
I'm blocking the gas station.
What the hell É
- Get back!
Come on, let's get out.
That's outrageous!
Can I help you?
I'm OK, thanks.
You wait here.
I'll be back in a minute, OK?
Don't go away. You sit there, OK?
I'll be back straight away.
'Morning.
Mrs. Tomek, countersignature please.
Right É Have a nice holiday.
- Thanks, you too.
É Billrothstra§e,
shortly after the fatal shots.
The bodies of the three victims
are being taken away.
Police experts are searching the bank.
They are searching between the pools
of blood for a clue to a motive,
not to the identity of the perpetrator;
he has already killed himself.
After the bloodbath in the bank
he ran across the street,
got into his car at this gas station
and committed suicide
with a shot in the head.
The police have identified
the killer as Maximilian B.,
a nineteen-year-old student.
The motive for this senseless murder
is still a complete mystery.
However, it is clear
that he did not intend to rob the bank.
The gas station attendant,
one of the last people to speak to him,
has no explanation.
No idea, I dunno.
It's absolutely crazy.
Vienna, the day before Christmas.
People stunned by an act of insanity.
In Brussels today the last attempt
to secure peace for Bosnia
before Christmas has failed.
Talks between the two sides
in the civil war
were broken off at midday
without result.
In central Bosnia,
Bosnian army soldiers abducted
three UN soldiers in a tank.
The ceasefire agreed for Christmas
is being disregarded
on almost all fronts.
É a peaceful Christmas is what
most people in Sarajevo dream about.
Like seven-year-old Dalida
and her friend Boris.
While they decorate the Christmas tree,
hundreds of grenades fall on the city.
People run,
trying to dodge the snipers' bullets.
In Sarajevo nearly all
the black market stands are empty.
Only a few Christmas wreaths
are for sale.
"But they're much too expensive",
says this young woman.
"We're just glad to have enough food
for a small Christmas dinner, at least."
But many people are desperate,
like this mother.
This afternoon she took
her baby to hospital.
Her little boy had been hit
in the leg by shell splinters.
Is Michael Jackson telling the truth,
or was he putting on an act?
That's what his fans are asking
after the superstar's appearance
on TV yesterday evening.
After weeks of silence while undergoing
withdrawal treatment,
in a live TV broadcast
from his ranch in California
he denied all charges of child abuse.
Ralf Hoogestraat reports:
"Don't treat me like a criminal,
I'm innocent."
says a tearful Michael Jackson,
broadcasting from the privacy
of his Neverland ranch.
Visibly moved, he described how police
had examined his genitals.
Supposedly, some of the descriptions
given by the boy allegedly abused
have been confirmed.
Jackson's lawyer, Tommy Cochran,
defended the media offensive.
"Michael Jackson thought it appropriate
to answer the allegations now."
According to the Jackson camp,
when this is all over
Jackson
will start a world-wide comeback.
His career É