# Word up, son, word #
# Yeah. To all the killers
and hundred dollar billers #
#Fellas #
#For real n--as
Who ain't got no feelin's #
# Check it out now #
#l got you stuck
off the realness #
# We be the infamous
You heard of us, official
Queensbridge murderers #
# The Mobb comes equipped
for warfare #
#Beware of my crime family
who got enough shots to share #
#For all those
who want to profile and pose #
#Rock you in your face
Stab your brain with your nosebone #
# You all alone
in these streets, cousin #
#Every man for theyself
in this land we be gunnin'#
#And keep them shook crews
runnin'like they suppose to #
# They come around
but they never come close to #
#l can see it inside your face
You're in the wrong place #
# Cowards like you just get
their whole body laced up
with bullet holes and such #
#Speak the wrong words, man
and you will get touched #
# You can put your whole army
against my team #
#l guarantee it'll be your
very last time breathin'#
# Your simple words
just don't move me
You're minor, we're major #
# You're all up in the game
and don't deserve to be a player #
#Don't make me have
to call your name out
Your crew's featherweight #
#My gunshots will
make you levitate #
#l'm only 19
but my mind is old #
# When the things get for real
my warm heart turns cold #
#Another n--a deceased
Another story gets told #
#lt ain't nothin'really
Hey,yo, son spark that Phillie #
#So I can get my mind off
these yellowbacked n--s #
# Why they still alive
I don't know, go figure #
Hold on a minute!
#l couldn't choose
a better location #
# When the slugs penetrate
you feel a burning sensation #
# Getting closer to God
in a tight situation #
#Now, take these words home
and think it through #
# Or the next rhyme I write
might be about you #
#Son they shook
'cause ain't no such things
as halfway crooks #
What the fuck.!
Hold on a fuckin' minute!
# 'Cause there ain't no thing
as halfway crooks #
#Scared to death
And scared to look #
#Livin'the life
that of diamonds and guns #
# There's numerous ways you
can choose to earn funds #
#Some get shot, locked down
and turn nuns #
# Cowardly hearts end
straight up shook ones #
#Shook ones ##
##
Yo! What the fuck?
Yo.! What the fuck, man.!
Quit playin'with
your fuckin'self!
Open the door.!
What the fuck, man!
Who the fuck is you, nigga?
Where the hell do you
think you going?
Going backstage.
I'm in the battle.
You can't go backstage.
Come on, dawg.
I got a stamp on my hand.
You gotta go around front.
You just seen me, dawg!
I just came from--
I didn't see nothin'.
Man, you just fuckin' seen me!
I just went to the bathroom!
Whoa! What's happening?
This guy's got a fuckin'
problem with me!
Shut the fuck up.
He's straight, dawg.
He's straight.
He with you?
Yeah.
Okay, cool, Future.
But I think your boy
got a attitude problem.
You a crazy motherfucker,
you know that, trying to
fight bouncers and shit.
The fuckin' guy's obviously
got somethin' against me.
I go to the bathroom,
come right back, he's actin'
like he don't know me.
Hold on, man.
You fuckin' threw up
on yourself, huh?
Come here, man.
Hey, Rabbit.
I know you ready, Rabbit.
Where you going?
He hurled on his shirt.
Let's see.
Yo! Get the fuck off me,
Cheddar.
What are you doin', man?
Come on.
It's deal time, Rabbit.
Our clique'll be on the map
after you whup some ass tonight.
Me and Janeane
just broke up.
What, again?
And I left her the car.
Oh, come on, Rabbit.
Yo, she says she's pregnant.
She's gonna need the car
if she's pregnant.
I'm gonna need
a place to crash.
- You gonna stay at your mom's?
Come on.
Yo! Can I get some fuckin'
privacy here, man?
All right.
Come on, man, come on.
Why?
Yo, my bad, man.
Look, if something's going
to happen with this shit,
it needs to happen now.
Hey, man, I feel you.
I know exactly what
you're talking about.
All right, come on, man.
How you feelin'?
I feel good.
You feel good?
Yeah.
I'm ready.
You sure?
You ready, baby.
I wanna see you rip
that shit, all right?
It's time to let
these motherfuckers know.
Yeah, you, baby.
Three-One-Third.
It's all you, baby.
#Your lyrics are shitty
Like when I cop a squat #
#Who told you could fuck
with the mighty Papa Doc #
# For steppin' on his stage
I should rock your knot #
# Don't get too close
or you might get shot #
#Yo, nigga, call your mama
and tell her come get you #
#And if she knew him
she could bring your
midget pops with her #
#l put a hole in your head
like a. 12-gauge #
#Lookin'like Kris Kross
Jiggity-jump your ass on stage #
# 'Cause I'm a grown man, son
I'll slaughter you #
# Make your ma wish that
her fat ass aborted you ##
Whoa.! A lot ofhostility
at the end of the 45 seconds.
Let me get that mike from you.
Open up a little bit.
Let everybody see your Future.
Know what I mean?
How y'all feelin' about
Shorty Mike right here?
Kind of mediocre love?
Just a'ight for Shorty Mike?
What do you all think
of Papa Doc, man?
That's what I'm talking about.!
Papa Doc.!
A'ight, brother,
you go to the next round.
A'ight, next up, next up...
is my man Bunny Rabbit...
and Li'l Tic.
Come on, man,
bring your asses to the stage.
We ain't got all day.
All right, all right.
Enough of the fanfare.
Call it--
heads or tails.
Heads.
Tails. Choose.
You first.
- Show.
- Li'l Tic, set it off.
D.J., 45 seconds. Spin that shit.
- # I'm gonna murder this man #
#He the type to lose
a fight with a dyke #
#They don't laugh
'cause you wack #
#They laugh 'cause
you white with a mike #
# You're a laughingstock
When will this laughin'stop #
#When you and Everlast
Bitch-ass, get popped #
# You a wigga that
invented rhyme for money #
#Watch Li'l Tic split kick
the Energizer Bunny #
# Rip the Rabbit head off
Toss it to Hugh Hefner #
# 'Cause I don't play, boy
Now tell me who's fresher #
You are!
#L. T., that's right
Cock the heat and shoot ya #
# I'll punish Rabbit
Or obsolete Future #
# My paws love
to maul an M.C. #
# 'Cause he faker than a psychic
with caller I.D. #
# So that bullshit
Save it for storage #
# 'Cause this is hip-hop
You don't belong
You're a tourist #
#So put your hockey sticks
and baseball bat away #
# 'Cause this here Detroit
16 Mile Road is thataway #
#Thataway ##
Whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay.
Forty-five seconds. Very nice.
And you did a good job,
Li'l Bitch--
I mean, Li'l Tic. My bad.
Next up is my boy
Bunny Rabbit.
Hey, nigga, talk all
that shit if you want to,
but I vouch for
this motherfucker right here--
he's a motherfucking genius.
Dig that shit.
Forty-five seconds, Rabbit.
D.J., kick it.
Hey, yo.
-
- Come on!
- Where'd y'all find this nigga at?
- Hey, Rabbit!
Come on, Rabbit!
Come on!
Choke! Choke! Choke!
Choke.! Choke.! Choke.!
Fuck you, motherfuckers!
Fuck you!
Yo,Jimmy.! Hold up.!
Man, don't even worry
about it, dawg, a'ight?
I'll call you tomorrow.
I got to go back inside, a'ight?
A'ight.
Stay strong, my brother.
- Yeah.
- You'll rip 'em next time.
Yep.
Yeah, next time.
Peace out, Rabbit!
What the fuck?
Oh, God.
Oh, shit, Rabbit.
You okay, baby?
Don't you think you should have
called or knocked first or something?
I mean--
The phone's disconnected.
I know that, Rabbit.
I got to get down to
the phone place tomorrow and--
- I been busy, you know?
- Rabbit, what the fuck
are you doing here?
How about knockin'?
Me and Janeane just broke up.
Oh, I'm sorry, honey.
I thought you had a really
good thing goin' with her.
- She sleepin'
with somebody else?
- No.
Yo, I got to work
in the morning, so--
You and Future still,
um, at that Little Caesars
over in Warren?
No. I'm down in
New Detroit Stamping now.
Oh. Well, that's good.
What?
He got fired from
a pizza place.
Yo. At least
I got a fuckin'job.
Okay, stop it.
Only ex-cons and welfare moms
work at that plant, man.
Baby, are y-you stayin' here
for a while or what?
Just for a couple weeks.
Got to save up enough
to get my own place.
Just like Bob Zurowsky.
You're plannin' on still living
at home, aren't you, Rabbit?
Okay.
What a bunch
of fuckin' losers.
- Fuck you.!
-Jimmy.!
- What's your problem,
you little ingrate?
- What's your problem?
Don't kick my fuckin' clothes!
Don't fuckin'judge me, man!
Why don't you grow up?
Goin' around actin' like a punk.
Motherfucker, what's up?
Stop!
Fuckin' punk!
Stop it.!
Hey, Lily.
Hey, baby.
What are you still doin' up?
You woke me up, you know.
- Yeah, I'm sorry, baby.
- What'd I do?
Let's go back to bed.
Will you sing to me?
Yeah, of course I will.
Come on.
# I know this girl #
# Her name is Lily #
#And it's past her bed #
#T-I-M-E #
# She goes to sleep #
#And she can just dream #
#And not have to be #
# ln a stinky trailer with me #
# So when I feel blue #
# Don't know what to do #
# I look at you #
#And I just say-- ##
Good night, baby.
Go to sleep.
Rabbit, if you're gonna live here,
you have to get along with Greg.
He started it.
You can't fuck this up
for me, baby.
You just can't.
Whatever.
No milk.
Yo, can I get a ride
to work in the morning?
Where's your car?
I left it with Janeane.
- You're gonna let me
borrow your car?
- Nope.
It's your birthday present.
My birthday's not for two weeks.
I know.
But you're still
my little Rabbit, right?
I need to get to sleep.
Bunny.! What up, doe?
Heard about
you and Janeane, dawg.
- Thought you
might be back home.
- This ain't my home.
Why you up so early?
Up, man?
I ain't even been to bed, dawg.
I came to talk to you--
Yo, I don't got time to talk
right now. I'm late for work.
Can you give me a ride?
My ma's got the car.
Yo, don't tell nobody
I'm livin' back here, man.
All right, dawg.
What happened to you last night?
I heard you got caught out.
People sayin'
some fucked up shit.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Man, why you still goin'
to The Shelter, dawg?
Ain't nobody down there
but a bunch of clowns who ain't
got deals and never gonna get deals.
You need to stay at home.
You know Wink's got ya.
Whatever, man.
Look, I'm telling you, man,
I'm on my way.
And I'm takin' you with me.
You're the franchise, baby.
The franchise?
Yeah.
I'm takin' a fuckin'
bus to work, man.
Look. I was just on the horn
with my man Roy Darucher.
That promo guy?
Yeah. Now Roy's
all hooked up at 98.
So what's he need you for?
What's he need me for?
Talent, dawg.
And you know
that's my specialty.
I'm the one that tipped him
on Big O and got that fat man
out of flippin' burgers.
Roy liked what he heard,
split some cash out
for that nigga's demo...
and-- boom--just like that,
Big O got himself a deal,
and it's all because of me.
Roy paid
for Big O's demo?
Every penny.
If they thought Big O was hot,
wait till they get a taste
of B-Rabbit.
I'm building an empire.
I'm taking you with me.
You're next.
A'ight.
I'll talk to you later.
Call me later, dawg.
Okay.
##
#Feel like
Still might #
#Still write #
#Real life #
# Gonna jump on stage
Kill mikes #
#Still white
Hate life #
#Brake lights
Stage fright #
#Drawin'a blank, like ##
Up! Down!
Up.! Down.!
What up, Manny?
I know.
You was late today, Smith.
It wasn't my fault.
My car wouldn't start.
It ain't never your fault.
I don't want to hear it.
I guess this probably
isn't the best timing,
but I really need
some extra shifts, Manny.
Are you shittin' me?
You just started working here--
Hey, Dutton.
Is he shittin' me?
What?
You late again, Smith,
and you're fired.
I'm lookin' for
John Latourno.
I can take you.
I don't think so, Smith.
Right this way.
Thank you.
##
#Big wheels keep on turnin'#
Who the fuck is that?
Greg Buehl.
# Carry me home to my kin #
That dude is practically livin'
with my fuckin' mom, dawg.
#Singin'songs
about the Southland #
They met at bingo.
Wait. Greg Buehl?
##
He went to our school, right?
Yeah.!
I got to save up some money
and get the hell out of here.
This shit is ridiculous.
##
#Well,Jimmy moved in
with his mother #
# 'Cause he ain't got
no place to go #
#And now I'm right back
in the gutter #
#With a garbage bag
that's full of clothes #
Bust it, bust it.
# 'Cause you live at home
in a trailer #
#What the hell
you gonna do #
Yee-haw.!
# 'Cause I live at home
in a trailer #
- # Mom, I'm comin' home to you #
- Break it down.
#Well, my name is Jimmy
His name's Greg Buehl #
- # Me, him and you
We went to the same school #
- # School #
# This ain't cool
I'm in a rage #
# He's tappin' my mom
We're almost the same age #
# On the microphone
I drop bombs #
# Look at this car
Thanks a lot, Mom #
#Here, happy birthday, Rabbit #
# Here's a brand-new car
You can have it #
#A 1928 Delta #
#The shit won't even
get me to The Shelter #
#And I can't even say
I'm from Motown #
# 'Cause I'm back in the 8-1 -0 now #
# 'Cause I live at home in a trailer #
# Mom, I'm comin' home to you ##
Jimmy,
you know there's another
battle next week, right?
- And I don't want to hear shit
about it. I'm signin' you up.
- Man, don't.
- Come on. You got to battle.
- Future, I'm not you, dawg.
- Look at me.
- Listen, once they hear you,
it won't matter
what color you are.
Look, you win
some of these battles,
Three-One-Third will have
all the street credit we need,
with you and me as the anchors.
Yo, did you hear that,
uh, Wink has been talkin'
to that promo guy?
Yeah. I heard that bullshit.
- Look, Wink is scandalous, dawg.
- Could be a shot.
You know I'm tryin' to get
straight with the Lord,
my man up there.
So I don't really like
bringin' too much negative
toward my positive world.
But Wink is just talkin' shit.
There'll be no action,just talk--
# Sweet home Alabama #
You got a cigarette?
- The dude mentally ill?
- Car accident, man.
He's supposed to get some big
settlement check soon or some shit.
Man, will you hurry up
with that thing?
- Yo, try it now.
Give it some gas.
That's what
I'm takin' about, baby.
Come on, man,
we goin' out tonight.
Uh! Uh!
Yeah, tonigh--
Tonight?
Look, fuck last night.
Okay? Forget it.
What about gettin'
straight with the Lord?
Come on, man, it's Saturday. I can
get straight with the Lord on Sunday.
##
Oh, hey, "B", I got
these new beats, man.
You know how much I like
your moms and everything, "B"--
Shit. How much I really,
really like your mama, Rabbit.
But she wasn't doin'you no favor
when she left you this car, man.
Fuck you.
Get out and walk.
At least the radio plays.
##
What up with the whole
East Coast/West Coast thing?
Word.
We got to put the Mo
on the map.
Yeah. Talk about the 3-1 -3.
Man, nobody even knows
Detroit is in 3-1 -3.
Three-one-three!
What the fuck
you talkin' about?
You from 8-1 -0.
Man, we just got
to make our own sound.
Fuck everybody else.
Then we get us a deal,
go platinum,
get cheesed out...
and get all the bitches!
- All the ho's.
- Mmm!
Do you think
I have a big head?
-
- Ohh! Ohh!
- Oh, shit!
- Why'd you bring that
damn thing, man?
- Oh, man. Do it.!
-Shoot.! Shoot.!
- Pinkeye, bitch!
- Let me see! Let me see!
Let me see! Let me see!
Let me show you motherfuckers
how to shoot something.
Let me show you.
- Do it, do it, do it.
Oh, okay, okay.
Here we go. Here we go.
Here it is. Here it is.
Here it is.
Take the wheel, man.
Come on,Jimmy.
Come on, man.
Take the gas.
You got the gas.
Man, come on, Rabbit.
Hey, Rabbit,
get back in the car, man.
Hit the bus.! Hit the bus.!
Hit the bus.!
- Ooh!
- Oh, no!
- No.! Don't do that.!
Oh, shit, man!
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
- Oh, shit!
- Fuck!
Toss the weed!
Toss the weed, Cheddar!
- Toss the motherfuckin' weed!
- Throw it out!
What the fuck you doin'?
- The fuckin' car just died, dawg.
- Oh, come on, man.
I told you stupid-ass niggas
not to be doin' that shit.
That rifle ain't mine, right,Jimmy?
I don't want to go to jail.
Shut the fuck up, Cheddar.
I'm fuckin' serious.
I get claustrophobic.
You were scared.
No, you were scared.
Man, you know how many
abandoned buildings
we have in Detroit?
How are you supposed to
take pride in your neighborhood
with shit like that next door?
And does the city
tear 'em down?
No. They too busy
building casinos and taking
money from the people.
Shut your preachin' ass up.
Nobody care about that shit.
Did you care when
that crackhead raped
that little girl?
You think that would have happened
if he didn't have an abandoned house
to take her to?
They caught him,
didn't they?
Yeah, they caught him.
Dumb motherfucker
went back to the house.
How stupid
could a nigga be?
Yo, Rabbit. What's happening
under that hood, man?
It's just a short. Chill out.
I ain't gettin' back in
that piece of shit.
It's a deathtrap.
I think Jimmy's mom's
tryin'to kill him.
Yeah. But she's
so goddamn fine.
Hell, yes.
Don't be sayin'
shit about my mom
or my fuckin' car, man.
I hear everythin'.
- He a ninja now?
Hey, Rabbit!
Okay, okay, okay.
It's about time.
#Money under the hood
Money on the mike #
# Freaky gals
here we come ##
Yo. Let me get a light, D.J..
##
#l gotta get mine
You gotta get yours #
##
Aw, shit. What the fuck's
goin'on out here?
What's up, man?
You all right?
Yeah, I'm cool.
Yeah? You sure?
Yeah.
You the man, Rabbit.
# I use my voice to speak
the fiery frame, try and refrain #
Come on, baby,
it's redemption time.
Come on, man. Come on, man.
#l be the nigga in The Shelter
I aim to change #
#Three-one-three area
Bomb and bury you
with vengeance #
# My rhyme sentences will put
an end to your existence #
#With a rigorousness
Niggas, I'm serious #
# Delirious
Cause a curious #
# Pause the fury calls
Through my jaws from
devouring y'all raw #
Whoo.!
Okay, okay. Three-One-Third,
we in the house.
You know what I mean.
Mac Mitten's finest.
D.J., give me that beat.
#You forced to listen to
the individual, the metaphysical #
# The Mac Mitten rhyme ritual
Heterosexual #
# Syllables, they sound
complex to you #
# Line's perplexin' you
With words that could
put a hex on you #
# Snap that neck on you
Murder you, boil you #
#We keep a white boy or two
Let my man grab the mike #
# You'll see how Bunny Rabbit do ##
Come on, man.
Come on, man. Come on.
Kick that shit, baby.
Come on.
Come on, man.
- Uh, uh.
- Watch that nigga kick this shit.
Uh, uh.
- All right, speed it up a little bit, lz.
- Come on, baby.
All right, look.
Yo. Yo.
#Your style is generic
Mine's authentic made #
# I roll like a renegade
You need clinic aid #
# My techniques bizarre and ill
I scar and kill #
#You were a star until I served
you like a bar and grill #
#As I proceed to cook
and grill ya, that's
all it took to kill ya #
#You better recognize me
Like I look familiar #
#You wanna battle
You beat around the bush
like you scared to lick pussy #
# So you eat around the tush
I need a clown to push #
# Someone that I can bully
Wait a minute, I don't think
you understand fully #
# Me without a style is like
mustard without the Heinz
I lead the new school #
#You're a buster without
the rhymes, I'll crush
the shit out ya lines #
# Now I'm Da Sheki
Smokin' da leaky leaky #
#Ten freaky girls
inside the Chin Tiki #
- # Girl, when you see me #
- #You better believe me #
#This ain't a game #
#And pimpin' ain't easy #
#Anything goes
when it come to ho's #
#l'm the kingpin
when it comes to flows #
#You better ask someone
if you don't know #
- #When you see me girl say #
- #What up, doe #
# Chin Tiki girls #
# Chin Chin Chin
Tiki girls ##
- Oh, shit. Look, man.
Listen up now.
Leadaz ofTha Free World
in the motherfuckin' house.
- Me and Papa Doc will battle
any motherfuckers here.
- Yeah.
- Told you them niggas
was talkin' shit.
- Man, fuck Tha Free World.
- Yeah! Fuck Tha Free World!
- Fuck Tha Free World?
You Three-One-Third bitches
is wack.
# Hey, yo, fat ass
Yeah, I'm talking about your man Sol #
# I bet if I kicked you
in your chest, pork chops
will fall out your asshole #
# You cats is pussy
Soft like wet flowers #
# Leadaz ofTha Free World
here to smash all you cowards #
- # Look at Future-- ##
- Don't even start, nigga.
- What you gonna do about it, faggot?
- Who you callin' a faggot?
Don't play yourself, bitch.
Hold on. Yo, Elvis.
You don't wanna step to this.
You need to take that
white-ass rap shit of yours
back across 8 Mile.
Caught your choke act
at The Shelter last night.
- Oh, shit!
Hey, what you gonna do
about this, niggas?
- Come on, man.
- No, no, no. Put the shit down.
- Come on, now!
- Pull out.! Pull out.!
- Chill, man. Come on, man.
- Yo, yo. It's cool.
Come on, now.
It's cool.
- Yo, come on, man, let's go.
- Come on!
I should fuck you up,
Cheddar.
What the fuck
were you thinkin', man?
"Fuck Tha Free World."
You just said it.
##
Yeah, Hip-Hop Shop.
Leadaz ofTha Free World.
A'ight, dawg.
Hey, Hip-Hop Shop,
Wednesday night.
Come on down.
Hey, girl, uh, it's gonna be
your only opportunity to blow
the both of us, baby.
'Cause after we go platinum,
you won't be able to get
to me and Future.
And, uh, why do
they call you Future?
See, I had a lot of names,
you know, the most conceited kind.
I was, uh, Maximum Brimstone,
Godfather "D', Devastatin' "D',
Big "D"--you know,
that has a double meaning to it.
But see, none of those
really worked for me...
till I started hosting those battles
down at The Shelter.
One day, somebody said,
"You know what, man?
You are the future
of hip-hop in Detroit."
So you see, baby,
sometimes you got to find
your name and, uh,
other times,
your name finds you.
You want to
smoke some ganja?
See, that's our problem.
If we don't respect
our sisters, who will?
Yo, we're doin' it
to ourselves.
He's my brother.
He don't like pussy.
Yo, Rabbit.
Teach me to write rhymes.
That's the way
to get the ladies, right?
Let me out.
Yo, yo, hold up.
Look, I'm sorry.
I didn't know Papa and L.C.
were on their bullshit until tonight.
Look, man, you know I wouldn't
be messin' with them...
except I'm promotin' a show with
them at the Hip-Hop Shop next week.
Those Free World bitches?
You see that the fuck
I'm talkin' about,Jimmy?
Look, man, they're
just one of the acts.
Hey,Jimmy, if you want,
I'll step out, man.
You're my friend.
I don't want you
bein' mad at me.
Man, do what you want to do.
Yeah, do what
you want to do, dawg.
Only respect, baby.
Let's go.
Respect yourself, sister.
Hey, don't you
ever shut up, man?
Why you got to push me?
Damn, Future.
Man, what the hell
is his problem?
Future?
Yeah.
- Thinks sometimes
you talk some bullshit.
- Who is he to say what's real?
Just 'cause he hosts
those battles?
Ain't thatJaneane
over there?
- Oh, yeah.
- I thought she was pregnant.
- I'm out, dawg. I'll be outside.
- Yeah.
A'ight.
A'ight, man.
By myself.
I'm gonna ask him.
Well, here's your chance, girl.
Go ahead.
You'reJimmy Smith,Jr.
Yeah.
My name's Alex.
So did you find the guy
you was lookin' for?
What guy?
The friend.
Yeah. That was my brother.
I was borrowing a car.
So... I hear you're
a real dope rapper.
A dope rapper?
Yeah.
Who told you
I was a dope rapper?
You know, it's around.
If you're so dope,
what you doin' workin' over
at Dead End Stampin'?
Your brother works there.
Yeah, my brother's a loser.
What about you?
I'm workin' at lntermezzo,
savin' up enough cash
to get out of this place.
Well, busin' dishes is much better
than pressin' bumpers.
I'm not gonna
be there long.
Where are you goin'?
New York.
I won this modeling contest
a couple of months ago.
One of the judges said
he could help me out.
Just got to get
a book together.
What if he ain't for real?
All I'm lookin' for
is a ticket.
Yo, Rabbit. You and your
new friend want to bounce
to an after-hours spot?
Rabbit?
Let me go ask my friends.
So how'd it go?
Guys, why don't we go to
this after-hours club?
So where we goin'?
Hmm? Oh. My house.
What about your mom?
Workin' nights now.
This the after-hours spot?
Heck, yeah.
Can some of us
ride with you?
- Why do they call you Rabbit?
- He's fast and he likes to fuck.
- Oh, well.
- Get your hand off my balls!
- Man, why do you be all ignorant for?
- Oh, shit!Jimmy.
- What's the matter with you?
- My bad, you guys.
So you signed anything yet?
Not yet, but but I'm workin'
on a little somethin' somethin'.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. He's gonna be courtin'
a demo at MCA soon.
- Really?
- Yeah, well--
If you really
want to seeJimmy flow,
make sure you come down
to the next battle at The Shelter.
Yeah.! He's the best.!
- Shut up, Cheddar.
- When's the battle?
- Friday night.
Yeah? Can I come?
There's no way I'm fuckin'
battlin' next Friday, dawg.
You know damn well
you're gonna battle if she's there.
'Cause you're gonna
want to be the man,
you know what I'm sayin'?
All right, man.
Just don't fuckin' push.
Guess we all need to be pushed.
Ha. My bad. I'm sorry.
You gonna let him push you?
You could never catch me
and you never will!
Out of my way,
freaky girl!
Wipe your feet!
##
You like?
Hmm?
She's getting out
of the "D," though.
Hey, bro, please.
That's what they all say.
Nah. I think she's different.
Hey, man, that chick
really blew both you guys?
I'm a sinner,James.
Come to the church with me
in the morning, a'ight?
Hey.
Uh, I saw you talkin'
to Papa Doc in Chin Tiki.
How you know him?
You mean Clarence?
He went to Cranbrook
with Christine's brother.
Do you want to dance?
Not right now.
Fuckin' Wink, man.
Tryin' to keep us in division
with all that fake-ass,
Big Willie wannabe talk.
Shit wrong with a free demo.
Free comes with a dick
right up your ass,Jimmy.
Three-One-Third is real.
The shit that Wink
is talkin' about is wack.
I don't understand
why the media's not
all over this.
It's just a matter of time
before it all happens again.
The city don't give a fuck.
What the hell
is he talkin' about?
That abandoned house where
that little girl got raped.
What you call
"an attractive nuisance. "
You better believe that place
wouldn't still be standing if it
was on the other side of 8 Mile.
It could have
been Lily, Rabbit.
Burn this shit
down to the ground.
Burn it down.
- That's what I'm talkin' about.
- Okay, I got it.
Fuckin' yeah, man.
Let's burn this fuckin' thing down.
- Let's go, Cheddar.
- This is the definition
of an attractive nuisance.
- Hey, Rock.! Come on, Rock.
Let's burn this thing.
- Right behind you, man.
- That's what I'm talkin'about.
- Yeah, baby.
Could have sworn
I had some matches.
You got some?
You got my lighter?
I gave it back to you.
- I got one.
- Wink,you got the lighter?
No!
- Oh, shit! Get out!
- Run!
Hey, what the fuck,
you guys?
I'm out!
Fuck you, Cheddar!
Hey, Rabbit, word!
Rah! Hey, I burned
the house down!
#The roof
The roof #
# The roof is on fire
We don't need no water #
# Let the motherfucker burn
Burn, motherfucker #
#Burn ##
It's almost beautiful.
When I was little,
I used to want to live
in a house like this.
You know, how it used to be.
You live with your family?
I got out of there
as quick as I could.
Left home when I was 17.
What about you?
Sort of the same.
When you record a demo,
I'd really love to be there.
Alex.
Hey, girl.
You're gonna be great.
I got a feelin' about ya.
Let's go, Alex.
See ya.
Cheddar, bring your ass on.! Come on.!
Doggone pesky mosquitoes.
Now, let's see.
Oh, yeah.
And the mirror said--
Shit.!
What's the matter?
We're bein' evicted.
Goddamn it!
Come on, Mom.
Not in front of Lily.
I can't let Greg
find out about this.
Fuck Greg.
Okay.
I'm three months late.
We got 30 days
to come up with the money.
What do you mean "we"?
If you're gonna live here,
you got to start chippin' in, Rabbit.
When's Greg gettin'
his settlement check?
Get the money from him.
No, no, I can't.
He's gonna ask me and Lily
to move away with him.
Someplace nice, real soon.
I-I can't freak him out.
You got to stop
livin' your life like this.
If you really cared about Lily,
you would get a job
and quit fuckin'around.
I got to go.
Be late for work.
What are you doin'
with your life that's
so great, Rabbit?
Wink's workin' on a deal where
I can get free studio time...
to record my demo.
Yeah. Right.
Bye, baby.
#Alex Latourno
Hotter than an inferno #
Up.!
# Hotter than
a crack house #
- Down!
- # Burn internal #
Up.! Down.!
I don't know why Manny's got to
give me so much shit all the time, man.
Maybe it's 'cause you
keep giving him reason to.
Stick to the plan, man.
Just do your work
and shut the fuck up.
Up.!
Down!
Why haven't you called?
Janeane, I can't
talk about this here.
You're gonna get me fired.
I'm your girlfriend.
No, you're
not my girlfriend.
We broke up.
I'll call you later.
You just took off
without sayin' a word.
At least I left you the car.
Was it 'cause I said
I was pregnant?
Come on,Janeane.
I know why you said that bullshit.
You got to get out of here.
I didn't know
what else to do.
Tell me why you left
and I'll leave you alone.
It's not you, okay?
Janeane, it's me.
It's my shit. I had to go.
Why?
What are you running from?
Nothing.
Would you just go?
You know that everybody's
calling you a loser
from the other night?
- Who said that?
- Everybody's talking about it.
How you froze up
and got booed offstage.
- Fuck you,Janeane. Go home.
- What was all that about?
- I'm sorry, Manny. It wasn't my--
- It won't happen again.
- Good.
Don't be bringin'
that shit around here.
Now get back to work.
Rakim was the first rapper
to get complex lyrics, man.
I give you Rakim, no question.
But as far as beat and lyrics
go, Biggie is the bomb.
I don't believe this shit.
Y'all gonna talk about
complex shit and then
leave out my man Tupac.
Fuck Tupac!
Fuck Tupac?
Nigga, you crazy!
- Pac's the only lyrical
motherfucker out there.
- His shit do got emotion.
What about the Beasties?
Man, fuck the Beasties.
How you even gonna bring
the Beasties' shit in the mix?
They bust
some serious shit.
No. The white boys,
that's more like busters
on some serious shit.
I ain't gonna
be bumpin' no Beastie,
but it's always easier for
a white man to succeed in
a black man's medium, right?
Word up. That's true.
Yo! Whoa!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.!
-All right.
What you doin', man?
Rabbit!
- Oh, shit.!
- Don't you worry, Rabbit.
I got your back.
Hey. Hey, what's up, "B"?
- You wanna fuck with us, bitch?
- Shut your bitch-ass up.
-
- Get off my man!
Yo, get off me, man.!
Yeah! You wanna
fuck with us? Huh?
- Fuck with us, yeah?
- Cheddar, what the fuck
are you doin'?
- Where did you get that shit?
- It's my mom's.
Man, put that shit away, dawg,
before you fuckin' kill somebody!
- Papa Doc had one!
- Put it away!
- Man, put that down, man.
- Come on, Cheddar.
- Okay. All right.
- Fuck man.!
- Oh, shit.!
- What the fuck?
- Shit.
- Let's get out of here.
You all right, man?
Oh, shit!
We got to get him
to a hospital, dawg.
Keys?
Where are the keys?
Get the fuckin'car.!
I got to put pressure on it.
- Try not to think about it.
- He shot his fuckin' dick off!
Did I?
Man, shut the fuck up, man!
Future,
take Gratiot to McDougall.
I live here too.
I know how to get there.
Then fuckin' get us there then!
Rabbit's gonna teach me
how to write rhyme.
What the fuck were you doin'
with a gun anyway, man?
with those motherfuckers?
- You know I had
a show tomorrow night!
- Calm the fuck down!
What are y'all trippin' about?
M.C. Bob.
What?
Man, what are you
talkin' about?
Is that a good name?
What's wrong
with Cheddar Bob?
I like M.C. Bob.
Right?
Yeah. M.C. Bob.
I'm the one that got that
fat man out offlippin'burgers.
Really?
Yeah. Now Roy's gotta
interview him down atJLB.
And I'm gonna be there.
Oh, it's finna be on.
So the doctor said
that he hit an artery,
but he's gonna be okay.
Oh, yeah.
That's good, man.
Where you been?
Prayin'.
Is he all right?
Yeah. It's cool.
Let's go.
Wink was just tellin' us how
he got in with Roy Darucher.
Yeah. Shit's hot, man.
He doin' an interview
down atJ LB.
Why you even listenin'
to this clown?
What?
You heard me.
Clown.
Man, I don't even know why
you got to be all like that.
This is a good deal for him.
This shit is for real.
Oh. It's for real?
- Like that time you said
your cousin worked for Dr. Dre?
Or like that time you were
real tight with that intern
in Russell Simmons' office?
-
- Or how about the time--
Man, shut the fuck up!
Why you always
givin' me shit, man?
I mean, is it because
I'm makin' moves?
Or is it because your ass
is stuck hosting battles
for, like, two years?
- You're a fuckin' loser.
- Who the fuck you callin' a loser?
Chill, man! Chill!
How can you guys fight
about this shit now?
I know what you're trying
to do with our group, bitch!
Cheddar's layin' up
in the fuckin' hospital and
you guys want to fight about this?
So fuckin' stupid.
Forget this car, "B."
I'll give you a ride
to work in the morning.
I'm afraid you've made a mistake.
I don't have any
little colored girl in my class.
Why, there's Sarah Jane.
There's my baby.
You mean Sarah JaneJohnson?
Yes, ma'am.
I'm Mrs.Johnson.
Sarah Jane, baby,
I brought you--
Sarah Jane.!
Did you win at bingo tonight?
No.
You record your demo yet?
What happened to you?
Cheddar Bob had an accident.
He's fine. I'm fine.
You and your friends.
Mom, don't start, please.
It's been a long fuckin' night.
Tell me about it.
Me and Greg
are havin' problems.
- He found out about the eviction?
- No.
The settlement check
ain't comin'?
No, it's comin?
It's comin'. It's our--
It's our sex life.
Mom, I don't want
to hear this shit.
I mean, it's good.
It's real good.
But he just doesn't like--
Mom, I don't want
to hear this.
Greg won't
go down on me.
Mom!
Hey, Sol. You ever wonder
what point you gotta
just say, "Fuck it, man"?
Like when you gotta
stop livin' up here
and start livin' down here?
It's 7:30
in the morning, dawg.
Yo, thank your mom
for the car, dawg.
A'ight.
# Man, I'm gettin'
so sick and tired #
# Of fuckin' with this steel #
#They only give us 30 minutes
to eat lunch and chill #
#My body achin'
just to get a buck #
# I'm sick of eatin' this shit
off this fuckin' lunch truck #
#Nasty-ass food
I'm in a nasty-ass mood #
# I should have called in sick
Shit, I had somethin' to do ##
# I can't believe I'm hearin'
all this ravin' and rantin' #
# From Vanessa up here
at the New Detroit Stampin' #
# You need to get your food
and take your ass back to work #
#You're dreamin' if you think
them corny-ass raps will work #
#Look at y'all
Standin'out here freezin'
like dumb fucks #
# Rappin' away for food
off this raggedy lunch truck #
# Who want what
Who pumped up
to get rolled up #
# I spit venom
in every direction
Soak some up #
# Look at this fat-ass nigga
Sloppy sucker #
# You an ugly motherfucker
Your pop should have
wore a rubber #
# Stop rhymin'
Keep your day job, Vanessa #
# Next time, leave that bullshit
home on the dresser #
#Speaking of dresses
Take a look at Paul the fruitcake #
# When you travel you probably
pack panties in your suitcase #
#Made out oflace
from Victoria's Secret #
# lf ten men came in a cup
you'd probably drink it ##
# Okay folks
Enough with the gay jokes #
# Especially from a gay broke
bitch yourself, eh, loc #
Who is this--
# His style is doo-doo #
#You've worked here
longer than me and I get
paid more than you do #
Serious, man.
# Dawg, take a seat #
#What's this guy
standin' in line for
He ain't got money to eat #
# Check this out
Yo,yo #
#This guy cashed his whole check
and bought one Ho-Ho #
# Fuckin' homo, little maggot
You can't hack it #
# Paul's gay, you're a faggot #
#At least he admits it
Don't even risk it #
- #This guy's starvin' to death
Someone get him a biscuit #
# I don't know what
they told you, Mike #
#You must have had them
cornrows rolled too tight #
#This job, you wanna quit
But you can't #
#You've worked at this plant
so long, you're a plant #
# Look at your goddamn boots
For Christ sakes #
- #They're startin' to grow roots #
# On this mike you get faded #
- #You look like a pissed-off rapper
who never made it #
- Ooh!
# Hey,why you fuckin'
with the gay guy, "G" #
#When really you're the one
who's got the H.I.V. #
Ooh!
# Man, I'm done with this clown
He's soft #
# Fuck it, I'll let homegirl
finish you off ##
#A guy like you
would never get a real woman
You jackass, gojack off #
# That's the only way you comin'#
Hey, lookin' for your brother?
I was.
Do you want to
do somethin' tonight?
Are you askin' me out
on a date,Jimmy Smith,Jr.?
Yeah, as a matter
of fact, I am.
Why don't you
take me somewhere now?
Come on.
Where are we going?
Bro.! We gotta start
that second pallet.!
You were so good outside.
- In line at a lunch truck?
- Yeah. And at the Chin Tiki
the other night?
And that demo thing
with Wink?
You're gonna get a deal soon.
I feel it.
You was in the parkin' lot
the other night?
My friends think you're crazy.
Yo, your friends
don't even know me.
Man, ain't nobody here.
I can't believe
they sent him home already.
If you ain't got insurance,
the medical establishment
will fuck you up.
Where the fuck else
would he be?
Just thank God he's alive.
No. Thank God he didn't
shoot his fuckin' dick off.
That's why brothers need
to sign themselves a deal.
I'm tellin' you.
Record labels supply niggas
with the benefits they need.
Dawg, if we sign us
a deal, you can take
the motherfuckin' benefits.
We talkin' Bentleys and Benjamins,
not Blue Cross and Blue Shield.
I don't give a fuck
about none of that.
I just wanna hear
Three And A Third on the box,
know what I'm sayin'?
One of them strong songs
on J LB, you know?
We need to save that shit up,
put it into savings bonds.
We can build
our own studio--
Savings bonds?
Let me ask you
a question, dawg.
How the fuck are we brothers?
We need fine bitches and phat rides,
- No goddamn savings bonds.
- That's all we ever do, man, is talk shit.
"We need to get fine bitches
and phat rides!"
"No, what we need to do is
put our money in savings bonds."
"No, what we need to do
is get our songs on J LB."
Man, shut the fuck up.
All of us never do shit about nothin'.
We're still broke as fuck
and live at home with our moms.
Yo, I'm outta here.
I'll catch you guys later.
Man, get yo' mad, ramblin'
ass in the car!
Yeah.
I hope you get a new ride soon.
Maybe for that
birthday trippin' ass.
I'm gonna call yo mama,
see what I can work out.
- I got shotgun, Shabba.
Nigga, get in the back, Farrakhan.
Man, why you pretendin'
to be asleep?
Yo, I seen you
out the window, Bob.
I didn't feel like talkin'.
Why not?
I didn't want them
makin' fun of me.
Do you know what
I'm sayin, Rabbit?
Yeah.
You do?
M.C. Bob.
It's like you see
in the magazines and stuff?
Without doubt.
Hey, Rabbit.
Where ya been?
You call him Rabbit, too?
I gave him
that nickname.
Stop it.
N-No, I did.
When he was little,
he had buckteeth
and big ears--
He was so cute.
"Wike a wittle wabbit."
Right, baby?
I got some good news--
You brought her
to my fuckin' moms?
What the fuck?
I invited her to my show.
She said we had to come and get you.
What was I supposed to do?
Look.
I been helpin' Al find
a photographer for her book.
All she keeps tellin' me is
how much she really likes you, man.
Damn!
Now, check this, dawg.
I heard from my man Roy today.
Now, he's gonna be down
toJ LB tomorrow night.
Doin' an interview with
Big O and shit. So what?
So what?
I dropped it! I told him
about your skills, man.
I said,Jimmy Rabbit's your man!
He said, bring him down...
and let me see
what he can do.
Look, man, if everything
goes well, you could be flowin'
down 54 Sound next week.
Now, can you get
your shit together in time?
Yeah.
I can do it.
My bad, man.
Oh, no problem, dawg.
Big time,Jimmy.
Why'd you take off?
I don't really live here.
So?
Why'd you take off?
I just--
You don't have to be
embarrassed about
where you live,Jimmy.
I don't live here!
What's up with you
and Wink?
He's helpin' me
get my book together.
Usin' his connections.
Same way he's
helpin' you out.
So--
You probably have to
stay home tonight, huh?
Yeah, I should work
on some songs for my demo.
Okay.
##
#Palms are sweaty #
#Sweaty already,
moms's spaghetti, he's nervous #
#Keeps on forgetting
what he wrote down #
#He opens his mouth
Words won't come out #
# The clock's run out #
# Turnin'and turnin'#
# You only get one shot
One shot, one shot #
# Opportunity-tunity lifetime #
#Lose yourself
Lose yourself, lose yourself #
# Turnin'and turnin'#
# You only get one shot
One shot, one shot #
# Opportunity-tunity lifetime, turn #
You know your mom's
gettin' evicted?
Says right here.
"Tenant must vacate the premises...
due to non-payment of rent."
You know about this?
Morning.
Sweetie, you want some cereal?
I was just talkin'to your precious son
about this eviction situation.
You plan on tellin' me
about this, huh?
Oh, honey, th-that was
just a mistake.
You're
a fuckin' liar.
Hey, man!
No, no.
Stay out of this, Rabbit.
It's okay, don't worry.
I'm takin' care of--
- Don't!
Fuck, man! What the fuck
is your problem?
You don't touch my mother, man.
Just stay out of it.
Stay out of it.
I'm out of here.
Can't go out with
someone like you.
Are you gonna let him just
talk to you like this?
- With two homeless kids.
Rabbit.!
Jimmy, no.! No.!
Rabbit!Jimmy!
Jimmy, please!
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop!
- Fuck you!
- Rabbit! Don't!
-
- Fuck you!
Stop it!
Stop it, Rabbit.
Oh, my God. Lily.
Come here, baby.
Come here.
It's okay.
Come here, baby.
Come here.
It's okay.
It's over.
It's over, baby.
Yo, what up, doe?
Alex just called. I got
one of my friends to take pictures
of her when she gets off work.
So she needs a ride.
You know, that's why she called.
- Yo, can you drive?
- I don't care. I'll drive.
The others be here in a minute,
so's my uncle can drop 'em off
on the way to work.
Hey. I heard that
your battlin' tomorrow night.
- I'm doin' what?
- Someone told me Future
signed you up at The Shelter.
- Who told you that?
-
- Yo, what up, dawg?
- What up, dawg?
Wipe your feet, dawg.
I ain't gonna wipe any feet.
Hey,
where yo' mama at?
Workin', dawg.
Yo mama.! Tell yo'moms
to hang all that shit up.
Yo, did you sign me up
to battle tomorrow night
at the fuckin' Shelter?
What?
You heard me. Don't play
fuckin'stupid with me, man.
Did you sign me up?
Jimmy--
You know Papa Doc won last week,
so he'll be defending his title.
You gotta try to take
that shit from him, man.
You win battles,
you get respect--
I don't give a fuck, man!
I'm sick of you
always thinkin' you know
what's best for me, dawg.
You ain't my fuckin' father.
I'm a grown man.
Look,Jimmy, I know--
LookJimmy nothin'.
Fuck you!
I told you not
to fuckin' sign me up.
What the fuck?
You wanna fight me now, huh?
Yo, you ain't the Future
of shit, bitch!
You just
David fuckin' Porter.
Hey, come on, fellas.
You know what?
Do what the fuck
you wanna do, man.
'Cause I don't
give a shit anymore.
I really fuckin' don't.
So you comin'
toJ LB tonight?
I don't know, man.
##
I look like crap.
If we knew it was today,
I wouldn't have never
gone out drinking...
after the show last night.
I could always reschedule.
No, no, no, no, no.
I want to do it.
Yeah. You want to do it?
Yeah.
When are we gonna see
this little pictorial
in a magazine, Alex?
Pictorials for Playboy, fool.
In fashion, it's "editorial."
God damn, Frederick Douglass,
will you shut the fuck up?
It's for her book, man.
- So she can get a job.
- That's one book
I'd definitely read.
That'd be the only one.
##
Don't forget this.
Thanks, guys.
- See ya.
- Bye.
- # Can't keep runnin'away #
- Want me to come up?
- That's okay.
- # Can't keep runnin'away #
# Can't keep runnin'away ##
Mom.
Mom, come on.
Get up.
Come on.
Come on!
Greg left me.
Yeah?
He left me.
Oh.
Damn!
Come on. Get up.
Hi, honey.
It's okay, Lily.
It's okay, honey.
His settlement check came in.
And now that he's got money,
he can't be with somebody
like me anymore.
It's Thursday.
I got-- I got--
I gotta go to bingo.
Maybe he'll be there.
You're goin' nowhere.
Better off without him.
Stop it.!
Stop it.
It's your fault he left me.
You ruined it! You ruined it.
You fucked it all up for me.
Who's gonna want me now?
Who's gonna want me?
Where are we gonna live?
We don't have any money!
We don't have anything!
What am I gonna do?
- What am I gonna do?
- What are you gonna do?
Lily's out there
by herself right now!
Why do you got to
be like this?
What did we ever do to you?
Get the fuck out of here.
Get the fuck
out of my house!
out of my house.!
Come on, baby.
Put your coat on.
We're goin' next door, okay?
We're gettin' out of here.
Come on.
I love you--
What floor is J LB on?
Twenty-eight.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
When we look at Big O,
what are we lookin'at, baby?
I'm givin'you poverty.
I'm givin'you the slums.
That's where I'm from.
So I put it all in the music.
I'm lookin' for
Wink Harris.
Who?
He's supposed to be here
with Roy Darucher.
Oh, I think they're
all down in Studio "B."
All right. Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
I did anything for free--
anything for the exposure.
No doubt. Big "O, "big ups
and congratulations, playboy player.
You finally got your record on the radio.
How does it make you feel, man?
Oh, man, that's much love.
I want to thank you
and WJ LB, man...
for lookin'out for me
like that, dawg, so much love.
I'm tryin'to put Detroit--
the east side, for sure-- on the map.
Know what I'm sayin'?
And we gonna do it for real.
We'll get a pipeline
to come through here, and
the industry'll look at us...
and they'll sign all of us,
man, we'll all be eatin?
Whoa, whoa--
Wait, wait, wait--
Jimmy!
Stop it! Stop it!
I've seen you flippin' burgers,
baby, I know I have!
Yeah, I did that, man.
I thought I recognized
your face, baby.
Stop it! Fuckin' stop it!
Please! Please stop.
Stop it.Jimmy, stop it!
-Jimmy--
- How long you been
in the game, baby?
- Aw, man, fifteen years.
It's an honor for mejust to come on WJLB
and have you doin'this for me.
I really appreciate it.
No problem, baby.
You know, wejust here
to represent the "D. "
You know, and take care of
our artists and take care ofhome.
And I hope you have a successful career,
'cause I know you puttin'it down.
You represent real hard
for the 3-1 -3.
For sure, man, I'm doin' it.
I'm doin' it for y'all, man.
This is for Detroit.
3-1 -3, baby. Love.
Thank you,
Mrs. Helgeland.
Any time,Jimmy.
Have a good night.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, did you have fun?
Yeah. I know.
##
Okay, baby. I want you to go inside.
I want you to lock the door, okay?
Listen to me.
Go inside, lock the door.
I'll be in
in a minute, okay?
Okay.
Okay. Go.
Go!
Yo, what up, bitch?
You ready to get
knocked out, doe?
Wink said you lived
in a trailer with your mom.
But we didn't believe him.
Come on, Elvis.
Get up.
Get up, bitch.
##
Get yo'faggot ass up and fight.
What? What the fuck
is you lookin' at?
Get down, you faggot.
Get down!
-Jimmy!
Come here.
Get the fuck up there.
Stop it!
Fight me,
you punk-ass bitch!
- What the fuck you gonna do?
I could end your shit right now,
and nobody would even miss your ass.
No, no, no. No, no.
Don't do this.
Come on. He's done.
- Free World, motherfucker.
Don't forget to come
to The Shelter tomorrow night!
Yeah, see you down there
you li'l rabbit!
Jesus!
What happened to you?
I fell.
You fell.
Come on in.
I'll make you something to eat.
What?
I'm your mother.
I want to make you
something to eat.
What's the big deal?
I thought you wanted me out.
You want
the fuckin' pancakes or not?
What's gotten into you?
We're not gettin' evicted.
Why not?
I went to bingo.
And I won!
Thirty-two hundred!
- You're kidding me!
- Nope.
Our luck's finally changing
around here.
Did you mean what you said about
doin' that demo with Wink?
No.
I'm gonna do it on my own.
You know, Rabbit?
I think that's the best way.
Hey, Smith!
Hey! Smith!
Are you all right?
I fell down some steps.
You been doin' much better here.
You still want those extra shifts?
Yeah.
You got 'em. I need you
to work tonight. I'm a man short.
Tonight?
Is that a problem?
No problem.
Good.
Go on.
Get back to work.
Hey, Manny!
Thanks.
What up?
Shit.
Waitin' on this slow-ass ride.
What are you still doin' here?
Somebody called in sick,
so I'm just fillin' in.
She ain't waitin' on me.
I'll be back.
What do you want?
I wanted
to say good-bye.
I'm goin' to New York.
Yeah? And--
Can I give you a ride?
There's some things--
No, I'm cool.
Workin' overtime.
Saving up for
something special?
Yeah.
Studio time.
Good.
Good for you.
I was hopin' to see you
at The Shelter tonight.
But if you're afraid--
I'm not afraid
of them guys.
I didn't say you were.
Bye.
Hey, Paul.
Would you mind covering
for me for a couple hours?
Yeah, I can do that.
Thanks, man.
I owe you.
##
- Hey.! It's Rabbit.! Hey.!
- Come on, man.
Yo, Rabbit, wait up!
What's up, man?
What the hell happened to you?
You straight?
Look at your eye.
Yeah, man. I'm fine. Come on.
Wink's sayin'you blew up
'cause Roy Darucher
wouldn't pay for your demo.
He's also sayin' some crazy shit
about him and Alex.
We gonna jump
those guys again?
Fuck that.
I'm gonna battle 'em.
- For real?
- Yeah.
Damn.
Yo, you guys comin'
or what?
##
Cheddar, I can rip you to
a shred of cheddar cheese.
There's not
a better M.C. than me.
I'm B-Rabbit, bitch.
Sting like a bee.
Float like a butterfly.
What am I?
So what if I cut a guy?
Did I s-s-stutter, guy?
Leave you punch drunk
From lunch truck to Shelter.
You never felt the wrath
of helter-skelter melt ya,
got the belt
for the welterweight champ.
You got in
with a fake stamp.
Garbage bag full of clothes,
still pullin' ho's.
Rip you from head to toe,
from leg to bullet hole.
Next gun, pull it slow.
And aim at Tha Free World
'fore you let it go.
Instead of,
"Oh! I just shot my dick head."
And yes, you do got a big head.
I can't call it.
Cheddar, where's your wallet?
You're so drunk, you can
out-drink the Alkoholiks.
Make 'em say,
"Damn! Cheddar's the man.
He needs a can
surgically removed
from his hand--"
You again? It look like a fuckin'
handicap convention in here.
- Bunch of crippled motherfuckers.
- Oh, yeah. Don't shoot!
Hey,yo.
Let's get the fuck out ofhere.
Fuck them.
Yo, I need to get
some privacy, guys.
Can I come?
##
Hey, man.
I apologize--
Stop it.
Don't do it.
I ain't even trip.
But you just make sure...
you flip the script
on this shit tonight.
You understand me?
Hmm?
- Thank you.
- It's on tonight, Rabbit.
Let's do it.
A'ight, a'ight, a'ight, a'ight.!
How you feelin' out there?
You feelin a'ight?
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
- Next up is L.C. Lyckety-Splyt.
- Slaughter 'em, Lyckety. Slaughter 'em.
And my man B-Rabbit.
B-Rabbit, where you at?
B-Rabbit, come to the stage.
Where the fuck is B-Rabbit?
Yo, homie. Where's he at?
Yo, "B." They're callin' your name.
You drew Lyckety-Splyt in the first round.
You okay with that?
Yeah.
Don't give a fuck who it is.
Okay.
Where the fuck
is B-Rabbit?
B-Rabbit?
What're you sayin,
brother?
Got everybody waitin?
All right, let you all know,
it's gonna be blazin'
up in this bitch tonight.
Got a lot of dope rappers
comin'to the stage,
and it's gonna be nice.
One of these cats
is goin'down a winner
via sweet Papa Doc.
Trust me. If this shit is goin'where
I think it is, I might want to stick around.
Come to the stage, Rabbit.
Come to the stage.!
B-Rabbit, where you at?
Oh, there he is. Come on.
All right, make way for the Rabbit.
Let him come through.
Come on, let the artist
get to the motherfuckin'stage.
Come on, man.
All right, come on up.
Come on, B-Rabbit.
Let him up, let him up.
You good? Choose somethin'.
Heads.
Heads?
- You got it.
- All right, my man.
I'm goin' first against
this choke artist here.
Well, baby, you got
enough confidence.
Get serious.
Okay, do your thing.
Forty-five seconds.
Yo, D.J., spin that shit.
##
Free World, okay?
Tell you somethin'.
##
Check this out.
Yo.
This guy's a choke artist.
#You catch a bad one,
you better off shootin' yourself
with Papa Doc's handgun #
# Climbin' up this mountain
You're weak, I leave you
lost without a paddle #
#Floatin'up shit's creek
You ain't Detroit, I'm the "D"#
#You the new kid on the block
'bout to get smacked back
to the boondocks #
# Fuckin' Nazi
Your squad ain't your type
Take some real advice #
#And form a group with Vanilla lce #
#And what I tell you
You better use it
This guy's a hillbilly #
#This ain't Willie Nelson music #
#Trailer trash, I'll choke you
to your last breath
And have you look foolish #
# Like Cheddar Bob when he shot himself
Silly Rabbit #
# I know why they call you that
'Cause you follow Future #
# Like he got carrots
up his ass crack #
#And when you acted up
That's when you got
jacked up and act stupid #
# Like Tina Turner
when she got smacked up #
# I crack your shoulder blade
You'll get dropped so hard #
#That Elvis'll start
turnin' in his grave #
-
- # Now I know why they left you
out in the dark #
#Take your white ass back across 8 Mile
to the trailer park ##
Oh, no, oh.!
Okay, okay, okay. Okay, okay.
Very nice, very nice.
Let me get that mike, man.
Pretty good, pretty good.
Hip-hop 101 .
Hey, Bunny Rabbit.
It's your turn, baby.
Forty-five seconds.
Let this motherfucker feel it.
A'ight?
Yo, D.J., spin that shit.
##
- Come on, Rabbit!
- Don't choke this time.
##
A'ight, look.
He's chokin'!
##
Hey, yo.
#This guy raps like
his parents jerked him
He sounds like Erick Sermon #
#The generic version #
#This crowd looks suspicious
It's all dudes in here
Except for these bitches #
#You want a German, eh
That's okay, you look like
a fuckin' worm with braids #
#These Leadaz Of
Tha Free World rookies
Lookie #
# How could six dicks be pussies #
# Talkin'bout shit's creek
Bitch,you could be up
piss creek with paddles #
#This deep
You're still gonna sink
You're a disgrace #
#Yeah, they call me Rabbit
This is a turtle race #
# He can't get with me
spittin' this shit wickedly
lyckety-shot #
- #A spick-a-spickety, Split-Lickety #
- Oh, no, no!
# I'm gonna turn around with a smile
and walk my white ass
back across 8 Mile ##
Oh-h! Oh, oh! Say no mo'!
That's what I'm talkin' about!
It's unanimous!
Bunny Rabbit goes
to the next round!
And Lyckety--
Tell yo' mama I'll be over later.
Tell her to save me a plate.
You killed him. Good shit.
A'ight, a'ight, a'ight.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Next up, next up,
we got, uh-- Ox and Strike.
Come to the stage, motherfuckers.
We ain't got all day.
Yo, Rabbit!
Okay, okay, B-Rabbit.
Call it.!
Heads.
Heads!
Choose. Lotto, it's on you, baby.
You first.
Don't matter none.
D.J., spin that shit!
##
Oh, look!
Oh, he's takin' his shirt off.
Come on,
smack this cat, all right?
Fuck this coward, dawg.
Free World's in
the motherfuckin'house.
What's goin'on, baby?
Yo, it's time to get rid
of this coward here
once and for all.
I'm sick of this
motherfucker.
Rip it, Lotto.
Rip it, baby, rip it.! Yeah.!
#Yo, I spit a racial slur
Honky, sue me #
#This shit is a Harlem flick
But the black guy doesn't
die in this movie #
-
- #Fuckin'with Lotto, dawg
You got to be kiddin'#
#That makes me believe
you really don't have
a interest in livin' #
#You think these niggas gonna
feel the shit you say #
# I got a better chance
joinin' the K.K.K. #
#Know some real shit, though
I like you-- that's why
I didn't want to be the one #
#You commit suicide to
Fuck Lotto
Call me your leader #
# I feel bad that
I got to murder that dude
from Leave lt To Beaver #
#l used to like that show #
# Now you got me in fight back mode
But oh well, if you got to go
You got to go #
# I hate to do this
I would love for this shit to last #
# So I'll take pictures of my rear end
so you won't forget my ass #
#And all is well that ends okay
So I'll end this shit with a
"Fuck you, but have a nice day" ##
Whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay.
Can't be bad.
- Kill that fucked-up white boy.
- That ain't shit. That ain't shit.
Settle down, settle down.
Give the man a chance.
All right, Bunny Rabbit's up next.
All right, B-Rabbit? You got the mike.
It's on you.
You know what to do.
D.J.! Spin that shit!
##
He ain't got shit, I say.!
What up?
You got somethin'?
- Let me hear somethin?
- You can't fuck with us. Yeah.
- Let's see what you got.
- Come on, Rabbit.!
Come on, Rabbit!
Get him!
No more here.
Nah!
#Ward, I think you were
a little hard on the Beaver #
# So was Eddie Haskell
Wally and Ms. Cleaver #
Who-oa!
# This guy keeps screamin'
He's paranoid #
# Quick, someone get his ass
another steroid #
# Blah-de-bee-bee, blah blah
Blah-be-dee, blooh blah #
# I didn't hear a word you said
Hippity-hoo blah #
# ls that a tank top
Or a new bra #
# Look, Snoop Dogg has got
a fuckin' boob job #
# Didn't you listen to
the last round, meathead
Pay attention #
- #You're sayin' the same shit
that he said #
- I'm gonna fuck you up!
# Matter of fact, dawg, here's a pencil
Go home, write some shit #
# Make it suspenseful
And don't come back
until somethin' dope hit you #
# Fuck it, you could take
the mike home with you #
Whoa.!
# Lookin' like a cyclone hit you #
#Tank top's screamin'
"Lotto, I don't fit you" #
#You see how far
Them white jokes get you, boys like #
# "How's Vanilla lce gonna dis you" #
#My motto, fuck Lotto
I'll get the seven digits from
yo'mother for a dollar tomorrow ##
-
- Oh! O-Oh! Oh, oh, oh!
Whoo!
It's as real as it feels.!
A'ight, hold on.
Hold on. Hold on.
That was some close shit.
Let's see what's poppin'.
A'ight, how are you feelin'
about Lotto up here?
Okay, okay, okay.
B-Rabbit.
Okay. We gonna do this again.
We gonna do this again.
It's hard to judge.
A'ight, we'll start with Lotto.
Okay, a lotta love.
A lotta love. Lotta love.
What about B-Rabbit?
"B. "got more.!
Say no more.!
B-Rabbit advances
to the next round.!
He's goin' to the finals.
He's goin' up against Papa Doc.
That's the way
it's goin' down.
A'ight, check this.
Check this. We're goin' to have
a 15-minute intermission.
Make sure you tip
the bartenders and all that.
Fifteen minutes, y'all.
Y'all be back for
the final round, all right?
Yeah, that's all right, 'cause Wink got
mo' than seven digits from yo' bitch!
##
Yeah. You hit it, kid.
Boom. Boom. Boom. Boom.
Ha-ha!
Man, fuck him.
Fuck Lyckety, man.
Yo, that Leave lt To Beaver
line almost killed me.
You flipped it on him.
You got it, man. You're
a fuckin' genius, man.
Just make sure you serve
this clown in the next round
for me, please.
Whup Papa Doc's ass.
Yeah, he ain't got
no vocabulary.
Are you worried about
what he's gonna say?
What do you mean?
You know, about Wink
and that Alex bitch
gettin' it on...
and then, them beatin'
you up and givin' you
a black eye and shit?
- Come on, Cheddar!
- Fuck all that.
Listen to me, man.
- You makin' history tonight.
-
It ain't nothin'. You got him.
- Oh, yeah.
- You got this.
Oh.! Now right beside me
is the championship round.
And yes, believe it's real.
It's time!
We got Papa Doc...
and we got B-Rabbit.
Now, I don't even have
to stress how important this is.
It's the championship.!
This motherfucker
is what we came to see.
Know what I'm sayin'?
That's why the fuck we're in the "D."
We represent!
We at The Shelter, goddamn it!
It's real! I hope y'all ready!
This shit is about to be
already crackolatin'
up in this bitch.
A'ight, hold on,
hold on, hold on!
Gotta do this coin toss.
And bein' that Papa Doc is
the champion, you get to choose.
What do you want to do,
heads or tails?
Heads.
Okay.
Who goes first?
Let that bitch go first.
Whoa, ho, ho.
Whoa, ho, whoa!
I can't believe my ears.
A lot of hostility!
Papa got a lot of anger!
All right, all right, all right.
Hey, check this out.
We got new rules.
Bein' it's
the championship round.
Each of these cats, they get
a minute and a half apiece.
I don't know what's
gonna happen. You ready?
You know what to do?
D.J., kick that shit!
##
Fight.! Fight.! Fight.!
# Now, everybody from the 3-1 -3
Put your motherfuckin' hands up
and follow me #
# Everybody from the 3-1 -3
Put your motherfuckin' hands up
Look, look #
# Now while he stands tough
Notice this man did not
have his hands up #
#This Free World's got you gassed up
Now who's afraid of the big, bad wolf #
# One, two, three
and to the four #
# One Pac, 2Pac, 3Pac, four
4Pac, 3Pac, 2Pac, one #
#You're Pac, he's Pac
No Pac, none #
#This guy ain't no
motherfuckin' M.C. #
# I know everything he's got
to say against me #
# I am white, I am a fuckin' bum
I do live in a trailer with my mom #
# My boy Future is an Uncle Tom
I do got a dumb friend
named Cheddar Bob #
#Who shoots himself
in his leg with his own gun #
# I did get jumped
by all six of you chumps #
#And Wink did fuck my girl
I'm still standin' here screamin'
"Fuck Tha Free World" #
# Don't never try to judge me
Dude, you don't know what
the fuck I been through #
# But I know something about you
You went to Cranbrook
That's a private school #
# What's the matter, dawg
You embarrassed #
#This guy's a gangsta
His real name's Clarence #
# Clarence lives at home
with both parents, Clarence's parents
have a real good marriage #
# He don't know how to battle
He's shook #
# 'Cause ain't no such things
as halfway crooks #
#He's scared to death
He's scared to look
At his fuckin'yearbook #
- # Fuck Cranbrook #
- ##
Fuck a beat.
I go a cappella.
Fuck a Papa Doc. Fuck a clock.
Fuck a trailer. Fuck everybody.
Fuck y'all if you doubt me!
I'm a piece of fuckin' white
trash, I say it proudly.
And fuck this battle.
I don't want to win.
I'm outtie.
Here, tell these people something
they don't know about me.
Papa Doc!
What you gonna do?
D.J..! D.J..!
A minute and a half!
Spin that shit.!
##
What? What? What?
Yo.
Whoa! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
We got a new champion.!
We got a new champion.! B-Rabbit.!
- B-Rabbit.!
- Let's roll.
Fuck Free World!
3-1 -3!
B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit,
B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit--
Three-One-Third!
We in the house!
Never get it twisted,
this is my man right here!
B-Rabbit!
This is my man,
right here!
Yo, we have it, Rabbit.
Yo, we on our way, dawg.
We gonna get that
big deal soon!
And then we go get
all the bitches!
All the bitches!
- Where we goin'?
- I'm goin' back to work.
Work?
Get the fuck outta here.
You ain't goin' to work!
Yeah, you the man now, dawg.
You ain't gotta work.
Yeah, fuck Wink.
Fuck Tha Free World,
we are the shit!
- Hey, what's up, y'all?
- Hold on.
Look, man,
I been thinkin'.
You and me
to host the battles
together.
You know
what I'm sayin'?
Nah. That's you, dawg.
Come on.
Tell me you don't want
to host with me.
I mean, you have everybody
lookin' up to you,
everybody know
who you are--
Yeah, but...
I think I kinda need
to just do my own thing, man.
You know?
Yeah. I think I do.
A'ight, Rabbit.
Peace out, Rabbit!
##
Look.
#lf you had one shot #
# Or one opportunity #
# To seize everything
you ever wanted #
#ln one moment #
# Would you capture it
Orjust let it slip #
# Yo, his palms are sweaty
Knees weak, arms are heavy #
# There's vomit on his sweater already
mom's spaghetti #
#He's nervous but on the surface
he looks calm and ready #
# To drop bombs but he keeps on
forgetting what he wrote down #
# The whole crowd goes so loud
He opens his mouth but
the words won't come out #
#He's chokin'how
Everybody's jokin'now
The clock's run out #
# Time's up, over, blaow
Snap back to reality
Oh, there goes gravity #
# Oh, there goes Rabbit, he
choked, he's so mad but he won't
give up that easy #
#No, he won't have it
He knows his whole back's
to these ropes #
#lt don't matter, he's dope
He knows that, but he's broke
He's so sad that he knows #
# When he goes back to this
mobile home, that's when it's
back to the lab again #
# Yo, this whole rap shit
He better go capture this moment #
#And hope it don't pass him #
#Just melt in the music
The moment you want it
you better never let it go #
# You only get one shot
Do not miss your chance to blow #
# This opportunity comes
once in a lifetime #
# Give it up
Just melt in the music
the moment you want it #
# You better never let it go
You only get one shot, do not
miss your chance to blow #
# This opportunity comes
Once in a lifetime
Give it up #
#Soul's escaping, through
this hole that is gaping #
# This world is mine for the taking
Make me king #
#As we move toward a
New World Order
A normal life is boring #
#But superstardom's
close to postmortem
It only grows harder #
#Homie grows hotter
He blows us all over #
#His ho's is all on him
Coast-to-coast shows, he's
known as the Globetrotter #
#Lonely roads, God only knows
He's grown farther from home #
#He's no father, he goes
home and barely knows
his own daughter #
#But hold your nose 'cause
here goes the cold water #
#His ho's don't want him
no mo, he's cold product #
#And they moved on
to the next schmo who flows #
#He nose-dove and sold nada
And so the soap opera #
#ls told, it unfolds
I suppose it's old, partner #
#But the beat goes on
Dah-da-dum, da-dum da-dah #
#Lose yourself in the music
The moment you want it
You better never let it go #
# You only get one shot
Do not miss your chance to blow #
# This opportunity comes
once in a lifetime #
#Lose yourself in the music
The moment you want it
You better never let it go #
# You only get one shot
Do not miss your chance to blow #
# This opportunity comes
once in a lifetime #
# Give it up #
#No more games
I'm gonna change #
# What you call rage
Tear this motherfuckin'roof off #
#Like two dogs caged
I was playin'in the beginning #
# The mood all changed
I been chewed up and spit out
and booed off stage #
#But I kept rhymin'
and stepped right in the next cypher #
#Best believe somebody's
payin'the pied piper #
#AII the pain inside
amplified by the #
#Fact that I can't get by
with my nine-to-#
#Five and I can't provide
the right type of #
#Life for my family
'Cause man, these goddamn
food stamps #
#Don't buy diapers
And it's no movie
There's no Mekhi Phifer #
# This is my life
and these times are so hard #
#And it's gettin'even harder
Tryin'to feed and water
my seed plus #
# Teeter-totter caught up
between bein'a father
and a prima donna #
#Baby momma drama screamin'
on her too much for me
to wanna stay in one spot #
#Another day of monotony's
gotten me to the point
I'm like a snail #
#l've got to formulate a plot
or end up in jail or shot #
#Success is my only
motherfuckin'option
Failure's not #
#Mom, I love you but
this trailer's got to go #
#l cannot grow old
in Salem's Lot, so here I go
It's my shot #
#Feet fail me not
This may be the only
opportunity that I got #
# You better
Lose yourself in the music
The moment you want it #
# You better never let it go
You only get one shot #
#Do not miss your chance to blow
this opportunity comes
once in a lifetime #
# Give it up
Lose yourself in the music
The moment you want it #
# You better never let it go
You only get one shot #
#Do not miss your chance to blow
this opportunity
comes once in a lifetime #
#Move it up #