The death of the unknown
singer named Shin Jae Hyun...
has been known as suicide,
but it was actually...
homicide staged as suicide.
Who knew you'd end up helping
me out so much in the end?
Let's toughen up and do this in one go.
Wait. Please...
Please... Please don't kill me.
Please don't kill me.
Let's do this in one go.
This can't be.
Four years ago, Shin Jae
Hyun's death was...
disguised as suicide.
It was done by Jang Do Pal,
the former vice president...
Mr. Jang Do Pal.
(Arrest Warrant)
Also, Actor Choi Tae Ho was...
implicated in the crime.
It was a murder plotted...
by those two men.
I hereby request the prosecution...
to re-investigate this case.
- Watch out!
- Gosh. I said I wasn't in danger.
You were. You know what
kind of a person he is.
Hello?
Tae Ho just left.
Gate Three.
Okay.
Moreover, Yoon So Hee recorded the
sound of this murder scene...
using her cell phone.
Because of that, she became...
the target of Jang Do Pal and
Choi Tae Ho's deceptive act.
I'd like to request...
a thorough re-investigation
of Yoon So Hee's murder case.
How did So Hee record it?
Do you think Seo Joon Oh is
irrelevant to this case then?
Is Joon Oh going to be here
at the conference today?
Is it certain that he's still alive?
We just arrested Choi Tae Ho.
We caught him running away.
Okay.
Choi Tae Ho has been
arrested by the police.
That's enough.
You should leave us something
to investigate on at least.
I urge the prosecution to carry out...
a fair investigation, so
that there won't be...
any more victims.
That's all for today's conference.
(Episode 15)
Gosh, Ji Ah. Thank you.
Thank you so much for not doing anything.
Ji Ah played a very crucial role.
She didn't do anything.
- That's right.
- Why do I feel strange?
I was worried because I couldn't reach you.
You too, Mr. Jeong.
By the way, is Tae Ho really arrested?
Why do you keep asking that?
Are you disappointed?
I'm not disappointed.
I just can't believe it.
Jang Do Pal and Tae Ho are both arrested.
I think you should...
take care of the company from tomorrow, Mr.
Vice President.
- That's true.
- I'm going to find another agency.
I didn't exactly ask for the job.
Besides, why would I take
care of the company?
President Hwang is awake now.
He'll take care of it.
Am I right, President Hwang?
Joon Oh. You should've asked
Ho Hang to be the spy,
not Byeong Joo.
He's so good at acting that I thought...
he was on Jang Do Pal's side.
You don't get it.
It was so hard for me.
That's not how it looked.
I wish every day is like today.
I'm a bit anxious that only
good things are happening.
You shouldn't be anxious about that.
We still have one big task left.
Clearing Joon Oh's false charges?
Joon Oh. Don't worry about a thing.
We'll tell the truth this time...
and roll out a red carpet for you,
so that you can make a glamorous return.
Should I wear a suit?
Get me a suit.
I will.
Hello.
I'm an attorney from Choi and Park.
The Legend Entertainment's attorney
is already on Jang Do Pal's side.
He hired another attorney.
He knows how to protect himself.
Search every detail of his doing.
Make sure Choi Tae Ho
doesn't get away with it.
Of course not.
Why are you here?
I have the right to be here.
I heard you don't work in this office.
It isn't your case either.
It's considered malfeasance
if you don't stop.
Consider it however you like.
Resume the investigation on the
survivors' testimonies tomorrow.
What about Seo Joon Oh?
I must meet him first.
Get the testimonies first.
I need to see Joon Oh before
we resume the investigation.
When is he coming?
Get the testimonies first.
- Follow the proper order.
- Proper?
We work in the same industry. Don't
tell me about what's proper.
We suspended the proceeding...
only because Seo Joon Oh was absent.
We'll do it properly when we meet him.
Tell him...
to come see us.
If we resume the proceeding
of Seo Joon Oh's charges,
you'll be charged for helping the culprit.
Aren't you aware of that?
You aren't in the position
to be so confident.
Try me.
You're in trouble for having much evidence.
I have nothing to fear anymore.
You promised to investigate properly.
Lock up Jang Do Pal and Choi Tae Ho first.
Everyone is watching you,
so you'd better be careful.
- Prosecutor Cho?
- Yes, sir.
It's evidence for attempted
murder of Hwang Jae Gook.
The culprit works for Jang Do Pal.
This is also related to Choi Tae Ho.
Keep it in mind.
Let's go, sir.
(Hwang Jae Gook Attempted Murder Case)
There must be a special bond between us.
I'm in charge of investigating...
your two murder cases.
What's the conclusion you
reached with your attorney?
Mr. Jang said he knows nothing about it.
He has nothing to say
because he's the culprit.
How about you?
Sir, I know I'm asking a big favor.
May I see Mr. Jang?
Why should I let you?
Do you need to have a chat
with your accomplice?
I'd like to reduce your work.
Please let me see him once.
Yoon Tae Young finally caused a disaster.
How dare he? He's a prosecutor like us.
He can't do this to a fellow prosecutor.
Listen carefully.
Nothing has changed for us.
We investigated fairly.
We concluded Seo Joon Oh as the culprit.
- Defend our position.
- Yes, sir.
Yoon Tae Young, that jerk.
Prosecutor Yoon, we're in
front of Bong Hee's house.
There are some police officers.
I know it's inconvenient, but
keep in hiding for a few days.
Prosecutor Lee Jae Joon
is desperate to find you.
Don't let him find you before...
Choi Tae Ho is locked up.
Are Jang Do Pal and Tae Ho arrested?
Yes.
You can sleep in peace tonight.
I can't sleep in peace
tonight if I have to hide.
Thank you, Prosecutor Yoon.
Come on, we expected this to happen.
I'll move the car to somewhere discreet.
You don't have to do this.
Go home and get some rest.
Here you go again.
You told me to stay by your side.
How can I go home alone?
It's unnecessary for both
of us to go through this.
It's better that I suffer alone.
If you were me, would you
have gone home alone?
Of course not. I care
about others too much.
See? I wouldn't feel
good if I rested alone.
I won't feel comfortable.
There isn't much we can change.
Let's go through this a
little longer, okay?
Besides, you'll be very bored without me.
Of course, but I don't want
others to suffer because of me.
- Stop it.
- "Jerk"?
- Stop it, stop it.
- "Jerk, jerk"?
I said stop it. Don't say things like that.
At times like this, we should stay strong.
We can do it. Okay?
- Okay?
- We can do it.
There we go.
Hello, Reporter Park.
Please don't do that. The
election is in a few days.
Don't publish the article yet.
You're doing it again!
You're smart enough, but you keep doing it.
Wait, I have another call.
Hello?
It's not Ms. Cho.
It's not true. Who told you that?
It isn't true. I'm hanging up.
Hello?
Let's meet and talk over a meal.
See you later.
Put your phone on vibrate.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
What time is it?
Where's Ji Ah? Let's check on her, Ki Joon.
Where do you think you're going?
You're identified as a criminal.
He's identified as a criminal?
Goodness, didn't you know?
- No.
- Jae Hyun's case is solved.
What about So Hee's case?
I believe it's still in progress.
It's okay.
Did Mr. Jang visit you in China?
He didn't visit us.
He attacked us.
He bribed the hospital staff.
At first, he tried to kill us.
At that time,
Ki Joon and I were being treated
at the hospital in China.
Tae Ho came...
with men who looked like gangsters.
They chased and attacked us.
This is what I found out later.
He threatened Ki Joon that he'll
let us live if he says...
Joon Oh murdered So Hee.
- Hello, Ji Ah.
- Come in.
How was it? Are you okay?
He only asked me to testify.
- Don't be nervous and good luck.
- Really?
- Okay, I'll be back.
- Good luck.
I'll be back. Don't worry.
Don't be nervous.
- See you.
- Bye.
I'm relieved to hear that.
- Prosecutor Yoon convinced him.
- I suppose so.
Something seemed strange though.
What do you mean?
He asked me strange questions at the end.
I did it for President Hwang.
I wanted to save him.
If I didn't listen to him,
he said he'd kill President Hwang.
You saw it too.
Joon Oh killed her.
I had no choice but to obey him.
I tried to tell the truth a few times.
When I saw him kill So Hee,
I tried to tell the truth.
Unfortunately, I was kidnapped by Tae Ho.
Sir, I know it's hard to believe me,
but I did it out of fear.
Tae Ho is really frightening.
It's worse when he's angry.
His eyes get very big when he's angry.
In the ship,
he stared at me and smiled...
while covered in blood.
He was so scary.
He's practically a psychopath.
When he's angry, you never
know what he'll do.
So please...
put him in jail this time. I'm begging you.
By the way, Mr. Tae.
Isn't it that psychopath...
who made you the vice president?
What?
It's true.
According to your testimony,
it's clear that you're a victim.
But it's doesn't seem that way on paper.
I could understand it if you're
doing this to get a raise.
What?
I thought it was done,
and that's when his eyes changed.
Ms. Ha. Your image matches your
true personality very well.
You're very straightforward.
I don't think you'd let
someone threaten you.
Well... Nobody should let
someone threaten them.
That's not what I meant.
I'm a huge fan of yours.
I just felt bad for you.
Goodness. By the way, it says here...
that your mother received a lot of
money from your company in advance.
How much money did she get?
Why are you asking me that?
I just wanted to check.
You don't need to answer.
For a mother whose daughter
was being threatened,
she received a rather large sum.
What are you talking about?
Is it true that you suffered
from a memory loss?
The doctor's note said that
your memory had returned.
Did you pretend not to remember
to protect Seo Joon Oh?
Prosecutor Lee.
I heard you two were a couple.
Is that correct?
When did it start? From the deserted
island or since he was on the run?
Is it something like Stockholm syndrome?
What are you talking about?
Where is Joon Oh?
Where is he right now?
Maybe that prosecutor has...
figured out everyone's disposition,
and he's catching us off guard now.
Gosh.
Why is it so hard to reach you?
How is it going?
Which one are you asking about?
The testimonies,
or Choi Tae Ho and Jang Do Pal?
Both.
Jang Do Pal is with Choi Tae Ho right now.
What?
What brought them into the same room?
Choi Tae Ho asked me if he could see him.
He did?
President Jang.
You said you will help me.
Do you still mean that?
What are you talking about?
How can you be saying that
while I'm in handcuffs?
When you picked me for Dreamers,
you told me that...
if you could take one artist
from the entertainment,
you'd choose me.
Isn't that why you helped
me when Jae Hyun died?
You're right.
We did have those days.
Please help me out one more time.
The attorney says...
I can be released...
if you take all the blame.
Let's toughen up and do this in one go.
Please... Please don't kill me.
Let's do this in one go.
At once.
Mr. Choi.
You're not a man of many words.
Excuse me?
You're right.
It looks like you've
been threatened as well.
You're right about that too.
If that's how this sounds to me,
it will sound like that in
other people's ears as well.
I'll get out of here first and back you up.
One of us has to get out of
here if we both want to live.
I'll go out first and get you released.
You know that I'm the only
one who can help you.
This is what we've been always doing.
Am I right?
He's trying to pressure your friends...
to capture you, Joon Oh.
You shouldn't let it get to you.
If you do, you'll be doing
exactly what they want.
We totally let it get to us.
Did you hear that?
Bong Hee isn't saying anything
after giving her testimony.
Maybe something happened in there.
Nothing happened.
I just gave my testimony.
Your face doesn't say so.
Ji Ah and Ho Hang said they
don't feel good about it.
It doesn't seem like
something serious happened.
You need to endure it.
Both you and Bong Hee.
What about Tae Ho? Is he behind the bars?
By tonight, he will be.
They can't keep him there much longer.
I'll call you after checking if
there have been any changes with...
Jang Do Pal and Choi Tae Ho.
Bong Hee. I picked out
this shirt on my own,
and it's not itchy. Touch it.
- Come on.
- It's dangerous.
Get back on your seat...
and look ahead.
(Seoul Supreme Prosecutors' Office)
Tae Ho just got released.
From this moment on,
we're changing the plan.
Fine.
I need you to do something for me then.
What is it?
The attorney says...
if they find out that I tried
to kill President Hwang,
I'd get a 20-year sentence.
You can take care of that for me, right?
Prosecutor Yoon gave the proof
of President Hwang's case...
to Prosecutor Lee.
There isn't much time.
What are you doing?
Gosh. Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Make sure...
you get rid of him,
so there won't be any
problems in the future.
Can you do that?
I'll take care of it as
soon as I get out of here.
I'll try to reduce...
your sentence as much as I can.
I'm fine.
I'm just worried about you.
This feels cramped and uncomfortable.
It's uncomfortable for me too.
I'm not doing this for you.
It's just too cold.
If you don't share this blanket with me,
your contract as my stylist will
be cancelled. Do you hear me?
We don't need a contract.
I'm walking on eggshells...
because you're acting this way.
Walking on eggshells
makes me feel pathetic.
Do you want your artist to be pathetic?
Is that what you want? Should
I be pathetic and small?
I didn't do anything to
make you feel pathetic.
If you don't want that, lighten up.
Hey. I consider talking to
you as talking to myself.
Since you don't answer me,
I feel like I'm alone
even when I'm with you.
Gosh.
What are you saying? Talking to
me is like talking to yourself?
I know you're frustrated too.
I know it's hard for you.
If it was an ordinary woman,
I'm sure she couldn't have
endured a single day.
You've endured it because it's you,
and you made it possible
for me to endure it too.
Thank you.
I'm nothing special,
yet you've always trusted
me, stayed by my side,
and protected me.
Stop it. You don't need to thank me.
I'm fine. I really am.
Don't worry about me.
All right. If that's the case,
do you want this? You can have it.
- It's a different color. Try it on.
- What?
Oh, the prosecutor is calling.
Hello, Prosecutor Yoon.
Why didn't you come?
My voice? Why? Is something going on?
We've got a problem.
Choi Tae Ho...
got released.
Lay low until things quiet down.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Should I be congratulating you?
You're finally free.
- I owe it all to you.
- What will you do now?
Will you get yourself into trouble again?
No.
I want to live a quiet life.
Can I trust you?
This time,
you got out somehow,
but I can bog you down with
it anytime if I want to.
You must know that better
than anyone else does.
Reflect on the things you
did and repent. Got it?
Jang Do Pal...
apparently said that he acted alone.
He said that Choi Tae Ho...
had no choice but to comply
because he threatened him.
What... What does that...
even mean?
Tae Ho is obviously not innocent.
How can they just release him?
From Jang Do Pal to the prosecution,
has everyone gone insane or what?
Lee Jae Joon helped him. I think
it's the prosecution's way...
of declaring that they won't
change their decision.
I'll send you the information.
I look forward to reading a great article.
(Is Ra Bong Hee Guilty of Aiding
and Abetting the Murders?)
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Bong Hee.
Where are you now? Are you...
with him right now by any chance?
Yes.
What's wrong, Mom? Did something happen?
Bong Hee.
Just come home now.
Let's talk in person
when you get here, okay?
(Is Ra Bong Hee Guilty of Aiding
and Abetting the Murders?)
What is this now? Get in touch with
the reporter who wrote this...
and ask him to remove anything
related to the commission.
Why do these jerks keep trying
to drag us into the mess?
Well... But...
Don't you think it's too harsh
to frame Ra Bong Hee...
as an accessory to the murders?
I get that it's important we
catch Seo Joon Oh, but still...
We have no choice.
All right. Let's head out now, everyone.
- Let's power up. We can do it!
- We can do it!
We got this!
Let's do it. Goodness.
At the special press conference
that was held a few days ago,
Choi Tae Ho was named the prime suspect...
for the Yoon So Hee murder case...
as well as for the murder of an
unknown singer four years ago.
However, Choi Tae Ho has
been acquitted and released,
and the seeming lack of evidence...
- Can you turn the volume up?
- Louder?
The police are facing
strong public criticism.
Gaining sympathy and pity from the public,
Choi Tae Ho's popularity has
surpassed even that of his prime.
(Restricted Caller ID)
- Joon Oh. It's me, Ki Joon.
- Hey.
Joon Oh, have you seen the newspaper yet?
Oh, right. You never read the newspaper.
What's up? Why did you call me so early?
Are you with Bong Hee now by any chance?
She's in big trouble. Look
up her name on the internet.
All right. I'll call you back.
I'm going home for a bit
because my mom is sick.
Don't worry too much and
call me if anything happens.
(Notice of Disciplinary Action)
This notice of termination made
its way to me safe and sound.
Shouldn't you be packing up now?
I will leave,
but there's something I want to know.
The Yoon So Hee murder case.
Have the two of you...
already planned everything
out with preset results?
- What?
- How dare you...
Prosecutor Yoon. I mean, Tae Young.
It looks like you're approaching it
with an outcome already in mind.
- Me?
- I think you want...
Choi Tae Ho to be the culprit
no matter what. Aren't I right?
You've been planning everything out
with Seo Joon Oh as the culprit.
What are you talking about?
That's also why you released Choi Tae Ho.
Yoon Tae Young, just leave quietly.
Why are you trying to cause a ruckus?
You think we have it planned out?
Do you falsely accuse people
whenever things don't go your way?
Fine. I was mentally ready
to leave the prosecution,
so I have no problem with actually leaving.
But just because I leave...
doesn't mean you'll get a
free hand with this case.
I'll be sure to put what I learned here...
to good use even after
leaving the prosecution.
I'll keep you on your toes.
That little...
Gosh, I'm speechless.
(Seo Joon Oh in Hiding)
(Why Is the First Survivor
Hiding Seo Joon Oh?)
That minx sure looks like she'd
be good at bewitching guys.
How can she walk around after
framing Tae Ho as a murderer?
I wouldn't even be able to step
out of my house if I were her.
She wouldn't have done it in the
first place if she had any shame.
Has she completely lost her mind or what?
How can she dare to falsely accuse Tae Ho?
Shouldn't we report her to the police?
Is there any cash reward?
- Cash reward?
- Call the police now.
How dare she? That little...
Isn't she the woman who was on the news?
That case...
- That murder case?
- Yes, that's it.
Seo Joon Oh.
- Right, Seo Joon Oh.
- Does she have no shame?
Gosh, seriously?
President Hwang, isn't
the air so fresh here?
Gosh, how nice.
President Hwang, shall
we go back to the ward?
President Hwang. We're
being watched, right?
Joon Oh.
Joon Oh?
We're being watched because of him?
Gosh, what about Joon Oh?
Let's go to the restroom.
Let's hide there.
Let's go.
I think someone is tailing us.
Should we stop contacting Joon Oh?
Yes, for the time being.
Hello.
Bong Hee went home.
It's safer than being with me.
Yes.
It's better that...
you stay separately.
Ki Joon.
I'll call you later.
Isn't that Seo Joon Oh?
I doubt he'd be out in broad daylight.
I heard that girl was Seo
Joon Oh's accomplice.
Who?
Why would I ask if I knew who?
(Why didn't you just die on the island?)
(A murder accomplice)
(Get lost. Why didn't you
just die on the island?)
- Stop it!
- You wench!
What did you say?
My goodness.
What? I didn't say anything wrong.
Your daughter fell in love with a murderer.
She's so naive.
It's true that she lost her mind, isn't it?
What did you say?
How dare you say that?
Instead of pouring soy sauce on you,
I should have sealed your lips.
- Goodness.
- It's not me.
I didn't say anything.
- I won't let you offend me again.
- I didn't say anything.
No, it wasn't me.
Gosh.
Why did you appear out of nowhere?
Get out now!
You idiots!
How dare you splash water on my daughter?
Hey!
Mom.
Has it been difficult because of me?
Are you upset?
Gosh.
You must be very angry.
Don't be angry, please?
Goodness.
You have no idea, do you?
Do you know how terrible it is...
when people have the
wrong impression of you?
How did things turn out like this?
No, Mom.
It's like a storm in passing.
Everything will pass.
Once it does, the truth will be revealed...
that Joon Oh and I...
are innocent.
You're so stubborn. Whom do you take after?
I'm strong...
and soft-hearted just like you.
I'm just like you.
Mom.
I'm hungry.
I haven't eaten anything all day.
How about some rice you make...
with vegetables and gochujang?
Can you eat at a time like this?
Yes.
Things turned out this way,
so let's keep strong until the end.
Tell that man.
If he doesn't handle this situation,
I'll scold him.
Joon Oh is very grateful to you.
Forget it.
Where are you going?
How many spoons of gochujang?
Three spoons, please.
I went to visit Jang Do Pal yesterday.
I couldn't see him.
They told me...
he hasn't met anyone yet.
Is he afraid that he'll change his mind?
That's possible.
He has a lot to think about now that...
Tae Ho is released.
For now, it'll be difficult
to visit Jang Do Pal...
unless Tae Ho makes a move.
I have a lot of time now.
I'll investigate both Jang
Do Pal and Choi Tae Ho.
Do you think there is a way?
Anything is possible.
What's difficult is...
persevering until then.
Let's show them that nothing is impossible.
I couldn't reach you all day.
You startled me.
Why did you pick up so quickly?
I've been calling you. Don't
you check your phone?
Really?
Is everything okay at home?
You read...
the article.
I'm okay, Joon Oh.
No, you aren't.
Tell your mother.
Once I wrap things up,
I'll apologize to her in person.
There's no need to worry.
Don't worry about that.
Keep hiding and be safe.
I'm safe, so don't worry.
I'm worried about you.
I'm fine.
Don't worry about me.
I'll come back tomorrow.
That's too soon.
Stay there longer. It's
difficult for you here.
You'll be bored without me.
Right, Joon Oh?
That's true.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Bong Hee.
Yes?
Come back soon.
I will.
Bong Hee.
Mom.
What about breakfast?
It's okay.
I'm not hungry.
You should eat at times like this.
It'll help you.
Bong Hee.
Are you...
sure that...
you can trust him until the end?
Mom.
To trust someone...
and support him always,
you must be strong yourself.
Can you do it?
Mom.
You're crying again.
Thank you.
Come here.
Are you talking about me?
Do you have your phone?
Yes, I do.
Give it to me.
Hello, Byeong Joo.
It's me, Joon Oh.
Who?
I was never acquainted
with someone like you.
Why did you call?
We used to call each other often.
Things have changed so much.
Stop spewing nonsense.
Hey,
I don't even want to hear your voice.
I'm going to hang up.
Joon Oh.
I don't want to take
things this far either.
I'm human too.
My heart will break if I have to
watch you become more pitiful.
So please give up already.
Give up if you want to make things
easier for those around you.
I called to tell you that.
Tae Young, Tae Young!
We've got a problem.
We got Ra Bong Hee's current location.
She's on her way back to Seoul now.
Okay. Bring her here as
soon as she gets back.
An arrest warrant has
been issued for Bong Hee.
It looks like Lee Jae
Joon dropped the bomb.
What should we do?
(Resume)
(Prosecutor Yoon Tae Young)
The number you have dialed is not...
She's not picking up. I think
she's on her way back.
She has no idea what's happening though.
Shouldn't we try to find her?
What will you do? They're
doing this to track you down.
I'm aware. How can I not do anything?
Please don't do this. Let's think
about what the best way is...
What's there to think about?
Bong Hee didn't do anything wrong,
yet she's about to be arrested.
How could I...
I must try to stop it.
(Prosecutor Yoon Tae Young)
Is Bong Hee still not picking up?
Tae Young, I'll try to find Joon Oh first.
Excuse me, miss. Just a second.
Well...
Here.
Right. Thank you.
Gosh, my neck. It's so tense.
Ms. Ra Bong Hee.
Why are you doing this to me?
Where are you taking me? Let go.
Please let go of me.
Please tell me what's going on first.
- Please come with us.
- What's going on?
- Let go. Why are you doing this?
- Please come with us.
Please let go of me.
Let's retreat for now.
If people notice you,
you'll get caught too.
- Let go of me, please.
- Please move out of our way.
Come to your senses.
If you get involved now, both
of you will be arrested.
There won't be anything I can do.
Hang back if you want to save her.
You have to, no matter what.
Let's get out of here
before things get messier.
I'll ask...
Byeong Joo to bring your car.
You have to be extremely careful
with everything at the moment.
If they catch onto your tail,
you'll get into big trouble.
What's going to happen now?
They took Bong Hee.
What will happen to her?
When she meets Lee Jae Joon,
he'll ask her if she knows where you are.
He will say that he'll let her go...
if she tells him where you are.
He'll keep asking her your
whereabouts persistently...
until she tells him.
He knows that making her suffer...
is a sure way to catch you.
He'll do his best to drag it on...
so that you're left with no choice...
but to go to him on your own.
Where is Seo Joon Oh now?
I don't know.
If you keep this up, it'll only
make things more difficult for you.
Just tell us, Ms. Ra.
You can get out of here if
you tell us where he is.
Are you really going to be like this?
All right.
Let's see who wins. Bring it on.
About what you just said... Are you sure?
Yes.
I really don't think this is right.
I can't let them do this.
You can go now.
What happened?
How did I...
get released, Prosecutor Yoon?
(Prosecutor Lee Jae Joon)
Joon Oh chose to do it.
No, Prosecutor Yoon. No.
You may think I've lost my mind,
but there is no choice.
There is only one way.
I'll turn myself in.
Goodness, Mr. Seo Joon Oh.
It was very hard to meet you.
Since you have turned yourself in,
why don't we turn this into a great show?
You should've stopped him.
You're the one who said he shouldn't
go to the prosecutors' office.
How could you let him go like that?
Turning himself in without any
plans means the end for him.
What should we do, Prosecutor Yoon?
Mr. Seo Joon Oh.
Look.
You've been silent for hours
since you stated your name.
For hours.
Why aren't you answering my questions?
Didn't you come here to turn yourself in?
My goodness.
Is he still not talking?
No, sir.
It's been six hours.
What is he trying to do?
What is he doing with his food?
My gosh.
He is a lunatic.
Don't tell them anything for now.
Whatever they do, do not
show any reactions.
If you do that, they
will talk to you first.
You eat your food in a funny way.
Are you full?
Let's do this quickly.
Why did you kill Yoon So Hee?
I heard she called you a murderer.
Is that correct?
Are you going to remain silent?
How long are you going to do this?
Listen.
You came to us yourself, didn't you?
Why aren't you talking?
Things aren't going to get better no
matter how long you hold out for.
Do you think this will stop me
from putting you behind bars?
What is it that you want?
What are you doing this for?
That's when you say this.
It's an offer that Prosecutor Lee
will find the most tempting.
I'll talk.
I'll talk,
but do me a little favor.
A favor?
Jang Do Pal.
Please let me see him.
Why do you want to see him?
If I let you see him,
what good will it do me?
You want only one thing, right?
Who knows?
If you let me see him,
maybe I will do something...
for you in return.
To Prosecutor Lee, nothing would be...
more important than your
confession right now.
He will let you see Jang Do Pal...
at least once.
It's you who ordered someone to kill...
Hwang Jae Gook, right?
Where did you hide the hitman?
There was a man with the injection.
Answer me right now!
Jang Do Pal will feel so much pressure.
The police are...
doing everything to find his henchman.
Where are you taking me?
If he gets caught,
Jang Do Pal will soon be found
guilty of attempted murder.
That means, he will probably die in jail.
He knows that,
but he's still not doing anything
except remaining silent.
What do you think that means?
It means there must be
something he's counting on.
Tae Ho must've been released
after an agreement.
He must be it.
Tae Ho must've promised to
take care of the hitman.
Are you saying...
I should come between...
those two?
Whether you can win over Jang
Do Pal to your side or not...
is up to you now, Joon Oh.
Nothing is certain,
so...
it won't be easy.
What are you wearing on your head?
You look good.
Why did you want to see me?
Do you think it's okay to leave them...
alone like that?
Just turn up the volume.
How is your stay here?
I have nothing to worry about now,
so I do feel better.
You're just broad-minded.
You're in jail instead of Tae Ho.
Listen.
If you're trying to provoke me...
to gain something out of it...
Does Tae Ho...
come to see you often?
Do you know what he's up to these days?
Do I have to know that?
Of course, you do.
If you took all the blame...
in exchange for a favor, you
should at least know...
if he's doing a good job.
Do you think Tae Ho will really
do what you asked him to do?
You do nasty things for him,
but he won't do anything for you.
It looks like he has forgotten
about what you asked him.
I don't know what you're saying.
I never asked him to do
anything for me, and...
President Hwang...
can speak now.
So? What are you trying to say?
I don't know why I'm listening to this.
What is he doing?
Do you trust Tae Ho that much?
Get off of me!
- Get in there. Hurry!
- Yes, sir.
What is Joon Oh doing?
Open the door.
Open it now!