Yeah.
Oh.
Oh, Jesus, no.
This isn't a good time.
Rick?
- Mr. Carver?
- Yeah, I'll be with you in a second.
Huh? Well, I'll tell you what you do.
Remove the meter, turn the water off,
and let them sweat for a couple of days.
Then you ride in
on your white fucking horse,
tell them you have a cash buyer
and Richard Carver
can approve a short sale.
You want me to spell it for you?
R-I-C...
OK, well, I can't hold your hand
while you give them a hand job, Bill.
Just get me the property.
Yes, John, Officer Dudura, you have
my court order signed by the judge.
What can I do for you?
You're the bank's realtor
on this eviction.
I need an official statement.
What happened and why?
Well, Dudura, it's a real shame
cos we arrived here with two pizzas
for Mr. Kadwell, the property owner,
but he didn't want anchovies,
so he went into the house,
pulled out a gun
and he blew his brains out.
And that set off Mrs. Kadwell
who was expecting Chinese for dinner.
You're talking about a man
who just killed himself.
I am the last man who knocked
on Patrick Kadwell's door,
in his life.
That is his wife of 15 years, Samantha,
his daughters,
Dylan, 6, Paige, 11.
What official statement
can encapsulate
the tragic absurdity
of this fucked-up situation?
I can't bring him back to life.
Stop wasting my time.
Yeah?
No, I'm fine, honey.
Turn the TV off,
keep the girls away from the internet.
Er...
I got a call. Yeah.
Hello?
No, no, no.
You ride that up to 200.
220 tops.
No more than 10% down.
7.5% makes me sing.
Get the Miguels ready.
It's 2 grand a month
in interest alone.
We got to flip this thing.
Get back to me.
Call office.
Have we got anything else, boss?
Next eviction's Tuesday.
Natalia will call you.
Roger that.
- 'Rick Carver Realty.'
- Talk to me. My world's upside down.
'I'm emailing your revised itinerary.
And Jerry called again...'
Jerry's full of shit.
Keep talking.
'The Sutton Place high-rise came up.
The UD's in order.
'What do you want me to tell Elliot?'
No, no!
Please!
Yo, Nash, you can stop working now.
We're done. We're done.
- What?
- Hey!
Listen up!
The buyer didn't qualify.
We're shut down.
- What about payment?
- We don't get paid.
For 2 weeks
we've been working for free.
All this from roof to cement
is for nothing.
Stop working!
Put the hammer down, man.
Unplug everything, wrap it up.
Let's go home.
No dinero.
That looks like the United States
upside down, but flipped this way.
- It actually does.
- Connor?
Connor!
- We were just looking at the countries.
- Connor!
- We're naming the countries.
- It's our time. We're up.
- Gotta go.
- See you.
Bye.
Who was that?
- Who was that?
- That's my friend Alex from school.
- You dropped this.
- Good catch.
Your Honour, he missed 3 payments
and is underwater over 80 grand.
The bank can have a buyer in place
within 30 days.
- Did you in fact miss 3 payments?
- Yes, sir, but I was told to.
2 departments at the same bank
were telling me opposing things
and then, just recently,
I got a final notice for eviction.
We'd like to get
this property off the market.
- I see no reason to hold up the sale.
- They told me not to pay.
And that's why I'm behind.
They told me not to pay.
While I sympathise with your situation
I have 40,000 cases like this
backed up behind yours.
Final judgment granted.
I'm ordering you to vacate the premises.
That's my family home, Your Honour.
I was born and raised in that home.
He was born and raised there too.
He's my son, Connor.
Please don't do this.
We've lived there our whole lives.
My mum runs her business
out of that home.
That's our second source
of income right now.
- Is this your son?
- That's my son.
He should be in school and not here.
He's gonna lose his school,
with all due respect.
Sun United Bank versus R. Rogers.
- Give me a bit more time, please.
- Please remove Mr. Nash.
Your Honour, I just need a bit more time.
I need a bit more time.
Excuse me for a second.
I need you to follow me now.
You have 30 days
to file an appeal.
- Bailiff, please remove Mr. Nash.
- I need you to follow me now, sir.
Right now.
Where are we going to stay
if we lose our home?
- We're not gonna lose the home, bud.
- How do you know?
The cops are coming back.
I just wanna know
how you're gonna pay for it.
Connor.
Connor, I'm gonna figure it out, OK?
That judge gave us 30 days.
Ain't no one taking the home from us.
I'm gonna win this.
I'm gonna figure it out, simple as that.
We're good.
1 hour.
Hey, Bo.
I got that new blade for your skill saw.
I'll bring it over tonight.
- OK.
- You be careful, Connor.
- Got a new scooter?
- Yeah.
Hey, Mum.
So, tell me everything.
- Did they give you a lawyer?
- Mum, it's the same story.
Same story with the bank guys.
It's the same story everywhere we go.
We have to find a lawyer.
I'm just trying to understand
what this 30-day thing means.
Does that mean the eviction's
not gonna happen tomorrow?
- The judge told you. It's 30 days.
- 30 days to file for an appeal.
It's a judge, it's not a bartender.
We're in good shape.
My name is Dennis Nash
and I'm looking for representation.
I understand that you guys
sometimes do not need a retainer.
When you went through
what you went through,
you found someone pro bono.
I'm wondering if he's gonna help...
Lost is to found
as outside is to indoors, inside...
And what's another example?
Here you go.
- Have some salad.
- Black and white.
Black and white.
What's another one?
Give me one more.
4540189.
Please give us a call back.
I don't know
what to say to him sometimes.
I was so young when I had you.
I feel like you've had to raise me.
You know just what to say.
Borrow against Blair Street
to cover Via Alizar.
'Good.'
- I'll flip that this quarter.
- 'And London at Code Enforcement?'
I got a short sale for that cocksucker.
I'll email you the details.
- 'OK.'
- All right.
Afternoon, boss.
Love the new ride.
- Range Rover HSE.
- Is this the Nash eviction?
Yeah. Anyone home?
I'm not sure, but his vehicle is home,
so I'm assuming he is.
All right, let's get to it.
- Morning, y'all.
- How's it going?
He's at the window.
Sheriff's department.
Come to the door.
- What?
- Sheriffs are here.
Why are they here?
- You need to come to the door.
- He saw you.
They saw you through the window.
Just answer it. We just got to explain it.
Oh, come on.
Don't fucking do this.
- Good afternoon.
- Afternoon.
I'm Deputy Anderson
with the Sheriff's department.
We're here to serve you
a court-ordered eviction.
- OK, well...
- So, ma'am,
do you have any weapons on your body
or anywhere in the house?
- No, no, no, no. Not us.
- Mr. Carver?
Good morning.
My name's Rick Carver.
- I'm a licensed real estate broker.
- Mr. Carver.
Hi. Lynn.
And, er, I'm very sorry to tell you
that this home has been foreclosed on
and officially transferred to the bank.
- I need you to vacate the premises.
- I understand what you're saying.
And I've... I've... I've...
We've been getting
our eviction notices.
I was in court yesterday
and the judge informed me
that I got 30 days
to file for an appeal
and that's what I intend to do.
If you have an emergency stay signed
by the judge, you're welcome to remain.
I got a question. You guys didn't get
any rescheduling of the eviction date?
What I've received is a court order
signed by a judge.
It says you are to vacate
these premises today.
- We were scared of this.
- This home is owned by the bank.
- This is the information that we have.
- And we're sorry to waste your time.
My office offered you a $3500
cash-or-keys settlement from the bank
which would have given you time
to vacate the premises and you refused.
- Yes, sir.
- We didn't refuse.
- We tried to save our home.
- We were trying to save it.
This is a very painful time, I know.
It's a difficult thing to carry through on,
for me as well.
But the time has come.
You have to leave your property.
You are trespassing right now.
You are breaking the law.
Sir, this is our home
so we just need a few minutes.
We're going in circles here
so I'll let the sheriffs take care of it.
- Randy?
- All right, sir.
We've got a judge, sir,
and a lawyer who told us we can stay.
- Is this your mum?
- Yeah, this is my mum.
I'm gonna need you and your mum
to step off the property now.
You know what? If you all can
come back tomorrow same time
and if we don't have the papers,
we don't have the proof,
- then we will leave.
- We have a lawyer.
- We got it all figured out.
- Just give us a day.
We can dance together,
but we can't talk together.
- OK. All right, sir, we need a day.
- Do not close the door.
- We need a day.
- Listen, this is what I'm gonna do.
- Do not close the door.
- We need a day.
- This is my home. I can do what I want.
- I will give you two minutes
to pack whatever belongings you need
- Cash, chequebook, medicines.
- No, this is not happening.
- Yeah, this is happening.
I'm getting my cell phone
so I can get the lawyer on the phone.
- Ma'am? Ma'am?
- Excuse me, sir.
- I'm just walking by, sir.
- I don't know what this is.
We can't let someone out of our sight
once we start an eviction.
- Please don't come into my house.
- Listen to me.
There are two ways
that we can do this.
Right? An easy way which is
you do what you're told when asked.
The other way is
that I take you and your mum to jail.
Do you want
your mum to go to jail?
What I'd like you to do
is take advantage of the 2 minutes,
gather what you need,
cash, cheque books, medicines,
things that you need...
Excuse me, sir, would you mind
stepping outside of the property?
Listen to me, sir.
Let me put it to you this way.
- Excuse me.
- This isn't your home, son.
Mr. Carver?
Excuse me.
- Mr. Carver?
- According to Florida statute 801.08
- I have the authority...
- Sir, we have the right to an attorney.
Right? Then why
are you coming into our house?
Somebody forgot to call you,
we don't get a lawyer?
It's better not to get emotional, ma'am.
- You're kicking us out of our house.
- Please, OK? Please!
Ma'am,
please don't ask questions.
- Please!
- Enough of this. Let's go.
Get what you need to get,
then you need to go.
- Let's go. No more of this.
- Sir, I don't need your help.
OK? I can take a minute.
Do you need to follow a woman
into her bedroom?
I got a full house here.
I'm gonna have to be late
to the next one. I know.
It's just department policy.
Money, chequebook.
- Things like wallets, pictures.
- I'm trying to get pictures!
- Does he have to stand there?
- Yes, sir.
He has to fucking stand there
while she packs up her underwear?
Is that right?
Dennis, please!
It's policy.
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
I got to keep you in my sight, ma'am.
Sorry about that.
Anyway, ma'am, just take
the most important things.
What else, Mum?
Can I ask if it says 2 minutes
on your clipboard?
The 2 minutes is a courtesy.
Let her take the plant.
- You don't need it.
- The 2 minutes is what?
- A courtesy.
- Oh, my God!
You're trespassing right now.
I know it's painful to hear it,
but it's the truth.
This is our home.
- Oh, my God.
- Anything else, ma'am?
Oh, my toaster.
My toaster oven
to make toast for my grandson.
Uh-huh. Ma'am.
Dennis! Did you get
your chequebook out of the desk?
- You said the 2 minutes was up.
- We're getting the bills.
- All right, let's go.
- Dennis?
His basketball, his basketball.
Will you just let her go in
and get the ball?
Right, Jeff, get to it.
Rhonda, get the locks.
Hey, what about the rest?
They're gonna
bring everything out.
There's no need to worry.
You mind helping me move all this
to the other side of the sidewalk?
We're moving it, OK?
Just give us a second.
Now, my advice would be
to get a moving truck
cos your neighbours
are gonna have access
to everything you own
by the end of the day.
I got it.
Can you believe this?
They cancelled it and then
they didn't even tell these guys.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe this is happening.
Hey!
- What are you doing?
- Moving stuff.
Don't go in there.
You got no business going in there.
- Shut the lid.
- All right, keep your pants on.
- I'll take him next door.
- OK.
- OK?
- Hey, buddy.
- What are they doing?
- Nothing.
- This is our house.
- It's OK.
- Son, where are you heading?
- Get off me!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Get away from him.
- This is our house.
It's a very difficult situation.
Please take your son off the property.
- What do you think I'm doing?
- Those are my toys.
It's OK. It's OK.
It's OK, sweetie.
- Let go of me.
- Come here. Come here.
Just tell them.
I just wanna go to my room. Please.
You can't go to your room right now.
You said we weren't gonna
lose our house. You lied to me.
Sweetie, he didn't lie.
He didn't know.
Do you think you're gonna
come to school tomorrow?
- I don't know.
- Connor.
Got to go.
Well, what about our NBA 2K series?
See you later.
Not a problem.
- Thank you for everything.
- Absolutely. Take care.
See you soon.
Mr. Nash?
You have 24 hours before my crew
returns to dispose of whatever remains.
Not my choice.
Code enforcement.
Good luck.
You OK?
Hey.
Hey, do y'all know
where 229 is?
229's up there.
Up here?
Is there a stair near there?
- Around the pool.
- OK. Thank you.
- You got a lot of stuff.
- Yeah.
- We can watch your stuff
- while you take some of it up there.
- OK. Thanks.
- You want a hand?
- That'd be great.
- Are you planning on staying a while?
- No, just a couple of nights.
2 years ago that's what we said.
But, er, welcome anyway.
Come this way.
Come on.
- Where am I gonna sleep?
- Where do you wanna sleep?
How about in this one
cos it's closer to the TV?
That's a good call.
How about this, buddy?
Take that off, put this one on.
Wait, this has to come off.
Am I going to school tomorrow?
We got to figure all that out,
don't we?
Yeah, cos, er...
I have to see Derek.
And I promised him, so...
Er, my name is Dennis Nash.
I'm calling about the roofing job.
Yeah, I work for Crown Construction.
About 5 years.
Um, you got anything else
on the books right now?
All right, well, my number...
Yeah, I got a ton of experience.
I do electric, construction,
plumbing, anything.
All right. Lower-level stuff?
Anything? Anything going?
Do you know of anybody
that's hiring right now?
All right. Thank you for your help.
Thank you for your time.
Dennis, this motel
is half full of people like us.
They're not people like us.
They're all evicted
and they get stuck here.
I could maybe take the bus
and start looking for apartments.
- We can't afford it.
- It's just first and last month's.
Plus 2 or 3 months' security.
4 maybe, cos of our credit.
Our credit's shot.
Dennis, we've...
We've got to get out of here.
We've got to go to Tampa.
- We gotta go to Uncle Jimmy's.
- We're not going to Tampa.
Uncle Jimmy said we could come.
I talked to Mary Margaret
just 3 days ago.
We're not going to Tampa.
You really wanna go to Tampa?
You wanna take Connor out of school,
take him away from his friends?
We leave, we give up.
We leave, we let the house go.
I'm gonna figure it out.
No choice.
- Baby, you want some toast?
- No.
You don't want any toast?
I didn't leave any tools
in my truck, right?
Huh? We got everything, right?
What's wrong?
Man, I mean, that's beautiful, but...
- I was catching 2lb bass...
- Excuse me.
- ...when I was 6 years old.
- Hold up.
Hey.
You stole some tools from me
during my eviction.
I'm the senior sales manager.
What's the problem?
- He stole 500 bucks' worth of my tools.
- You're just making up bullshit.
I didn't steal your fucking tools.
- We have a form you can fill out.
- Just give me my tools.
If you have an issue
we got a form you can fill out.
Just go back to your house
and look for your tools again.
Oh, wait. You don't have
a fucking house, right?
What the fuck?
- Goddamn it!
- Give me my fucking tools back.
- Fucker!
- Kick your arse.
Chill the fuck out!
Hey, buddy, chill the fuck out!
- Hey!
- Fucking call me a fucking thief!
- Give me my fucking tools back.
- Knock that shit off right now.
- Chill the fuck out!
- Get the fuck off of me.
Bill, you wanna throw a couple of licks
or are you just officiating
this event today?
Sir, I was just...
I was trying to intervene, sir.
What the fuck
are you still doing here anyway?
- I thought, sir... I thought you said...
- You thought? Lord Almighty.
You have evolved.
Has Darwin come to Orlando, Florida?
- Well, Bill?
- We'll be there on time, Mr. Carver.
- Get to it.
- Yes, all right.
All right, come on, vamanos.
Freddy, let's go.
Guys, we're going to Vista Lakes.
Here we go.
And you, sir, are you finished?
Cos I got the cops on speed dial.
They could chase you out of town.
I didn't come here to fight.
I came to get my tools
that your guy stole.
Do I look like Ace Hardware?
I don't deal in tools.
- I deal in homes.
- Your guy stole the tools.
- I understand what you do, sir.
- You do?
You evicted me yesterday.
You kicked me out.
I didn't kick you out, the bank did.
I just represent it.
Richard Carver.
What? You gotta be kidding me.
When?
Uh-huh.
Yeah. Fuck Hazmat.
I'll call them myself.
- 914 Shader Drive, now.
- What about Via Alizar?
- Move it!
- Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Mr. Carver, I'm sorry
to interrupt your day.
- Are you Miguel?
- What?
Do you work? You got tools?
You do construction?
- Yeah, I do work.
- 914 Shader Drive.
I'll pay you $50 cash.
- What? Are you kidding me?
- $50 shouldn't be a joke to you, son.
Are you gonna look into my...
Motherfucker!
Fucking shit!
Fucking cocksucker!
I need your team out here in 30 minutes
or it's gonna be a total gut job
to the goddamn studs.
Yeah, these animals backed up
the sewage and skipped town.
I'm glad you think that's funny.
I got the neighbours threatening
to call the department of health.
If your team isn't here in 30 minutes
my next call's gonna be to Fannie
about your slow-arse response time.
What do you mean,
shit's not a hazardous material?
Why don't you come and eat some?
Maybe that will change your mind.
Yeah, fuck you too.
Rick, no.
- Mr. Carver, we don't...
- You know what's gonna happen, right?
By tonight the mould's
gonna be up to the ceiling.
By tomorrow someone's paying money
to demolish it.
- And it ain't gonna be me.
- 300 bucks.
200.
That's a bear and you know it. 250.
All right.
Is this yours?
Oh, fuck.
Harden the fuck up, son.
There better be container trucks,
shop vacs and a blower here in one hour
or I will make it my business that
you never work in Orange County again.
You will also finish Via Alizar today.
You are on my list, shit-fuck.
Nash.
What else do you do?
Framing, electric, roofing, plumbing?
All that, more.
Go on, finish it.
Ahh!
All right, a 6-pack
for the first guy in here with a shovel.
Anybody?
How much you pay for it?
- $200?
- 150.
Plus the 6-pack.
- Cerveza por trabajo, si?
- Cerveza? Good.
All right, let's go.
Anybody else? How about you?
It's just shit.
I know you need the money.
There you go, there you go.
Come on, red shirt.
What about you, pretty?
All right, let's do it.
Let's get this shit done.
- Dennis? Are you kidding me?
- Is that real money?
- How much is this? 50.
- That's real money. Count it out.
- 100. Another 50 is 150.
- Keep going.
- $200?
- 250.
Hold on a second.
Who called you? What's that?
Some guys.
It was through, er...
Not that guy Dan?
- Is this a new job?
- It's a new guy. You don't know him.
Javier called me
and we figured it out.
This is serious money
and your son has just totally pocketed it.
- Where have you put it?
- That's the biggest money ever!
- It's right here, Dad.
- That's my money!
Don't you believe it!
You're gonna make
new friends right now.
You're gonna jump on here.
I don't want to.
I know.
But I need you to be brave.
But it's a different school.
I don't want to go to that school.
I know you don't, but you got
to keep your grades up, remember?
- You got to take care of yourself, OK?
- Yeah, I know. Bye.
Hey, hey!
I love you.
Be safe, OK?
Take care of yourself, all right?
- 'I see you.'
- Hey, Rick.
'Come round back
to the screen door where the pool is.'
Who's that guy?
All right, thanks. Bye.
Nash. If it's not one thing
it's another.
Come on.
Oh, girls, it's hot in here.
Calling all princesses.
It's time for the royal ice cream.
Yeah!
It's a pretty place.
Ah, it's OK.
I got it 18 months ago.
I'm gonna flip it after New Year's.
Let's have some Ben and Jerry's,
Cecilia, please.
What is this?
Did you make these?
What? Oh, it fell off.
The AC's been out for 2 hours.
Through there to the left
there's a leak. You'll see it.
- Do they fly?
- No.
- This is Richard Carver.
- 'Adjustable rate mortgage, cocksucker!
- 'I'm homeless, you motherfucker!'
- Stop calling me, you freak.
'I'm gonna call you every goddamn day
'to remind you
what a piece of shit you are.'
They called here 2 days ago.
I don't wanna change
our phone number again.
Come on, boo. I got you and your mum
a week at the Corazon Spa in the Keys.
I want you to enjoy yourself.
- What?
- I should divorce you.
We'd lose on taxes.
And you'd miss me.
You'd miss your little Richie,
wouldn't you?
- What are you doing?
- I'm all done.
Give the coils 5 minutes to dry,
but then you got cold air.
- It's not even been an hour.
- I salvaged your ceiling with mud.
I didn't want to tear up that dry wall.
I found some paint in your garage
so I just patched that up too.
Well, unless you're planning
on taking a swim, let's go.
What do you see out there?
I see homes.
I just saw nine opportunities
to make money in the last 5 blocks.
3 properties without mailboxes
and one with an overgrown lawn
and no car in the drive,
two with white signs in the windows
and three with shiny new doorknobs.
If you can get attuned
to seeing those kinds of opportunities,
you can get up off your hands and knees
and really start working for me.
I can work.
You've seen me all week.
Yeah, I know you worked for good crews
with Rick Kirby, Chris Camilleri, right?
But the unfortunate thing is,
they're out of business.
Cos they build homes.
I own homes.
You know what I am? I'm a man
who owns a hell of a lot of properties.
You can be a part of that,
but it's a hell of a responsibility.
What I need to know
is that I have someone
who can handle any situation
I want to walk away from, 24/7.
I don't care
if your kid's in the school play,
it's Christmas,
you lined up
the best damn blowjob in Orlando,
when you work for me, you're mine.
What the hell?
Call office.
You see that?
The cable and the hose?
- I see it.
- 'Rick Carver Realty.'
I got some jack wagon
at 3505 Ridgeway
stealing water and power
from 3509 Ridgeway.
Call up the county court website,
find out if he's in default.
- 'Yes, sir.'
- Quickly, please. I'm at his house now.
'You got it.'
You know how to shoot, right?
I'll run a background check
so you can carry a concealed weapon.
Go on.
Are you fucking with me?
Surly homeowners.
You're gonna need it.
I'm not... No, I'm good.
Suit yourself.
The person on the other side of the door
doesn't always feel that way, trust me.
See? They can feed their Rottweiler,
but they can't pay for their house.
Mm-hm.
Frank Greene. All right, let's go.
Mr. Frank Greene?
- Yeah.
- I'm Rick Carver.
- You're stealing from me.
- You mean the extension cord.
Yeah, that property next door belongs
to Fannie Mae. I represent it for them.
So you're not just stealing from me,
you're stealing from the US government.
I'm with Frank Greene now.
What have you got for me?
Remove the lines.
I saw you at the foreclosure court.
Our boys go to the same school.
They were playing with the globe.
- Oh, yeah.
- I had my show-cause hearing.
- What happened with you?
- I lost.
Got evicted,
living in a motel right now.
What are you doing with him?
I got to work, you know.
He offered me a job.
I usually do construction, but...
it's been dry for the last however long.
- You know, this ain't what I do.
- This isn't me either.
I was a manager,
Custom Cabinets and Lighting.
Lost my job 2 years ago. 2.
I'm not a thief.
I know.
I've been researching
on the internet, public libraries.
I'm gonna save my house.
I hope you do.
Custom Cabinets?
Yeah, I installed your stuff.
- Oh, yeah. A bunch of times.
- Hey, Dad.
- Yes?
- The TV turned off.
OK.
You know my boy?
Connor? Connor Nash?
Yes, sir.
Yeah, thanks.
Looks like the Bank of Greater Santa Fe
filed for final judgment of foreclosure.
My money says the judge has me back
for your eviction in less than 90 days.
I took down the extension cords
and the hose.
I shouldn't have done that.
I apologise.
- It's OK.
- No, I assure you, stealing is not OK.
Mr. Nash will be talking
to your neighbours personally.
If we receive any reports
or if we drive by and see you
stealing my water and power again,
the next visit's
from the Sheriff's Department.
Understand me?
- Yes, sir.
- Good day.
Nash, come on.
Don't be soft.
They all got a sob story.
But the law's the law.
That's the side you're on.
You should be smart enough
to know the outcome of this situation.
So toughen up.
I'm evicting a hedge-fund manager
out of here in two weeks.
Keep your mouth shut
and your eyes open
and maybe you'll learn something
this time.
I'll take the Moder sconces,
the chandelier,
the Haleakala marble,
Harwood cabinets,
range, Sub-Zero.
- What about the microwave?
- I don't need a microwave.
Three grand and you gotta
be out in 2 weeks.
- How about 5?
- 4.
And Dennis here will get right to it.
Done.
The screws are right on in there.
Pop 'em right out, OK?
Yup.
Install everything, patch the tiles,
caulk the cabinets.
Connect the gas line
when you bring in the appliances.
- All this in here now?
- I'm selling this home for Fannie Mae.
I can't do that
if it doesn't have a kitchen, can I?
No.
So, who just paid me $33,000
for new cabinets, appliances
and a counter top plus labour?
- Fannie Mae.
Congratulations.
You just fucked the government.
- Mr. Nash?
- Yeah.
If you're interested, let me know.
If not, you can use this
to take your kid to Disney World
and get yourself a job
Migueling Cinderella's castle.
I don't give a shit about the government.
They ain't never done
nothing for me, so...
That's a lot of money
you just gave me.
Feels a bit like trouble.
You done honest work
your whole life building homes.
What did that get you
but me knocking at your door?
Are we stealing? Is this stealing?
Well, in 2006 you borrowed $85,000
against your home
and never paid it back, Nash.
- You telling me that's not stealing?
- What? Are you serious?
That's not stealing,
that's me taking a loan.
That's me working my arse off
to pay back that loan.
I wanted to pay it back.
I didn't steal.
That's not how the banks see it
or the taxpayers paying for the bail-out.
You think I bought a Porsche? No.
I invested every cent I borrowed
into construction equipment
so that I could pay back that loan
and put a roof over my family's head,
put food in my kid's mouth.
The economy crashed.
I can't predict the weather.
I can.
I'm a Doppler fucking radar.
You took something you didn't give back.
The bank screwed you over.
Take your pick.
Either way you lost.
But I made more money
during the crash than before it.
You can too, you just gotta stop
lying to yourself and ask,
what did you do wrong
that your family lives in a motel?
I'm gonna do it.
Whatever you want me to do,
I'll do it, but...
I need you to do me a favour,
help me get my family home back.
I want you to take this
as my first payment.
Don't get emotional about real estate.
It's too late for that.
That's my family home.
That's my boy's school,
so please just take this.
This ain't gonna cut it.
Put that under your mattress.
Don't put it in the bank.
You're just giving them more money.
When you get enough
I'll tell you what to do with it.
Now, do you want to double
what you just made or not?
It's about fucking time, playboy.
Damn.
Always late, papa.
You always late, man.
Yeah.
That's the jackpot.
- So who's this Rick Carver dude?
- That's my boss.
For the time being.
- What's that like?
- Oh, it's great. He's...
Nah, he's a fucking arsehole.
1, 2, 3.
Straight on.
- What are you doing?
- Got to take a picture.
to prove to the bank this shit's missing
so they pay us to put it back in.
We're stealing it
to then bring it back?
- You wanna get paid?
- Hell, yeah.
I got to take a picture.
- Yeah?
- Mr. Tanner, my name is Dennis Nash.
I'm here representing
Rick Carver Realty.
Um, I'm here to, er...
I understand your house
has been foreclosed on.
The house still belongs to us
and we intend to keep it that way.
I hope that works out.
God forbid it doesn't.
If you got a second
I wanna tell you about cash for keys,
here on the form.
What do you mean,
cash for keys?
If you leave your house
in a broom-swept condition
prior to your eviction date,
banks can give you 3500 bucks
cash in your pocket.
We're not interested in anything.
Take your papers.
We'll contact our attorney
and they'll get with you.
What you doing, son?
Who'll buy a home with a pool
if the pool don't work?
- What do y'all think y'all doing?
- Doing some repairs.
I know this house has been empty
for 2 or 3 months.
You know Rick Carver Realty?
You see that sign on the lawn?
- Yes, I did.
- That's who we work for.
I hope you have a good day.
- Is she your type?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah!
It ain't a lot,
but it's gonna pay for U-Haul,
storage, a down payment
on an apartment.
I have no idea what's going on.
because my mum and dad
from Vietnam is coming
and the house can't be foreclosured.
Have you been putting notices
on my window?
- No, that's the Sheriff's Department.
- Well, that's trespassing.
I can't control what the department does,
but I can give you this form.
I don't want your papers.
Don't hand me no papers.
I don't want your papers or notices.
I want you to get the hell out of here.
I've been owning this house
for 7 years already.
I met my wife right here.
We're about to have a baby here.
I just made an addition in the back.
I wanna save the house.
I wanna keep it.
- Who are you?
- I work for a real estate company.
This is a KYO form. Basically,
it means knowing your options.
- My options?
- I'm putting it all on Facebook.
- Kayla, put it away.
- We don't know who this man is.
Kayla, go inside.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I'm gonna have to take care of my kid.
I advise you to call
that number at the bo...
- If you wanna just take a look.
- I'm not looking at anything.
You could just take it
and not look at it.
Hold on a second.
I think I've made myself clear to you.
I don't wanna see you again.
Both Victor and Andy.
Neither one of them showed up.
- Hey.
I can't even give Connor his vitamins.
I have one little kid Flintstone vitamin.
They're good.
- What do you got in there?
- What do you have in there?
- A steak.
- What?
That's Hamburger Helper
if I ever heard of anything.
What does that look like to you?
That looks like dinner for Day and I.
Day, you come on and join us.
You put that under your T-shirt.
No, I'm not kidding.
Oh, that was in.
Come on, Dad!
Watch the lamp!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8 ACs.
And 5 pool pumps.
- A good addition.
- I figured why not.
Better count on 7.
I dropped that one. It's beyond repair.
- Sell it for scrap metal.
- I already priced it out. 100 bucks.
Good. Invoice Rick Carver Realty
24K for the ACs
and 3200 for the pumps.
The bank will reimburse me
to the same amount.
Your cut is 25%, about 6700.
- 6700?
- That's right.
- Hey, Rick.
- What?
You still got that Ruger?
Excuse me? What did you say?
Are you saying you want the gun?
Did I understand you?
I ran the background check already.
You're clear to carry it.
Who pays the most out
in cash for keys?
Fannie and Freddie, then BoA.
I want you to go to every one
of their foreclosed properties
and find any that are unoccupied.
No homeowner, no tenant.
You got it?
Yo, Terry, let's go.
- Motherfucker didn't pay again.
- We got some money for you.
Send 'em back, Luis.
Send 'em back, brother.
- Dennis, where are we going?
- Be patient. Don't ask questions.
- You don't trust me?
- You hired me, so I got no choice.
Go, Terry.
- Tell him to hurry up.
- Yo, T, let's go, baby.
There's nobody here.
11286. There's nobody here.
All right, bub. Jump in.
How we doing, Javi?
267 Lakewood.
Empty as a motherfucker.
Right, turn to the back page.
I need y'all to sign these leases.
The banks need to think you guys
are tenants in all these properties,
so that I can negotiate
cash-for-keys deals with all y'all.
- How much they paying?
- You can count on a $2500 cheque
from the government
and the motherfucking banks.
2500?
They been fucking me for so long, man.
Shit, I'll take it back, brother.
Somebody getting pregnant
tonight, baby.
Who we fucking, man?
The government or the banks?
Ah, Jim. See you for lunch
Wednesday, OK?
You think Freeman
is the way to go?
He's Fannie's number one attorney
3 years running.
He can connect us to bulk buyers.
I'm not talking millions of dollars,
I'm talking billions.
All right, so this is Dennis Nash.
- County Commissioner Arthur Link.
- Pleasure.
Your property at 2102 West Jefferson,
I'll have Dennis make sure
the gutters are redone.
- What happened to Bill?
- Killed him.
This is my new guy.
I think he's gonna last.
I'll get us a meeting with Freeman.
And stick with this guy, you'll go far.
Thanks for the recommendation.
See you, Arthur.
What do you got for me?
Successfully negotiated
6 cash-for-keys with 6 tenants.
Good. So, Nash, how much
did you tell your buddies per home?
- 3500 or less?
- Yeah, 3500.
Oh, you told them the full amount?
I told 'em what I told 'em.
What do you care?
Yeah.
Hey, baby. Look at that smile.
You're gorgeous.
Don't you have class today?
Er, they're all online,
plus I finished that website.
Congratulations.
She's my sweetheart.
Studies graphic design.
I had her do my business card.
- This your place?
- No, just keeping it warm.
Why don't you scan those leases
and email them to Fannie and BoA.
So, Nash, why aren't you married?
I don't really got time for it.
I don't trust a man who's not married.
Nobody does.
Wanna tell me
what happened to Connor's mum?
I don't think so, no.
Prom night fiasco?
Close, pretty close.
The cheque for the AC
and pool pumps came in.
It's a lot higher
than what I expected.
7200.
You wanna keep that?
I'll give you the 3 grand
I already made.
And whatever my share is
from these leases.
Cos I want my home back.
The BPO on your home
came in at 170K.
I'll buy it
and then you'll owe me 155
at 12% amortised over a 30-year period
with a 2-year balloon.
That's a shitty rate, Rick.
No bank's gonna loan you that money.
If you don't pay, I'm on the hook.
I don't want that property.
It has no future.
- Yeah, but that's my family home.
- It's a home.
But if you want it, it's yours.
It'll take eight to 12 weeks
for the bank to list it on the MLS.
You can do repairs,
but you can't move in till then.
Can we figure out
some kind of contract?
Yeah, I'll have the office
draw up a contract for deed.
Is it mine again?
Yeah, it's yours.
OK, thank you.
Seriously, thank you.
- Rick, thank you.
- All right.
No tears.
Drink?
No, I'm good, I'm good.
High on life.
Well, you might wanna reconsider.
We got one more stop.
224 Lake View Court.
Is that Mr. Tanner? I offered him
a cash-for-keys from the bank.
Guess what? He never called.
And his eviction's today.
You can pop your cherry
with this one.
First one's a bitch,
but you get numb to it.
All you gotta do
is stand next to me today,
but after this
you're gonna do 'em on your own.
Listen, Rick, I don't...
- Could I... Could I just...
- Go fuck yourself? Yeah.
What did you think it was gonna mean,
working for me?
- I just thought that maybe...
- No, you didn't. You didn't think.
You didn't have the guts
to ask me either. Nobody does.
Because who in their right mind
wouldn't rather put someone in a home
than drag 'em out of it?
Up until 3 years ago
I was a regular old real-estate agent.
Putting people in homes,
speculating on property, that was my job.
Now, in 2006 Robert and Julia Tanner
borrowed $30,000
to put an enclosed patio on their home
that they had somehow managed
to live without for 25 years.
Why don't you ask them about that
when they're spitting in your face
while you walk 'em to the kerb?
Why don't you ask the bank
what they were thinking
giving them
an adjustable-rate mortgage?
Then you can go to the government
and ask why they lifted every regulation
and sat there like a retarded stepchild.
You, Tanner, the banks, Washington,
every other homeowner
and investor from here to China
turned my life into evictions.
I'm not an aristocrat.
I wasn't born into this.
My daddy was a roofer, OK?
I grew up on construction sites
watching him bust his arse
until he fell off of a townhouse one day.
A lifetime of insurance payments
and they dropped him
before he could buy a wheelchair,
but only after they got him
hooked on painkillers.
Do you think
I'm gonna let that happen to me?
Do you think America 2010
gives a flying rat's arse about Carver?
Or Nash?
Uh-uh. America
doesn't bail out the losers.
America was built
by bailing out winners,
by rigging a nation
of the winners for the winners
by the winners.
You go to church, Nash?
- You go to church?
- Sure.
Only one in 100
is gonna get on that ark, son.
And every other poor soul's
gonna drown.
I'm not gonna drown.
I wanna do it alone.
I've seen you do it.
I know how it's done.
I'll do it alone.
Help yourself.
Wow.
Rick told me there was a new guy.
Let's go, rookie.
I didn't get all dressed up
just for you.
You ready?
Mr. Tanner?
Yeah.
- Mr. Nash.
- Mr. Tanner.
Good morning.
Dennis Nash from Rick Carver Realty.
Remember?
I remember you, Mr. Nash.
- What do you want?
- I hate to say it,
but your eviction
is scheduled for today.
And, um, your house
has been foreclosed on
and it's been transferred to the bank.
Now, I hate to be here doing this,
but I'm gonna have to ask you
to leave the property.
Now, look, my wife's on the phone
with her attorney right now.
There's been a mix-up.
We're gonna get this sorted out.
If there's been a mix-up, sir,
I can't do anything about that.
I'm just gonna have to ask you to leave.
Look, honey,
have you got him on the phone?
Yeah.
It doesn't matter whatever's happening
on the phone or not with your lawyer.
- This is happening now.
- He said he'd call us back.
Well, there you go.
This is gonna have to wait.
Now, look we've got an appeal filed,
- so there's no point in you being here.
- I understand how you're feeling.
It's a tough day and...
We're going to have to wait
till he calls back. We can't leave today.
- I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
- We're not ready for this.
What I can do is give you some time
to go into the house,
grab all the stuff you need,
whether it's medicine,
stuff for your baby,
jewellery, any pictures,
anything valuable.
No, no, no. You aren't supposed
to be here today, OK?
So you're leaving.
I can only give you a few minutes
to grab some personal belongings.
- I'm gonna ask you to leave.
- You are leaving.
- We need to calm down.
- I am calm.
We're not going back.
Do not close the door.
You're all trespassing.
All of you, get off of my property.
No, sir, you and your wife
are trespassing.
This is the property of the bank now.
We're giving you an opportunity
to collect some of your belongings.
I suggest you take advantage of it.
There's 2 ways to do this:
the easy way where you pack up and go
or I escort you to jail.
It's your choice.
Yes. Let's go.
- Gonna clear it.
All right, we're clear.
Now.
Be careful.
You wanna handle that?
You know what to do.
Mr. Tanner, I'm gonna have
to ask you to move to the kerb.
- What?
- I know, I know. I'm sorry.
Real sorry.
- If I can help you with anything...
- No, I got it, I got it.
- Let me grab this.
- No, no, no, no. I got it.
I'm sorry. I didn't wanna do this today.
I tried to avoid this.
How do you live with yourself?
You make me sick.
It's OK, baby. It's OK, baby.
Oh, honey. No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
- Where are we going?
- Where do you think we're going?
- To see the Orlando Magic practise.
- Er, close, actually pretty close.
We're gonna get myself
a tattoo of a snake
all over my arm,
wrapping around my arm.
You want a tattoo of a snake?
I'll give you a tattoo of a snake.
- Ow!
- That will be the day.
Are we gonna pull up?
Get out.
What are we doing here?
- Take that.
- What are we doing?
- What are you doing, Dennis?
- What are we doing here?
I don't know.
What are we doing?
- You're making me nervous.
- How do you expect us to know?
Don't be nervous.
There's an app for that.
What was that?
Cops are coming back?
- What are we doing?
- What are we doing here?
Oh, my God, look.
Oh, God.
- What are we doing here?
- I got the home back.
- What?
- So I have my room back?
- Yeah.
- How are we getting the house back?
I mean...
- My room looks so big.
- That's cos it is.
We can't move in for a couple of weeks,
but it's ours.
- Dad, come see my room.
- I'm gonna explain.
Come here.
I know, it's huge.
Oh, my God.
Do you want bunk beds?
I'll make you bunk beds.
A basketball hoop
so I can dunk it right there.
- What else? What do you think?
- A hot tub.
A hot tub right there.
And then paint it
black, blue and silver
like the Orlando Magic.
It's gonna be blue and blue and then
one small black strip all the way round.
I love it. You know
what else I was thinking?
- In the back yard we can get a pool.
- A pool? Yeah.
- It better be a heated pool.
- Let's start painting.
There's a bucket right here.
I'm gonna join you.
How are you doing this?
- How is this... How is this real?
- It's a contract.
My boss bought it for me.
- Why?
- And I'm paying him back.
In instalments, just like a bank.
- OK?
- What does he get?
He gets...
He gets his money back.
He's giving me work
so he's gonna keep me in work.
He's painting the room right now.
I got it back.
With your name.
- Derek.
- Hey, Connor.
What's up?
- Hey, buddy.
- Hi, Mr. Nash.
What's up?
What do you wanna play?
A dominant silverback gorilla.
We've been spotted.
Sheriff's department.
Anybody here?
All right, jump in.
Thank you, Carl.
- Mr. Curtis, do you have any weapons?
- Mr. Curtis doesn't live here.
- Er, Mr. Nash?
- You're not Mr. Ron Curtis?
No, that's my landlord.
He lives in Miami.
- You're not the owner of this property?
- No, we rent.
- We've been here for eight years.
- I posted notices on the door.
He said not to worry about it,
he's doing some type of...
- Like a modification or something.
- He scammed you, sir.
Mr. Brady, you've been scammed
by your landlord.
- Now it's 3500, right?
- Yeah.
3500.
I can't... I can't get it.
- Mr. Baldwin?
- Yeah?
Mr. Nash.
Evening, Mr. Baldwin.
My name is Dennis Nash.
I'm here representing
Rick Carver Realty.
Um, today is the day of your eviction,
I'm afraid to say.
Um... the, er...
Your house has been...
- passed over to the bank.
- No, no, no. No, no.
No, I...
I have a reverse mortgage
on this house.
My wife and I took it out 2 years ago
and we're here forever.
- You violated the terms of the mortgage.
- My wife went down to the bank.
She signed the papers
and that was supposed
to be for her and for me.
Mr. Baldwin, there's a process
that took place.
All the paperwork was submitted,
signed by a judge. It's all legal.
You wanna step outside?
You wanna sit with me?
OK, but I don't have the money
to buy the house back.
We did the modification.
They approved it.
- We sent in our first cheque.
- I suggest we figure out a way
to get all your stuff safe in a U-Haul.
I'm gonna have to call my husband.
I could maybe store it
down the street at my sister's house
for the day or something.
The house
isn't yours anymore.
Easy now.
Anyone know what to do about a bird?
3500.
I'm giving you the better option.
I'm gonna have to send these guys
who are being employed today
to get your stuff
and throw it on the kerb.
- I don't want to take you to jail.
- You do what you have to.
- You know what you can do with that?
- You folks need to pack up.
You do something else with that
cos I'm not gonna touch it.
You got any family or friends
who can come and pick you up?
I have a son.
He's up in Michigan.
But I haven't seen him
in a couple of years.
- Do you have his phone number?
- No, no.
No, I don't. No.
- Nobody you can stay with?
- No, I don't.
Are there any neighbours you can call
to help you out for the night?
I-I-I... I don't.
I don't know my neighbours anymore.
I can give you a ride to the Red Cross.
That sound all right?
I can do that.
We'll find you a place, all right?
Say short sale three times
and smile.
Short sale, short sale, short sale.
That's great. Perfect. Thank you.
- Really nice. Last two.
- All right.
OK.
Pretty civilised.
Tesken Equity Management picked up
400 homes in the past two months.
All cash sales, no loans, $100 million.
Orange County needs your help
in finding another bulk buyer like Tesken.
I see. Then I'd like to know
where that highway is gonna be built
connecting the 414
and the Apopka Expressway.
Well, that information
is not public knowledge, so...
A lot of property's gonna be affected
by the zoning board's decision, Arthur.
Anything else, Arthur?
OK, yes, I know the route.
Good. There's a bulk buyer here
out of New York.
Vesic Investment Group.
They're shopping with a piss-ant broker
out of Kissimmee, Ortiz.
- Sold him 15 homes last month.
- Mr. Freeman, I know Ortiz.
I can get Vesic Investment Group
away from him
and my team can handle
as many homes as you have to sell.
Well, I have
upwards of 1,000 homes.
Possibly more.
You get me Vesic Investment,
we're in business.
1,000 homes.
Do you know how much money
we're talking about?
I want you to track Ortiz,
find out who he's talking to,
what properties he's looking at.
- We got to know what this Vesic deal is.
- What's my cut?
- Don't worry, I'll take care of you.
- I know standard commission is 6%.
So what's my cut?
I'll give you 5% of my take.
- 10%.
- 6%, and a hand job.
No callouses.
You'll probably pull in
somewhere between 200 and 300K.
- More than you made in your whole life.
- Yeah, that's more than I ever made.
- 'What do you got?'
- 3217 Lonson Cove.
It's the fifth one.
They're all Bank of Greater Santa Fe.
'Keep following that cocksucker
and get back to me.'
OK.
Hey, Frank.
What do you want?
Are you with those guys?
No, no, not at all.
Er, I've just come to see
how you're doing.
And, um, if you want,
I think I can get you a job.
That's a nice shirt.
You still working with your friend?
I didn't have to come over here.
I just wanted to, um...
- To what? To lie to me, to cheat me?
- No, to help you if you wanted it.
Have you figured out
where your kids are gonna stay?
My kids have a home.
This is their home.
- Well...
- I did research,
gave boxes of files
to a lawyer pro bono.
We're gonna win, legally, in court.
It's not gonna make any difference.
I've been there, Frank.
I've been there.
- You gotta be realistic.
- I'm being realistic.
I didn't ask for your help, sir,
and I don't want it. Please leave.
Please get off my property.
You're trespassing.
Hey, are you awake?
Ortiz, the king of Miguels,
is gonna sell 100 homes to Vesic.
They're all in these neighbourhoods,
priced between 165 and 200K.
We're talking over a $20 million deal
and it's not mine.
- Holy shit.
- Yup.
Triple word score.
- Take that.
- We're working, baby.
Dennis, tell him to take a break.
Take a break, Rick.
You inspire me, OK?
We'll play later.
Er...
OK, so you know Vesic already bought
15 homes from Ortiz last month.
So?
So, what if I take all the ACs,
all the water pumps
and the appliances
out of those homes?
Who do you think
Vesic's gonna blame?
Ortiz.
They'll call Immigration, put him
on his lawn mower back over the border
while I'm on the phone
with Bank of Greater Santa Fe.
Yeah.
And we'll sell these 100 homes.
And 1,000 more for Freeman.
I see green skies ahead.
Put some green in my pocket,
I'll empty those homes tonight.
100 bucks a pop, 1500 bucks.
Big talk. All right, do it.
- Tell him to hurry up.
- We got that cube truck too.
- HVAC pool pump.
But come this way too.
I wanna show you something.
- Are you going in?
- No, you're going in.
Nah, that's B&E, man.
That's guaranteed time right there.
It's not B&E if you got a key.
We're doing appliances too.
We're doing fridges,
stoves, dishwashers.
- You gonna take care of me?
- You know I will.
Whatever I can afford.
You know that.
I'm heading to handle this cash-for-keys
Rick wanted me to do.
Yeah. Hold on.
1485 Lake Shore Circle.
Is that property for sale?
Does it have a swimming pool?
All right. I'll call you back.
3, 2, 1.
Derek, over here.
- Every put your hands out.
- Yes!
Happy birthday!
All right, Mountain Dew.
What's happening?
- Who wants it?
- Connor.
God, Dad!
- What do you think?
- Awesome!
Jump on it. Jump on it.
Sit down on it. Sit down on it.
Show us what you got.
Nice.
Careful.
Car, guys.
Hey.
Hey, Connor. Let's see
if these guys want some of your cake.
Do we have a cheese pizza left?
Do you guys wanna ask them
if they want some cheese pizza
and some birthday cake?
- All right, I gotta get Derek home.
- OK.
I'm gonna grab that cheese pizza
and some cake.
I think it's nice for them
to say hi to these guys.
- I gotta get Derek home.
- Hey!
Hey, where are you going?
Hey, you!
Over here.
- I'm talking to you.
- You're talking to me?
What are you doing here?
Are you following me?
No, I live here.
I don't know what you're talking about.
- Yeah, I know who you are.
- Have a good day.
- What are you doing here?
- What do you mean? I live here.
I just told you.
I don't know you.
No, you're Rick Carver Realty.
I know exactly who you are.
- You don't know me.
- Oh, I know you.
- You kicked me out of my home.
- What?
I don't know you, bud.
Come over here and we'll talk.
Why would I walk over here?
Nash. That's your name, isn't it?
You don't want
everybody else to hear about it,
what a fucking arsehole you are
and how you kicked me
and my entire family out of our home?
- You got me mixed up with someone.
- No, I don't.
I know exactly who you are.
Oh, you know it was you.
And here everybody else
is gonna know.
- Just calm down.
- You kicked me out of my home.
You ruined my fucking life.
No, you don't get to go anywhere.
- Dennis!
- Don't do that.
- Don't you tell me what to do.
- Get inside.
- Yeah, get inside.
- Don't fucking talk to her like that.
- What are you gonna fucking do?
Please, guys. Please!
Go inside, go inside!
- Take him inside!
- OK.
- Go, go, go.
- You little fucking piece of shit.
- You ruined my life.
- I'm not fucking with this guy.
Yeah, you better not fuck with me.
- I don't know you, man.
- You know me.
- I don't know you.
- Bullshit!
- I don't fucking know you.
- I know you, Rick Carver Realty.
I know you
and I'll see you every day,
when you wake up, when you go to bed,
when your fucking kids are playing.
You OK?
How did he know your name?
I don't know.
- Cos he knew your face too, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
Maybe I worked on his house.
I work on foreclosed homes.
Maybe he saw me at his home.
I don't know.
Rick Carver.
Right?
How did he know your name?
Fucking arsehole!
- We gotta get Connor out of here.
- That's what I'm trying to do.
- Now.
- That's what I'm trying to do, Mum.
Right now.
- Get the fuck outta here.
- Fuck you!
- You motherfucker.
OK, we need to go.
We need to get out of here, OK?
Have some fucking balls.
- Are you evicting people?
- Mum!
- He said you were at his eviction.
- I don't know that fucking guy.
I don't know how he knows me.
I work on homes.
I work on foreclosed homes, Mum.
This guy was being foreclosed on.
Maybe he saw me working on his home.
Maybe. I don't know.
- OK?
- Just tell me.
I'm telling you.
Bolt the door. Don't leave.
Disney World, Sea World,
Universal Studios.
Downtown Orlando's
about 20 miles behind us.
And then at your nine o'clock
are the vacant Greater Santa Fe homes.
Wow, I never realised
how close they were to Shinola.
Mm-hm.
- About the Santa Fe deal.
- It hasn't even been a week
since we picked up 15 homes from Ortiz
and all the ACs, water pumps,
appliances are missing.
- You're kidding me.
- Hidden expenses, they kill returns
so Vesic's not interested anymore.
That Santa Fe deal's like
one giant ATM machine.
What can I do to get Vesic
back into those homes?
I just don't think
that's gonna be possible.
How about this?
I'll put brand-new appliances
in all 15 of those homes free of charge
if you move the deal
from Ortiz over to me.
I tell you what.
You put brand-new ACs,
appliances, water pumps
in any of the 100 homes that need 'em
you got yourself a deal.
Appliances, yeah.
ACs and water pumps, no.
OK.
But the homes have
to be vacated in 30 days.
Put it in writing, it's a deal.
Hey! Look at that!
Bring him in. Bring him in.
The Santa Fe deal,
I'll give you 6% of my share.
Around $63,000 before taxes.
OK. I mean, I guess
I can accept that. That's fine.
Yeah, I can deal with that amount.
$63,000 did you say?
- What are you boys up to?
- Aren't you so sweet?
I used to dream about one home.
Now it's 100.
All right.
- Dreams.
- To dreams.
Fuck dreams. To 100 homes.
Hey!
Uh-oh. Zombies coming to get me.
- Oh, fuck.
- Damn, pilgrim.
Did anyone ever come up to you
after an eviction?
Yeah, someone tried
to run me off the road last year.
I haven't gone out to dinner once
with my wife and girls
in the last three years
without looking over my shoulder.
That's why I carry this.
Even now at 5am.
Is it worth it?
As opposed to what?
Did somebody get to you?
Don't bullshit me.
Someone's calling you.
Or they tried to find you.
So, Nash,
the sun's gonna come up
and here we are.
What do you think?
Huh.
- Think about what?
- Well, you wanted to kill me once.
Now you're gonna make a lot of money.
I did want to kill you.
I don't know.
I don't know what I'm doing here either,
but I'm thankful.
You know.
I don't know. What could I do?
You know, my dad...
Well, he killed himself pretty much.
Fuck it, no. Sorry.
I don't wanna waste your booze.
He... He died of a heart attack.
Booze, food.
Whatever you wanna call it.
Left me with my mum.
My boy.
My boy, my boy.
As opposed to what?
I gotta get out of that motel now.
I gotta get into my home.
I gotta get my family out.
It's gotta be listed on the MLS,
for sale.
- I need it.
- 2 more weeks, OK?
I need it now.
- Get another one.
- Help me with it.
You got the money.
Buy whatever you want.
There's plenty of homes in the sea.
Like I said,
don't get emotional
about real estate, Nash.
They're boxes.
You listening?
Big boxes, small boxes.
What matters is how many you got.
You're gonna have more properties
than women to fill them with.
You know that, right?
You love your mum, you love your kid.
Buy 'em a house.
Buy one for your mum.
Buy one for your kid.
Buy one for yourself.
What do I care? Jesus.
100 homes.
1,000 fucking homes.
Watch out for the gators.
They don't sleep.
And make sure I don't roll in the water.
Why are we going this way?
I just wanna show you something.
Dennis, what are we doing?
Just trust me
and follow me, please.
- What is this?
- Have a look.
Why?
Will you just have a look?
- It's a cool pool.
- Cool pool.
I'd say.
Makes you wanna dive in, right?
- Whose basketball goal is that?
- That belongs to Shaquille O'Neil.
He lowered it cos he likes to dunk
from sitting down.
- Can we go now, please?
- Have you seen the pool?
I bought this for you.
And you. That's your pool.
This is your house.
Let's go home. This isn't funny.
- I'm not joking, Mum.
- That's not his basketball net.
This is somebody else's
and I want our house.
I wanna go home.
We don't have that home anymore.
I sold it.
I sold our old home
and I bought this.
Fresh start. I don't wanna go back
to that house we were evicted from.
You sold our house?
We couldn't move into our old home
for 2 to 3 weeks
so I had to get us out of that motel
so that Connor wouldn't get killed.
By kicking people out?
By kicking people out of their houses?
- You buy this?
- I didn't kick anybody out of this home.
I bought this home
with money I earned
so I could put a roof over your head
and I could put food in his mouth.
- We were drowning, Mum.
- This stops here.
I bought this fair and square.
- I didn't take it from anybody.
- I'm gonna call Jimmy
and we're going to Tampa, OK?
Come on, Connor.
I'm gonna call my brother.
We're gonna go to Tampa
and you're gonna figure this out.
I did this for the boy.
We were drowning.
Rick Carver? Rick Carver
who bought our house for us?
I'm not staying here.
I'm not staying in this home.
What do you want?
Is Connor OK?
He's sleeping.
Hey, Rick.
Yeah, sure.
OK.
- Give it to him.
- Yep, all right.
- See you, fellas.
- 9:45.
Yes, sir.
- Goddamn it.
- What is it?
One Santa Fe homeowner is gonna try
and block his eviction in court today.
If he's successful and others follow,
Vesic will pull out.
This is proof of publication.
It wasn't filed 2 years ago,
so Freeman's boys
backdated and notarised it.
Now, I need you to be
at the courthouse plaza at 9:45am.
The court clerk will meet you there.
Just give it to him, OK?
This is forged?
It's a stupid piece of paper
someone forgot to file
when the loan was being bought
and sold a million times over.
It's just a technicality.
- It's Frank Greene.
- Yeah.
Same deadbeat stealing my water
and power. I told you he was no good.
Hey, that's not your dick
in your hand, son.
That is the Santa Fe deal.
100 homes, 1,000 more for Freeman.
Our money, Miami.
Your home, everything.
- Got me?
- Mm-hm, yeah, I do.
Don't "mm-hm, yeah, I do" me.
Courthouse plaza, 9:45am.
Hey, honey.
- Hi.
- Say hello.
Hi, Mr. Peters.
- Hello.
- What the hell is going on?
'What do you mean?'
You get your arse over there now
or consider your life over, do you hear?
- Where are you?
- 'I'm here now.'
And?
- I'm about to do it now.
- 'You dumb fuck.'
You call me as soon as it's done.
You hear me?
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
Hey!
Are you with Rick Carver?
Are you with Carver or not?
Is that it?
Idiot!
As far as I can tell
the proof of publication is here.
Your Honour,
we have a buyer in place
and we'd like to get
this property on the books.
If we check the fall index
this has not been docketed.
Well, that may be,
but the proof is in the file.
That's all the statute requires.
I'm ordering the sale to go forward.
Your Honour, we know for a fact
that the files weren't there.
ESP versus Ballard.
Your Honour, I know
that there was no proof of publication.
- You can't look at me...
- What is it?
I have a wife and I have...
These guys. You see them?
You see my wife and my children?
Connor?
Mum? Connor?
'Please record your message
after the tone. When you have...'
'Hey, Rick.'
Morning, Donald Trump.
I'm outside your new mansion.
Where are you?
Frank Greene's eviction. Let's go.
'Hello? Dumb arse, are you there?'
There's 8 other homeowners
we got to evict after Greene.
I'll start out nice
with an aggressive cash-for-keys.
I'll pay out of my own pocket
if I have to. I don't give a shit.
But if they give me any flak,
Freeman's boys
and the court clerk, baby.
No big deal.
We've been neighbours for a long time
and I've never seen
anything like this before.
Do you know if they have
any guns in the house?
- I mean, he likes to hunt.
- He's a hunter?
Yeah, he likes to hunt.
She gripes a lot,
but he's a pretty even-keeled guy.
- Not hot-tempered or anything?
- No, I wouldn't say that.
I can tell you, it's been really hard.
His wife's been a worried wreck.
Morning, Rick. We may have
some trouble with Mr. Greene, the tenant.
He and his wife
have been looking into stuff.
Well, I mean, you know.
Look, last night I heard 'em yelling.
Ma'am, thank you.
We're not marriage counsellors, OK?
Let's get cooking.
The problem is,
this guy may be armed.
Go find out.
I got two more evictions today.
All right. I'll contact Orlando PD,
get a back-up come in and check it out.
- Is his family in there with him?
- The kids didn't go to school.
They're definitely home.
She came over this morning, crying,
until he called her back in.
I'll go and check it out.
Thanks for the play-by-play.
Hurry up.
Watch out! Get back!
Run!
I do not wanna hurt anybody.
Sir, put the gun down.
Put the gun down.
Put the gun down, sir.
You put that down.
My wife and kids are in this house.
Get your gun. You don't have it?
- Dumb shit.
- Sir, put the weapon down.
Trespassing.
- Sir, don't do that.
- Shots fired, shots fired.
- You wanna shoot my kids?
- Oh, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
I am not gonna leave here.
Go in the bedroom.
Don't stand there.
Get in the bedroom.
Now.
- I shot at the grass.
- Put the gun down.
God damn it, stop it.
Put that down.
- Put it down now.
- Not gonna happen, sir.
Sir, why don't you send
your wife and kids out?
Send your wife and kids out.
Sir, drop your weapon.
The court decided my case
in 60 seconds flat.
Nobody checked the file index. Fact.
No proof of publication filed. Fact.
Nobody looked at the cancelled cheques
to prove bank payment. Fact.
The judge, he wasn't up for re-election.
He wasn't beholden
to anybody in this county.
60 seconds for a lifetime
and this is my home.
Dad.
Get in the bedroom.
- Get in the bedroom!
- No, Dennis.
- Dennis.
- Get the fuck off.
- No.
- Sir, Mr. Nash.
- What the hell are you waiting for?
- Mr. Nash, get back behind the car.
Get back! Sir, get back!
Stop! Stay right there.
I'm gonna shoot you.
I will shoot.
- This is my home.
- Listen to me.
- Get off of my lawn.
- This is your lawn.
- This is your home, I know.
- What are you gonna do?
Do you hear me?
The banks made more money...
- Frank.
- I have got the right to shoot anybody
who is on my property,
who sets foot on my property.
- I don't want to do this.
- Frank, I know this is your home.
Put the gun down
and let your family out, please.
Look up there. Look up there!
You see that?
That is the sun
and it is shining.
Nobody is gonna tell me
it is night when it is day.
And God Almighty could come down here
and tell me it's night
and I would know that it's day,
because I know what I know.
And nobody is gonna tell me
the sun isn't shining. Nobody.
I cheated you.
I put a forged document in your file
on the day of your court hearing, Frank.
This is your home.
All right, I'm coming out.
All right, sir.
Keep your hands up.
Walk this way slowly
with your hands up.
- Hands up.
- Put your hands up. Hands in the air.
Walk out slowly.
Keep your hands in the air.
Keep walking. Keep walking.
Stop. Turn around, face the home.
Turn around, turn around.
Now walk slowly
towards the sound of my voice.
Stop. Go down on your knees, sir.
Lie down on your stomach, sir,
with your arms extended to the side.
We're coming in, ma'am.
Stand up.
Got anything on you that could
poke me, stick in me, hurt me?
Call it in.
No, sir. No.
All right. You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say
can be used against you.
You have a right to have an attorney
present during questioning.
If you can't afford one,
the court will appoint one for you.
Sir.
OK, I just wanted...
He didn't do anything.
- He didn't do anything wrong.
- Calm down.
- What is your business here?
- I came here to evict Mr. Greene.
- Who are you working with?
- Rick Carver Realty.
- Is Rick Carver here today?
- There he is right there.
That's a hell of a thing you did, son.
Hell of a thing.
You Rick Carver?
Sir, are you Rick Carver?
Thank you.
Yes, sir, I am.
We need to speak to you.
Don't leave.
Mm-hm.