Hilario.
Papa!
Sotero!
My good friend.
How are ya?
You have a drink?
I can't tell you what
a pleasure it is to see a village like this.
Santos!
So much restlessness
and change in the outside world.
People no longer
content with their station in life.
Women's fashions?
Shameless.
Cigar.
Mire! Religion!
You'd weep if you saw how true religion is
now a thing of the past.
Last month we were
in San Juan - a rich town. Sit down.
Rich town,
much blessed by God.
Big church.
Not like here - little church,
priest comes twice a year. Big one!
You think we find gold candlesticks, poor
box filled to overflowing?
You know what we found?
Brass candlesticks,
almost nothing in the poor box.
But we took it anyway.
I know we took it anyway.
I'm trying to show him
how little religion some people now have.
That I could see
for myself.
Don't see!
What if you had
to carry my load, huh?
The need to provide food, like a father, to
fill the mouths of his hungry men.
Guns. Ammunition.
You know how much money
that costs? Huh? Huh?!
No.
The days of good
hunting are over.
Once there was horses,
cattle, gold, fruit from the trees. No more.
Now I must hunt with
a price on my head, rurales at my heels.
I'll be back.
Enough!
We'll get
the rest when we come back.
I love this village.
I know you have
your problems...
Murderer! Thief!
Rafael!
Rafael...
Stupid!
We have to have
another discussion very soon.
It's always a pleasure to hear the views of
my good friend Sotero.
Maybe when
I come back, hm?
Adiós!
Let's go!
Help me bring him in.
If he steals
our harvest again,...
...we might as well
cut our throats and be done with it!
Leave the valley.
That's what we must do.
Live somewhere else?
Take our homes
with us? Our farms?
We... could
hide some food.
From Calvera?
He never steals all our food.
He leaves us
enough to go on with.
That's something.
We could beg him
to leave us more.
No, no. That would make him more angry. I
don't think we should do anything.
We must
do something!
Like Rafael?
Talk sense.
We break our backs
in the fields, and our bellies stay empty.
We must do something!
We must do something.
But what?
I don't know.
We'll ask the old man.
He'll know.
Fight.
You must fight. Fight!
With machetes
and bare hands against guns?!
Buy guns.
Buy?
Go to the border.
Guns are plentiful there.
But what are we
going to use for money?
Sell that.
And anything else
you can collect.
Even if we
had the guns,...
...we know how to plant and grow
- we don't know how to kill.
Then learn.
Or die.
Hey! I've been
waitin' for you.
Oh, you did
a wonderful job.
I'm sorry, but
there'll be no funeral.
What?!
The grave's dug, and the defunct is as
ready as the embalmer can make him,...
...but there'll
be no funeral.
Didn't I pay you enough?
It's not a question of money. For $20, I'd
plant anybody with a whoop and a holler.
But the funeral's off.
Well, how d'ya
like that?!
I want him buried. You want him buried. If
he could talk, he'd second the motion.
That's as unanimous
as you can get.
You've behaved
like a Christian, but...
Now, look. I'm not
lookin' for any praise.
I'm a traveling salesman
- ladies' corsets.
I'm walking
down the street and a man drops dead.
For two hours people stepped over
him, without lifting a finger.
I'm doing what
any decent man would.
Come on, Henry...
No! This man
has to be buried.
Soon. He's not
turning into a nosegay.
I know. I would
if I could, but...
...there's an element
in town that objects.
Objects? To what?
They say he isn't
fit to be buried there.
What? In Boot Hill?
There's nothing there
but murderers, cutthroats and barflies.
And if they ever
felt exclusive, they're past it now.
They happen to be
white, friend.
And old Sam...
Well, old Sam
was an Indian.
Well, I'll be damned!
I never knew you had to be anything but a
corpse to get into Boot Hill.
How long's this
been going on?
Since the town
got civilized.
It's not my doin', boys.
I don't like it. No, sir.
I've always treated
every man as another future customer.
In that case,
get that hearse rollin'.
My driver's quit.
He's prejudiced too, huh?
If it comes to gettin'
his head blown off.
Well, get somebody else.
Nobody else
will drive it! So here.
Oh, hell! If that's all that's holding things
up, I'll drive the rig.
Can I borrow
that scatter-gun?
You're more
than welcome.
Hey! Wait a minute there.
This hearse cost me $840.
It's the only one
in the county.
I'll be darned if
I let it be shot at.
I'll pay for
the damages.
I wanna see this.
Me, too!
Never rode shotgun
on a hearse before.
Let her buck.
New in town?
Yeah.
Where are you from?
Dodge. You?
Tombstone. See any
action up there?
Uh-uh.
Tombstone?
Same. People all
settled down, like.
Same all over.
Injun lovers!
Easy. Just wind.
We'll get there.
It's not gettin' up there
that bothers me.
It's stayin' up there
that I mind.
Comin' up behind
us on the left.
I don't think so.
Second-story window.
Curtain moved.
I'm not in a good position.
Let him stick his neck out.
You elected?
No.
I got nominated
real good.
Boys, why don't you just turn around now -
save yourselves a lot of trouble?
Soon, huh?
The reception
committee is forming.
Hold it.
Hold it right there.
Anything wrong?
Turn that rig around
and get it down the hill.
I need six men up here.
Yahoo!
Boys, the drinks
are on me!
Hey! Hey!
I'd like to buy
you a drink. And your friend, too.
Thanks.
Where are you from?
Oh, yeah. Where
are you goin'?
Thanks for
the free show.
You're more
than welcome.
Boy, that was really something. I won't
forget that if I live to be a hundred.
Henry, the stage
is leavin'!
All right, all right!
Wait till Flora hears about this. Y'know,
she won't believe one word of it.
Henry!
The stage! Come on!
You keep this.
Where are you headed?
I'm drifting south,
more or less.
You?
Just driftin'.
Any action here?
Yeah. Grocery
clerk and bouncer
in one of those bars
across the street, if that's your taste.
Ah.
Yeah.
Well... see ya.
Say, uh...
what's your name?
Make it Vin.
What's yours?
Chris.
Yes?
We think you are
a man we can trust.
Thank you very much.
We wish you
to help us.
There's this man,
Calvera.
A thief.
A murderer.
He and his men, they steal our food, and
then they leave us to starve.
Not only that,
but our women...
Wait, wait.
Just a minute.
If you need protection,
go to the rurales.
We did. Twice.
But they can't station men in a small
village for... who knows how long?
So they left.
And when they left, he came again -
Calvera - and every year since.
He will do so
until he is stopped.
Sit down.
We need help.
We must buy guns.
We know nothing
about them.
Will you buy
guns for us?
Guns are very expensive
and hard to get.
Why don't you
hire men?
Men?
Gunmen.
Nowadays men are cheaper than guns.
Will you go?
It will be a blessing
if you help us.
Sorry, I'm not in
the blessing business.
No, no. We offer
more than that.
We could feed
you every day.
And we have this.
What's that?
We can sell
this for gold.
Everything we own.
Everything of value
in the village.
I've been offered
a lot for my work, but never everything.
Will it be enough?
You see,
if we could drive the bandits away,...
...life could be very
good in our village.
But as it is, we ourselves
could stand it a little longer,...
...but the children,
they cry because they're hungry.
Do you understand what it means when
you start something like this?
We will fight, too.
Every one of us.
When Calvera comes,
the church bell will ring the alarm.
We'll fight with guns,
if we have them.
If we don't, with machetes,
axes, clubs, anything!
Once you begin,...
...you have to be prepared
for killing and more killing.
And still more killing -
until the reason for it has gone.
We understand.
We've considered that.
Does every man
in the village feel the same?
Every man.
I'll see what
I can do for you.
Gracias. You know...
Now, wait.
I didn't say I'll go.
I'll pass the word
around that you're looking for men.
It won't be hard
to find men here. Everyone wears a gun.
Sure - same as
they wear pants. That's expected.
But good men?
That's something else again.
How can you tell
they are good?
There are ways.
Come in.
The word is out
you're looking for men.
That's right.
Men who are good with that.
I'm good with it.
Fast?
Try me.
I aim to.
Step in closer.
Now, hold your
hands like that.
Now, clap.
Faster.
Now, as fast
as you can.
Now you try it.
Very young and...
and very proud.
The graveyards are full of boys who were
very young and very proud.
Come in.
No tricks now, Chris.
Harry! It's good
to see you again.
Chris.
What are you doing
in this dump?
I heard you've got
a contract open.
Not for a high-stepper
like you.
A dollar bill always
looks as big to me as a bedspread.
It's just eating money.
A gold eagle, room and board.
Six weeks gunning for some farmers.
You old Cajun! You don't talk so good, but
you always know what's goin' on.
Oh, Harry.
With your permission.
All right.
All that's on top. What's underneath?
Only what I told you.
Gold? Cattle? Payroll?
Sure, never mind.
Tell me when you can.
Harry, please don't
understand me so fast!
I said never mind.
I'm in.
You dirty dog!
Place your bets.
Five.
Eight.
Eights again.
Ten at the point.
The cowpoke that
just walked in in the stovepipe chaps,...
...I'd like to buy
him a drink.
Yes, sir!
Válgame Dios.
There's one. Look at the scars on his face.
The man for us
is the one who gave him that face.
Hey... you learn fast.
Next bet comin' up.
Crap.
Next man.
Gent over there
wants to buy you a drink.
Vin.
Howdy.
I'd like to buy
you a drink.
Whiskey.
Have you anything
lined up?
Yeah. I'm gonna
take a job in a grocery store.
Fella says
I'm gonna make a crackerjack clerk.
Crackerjack.
If that's your taste...
I heard of a job shooin' some flies away
from a village, but I don't know the pay.
$20.
A week?
Six weeks:
the whole job.
Well, that's ridiculous.
You heard of anything?
Yeah.
Shooing some flies away
from a little village.
Their village.
It pays $20?
I'm looking for
men right now.
No, it wouldn't even
pay for my bullets.
Ours is a poor village.
We understand. You could get much
more in a grocery store,...
...and it's good,
steady work.
Yep.
How many you got?
Looking for O'Reilly.
Don't know his name,
but there's a fella
in back choppin' wood for his breakfast.
Mornin'.
I'm a friend
of Harry Luck's.
He tells me
you're broke.
Nah, I'm doing this
because I'm an eccentric millionaire!
There's a job for six men, watching over a
village, south of the border.
How big's the opposition?
Thirty guns.
I admire your notion
of fair odds, mister.
Harry tells me you faced bigger
odds in the Travis County war.
Well, they paid me
$600 for that one.
He said you got
that Salinas thing cleared up.
They paid me $800
for that one.
You cost a lot.
Yeah...
That's right,
I cost a lot.
The offer is $20.
$20?
Right now,
that's a lot.
Where can
I reach you?
Right here.
I still say he can't.
And I tell you he can.
If he claims that,
he's a liar.
Not so loud.
He might hear you.
I don't give a damn
if he hears me or not.
I got two months'
salary comin'. I'll bet it all it ain't so.
Well, you ain't
bettin' with me.
Me either.
I told you what he said,
and I believe him.
Well, one of us
is a fathead.
You can get good
odds on which.
Ha! Ha! Ha!
Britt. Britt,
wake up.
I'm talkin' to ya!
Look at me!
Filene told me what you said.
I say you're wrong. What d'you say?
Ha! Ha! Ha!
What's the matter?
You afraid? Afraid to tell me I'm wrong?!
Call it.
Well, you see, I won.
Well, how about it?
Well?
Filene, how about it?
I don't know.
It was mighty close.
Close? What d'you mean, close? You all
got eyes. You saw what happened. I won!
You tell 'em.
I won, didn't I?
You lost.
You're a liar.
I said you're a liar!
I said you're
a coward and a liar!
Get up. Let's
do it for real.
Get up!
Get up, I said!
So help me,
I'll let you have it right where you are.
Call it!
I want nothin'
to do with this.
Call it!
Drop it, Wallace.
Forget it.
Get away from me.
Call it.
Britt.
Chris.
Can I have a word
with you?
Did you have any luck?
Found a man
who would have been perfect.
Gun or knife, you couldn't want any
better. Wasn't interested.
The money?
It wasn't enough?
He doesn't care
a hoot about money.
A man in this line
of work who doesn't care about money?!
Men in this line of work are not all alike.
Some care about nothing but money.
Others, for reasons
of their own, enjoy only the danger.
And the competition.
If he's the best with a knife and a gun,
with whom does he compete?
Himself.
You.
I've been looking
for you!
Uh-oh! What have
we got here?
Never mind.
He knows.
Clap hands, he says.
Clap your hands,
and let's see how fast you are.
Clap hands!
A man comes to him...
cos he respects him,...
...cos he'd be proud
to work with him.
He makes me look like two cents
with some damned kids' game!
Hey, kid, that's
enough of that!
You stay away
from me, will ya?
Come on, now,...
...and let's see
how fast you are.
And no games, huh?
No clapping hands - none of that stuff!
Just draw.
Come on.
Come on, draw!
- Campesino. Come on!
- You say campesino to me?!
You get out of my way,
you dirt farmer!
You don't think
I mean it, huh?
You... think
I'm just talking, huh?
Hey... get up.
Do you hear me?
Get up and face me!
Do you hear?!
Hey,...
...give him my gun, huh?
Sorry this happened, friend.
Let him sleep it off.
When he wakes up,
let him have his gun back.
And give him a drink.
I changed my mind.
There's a man waiting in your room.
Said he was a friend of yours.
Remember me?
Yep.
You need men to
do a job in Mexico.
That's right.
How long?
Four, six weeks.
That ought to do it.
How much does the job pay?
I thought you were
looking for the Johnson brothers.
I found them.
How much
does the job pay?
20. We leave
tomorrow.
I'll have the money
before I leave.
It'll just take care of
my last two days' rent.
$20? You must
be livin' in style.
Yes.
I have the most stylish
corner of the filthy storeroom out back.
That, and one
plate of beans:
$10 a day.
Yeah, things do get high
when they find out you're on the run.
There's a dry wash
south of town.
Pick me up there.
He's a good gun.
And we aren't heading
for a church social.
Chris.
Yeah. He picked
us up at dawn.
Any idea who it is?
Yeah. That kid
from the saloon.
Won't take no
for an answer.
Doesn't show much
sense, does he?
I'm getting a stiff neck
keepin' track of him.
If you can't forget him,
why don't you ride side-saddle?
Ah, well... he won't
last much longer.
That so?
Ridin' out there in all
that dust and heat - what a chucklehead!
Yeah. Not
smart like us!
Yep.
Suppose our friend
over there has got anything to eat?
How about
I bring him some?
Ah, it isn't food
he's hungry for.
Then let me tie a can to his tail. Right
now, he's like an itch I can't scratch.
Ah, leave him alone.
It's a free country.
And it's his.
You know, it's funny.
Now that he's gone, I kinda miss him.
Where is everybody?
Where are they, Tomas?
Luis! Asunción! Demetrio!
Emilio! Sotero!
What kind of a reception is this?
Come out! Come out and make them
welcome, before we die of shame.
Hilario, stop your shouting.
Do they call this a welcome?
What are they thinking of?!
Come in.
You must be thirsty.
You must excuse them.
They are farmers here.
They are afraid
of everyone and everything.
of rain, and no rain...
The summer
may be too hot, the winter - too cold.
The sow has no pigs,
the farmer is afraid he may starve.
She has too many,
he's afraid she may starve.
There's no need to apologize. We
didn't expect flowers and speeches.
Tomorrow is the anniversary
of the founding of the village.
They will be celebrating -
then, you will see them in a better light.
Who sounded the alarm?
Who sounded the alarm?!
I did.
Thank you, amigos,
for coming out to greet us.
Thank you for
letting us see your beautiful faces!
Thank you,
thank you, you chickens!
You come running
out like chickens!
We ride to this
middle of nowhere.
We're ready to risk
our lives to help you.
And you?
You hide from us!
Hide... from us!
Ah... but it's a different
story when you're in danger, huh?
You might lose
your precious crops.
Then you flock to us. Huh?
Well... we're here,
my compadres and I.
And here we stay.
And you?
You prove to us
that you're worth fighting for.
Now get back to your houses,
back to work. Go on! Go back.
We'll let you know when to fight and how
to fight. Go back! All of you, go back!
Go back!
Now we're seven.
You know, I've been in some towns where
the girls aren't very pretty.
As a matter of fact, I've been in some
towns where they were downright ugly.
But this is the first time I've been in a
town where there's no girls at all.
Except little ones.
If we're not careful,
we can have quite a social life here!
Oh, it's not so bad. I fell in with a fast
crowd that hangs out near the fountain.
We got to predictin' the weather for today
and didn't break up till twilight.
Stop the music!
Bring out the other bull!
Hilario!
Britt.
The boy saw three of Calvera's
men. The horses are in the arroyo.
Lee.
Get one alive.
Yes.
I'll show you where.
Rico, he knows
where the arroyo is.
I'm sorry, Britt.
I didn't mean to spoil it.
Shut up!
Oh... That... that
was the greatest shot I've ever seen.
The worst.
I was aiming
at the horse.
Three men were sent
by Calvera to spy.
It's almost certain
they saw us.
Whatever they learned
will be buried with them.
Válgame Dios!
If he comes now...
He'd never send men ahead
if he was near enough to see for himself.
So we have time to get ready. And we
have something else - surprise.
If he rides in with no idea of the
reception we can prepare for him,...
...I promise you, we'll all teach him
something about the price of corn.
Aim,...
...squeeze,...
...cock.
Aim,...
...squeeze,...
...cock.
Settle down. Now, you miss the first
chance, you may not get a second.
Get that butt tight in your shoulder. If you
don't, two things will happen.
One: you'll waste a bullet.
Two: you'll break your arm.
Now, close your eye.
Aim from here, to here, to the target.
Fire.
That rock?
No, that man
you're gonna kill.
Good!
If only we had more guns,
think what we could do!
You'll get more guns.
How?
The same way
you got these. Calvera's men.
The ones who spied
on us brought them.
Like three kings
bearing gifts.
If Calvera
does not come now, after all of this,...
...what a waste!
A pretty foxy fellow,
this Calvera, eh?
Señor, not a fox.
A coyote!
How did he
ever find out about the gold mine?
Gold mine?
What gold
mine, señor?
You know, the one
in the mountains.
In our mountains?
We never had a gold
mine around here.
Say, come to think of it,
it was a silver mine.
Whatever happened to it?
We have no
silver mine either.
I mean in the old days.
Not at any time.
Where did you hear
of this gold and silver, hm?
All right, come on, boys.
More work, less talk, huh?
Toro.
Toro!
Come on,
little bull!
Toro.
You do anything to me
and I'll kill you while you are doing it.
You almost
took my eye out!
Let me go.
Let me go!
Oh, you bite me
and I'll bite you!
I got a good mind
to throw you in the water.
Smash you with a rock!
Cut your head off!
Shut up.
Shut up!
Where are
the others? Huh?
I'll never tell you.
Look what I found.
Who is she?
From our village.
So that's
where they were. You hid them.
Sure they hid them.
But she won't tell where.
They're afraid.
She's afraid of me, you, him... all of us.
Farmers! Their families
told them we'd rape them.
Well, we might.
In my opinion, though, you might have
given us the benefit of the doubt.
But... just
as you please.
As long as you were
out there, why didn't you bring 'em all in?
What for? Leave
them out there.
Let Calvera find them.
He'll take good care of them.
Bring them in.
Show him the way.
Ma'am.
Come on,
little angel!
Gently, boy.
Gently.
I can't tell you how wonderful it was for
you señoritas to fix dinner for us.
How's the food?
Great.
Chicken enchiladas,
carne asada and Spanish rice. Looks good.
These people really know how to
cook. Dig in, there's tons of it.
Do you know what the villagers have
been eating since we got here?
Tortillas
and a few beans, that's all.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Do you have
an older, grateful sister at home?
No, sir.
Many thanks.
You're welcome.
One, two,
three, four.
One, two,...
...three, four.
One, two, three, four.
Squeeze.
Miguel, didn't I tell
you to squeeze? Hm?
Just like when
you're milking a goat, Miguel.
It's that I get excited.
Well,
don't get excited!
Now, this time, squeeze.
Slowly, but squeeze.
All right... squeeze.
Squeeze!
I'll tell you what.
Don't shoot the gun.
You take the gun like this and you use
it like a club. All right?
Right.
Flaco!
Muchas gracias.
Good afternoon.
Howdy.
We've come
to move you into the village.
Move into
the village?! Me?!
Everybody who
lives outside.
Oh, no.
We can't protect
you out here.
Rojas is makin' room
for you in his home.
Rojas?! His conversation
would bore me to death!
Yeah, well, uh...
...maybe somebody
else, huh?
They are all farmers.
Farmers talk of nothing
but fertilizer and women.
I've never shared
their enthusiasm for fertilizer.
As for women...
I became indifferent when I was 83.
I am staying here.
Yeah, well, uh... what are you gonna
do when Calvera comes?
At my age, a little
excitement is welcome.
Don't worry.
Why would he kill me?
Bullets cost money.
All right.
Have it your way.
You worry about yourself.
Are you ready for him?
What if he comes now, eh?
It's like that fella
who fell off a ten-story building.
What about him?
As he was falling, people on each floor
heard him say "So far, so good."
So far, so good!
First of all,
they'll see that ditch.
More water
for the corn.
Awful lot of new walls.
Civic improvements.
Hey, Chris,...
...what about
that net, eh?
Well, if he's not
looking for it...
If he rides in
unsuspecting.
If, brother!
If!
Yeah.
Yeah!
I should have guessed. When my men
didn't come back, I should have guessed.
How many of you
did they hire?
Enough.
New wall!
There are lots
of new walls. All around.
They won't keep me out.
They were built
to keep you in.
Did you hear that?
We're trapped!
All forty of us!
By these three.
Or is it four? They couldn't
afford to hire more than that.
We come cheaper
by the bunch.
Five!
Even five won't give
us too much trouble.
There won't be
any trouble - if you ride on.
Ride on?
I'm going into
the hills for the winter.
Where am I going
to get food for my men?
Buy it or grow it.
Or maybe
even work for it!
Seven!
Somehow, I don't think
you've solved my problem.
Solving your problems
isn't our line.
We deal in lead, friend.
So do I. We're in the
same business, huh?
Only as competitors.
Why not as partners?
Suppose I offer
you equal shares?
In what?
Everything.
To the last grain.
And the people
in the village? What about them?
I leave it to you.
Can men of our profession
worry about things like that?
May even be sacrilegious.
If God didn't want them sheared, he would
not have made them sheep.
What do you say?
Ride on.
You hear that, Sotero?
You hear what he said?
Ride on.
To me!
You tell him to ride on
before I become angry.
Him, and the others!
Because, if I leave
with empty hands,...
...everybody in this village
will answer to me - when I come back!
You won't come back.
Why not?
You won't have any guns.
Take them off right
now and drop them.
Generosity.
That was my first mistake!
I leave these people a little bit extra and
they hire these men to make trouble.
It shows you... sooner or later, you must
answer for every good deed.
You were safe.
I was face to face with them as they rode
toward me. Ten of them, screaming.
The last time
you told it, it was five!
They multiply
like rabbits!
Ten. Ten!
Yeh-hey!
They got a good
kick in the behind.
If they try it again,
they'll get another!
We'll tear them to pieces.
We'll bury them all.
Calvera too, huh?!
Any sign of 'em?
No.
That is bad luck.
Can you imagine?
I knew him when he was a mouse!
I was never so frightened in my
life. My knees were like jelly.
I would never
have guessed it.
Well, he'll leave us
alone from now on.
- You think so?
- Of course.
He'll go away.
There are other villages -
other villages
that don't sting the way we do.
Señor!
Neighbors...
I drink to our friends.
They armed us, fought at our sides, and
will forever live in our hearts.
They haven't gone, then.
See the gun
flashin'?
No.
I make it
two of them.
Three.
Fool kid's
gonna get his head blown off.
Chico! Stay put.
Three?
Three.
O'Reilly?
Do you see them?
No... They're too
far back in the trees.
- Chris.
- Yeah?
Try and make it up
to those rocks. I'll cover you.
Chico...
cover the back door.
Get back!
Go on!
What's the matter?
Don't you hear so good?
Get down.
Now stay down!
Crazy kids!
You might have been hurt.
So might you.
It's not the same thing.
This is my work.
It's our work, too.
Everyone tells us
"Hide! Get back! Stay out of sight!"
But we're not afraid.
He's very brave.
It's the truth.
So is he. We all are -
every boy in the village.
We had a meeting
and we drew straws and we got you.
You got me?
What d'you mean, you got me?
If you get killed,
we avenge you.
And we see to it that
there's always fresh flowers on your grave.
That's a mighty
big comfort!
I told you he would
appreciate that.
Don't you kids be too disappointed if
your plans don't work out.
We won't.
If you stay alive, we'll be just as happy.
Maybe even happier.
Maybe.
Can you see them?
No.
Do your, uh,...
...hands sweat
before a fight?
Every time.
Mine are sweatin' now.
Funny...
Hands sweat,...
...mouth is dry.
You'd think it would be
the other way around.
Does my... talking
annoy you?
Mm-mm.
It's because I'm...
...I'm frightened,
you know?
Yeah. I guess you kinda wish you'd
given your crops to Calvera, huh?
Yes...
...and no.
Both at the same time.
Yes, when I think of,...
...of what he might do.
No, when I remember
the feeling in my chest this morning...
...as I saw him run away.
From us.
Man,...
...that's a feeling
worth dying for!
Have you ever...
felt something like that?
Not for a long, long time.
I, uh,...
...envy you.
What are you doing here?
You shouldn't do
things like you did.
Go back.
You mustn't take
foolish chances.
All right, I won't.
But go back.
Does it hurt?
What?
No.
I'm sorry I did it,
but I thought...
You know what I thought.
Yes, yes. I know.
I wasn't afraid of you.
It's my father.
He says "Stay away
from those men."
"They are brutes.
They are cruel."
He's right. Do you
know that? He's right.
Well... go back
home now.
He is wrong.
Well... go home anyway,...
...before he finds
out you're here.
He already knows.
He said he'd punish me
for being so shameless.
But I don't care.
They got them.
They got them all!
Result.
Do you think
they'll try that again?
I doubt it.
For all they know,
we're still out there ready to jump them.
He didn't go.
Calvera didn't go?
Did you think it
would be that easy?
What do we do now?
Well, what
do you say?
Me?
We work for you,
you know.
What else is there
to do but... wait?
It's Calvera's move.
Right.
Now you'd better
replace the guards. They must be tired.
- If you were Calvera,...
- Yes?
...you'd go away,
wouldn't you?
If you'd paid the price
we make him pay.
Yes, I would, only...
Only what?
Only I'm not Calvera.
Take the rifles
and the bandoleras and pass 'em out.
Now, let's get out
there on duty.
Food, woman.
They'll be hungry.
That was... that
was the greatest...
New hat for you, sonny.
Hey!
How do I look? Huh?
Big improvement.
You know what? They'll make up a
song about you and this hat.
Villages like this make up a song about
every big thing. They sing them for years.
Do you think
it's worth it?
Don't you?
It's only a matter
of knowing how to shoot a gun.
Nothing big about that.
Hey... how can
you talk like this?
Your gun has got you
everything you have. Isn't that true?
Mm?
Well, isn't that true?
Yeah, sure. Everything.
After a while
you can call bartenders by their first name.
Maybe 200 of 'em.
Rented rooms you live in: 500.
Meals you eat in hash houses: 1,000.
Home: none.
Wife: none. Kids:
none.
Prospects: zero.
Suppose I left
anything out?
Yeah.
Places you are
tied down to: none.
People with
a hold on you: none.
Men you step
aside for: none.
Insults swallowed:
none.
Enemies: none.
No enemies?
Alive.
Well! This is the kind
of arithmetic I like!
Yeah, so did I
at your age.
Give these
to someone who knows how to use them.
Yeah.
Why don't you ask
Calvera what he has in mind for tonight?
Yes, do that.
And I'll write a song for you myself.
Andrés,
Lorenzo and Felipe never came back.
That's three.
Armando in the plaza.
That's four.
And Jorge and Memo
in the pass,
where they were caught
by that cursed net.
Damn them!
Five and six.
Emilio going
over the wall.
Seven.
José near
the fountain.
Eight.
Gregorio near
the fountain.
That's nine.
Nine.
Fortuno by
the water ditch.
Rico in the fields,
where they slashed him to pieces!
That's... 10 and 11.
Go on.
Talk.
Talk! Talk!
They're all dead anyway.
Forget about them.
There's still plenty
of us here... to make them pay.
Our friends down below.
Please, no!
It's all right.
You're all right.
You had a dream.
Just a bad dream.
Have no fear.
"Have no fear"?
My very words.
10,000 times a day.
Señor, don't
punish yourself.
A man who has fought so many times...
You must have great courage.
Until the day
you lose your nerve.
You feel it.
And then you wait,...
...for the bullet
in the gun that is faster than yours.
Señor, don't.
And the lies you tell,
to fool yourself.
No enemies:
alive.
I have lost count
of my enemies.
But you're
with friends now.
Yes.
The final,
supreme idiocy:
comin' here to hide.
The deserter...
hidin' out in the middle of a battlefield.
One.
There was a time
when I woulda caught all three.
We know what fear is.
We live with it
all our lives.
Only the dead
are without fear.
Rico!
One minute,
Mother!
Ten minutes to pretend we're asleep, and
then we'll be back on duty.
All right, Bernardo?
Yes, but not you, Juan.
You're too young.
Come on.
Bernardo O'Reilly!
You've been adopted.
Yeah, it's my real name.
Mexican on one side,
Irish on the other, and me in the middle.
Now, watch carefully.
Here we go.
See? All three,
right side up.
Think you can do it?
Of course.
That's very easy.
Would you, uh... care
to make a friendly wager? A little bet?
You know we
have no money.
It doesn't have
to be money.
Whatever you have hidden away, buried
out where Calvera can't find it.
- Like jewels.
- Jewels?!
Yeah. They tell me a lotta precious stones
have been dug out of the mountains.
Opals, emeralds...
sapphires.
Oh, yes. Yes,
that's very true.
There's no denyin' it.
Well, then!
No! When you're finished,
they should all be right side up.
Let me try
it again, eh?
About those precious stones...
Where are they found?
As you say, señor,
in the mountains.
Where
in the mountains?
That I couldn't tell you.
There! I got it!
Never mind that.
Why can't you tell me?
Because I never
have found any precious stones.
Wait. You mean Aztec treasure buried in
the hills, from when the Spaniards came?
That's exactly what I mean. Aztec
treasure. Have you found some?
Would to God we had!
I would not be sitting here.
I'd be living
in a big city, in a palace.
Then tell me this - how come
Calvera keeps hangin' around here?
Calvera... We've seen the end of him. He'll
be gone in the morning.
No, he will not.
He won't go anywhere.
Why do you say that?
Calvera isn't worried
about food for winter.
He's worried about the food his men
haven't eaten for the last three days.
The price of corn
is going up.
They're starving.
How do you know?
Starving and broke.
How do you know?!
Oh...
I've been up there.
Well, we'd better
be ready for them.
Because they
gotta die or win.
Válgame Dios
if they do win.
They won't win.
Are you God,
that you can say for sure?
We're surrounded.
Outnumbered. What are we to do?
Keep on fighting.
Do you want to see us
killed off one by one?
That is not what
you were hired for.
Once you start,
there's no stopping.
You understood that,
and I told him!
I don't care.
Go away. All of you.
Get on your horses and go.
Let Calvera
have the food.
Give him what he wants.
At least we'll be alive.
Quiet!
And listen to me!
No! It is easy
for them to say fight.
They have no sons,
no daughters, no wives.
Go. Now, before
it's too late.
Is that what you want?
Answer me!
Who's for going on and who's for giving
up? I want to know now.
Don't be fools!
You'll turn our village into a graveyard.
Tell them to go.
It's the only thing for them to do.
I'll tell you
what I can do.
I can kill the first man who so much as
whispers a word about giving up.
The very first man,
so help me, I'll blow his head off!
We started this fight...
and we're gonna finish it!
With or without you.
I'm not sayin' we bit off
more than we can chew,...
...but we oughta
talk about what we're gonna do.
We start acting
like we had some good sense.
We figured to raise the ante just enough to
make Calvera play someplace else.
We figured wrong.
We're the only
game in town.
A man can't call 'em all.
I didn't say he could.
All I'm saying is that sometimes you bend
with the breeze... or you break.
D'you wanna go?
There comes a time to get out. The village
will be no worse off than before we came.
You forget one thing.
We took a contract.
It's not the kind
courts enforce.
That's just the kind
you've gotta keep.
A noble thought,
but the way things are right now,...
...I don't know.
The odds are too high.
- Much too high.
- Then we go?
No.
We lower the odds.
Right up
into the hills,...
...past the men
on guard,...
...right into their camp.
I sat there, I smoked a cigarette with
them, we discussed a few things.
We... you know...
All of a sudden,
there was Calvera himself.
Right beside me.
When I brought back the news,...
...you should have seen
the look I got from Britt - and from Chris.
They have seen a thing
or two in their time, and done them too.
They're not men
you can impress easily. Oh, no.
But when they looked at me,
I knew I was one of them at last.
Well,...
...you'd better take
a look at me, too.
Am I the kind of man
who'd live in a place like this? Hm?
Digging my life away
out in the fields?
Me, a farmer -
a peasant?
You know what
I'm saying, huh?
Wherever they go -
Chris, Vin, Britt, the others -
I go with them.
And if you think you,
or anything you do,
could make me change
my mind, forget it.
I want you
to understand that.
I... want you
to understand that...
...this...
...will get you
nothing but this.
We're going
to hit Calvera,...
...maybe drive off
some of his horses.
Then if he attacks,
he'll be on foot.
I'll go with you.
I know every rock.
No, you stay.
You're in charge here.
You can count on me.
I know I can.
They've left
to hit the village.
No.
We'd have heard shots.
They've gone.
Good evening.
You'll be dead.
All of you!
Like that!
If that's what you want.
Do we have a choice?
Of course.
Sit down.
Let's talk.
Things are turned
around now, uh?
You're wondering how.
Your friends,
they don't like you very much anymore.
You force them
to make too many decisions.
With me...
only one decision.
Do what I say.
You should not be surprised.
My good friend Sotero,
he arranged to let me come in.
Understand?
Well, anyway,...
...to business!
I could kill you all.
You agree?
Well... you
don't disagree.
Anyway, I don't
want to kill you.
Why so generous?
Practical. They hear
about it up north.
Maybe some friends
of yours make more trouble for me.
A man who never
wants no trouble.
We have a saying here.
A thief who steals
from a thief is pardoned for 100 years.
All right,
what does that leave?
Only one thing.
I pardon you.
Ride on.
Just like that?
Mm, just like...
I'll make it easy
for you. You want food?
Give them food.
Water?
All right. Water.
Horses?
Saddled and waiting.
Guns?
The guns... the gun belts,
you take off and put here now.
What about
these people?
What happens to these people
will happen whether I kill you first or not.
Just a little
gesture, huh?
To show these people
who the real boss is.
You go, then I give
you the guns back.
I know you won't
use those guns against me.
Only a crazy man
makes the same mistake twice.
I don't understand why a man like you took
the job in the first place. Hm? Why?
I wonder myself.
No, come on.
Come on, tell me why.
A fella I knew in El Paso took all his
clothes off and jumped on a cactus.
I asked him
the same question: why?
And?
He said "It seemed
to be a good idea at the time."
Good!
Right.
Go get your clothes, your
saddlebags. Anything you want, take it.
Your friends
in there owe you at least that much.
Santos,
pick up the carbines. Cirillo, the guns.
You know,
the first time I took a job as a hired gun,...
...a fella told me
"Vin, you can't afford to care."
There's your problem.
One thing I don't need
is somebody telling me my problem.
Like I said before,
that's your problem.
You got involved
in this village and the people in it.
Do you ever
get tired of hearing yourself talk?
The reason I understand
your problem so well...
...is that I walked into
the same trap myself.
Yeah.
The first day
we got here, I started thinking...
...maybe I could put my gun away and
settle down and get a little land,...
...raise some cattle.
The things that these people know about
me wouldn't work against me.
I, uh... just didn't want you to think you
were the only sucker in town.
Can we go
with you, Bernardo?
No.
You like us,
don't you?
I guess so.
You're one of us,
aren't you?
Yeah, I'm one
of us all right.
Take us with you!
Please?!
No!
We're ashamed
to live here. Our fathers are... cowards.
Don't ever say
that again about your fathers.
They are not cowards!
You think I am brave
because I carry a gun.
Your fathers are much
braver because they carry responsibility.
For you, your brothers,
your sisters and your mothers.
This responsibility
is like a big rock that weighs a ton.
It bends and it twists them until finally it
buries them under the ground.
Nobody says
they have to do it.
They do it because
they love you and they want to.
I have never had
this kind of courage.
Running a farm,...
...working like a mule,
with no guarantee what will become of it -
this is bravery.
That's why I never
even started anything like that.
That's why I never will.
You'll do much better
on the other side of the border.
There you can
steal cattle, hold up trains.
All you have to face
is a sheriff, a marshal.
Once I rob
a bank in Texas.
Your government got after me with a
whole army. A whole army!
One little bank.
It's clear, the meaning?
In Texas, only Texans
can rob banks!
Adiós!
I could have told you
they'd sell us out.
Farmers...
Farmers!
No honor,
no loyalty - nothin'.
All they care about is their precious crops
and the miserable dirt they dig in.
I hate 'em.
I hate 'em all.
Sure you hate them.
Because you come
from a village just like that one.
You yourself are a farmer.
Yes.
Yes, I'm one of them.
But who made us
the way we are? Hm?
Men with guns.
Men like Calvera and...
...men like you.
And now me.
So what d'you
expect us to be?
Nobody throws me
my own guns and says run. Nobody.
It took me a long, long time to learn
my elbow from a hot rock.
Right now, I belong back in that border
town, sleepin' on white sheets.
I think I'll ride back
to that village.
You're crazy, all of ya! They won't lift a
finger to help. Think of the odds.
Harry... nobody's
asking you to go back.
Ride on, Harry.
It's all right.
Bet your sweet life,
I will!
Come on, Lee.
They wanna get killed? Let 'em.
Go ahead, Lee.
You don't owe anything to anybody.
Except to myself.
You're crazy!
All of ya!
Come on. Ya!
Hold on, Chris,
I'll get ya outta there!
Chris...
Yes, Harry?
I'd hate
to die a sucker.
We didn't come here just to keep an eye on
a lotta corn and chilli peppers.
There was something else
all the time, wasn't there?
Yes, Harry.
You had it pegged right all along.
I knew it.
What was it?
Gold.
Sacks of it.
Oh... sounds beautiful!
How much?
At least
a half a million.
My cut woulda
been what?
About 70,000.
I'll be damned!
Maybe you won't be.
You came back.
For a place like this.
Why?
A man like you?!
Bernardo!
No. No, get back.
Go on! Get back.
We didn't...
We didn't mean to do it.
We didn't mean
to do it.
You see?
I told you.
You see your fathers?
What's my name?
Bernardo.
Bernardo!
You're damn right.
You could stay,
you know.
They wouldn't be sorry
to have you stay.
They won't be sorry
to see us go, either.
Yes.
The fighting is over.
Your work is done.
For them,
each season has its tasks.
If there were a season for
gratitude, they'd show it more.
We didn't get
anymore than we expected, old man.
Only the farmers have won.
They remain forever.
They are like
the land itself.
You helped
to rid them of Calvera,...
...the way a strong wind
helps rid them of locusts.
You are like the wind,...
...blowing over the land
and passing on.
God be with you.
Adiós.
The old man was right.
Only the farmers won.
We lost.
We always lose.