{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}sub_master-HD
Who can tell me another colour
other than red and black...
What other colour can you see?
Silver
So we have red, black, white, silver...
(Japanese) Idiot!
Get out of the way!
"DAHAI - AMATEUR TAILOR"
Hey!
"XING'ER - HANDYWOMAN"
Why're you here?
Can't you stop making trouble for us?
"ROB THE TRAIN"
You! Get up!
You never take me on big missions
I only wish we had big missions
I am Feng Banxian, magician of the snake box!
"FENG BANXIAN - FORTUNE TELLER"
There's a snake in the box. Trust me?
Just you?
I grabbed it from
outside the train this instant
Wow!
"MA YUAN - HEAD PORTER"
"XIAOHU - PORTER"
"RUI - MAINTENANCE WORKER"
"DAKUI - STATION WORKER"
Turn around
Turn around!
(Japanese) Stop!
Ya! Me! Te?!
Your dad!
You Chinese?
Uh...Hai
Speak Chinese!
Chinese
I'll give you two choices
One, I drop you with this
Two, you drop to the ground
Drop! Not knock!
Drop? Knock?
What are you doing? Let me go!
(Japanese) You bloody idiot!
What are you doing?!
(Japanese) What?
And I've just stepped off
the train to release it!
- See, an empty box! That fast!
- Wow!
That's how fast I am!
Patata latte!
Sit down!
Turn around
Turn around!
Who brought you?
Aaaaah! Snake! Why is it back again?!
That's my trick, just don't worry
Hey, pal
Do me a favor and strip him down!
I didn't know you spoke Japanese, bro!
Today aloha
Today aloha. How's your Chihuahua?
Tea or latte? Tea or latte?
Tea or latte, tea or latte!
Potato latte! Hai!
Today aloha
Potato latte!
That's the head...
The ear...
The eyes...
The tail
These are the wings
That's a flying tiger
- Draw it just like that!
- Alright!
Whoa, that's a big fire
This way
"The evening sun is setting in the west"
"In the west...
Weishan Lake is peaceful and still"
"I will go play my Chinese lute"
"Singing a peaceful and lulling tune"
"The road is leading me all the way back home"
"My home sits on Mount Liang Liang Liang"
(Japanese) Begin!
"YAMAGUCHI - CAPTAIN,
JAPANESE MILITARY POLICE"
(Japanese) Captain! Phone call for you
(Japanese) Hello?
Candied fruit
Yes, sir
"SASAKI - STATION MASTER"
(Japanese) Sir. Please come and look
(Japanese) Get ready to deploy!
(Japanese) Deploy! Time to move out
"SAKAMOTO - TRANSLATOR"
There's a problem
"HUANG YIFENG, DEPUTY STATION MASTER"
Stop nagging! Fine! Fine!
Give me another one!
Yuan! Yuan!
(Japanese) Hey! What are you doing?
"AUNTIE QIN - PANCAKE SELLER"
It's delicious!
Yuan, do you want pancakes?
Yes!
I don't have enough for all of you
Eat them while they're hot
The one on top
Share them amongst yourselves
I saw the Station Master, something's wrong
It's fine. This is delicious!
Get off the train! Now!
(Japanese) Something's not right
(Japanese) Why are you smiling?
- (Japanese) I'm not, sir
- (Japanese) Yes, you are!
Xing'er
"SAN LAIZI - THIEF"
Get lost! Why are you everywhere?
(Japanese) I'm sorry!
You don't have to turn
Why can't you act serious for once!
(Japanese) It's that winged cat again
Who did this?
- I didn't do it!
- (Japanese) Who are you?
What do you do?
I'm just a tailor
(Japanese) Prove it
What's there to prove?!
Wait! Relax!
Tailor
(Japanese) He wasn't the one...
Stay back! Don't get off the train!
Good...morning! Have you...eaten...yet?
(Japanese) He's amazing!
(Japanese) He can hop on
and off trains in a flash!
Yes!
(Japanese) Take him away
Wait!
What did you say?!
You're scaring me!
(Japanese) Who did this to you?
(Japanese) Answer me!
Don't look over
Brother, what now?
It's fine. Just don't run
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
(Japanese) Hey! Don't shoot!
(Japanese) Sorry
(Japanese) Go get the duty logbook
(Japanese) Yes, sir!
Sir! Captain! Commander!
What have we done wrong?
I'm sorry
I'm the foreman here
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
Sir, don't hit him
Don't hit anyone
It hurts!
(Japanese) The duty logbook, sir!
(Japanese) What is his name?
What's your name?
I'm Ma Yuan
(Japanese) He signed in this morning
(Japanese) So did everyone else
We've been here since dawn
That's right, we're all here
You alright?
I'm fine. I'm fine
Brother
Go hide the clothes in a few days
Brother, we have guns that we've no use for
and clothes that we can't wear
So why do we keep them?
For a big fire?
If it wasn't for Brother,
you'd be in the hands of the Japanese
And you? If you'd aimed better
with that crate...
You're one to talk
I said get on the passenger car
Not cargo
So what? Careful!
When can we do something really big?
Talk less!
Brother, you don't even smoke
Why do you always carry that pipe?
No reason
How do I draw the tiger?
I couldn't get it right
What is that?
(Japanese) Where the heck are they?!
The Captain wants to know where they are!
Let...let me ask the deities
Abracadabra!
Please appear before me!
Looks like something big will happen today
(Japanese) He says something big
will happen today
Hahahaha!
(Japanese) Hello?
Something major is going down!
Let's go see what's happening. Dahai!
Go eat your pancakes, brother
- See you at the noodle shop
- Okay
You don't have to see me off. Really!
(Japanese) Lock him up!
I'll let myself out! I'm not going that way!
"RESCUE THE INJURED SOLDIER"
- Hey, Ma Yuan. Visiting Auntie Qin again?
- Talk less!
I'm home, Mom
The pancake smells great!
Dahai, help me out!
- I'm bleeding again
- What's wrong?!
Come sit down!
What's wrong with the donkey?
It kicked me. So I drugged it,
It calms down a little
Such bad luck today!
Daytime, beaten by the Japanese
I was beaten by Japanese too
Were you kicked by a donkey at night?
Well, no...
How unlucky I am!
You are pretty unlucky
Have some pancakes
I thought you were all just messing around
But now you've stirred up such big trouble
It's nothing big, Mom. Right, brother?
I want to join small missions too, Dad!
This isn't right
Dahai, you call me Brother and call her Mom
What if I marry her
Then will you call me Brother, or Dad?
Come on
Xing'er, what about you?
Will you still call me Dad or...
What are you blabbering on about...
- Serious question!
- You always tell people to talk less,
but you talk the most
Maybe, I'll drug you too one day
Just put some in the pancakes.
The more, the better
You think I won't do it?
You should mark the drugged one,
so you don't eat it
You really think I won't do it?
"DAGUO - EIGHTH ROUTE ARMY SOLDIER"
May I hide out here?
Sorry, I'll go elsewhere
(Japanese) Get in there!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
(Japanese) Get him out
(Japanese) Search thoroughly
(Japanese) You again
Why are you here?
Someone went over the wall!
You see, I'm a widow
It would create gossip if he was seen here
So he had to sneak in
Sneak in?
That's right, he snuck in over the wall
You've forgotten? You
You. This morning. Hit me
Blood. Pain
So you're a sneaker
Right, a sneaker
(Japanese) Captain
(Japanese) We've found someone suspicious
No wonder we're always
losing things in the cellar
- You're stealing from me!
- (Japanese) Get him out of here!
I'm only borrowing!
(Japanese) Hicks!
(Japanese) Next house!
He's on fire!
- Get water!
- What do we do?
Are you okay? Say something!
Hurry!
I'm okay! The fire's out!
Everyone else was killed by the Japanese
They all died but he alone survived?
Is he a deserter?
I doubt it
Where have you hidden him?
At Auntie Qin's. They're taking care of him
We'll move him to the cave later
Fan Chuan. Here late
"FAN CHUAN - NOODLE SHOP OWNER"
Where have you been having fun?
- Kid...
- Yes, Boss
Go feed the horse
Sure
- Make sure it eats its fill
- Alright
That's a nice jacket
I hate that.
Try giving attitude to the Japanese!
He really did fight the Japanese
I hear he's a sharpshooter
Whatever. Why did they want
to blow up the bridge?
He didn't tell me
I don't get it
They sacrificed all those men
to blow up our bridge?
The Japanese are there,
so it's their bridge. Get it?
How dare they! That's our home turf!
Take it outside.
Stop screaming about the Japanese here
What'd you mean?
You heard me. All you guys do is talk
That won't accomplish a thing!
How do you know we haven't?
Shoot!
Exactly, today we...
That's all you guys can do
At least we're not cowards like you, Fan Chuan
What'd you say?
Actually Fan Chuan is right. Bill please!
Zhu, let's go
Have you heard?
Fan Chuan was a warlord's bodyguard
Ma Yuan! Get down here
What's up?
Listen, stop causing trouble for me, okay?
Just one more job. We're done
Don't push me.
I don't want to be forced to rat you out
"YUKO - INSPECTOR,
JAPANESE MILITARY POLICE"
(Japanese) Welcome madam
(Japanese) What?
(Japanese) Banzai!
Bonfire?
What're they saying?
It's Japanese!
Long life!
(Japanese) Banzai!
Why're there so many soldiers?
They must be reinforcements for the bridge
I'm feeling much better. Can I leave now?
This injury will take
at least ten more days to heal
Ten days?! If I don't blow
the bridge in four days...
Then what?
You wouldn't understand
Just pretend we've never met.
And let me go okay?
I don't want to fight anymore. I miss home
I miss mom!
Fine! I just can't stand crying
I miss my mom, too
She was also killed by the Japanese
I didn't even get to see her one last time
Alright. Stop crying
I can't stop you. Just leave
How do I leave?
How would he leave?
By train
The train is here!
- Get ready!
- Shoot!
Don't be scared
Lower us!
Thanks. You guys can go
Dahai, you go first
Go ahead
It is going to snow...Let me send you off
It's not easy to be a soldier.
When you get home...
Brother, I was lying
when I said I was going home
I'm actually going back
That bridge, must be blown up
Tell me, why do you have to blow the bridge?
It's for the war effort.
You wouldn't understand
People like you don't do big things, right?
Fine. Your leg injury isn't that bad
Get off the train when it stops
It's stopping
The Japanese are inspecting the train. Run!
I told you to leave! Now we're both stuck!
Don't worry,
there are plenty of places to hide. Hurry!
They're here for me
I'll deal with them
Leave! It's an order!
- One more favor!
- Go ahead!
(Japanese) Search thoroughly!
If I don't make it, find my platoon
Tell them that I failed
And tell them to blow the bridge in three days
Also, I'm not a deserter
Of course not. Where's your platoon?
(Japanese) Search up there!
Hurry. There's no time
Remember what I said
The bridge must be destroyed
What's up? Brother?
Come and see!
Off on another big mission, Brother?
"ERPANG - BLACKSMITH"
Dad, that soldier from the Eighth...
He should be home now, right?
What do we do now?
Yeah. Tell us something
I'm skipping work today
I'm going to your mother's grave
(Japanese) Don't worry
(Japanese) Although we have reinforcements
(Japanese) We should remain cautious
(Japanese) Even the Eighth
couldn't blow up the bridge
(Japanese) So...
(Japanese) Who else can can do it?
You keep saying that I won't do anything big
I'll show them what I can do in a few days
Maybe, I'll finally avenge you
Really
What are you doing?
We're doing whatever you're doing, Brother
- Shoot!
- Dad,
- I know...
- Talk less!
Don't tell me that
you're going to blow up that bridge
You're right. I am going to blow it up
See? I told you so
We're going to do something big!
Let's do it then!
An entire Eighth Route Army couldn't do it
Can people like us do it?
Him? Him? And Me? How can we?!
Did I say that you're doing it with me?
We're a team!
We do everything as one!
- We eat together, we...
- Quiet!
I was going to ask you guys
I can't get to the Eighth
So we have to do this for him
That's great! Let's do it!
Hold on! Know how much explosives do we need?
I know where we can find some
In the armory at Shagou Station
Station Master Huang mumbled
while I was fitting him
He said there's a load of explosive packs
We'll do it tomorrow!
Shoot!
How do we blow a bridge with explosives?
Easy. We just throw them at the bridge
Duang! Duang! It explodes!
Duang?
"GETTING EXPLOSIVES"
Fan Chuan
Here. Noodles up!
I asked for an large bowl with extra meat
Can you afford it?
I got it from the Japanese
Fan Chuan
What's up?
You've fought in the war right?
How'd you detonate a Japanese explosive pack?
- Just throw it
- Throw it!
- Throw it
That will never work
Oh. Then...
Figure it out yourself
Listen. We can't beat the Japanese
I fought for a warlord.
That's pretty awesome, right?
And we still lost
With so few of you,
don't even bother
Count me in, Brother. I'm not a coward
Dahai, I want to join your next big mission
Something's bothering you inside
You can't even hide it
About us...
when are we going to get hitched?
Later. A little longer
Hey, get out of here
Hurry up
He beats me
Here!
Go!
Hey, there's a ladder here
That's mine. I'm sending the ducks to you sir!
(Japanese) Hey, what are you doing?
What do we do?
Go up
How?
Drop two packs
Why do you drop so many?
How are you going to go up if not?
There's one left
Take it
All that work, and you stole one pack?!
You try it then!
If I was there...
- Forget it. You can't even climb up to the roof
- Talk less!
(Japanese) Assembly! Go chase the train
(Japanese) You, over there!
Go check it out
So many Japanese!
Don't worry. We're safe here
Not safe
Are they here for us?
You take the pack. You three to the front
Let's go
I'll go first. You guys follow me
Okay
You. You go first!
What do we do now?!
How would I know?!
The explosive!
(Japanese) Hurry!
Hey, there's flour here!
Shoot!
(Japanese) You idiot!
Okay, we're done
See how many you've left
Be careful!
- Thank you
- You are welcome
Where are you going?
Hey!
How do you use the explosives?
Just light it up
Go, go, go!
Hide, Dakui!
Nice flour. I can make Brother
some buns tonight
Put that down!
Where is he?
That's a really big explosion!
That was close
Soon, we'll be the rulers of this place
What do you mean?
The battle in China is growing
In a few days, we'll, have an unending chain...
of supplies to the front line
(Japanese) Did something unusual happen today?
(Japanese) Did anyone miss work today?
Did anyone miss work?
No cargo truck today,
- so there's not many people...
- (Japanese) Why are You smiling?
(Japanese) I'm sorry
(Japanese) Kameda, you're responsible
for the lost explosives
(Japanese) What the heck is this?
(Japanese) This is the only thing I could find
(Japanese) Let's start
(Japanese) This is going to hurt
(Japanese) Don't be a coward!
(Japanese) My hand!
(Japanese) It hurts!
(Japanese) Imbecile!
We can't blow up the bridge!
Why not?
It's rare we get to do something so big
Don't you want revenge?
Of course I want revenge
But blowing up the bridge isn't revenge
- Yes it is revenge!
- Stop!
First, they know their explosives
have been stolen
They're out for blood, so we must be careful
Second, if they know...
the explosives were for blowing the bridge
It'll make it more difficult. Third...
So what?
We just let Daguo
and the soldiers die in vain?!
In vain?!
What's the third thing?
What?
The third thing!
Forgot
Come here!
What's going on?
Erpang's butcher knife!
Knives, rods, chains. All solid
Come take a look at this!
I'll kick! Go!
Come on!
Go Away!
- It's okay
- Get off me!
They are not local!
Are you okay?
I'll kill you with spice!
Go!
So many Japanese soldiers
Brother, run!
Stop. Don't move!
(Japanese) Keep searching!
- (Japanese) We've found him!
- (Japanese) That's him!
(Japanese) Arrest them
That looks painful. What'll we do?
Can we get through this without any pain?
I wish
Let's give it try
(Japanese) You two look alike
He says you two look quite alike
Alike?!
- (Japanese) What I want to know is...
- Alike? I'm much more handsome
You're more handsome?
I was more handsome than you
when I was your age
Did you see me when I was young?
Of course not
- How is that possible?
- Wasn't that decades ago?
I wiped your butt when you were little!
What do you think?
Look at his nose!
- What's wrong with my nose?
- It's too big!
What's wrong with a big nose?
Your's is too small!
A big nostril collects dirt easily
- Tiny nose can hardly breathe
- Shut up!
(Japanese) What'd they say?
(Japanese) Noses...
(Japanese) Noses?!
Stop rambling!
I don't understand
Get a Chinese, Captain
We don't understand him
We...Don't...Understand...
(Japanese) What are they saying?
They got themselves in trouble
My dad says you're an amazing sharpshooter
Please help him
I'm not a sharpshooter
Look at these!
Do they look like they can shoot?
They do
If I was a sharpshooter, then why am I here?
I'd be doing big things
The Tigers are doing big things!
Well, I have my little business to take care of
Get someone else
Go! Go!
What if they won't talk?
Chinese?
Hi...
Speak Chinese
We have a saying...
A wise man doesn't join a hopeless fight
Exactly! Since you know what I mean...
Talk less!
You don't want to get beaten, right?
- Of course not
- Good to know. So...
Hey, tell them...
That's all I can do to help you
Well...they've revealed everything
(Japanese) They admit that...
they stole the explosives
(Japanese) They admit to
stealing the explosives
(Japanese) Why?
Why
To fry fish! Frying fish with explosives!
(Japanese) They fry fish with explosives
(Japanese) Why?
Why
To make them more crispy and delicious
There's a saying...
every movement needs a pioneer
Different lands have different customs
You'd be lost everywhere
if you didn't go anywhere
(Japanese) Translate!
(Japanese) I'm sorry
(Japanese) I'm so sorry
It's not my fault that you don't get it.
Why hit me?
Shoot!
You keep saying "shoot" all day
but why didn't you do any reconnaissance?
Stop arguing!
Arguing doesn't solve a thing!
I'll ask Auntie Qin for a solution
(Japanese) They're lying.
Let's have some fun with them
(Japanese) What do you mean?
(Japanese) These hicks all have simple minds
(Japanese) They will definitely
attempt a rescue
(Japanese) We have our soldiers everywhere!
(Japanese) They wouldn't dare to
(Japanese) I'll bring a few soldiers with me,
(Japanese) and wipe them all out tomorrow
(Japanese) Don't underestimate them
(Japanese) No one can defeat me
(Japanese) Certainly not hicks
"THE GREAT RESCUE"
Listen up
These two stole from the Imperial Army
In two hours, they'll be taken away by train...
to face judgment at the next station!
These two stole from the Imperial Army...
What're they doing?
In two hours,
They want to see if anyone will rescue us,
I hope our guys won't see us
How do we stop them, Brother?
We can't stop them
Kite!
What happened?
You Tigers...
You aren't going to give up
until you go too far
Excuse me
Wait!
Sir! Captain!
Please let me through.
I'm giving them some food!
(Japanese) What did they say?
(Japanese) They just want to give them food
- (Japanese) Let her through
- (Japanese) Let her through!
It's you. Sneaking around again?
What is this?
Pancakes
How dare you put our flag on them!
What flag? It's just a red dot
That's our national flag!
It's just a red dot. It's auspicious!
The dot on your flag is bigger
(Japanese) What did she say?
(Japanese) She says it's an auspicious pattern
That's scallion
I love your pancakes
(Japanese) What did he say?
(Japanese) He says he wants to eat badly
Please let them have it
Don't eat that. Give it to him!
I made it for him
(Japanese) Tell them to leave
Get out of here!
(Japanese) If your friends
come to rescue you...
If your friends come to rescue you...
(Japanese) They'll all be captured
they'll all be captured
(Japanese) If they don't,
If they don't,
(Japanese) then they're not really your friends
then they're not really your friends
The Captain says that woman treats you well
Auntie Qin is truly a great woman
Talk less!
How much of the drug did you use?
Enough?
It ought to be
I gave him a bigger dose than the donkey!
You're so greedy!
There are two pancakes.
You should give him one
(Japanese) What did he say?
(Japanese) Nothing
(Japanese) Tell him that it's delicious
He really is a bit greedy
Go!
(Japanese) Attention!
(Japanese) You are all excellent marksmen
(Japanese) When the enemy approaches,
(Japanese) fire on my order
(Japanese) Wait for the order
(Japanese) Don't fire until you hear it.
Understand?
(Japanese) Yes, sir!
(Japanese) They're all Japanese
(Japanese) I'm sorry
(Japanese) Load up and stand by!
(Japanese) Yes, sir!
(Japanese) Captain, they're here
How many Japanese inside?
(Japanese) Sir! What do we do?
(Japanese) Captain!
(Japanese) Captain! Captain!
Don't move!
(Japanese) Please give the order to fire! Sir!
(Japanese) Fire!
Dakui!
Talk less!
Thank you all
Good work, Fan Chuan
Are you one of us now?
Shoot!
Your little band doesn't look proper
How are we not proper?
- We have hats like you do!
- Talk less!
I'll consider it
No one knows this place. We'll hide here
I didn't badmouth you.
They were talking that...
the prisoner train was ambushed
I know you have nothing to do with it
I was just blending in with the crowd
I didn't say you're one of them, I swear
Enough. Take this money
What is this?
Auntie Qin will know
Go buy two pancakes, with this money
No, no, no. I can't take your money...
Why're you standing there?!
I'm sorry!
Get out of here!
Thief
(Japanese) Arrest him!
What's the point of hiding these worn clothes?
Fan Chuan. You in or out?
I'm in!
I'm with you all the way
- That's more like it! Do it together!
- Shoot!
But I have one condition
Condition? A businessman!
Fan Chuan, we have no money
Say it!
Don't treat me like an outsider
I didn't mean it like that
You ruthless shrew!
I really don't know anything...so painful
(Japanese) Yuko!
I didn't see anything
Stop! I'll talk! They're at Weishan Lake!
"The evening sun is setting in the west"
"Weishan Lake is peaceful and still"
"I will go..."
Brother, your key is too low
I'm not too low. He was high!
He was too low.
I think Brother is singing it good
You're clearly singing too low
I'm too low?
Or you're too high
I choose the key so I'm right. He sang too low
My key's correct. Peaceful and still
- Brother's correct
- But I set the key
Then you set the wrong key!
Start it again
"The evening..."
See? Too high!
Peaceful and still
Brother! It's the Japanese!
How many bullets do we have left?
I can kill one with each...
Get down!
(Japanese) Give me the gun
You want to fight your way out?
We can't do that now
There's only one way out. Move
They're gone...
(Japanese) Found them?
Hai!
- (Japanese) Where are they?
- Hai!
(Japanese) Where are your guns?
(Japanese) Banzai!
Hurry!
(Japanese) Where are they?!
(Japanese) You idiot!!
Hanzhuang Bridge is a major route
The Japanese need it to send supplies
to the front line
I think that's why the Eighth
wants to blow it up
They want to cut their supplies
Be careful
Fan Chuan. In the, 36 stratagems.
What's this called?
"Taking the fuel"
It doesn't matter now
The Eighth says the bridge must be
destroyed by tomorrow
You haven't told us why you decided to join us
Would you let people call you a coward?
Auntie Qin told me to bring him
Huang gave it to me before he was arrested
What's that traitor up to?
He asked me to buy pancakes from Auntie Qin
I can't see it
What does it say?
A supply train is
crossing Hanzhuang Bridge tomorrow
What does that mean?
Supply train...we have our explosives!
Can we trust that traitor's words?
That traitor sent the Japanese
to the island for us
And now he let us go!
What is he up to?
Means he changes sides whenever it suits him
I've seen people like him
I believe him this time
Either way, this is our only chance
Ask your spirits! Where are they hiding?
There'll be many Japanese
on that train tomorrow
We're outnumbered
We need more men
I'll go!
Me, too!
Not you
Abracadabra...something big is happening soon
Ow, that hurts!
My leg!
Abracadabra...
Great!
I've waited for this too long!
So we'll leave it to you?
Sure. Don't worry
Listen, everyone
If we really are blowing up the bridge
We won't make it back
Do you understand me?
If anyone wants to back out,
say it now
Well?
Yes! Let's do it!
The Tigers aren't cowards!
We'd rather die than be slaves
For our country!
We all have a duty!
Silence! Let Brother speak!
Brother, what'd you say?
Right! Brother
You should say something wise!
Talk less!
Eat up before fighting the Japanese
Make it home alive...
and you can eat pancakes all you want. Okay?
You hear me?
Say, Brother. Why do you carry that
pipe with you?
He used to smoke, but not anymore
He misses the taste
The truth is,
years ago, my father was smoking this...
when the Japanese shot him
Later, my wife was killed by the Japanese,
while loading the tobacco for me
I don't smoke now
But, I'll remember my grudge
Sing a song, Dahai
No way. They keep saying that I'm off-key
You do go off-key...
I don't!
Never mind
What's the plan tomorrow?
Well
Tomorrow when the train leaves Shagou Station
We hop aboard
First, find the explosives
They should be in a closed cargo hold
The Japanese will inspect the train
at Zaozhuang Station
We'll hide, making our move
as the train leaves!
The train mustn't stop under any circumstance
We'll stop the train
in the middle of the bridge
Wrap the explosives around the bridge pillars
When they explode. The bridge will collapse
You understand?
But what will happen to you?
Duang! Into the air. Mission accomplished
Dad!
Why're you here?
I have to be with you all!
Get off the train before we blow the bridge
Fine
Give me that
Blow it!
Let's go
- Go away!
- Sir! I can't move them
I'm sorry, sir!
Cargo holds, front and back
Who's going to check them?
I'll check the back
I'll bet that they're in the front. I'll go
Go to the back,
You're clumsy. I'll check the front
Zhu, you stand guard
I'll take the cab
The rest of you, hide.
Wail till we leave the station
Shoot!
"BLOW UP THE BRIDGE"
(Japanese) Attention!
(Japanese) Sir! Your orders?
Who said the explosives would be here?
(Japanese) Sit down!
(Japanese) Go ahead, sir!
(Japanese) Rock, paper, scissors!
(Japanese) Again! Rock, paper, scissors!
(Japanese) Sit down!
(Japanese) Be seated!
(Japanese) Rock, paper, scissors!
(Japanese) Why are you crying?
(Japanese) I'm so moved,
but bad things happen when I smile
(Japanese) Everything good?
(Japanese) Everything's fine, sir
(Japanese) Are you sure?
(Japanese) Of course.
I'll commit seppuku otherwise
(Japanese) That's gonna hurt
(Japanese) This is no time for jokes!
(Japanese) Open the door
(Japanese) Stand up!
(Japanese) What are you wearing underneath?
(Japanese) Same as you
(Japanese) I'm serious
(Japanese) Close the door
(Japanese) Close the door!
(Japanese) Raise your hands!
(Japanese) What's going on here, sir?
(Japanese) She was being rude
(Japanese) He's a fraud
(Japanese) Fire!
(Japanese) Where's Yuko?
(Japanese) She's still on the train
(Japanese) Give me a smile
(Japanese) Don't move!
(Japanese) Hey!
(Japanese) Give me a smile
(Japanese) There it is!
I told you not to move
Don't move! I'll shoot anyone that moves!
I'll shoot anyone that moves!
(Japanese) Squad, engage!
If you hadn't come,
I'd have shown them my shooting skills!
Go where?
(Japanese) Fire!
Don't push!
Got the explosives?
Zhu. Get on top of the last carriages!
Don't let them attack
- Everyone...
- Watch out!
Everyone what?
I've forgotten
Block the side door, Brother.
Don't let them out
You go help Sanlaizi
Okay
The rest of you, help me with the cannon
I don't know how to fire a cannon!
- I do!
- Where's the ammo?
Over there, under that cloth. Go!
I have bullets in my bag. Get them!
"December moon, what flowers will you bloom!"
"December flowers will bloom..."
You almost hit me!
- Hurry!
- Dad, I'm useful!
Talk less! Hurry!
Come help us, Brother!
I'm busy too!
Where should i put this?
Blow them away!
Place it aside. Don't rush!
What are you doing?
I'm aiming
Lift the cannon
One, two, three! Go!
Wait! What are you doing?
- Push it in
- Good! One, two, three!
This isn't the proper way!
We don't do things the proper way! Push!
Fire!
- What?
- Fire!
(Japanese) Get away!
Pull!
- How?
- Pull it back hard!
(Japanese) What is going on?!
That was a pretty good idea, right?
This is definitely not proper...
- Again!
- Yes!
Fire again. I'll help the others
And me?
Keep covering your ears
Be careful
Explosives there?
A lot!
Set one off!
Sure!
Fire in the hole!
Watch out!
Get away!
(Japanese) That really hurts...
(Japanese) Shoot!
(Japanese) Darn it!
Alright then let's play
(Japanese) It's those hicks!
Guys, leave it to me
Blow him away!
I may have lost to you years ago...
(Japanese) You hicks!
But I'll get you today
Shoot!
Watch out!
That really hurts
Dakui!
Are you hurt?
How many of these do we have to tie up?
The more the better!
I'll pay you back some day
Talk less!
It hurts!
Don't let the train stop, Rui!
Dahai, don't you think that Xing'er likes me?
Where did that come from?
The train can't stop! The train can't stop!
This is easy and boring
Come on!
I'll show you what a proper solder...
can do!
- Shoot!
- Good work!
What's that?
Fan Chuan
Look what we found!
Quick! Give me!
Brother, the boiler is leaking
Dakui
Zhuzi's fallen off the train!
(Japanese) Surrender!
What are they saying?
They're asking us to surrender
I'll shoot the one talking. You take the other
Wait, that's too risky
He's right behind Xing'er
Aren't you a sharpshooter?
No sharpshooter can curve a bullet
Come back, Dahai
I'm coming, Xing'er
- Xing'er
- Stay back!
- Dahai
- Come back here too, Sanlaizi!
Just listen to me and stay over there
A tiger? Are there wings on that?
What'll we do?
I don't have any experience with this
Run, Xing'er!
Just leave them to me!
Everyone back off!
I'm not afraid, Dad!
It's okay
Time to go. You promised
I want to be with you all to the end!
We'll be back soon
Dad!
Xing'er
Come
What are you doing?
Roll
Roll!
Don't let her go!
The boiler's leaking.
We might not make it to the bridge
Get your weapons, boys!
Shoot!
The train is stopping, Brother
We've nowhere to retreat
We'll fight them!
Shoot!
Now!
(Japanese) Retreat
This rifle is no fun
- How about this one?
- Great!
This is awesome!
Dahai!
Someone's joining the party
(Japanese) I'm back, you hicks!
Watch me. I'll blow him away with the tank
What do we do now?
We still have our cannon
Now what?
(Japanese) You want to beat me?
This is bad. We're running out of ammo
Not blown up yet? No way
Rui!
Aren't the explosives over there?
We'll each take one pack
and charge at them, maybe...
It's useless. We won't make it past them
We were so close!
Looks like our big mission is set to fail
I started this mission,
so I'll see this through
You guys still have a chance to flee
Talk less!
You're not the only member of the Tigers
None of us are running
We may not be proper soldiers,
but we do just fine against the Japanese
Tell us. What to do!
Shoot!
I don't think we can take them head on
How does the 36 Strategems go?
How would I know
which one you're talking about?!
We will hide!
(Japanese) You'll never beat me.
Not in a million years!
Switch the tracks!
I'll block the train
Got it!
- What are you doing?
- Your dad said don't let go!
Let me go!
You got a death wish?
(Japanese) Search the train!
I speak Chinese!
I'll say it clearly this time
You have two choices
One, I knock you both out
Two...
Zhuzi!
Who's on the train?
Put your backs into it!
It won't budge!
Dakui?
- Why are we pulling that?
- Talk less!
Move! Hurry
Why won't you go away?!
Can't stop it now
What is he doing?
(Japanese) We've got nothing, sir!
(Japanese) Found them?
(Japanese) No, sir
(Japanese) Search again!
(Japanese) Yes, sir!
(Japanese) Back away! Back away!
(Japanese) Back away!
(Japanese) Don't move!
(Japanese) You hicks!
(Japanese) Back away!
Shoot!
Xiaohu!
Brother
Who's driving that train?
It must be Rui
We're the only ones left!
Keep them back.
I'm going to set off the explosives
Hurry! We can't hold them off for long
Brother!
Talk less!
We can't hold them any longer
Why won't that Japanese die?!
I have you now
Are you going to shoot or what?
Can you do this?
They're too close. I'll hit both of them
(Japanese) Hold your fire!
(Japanese) I'll get him myself
Brother, looks like our mission has failed
I'm sorry I couldn't hold them
We've failed Daguo and the Eighth
(Japanese) We'll start with you
(Japanese) What's going on?!
Charge!
(Japanese) Fire! Kill them all!
(Japanese) Go, all of you!
(Japanese) Kill them all!
(Japanese) All of you, go!
(Japanese) Don't worry about those guys...
(Japanese) I can handle them myself
I'll kill you!
(Japanese) That hurts!
Charge!
(Japanese) You hicks...
Tiger. Come on, time to go
Can this be our secret?
Sure, no problem
Did they all go to heaven?
Actually...
they all joined
the Eighth Route Army afterwards,
and protected our country
What about the injured soldier?
Did he go to heaven?
That's another story. Do you want to hear it?
Yeah!
Okay, I'll tell you
Sorry, my hat fell off
Hit me? You hit me?!
I forgot my lines...Sorry
Running around...And I...I...
I'm Dahai, he's Daguo, and you are?
I'm Daguo
What's your character's name?
I'm Dahai, he's Daguo...
What's your name?
I'm Ma Yun...Ma Yuan
Again. I almost fell off
I almost...
You want me to do it again?
Sorry, sorry...
I don't know how to draw it
It's so cold that I can't speak. Again!
...there are no Howards
Cowards!
You said your mother killed you
You said your mother killed you!
Wait, I sang the wrong song
The evening...I've forgotten
The evening sun...
"The evening sun is setting in the west"
What lake?
Weishan Lake! Again
They're at Weishan Lake!
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}sub_master-HD