Loving You a Thousand Times
Kang Ho. Why are you doing this?
Listen carefully to what I'm saying.
You have to choose one from two options.
Do you want to live with me or see me die?
What do you mean by that?
Hurry and make a decision!
Kang Ho.
Don't be like this.
What's the use?
Right, fine then.
Kang Ho!
Kang Ho, why are you doing this?
Hurry up and come out!
Let go of me.
You go over there!
Why are you being like this?
If you do this, then what am I supposed to do?!
I told you to let go of me!
Do you want to die too?
Fine!
Then let's die together.
Let's just die together.
Does anyone say that they want to
break up because they really want to?
I don't want us to end either!
But we have no choice!
So, let's die together!
Eun Nim!
I'm sorry! I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
What do you want me to do?
What am I supposed to do?!
I'm sorry, I won't do it again.
Kang Ho, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that this is all I can be for you.
No, I'm the one who's sorry.
I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
We...
Should we date?
I love you Eun Nim.
I really love you.
Eun Nim,
what I said yesterday...
was sincere.
If you really love me, don't be like this.
If you're like this, Kang Ho,
it makes things harder for me!
If it's because of me,
I'm really okay so go slowly.
I can't bring myself to do it.
I don't have the heart to make things difficult for you.
So please, let go of me.
So this...
It's the end for us.
Be well,
and don't get sick.
I'll leave now so drive home safely.
Go Eun Nim!
It's cold.
What?
Is Eun Nim not back yet?
Yeah.
It's already almost midnight.
Why isn't she coming home?
Honey, could she have gone on a date
with Son-in-law Baek somewhere nice?
I'm not sure. It would be nice if that were the case...
Eun Nim isn't a child.
You must be cold too so go in and sleep
so you can get up for work tomorrow.
All right, just go in and sleep first.
Eun Nim!
Why? Why are you in this state?
You weren't sleeping yet?
Did you fall in the water or something?
What happened to you?
I'm going to wash up and change my clothes.
Hey, Eun Nim!
What in the world happened to her?
After Eun Nim's washed up,
tell her to come to the room.
Did something happen today?
Were you with Son-in-law Baek today?
Yes.
But then why did you fall in the water?
Did you and son-in-law Baek go play
around in the water or something?
Does she look like she went to play with water?
Please, tell us.
Your eyes are swollen like you cried a lot..
And it seems like something did happen.
That's right.
You said you were with son-in-law Baek,
but why didn't you come in together?
Dad, Mom.
Kang Ho's not going to come here anymore.
What do you mean by that?
What do you mean Son-in-law Baek
won't be coming by anymore?
Kang Ho and I...
We have cleanly ended things between us
and decided to get a divorce,
so I just wanted to let you know.
What?
Wh-what are you talking about?
Even until yesterday Son-in-law Baek said
that he'd never be able to get a divorce..
So did you insist on it then?
Eun Nim, what kind of manners are these?
Continuing to talk about divorce in front of adults...
Divorce isn't something so easily spoken about, but you're
talking about it as readily as you would have a meal!
Throughout life, there are times when men and women
make mistakes and sometimes fall into temptation.
But just because of that, do they all divorce?
Eun Nim, were you always this reckless?
You've severely disappointed your father.
I'm sorry.
Why are you really being like this?
You let that great husband go, and have you decided to
kick away all of your blessings with your own two feet?
Oh dear.
What are you doing?
Are you drinking right now?
I can't fall asleep.
Yes, it'd be weird if you could fall asleep right away.
Give me a glass too.
You want some liquor too, Mother-in-law?
Yes.
If I drink some liquor, I'm hoping
I'll be able to get some sleep.
I couldn't fall asleep, so I came
out to warm up a cup of milk.
Here.
How strong.
How could you drink this when it tastes so bad?
Anyway,
you don't think Kang Ho is going to
sleep at his in-laws' house, right?
Your sister-in-law told us that she was
going to cleanly cut things off and divorce,
but you don't think she's trying to force him
to live with her there, do you?
Do you believe what that woman says, Mother-in-law?
That woman is capable of more than that.
I can't ever believe what that woman says until she
stamps the divorce papers with Brother-in-law.
She says she won't do that in front of us, but see
what happens if she goes back on her word.
What are you doing here?
What... are you two drinking
in the middle of the night and gossiping?
No, of course not. Why would we drink?
Why aren't you sleeping?
Kang Ho hasn't come home yet!
And he's not picking up his phone either.
Why aren't you all sleeping yet?
You weren't sleeping yet either?
Ah yes, I have a meeting early tomorrow morning
so I wanted to go over some of the documents.
Is there something wrong?
Brother-in-law hasn't come in yet and isn't picking up
his phone so Grandmother-in-law has been worrying.
Mother-in-law, he's probably with
his friends drinking or something.
It's because he went out in the morning like that.
I don't know if I pressured him to divorce
Granddaughter-in-law and made things worse.
Maybe I should've just left them
to resolve things on their own.
People always said that if the wrong woman
marries into a household, their bad luck never ends.
I don't know what all of this is.
Grandmother, don't worry too much and get some sleep.
Okay then.
No. Oh dear, I don't know why I'm so anxious.
Hey Daughter-in-law, call Granddaughter-in-law.
What?
At this hour?
Yes, Mother-in-law.
Are you with Kang Ho right now?
No, I'm not.
Is it... Kang Ho hasn't gone home yet?
Yes.
Did you meet him then?
We split up though.
I thought he went straight home.
What did you do when you two met?
The problem of Kang Ho and I has been resolved.
You don't have to worry.
Really? All right then.
What did she say?
The two of them met, right?
Yes. But she said that they already
went their separate ways.
I wonder where he went.
What did she say they talked about?
Did she say something else happened?
They've decided to end it.
End it? Is that true?
Yes.
Oh dear. Oh my, why is my heart racing?
Why am I so anxious?
You don't think something bad is
going to happen, do you?
Mother-in-law, please!
What do you think could happen?
Did Grandmother-in-law go into her room?
Yes.
Even though Grandmother-in-law is upset about it,
it's a good thing that Brother-in-law and
Sister-in-law have decided to divorce.
It's for everyone's sake.
Do you know that you're really
cold and cruel sometimes?
What did you say?
Even though you know how much
Kang Ho and Eun Nim love each other,
how can you speak like you're talking about strangers?
How deep do you think Kang Ho and
Eun Nim's pain is right now?
It seems that you only know one thing instead of two.
Just because it hurts a little right now, what if
they were to leave things the way they were?
With time, things will explode.
Then they'll have to cut things out
and operate, and it'll hurt more.
Why don't you know that?
What?
And just because they're having a hard time since they've
decided to break up, you want to keep living with them?
What's bad about that?
What?
Honey,
why do we have to fight about something like this?
They're adults and they've come to
this decision themselves, isn't that so?
It seems like you don't feel sorry towards
Kang Ho or Eun Nim at all.
What's that supposed to mean?
Who's the one who should be sorry?
Do you know how hard it was
for me because of that woman?
Why did all of this happen?
Where did it start?
What?
I think that the two of us should be feeling
incredibly sorry to the two of them.
Just now, you...
What is it you want to say?
Are you saying this is all my fault?
You of all people should understand
what I'm trying to say.
So you're saying that this all happened
because I couldn't have kids?
This device has been turned off, so please
leave a message after the beep.
He didn't even change out of those wet clothes.
Where did he go?
That's Kang Ho's car.
He wasn't inside though.
Kang Ho!
What's wrong with you, Kang Ho?
How could something like this happen?!
What are we going to do if something
bad happened to Kang Ho?
I can't live if it does!
Mother, don't worry too much
He'll be fine.
What are we going to do?
Did Chauffeur Kim come yet?
Yes.
I'll take Yoo Bin to kindergarten and go right after.
All right.
Oh no, what are we going to do about our Kang Ho?
Ahjumma, please make a simple breakfast for Yoo Bin.
How could all of this happen?
Yes, it's me.
Did Kang Ho go home last night?
He's not picking up his phone.
Something terrible has happened!
Something terrible?
What happened?
What?!
Kang Ho did what?!
But, Doctor.
Why is he like this?
Why isn't he opening his eyes?
It seems like he's dead!
It's a huge relief.
If we'd been any later,
his heart would've stopped beating.
What did you-
Oh my.
Oh no, Grandmother!
Then...how is he now?
Will he be okay?
When he first arrived the hospital, his breathing
was light and his pulse was weak.
He's slowly getting better so I think
you can stop worrying now.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you so much.
Why would he sleep in the car in wet clothes
during this cold winter and create such a ruckus?
Sae Hun, you saved your little brother's life.
If we had found him a little later,
would would've happened?
Sister-in-law!
Why have you come here?
Kang Ho... they've said that Kang Ho collapsed!
Sister-in-law, why would Kang Ho collapse?
What in the world happened?
I thought you said you two have decided to end it.
Then shouldn't you mind your own business?
What?
You're about to become a stranger
to us, so why would you come here?
You could make Brother-in-law think
second thoughts, so go back home.
I've come because they told me that he's collapsed
and not anything else, so how could you be like this?
You!
Does what I'm telling you not seem like words to you?
I said go home!
Let go of me.
If you're that curious, I'll tell you
how he is over the phone.
So go home.
Yoo Bin's mom!
Sister-in-law, you've come?
Yes.
Where's Kang Ho?
Go on in.
It's all the way on the end.
Yes.
You, stop right there!
Why are you doing this?
How can we send that woman to Brother-in-law?
We've just managed to tear them apart!
You stay still.
Let the two of them handle their own problems.
Got it?
The color of his face has gotten a lot better than before.
Yes, he has.
Mother, the doctor said that
he's okay now so please go home.
No! Don't worry about me and go to work, Son.
That's right, we'll stay here so go to work.
Yes! Now all we need to wait for his pulses and body
temperature back to normal, so don't worry and go on.
All right.
If he wakes up, give me a call.
Okay.
Daughter-in-law has come.
Huh? Granddaughter-in-law has come?
Oh no! How did she find out and come?
Why aren't you coming in? Go ahead.
Yes, sir.
Kang Ho, your wife is here.
Huh? So you have to wake up now!
Let's go home, please!
He was on dangerous ground and almost died.
He spent all night in his car in soaking wet clothes..
What did you do to get your clothes all wet?
But why has your hand been in a fist since before?
Unclench it!
Unclench it.
What is this?
Isn't this your wedding ring?
Oh my heart feels like it's going to explode.
You had this clenched in your hand
and wanted to die, you rascal?!
Grandmother.
That's right! He's come back to.
Kang Ho! Your wife has come too.
Kang Ho.
Mother-in-law!
Huh? Oh.
Where's Sae Hun?
He went with Father-in-law to the office.
But how did she know to come here?
I'm not sure.
How are the two of them right now?
Sad, very sad.
And your grandmother-in-law is
next to them making it worse.
If they get back together at this rate,
what do we do then?
Hey, let's go now.
Then what do we do about Kang Ho?
I left him to granddaughter-in-law.
Mother-in-law! They said that
they were going to divorce!
Why would you leave Kang Ho to her?!
It seems like all you want is for them to divorce!
What in the world is your reason for acting like that?
When did I?!
From what I can see, those two cannot divorce.
They can never divorce!
Let's go home now.
Come on.
How can you sleep in your car
when you're wearing wet clothes?
What would I have done if you died that way?
Are you a fool, Kang Ho?
I just...
didn't want to go into the house when you weren't there.
So..
I was just going to sit for a while before I went in.
I get so sad because of you, Kang Ho.
What's wrong, Mother-in-law?
Huh?
It's just I felt like I saw that woman somewhere before.
Maybe not?
I'm such a fool..
All I have to do is disregard my pride one more time,
so why can't I involve myself?
If Yeon Hee were to find out that
I was doing this, I really could die.
This brat.
She won't even pick up my phone calls
and I don't know where she is.
Will she appear if my heart were to explode and I died?
Where did my Chul go?
How can you go out by yourself without waking me up?
I heard that women tend to sleep
more when they're pregnant.
And also, Nan Jung, you over-exerted
yourself too much lately.
You're really tired, aren't you?
Tired? I'm not tired at all!
I'll be right there.
I'm telling you to rest a little more!
I'm saying I want to go because I miss you soooooo much.
Okay then. If that's the reason, come right now.
Okay! I'll be there in a flash.
Hey, what are you doing right now?
Wow, you guys even kiss like that over the phone?
Honey, I'd better get off the phone.
I'm sorry.
Oh my.
What was that look?
Was she feeling sorry for a single old spinster, or what?
Oh, my blood pressure. Oh it's going up again!
Yes, it's me.
Did you.. eat breakfast?
I drank coffee.
What about food?
I don't know!
Why did you call?
Why don't you ever eat?
Eat some food, food!
You need to eat in order to have energy!
My stomach keeps getting fatter
because I only eat and sit!
I'll take responsibility for that stomach,
so don't worry and eat some food.
Okay? Got it?
Oh my!
Unni,
Did you mention me to PD Bong?
I'm.. hanging up now!
Huh?
What about you?
I asked you to properly introduce me and PD Bong.
Uh.. well,
So Weol, I did that before you said anything.
But... I don't think he's right for you.
You're right..
since he works in entertainment, he must have young,
sexy girls following him around.
He probably wouldn't even notice a person like me.
Hey!
When I was begging you to get married,
you just sat back and didn't do anything about it.
Why are you acting like this now
when I have so much on my mind?
I'm sorry, Unni.
I couldn't get married like everyone else
does and I'm just a nuisance to you.
Why don't you sign up with a matchmaking agency?
I'll pay for the enrolling costs.
R-really, Unni?
Your age is 41?
Yes.
You don't have a job.
Instead of saying I don't have one,
I'm actually helping out my sister as a housekeeper.
If I were to calculate my salary,
it'd be 2 million Won.
Right?
Yes!
So you're saying you are looking for man
that is first time marriage with steady job?
Yes!
I'm sorry, but there's no one who would
match you in our registry, Miss Kim So Weol.
W-w-what?
Even if I pay the enrollment costs?
Why don't you try going somewhere else?
Your qualifications don't meet
what we look for in candidates.
I'm sorry to say this, but I think it'd be faster
if you went to a matchmaking instead.
Even though I don't have anything of worth,
I'm still a pure virgin.
But what?
Go to matchmaking?
What did he see me as?
Just because I'm old, I can only get single fathers
or divorcees, that's all that's left for me!
This dirty society that cares so much about age!
Aunt!
Forget those ridiculous things
as you drink a refreshing beer.
Chul, it really is ridiculous, right?
Of course!
Where is it?
Should I go and have a word with them?
Honey, are you really going to go?
Moooommmmm...
Aunt, please stop crying.
Ah Aunt, I'll do whatever I can to find
someone who matches you perfectly.
That kind of person doesn't exist.
So why did you waste money
and go to a place like that?
Did the money rot?
Mom, please, stop.
Mother-in-law..
Instead, think about it carefully.
You never know, there could be someone around you.
People have always said that your future
spouse can be found near you, not far.
Do you really have no one that you like right now?
Aunt, is there?
Tell us!
We'll help you along!
Well that..
There is someone, isn't there?
Who is it?
That..
He's younger than me, and I'm lacking in so many ways..
Oh please! That doesn't matter
in man-woman relationships!
You just give it a shot and if it doesn't
work out then that's that.
It won't cost you any.
Tell us, who is it?
That's right, Aunt! Tell us.
If it's someone we know, we'll help you.
I don't like him a lot, but I am a little interested.
Ah it doesn't matter how much, just tell us, who is it?
PD Bong...
What?
PD Bong?!
You mean the man who's working
with Chung Ja, Director Bong?
Oh my god.
Oh, Mrs. Ahn. Did you clean Kang Ho's room well?
You changed all the sheets as well?
Yes ma'am.
They said that he left the hospital already,
so why isn't he home yet?
Kang Ho!
Are you okay now?
I'm okay, Grandmother.
Great.
Go on up.
Go upstairs and get a lot of rest.
Granddaughter-in-law, you'd better take good care of him!
Yes ma'am.
Seeing them together like that is
finally giving me peace of mind.
Oh, Mrs. Ahn, please give me a warm
cup of ginseng tea too please.
Yes, ma'am.
Don't go anywhere from now on.
Okay?
All right.
I'm not going anywhere,
and I'll stay right next to you, Kang Ho.
She... she's still in Kang Ho's room?
Yes.
What should we do, Mother-in-law?
What if she doesn't leave?
She said with her own mouth that she was going to
divorce him, so do you think that would happen?
She just came because Kang Ho wasn't well.
That's what you and I are thinking.
What if she doesn't leave?
Why do you keep thinking that she's not going
to leave? Does that even make sense?
How could she live in this house?
What are you doing right now?
I'm making some rice porridge for Kang Ho.
There are many people who can make rice porridge here,
so it'd be best if you left now.
Mother-in-law,
I've come in for good.
What?
For good?
With whose permission?
You... we need to talk.
Why is madam acting like that?
Why are you acting like this?
With whose permission would you come back for good?
You said with your own mouth that you were going
to divorce Kang Ho, that it was all over!
What are you doing?!
I...
I've tried to break up with Kang Ho.
But I can't bring myself to go through with it.
Mother-in-law.
Can't you just give Kang Ho and I a chance?
Kang Ho and I will go somewhere far away to live.
Don't worry about Yoo Bin.
I won't get greedy about him at all.
So Mother-in-law, can you just give me this chance?
Is this something that'll work out
even if I give you a chance?
Then I would've given it to you already.
Because that's not so,
because this can't be, I said no already!
Mother-in-law.
Aunt!
Yoo Bin! Let's go eat some snacks.
Yes, Yoo Bin. Go eat a snack.
Take Yoo Bin and get out.
Yoo Bin, let's go eat something good.
Do you want ice cream?
Let's get out.
Yoo Bin is here!
What are you doing in here, Granddaughter-in-law?
Ah, it's just because I thought
Mother-in-law needed something.
There are a lot of people who'll
take care of your mother-in-law,
so go on upstairs and take good care of your husband.
Yes.
Kang Ho, you're so good,
eating all of your rice porridge.
I need to eat a lot and be healthy so I can look after my wife.
Here.
Now take your medicine.
Since you've eaten your rice porridge and
taken your medicine, get some sleep.
Don't think about anything.
All right.
I listened to everything you told me to do,
but you're just leaving like that?
Okay.
You're not going to run away
while I'm sleeping, right?
I won't run away! I told you
I was going to stay by your side.
Then come here.
Kang Ho.
If you're really not going to run away again,
put this ring back on.
He ate all of the rice porridge.
Yes. He ate it all, and he's sleeping now.
It's good you came.
While you were gone, Kang Ho looked so pitiful.
Aunt!
Yoo Bin.
This is a present.
Present?
What could this be?
It's you, Aunt.
The title is A face that I miss.
Wow.. our Yoo Bin drew this so well.
Thank you.
Sister-in-law!
Mom, you're mean!
Yoo Bin! Stop crying!
Come.
Mom, you're mean!
Why is Yoo Bin's mom like that?
Ahjumoni. Please don't tell the adults what happened.
All right.
Yoo Bin, stop crying!
How important is that drawing
for you to cry this much?
Mom, you're mean!
I don't like you!
If you don't like your mom,
then who do you like? Huh?
Yoo Bin, if you don't stop crying,
I'm really going to scold you!
Come here!
Bend over.
I told you to stop crying!
Why, why are you crying?!
Huh?
How important is that drawing for you to cry? Huh?
Sister-in-law, stop it!
What do you think you're doing?
Don't hit Yoo Bin!
Why would you hit a child?
You.. who do you think you are?!
What are you doing in front of a child?
What's going on here? Huh?
Mother-in-law.
So why did you hit Yoo Bin?
What did he do for you to hit him?
Despite all that, who does she think she is to do that?
For as long as that woman is in this house,
she won't be able to let go of Yoo Bin.
What should we do?
I don't know.
She's hiding behind your grandmother-in-law and
father-in-law who don't know anything.
But even so, we can't tell them about it.
No way, of course we can't!
If we did..
Oh, I don't even want to think about it.
Mother-in-law, Sister-in-law, I'm sorry.
Yoo Bin is Sister-in-law's son..
It was wrong of me to do that,
I overstepped my bounds.
Nothing like that will ever happen again.
Oh my..
She scares me now.
She's a frightening girl.
You're really staying by my side and not running away.
Did you sleep well?
Are you okay now?
I'm okay now.
My body feels refreshed too,
maybe because I slept deeply.
Yes?
Kang Ho, you're awake.
Yes, he just woke up.
The color of his face is completely back to normal now!
Because my wife was taking care of me, Grandmother.
Here you go again.
You should come down now.
Your father-in-law and brother-in-law
have come home, so you should say hello.
Yes, ma'am.
Okay.
I'm by your side.
It'll turn out fine.
I hadn't said anything, but during that time,
I was feeling really frustrated.
Come and sit down.
Now the house seems full.
Looking at you two makes me think that during that time,
our family had seemed frozen.
Now it finally seems like a flower has blossomed, Son.
Yes, it does.
We won't have to worry about you two now, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry about making you worry all this time.
I'm not sure what was going on,
but Daughter-in-law, don't leave this house again.
Even if problems arise, you need to
be together here to resolve them.
Yes, Father-in-law.
But... I have something I want to tell you.
What is it?
Go ahead.
This person and I want to go live abroad for a while.
Abroad?
Our subsidiary in America needs help,
do you want to go there?
Yes, that would be great, Hyung.
I'll go there.
But why do you want to go live abroad all of a sudden?
I have a reason for that, Grandmother.
So please don't ask why, and let us go.
Father, please give them permission.
All right, let's do that then.
Did you want to see me?
Yes.
Is it about going to the U.S. branch?
That, and...
It seems like there's something going on
that I don't know about.
Yes.
There was.
But I can't tell you what it was.
Trust me and please understand.
It's not a woman or a man problem, right?
No, it's not that kind of problem.
All right, fine. If it's not that kind of problem, that's fine.
All right, go on out.
Father.
Thank you, and I'm sorry.
What?
You're at your in-laws' house right now?
Yes, Mom.
Kang Ho and I have decided to try again.
So don't worry, Mom.
Is that really true?
Oh, great! You decided well, Eun Nim!
Oh, my Eun Nim, you're so brave.
My daughter is so brave.
What? What is it? She said that
she's back at the in-laws house?
Eun Nim, your grandmother came here
because she was worried.
So talk to her, okay?
Eun Nim!
Grandmother.
Yes, it's me. You decided well, Eun Nim!
Yes.
What?
Oh, all right.
Let's talk again soon then.
Okay.
Now I finally feel assured.
I know, right?
You're here?
Oh yes!
What's going on?
Honey, Eun Nim has gone back to the in-laws house.
Really?
Is that really true?
Yes!
I think she and son-in-law Baek have finally made up.
That's great!
I finally think I can live now.
Oh my.
But now that the kids are trying again, I don't know
if her sister-in-law will try and keep them apart.
What?
What do you mean by that?
What about Eun Nim's sister-in-law?
What?
Oh, it's nothing.
This is great.
Wow, how long has it been?
Coming out with you like this.
Do you like it that much?
Yes, I do.
Then every time I have off, we should go out.
Honey, we're people who've
received a lot of blessings.
Everything's gone well with our kids.
Yes, we are.
Here!
Is it refreshing?
Yes.
Wow, it tastes good.
Oh yes, let's see here.
Thank you for this.
Go on and rest.
Yes ma'am.
I can't live with her.
If she stays in this house,
everything will blow up in our faces.
What should we do now?
Mother-in-law,
now,
there's only that option left.
I feel so refreshed.
Oh my! I completely forgot to buy the meat.
I'll only be a second in buying it the meat that you love.
Okay.
Is anyone here?
Did someone come?
Who's there?
Oh! Why have you come?
The in-laws...
have something they wanted to tell you,
which is why I've come.
To me?
Yes.
Hey!
You're the one who did the surrogacy though.
Sister-in-law was the one who gave birth to Yoo Bin.
You mean, you told the in-laws that?
Were we supposed to let Sister-in-law
and Brother-in-law stay together?
I want to take a bath and water gun fight with you, Aunt!
How lonely were you with that child by yourself?
Eun Nim was given money to give birth to that child.
Is that really true?!
She did it to save you! To save you!
Just give our Eun Nim a chance.
She did it to save her father!
Sister-in-law's boldness has a motive behind it.
I can't do that, Sister-in-law.
Whatever results come out of this,
don't forget it's all your fault, Sister-in-law.