LOVE AND ANARCHY
Or
"This morning at 10:00 in Via dei Fiori,
in the well-known whorehouse..."
Mom, what's an anarchist?
Someone who kills kings and throws bombs,
then ends up on the gallows.
Now shut up.
Socialism's what we need, not anarchy
and people who end up on the gallows.
We need the people
who end up on the gallows too!
As long as the world is for all of us,
brothers and sisters, equal and free,
all of us the same, like nature made us.
I came back to kill Mussolini.
Love, love!
Giovinó's is closed.
This is a first-class joint, you know?
We open at 11:00.
You'll have to wait.
Bring me a lot of roses
And a whole lot more
Choose the thorniest ones
Go clean the rooms.
I'll press them to my heart
Excuse me.
Do you have a hearing problem?
We're closed. We open at 1 1:00.
Don't start getting pushy!
Shit, you're really ugly.
Where in the hell did you come from?
Do you have any money?
You know, it's expensive here.
This is a first-class joint.
Do you know how much a fuck costs?
Seven lire.
You're scared?
What happened?
I'm here!
Odette, where's the clean laundry?
I've been looking for it for over an hour.
What a mess!
They never find anything in here.
Oh, dear Saint Rosalia.
If you're in a hurry to fuck, why don't you
go to Pellegrino's? It's cheap there.
Actually, why don't you give yourself
a nice hand job?
You'll have fun and save money.
Actually, I'm looking for Miss Salomè.
- Shit!
- I'm a relative.
Where is he?
Shit, Zoraide, you idiot!
Why did you wax the stairs?
Everyone is falling down.
Where is he?
There he is, my cousin.
Well, you've grown up, cousin.
You became a hunk, baby.
It's about time you arrived.
Sorry, I can't kiss you
with this stuff on my face. Beauty mask.
Zoraide, isn't he handsome?
How is my aunt? Does she still
have problems with varicose veins?
Come on up.
Let's get comfortable and talk.
Zoraide, can you tell Madam Aïda
I'm busy this morning?
I have a relative visiting.
Come this way. It's faster.
My room is the mirror room,
the best in the house.
It's straight out of the Arabian Nights.
Just imagine that!
Come on. Follow me.
See what a beautiful house this is?
It's the most elegant house in Rome.
- Hey, who's that asshole?
- Shut up. He's a relative.
Carmela, the lieutenant of the house.
- Hello.
- Hello, my ass.
What about this morning at 11:00?
Who's gonna do it?
- Shut up. I'll ask Ivonne.
- Yes, ask Ivonne.
- My cousin has just arrived.
- The cousin, the cousin.
He comes here to get it.
Wait. I need to ask
a favor of a friend.
Ivonne?
No kidding.
She's snoring like a train.
Ivonne!
Would you shut up? Shit!
Oh, I'm sorry, milady,
for my loud voice.
- Sleep is sacred.
- I'm sorry, okay?
Introductions:
Miss Jacqueline, my cousin.
Who cares?
- What do you want?
- Some family business came up.
Can you take care of my morning shift?
My cousin is visiting.
Let me introduce you:
Ms. Ivonne, my cousin.
- Good morning!
- My pleasure.
Your cousin.
Meanwhile, I take it up the ass.
Quit busting my balls.
You owe me.
What's wrong?
Are you in love? Tunin!
Come on in.
Get comfortable.
- Excuse me.
- Come on! Leave him alone!
Look at all this stuff on the bed.
Come on.
Make yourself at home.
I'm sorry I said you're my cousin,
but this way they won't bother us.
Close the door.
Those idiots are always
walking up and down the hall.
So, you're Antonio Soffiantini,
alias Tunin, right?
I'm Salomè.
Pleasure to meet you.
How was the trip? Good?
Good.
Come here. Sit down.
Make yourself at home.
Shit, those idiots
haven't prepared my room yet.
I'm really sorry, but sit down.
Oh, sorry.
There we go.
Now, let's have a cup of coffee.
Okay?
Odette!
Two coffees, room nine, please.
Quickly!
So the news is confirmed.
We're all set.
Wednesday, July 8.
It's certain.
Tomorrow, we're going to the place.
By the way, those windows
I wrote to the comrades about?
They are right over the square,
just in case you prefer a rifle.
No.
I practiced with a handgun.
I don't trust rifles.
Rumba, the longer you touch it,
the longer it gets.
Rumba? Please.
You don't even know what the rumba is.
Leave me alone, whore!
Who do you think you are, huh?
- Excuse me!
- Watch it!
She's so ugly anyway.
Yeah. Who'd take her?
Coffee!
I'm not gonna bring you coffee,
shame of our land, you whore.
Come in.
Come in, Odette.
Finally, the coffee.
My mouth is like a toilet bowl
if I don't drink coffee in the morning.
Have you seen Madam Aïda?
- No.
- Okay, then.
But Donna Carmela has taken charge.
She's downstairs in the hall.
- Do I need to tell her anything?
- Let sleeping dogs lie.
But if she asks, tell her that I have guests
and not to bother me.
What are you looking at?
He's my cousin.
I'm almost his aunt.
Go. Go!
These snoopy ones
always think the worst.
And close the door, stupid!
How much sugar?
- One or two?
- Two, thank you.
So, I think we've said
everything there is to say.
You know, the information
should be accurate
because most of our clients
are very important people.
Military officials.
All the good ones.
Filthy and vain men
who like to talk about ceremonies.
May they all get cancer.
You can't imagine
how filthy those pigs are.
Well, good luck.
For July 8?
To July 8.
Listen.
Do you really come from Paris?
Don't tell me if it's a secret.
The less one knows
about these things, the better.
Well, let's hope we come back alive.
I don't know why I'm doing this,
because you're all crazy.
I can't stand these "respectable" bastards
who create such a shitty world.
And you?
Isn't it the same for you?
You're still so young.
Otherwise, why would you be doing this?
I...
I hate tyrants.
But you...
Tell me the truth, Tunin.
You're not thinking about tyrants, are you?
- What are you looking at?
- Oh, fuck. Come on.
You're staring at my legs.
Those eyes look like
you're starving in front of a rotisserie.
I can't keep watching those eyes.
I'm sorry, but have you
ever been in a brothel?
Never.
When I was serving in Cuneo,
there were girls under the bridge...
but I've never been in a brothel.
Not even in Paris.
I was busy there.
Oh, well.
Why didn't you say something?
You’re just sitting there, so quiet,
looking at me like a hungry kitty.
Come on.
Given our plans, let’s just do it.
I'm actually very happy
to satisfy someone like you.
You never know.
It might even bring me some luck.
Come on. Come here.
Come on.
What are you waiting for?
Don't make a fuss about it!
If I don't like it,
it's the same anyway.
No, it’s just I still have to settle
into a hotel, find my room.
Maybe later,
if it's not too much trouble.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
We'll find some time, right?
But tell me, are you okay?
Thank you very much.
By the way, Pensione Margherita
is right around the corner.
- I got you a room there.
- Thank you, very kind of you.
Via Manziana. It's the first one
on the right after you leave.
If you need anything, don't hesitate.
Thank you.
Thanks for the thought.
Then, Tunin, when you get settled,
you can come back to eat.
Thanks.
I'll be waiting for you. Bye.
- Well, maybe...
- What?
Well...
Maybe I'll settle in later,
unless I'd be an inconvenience?
Sure, I told you.
You need some satisfaction.
Especially here with all these beautiful girls.
This way it's over with,
and you get your head back on track.
Exactly.
Thank you very much.
Come on.
Come here.
Anteo Zamboni.
The attack on Mussolini in Bologna.
- You were there?
- I was with Anteo.
But we weren't involved.
We were there, in Via Rizzoli.
It was around 5:30 p.m.
The procession with Mussolini's car
was passing by.
He was standing up
among all the black shirts.
Then suddenly a gun shot, loud.
I can still hear it.
Then complete confusion.
The shooter, a guy in his thirties,
threw the gun at Anteo's feet like a dirty snake,
and shouted, "It's him. It was him!
Get him! Get the killer!"
Then he disappeared, that coward!
I'll never forget Anteo,
not even if a hundred years go by.
Poor guy.
With that haircut and face.
So young, he looked like a baby.
1 5 years old.
He stared at me, all pale and sweaty.
He couldn't even find the strength
to say, "Help! It's not true!
I didn't shoot anybody! No!"
While those crazy bastards,
bastards in black shirts,
jumped on him like animals,
I was screaming.
They pushed me away.
And that's it.
They beat him so badly
that, back at the police station,
Balbo threw up when he saw him
and some leader from Brescia passed out.
That's how bad he was.
And then they constructed a bunch of bullshit
that served only to show
there are far more cops than citizens here.
And then they completely
pulverized the family, you know.
Why? What did they do?
Mammolo Zamboni, the father,
and the sister Virginia Tabarroni
were ex-anarchists.
You can imagine.
Thirty years in jail.
I can't even find out if they’re still alive.
The mother died in a madhouse last year.
But it's better that way.
And me, I was like a fiancée.
And in the middle of all that shit,
it was like I had leprosy.
So I left.
Oh, shit.
It was hell.
I changed my name, and here I am.
And here I am playing Salomè.
Here, yes, but to prepare everything for you!
To prepare this nice July 8.
You know, I promised myself and Anteo.
I promised those eyes crying for help.
I swore to him, "My love, someone will pay.
That bastard has to die!"
Enough now with these stories.
It's useless to talk about it anyway.
Salomè!
- Oh, Jesus! I'm sorry.
- I can't...
God damn it!
- I'm really sorry. May I?
- No, he's my cousin.
- It's an honor.
- I'm sorry. It's a pleasure.
I'm Tripolina.
Come on. Give him more chicken.
The salad too.
Eat, Tunin, it's good for you.
A big boy like you, used to the country.
You know, I don't like to send
a relative to the restaurant.
Madam Aïda, thank you.
It was kind of you
to invite him over for lunch.
Great! I've been waiting
for three hours!
- I said thank you, Madam.
- You're welcome.
Oh, shit, Madam, this egg is not fresh.
What? You're such a drag.
My eggs come fresh
every day from the country.
Fresh every day?
A little chick is going to hatch
any moment now!
What did she say?
She said that a little chick
is coming out any moment now.
Nice.
You have that little chick right up here.
- In this house, you eat very well.
- Oh, sure!
In Florence, at Madam Saffo's,
Madam Valeria got a chef from Paris
to please her girls.
Madam Valeria?
Who knows what's behind that?
What's the chef's name?
- René, maybe?
- Yes. Do you know him?
Darling, René isn't there for cooking.
He's there for sleeping. Let me tell you.
Forget the kitchen.
He's working in Valeria's bed.
- She's making him earn his money.
- And his food!
In Turin, at 1 3 Via Fratelli Calandra,
there you really eat like a king!
No, no. Young man, this is the house
where you eat the best.
You're the guest.
What do you think?
Actually...
the food seems great,
and there's plenty of it.
- Oh, sure. Like in the army!
- How nice. Funny girl.
How finicky.
All princesses on a pea.
You see how ungrateful they are, boy?
On Sunday, I even send them
to Faraglia for a sorbet.
If you listen to Madam, this is better
than Danieli's restaurant in Venice.
Don't remind me of Danieli's.
That was my realm, you know.
Yeah, when you used
to wash dishes there, baby.
- May you get cancer, fucking bitch!
- You get something, idiot.
You know, Tunin, I'm not like them.
I'm an artist.
You know what they used to call me
at the Salone Margherita?
Ivonne is the Italian Josephine Baker.
Just think of that.
Shut up, bitches!
What do you know about my life?
When I had on my silver dress
and my ostrich feathers,
the royal princes started salivating.
- Oh, no. Don't tell me she's gonna start singing?
- I was a star.
I still have my voice, you know.
Listen to me.
Idiots!
Ever since she got syphilis,
she's gone insane, that girl.
She's stupid.
What do you think, stupid?
You think we can't sing too?
Just listen.
- Bitch!
- Idiot!
Fuck you, you know?
They're really shouting!
They're giving me a migraine.
Ivonne, for crying out loud,
you're giving the baroness a migraine.
Baroness Fornigotti,
the baroness of the broken asses.
Well, well!
Stop it now! Enough!
- What is this? Where are we?
- Well, in a brothel, Madam.
No, baby.
This is not a brothel.
This is a maison.
Understand? Good.
If you don't, take your stuff
and get out of here!
She's right!
Go tell her I don't give a shit, spy!
I'm gonna tell her right now.
Fuck you!
Go ahead and tell her, you fucking bitch!
You eat. Don't pay attention
to these bitches. Eat.
That's where you copied your
Jean-Harlow-of the-Renaissance haircut.
Look.
Stick it up your ass, bitch!
Coffee!
Jesus! Don't get all sentimental listening
to a girl who makes a living with her genitals.
Beautiful. I like it a lot.
Now sing another one.
We still have time. Come on.
- I have to go now.
- But that was so beautiful.
- Don't be difficult. Just sing.
- You take the guitar.
Miss Salomè, you have a phone call.
Come on.
It must be Uncle.
You're such a pig.
Shut up.
We're on the phone.
I don't know, darling.
Sunday is a day of rest, you know.
What?
No, I said rest, stupid!
Listen, stop it.
It's all right, as long as
you promise to be a good boy.
But I have my cousin here with me.
Yes, poor guy. He's from the country,
and he looks like Alice in Wonderland.
I'm not gonna leave him alone
in a whorehouse. I can't!
Well, okay.
I'll ask Tripolina to come along.
Yes, it's all settled then.
Shut up, you filthy thing.
Okay, bye-bye.
Shit! I did it!
Do you know who that was?
That was Spatoletti.
Do you know how lucky we are?
Tomorrow we'll go together.
- But who's this Spatoletti?
- Are you kidding?
He's the one who positions the secret service
around the piazza to protect Mussolini.
I've been after him
for three months, that pig.
That son of a bitch was part
of the first squads, you know?
Listen. Do you think we're blankets?
Leaving us there under the sun?
There'll be so many people
that we won't see shit!
And I'm pissed off
because I wanted to see Mussolini.
Calm down, honey.
Spatoletti is here!
I'll find you a first-class spot.
No, I wanna stay close to you,
or at least one of your secret agents.
You know, if they're secret,
a lady nearby can be useful.
- But will there be other secret agents?
- Yes, 35 of them.
Imagine!
- 35! That's right!
- That's too many!
Security is all my responsibility!
As long as Spatoletti is there,
Italy can sleep tight.
Damn it! They just have to try,
and I'll break them.
Watch out if they touch the Duce!
You drive like a madman!
I'm never riding with you again!
Romoletto, what beautiful girls
I've brought you!
- Hands off!
- Come on, honey. Let's eat.
- Keep your hands off me.
- I'm starving for your ass too.
- Hands off. Come on.
- I'm so hungry, I could eat a cow.
Sit down.
Come on, everyone!
So what's cooking, Romoletto?
- Today, bucatini all'amatriciana...
- Bucatini all'amatriciana.
You've got everything, Romoletto.
Good, good.
Here we go. Quickly.
Who are they? Your daughters?
They're beautiful, nice and firm.
Fortunately, they weren't ready
for use yet in 1 922.
Otherwise...
The whole Tamburini squad, 2,000 of us.
We camped out here for the march on Rome.
- Do you remember, Romoletto?
- Yes, I remember.
Since then, they call me "Five and three-eight".
"Five and three-eight," right.
Who was it?
Chiusini or Govoni?
We were probably hungry,
drunk on bad wine from Castelli.
We weren't gentle.
He was late bringing the chicken.
I remember he said, "You need to be patient."
And zap!
A knife cut off two of his fingers.
You understand.
Patience? Us Fascists?
Romoletto!
We were on the edge.
That was during the revolution, right?
We were making the Italy of Mussolini.
And if Romoletto gave two fingers up,
you have to feel honored.
It's like you have a medal this big!
Sure, I'm honored!
But there's a little political problem.
Ifyou'll forgive
my impertinence, Commander,
when I make the Roman salute,
it looks like I'm making the sign of a cuckold!
I wouldn't want Mussolini to be offended.
Damn, that's funny!
I think they understand.
Romoletto, I —
Salomè, don't sit like that,
because I'm going to jump you.
I will split you open.
You bitch, you do it on purpose
because you like me.
My little puppy, isn't it true
that I make your mouth water?
Everyone knows that
I love macho men like you.
But then, you filthy villain,
who can resist you?
- Romoletto!
- What are you screaming for, damn it?
At once, Commander!
Romoletto, hurry up!
I'll throw you in jail, damn it!
- I'm hurrying!
- Run!
Tunin, listen. I'll keep him in the room
for a couple of hours, okay?
You're going with that asshole now?
Stupid. I'll get him
to explain the ceremony in detail.
In the meantime,
check out the square. All right?
- Blondie, are we going?
- Yes, calm down.
And if it's true that you have a soft spot
for me, this time I want proof.
Yes, baby. Look.
Honey, if you if you really liked me,
you could do it for free occasionally.
I promised myself. When my fiancé left me
pregnant at 1 6, I promised myself.
Not even with the pope.
I'd rather close down business.
The exception confirms the rule.
Come on.
No, Commander! I told you.
Free, not even for his sanctity, Pius XI.
Today's Sunday.
The rate is 1 2 lire. So?
- Why won't you give me the satisfaction?
- Twelve lire or nothing.
- So?
- So, I'll give you the 1 2 lire.
How generous. For 12 lire.
- You could have done it once!
- Sure!
- With a Tuscan big spender like you.
- For love!
- What love? Enough!
- You cynic.
You've been destroying my buttocks
since this morning.
You love me so much.
I can feel it.
I'm gonna do you in the ass right now.
Well, he did it. He finally gave me
a headache with that voice.
- You too?
- Yes, madam.
Madam?
My name is Tripolina.
Like the song.
"Tripoli, beautiful land of love."
I was looking for an eccentric name.
Tripolina came out.
Maybe I've always liked Africa, the palms,
Rudolph Valentino doing The Sheik.
How stupid!
Well, instead you could have
called yourself Curly.
Yes, Curly.
The country is so beautiful,
lots of fresh air, so green.
I like it.
It's very hot today.
It's time to go swimming.
- Do you like the sea?
- I've never seen it.
You've never seen the sea?
I've always lived in the country.
That's why you've got such a clean face.
You're a great dancer.
I get by.
What are you looking at?
Don't look at me like that.
You're making me sad.
I'm sorry, but I wasn't looking at you.
I was thinking.
You were looking at me,
but you didn't see me.
Can't we play something happier?
I don't know.
A fox-trot? A one-step?
Here.
Miss...
If I may, I'll change the record.
Good. You take care of it.
I'll go back to my boyfriend.
Here you are.
- Why did you leave like that?
- Why?
- Are you angry?
- Not me.
- Did I do something?
- What? No.
And so?
I'm sorry, but can't you explain?
What happened to you?
Why did you leave me?
Well, I just went for a walk.
- Why? Are you upset?
- A little.
I'm sorry.
- You didn't get offended, did you?
- Well, yes!
- I'm sorry.
- You'd better be.
Oh, well. It's okay.
You know, there was a guy after me.
Do you know what I told him?
That you were my boyfriend.
Do you mind?
I wish.
What?
Are you kidding?
What a face.
Why are you always so down?
Tell me.
Nothing. It's like that.
- Maybe because it's spring.
- Yeah, spring.
Beautiful cows.
I love the smell of lemons.
Smell.
You smell it too.
Do you like it?
Funny.
This morning, I was thinking
it's too bad you're Salomè's cousin.
Otherwise...
- Otherwise, what?
- Stupid.
We could... do it.
But actually...
I just don't feel like it anymore.
I just can't do it,
and I don't understand why.
Why?
Because if you don't like somebody,
you just don't like them. That's all.
Basically, it's because you don't like me.
No, I do like you.
Too much.
That's why it's better not to.
What do you mean no, damn it? Yes!
May I?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
If you want, I have a little room.
It's my brother-in-law's.
- Look, I —
- We don't, well, allow it,
but for Commander Spatoletti,
if you would like to...
I'm serious.
You're doing me a favor.
I have those two little girls around.
If they came here...
They're two angels.
I wouldn't like...
- You understand.
- I really...
The lady and gentleman understand me, right?
Please, no compliments.
Please, make yourselves at home.
Follow me.
Looks like my parents' home.
Look. Like my mother, always knitting.
She knits here and she knits there.
Then, after all that knitting,
we don't have any socks.
Hey, Curly.
Come on, don't act stupid.
Don't cry.
Oh, Jesus, what's happening to me?
Listen, get undressed.
Let's make love.
Why all this respect for me?
Did you forget who I am?
I'm Tripolina!
What are you waiting for?
Get undressed. Come to bed.
Let's make love, right now,
so I can get rid of this craziness!
What's happening to you?
Calm down, okay?
Come on. Calm down.
What are you waiting for?
At the whorehouse, they wait in line
to make love to Tripolina.
Come on.
Let's make love.
Let's do it, and maybe
you'll give me a present later.
Come here!
Take off your pants, quick.
Stop looking at me with those eyes,
those beautiful eyes.
Get undressed. Let's make love
without problems, without staring.
I'm good. Come on!
Stop it, damn it!
Stop.
Listen...
it doesn't have to be like this.
Everything becomes bad like this.
It could be nice, couldn't it?
Don't hurt me.
Hurt you?
We'll be nice to each other, Curly.
Oh, my God!
Did you see your cousin?
He's been screwing for three hours.
Who could imagine it? That loser.
Shut up, you pig!
Tunin is a country boy.
He's never had this kind of fun.
Let him get it out of his system.
Getting it out of his system is fine,
but is he going to do it 1 2 times?
Who is he? Joe Fuck?
He's a loser!
He's an artichoke without the sauce.
He's probably sleeping.
Cousin!
If you're sleeping, wake up!
And if you 're fucking, put your pants on!
It's time to go! It's late!
Move it!
Get your ass down here!
Put your undies on!
I'm gonna kick his ass.
It's very late.
Zoraide will kill us
for waking her up at this hour.
Look! You snagged my hose.
You'd better buy me new ones!
What the hell are you doing?
You idiot!
- Come here, sugar.
- Let go of me!
Just feel that nice, hard ass.
Salomè, fucking is good for you.
You're a flower.
Are you coming tomorrow?
Come after 11:00, when we're closed.
I'll be waiting.
- We can do it up against the wall.
- Stop it.
- I told you I'm tired!
- Fuck you.
- Did you hear that?
- God fucking damn it.
And you're having the altar boy
defend you, that freckle-face.
You asshole. Don't even joke,
or I'll kick your ass!
- Don't even think of provoking Spatoletti.
- Come here now. What are you doing?
You fucking men.
Let us sleep. Fuck!
Did you see that?
You heard Zoraide? Stop it.
Move it, Tripoli.
You go to bed.
Come on. Don't go.
Stay here with me.
- That's enough!
- What are you doing tomorrow?
Stop it now! Enough!
You've been pinching my ass all day!
- Come back here!
- That's enough, you pig.
Listen, witch!
Where do you think
you're working? In a church?
This is a whorehouse, thank God.
And the ladies are whores.
Hours are hours,
and we're closed, faggot!
Faggot? You bitch!
Call your own son a faggot!
Got it?
Did you hear that?
Me, a faggot?
Well, Zoraide can say whatever she wants.
I've known her for 1 0 years.
I could use a drink.
My turn.
Nice day.
We ate, we drank, we laughed,
we belched, we fucked,
we farted and we fought.
What more do you want?
A perfect Sunday.
You know what we're gonna do now?
We're gonna take a nice walk.
I think it's getting a bit late.
Don't be an asshole.
Don't you feel the fresh breeze?
At this hour, I get that old longing
to run around raising hell like I used to.
Like when our squad used to go out
and funnel castor oil down the anarchists' throats.
Those were the days.
Greetings, Emperor Marcus Aurelius.
From up there, you can see the lights
in Palazzo Venezia, can't you?
That's where he is.
He works for everybody, even for you.
Duce, you're the light.
It's true.
If I was you, Emperor,
I wouldn't be so calm on that horse.
Some day, they might take you down
and put him up there.
What a man.
What a man, God damn it!
Have you ever seen him up close?
No? Then you don't understand shit.
When I see him, I tremble.
He's got a pair ofeyes
that could bring the dead back to life.
If you see them, you'll understand
he could take the whole world if he wants.
Let me tell you something.
A superman like him is only born once in a century.
There aren't many men
who have balls like that.
And the rest?
What are the rest?
Losers, common people.
The masses, the beggars, hungry little men.
Ready to shit themselves
and drop their pants for nothing.
They would even sell their sister
and their ass for a piece of bread.
That's the people.
The people.
Those socialist pigs were fattening
themselves offof the people.
Damn them!
It's because they're so poor, Commander.
You know, courage is for gentlemen.
Me, for example.
I'm from a farming family.
And my mother, the priest
and everybody taught me this:
"Better to kneel down and live
than stay put and die."
There it is.
The morale of the losers.
Well, now we can make them have the balls.
All they need is an iron fist
and some orders.
And ifthey refuse to understand,
beat them, by God!
- Give me the bottle.
- Oh, sure.
But, Commander, that's dangerous,
because you could end up
like the innkeeper.
What kind ofshit are you talking?
In my town, the innkeeper had a dog.
He was always kicking him
in the ass, every day.
But the poor dog always went back
to the innkeeper, good as ever,
licking his hand,
so he would feed him scraps.
He was hungry, you know?
And the innkeeper kept kicking him.
But one day, the dog got angry,
and after the first kick, he started to bite.
And then?
You won't believe it,
but he never let go of the innkeeper
until he saw him dying on the ground
with foam coming out of his mouth.
Well?
What I mean is that maybe one evening
a loser, a crazy loser like me —
He's gonna be pissed off.
You come along
with your iron fist, and zap!
That guy stabs you
in the stomach, for example.
The man hasn't been born
that could stab Spatoletti.
You never know in this world.
Really, I'm serious.
With all these poor people,
you never know what someone could do.
I'm talking about the stabbing.
Maybe one day someone will think of it.
There are so many desperate people.
Desperate people are crazy.
I don't give a shit!
It feels so good here
in the arms of the god Tevere.
You feel likeJupiter, god of Rome.
No place is better than Rome,
and you can see everything from up here.
Weakness, betrayal, scumbags.
How many do you hide?
Rome, the capital.
Seven hills full ofshit and snakes.
We have to do more than just dust the corners.
If he would listen to me,
opportunists, anarchists,
traitors, subversives,
we should have gotten rid of them.
Even today, I'd just need a sign.
Imagine, it's fun for me. It's like a party.
I've killed over 1 00 with these hands,
but now we have to be good.
According to him, we need to be politicians.
You know what?
I'll probably go wake up Salomè,
that beautiful witch.
What a woman.
You know, a Fascist doesn't pay women.
He takes them.
But with Salomè, it's another story.
You pay her, all right.
Because she's got something special.
So much that there's a line
at the brothel for her.
Because she's a real tramp.
I don't know if you can understand,
being her cousin.
But your Tripolina doesn't have anyjuice.
I've been with her.
I know a thing or two about whores,
and poor little Tripolina...
Shit! Enough now!
You've been bragging all evening!
- Enough!
- You idiot!
- Stop busting my balls!
- Get out of here!
- I'll smash your face in!
- You pain in the ass!
Don't even mention their names!
Got it, asshole?
- All this for Tripolina?
- I'm not the loser. Guys like you are!
Oh, boy, the baby's in love.
In love!
Watch it! I can be a tiger!
I'll kickyour ass!
I'll slaughteryou!
I'm gonna have your balls for dinner!
I'll smash your face!
You're crazy!
Look at this loser!
He's in love,
and he takes it out on me.
You're right.
I feel sorry for you.
You're drunk as hell!
It's a good idea to run away, asshole!
If I catch you, I'll throw you in the fountain
and sober you up Spatoletti-style.
Run away! They're whores!
My love, my love
Why are you a whore?
Did you hear that, Caruso?
Are you fucking crazy?
You're still here? Shut up!
- I wanna come in.
- Who is it?
My Lord. This faggot again.
Do you wanna let us sleep?
Tripoli, my ass.
Will you go away?
Do I have to call the police?
You're drunk!
Slam the door in his face,
or he'll throw up on the rugs.
Go, go, go! I'll call the police!
Close the door!
Will you leave already, you ugly bastard?
Think you're smart?
Slam that door!
His foot's in the door!
- Take out your foot, asshole.
- No, ma'am.
- Tripoli!
- Is he Salomè's cousin?
Yes, let me in.
I want in, Madam.
Come in? At this hour?
Are you crazy?
- Go! Get out! Close the door.
- Madam, be nice!
Go away, on two feet!
Actually, just one!
Shit, right on my big toe!
Fuck!
- You hurt me!
- I meant to hurt you.
You old witch!
This isn't the way. Hurting people.
You can walk, so go to bed.
Go to sleep and come back tomorrow
to visit Salomè, maybe at lunchtime.
Ugly baboon.
She broke my foot,
and my shoes were already hurting me.
Shit, my toenail is gonna come off.
Go away, you!
Go, stupid! Go away!
What do you want from me?
What is it you want from me?
What are you trying to do?
Go away.
Bye, kitty. Bye, stupid!
You don't give up, huh?
Go home, kitty.
Why are you following me?
I'm not a pussycat.
And you're young for those things.
You're still here?
Did your cats kick you out like me?
You feel lonely, don't you, kitty?
It's dark, isn't it?
Maybe it's because of all these lights,
but the night is scarier here in the city
than in the country.
It's darker.
Why are you purring?
You're comfortable in my arms.
Listen to me.
Go look for a warm corner.
Because you're better off losing me
than finding me. Got it?
You're lonely. You're so lonely.
Holy Mary, this Rome...
Just look at this Rome.
Shit, what a city, Rome.
Hey, little kitty.
Do you have a home?
I have a hotel.
I'm gonna take you there now.
But listen,
you're making a big mistake,
because, friend, today I'm here,
but tomorrow who knows where I'll be?
Boy, you're a sharpshooter.
Where did you learn, in the army?
No. Another round, please.
My God, you've been shooting all morning.
It clears my head.
For that, you need a girlfriend, not a rifle.
- Right.
- Boy, I'll read your palm.
I'll tell your future. Yes?
No.
No, better not,
but thanks for the thought.
- Nice of you.
- So do you have a girlfriend or not?
- More or less.
- Yeah?
Why aren't you with her
if you need to clear your head?
She's working.
What does she do?
Will you tell me
what your girlfriend does?
Commerce.
Come on, beauties.
We're opening the whorehouse.
- Hello, prostitutes!
- Fuck you!
Professor Flannel!
How rude.
What's with all the long faces this morning?
Everybody's a faggot this morning.
Get them up to the rooms!
Look, professor, let's go to my room.
The first fuck is always the best.
Let's go, guys!
I don't have time to waste.
I don't like you anyway.
What's your name, honey?
So, what are we going to do, sir?
What's this crowd this morning?
The Fascist gathering is going on.
I don't understand why
whenever there's a military ceremony,
everybody winds up in the whorehouse.
Maybe it's the brass band?
See? Looks like it's going
to be a good morning.
There's a crowd, Madam.
Is there a problem?
Introduction maybe?
What are you, gay? Come on.
Why are you all still dressed?
Come on. Go up to the rooms.
God bless you!
Where do you think you are?
In the barracks?
Carmela, don't you recognize me?
What an ass!
It's like a flower today.
Who's gonna deflower me this morning?
Me, beautiful. Thank you.
Bologna's arriving on track 4.
What a blonde.
What a crowd.
Salomè from Bologna is here.
I've got 1 5 minutes free.
Any gourmets want to try a new dish?
Shoot. What a pain.
Whoever wants me, follow me.
Let's go, baby.
Come on, honey.
I'll show you a little piece of heaven.
Let's go, let's go.
This morning is not that good, girls.
Tripoli, land of love.
Tripolina's coming!
Hey, you. Is he deaf?
What a beautiful beard, professor.
Are we going up?
Yes, sweetie.
God damn it.
The flight arrives, and it departs again.
Did you see that? The salon,
and then straight back to the room.
They should give her a medal, like Balbo.
Have you lost your head
looking at all these nude women?
What have you done so far this morning?
- You're a student.
- Be nice.
- You've got no money.
-Just five minutes.
Go away. Get out.
Take them up to the rooms, gentlemen.
What a lovely fresh bunch of girls
we have this morning!
Tunin, what are you doing here?
- Here for breakfast?
- No.
No?
Don't tell me you're a client?
For relatives, I have a special deal.
I'm all yours, okay?
Obviously, after hours.
I've got to go.
Today's a busy day for fucking.
Listen. Go for it. I feel crazy today.
I'll give you a half hour—
Did you want something?
As I was saying, go for it.
I'm in a bad mood today.
I'm gonna show you
my whole repertoire, like in a movie.
What do you want?
Leave me alone!
Wanna try some Bolognese pasta?
Try me out, honey!
You want to 69, handsome?
Come here, handsome.
Admiral...
Sailor...
Faggot.
Hey, look who's here.
The cousin.
Are you looking for Salomè?
She's fixing herself up.
She picked a fat turkey,
the honorable Pezzotto's son.
She got him in her room.
She screwed him for a half hour.
She can smell a rich one a mile away.
Now where's that ship captain?
Oh, ship captain!
Bye, Fefé.
Come again.
I'll treat you nice.
It's hot! I'm dying.
Worse than in Catania.
Have you been to Catania?
Yes or no?
What's wrong?
Bye-bye, and come back to visit me, professor.
Hey! Tripolina's here.
Hey, it was my turn.
Where are you going, son of a bitch?
Here, damn it. I'm paying.
I've got the same rights as anyone else.
Seven lire, shit.
Quick. This is rush hour.
We're crowded today.
Let's move it.
No. Tunin, no.
That's private.
Tunin!
Well, what's this?
I'm sorry.
Look. Leave me alone, okay?
- What did you do?
- What? Leave you alone?
Tunin, wait.
Listen, Tunin.
- The cousin with Tripolina?
- Tunin, open up. You're pissing me off!
That's funny.
He wants a good fuck, does he?
Hey, Salomè, are you jealous?
Stop being a pain in the ass,
or I'll rip your heart out.
Why are you behaving like this?
What's wrong?
I can't watch you do this.
Can't you just be with me
for a couple of days?
What are you saying?
Only two days.
Will you just be with me for two days?
Two days, and then?
Then I have to go away.
Don't ask, damn it!
Are you gonna spend two days
with me, just with me?
Listen.
I've lost my mind for you,
and I'll do anything you want,
but tell me the truth.
There's nothing to say.
Nothing!
Sure!
Do you think I'm stupid?
You're hiding something.
I've known it since I met you.
Sometimes, you're like a crazy man.
- Tell me the truth.
- Stop it.
I can't tell you anything.
Just tell me if you'll be
only with me for two days.
You don't trust me?
I love you.
It's not that I don't trust you.
It's just that the less you know, the better.
Oh, well.
It's the same anyway.
Look here.
Do you see this bullet?
This "B" and this "M"?
Pay attention, Tripolina.
Look at it.
I'm here to put this bullet
in Benito Mussolini's head.
My God!
You're an anarchist?
Now, my love,
my life is in your hands.
Come on.
- Where are you going?
- Let go of me.
Wait. Wait a moment.
If you wanna get killed by the Fascists,
then leave now. Just go.
I'm going back down to work,
to have them abuse me,
so I don't think about it anymore.
It was too beautiful.
Get out.
Leave me alone.
This is the worst.
No. No, it's not the worst.
I said the same thing to myself.
But, Tripoli, listen.
Many people will never have two days of love.
- Don't throw it away like this.
- Me?
You're the one that wants to.
Why? For politics?
What the hell do we care? Why?
Why?
Well, because sometimes
someone has to say, "Enough!"
You feel you have to do it.
Anyway, I have to do this,
and I'll do it.
Understand?
No.
I only understand that
when someone is born unfortunate,
she remains so.
Calm down, baby.
Calm down, Curly.
What?
Two days' leave in the middle of all this?
Tripolina, you're not a teenager in love.
Do you know that?
Then I'm sorry, Madam.
I'll take my two days and go.
You're going?
No problem.
But, watch it. If you screw me over
like this, I'll ruin you.
You can count on it.
You're off the A-list.
So says Madam Aïda.
And for what?
For that loser farmer with the freckle-face?
Come on, stupid.
You don't know men.
They come, fuck and go away.
Come on!
And remember, you're under contract.
Do the math. These whims of yours
are costing you a lot of money.
I've never gotten anything for free
in my whole life.
I've seen many end up on the sidewalk for love.
It doesn't matter.
Stupid idiot. Loser.
You'll believe anything.
Still believe in Santa Claus, eh?
Isn't it enough at your age
to be a prostitute in this whorehouse?
Madam, the Commendatore isn't feeling well.
I was working, and I started caressing him.
He's white as a sheet.
He's shaking.
Pull! Put him on the bed.
Grab hold of him.
Get him up there.
- Shit! He's heavy, poor guy.
- Careful!
He's chubby, isn't he?
Damn, he's heavy.
Careful, careful.
Shit! Put him on the bed, Maurizia.
- Pull him up!
- Right away.
Call Zoraide.
Not a word to anyone!
Giuliana!
- Who's this Giuliana?
- I dunno.
Who's she? His wife.
She died not long ago, poor soul.
Otherwise, I'll throw all of you out. Got it?
I'll take care of it, Madam.
Go get some water.
Shit!
The papers.
And, honey, continue with the vinegar massage.
- But, it's disgusting.
- Disgusting?
If you'd do your job well,
this wouldn't happen.
Poor guy.
He's an old guy who's sick.
Is this everything?
Nothing else in his pockets? Are you sure?
Poor guy. Is it true
that he lost his wife a year ago?
Yes, she died last year.
Shit! A good client.
He always came here
just to spend time with us girls.
He said that the smell of youth
made him feel young again.
He's frozen.
He's dying.
We've got to get him out of here.
Can't we ask one of these big shots for help?
The police commissioner's nephew,
the general.
They're all good clients.
Yes, sure. You find one
that's willing to expose himself for us.
Come on, Nina! Wake up.
We've got to get rid of him.
He can die anywhere but here.
I don't want dead people around. Go!
- Sure. Like it's easy, right?
- Easy or not, we've got to do it. Period.
I'm here, Madam.
Did you want me?
Zoρaide, come here.
Madam Aïda needs to have a word with you.
Oh, shit. Is he dead?
Listen, Zoraide, does your brother
still have his carriage around here?
Sure, he has it right down in the alley.
- Do you need it?
- Bring it here right away.
Look how sweaty he is. Damn it!
He looks better,
but it's safer to take him home.
Well, I don't know Rome that well.
Where am I supposed to take that guy?
Right around the corner, near the Forum.
Nobody's around at this hour
in this heat, not even the cats.
It won't make a difference for him, poor guy.
For me, on the other hand —
You can imagine, right?
You're helping me out of a bad jam.
Then, Ninni, if you do me this favor,
I'll give you Tripolina.
Tripolina is a gold mine for us,
right, Carmela?
You can have her until the day after tomorrow,
meals, lodging and laundry included,
everything free and loving.
And look, I wouldn't do this
even for Benito Mussolini.
Listen, you!
I knew he was crazy, but you?
What is this? While I'm working,
you're busy framing my cousin?
Carmela! I ordered maximum discretion.
No, who talked?
I didn't say a word!
Sure, everybody's talking downstairs.
Anyway, Tunin can't do these things!
I didn't know you were his governess.
Anyway, he's an adult.
Besides, if he does me a favor,
I'll do him one.
Sure!
Bringing him oranges in jail.
There is no need to talk.
My cousin won't do it.
It's dangerous. Got it, Tunin?
Come on.
With this heat, the lady says
only the cats are around now.
- She said that?
- Isn't it true?
So?
Sure, and if a cop catches you
carrying a dead man, what will you say?
I said you're not going to do it.
It's dangerous!
That's enough!
There's no need for a big scene.
I said I'm going,
and that's the end of it.
- Let's go.
- Wait, Tunin.
Come on. Let's go.
- Don't be a pain!
- If he goes, I go.
Are you crazy?
Carmela's going.
What do I tell the guys who want Salomè?
Tell them that Salomè's
fallopian tubes shut down.
- Hurry.
- This way.
- I'll do it.
- Take this.
- Come on. Jump up.
- Let's go.
- Well, come on. Move!
Stay here and whistle if someone comes.
No, I'm coming with you.
He's heavy.
Poor Carmela has varicose veins.
I prefer to wait here.
I don't feel well.
- Pull him up.
- Be careful.
Let's go.
Hurry.
Come on.
Let's take him behind the column.
It's more private.
Let's hurry, damn it!
Listen to me.
Stop giving me that look.
If you're angry at me,
it's better if you just tell me.
Listen. A joke is a joke,
and I like to joke. Life is a bitch.
If you don't laugh at it,
better to shoot yourself, and that's it.
But for someone like you,
with what you have to do, it's different.
- I know how I'm supposed to behave!
- No, you don't!
Because I imagined you like a saint,
someone without room for anything except
those who suffered and died for the cause.
Why? Don't I suffer?
I don't want to die doing this stuff.
Right. Doing this stuff...
- But you fell in love!
- Go to hell!
So take your Tripolina, go to France
and stop thinking about —
- Oh, my Lord!
- Giuliana, forgive me.
Commendatore, calm down.
Don't get excited, Commendatore.
There. Put him there.
Come on, Commendatore.
It's nothing.
It's the hot weather.
Come on, Commendatore.
It's nothing.
You feel better now, right?
He's dead.
Let's go.
Come on.
Hurry!
- How did it go?
- Good. Nice.
- I had a nice sight-seeing tour.
- I was so scared.
I'm sorry, but I've got to talk to Salomè.
- Wait here.
- But... wait. Tunin!
What are you doing here?
Go make love to your Tripolina.
After a couple ofdays of gymnastics,
you'll see what a nice steady hand you have.
You won't be able
to even pick up your gun. Go!
I don't want to talk to you.
Listen, I'll probably die in two days.
I need to stay here.
What's the matter with you?
What the hell is going on?
I can't stay alone in that hotel
anymore, thinking about it.
Look how shaky my hand is.
I'm always thinking about it,
about that moment when I'll have to shoot.
And shit, I feel like I'm dying.
I feel a pain right here.
I'm scared shitless.
That's why I wanted
to take that poor guy there.
- To see if I could win it over.
- You won, right?
And now you're not going
to be upset, are you?
Fear is normal.
The Fascists are not scared
and kill people, but you...
You're an anarchist.
Yes, anarchist.
Drop it, okay?
I'm not Michael Sgaravento.
I'm Antonio Soffiantini, and that's it.
What does that mean?
You're a comrade.
Yes, well...
I'vejust recently become involved in this.
I joined after I saw the police
shoot Michael Sgaravento in the back.
Nothing before.
Antonio Soffiantini
was just a simple farmer. That's it.
One of the flock.
But he...
I mean, I...
Shit, Michael was different!
I'm a joke.
While he, even in that bush,
dead, with his mouth full of mud,
he looked like a king.
What the fuck?
What kind of bullshit assassin
did the comrades send me?
Explain yourself!
Who are you, exactly?
Are you one of the Brighenti group or a loner?
I'm nobody.
I was a friend.
Michael was like a brother to me.
When he came back,
he confided only in me.
"I came back to kill Mussolini."
That's exactly what he told me.
He told me everything.
He left me the suitcase.
He trusted only me.
He told me, "If something happens to me,
take this to the comrades."
As if he knew.
So why are you involved then?
I'm involved because,
when I saw him killed like that,
I sold the cow, I took the suitcase,
I went to see Brighenti in Paris,
and I told him that I would
come here to kill Mussolini.
They taught me how to shoot...
and here I am.
Listen.
Have you given it some thought?
Michael was a dedicated anarchist.
He dedicated his life to it.
But you, I mean...
Maybe at the time you thought
of revenge, but now...
If you don't feel up to it,
you shouldn't do it.
Something like this is a desperate act.
There's no way out.
Why? Do you think I'll end up like Anteo?
Forget Anteo.
If they arrest you, it's the firing squad.
Or worse, the Saint Anthony.
Saint Anthony?
They'll beat you to death,
and no one will know a thing.
What do you want to do?
Scare me?
You're wasting your time,
because I'm already so scared
that you can't even imagine.
But I have to do this.
Even if I'm not an anarchist now,
maybe they'll make me one later.
Look, I promised myself
I wouldn't go back to that slave life.
Day after day, only to die like a dog.
I can't do it anymore.
A farm rat lives better than us.
I promised myself
to never again crawl around in shit.
This action is what I need
to feel like a man.
Maybe now you don't trust me.
No, it's not about trust.
It's this war we're fighting.
You don't even know why you're doing it.
You're the one to be sacrificed,
and you're not involved at all.
Once I've killed Mussolini,
I'll be involved, right?
Yes.
Enough now.
It'll be okay.
Go to that girl now.
She's waiting behind the door for you,
dying with anxiety.
When she looks at you,
you can see little stars falling from her eyes.
Poor Tripoli.
Life has already been so bad to her.
Go now.
Good morning.
This is really funny.
I knew the cousin lost it for you.
Did you know the other night this jerk
almost smashed a bottle on my head?
I didn't break him
because I felt bad for him.
He was drunk as hell.
Well, well, Tripolina, who knows?
Maybe you found the jerk
who's going to marry you.
Best wishes for male children.
Pardon.
These, Tunin, are our passports.
The comrades delivered them.
It's better to cross the border legally
as emigrants than illegally.
Because if everything goes well
and Mussolini dies,
you know how many problems we'll have
with those jerks at the border.
Right.
If everything goes well, then we'll see.
I'll wake you up at 6:00.
Everything will be okay. You'll see.
Put this stuff away now.
Don't make this kitty wait for you.
Isn't love beautiful?
But it sure is headed
in one hell of a direction.
I'm sorry, honey,
but I've got to sleep, at least a little.
Love.
My love.
Hey, girl.
You're always crying, you know?
Listen.
Come here.
Don't do this.
You're making it worse.
So, Curly.
Tell me.
Damn, it was beautiful, wasn't it?
The two of us alone,
like a honeymoon.
Two days only for us.
They flew by.
And now?
Now we've got to sleep, and that's all.
And she's crying again.
Listen, Curly.
Listen to me.
I want to tell you something.
You're the best thing...
that's happened in my life.
What are you doing up?
Is he up already?
We must wake him.
- No, you will not wake him up.
- Are you crazy?
- Come. I need to talk to you.
- Don't be stupid! It's late already.
If you wake him up,
I'm going to report you and him.
Let's go.
Let's talk in the bathroom.
Okay.
- And now?
- Now, you will not wake him.
He's sound asleep,
and when he wakes, it must be too late.
Listen, little girl. Get out of the way.
You were never involved to begin with.
This is not a teenage romance.
Give me the key.
No!
I know it's the cause and all the rest.
But you're not waking him up!
Because no cause is worth
a poor, young guy having to die like a dog.
- Because you know he'll die like a dog.
- Of course he'll die like a dog.
Like all the others even younger than him,
more innocent than him.
I saw them with my own two eyes.
He knows it too, but he doesn't care,
because he'd rather die like a dog
than live like a dog.
But only after he does what he has to do.
Yes, you die for these things!
All of us are ready to die for this dream!
Get out of the way!
You cannot understand.
- And give me the key!
- Damn you!
Give me the key!
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
Watch it! I'll smash your—
You're not going to wake him!
I'll kill you!
You're completely insane!
Yes, I'll kill you!
And then I'll kill myself.
I don't give a shit about living anymore.
You've got a black heart.
You don't care about that poor creature.
He's got that nice cause.
Sure, it's the cause.
Maybe one day it'll happen,
and what if it doesn't?
But he's got to die this morning.
If you wake him up,
you're killing him!
- With those dirty hands!
- Shut up, you idiot! Don't scream.
Do you think you're doing him a favor?
It's his decision.
- When he wakes up, he'll hate you.
- I know.
He won't see me anymore.
He'll leave full of hatred but alive.
- That's enough for me.
- Not for me. I can't.
That pig has to die.
I made a promise to a dead boy
that trusted me.
The comrades trust me.
He trusts me.
I can't listen to you.
I don't want to!
You must listen.
Because you have another reason.
- You're jealous.
- Up yours!
- You idiot!
I beg you to help me save him.
- I know you care about him.
- Of course!
Of course I care about that boy.
Poor guy.
He just fell into this political mess
like a fly into a glass.
It's even worse than Anteo.
He's so young that my heart breaks.
I would go if I knew how to shoot.
Too late!
I can't afford these fucking feelings.
Feelings are a luxury, and this is war!
What would happen if all women stopped
their soldiers at the door during war?
You die in war.
It would be great if every mother did that.
Why not? Why?
For history?
For justice?
They've been fighting
since the creation of the world.
Explain it to me, all this justice.
The dead stay dead, and that's it.
Damn you, and damn me.
Fucking sentimental whores that we are.
Open up the door.
I can't stand this bullshit any longer.
I disgust myself. Go away.
They're right.
Never trust a whore.
Why didn't you wake me?
Fucking traitor!
It's 1 0:00! I'm ruined!
Why didn't you wake me up?
And you,
you fucking treacherous whore,
why didn't you call me? Why?
Because right now you'd be dead,
with a bullet in your chest.
I'm worse than dead now.
Like a worm sleeping in a whore's bed.
That's what you are to me, whores!
What am I going to do now?
I'll kill myself. I'll do it.
Where's my gun?
Where did I put it?
- Where is it?
- Wait, Tunin. Stop!
I'm going to put that bullet
in my forehead anyway.
- Stop it!
- Fucking whores.
Get away from me, whore!
Go away!
Stop crying!
We've got to stop him.
I'm gonna shoot myself in the head!
Let go of me!
Give me that pistol!
Shut up.
Please shut up.
You're gonna ruin everything. Shut up!
Coming. Stop it.
What the hell do you want?
Salomè!
Can't we even have
a private family argument, damn it?
Fucking whores. Everybody behind the door
shrieking like a bunch of hens.
Mind your own business! Got it?
That has nothing to do with it. You know
I don't allow people to make a scene in here.
- What do I care?
- It sounded like you were killing each other.
You, shut up!
Look who's talking.
The other day, this one and the Spanish girl
screamed like hell over a pair of underwear.
Get a life!
What's wrong?
Oh, shit.
They're coming for me.
- Calm down.
- They're going to arrest me, arrest me.
Stay calm.
What am I going to do now?
They're here for me.
You betrayed me.
Stop with this bullshit.
Nobody betrayed you. You know it.
- Calm down.
- I can't end up like this.
They're coming.
I knew it. They betrayed me.
What the hell have you done to me?
- Love!
- Fuck! I feel sick.
I'm scared shitless.
Listen. Nobody here betrayed you.
You know it.
We did it only to save you and for love.
I love you two also.
Don't leave me.
Don't abandon me.
Enough!
For Christ's sake, Tunin!
I'm going down to delay them.
You and Tripolina can escape out the back.
She's got some money,
and you can take mine too.
It's in the bottom drawer.
The gun's there.
You'll make it. You'll see.
Go back to Paris, to Saverio Brighenti.
Listen to me! Saverio Brighenti!
Mother, please don't leave me.
My mother!
Tunin, enough!
Don't waste time!
And don't be upset with yourself.
Not everyone has to be a hero, damn it!
Come on, Tunin. Here's the money,
the passports and the gun.
Oh, dear God!
What are you doing?
Come on, honey. I'll help you.
Why are you acting like this?
Don't worry.
Everything will be okay.
We're going to make it.
- No, baby.
- I love you. Calm down.
I'm going to calm down now, you'll see.
You'll see how calm I'm going to be.
No!
What are you doing?
Let's go! Let's run away.
No, I'm not running away anymore.
Go away!
- Tunin!
- It's over.
It's all over.
I won't run away!
The medical checkup
is on Thursday, my dear Marshal.
In any case, the girls are in order.
They're up in their rooms.
You're at home here. If you want to come in,
you know the way, right?
Yes, ma'am. I know the way.
-Jesus!
- Who's that?
I wanted to kill Mussolini!
Stop!
What are you doing, Tunin?
Run, Tunin!
Tunin!
Run away, Tunin!
Long live anarchy!
No, Jesus, no!
Tunin, run!
Tunin, shut up!
Don't say anything! There's no use!
Stop it!
Stop that car!
Not like this.
Not like Anteo!
I wanted to kill Mussolini
for all of you comrades,
equal and free like nature created us.
- Stop him! He's an anarchist!
- I wanted to kill Mussolini!
Not like Anteo!
Just like Anteo! Not you too!
Shut those whores up!
My love!
Tunin, my love! Tunin!
Help!
Stop! Do something.
He was doing it for you, you bastards.
He did it for you!
You're all slaves,
and you don't even know it!
Bourgeois sheep!
He was a poor guy with a big heart.
He was better than all of you, you bastards!
Enough. That's enough.
Excuse me, Captain.
Pull him up properly in the chair, like that.
Here, honey. Have a cigarette.
So, Professor Soffiantini,
your jail is going to be
30 feet under the sea.
Air comes in through a little pipe.
Little air and no light.
Complete darkness.
They lock you up, and you stay there
in the silence. Nobody says a word to you.
Sooner or later, you go crazy.
Passannante was found eating his own shit.
He had turned green, flabby and bald.
He looked like a worm.
But give me a few names and addresses,
and I'll consider the mental illness excuse.
I give you my word.
Maybe 1 0 years, and you're free.
Who sent you?
Are you part of Brighenti's gang?
Tell me.
Are you with Brighenti's gang?
Are you from Paris?
From America? Who sent you?
You don't think I'd believe you came
to Rome alone to kill Benito Mussolini?
- Who sent you?
- Love live anarchy.
What'd you say?
I don't know anything about anybody.
Shoot me. I want you to.
Fucking anarchist!
I'll teach you!
"Love live anarchy!" Shit!
Away! Take him away!
Rough him up nice and good.
Because he's got to talk.
Hello? Captain Fautasso.
Yes, Your Excellency.
Of course.
Don't you worry.
Good-bye, Your Excellency.
They don't want it known.
He prefers it.
The number of these crazies
has tripled lately, huh?
What are you saying, Captain?
The Italians love their Duce.
Besides...
there's been no negative talk for years now.
Then again, instead of killing them
like they deserve, he pardons them.
Oh, my poor child.
What are you talking about, Commander?
He pardons them! What pardon?
Who got a pardon?
He pardoned those two we know about,
but what about the others?
He's a hero, but he's not stupid.
It's better to make some people
disappear without publicity.
And this is one more case like that.
It's faster. More political, right?
Damn it!
Go ahead.
This morning at 1 0:00 in Via dei Fiori,
in the well-known whorehouse,
an unknown man,
overcome by a fit of madness,
fired some shots at a police unit
during a routine inspection.
Once arrested,
the unknown man took his own life
by violently beating his head
against the wall of his cell.
Mother!
I wish to repeat my horror at attacks,
which besides being bad
in and of themselves are also stupid,
because they harm the very cause
they are trying to serve...
But those assassins are also saints and heroes...
And they will be celebrated
once the brutal facts are forgotten,
and all that is remembered
is the idea that inspired them
and the martyrdom that made them saints.
- Errico Malatesta
LOVE AND ANARCHY
Or
"This morning at 10:00 in Via dei Fiori,
in the well-known whorehouse..."