God's Angel took me up,
and he of hell
Shouted, "O thou of heaven,
why dost thou rob me?
"Thou bearest away
the eternal part of him,
"For one poor little tear,
that takes him from me..."
Well, this is really the end!
Now I can see you.
In daylight for the first time.
Are your women on strike?
You're still alive?
They say work will kill you.
It's an honourable death!
Hey, martyr!
Listen to me, quit working.
Come and join us
at Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.
What makes you do it?
Sleep at night
instead of playing cards.
It's like a morgue here.
Here's a man who knows Scucchia.
Come here.
You tell them what happened
to poor Barberone.
Weren't you here when
he decided to make that bet
with The German and Peppe the Nut?
He said that he'd eat
a kilo of potatoes,
a bag of persimmons,
and then swim without any problem.
Yeah, so?
And that Peppe the Nut
wanted him to cross the river
to the other side and back,
not just dip in and out.
- Yes.
- He didn't die of indigestion.
He was exhausted.
He'd never crossed the river.
You dope!
You can't eat a meal
and then go swimming. You'd die.
The reaction from heat to cold
stops your digestion,
the blood circulation,
and that's it!
I lost my money,
but I still have my ring to bet.
Bet, if you have the nerve.
You're all talk.
You're stubborn.
Yeah! I want to kill you, too.
What are you alive for anyway?
The cemetery has room
for everybody.
Your brother's courage
would have won the war.
Besides the ring, if I make it,
- I'll spit in your face!
- Save your breath, you'll need it.
Come on. Maybe your brother'll
make you his substitute.
- I'm going to work.
- He said a bad word!
And my 1,000 lire?
Before killing yourself, pay me back!
Buy a wreath if I die.
What's 1,000 lire?
So give me another 1,000,
take up a collection right now.
Accattone, who are you leaving
your Maddalena to?
The vice squad!
Joking aside, Accattone,
you know, I'm an educated person.
You can trust me.
Can I help you with your funeral?
With my friends laughing,
and if anybody cries,
he pays for the dinner.
And what do we write
on your stone?
"Try it yourself."
You're diving
with all your gold on?
Not taking off
your chain and bracelet?
I want to die with all my gold on me,
like the Pharaohs.
Give it to us!
Come and dive for it.
I've got a stiff neck.
Go on and dive!
Okay, let's satisfy the masses.
Hey, lunatic,
you could've warned me!
The digestive tract,
the circulatory reaction...
But Accattone...
Not even the river
can carry away Accattone.
The wise guys,
the Hun and Peppe the Nut.
He did it!
I'm alive.
You wanted to sing
the funeral march.
I've still got to make
lots of people cry.
Saint Barberone protected you.
Barberone was like this,
with his eyes wide open,
his belly swollen like a drum.
God, he was ugly!
Who carried off Barberone,
Christ or the Devil?
They're fighting over him.
Let's have a swim.
Let's go, German.
Accattone,
I was supposed to tell you,
Maddalena was hit
by a motorcycle.
She's hurt. She's home now,
bandaged like a mummy.
I knew it. Good thing I remembered.
Come on.
- When?
- Two hours ago.
- And I came to look for you.
- Come on.
Well? What happened?
See for yourself. The bastards!
I'd like to know where your head is
when you're walking!
Stay home, then.
What's the use of you going out?
If they hit you,
then I'd be rid of you.
I was going to pay
for the shirt I bought you.
1,000 lire I pay every morning.
And you had yourself
all bandaged up.
Afraid you'll lose your leg?
Did I tell the doctor?
It must've been necessary.
Nannina! Nannina!
Don't let anybody in,
understand?
- Salvatore, how's things?
- I get by.
Milk for the kid.
- You have any?
- Thanks, but don't worry about us.
I'm mad as all hell.
Has your husband written?
I know what jail is.
With so many things on your mind,
you never feel like writing.
Don't worry.
The Madonna sees all
and provides for all.
- Is Accattone at home?
- Should I call him for you?
Yeah, I'd like to meet him,
this cardboard man.
A friend of my husband
wants to talk to you.
- Who is it?
- Salvatore, his pal.
My God, what does he want?
Ask him to wait a minute.
He'll be right there.
Be careful now,
he's big buddies with Ciccio.
Ciccio must have sent him.
What do I care?
He's young,
but he's the biggest pimp in Naples.
He'll kill for nothing.
All the time he's done...
You are Master Accattone, right?
Pleased to meet you,
Salvatore from Torre Annunziata.
- Nice to meet you.
- Sorry to bother you.
I was in the neighbourhood
on personal business,
so I took the opportunity
to make your acquaintance.
So you're Ciccio's young friend?
We're closer than a father and son.
- Poor Ciccio. He's had bad luck.
- To each his own.
I wanted to thank you.
You're big-hearted.
You took this girl in
and helped her and her kids,
who were starving to death.
What does it cost me?
A bowl of soup here and there?
- Let's drink on it?
- Why not?
Maddalena, be a good girl.
Let me introduce my friends.
All bums, that's us.
Used-up men.
We're rejects. Only worth something
with 1,000 in our pocket.
If not, we're worth nothing.
They don't even want us in jail.
We're through because
we can't manage on our own.
Better be a thief
than do our lousy job.
If I could relive my life,
I'd make a different fate.
You're a good kid.
Don't take it so hard.
It's in God's hands.
I should have met you before.
See what's happened to Ciccio,
your partner,
that could happen to me,
you know that.
Maddalena met me.
"You're a better man than Ciccio,
"your heart is more noble
than Ciccio's."
That's what she kept telling me
to convince me, the bitch.
And besides, Ciccio had five kids
and he hit me all the time!
So she turned him in.
Poor Ciccio, there he is!
What are all the tears for?
You don't break any hearts.
When you're begging,
you brought tears to the eyes
even of the cops.
Now you're not touching,
you're a mess.
Look, Balilla!
You're through, too!
Come here and drink,
drown your sorrows.
When did he ever suffer?
I'll say he suffered,
16 years in the orphanage.
- Are these your friends?
- Nice to meet you.
- The Honoured Society!
- Poor guys!
Drink.
Damn all women!
They take you up to heaven
and then they drop you.
Up there amid the angels
They sang for you alone, Maria
Ah, give me back that angel
The fair sex!
When I go home she'll hear me.
She turned in my friend's pal,
a fine man, to be with me.
To ruin me, too, the prostitute!
Curse her! May she never have
a moment's peace.
Don't worry, Ciccio's in good hands
with the custodians of order.
You should see the pretty girls we've
brought from Naples to Torre Annunziata.
One more stacked than the other.
If you don't believe me, ask my friends.
Classy stuff, chic goods.
Little girls, 18 years old. Special!
Accattone, you should've been
with us last night.
There was me,
Tintura and Il Droga.
- We picked up a hooker.
- Good boys.
First we acted sweet.
We took her to the field
then we beat her.
What a beating!
You should've seen it.
How she cried,
how she begged us!
She's still yelling,
"Oh, God. Oh, God!"
We're amazing.
We're the terror of Rome!
What happened?
What do you care what happened?
Are you my mother?
Oh, the wine goes to your head
and you take it out on me?
Not working tonight?
Do you think you can stay here?
You don't draw unemployment.
Look, handsome,
can't you see the state I'm in?
You think this is a joke?
I got a broken leg!
Broken?
You make me laugh, broken!
You work tonight,
the same as every night, the same!
You can't play the lady,
that's your life!
You think you bought me with
the dirty money you give me every day?
You ruined me!
I'd have been a good worker now,
or a thief!
I wouldn't be here!
You better work tonight.
Or I'll break your other leg, too.
Then it'll be over with.
I won't go to prison
Because I did nothing
May all the police in the city
Have a stroke
Go sing elsewhere! First you get drunk,
then you come to vomit here?
You're not romantic,
they're serenading you. Crummy whore!
Come and cook yourself
a couple of eggs,
you're nothing but bones.
You should end up like Nero,
you and these bastards!
Let's stay up here.
Down there it stinks.
Pick on your own kind.
Shame on you!
Ugly killer, I should stab you,
that's what.
Don't get mad.
You're crazy.
Look at that leg!
Who made you come here
in that condition?
If you die, nobody's going to cry.
At least if you did it for yourself...
You mean that my man
doesn't take care of me?
At least he's good
and he loves me.
Sure, he loves you.
Tongue, behave!
Or I'll bite you off!
Be like me,
I don't love anybody any more.
And they call me Amore.
Look what those punks are doing!
Leave the poor guy alone!
I wish all the worst for you. Jailbirds!
- Let's see you in the light, come.
- A car, or it's off.
Don't worry.
It's parked over there,
nice and close.
Bye, Amore.
You like Neapolitans?
Don't take us for Italians,
we Neapolitans are special.
There's our car.
Get in, get in.
We've met before.
- We're old friends.
- Who are you?
What? Have you forgotten me
already?
We were good friends.
The friend of Ciccio who's in jail,
remember?
Let me get a better look.
Yeah, you came
to my house today.
It took you a while,
but you got there.
What did you want
with Accattone?
He's a real good kid,
a pearl of a man.
Where are we going?
Now that you're here
with these friends of mine
who want to have a good time,
we'll go where we like.
Ah, what a beautiful spot!
Gennarino,
what are you waiting for?
Have you gone to sleep?
I don't like this place, I'm afraid.
Afraid? What are you afraid of?
I've never been here before.
The ditches, and the sheepdogs.
Let's go somewhere else.
What do you think I am, an animal?
Take your hands off me! I'll get out.
You get mad fast!
Instead you ought to be glad.
I was kidding.
I'm a physical kind of guy.
Why don't you be nice?
Let's go somewhere else.
With my leg bandaged, I can hardly
walk. Let's go somewhere else.
Don't worry.
Gennarino, go ahead.
Give me your hand, I'll help you.
Trust Gennarino.
We're all here.
Don't worry.
Your Anna has died
And they buried her
She always cried
Because she slept alone
Now she sleeps
Accompanied by the dead
What's she got in this bag?
She doesn't have two pennies
to rub together.
Damn.
Here they are.
Well?
Turn them off!
You want to blind me?
He'd crush you like a snake.
Have you gone crazy?
Leave me alone.
Pay no attention.
He's a hick, this guy. No style.
Get up. What are you doing?
Can't you stay on your feet?
Help! Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, God! No. No!
Help!
Don't leave me here alone!
I won't say anything!
Italy awakes!
What have you done?
You look kind of down.
Not at all!
I'm a free citizen.
My woman didn't come home last night.
They must have beaten her.
- I want to die!
- Hang yourself!
Laugh, you've gambled away
your food.
What are you going to do now?
Going to collect rags?
You'll be selling holy cards.
Get busy, kid,
or you'll starve to death.
Damn.
Easy, fellow Italians, behave.
Cops are on the way.
Act natural.
I'm going to church
to clean up the sacristy.
Listen, you...
Me? You've got the wrong guy.
Yes, you. Just a minute.
- Something wrong?
- Papers.
Who has their papers?
I can remember my name.
- What do I need my documents for?
- Papers.
Why?
Come along for a verification.
Out of 3 million inhabitants in Rome,
you have to pick me for a verification?
If you want a coffee...
- Come on, let's go. Don't be an idiot.
- Let go. Take your hands off me.
Don't make a fuss
and it'll be quick.
I'm not coming.
I'm fine where I am.
Go on, you tell him, too,
since you're his friends.
Isn't it better for him
if he comes quietly?
Okay, I'm coming! Enough!
I didn't do anything. Let's go.
You realise you've kept me here
for three hours?
What do you want?
I don't bother anybody.
You shouldn't bother me.
You have to let me go.
I'm fed up being here!
It's no use yelling.
Be a good boy.
Who has to question me?
Why doesn't he question me
and let me go?
I'm fed up being here!
Enough's enough, I don't know
anything. What do you want?
What do you want with me?
I'm sick, and you'll pay
or send me home.
You're making me mad,
you know.
Take it easy and sit down.
You're not at your house.
The sergeant will call you
when it's convenient.
When it's convenient?
I'm not waiting
for anybody's convenience!
I want to go! I've had enough!
Shut up, and sit down!
What are you doing?
Let me go!
Keep still!
Hold him, tight.
- I didn't do anything!
- We need a straitjacket.
- Let me go. I didn't do anything!
- Stop!
Oh, God.
Do you recognise anybody?
Don't be afraid.
No.
Get out. Go.
These?
No.
I recognise him, it's him!
It's him!
What's this all about?
Are you sure of what you're saying?
Look carefully.
It's them.
I saw their faces clearly.
The other one, too.
It's them.
Hey, Sarge, she's crazy!
Send her to the nuthouse!
You trying to ruin me, you bitch?
You must be sure,
because you can ruin them.
I swear on my mother, it's them.
These bastards,
they ruined me!
What did I do to you?
For no reason, they beat me up.
They nearly killed me.
- Get them out of here.
- I swear, I didn't do anything!
Now we'll see
if you did anything or not.
I'll kill her! I'll kill her!
Pea-brain!
Take care in recognising
your attackers.
If anyone proves innocent,
you're in trouble. Be careful!
They were with me half an hour,
you think I can't recognise them?
Well?
Didn't you say he had brown hair,
kind of stocky?
It wasn't them.
Let's go.
Who wants to buy this ring?
I'm selling gold, not rags.
Accattone!
Accattone, explain something.
They let you go?
You're out already?
No, I'm going to jail
just because your girl is so pretty.
That would really be ridiculous.
If the guards hadn't been there,
I'd have eaten her alive.
That bitch!
What do you want from me?
Did I turn you in?
They want to put me in jail, too.
Be glad they let you go.
Stay out of jail
and enjoy your freedom!
She had to report me?
Am I an orphan?
I'd show her.
For slander and perjury,
the minimum's two years.
What'll you eat then,
soup from the women's prison?
Come on, who wants to buy this ring?
Start the bidding.
- How much?
- I paid 15,000. I'm asking half, 7,000.
Life's smiling on me today.
I want to make you smile, too.
Take advantage of it.
Hear what the prophet says.
Today you sell the ring,
tomorrow the chain,
in seven days the watch,
and in 77 days you won't have even
your eyes to weep with.
Accattone, look,
the cemetery's there.
Give it my best.
I don't need a nurse yet.
Did you sell your car?
Is the gold all gone?
You really look like a dirty beggar.
What a way to end up.
Long live us thieves.
We always know where to go.
We stretch out our hand,
we catch something.
Sure, a nice long stretch!
Remember,
we're all born with a vocation.
Mine was to be a thief,
and here I am!
You weren't born to be a pimp,
but a beggar... There you are!
Don't you have
anything to do today?
Piss off! I was fine
minding my own business.
Get a hold of yourself.
For thieves,
there's no being unemployed.
You're lucky to be so secure.
Not all thieves are rich.
Leave me alone.
The war days are past.
Today, as soon as you step outside,
they put you in jail.
Don't you see
what the police chief's doing?
Iaio!
I'm the poor soul of your father.
Don't you know me any more?
Damn.
Your mother lets you
run around like this, all dirty?
Don't you know you're a man?
Give your father a little kiss?
Iaio! Iaio!
- What are you doing here?
- Am I robbing your food from you?
Where's my wife?
Where is she?
Earning your son's bread.
Go away, the less she sees of you
the better for her.
I get it.
A renaissance family.
Laugh it up. Somebody'll kill you.
That's your fate.
It's lemon blossom
Who can this proper youth be?
A working man
or a great gentleman
Have you seen my wife?
Ascenza!
Ascenza, here's that
fine husband of yours!
- When do you knock off here?
- In a few minutes.
Since six this morning
we've been at it.
These things happen.
Is it hard work?
When you need it,
any job is good.
Do they pay you well, at least?
Enough to keep us from starving.
You're new.
I've never seen you before.
Just a month.
I could tell you what Italy needs.
Yes, let's see.
Lincoln freed the slaves.
In Italy, they've just started
with them.
Give me a gun,
and there'd be nobody left standing.
- What's your name?
- Stella.
I'm Vittorio. Nice to meet you.
Stella, star, show me the way,
teach me the way
to a bowl of bean soup.
- Hungry?
- Hungry, no. A little appetite.
It's noon. It's that time of day.
Tell me something,
you seem so innocent,
like a little girl,
good and not sly. Hmm...
I can't explain.
Are you from Rome?
- Me? Yes.
- Funny.
You're lucky,
not to know things.
- Bye, see you later.
- Bye.
I was waiting for you.
I have to talk to you.
Didn't you see me?
Will you stop!
Do I need a permit
to talk with you?
Do I have to pray to you
like a saint?
We don't have anything
to say to each other.
What we had to say,
we've already said.
That's that!
Don't yell!
Don't make a big scene.
Will you go?
I'm not talking to you any more.
Understand?
I don't want anything to do with you,
understand? Go away!
Let me lead my life,
and you lead yours.
Don't act like a kid,
listen to my side.
I won't listen to anything.
I know what you want.
There's nothing left,
forget about me.
I didn't come begging for anything.
If I want to eat, I can find food
for myself and others.
I don't need anything from anybody.
What are you thinking?
You find a way to eat, sure.
Shame on you!
And you come out and say it.
Oh, cut it out.
You've never been good
for yourself or me or your son.
This is no land of plenty!
Don't make me say it again!
I know, I was lousy.
I made mistakes,
but give me a way to make it up,
to show you what I'm worth.
I'm fed up with this life.
I've decided,
I'm looking for a job.
It's not easy, you know that,
but I intend to find one.
Believing you was
the biggest mistake of my life.
What's wrong? People change.
So, decide before we get
to your house.
I don't want to see your idiot
of a brother and your father.
Well, then?
Get out of my sight! Go away!
You see how mean your mother is?
She doesn't have a conscience.
She wants you to grow up
without a father.
- What does he want?
- What's he doing here?
What does he want?
Someone to support him!
Now he has nobody, understand?
And he comes here
to eat at our expense.
Listen, idiot, stop coming here.
Someday, someone's going to
break your neck.
This isn't a soup kitchen.
Go and work if you want to eat.
You want to scare me?
Bash his face in.
That'll stop him
acting the bully in our house.
Crook! Bum!
Get out of here!
You're a sweet bunch.
The hicks' revenge!
You take it as a joke.
Just your nerve! Get out of here!
And remember,
don't come around here again.
I don't want your son to see you
and be ashamed of a father like you!
Stop! Stop, Father!
Help! Help!
He's got a knife. Hold him.
Hurry! Stop him!
Pimp!
Bad shape, eh?
Jesus, you're changed.
When are you going to have one
of those great dinners at Fiumicino?
Fish soup and mixed fry.
Do you remember? A dream!
Haven't they jailed you yet?
Piss off!
There's a rumour
you haven't eaten for two days.
Is it true?
If I vomit on you,
you'll eat for a week.
Oh, you've eaten! You're fine.
And I was so worried
that you were hungry.
I wanted to help you out.
Thank Jesus Christ!
Want an Alka-Seltzer?
Piss off! Don't you have
anything to do?
Come here.
You're lucky you can eat bones.
"...and in 77 days you won't have
even your eyes to weep with."
This is starvation, Accattone!
Why am I wasting my breath?
An angel will pass
and make it come true.
You've 200 lire, Cipolla. Buy us five
sausages, oil, tomato sauce, bread.
And take a taxi!
Go on, charge it.
Get it from the bakery.
It's that dumb father of yours
who'll pay.
And if his father finds him,
he'll hang him!
Don't the hungry
have a patron saint?
If you exist, lend us 2,000 lire.
Colonel, I don't want bread
I want a kilo of pasta
Don't worry,
I'll eat it all
Hey, kids, you like sausage?
Clear out or I'll eat you.
Accattone, if it wasn't for
the priests today we wouldn't eat.
Read this.
"Vatican assistance
for needy families."
Long live the clergy!
Fulvio, light the gas!
What do you want to do,
kill yourselves?
Fulvio, please!
Lend us the stove so we can cook
ourselves this spaghetti!
- We're hungry.
- Hurry, come up.
The stove is free,
we don't have anything to eat.
"It's the universal fast!"
Mama, put the water on,
make some pasta for them.
Fry, pan, fry!
Hurry up, ma'am.
It's a miracle we can stand up.
I'll make the sauce.
My speciality! Starvation sauce.
Sit down. Leave it to us!
Excuse us, ma'am.
Today I feel like a great cook.
Are you on a diet?
But what's hunger, really?
A bad habit!
It's all in the mind.
Ah, if they hadn't got us
used to eating as kids...
Hey, kid, who gave you
the habit of eating?
This starving father of yours?
Accattone, remember that time
when we stole that money
from a blind man to eat?
And the time
we sold your father's false teeth?
Hurry, or we'll end up like those guys
in the Nuremburg trials.
Are you game to screw them?
What for?
What do you want to do?
There's eight of us
for a plate of spaghetti.
How?
How can we get rid of them?
It's nothing.
You insult us,
call us good-for-nothings.
It's an offence to our honour!
I'll take care of them.
They'll leave,
and we'll eat the pasta.
Fulvio, they'll make you
a monument!
- You've saved four Italians.
- Yeah, a monument.
Right, the more good you do,
the more kicks you get.
Look here, what do you think we are?
We're good Christians.
We're grateful.
If you get into trouble, we'll always
find a bowl of soup for you.
Me, if I don't eat,
I stay in my house, not others'.
You're insulting us!
You were doing us a favour.
- No, giving you charity.
- What charity, you bastard?
Four boys your age
and you can't manage to buy meat?
You should be ashamed.
Look who's talking about hunger.
Yesterday, your wife told me
you ate up all the kids' dinner.
That's enough.
Tell the police about it!
You're their informer,
you think people don't know that?
Are you kidding
or do you mean it?
Kidding?
Everyone's talking about it.
Everybody!
Don't pay attention
to this poor idiot.
We're not trash.
We have our pride,
and we're capable of giving you
our pasta as charity.
Pride? What pride?
Pride in taking money
from women?
Even in jail, nobody associates
with the pimps.
What are you doing?
The Hun's right, we'll all leave.
Hunger's driven this jerk crazy.
Let's go.
It was almost done!
I didn't expect an attack like that.
Me neither.
We've taught him a lesson.
- St Bosco, help us!
- Yeah, to die of hunger.
Accattone, how come
you look so pensive?
Is your arse itching?
Pio, what did you eat at noon?
I won't give him this satisfaction!
He's not going to eat that stuff!
I'll throw it out first!
Wait here. I'll bring the stuff
back to him. Leave it to me!
- Pio, go on, hurry, start it.
- Why? What's going on?
She'll get away. It's a girl.
Move, or we'll lose her.
- What do you guys want? Get out.
- One for all and all for one!
Now these bastards
will ruin everything.
Move it.
You'll pay for this. If I lose out,
you'd better run away.
You're making all this fuss
over a woman!
Hello, don't you recognise me?
Oh, hi.
Not working today?
I just finished.
I gave myself a half day off work.
- You're off?
- Yes, off.
A pawn ticket's about to expire.
It's a medal of my father.
I don't want to lose it.
- You're taking the tram?
- Yes, I'm going to catch it now.
If you want, I've got a friend's car.
There it is.
That's all right,
I'll take the tram.
We don't have anything to do anyway.
We'll go for a ride.
Come on,
don't be embarrassed!
Embarrassed?
My friends.
They'll leave right away.
They're all invited to a banquet.
The last supper.
Nice to meet you.
Sit in the middle.
You can take the tram tomorrow.
- Where're we going?
- The pawn shop.
What are they doing?
Producing.
Stop, stop, let me see.
You really want to look?
You like it?
Turn back. Are they bad women,
those two?
Bad women?
Can't you see how good they look?
- Never seen any?
- I want to look at them.
Look, then!
Now what? Some girl she is.
When will you wake up?
What are they doing?
They're doing what all women do.
Poor things.
Poor things?
They're smart kids,
smarter than you'd ever dream of!
What's to look at?
Have I got scabs?
Amore, don't you recognise me?
Is that you?
I didn't recognise you.
You're getting old.
I'm the best on the market.
Who's this? I don't know her.
What do you think?
She's in another class.
Ah, another class?
How's Maddalena?
Does she write to you?
They gave her a year.
- Her fault!
- You don't care about Maddalena.
Me, I'm smart,
not having a man.
Can't you change the subject?
My God,
you treat this poor child badly.
Dress her decently
when you send her out.
This dress is a rag,
and look at those shoes.
Mind your own business!
Pio, move!
Dumb hooker!
She's right,
you're kind of ragged.
This is the only dress I've got.
I have to give my folks
the money I make.
I'll bring you a dress.
- Will you really bring it?
- Why not?
You bring a dress,
I'll get the shoes.
Laugh, Stella.
Iaio, forgive me, I'm a bum.
A pair of shoes, 6,000 lire.
Where would I get 6,000 lire?
If he'd just let her leave,
this dirty hick.
Iaio, don't you ever recognise me?
I'm your father, after all.
Give Papa a little kiss.
A little kiss. Come on.
A good kiss. Come here.
The things I have to do.
Bye, behave yourself.
Now you're really a star in name
and in fact. It's clothes that count.
- Give me 1,000 lire.
- Yeah, we're rich.
Accattone, what's
the sudden inspiration?
If you want to eat,
the food stall's in the other direction.
Are you happy?
I'm happy,
you've both been so good.
Nobody's ever done
anything like this for me.
What did we do?
You deserve it, you're a fine girl.
I hope I can repay you.
The final touch!
A little kiss? Come on.
And Pio, too.
We're all crazy.
- Bye, then.
- You're leaving already?
I got to go to the shop,
my wife's expecting me.
See you tonight.
- Bye.
- Bye, Pio.
- Thanks.
- Take care of yourself! Bye.
You're loyal.
Let's go this way.
Mind if we walk like this?
I already know, I love you.
It doesn't take me long
when a person deserves it.
Don't you feel anything for me?
I'm serious.
Don't you believe I love you?
- I swear.
- Why?
Why? First of all
because I like your looks.
Second, because you seem
different, helpless, alone.
And you need some comfort, too.
We're good together,
don't you think?
- I should make you a speech.
- Mussolini made speeches.
No, don't joke. This is serious.
I've got to tell you.
I want you to know
everything about me.
My father died in the war.
- Can I talk?
- Talk, talk.
My father died, and my mother
managed by being on the street,
like those women
we saw yesterday.
I'm saying this so you won't think
the wrong thing of me.
Let's go this way.
I feel only hate for my mother,
even if she did it for me.
There were other ways.
What did she do?
Instead of feeling sorry...
It's a mother's situation.
Cheer up.
When a person does that,
they love you.
It's not her profession,
she did it for you.
Don't you understand?
You ought to make her
a monument.
Are you mad, Vittorio?
Don't call me Vittorio,
call me Accattone.
There are lots of Vittorios,
I'm the only Accattone.
Those beads look nice on you!
It was a lovely thought.
Have you ever been with a man?
Tell me the truth.
A few times.
And what did you do?
We talked...
I don't know, what else?
Let's go over there.
Then nobody's touched you.
Is that true?
What's happened to Accattone?
Nothing. He's in love.
The happiest of men,
the smart guy!
In love? What do you mean?
You're telling fairy tales.
If you tell me Accattone's hungry,
I believe it.
- But in love? Hmm!
- If he's dumb, yes.
Here comes the prodigal son!
Come over here!
What do you want?
What's happened to your brother,
Accattone?
He's disappeared for three days.
You guys should know,
you're his friends.
- You on the way home from work?
- Yes, so?
You follow your brother's example?
Shame on you!
Your brother makes others do
all the work, your degenerate brother!
For us, it's always a holiday,
for you only May 1st!
You say Accattone isn't in love?
What's wrong? You got the fever?
Get your brain examined.
Can you imagine him in love?
Look, I've got good eyes.
Who's Accattone anyway?
The tough guy of Rome?
I tell you, basically he's stupid.
But he's got the profession of pimp
in his blood.
Bread is bread.
I say in 10 days at the most
we'll see Stella on the street.
- What'll you bet?
- Anything you like.
Your jacket, and if I win,
I'll give it to the orphans.
Listen to me.
If Maddalena hears anything about
Accattone having another woman
and putting the poor bitch to work,
nobody'll keep her
from sending him to jail.
"Orate, frates."
Drink and get drunk
and you'll make the cops come.
Are you paying? Piss off!
You're a mess.
Here's to you!
- You hear how they're in love?
- Men!
Look at these who have their men,
look at these two lost souls.
They've been in the life,
and what do they have?
They don't have anything,
not even a bit of gold.
- We wear that.
- You need a man beside you.
At night when I come home,
if nobody's there, I feel like crying.
You understand?
Accattone, excuse me...
There's those two guys.
Guys with cash.
They like that girl. She doesn't look
like a whore and they like that.
Want me to fix it up?
It's just some company.
Let him step up.
Do I have to throw her at him?
May I have this dance?
Dance with the gent.
Allow me.
Look at that dope.
Ah, Stella...
You're trapped, too,
and don't know it.
"All hope abandon ye
who enter here."
I bet the jacket.
You win!
I've got a nasty eye.
I thought you'd fallen.
Congratulations. You're an artist.
Nice jacket. A real man's jacket.
- For me?
- Yes, it's for you.
Go with God.
The dope's got long arms,
he's having a try.
Okay, cut it out.
Who'll bet all we've drunk tonight
that I'll jump off the bridge?
I'll jump off the bridge.
And die like Tosca!
You don't believe me?
Then bet, you clowns!
And with my clothes on!
Don't go too far.
The guy's drunk, he'll really jump.
Run!
Let him jump, then!
Stop! I can't run any more.
Stop. I can't breathe.
The water's cold!
- What was I thinking?
- At least put a stone around your neck.
I understand you.
Is the fit over
or do I call for a straitjacket?
Ah, here we go again.
Aren't you ashamed?
Wash your face.
You're so drunk.
It's disgusting.
Good! You see, when you want to,
you understand things.
What are you doing?
Now what are you up to?
You're cute!
Hi, Vittorio.
What's wrong?
Why should anything be wrong?
Can't you see?
I make myself sick.
Before I met you, who was I?
I had a car and plenty of money
and everything I wanted.
Clothes, watches, rings, bracelets.
Gold!
And now I'm waiting for manna
from Heaven.
Find a job, then.
Doing what?
Giving other people my blood?
I'm not letting anybody
drink my blood. Work?
Animals work.
Last night you had
the time of your life.
You let that dope cheer you up
by the river.
If you'd shown
some respect for me...
I thought you were different.
It's the first time
I've made a mistake.
Embarrassing me
in front of my friends.
They laughed behind my back.
I thought that was how I should act.
I told you to dance with him.
Instead, you wanted to be
the sophisticated lady.
You wanted the honeymoon.
You liked him, didn't you?
Deny it!
- Now you're insulting me.
- I'm insulting you?
You insulted me.
You had fun behind my back.
You offended my pride!
I should have expected it from you.
Like mother, like daughter.
I know where you want to lead me.
I expected it, believe me.
Don't get too worked up.
I know what you want from me.
Ah, you know! Then do it!
What are you waiting for?
Why do you talk to me like this?
You know I'm not experienced.
I've been through sorrows
and hard times.
I'm not like the other girls.
How should I know what to do,
what not to do?
What do I know?
Learn from your cow of a mother.
Now you cry, stupid!
If I'd known you'd cry,
I wouldn't have said it.
I was kidding.
No, you weren't.
I know what you want.
That's your aim.
Let's forget about these things.
What matters is that we're in love.
One day we'll say
to hell with everything.
Our Lady, make me a saint,
I've done my penance.
There he is, the beggar!
He's back in business!
Booming, eh, Accattone?
I know somebody that
if they saw for themselves
would give Accattone
a big surprise!
Unfortunately she can't see or hear,
lying in her cell
counting the days on the pisspot.
Here's the hawk.
Well? You hiding?
Afraid of the john
who'll take you away?
Now you're here, do what all of us do.
Make peace with yourself.
There's no Hell anyway,
and no Heaven.
She's ashamed.
I was so ashamed the first time.
Now I'm the most shameless of all.
Amore! Here comes the sacristan.
Run to the man who loves you!
Come on, let me in.
How about this masterpiece?
Let her be. She's a poor victim.
Well? Shall we get going?
Oh, don't tell me
you're really going with her?
She's wasting no time!
You expect him
to always eat the same dish?
Bye, Amore.
I'm being unfaithful to you!
Amore, make way for the young.
It's time for you to retire.
Do I have to file an application or what?
Is this the first time you're doing it?
The first time you...
Yes.
The world's a big garbage dump,
everything's changed.
And one tramp more, one less.
What do you think?
So I'm lucky. It's the first time.
Are you embarrassed?
You don't even know what it is.
Come here. Get moving.
I didn't pick you up
so we could take a drive.
I disgust you?
You take me for a dope?
Then why did you come?
I don't want to do it.
Take me back.
Take you back?
What did you expect
from this kind of a life? Candy?
Take me back.
Walk! Go on, get out!
Clear out!
You dope!
Hey, look, he's back alone.
Did you lose Accattone's girl?
You sent me off with a nutcase?
What was wrong with her?
She started crying.
She wouldn't play
so I dumped her there.
From the Appian Way
she'll make a pilgrimage here.
What can she do,
the Quo Vadis?
Laugh, damn you! You idiot!
Lend me your bike.
Easy, or you'll kill yourself!
You're leaving?
You leave me like this?
- I'm full of poison, if I bite I kill.
- That's how it is?
Don't let me lay eyes on you again!
Go back to your village,
in Rome you stink!
You would have liked
the innocent, eh? Idiot!
Amore, watch out, the cops!
So what? I'll take it out on them.
What do you want? Leave me alone.
I won't go to the police station.
I'm in charge of my own life.
I do what I like.
Calm down
or we'll take you to the nuthouse.
What do I care!
When is she getting here?
She's going to keep me up
till morning.
Damn it!
What a life.
Always fighting for everything.
Do I really have
to end up like this?
I'm not putting up with it.
Not even for Christ himself.
Come in.
Maddalena, you're here?
Where else? On the Riviera?
How are things?
Who are you primping yourself for,
may I ask?
Why?
The man who loved you
has left you.
Really?
Lina, did you hear her?
- Who's he with?
- He's with a young kid.
You don't know her.
Name of Stella. A beautiful girl.
He's put her to work, too.
Poor Stella.
That man you had is a genius.
Bastards. You and him!
What's wrong?
I wanted to report Cataldi Vittorio
known as Accattone.
- For what?
- Pimping.
- Did he pimp for you?
- No.
Who, then?
What are you reporting him for?
Pimping! Don't you understand me?
I told you.
Are you deaf?
Who is it?
The charge can come only
from the person involved
incited to prostitution.
You don't know him!
He's capable of anything.
He's capable of anything
for his comfort! Even killing.
You've got to jail him!
He's not worthy of living.
Jail him!
Where did you find her?
- I'll carry the suitcase.
- Me, too. Me, too.
I'll carry the stuff.
Come in.
Stella, introduce yourselves.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Same here.
We managed before, so we'll
manage now, won't we, Nannina?
Let me have that.
Thanks, Nannina.
Are you happy?
This is no palace.
At least the roof doesn't leak.
- Happy?
- If I'm not a bother.
There are two possibilities.
Either I've gone crazy,
or I'm sane again.
You like Marsala?
- Let's have some?
- There's still some Marsala?
The great times!
Yeah, let's have a glass.
This Marsala's historic,
if you knew...
Eh, Nannina?
Let's hope all goes well.
Mamma, us too.
A little Marsala?
Thank you.
Here's to us, then.
And screw them all.
Aren't they a picture?
Here's to Heaven,
and Stella, who's found a home.
The first step's made!
Hey, brother.
Come on, we'll be late!
I can't do anything.
Learn.
Here's the cattle car!
The boss is kind of grouchy.
When you work,
nobody gives you the money.
What a brother!
Who did you take after?
After St Sebastian the Martyr.
Good morning.
Sor Pietro,
I told you about my brother.
Changed your mind?
- All right.
- So long, Sor Pietro.
Goodbye.
Hey, Panzone, we're loading.
Where's our iron?
- Over there.
- Is it 80 quintals?
80! You think I'm robbing you?
80 quintals.
There's all this iron in Italy?
Go on, work hard
and you'll finish quick.
Yeah, finish living.
- How many trips?
- Six, if we really push it.
Push yourself!
Are we in Buchenwald here?
- And I thought it was easy.
- You fade out fast.
You're lucky I'm winded,
or I'd kill you.
Working has a bad effect on you.
Come on, one more trip
and we're through.
God's will be done!
Poor Accattone.
There's a finished man.
Watch out,
the dog catcher's coming!
What's wrong?
Why's he acting like that?
Search me. This morning he looked
like the Statue of Liberty.
He looked down on everyone.
Hey, victim!
You pathetic case!
That's enough from you, bastards!
You're so prosaic.
Vittorio. What have they
done to you?
My God, what's happened?
I'm a dope, that's what happened!
For 1,000 lousy lire
I went and killed myself.
I should've had a stroke
instead of going there.
Calm down. Don't say that.
Mind your own business.
That's enough.
Listen. Let me say something.
Skip it, forget it.
Vittorio,
if you aren't up to working,
I'm ready to go on the street again,
if that's better.
What are you saying? Shut up!
What do you care about me?
Nobody's going to cry over me.
You on the street? Cut it out.
I decided, I'll look after you.
You'll stay at home!
If I decide something, that's it.
Either the world kills me,
or I kill it.
Mama, wee-wee.
Master Accattone! Master Accattone!
Come here. Sit with us.
Come on.
Aren't you coming?
We're all ready.
We're waiting for you.
Where'd you get all these flowers?
- Over there.
- Let's go.
What's happened?
Won't you tell me anything?
Will you tell me what's happened?
I can't hear you.
What's happened?
Don't you know? Accattone's dead.
Vittorio, let's move...
You could've told him not to do it.
What kind of friends are you?
You can't go in.
Why not?
No.
Say, sir, why don't you dig
a bit further on?
The earth is all dark here.
Sorry, but I can't.
Just a bit over there, a little.
Please, sir.
There in the light, it's better.
Very well.
Where's Balilla?
He's filling his tank.
Hey, Balilla, you drunk,
somebody wants you!
Is it the cops? I'm innocent.
Balilla, I've got to talk to you.
Come here and have a drop.
- I don't have a cent.
- So?
I tried working yesterday.
You know, right?
Shame on you!
What'll we do?
The world belongs to the happy.
Come here, Cartagine.
I'm done.
Who do we hit?
We don't do light stuff,
we just trust our luck. Cartagine!
Here I am!
Blessed be the day I was born.
- Where are you going?
- Divino Amore sanctuary.
Take these flowers.
A present.
Load up this garbage
and take it away.
You're joking.
Come on, Cartagine,
always in the mud.
I want to be in the flowers,
damn you!
For eight hours,
we've been walking.
I've never managed to steal
this damn truck. I have to get even.
Maybe this is it.
Damn it! God damn it!
That's enough!
Put your shoes back on!
You want to gas us?
You really stink!
Is that my fault?
We've been walking all day.
You stink worse alive than dead.
I'll confess something to you.
You know
when I last washed my feet?
August 15th, at the beach.
Cinderella's shoe was brought back
by the prince.
Yours by the fire department!
Do you realise?
You have a fortune in those feet
to exploit!
DDT is for killing flies.
You kill horses!
Heaven's sent us this truck.
It's salami, 20,000 lire at least.
Go, Cartagine.
If you believe in providence,
you don't starve to death.
Stella's right, my poor Stella...
Stop. It's useless to run.
We know who you are.
Oh, God!
Accattone. What's wrong?
How do you feel?
Accattone...
Ah, now I'm fine.
Why?