Subtitles by DramaFever
Uploaded by: asiandramasubtitles.tumblr.com
I'm back.
Kang Dong Suk.
Aren't you glad to see me?
You're waiting for
President Cho, right?
Before he gets here
you can talk to me first.
What?
Didn't you say you'd need
to sell the company?
President Cho gave me
all authority in this matter.
You can talk to me.
What nonsense is that?
Nonsense?
You don't seem to be in
the position to say that.
I'm your client right now.
Are you in your right mind?
Do you seriously think you
can talk to me about business?
If you fail to sell off the company
I heard Hyun Sung, even
the headquarters will get hit hard.
Think carefully...
which one of us has the upper hand.
You want to fight me with
the help of President Cho, huh?
Scared?
If I get involved
it's like selling weapons
to your enemy, huh?
I'm sorry, but...
I don't consider you as my enemy.
You're less than scum
under my toe nails.
You called that scum under
your toe nails brother, didn't you?
Since we're here
let's talk business.
You're good enough to
be my business partner.
You're easy to control.
Oh, hello.
Is everything going alright?
Yes, everything is going fine.
You two have met before, right?
Yes.
According to what I heard
things went sour between you two.
But this is business, right?
It's irrelevant, don't you think?
Yes, I agree.
Does he want to sell?
He will sell.
He thinks I'm a very
good business partner.
I understand.
First, come back with
all the conditions met.
I will take a look and make a decision.
I heard that we didn't have
to come up with the terms.
What we're trying to sell
off is not Hyun Sung.
It's only a branch attached
to a giant tree, Hyun Sung.
Of course, you're right.
Just because a tiger is hungry
it shouldn't look down to its babies...
We will tell you our terms first.
I'd appreciate that.
In a battle for money
you will definitely lose
if your feelings get involved.
That's the reason why
I let them see you.
Good job.
Get on his nerves.
By the way
what if he decides not
to sell it to us?
He will sell it.
Plus for a dirt cheap price.
From now on, that's what
you and Manager Gu will do.
If this deal goes well
You will become the president
of Hyun Sung Distribution and...
I will be the owner of the company.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Going back to being
the president again.
Yes sir.
Gosh, he's one persistent man.
The one you thought you
saw was him after all.
I guess.
What are you going to do to him?
What do you mean?
What I mean is...
I want to kill him.
Dong Suk.
I was kidding.
I'm just saying that's
how I feel right now.
What is it?
Gosh, he's one tough man.
What is he doing on the phone?
Okay.
Hey, he's leaving.
Follow him.
Gosh, you scared me.
Hey.
Who are you guys?
You asked for me, sir?
Why did I have to see that guy again?
Pardon?
I'm asking what happened.
Why did I have to see the
face of Kim Ji Hyuk again?
Are you saying that
Kim Ji Hyuk is alive?
Damn, this is frustrating.
Don't you understand what I'm saying?
I will say this for the last time.
Kim Ji Hyuk, that bastard has returned.
- Now do you understand?
- I'm sorry.
I will take care of it...
I told Mi Ra that he left for America.
Now I have to make
another excuse again!
Don't keep embarrassing
me in front of Mi Ra.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Yes, sir.
It won't happen again.
I'm sorry.
Why are you working with
such a dangerous man?
When I was at Hyun Sung
it was much more dangerous.
That was crazy...
What's so important
about having a family?
Honestly, it doesn't matter
if something happens to me.
But people around me were hurt.
The only way to make up
for their loss is...
to take from those
bastards and give it back.
One by one...
Shall I be frank with you?
Compared to those guys
you're no better than
a speckle of dust.
Don't be mistaken because
you were once the president.
The position was given to you by them.
You didn't earn it by yourself.
Now you're back to being
the punk you used to be.
Correct.
I'm a punk.
But I cannot give up.
This is not a battle for myself, but...
a battle for the people around me.
So I can never give up.
Even if that's the case
this is a meaningless fight.
You will be the only one who will hurt.
I'm more worried about you.
Do you still think Hyun
Sung will protect you?
Hyun Sung will protect
their family only.
All the rest besides themselves...
I think you know better than I do.
Get out of there, please.
What happened?
It's been a while since
you started looking.
You haven't found him yet?
Well, it's just that...
We did find him, but...
I will not do this any more.
I can't do it. I won't do it.
We won't do anything to
Kim Ji Hyuk any more.
Just know that.
Happy?
If you're around that man ever again
what did I say will happen?
I will die.
How will you die?
In great pain.
Good job.
Seal.
He did irritate a powerful person.
Besides, he is now being hated.
There will be more coming after him.
Please take care of him
be his shadow.
Seeing Kang Dong Suk care
he must be worthwhile.
Then to me...
is he the set of black plant or...
a bundle of money?
Hey, wake up.
Wake up now!
- What is it?
- Where is the coffee?
Gosh, coffee is in the
cupboard over there.
Not that instant coffee...
Do you have any brewed coffee?
We don't have that here.
What kind of house doesn't
have proper coffee?
Hey you.
Since you're up, go
clean up the toilet.
It's too dirty to sit on.
What?
This has gotten too much. Hey!
Am I your servant or what?
Where do you think you
are to be playing princess?
How dare you speak to me so rudely?
When you look like a mole, seriously!
Hey, how old are you?
Me?
I'm as old as your fat cheek, why?
Seriously! Man!
Ji Hyuk, can you kick her out?
Who is kicking out whom?
- This is my house.
- What?
You were trying to sell this, right?
I signed the contract with
the landlord directly.
Now you guys are living
here rent free, okay?
You get out!
If you're not going to
listen to me, get out!
I will start with cleaning.
How is it so simple?
I thought Cho Wha Soo was well known.
There are all kinds of
rumors about him, but...
there is only little known about him.
It's known that he used to
be a gang member, but...
it's not confirmed, either.
About his estate, it's all rumors, too.
But no one knows for
sure how much they are.
Wow, he's one scary man.
Or he might turn out to be some nobody.
But the most reliable rumor is...
he hates losing his money.
If he suffers a loss
he punishes the one responsible.
How?
The punishment is quite simple.
The person dies.
I see.
Interesting.
We might not have to get
our hands dirty after all.
Whether it's a building or a company
I've never paid the full price.
You, the previous president of
Hyun Sung Distribution, and...
the main player, Manager Gu
that's why I hired you two.
Insiders know where it's rotting
better than the outsiders.
Take out the rotten area.
Take it out and bring it to me.
I will do the rest.
I understand.
Be careful.
Don't make me suffer a loss.
Didn't you say you
sent him off overseas?
Not overseas...
It's not important.
What matters now is...
Cho Wha Soo is working with him.
What?
Are you saying he won't
buy Hyun Sung distribution?
We don't have to make that
much of an effort yet.
Man, Hyun Sung Energy is bottoming out!
Banks are asking for
the loan back early.
The core of Hyun Sung is shaking, man.
I will talk to Dae Sam again.
Will that work?
Jin Ah blew it all off.
I am close to Myung Ho, so...
I will go talk to him personally.
Damn it.
How did this happen to Hyun Sung?
Now we have to beg Dae Sam
who's smaller than us?
What is Ji Hyuk up to?
You don't have to worry
about him, father.
Hey, don't underestimate him.
He rebuilt the company
you brought down.
He took care of the union matter
and even got Zaroque to join us.
Frankly
for three months, he did 100 times
better than you did for five years.
Then what should we do?
Should I go ask him to
take over the company?
Alright.
It's all my fault.
It was all my fault for having
him involved in the first place.
Don't kill him.
Keep him alive.
Keep him alive and I will
make him live like a bug.
Like a bug...
What do you think a big company
like Hyun Sung is afraid of the most?
- Prosecution?
- Well...
Most people will assume
it's the prosecution.
But...
to a company
they fear the IRS or an audit.
Why?
They can take their money away easily.
If they are afraid, it means
they are guilty of something.
We have to find out
what that something is.
When it's a distribution
company like Hyun Sung
it's the collusion.
If we can prove Hyun Sung
was involved in collusion
we can definitely grab
hold of their lifeline.
You still have it, Manager Gu.
- That's what we need to do.
- Yep.
By the way, what is a collusion?
Collusion?
According to Fair Trade Act
between companies
What it means is that...
in a village
if there are ten stores that sell Ramen
they all charge 100 won for one.
One day, suddenly...
The store owners get together.
They decided to charge
200 won for one Ramen.
Now people in the village
have to pay 200 won.
But it was originally 100 won.
It's bad, right?
Manager Choi.
Please help us this once.
I want to help you out too, but...
I don't know much to help you.
As you already know
As for the person in
charge of collusion
it's only known to people above
directors' level within the company.
When you were with the company
you didn't know, either.
Did you know?
I didn't know either.
See?
How am I supposed to know
what you didn't even know?
Plus...
what would you do with
that information?
You're trying to bring
down the company?
Hyun Sung Distribution
will be sold soon.
President Kang Dong Suk
already made up his mind too.
If it's sold off to us
we will provide you with
the maximum settlement.
We won't make you regret it.
About the sale it off
it's not a game between kids.
Why would Hyun Sung do that?
Of all people...
would they sell the company to you?
What are you talking about, huh?
When we had a problem
with the union last time
who took care of it when
the heads of the company gave up?
- He did.
- Didn't he?
When the deal with Zaroque
wasn't going well
who got the deal in the end?
He did.
I wasn't going to say this, but...
When you took the bribe last time
who forgave you?
Who was it?
It was him.
Don't speak rashly.
Manager Choi.
Please help us this once.
If you help us this once
we won't forget what you've done.
I'd really like to help too, but...
I don't have the
information that you need.
I really don't know.
I really know nothing.
I will pay for our drinks and go.
I don't know.
Don't worry about
paying for the drinks.
Just watch your mouth.
He really doesn't seem to know.
What do we do now?
Nothing we can do.
We will have to try
to find it ourselves.
Our terms are quite simple.
If you show us your cash power that's
large enough to buy our company
Do you
have the intention
to sell it to us?
Of course.
But I would like it if we
could speed up the process.
There is a need for
funds at our headquarters.
Well, I'm not sure.
Usually, the price tends to go down
when there is an urgency to sell.
First, show us that
you have enough cash.
We have to sell off
our real estate, too.
If there is not a guarantee
there is no reason not to sell.
I guarantee.
There is no other person to sell it to.
Yes, I understand.
Sooner or later
We will stop by.
Sure, I will expect you.
- Are you done?
- Yes.
Let's go.
There is a place I want to take you.
Where?
Just follow me.
Why does he suddenly want
to bring a girl over?
Anyway, Dong Suk says he's
bringing over his mate.
Doesn't this feel like a dream?
What if he brings someone weird?
No way.
He's not the kind of person
to make rash decisions.
He will definitely bring someone
who is a good match for him.
I'm home.
Oh, there you are.
How come you came alone?
Hi.
You said you'd bring a
girl you'd like to marry.
I will introduce her to you properly.
This is the woman I'll marry.
Dong Suk.
I'm sorry.
You might resist, so I
didn't tell you sooner.
Dong Suk.
What is this about suddenly?
It's not suddenly.
We've been going out for a long time.
We just haven't told you.
It's something you can't talk about.
Then you should've
never talked about it.
No.
I should tell you now.
No!
This is not you...
I will pretend I didn't hear any.
Mi Ra.
In my opinion
Dong Suk was drawn to you temporarily.
He was playing with you.
You can understand that, right?
Instead of my son
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, so...
Mother.
Please just accept it.
She will be your daughter-in-law.
I will never change my
mind about her ever.
Dong Suk, are you
thinking clearly or not?
You're the one and only
son in our family.
You're the heir to Hyun Sung.
Then you should've brought
the right woman for that.
Father.
Can't you let me do what I want?
We never know when my
heart will stop again.
Are you threatening me now?
- Honey.
- So what?
Since you're sick, we should let
you do whatever you want, huh?
Whether your parents get upset or...
our family gets crushed.
Are you saying you don't care?
Do you know what we went
through to save you?
You did that to save me, right?
So if I die, it becomes
all useless, right?
What?
I will do my work at the company.
I will do it diligently.
Not for you two
I will work hard for myself.
I have to be the best.
Whether it's work or love.
Fine. Do whatever you like.
I will not consider Jin Ah
or you as my children.
Whether you move out of
the house to live with her
do whatever you like.
Instead, do not show
your face ever again.
Damn it!
You don't have to look like
you've done a terrible thing.
It's okay to be brave.
You're like my other heart.
She's a daughter of the driver
who worked at our house.
Of all women, why her?
He's determined to ruin our family.
Let's approve of them.
What?
Are you crazy?
We have to keep our son safe first.
We shouldn't irritate him.
What if something goes wrong?
Where would we send
him again this time?
China or the Philippines?
Should we send him even to Africa?
Marriage means nothing.
If he gets bored
we can send her away.
Like Ji Hyuk recently...
We will dispose of her after using her.
I...
you give me the creep sometimes.
You're scary.
What is this?
It's not much.
It's his security deposit.
This won't be enough at all.
Just take it back.
First, go help the ones
who are desperate.
It will make me feel better at least.
Where are you going to live then?
I never had a place to
live to begin with.
If this is what you want
there is nothing I can do.
How is everybody doing lately?
Don't get me started.
Mr. Song gave up the store and...
has been drinking every day.
Because of the loan
interest, Mrs. Oh...
has been in and out of the bank to beg.
Because of the tuition,
Myung Ran's mom...
she's in tears all the time.
Tell them to wait a little longer.
A little bit.
According to what I heard
A meeting takes place during work
time, not during their lunch time.
So he should be among the
ones who are leaving now.
He's the one.
Pardon?
We should follow that man.
No, he's not the one.
When it comes to a meeting
they are supposed to use the public
transportation to avoid a tail.
So he's not the one.
He's the one.
Who is he?
How can you tell by just looking?
- What took you so long, honey?
- Sorry.
He's having an affair.
He's the one.
Who is he?
The one in the black suit?
He's a car salesman.
He's the one.
Who is he?
Wait a second.
He's Manager Song from the
purchasing department...
If it's Purchasing department...
It's possible.
I can sense it.
Can't you?
It's definitely him.
You came for massage, huh?
We will give you a special treatment.
Will you take one?
The terms of sale aren't bad.
Just tell me whether
Dae Sam will consider it.
Well, there is no reason not to.
With one condition.
Keep this between us
until the deal goes through.
When the contract is ready, call me.
I will convince my
father in the meantime.
- Sure.
- I will go.
This is driving me crazy.
As far as I know, the secret meeting
takes place only once a month.
If we miss it this time
we will have to wait a month for it.
We have a problem.
In the meantime, Dong Suk...
he will try to sell it
to someone else.
I finally found him.
What?
It's Manager Choi.
Where is he going during his work hour?
Wait.
When we met up with Manager Choi,
actually I felt something.
Manager Gu.
Did he ever buy us drinks before?
He's not someone who
would do that, right?
Now I think about it,
you are right.
But that day, he definitely
said he'd buy us the drinks.
It was because something
was bothering him.
Someone who acts kind
all of a sudden...
is usually in the wrong.
I'm positive this time.
Follow me quietly.
He's from Dae Sam.
He's from Kang Sang Food.
I even know his name.
That's Park Yong Chul at Yi Ban Group.
I think this is it.
Thank you.
Dong Suk has gotten stable now.
Especially gaining his sense
of mental stability...
As his mother, I am
relieved to see that.
It's all thanks to you.
No, I didn't do anything.
But it will be hard.
You know that, right?
Yes, I understand, ma'am.
Mi Ra.
You've been very good to my family.
You will be good to Dong Suk too.
However...
is this marriage a
future you can handle?
Whether this is for you or not
think carefully.
I will.
How much is it?
It's 53,000 won.
Let's eat before we start.
Good job.
Tell your boss that you lost the bowls.
Be careful.
By the way
What price are you
thinking of at Bum Yang?
We will follow the price
that Hyun Sung decides on.
We'd appreciate it.
It's gotten a lot brighter.
What kind of emergency is this?
It wasn't even that dark.
You just don't understand, do you?
Without this, it's dark here.
I will go.
- Already?
- Why not?
What do you want me to do?
Since you helped me, I
will give you food.
I brought the meat and...
I even bought the rice and the sauce.
I got most of the food here.
What did you really make?
All good?
Do you think I'd do
that for just anyone?
It's your lucky day today.
Man, it's weird.
I always seem to pay for everything.
But every time you take
the credit for it.
The reason is your face.
What?
You are a fat squid
and I'm the princess.
If you want to close the
gap between us and...
try to go out with me
this is not much of an investment.
I never said I'd want
to go out with you.
You're giving up too easily.
Have courage. You can do it.
There will be lots of
mountains to climb.
The only merit you offer is that
you work at a meat restaurant.
But I've decided to give you a chance.
You and I are the only people in here.
If you let this chance go by
you might regret it for
the rest of your life.
Oh my, I might be drunk.
Oh my, I'm dizzy.
Are you dizzy?
Oh my goodness!
So Hae Ra, what are you doing in here?
Mom.
Hello.
With someone who looks like a thief
what were you doing in here?
- It's just that...
- And you!
Didn't you say you'd gone
to Australia to study?
Why are you here?
You, come here!
- You lied to your mother?
- I won't do that again.
How long will you live off your mother?
Mom!
I had my reasons.
What reasons?
Why didn't you go to
Australia to study?
What's the reason?
It was because of him over there.
What?
That man talked me into staying here.
I lost all the money because of him.
- You bastard.
- No.
I only bought her meat...
You hit on Hae Ra with meat, huh?
You.
Oh no.
- Ouch!
- You thief!
You stop right there!
No, ma'am.
I'm the victim.
I only bought her things...
You bought her meat?
I only ate meat.
You bastard.
Mi Ra.
I replaced the light bulbs and...
Hae Ra wanted to have
pork belly, so I got her some.
But she walked in and...
Mom.
By the way
What price are you
thinking of at Bum Yang?
We will just follow the
price Hyun Sung decides.
I'd appreciate it.
We got it.
With this, we can throw a
big punch.
Mister.
I won't make victims like you again.
Absolutely not.
What? Wedding?
Oh my, congrats, sister.
You finally made it.
Get back into position.
How dare you?
Did you make that decision
after careful thoughts?
Yes.
You got his parents' approval?
Yes, almost...
Mom, why are you worried?
Now you won't have to drive a bus.
Dong Suk will not let you
drive a bus, will he?
Stay out of it.
If you want
I won't stop you.
You've been good at living on your own.
Considering the fact
that Dong Suk chose you
he doesn't seem like a bad guy.
But, Mi Ra.
If you marry him
do you think you will
be happier than now?
So now
after selling the buildings
and properties
how much money did we get so far?
So far
we have half of the
money suggested.
We only have that much?
Because we're in hurry,
we have no choice.
If this deal doesn't go through
we will end up losing
about ten billion won.
What do you think?
Isn't this a solid evidence?
If we hand this over to
Fair Trade Commission
they will get charged with
a large penalty.
Then who else will buy such
Hyun Sung Distribution?
Naturally...
Hyun Sung Distribution will come to us.
What do you think?
Who came up with this idea?
Ah, it was obviously him.
- It was all thanks to him.
- Don't do that.
If you submit this
you will be arrested instead.
Pardon?
For illegal wiretapping.
Without such knowledge
how can you work?
To make this work with Hyun Sung
we have to have someone
in this conversation as our witness.
Did you know that?
That's how it becomes effective.
That sounds right now.
Go get someone as our witness.
I will say this one more time.
Don't make me suffer a loss.
About the life you've
been living until now
you can't erase it all.
It'll make us uncomfortable too.
Perhaps you will be most uncomfortable.
- Lady, what are you doing?
- Sir!
- Can I talk to you, please?
- Lady!
Please, sir.
Let her come in.
Sir.
How can you possibly charge the
deceased with such a ridiculous crime?
My husband would not have done that.
He couldn't possibly have
embezzled the company money.
Do you have evidence that he didn't?
- About that...
- Think carefully.
Driver Song has already passed away.
We can't send him to prison.
But still...
How could you charge him wrongly
when he's already dead?
Ma'am.
You said you have two daughters, right?
Without any recommendation letter
are you sure you can support
them in the future?
Pardon?
Their tuition until college
and living expenses...
Hyun Sung will provide them.
If your daughters want
they can come work at Hyun Sung too.
More than Driver Song who passed away
keeping your daughters safe
isn't that what he
would have wanted too?
Thank you.
Are you asking me to
betray Hyun Sung now?
What betrayal are you talking about?
You deceived us first.
That's true.
I was wrong, but...
this is a separate issue.
If I come forward as a witness
would Hyun Sung leave me alone?
Obviously, I will get fired.
Where else will I get a job?
Would Hyun Sung let me
go on and live my life?
How could you say that
when you know what it's like?
When we buy Hyun Sung
We will definitely give you a good
position within the company.
Sir.
If you do this
will you be able to
take over Hyun Sung?
Don't think so rashly.
I understand where you are coming from.
Can't you just trust us this once?
Between you and me, we had loyalty.
Loyalty?
Because of it
me, my wife, and my kid
what if we have to live on the street?
If you go against a big company
you could ruin your life.
Just go back to living
your previous life.
I'm begging you, Manager Choi.
Please help us this once.
This is the only way to save
everybody and Hyun Sung.
I'm begging you.
No...
Please don't call me again.
I'm going abroad for my
vacation today, anyway.
I won't be able to answer your calls.
Jung Sun.
How did it go?
I gave the president
the contract today.
It sounds like he's signing
the contract with Dae Sam tonight.
Tonight?
Okay, thank you.
She said President Kang will sign
the contract with Dae Sam tonight.
If he signs the contract with Dae Sam
we will lose the deal for good.
Dae Sam is also all about
making money, too.
Including the compensation
for the people at the marketplace
we may have lost it all.
We will have to think
about another method.
Isn't it too late?
You can't say that now.
Cho Wha Soo is a scary man.
He has his own set of laws.
Don't worry about people
at the marketplace right now.
Worry about yourself.
So you can't let this deal fall apart.
I might have a way.
Hi, Manager Gu.
I'm sorry to ask you such a favor.
We're in a jam now, so...
Did Ji Hyuk ask you to do this?
No, it was my idea.
Since you are on the FB team
I thought you had access
to such information.
What do you think?
I'm not in charge of
that, to begin with.
Even if I know how
I wouldn't want to do that.
It was too much to ask.
Manager Gu.
It's reckless to fight
against Hyun Sung.
Go stop him.
He will never win.
I also know it's reckless.
But it's not only for him.
You know that.
He's not someone who is
after his own interests.
If Hyun Sung distribution
gets sold off to Dae Sam
who will get hit hardest?
It's the people at the marketplace.
The people at the marketplace
who are like family to Kim Ji Hyuk.
Dae Sam will not
compensate them properly.
Then the people will get
kicked out to the street.
One of them already killed himself.
To prevent any further damage
in my opinion
it's right that Kim Ji Hyuk
takes over Hyun Sung Distribution.
Let's go.
- Get ready.
- Yes, sir.
[Someone is hacking
into your computer.]
Stop the elevator.
Why are you in a hurry?
So Mi Ra.
Mi Ra.
- Dong Suk.
- Here you are.
I've been looking for you.
Let's go. You need to come with me.
Sir.
I have an urgent matter
to discuss with her.
- If you don't mind...
- I'm in a hurry too.
Sir, it's about...
Talk to her tomorrow.
Let's go, Mi Ra.
Where are you?
You should've told me
about this earlier.
I wanted to see you like
this as soon as possible.
You look so beautiful.
Although I am the one
who made this gown
I had no idea it would be this pretty.
Is it because of her?
It's true.
That's why.
Would you like to see any others?
[Mi Ra, where are you?]
[Mi Ra, we have to get it now.
We don't have time.]
[Mi Ra, please.]
I like this gown.
I don't think I should try others on.
What are you talking about?
One gown won't be enough for me.
It's just that...
We will be ready quick.
Please wait a little bit.
Let's go.
- Manager Gu!
- Mi Ra!
Here it is.
Thank you.
Mi Ra, by the way...
What's taking this long?
Wow, it's pretty.
I like this one better.
What took so long?
- What?
- Well, the size didn't fit well.
We had to fix it a little bit. Sorry.
- Would you like to see the back?
- Sure.
Turn to the front.
Would you like to see one more?
What do you think?
Okay.
Let's go on a plane now.
Shall we take off the jacket?
- Not taking it off?
- Take it off.
Yes, I just came in to gate 12.
Where? K?
- Here!
- I see.
- Where is Manager Choi?
- Over there.
Manager Choi!
Long time no see.
How have you been?
Sorry. There was an
urgent matter at work...
Can we talk to you?
Did you secure the cash now?
Yes.
I can even show it to you now.
I see.
Then I will talk to you
later this afternoon.
As soon as we confirm it,
let's sign the contract.
By the way
about the price for the sale.
We are in such a hurry.
We will meet the reasonable
price you offer.
I understand.
Now it's time to throw
in our last hand.
What do you think?
Your wife can go on vacation
all happy if she sees this, right?
How could you?
FB team.
Scary, huh?
This is how things work in a company.
Did you really have to go this far?
Can't you understand why?
So please help us, Manager Choi.
Why would I pull this
dirty trick on you?
What are you doing, sir?
Manager Gu.
When you said you could convince him
you meant blackmailing
him with this trash?
I wouldn't do this
even if I'm a punk.
Go ahead.
Your family is waiting for you.
Have a good trip.
Sorry about your trouble.
- Let's go now.
- Daddy!
Let's go.
Even if we are in a jam
we shouldn't destroy a family.
Families are off-limit.
Now Hyun Sung Distribution
has gone over to Dae Sam.
What about President Cho?
He won't leave us alone.
We will still need to go see him.
I swear!
In my life, the only president is...
President Kim Ji Hyuk.
You're the only one for me.
What do we do now?
Can we trust that?
Excuse me.
Yes, sir.
When will you sign the
contract with us?
What price are you thinking about?
How about four hundred billion won?
Oh my.
There is a big difference
from what we have in mind.
I'm sorry, but let's
just forget about this.
I don't think you can
What do you mean?
In our hands
we have evidence and a witness
about your collusion.
We are thinking about submitting
this to Fair Trade Commission.
Of course, we will share
this with Dae Sam too.
Then...
will Dae Sam try to buy
Hyun Sung Distribution?
They will have to pay the
penalty on top of it.
Do you really need to do that?
I think four hundred billion
won is a fair price.
I understand.
I lost.
Okay.
Come by my office with
the contract tomorrow.
I will.
I will see you tomorrow then.
He wants to sign the contract tomorrow.
Good work.
Yes!
Congrats.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Let forget about the deal.
Really?
Are you sure you've become
the president of Hyun Sung again?
That's right.
I will become the president
of Hyun Sung Distribution again.
You're sure, right?
If this turns out to be a lie again
you will die in my hands.
Gosh, have you always
been lied to or what?
If I go and sign the contract tomorrow
I will become the president
of Hyun Sung again.
You're the same porcupine I know.
Hooray for porcupine!
I knew that he would
take care of it all.
It really happened.
Thank you all.
You trusted me and waited for me.
Now your struggles are
really over!
I really feel like that.
We will have 30% off on
Ddukbokgi and sausage.
Hey, what are you doing?
Wow, you made all this?
I was bored, so I made this.
- Wow.
- Hey, watch it!
You won't spit it out?
Good.
I didn't mean to spit it out.
My tongue rejected it.
What?
What smells so good in here?
Ji Hyuk.
- Wow.
- You're home.
- What is all this?
- Try.
I tried so hard...
- It should be good.
- Really?
Ji Hyuk...
Is it good?
Try this one too.
Hey.
What happened to your hands?
It hurts.
Hold still.
All better.
Don't try to cook again.
Doesn't this look like a ring?
What?
About the witness
they seemed to have used our
personnel information from FB team.
What are you talking about?
So Mi Ra pulled out some private
information on Manager Choi.
How is it related to this
deal with President Cho?
He's in charge of our
company's collusion.
If they blackmailed him with
his private information
he may be cooperating with them.
When was that?
It was the day when I ran
into you at the lobby.
Turn to the front.
How are you, sir?
How are you?
In my opinion
it was a reasonable price for the sale.
What do we do?
I can't sell off the
company for this price.
Why are you doing this?
Does this old man have to
involve a dirty trick?
Hyun Sung Distribution filed for
chapter 11 earlier today.
What do you mean?
I heard that you even sold
all your properties.
That became useless, huh?
I even heard that you suffered
a loss in the process.
Subtitles by DramaFever