BATTLE IN HEAVEN
Shit!
How did it happen?
The day is about to break.
I'll run over to the shop
and see what we can do.
So, the baby didn't even cry?
Just a little scream.
What a fuck-up!
Yeah, too bad about the money.
I'm not talking about that.
You're right... poor Vicky.
Poor Vicky?
The baby died, not its mother.
Understand?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah...
You and your yeahs.
Ma'am?
Ma'am!
- What's for sale?
- Everything there.
How much are the clocks?
Depends which one.
How many hands do they have?
Four.
Are they authentic
''made in Taiwan''?
They were shipped from Paris.
Is the jelly free?
No, you have to pay for it.
How much is it?
Depends, there's water ones
and milk ones.
What flavors?
Strawberry, eggnog,
toffee, coconut,
aniseed, lemon, sherry...
bubble gum...
Hurry-up you bugger, I'm late!
I'm going to the airport
to pick-up the general's daughter.
I'll see you tonight.
What's in the cakes?
One moment, please.
As usual.
Sorry, what is it you wanted?
- What's in the cakes?
- ''Sugus''.
- How much are they?
- Forty pesos.
I'll have one.
Here's fifty.
Here's your change. Thank you.
Your jacket, mister!
Is he drunk orwhat?
Excuse me, please.
Stop it, you damn pervert!
What are you looking at?
Thank you.
Hello Marcos.
They sent you to Cancun?
What a pain in the ass.
I wanted to see you so bad
I came back early.
Well, to see you.
Fine.
What are you talking about?
Well, if you interrogate me
I might become suspicious.
OK, we'll see.
I'll stay at your place
for the weekend then.
I'll ask Marcos to tell my parents
I didn't show up.
You won't be back before noon?
In that case,
I'm going to work all night.
And in the morning,
I'll come sleep at your place.
Wake me up when you arrive.
Yes, I really want to see you.
That sounds good!
Of course, Jaime.
I won't hang up, darling.
But don't take long.
Remember
that ugly uniform, Marcos?
Of course, Ana.
How could I forget?
Yeah, but wasn't it much better
when I was there?
- Yes, Ana...
- You're back, love?
It's just that
we went past my old school...
and I asked Marcos
ifhe remembered driving me there.
What a pain.
I hope you will!
Really?
Let's see
how you talk in bed then...
See you tomorrow.
Listen...
I love you.
Let's go to the boutique instead,
Marcos.
I'll turn at the corner, Ana.
Jaime's ice-skates are fixed, Ana.
Did they do a good job?
Great Ana,
I took them to a digital engineer.
Here they are...
Razor-sharp... He'll be happy.
Pardon?
Nothing,
just turn the music on, Marcos.
Wake up,
you fucking piece of shit...
and go fuck your mother
you faggot!
Get moving, damn it!
Now turn off the music, Marcos.
Are you all right, Marcos?
It's just my mother.
Her body's full of water.
Is that all?
Yes, Ana.
Well, I've never seen you
so absent-minded.
No, Ana.
Well at the boutique,
you're coming in...
so I can set you up
with one of my friends.
Can we do it another day, Ana?
Don't tell me
you're faithful to yourwife?
Yes, Ana. But sometimes
I go out with other women.
You've always wanted
to see the boutique, right?
Yeah... whatever you say, Ana.
Lie down.
Ana!
The fatso is out of order.
He says
he only wants it with you.
What are you doing, Marcos?
I was just taking the condom off.
You've worked for my dad
for 15 years.
You've known me
since I was a child.
You're the only one
who knows about this place...
I invite you here...
and you go telling my friends
you want to screw me.
How's that?
All I said was
itwas your idea, Ana.
You think I didn't notice how
you stared at me at the airport?
What's wrong?
Tell me.
The thing is my wife and I
kidnapped a baby...
and he died this morning.
It was an accident.
Why are you telling me this,
Marcos?
You asked me.
Those things you shouldn't tell.
Take my bags to Jaime's.
The maid will open the doorfor you.
Take the car with you as well.
See you on Monday.
Now leave, Marcos!
Just don't tell anyone.
Full service?
Pardon? Yes.
Mexico loves you...
You are our Virgin mother.
We're going to heaven...
and you hold the key.
And we honor you...
on this pilgrimage.
What do you think?
They're a flock of sheep...
How many are there?
The pilgrims have been coming
for 3 days and nights.
But I was talking about the car...
and the engine is fine.
We're almost there.
Careful with Grandma.
What's this music, son?
Don't worry, Grandma.
Mister! Put in 200 pesos, please!
And change that music now!
Irving, Irving...
Wake up, your dad's arrived.
Sorry for being angry
this morning.
We've got to talk.
Did you lose your glasses, love?
They were all scratched anyway.
Take your old pair then.
I told Ana.
Your boss's daughter?
Are you fucking crazy, or what?
I feel better.
You're not well, are you love?
I understand...
Now you'll have to make sure
she keeps her mouth shut...
We can't have
the princess talking.
You better leave her out of this!
You fucked up, you idiot!
Vicky came to me crying today...
she said she's had no news
from the kidnappers for 3 days...
I'm afraid that if we don't call her
tonight, she'll go to the police.
If her husband were still alive,
he'd have broken both our necks.
Should we go
to Sunday's pilgrimage?
Where do you get
those fucking ideas?
After all the shit we've done...
don't you realize?
He's not big enough
to come by himself?.
Why don't you ask him?
Stop it, Dad!
Your pet is waiting for you.
I brought your car Ana!
Go prove you're a man, son.
- Bye, handsome.
- Thank you.
- Wait for me outside.
- Yes, Ana.
Fuck off you faggots!
I took her twice up the shitter!
Tona, Juanita, come get
our stuff from the trunk.
- What's the shitter?
- The shitter?
You'll learn soon enough,
my dear...
Watch out!
Good morning, Juanito.
What's up, Tonita?
Hello, Tonita.
Get inside Ines. What kind of time
is this to come home?
- I'll tell your parents.
- Come on, Tonita.
Good morning, fatso.
What is it now, Marcos?
I told you
I'd see you Monday, Marcos.
I wanted to tell you
something, Ana.
Good morning.
He likes to listen
to the morning birds.
What you really want
is to fuck me, isn't it Marcos?
No, Ana.
Where's my car?
Up the road.
We just came that way.
You didn't ask me before.
Calm down, Marcos!
If I won a million in the lottery...
I'd forget about you.
You'll have to turn yourself in,
Marcos.
You have to go now, Marcos.
Ladies & gentlemen...
20 seconds from now the PUMAS
will once again be crowned
champions of Mexico.
One of the most prestigious
squads of the country...
an institution
that loves expansive football...
PUMAS is the home of artists
and imagination...
Ladies & gentlemen
the PUMAS are champions...
champions of Mexico!
How our league has changed...
now that financial speculation
has stopped...
now that we've reduced
the number of foreign players...
What's good for Mexican football,
is good for Mexico!
And now overto Andre,
on the field with Vignatti...
Here is the great
Argentine keeper, Vignatti.
Finally, champion with PUMAS...
As they would say
in your country: ''refashion''.
This is unreal.
This is the best thing
that has ever happened to Vignatti...
I want to thank my family...
who convinced me
to come to Mexico.
This is a huge league,
PUMAS is a major team...
Now we'll go and celebrate
with our families in Argentina...
with ourwives and friends...
This is unreal...
The best thing
that ever happened to Vignatti...
The best thing.
Dad! Dad!
Hurry up, we're going
to the countryside!
Marcos, my love,
don't make the family wait.
What are you doing, Dad?
Stop crying, Vicky.
You'll see your baby very soon...
We'll raise the money, Grandma
will sell the house. Don't worry...
Tomorrow's the pilgrimage.
Tomorrow I'm turning myself in
to the police...
Forgive me.
We'll be separated
but you'll always be in my heart.
I couldn't live without you.
Please wait one more day.
Wait for the pilgrimage.
I feel something's
going to happen there...
Something's going to change...
What's a single day,
for God's sake?
OK. Now promise.
Swear on our love.
Thanks, love.
Are you raising
the flag tomorrow?
Yeah, I have to go twice.
Well, after you've raised it
at dawn...
come pick me up at home
so we can go together
on the pilgrimage.
Then at sunset I'll go with you
to bring the flag down.
I haven't seen you in action
for a long time.
OK.
All these clouds
are making my eyes itch.
Children, stop playing around!
Who do you think
does the washing?
Marcos! Take care of the children,
for God's sake!
Come over here, children!
I can't see you!
It's dangerous to play like that!
Marcos, come back to the car!
Good job, Marcos.
See you tomorrow.
Yes, General.
Thank you.
Have a good morning.
Good morning, Marcos.
You've come to see Ana?
- Just for a minute, Jaime.
- Come in.
Thank you.
Were you on top or underneath
this morning?
On top.
Come in the living room.
Don't be stupid!
I'll let Ana know.
Hello, Marcos.
Jaime is going to buy
the newspaper.
Yes, Marcos. I'll be right back.
I'm turning myself
in to the police now, Ana...
Sit down then.
Won't you mind us
being separated, Ana?
No, Marcos.
I'll keep you in my heart.
Goodbye.
You forgot your jacket, Marcos.
Take care, Marcos.
Yes.
What do you mean ''naked''?
Thank you.
Goodbye.
The suspect's cellphone
was found, Inspector.
He was seen half-naked
in the street 5 minutes ago...
and he wanted
to join a pilgrimage.
Some pilgrims showed him
the way to the Basilica...
They sent him on a bus...
as they thought he was a spastic.
Ma'am, you're coming with us...
We're going to find
your beloved fucker...
And your child stays here
with the lieutenant.
Station calling Blue Wolf...
We have some information
from the house.
I copy you station.
The kidnapper's son just
led us to a baby's body.
Ask for backup, damn it!
Jesus will help you change!
This is the way of the light!
Save yourself!
I have the key to salvation!
You that are addicted to drugs!
Those pills...
They get you nowhere!
There you are again brother!
I will solve all your problems!
You poor sheep! Jesus loves you!
Return to the path!
Take this. You are saved!
I have saved you!
Yes, brothers!
This is the only proof!
You have your medicine now!
Go forward! No more drugs!
No more alcohol!
No more women!
No more tits!
We're here, Inspector.
Inspector, how are you doing?
I must inform you, Inspector...
Inspector, I must inform you that
the girl who was stabbed...
has just died.
It's disgusting, Chief.
Hello station...
Calling station.
Yes Officer.
We have information...
The suspect has been
located near the Basilica.
Beware, he's likely to be armed!
We bring these gifts for you.
Oh, father!
This is our song.
I've tried to live
by your light...
we love justice and peace.
We know you will come...
On your feet...
and bring peace to the poor.
Please.
Let me go in first.
We've been waiting so long...
I love you so, Ana.
I love you too, Marcos.
Subtitles: Benjamin Mirguet
In memory of Alejandro Ferretis