Catch him! Stop!
Over there!  That way!
Catch him!  Stop!
Father
Wake up, Nam-yi!
Are you afraid?
I'm asking,
are you afraid?!
Yes, father
That fearful heart,
look squarely in the eye of it
that's how you come out of it
Father!
Don't forget,
it's Kim Mu-seon in Gyeseong
Got it?
...I want to stay
with you, father...
You're now Ja-in's father
You must take care of your sister 'til you die
Do you understand?!
- Yes
- Get up
Father!
Get out of here, Nam-yi!
Capture the traitor!
Father! Father!
Father!
I have to
go back to father!
Didn't you hear father?
Father is still fighting!
I have to take the bow to him,
so he can win!
Stupid! Father told us to take it
Do you even know what that implies?
I'm gonna go!
Brother, let's go back
Let's give him the bow, please
We've captured the traitor!
Now, find his children!
Hwal ("bow")
Did you witness
your father's end?
Are you Ja-in?
So, did your father leave
any last words?
People ignorant of foreign affairs
support the King...
...so there will surely be a war.
The country and
the safety of people are...
...like a lamp before a storm
Aye, what can be done?
I entrust the bow to you
until the child grows up
"Push like pushing a mountain...
...and pull like holding a tiger's tail"
Gap-yong, please ask my wife
to get them new dresses first
Yes, sir
Go ahead and change
Don't be going outside
without caution
If someone asks you
who you are...
...don't answer until an elder
of this house answers first
You got that?
Father.. father..
father..
"You're now Ja-in's father
You must take care of your sister 'til you die"
Do you understand?
[13 years later]
.. This way! This way!
.. That way! That way!
Ugh.. darn it!
It's hit!  It's hit!
It's dead!
Wa.. wa.. wait!
Why?
What is this place?
This is just..
Isn't this tiger trap?
Let's hurry and carry it out
Wa.. wait..
Th.. that is..
I heard it
It.. tiger! Tiger! Tiger!
Tiger! Tiger!
? Tiger, tiger,
? my tiger at Mt. Dongak
? I'll give you a rice cake
? So fetch me a bride
There's this place in Gyeseong
where all beautiful girls are
I went there and
they were all just looked homely
Really?
So the most beautiful girl
in Songak...
..is our lady Miss Ja-in
If only things
had gone better for her...
...distinguished guys would be
standing in a line mile long for her
Now 'nuff with banter
and have some drink
Speaking of which, I think
Madam is so harsh...
...seriously, isn't Miss Ja-in
out of Master Seo-gun's league?
Can any imperfection
be found with Miss Ja-in?
And what about her womanly figure?
She beats an angel
from heaven any day
What has Young Master done?
Did he pass the civil service exam?
You're right
I said that's enough!
Brother,
did I say something wrong?
C'mon, enough already,
you know the whole story
It's because I know the story
and it suffocates me!
I told you to stop already!
/Idiot!/
Hey, jerk,
I even got on your side...
Hey! You just cuss'd
at me, didn't you?
You cuss'd at me, didn't you?!
You bastard,
you disrespect me...
...because you've played
around somewhat, eh?!
I'll rip your mouth wide today..
...and fix your bad habit for good!
You jerk!
Kang-du, please stop!
I came to have some drink
but it's a big mess here
Master, glad to see you
Eh..
Does it help with digestion
if you drink like this?
What made you have
a fun fight like this?
What made you come out
at this time of night?
Come here
I'll pour you a drink
Brother, this is no way
to have a drink tastefully
How about if we move
to a real nice place?
A nerd like you
know of any place to drink?
Well..
...you'll find out
once you get there
Whoa, there's surely a lot
of rare beauties for a drinking bar
Yes, this place is
well known for drinks
The drink does
taste different here
- The sword..
- Wait!
- I'll pour one
- What's with this?
Nothing at all
I just want to serve one
Serve one?
Please, receive one
Now.. I'm treated properly
as an older brother finally!
So.. I have...
...something I'd like to tell you
Brother, I'd like to
marry Ja-in
What did you say?!
Please approve, Brother
You're her guardian, aren't you?
Does your mother know about this?
And your father?
I only need to persuade them,
and that's all
Brother...
...I'm really.. desperate
Brother
Please approve for me
downloadbox.net
You and I are...
...brothers..
closer than regular friends
Who says you and I are closer
than regular friends?
It's like that 'cuz I said so
Are you insane or something?
How can family members
living under the same roof..
.. no.. that isn't it..
.. you want to marry a traitor's
daughter who's in hiding?
Are you trying
to ruin your own life?
I know exactly
what you're worrying about
My parents..
.. I will persuade them over
Brother.. we lived together
in the same house all that time..
.. they surely wouldn't
They surely suffered from
a lot of anxieties
'cause they lived with traitor's children
in their bosoms
And you want to put that yoke
back on your parents for life?!
- Brother
- And ! ..
.. how do you think Ja-in would be
under such mother-in-law?
Whatever anyone else say
I will not be detered
And ..
.. I can do anything
and everything for Ja-in
You can do anything
and everything..
Sure
- I'll make an offer then
- ?
Brother!
- What offer ..
- Is anyone here?
If you cut me...
...I'll give you Ja-in
But if you can't
I will cut you...
...and I'll leave
this town with Ja-in today
You got that?
Brother!
What kind of offer ..
Look at this weakling
How dare you covet my sister?!
I'm a son of a warrior too!
I'm being easy on you, Brother!!
I will never give my sister
to a dimwit nerd like you
I'd rather give her to
a butcher ..
A butcher would be
a lot better choice
This is enough
Sorry for my rudeness
Sit down!
Drinking, and even fighting!
Is life so easy for you?!
Yes, sir
My heart is at peace, and the world
seems laughable like a flea to me
It's been 13 years
since you came to this house
You abandoned desk study
and you stopped martial arts training...
...you wander outside all day
What are you going to do with your life?!
Can I take a civil service exam
by memorizing words? ...
Or can I plunder a country
by training in martial arts?
I'm nothing
but a traitor's child
I shall live through today
and I'll probably die tomorrow
How dare you?!?!
You really don't know
what an honest man your father was?!
- Yes I know
- And ?!
And ..
I did indeed see the final end
of such father! I sure did!
What good is a diligent life?
You stick yourself out to do...
..something great and you will
only get cut down by a sword
You're here like this
because you fear that too, isn't it?
Why you !@#$
If you have nothing more to say
then I'd like to go...
...and have one more cup
before I sober up
You know...
...I named Ja-in
when she was born
And Seo-gun was named
by your father
I approve of
his marriage to Ja-in
This way please
How have you been?
What are you doing here?
The guardian should be
sitting in his place
"Bow .. to .. groom .. first"
"Bow .. once .. in .. reply"
Master, it's your turn
What are you waiting for?
Are you all right?
How would you go through
the first night with such stupidity?
"Bow .. twice .. in .. reply"
.. be quiet will ya!
Get in position!
Close the gate! Close the gate!
Quickly, get ready!
Attack!
[Year 1636, the second Manchu invasion of Korea]
Get out of here!  Run away!
Kang-du!
Escort the Prince!
Ja-in!
No, you bastards!
She's my daughter!
My dear wife!
Young Master!
Father ..
My child ..
Father!
Where are they taking us?
It's a war
Don't be sad
My cousin
Our Mangudai siege strategy...
...he broke through with a bow.
I've never seen someone
shoot arrows like that in Joseon 'til now
It happened because
of our small number
I thought it's only
a weak arrow from a weak bow..
Their bow comes
from the same root as ours
It's short and thin,
but great for distance and mobility
We must never underestimate
Jushinta! Wanhan!
We now have more captives
than ourselves
It's all because
of your works, uncles
Have a safe trip back, Prince.
They're ready for you now
Come back quickly
I have much to plan with you
For our Manchu!
General, we are ready to move
Keep Prince safe, Hu-man
Yes, General!
I entrust the envoys too
Yes, sir!
Ja-in!
[King Injo escaped to Fort Namhan..
..ultimately surrendered
after a painful fight]
[500,000..]
[Many people,
with no regard to gender or age...]
[...were captured as prisoners and hostages]
[Much abuse and harsh march...]
[...had killed countless people]
Who will give the sacrificial rite
for my deceased father?
Father!
Please spare me!
There's a blue dragon
on the brown flag
Where is he now?
Please!
I will decide
after I hear your answer
To north..
everyone's headed north..
I don't know
any thing more
He was killed immediately
after the arrow went through the neck
They all did
We better hurry
It looks like
enemy soldiers' work
Take this girl!
General, there is
something you have to see
It happened all too quickly
He would appear for a moment
and then disappear again
And an arrow came
at me once again
It was from a place
where he ought to have stood
He speaks our tongue
And he's pursuing
our King Flag?
He clearly asked me
about it
Did he use red arrows?
How did you know?
downloadbox.net
I don't know who this is...
...but he's clearly
pursuing the Royal guard unit
By the way..
...he said something strange
Why aren't you killing me?
Killing is not
the purpose of my bow
He said killing is
not the purpose of his bow..
Stop hunting, and the elite unit
shall follow me immediately
Brothers!
We now go back to our motherland!
Interpreter!
Now..
..listen to me carefully!
/If you cross this river...
...you'll never be able to go back home/
You all know this right?
If you run away crossing
this Aprok river...
...you become a traitor!!
/I'll let go of whoever wants
to run away, so have them run/
Now..
We ..
He says to run away right now
if you want to!
Run away, run!
/It's your last chance
Don't you miss home?/
You know that you shouldn't
run away just because he tells you to!
/I will count to five/
/Go now
if you want to go back/
Just wait out the five count!
You should survive this anyhow!
- /One!/
- One!
- /Two!/
- Two!
- /Three!/
- Three!
- /Four!/
/This is the last count!/
What's going on?
Don't you move
It's useless
Wuri!
Father!
See you later!
Wuri, no! Don't!
/Joseon people!/
/You can go back home/
/However!/
/You can't go back alive!/
/Go!/
You see that?
He's just trying to tame us
Those damn savages!
Wuri!
I should step out
If even only one can survive
and get out of here...
...then people can keep
the hope alive, to run away alive
Master, you'll die
if you step out!
Come here
if you dare!
You have to overcome me first
before you cross here!
Anyone from our brothers...
...is a true warrior?!
You bastard!
Come crawl towards me
like your own king!
Else, I will pierce
through your heart!
Kill him!
You !@#$!
Why you..
Let's fight them together!
Ja-in..
Don't be too harsh on me
for not being able to protect her...
...didn't I give you my word before?
I said that I can do anything
and everything for Ja-in
Ja-in is probably
perservering well ..
Anyway, do you think
it'd be all right?
Even though you have their map,
if you cross the river...
...and come back,
you become a traitor...
...and you'll have
to answer to the king
King, who has forsaken the country
and his people, is already a great sinner
Wash her and bring her to me
You've brought
an interesting gal today
Please forgive me
Just take her clothes off
I am already married
Please don't let me
live this way!
Wait
When did you learn our tongue?
When I was a child, when my father
was based in northern territory
Then you must have learned
of the greatness of our Great Qing
Please, don't let me
live in shame
Even your king has submitted
and you think this is shameful?
How can a true warrior
keep persecuting the people...
...just because one achieves
a victory?
This is a tiger skin
My bravest uncle, Jushinta
has given it to me as a gift
It keeps me safe from
cold, hot, rain, and even fire
Even this soft leather
was hard as a stone at first
The owner has to tame it well
to make it into a good leather
Taming a leather
is very interesting
Tie her to a pole outside
until she cries for her life
Only the strategy map that
has our movements has disappeared
We must hurry to pursue him
We'll leave the bodies of
our brothers to the oncoming unit
We shall obey
We have followed
the right path
Those damned !@#$ savages!
Th.. that's Miss Ja-in..
Wait until the nightfall
What? Are we going to
have some special plan afterwards?
Even so, I don't think
charging like a bull is a good idea, sir
Just take a look, there is
just too many of them
We'll capture the captain
and exchange him with Ja-in
There's no other way
You think that's going to work?
Then.. how are we
going to get out?
After we get Ja-in, we'll cross Aprok
and then meet at this hut
By tomorrow noon, got it?
Yes, Brother
Nam-yi, but how are we capturing the captain?
We don't have any plan yet!
Kang-du, I have something
you two need to do
No fun at all
Men don't have spirit,
and women don't have constancy
I'm curious
What made you break down so easily?
Thirst?
Hunger?
Or despair?
Ka-in, my father said it's best
to rule man or beast with food
Seeing you, I think
those words weren't wrong
My father said hunger
makes your vision blurry
So he said to eat well
before the fight
Are you a soldier or something?
I am a daughter
of a warrior
I don't live just to live
or die just to die!
You impudent !@#$!
This is fun, yes, fun indeed!
Try it again!
C'mon, don't give up now
Who are they?!
Catch them!
Prisoners are escaping!
Prince, outside ..
Don't interfere,
you'll be executed if you disobey!
Get out!
That way!
Catch them!
This way!
Come this way!
That way!
You! Who are you?!
For our Manchu!!
Now I see
How foolish and stubborn
Joseon girl is
All you have to depend on
is a skewer
Our plan worked!
All we have to do now
is just run away!
Sorry, but you two
need to help me here
Master.. Master..
Master!
It's them!
Catch them!
What are you?
Are you all right?
Dear brother ..
I'm sorry ...
for getting here late
Let the Prince go!
Else this girl will die!
Dear wife!
Who the heck are you people?!
Wh.. what are you doing?!
Make a way!
Just shoot!
- Get out of here
- What about you brother?
You remember what I said?
We'll meet at noon tomorrow!
We'll wait for you there, Brother!
No, Brother!
We have to leave together!
You want all of us to die!
Get going now!
If we don't leave together
then we will die together 'stead
You want me to part
like this again ..
Let's go, dear wife, we can't
possibly leave together right now
Go and wait, I will live
through this and be there!
You think you can live
after doing something like this?
If I had thought of living through this
I wouldn't have done this
You say you came expecting death,
and yet are you afraid now?
The wood has turned into ash,
and the fire is dying out
Thank you,
for enduring this far
Where is the Prince?
He was murdered
General, he's over that way!!
Soldiers are pursuing him!
Nam-yi!
Glad to see you again!
So you're still alive!
What happened to Miss Ja-in,
and Master Seo-gun?
They should be ahead of us now
That's a good news indeed!
But we must hurry to follow them
They're probably pursuing them too
Wh.. what are those blokes?
There is a white one
and red ones too
Half-pounders
What? Half-pounders?
Only the arrows weigh a half-pound
They are more powerful than
even mechnical crossbows
Let's go back into the woods
Execute the Mangudai strategy!
We shouldn't go that way
Let's go this way!
We have to go around this way!
C'mon, let's go!
I think Kang-du is right!
Let's go!
It's a dead end,
so I think we got 'em
Catch 'em live
They have to die in pain
Hurry, hurry
Kang-du!
Be careful!
We must hurry!
Kang-du!
.. Kang-du!
It's already a miracle
that we made this far
So just leave me here now
Hurry now
Go now!
Leave now!
- Cut with your sword!
- I can't move my limbs!
Get moving!
It's a tiger trap .. you fools
It's the same way here
I am old,
and I don't think I can go any further
Gap-yong ..
- Gap-yong ..
- Get going now!
Keep Missy and Master safe!
All right, I shall depart
after I kill you
Shoot!
It's him
How surprising
it is to see him still alive ..
We cross over
Hurry and cross over!
Adai, hurry!
Let me go..
Go get him..
You can live..
He's farther away
We speed up now
I'll do it
Let me
Your foot is all swollen
But .. I heard that you get arrested
if you cross Aprok river again
Surely the same Joseon people
wouldn't treat us that way
It's just a nonsense to keep
people from running away
Dear husband ..
uh, that ..
That shoe..
I'll hold onto it
And ..
.. I'll get us some drinking water
Get back inside!
Dear wife!
Dear wife ..
Keep him cornered!
Got him!
He's going back
I'll ask you one question
At the cliff ..
Why didn't you shoot me?
Was it ..
.. out of contempt for me?!
He must die in pain
Cut off his limbs
Dodge!
Which direction?
I'm not sure
But there's only one path...
...so we can go after him
There is only one path?
We're near Aprok river
We pursue him immediately
Back to your senses, Hurau!
The mountain is haunted, General
Is this all there is to
the spirit of Manchu?
Hurau!
You lead us!
One
Two
Three
It's a baby arrow
You mean that secret weapon
used to attack our brothers...
...at the Namhan fortress?
But I've never seen one
that damaging
It's just missing a tip...
He merely broke one off to make it
But a baby arrow is
only a baby arrow!
Brother!
Don't come near!
Stop!!
Ja-in..
Dear wife!
Brother!
Finally.. is she the reason
why you've been so tenacious?
Are you calculating for the wind?
I already saw your bow
downloadbox.net
But what good would
your consideration of wind do?!
Were you afraid
because of your girl?!
Even if you're good
with curving arrows...
...your fear has killed you
and your girl
Now feel for yourself...
...the death of a beloved
Brother, don't!
You'll die if you pull
that arrow out!
You lost
Brother .. no !!
Are you going to
sacrifice this girl?!
Even the wind isn't helping you
Fear is .. something you look
squarely in the eye to rid of
Wind is.. not something you calculate
but overcome
Why.. you..
Brother!
Here.. I have one too
downloadbox.net
So you knew ..
'course I knew ..
'cause they were too big
How come you don't even know
your sister's shoe size?
So they were too big.. too big..
I thought
you're fully grown already
You still have more to grow
Ja-in
Let's go to our house
in Hanyang
Let's go there and ..
.. wear your flower shoes dandy and ..
Look
That's the land
we must return to
[1637, there were no efforts to repatriate
after the invasion of Manchu]
[Only a small number of people
returned on their own efforts]
Translation and timecoding
by Michael Han (clayjar@gmail.com)
Feel free to drop me a note
if you enjoyed the translation!
Support the artists and writers
by purchasing the DVD!
downloadbox.net