Adventure time Season 01 Business time
by Rumi(http://rumistar.blogspot.kr/)
Subtitles for English learners
I found another bike, and more computers.
What do you got?
I keep finding baby shoes!
WHAT THE HECK, MAN?!
And they're all lefties!
Sorry I'm not finding any loot.
Keep it together, chubby,
because I think we found enough scrap
to finish building our gauntlet dock
a dock that is also a gauntlet.
Aww. Building this gauntlet dock is hard, man.
Hard work sucks
Don't be lazy, Jake.
Incoming iceberg!
Whoa! That one's huge!
I got dibs!
Ooo. I hope it's not baby shoes.
[Gasps] It's a guy.
Creepy. It's a buncha guys.
You know what they remind me of?
Well-dressed pickles.
Stand back, Jake!
I'm gonna melt 'em outta there!
Full charge.
Whoa, don't roast 'em, man.
You gotta flambe.
Ah. Perfecto.
Bon appetit.
Hey! Can you hear me? Hello?
I don't think they made it.
Hey.
This one's got some kind of pack.
[Finn screams]
I remember... business.
Let go! Let go! Let go!
We... are businessmen.
Oooh... Well, I'm Finn and he's Jake.
What kind of business do you do?
Been frozen... so long,
I...
can't remember.
Can't remember!
Oh. Looking for help, your business?
We love work for you.
Nah. Adventurers don't need any help.
- Yes! Help us fix that dock.
Dock-ka?
Yeah! Right over there.
Yes. This dock-ka...
could be more... efficient.
No! Wait!
Jake, this dock is our fun pie.
We should be the ones to bake it.
But they're begging for it, Finn.
Just look at 'em.
[Murmuring] Build dock. Build dock.
Finn. These poor souls are lost without jobs.
We can't ignore their plight.
Uhh...
Go on guys, fix it up!
Woo!
Well... they do seem really happy to do it.
Of course, man.
They said they "love work for you."
Uhh... We finish.
Whoa!
Told you so.
Come on!
Let's try it out!
Yeah! Woo!
[Panting]
See? If we hire them full time,
they'll be back in business
and we'll be able to focus on fun stuff.
Everybody wins!
Maybe you're right.
You hear that, guys?
Maybe I'm right!
Really? Job?
With... ad-ven-tur-ers?
Yeah, mans!
Feels weird doing nothing.
Relax, man. This is your day off.
Help! Somebody help!
Trouble, dude!
Get your axe! I'll get my... wha?
Adventure pack... ready for you.
Hey, thanks man.
I have to say, Jake.
My sword is totally shiny and stinkin' sharp!
Uh huh.
Even my shoes feel different.
Not only are they clean,
I feel radder, faster, more... adequate.
Cool!
Help!
Don't cry, Hot Dog Princess!
Jake and I will fend off these battle cubes!
Man. I'm getting tired.
[Groan] Me too.
These cubes are... frickin' resilient.
Hey, business dudes!
Hold off these cubes so we can catch our breath?
Jake! They don't know how to fight.
Water. Orange slices. Help rehydrate.
These guys are great, right?
I gotta admit... they are helping.
Oh! I think I figured out how to defeat the battle cubes!
That's 'cause you had time to rest your body
and refresh your brain.
Ok! We'll take it from here, guys!
Yeah! Good work.
Grab all the cubes together!
Got 'em!
It worked!
Wake up, Hot Dog Princess.
You're free.
Oh! Thank you, Finn and Jake!
Especially you, Finn.
Ugh. She smells like old hot dog water.
I take one for team.
This is awesome!
You get a promotion, fella.
Take one for team, too.
Oh... Lost again!
My turn.
What's that?
Hero vision monitor.
Use satellite to tell us world problems.
Oh, wow. Anything going on?
Just small things.
You save stress for big thing.
Freakin' awesome, man.
What are they doing?
Takin' care of business.
Jake, hit me!
Mission complete.
Yeah!
We beat Adventure Master!
Holy moly!
We're adventure masters!
Woo! Yes!
I never knew being fat and lazy was so rewarding.
Yeah.
You're gut's so huge and moldable.
Hey!
Hold on a sec!
[Laughs] Man, that tickles.
I'm the Ice King, and I'll never find a bride
because I'm such a tool.
[Laughs] Alright, let me try.
I'm Princess Bubblegum and I'm a dork,
because I like science!
I've also got a really annoying voice
that Finn thinks is attractive!
[Laughs] That's a- Hey, what'd you say?
Ahh! Oh, my gosh!
Leave me alone.
All I said was "you're ugly," which is totally true.
Somebody help me! Oh no!
Man, I am not in the mood
for saving Lumpy Space Princess
Hey, business dudes!
What do you guys think?
Hmm... Just one monster. We do.
Right. We'll just save our strength
for the big adventures, then.
Ahh. Nice call, dude.
Imagine how awesome the adventure's going to be
when it's time for us to go out there.
I'm too tired to imagine stuff,
but I bet you're right.
To being great adventurers!
Oh, gosh.
Help us!
Huh? Jake! Did you hear that?
Yeah. Let the businessmen handle it.
Help! Please!
I heard it again.
Businessmen, dude.
Heeeeeelp!
Woo-hoo! Woo!
Jake! We messed up!
The businessmen have gone bat-crazy, dude!
Man, just let the businessmen handle it.
THE BUSINESSMEN ARE THE PROBLEM,
you lazy plug-hole!
Huh?
Guys!
Guys, stop it!
Stop it, guys!
Stop what, boss?
You're jacking up those Fuzzy Friends!
But... We're being heroes. Like you, boss.
We're protecting them.
Collecting them in our care-sack so they cannot be hurt.
It's the most efficient way to save people.
But you're making them unhappy!
Irrelevant! These people are in our care-sack.
Their happiness is not priority
I am your boss! And you guys are all fired!
Fi-red?
Nooo! Alright, guys.
Now I've gotta take you down... Finn style.
I'm kicking your care-sack, dudes!
Finn? Whoa... Crud.
I'm comin' buddy!
Ahh. I'm so fat, dude;
I don't know what to do.
[Gasp] That's it! Jake! Demoralize them!
What? Why?
Do it, man! I have a legit plan!
Ok, Alright.
Hey! You guys are horrible at business!
Huh? They're sucking me up, dude!
Now, eat that ice cream some more to become fatter,
while also using your Stretchy Powers to grow huge!
Ok!
This sucks.
Yeah, dude! Keep growin'!
You're breaking apart their robot!
Oh no!
I'm going to kill you, not-boss!
Wait, man! Wait!
I wanna re-hire you guys!
Re-hire? Really?
Yeah, mans.
Woo hoo!
Yay! Hip-hip hooray! Pancakes!
So, wait... What'd you hire them to do?
I hired them to stuff themselves in that iceberg
and get outta here.
[Sigh] I'm gonna miss 'em.
And I'm gonna miss this gut.
[Laughs] I'm gonna miss my gut too.
Aww! Aww...