Ground.
Okay.
Ten.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Fifteen.
Sixteen.
Seventeen.
Eighteen.
Nineteen.
Got it.
- Good.
- You're slipping, Larry.
Give me a break.
The guy's got a ten-digit PIN.
- Check the basement first.
- You got it.
Excuse me!
- Is that it?
- We got it.
She got it!
- Is the expert here?
- Ready and waiting.
- Let's see what you got.
- Okay.
This is George French, head of forensics.
- Hi, George.
- Hi.
This is Dr Cornelius of Manhattanville.
Come in, Doc.
Catherine Banning.
- How do you do?
- Hello! Well, go to work, Doctor.
Don't glare at me, Michael.
So, are the laws of the United States
completely unknown to you?
- Or is it cos you've lived in Morocco...
- Monaco.
I don't care.
It's illegal entry, theft, trespassing.
- I'm not a cop.
- Exactly. Cops know this won't hold up.
- Don't you want him to go up for...
- My job is the painting.
You've got a ghost here.
What?
Another painting underneath.
Monet reused his canvases.
Monet's unknown masterpiece,
"Dogs at Cards".
Where is that sack of shit?
Where is he right now?
Excuse me?
I'm cutting in.
It's all right, Anna.
I'll see you later.
It's a black and white ball.
Oh, I'm sorry. I wasn't invited anyway.
- You left yourself wide open.
- You're all flushed.
How many people can forge a Monet?
Five? Maybe six?
I'm sure I can't be arrested for a joke.
- This was a little too good.
- You're just inches away.
I am. You think
I'll just peck up crumbs you lay out?
I can smell blood on my own.
You smug son of a...
Do you wanna dance
or do you wanna dance?
No!
Get away! Get away!
Oh! You are...
the most remarkable woman.
You don't think
we're finished, do you?
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Morning, Paul.
- Can I get you anything else?
- Not a thing.
- Thank you, Paul.
I suppose you didn't just run out for that.
No.
Damn. I hate being a foregone conclusion.
You live very well.
Thank you.
It'd be a shame to lose it all.
That depends
on a very large presumption.
Yes, it does.
I won't back off, you know.
Not even for a minute.
I would be hugely disappointed if you did.
How do porcupines mate?
Old joke. Very carefully.
Carefully. Or... unsuccessfully.
Don't see many porcupines.
Creatures with highly evolved
defence systems.
Like porcupines?
Like 42-year-old, successful
self-involved loners.
If you've found a female mirror image
and think you'll form
a rewarding relationship...
Think again?
Good morning.
Nice dress.
Looks like it was a great party.
You gonna be a cliché?
Did you even think twice?
- No.
- You knew what you were doing?
My job. He likes me. He'll keep liking me.
Keep him right next to me.
And you don't care
what that makes you.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Do you really?
This is just about money, Mike.
Oh, oh, oh, he's got a problem.
I could get used to this.
- Just hold on now.
- Hold on why?
- Take the stick.
- Oh, I'm not...
- Take it.
- I'm not taking...
- Put your hands on it.
- Oh, no!
That's it. That's good.
- That's good.
- Oh, my God!
Head for that hill over there. Don't lose it.
There you go.
This is ridge-running. We're doing it.
- Oh, this is great.
- I'm in your hands.
- Just feel that. You feel it?
- I do.
Left. To the left.
We'll pick up a thermal
coming over the hill.
Just like a hawk.
Cows.
Oh, that's okay. We're only about
four states from your car.
That island
isn't Manhattan.
- It's not?
- No.
I have appointments.
Wanna keep them?
Door's welded. Throw your leg over.
Throw my leg over.
This must go over.
With whom?
Whomever you bring here.
I never bring anyone here.
I bet they're all my size.
Could be. Might be off a little
here and there, but I think they'll make do.
I'll go make dinner.
Come on!
- You want some wine?
- Yes!
It's beautiful!
Want to see it?
No.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
Like a splash?
Come here.
Wanna see it?
No.
You sure?
You think I believe you'd leave
your hard-stolen painting
Iying around a Caribbean hut?
What if I did?
And that you'd tell me?
Well, what if I trust you?
You know you can't.
You don't believe you could trust me?
You know how likely I think that is?
Excuse me.
Should I open another bottle?
Yes.
- I think so.
'85 wasn't very good.
- No, it's not... No...
- Truce. A truce would be good.
That'd be great. That'd be good.
What was it?
A nice little Renoir.
Renoir.
A nice little copy?
We'll never know, will we?
- Okay, I give up!
- Easy, easy.
- I'll get that bottle.
- Oh, yeah, that would be good.
Oh, you're not boring, I'll give you that.
- You complimented me.
- How?
- They were bankers.
- Who?
Who? The suits.
You're transferring assets.
Getting ready to run.
And suppose I did run?
Then what would you have?
Not the painting,
not the $5 million fee, not me.
Yes?
Suppose I gave you ten?
To fail?
How would I hide it?
I'd teach you.
You really think there's
happy ever after for people like us?
So just how big of a thief are you?
Well, if you count Wall Street,
pretty big.
If you mean art,
I'm just an amateur.
Beginner's luck, huh?
Gentleman jockey wins the Derby.
Something like that.
You got your hand caught
in the cookie jar now.
How are you gonna get out of it?
It's just a game, love.
Just a game.
- Nice tan.
- Thanks.
I went to the beach for a couple of days.
On the job?
That's right.
And did you pick anything... up?
Well, he's got an ornament
worn by Barbarossa
at his coronation in 1 1 52.
Really? Stolen?
No.
So that's it, after two days
and two nights?
That was it.
Would you like to know where he was
the night before you left?
Or after he left you last night?
Not really.
Okay. Suit yourself.
Michael.
Oh,...
she's
striking.
He seems to think so.
Three dates in six days.
Well,
where does he find the time?
You okay?
Yeah.
You know, I was okay once.
My girlfriend got drunk.
Stayed out all night,
came back in the morning... married.
Yeah.
I told people I didn't care... and then I
fucked five women in three days,
flipped my car on an on-ramp,
beat a suspect unconscious,
got suspended.
But I was okay.
Is there a point to this story?
But he was with him.
What's this?
Photos of the Monet's borders.
The borders?
Insurers remove a painting from the frame
to photograph its borders.
Borders are never seen in galleries
or auctions, so if a picture's stolen and
someone makes a forgery,
the borders won't match.
And if they do happen to match?
Then the forger
was in the presence of the original.
- So, if Crown's prank Monet is too good...
- Then we find the forger
and nail the bastard.
- How long have you had these?
- Five days.
And you didn't open them?
Yeah, well, they're open now.
- It's beautiful.
- You're not going to say
"I couldn't possibly"?
No.
I...
I wouldn't say anything that boring.
She's an old friend,
but it'll be like
having dinner in a morgue.
But you know, it occurred to me, I might
be able to bear it if you came with me.
Tomorrow? That's so soon.
I sense hesitation.
No...
No.
Do you find my company monotonous?
Cos I'd hate to think you could.
What, be bored by you?
Require a little variety?
You're referring to Anna.
They photographed me with Anna.
- You know, that's your prerogative.
- I thought they were.
I let it happen.
- Want to know why?
- No.
- I'll tell you.
- Don't.
- I want to tell you.
- I don't want to know.
Jimmy, I'd like to get out.
- Keep driving.
- Stop!
- I don't want to know why!
- Let me tell you!
- No!
- Ah, shit.
- Now ask me why!
- I don't want to know!
- You're upset about it!
- Yeah, cos you wanted me to be upset!
- I needed you to be upset!
- Ho-ho, he's sadistic! Who knew?
- Did it occur to you I needed to know?
- Know what?!
Know whether all it was to you
was the painting?
How else could I know?
What about you?
I can leave here tomorrow.
So can you.
- We'd be fugitives.
- Fugitives with means.
All the difference in the world.
I don't know.
Oh dear. Peter Pan decides to grow up,
and finds there's no place to land.
The only sad part is,
if she's anything like you,
she won't know what she's lost
until it's gone.
Hey! Let's go.
Where?
The borders matched perfectly.
Then again, I'm sure you knew that,
didn't you?
Come on. Let's go meet some forgers.
I was never an lmpressionist.
Anyway, I pay taxes now.
Doing what?
Portraits.
Inserting the rich into old masterpieces.
The wife's face on the Mona Lisa.
From Brooklyn to Greenwich
in one generation.
You've gotta have the paintings to match.
So, who did it?
The German.
Heinrich...
Knutzhorn.
Art's a small world, Michael.
So, who do you think did this?
Frederick Golchan.
He said you did.
So you think if I want paint,
it just comes Fed Ex?
And the guards just think it's therapy,
while I madly copy a Monet
in my cell from the original?
What?
Nothing.
What?!
I was just wondering
about what he wouldn't say.
Give.
There's nothing.
You know what?
Life is full of shitty conflicts, okay? Give.
I just wondered if there was
a connection between them, that's all.
Between Crown and that old man?
Yeah.
- You are spooky. You are really spooky.
- They owned a gallery together,
Crown and Knutzhorn. In Berlin, 1990.
Another one in Hamburg.
And one in Paris in '94.
You notice the one-man show
in Paris in '95?
The artist is Knutzhorn.
So?
So look at the first name.
Tyrol Knutzhorn.
Yeah, we spoke to a Heinrich.
You know what it was?
The way he smiled at the painting?
Pride.
Paternal pride.
I bet you it's his son.
Son of a great forger,
who paints as well as Dad.
Just hasn't been caught yet.
Well, I assume if you look,
you'll find Tyrol Knutzhorn
lives in New York.
You know what?
l... I owe you an apology.
I didn't think you had the chops
to see this through.
You don't know me.
Yeah, but I should have. Cos...
I bet you'd stand at the Pearly Gates
and kick St Peter in the teeth
before you'd let someone play you.
Harold, listen carefully
and please don't interrupt.
If I had to be gone, and I mean
seriously gone, in about eight hours,
how much could I take with me?
- Are you okay?
- Harold...
You'd take an enormous loss,
liquidating like this.
I understand, and that can't be helped.
What could I leave with?
Call me in an hour.
I'll have a number for you.
Okay.
Leaving us?
No, you're not that lucky.
I'm organising.
No Knutzhorn has been
to see the old man.
No?
There was a Knudsen, though,
three times last month.
Think that's a coincidence, or...?
Could be.
Yeah.
Probably is.
Look, here's an extra hundred.
Just go, go!
- Paul, is he here?
- He's in a meeting now.
- It's very important.
- If you wait in the living room, I'll get him.
Ma'am, wait.
I know we have plug adapters,
I saw them.
I just can't find them. Would you go
downstairs, Anna, and ask Paul...
Well... we seem to have backtracked.
- No!
- No.
Take your hands off me!
Come on,
what do you have that's fresh?
Who's that girl and why is she here?
Anna works for me.
You never thought I was a fool before.
I owe her money
and I wanted to pay her before I go.
Oh, really?
And what is it she does for you?
I would be compromising her to say.
Oh, Tommy, you're going away together.
No, I'm going with you.
Of all the things in the world
to take with a leap of faith,
- how can I possibly trust you?
- I'm not gonna ask that.
I'm going to trust you.
Isn't that what you wanted,
my trust?
Tomorrow afternoon
I'll put the Monet back.
Where? Hanging back
on the wall in the museum?
Yes.
You know, Tommy,
I'm all checkmated out.
If the painting's back, we're free.
We're only for each other.
Back on the wall, in the museum?
Yes, and you'll meet me
at four o'clock
at the Wall Street heliport,
and we'll leave together.
Or...
Or you can have them at the museum
waiting for me.
I'm trusting you.
I can't... do that!
Damn you, you son of a bitch! Get away!
Hey.
Hi.
I need to talk to you.
- Paretti.
- Yeah.
You're in the lobby, right?
Yeah, Mikey, I'm here.
Me and about 30 other guys.
Let up on yourself.
You did the right thing.
Assuming the son of a bitch shows up.
Mark, stay with the car.
Get a uniformed man on the fire escape.
Got it.
Detective!
Yeah.
Goddamn it.
Did she leave anything behind?
Stake out the whole place.
Maybe she'll come back. I don't know.
No, no, no.
Is Jack there? Put him on the phone.
Get Jack!
- What?
- The forger.
You didn't think we just dropped that,
did you? Jack ran it down.
It was a daughter.
She was under our noses the whole time.
Tyrol Anna Knudsen, Knutzhorn,
whatever.
Crown's known her since she was ten.
When her father went to jail, he became
her guardian. Put her through college.
Now she works for his company.
Jack, here's what I want you to do.
He's in.
Got him.
I'll call you back.
That's him.
Overcoat and briefcase.
Yeah, Mikey. We got him.
Centre entrance. Grey overcoat.
Bring up the lobby on the big monitor.
Move in quietly.
- We don't wanna make a scene.
- Tommy...
What the hell's he doing?
Almost like he wants
to make sure we see him.
Let's play ball.
There he goes. Bowler hat.
Move in and pick him up.
Go. Move it.
Quietly. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Shit. He switched the painting.
Stay with the painting.
What? Look, I can't...
Shit! There's another one.
- There's guys with bowler hats...
- All over the goddamn place.
- Did you warn him?
- What? No.
- No!
- Then he knew you'd betray him.
- They're going for the staircases.
Now we got four floors to keep track of.
Stay with him. He disappears,
it'll be ten years before he resurfaces.
- Is the lmpressionist Wing sealed off?
- Yes.
- No way to get in?
- The gates are down.
He can't return the painting to that room.
- They're everywhere.
- What's the deal?
He's going the other way!
What? What? Look, I can't hear you.
This is ridiculous.
He's got us running around in circles.
Paretti's trying to reach you.
- I can't...
- You're fucked. I'm coming.
What do we do?
- What do we do?
- Start arresting people. Come on.
Excuse me, sir. One moment.
Shit.
I knew it.
Excuse me.
Get the civilians outta here.
How do we get this gate open?
Kill the sprinklers
in the lmpressionist Wing now.
It's water paint.
It's been here the whole time. From what?
One, two days after the robbery?
Something's jammed in the track.
He returned the thing
almost as soon as he stole it.
Er, sir?
Oh, Lord.
Oh, dear, dear. This can't be.
This simply can't be.
How the hell did he do that?
Where are you going?
Er, office.
Write up my report.
- The job's done, right?
- Yeah!
So, the other painting. Why do you think
he chose that particular one?
I have no idea.
But, um, it's not insured by my people,
so I'm out of it.
Obviously you'll still have to pursue it.
I don't really give a shit.
You don't care if you catch him?
Well, I'll do what they tell me to do.
- Did you ever care?
- Yeah!
He pissed me off.
But, look...
The week before I met you,
I nailed two real estate agents and
a guy who was beating his kids to death.
So if some Houdini wants
to snatch a few swirls of paint
that are only important
to some very silly rich people,
I don't really give a damn.
You're a good man.
Okay. Get out of here. And tell him
I said hello.
I've no idea what you're talking about.
Go on.
And don't stiff us for your phone bills.
No.
Taxi!
You know, I'm just going to run. Thanks.
Excuse me.
Ma'am, you can't go out there!
Tommy!
You would be Catherine?
Yes.
He wanted you to have this.
Good day, ma'am.
Hi there.
How can I help you?
I have a reservation.
Okay. Miss Banning.
Will you be carrying any luggage today?
No.
Can you see that this
gets to this man at police headquarters?
This should take care of it.
It won't get there till morning.
That's fine.
Departures for international flights
are up the escalator to your left.
Ma'am?
Is everything all right?
Everything's fine.
You don't need to cry there, lassie.
Did you set this up?
Did you?!
Miss, please,
the seat belt sign is still on...
I'll tell you what.
You pull a stunt like that again,
I'll break both your arms.
Visiontext subtitles: Marc de Jongh