Subtitle by shinostarr
for myasiancinema.com
and asiatorrents.com
On top of the Ningbi cliffs there is a temple.
It is the most famous temple in the Ngormei Mountains,
where people from all over the world come
to pay their respects
to the Kuan Yin statue
which was believed to have been created by Ng Daozi
and has seen almost 800 years of history.
It is said that it grants the wishes of whoever prays there.
People tend to seek
better health
home
or even exorcism
when they pray to the goddess, Kuan Yin.
Move! Get out of my way!
- Whoa!
- How can he do that?
Oh my god! Somebody do something!
You should not being doing this!
You will be cursed for life!
Go and die!
Unbelievable!
Woah!
Let's go, let's get out of here!
Run! Run! Run!
What is true happiness?
Today's happiness is but what the future may hold
and the sadness of the future is the consequence of today's actions.
Even though this may be true,
I would rather seek today's happiness.
Then you are wrong.
Take Prince Ling as an example.
He is an extravagant, rich man.
He collects all the beautiful treasures of the world,
but is this really true happiness?
In his pursuit of the great treasures of the world,
a famine is happening in his country.
Do you think he'll have a guilty conscience?
Will he be happy?
How can you compare me to that person?
And I will not forgive you for this matter!
Brother Lam
We are still young, we should spend this time playing.
If you bring home a woman and marry her,
you will have no life of your own -
you will definitely regret it.
Having a wife
won't tie me down.
What harm can there be?
You need to get out there and socialize.
If you don't like him then don't marry him.
If you like him then get married, simple.
I don't want to be married.
Master, Mr. Lam has arrived.
I don't care whether you like it or not
you have to get out there and see if you like him.
Please reconsider miss,
there is no harm in going to take a look.
I am not going.
Mr. Fei is so old-fashioned,
His daughter must also be very old-fashioned.
Just wait till you get in bed with her...
Hurry up miss.
Go up.
Don't mess around.
Mr. Lam.
- How is your father?
- Thank you for asking, he is well.
This man is a well known scholar, Mr. Mei Yeung Sam.
He has accompanied me here.
Mr. Lam.
I am very sorry
I cannot control my daughter.
Alas,
My daughter doesn't want to come out to meet you
Sorry for making you come here for nothing.
Then we will leave first, since we have other commitments to attend to.
- Let's go.
- Goodbye then.
Master, Miss is coming out to see the guests.
Ah, since Miss decided to come and meet us,
- Then let's stay a little longer.
- Oh yes, definitely.
My daughter's mother died when she was young
So, she is a little spoiled.
She does what she wants and manages her own affairs.
Of course, father
I would normally take control over minor affairs,
However, an affair such as marriage is something you should take care of.
Being a lady, I will have to follow the rules.
It has been many years and my daughter hasn't found a suitable partner.
This is because she is my only daughter
so my son-in law must marry into the family.
- The first child must bear our surname.
- Ah, how can that be?
That is why her marriage has been delayed until this date.
However,
I am the male of the 3rd generation.
I am the male of the 7th generation,
there will be some difficulties,
However, if
I can marry such a beautiful lady as Miss, then
I do not mind marrying into the family.
I have decided, marrying into the family is not a problem.
All my children can bear the surname of Ti (metal)
I have also decided that
all of my grandchildren can bear your surname
But,
I had a pre-arrangement with Mr. Lam's father about this marriage...
Then
Miss,
Do you have a piece of paper?
Miss, he is very artistic.
Sir and Miss can you please evaluate my work?
[Poem]: Dainty hands,
pretty eyes, pouty lips,
young and supple body
with long hair that reaches half way down the body.
Father,
I have decided, if I can't marry him,
I will not marry anyone else.
If I can't marry Miss, then I also will not marry anyone else.
Congratulations!
Ah Mr. Lam, Mr. Lam!
Mei brother, Mei brother
Let me introduce you to a good friend of mine.
This is Mr. Seung Guan Sam.
This is Mr. Mei Yeung Sam.
- Nice to meet you.
- Your head...
- Mr. Master is asking for you.
Oh, please excuse me.
These two are lucky grandpa and lucky grandma.
They are 93 years old, and have been happily married for over 70 years.
They are still so intimate.
Master, has specifically invited them here
to wish you and Miss luck.
Mr. and Mrs. Lucky, I am happy to meet you.
Good boy,
I will give you a red pocket later ok?
So I have to give you, ah benefit package
Old man, look at how clumsily you eat, you got food all over yourself.
Pardon my naivety, but
both of you have been married for so long,
how can you still be so affectionate in front of other people?
Oh I don't have any reason.
I only know that I really love her.
The so-called love, it can only exist if you make love
If you haven't
made love for so many years
then how can there be love?
Even if there is no sex, it is not a problem,
you will understand later in life.
Geez...
Tsk.
First, may the couple pray to the sky and land.
Second, bow to the parents...
Oh this is so fun!
Hold on
husband,
will this hurt?
Even though it will be painful, it will also be fun.
Luckily it doesn't hurt,
but
it's not fun at all.
I must admit, there will be room for improvement.
I think
More practice will make things better.
- Ok.
- Did you see?
Oh no, I just blinked, I didn't get to see.
You hate Emperor Ling so much,
why are you getting me to take you to his collection chamber?
If I don't come here, then how can I get any evidence?
You have a point.
Prince, I have brought my friend along today to meet you.
You don't need me to repeat the rules to enter the collection chamber.
To enter the chamber I know we need to offer a gift.
This is a gift from my father's collection.
Although it's not a rare item.
Coral is very common,
however
red coral is very rare.
Go and pick up some coral that will be placed
in the storage room for them to look at.
Bringing such a thing with the intention of entering
the chamber is ridiculous,
I have so much of this coral,
you can take any to replace the one I have trashed.
I don't want to see you again.
I am sorry for being rude,
I can't ever take the replacement,
I will take my leave first.
I have finally witnessed the prince's collection.
How can you hang a fake painting?
This painting has been verified by many professionals
The paper, ink and the seal signifies it is from the Tang Dynasty
So it is definitely Ng Dongzi's genuine painting.
Where is your proof that it's fake?
You can cut open the painting and
you will see two pieces of paper.
One will have the fake painting on it,
the second
will have Li Yu's wife's sakura flower painted upon it
What is it?
Tang, Li Yu's wife is a temple
A hint of plum on the Indian.
Moreover, a there's a difference of 200 years.
Not fake.
What, ah?
Your talent is definitely a treasure,
I will grant you access to the collection chamber.
Thank you.
Hey take a look at this.
It is a horse.
Touch it.
Huh? Could this be?
This is definitely a treasure.
What an eye opener.
I have more treasures in my chambers.
However, before you enter
you must take some opium.
After taking opium, you will have a floating sensation,
everything will seem like reality.
- Let's all have a drink.
- Really enjoyable.
Good things.
Don't run away if I get you,
you will regret it.
Do you know him?
Mr. Seung?
At my wedding,
I heard he was an honored guest.
Seung Geung Sun is my honored guest
- he can enter this chamber as he wishes,
because he has 127 wives.
Besides the Emperor he has
the most wives in the world.
But
their quality is average.
She is the world's most beautiful woman,
Gei Fu Yeungkbing Shuet
has the perfect measurements,
not too short, not too tall
every part of her
is of high standard.
However,
she has a terrible temper.
Sorry sir.
Bitch.
Sister, please stop!
Stop!
Stop it!
Please don't!
Even if she has done something wrong,
you should not torture her.
You can just shoot her,
you can't torture her to death
understand?
Don't do it next time.
Hurry, hurry, or we will miss out!
She's so beautiful!
Let me in on the fun.
Get out of the way, get out of the way!
Get out!
Your Highness
Her name is Sleeping Pearl,
she is part of my collection.
She specializes in martial arts particularly the yin, yang style
her abilities are a rarity in this world.
She can make a dead man come back to life with her abilities
however, she will only serve one man per day.
And of course for that to happen,
my approval is required.
It seems that she is interested in you.
If you want to have sex with her,
you have my approval.
- Thank your highness.
- Hold on.
Only on one condition.
Your highness
Please tell me.
I want you to serve me for 10 years,
when I call for you, you need to be here.
If you agree to these conditions you have my approval
to spend the day with Pearl.
No problem,
I promise you.
Oh my god, I have never even tried being with her...
Wait a minute
We have all day.
I'm afraid
that I won't last that long.
Don't worry you have me.
I can't hold it any longer.
Reporting to you my prince
Mr. Mei Yeung Sam and Pearl have been together for over 24 hours
and are still having sex.
I am willing to divorce my wife
because I have been cheating on her
and neglecting her.
From this day forth she can marry whomever she pleases
and I whomever I please.
We will go on separate paths.
I have made a grave mistake and have hurt Miss.
I don't have anything to say to defend myself.
You don't need to say anything, just sign the divorce papers.
My heart will always remain with Miss.
Cut the crap,
From morning till night you were out having sex with other women.
Even when she fell ill you ignored her.
You are inhuman.
Yuxing,
this is my pen
it is my favorite and most precious family heirloom.
It is hard to fix a broken mirror.
I swear to god,
for the rest of my life
I will never draw again.
Miss
How come Ray doesn't seem to feel any pain?
This is because she uses pain
to reach an orgasm.
How interesting!
When you try it you will know.
Ah, don't get me involved.
Your highness
Can you please let me look at that painting?
Use more strength
Harder!
This stamp is fake,
the authentification certificate is also fake
then this painting is worthless.
By how much was the timing off by?
Take a look.
It was off by approximately 300 years.
Congratulations, Prince,
It is priceless.
This painting is Lam's dynasty's treasure,
It is the world's most ancient painting
But, Guandong made a mistake
and marked it with a fake stamp.
Amazing,
I got my hands on another treasure.
Good
Follow me.
Besides the prince
no one can enter!
It hurts!
I want to give you a reward, what do you want?
Your highness
I don't have any requests.
I see.
Congratulations Prince
Do you know what bittersweet means?
Last time you won so much,
this time it's my turn.
I won three times, I want revenge
We'll see about that
Coffin, here you go.
Bird, your favorite.
We have to wait for you every time.
If you're gonna use this move you will lose.
Hurry, you take too long to think.
If I'm not allowed to think then you move first.
Hmm, Which move?
This move, green mistress, stupid!
Wow! Awesome! It is so big.
I really want it.
Do you know why she doesn't respond to you?
Want to know why?
Your highness
It is not because she is unresponsive,
it is because your manhood is not big enough.
How can there be such a small penis?
Hey you
Who told you to come here?
These are miss's quarters,
you can't just enter as you please.
Get out of here.
I am very sorry,
I am stupid,
I will leave,
please pay me.
Mr. Ding
He has already apologized
please let him be.
My name is Quan Lao Shi.
Thank you Miss.
It's okay, please stand up.
Why are you still standing here?
Quickly move the coal.
This type of man who sells his body to bury his father,
no one will pity him.
Please help me
reward him with this money.
Come here
Miss has given this reward to you.
Thank you, thank you.
Why aren't you leaving? Hurry up!
So slow and clumsy, you are not really working.
Why are you always so late?
You are so impatient.
Of course,
I am eager to see
the oldest person in the world.
Let's go
Seung Guan Sam
When will you marry your 128th wife?
- Your Highness
- You're late
Take a seat
Your Highness
You said that Yat Yong's oldest man will come today?
He's late even though the prince invited him to come?
Since you are so impatient
How about this?
You can represent me and have a drink with him.
Your ornament is quite interesting
I am the oldest person
Li Chang Xu
You're ignorant, and disrespectful,
Your bedroom skills are definitely awesome,
I am lucky to be able to witness it.
You are too flattering Prince,
however I just used too much of my energy
and I am very tired.  If I'm not needed
Then I will take my leave first.
Please!
Here
Here, here
Come back here
I will throw it to you
You don't have to be afraid
We're here to find the oldest person.
What are you saying?
I can't hear you
They are deaf, they can't hear you.
Sir
God father?
They are calling you god father.
Tell them how old are you.
I am 14 years old
I am 15 years old,
14 years old,
I am 16 years old.
Huh?
They are actually the leftovers from my medication.
Have you heard of ying and yang?
Are you saying that the reason they have turned like this
is because you have used them to keep your youthfulness?
Exactly
You go and play
Yay let's go and play.
Let's go and play!
Sir, sir, sir
Why did you follow me?
I feel so lucky today
to be able to witness your bedrooms skills.
They are truly awesome.
I am in a hurry to improve my skills in bed,
I was wondering if
you would take me as your disciple?
Bedroom skills
are not something that can be passed on
so I cannot help you.
Then what is your price? Name it
I will try and give you want you want.
As long as you can teach me
some of the skills I am satisfied,
I will do anything.
Please
Stand up.
Wahh! Is it really that small!
Your qualifications are so poor,
it will be a waste to teach you.
Ok I will accept you,
however there are two conditions that you must adhere to.
Definitely no problem I will follow your wishes.
First, I want you to help me out with this task,
as to what it is
I will tell you in due time.
No problem
What else?
He's so handsome,
if he is not used to keep me young it is such a waste.
You always tell me
that you are loyal to me, and will do anything for me
now the opportunity has arisen.
We came to help.
No I don't want to.
Do you know what this is?
Oh no the butt will hurt.
Take him in!
Sir, save me! Save me!
Then when can I...
Have you not heard of when you are trying to get well,
you are not to be disturbed.
Go and find my friend Yi Sing Tien Gei Zhi
Looks like you need to replace your sex.
Replace my sex?
Can't we just take the special medication?
This medication has not been fully brewed yet,
and is still in the trial periods.
There may be some side effects.
Here is the manual for the skills that I have performed.
It will show you how to strengthen your sex
and also gain more control over it,
making all the women in the world worship you.
Be quiet lucky!
Go bathe inside.
Who are you looking for?
My name is Mei Yeung Sam,
the oldest person has told me to come here.
Is Yi Sing Tien Gei Zhi here?
- You are looking for my master?
- Yes
He died!
He died?
Why are you looking for him?
I was his disciple Tien Chan
I am his first disciple Tien Knot,
come in and talk to me.
Come in and tell me.
Since the old man told you to come,
let's see if we can help you.
I want to...
Wah!
No Way!
Change your sex?
Who is changing their sex? Hey!
Someone is changing their sex, come and see...
Who?
I have this book!
We've been studying this book with our master
we know what you are talking about,
and we are interested in it
and would like to try.
What, you haven't done this before?
Our elders has helped someone
to change their sex in the past,
but finding someone that is willing
to exchange his sex for yours will be quite difficult.
Can't we find an animal to exchange it with?
Theoretically, that is possible.
What animal do you want to swap with?
Something that has a long one - a horse!
That's a great idea!
That's great!
Can you guys actually do it?
What?
Are you discriminating against the disabled?
Before the operation
You need to be aware of two things
First, we need to finish the operation before the incense burns out
Otherwise, you will become impotent.
Second, after the change
for one month
do not have sex
otherwise, you will be become impotent.
This is an anesthetic, drink it and you won't feel a thing
No need to be so nervous
Look around and focus your attention elsewhere
It'll be over in the blink of an eye.
Ok.
Wow!
See? I told you, I cut it off so quickly
Did it hurt?
Wipe my sweat.
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
Oh right
how did your master die?
Oh, he botched an exchange operation
and was killed for it.
Look at us disabled people
Just give us a chance, we can do
just as good a job as you normal people
Oh no!
It's all flat!
Huh?
Do you think this is still usable?
While there is still time
we should reattach your own
before you become impotent.
That's the only way! Hurry up!
Hey! hey!
No! That's my penis!
Where are you going?
Lucky! Come back!
Hey! Why don't you quickly grab the penis back
But I don't have hands!
Huh? No hands?
Then use your mouth.
Use my mouth?
Hurry up!
Success! We got it back!
Um, but
there is only a little bit left.
Don't tell me you still want it?
Huh!
Oh no the incense is almost finished
Why don't one of you give me yours?
Even if I wanted to, you wouldn't be able to use it!
Even if I wanted to
I don't have hands to perform the operation.
If I change
no one can help me
There will be no time.
I must be fated to be impotent.
Oh?
Hey! Hold on!
Hey! hey! Stop!
Where are you going?
Hey, come back to it!
Aren't we nice?
Since there isn't a horse penis, we got you a donkey's penis.
Bring her back in!
Bitch! She should die!
You slut
you seduced a servant
and caused your father's death.
what have you got to say for yourself?
I have nothing to say.
Ok, throw her in.
Throw her in, throw her in!
No!
Stop!
I raped her!
You say you raped her
don't try to protect her,
being a rapist is a serious crime
Yes ah!
I am a rapist and I raped her.
Since he is the rapist
Catch him!
Stop! Hold on!
Yang honest
I believe you, however
for a person with such martial arts skills
it must have been really easy to
rape a weak woman like her
We have nothing else to say. Let's go.
Go?
I said go.
Mayor, your bottom...
Be careful Mayor.
Where's the money?
Miss Yuxing
Yang has sold you to me
Are you willing to follow me?
Help ah! Really big ah!
He's so brave
with such a large penis
he's my idol.
he's my idol too.
Come here! come here!
- Call for Dongmi
- Yes
Me against 10.
Come! All of you.
Come!
Wu Di Zi
Miss! Master Yang is resting inside.
You cannot enter.
You saved me in order to have me
I am here to let you do as you please.
You guys go out first
I want to tell you
Everything I have done is because I love you.
I never force people
That is my principle.
Even though I have so many wives
Not one is unwilling
I want you to follow me willingly.
You to be with me?
Very well
But I tell you
I will accept if there is only ...
... One love.
I have given each of you three thousand
Should be enough for you.
Please take your jewelry with you.
I don't want the money.
I want to follow you.
Please don't make us leave.
Please don't be like this.
This is the only way
I can be with Yuxing.
I'd rather die than leave you.
Stop.
No one has to leave.
I didn't tell them to stay
Master, can I join?
Come in to join me in giving him pleasure.
Sure thing.
Ok.
We're here master.
Yuxing
You woke up
It's you master
Old man,
the way you came out would scare the life out of anyone
Unbelievable
Sir, it's me..
Me
Char Dong
Don't tell me she did this to you.
Stop talking so much. Come here.
Do you remember...
you promised me you'd do me a favor?
- Humm
- Ah!
Yes, I remember
I want you to help me steal the scripture that
was given to the Emperor by Dan Ning Wangzu
Huh? Why?
These past few years I have been using a woman's body
to infiltrate the palace and rape their children.
Now I'm on the court's most wanted list
and only that scripture can help me.
Scripture?
The one that can be used to get a pardon?
Yes.
But how can I steal it?
Where do you think Emperor Ling keeps his most precious possessions?
How dare you steal the scripture?
I... I...
"I" what?
Prince, Mei Heung Sam has always liked to steal things
and now he's been caught red-handed.
Don't say such nonsense.
How is this nonsense?
Don't you remember the day
you stole Yuxing from me?
Did you really think I wasn't angry?
Oh ...
- You and the prince ...
- Yes
The prince and I got together to play a trick on you.
Who told you to make enemies with the prince?
When did I make enemies with the prince?
No
Do you remember what you said at the temple to the monk?
In his pursuit of the great treasures of the world,
a famine is happening in his country.
Do you think he'll have a guilty conscience?
Will he be happy?
How can you compare me to that person?
Don't worry, I treat people fairly.
After I have dealt with you, I will deal with the monk.
Don't hurt the monk!
Don't!
Worry about yourself first.
This man is called Keun Cosut
he is the world's best knife-thrower.
It was me who hired him to
rape your wife,
which caused her father's death
and now she is Go Sam's concubine
What I said was so trivial and you
go to such extremes to hurt me
and my wife?
You're still talking,
You teamed up with the other scholars to try to get rid of me.
For the love of the world,
I, Mei Heung Sam,
will die
an honorable death.
Shut up!
We educated people will not back down even if we die.
Screw you! Educated people?
Educated people who like to have sex
then go and complain about me?
So noisy!
What a loser!
Just kill me!
Do you know how much you energy and money I've wasted on you?
Tie him up!
I will slowly torture you to death.
Go! Walk!
Stand up!
I want you to teach me your skills
so I can give Dongmei over 10 orgasms
and I will let you go in exchange.
No problem, prince
as long as you do not kill me.
I did say I'd teach you, but I've changed my mind.
I don't want to be without descendants.
That's not right though.
Tell the guards
the court's most wanted criminal is here.
Please don't, prince
You said you not want to be childless, no problem.
I can help you figure out a solution.
When you came here, you were holding onto this pen.
I assume it is important to you
so I told someone to fix it.
- Sir
The generosity and love you have shown me
I can only repay you in the next life.
Yuxing
will now take her leave
If I could save your ex-husband,
I would already have done so.
If you go now, you will have sacrificed yourself for nothing.
If I, Yuxing
can die with him at the same time,
I will die with no regrets.
Prince, where is my husband?
Take a look and you will know.
I'm surprised at his determination.
If not for the maggots eating his bone,
he'd be in much worse condition.
Your highness, I beg of you,
please cure him I beg you
Why should I cure him?
If you promise me, I will do anything you want.
Your highness! I beg you!
Please save my husband.
Dong Mui
Prosecutor, thank you for your hard work.
I'm just a lowly prosecutor
I can't help you.
I understand
please bring the heirloom. Yes.
Open the locks.
Understood.
- Stop, leave us
- Yes
You aren't dead yet?
The prince wants to see you.
In the past I took your love from you
but I
have already divorced my wife
and I may be crippled for life.
Has your anger diminished?
Let's forget
the feud between us.
Although I have done many wrong deeds
the monk has sacrificed 50 years of his life to
get where he is now.
He is innocent.
We've been friends since
we were six years old.
I beg you to do one thing for me.
To warn the monk that
the prince will be after him.
I beg you to help me.
How are you going to torture me now?
Let me show you something
This horse is interesting
When you play with its tail, the lotus flower on
the saddle opens and closes.
Take a closer look
Stop
Your highness, I offended you
I deserve to die
please torture me, please let her go.
your wife came here to beg me to let you go,
and you are begging me to let her go.
Are you two trying to trick me?
As long as you let her go
I will promise you anything
torture me, kill me, anything you want.
Killing and more killing, no.
If you cut off your manhood I will let your wife go.
I'll cut it off.
You would even promise me this?
How useless!
Let's see how you can be a man in the future.
Bring the old man to me.
Old monster
Do you know why I spared your life?
The prince must have a task for me.
Come out!
You dare prescribe me the wrong medicine?
I have given you a poison
If you do not have the antidote
within 6 hours,
you will die a bloody, gruesome and painful death
Take Pearl to the temple
with you and
help her seduce the monk.
If you can carry out this task within half a day
I will consider giving you the antidote.
What if...
If you utter another word, I will kill you!
- Stop pushing me! I have legs, I can walk!
- Are you blind? Can't you see I don't have legs?
Where are you going?
The show is about to start.
Ah, I ...
Come on
Hurry up!
Stay here and watch me torture the both of them,
You will feel so much pleasure from it.
Please save the monk, save the monk, save the monk!
Kneel!
Hurry up and save the monk!
Gag him!
Save the monk!
That's strange, how come the supporters are missing?
I agree.
Your manhood is so powerful, huh?
You can take on 10 women at a time,
I'm going to make your woman watch me
cut it off.
Take Yuxing out.
The guest has arrived.
- Sergeant?
- Sergeant.
Prosecutor, we've traveled here from the city
at your request,
we can now take action.
Prosecutor, please...
Take a look.
- Husband...
What a great pair of lovers, who care for each other.
I really want to hear what lovey-dovey words you'll say
I've already divorced you,
Why are you here to sacrifice yourself?
After the divorce
I realized
I can't live without you.
But even though
you are still sacrificing yourself
Husband
It does not matter
As long as we can die together
I will be satisfied.
Same goes for me.
- Husband
- Wife
That was very moving
I almost shed a tear.
Tie her up
Are you ready yet?
Prince, we are nearly ready
however
even if we aren't qualified doctors
we're still doctors
and saving people is our moral obligation.
Their love has reached us and awakened us
For us to ruin them
Want us to hurt people's lower body
in order to break them up is something we cannot do.
The number two rule
karma will come around to get you
if you ruin someone's life.
The rules we follow
cannot be changed and our morals are also unchangeable.
-We are very stubborn with our views
-Yay!
But life is very precious so
your highness, how do you want us to cut it?
Slice it or dice it?
You guys can put aside your morals?
Oh, we also have rule number one:
Our techniques must be passed on, so
if both one and two happen at the same time,
then rule one will take priority.
We are both first disciples
so we cannot die.
Your highness,
I will get back to work first.
Let's go.
You must keep him alive,
the point of hiring you guys is to keep him alive and not let him die so quickly
so I can slowly torture him.
What's wrong?
Both of you take a look at him.
It's okay, Prince
I just need to go outside to take a breather
and I should be fine.
It's ok.
Sir, are you alright?
I am fine
You go back inside
Go, go, go
How dare you trespass on the Prince's property?
On the Emperor's order, we are to arrest the Prince,
surrender him now or die!
Your husband's manhood is going to be removed
So you can never have sex with him again.
Your highness, I am very sorry!
Cut it!
Hurry up!
Husband
Even if we can't have sex
it does not matter.
As long as I know that
you love me
I will be satisfied.
Even if they kill both of us
our love will live on.
Husband!
I love you!
Monk.
Who are you?
Master Mei Yeung Sam
has sent me to bring you some scriptures.
Master Mei cares for me so much please go back
and send him my gratitude.
Very well, monk, I will take my leave.
What happened?
Are you alright?
Then
can you please let Yuxing go?
Let her go?
I am a man of my word,
I have only tortured you,
I haven't tortured her yet.
Let her go, your highness!
This is a chastity belt,
that the predeceasing emperor had designed
I have the only key
that will open it.
No one else can open it I will now put it on your wife.
So she can never have sex,
not even to touch herself.
You asshole!
Move out of the way!
Now that you don't have a manhood to use,
I will take your wife.
I'll kill you!
I am going to rape her now.
No one move
Brother
You hurt my eyes.
No!
You are torturing the disabled,
we have both always been disabled, but you are different.
Karma will get you!
Karma?
Who can stand in my way?
I will now rape your wife.
From listening to your pulse, you don't seem to be sick
But monk my stomach really hurts.
In that case,
I will go and find someone to help you.
But, please monk
you don't need to go.
I have to confess
I was born with this strange disease,
Every month
my stomach will hurt
Oh? There is such a strange disease as this
in the world?
Yes, monk,
As long as your stomach touches mine
my pain will disappear.
Dear god,
Such a cure is unheard of.
Yes monk
that is how it is.
Oh, now that you are not in pain
please get off of me.
Monk, please wait a little more,
I will feel much better, ok?
No I can't, get off me.
Why are you taking off your clothes?
Oh my god, you are a woman?
- Oh my god
- are you blind?
Save me, save me.
No, don't!
What are you doing?
Get away from me!
Sex is zero, the color is empty
Where is he?
After him!
Sex is zero, the color is empty
Amitabha
Sex is zero, air is the color ...
Monk,
You have now ruined yourself
Amitabha
Sex is zero, the color is empty
Put on the chastity belt.
You will never be able to take it off.
Wife,
Do you remember
the first time we met, it was
the best time of my life.
All the women
I have been with
in the chamber
every night
I have learned
that love
is precious.
Wife
Husband
Prince
the Emperor has sent an army
to arrest you because you broke the law.
Please run away your Highness.
Run, run!
Thank you Prince.
Run? Run?
Who else dares to run away?
Run!
Abbot
Abbot, why must you kill yourself?
Monk
50 years of practice,
gone in a flash.
Abbot
It was the two before that caused our master to die
Even Buddha is angry now, Catch them!
Chase them!
Abbot
Deceive me?
You have no chance in this life
Stop
Stop, don't go!
Are you okay?
Hey! hey!
Catch him
Stop, do not go
Hey, do not go
How to do?
How could this be?
Mei Yeung Sam, you are my friend
Why do you spread rumors about me?
To betray me?
What are you laughing about?
I will now kill your wife.
In the name of the Emperor, we are here to arrest the prince.
Yuxing
Catch him
In the name of the scripture,
whoever dares take me away, their family will die.
All kneel or else your family will perish.
So what if
you have the Emperor's name or his scripture?
Backstabber!
I'm going to kill her in front of you.
Think of a way, prosecutor!
Sometimes even we run out of ideas.
I will now kill you.
How dare you shoot me?
How can you not shoot him properly?
In this lifetime, my goal is to cut off your manhood.
- Arrest all of them!
- Yes!
Husband
One bow
Two bows
Three bows
Sir, drink some tea.
Drink this tea offered by your daughter-in-law
and you will prosper.
This lucky old couple has been
Married for a long time and
are here to congratulate you.
Lucky old man, lucky old woman,
I am here to greet you.
Good boy,
I will give you a red pocket in a moment.
Call me naive, but you've been married for such a long time,
how can you still be so loving?
Because I love her.
But from what I know,
you have been impotent for quite some time.
How can there be love without sex?
Chastity belt?
When I was your age
I couldn't do it.
Oh
Everyone is watching old man, it is embarrassing.
It's okay.
Eww..
Young man,
it doesn't really matter if you have sex or not.
In time you will understand.
Let's go over there.
Tsk, they don't make any sense.
Translation by watashi
Timing and QCing by shinostarr
Editing by omgsun