[helicopter whirrs]
How are you, Mr Stevens?
Good to see you again.
Save some of that film for the official opening.
- It's gonna be a real wingding.
- When was the house built, Mr Stevens?
My father started it in 1916.
Took four years to complete it.
Whose idea was it to turn the estate
into a museum?
Mine. I've always wanted a place
where people could come and visit,
rest a while and look at beautiful things.
How long have you been collecting?
Let's Well, I guess
I've been collecting all my life.
I started out as a boy collecting stamps
and then I sold them.
Then I started collecting bicycles.
Then bicycles led to old rs.
Then one day I saw this painting.
It was a Renoir. I guess that did it.
That led to another
and then to another and to another.
Then after all these years I decided
it was time to share my collection
with anybody that might enjoy it,
give it to the people.
[reporter] Will your prototype
executive aircraft revolutionise
the private and commercial industry?
[Stevens] I certainly hope so.
[reporter] Will we be receiving a list
of the guests you've invited?
You'll all get a press kit.
What about the plane
that's bringing your guests?
You'll see the airplane when it arrives.
I think you'll agree that we brought
these guests down in style.
Dulles Tower, 2-3 Sierra Heavy,
out of 3,000 VFR for landing.
The emergency lights?
- Off.
- Beacon light off. Radios?
- Orr.
- OK.
All I'ighty, gents. She's all set for tonight.
Sony I was late on those boost pumps.
Don't worry about it. See you guys later.
Why did you mention it? He didn't notice.
Are you kidding? Why do you think
Stevens hires a guy like him?
He notices everything.
Well, how did it check out'?
Just beautiful. She behaved perfectly, Stan.
She damn well better.
I spent the best part of a year on this project.
Now Stevens has got his dream machine,
you n go back to that nice executive life
of two-hour lunches, golf...
I don't play 9°"-
Besides, the job won't be finished
until we deliver this baby tonight.
That's true. You're not gonna
light that thing, are you?
No, I've quit smoking. Well, I'm quitting.
[woman on Tannoy] TWA Flight 34
now arriving at gate 26.
Passenger Dupyeq
phase Pick "P While courtesy phona
[phone rings]
All passengers holding tickets
on Pan American Flight 10
should been board.
TWA Flight 36 now arriving at gate 37.
Passenger Troutman, please come
to the American Airlines ticket oftioe.
All passengers holding tickets
on American Airlines Flight 12
should be on board.
- Hows it going?
- OK.
- OK, thank you very much.
- Thank you.
Wonder which is worth more,
the cargo or the plane?
It's a toss-up. I'll bet that together
they're equal to the GNP of T.
Lafite Rothschild '45.
I didn't know there was any left.
- After tonight there won't be, Captain.
- [men chuckle]
[woman on Tannoy] “tickets on Pan American
Flight Four may proceed to the boarding area.
- Julie, where's Eve?
- In the offioe.
See you later.
Mm-hm.
- My problem is a fear of flying. What's yours?
- What makes you think I have a problem?
We've been living together longer
than most people are unhappily married.
- I don't think you can help me with this one.
- I can't help you?
You forget that I'm a pilot,
the symbol of strength and security.
Lightning may flash
and thunder may roar around my plane,
but when the biggie walks through the bin,
little old ladies stop fingering their beads
and sweaty palms dry up.
Gallagher is at the controls.
No harm n come to anybody.
You tell me I can't help you.
- Stop talking and hold me.
- I can't do two things at once.
- Will you we
- I'll try.
Listen, wouldn't it just be sensational
if after the festivities tonight
we announced that we were getting married?
Mr Stevens has asked me
in take over the Geneva dime
for a year or longer,
and I think I might like to try that.
Well, I'll just get the job
flying the route from New York
to Paris to Geneva.
I'll see you once or maybe twice a week.
I n't think of a more solid basis
for a happy marriage.
- I've been through one divorce.
- That doesn't make you unique.
- Why can't we just keep it the way it is?
- No.
Because I want a wife and children.
Not necessarily in that order, but...
Until you make up your mind,
why don't you buy me lunch?
Yeah... You make more than I do.
We'll go Dutch.
- They've gone.
- Good.
Let's get moving. We're behind schedule.
Thanks, Julie.
Lisa, I'm so glad you're here.
I didn't think you were coming.
Me neither.
Benjy, you remember Eve, don't you?
Hello, Benjy. Your fatherll be
so pleased to see you.
I wish the feeling were mutual.
I'm doing it for Benjy.
- You're just like your father.
- What'?
Stubborn. Stubborn woman.
- Have you got everything, Dorothy?
- Yes.
Good.
- Get these stowed away.
- [mocking]
Hey, help me get these things
stowed away for take-off.
Mrs Livingston, you look wonderful.
Is this plane as fantastic
as the newspapers say it is?
Come and see for yourself.
- Well, what do you think'?
- It's magnificent.
Excuse me.
Dorothy, get comfortable.
And try to relax
Have a drink It'll do you good.
Emily.
- I hoped you'd be flying with us.
- You're missing a fourth.
She just arrived.
Come and sit down and join us.
- Dr Herbert Williams.
- How do you do?
- Gerald Lu.
Delighted to meet you.
I admire your sponsorship of young artists.
Unfortunately, I don't admire
your printed attacks on them.
My reviews are never meant personally.
Only a politician could have said that better.
Don't worry, gentlemen.
I declare a truce on all art critics.
But only for the duration of the flight.
Right now the name of the game is poker.
Five-card stud, ten-dollar ante.
No ceiling on raises and nothing is wild.
Any objections, boys?
- One of the nicest pictures I've ever seen.
- Did you hear that, Mommy?
Bonnie's class wrote to Mr Stevens
about their painting.
He asked them
to pick someone to bring it.
And they chose me.
Well, they couldn't have made a better choice.
Flight service, this is 2-3 Sierra Heavy.
Any weather updates?
[over radio] Heavy frontal activity off
the Guif Coast is continuing to build.
Better keep a pretty tight
schedule, Captain.
Roger and out.
May I have your attention, please?
I'd like to take a moment of your time
to acquaint you with our airplane.
You are now located in the main lounge.
Aft of our main lounge area,
we have the communication centre,
bedrooms and the library
with conference facilities.
Below, down the centre stairs,
we have our crew seating area,
cargo storage fore and aft,
and a complete galley pable of preparing
the most eacotic of dishes.
Up the forward stairs, we have a small offioe
and, of course, the flight deck.
If there are any questions,
please, feel free to ask. Thank you.
2-3 Sierra, proceed to runway one niner light
and hold for clearance.
[Gallagher] Roger, Tower.
2-3 Sierra, you're next for take-off clearance.
[Gallagher] Roger, Tower. Thank you.
Good evening. I'm glad
you could join us in the inaugural flight
of the Stevens Corporation new airplane.
-lwishloouldbewithyou, but...
- Who's that'?
- That's your grandpa.
- Have I ever met him?
- Mm-hm. Once, when you were a little boy.
- How little?
About like that.
In the meantime,
have fun and enjoy the flight.
Good evening.
This is your pilot, Captain Gallagher.
Mr Stevens thought you might like
a plane's eye view of the take-off.
We'll be getting clearance momentarily,
so just sit back and enjoy yourselves.
[tower controller] 245 Siena,
you're cleared for take-off.
[Chambers] Roger, Tower. I understand.
Cleared for take-off.
[Chambers] We're rolling.
How fast n this plane go, Mommy?
Fast enough.
Grandpa sure has a neat plane,
doesn't he, Mom?
Grandfather has a lot of expensive toys.
Who's light?
RBeautyisintheeyesofthebeholder
♪ And that's what I want to do
rHoldyouinmylifeforever
rAndjustkeeponbvimw"
rBeautyisintheeyesofthebeholder
rSotakeaspeciallookandsee
I' And just possibly
♪ Youtl see the beauty that's in me A'
[girl] Come onl Come onl
Come onl
- I wonl
- I guess you're just too good for me.
- I wanna play with Dorothy now.
- Are they getting the best of you?
I'm outclassed, that's all.
Bonnie, let's see if I n beat you.
[man 1] This will be the last to go in.
[man 2] Right. It's more complicated.
And the crews quarters here?
You're talking about a ten-storey structure
that's gotta take the stress of the sea.
I'll show you the notes I made
at the last meeting with the architect.
You men are so lucky.
I wish I had a hobby like yours.
A plan that n harvest the seas for food
and save millions from starvation
can hardly be called a hobby.
I'm terribly sorry. I didn't mean to offend.
I can't imagine
what made me say a thing like that.
I hope you'll let me apologise. I do.
You know that I do. I'm terribly sorry.
- Mrs Wallace.
- Yes.
- Hows the parbf?
_ paw? What paw'?
Oh, I've found a hobby of my own.
Philip Stevens collects art.
I have now become
the foremost collector of toy booze.
Wait till you see this. I have a mini margarita.
And a teeny Martini.
Aren't they cute?
This is just about your size, Martin.
Come on. Drink with me.
Thank you, but I'll leave you to your collection.
- That was very good work, Frank
- Very good.
I'll put it in with the rest of the presentation.
Excuse me.
- Why do you treat him that way?
- He loves it.
Do you know how oonoemed he is about you?
I'm oonoemed about him.
I'm more oonoemed about him than you are.
You're the one
who seduced his wife, you know.
Yes, I know.
I'm lonely. I need someone
to be r1ioe to me this week.
Gen you be nice to me this week'?
No, I don't think so.
What would Martin say if he knew about us?
I really don't think he'd mind, do you?
Do you? I'm gonna ask him.
- Karen.
- What'?
- You're blackmailing me.
- Who else have I got to blackmail?
I don't get to fool around that much.
See you on the ground.
We're light on schedule, sir.
I don't think the weatherll be a problem.
Eve Clayton just walked in.
She has a message for you.
It's Mr Stevens.
- Hello, Philip?
- Eve, how are things going?
Everything is fine. Lisa and Benjy are here.
They're there? Well, that's wonderful.
I don't know how you did it,
but I thank you a million times.
You don't have to thank me.
She decided all by herself.
Isn't that wonderful?
I'll see you at the airport. Bye.
Goodbye.
Robert, get the r ready.
We're going to the airport.
And how about this?
Lisa and Benjy are coming home with me.
By the way, Captain,
I've been thinking about what you said.
So have I.
Can we talk about it in Palm Beach tonight?
I think that could be arranged.
Yeah.
We're right on schedule, but we have to
do something about that security guard.
Don't wony. When the time comes,
I'll take re of him.
Champagne on the rocks?
I haven't had that in years.
How did you know'?
"Mr Nicholas St Downs lll."
"London, 1936. "
I don't believe it.
It IS Nicky.
After all these years and you turn up here.
Where have you been?
- London, mostly.
- And you know Philip?
Hard to work in the worlds of art and money
and not know him.
- And which world is yours?
- Both.
I arrange financing for a number of museums
and I've acquired
a modest collection of my own.
Would you re to see the present
I am taking to the museum?
I certainly would.
I don't know what I'd do ifyou'd said no.
How beautiful.
Oh, Nicky. It is good to see you.
Captain.
We have a low reading
for the middle cargo hold.
It is low. Maybe one of the sensors is out.
Buchekll take a look at it.
Yeah?
- Mr Buchek, it's for you.
- Yeah?
I hear this is a special day for you, Eddie.
- The doctor said it's gonna be twins.
- I'll check light away.
Twins? You must be nervous.
No... terrified. It's the first time.
I see. Have you seen Mr Stevens' daughter?
She was upstairs in the offioe.
I sent her a drink
- Doyou mind if I ll mywife?
- Please do.
- Larry, would you take over for me?
- Sure thing.
- That's OK.
- You shouldn't be down here, son.
That's all light. Benjy, how are you?
Close that hatch.
We'll check the pressure on this one.
What was that? My ears popped.
That's air pressure.
Each one of these holds
is airtight when it's sealed.
How come?
So we n rry all kinds
of different things in the rgos.
This ship's special.
- Captain Gallagher.
- The dumb indicator light was stuck
- How's the reading now'?
- Good. Thanks, Stan.
- Are you a real policeman, Mr Hunter'?
- Sort of.
- Have you ught a lot of crooks?
- A few, but none lately.
Will you tell me about them?
- Sure. Any time.
- OK, Benjy. Hup, hup, hupl
Lisa, Lisa. What's wrong?
It's the same old story.
My father calls and I come running.
I think it's wonderful that you me.
He's missed you. Two years is a long time.
I know that. And in that time
I've made a life for myself and Benjy.
I'm finally someone
other than Philip Stevens' daughter.
All he ever wanted to do
was to try to help you.
I know that.
My fathers a very powerful man.
I don't think he realises it, but he tends
to dominate everybody around him.
Especially me. But I'm going to tell him
that I'm finally living my own life,
once and for all.
This is a very important time for him.
Don't upset him, please.
I don't intend to upset him,
but I have to tell him how I feel,
whether it upsets him or not.
I don't think you should.
Your fathers very ill.
The doctors say he has a few months,
maybe a little longer.
- That's impossible.
- No, it's true.
I'm sorry, darling.
Oh, my God, Eve.
It's time for me
to stretch my legs, Captain.
Right.
- [woman 1] Tried the caviar'?
- [woman 2] No.
We've got ten minutes. The important thing
is to get Gallagher out of the cockpit.
Leave it to me.
The diving's the best part. You can't
imagine it if you haven't experienced it.
It's like exploling a world hidden from man
since the beginning of time.
It's beautiful, really beautiful.
I couldn't do that. Water terrifies me.
It shouldn't. It's wonderful down there.
In fact, it's about the only time
I ever really feel free.
Excuse me. I don't mean to intrude,
but could you move your ass, dear?
Thank youl
That was very cruel.
If I weren't cruel,
how would people know how kind you are?
If I weren't a sinner, how could you look
like a saint'? isn't that why we're together?
If it isn't, tell me.
I'll stop acting like such an idiot.
Why should I, my dear?
You're so proficient at it.
- Forget it.
- What'?
You hit him too hard. He's dead.
Come on. Let's get him outta here.
Captain Gallagher.
This is the flight steward. I'm in the bedroom.
- You'd better come back here.
- What's your problem?
It's one of the passengers, sir.
He seems very ill.
I'll be right there.
One of the passengers isn't feeling well.
[chattering and laughter]
Nicks"
[woman groaning]
[coughing and splutteling]
[clock ticking]
There's no time for that.
Get down to the cargo hold.
- How are we doing?
- Fine. Get him outta here.
Tune for us to duck
under the radar scan and vanish.
Flight 2-3 Sierra is about to disappear
into the Bermuda Triangle.
Somethings wrong.
- You having problems with that repeater?
- No, it's just not here.
- I've lost contact with 2-3 Sierra.
- Hang on.
They're in the Bermuda Triangle.
I'll try to contact them by radio.
[man] 245 Siena,
this is Palm Beach Approach. Do you read?
- We n lose these now.
- We have lost radar contact.
[chuckles] Home free. In 20 minutes
we'll be on St George Island.
- Any problem on that end?
- Why should there be?
The airstrip hasn't been used
since World War ll.
We'll have to make the transfer
before those people wake up.
Relax. They'll find themselves
sitting on an empty 747
wondering what happened,
[chuckles] and we'll be halfway
to South Amel'i.
Yes, I'll speak to Mr Stevens.
Phil, Herb Corrigan.
We have aircraft and ships
heading to the point
where the 747 disappeared.
- I'll be waiting light here.
- You're welcome to join us.
We're monitoring the coastguard search too.
I'll get out there as quick as I n.
Thanks, Herb.
Navy Search Base, this is Navy Search Three.
On station. Over.
[man on radio] Navy Search Three, this is
Navy Search Base. Roger. Out.
Navy Search Base, this is Coastguard
Cutter Venture on course to search area.
Navy Search One, this is Navy Search Two
proceeding to Sector Charlie. Over.
This is Navy Search Four
proceeding to Sector Dena.
Negative sightings in Alpha Sector. Out.
- Any chance of them spotting us?
- Not a chance.
We're headed away from them
at 600 miles an hour.
I'd better help Banker.
Thank you.
This weather fronts going to limit
the air operation's effectiveness.
We need more ships.
Get me CINCLANT Fleet Operations.
[ticking]
Stays.
Oh, yeah.
What is it? What the hell happened?
Jesus Christ.
[alarm sounding]
Bonnie? Bonniel
[screams] Bonniel
Bonnie. Come on.
- Oh, my Godl
- Face the rear of the plane.
- What's happening?
- Put anything solid behind your back
- Get down.
- Back inside.
[screams]
[woman sobbing]
[woman groaning]
[man] Just take it easy.
Jesus Christ. Give me a hand here.
Move it. Move itl
- Is it broken?
- I think it's broken.
- Kid, take it easy.
- All light, honey.
- Oh, my Godl Bonniel
- She's OK.
- Don't move her.
- Keep her still.
[girl crying]
On, my God. Look.
Lookl
Look.
[woman] Oh, my Godl Oh, my Godl
- Hold onl
- [screaming and sobbing]
Look nu“
Don't panic. The emergency lights
come on automatically.
- The life jacketsl
- Nol Forget the life jackets.
- We can't open the door.
- We're gonna drown.
- Nobody is going to drown.
- Have you radioed for help?
Radios don't work underwater,
but they know ctly where we went down.
- What if we run out orfair
- Calm down. I said calm downl
Everybody. People are seriously injured
and they need our help.
Get pillows, blankets, sheets,
anything that will make the injured
more comfortable.
- Where's that Dr...
- Williams.
Here, Captain.
There's a little girl that's pretty bad off.
Put a tourniquet on this man's arm.
See if you n move that piano.
Give me your belt.
Goddamnitl How could you let
a thing like this happen to us?
- How oould you?
- Stan, give me your belt.
Don, what in hell happened?
I don't know, but I'm gonna find out.
You check the damage.
Sir, could you hold this tight'?
Every five minutes let it go
and then do it again.
Sir, I'm gonna need a little help.
Can you come with me?
- Will you be all light here?
- Of course. Go with him, Nicky.
Thank you.
The children, are they all right'?
Yes, they're fine.
Now, you just lie back
and let me take re of you.
Oh, Jesus, nol Where's Benjy? Oh, Godl
He's down below in the main cabin.
He is all fight.
- My God. What's going on here?
- We crashed.
- We crashed?
- Yes, we crashed.
People down below are seriously injured.
We've got to help them.
- I'm too frightened.
- We're all frightened, but we can't show it.
We're gonna have a panic on our hands.
The people down below need your help.
So do I.
- I'll try.
- You'll do it.
Come on.
You'll be all light.
On, my God.
OK.
- Do you need any help?
- Yeah.
Help me get this bastard into the otfioe.
How badly is she hurt, Doctor?
She has internal injuries,
how extensive I'm not sure.
- Let's put her over here.
- [woman whimpering]
No leaks so far, but it was never built
to withstand this much outside pressure.
- How long will it last'?
- Who knows?
1'lll the rescue units get here?
- I hope.
. [man groaning]
Somebody... help me.
Christ, Mr Buchek. I'm glad to see you.
My God. Give me a hand with that.
[Buchek] It's gonna hurt a little, Eddie.
Hang on.
- Easy.
- Owl
- You said it was only gonna hurt a little.
- You got a knife?
- [Buchek] Take it easy.
- Hold still.
This won't hurt.
I'm only gonna cut your trouser leg.
But hold still, please.
You got it?
Oh, Jesusl
- Oh, boy.
- That ain't good.
- Just lie still.
- We need some help.
- I'll get somebody to help you.
- See if you can find that doctor.
His pupil dilation's fine.
It's probably a concussion.
He should come around.
He's got a hell of a lot of explaining to do.
Doc, you come with me.
- What's the condition of the fuselage?
-
Eddie is in the communications room.
His leg is smashed to hell.
See if you n help him.
[man] It's not good.
[woman] Why don't we put on the life jackets?
- How is he?
- OK.
- I'm gonna need your help.
- Sure.
Let's see if we n find a bottle of whisky.
Karen, it's going to be all light.
I promise you, it's going to be all light.
Don't leave me just for a minute.
Just don't leave me alone.
But there are injured people who need help.
Well, you're supposed to take re of me.
I mean... What's going to happen to me?
I'm sorry, my dear, but... the doctor needs me.
No, it's back aft here.
There. There we go.
Let's see what we got here, now.
Electric storage cell, no.
Interrupted service. Here we are.
CM-1, CM-2... CD-1. That's it.
[water gurgling]
On, my God.
Oh, bw-
Look at this.
- It's cold all the way to the top.
- Completely flooded.
Better check the near cargo holds.
Do you want some more water?
- Yeah, please.
- OK.
- Julie?
- Yes?
I love you, Julie.
Here.
Steve.
- That doesn't seem to be flooded.
- Seem?
Let's hope you're light-
- Looks dry.
- Yeah, for now.
How long n she stand the pressure?
Who the hell knows? I just hope
it doesn't slide down any deeper.
Any increase in pressure'll crush this fuselage
like an empty beer n.
And the lack of a fresh air supply, oxygen,
that could become a very big factor.
Captain,
the oopilofs regained consciousness.
- Mama.
- Yes, darling?
Is Bonnie gonna die?
No, love.
She looks real sick.
I know, but she's gonna be all light.
You'll see. Come here.
LS that all of it?
- Just about.
Coastal radar did have a fix on us
before the crash, didn't they?
No. We were too low for radar interception.
It's fortunate that you are injured,
you miserable son of a bitchl
I'd take you apart... Get him down below.
Come on.
What did you mean about the radar?
Chambers flew us off course.
The search planes'll never look for us here.
- There's no chance they'll find us?
- We're on our own.
And that is the total situation
as of this moment.
I'm glad you came down here.
I'll act as liaison
between my company and the navy.
I'll bring Mr Stevens up to date.
Phil, let's take a walk and get some fresh air.
[Stevens] Do you think there's
a chance, Joe?
Patron“ Between the new
and the coastguard,
there are twenty planes
and six ships out there.
The area where they think the plane went
down is covered. The search is expanding.
[Stevens] So far they've
come up with nothing.
[Patroni] If there are survivors,
they're gonna find 'em.
My daughter and my grandson
are on that plane,
you know that'?
I have a picture of her here.
- She's a beautiful girl.
- She is.
I only hope there'll... there'll be a miracle
and I'll have a chance to see her again.
They'll just keep searching, Phil.
They'll keep searching.
- Go ahead.
- OK, I'm through.
[indistinct chatter]
Would you move, please?
- Please move.
- Hold on.
- Julie, dear, would you move, please?
- Come on.
[Frank] I got him. Let go.
How is he?
It's a bad fracture, but I think he'll be OK.
You don't sound too sure.
Although there are similarities,
this isn't my usual line of work
You see, I'm a doctor of veterinary medicine.
I look after the horses
at Mr Stevens' racing stables.
Maybe we ought to keep that
to ourselves, Anne.
Whatever you say, Doctor.
[Gallagher] This way. Where is it? Right here.
Ah, here we go. Where is the E-15 circuit?
[Buchek] The E-15 circuit breaks
light through the bulkhead light here.
[creaking]
Oh, God.
I'll be right back
- It's started.
- HOW bad?
- Bad. How we doing here?
- Take a look at 57-W.
[woman whimpering]
What's the matter'?
- Listen. Did you hear that'?
- [faint whispering]
No. I don't hear anything.
Everyone be quiet for a second.
Listen.
- What's that sound?
- Quiet. Listen.
[engine running]
- It sounds like a ship.
- They're coming for usl
- [woman 1] Thank Godl
- [woman 2] Thank God, they're coming for usl
[engine fades]
- [sighs] It's gone.
- It can't be.
It just can't be.
How could they leave us like this?
How could they?
- I don't know.
- Lisa...
I know. Because they never even saw us.
It's a passing ship.
They didn't even know we were here.
- That's enough.
- Nobody does.
- I said that's enoughl
- More than enough, Mr Gallagher.
Goddamn mess we're in.
I think it's time we took a crack at this.
Is she any better?
Her temperatures gone even higher.
Isn't there something we could do?
E-15... Here.
Let's see. Yeah, that's E-15 all light.
- Gen that circuit be jumped?
- Well, sure, it n be jumped.
But what worries me is whether
that bulkhead n withstand the pressure.
If we don't get a man up to send
a mayday signal, they'll never find us.
You're light. Some choice we got.
Either we all drown or we all suffocate.
- Come on.
- [roaring crash]
OK, everybody. Quickly, please.
Settle down and listen very closely.
This raft has got a small built-in radio
that activates
when the raft hits the surface of the water.
It's gonna send a distress signal.
On the surface of the water?
A lot of good that does us dovm here.
Well, you're light, aren't you?
We have to get the raft out of the plane.
One door opens in,
in the near cargo section.
- We n open it electrilly.
- Won't that flood the plane?
No. There's a sealed door
between the cargo hold and here.
If the bulkheads don't give way,
that's the only place it'll flood.
I'll be in the hall with this oxygen.
If I n get the raft out,
get that damn thing up and inflated,
the search parties'll hear it.
- That's about it. Let's go.
- Captain.
- [Wallace] I think I should go with you.
- No.
I'm an experienced scuba-diver.
Two men have a better chance
of making it than one.
[Buchek] He's light, Don.
Go up in the cockpit,
get another one of these rigs and join us.
It's in the starboard locker.
Get a couple of life jackets.
[worried chatter]
Put that wire on the blue terminal.
OK.
- How much more?
- Not much. Just one more wire.
Nothing I say will make any difference. Why?
Let the pilot go. Why are you taking a chance?
- I'm doing this for all of us.
- We're usl
They're a bunch of strangers.
You think everybody is us.
Oen't you forget about other people
and think about yourself?
Other people thinking about themselves
got us down here in the first place.
You've got a lot of brains, Martin,
but you're not a smart man.
Help me off with this.
Careful with that one.
- You've got it.
- OK. Now...
I touch those together and that should do it?
- That ought to do it.
- Then we do it now.
Look, we have a date tonight in Palm Beach,
so you take re of yourself.
Promise.
There really isn't much more to say.
There's a hell of lot more to say.
There just isn't time enough to say it.
You all set'?
Get up against this bulkhead
and stay as flat as you n.
When that damn door opens,
you're gonna think
the gates of hell me open.
We've only got two minutes of air.
Here we go.
[buzzing]
What's wrong?
Must be a short in one of those damn wires.
[creaking]
Don't get too close to the door.
Mrs Wallace, come away from the window.
Lay her back
Get her something to drink
[Emily] Look. He's made it.
Here, have some more. Easy. Here.
Come on, drink it.
- Take it easy.
- [sobbing]
OK, Frank
[whispering] There you go. Easy, now.
All light. Easy, Mrs Wallace.
[gasping]
[beeping on radio]
We have a beeperl
Navy Search Five, this is Navy Search Base.
We have an emergency beeper
at 27 degrees north, 65 degrees west.
- Proceed and investigate.
- This is Navy Search Five.
Wiloo. Out.
[beeping on radio continues]
200 miles off course? That's incredible.
- What ships are in that area?
- Agerholm and Cayuga.
- They're not part of our operation.
- They are now.
Get me Admiral James at CINCLANT Fleet.
- And check the coastguard.
- Aye aye, sir.
Isn't there something I n do to help?
Hows your breast-stroke?
- [reassuring whispering]
- [woman crying]
- Mrs Wallace?
- I have to leave.
Why? If you open that door,
you'll hurt a lot of people.
Please, don't... Don't do thatl
God
[woman] Stop in
Take your hand off that door.
Listen to me.
Stop m
Someone help theml
on, my Got“
Look at that. There it is.
Hey, looks like we've got a survivor in a raft.
[Gallagher] Come on, baby. Come onl Yesl
Yeahl
Give meawagl Atta way I
Navy Search Base,
this is Navy Search Five. Over.
This is Navy Search Base. Go ahead.
Have located the aircraft at coordinates given.
One man in a life raft.
No other survivors sighted.
- Aircrafl is completely submerged.
- Is the fuselage still intact'?
- Roger. Appears to be.
- I want this to be a first-stage alert.
Get me helos, scuba teams,
compressors, air-hose packages, the works.
I want this treated like
an emergency sub-salvage operation.
Get me the plain of Cayuga
on a voice circuit.
- This is Captain Guay.
- I'm sure you know why I'm fling.
Yes, sir. We're prepared
to take that man on board.
We have a UDT team,
but we'll need additional equipment
and more divers.
- Mrat is your ETA?
- Less than half an hour.
I would like to embark the aircraft owner
on Cayuga. Do you concur?
- We'll be happy to have him aboard.
- Thank you, Captain.
Phil, we n get you out there
by helo immediately. You too, Joe.
No, I'll be of more use here, Admiral.
They're gonna need the spew
on that planes stress points.
Get Mr Patroni a direct line to his company.
And he'll need to be in constant contact
with Cayuga.
- This way, Mr Patroni.
- We'll get that plane up.
And in one piece.
[creaking]
- Buchek.
- We've got to move Dorothy.
[Emily] We're going to have to move her.
Get her in the back of the plane.
Quick, move it.
[man] Don't worry.
I got her head.
- Hurry it up.
- Easy. Take it easy.
Sir. I have contact out there, sir.
OK.
Lookout reports we have a life raft
off the starboard bow.
Come light and prepare to put a boat
in the water.
- Aye aye, sir. Right, full rudder.
- Aye aye, sir.
[chattering]
[T annoy] Lower the stem ramp.
Thanks. Am I glad to see you guysl
Hang on. Here we go.
[T annoy] Raise the stem ramp.
Don't let it slip.
IT annoy] Stand by.
Let's get down there.
- Mr Gallagher, the pilot.
- Are you all right'?
- Yes, sir. I'm fine.
- What's the situation?
Most of the passengers are alive,
but that fuselage is gonna give way.
- Air?
- They've been down there too long.
We'll get this rescue operation going.
Get him some dry clothes.
- Thank you.
- Main line.
AYE aye, sir.
[panicky screams]
Eve, Powers, come here.
Distribute these to the passengers.
- One at a time.
- They slip over the head.
Make sure they're secured tightly.
As far as the other stress points go,
watch out for sections 5-B and 9-L.
They can'! take much torque.
We're keeping a line open at this end.
Don, I don't need to tell you the risk factor
of getting the plane up in one piece.
It could split wide open at any time.
Take re and good luck.
Thanks, Joe.
- My daughter and grandson...
- They weren't injured, sir.
We're gonna raise the plane
with salvage pontoons.
Lieutenant Norris will lead the UDT team.
- I'll go with them.
- You a diver?
- Amateur.
- I'm not sure I n permit that.
Your men don't know
the stress points of a 747.
Attach the pontoons in the wrong place,
that ship'll crack wide open.
You need me down there.
Get this man into some scuba gear.
Right this way.
- Grab the stern line.
- I got it.
Stand clear of the airline.
L got YOU.
Play it out eafiY-
Hook it up.
Easy does it.
The main damage is in the forward cargo hold.
Gen we get air to the passengers?
Too risky. You can't cut through
that thin aluminum.
OK, let's get going-
The captain's gotta be kidding.
He thinks we're gonna attach
some air balloons to that 747
and it's gonna float light up to the surface.
- It's gonna blow up like a bomb going off.
- They gotta try something.
Those people'll die from lack of oxygen.
Don't bet anything on their chances
with this balloon routine.
- All set, sir?
- I'm ready.
All light, let's go. Over the side.
There's divers out there. They're coming for us.
- What did he say?
- Where? I can't see them. Move over.
There they are.
They're gonna try and raise the plane.
It's gonna be like a tidal wave.
Grab anything solid
you n get your hands on.
Grab that companion-way rail.
Use your belts. Strap yourselves in.
Doctor, get that child up here
by the pong table.
Move it out. Come on.
[gushing Miter]
Here, grab this.
[thumping and rasping]
[scraping]
- Here's number one line.
- Number two.
Gdtil?
OK, take it on down.
[creaking]
Captain Gum].
- Go ahead, Norris.
- Plane's leaking like a sieve.
- Gallagher says it's now or never.
- What about the weight distribution?
It's gonna come up at a steep angle.
- Any way to equalise the load?
- No, sir.
Let's get those boats out of the way.
We're gonna have to chance it.
Let's go.
Hold on to me, Dorothy.
It'll be all right.
The boats have pulled back a safe distance.
We n start.
Start the compressor.
[creaking and groaning]
[creaking]
Reduce the air pressure.
We can't afford to lose another one of those.
[panicky screams]
Martin, help mel
Nickyl Hold onl Nickyl
Benjyl
Somebody help himl
I got himl It's all light. Hold on to me.
Increase the pressure.
My God.
Get readyl
We made it.
[cries of relief]
Let's gol
Better get those people out fast.
That plane could go down
as quick as it came up.
You're safe. You're going to be all light.
Dorothy?
Let's get out of here.
Tam your shoes um
We'll disembark in the following manner.
The injured first, then the children, women
and finally the men.
- Give me the girl.
- I'll help with the child.
I'll take the kid.
Watch nu“
inflate your life jackets before getting outl
Wait for the boatsl
Come on inl
All light, step on it.
Let's get 'em on that boat.
- My legl
- Take it easy.
Oh...G0dl
Put her over there.
Come on.
Careful. Oarefull
Sir.
OK.
Get them in life jacketsl
Gol Take that one offl
- Frank
- Chambers is dead.
[Eddie] om om
Go ahead
Evel
The oockpitl Come onl
- Nol
- The oockpitl
I n'tl
Stay there.
Come onl Jumpl
Grab me.
Watch her head. Be careful.
Benjy.
I'm your grandpa.
- She's gonna be all light.
- Thank you.
Easy, Eddie.
Cold?
L.__ rm WE
"hing Up
You'd better. You got a date with me tonight.
I love you.