You can´t...
have my daughter.
No.
No. Stay away!
Stay out of here.
Stay out!
She´s my daughter!
Stay away.
Mommy.
Mommy, come and play with me...
in my room.
Right now, Mommy. Okay?
l got an idea.
No! Let go of me!
No! Who will protect her? No!
Let me go!
Rachel! Rachel!
No! l can´t leave her!
l have to protect her! Rachel!
Okay, Rachel...
your momma´s gotta go somewhere to get
some rest so she´ll feel better, okay?
Are you okay?
ls your dad around?
l don´t have a dad.
Okay, here´s what we´re gonna do.
We´re gonna take you someplace
real nice...
with a really nice family
until we get this sorted out, okay?
Rachel!
Stop it!
Stop!
Hello. lt´s Monday morning.
Time to get up and go to work.
But never fear because
the Moneyman is here...
Sorry, Walt.
- Are you workin´ tonight?
- They moved me to the graveyard shift.
Was the dog in the house last night?
He´s allowed in the morning.
Daytime´s okay,
but not at night.
l only let him in this morning.
There´s no juice.
We´re out of a lot of things.
l heard dog noises last night
when l was trying to sleep.
Walter was not in the house last night.
That voice!
As long as you´re under this roof...
you´ll respect us as your parents
and treat us like that.
Sorry.
Take it easy, Boyd.
She might not be with us much longer.
Your mom´s making progress, right?
On her new medication,
the Clozaril?
Where are we gonna make up
that 300 bucks a month?
May l be excused?
Well, hello.
Oh, she speaks.
Her mouth opens, and sounds come out.
She didn´t call all weekend.
l figured her voice was gone.
What´s wrong?
Foster dad being a pain again?
Yeah.
Why are you so weirdly happy?
Do l look any different?
Do you look any--
Oh, my God!
You did it?
Yeah.
Who?
You wouldn´t believe me if l just
told you, so l´m bringing him to lunch.
- You suck.
- Oh, love you too.
- Best blood.
- One. Two. Three.
Four.
Are you ready to beat beat?
Morning, ladies.
How you doin´ this morning?
What´s goin´ on, bro?
Get away from me!
Dude, according to these new rules...
how many points do l get
if l do that chick over there?
The fat one? Six.
No, bro, l did her last week and you
only gave me five. And she´s not fat.
Yeah, but l figure if he´s got the balls
to go in after you, you dirty shit...
l´m giving him an extra point.
- Hey, guys.
- Oh, Jesse, that Tracy girl.
You gotta get all over that girl, man.
Serious, bro.
- She´s on my list.
- She´s definitely fine.
She got an ass stamped B.P., baby!
Bulldog property.
Can you develop these at work for me?
- Total coyote date.
- That´s harsh, bro.
lt´s the truth.
- What´s a coyote date?
- You don´t know?
That´s when you wake up in the morning,
some ugly chick sleeping on your arm...
and you´d rather gnaw it off
than have to wake her up.
God, woman, you come prepared.
Tell me who the special someone is.
All will be revealed in due time.
""Romeo and Juliet,"" a tale...
of star-crossed lovers, pulled apart
by their families, society...
and, some might say, by fate.
Why is it that we are so moved by love
that ends with separation?
What say?
Anyone.
Anyone!
l don´t know that l believe in it.
Believe in what?
Love.
Well, then you´ve got bigger problems
than passing this class.
- Who would love her?
- Yes, Arnold.
""Love is 15 seconds
of squishing noises.""
Unquote. Johnny Rotten.
Know what l´m saying?
Dork. Kill that kid.
Do you think all love stories
are tragedies?
Unless they die at the same time...
all lovers are eventually separated
by death, right?
Then ""Romeo and Juliet"" isn´t a tragedy.
They could only be together in death.
Yes! Very good!
A foul cynic, most cliche.
- A true romantic. How refreshing!
- Yeah.
Shut up.
Oh, hello there.
Hey, girls, what´s happenin´?
Move out. Thank you.
Mark Bing wanted me to invite you
to his party Friday night.
- ls Jesse going with anyone?
- l don´t think so.
Could you please refrain
from shooting my ass?
Lisa.
Did you see that?
Oh, my God!
Let´s go. Stay back, please.
Let´s stay back.
You better come with me.
A girl just killed herself in the lot.
Stay here.
Best blood.
Oh, my God.
Rachel, come on, back away.
Attention all students.
Report to your homeroom classes.
Oh, man.
Whose car is this?
She was really happy this morning.
l don´t understand why she--
lt´s okay.
Let it out.
No.
l don´t cry.
Miss Snell, please report
to the principal´s office.
Miss Snell, please come
l have to go.
Rachel, stay here, okay?
l´ll be back as soon as l can.
One of our students died today.
We will observe at exactly 1:00 p.m.
a moment of silence.
- Lisa Parker may be gone.
- Hand me the score book.
But she will not be forgotten
by her friends.
She will not be forgotten
by her fellow students.
by her teachers...
or by her school.
Her parents are going to want
all this.
Oh, my.
That girl Lisa, right?
Yeah.
l was supposed to have lunch
with her today.
Yeah?
You guys thought she was shit, right?
Mark.
Don´t look at me like this. You guys
said it. You thought she was shit.
What did you do?
Nothing. l didn´t do anything.
lt´s just Lisa was acting all happy,
you know, like we were going steady.
And l had to break the news to her
that she was just a pump.
You know, a nut.
She didn´t mean anything to me.
l guess she couldn´t handle it.
ls that your brilliant attempt
to fix it?
That´s good.
You need all the points you can get.
l don´t know why you´re erasing them.
That´s cold, man.
On Friday we have the Kings University
scout coming to the game.
lf all this gets out--
Sex and suicide.
Come on, man. Catholic schools
frown on that shit.
lf l don´t get into a good school,
my dad´s gonna kill me.
But nobody´s gonna find out about this.
Lisa took a picture of us last night.
What if her parents ask questions?
That´s a problem.
Oh, shit.
All right, l´ll handle it.
l´ll take care of it.
How?
Relax, man. Come on.
Come on.
- Sorry. Didn´t mean to scare you.
- lt´s all right.
You´re Rachel, right?
Yeah. Yeah.
l´m Jesse. English?
Right.
The true romantic?
- Yeah.
- Rachel, listen. That Lisa girl?
She had these pictures that have
what you might call sentimental value.
l figured 20 bucks ought to cover it.
What do you want, 30?
They´re not your pictures.
lt´s not like she´s gonna be
pickin´ them anytime soon, is it?
Cut it out, man.
All right, Rachel, l´ll tell you what.
How ´bout l swing by
when you get off work?
l´ll take you out for a cruise.
Come on. l don´t bite.
Unless you want me to.
l don´t think so.
Why not?
Because l´m a dyke.
That´s funny.
- Don´t laugh, man.
- Just drive.
How you doin´ tonight?
""For a moment, l thought someone
was actually seeing me...
but it was all a lie.
Eric lied when he said l was special,
and l guess l was lying to myself.
l believed him.""
Rachel, is there anything in there
that strikes a chord for you?
Do you know what Lisa
was referring to?
Yesterday, she--
She told me she lost her virginity.
Do you know this boy?
Eric Stark.
He´s on the team.
Can l talk to you for a second?
Excuse us, Rachel.
Robbie, l had a freshman girl crying
in the hallway last week.
Five more have been in my office
this semester.
l couldn´t get anything out of them,
but their friends told me...
that football players slept with them
then dumped them.
There´s nothing illegal
about breaking a girl´s heart.
Eric is 18.
Lisa was 16.
That´s statutory rape.
That´s a stretch.
Let´s make it before someone else´s
daughter jumps off a building.
Listen.
Are you sure you´re still not trying
to save a girl that died 20 years ago?
Help me!
Plug it up! Plug it up!
Okay. l´ll look into it.
That was great.
Yeah.
The Minute Man!
Do it, baby!
Do it again.
Gimme the book.
That´s in the book. Panties.
Oh, my--
He´s going back in for double time?
l don´t feel good.
l´m gonna be sick.
- He´s gonna puke!
- Not in my car.
You know, Mark invited me
to his party on Friday.
What are you thinking about?
Nobody.
l asked what, not who.
lt´s nothing.
Doesn´t it bother you that some girl
offed herself yesterday?
- Why? She wasn´t anybody.
- What?
l mean, l didn´t know her.
You know, l still don´t have a date
for Mark´s party.
Hint, hint.
Shit!
Stop.
Rachel, stop this.
Hey, get back here.
That rotten dog.
Hey, your dumb dog got out.
Walter!
Stay!
Stop!
Walter! My God!
Stop! Help!
Please stop! Stop!
Stop!
Rachel?
- Please.
- What happened?
Please help me.
Are you gonna be all right?
Sorry.
For what?
For making you come out here
all this way.
Don´t worry about it.
And what about my windshield?
How bizarre was that?
l´m sorry about your car.
lt wasn´t your fault.
lt was probably a rock or something.
Walter´s banged up pretty bad.
Has broken ribs.
He tore an artery in his front leg.
He´s lost quite a bit of blood.
His pressure´s stabilized.
He´s gonna make it.
- Can l see him?
- Come back tomorrow.
Any time after 8:00.
Don´t worry. lt´s because you look
like a mass murderer.
What´s up with the music here?
Don´t they have anything good,
like some Garbage?
- You like Garbage?
- Yeah. Shirley Manson, she rocks.
Lisa loved her.
You two were really close, huh?
l´m really sorry.
Sometimes...
l´d see someone from behind...
and l´d know...
l´d just know it was Lisa.
And she´d turn around,
and it wasn´t.
But sometimes it was.
And now...
whenever l see someone who looks
like her, and she turns around...
it won´t be.
Ever.
lt´s gettin´ pretty late.
- Can l give you a ride home?
- No, l can walk.
Yeah, right.
l can hitch. Don´t worry about it.
Then you can go hitch.
Or l could just...
wait for my limo.
Yeah, you could do that.
Just wait for your limo.
Come on.
All right, l guess
l´ll see you in school tomorrow.
Sure.
You´ll let me know
how Walter´s doing?
Yeah.
And thank you...
for everything.
Well, good night.
Good night.
- lt´s the dry weather.
- An acrylic sweater.
l shook her hand.
Thank you for your support.
l´d like your vote.
Stupid.
Lisa!
Don´t! Don´t jump!
Last night, l took a look at your file.
Your mom is at Arkham for schizophrenia?
How´s she doing?
She´s gonna be fine.
l had a really traumatic experience
in high school.
l tried to help someone,
and it backfired horribly.
No, stop!
l spent some time at Arkham...
as a patient.
Does that shock you?
l guess. l mean, you seem
pretty normal to me.
Yeah, well, l try.
Do you visit your mom often?
ls that scary for you?
What do you mean?
lt´s perfectly normal to be afraid
of turning out like your parents.
Come on.
l know l´m ten times more likely
to get it than most people.
l didn´t mean to patronize you.
So, is that scary for you?
Rachel...
in a way you´ve lost your mother...
and now you´ve lost a friend.
Losing people close to you can be...
very painful and lonely.
- lf you want to talk--
- No!
l´m sorry.
l must´ve knocked it.
l didn´t see you knock it.
l know.
l know what you did to her.
As we can see from last year´s film...
the Carlin Devils play tough,
smash-mouth football.
Here we see Mr. Bing--
- l thought you got the pictures.
- Just relax, all right?
Nobody knows but us. l´m sure they´re
at the Photo Mat. l´ll get them.
lt takes an hour to develop film.
Come on, man.
Mr. Bing, on your feet.
- Turn around and drop trou.
- What?
You heard.
Drop trou, shorts and all.
Now, son!
lf you wanna stay a starter
on this team.
You undress like a girl.
Let´s go.
After that half-assed block...
l wanted to check to see if maybe you
had a tampon string between your legs.
Sit.
All right, girls, come this Friday
it´s gonna be kill or be killed.
Let´s go!
- Yeah, Bing!
- You ready for the game Friday?
You´re saying you´ve never seen,
met or talked to Lisa Parker at all ?
No, sir, never.
Who´s this you´re hanging on to?
Salvation Army alert.
Look who Jess is talking to.
She´s such a bottom-feeder.
You working tonight?
No.
You wanna meet me at the diner?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Cool. See you there.
So, what did he want?
He asked me out.
- And what´d you say?
- l said, ""Okay. lt´s your funeral.""
Well, okay, pardon me.
But is hanging out with jock-boy
such a hot idea?
l just heard that
he´s dating Tracy Campbell, you know.
And she--
Right now she´s giving you the look
of a thousand deaths.
She´s beautiful.
Yeah, duh!
Coach says l´m starting this week.
What happened in there?
Kelton, with the frickin´ sheriff´s
badge he pulled out of a cereal box.
Somebody told him l did Lisa, and
l´m suspended. My dad´s gonna kill me.
- What about the game?
- Who cares?
Kelton nailed me with a picture of Lisa
and l, started talking statutory rape.
Now l face the D.A. on Thursday.
Relax. lt´s bullshit, all right?
Your dad´s gonna kick your ass, but he´s
a lawyer, and he´ll kill that shit dead.
l´ll miss the game of the year.
Football scouts are gonna be there...
and l´m gonna be sitting on the bench
with my thumb up my ass.
And that bitch Rachel.
You know she´ll be talking all kinds
of shit to anyone who wants to listen.
The best defense is a good offence.
- What´s that supposed to mean?
- Get in. We´re gonna do damage control.
Get it together. He´s just a guy.
You are gonna be late.
Boyd?
Emilyn?
Forget your keys?
Let´s take the front.
Stop it! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Rachel.
- Hello.
- What´s your favorite scary movie?
Rachel?
What?
Are you naked?
Who is this?
Or are you wearing
a little red towel?
lt´s playtime.
Who the fuck is this?
Why don´t l come in and show you,
you fuckin´ dyke?
What do you want?
Who is this?
Don´t you recognize the voice?
Who does it sound like?
l´m calling the police.
Come on out here, Rachel.
You bitch!
- What are you doing?
- Fuck her over like she´s fuckin´ me.
No way.
What the fuck are you doin´?
l have an emergency.
l´m at 3366 Broad Street.
- lt´s the parents!
- Let´s go. Let´s get out of here.
Yeah, l´m still here.
- lf she touches you one more time--
- You never liked her.
Everything´s okay now.
What´s this?
Really.
Thanks.
Look at the window.
What the hell happened here?
How should l know?
Ah, Jesus!
Don´t go tellin´ no stories
about my boy Eric.
Why do the innocent always get hit
in a drive-by?
What happened to you last night?
l waited up for you.
- Why don´t you tell me what happened?
- What are you talking about?
l waited in the cafe for over an hour.
l´ll tell you what happened.
Okay, what is wrong with this picture?
What does he see in her?
Come on, Trace.
You´re caviar, she´s Cheez Whiz.
He´ll come around. He´s letting little
Jesse do the thinking for big Jesse.
l just don´t want
any part of this, okay?
Look, let me talk to Mark.
l´ll work this out.
They were probably drunk
and just being stupid.
No, don´t.
You know what? Maybe all of this
isn´t such a good idea.
All of what?
Guys like you are supposed to date
girls like Tracy, okay?
That´s what this is about?
No. Hold on.
Her? Let me take you out
for a date.
A nice mellow one.
Tonight.
l´m not going anywhere
until you say yes. Go ahead, try me.
See?
l mean it.
l´m telling you.
Just say yes.
What was that?
All right.
Yes.
Rachel, l need to talk to you.
We need to talk.
- What´s the matter?
- Did you go by Rachel´s?
Yeah. We were just sending her
a little message.
Give it to me next time.
l´ll make sure she gets it.
What are you gettin´ all bent for?
This girl´s just a skank.
- You don´t even know her.
- You do? What do you know about her?
She´s a nice girl. She doesn´t deserve
to be treated like that.
- Who are you to send her a message?
- Who am l?
l´m a friend who gives a shit that my
boy´s goin´ down for rape. That´s who.
l´m gonna do anything l gotta do
to keep her from fuckin´ talkin´.
Eric´s a big boy. He made his own
decisions. Let him live with them.
You got say anything else to say to her,
deal with me.
- Deal with you?
- Deal with me.
No. You´re gonna have to deal with me.
What is wrong with you, Jesse?
This is us, man!
We´re all friends here.
No, we just grew up together.
This is just a test that will
let me know how to help you better.
You´re wasting your time.
Just answer the statements
true or false, okay?
""There´s a man inside the television
who tells me what to do.""
False?
l don´t see the point.
""Sometimes my thoughts assume the form
of a giant insect.""
- This doesn´t make any sense.
- Answer true or false.
Again. ""Sometimes my thoughts assume
the form of a giant insect.""
False.
""lf you want to play the piano well,
you have to practice.""
True.
""Large furry animals crawl on my face
every night while l sleep.""
True.
l have a dog.
""Sometimes l can move things
with my mind.""
- You can´t make me do this.
- Honey, sit down.
l´m trying to help.
- You´re not my mother, you know.
- l´m trying to be your friend.
Let go of me!
They´re all gonna laugh at you!
Selling used cars is not what l want.
Unless l nail that football scholarship,
that´s what l get.
l can´t believe l´m telling you this.
l never told anybody this before
in my life.
lt must be nice not having to be
like everybody else.
lt´s not so great.
l mean...
sometimes l wish l could just be
one of the shiny, happy people.
Does that surprise you?
Yeah.
Everything about you surprises me.
l knew this guy once.
He did this thing.
He could suck a strand of spaghetti...
up his mouth
and right out of his nose.
Brain flossing?
He called it a talent.
l bet you´re wondering
where l´m going with this, right?
Well--
You really have a talent.
You´ve got football.
lt´ll get you out of this place.
After that, you can do what you want.
Make your own path.
Write your own book.
- Think so?
- Word.
Word?
Word.
You wanna come with me?
What?
Your brake.
lt´s poking me right in the back.
You wanna--
l really don´t know how to say this.
What?
l´ve never--
Yeah.
- And l want it to be special.
- Yeah.
Like, you come to my door
with flowers in your hand.
Oh, well, okay.
What kind of flowers
do you like?
Daisies.
Okay. l´ll have to remember that.
l don´t know! l don´t know!
Mrs. Lang, l need to ask you
a few questions about Rachel.
Who is--
Who is her father?
lt isn´t important.
- l knew you´d come back.
- l´m afraid we don´t know each other.
We can still get married.
l´ll marry you.
- l need to know who he is.
- l´m sorry, that´s private.
The hell with them!
What do they know?
Cut it out! She´s not Terry.
Kindly go away.
Poor thing. He´s never had a visitor.
Wants to share everybody else´s.
Mrs. Lang, it´s very important...
that you tell me
who Rachel´s father is.
l don´t see how that´s
any of your business.
l´m trying to help Rachel.
She seems troubled,
and l´m very worried about her.
You´re worried?
Are you very worried?
l am, yes.
You don´t have any children,
do you, miss?
No, l don´t.
Then you don´t know. You will never know
how terrifying children can be.
Mrs. Lang, l know this is
a really strange question...
but when Rachel was growing up...
did you ever see objects move
by themselves?
And did the doctors convince you
it was all your imagination?
The Lord is with thee.
No. l was crazy then.
l thought she was possessed.
l thought the devil was inside her.
Mrs. Lang, Rachel needs help.
She may have a disease,
a genetic disorder.
l believe her father
may have passed it on to her.
Disease? Could l have it?
Did l give it to her?
- No.
- How do you know?
Because the male is the carrier.
Mrs. Lang, you must tell me his name.
Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners...
now and at the hour of our death, amen.
l did tell Rachel once
how we met.
He said it was love at first sight.
l´ll tell you, but don´t you dare
hurt my daughter.
l never told her ´cause
people around here...
aren´t so fond of Carrie White
´cause of what she did.
See, he was her daddy, too.
His name was Ralph.
Ralph White.
Rachel?
l need you to come with me.
The night of the prom...
73 people died.
A few of us survived...
but we´ve never talked about that night.
That´s why l ended up at Arkham,
if you wondered.
l witnessed something
l can´t even begin to tell you about.
But look around.
See for yourself.
This was the original high school.
l wish they´d tear this place down.
lt´s like some twisted memorial
to that night.
l haven´t been here in over 20 years.
Happy homecoming.
You´ve heard of Carrie White,
haven´t you?
Supposedly she set the fire...
as some type of revenge-suicide thing.
Elvis was her date,
and they escaped in a UFO.
l know what happened
to that snow dome on my desk.
lt fell.
We both know.
Rachel, is Jesse Ryan pressuring you--
Excuse me.
That´s none of your business.
l know everything there is to know
about Carrie White.
She did this.
lt began with something like you did
with the snow dome...
and then it got out of control.
- l´m leaving.
- Rachel.
- lt´s a genetic recessive trait.
- What are you saying l have?
l´m saying you´re not crazy,
and it´s not the devil.
lt´s a trait you´ve inherited.
Telekinesis: the ability
to move objects with your mind.
For years, l didn´t believe it existed.
But there are places that study it.
There´s a lab at Princeton.
l can take you there.
With all respect, lady...
you are seriously bat shit.
l´m walking back to the real world now.
You mother told me your father
is Carrie´s father.
No, my father´s name was Bill Kirk.
- He left when l was three months old.
- lt´s a lie.
My mother wouldn´t lie to me.
Believe me, you need help.
Like what?
Like they helped you?
l can help you to get it under control.
l don´t want or need your help.
You´re not really thinking
of pressing charges against my son?
Oh, we´re doing more than thinking.
Look, Eric´s a good kid.
He may be guilty
of some youthful transgressions--
Youthful transgressions?
A girl killed herself, Lou.
Hello, Jay.
Sit. Everybody sit.
l´m just listening in.
Okay, then.
Cards on the table.
My boy isn´t going down alone.
Go on.
Mark Bing, Jesse Ryan,
Brad Winters and Chuck Potter.
We´re talking about the most prominent
families in this town.
Maybe they´ve all slept
with underage girls. Who can tell?
And, yes, maybe they made
a game of it.
And perhaps Eric
can even get proof of that.
l agree it would be awful,
but l don´t think it´s criminal.
Now, there will be scouts
at the game on Friday.
Eric takes a fall,
maybe they all will.
You wanna be responsible
for ruining these boys´ lives?
That sums it up.
Karen, what we have here
is an issue with intent.
- Blue-sheet it.
- Oh, but Jay--
What you don´t have is evidence enough
to tarnish this boy´s reputation.
lt´s not about evidence, is it?
lt´s about elections, right?
That is it, Robbie.
That is all.
Lou, thanks for coming by.
l´ll walk you out.
- Appreciate it.
- l know what you´re going through.
- l hope we see you at the game.
- l´ll be there.
- Hey, is this seat taken?
- No.
- What´s goin´ on?
- Just studying.
You gonna come
to the game Friday?
l don´t really do football.
lt´s the season opener.
There´s gonna be some scouts there.
l need you, for luck.
lf he´s gonna do it, you know, be seen
talking in public with someone...
he should show some respect.
l mean, he should show me the respect
at least to be seen with someone pretty.
Someone cool,
someone who counts.
You know, someone.
But instead, it´s her.
l just feel totally--
Disrespected.
Yeah.
Honey, you´re being
seriously dissed.
Man, l just wish there was something l
could do to make him come to his senses.
Mark´s got his wheels turning.
What?
Come on. Good lift.
One more. Push it out, man.
Come on, push it.
Nice.
Look, man, l´m sorry.
l guess l overreacted.
- Don´t fuck with me.
- l´m not, man.
You know, we´ve been friends since
we were both dumpin´ our drawers, dude.
l thought we´d be
best friends forever.
Never figured some girl
would come in the way of that.
Look, l know l´m scum.
l´m prepared to admit that.
l´m lower than scum.
l´m smegma. l´m butt lint.
- Keep going.
- l´m a prick. l´m an asshole.
- Asshole, yeah.
- lt´s that good.
l´m sorry, man.
l´m not the one
you should be apologizing to.
l know.
Karen, watch my counter, please.
Can l help you?
Just-- Just looking. Thanks.
Mrs. Porter, this is
a friend of mine from school.
l thought she was gonna frisk me.
She does step class with my mom.
So, what are you shopping for?
Oh, nothing. Just looking.
ls it perhaps something
to wear on a date?
Perhaps with a certain
jock hunk we all know?
You know,
Tracy isn´t universally loved.
There´s a shocker.
Exhibit A:
She tried to steal Brad from me.
She´s a ""Melrose Place"" superbitch.
You have got great lips.
Really. Look. This shade
will look very kissable and soft.
Come here.
Trust me, okay?
Hold still.
So, are you going to the game?
Just blink once for yes.
Great, ´cause there´s this big party
afterwards, and l hope you can go.
l don´t think so.
Oh, come on. You really should.
l mean, for Jesse.
l know it´d mean a lot to him
if we all got along.
Yeah. So you´ll go?
Great! See?
Can l ring that up for you?
Sure. How much is it?
Oh, um, maybe next time.
Thanks, Mrs. Porter.
l kleptoed it for you.
Hey, over here!
Figured out how to make it up
to you and Rachel.
The summerhouse, bro.
My parents aren´t gonna be there.
l figured you wanted to get away
from us idiots for a little while.
Have a nice, romantic time.
All right?
But you´re gonna
bring her by my party.
So l can apologize to her,
all right?
Then we can all be
one big, happy family again.
All right?
Have a good time, man.
- You look great.
- Thanks.
l really like your hair.
Oh, you can just, you know,
throw those in the back or something.
l know Mark can be a jerk sometimes,
but, you know, he´s trying.
He´s got a party Friday,
and he invited us.
- We won´t go if you don´t want to.
- No, let´s go.
Really?
What´s wrong?
l´m just a little scared.
Don´t be scared.
l know. l just feel
kind of strange.
Look, we don´t
have to do this tonight.
Whenever you´re ready.
God, l must be crazy.
Actually, you´re
about the sanest person l know.
You´re sane.
l love you.
You´re grounded, for a week!
- But l´ve gotta go to the game--
- You wanna make it two?
You stay in this room.
Am l clear?
Yes, sir.
Come on! Shave it off!
Hey, you´re next.
Get in the chair.
- Come on!
- Come on, bro!
- Come on, man!
Oh, you´re gonna ruin
the whole effect, bro!
Oh, Jess, where´s your sac?
Come on!
You have to tell her
who her father is.
- Why?
- Because she´ll believe it from you.
Rachel needs to seek treatment
before it´s too late.
Too late for what?
Rachel´s best friend
committed suicide...
and l´m afraid Rachel may...
harm herself or others.
And you want to take me
out there?
Yes.
He saw me!
Go get ´em, baby!
Good afternoon, and welcome
to today´s matchup...
between your Bates Bulldogs
and the Carlin Devils.
This is the first game
for both teams...
as the Bulldogs seek
their seventh consecutive championship.
However, there is a history
of bad blood between these two teams...
as the Devils have consistently
been a thorn in the Bulldogs´ side.
Well, let´s hope the Dawgs can
pull that thorn out once and for all...
as the special teams get set
for the opening kickoff.
Number 42 of the Bulldogs,
Chuck Potter, receiving the kick.
Oh, my! He´s popped.
Could l have my purse, please?
Just about five minutes to go now
in the second quarter.
Go, Jesse!
A vicious hit by Stark.
Johnson, number 45, isn´t getting up.
- What the hell kind of call was that?
- And it looks like number 33, Stark...
is being ejected
for a flagrant personal foul.
What the hell is he fuckin´ doing?
- That was not a flagrant foul!
- Thirty-three has been disqualified.
Oh, why don´t l just take
every starter out for you, all right?
Touchdown, Devils!
The Bulldogs are trailing in the second
half as they receive the Devils´ punt.
Number 42, Chuck Potter,
takes the kick again for the Dawgs.
And there he goes...
cutting across the field,
racing down the sideline!
Fourth quarter action.
Here´s the snap.
A quick pass to Jesse Ryan,
and, oooh, he was hit hard.
What a pop.
He is down.
He is not getting up
right away.
Wait a minute. l see--
l see movement.
Yes, he´s finally moving now.
He´s up.
Shaking it off.
And there he goes.
Everything´s so different,
so very different.
Things change.
There´s Mr. Bellows.
Hello, George!
He always had an eye for me,
that one.
- Where?
- Right there.
Hello, George.
Devils suck!
Well, it´s pretty much
do or die time now, folks.
The Dawgs down by four
with only 12 seconds left on the clock.
Boy, it´s been a struggle all day
for these Dawgs...
trying to move the ball
against the very stingy Devils defense.
l think it´s safe to say this is not how
the Dawgs wanted it to come out today.
They´ve had a very tough time
on defense.
- They´re not moving the ball as usual.
- Ryan, get up here. Come on.
All right, son, trips right,
crazy eight. Let´s go.
They´re really taking their time here.
Probably their last play of the game.
Trips right, crazy eight.
Go, Bulldogs!
Hey, come back here!
Last chance. We´ll look for a Hail Mary.
We´ve got Jesse Ryan set wide.
Bulldogs set.
There´s the snap.
Miller drops back.
A long bomb down towards the corner.
Ryan is there. He´s under it.
He jumps. He´s got it!
Complete!
Touchdown, Bulldogs!
Touchdown!
The Bulldogs win it!
College scout´s here.
He wants to talk to you.
Could you tell Rachel to wait for me?
l´m gonna be a few minutes.
No problem.
And, hey, good luck.
Thanks.
Jesse´s gonna be a while.
He´s talking with a scout.
- He said to go ahead to the party.
- You hear that, Rachel?
Jesse´s talking to a scout.
lsn´t that great?
- Yeah, that´s great.
- All right.
l´m goin´ with the guys.
See you there.
Come on.
l´ll give you a ride to Mike´s.
- Thanks.
- Deborah!
Dress. Dress time.
- Try this.
- Thanks.
Mascara. Mascara!
Sorry.
Done. How do l look?
- You look beautiful.
- Thank you.
- You look good, Monica.
- Thank you. You look pretty, too.
- You look really pretty.
- You need lipstick.
Yo, check it out.
Goddamn it!
Whoa, that sucks.
They even slashed my tires.
lt´s further proof the Devils
are just a bunch of pigs, huh?
- Are you looking for Rachel?
- Yeah.
Well, she´s at Mark´s.
You want a ride over there?
l just have to stop
by my place real quick.
- Tommy, have you seen Rachel Lang?
- Who?
- Rachel Lang. Was she at the game?
- Oh, yeah. With the tattoo.
l saw her leave with Monica Jones.
l guess they went to Mark Bing´s party.
Rachel with Monica?
Just go away!
Todd, get off my butt!
Stop.
Whoa, bro, what are you doing?
You bust something in this house,
heads are seriously gonna roll.
Yes!
Rachel, yo.
You could get me
into this party, right?
Hey, Arnie, wait right here.
We´ll come back for you.
- See, l told you.
- ln a couple of years.
How come she gets to go in, then?
- She´s one of us.
- l´ll try and get you in, Arnie.
Fuck that. Come on, guys,
let´s do some serious doughnuts now.
Come on. Hit it!
So, then the scout said,
and l quote...
""l love your aggressive play.
You have that killer instinct.""
That´s great, buddy.
For you, that is great.
- There she is. You better disappear.
- No problem.
Swank.
Relax. They just need to get to know you
for who you really are.
- How about a drink?
- Right on.
What can l get you beautiful ladies
to drink?
Some margaritas would be nice.
- B-Rad.
- Yo!
- Margaritas.
- Comin´!
- Thanks.
- l´m glad you could make it.
Look, l´m sorry about
the other night at your house.
lt was just a bunch of guys
being guys. l´m sorry.
Jesse told us to cool it
and explain everything.
So, no hard feelings? Peace?
Well, as long as you
pour me a drink, all right.
Sho´.
- Thanks.
- To new friends, then?
- Drink to that.
- Okay.
Tracy, l appreciate the ride,
but, uh, let´s go.
Just a minute.
l´m trying to figure out what to wear.
Of course.
Hey, what do you think of this?
- Looks good.
- Really?
Well, l don´t know.
l think it might be a bit much.
Don´t you?
We´re gonna be late.
Pretty soon she won´t care
if you´re late.
What´s that?
Well, if she cares about you,
she won´t mind if you´re late.
- Come on, wench, let´s dance.
- Don´t you ""wench"" me.
Come on, Rachel, let´s dance.
l think l´d rather wait for Jesse.
- He´d want you to have fun.
- Come on, have some fun.
Yeah, come on, Rach.
l got you, babe. Come on.
Go, Rachel!
Hey, Mark, l got a little present
for you, right here.
Hey, Mark, you like
the game footage, huh?
l love the footage.
Yes, l do.
Are you talking about today´s game?
No, l´m talking
about the other game.
What other game?
- The game that you´re in. My turn.
- Yeah?
- The game that you played, Rachel.
- That´s right. What was the score?
Chuckie, grab that score book.
l wanna see it.
- Want to see it now? All right.
- Come here, baby.
l wanna show you how you helped
Jesse win the game.
Two-twenty-four!
Hut, hut, hut, hut!
Rachel, catch!
Yeah, baby! Yeah!
Hold it!
l gotta get my camera for this.
- Read off the scores.
- Whoa. Hold on.
Come on, Rachel. Give it to us.
Read the scores!
Come on. Please.
Let´s start with Eric´s scores...
´cause it´s gonna be so sad.
Start with poor Eric.
What´s the matter, Rach? ls there
someone there that you recognize?
Someone you know? Huh?
Lisa. Forgot about Lisa.
Come on down!
That´s our brother!
The D.A. kissed his butt!
- We were just talking about Lisa.
- Oh, Lisa.
How was she?
Well, to be honest,
l just about split her in two.
- How many points was she?
- She was worth four points.
But l think we should deduct those
since she offed herself.
Wait. Think of how many points he´d have
got if he´d done her after she was dead.
- A bit cold, huh?
- Chuck, come on!
Rach, baby, read that.
Open it up to Jesse´s page.
l want you to see
how many points...
Jesse got for you.
Oh, well, l think that´ll be
about a two-four-six-eight!
Who do we appreciate?
More than that, ´cause remember,
Rach, you said you were a dyke...
so he got extra points
for the conversion.
Oh, the conversion!
Two points!
Not two. Thirty!
Thirty!
You gave her thirty?
She should get extra points,
being that she´s so skanky.
Look at that.
Look at it.
See, we didn´t think
Jesse could do it.
- So he offered to get us proof.
- How do you like Jesse´s big play?
Lookie, lookie here, Rachel.
- They´re all gonna laugh at you!
- Was it good for you?
ls that you?
They´re all gonna laugh at you!
Oh, come on, Rachel!
Was it good, Rachel?
Sucker!
Hey, is that a zit on your ass?
lt is! lt is a zit on her ass!
No, that´s a mole.
Holy shit.
What?
- Mark, what´s going on?
- l have no idea.
Out of my way!
Brad, you bastard!
- Get out of the way! Move it!
- Shit! lt won´t open!
Holy shit, dude!
lt´s her doing it!
Go!
Somebody put me out! Help!
Oh, God, help me!
Oh, my God!
Let me out!
Man, we´re missing
one killer party.
- Where are the fuckin´ keys?
- Hurry!
My stupid dad.
He´s always hiding these friggin´ keys!
Hurry up! Come on!
Tyler! Tyler, get up!
- What the hell´s this?
- lt´s a spear gun, idiot.
- Give me that shit.
- Hey, man, forget the flare gun.
What are you gonna do
with a flare gun?
lt´s all my fault.
Let´s go! Get outta here!
Oh, shit!
Go on! Through the glass!
Come on!
Get up!
- Pull the cord!
- Where´s the fucking cord?
Oh, shit.
Momma?
What´s wrong?
What are you?
You´re not my little girl.
The devil´s in you!
Momma, please!
Momma, don´t leave me!
Don´t leave me!
l don´t have anyone.
Please.
Please, God...
let me die.
Please?
Come on. She´s dead.
They´re all dead.
We have to get out of here.
Let´s go.
Oh, my God.
Forget about that!
Let´s go!
- You used me.
- l had no idea they were taping us!
Liar!
ls that all l was to you?
Thirty points?
l would never do that to you.
You have to trust me.
- l would never hurt you.
- Stop lying!
l believed you.
You know that?
God, l believed you.
Listen to me.
l love you. l do.
- You´re a liar!
- No, l love you.
l love you.
Get out. Stay away from me.
Please go.
- l love you.
- What?
l love you.
Hey, Walt.
You´re gonna get us kicked out of here.