Burden!
Hey, Jack Burden!
The boss wants to see you.
Jack, ever heard of a fellow
called Willie Stark?
No, who'd he shoot?
It'll be the other way around
if he keeps it up.
He's got the boys in the
Kanoma County courthouse worried.
Politician?
What's he running for?
County treasurer
or something like that.
What's so special about him?
They say he's an honest man.
-I want you to hop into your car.
-You promised me a vacation.
That can wait.
But there's a girl I know.
She can wait too.
The question is, can l?
And the answer is, get up there.
Right.
What did you say his name was?
The fellow's name.
Stark. Willie Stark.
I found him in Kanoma City.
A typical, hot, dusty,
backwoods county seat.
--lie in order to line their own
dirty pockets with taxpayers' money.
When have Kanoma citizens ever
witnessed a campaign like this?
Why is the opposition
so anxious to defeat me?
Why have they used every dirty method
to make sure I'm not elected treasurer?
I'll tell you why.
They're afraid of the truth.
And the truth is this:
They're trying to steal your money.
Yeah, I said ''steal.''
The commissioners rejected
the low bid on the schoolhouse.
Why?
They'll say that
the job will be done better.
They would have you believe
they're interested in public welfare.
They're interested in welfare, sure.
But it's their own.
Let's look at their reason
in the light of the facts.
That factory's owned by
a brother-in-law of a commissioner.
That same brick factory
uses convict labor.
Sorry, Willie,
you'll have to move on.
Why?
City Ordinance Number 1 05.
More than five people congregating
is disturbing the peace.
If you folks will read
these handbills...
...my boy will pass them out among you.
There's an ordinance
against that too.
Pass them out, Tom.
-Let him alone.
-Get that camera!
Willie, you're under arrest.
Where can I find Tiny Duffy?
Right over there, mister.
They told me I could get
my camera back here.
Who told you that?
People. Can l?
You the reporter that's been
snooping around town?
Are you Tiny Duffy?
What paper?
Chronicle.
You come a long way to stick your nose
into other people's business.
True, only my boss
on the paper can't see that.
It ain't any of his business either.
-Whose business is it?
-Them as that's tending to it.
County commissioners
the voters of Kanoma elected...
...to tend their business
and not take no butting in.
You a commissioner?
Name's Pillsbury.
Dolph Pillsbury.
Me too.
I'm a commissioner too.
Who isn't a commissioner?
He's the head man.
You're in a position to know--
ln a position to know nothing
and to say nothing.
I thought you said he was head man?
He uses my head.
Tiny, you're a card!
Ain't he a card?
He's a card.
Who thought up ordinances about
arresting someone for making a speech?
Who's arrested?
Ain't nobody arrested.
Hi, Willie.
Did you apologize to Willie?
I apologized to Willie.
-Did you give him his handbills?
-I gave them back.
And give him back
his flag and his bag.
And give this man his camera.
I'll be on that street
tomorrow, Mr. Duffy.
You go right ahead.
We all believe in free speech.
We got to.
It's in the Constitution.
My boy is distributing
those handbills now.
It's a free country, Willie.
If you can convince people
to vote for you...
...you go right ahead.
What did you want to see me about?
I wanted you to meet a fella...
...that came all the way up
from the state capital to meet you.
A reporter.
Wants to write you up.
Maybe put your picture in the paper.
I'm happy to know you.
Burden's my name. Jack Burden.
Can we go somewhere and talk?
That ain't polite.
Don't you want to hear
both sides of the story?
I know your side.
Where's the slate
your men took from my camera?
Must have dropped out.
Come on, fellas, let's relax.
It's a hot day.
Hey, Sugar Boy!
Bring some cold beer for the boys.
None for me.
Thank you kindly.
You know Willie don't drink, Tiny.
His wife don't favor drinking.
And Willie's the teacher's pet,
ain't you?
I'll have orange pop,
if you don't mind.
Orange pop?
All right, Sugar Boy.
Bring him some orange pop.
The pop, sir, is sold out.
Did you hear that, boys?
''The p-p-pop is sold out.''
Now ain't he a card?
He stutters, Mr. Duffy.
But you don't say anything.
Let's go, mister.
This is my wife, Lucy, Mr. Burden.
-How do you do?
-That's my pa.
Now we'll talk.
You've been talking for a long time.
Willie's got a lot to say.
You sleepy, Pappy?
You want a nap?
I want to hear it.
I'm worried about Tom.
It's getting dark.
He should have been home.
He's a strong boy.
He can take care of himself.
-How old is the boy?
-Fifteen.
How long have you been married?
Nine years.
He was a neighbor's boy.
They were poor folks.
Both died.
I couldn't have any children so....
-He's a good boy.
-He's the best.
I couldn't love him more
if he was my own flesh and blood.
And now you, Mrs. Stark.
There isn't very much
to tell about me.
How did you meet?
I was teaching school.
One day, a pupil walked in.
It was Willie.
I couldn't have a man in class,
and Willie wanted to learn badly...
...so I married him.
ls that the only reason?
Except that I loved him.
Get the coffee, Lucy.
When did they fire you, Mrs. Stark?
A couple of weeks ago.
l've been teaching a long time.
Nobody ever said I wasn't all right.
But I don't care.
I won't teach in a schoolhouse built
so somebody can steal some money.
Willie doesn't want
to be treasurer either...
...if he has to associate
with those dishonest people.
I'm going to run.
They can't keep me from running.
If you want the truth,
you haven't much of a chance.
I'm going to run.
They won't kick me around.
I don't care if Willie loses...
...just so he gets the truth
to the people.
lsn't that true, Willie?
lsn't it?
Sure, that's right.
If you lose, you can study
your law books more.
Are you studying law too?
By myself, at night.
Willie's a smart boy.
If I find time,
I'll take a university course.
What happened, Tommy boy?
What's the matter?
-I gave out the handbills, Pa.
-Speak up! Speak up!
Let him tell it in his own way.
Go on, Tommy.
They were waiting for me.
They took them, threw them
in the dirt and beat me up.
I brought some of them back.
Good boy!
Have you eaten?
Let him wash up first.
Why don't you lie down, Pappy?
I'm going to run.
You're not going to stop me.
I'm going to run
even if I don't get a single vote.
Here you are.
The last of the Willie Stark articles.
Can I go?
Yes, you've earned your vacation.
You've been writing these
like you really mean them.
I do.
I hadn't been home in a long time.
Home was Burden's Landing.
Only 130 miles from Kanoma City.
It was separated from the mainland
by a body of water.
For the first time, I wondered
if it wasn't separated by more.
Hello, Mother.
Floyd, Jack's home.
He looks fine.
Doesn't he look fine?
How do I look, Jackie boy?
You look beautiful, Mother.
l've got so many things
planned for you.
Parties and--
It'll be like old times.
Let's have a drink.
Can't that wait till evening?
Floyd, my son's home.
How long are you staying?
Two or three weeks,
if that's all right.
-Your father--
-Stepfather.
Now, Jackie.
Here we are. Floyd.
Jackie.
Myself.
To the best time
we've ever had together.
Yes, Mother.
Excuse me, l--
Dr. Stanton, I presume.
ls my shingle showing?
-Good to see you, boy.
-Good to see you, Judge.
How've you been?
What've you been doing?
Just sitting here, waiting
for all of you to come home.
When a man starts to get old,
his eyes play funny tricks on him.
As I watched you in that boat...
...I saw a boy of 1 2
with a fishing rod.
And I was sure the first thing
he'd say would be--
Mind if I kiss your niece?
To all the good times
we've had at Burden's Landing.
And especially this one,
because my son's home.
Thank you, Mother.
Thank you very much.
Monty, we've been discussing
Jack's career.
What do you think he should be?
A lawyer?
Doctor?
-We were discussing whether--
-I like what I do.
You do very well at it.
I read your articles
about Willie Stark.
Very convincing.
Too convincing for my tastes.
People like them.
People are fools.
Articles like that
shouldn't be permitted.
They incite people.
Why are you afraid?
I thought they were very good.
I was proud of you.
I was interested in Stark's ideas
on health and medicine.
You know hospital conditions.
They're intolerable.
l'd like to meet him.
He sounds like an honest man.
Honest man?
This state is full of log-cabin
Abe Lincolns with price tags on them.
The louder he yells,
the higher his price.
You think you can buy anything.
Yes, don't you?
What do you think, Judge?
-This state could stand a few changes.
-I'll tell you what I think.
Please.
Let's not talk politics.
Anne is right.
I absolutely forbid any more of it.
I know what we need.
We need another toast.
You propose it, Monty.
You're so good at it.
To the young people.
To Anne, to Jack, to Adam.
To what lies before them.
To the world they'll make,
in spite of the mistakes we've made.
The mistakes you've made, not me.
You're all still pretty
high and mighty, aren't you?
You think this state needs a change.
You don't like how it's run.
Who's going to run it?
Willie Stark, the Judge, you?
You can be bought too.
ln fact, you have been.
And with my money.
That's a waste of good liquor, boy.
Your mother wouldn't approve.
-You go back and apologize.
-I'd rather die.
-I've got to live with him.
-You don't love him.
Don't spoil anything.
He can help.
You need this house
and the parties...
...the cars, the clothes, the lies.
I don't.
It's the truth, face it.
For once in your life, face it.
Anne, please.
Make him understand.
Burden's Landing is
a place on the moon.
It isn't real.
It doesn't exist.
It's me, pretending
I live on what I earn.
It's my mother,
trying to keep herself young...
...and drinking herself old doing it.
It's you and Adam living here
as if your father were still alive.
It's an old man like the Judge,
dreaming of the past.
Anne, come away with me.
And do what?
Live in a shack and eat red beans.
What do you want me to do?
You haven't been sure. You've gone
from one thing to the other.
A year at law school,
this job as a reporter.
-Are you afraid I can't make a living?
-No, it isn't that.
I don't care about the money.
It's just that
I want you to be something.
-What is it you want me to be?
-I don't know.
I want you to be,
to do something important.
Like your father?
All right, I'll run for governor.
Anne, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I said that.
All right, Jack.
I'll go away with you.
I'll do anything you want me to.
l've wanted you to say that
more than anything in the world.
And now that you have said it--
I guess you were right.
I'm not sure of anything,
including myself.
I'm not sure I could live up to the--
Wait for me.
Please wait for me.
I'll wait for you.
Hello, Jack.
Cut your vacation short, didn't you?
By the way, Jack...
...the fellow you wrote
the articles about, Stark.
He lost.
I guess that's the end
of Willie Stark.
The measure of the damages
is caused by--
A breach.
-A breach.
-Of an agreement.
-To sell personal property.
-To sell....
-Two years of this!
-Go on, Willie.
''Willie Stark.
Bachelor of Law.''
If you'll let me take your case...
...I'll wait for my fee
just as long as you want me to.
They won't kick me around.
If you lose, you can study
your law books more.
I'll be on that street tomorrow!
By all means.
Free speech, free country.
That factory's owned by
a brother-in-law of a commissioner.
The commissioners rejected
the low bid on the schoolhouse.
All right, children,
this is a fire drill.
Remember now, walk.
Quietly.
''Verily I say unto you...
...except ye turn
and become as little children...
...ye shall in no wise
enter the kingdom of heaven.''
Let us pray.
''The grace of our Lord, Jesus Christ
and the love of God...
...and the Holy Spirit
be with us all evermore.''
Amen.
Lord, I'm punished for voting
against an honest man.
God bless you.
-If we'd only listened.
-We'll never forget.
You were right.
-Let me shake your hand.
-We should have listened.
You were right all the time.
''Voice in the wilderness.
A man named Willie Stark.''
How about that, Lucy?
That's me.
Get up there fast.
Willie's hotter than a firecracker.
And stay with him.
Before this Kanoma City business,
we had this whole area tied up.
Now we're losing the hick vote.
Let's find a way to split that vote.
All I know is, the way it is now,
it looks like I'm not going to win.
I know a way. Find a dummy.
Find a dummy.
That's what we got.
A guy from the sticks,
strong enough to grab votes...
...and dumb enough
not to ask questions.
If you want to listen to a boy
from the sticks...
...I know just the guy.
So it's no more politics?
l've worked too hard
in my time to get there.
I'll just go on practicing law
and making more money.
l'd like to ask...
...why all the speeches you're making
around the countryside?
I wonder who that is.
I brought some people up
from the capital just to meet you.
Folks, I want you
to meet Willie Stark...
...the next governor of our state.
Bear patiently with me
for a few minutes.
l'd like to tell you
what this state needs.
It needs a balanced tax program.
l'd like to give you the facts
and the figures.
How did it sound?
Fine, fine.
I forgot to send a telegram to Lucy.
Conductor!
l'd like to add something
about last year's taxes.
I wouldn't add a thing.
Just give them the facts.
-And the figures.
-Great speech!
What this state needs is
a balanced tax program.
Last year...
...the state claimed
to have spent on roads....
We know figures don't lie,
and facts are easy to understand.
-Do you mind if I sit with you?
-Stand, sit, whatever.
Thanks.
What are you
on this merry-go-round for?
I take notes.
-For whom?
-For those ''whom'' pay me.
-Which is?
-People.
Smart people?
Anybody that pays me is smart.
You don't have to be smart
to frame Willie Stark.
No, you don't.
lsn't it a frame?
Why don't you give me a cigarette?
To split the vote,
so Harrison can win.
If you know, why you ask?
I just want to make sure.
Why don't you tell the boys
to save their money?
Willie couldn't steal a vote...
...from Abe Lincoln in
the cradle of the Confederacy.
I wish the poor had enough sense
to have somebody give him...
...a greasing for the beating
he's going to get.
All he gets out of it is the ride.
Those speeches.
Ain't they awful?
Ain't they just plain awful?
Question to you:
If somebody told him
he was a sucker...
...you think he'd quit?
I don't know, Sadie.
I really don't know.
-Did it sound all right?
-Fine.
Now if you'll bear with me
for a few minutes...
...I'll give you the figures.
What we need is
a balanced tax program.
I need sleep!
-Shut up.
-Shut up yourself!
Try it on your feet.
My feet are killing me.
Let me stay here.
Look, you tell them too much.
Tell them you'll soak the fat boys,
and forget the tax stuff.
That's what I say.
But it's the way you say it.
Make them cry or laugh.
Make them mad. Stir them up
and they'll come back for more.
But for heaven's sakes,
don't try to improve their minds.
A man don't have to be governor.
What?
-They haven't counted the votes yet.
-I'll lose, I know that.
Don't try and fool me.
I won't lie to you.
I wanted it.
I wanted it so badly,
I stayed up nights thinking about it.
A man wants something so badly,
he gets mixed up.
It's something inside of you.
l'd have made a good governor.
Better than those others.
-Come in.
-A great governor.
Give me a drink.
Build them highways....
Help yourself.
-I'd build them schools.
-What's up?
Nothing, except he says
he's not going to be governor.
So you told him?
I don't tell anyone anything.
I just listen.
Who told you?
Told me what?
That you won't be governor.
Jack, told me what?
That you've been framed,
you poor sap.
-Framed?
-And how!
Oh, you decoy.
You woodenhead decoy.
And you let them.
You know what you are?
You're the goat.
The sacrificial goat.
You are a sap because you let them.
-That's enough!
-Enough?
He didn't even get
anything out of it.
They'd have paid you
to take a rap like that.
But they didn't have
to pay a sap like you.
You were full of yourself.
All you wanted was to stand up
on your hind legs and make a speech.
''My friends....
My friends, this state needs
a good five-cent cigar.
What this state needs is a--''
-Is it true?
-He wants to know if it's true.
ls it true?
That's what they tell me.
Here.
-You're not used to it.
-He's not used to a lot of things.
Why don't you lay off him?
Are you? Are you?
Things seem to have quieted down.
Yep, I quieted him down.
How was he? Noisy?
He reared some.
He's been telling me
the things he'll do.
He's going to do big things.
He's going to be president.
He's going to kill people
with his bare hands.
I quieted him down.
Hey, who's Lucy?
His wife.
He talks like she's his mammy.
She'll blow his nose for him.
I'll take him from here.
They're waiting at the barbecue.
Give me a receipt for the body.
I'll be on my way.
Come on, wake up.
Where is he?
There he is.
ls he drunk?
Never touches the stuff.
Lucy doesn't favor drinking.
How'd you get him here?
He was out stiff.
Hair of the dog that bit him.
He must have swallowed the dog.
Ladies and gentlemen.
It gives me pleasure to introduce
that true man of the people...
...the next governor of the state...
...Willie Stark.
My friends....
My friends, I have a speech here.
It's a speech...
...about what this state needs.
There's no need in my telling you
what this state needs.
You are the state
and you know what you need.
You over there.
Look at your pants.
Have they got holes in the knees?
Listen to your stomach.
Did you ever hear
it rumble for hunger?
And you.
Do your crops ever rot...
...because the road was too bad
to get to market?
And you.
What about your kids?
Are they ignorant as dirt, like you,
because there's no school?
I'm not going to read you any speech.
But I will tell you a story.
It's a funny story.
-What's he up to?
-Shut up.
Get ready to bust your sides laughing
because it's funny.
It's about a hick.
A hick like you, if you please.
He grew up on the dirt roads
in the gully washes of a farm.
He knew how to get up before dawn,
get feed, slop and milk...
...then walk six miles to a one-room,
slab-sided schoolhouse.
This hick knew
what it was to be a hick.
He figured that to get anything done,
he had to do it himself.
So he sat up nights and studied.
He studied law because he thought
he could change things...
...for himself
and for folks like him.
I'm not going to lie to you.
He didn't start off
thinking about the hicks...
...and the things he'd do for them.
He started off thinking
of number one.
But something came to him on the way.
He could do nothing for himself
without the help of the people.
It came with the force
of God's lightning...
...when the school building collapsed
because of politics' rotten brick.
It killed and mangled a dozen kids.
But you know that story.
The people were his friends
because he fought it.
The politicians in the city knew that.
So they rode up to his house...
...and said they wanted him
to run for governor.
He's wonderful!
And he swallowed it.
He thought in all humility how
he'd like to try and change things.
He was a country boy who thought
even a poor man can be governor...
...if his fellow citizens find
he's got the stuff for the job.
Those fellows in the striped pants
saw that hick and took him in.
-What are you doing?
-There's your Judas lscariot!
Lickspittle, nose-wiper!
Play! Play!
-Play anything!
-Harrison's dummy!
-Look at him!
-That's a lie!
Go get him, boys!
Now shut up!
Shut up, all of you.
Listen to me.
They fooled you 1 000 times,
just like they fooled me.
But this time, I'll fool somebody.
I'll stay in this race.
I'm on my own and out for blood.
Listen to me, you hicks!
Lift up your eyes and look at
God's blessed and unfly-blown truth.
This is the truth!
You're a hick.
Nobody ever helped a hick
but a hick himself.
Listen to me, listen to me!
They were going to use me
to split the vote.
But I'm standing here now
on my hind legs.
Even a dog can learn to do that.
Are you standing on your hind legs?
Have you learned that yet?
Here it is, you hicks!
Nail up anybody who stands
in your way.
Nail up Joe Harrison!
Nail up McMurphy!
If they don't deliver, give me
the hammer and I'll do it.
I want his throat cut
from ear to ear.
No use going any further.
We're not printing them anymore.
-I thought the Chronicle line was--
-Divide and conquer.
Stark's getting big for his britches.
The hicks are getting too smart.
We're now supporting Harrison.
How do you square that?
I work here.
I don't, not anymore.
You fool.
-If you had guts, you'd print this.
-I take orders.
You've got a wife and three kids,
and your boy goes to Princeton.
You won't find it easy
to get another job.
I'm too rich to work.
We didn't do so good.
-Double bourbon.
-Same for me.
And a beer.
I hear you got fired from the paper.
You heard wrong. I quit.
You're smart.
Before I'm through,
they won't have money...
...to pay the boy
that cleans the spittoons.
How do you feel?
I feel fine.
You see, Jack, I learned something.
What?
How to win.
I didn't see Willie again
until his second campaign...
...four years later.
I drifted from job to job.
That is, whenever I could find one.
But always further
and further away from Anne...
...and the life at Burden's Landing.
But Willie wasn't drifting.
He knew where he was going.
He had his foot in the door
and kept right on pushing.
He'd lost the election
but he'd won the state.
And he knew it.
And the people knew it.
They all were hopping on
his bandwagon, even Tiny Duffy.
Willie came back
like he said he would.
You want to know
what my platform is?
I'm going to soak the fat boys
and spread it out thin.
Willie was right.
He'd learned how to win.
He spent a lot of money doing it.
An awful lot of money.
I was beginning to wonder
where he got it from.
There were rumors...
...that Willie was making deals
with all kinds of people.
Strange deals.
For Willie Stark.
The second time wasn't a campaign.
It was a slaughter.
It was Saturday night
in a mining town.
Willie came back
like he said he would.
He came back
and he took me with him.
This is a friend of mine.
He's going to live here.
Let these boys through, officers.
-Duffy works for me.
-Everybody does.
Not yet.
I want him around.
He reminds me of something
I never want to forget.
Come on.
-These the boys?
-The boys that can get the boys.
-How many can you get?
-Fifty.
-How much?
-Five dollars a head.
What do you think?
They look like good boys?
They better be.
Get 1 00.
Go on, all of you. Blow.
You too, Duffy, go on.
Handbill distributors.
If they all look like them,
l'd take one.
That's the object. Not like
when they beat up my boy.
-How is Tom?
-He's fine.
-He starts college in the fall.
-And Lucy?
Fine.
I need a boy.
Where's a boy?
Take that downstairs
right away, on the double.
Double-space all of this.
He can't read it.
-Hi, how are you?
-Sadie is my secretary now.
Fix your tie, Willie.
Hey, Sugar.
Keep everybody out.
I want to talk to Jack and Sadie.
Now you'll work for me.
Doing what?
I don't know.
Something will turn up.
We need a college man around.
For research.
How much they pay you
on that newspaper?
Three hundred dollars a month.
I could buy you cheap, couldn't l?
For a bag of salt.
I don't play that way.
I like you. I always have.
I tell you what I'll do.
I'll give you $400 a month
and traveling expenses.
You throw money around
like it was money.
Money.
I don't need money.
People give me things.
Why?
Because they believe in me.
I was going home again.
But this time, it was different.
I had a feeling that
maybe the waiting was over.
For me and for Anne.
It's a far cry from where
I come from to this house.
Standing under the portrait of
one of the greatest governors...
...and talking to you...
...it's an honor I never
thought l'd have.
Are there any questions?
Mr. McAvoy?
I have no questions.
Judge?
-A few, but it will hold.
-I have a question.
Shoot.
A lot of people in this state say
that you've been making deals.
Some of them with the groups
you claim you're against.
ls that true?
-You know how rumors start--
-Yes, that's true.
I have nothing to hide.
I'll deal with the devil
if it'll help with my program.
But believe me...
...there are no strings attached.
You're sure about that?
Jack has been telling me
how you feel about things.
You'd like the sick people
given a break.
You'd like to see
a new hospital built...
...a hospital that's the best
that money can buy.
You want those things because
you're a man who wants to do good.
l'd like to ask a question.
Shoot.
-Do you know what good comes out of?
-You tell me.
Out of bad, that's what.
Because you can't make it
out of anything else.
Did you know that?
No, I didn't.
There's another question
l'd like to ask you.
You say there's only bad
to start with...
...and the good must come from the bad.
Who's to determine
what's good and what's bad?
You?
Why not?
How?
Why, that's easy.
Make it up as you go along.
Folks.
There's a time to talk
and there's a time to act.
I think the time to act is now.
With your support, I will win
and do all of the things I promised.
I need your help.
I need it badly.
But I won't beg for it.
ln the name of this state
which we love...
...and the governor in whose house
we meet, I demand it.
-What do you say, sir?
-You've got to say yes.
-I'm an old bird.
-But a game one.
I'll give you complete power
as attorney general.
You can do anything you see fit.
I'll clear your way.
-Is that a deal?
-It's a deal.
We have to get back to town.
A lot to do.
Good night.
I'm glad to have met you.
We want Willie!
This is not a time for speechmaking.
I should ask God for strength
to carry out your will.
This much I swear to you.
These things you shall have:
I'm going to build a hospital.
The biggest that money can buy.
And it will belong to you.
That anyone who is sick or in pain
can go through those doors...
...and know that everything
will be done for them...
...to heal sickness,
to ease pain.
Free.
Not as a charity...
...but as a right.
And it is your right.
Do you hear me?
It's your right that
every child have an education.
That all who produce can take things
to market without paying toll.
And no poor man's land can be taxed
or taken away from him.
It is the right of the people that
they shall not be deprived of hope.
Does he mean it, Jack?
That's his bribe.
What if it is his bribe?
He swept the old gang out of office.
They hollered like stuck pigs.
He jammed through bills,
and the people got what they wanted.
I demand that this bill be passed.
Nobody tells me
how to run this state.
He started to build roads...
...schools, power dams...
...to change the state
from one end to the other.
His methods?
Politics is a dirty game.
And he played it rough and dirty.
Willie's little black book was
a record of corruption.
And me, Jack Burden, I kept the book
and added up the accounts.
''Clown, show-off, playboy,''
they yelled out.
Building stadiums.
Fiercely proud of his son
who played in them.
They said he was building
a private army.
But he was always building.
Playing up to the crowd,
letting them trample on tradition.
Well, tradition needed trampling on.
The crowds loved it.
Willie loved it...
...and so did I.
You low-down, no-good redneck!
-What goes on?
-That's what Sadie wants to know.
The boss poses for too many pictures.
I'll kill him!
Why, Sadie!
I'm surprised at you.
I'll kill him!
I hate all women!
Was she pretty?
If I met her on the street,
l'd never recognize her.
I wasn't looking at her face.
If it'll cause this grief,
let him go.
Let him go?
I'll kill him!
I'll drive him out of this state.
A guy sits with girls
on his knees in public--
Public or private, I know him.
How about Chicago?
That girl on skates.
And the time you both
went to St. Louis?
There's a new invention, you know.
Photography and newsreels.
Willie Stark in a nightclub.
Willie with a blonde.
-You could always bleach your hair.
-I could also break his neck.
After all l've done for him,
now he's two-timing me.
He's two-timing Lucy, so there's
another kind of arithmetic for you.
Lucy's a fool.
If she had her way,
he'd be back slopping the hogs.
He knows what she'd do for him.
She had her chance.
You think Lucy's out?
-He'll ditch her. Give him time.
-You ought to know.
You got the wrong guy.
I'm not the hero of this piece.
Come on, both of you.
Let's go, hurry it up.
Pillsbury got caught.
I never did trust that guy.
-Later, boys.
-What about these charges?
Go get the Judge.
Get him over to my hotel
as soon as you can.
I waited for you.
You promised we'd discuss
my charity project, children's home.
I'm very sorry.
Something very important came up.
-You'll call me later, won't you?
-Certainly.
We're late.
Look at you, Pillsbury.
Fifty years old.
Gut sprung, teeth gone.
Never had a dime.
If the Almighty wanted you rich,
He'd have done that long ago.
The idea of you being rich.
That's blasphemy.
Ain't that a fact?
Answer me.
Don't mumble. Speak up!
Say, ''It's a blasphemous fact.''
It's a blasphemous fact.
I see.
Dumond can't come.
His wife is sick.
I don't care if she's dying.
Get him and bring him over here.
You know what you're supposed to do?
You stay poor and take orders.
There'll be sweetening sometimes.
Duffy'll take care of that.
Don't set up on your own again,
understand?
Say ''I understand that.''
I understand that.
Give him a pen and paper.
See who that is.
Hello, Judge, sit down.
I'll be with you soon.
Write what I tell you to write.
Dear Governor Stark:
I wish to resign as auditor
due to ill health...
...to take effect as soon as
you can relieve me.
Respectfully yours.
Did you sign it?
Well, sign it!
Don't date it.
I'll fill it in.
Bring it to me.
Now get out.
-The papers have the story.
-I know.
They're talking about
impeachment proceedings.
-Against who?
-This time, Pillsbury.
I got that ''this time.''
-How true is it?
-It's too true.
This is it.
Jeff Hopkins on the wire.
What have we got on Hopkins?
Hello, Jeff.
About that Pillsbury business.
Here's what you do
in the legislature.
Wait a minute.
You listen to me.
You got a mortgage due
on your place in five weeks.
You'd like to get it renewed,
wouldn't you?
Tiny will talk to you in the morning.
Get going.
You haven't answered my question.
Why are you saving Pillsbury?
Not Pillsbury. It's something
much more important than that.
If McMurphy gets away with this,
no telling where he'll stop.
Or where you will.
Pillsbury's guilty.
As attorney general,
it's my job to prosecute.
Judge, you talks like
Pillsbury was human.
He isn't. He's a thing.
You don't prosecute a machine
that makes a mistake.
You fix it.
Well, I fixed him.
I'm not interested in Pillsbury.
It's something much bigger.
Yes, it is.
He's right.
Can't you see that he's right?
Because you want him to be right.
You're afraid to admit
you made a mistake.
Do it now, before it's too late.
I'm offering my resignation
as attorney general.
You'll have it in writing
in the morning.
Dated.
It took you a long time
to make up your mind.
What made you take so long?
I wasn't sure.
Now you are?
I'll tell you what you are.
You're scared.
You sat for 30 years
and played at being a judge.
Then I put a bat in your hand
and said, ''Start swinging!''
You had a good time,
but now you're scared.
You don't want to get
your hands dirty.
You want to pick up the marbles
but not get dirty.
Look at my program. How do you
think I put that across?
I knew how but I never knew why.
You're not thinking of going over
to McMurphy, are you?
I'm through with politics.
I'm happy to hear that.
No hard feelings.
Goodbye, governor.
You coming with me?
You're making a mistake.
You think he means it when he says
he's through with politics?
No, I don't.
What about you?
l've known the judge all my life.
He's always meant
everything he's said.
All right, take it easy.
I'll take your word for it.
Sugar, take Miss Stanton home.
When am I going to see you again?
What's the matter?
Please take me home now.
-You've got to understand me.
-I understand you.
It's myself I don't understand.
Do you think I like sneaking around?
But with the Pillsbury business
and your uncle quitting, a divorce--
Maybe we'd better stop
seeing each other.
We won't stop seeing each other,
will we?
Because you believe what I tell you.
Because I believe what you tell me.
Good evening, Governor Stark.
You might like to know that
Judge Stanton kept his promise.
He gave the story
to every paper in town.
Sugar, meet me at the hotel
as soon as you can.
These are serious charges...
...that Judge Stanton
has given to the press.
This legislature is entitled
to a complete and full report...
...on the Pillsbury affair.
Let the truth be known.
Let it come out.
-I move we adjourn.
-I second it.
All those in favor say ''aye.''
Motion carried.
House is adjourned.
You let Stark get away with
the graft, there's no telling--
We beat the Pillsbury rap.
It's over.
These things are never over.
Tell you what I want you to do.
I want you to start
a new page in your book.
Under the name of Judge Stanton.
-There's nothing on him.
-Why?
Because his name is Stanton?
Easy.
What if I won't do it?
You know, some of this
has rubbed off on you.
What will you do?
Have me shot?
No, but I'll have
to get myself a new boy.
There's nothing on the judge.
There's something on everybody.
Man is conceived in sin
and born in corruption.
It's a waste of time.
What's the matter?
You afraid you might find
something out?
I kept saying to myself
that Willie was wrong about the judge.
If there was anything left
at Burden's Landing, it was honor.
I had to believe that.
I want to ask you a question.
Was the judge ever broke?
Really broke?
Why do you want to know?
I don't.
But l've got to.
-Did he tell you--
-Did who tell me?
I don't know.
How should I know
if he was ever broke?
Come on, take this food
and start cooking.
-I'm hungry.
-I'm thirsty.
Bring some glasses quick.
It's been a long time
since l've played this thing.
-Let's wake up the ghost.
-Another glass, Anne, for a ghost.
Remember the last time I played this?
You and Anne were dancing.
Shall we dance?
Let's have a drink first.
Keep playing.
Anne and I want to hear this.
Don't we?
Adam.
Ghost.
And me.
What shall we drink to?
To Ghost?
To Adam.
To the director
of the new medical center.
Don't you ever stop working for him?
-I'm sorry.
-Well, I'm not.
What's wrong with being
director of the center?
Nothing, except
I'm not going to take it.
Why?
Because your uncle resigned?
That's partly it.
-There are other things.
-What other things?
You too?
Me too.
If Adam doesn't want
to discuss it, let's not.
-Let's discuss it.
-But calmly.
Calmly.
Go ahead.
Why do you think he wants me?
You're the best man for the job.
It has nothing to do with my name?
It could.
Let's grant that.
-That's your answer.
-No, it's not.
If that were the only answer,
I wouldn't be with him.
There's another side of it.
I learned something from him.
You can't make an omelet
without cracking eggs.
Or heads?
A hospital will be built
and the sick cared for.
At what price?
At any price.
Do you really believe that?
I really believe
that Stark wants to do good.
You do too.
It's a matter of method.
Many times, out of evil comes good.
Pain is evil.
As a doctor, you know that.
Pain is an evil, it is not evil.
It is not evil in itself.
Stark is evil.
The people of this state
don't think so.
How would they know?
Stark took over the newspapers
and radio stations.
Why be so afraid of criticism?
If Stark does good,
he should be interested in truth.
I don't see how
you can separate the two.
-Stark is not for me.
-No, Stark is not for you.
Well, what's for you?
Pride. That's all it is.
Foolish, stupid pride.
You've talked about what you could do
if somebody would build.
Somebody has,
and he's given it to you.
But he's not for you.
No, he's not for you.
Will I find anything, Judge?
Will I?
I didn't find it all at once.
Takes a long time to go through
old records and musty deeds.
A very long time.
But it wasn't too hard for me.
I was well-trained in research.
Especially this kind.
I found what I didn't want to find.
Have some photostat copies
made of these.
I'll be back tomorrow for them.
-Who is it?
-It's me, Sadie Burke.
Wait a minute.
All right, come in.
Awful lot of smoke.
Awful lot of whiskey.
You sober?
Stone.
I'll have one with you.
What are you hiding out for?
-I've been sleeping.
-For four days?
You've been back in town
for four days.
-Willie knows everything.
-Willie's worried about his boy.
Willie's boy is worried
about Willie's boy.
Why don't you put a mean blues
on the phonograph?
Play it until you get sick of it,
then go back to work.
-I do it.
-That's not my problem.
No, it isn't your problem.
I'll wait for you
if you want to powder your nose.
I'll be with you in a minute.
I can see it.
l've got to look
in the mirror to see it.
Soft, white skin.
Not like mine.
I had smallpox when I was a kid.
Where I lived, it seemed nearly
all the kids had smallpox.
It leaves your face hard.
And she's got poise.
Look at the way she holds her head
at just the right angle.
That takes training.
That takes years of training.
I see what Willie sees.
-Willie's got big ideas.
-What?
A girl like that could be
a governor's wife or a president's.
-What are you saying?
-He ditched me and he'll ditch you.
He'll ditch everybody
because that's what he wants.
-Nobody in the world but him.
-What?
You and your high-toned friends.
What do they know about anything?
Why did you have to mix her in?
-You're out of your mind.
-Am l?
Why don't you go ask her?
-Or ask him, ask Willie.
-Shut up!
Nice catch.
All the ends over here.
All the ends over this way.
Come on.
He's off today.
It's only practice.
He'll be all right.
You've been gone a long time.
I figured if you needed me,
you'd yell.
Why'd you lay around
that hotel?
-Thinking.
-About what?
Things.
What did you find on the judge?
Nothing.
You sure?
-Yeah, I'm sure.
-You'll keep trying?
-If you want me to.
-I want you to.
-There's something else.
-What? Bucket boy? Towel swinger?
-What's eating you?
-What else do you want?
If you've got something
on your mind, spit it out.
What do you want?
Your pal Adam Stanton turned down
the hospital director job.
That's bad.
Especially at a time like this.
-How did you hear it?
-What difference does it make?
-I just wanted to know.
-I heard it around.
How did you hear he turned it down?
I'll be back.
Something's happening.
-You'll practice the way I say.
-I'll do it my way.
What's going on?
I don't care if he is your son.
No special rules for him.
It makes no difference
if I play or not.
It does to me.
What should he do?
Behave himself
like the other boys.
Four times, he's broken training.
He comes to practice half-potted.
You're going to have
to obey the rules.
Every Saturday,
I put them across, don't l?
I do it drunk or sober.
That's all you want.
So you can big-shot it around.
lsn't that all you want?
He's a little high-strung.
Tom, come here.
Come on, let's go faster.
Come on.
It's the governor's son.
Mr. Hale's here to see you.
Go upstairs.
I have some business with Mr. Hale.
What l've got to say
anybody can listen to.
-Where's your boy?
-Now don't get excited.
-Get me another drink.
-My daughter may die.
She won't die. She'll get
the best medical attention there is.
-Where is he?
-I'll get him.
Wait a minute.
He's asleep.
He'll be all right.
He won't be all right
unless you make him all right.
I'll get him.
-Care for a drink?
-No, thanks.
-Accidents will happen, you know.
-Accidents?
Your boy was drunk.
I saw the police report. There was
nothing about drunkenness on it.
Whose police and whose report?
I say the boy was drunk,
and I know it.
Here before your father, I want--
The doctor says you need rest.
I don't want you to try
to cover up for me.
I was wrong and that's it.
You don't know.
I saw the report.
I don't care
what the police report says.
I was driving and I was drunk.
It's all my fault.
Anything you want to do to me,
you can do.
Whatever you want me to do, I'll do.
Nobody has to do anything.
I'll take care of it.
I don't want you to take care of it.
Go on upstairs and get some rest.
Sugar, help him.
Come on over and sit down.
Sure you wouldn't care for a drink?
Tiny, go home, will you?
Go on, out of here.
What business did
you say you're in?
I didn't say.
-What business are you in?
-Trucking business.
Trucking business.
Trucks run on state roads.
If a man in the trucking business
had a contract with the state...
...that'd be pretty good,
wouldn't it?
Tell him what would happen.
Go on.
Trying to bribe me, aren't you?
No, I'm not trying to bribe you.
I'm only talking
things over with you.
You're pretty good at talking.
I remember when you
first started talking.
A place called Upton.
You did a lot of talking then.
The things you said made sense.
To me and a lot of other people.
I believed in you, I followed you,
and I fought for you.
Well, the words are still good.
But you're not.
And I don't believe you ever were.
Follow him.
Keep calling in.
l'd like Anne to see you now.
l'd like Anne to see you now,
you drunken sot!
Come on.
All right, I'll give you a statement.
This is a mess of lies.
Have the man that made that
statement repeat it to my face.
You can't.
He's vanished.
Let me ask you some questions.
Why has he gone?
Where is he?
Maybe you could answer those too?
-I won't dignify that with an answer.
-One more question.
Where's your son?
At the stadium, where he should be.
He'll play for the university, which
my administration is responsible for.
He's not hiding.
He'll be there in full view
of 70,000 cheering fans.
One of which will be me.
See you, men.
Where's Stark?
How about Tommy Stark?
Send your boy in!
Why don't they put him in?
Come on, Willie.
Send your boy in.
What's the matter?
ls your boy ashamed to show his face?
-Shut up!
-Get him out of here!
-Go on, get him out of here!
-What's the idea?
They're booing you.
-My head--
-The doctor said it's nothing.
-I get dizzy, can't see.
-You're scared.
-Get out!
-They're booing me too.
I built this for those dirty--
Thattaboy, show some spirit!
Tell him what his playing means.
You can't tell about a head injury.
Maybe he's hurt.
He's hurt. I'm hurt.
I didn't crash the car or get drunk.
But I'm taking the rap.
Get out there and play.
Show them what a Stark is made of.
I wouldn't know.
Come on.
Cut it out!
All right, I'll play.
Now get out of here!
Stark's going in.
One, two, three, four, five....
Boss, you got to eat.
You got to.
I'm the one that made him play.
I sent him in.
Sit down.
Please sit down.
-I sent him in.
-What difference does that make now?
What goes on?
-There isn't a plane flying.
-They got to. My son's got to live.
I got a call from Dr. Birnham.
The earliest he can get here
is tomorrow morning.
There's nobody else?
-Dr. Stanton should operate.
-That's up to Stark.
He wanted another doctor,
a specialist. I sent for one.
How bad is it really, doc?
He's unconscious and paralyzed.
-Has he got a chance?
-To live, yes.
What do you mean?
Even if the operation is successful,
that is, if he lives...
...I think he'll be paralyzed
for life.
You'll do everything you can,
won't you?
Anything between us wouldn't count,
would it?
Anything you want,
just ask for it and you got it.
There are some things
that even you can't buy.
Do you want me to operate
or don't you?
I want you to operate.
May I see Tom now?
How much does he know?
-About what?
-You know what I'm talking about.
-How much does he know?
-About what?
About Anne and me.
He doesn't know a thing.
Not a thing!
How is he?
The boy?
-He'll live.
-Thank God.
-How is--?
-Willie?
He blames himself, doesn't he?
He'll find someone else
to blame in a few days.
I tried to call here
at the hospital but I just--
Why did you do it?
He wasn't like anybody
I ever knew before.
You mean he wasn't like me.
It wasn't like anybody
I ever knew before.
I love him.
I guess that's the reason.
Everybody loves him.
He wants to marry me.
-Are you going to?
-Not now. It would hurt him.
A divorce would hurt his career.
His career!
What are you going to do?
You can't leave him now.
He needs you more than ever.
What Willie needs, Willie's got.
You don't know him.
You've known him all these years
and you don't know him.
What about Adam?
Don't worry about him.
If he finds out, it'll prove a Stanton
is no different than anyone else.
Just show him these.
Willie was right. ''A man is conceived
in sin and born in corruption.''
Even Judge Stanton.
Show them to him.
Change the picture of the world
that Adam has in his head.
Just like our picture of it
has been changed.
Wipe out everything he believes.
It'll be good for him.
There's no God but Willie Stark.
I'm his prophet and you're his--
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean--
What's going on here?
It's all right, officer.
We both work for Willie Stark.
That'll be the main building.
Fifteen stories high.
That's the laboratory.
World's finest equipment.
What are you trying to do?
l've taken the job.
Why?
My reasons are my own.
-Why are you building the hospital?
-To do good for the people.
And get votes.
-There's lots of ways to get votes.
-I know.
I won't stand for any interference.
I won't interfere.
I may fire you,
but I won't interfere.
You're wasting your time with threats.
You know what I think of you.
Yes, I know.
I'll tell you what.
We'll each stay
on our own side of the fence.
ls that a deal?
Now he had us all.
Me, Anne and Adam.
Now we all worked for him.
So the eyes of the entire nation
are now focused upon Governor Stark...
...an amazing phenomenon
on the political scene.
A whole state is filled
with his accomplishments.
Each one of them
bearing his personal signature...
...to make sure
no one will ever forget him.
This is the way
the roads used to be.
But some claim
that they were adequate...
...that you don't need a 4-lane
highway for a horse and buggy.
When Stark boasts of his great
school system, his critics say:
''You can't go to school
and work fields at the same time.''
They question the benefit
of these projects...
...charging that need and poverty
is as great as before.
Willie Stark has never forgotten
the source of his power:
The people who supported him.
He still keeps his touch
with these people of the backwoods...
...making periodic trips
to such places as Kanoma City...
...now famous as his birthplace.
For those who say Stark
is a man of destiny...
...there are others who claim
that he is evil.
A man who cares neither
for the people or the state...
...but only for his own
personal power and ambition.
Obviously, these ambitions go
far beyond the state's boundaries.
Just how far,
only time will tell.
Meanwhile, he is here.
From the looks of things,
he is here to stay.
Willie Stark.
Messiah or dictator?.
How do you like it?
-How many theaters will play this?
-All over.
Hear that?
All over the country.
There's one thing I didn't like.
That ''messiah or the dictator.''
That's our view.
That's the way it stands.
That's the way it stands
as of now.
How are you making it, Pa?
How are you, Tom?
I made some refreshments.
-I'll get them.
-I'll help.
No, thank you.
Thank you kindly.
The boys have to get back
to make the morning editions.
Set them up on the porch.
We'll take pictures here first.
Mrs. Stark.
Take one down there.
Shoot it up this way.
You're still a great cook.
I better be getting back to town.
Nice to have spent the day
with the family.
Goodbye.
Take care, Pappy.
How do you like
the new radio I got you?
You can get police calls on it.
I'll show you.
This one for police calls.
Car 62, proceed to 518 Oak Street.
Tom Jones is beating his wife again.
-Car 62, proceed to 518 Oak Street.
-Now this one, go ahead.
We interrupt this
for a special announcement.
Today, the body of Richard Hale,
father of the girl who died...
...in the governor's son's car,
was found.
A medical examination revealed
he was beaten to death.
The charge of murder...
...has been hurled
at the administration...
...by Stark's opponents,
led by Judge Stanton...
...lately an outspoken critic....
Your friend, the judge.
Thus an almost forgotten incident
provided the spark that might set off...
...the explosion needed to rock
Willie Stark out of power.
The latest report says impeachment
proceedings may be institut--
How long will it take to pack?
Come to the city with me.
-Why?
-Because I need you.
-What for?
-I'll explain later.
-I'll wait outside.
-Stay. I want you to witness this.
She can bear witness too.
-I'm going back to get Duffy.
-You stay right here.
Somebody's got to go back
to the capital.
I'll go.
Tell Duffy not to do anything
until I'm there.
Now that he's in trouble,
he needs us.
He can lead us around like monkeys
and say, ''Feel sorry for me...
...a family man with a wife
and a crippled son!''
Shut up!
-Why don't you leave us alone?
-Leave him alone?
How many scrapes
have I gotten him out of?
Stop!
It's not him they're after.
It's me.
How many half-wits
must I pay to square this?
What do you think this will cost me?
What do you think it cost him?
A man builds for his son.
That's all he builds for.
Give me a drink.
She'll go.
No good.
Mr. Speaker!
I offer a house resolution:
Whereas Willie Stark...
...governor of the state...
...has been guilty of incompetence...
...corruption
and favoritism in office...
...and other high crimes.
And he is hereby impeached...
...and ordered to be tried.
-What's the score?
-They're lined up against you solid.
Were you there?
-What would I be doing there?
-Selling me out.
-How many votes have we got?
-Eleven.
-We need 20.
-We might dig up a few more.
-Do you know how?
-No, do you?
Jack, come here.
What do you got on your friend?
-Who do you mean?
-Your friend, the judge.
-If you need it--
-I need it.
He's got four senators in his pocket.
What do you got?
If he can prove it isn't true,
I won't spill it.
I ought to bust you.
-I promised two people l'd do this.
-Who are they?
Myself and someone else.
It doesn't matter who.
-I'll give him a break.
-But if you got facts, you got them.
-The truth is sufficient.
-That's the way it's going to be.
All right, boy.
I trust you.
Where you going?
I'll be around.
Who else do you think he promised?
He's smart.
Play square with him.
You're going to need people
like us around.
Are you sure?
The chips were down
and Willie knew it.
He was fighting for his life.
He roared across the state
making speeches.
All of them adding up
to the same thing:
''It's not me they're after.
It's you!''
Willie hollered ''foul.''
He knew if you hollered
hard and loud enough...
...people begin to believe.
Just in case they didn't,
he organized demonstrations.
Tell the boys to get the hicks out.
Bring them in from the sticks.
Turn the yokels out!
In case anyone hollered back,
he organized spontaneous slugging.
Willie pulled every trick
he ever knew and added a few more.
You won't live to be impeached.
Boy, I'll live to be president.
Step on it.
l've got 1 4 senators to vote
against this impeachment.
If I win, you're out of politics.
I'll do whatever the judge says.
And always the trail led
to one place...
...to Burden's Landing
and the judge.
You sure you don't want me
to go in?
I'm sure.
Hurry it up, boy.
We got places to go.
I beg you, as a favor
to yourself, to me.
Call up, release your votes.
I made a mistake once.
When I resigned.
It was too easy then,
just resigning and pulling out.
l've made my choice.
I have nothing more to lose.
You know what Stark is capable of.
Think it over.
You can give me your answer tomorrow.
I can't wait until tomorrow.
I'm a very impatient man.
I told you not to come in here.
ls it true
you're behind the impeachment?
It's true.
-I wanted to hear you say it.
-You've heard it.
If that's all, you could have
saved yourself a trip.
Mind if I pour myself a drink?
How about you?
Will you have one?
You better.
You're going to need it.
What'd he say?
You'll get your answer tomorrow.
Are you kidding?
Did you show it to him or not?
Show me what?
That's what I figured.
Get down to cases.
You remember a man named Littlepaugh?
How did you find out?
You remember Littlepaugh?
Remember the Fortune
Electric Company?
Of course. I was their counsel
for over ten years.
-Remember how you got the job?
-How did you find out?
Do you remember how you got the job?
You know, dirt's a funny thing.
Some of it rubs off on everybody.
How did you get the job?
Blackmail?
I swear I never even
remembered his name.
lsn't that remarkable?
I never even
remembered his name.
It's so long ago
it's hard for me to realize it ever happened.
But it did.
Yes, it did.
Just difficult for me to realize it.
For me too.
Thanks for that much.
You know what the next move is,
don't you?
Yes, I do.
Jack Burden.
Willie Stark's hatchet man.
How did you find out?
This would never stand at law.
It happened over 25 years ago.
You could never get any testimony.
Everybody is dead.
Everybody except you.
You're alive.
People think
you're a certain kind of man.
You couldn't bear
for them to think otherwise.
But ever since then,
l've done my duty.
I'm responsible for many good things.
But I also did this.
-Yes, you did.
-Judge, I beg of you.
Call and release your votes...
...for your sake.
You have tender sensibilities
for a hatchet man.
Good night, gentlemen.
How about my answer?
-You'll have it in the morning.
-I want it tonight.
ln the morning.
Good night, gentlemen.
How did you find out?
We got a lot to do.
Let's get back.
-You know we're through, don't you?
-You don't mean that.
-Why are you here?
-It's all right.
Just here to discuss politics.
I see.
Well, good night.
-Did you give him--?
-Wait a minute.
Aren't you going back with him?
Why not?
You belong with him.
How could you have done it?
Anne said you promised not
to tell Stark--
Yeah, I know.
And I kept my promise.
From all over, they're streaming in.
From the hills, farms, lumber camps...
...by boat or train, by horse
and on foot. Willie Stark's army.
There are rumors that Stark
is planning to seize power by force.
As commander of
the state militia, he has--
Come in.
The door's open.
What do you want?
I want to see you cry.
Stop it!
-I called you all day.
-I know, I was here.
-You've got to tell Adam.
-Tell him what?
-He knows about--
-About you and Willie?
I tried to explain to him that
it wasn't the way he thought it was.
How was it? You tell me.
He hit me.
My own brother hit me.
Your brother's old-fashioned.
He believes in a sister's honor.
I'm modern man,
the 20th century type. I run.
I'm frightened!
For your brother or Willie?
We're through.
Who's through with who?
He called me this afternoon.
He's going back to Lucy.
He said it was better this way.
Better for who? Him?
Both of us.
Did he say that, too,
when he asked you to betray the judge?
At least I walked out on him.
Help me, please.
Adam's all l've got left now.
If you ever loved me....
If I ever loved you?
I'll go find Adam.
Where are you going?
Sorry, I didn't recognize you.
Do you know who Dr. Stanton is?
-Did he come here today?
-Haven't seen him.
Check the other entrances.
They're blocked off.
Orders are to take no chances.
Come in and wait.
We can find you a seat.
I'll wait here.
If he shows up, let me know.
Pass the word to the boys, will you?
All right, now.
Everybody!
That means everybody.
Let's let Willie know we're here.
All together!
Willie! Willie!
We want Willie!
We'll first take
the judgment of the Senate...
...on the question of impeachment.
Mr. Speaker.
This is a farce...
...to ask us to vote...
...in the face of the kind
of intimidation and pressure...
...that has been exerted
in the past few weeks.
Even that crowd outside...
...yelling on cue...
...is part of that pressure.
Attention, please.
This is an announcement from
Willie Stark to you people out there.
He doesn't want any one
of you to leave.
He wants you to stay in front of
this capitol until the fight is over.
If you want Willie Stark to win...
...stay where you are.
Do you hear me?
Stay where you are.
Don't go away.
Attention, please.
The balloting on
the impeachment proceedings...
...against Governor Stark...
...has just ended.
This is the result:
Willie Stark...
...has won!
They tried to ruin me.
But they are ruined.
They tried to ruin me because
they didn't like what l've done.
Do you like what I have done?
Remember.
It's not I who have won...
...but you.
Your will is my strength.
And your need is my justice.
I shall live
in your right and your will.
And if any man tries to stop me
from fulfilling that...
...I'll break him.
I'll break him with my bare hands.
For I have the strength of many.
I'm glad you're here.
Doctor, I'm glad--
Does it hurt much, boss?
Does it hurt much?
-Where are you going?
-Leave me alone.
-To do what?
-I don't care.
That's too easy.
-I don't know.
-I do!
-Leave me alone, please.
-No more.
-My brother's dead!
-We're alive.
We've got to go on living...
...so Adam's death has meaning.
So it wasn't wasted.
Our life has to give his death meaning.
Don't you see that?
Look at those people.
Look at them!
They still believe in him.
We must make them see
Willie as Adam did...
...or there's no meaning in anything.
The governor's asking for you.
You'd better hurry.
He's going fast.
Will you wait here?
It could have been whole world,
Willie Stark.
The whole world, Willie Stark.
Why does he do it to me,
Willie Stark?
Why?