Well, I should get there soon.
Luckily I had the GPS.
How is it?
Crazy. There's snow everywhere.
It's like driving on the clouds.
I am glad. You sound well.
Please help me find
the coordinates for the next act.
If not... Her son
is my last chance to find her.
I know, I am trying.
I wish you had changed your mind...
I can't help it.
Anyway, everything's fine.
Don't worry, I feel good.
I know, baby.
Give me that.
It won't be necessary.
Single.
Diagnosed in 2011.
You stopped treatment 5 months ago.
No kids.
I am sorry.
I don't know what to say.
I don't know why he reacted like that.
I hope... I don't know.
I don't know what to say.
I don't know why...
I am so sorry.
I hope this doesn't change anything.
Please.
You want Nana?
Don't worry my little girl.
Don't worry. Be strong.
I have some documents for you.
- Sign the papers.
- Thank you.
Confidentiality agreement.
Thank you.