Along the Ridge
Wake up call!
You kook!
- Stupid cow!
- It's for your own good!
Tommaso?
He can't still be in bed...
What are you still doing in bed?
I'm ready, Dad...
Ready my arse!
I just don't know, I'm fed up!
Viola left 30 minutes ago!
Same story every morning!
Put on your shoe!
One, two...
Send you to military school, I will!
Pack your bag and get going.
Dad, did you think it over?
What?
Football school.
You serious?
You wanna quit swimming
to play football?
Football's for dickheads!
They all play football, now you too?
Swimming's a noble sport,
it's a different story altogether.
You could become the Italian
100m freestyle champion.
I'm good at football too,
plus the pool is miles away.
Don't be a dope, go to school!
Everybody's complaining about you
and your darn soccer ball!
- Where's our teacher?
- In the headmaster's office.
They put a mute in class with us,
he's out there.
Did you see how tall he is?
He's massive.
Is he mute, like mute?
What's all this racket?
Have you all suspended, I will!
I don't want to hear anyone
so much as breathe.
He's big, but he's our age.
Says who?
He lives near me, he saw his dad die
and hasn't said a word since.
He was eating his soup and fell
face-first into the bowl.
Maybe the soup was foul.
Here she comes!
Good morning, kids.
We have a new classmate,
his name is Claudio.
Claudio, go sit near Carolina.
Time for roll call.
Come on Tommi, move it!
Goggles on and go!
Tommi
I'm fine thanks, and you?
What was your 25m time?
16 seconds.
Hi
What's so funny?
I'm chatting with this guy,
you can't believe what he's saying!
I want your room tidied
before dinner.
No, tomorrow, there's no school.
What d'you mean, tomorrow!
Tomorrow we're going
to Vincenzo and Marina's.
Cut it short Viola,
you can't spend two hours online.
What a bloody mess!
What's that?
What is that?
No, like hell, this is too much!
Whose is this?
Not mine.
Mine, I was going to pick it up.
You were going to...
Anyway, it's biodegradable!
Dad,
I'm sleeping in your bed tonight.
You slept here two Fridays in a row.
Am I made of honey or something?
Aren't you too big
to be sleeping with daddy?
Pia, someone's looking for you.
- Who is it?
- Dunno.
Off to the countryside!
Where'd you go to buy the sausage,
you took forever.
The butcher was closed
so I went to the market.
Sing us one of your made-up songs.
Go on, please!
Lady, outta the way
or I'll run you down!
Hold on...
- It's open.
- What's going on, Dad?
I gotta do something.
Tommi, come with me.
Good morning.
Is Barzelli in?
Let me check if he's in a meeting.
Do you have an appointment?
No, tell him I'm gonna wait
one minute this time.
I'll go check.
Sit down.
They'd better not piss me off.
Why?
They're trying to rip me off.
I'm sorry,
he won't be free for another hour.
Wanna see me pissed off?
- Sir...
- Wanna see me get pissed off?
Barzelli, get out here,
I'm getting really pissed off now!
No need to shout.
Shut up, I've been here 3 times!
Last time I waited an hour and a half.
Let's see today.
Come on Barzelli,
I swear I'll come and get you!
I'm gonna count to five. One...
How dare you?
We have a secretary,
call her and make an appointment.
I've been here three times,
you've fucked me around enough!
Dad
Want me to smash your face in?
- Dad, let's go.
- Stop whinging.
What are we gonna do, huh?
Gonna give me this fucking money?
I'll write you a cheque.
Then write me a fucking cheque.
How much do we owe him?
Let me check.
780 Euro.
We're through.
I decide when we're through, prick.
Let's go.
Tasty sausage.
A bit of jogging...
You look good.
I'm fine, we're doing all right.
The kids look great!
We're doing all right.
And the missus?
She hasn't shown up?
I'm going to the disco.
You're so rude!
Why?
You finally came to visit
and he runs off to the disco.
Does your girlfriend yell at you
if you don't go?
I got people waiting for me.
You're afraid!
- What do I do?
- Get naked.
- Totally naked?
- Yes.
Even my singlet?
How embarrassing!
I'm going.
No, you lost the bet,
now you have to pay up.
Ready?
Tommi, come on then.
Not like that,
like you're washing a car!
You have to caress us.
Enough!
I'm sick of these dumb games.
Dad's right, you're a wuss.
I'll tell him.
Is he serious?
No way!
My big baby!
What have you done,
you're so serious?
- Stop it!
- No fighting.
Tell dad what you've done.
Stop it, you slut!
Hey!
Don't you ever say that again!
Don't cry!
Six to four!
You're a pain in the arse Tommi,
get lost!
You be the goalie, asshole.
What'd you say?
Asshole.
You wanna smack in the face?
Try it.
Moron, you're a pain in the arse!
Recess is almost over,
if you don't wanna play
at least let us play.
You're all assholes, fuck off.
Hi
I just moved to the third floor,
near those air conditioners.
- Where do you live?
- Top floor.
Cool, we live on the same stairs.
- Hi!
- Good day!
See, there are kids your age here.
Can I play with you?
Here.
Careful, you sweated a lot already.
Letizia, leave him be.
Come in when you want a snack.
What'll we play?
Let's practice our passes.
What a scare!
Poor baby!
You got slapped yesterday...
You went to their house?
Yeah, to have a snack.
What's the house like?
Huge. They got plants like trees and
a painting that covers a whole wall.
His room is full of toys.
What kind?
All kinds.
I've run into them on the stairs,
they're rich.
They put grates on their windows
that face the courtyard.
Ready!
The plateau...
The plateau for the tongeau.
Don't make that face.
Tommi
Too much!
Don't start, you'd better lick
that plate clean.
This is no time for sophisms.
What the heck are sophisms?
Lots for me.
Good girl, see she makes me happy!
Eat up.
Dad's going away for two days.
Where to?
To Bolzano to get new equipment.
As of today, daddy's his own boss.
You got a second mortgage?
Yep, I'll have it paid off soon.
Hope so.
Aren't you the optimist!
We just have to save up a bit,
avoid eating out.
We can take a cut in our allowance,
from 7 to 5 Euro.
Right, little brother?
You've already paid for swimming?
Yeah.
Don't worry, no penny pinching
to be done there.
For now,
your allowance stays at 7 Euros.
Who the hell is that at this hour?
- Shut up!
- Don't you dare.
If you tell him, I'll clobber you.
This is my seat.
Go sit near Claudio.
Get up.
He's here now, go sit near the mute.
Tommaso,
go sit back there near Claudio.
Tomorrow, dinner at the porter's.
Tonight, do what you can.
No mucking around. Your backpack!
Bye, Giuseppe.
Bye
Tell your daddy that I gave you
sausage and broccoli too.
Ok.
When does he get back?
Around 10:30.
Set your alarm.
No probs!
I wanna watch the Pele video.
Who says you get to choose?
Don't be a pain, I said it first.
Gimme a kiss, hold me, sugar pie!
I love you, hold me!
Gimme kiss.
Get off me!
Gimme a kiss!
Get the key, slave!
My babies!
Aren't you going to
give your mum a kiss?
Viola
Please, my love...
My darlings!
My heart was breaking without you.
Don't you want to go to bed?
We'll wait for dad.
Aren't you tired?
Look how your hair's grown.
This fringe?
Me and Brunella
cut each other's hair.
Who's Brunella?
A friend from dance class.
You're still doing dance? Good girl.
Don't worry, I'll talk to dad.
Yes, darling...
Here's my pride and joy!
How'd it go?
Mission accomplished.
What have you been up to?
Come in, there's a surprise.
A surprise?
You tidied up your room?
No!
Dad
Hi
Can I talk to you?
Out.
Get out!
Please Renato, let me talk.
Please, don't throw me out.
Don't throw me out.
Please, let me stay.
Don't cry.
Viola, go to your room
with your brother.
Mum came back.
Go to your room!
Don't be mean.
Stefania, I'll give you
three seconds to leave...
Out.
Please, I want to stay with you.
Don't touch me!
Get out!
Damned slut!
Goddamned slut!
I want to stay with you all.
I want to be with my babies!
You're ruining my life.
You are ruining our lives!
I've changed, I swear.
Oh, cut the crap!
Get out!
Kids, go to your room.
I can't live without you.
You can't live without us?
Say it to their faces.
Tell them where you went,
look at them,
tell them where you go to get fucked
every time you disappear
like a crook.
Tell them you'd rather be
with a wealthy piece of shit
than with that pauper, your husband.
Stop it!
You've ruined my life,
you fucking slag!
Kids, to your room, I said.
I said go!
A goddamned bitch in heat.
Put on your pyjamas and go to bed.
Viola
Kids?
Tommi
Put some clothes on
and come into the kitchen,
we have a decision to make.
Darling!
Sit down.
Last night I decided to talk
to your mother a bit,
to give her another chance
to explain herself,
even if it's happened
one too many times before.
I don't even know why,
all I know is...
Maybe I just wanted to know
what goes on in her rotten head.
I understood
that there's so much confusion
in her mixed up mind,
that she's probably
the one who needs help,
not us.
Right? You agree?
Say something! You agree?
Agree!
Stefania,
now I want you to say this,
in front of them,
if you are sure...
Sure you want
to be a mother again
instead of screwing around all over
town as you've always done?
I'm sure.
Forgive me, I'm sure.
I was wrong, I know,
forgive me for making you suffer.
Forgive me, forgive me, Renato.
Forgive me.
I've had enough of this shit!
Got it? It's on their heads!
Okay, kids...
I think she's being honest.
You're big enough to be
a part of this decision.
Do you want your mother
to come back,
or do we leave her
to take care of herself?
Dad, let her come back home, please.
Thank you, darling.
Tommi
Want mummy to take care of you,
wake you up in the morning,
make you breakfast,
and take you to school?
Honey?
Yeah.
Yes? Come here!
Thank you.
Give me your hand, thank you.
Thank you, Renato.
God help us!
I'm going to clean myself up
then make you some breakfast.
I'll come with you.
ok
No school today, though.
Figures...
No swimming lesson today either.
Anyway, she'll leave again.
I have to go to work, we'll talk later.
Why are you here?
You have class at 5:00.
You had nothing better to do!
I'm early.
You went to the pool anyway?
Good boy.
I have to get a medical certificate,
it costs 60 Euro.
Same story every year! When?
The 14th.
I can take him.
Want mummy to go with you?
Viola told me the news
about your work.
Yes...
I work for myself,
I bought the equipment
and had a chat with the bank...
You don't work with those guys?
I cut them all loose.
It's a calculated risk,
I have some important gigs lined up,
I'm closing a big job tomorrow.
Things are good.
There's a new game.
What?
It's awesome.
On PlayStation it's the best.
The graphics are cool.
Come sit here Tommaso.
Can't you see I'm sitting here?
Have a go at him!
Come in!
How cool, you came to visit!
Mum, your massage is over now.
- Tommi here.
- How are you?
Fine, thanks.
Just let me take care of this muscle.
Perfect! Come on.
I saw your sister yesterday
with a blonde lady.
Who is she?
My mother.
I thought you lived
with your sister and your dad?
She comes and goes.
Huh?
Here I am!
Ready to scrub the little cheese.
I can do it by myself.
Mummy's here now.
I'll wash your back, bend over.
Are you embarrassed?
You're hiding your willie?
I made this willie, it's mine!
Stop it!
Viola's right, you are stingy.
I'm going to do my homework.
You're leaving me here?
The male swordfish
falls in love with the female,
and when fishermen catch the female
he swims around the boat
until he's caught
because he wants to
stay with the female.
Then there's the Orang-utan.
He only falls in love to reproduce.
Afterwards,
he takes a piece of forest
and stays there all alone.
I included humans too,
because men and women
are the only ones
who don't approach one
another out of shyness.
See you tomorrow.
Dad
Where were you all afternoon?
At Antonio's.
You're always at his house!
Your mum just got back,
spend some time with her,
show her some affection.
Keeping this family together
depends on you too.
I'm working in a nice place Saturday,
you're all coming with me.
Will you honour us
with your presence?
Thanks
Here.
Can I carry this?
Yes
What's the camel for?
It's a sort of fake desert.
How are you, Flaviano?
I heard you took the plunge.
Let's recapitulate,
it's getting late.
We'll start with the car, it leaves,
we follow it beyond the camel
until it exits the scene.
That's it. Ready.
Silence!
Tommi, come here.
Alberto, a suggestion,
I'd start with the animal's snout,
because the camel is lovely,
then pan to the car.
No, start with the car, follow it,
then show the camel
but keep following the car.
I'll do a lead-in on the camel,
you can always cut it.
The camel's terrific
but we need the car.
Gimme a drink.
You look awesome!
The director doesn't know shit.
Can we ride the camel after?
We'll see.
Mum, I want to ride it with you.
ok
Everyone in place, rolling.
All right.
How about that shot we decided upon?
Look how amazing
this animal's snout is!
Just try this shot...
We get the idea, you like the camel,
but we need the car!
Look at the snout from this angle,
let's do it!
Let me do it, it won't take long,
you can cut it after.
We don't care about the camel's head.
The car, did I make myself clear?
Shoot the fucking car.
Calm down, I understand!
Do I have to get pissed off?
You just have to respect the people
who work for you!
Fine, let's do this car!
Who is this?
Who is he?
Renato Benetti, cameraman.
Mr. Benetti is costing us time,
the only thing he does
is harp about the camel shot!
We'll take care of it.
Start the car.
What's going on with the steadycam?
It's leaving.
Let's stop for a drink,
they'll call me
and beg me to come back.
They'll never find
another steadycam in time.
If they apologize,
maybe we'll go back.
Why was that guy such an arsehole?
He didn't want him
to shoot the camel.
They think everyone's willing
to let themselves be walked over.
Not Renato Benetti.
Take a guess...
What are you saying? No!
I don't know yet.
I can't talk now,
I'll call you tomorrow.
Who was it?
Livia.
You still hear from her?
Well, she's is our neighbour!
I ran into her at the supermarket.
Supermarket?
Yes
I see.
We've waited long enough,
time's up.
If they make problems for me,
I'll talk to the Union.
Half-wit, half...
Don't worry, baby.
You did the right thing,
he's lucky you didn't smack him.
Everything's fine.
What a moron!
This place is nice.
Yeah, real nice.
Ma'am?
Yes?
Do you have rooms available?
Anything you'd like,
two adjoining rooms?
Perfect, we'll stay.
Thanks.
We're sleeping here? How cool!
Can we go to the beach?
Go ahead, we'll be right there.
70 Euro for mum and dad's room,
70 for ours, that's 140 Euro!
He's such a scrooge!
Can't see a thing.
What do you think they're doing?
Sleeping.
Making love, stupid!
Wanna play a game?
Which?
Fuck off!
Look up.
What lovely eyes!
Just like your mother's.
Open your mouth.
Tongue out.
You can get dressed.
Has he had all the usual illnesses?
Mumps...
Mumps? Yes, remember Tommi?
Chickenpox?
Chickenpox, no.
Little red bumps...
No.
Yes, I had it,
but you weren't there.
I scratched and it left a scar.
Course I was there!
I just forgot, silly me.
Were you scared?
A bit.
I was hungry.
Why didn't you have dinner?
You don't love me anymore, do you?
Why don't you love me?
I wanted to take you with me.
Know what your father said?
That if I tried to,
he'd shoot me in the mouth.
You mustn't judge me.
I was young when I got pregnant.
One baby after the other,
I felt like a cow.
I didn't want to
dump everything on Renato.
Honey, come to mommy.
You know what's important?
That I'm here now
and I'm not going to leave again,
I won't leave you again.
Your head hurts?
Yes
As usual, you know I'm a bit fragile,
like Renato says.
Want a massage?
Really?
You'll give me a massage?
Thanks
What a dear.
"She was proud yet resentful
of her husband's betrayals,
mercilessly pursuing
his lovers and their children."
Claudio,
do you feel like reading?
Tommi
"Poseidon, Zeus' brother,
and god of the sea,
dwelled in an underwater palace
where he bred..."
Benetti's mother would like
to speak to you.
Right now?
Excuse me, morning.
I've come for my son, where is he?
Over there!
Did something happen?
I need to take him with me.
Now?
You know I've been away
for such a long time...
We're in class now,
we meet with parents on Thursday.
- Great.
I'd be glad to talk to you then,
Thursday afternoon.
Can I take him with me?
Do I have to sign anything?
Yes. Luciano will you show her
to the office?
Ok.
Tommaso, gather your things and go.
Isn't this girl adorable!
I've got something for you,
share them with the others.
See you tomorrow, Tommaso.
Goodbye.
Thank you.
What's going on?
I kidnapped you to spend
time alone together, happy?
Yes.
Where are we going?
You decide.
You can skip
your swimming lesson today.
Who's going to tell dad?
I will.
It's closed?
Unbelievable!
Nobody's here. Excuse me!
Why's everything closed?
We open at 3:00.
Fantastic!
Should we wait or take a drive?
We could wait.
Let's go over there.
There's a lake with ducks, remember?
They like it, come on over!
Tommi
Give them some crackers.
They love crackers! Taking a dip?
I want to take them home!
No fighting.
You come with me.
Take out what you were
working on last lesson
Mind if I sit here?
Yes
What are you making?
I'm not sure yet.
I'm making a vase for dried flowers.
You're sweet for
being nice to Claudio.
I like him.
Tommi and Monica
are going out with one another!
Go back to kindergarten!
What fools! You're more mature.
Are you shy?
No
Can I do something?
Yes
Now it looks like a dolphin.
I LOVE YOU
Marcella, where are the students?
At gym or ceramics.
Let's do the rubbish bins.
I kept pushing
but you didn't want to come out.
I cried like an hawk!
You were already a pain!
Know how much you weighed?
Four kilos.
You were like a calf!
But I didn't feel a thing with you.
Know what you did
when you came out of my tummy?
You peed on the nurse's face.
- Pisser!
- Good shot!
Good day
I was telling my kids
about when they were born.
I can't, I'm with them.
No, they'd get bored.
Where, doing what?
It's Viola.
I'll think it over and let you know.
All right.
Who was it?
Livia.
Come on, let's go.
I like it! Where?
An art exhibit.
Can we go, please?
Please, let's go!
The kids are begging to go
to the exhibit with Livia
This afternoon.
Yes, you're right,
I'll get out a bit.
Yes, sure, we'll be home by 6:00.
Excuse me.
You bugger, you never visit,
I should spank you!
You're beautiful!
Heavens, all these kids!
Antonio's a friend of Tommi's.
Good day
How you've grown!
A kiss for your godmother.
Hit the buffet.
Looks like a dolphin to me.
Looks like a lard-arse!
What imagination...
Yuck!
How can you tell?
I have great news,
my father's buying me a dog.
It's from a litter of seven.
Why don't you get one too?
You even have a big terrace,
it's perfect.
A dog, that's all we need!
Bye, darling.
You got a ticket.
Throw it away, I won't pay it anyway.
They were nice.
They're show-offs.
Why?
Don't know, they just are.
That guy is loaded.
Let go! Kids, time to eat.
So when's the swimming race?
The 27th or 29th.
Two weeks? Go, my champion!
I sat in your spot.
Come on stragglers, last sprint!
Lanes 4 and 5.
You lengthened your stroke,
bloody amazing,
you thrashed all of them!
Thrashed them...
I timed you, you thrashed them.
It's going to be a sorry race
for the others.
This is beyond football!
There's Viola.
Daddy's darling.
Hello my lovelies.
How did it go?
Fine.
Did you shake your legs,
did you do a plie?
A whatchamacallit, a chignon?
Yes, right.
I'm tired, carry it for me?
I'm not your mule!
Dad, why is Tommi such a rude pig?
I ask myself that every night.
My stomach is growling!
It's time to eat.
I'm starved.
I was freezing today at work,
they had me standing around
like a dickhead for hours.
The lights at home are all off.
The lights?
The lights are all off at home.
You see them from outside?
I'm going.
Come here.
How did you sleep?
Fine.
You slept fine...
Are you sure
you want to go to school?
Viola's sleeping,
go lie down in my bed.
No
Look Dad, I'm going.
Bye my little man, see you tonight.
Bye
Bessi,
why didn't you do the homework?
My mum broke her finger
so we went to the hospital,
we didn't get home till 9:00.
Next year you're going to be
in 6th grade again.
Geography, open up to page 52.
We'll talk about city functions:
Political and administrative,
financial, economic,
and residential.
We also discussed city changes.
We spoke about the Roman city.
- Did you write it?
- No.
He's in the bathroom.
Monica's looking for you.
For me?
Yeah, it's about the note.
Hurry, she's really mad.
He wrote it during ceramics class.
Were you looking for me?
I was kind of upset,
an anonymous note...
How was I supposed to know
you wrote it?
What note?
What do you mean? This note.
I didn't write it.
You didn't write it?
I had nothing to do with it.
They said you wrote it,
but maybe they're lying...
No
They even opened my backpack.
Well, bye.
Quiet or they'll catch us.
What's down there?
Where?
Down there.
Nothing.
Yeah, right.
You're crazy,
that's at least a 40,000 meter drop!
If my parents find out,
we're finished.
Then don't tell them.
What's this filth?
What is this filth?
You trying to kill me?
I'm not your slave,
nor your housekeeper!
What is all this shit,
this rubbish on the floor?
And Dad cleans up, you two
wash a plate once in a while.
No fucking way,
it doesn't work like this!
I've been fucked over enough times
for one lifetime,
by everybody,
now you two want to have a go at it?
Be my guests!
Sorry, Dad.
We'll be neater.
I told you to clean up
this fucking mess two hours ago.
Get ready,
I convinced Dad to go jogging.
No, I'm going to the movies
with Antonio.
Are we going?
Just me and you.
The three of us
need to stick together.
Get ready.
- Get out!
- Dad, what does it matter?
Why are you sitting there
like an idiot?
Run, we'll see
if I can turn you into a man!
Run!
Up you get champion,
today's your day.
I made you tea, milk's a bit heavy,
you know.
A royal breakfast today!
I made you an egg too,
it'll give you energy.
What time is warm up?
8:15
Want some lemon?
Marcello said you have
the third best time.
You're the favourite for the heat.
What's the regional record?
1.2.
Bet you're gonna take all of them
for a ride in the final.
What do you think?
The other day I was thinking...
Why'd I get stuck
with a girl like her?
A girl whose pussy's
always itching for more.
It's absurd!
Can you believe her?
She cries, comes crawling back
on her hands and knees:
"I've changed!"
What's changed?
What has changed?
I'm telling you this
because you're big, you understand.
Anyhow, I've always managed
to bounce back.
Eat up! Have some honey,
it gives you energy.
On the starting block,
shift your weight back,
or else you'll take forever to start.
Lean forward,
so when the race starts
you're already in the water,
they're still standing there.
Gotta go, they're in the pool.
Save some steam for the final.
They're all hopeless in your heat.
Tommi, 200m, nice and easy.
Tommi and Francesco.
I don't like swimming.
You're no son of mine.
My son wouldn't do something
like that.
Do whatever the hell you want.
Then I want to quit.
Who gives a shit!
What are you doing there?
Nothing.
Why didn't you ring?
It's early.
Antonio went to his grandma's
in Naples, she's not well,
but he'll be back tonight.
Are you home alone?
No, they're home.
I'm going to the garage
to get my fishing gear,
have you ever been fishing?
I'm Antonio's father.
I ran into Tommi on the stairs,
I asked if he wanted
to come fishing with me.
Is it all right with you
if he comes with me?
No problem.
I'll have him back tonight.
Right, no problem.
There it is!
Reel it in slowly.
Keep it tight.
Good job!
Let me pull out the hook.
How many have we caught?
This makes four.
We'll have a feast tonight!
I have to catch one more.
Why?
Antonio eats a lot.
You're right.
Here's the trout!
Dad, when we go...
to the mountains,
can we go fishing in that stream?
What stream, it's a river!
Fishing in the freezing cold?
Wouldn't it be better
to warm up a bit skiing?
Just to stand out from the crowd.
Do you like skiing?
I've never been.
It's really amazing!
It'd be nice if you came with us.
You have to, can he daddy?
You're asking me?
I'd take him everywhere!
Go to church, hypocrites!
Takes courage to accept the fact
that we're dead flesh,
decaying flesh.
A nice warm revolver
one of these days,
and we'll end it all.
There I'll be,
finally face to face with the Eternal.
The Almighty...
Almighty, my arse!
What time is it?
5:10.
Where's my jacket?
Where the hell is it?
Where is my striped jacket?
Disappeared.
I managed to get a gig in Naples.
I left 50 Euro on the table
for dance class.
Tell them I'll pay the rest next time.
Tell that wuss, your brother
to go earn money himself
for his snack. Go to bed.
I left some omelette for you.
I'm going out with Brunella,
want to come?
You're staying home alone?
Yes.
Bye, sugar.
I thought we had a deal?
Ma'am, you're making a mistake.
Allow me to say
you're making a mistake,
you won't find anyone else like me.
I'll bring the steadycam.
All right, thanks.
Dad?
What is it?
Antonio invited me on a skiing trip.
What?
Can I go away on a skiing trip?
When?
They're leaving in two days.
Are you serious?
What the fuck!
We're drowning in debt,
we're about to lose our house,
I'm up to my eyeballs in shit
and you wanna go skiing?
They're paying.
They're paying?
What the fuck are you saying?
Calm down!
Bastards, God almighty!
Traitor!
Get out of this house,
son of a bitch!
Go stay with your fucking friend!
- Sorry!
- Get out!
Get out of this house!
Fantastic! Let's go tell my mum!
Tommi's coming with us.
What great news!
Did I hear correctly?
Wonderful, aren't you happy?
No doubt!
Know what we'll do?
We'll have dinner at auntie's,
then you'll sleep over
and we'll leave early in the morning.
We'll call your dad tomorrow,
since he barely knows us.
Anyone home?
We have to remember
to pick up the other snowsuit,
so we'll have an extra one.
Already got it.
Surprised, aren't you?
I'm setting the alarm for 6:00.
No kidding!
You can bring us
breakfast in bed then.
I can't believe
we'll be in the mountains tomorrow.
Dad?
What is it?
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
My little boy!
It's all right.
Understand? It's nothing.
My boy!
I love you.
Where did I put it?
Here it is.
I went yesterday, it's a nice place.
There are two footy fields,
it's nearby.
There were tons of kids.
They were all wearing
those neon yellow thingies.
Bibs
Bibs?
Out of curiosity,
what position do you wanna play?
striker
I like sweeper.
Sweeper's a nice position.
Sweeper's good too.
But I'll sign up next year,
we already paid
for a year of swimming.
Benetti?
Your mother passed by,
she left this package.
Wake up sleepyhead, take it!
Bye!
Why didn't you go skiing
for the winter break?
Because I didn't.
MY LOVE, MOMMY'S ALWAYS WITH YOU.
YOU'RE THE ONLY MAN IN MY LIFE.
I'M NOT WELL,
BUT ONE DAY
I'LL EXPLAIN.
I LOVE YOU.