Subtitles brought to you by the Love Chocolate Team @Viki
Episode 79
I promised you
a romantic proposal.
Hence,
I especially chose this ring out.
I never thought that
it would be under a situation like this.
It's okay, it's not important.
It is important.
You are very important to me.
Are you willing to accept this ring?
Are you willing to accept my heart?
Subtitles brought to you by the Love Chocolate Team @Viki
In the name of God, Mr. Fang Jia Hua
and Miss Hong Xi En, I now pronounced you...
man and wife.
Congratulations on finding your eternal happiness.
Congratulations on fulfilling your wish.
Right now it is time for me to find my happiness.
To find someone who will love and
cherish me forever
Subtitles brought to you by the Love Chocolate Team @Viki
Mr. Fang.
We are now family.
Close family?
Let me tell you in advance first.
If Chocolate were to bully Xi En, I will discipline him like my own son.
This is necessary.
Thank you.
Next time it's you guys.
Not necessarily. You guys might be before us.
Impossible!
Jia Hua. Take good care of Xi En.
After you guys leave you always have to be careful.
Remember to call if there are any matters.
That's not important. They are already adults.
What's important then?
HAVE CHILDREN AS SOON AS POSSIBLE!
Did you hear that? We have to have a son, who knows
how to make chocolate.
Boss.
Boss!
He didn't go overseas.
Sorry but the number you have dialed has
no reply so they cannot be reached. Thank you.
- Xi Hui. What's wrong?
- Have you guys seen my boss?
No he hasn't come here.
What's the matter?
He lied and said he went abroad for business.
I'm worried that for the sake of protecting us, he may have gone to perform some illegal task for Zhao Hai Feng.
Hurry up and return home.
I'm going to look for Hai Feng and ask him.
How can you? I'm going too!
No. It's too dangerous.
It's because it's dangerous, we should go together.
But Boss won't be happy if you go.
Hence, in any case, if you go, he won't be happy.
If we go, he won't be happy too.
Why don't we do this? Let's all go together.
Then promise me you won't be rash and irrational.
We are just going to ask him some questions ok?
Okay.
What are you doing? Field trip?
Isn't it too late?
Where is Boss?
Lovely, just because your boss isn't here you think you can
become the hero?
Actually it's not enough. Keep training, baby.
Hey!
Wow.
You switch sides so fast.
Stop your crap. Where is my boss?
Do you have THE RIGHT TO SPEAK?
Are you going to tell us or not?
Why are you asking me? Who do I ask then? This is a pool place.
Or you've been in love with me for a while now?
Just another excuse.
Hey! Are you going to tell us or not?
Move back.
Boss is calling you, right?
So what if it is? So what if it's not?
Tell me where he is now! I want to see him!
How would I know?
I don't understand you.
Lu Zheng Ting pushed you away so frantically and asked you not to stick with us
but you choose to dig deeper.
You know you're a busybody?
But honestly speaking I still have to thank you.
If not for you how would he listen to me?
Maybe you think that women are useless.
But just like how men can sacrifice for loyalty, women can also sacrifice for love.
If you let him get harmed, I WON'T LET YOU GO!
So sweet, right, baby?
What can you do?
Not only her, but us too.
If you dare to touch a single hair on his head,
we won't forgive you.
Did I ask you to move, go back.
Hurry home, little girl. Don't waste Lu Zheng Ting's efforts.
"You have been transferred to the voicemail box. Charges will apply after the 'beep' sound. If you do not wish to..."
Boss it's me, I know Hai Feng just called.
But could you tell me your location. I want to see you.
I know you want to protect us and protect my feelings.
But right now you're making me worried and
only harming me even more.
Because of me you did a lot of things you didn't
want to do.
You even wore the shirt I gave you.
I beg to promise me one thing: let me be by your side ok?
Press 4 to replay. Press 7 to delete..
I just phoned and ask, and they said he's not there.
Where exactly is he?
I think I saw Boss just now.
Didn't he say he went abroad?
But I really saw his car.
There are so many types of car.
Of course, there are lots of the same type of cars out there. Impossible, he has already gone overseas.
All of you, go back first. I will think of a solution.
Hey, Sister Xi Hui!
What should we do?
What are you thinking of?
I'm wondering if I'm dreaming now.
Do you want me
to hit you to make sure that you are not dreaming?
Home violence the first day we got married. That isn't good.
If Father Hong,
finds out, he will be very sad.
My mom would probably feel sad
but my dad
did asked me secretly
if I brought the scissors.
Really? You really brought it along?
What do you think?
Impossible. You wouldn't bear to use it.
My dad just gave me a big bag of things.
What do you think they are for? Let's look.
Computer keyboard.
That's great.
And also a pair of scissors.
Give this to me.
Do you still remember what I said?
Every time you do something wrong,
you have to be punished with 50 push-ups
and kneel thirty minutes on the keyboard.
And also sleep on the sofa for 18 days.
You don't need a tool for push-ups.
We already have the keyboard. The sofa is over there so...
Does it count tonight?
Tonight is our matrimonial night.
There isn't anyone to mess up our night.
There's only the both of us.
Because it's between the two of us,
you better consider this over carefully.
We are already married.
You don't need to be that calculative.
Nowadays, the assets of the parents
can be split.
If this is the case, I should be calculative.
The money that you owed me can be not counted.
But
this debt has to be counted.
The chocolate order.
I want to change products.
The chocolate before was spoiled.
After eating that,
I was so upset.
Hence, my request now
I want a complete
chocolate without any flaws.
Don't worry.
The Chocolate who is in front of you now,
is guaranteed complete,
without any flaws.
- Really?
- Yes.
Although sometimes,
it may include impurities,
or make you angry,
but I guarantee that I will not leave you again.
I will stay by your side forever.
I swear that.
Okay.
Looking at how sincere you are,
I'll accept it.
But...
if you make me sad,
I would be letting myself down if I don't punish you.
Okay.
If you want to punish me,
just punish me.
Subtitles brought to you by The Love Chocolate Team@Viki
I would be letting myself down if I don't punish you.
Okay.
If you want to punish me,
just punish me.
Okay. Just do according to what I said.
50 push-ups, kneel on the keyboard for 30 mins
and sleep on the sofa for 18 days. Starting now.
Can I not do it?
Is there any other option?
Yes.
Then, you must
devote your lifetime
be with me
and take care of me forever.
Which option do you want?
Of course, I choose this.
What are you doing?
Quieter. What if you wake up the other hotel guests?
I'm on my honeymoon!
Chocolate!
Hong Xi Hui.
Where is Boss?
What are you doing?
You have been acting strange lately?
I didn't see you after the wedding is over. Where did you go?
Dad. You know where Boss is, right?
What are you talking about?
You know that Boss didn't go overseas.
You also know what he's going to do, right?
How would I know? I don't know anything at all.
I'm telling you.
I'm not that close with him.
Dad. Don't help Boss to hide matters from me, okay?
I'm really very worried that something could happen to him.
I have been looking for him the whole night.
I really don't know where else can I find him
What's going on?
Mom!
Xi Hui, be good. Don't cry.
Dear. What's going on?
Why is she crying so early in the morning?
Don't cry. Tell me now.
Aiyoh, dear.
She... Okay, I will talk.
I really only know a bit.
Lu Zheng Ting told me that he and that
police are going to join forces.
He is going undercover to Hai Feng
and together with the police,
catch the bad guys.
I knew it!
Xi Hui!
- Dear, be careful.
- Don't bother about me.
- Go after her now.
- Okay.
Xi Hui!
This child...
Dear. Go after her. What if she goes missing?
What should we do?
Don't worry. Now that she knows he didn't go overseas,
she will definitely go and look for him.
She will be back soon.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
You...
I haven't even open my mouth, why are you so noisy?
Yes, Boss.
Hong Xi Hui. You miss me that much?
If not...
Cut your crap. Take me to see Boss!
You are getting even more arrogant.
Why don't you do this? Leave Lu Zheng Ting,
come to me and assist me?
Take me to him.
What I want you to do is very simple.
Tomorrow the boat will come from this direction
and throw the bag later into the sea.
Go into the water and help me to retrieve the bag.
There will be two person to take over.
That's it?
Don't be so boring, okay?
The fish this time is very fat.
I can travel the world after this.
The both us can not keep in contact after that.
Hopefully you will keep your word this time.
Of course.
Oh yes, to express my kindness
I brought someone here.
to express my kindness
Hai Feng. You...
It's not me.
She came here voluntarily.
Xi Hui.
I brought her here with sincerity with any damage done to her.
What happens next depends on your performance.
Your girlfriend really has guts.
If you don't want her, I will.
Zhao Hai Feng...
Okay, okay, okay.
I'm only just joking.
Do you know how it feels to have someone suddenly disappear?
Why do you force me to feel this way again and again?
I have no news of you and I can't find you.
You cause to be frantic and scared.
I didn't dare to sleep the whole night!
I have been looking and waiting for you.
I waited till I was scared.
Sorry, Xi Hui.
Xi Hui
I really have no idea what other ways to keep you by my side.
I beg you not leave me again okay?
Stay with me.
The food will be here soon.
So scrumptious.
Did you wonder why there is a kitchen in this suite?
You personally cooked this?
- If not, then.
- Really? Is it cooked all the way?
Please.
I used a small fire, added it with my fiery passion
and cooked it.
I guarantee that it's cooked
and it's filled with sweetness(love).
It will definitely be very delicious.
What?
Since I did so much for you,
give me a kiss, quick.
Come and give me a kiss.
Stop fooling around. Let's eat.
There is no wine opener.
I seem to have one in my bag.
Thanks.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I just wanted to say that
this plane ticket is for one.
This plane ticket, giving it to someone
or sell it online
is hard.
Why are you selling it?
Use it for yourself.
What are you talking about? We are already married.
I'm Mrs. Fang now.
I have to take care of my husband.
Xi En.
I'm very happy that you married me.
I'm not going to plan your future.
You finally got this opportunity.
You should treasure this
and use it.
But I don't want to be apart from you.
I didn't say that we will be apart.
When you go to Paris to study how to make chocolates,
I will go with you.
Do you mean it?
Don't forget that
both of us originally wanted to take part in the Chocolate competition together.
We both shared the same dream.
What?
I can give it to you now.
Your eyes are very swollen.
Do you need an ice pack to bring it down?
No.
Do I look ugly?
I saw it when you looked even terrible.
For example,
your ugly eating looks.
I was careless.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
This is the second time that we are having a meal together.
It's the first time.
This is our first time that
we are having a meal together.
We will have many such opportunities in the future, right?
Yes. there will be.
Here.
What?
You are really going to Paris?
Dad, what's wrong? Is Paris very far away?
Of course, it's very far away. It's on the other side of the globe.
Dad.
This is a hard-to-come-by opportunity for me.
It would be a pity if I don't go.
You are right but...
it's for two years.
Don't worry.
Chocolate will be going with me.
He will take care of me.
Of course, he has to take care of you. He's your husband. If he doesn't take care of you,
who would?
Chocolate will be with her.
What are you worried about?
You didn't hear what I just said.
It's for two years.
I won't be able to see my Princess for two years.
I can't bear to do that.
Dad, let me tell you.
You don't have to worry.
Technology is very advanced now.
There is video chat.
We can see each other and talk every day.
It's not like I don't know.
But it doesn't feel real.
Xi En and Chocolate
are also working hard for their future.
As parents,
we should support them.
Dad, it's okay.
I will keep you company.
Haru, too. Isn't that so, Haru?
Okay, I know.
This can't be helped.
But Xi En,
You must tell Chocolate
that I said
he must take good care of you.
He must not let you suffer at all.
If not,
tell him that I'm sharpening the scissor every day.
When he comes back, I will cut him.
Okay.
Answer it.
Hello.
Father Hong, it's me.
Mom. I'm not going home today.
Don't worry.
Nothing will happen to Xi Hui.
Okay.
I know.
I won't let Boss do any dangerous tasks.
I will be careful. Thanks, Father Hong.
Okay, I know.
- Do you want juice?
- I'll sleep alone.
Dad.
Mom.
What's wrong with you both?
Nothing.
After talking on the phone,
your expressions turned strange. What's wrong?
Did I?
I already told you that it's nothing.
I have cleared the table.
Okay, take a break first.
I will do the dishes.
What's wrong?
I'm afraid that you will disappear.
You are going to watch me doing the dishes?
Why don't I do the dishes...
No need. It's okay.
Don't make it so hard on yourself.
Just treat it as an atonement for my sins
Take a break. I will be done soon.
What's wrong?
I'm just watching over you and not even hindering you.
Jia Hua. You just got married to Xi En
and you are going to live in Paris now. How can I bear to see you go?
Granny. I can't bear to leave too but if we don't go now,
I'm afraid that Xi En won't get used to the environment there.
Mom.
It's good that they have their own opinions.
But...
Do you have any plans when you go with Xi En?
I'm going to study chocolates with Xi En and at the same time, study retail management.
Retail management?
Are you saying that you will join our company when you are back?
Dad. I only just want to learn new things.
Maybe see if there's any business oportunity
and let Jia Rui consider.
You don't have to worry about Jia Rui and the company.
Okay.
I won't force you again. Go and do whatever you want to do.
Jia Hua.
When you are living overseas, there are many things that are inconvenient for you to buy.
I have prepared some stuff for you to bring over.
Remember that
the both of you must be very careful when you are out there.
You must take special care of Xi En.
Also,
if you lack anything wherever you go,
call home immediately. I will send them over.
I know.
Thanks, mom.
What did you call me?
Pei Long.
Did you hear that?
Jia Hua called me mom.
I'm sorry
for being immature.
In the past, I...
thought that by doing this
it would be better for everyone.
I was wrong.
Please forgive me for giving you a hard time.
Don't cry anymore. You won't look pretty when you cry.
Jia Rui said this too.
You are going overseas.
What about the chocolates for my 13 year old Jia Hua?
I have already sent it to him.
Really?
Was he happy when you gave it to him?
Very happy.
Furthermore, I also met his girlfriend.
Girlfriend?
My Jia Hua is only 13 years old.
He already has a girlfriend?
Then, what does she looks like?
- She looks exactly like Xi En.
- Xi En?
She must be pretty.
Very pretty.
A good person
but she's fierce.
Would Jia Hua be bullied by her?
Don't worry. She won't do that.
From the look of it, that girl really likes him.
Your son is very good looking.
Of course.
That's good then.
Master, I have to trouble you with the shop and Sister Hao.
Don't worry. Whatever you want to tell me, Chocolate has already told me.
Continue to study well.
Jia Yi and I will be here waiting for you both to come home.
Thank for sending the chocolates to Jia Hua.
I will definitely think of you.
I will think of you too.
Can you hug me for a while?
Subtitles brought to you by the Love Chocolate Team @Viki
Mom.
You must take good care of yourself.
Here's your fruit juice.
I want to drink coffee.
Aren't you afraid that you won't be able to sleep?
I'm not afraid.
It's because I don't want to sleep in case you leave when I sleep.
Not every one can keep awake by drinking coffee.
It's okay for me.
I'm very sensitive to coffee. Just one cup and I can stay awake for the whole night.
Don't worry, I won't.
You always say this. Saying nothing will happen to me.
In the end something always happens.
- Okay.Watch television with me.
- Okay.
Sorry, Xi Hui.
This is the last time.
I don't want you to get involved in
a world not for you just because of me.
Just say that I'm selfish.
Boss!
All the stuff that you need is already here.
And the things I need are in the ocean.
Retrieve that for me and we will be squared off.
Zhao Hai Feng conned Boss into going into the water.
I'm afraid that his life will be in danger. What should we go?
Brother, where are you?
Brother!
Subtitles brought to you by the Love Chocolate Team @Viki