What's the problem?
You know what's the problem.
It is nice. Rhythmic.
I don't like it.
It unstrings me.
Why not work with something
more... pop?
You're not ready for something
more pop.
If you really want to know what the real
problem is, I'm going to tell you.
The problem is
you don't trust me.
The problem is...
you believe I'm not yet ready
for something more pop while I am.
If you raise your voice
to me again...
I'll take a juggling club
to smash your head.
And, then, I'll break
your arms and legs.
And then you won't be able
to work with "something more pop".
In fact, you won't be able
to work with anything at all.
Either rock or fox-trot,
either latin or whatever.
I know very well when one
is ready for pop.
I'm sorry.
You know very well when one
is ready for pop.
What's your name?
Mary.
Mary or Maria?
How do they usually call you?
- Mary.
- I'm going to call you Maria.
Have you got any
brothers and sisters?
No.
Maria, you have been badly hit.
The chances of dying
are high.
If I asked you now to pick
an actor, whom you'd say?
Who's your favorite?
Well, I'll tell you names.
If I find it, wave to me.
Brad Pitt.
No?
Johnny Depp?
What? Not even Johnny Depp?
We've brought a young girl,
around 16 years old.
Car accident. Internal
haemorrhage, broken ribs.
She plays tennis.
Maybe for several years, cause
her racket was quite lightweight.
Was she taken to surgery?
Yes.
- Any relatives?
- Her parents are notified.
Where's she going to?
To room 205.
OK.
She has no brothers or sisters.
Her favorite actor is Jude Law.
OK.
Brown-haired? Blonde? Brunette?
Dark brown, though her head
was covered in blood...
I think, dark brown.
- Do you want some coffee?
- Yes.
- There's inside.
- Shall I take your cup?
Only for today.
Tomorrow, I'll bring mine.
What's yours like?
I'm asking for not to mess it
with another that looks alike.
Blue with red letters.
What's written on it?
"Los Angeles".
No, there's no other like it.
In these occasions
you need stay calm...
however hard it's what I'm saying.
- Have you got any other kids?
- No.
Everything's going to be all right.
She'll make it.
She seems a tough nut to crack.
She's a sportswoman.
She plays tennis.
That's very good.
I play tennis too.
I've surely suffered an injury
that held me back...
but for the last two years
I'm getting better.
My wife is a former
tennis champion.
I don't want you to worry.
We're going to do everything we can.
You're daughter is going
to be all right.
She'll come back to the tennis court
sooner than you may realize.
And you won't even remember
all this.
I want you to make me a favor.
This is her favorite wristband.
She used to wear it
in every match.
I want you to give it to her.
It will give her strength.
I don't know if it's allowed
to wear it.
There's no problem.
You may give it yourself to her
whenever you see her.
Thank you.
Hi, dad.
You're late.
It's just five minutes to ten.
It's 10:10!
- There was heavy traffic.
- I was worried.
I'm sorry.
I don't mind that you're being late.
Just warn me about.
I'm sorry.
I go to bed.
Do you want me for something else?
Tomorrow it's going to rain.
Take your jacket with you.
OK.
Good night.
Today is a special day.
As you know, we've been long
looking for a good-sounding
and suitable name for our team.
After a lot of thought, I ended up...
...to the name "Alps".
Alps?
Yes, Alps.
Why Alps?
Alps, for two important reasons.
The first one...
it doesn't by any means reveal
what exactly we are doing.
And the second one is purely
symbolic.
No other mountain can stand in
for the mountains of the Alps.
Anything else would be smaller
and less imposing. Therefore...
...a poor substitute.
What is amazing with
the mountains of the Alps is...
that while can not be
replaced by any other...
they can stand in for
all the others.
Who could mind seeing in
the place of Ararat
or Mount McKinley...
the Alps?
Would you mind?
Neither could I.
Besides, I will take the name
of the highest mountain of the Alps...
which is called Mont Blanc.
What about us?
You may choose names among
the smaller mountains.
Do you know them?
Monte Roza, Dom...
Weisshorn, Matterhorn...
Finsteraarhorn...
Aletschhorn...
Barre des Ecrins...
Gran Paradiso,
Piz Bernina and one more.
Weissmies.
I've printed copies for you.
I'd like to take Matterhorn.
That's good.
Why?
It reminds my father.
When I was very small,
we had gone there for excursion.
Where to?
- Matterhorn!
- In Switzerland?
At the foot of the mountain.
Good evening.
Good evening. Just a moment.
I'm coming.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening.
- Take a seat.
- Thank you.
I've brought you the list you asked
and the photo.
Very nice.
- Don't you have a closer one?
- Unfortunately no.
- A captain.
- A captain of the merchant navy.
These are sub-lieutenant’s badges.
The photo is old.
I couldn't find
a more recent one.
He used to wear glasses.
I couldn't find them.
But you have to.
I'm going to look over again.
We can't replace them with others.
It wouldn't be plausible.
I'm going to look over again.
Zachos.
Yes.
Any relation with the chop-house
in Varkiza?
No, no. It's just a coincidence.
Did you know each other for years?
We were friends for about 20 years.
From higher school.
Cause of death?
Heart failure.
Favorite food?
Not something special.
Maybe he liked spaghetti
a bit more.
Plain spaghetti?
- With tomato sauce.
- Alla Napoletana.
Yes, alla Napoletana
Don't get upset.
He was using very frequently the word
"yet", before any sentence.
That is, he was saying "yet,
today it's very windy".
Or "yet, see you later."
Or "yet, today it's too cold."
Got it.
Favorite foreign actor?
It was Morgan Freeman.
He liked going to the movies alone.
He went to see all his movies.
He was usually going alone.
Is it too small?
- Yes.
- I think so, too.
We'll have it remade.
Is it that your hair is too thick?
No, it's not that.
My friend had no hair.
- Does this bother you?
- No.
I don't think so. No.
Very nice.
If he wore glasses,
he would be completely different.
I'll look again.
I'll find them.
- You have to.
- I'll do it.
Hello!
Darling, Anna came.
My beloved friend.
Come on. Take a seat.
What a pleasant surprise!
I wasn't expecting you.
- I missed you.
- I missed you, too.
Anything you want? Some tea?
- Tea.
- Good.
- Come on.
- Thank you.
How are you?
- I'm fine.
- I'm glad to hear it.
Hello there.
How are you, Anna?
It is so long.
We've admittedly missed you.
I'm all right.
- Isn't it a fine day, today?
- Indeed.
I go to the office.
I've some important business.
- Will you be late?
- Yes, I'll be back very late at night.
Good! I'll make your
favorite food.
Schnitzel with mashed potatoes?
Perfect!
I don't know what I could do
without him.
You're very lucky.
- Do you want me to read for you?
- Yes. I'd like it.
A book or a magazine?
A magazine.
"Fashion trends of the Summer"
"Gianfranco Ferre:
The King Is Naked."
"Trip to Guatemala:
Exotic and unknown."
- "Interview: Winona Ryder."
- This one!
"Tell me how do you
start your day?"
"If I'm not working, I get up
around ten o' clock...
and prepare a cup of tea.
Then, I sit down and read
NY Times.
For the rest of the morning
I make my phone calls...
and arrange several tasks.
When I am in Los Angeles...
some times, I take a long walk
around my house...
either to refresh myself
or in the evening to relax."
I've got a surprise for you.
Close your eyes.
Do you like it?
Isn't it awesome?
Sorry.
It's amazing
we've become friends.
Would you like me to sit next
to you to talk just for a while?
I want you to know that whatever
you have to say to me,
I won't say a word to your parents.
It's going to stay between us.
Are you possibly pregnant?
Don't get upset!
After all, you are too young
to have a child.
You got a lot of time
ahead of you.
Now, you must focus
in your homework and tennis.
I also want you to know
that if you were pregnant
you shouldn't dye your hair.
It's too dangerous.
Besides, your natural color
is very nice.
It's dark brown, isn't it?
What happened?
Nothing.
I couldn't say something
I had to.
What was that you couldn't say it?
"Grandpa look here a nice cup
for your coffee or your tea."
And Grandpa, what did he do?
He got upset.
And you?
Me? Nothing.
I left.
Don't speak to Mont Blanc about it.
Please.
He won't give me the girl with the
car accident, if you speak to him about.
You're the King of the coaches.
You're the best...
You're the best coach
in the world.
It is impossible not to say it.
I'm sorry.
It is wonderful!
Is it cold?
No, not at all.
Come out now. It's getting late.
We have to leave.
Just a little longer.
Please. A little longer.
All right.
Cold is a word
but winter swimmers don't know it.
It's an odd fate that you can not
eat ice-cream.
Because of your diabetes.
But you hate chocolate anyway.
I would have a different flavor
like strawberry
which is my favorite.
There's no point to talk about it.
The doctor was quite clear on it.
You're right.
How about a walk on the beach?
That's a wonderful idea!
Light fittings fall into
three main categories.
Domestic interior, domestic exterior
and professional.
Then, there are various
subcategories...
such as ceiling lamps...
shade lamps, wall lamps...
modern chandeliers,
classic chandeliers...
rack-lighting, uplighters...
spotlights, pendant lamps
and floor lamps.
Repeat them back to me.
Wall lamps, ceiling lamps...
classic chandeliers,
modern chandeliers...
uplighters...
floor lamps, table lamps....
And pendant lamps.
Uplighters...
and uplighters...
Once more in the evening.
This evening we have a ball.
- What types of dances do you dance?
- Various.
Blues, tango, waltz...
And latin?
And latin.
- Nice.
- Will you come?
I will come.
Are you ready?
Now.
Your daughter lost in
the most important...
...the most important match
of her life.
I'm very sorry.
My condolences.
Nonetheless, keep in mind...
death is not the end.
On the contrary.
It is a new,
often a better start.
Your daughter fought hard
but the opponent was stronger.
She was a remarkable person
that everybody will remember.
I'm sure about that.
And now, I got something
very pleasing to tell you.
I myself can replace her
if you want it.
You're grief will ease
and after a while...
will disappear completely.
A couple of two-hours visits
a week are enough.
The end can be a new,
better start.
It's up to you.
For the first four visits
you won't be charged.
"Grandpa look here a nice cup
for your coffee or tea."
As soon as Granma sees it,
she will surely feel jealous.
but never mind...
because I bought her a gift too,
this wallet here...
which has a coin compartment
and a photo holder.
"Grandpa, look here a nice cup
for your coffee or your tea."
The girl with the car accident
is getting much better
and doctors say that she
has overcome the danger.
They speak of a miracle.
What a pity.
Indeed.
Again.
"Grandpa, look here a nice cup
for your coffee or tea."
As soon as Granma sees it, she
will surely feel jealous but...
never mind because I bought her
as a gift this wallet
which has a coin compartment
and a photo holder.
However, you lost a great deal
by not coming.
It was wonderful and the view
from the room was amazing.
You won't be paid this month.
I'll keep your money.
Repeat and clearer.
"Grandpa, look here a nice cup
for your coffee or tea."
As soon as Granma sees it, she
will surely feel jealous...
but never mind because
I bought her too...
What's the matter with her?
She made a mistake.
Has it happened before?
This is the second time.
With the grandpa again.
The man who cut my hair for the
last twelve years died yesterday.
He had no relatives.
I went to the hair salon
today and he was not there.
He was the only one
to cut my hair. No one else.
He was always taking care of my side-burns
to be at the exact same length.
Both of them.
- Are they now at the same length?
- Don't know.
They're not.
I've not gone for a long time.
I never fixed an appointment
without him being there.
I was on any occasion arranging it
when he was there.
- Are you going to attend the funeral?
- No.
- Why?
- I don't go to funerals.
- How did he die?
- Heart failure.
You danced very nice.
Thank you very much.
Your escort was amazing too.
We always dance together.
Do you know each other
for a long time?
Almost five months.
Do you like her?
She's very likeable.
What's the time?
I didn't know you are
so good a dancer.
We used to dance
with your mother as well.
Save for latin.
She hated latin.
You should always tie
your hair back.
- These are not tennis shoes!
- I see.
What is your shoe size?
Thirty-eight or thirty-nine.
As the case may be.
This is incredible.
This is perfectly fit to me.
Incredible.
That's her perfume, "Eternity".
It was a gift by her boyfriend.
You have to meet him someday.
I was quite sure
I will drive her off.
I knew it.
Her reverse forehand was lousy...
I knew it right from the start
she was hopeless!
Do you want some water?
No, dad. Thanks.
You usually drink a plenty
of water after the match.
It's OK. Thank you.
Bite your nails a bit.
That's enough.
I like last replacement a lot.
- The blind one?
- Yes.
She lost her vision at an old age.
She hasn't ever told me how.
She's a beautiful woman
with vivid colors.
What do you mean "vivid colors"?
Green eyes, light brown hair.
A peculiar combination.
I go to her house,
in Athens center,
a maisonette with yard.
She hasn't much furniture
not to stumble.
- We sit and I play her husband.
- Yes, I know.
And I tell her stories for hours.
She likes them a lot.
Whatever comes to mind.
Sometimes, she asks me
to kiss her.
And we kiss.
- Do you like her.
- I like her a lot.
I'm having fun.
I mean, do you like
your kissing.
Yes, I like it.
She's an active woman.
Imagine you were blind.
You couldn't do rhythmic gymnastics.
Get out of here. Collect your things
from home and leave.
Go back to Toronto,
go wherever you like...
so long as I will
never see you again.
Fuck you. You are so controlling.
You make me miserable.
I'm only thinking of your health,
idiot!
But I don't care any more. Leave and
then eat all the cakes and all the deserts you like.
I will leave.
Get out of my sight.
I don't want to see you again.
Get out of here. Collect your things
from home and leave!
Go back to Toronto,
go wherever you like
so long as I will
never see you again.
Fuck you. You are so controlling.
You make me miserable.
I'm only thinking of your health!
But I don't care any more. Leave and
then eat all the cakes and all the deserts you like.
I will leave.
Get out of my sight!
I don't wanna see you again!
I'm sorry. I love you.
I love you too.
I'm only hard on you
for your own good.
I know.
If Mont Blanc learns about,
there will be a problem.
Our collaboration may be over.
He won't learn anything.
I for one won't tell him
anything.
Let your blouse.
Take off your skirt.
- The pantyhose?
- Take off the pantyhose, too.
Try not to speak loud.
To be nearly inaudible.
There will only be a moment
when you are going to say
"Please, please don't you stop."
It feels like heaven."
That's it.
Please, don't you stop!
It feels like paradise.
Heaven!
Please!
Don't you stop!
It feels like heaven!
Please, don't you stop!
He said we are never going
to work with something more pop.
- Why?
- Don't know.
But I can't stand it any more.
What you were about to do
it was completely immature.
You're a very good gymnast
and it would be a shame to die.
I'm going to speak to him.
Thank you, Monte Roza.
You imagine that's very difficult
for him to step back.
But there's nothing to lose
giving a try.
Do you want any specific
piece of music?
There are two pieces
for me to choose.
I'll do anything you want.
Let her work with a piece that
is more pop and I'll do anything.
- Anything I want?
- Anything you want.
Think about it.
I thought it over.
- Tell me.
- Come closer inside.
- Come on, Ok?
- Yes.
How could you do it? With my husband?
You, my best friend!
I hate you both.
Shame on you!
Get out the way!
You have a nice body.
You, too.
- Are you getting cold?
- No, not in the least.
I've turned the heat on
but it's a bit slow to warm up.
I don't mind.
Dad, want to dance with me?
Not right now.
Some other time.
- In the evening?
- In the evening.
- You promise me.
- I do.
I have to leave.
Stay a little longer, please.
All right.
I say not waiting for her.
She probably won't come
Agree. She's too late.
Who's first?
May I go?
A man or a woman?
A man.
I keep waiting for a while.
- I don't know.
- Neither do I.
- It's Prince.
- Who?
Prince.
You can't replace Prince.
- Why?
- Prince hasn't died yet.
- Prince has died.
- Prince is alive.
I'm sorry.
You didn't come to our
yesterday meeting.
I know it.
I was just needed to replace
a colleague who had something to do.
Here.
That is to say, you were here.
Your cup is cleaned up. Didn't you
drink any coffee all night long?
I did used it.
I hope you don't mind.
No, it doesn't bother me.
Not at all.
I couldn't find my own.
Anyway it's a shame you didn't come
yesterday. It was so much fun.
Junior replaced Prince
who hasn't died.
Isn't Prince dead?
No.
He's not.
Have you ever seen anyone
drinking from my cup?
That one with the red letters
that say "Los Angeles"
No. As far as I remember.
That's strange!
You may take mine
whenever you want.
Thank you very much.
I don't smoke.
You better quit smoking too.
- Nice shoes.
- Thanks.
I watched a movie yesterday
with a veteran...
whom they called
for his last mission.
While he wouldn't initially accept,
then he took up arms and went.
I think I've seen it.
Mum, dad, I wasn't expecting you
so early.
Vasilis is a friend from school.
All we did was dancing.
- Do you want to go to my place?
- Sure.
Hi, dad.
Here's Vasilis.
Vasilis, here's my dad.
- Hello.
- Hello there.
We're going to sit in my room
and listen to music.
- If you need something, say it to me.
- All right.
If volume's too high, tell me
to turn it down.
- All right?
- All right.
Volume is high.
Turn it down.
If you're getting cold,
tell me to turn the heat on.
I'm not cold.
Vasilis is younger than me
but we do match together.
In several things.
We got many common interests.
Music, sports...
We met at the hospital.
He's a track & field athlete.
In the 110 meter hurdles.
In a race he fell down
while jumping over the hurdle
and suffered a fracture of
the pyramidal bone.
I helped put the splint on him
and gave him a painkiller.
He is also very good
in arts.
He plays the guitar.
They make some covers.
With his band at school.
He is the singer and...
Hi.
Who is it, darling?
A schoolmate, mum.
Unfortunately
I can't come with you.
I have homework and after that...
I must attend a very
important tennis tournament.
See you tomorrow at school.
We're going to make a test.
We're going to use this object.
If it doesn't change color
and stays white,
that will automatically mean
you are competent
and reliable
to stay with us.
If it changes...
there are two possibilities.
First.
It becomes blue.
If it becomes blue,
that will automatically mean...
that you are competent
but not reliable.
So?
There's no "so".
It doesn't matter becoming blue.
I said it just like that.
The second possibility
and the worst is...
this club to become red.
This will automatically mean
you are unreliable
and incompetent
to stay with us.
Let's see.
It changed.
It became red.
Unfortunately, you must leave.
Drink it up before
the ice melts away.
It was very nice.
Who was mother's favorite actor?
Robert Redford
Mine, too.
Her favorite singer?
Harry Belafonte.
Yours?
Elvis Presley
Mine, too.
Nice shoes. Thank you.
I watched a movie yesterday
with a veteran...
whom they called
for one last mission.
While he wouldn't initially accept,
then he took up arms and went.
I think I've seen it.
Mum, dad, I wasn't expecting you
so early. Vasilis is a friend.
All we did was dancing.
Nice shoes. Thank you.
I watched a movie yesterday
with a veteran...
whom they called for one
last mission.
While he wouldn't initially accept,
then, he took up arms and went.
I think I've seen it.
Mum, dad, I wasn't expecting you
so early.
Dad, can you bring me some water
please?
Dad?
I'm back.
Can you open for me, please?
I was very good today.
4-2 in sets.
You're the best coach in the world!