- What is it boy? - It is a packet, granny!
- Who kept this here? - I don't know!
- What is it? - Feac...
Keep quiet!
Do we have brazen people in our place to do this?
When I went to supply milk at Lonappan's place this morning...
I saw Bakery Mathai ducking here...
- Could it be him? - Not likely!
Ma'am, praise the Lord!
What is that golden covered packet?
Feaces!
Is it pork meat? Make pickled pig's knuckles!
It would be splendid!
Ma'am!
Can't you figure out what it is?
Feaces!
When did Mathai pack this and left it there!
He even asked ma'am if it is pork meat?
He told her to make pig knuckles and consume it!
I would make him eat it!
Get me two teak leaves!
- What is it Chachappa? - Few fishes Thangamma!
It is moray eel!
Would be great for fish gravy!
Is it a backwater catch?
No, it is baited from the toilet!
Thresy! Is the stove hot?
It is moray eel! if we don't heat it up...
...it would become difficult to peel them!
From where did you get moray eel?
Chachappan brought it
You prepare for the gravy!
My God!
Mathai! Salvage our family esteem!
Chachappa!
What happened?
Sir! This beggar hurled faeces in my house!
Sir! This fellow gave faeces to my mom saying it is moray eel!
'Police Station'
Stop it!
Don't come to my station with such faecal cases!
Have you both heard it guys?
'This is also a story of this town!'
'But this is not the story of this town!'
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"Hoshanna!"
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"Hoshanna!"
"We are the church bell!"
"It's ceremonial dance henceforward!"
"To fend off worries, let us unite"
"Haleluya!"
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"It's raining down on the lake, like on a tent!"
"We've built a heaven with moss and straw!"
"The dream flower has bloomed!"
"The new year has burgeoned"
"When the star gleamed the path became clear!"
"The world woke up to this truth!"
"Welcome the sanctitude by spreading it across the earth!"
"Hold it aloft when it blossoms"
"Make clear only good deeds are befitting to mankind"
"Never be diffident With youthful thrust..."
"...let's embrace it uniformly!"
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"We are the church bell!"
"It's ceremonial dance henceforward!"
"To fend off worries, let us unite"
"Haleluya!"
'Amen'
'Kollam year 619'
'Thus saint appeared in our parish to drive away Tipu!'
They have reached!
It is Jesus at top...
Underneath the box it is Gandhi...
...and at the middle is the sacristan
I will open the door!
Sacristan! Dhoti!
Your dhoti!
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"Hoshanna!"
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"Hoshanna!"
Where are you looking man?
I mean you!
Yes you!
Get up man!
Out! Get out man!
'Walking out of the Church Pailakutty...'
'...felt the same solitude of Neil Armstrong when he stepped out to moon!'
Amen!
'Don't mull over this!'
'It is out of agony! Poor fellow!'
Don't come to church to sleep or converse!
Bless me and sanctify me Lord!
Fill me with your...
The mass is not yet over Sit down!
Where is solomon? Has he not come?
Not only Solomon Shoshanna has also not come!
Some other girls are singing the prayer choir!
I did everything possible!
In the name of the Lord and the Holy spirit!
Amen!
Give him a slap
What is it, dad?
You will not allow me to even sleep!
The entire parish is inside the church
Like a pig in the mire you are crouched here!
Umpteen times I have told you not to lie like this!
It is because I have fever dad!
Mercy Angel! Give him the coffee!
- Have you added sugar? - Sufficiently!
Drink this and join the mass at the church!
You need not have any misgiving!
This time I will make you play at least once
- What is pricking me? - It is my wings dad!
Can't you clip your wings?
"Solomon and Shoshanna met long ago!"
"From baptism days they knew each other!"
"Their eyes and souls were speaking nonverbally long since..."
"Through eyes and souls..."
"...they spoke nonverbally long since"
"Liked the moon that went to church at midnight!"
"The church bell rang within The reverberation took me somewhere"
"Wrote name in soul with rainbows!"
"Like a ferry boat moved back and forth!"
"Solomon and Shoshanna met long ago!"
"From baptism days they knew each other!"
"Bought a sugarcane grove in dream!"
"Gave a firefly field in return!"
"The produce were shared by both"
"When fifty vows finished up the emotions unfolded"
Solomon! Come here!
Are you going to play band tomorrow?
Brother!
When I started for the church did I not wake you up?
Did you sleep again?
After you left, I felt little feverish...
So I went to bed again!
Jesus! Let me see!
Like cows defecate this guy gets fever so often!
He needs bum whipping!
If this is repeated that is sure to happen
- It is true mom! - Is it!
Dad and his angels gave me coffee and left!
Jesus!
There is no coffee powder and sugar at home!
Then how could dad prepare coffee?
Keep quiet, Clara!
The angels would have brought coffee powder and sugar!
Son! Did dad say anything else?
Mom bless me!
I am going to play the band tomorrow!
Hey! Bless me and go
Tomorrow your brother is playing the band!
- Are you coming mom? - Go woman!
Bye!
Saint! For the first time...
I am going to play before a gathering!
In case I tremble, stay along with me!
Solomon! Is this the attire for an helper of the church?
Pope told me to join the band today!
An helper's job in church is not playing the clarinet!
Those who did not take part in new year prayer...
...need not play in church band!
Please don't talk like that, Father!
I informed everyone that I would play the band tomorrow!
Don't look at him!
Gee Varghese band expenses are not borne by the pope
It is borne by the church!
Church may bear the band expenses!
But it is me who decide who should play in the band!
I am a vicar in this parish for the last 15 years!
All these years the church band has lost everywhere!
I believe Thomas's contention is do not accept anything...
...until seen by your own eyes!
Why are you creating an issue Father?
Is it because we asked him to play?
More than this guy he has all the credentials...
...to play for the church band
He is the son of Esthappan master!
A person is not selected for band...
...based on his dad's name and his lineage!
Have you heard him play?
You may play now!
Let me hear you!
No sound is coming from this!
Has someone packed cloth inside?
Father...!
Come on play man!
When you suddenly asked me to play...
Are you going to play in toilets?
Come on play, man!
Play man!
First learn to ring the bell and make frankincense
Try to become a sacristan!
Remove the shirt and give it to the pope!
Must be at the church at 5 AM...
...and ring the bell for the first mass!
Leelamma! Keep this at the Kitchen!
Kamalahasan engineer bought this!
On the other bank today it is Davi's band!
It is impressive
Leelamma!
Is it grilled breast or duck roast?
Leelamma, you didn't answer me!
Engineer sir! What is that you want?
You take it home I will answer him!
Kamalahassan Engineer!
This is not meant for today!
For tonight all creatures living in water and land...
...are cooked and the curries are swanked on table!
The only one left out is the cow in the cowshed!
Shall I cut the cow's udder and make pickles for you?
- What are you talking? - How else can I answer him?
Engineer sir! He was just joking!
Come on sir Climb up sir!
I thought...
Matha!
That guy Solomon who is after this girl...
...stitched shirts for band and went upstairs
Will the Father allow him?
Instantly he drove him out
Dad! Don't talk ill of Solomon!
I would splash chilli water on your face!
Who is Solomon for you?
Shall I serve you a cutlet?
Did you not hear me?
Who is Solomon for you?
I am going to marry him He is my groom
What have you done Mathacha?
Coddle her! You pampered her and now...
Wash the face!
- Mom! - Stay there!
Are you going to kill her?
Mom! I was...
- Mathacha! She has fainted! - I will be back now!
Binamma!
Serve little buffalo meat!
My god! Mom...
Binamma! Get some water soon!
Coming!
My God! What happened to you?
Binamma, get some water
- I just enacted a scene! - Water!
I just tested if my son still has affection for me!
This is queer!
What are you looking at?
Get me two pieces of duck meat and one appam!
- This is excessive! - Are you a big...
Let me go to bed!
Granny!
When I mentioned your name...
...yesterday my uncle was about to kill me
I don't think I can hold out any longer!
You are bothered about your problems only
I yearn to play in the band!
When Father asked me to play...
...I trembled
He drove me out
The other guy is now wearing the shirt stitched for me!
If you couldn't play there then you are unsuitable!
You play standing beneath my window
Why are you not able to play before a gathering?
You know everything! Yet should you say this?
When I hold the clarinet before a gathering...
...I get to see my dad drowning!
That makes my throat dry! I would tremble!
Are you not ashamed to say you are Esthappan master's son!
It will be better for you to discard this and seek some other job
I wanted to become a Father in church!
- You only prevented me - Because I loved you...
But if you continue to behave like a child...
...one day I would leave you!
They are celebrating their victory!
You don't waste time standing here!
Clean your clarinet and put it on the attic
This is appam Give it to your mom!
How great was this band?
Now every year we are losing It has become a routine!
Gulp it!
Can you get me pork meat?
I would whack your throat
You have already devoured 2 Kgs of pork meat
Slug! Has lost the competition!
Jesus! He is crestfallen!
He is not playing the clarinet! He is weeping through the instrument!
Take the boat to the toddy shop! Today we must batter them!
My Lord! Thommeri Davis and his group are coming here!
Don't know what is going to happen today!
Guys! They are coming here!
"Granny's children! You are a pain in the neck!"
"Will you not go?"
"Don't play an endless game This is a queer lancet!"
"We don't want to win or lose! We are incompetent!"
"Times have changed! Appearances also have changed!"
"It is all seamed! It is a raucous rooster call!"
"Losers became obdurate!"
"Why did your nose tip turn red?"
"Why is your gaze embarrassed?"
"Why your words are incisive?"
"Am I your kith and kin to clap?"
"Are you a rogue because you consume Therutha's toddy!"
"Who am I to you! Am I a brother or a bother to you!"
"Don't you want to be well disposed with your neighbour!"
"Did you not run away without turning your back?"
"But now are you not panting?"
"After drinking toddy you can't even stand erect!"
"Come straight to me!"
"Lying down and staying at home You were shamed!"
"To win or lose, you could not bid on us!"
"Times have changed! Appearances also have changed!"
"It is all seamed! It is a raucous rooster call!"
"Was it not Mariamma on the dais?"
"While she strip teased her hubby would sit in front yard!"
"Look at the sun alas! It appears like moon!"
"It is a rhythmic beat!"
"Scamp, come on perform! How dare you abuse my dad!"
"You can't even uphold your esteem and repute!"
"You scoffed others! Have you got anything to say now!"
"When you strike back and forth to wash dhoti..."
"...the dhoti went past Bums did not notice this!"
"While stupes and dullards were watching two bums..."
"...they were busy making a mallet for a game!"
"They were busy making a mallet for a game!"
- Come here guys! - Stop it!
Dogs! Defeat us in slugfest, if you can!
Anybody can combat anyone
If you mean slugfest, come to our place!
We too have men at our place!
If we want to bash you...
...we would come to your house
Do you want to see that?
Then bash me!
You should have shown this spirit while playing the band!
Move away!
Your dad Kochu Lonappan taught me to play clarinet!
Do you know what he told me...
...when he gave me the clarinet for the first time?
God blew soil and made man...
...and gave music to give life to man
Every time we breath we are giving life to this clarinet
There is neither defeat nor victory for a genuine musician
Only music dwells!
Do you mean to belittle our musicians!
If you have any self esteem, compete and defeat them
Then deliver your discourse!
Even if the Gee Varghese Band toils for 50 years...
...this trophy in the name of the Lord
...would stay before the garlanded photo of my dad Kochu Lonappan
This is a challenge thrown by Thommeri Davis!
Come Mariamma!
Don't blabber because you won this time!
Come on guys!
We will show our mettle in the next year's competition!
Year long toils for teaching a band like this...
...and later dumping in the attic is futile
It would be better to fart in the backwaters rather than doing this
At least two bubbles would surface and blast with a sound
Trumpet, Clarinet and yosr attires keep everything on the attic!
Unless I tell you no one should touch it!
Go to the other side of the bank
If you come this side again...
...we would drop you guys in the backwaters!
- That is not required! - Not like that!
Father! When our band was victorious...
Louis Pope and Esthappan master were in the forefront!
When the boat capsized with Mathoon and 4 other people...
...my son in law and Molamma were also dead
Along with them our band was also drowned!
That can't be viewed as insignificant!
Stop it!
We are hearing this story for years!
When there is a difference of opinion on the church band...
...let us put to vote to decide if we should continue the band or not?
Before that let this guy give a reply, Father!
Let him respond!
He is silent when the church committee is questioning
Under the circumstances please don't think I am also raising an issue
We need an answer!
There was a time when the Gee Varghese band was a big-name
Those days band earned money for the church!
Those days even if a key is defective in clarinet...
...a new clarinet would be given
If someone can not play it right he would be replaced by a new person
Those golden days of the church band...
...are now enjoyed by the Martha Mariam band on the other side of the banks
Have anyone of you bothered to ask...
...how church band members make a livelihood?
Our band members fair Thoma and kochu Agusti...
...sold their houses and crossed the waters to join their band
They did so out of poverty
For the last few years the Gee Varghese band...
...is defeated by the church and no one else
I don't have any further elaboration on this!
Those present here want to dissolve the band
Please inform this in the Sunday Prayer mass, Father!
If the members of the parish also have the same opinion...
I have nothing more to say
Come on guys!
Go!
What is this pope!
You have not completed it this time also Half way through, is it not?
After the Edathuva Church festival we were all returning in a boat
All those who accompanied were sleeping!
It was a bright full moon day!
Suddenly Esthappan took his clarinet...
...and started playing a tune unheard until then!
In an excitement, I also joined him!
All those who were sleeping got up!
In that bright moonlit night...
...amidst few of us, I felt it was Saint sitting there right in the middle
In our experience none of us have ever played such a tune...
After birth and death you swim across to another point
It was such a bliss!
Esthappan used to tell me always...
...at a convenient time we should reach the ultimate
But it did not happen
It could not be completed by both of us!
Couldn't complete it
In life everything breaks halfway through!
Esthappan and Molamma are no more with us
Itteri, Kochu Thomma, Antappan All of them have gone!
Now our band will also go!
I have witnessed it
After winning the trophies from Edathuva, Chambakulam and Cherukara...
...you and Esthappan would reach the shores of our place in boat
Who recalls all those days?
Relax yourself pope!
To set right all these...
Saint will send someone This is my surmise!
This boat does not follow the safety regulations stipulated by the government
For all those travelling in this boat...
...there is only one life jacket and that is worn by me
If passengers sit quiet this boat will reach shore!
Quite for some time I wanted to sit with you people
Dead people are better than those living!
Cheers!
What is this? Come on have a drink!
'ITTOOP LOTTERY PAWN BROKERS'
Ittoop brother! Boat has come I am making a move
I said I am making a move!
Brother! Mom fainted!
Get her tablets! Get money from Ittoop's shop
I am going for collections!
You may go I will get her tablets!
Seems you would wait for the boat to return from the banks
You go home! Mom is alone
Don't order me Clara, I will go!
Are you trying to stare me down?
If you misbehave with me, with the umbrella I would throw you in the lake!
Let me see that!
Clara! You may go The boat has arrived!
- Yabber! - Go prattler!
Have this cashew!
Is he Saint Gee Varghese!
He has a lance with him What he needs is a horse!
Give me a lime soda!
Brother! The church...
Are you not the son of Puthukudi Thomas sir!
From America and then Bombay
How did you guess?
You are a replica of Thoma sir! Can't I recogonize?
Where are your things?
It would come in the boat later Now I have come!
Come on Ride as my pillion!
I want to go to the church!
Will people coming to Kumarangiri go home without seeing the Saint?
Get on to the bike
I am also going to the church!
This bike belongs to the church!
I am the sacristan, Ouseph!
Are you the sacristan! Then let us go!
Brother!
Sacristan! Give this to the senior Father!
Tell him Chachappan gave this!
- What is the matter! - I want to stop drinking!
Inform Father to pray for me at a convenient time!
There is no urgency! He can take his own time!
I will give him!
'But this fish will not reach church'
'It will reach the kitchen at sacristan's house!'
'From there it will travel to sacristan's intestine!'
'Amen!'
Hold this son!
Is he using the oil meant for rockets in his bike?
Now you must buy some lands in Kumarangiri
Marry a beautiful girl and settle here
I would arrange for everything!
What do you say?
There are lot of beautiful girls in Kumarangiri
Shall I bring marriage proposals?
Is priests in our parish allowed to marry?
Why do you ask this?
I am the new junior vicar for this church!
Father Vincent Vattoli!
Fish!
Father! Praise the Lord!
All the time Praise the Lord!
I am the new junior vicar - Vincent Vattoli
I am telling the truth!
I have come to take charge!
I am Father Irunnalamkuzhi Joseph Irunnalamkuzhi!
Attuva parish vicar is my cousin Father idannalamkulam!
But there was no information about your arrival!
I had to come suddenly!
Where did you stitch this robe?
This is not stitched It is ready made apparel!
Pants and shirt!
- What? - Pants and shirt
Seems you didn't have time to wear the priest's robe!
No Father! Priest robe can be worn while doing religious duties!
I am used to wearing these!
I am comfortable in these attire at normal times!
- What? - Comfortable!
Besides, does our parish stipulate wearing robes all the time?
You must be weary after the travel Have some fruits!
- Come on! - No thanks!
Then it is ok
A priest is a replica of Jesus This is what I have learnt!
A replica of Jesus wearing pants and shirts is little excessive
Is it not Vattoli?
When I am a vicar of this parish I don't want any outside influences!
Glasses and shoes Glasses and shoes!
Even otherwise there are few revolutionaries in this parish!
This parish can not bear the brunt of having another revolutionary Father!
So if you want to continue as a junior vicar of this church
Change these attire and wear the priest's robe!
Yes Father!
Is it permissible to have two extra pockets in the robe?
I guess it is not permitted Okay
Tomorrow morning will be Vattoli's first mass!
Let me see how smart he is!
My god!
No problem! You can wear it!
Seems the church band lost this year also!
- Yes, we lost Father! - What happened?
That is a big story!
Seems neighbouring parish got the trophy this time also!
Right?
It was all planned! They have lots of money!
Thommeri Davis and his wife Mariamma
Both of them have lots of money
- Does Davis play? - Never!
His dad Kochu Lonappan used to play!
These people will make others play their band...
...win the trophy and steal the limelight Both of them
That lady is flashy!
She would wear a shirt, dhoti and a dark glass!
Is it?
Solomon, attend the call
Father! I am scared to attend calls!
There are just 2 phones in this town!
One in contractor's house and another one in church!
Your brother has assumed charge in a church!
Can't you visit me?
His aunt in Kayankulam slipped in bathroom!
We had been there and just returned!
Give it to me! Give
The jack fruit stain will go on the phone!
Dear Brother in law!
Big brother in law!
Dear brother in law!
What is the news! Did you not go home?
I had to come here earlier for some wok
Any way, if you call from the other banks...
...me and your sister would reach there!
Did you meet Ottapla Father?
Yes I met him, taunted and then only came here!
Your younger brother is taunting Ottapla Father!
Have you started your pranks!
If I come to know any of your mischieves there...
I would immediately come there in a boat!
Ok
Is it your sister, Father?
We have only one sister, Mariamma!
- You know her - Is it?
She is married to Thommeri Davis of the other bank!
I take leave Father! It is time to ring the bell!
Solomon, wait!
You complained about my sister and brother in law
How can you leave just like that!
I don't know anything
Vincent Vattoli from Changanaserry...
Why should he choose Kumarangiri parish to become a junior vicar?
Do you know Solomon?
I don't know Father!
Will the church band survive tomorrow's voting?
What do you think Solomon?
I don't know about that too, Father!
But I have understood one thing!
It is a concerted planned move!
Gee Varghese band does not belong to the church alone!
It belongs to this town and also to the Lord in this church!
I don't want anything to happen to the band!
Before we decide to continue or not the Saint Gee Varghese band...
...our church's new priest Father Vincent Vattoli
...would address you briefly!
I saw this place for the first time on a new year day long ago!
I was a young child then!
I was like the little son sitting in front!
- What is your name son? - Joy mon!
I was like Joy mon!
That day my dad said something to his brother!
That is still ringing in my ears!
In Kumarangiri, one can't find a person...
...who has not hummed a song or who has not fallen in love at least once
When I stepped in to this place...
...my dad and uncle took me first to this church!
Through the big gathering...
...what struck me first was a priceless thing!
People who came out of the church touched and caressed that!
It is still vivid in my memory!
After many years I have returned to this place as a priest!
When I entered the Saint's church again...
...my eyes were looking for that invaluable thing!
It is there It is still here!
When I returned on that day in boat with dad and uncle...
...along with ice stick and toys I took along one more thing
The music of this town!
The music of this place made Kumarangiri renowned!
That music was shared to everyone who lived here...
...by the saint Gee Varghese band!
That band is now like this neglected piano...
...full of dust and is getting ready to receive its last rites!
Esthappan master, Itteri, Kochu Thommy, Antappan
What was drowned in the lake was merely their bodies!
You have forgotten all of them After having lost all near and dear...
...Pope Louis is, still living for the sake of music!
If you don't want him...
...you would be losing the soul of Kumarangiri
...and also Kumarangiri's music
Let that music bring back excitement and integration of this town
Should we not submit the ever rolling trophy...
...at the feet of the saint again?
What do you say Lonappan brother?
Don't you want Ittoop brother?
- What about you Joy mon? - I want
Should we dissolve the church band?
No No
No
Father! You could have contested the election!
I have contested and won too!
"The entire village looked in overwhelming surprise!"
"From where did this divine messenger come?"
"You caress while weaving a tender leaf garland!"
"You have changed the feeble wind! Is it a fortune for this town?"
"Your flair is throbbing and shining outwardly!"
"Welcome you Welcome you!"
"You are a pulsating fortitude!"
"Vattoli father's gait is graceful and rhythmic"
"It's a rhythmic sway to left and right!"
"Have you not noticed his captivating smile!"
"How elegant he is! It is a treat to watch!"
"We are endowed with this gift today!"
"Vattoli!"
"His words are coated with honey! His looks are serene!"
"You are a fortune to this town!"
"Vattoli"
"The gentle breeze from south is nippy!"
"To get over the chill you fell in campfire and wine!"
"Sunshine of Kumaram!"
"Good people vowed for betterment..."
"...you sprouted like a golden ray from a mango seed!"
"You are like Kuravilangadu saviour! Country's first sailor captain!"
"It is cherubic! The song and rhythm!"
"Like an harvest let us celebrate!"
"Vattoli!"
He is wearing pants and sun glasses!
Is he a Father?
Saint has sent us Vattoli Father!
- Sufficient for one load - My god!
Say so You are an artist!
Yesterday I thought why should a Father coming from eastern hill side...
...argue for Gee Varghese band?
That is why I said only those who drink toddy...
...will know the taste of the carp fish!
Is it not?
Come in!
Have you seen her Father?
She is from France Michelle
All those who came with her have returned!
She wants to learn our music and stayed back!
Her parents are not in agreement with her
She is a smart girl!
Child! This is Father Vincent!
He is our church's new junior vicar!
Pappan! Shouldn't Solomon practice playing!
Let him first learn to hold it properly Father!
Is it not Charlie?
When one plays it should not be merely blowing out air!
Music should also come!
You are a Father in the Church!
Yes
But the other day you danced with me in the boat!
I understand English!
But I like to talk in Malayalam!
I can understand Malayalam!
What is wrong in both of us dancing together?
People and your culture...
...would miscon-
Will not misconstrue
People with good intentions never misconstrue!
They will look at us as two human beings!
It is like a cinema scene!
You dog! Go
Stop there!
You need not bathe at home sacristan!
I did not insist on selling the house...
...because I don't want you and kids to be left in lurch!
I have made some computations
I will take a decision shortly about that!
Then you decide quickly and inform us
Should we also not know about it?
- You... - Don't do it dad!
Hope you know...
If I consider the interest and compound interest Esthappan owe...
...even if the house is sold you may have to pay me
Went there to help them!
Come fast! I left the dinner half way
'The food left over by sacristan...'
'...would have been by now consumed by his pet dog Chakki!'
'The deal for Chakki will follow'
Stay there!
'That night 7 1/2 year old chakki died due to sacristan's fatal blows!'
Is there anything tastier than this?
Couldn't you get some fish?
Is anything stuffed in your throat?
No point in opening your mouth when you come for food!
Do you know what is happening here?
How will you know?
All the time you roam around carrying the clarinet!
My dad's name is Esthappan!
I will roam with the clarinet!
I care a damn if others feel bad about it!
For one week I have been telling you to change the bulb!
Today mom went there and fell down
Until now she was screaming! She has just gone to bed!
When can I see you thriving?
I will die only after seeing you well off
I don't know mom!
Don't cry dear
Clara!
- Is Solomon not there? - He is inside!
What is it?
He has been asked to go to the church!
Junior Vicar has a session!
Is it?
Yes, bro
I have just come from church!
You may leave! I will go
Give me some water, Clara!
No
I asked because of thirst!
Does this hen lay eggs?
No, it lays orange Shall I get some?
Give that vessel I have other works to do
Wait for a moment!
I saw you keeping the paper there!
Seems you took great troubles!
If you drink water like this you will find time only to urinate!
Have you not gone yet?
Get into the boat! I am coming!
Has Nancy come for delivery?
Yes
Go hen!
In whose house is the session?
Looks like at the contractors house!
My God!
- Sebi! - Brother!
Father! Should I accompany?
If I come, they may not like it!
You keep quiet!
We don't go for sitting on such criteria
Philipose!
What is it in the sac?
It is hen's dung, manure for plantains
Take care not to soil your foot!
It has a good smell!
What is this Father?
Will it be possible to hang on the comb of a rooster?
Because your family is big your parents would have...
...vowed to make one of them a Father, is it so?
Father Ottaplakal only does sacraments at our house!
The Senior Vicar considers them as insignificant!
Let it happen The saint will forgive!
Where are you going?
I am going for a blessing!
Will you not come for the band practice in the evening?
Seems you are close with the lady!
Poor girl! She is very religious!
Will blessing the house make it alright?
Do one thing!
I will give you the holy book and holy water!
You may do it and return them at your convenience to the church!
You sit quiet, but give knockout punches!
Keep quiet you dog!
I would jab at your vital spots!
Don't take it seriously It is somniloquy
He is not drunk!
Lord! Let this holy water provide protection...
...from evil spirits and all that is unholy
Amen!
Blessing is over
Someone from the house read the bible!
Child!
Psalms of Solomon!
The sacred poems from 1 to 10
Let HIM kiss me with his lips
Your Love for me is absorbing
Your oil is fragrant!
Your name is like an oil stream So virgins love you!
Draw me to follow you! We would run together!
You dog!
Are you showing roguery in my house?
- Mathacha! - My God!
Leave him Mathacha! Don't hit him!
Move away!
Run away from here! Run! Father! Move away!
- I would kill you beggar! - Stay quiet!
How dare he enters our house and make our girl...
Father! Take him away!
Go!
- You dog! - Calm down!
We will drown our girl and burn you fellow!
Get to the other banks Go man!
- Solomon! - Never mind Father!
Do you know father...
Actually I wanted to join the seminary!
Then...
It was Shoshanna who...
When your people said...
...have you started with your belongings to join the seminary?
What are you talking Shoshanna?
He got a divine call!
Then what else will he do other than joining the seminary?
You move away!
Give me the number of the God who called him!
Let me ask, if he called him?
When did I call? I have not called anyone!
What are you talking?
Is the God carrying a phone?
You move away! The boat will go now!
Have you forgotten the blooming at school?
What is that man?
- Blooming! - What does that mean?
Blooming is a word!
What did I give to guys like Francis, Anto and Raghu who gave me letters?
- What did she give? - Blows!
What did I give you?
What did she give you?
- Kiss! - Kiss?
Have you not heard about kiss?
At the cemetery bushes what did you do to me?
At the cemetery bushes what did you do man?
Don't you know what is done at the cover of bushes?
Shoshanna! I am like your dad...
...I tell you even if the leaf falls on the thorn or thorn falls on leaf
Move away!
It is confirmed the sacristan has fallen down!
- My God! - Stay there man!
I want to know your decision right now!
Do you want to join seminary and become a Father in church...
...or do you want to marry me and father my children?
I would father your children!
What?
I would like to be father of your children!
Heard you called me Father!
Heard it is urgent, so I rushed here!
More than 1500 people have signed and sent a petition...
...to the Bishop's house!
The demand is to remove Father Ottaplakan who is...
...the vicar of Kumarangiri parish for the last 15 years!
Today Bishop called Father and told him to change...
...parish after the church's festival!
We know not even a stone moves in Kumarangiri without your knowledge
Who spearheaded the petition drive got signatures of so many people...
...and sent it to the Bishops's palace?
This assignment should reach the destination safely!
My saint!
Sacristan! That is...
Any problem in revealing the name?
Though it is true how can I betray persons in the group?
I am also a witness to the preparation of petition...
...and making people signatories!
It was done by...
Is it not the Gee Varghese band group maintained by the church for decades?
Right?
I swear on Lord and saint...
...I am not involved in this!
I told Louise Pappan and Chali Pappan...
...umpteen times not to do this! They did not pay heed
When I eased myself what a great relief!
Dog faeces!
What is it Pappa! Have you started early today?
What is it in the boat? Is it shrimps?
Good riposte for Pappan's music! Who is it?
Might be someone from Davi's band on the other banks
Then take this one!
That is Esthappan's style!
Who is there to play this?
- Who is it? - I can't see!
There is no light in the boat!
Go close to that boat!
Give that light to me!
Who is this vying to compete with Pappan?
My God! Solomon! Was it you?
From whom did you learn this my son?
- Come near me! - Go there!
Go there!
Let me see your face once!
My Esthappan is not dead!
My Esthappan's music is also not dead!
Play my son! Play!
'When Louis Pappan learned Esthappan's son...'
'...Solomon is a wizard, it was exactly 7 hours and 2 minutes'
'The same evening, the mother duck did not know...'
'...if the egg was dropped in lake or boat'
'...looked perplexed and was staring at the sky!'
'Without losing a moment, an arched coconut tree over the backwaters...'
'...dropped a red coconut in water!'
'The same evening Shoshanna's marriage with Davis's nephew Alby...'
'...settled in US was verbally finalised by Philipose contractor'
'Esthappan master and Angels were sulking after a game '
'Ink spread on the speech I was preparing for the next day mass'
'At that time Ottplakkan Father was worried about his parish change '
'Sacristan Kochu Ouseph was closing the church doors with a bang!'
How old is this church sacristan?
Must be 300-400 years old!
Then balks and rafters would have attenuated
The roof and terrace would have eroded!
Then any time the church's roof...
...may fall on those assembled for prayers in church!
Yes Father!
Should we not protect the Kumarangiri devottees!
A Father thus protecting the Kumarangiri people...
...should never be disturbed from this parish!
We would send a petition to this effect to the Bishop's palace!
We would certainly send one!
The responsibility of building the new church...
...would be given to the devotee Philipose contractor
- Is it not Father? - Yes
So the sacristan will oversee the renovation...
...and the vicar of the church would close his eyes to some of the deeds of sacristan
'AMEN'
I saw...I saw!
Wearing red silk and an armour sitting on a snow white colour horse
I saw our saint!
'Kumarangiri church's terrace, balks rafters and pillars are weakened!'
'Ottaplaka! Before its roof fall on the head of my beloved people...'
'...Kumarangiri church must be rebuilt' Our Saint said this to me
He said
"Is it not a fete ordained from above?"
"Did not the saint say it univocally?"
"If postponed, it will ravage generations!"
"Who said it is a command from above?"
"Don't sow lies that would not sprout!"
"It's easy to demolish! But difficult to build and raise!"
"Don't we need a wall to draw the cross?"
"Don't we need a church to assemble?"
"To save our esteem under the sky, don't we need a roof?"
"To hold the roof, don't we need a firm wall?"
"Don't we need a roof and wall for the church?"
"Doesn't the church need staff and musicians?"
"Doesn't the church need a bell and a sacristan?"
"What...what?"
"Like the old one don't we need a new birth?"
"Should not the church also have a transformation?"
"Doesn't the church need an edifice and a tower?"
"Doesn't the church need a wall and a chamber?"
"To raise a new one need to demolish the present one"
"We can demolish and build a new one"
"Whether the church is there or not..."
"...don't wreck our boozing!"
"If we don't get booze..."
"We would stir up! Would stir up!"
"If the church is there or not..."
"...is there or not Is there..."
"Can't demolish the church"
"We can't"
"Demolishers hands would burn!"
"Hands would burn!"
"We would demolish!"
"You don't demolish!"
"We would demolish! You don't demolish"
"We would demolish! You don't demolish!"
She is far away Solomon!
Philipose contractor is smart!
Without anyone knowing in this side of the lake...
...he took her to a church across the lake for engagement!
Seeing the American groom she has fallen flat!
You take two pieces of this!
Bite the sorrow and push down the throat Solomon!
Paila! Is there pork meat in kitchen?
- Is it there mom? - Must be there in the vessel!
It is a never ending sorrow mom!
Don't you know Solomon that women are treacherous!
On the night of a festival in church...
...do you know with whom my hubby eloped to Tamilnadu?
...it was my own sister That whore...!
My god!
What is it?
Chain got entangled!
- What! - Chain got entangled!
Solomon his chain got entangled!
- All of you hear this! - Where did it get entangled!
- Mom! Don't put me to shame! - You are a shameless guy!
- Go fellow! - Is he not your son!
He is wearing a long chain like a father and...
My Jesus! You have given me a son who is a...
I am going...
Solomon! Wear your dhoti and go!
Poor fellow! He has started drinking toddy!
God has given you a talent!
Instead of refining and polishing that talent...
...you were after a girl See what has happened?
When she saw another guy...
...did she not prove she is her father's daughter!
During mornings, have you ever visited the band?
In 4 month's time we have the competition!
If you are not serious you will not play this time!
You are not a person to become obscure because of a girl!
Go, have a sound sleep and come for tomorrow's practice!
Father!
It was like a idiotic act, Father!
They were determined not to inform me beforehand!
I learnt the girl is Shoshanna only after going there!
If I tell you something, will you do it for me Father?
What is it Solomon?
Enough Father! We can go
That window will not open hereafter!
I will stop playing clarinet from today!
I think you can decide on that after getting down from my shoulder!
Father to the left!
To the right Father! To the left!
Father!
Your name is like an oil stream So virgins love you!
Draw me to follow you! We would run together!
I want to see you both together before I die
Granny!
Her marriage is fixed
Why should she come here? That too with him!
Mathacha! She is my daughter!
She will honour her words!
We have fixed her marriage!
Besides! She is right in front of us!
Yes If I say...
What happened?
- Has the power gone? - Is it power shutdown!
Power is resumed!
My God! Jesus and Mary are missing!
It is a festival and it is in procession
But we can't avoid saying this
- Who's face it is? - Ours!
Boat is coming! You may go
I will take care of the rest!
Brother in law! What is this?
You are having a lance and crown!
Who is this? Is it Jesus?
- Is it not Shoshanna? - Davis! Don't let him go
Don't let him go! Catch him!
- Matha! Don't beat him - Don't beat
Leave me...
Father, please tell them to stop beating me
I don't have any share in this blood!
Let someone call Father
Let Father take a decision on this!
He has abducted a girl whose engagement is over!
He is not doing a sacristan's job!
You beggar!
See the venomous guy's stance!
If we don't get a decision on this We would kill him today!
- Leave him - He would die
- Leave him! - Move away!
Shoshanna from a respectable family is engaged to another respectable family
Are you trying to tarnish our family esteem?
You sacristan!
If anyone touches him...
...he would not leave Kumarangiri with that hand
- Move away - You...!
- Stop it! - You...!
Our girl was abducted The loss is ours!
But you are trying to overawe us?
Who abducted your daughter?
They have eloped!
The entire town knows they are lovers!
But did you not fix her marriage with another guy?
If the children love each other You must help them to get married!
Damn it!
Come here girl! She is my only child
Have you understood?
Then for what fu****g thing are you here?
- You are... - Stop I say
The entire town knows the status of a sacristan of this church!
Every one here is involved in love
The sacristan is in love here!
- Stop it man - Leave it man
He is not a mere sacristan! He is a good artist too!
He is my Esthappan's son!
Artist! Does he have any value in Kumarangiri?
Does he have a penny with him? His intentions were different!
If he married my daughter, he can eat for life time without a job
Even otherwise for quite some time Kumarangiri people have started devouring
Sitting on terrace and whistling passersby at junction...
...are the only thing they know
Is there a single person here who knows to play clarinet?
Damn with Louis Pappan and his group!
They play in some toddy shop unnoticed by anyone!
Does anyone in Kumarangiri including Esthappan's son...
...has the guts to come forward and play?
If they climb the dais they would urinate!
Take it from me!
If the Gee Varghese band is playing for the coming new year
Solomon would be at the forefront!
For the last 17 years you have never come near the dais
Will you play in the band?
I will...
Then will you win the trophy?
Tell him brother! We will win the trophy!
We will win!
If the clarinet I play has life...
If the saint in this church is true...
We will occupy the dais and play!
We will win the trophy!
And we will dedicate it to the saint too!
In case you win the trophy we will offer last 8 years prize money...
...won by Martha Mariam band to this boy!
Is it not contractor?
Yes!
Shoshanna was engaged to our boy!
If you win the trophy, we offer to marry Shoshanna to Solomon
Tell contractor, you would abide it!
I would!
- If it is otherwise... - Tell me
Tell Pappan!
Gee Varghese band will never play again!
We will decide Shoshanna is not destined to marry Solomon!
That is enough!
Stop it!
Whatever is said here does not bind the church or the vicar of this church
But we did not ask you take this responsibility
Not only that, for a band of this type...
...church will not spend a penny!
The church no longer is associated with this band!
The church can only ban the band
You cannot forbid us from competing!
We will get a person to sponsor the band from this side of the bank itself!
Let us see that Bye Pappan!
Will see you at the competition!
We will
Do you know who helped the junior sacristan in abduction?
It was the junior vicar!
Mathacha take leave and come!
- Come! - Solomon...!
Come, let's go
Instead you could have killed me!
Father! Where should I keep this? I mean this lance and crown!
Father Vincent Vattoli! Pack your belongings
Don't forget to take your pants, shirt and sun glasses!
Hereafter you may not have to wear a robe!
You need not waste time until tomorrow morning to vacate!
I have not done anything so far that my conscience did not permit
I am damn sure it will not happen henceforth too!
Wait Father!
Senior Vicar feels you are against the demolition of the church!
This ire is because of that!
What do you want me to do sacristan?
You should not impede his actions
Demolishing the church stopping the church band...
...or preventing lovers coming together Which one I should not impede?
I said this because of my love for you, Father!
But if you help a devotee coming to church...
...and a helper of the church to elope
Will the locals tolerate you Father?
Sacristan! I have not made any vow...
...to continue in Kumarangiri parish amidst so many hardships
I would pack my things and will be ready!
When you get information from the Bishop's palace, call me!
Ok Father!
Pappan! What made you wager my affair with Shoshanna...
...for a band competition?
If Pappan did not do that together both sides would have killed you
Solomon don't you believe our band can stage a show?
How is it possible, Pappan?
All these years, all of you tried and could not succeed!
How will I do it?
Even after engagement with another guy Shoshanna came with me!
How will I pacify her?
All of you have ruined my life!
Pappan! On what basis you thought we can...
...win the trophy with Solomon at forefront!
Thoma! Keep quiet!
Seems Pappan forgot our efforts for this band for many years!
Has he proved his caliber for you to support him?
Who are you to say we would stop playing band if we lose this time!
For the sake of a good for nothing fellow...
...should we stop playing band It was a bit excessive Pappan!
Don't you want others to hear the music you held back all these years!
Don't you need your girl?
My Esthappan's son! Tell me
They would not win, son!
Tell me Will not we win?
If your decision is final, then we don't like to play in this band!
If that is band master's decision, Solomon would play from forefront
And we would win the trophy!
I tell you!
If anyone is opposed to Solomon as the lead player...
Tell that right now!
Chali Pappan! Why are you so worked up?
For quiet some time I have been planning this for you!
Don't think no one knows about your behind the scene maneuvers!
I don't want to see you around the band anymore!
Go man! Go dog!
Who is coming here at this midnight?
From now on Gee Varghese band is not run by the church!
I, Chachappan is going to sponsor the band henceforth!
Even if it means spending a lot, I don't mind!
I am not doing this for fun!
Gee Varghese Saint told me to do it!
'That night Ottaplakal Father and Ouseph sacristan...'
'...also had a dream that could not be deciphered '
Father Vincent is a son of my cousin!
This is his first parish Let him continue here!
- Yes! - Let it be so!
Then you think about it and do what is required!
Yes!
'Next day morning Vishakol Pappan crossed the waters and joined...'
'...Thommeri davis's Martha Mariam Band'
"You fluttered!"
"Weary eyes! Go to sleep!"
"My heart is stirred up"
"It's full of desires!"
"Will you not give yours!"
"You held my fingers even without me knowing it!"
"Soulfully...! One day when we dine together..."
"...my colours would bloom in sky"
"...bloom in sky"
"In the rainbow of my psyche..."
"...would sound the cherubic amen!"
"Honey! I initially I looked for you"
"Would commingle with your soulful emotion!"
"Go without informing me... Arrogant guy!"
"Came back on account of bewitching love!"
"The twilight is a blooming season!"
"Finally when we unite, it will be intense passion!"
"Rainbow of my psyche..."
"...would resound the cherubic amen!"
Ponnappa! Don't take the boat close!
Go straight!
I have something to talk to Father!
Is this your regular work Father?
I mean, abduction!
Don't stare Father! They are my friends!
He is Mr.Ernakulam
He is...runner up!
Father! For one day can I take her with me?
Amen!
Dear Kumarangiri residents!
For the 50th Gee Varghese ever rolling Trophy...
...there will be a three day Band competition at Church Premises
We welcome you all
The next day after the competition our church's demolition work will commence
Hence from the same day prayers and worships...
...would be held in the temporary thatched shed at contractor Philippose's premises
Son! Did you call me?
Here is a son who farts and a mom who responds to farts!
Son! Don't suspect the anus that farted!
If you wipe it with sand you can eat it with rice flakes!
In the boat that reached the jetty that day
There were 3groups who are going to rewrite the history of Kumarangiri maintenance
One was an archaeologist to take a final decision on demolition of church
Second was two thugs imported by Contractor Philippose to handle Solomon
Vikraman Muthtu
Come Walk
It is not yet over!
Third one - to drub Gee Varghese Band...
Thommeri Davis paid to bring from Fort Kochi
Chavelier Pothachan!
So this is Kumarangiri!
Sir! Jetty is on this side!
He has gone!
Hold my hand! This side
- Where? - Here!
Anyway I am drenched!
I will be there at the shop! You just come there!
- Saint has come earlier - Who is this guy?
Is this the horse or is it snake?
On inspection, we are convinced that...
...there is substantial weakening to the church building!
Kumarangiri church has to be demolished and rebuilt!
We don't see any other way out!
Come on guys!
How about it sir!
Is it sufficient to maul him or should we break his limbs?
Therutha! Get me two bottles of toddy!
He is Pothachan Chavelier Pothachan!
Davis has brought him from fort Kochi!
So if we bribe even any ancient thing is vulnerable!
Is it not engineer? Have one more egg!
Ancient thing will be vulnerable But not public works or maintenance!
Break his fingers so that he can not...
...can not happen
Dear! Do you know who they are...?
Poor girl! She does not know
They are the accused in the stabbing case of North station SI
Vickraman and Muthu!
I brought them To give few blows to him!
They are in doubt whether to break his hands or legs!
For the present they are biting the leg piece!
Poor fellows!
Shall I serve you some chicken curry?
You never told me your daughter is a hothead!
Who are the bootlicks of Gee Varghese band?
Were you asking for me?
If so, I am right in front of you, Pothacha
Pappa! Seems you have lost your old drive!
If someone plays, don't you have the strength fight back
"Desires were benumbed!"
"Hands wearing rings hardened"
"But mind alone... mind alone..."
First time, at the Kanjoor church for Saint Sebastian's festival
Is it not?
Later at Saint Sebastian's festival at Chalakudy church!
At Ollur Gabriela angel's festival
Lastly at Kottamam Sain't Rocke's festival
That day you floored me!
I was shamed and heard insults!
I think that was the last time, right?
No, I was waiting for your return!
Esthappan left without giving us a chance
Now you are the only one left
I have some scores to settle!
I have not come to Kumarangiri for money!
Not for wine or women!
I want to defeat you at least once!
I am obdurate about it
For this time you may discard that desire!
Come next time I will lose it for your sake!
No Pappan!
I have promised Thommeri Davis!
I have assimilated years of learning, playing and hearing
I have come well prepared!
I would not give up, Pappan!
I have also made a promise to deceased colleagues and to Kumarangiri Saint
That can't be changed!
You have an eternal soul that defies death!
Jesus!
I will leave this place only after shattering that!
So we will meet!
Come guys!
My Jesus! This is the first time...
...a guy is visiting this shop who consumes glass pieces along with toddy!
"Ascent, ascent thus! Hold your breath and ascent!"
"We can not now afford to lose!"
"Can not afford...!"
"Those who can't, may leave if they are work-shy!"
"This is our last chance!"
"If we don't win it will be a shame!"
"Will confront them To succeed..."
"...let us start our work sans barriers!"
"Commensurate with talent elegance soars!"
"We have esteem and regard too!"
"Don't you want to be in dais Come all of you!"
"It's excitement everywhere!"
"Join us Come, come!"
"Come, come! Come, come!"
"Break the barrier!"
"Join the band Join, join!"
"Join, join Join, join!"
"You be the blaze!"
"Come together! Come, come!"
"Come, come Join, join!"
"Break and recast!"
Mike check!
Farid! Bring sugar less tea and laddu!
Dear countrymen, friends!
I have come with a solution for everything!
Davis band's fair Thoma's brother Paulachan...
...would marry Clara without demanding a penny!
I mean the Paulachan who is working in the Cashew factory!
After the festival Solomon can play in the Davis band at a good salary
This is the house document I took from Esthappan
Besides all this, I take the responsibility...
...to see he marries Shoshanna at the Kumarangiri Church!
Tell us what we should do in return for all these favours!
She has understood it!
Just do one thing A help that does not damage anyone!
You should not play in the competition!
"Our band is named after the saint!"
"Whoever confronts us will lose!"
"Victory is not yours!"
"The honour is ours!"
"We know you bring outsiders and thugs!"
Matthai! Is it time for lunch?
"Even if we lose we walk with head held high!"
"Go man!"
- The programme is about to start! - Let it be
- How is my uniform? - Splendid!
- Shall I ask you something? - What is it?
In this uniform I look taller than you and my pomp has enhanced!
Now how should I call you mom?
Call me aunt!
My brother trembles when he takes the clarinet
He is going to lead the band
I can even give you a signed document!
The church band will never win!
Are you ready for a bet?
What about you brother!
Son!
Solomon! Please wait!
Let me tell you!
Solomon! I know you play better than your dad Esthappan
If you play the band would win too
After the competition you may play Play anywhere you like!
What will they pay you for this service?
Do you know what will happen to a family if the church excludes them?
You will not get rice Not even a crystal of salt
Will not get water!
Not even a child in the parish would talk to the family
Mom and children may have to leave the place in midnight!
The saint is inside the cage!
But all functions are carried out by the father and the sacristan!
"Our band is named after the saint!"
"Whoever confronts us will lose!"
"Victory is not yours!"
"The honour is ours!"
"We know you bring outsiders and thugs!"
"Even if we lose we walk with head held high!"
"Go man!"
Clara! How did we play?
Will we reach the Last Eight?
Tell me
I will be confident, If you say
Viewers!
For the second round 8 teams have been selected!
I will read out the names!
Makkamman Mary Matha Band!
Vettikavalam Eso Band!
Next is Chenkaiyil Chamayam Band!
Thommeri Martha Mariam Band!
Attookara Iruvetta Band!
Kurisadi Cherupushpam Band!
Kuruvithalam OK band!
And last Kumarangiri Gee Varghese Band!
Boss, for your happiness I have done a thing!
What is it?
I removed the reed from Solomon's clarinet and scathe it on floor!
So he could not play How will he play without reed?
His church cleaning job would end today!
You idiot!
It should be a manly contest!
Don't deceit to win! Get lost
I don't want to see you in the band!
- Leave the place - Go man!
He can't be blamed!
The sacristan asked him to scratch the reed!
So...
Can't be blamed!
Never mind Solomon!
Anyway we are not out of the competition!
You must think only about tomorrow now!
This has happened today
It should manifest your resoluteness tomorrow!
"Oh when the saints go marching in..."
"When the saints go marching in..."
"Oh lord I want to be in that number..."
"When the saints go marching in"
He may be sheepish! But he is Esthappan's seed!
This time he would revel!
"No one with us, but truth!"
"The saint is always with us!"
Dear people! A plantain cluster donation to Makkammam Mary Matha band!
Move away man!
This is plucked from my grove!
Thief! Thief!
Encourage him
Get down man!
- You thief! - Go man!
You drunkard!
Go man
Friends! Another happy news!
For Vettikaavala Eso Band 101 eggs are donated...
...by Chakkarakara Ambrose!
Go guys! Has anyone laid eggs here?
Friends! For the 2nd day's Semi final competitions...
...to be held in the afternoon session 4 teams are selected
I am announcing the band names!
Makkammam Mary Matha Band!
Kurisadi Cherupushpam Band!
Kumarangiri Gee Varghese Band!
Thommeri Martha Mariam Band!
Why do you touch and kiss the horse and the snake?
Saint or the horse or the snake...!
Let anyone of them help the band to win!
My Saint!
"We can not now afford to lose! Can not afford...!"
"Those who can't may leave if they are work-shy!"
"This is our last chance!"
"If we don't win it will be a shame!"
"Will confront them To succeed..."
"...let us start our work sans barriers!"
"Commensurate with talent elegance soars!"
"We have esteem and regard too!"
"Don't you want to be in dais Come all of you!"
"It's excitement everywhere!"
"Join us Come, come!"
Father! If you look from here...
...with the instrument and uniform he resembles Esthappan!
If you mull over It does not augur well
If the church band climbs the stage it will expose our vulnerability
"Those who can't may leave if they are work-shy!"
"This is our last chance!"
"If we don't win it will be a shame!"
"Will confront them To succeed..."
"...let us start our work sans barriers!"
"Commensurate with talent elegance soars!"
"We have esteem and regard too!"
"Don't you want to be in dais Come all of you!"
"It's excitement everywhere!"
"Join us Come, come!"
"Come, come! Come, come!"
Dear friends! In the competition held at Kumarangiri church...
Two teams are selected for the last round!
I am reading out the names!
Kumarangiri Gee Varghese Band!
Thommeri Martha Mariam Band!
No one in Kumarangiri would have thought you would play clarinet so well!
I was also diffident!
- Is this a new one? - No, it is an old one Father!
So, tomorrow will you play with this?
So the church band will win, right?
For your sake you want me to lose!
Now play tomorrow and try to win!
My God! What is it?
Son! What happened?
Jesus! Tell me son!
How will I play tomorrow!
My clarinet...
To play, I...
Is this not dad's?
I don't want to learn what happened!
Tomorrow you are playing with this!
It is our dad's desire that you should play with this at stage tomorrow!
I didn't know my brother is a whizz than our dad!
I didn't know about it!
Shoshanna! Don't ask me where is the clarinet you gave me?
That is no more with me
This is my dad's
Esthappan master's!
Wherever he has taken this or used he has seen only victories!
But I am not Esthappan master!
Have I ever won?
If I take the stage tomorrow, our band will lose!
I am going!
I can't...
Will you go? Will you lose?
If you lose, along with you Louis Pappan who has faith in you will also lose
Kumarangiri will also lose!
Don't you want to win?
Don't you want to marry me?
Whose screams you were responding at this midnight?
I will go!
If my Solomon calls I will go even if it is midnight!
Tomorrow will be your guys last day playing of the instrument!
Let me see how you will reach the church premises!
Until we return from the church tomorrow...
...don't open the door!
Aunt! Ask him to open the door!
Brother! Open it!
Vattoli! Are you going to hit me?
I don't want others to know about certain things!
Tell me, what it is!
What you did yesterday were deeds not supposed...
...to be done by a person wearing the robe!
What is it?
You broke Solomon's clarinet...
...you don't even qualify to be a human being, Father!
I am wearing this robe for the last 40 years!
You need not teach me the do's and don'ts of wearing this robe!
Diocese has not given you robe and authority to help a girl whose engagement...
...is over to elope with someone!
One does not become a father to work against...
...the church, diocese, superiors and noble Christians
Bible says a tree that does not produce fruit...
...will be cut down and thrown into the fire
But what I learned evidently from bible is 'let us love one another'
Father, you have time only to roam around with a foreign woman!
Locals say you would soon discard the robes!
Those days locals said the same thing about Jesus and Mary Magdalene
It was Lord Jesus Christ who was crucified
Not Father Vincent Vattoli!
So let us not try to taunt each other on this score!
You believe, if you close your eyes, it is night!
Don't think no one knows the motive behind the church demolition!
For certain deeds I follow my own style!
I will do what is required to make others also think in those lines!
You are not the congregation!
But I am the vicar of the Kumarangiri church!
Whether it is demolition of church or dissolving the band...
...or Shoshanna's marriage with Solomon it is I who take the final decision!
On top of that is the saint who protects the church and Lord Jesus!
They will also have made some decisions!
Father! Have a cup of coffee!
The competition is about to start!
No thanks, Father!
Will have coffee after the competition!
I...I will stay here!
Me and the saint want to hear you play and win!
Chali!
Dear friends! The exciting contest is about to start!
The two teams are ready like war horses!
I read your letter kept inside the rafter!
Try to play well and win! I will give you a reply then!
Clap your hands and encourage them! Yes clap like that!
Competition is going to start!
Dear friends! We welcome you all to witness this competition!
Dear friends! The exciting contest is about to start!
We invite both teams to the stage!
Both teams have occupied the dais!
Both teams are charged up electrifying competition!
Few minutes from now the competition starts!
Come on clap! Come on
Play soft where required and loud where required!
The clarinet now in your hand will decide whether you should live or not!
A sobbing person with prayers is sitting inside!
Don't forget that!
Did you not hear how he played the third tempo yesterday!
Is he the guy who is going to defeat me and win the trophy?
Today he would poop while playing!
"It is a prayer to Saint Gee Varghese"
"Challenge or defiance!"
"Even if we die we would not give up!"
"Defeat stares you! But putting up a brave face!"
"Challenge or defiance!"
"Death or defeat...!"
I don't know about the decision of the judges!
But I know about one thing!
I can't play better than this!
'Perhaps he did not want to witness the church demolition!'
'So he left us earlier!'
- Philipose! - What is it, Father?
Solomon! You proceed!
Should we not take a decision on this?
About what?
You made a promise!
If Solomon wins the competition...
You mean that one...!
Me making a promise on street and he winning the trophy is all true
But how can I give my daughter to him?
Is this a child's play, Father?
I can consider about it...
...if the guy who played the bet with me who is in grave or the saint tells me
As I decided earlier, my daughter would marry Davis's nephew
Is it not Davis?
If that is to happen my dad should not be Thommeri Kochu Pappan
If you are manly honor your words!
For idiotic acts like this don't expect my support!
After the first mass and first consecration of the new church...
...the first wedding at the new church will be my daughter's
We will invite all and sundry! Come and enjoy the free feast!
Go guys!
Come Matha!
Move away!
First remove the saint!
Then do the rest!
'Kumarangiri rained for one full day and night!'
'Along with that 3 great things happened!'
'Father Ottplakan had a dream that the church need not be demolished'
'Contractor Philipose understood Shoshanna is destined to be Solomon's wife!'
'Sacristan Ouseph decides to return Esthapan's house document to them!'
'Without much delay with locals as witness'
'Shoshanna and Solomon got married at the Kumarangiri church!'
'After few weeks, there were rain laden clouds!'
'Moist wind was blowing on that day'
'That day Gee Varghese band went to play at Paraman church festival!'
'That day Michele decided to return to France since her mom was unwell!'
I can never forget Kumarangiri!
I can also not forget you, Michele!
The boat has arrived!
Brother! Give me a lime soda!
Brother! Where is this church?
Calling from the Bishop's palace!
Father Vincent Vattoli who is to take charge of Kumarangiri church...
...will reach there today morning!
Let it be
Then who is the guy here?
"Gilded honey dew fills soul! It's a chill moon lit night!"
"It's raining down on the lake, as on a tent!"
"Hoshanna!"