You've got to be quick.
What?
Let's move, Bill.
Wait. Hold the door.
Could you hit five please?
She told me she was majoring
in political science.
You've reached the Sommers' residence.
Leave your name and the time you called.
We'll get back to you as soon as possible.
Hi, Mom. It's Marcus.
Marcus!
I figured it was time
we saw each other again.
I'm on the road right now.
I should be in St. Louis by dinnertime.
'Bye.
Good afternoon. Sommers Talent Agency.
Oh, hi, David.
Mrs. Sommers, it's David for you.
Hi, Davie.
Mom, guess who's coming home
for dinner.
Marcus.
Of course I'm happy, darling.
Mom, think peace. Okay?
Okay. Talk to you later.
I think I'm beginning
to like Brussels sprouts.
I'll get it.
Yes? Can I help you?
- You bastard.
- Son of a bitch.
- You've lost weight.
- No. You've lost touch. I got taller.
Who poured ugly all over the walls?
Mom just wallpapered half the apartment.
Tell her you like it, please.
No.
- He's here!
- Hi.
Sorry I'm late. I got held up.
Welcome home.
New wallpaper.
It's really nice.
I'm glad you like it.
I think the fish is still warm.
Come on, sit down.
I already ate on the road.
In that case, I might as well...
I'll take those, Mom. I got them.
Why don't you two...
I got it.
I came home because I'm worried
about Davie.
He should go away to college, Mom.
Look, I'm willing to help pay
if that's a problem.
- Come on, Marcus. Let's not start again.
- I know you don't want to talk about this.
He is really old enough
to be out on his own.
He's doing just fine where he is.
He's not doing fine.
He's almost flunking out.
I have friends on the faculty.
He is not doing well at all.
- He could've if...
- Could've.
He's had a very rough year.
That's our motto. That's our family motto:
"The Sommers Could've."
I could've. You could've. Daddy could've.
Now it's Davie's turn.
We're always looking for excuses.
I'll tell you about "could."
I could be crazy about you, but I'm not.
And you could've made
Dad's last few weeks a lot easier.
But you didn't.
I know that.
I got your pictures, Vera.
No, they're nice.
But I am a little disappointed.
I never thought it was true love,
you and me, but I did think it was true sex.
Now you're telling me it was true,
but it wasn't free.
I'm not in the modeling business, Vera.
My mother is.
If you want an interview,
you really should call her.
I don't want to fight with you.
I'm too worried about Davie.
He's a smart kid, Mom.
He just needs to get out of here.
Didn't you look at him
when you walked through that door?
You're a doctor. Couldn't you tell?
Tell what? What's the matter with him?
Kids lose weight for all kinds of reasons.
You can get dizzy spells
from an ear infection or even a bad diet.
Have you taken him to a hospital
to have him checked?
Have you forgotten
he's terrified of hospitals?
Well, I'm a doctor. Why didn't you call me?
Because I couldn't.
My God, Marcus.
The way things have been between us...
...you're the last person in the world
I could turn to.
I was hoping the symptoms
would go away.
They are not gonna go away
if it's what Dad had.
Why don't I take him back with me
to Wisconsin? We'll do a CAT scan.
I'll have him checked and I'll call you.
Your rear wheel's not true.
It's better than the front one.
Got a spoke wrench?
Yes.
Got to take care of your equipment, Davie.
I heard you dropped out of pre-med.
I've dropped out of pre-law, too.
So what are you studying now?
I have a double major.
Eastern philosophy and cowboy movies.
The Yin, the Yang and the bang-bang.
Think we can get serious for a while?
Marcus, what're you trying to do,
be a one-minute brother?
After a year and a half of phony
phone calls, you finally show up here.
You're late for dinner and now...
Now you want to hassle me.
If you're still concerned,
you can hassle me in the morning.
I have to get back to Madison tomorrow.
Why the hell did you bother coming then?
There.
Why don't you come with me?
Bring your bike. We'll ride around.
Just the two of us. How about it?
I would love to. I just...
I shouldn't leave Mom alone.
Mom thinks it's a pretty good idea.
What? With you?
- Ask her yourself.
- I will.
'Cause either you drugged her senseless
or you'll be up for the Nobel Peace Prize.
Mom?
Mom says you've been riding
the bike a lot.
Yeah, a little bit, 30, 40 miles a day.
- Ever done any racing?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Well, not really.
I go on these long rides by myself
and I sort of pretend I'm in a race.
I'm trying to get away
and the pack's chasing me...
...and then when they get me,
we sprint, you know.
It makes the miles go faster.
Keeps my mind off of things.
Do you ever race against me?
Yeah. We had a good one last week.
We did?
- How did I do?
- I nipped you at the finish line.
That's bullshit.
Are you gonna try out
for the Olympics again?
No. I'm getting a little too old for that.
At least you made the team once.
Really? That's funny.
I thought I was an alternate.
- Well, it's the same thing.
- It's not the same thing.
- You could've...
- No more "could've." I didn't.
There are decisive moments in bike racing.
When the moment came, I gave up.
Just set it anywhere.
- Want something to eat?
- No, I'm just sleepy.
If you do, the fridge is full.
- You like this sofa?
- Yeah.
Good.
It's all yours.
This really doesn't look like
a doctor's house.
Whenever the newspapers wrote
about "bombed-out Beirut"...
...this is what I imagined it looked like.
Oh, Sarah, this is David.
Davie, Sarah.
Nice to meet you.
"Bombed-out Beirut," eh?
If you hear strange noises
coming from the bedroom, don't worry.
It's just Sarah and I in the grips
of a wild sexual frenzy.
Yeah, sure.
You think he's joking?
No, ma'am.
You sleep tight.
Good night, Dave.
Where are you going to ride?
I thought we'd do a few sprints with Eddy.
Be careful, David.
Eddy's a real son of a bitch.
- See you guys later.
- See you.
Bye-bye.
Who's Eddy?
Sarah's right. He's a real son of a bitch.
Then why are we going to ride with him?
He's a good sprinter
and I need to work on my sprint.
I got a big race coming up.
I'm not in yet.
Good morning, Denis.
Good morning, Sarah. How are you?
- Fine. And you?
- Fine.
Want some juice?
Marcus came back last night.
I thought he'd be gone for a few days.
What happened?
It's his brother, David.
You know the family history.
Yeah?
There's a chance his brother
might have it now.
Oh, Christ.
That family's got a curse on it, hasn't it?
Sarah's Apache? She's really Apache?
Yes, among other things.
She's also Black, Scotch-lrish, Chinese.
I've met all of those before,
but I've never met an Apache.
Where does this guy Eddy live anyway?
Minnesota?
No. Right up there in this house.
Hey, Eddy!
Are you coming?
Aren't we going to wait?
He'll catch us.
Here he comes.
That's Eddy?
That's him.
You son of a bitch!
You better pump.
He likes you.
He hasn't eaten, Dave.
You son of a bitch!
Look out!
Get away.
Get away. Go.
Get out of here, dog.
He took the shoe.
He ate my shoe.
I got to go back.
On second thought,
do you want to go back?
- Wait for me out here.
- All right.
I got someone I want you to meet.
I took him for a ride with Eddy today.
He got his ass chewed off.
This is Dr. Dennis Conrad,
the founder of this place.
- How are you doing?
- Good. You?
Fine. Let me give you the ten-cent tour.
In sports medicine, we try to determine
what the potential of an athlete is...
...and then do all we can
to help him or her achieve it.
We analyze, theorize, proselytize...
...sometimes we even sympathize...
...but we never, never rationalize.
Never.
What do you think of all this?
There's our motto:
"Res firma mitescere nescit"...
...which roughly translated means:
"Once you've got it up, keep it up."
- Right?
- Right.
Are you ready for the torture test?
I love to torture guys your age.
We just finished a hard ride.
I think he needs a rest. Right?
Yes.
Maybe tomorrow.
- You free tomorrow?
- No.
Well, maybe...
Tomorrow it is. Nice meeting you, David.
I told you about those damn dogs, didn't I?
You didn't die yet, so die or do something!
Can I ask you something?
Does anyone ever say no to that question?
Go ahead.
Can you speak Apache?
No. Your mother's half French.
Can you speak French?
No.
I can.
- We're here.
- Hi.
- Dinner ready?
- Just about.
Good.
This is Leslie. Leslie, David.
I saw her.
I saw you today, didn't I?
Yes, at the institute. I saw you, too.
Nice to see you again.
You, too.
Butter.
I never expected Dr. Sommers' place
to look like this.
You've never been here before?
It's my first time.
I wonder who the occasion is?
Big mistake.
Why don't we sit down?
Leslie, take the spot right here.
Davie's taking our famous
torture test tomorrow.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
And I have a feeling
you're taking yours tonight, Leslie.
Salad. I love salad.
Tomatoes.
Great.
Dr. Sommers tells me
you're into Eastern philosophy.
Yes, I'm sure Dr. Sommers told you that.
When Dr. Sommers tells you
to come to his house...
...to meet his brother
who's into Eastern philosophy...
...you really don't have much choice,
do you?
You're being very inconsiderate, Davie.
My name is David.
And I'm not being inconsiderate.
- I'd better...
- It's all right.
Sit down. Eat your dinner.
Don't mind him.
You don't have to take orders from him.
You can tell him to go to hell.
You can tell me to go to hell.
- I didn't come here to tell...
- I know how you feel.
You seem like a really nice girl.
But for once I'd like to meet a girl
who doesn't know my mother or brother.
The world's full of them.
You have to leave home first.
That's great. "Dr. Considerate" speaks.
Father dies and you take off the same day.
What was I supposed to do?
This isn't the time to bring up
family problems.
I'd better...
It's all right, Leslie.
I'm not ashamed of my family.
You probably have a mother. You wouldn't
turn your back on her in a crisis.
She created the goddamn crisis.
I don't care who created it!
She was crazy about you, Marcus.
Bragging about her brilliant son.
Everything you did.
I know. Everything I did was great.
When I lost, she convinced me
I could've won.
That there's no difference.
I don't think that's so terrible.
Do you, Leslie?
I think it's terrible.
Many people would call it support.
When Dad needed support
when he was dying, where was she?
Where the hell was she?
You know where she was.
She was right there in the apartment.
Hiding out in the guest room.
She fell apart, okay? People do!
Goddamn it! You were there!
You didn't fall apart.
You heard him calling for her at night.
I had to plead with her to go to him.
Tell me, Dr. Sommers, when people aren't
as strong as you'd like them to be...
...and they let you down,
have you ever considered forgiving them?
I'm sorry, Leslie.
Perfect. Just perfect.
It's okay.
- I'll take you home.
- I brought her, I'll take her.
This whole thing was my idea!
I'll take her home.
No, thank you. I'll take myself home.
I've got to call my mother.
You never answered my question.
I don't have to answer your damn question.
I've considered forgiving Mother
many times. I almost did many times.
"Almost" isn't good enough.
Why the hell not?
"Almost" is good enough for everything
else in this family, isn't it, Davie?
Excuse me, David.
It's all computerized.
The speed will increase.
The grade will increase.
You'll go into oxygen debt.
If you last long enough,
you'll go into oxygen bankruptcy.
Don't worry about it.
I just want to go one second longer
than Marcus.
You do? Marcus holds the institute record
with 25 minutes...
...and 14 seconds.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
There's your clock.
Have a good trip.
This is the torture test?
He's going for 25.
Come on, David!
Come on, David. Keep it up!
Keep it up! Keep it up!
Come on, David! Push harder!
Come on, David! Keep it up!
Turn it off.
It's like Star Wars down here.
Warp speed.
I can't believe you're still planning
to go to Colorado.
I'll go if David wants to go with me.
He's always wanted to see the West.
- You've got to tell him.
- I can't.
Not now.
Not after what he did today.
I don't want to ruin it for him.
I love him too much for that.
I understand.
I got to run, buddy.
Wait up, I'll walk out with you.
No big deal.
What are you doing out here?
I just needed some fresh air.
I've been looking all over the place for you.
- Want to hear the results?
- I know the results.
You do? Who told you?
Nobody has to tell me.
I'm fine, right?
Physically, you're fine.
You have the cardiovascular system
of King Kong's first cousin.
Just emotionally, you're a mess.
Frankly, anybody who wastes
the potential you've got pisses me off.
Well, it pisses me off, too.
- What are you going to do about it?
- I don't know.
Shinto philosophy teaches you
to accept life as a seasonal occupation.
Sounds like bull Shinto to me.
I burned your ass on the treadmill.
Sure, you also beat my SAT scores.
You're great at taking tests
every few years.
Here's the thing, Shinto.
There's this bike race in Colorado...
The Hell of the West.
- It's the last time I'll race in it and I'd like...
- I'd love to.
- What?
- Race.
Give me a break.
I'm trying to talk you into it.
I had a speech prepared
about how we've never raced together...
...and this might be our last chance,
the Sommers team...
- There's just one thing.
- What?
I'm not shaving my legs.
We'll talk about it.
I think we should give Mom a call.
What do you think?
Okay.
Marcus? How is he?
- He's just fine.
- He is?
Clean as a whistle.
Oh, God!
Oh, darling.
Enough already.
You're supposed to be celebrating.
Oh, darling, I am celebrating.
It's just that I have lived with this
for so long and he's all I've got.
I thought you had two sons.
Marcus, of course I do.
That's not what I was going to say.
Marcus, come on.
That's all right.
This whole conversation is probably not
what I meant to say.
What does that mean?
Davie's all right, isn't he?
Davie's just fine. He sends his love.
I've got to go.
Marcus, I want you to know...
Please understand, I love...
I've got to go.
'Bye.
How's Mom?
- She's fine.
- You told her I was okay, right?
Is this a fish burger in here?
No. I told her you got hit by a bus.
What do you think I told her?
- I want to show you something.
- Where are we going?
Remember this?
This is the first of three stages in this race.
The field gets cut in half here.
If you don't finish in the top half...
...you're out.
- Pretty fast, huh?
- Yeah.
Well, it gets faster.
Coming in the back,
some guys will hit 60 miles an hour.
It can get really dangerous.
There's me and Muzzin going at it.
That's the guy on the poster in the kitchen.
That's Barry Muzzin.
He was my teammate. My best friend.
He's affectionately known
as "the Cannibal."
You know him?
Yes. I was married to him.
Did you see that?
See what?
Right there.
Did you see that? The race is over.
I quit.
You didn't.
Shows you how good I am at it.
Nobody can even tell anymore.
That's what it looks like when you win.
This is what it sounds like.
Two points.
Good shot.
I'm starved. What have you got?
- Give her one of these. They're great.
- Here, Beck.
I'm tired of granola and sesame seeds.
Sesame seeds are great. Pure protein
and energy. It's just what you need.
I need a chocolate shake and french fries.
And a Quarter Pounder with cheese.
Becky, that's flesh.
Have you ever looked in a cow's eyes
when it's killed?
You're eating fear, Becky.
You're becoming one with fear.
We were going to live off the land.
I don't see how eating generic nuts
from the supermarket is living off the land.
We made a vow.
Look into the crystal light
and release meat.
I can't believe this.
What the hell's that?
The Pony Express?
I was wondering...
If Dad were alive today...
Yeah?
Well, they didn't have any cure
for a berry aneurysm two years ago...
- I was wondering...
- They still don't.
If there's a weak blood vessel
and it's located deep inside the brain...
...you can't get to it without destroying
the patient's vital brain functions.
Meaning the patient could become
a chef's salad.
It's like a heart attack of the head.
Even if you're in the best shape,
it can still hit you right out of the blue.
The thing is, you know,
you read those stories...
Some bald guy grows hair again.
Now he needs a haircut once a week.
People doing things through willpower.
What do you think of that stuff?
Good night.
Good night, David.
I always wanted to do that.
Don't forget the napkins.
Can I take your order, please?
I'd like a Quarter Pounder,
large fries and a chocolate shake, please.
It'll be a minute for your Quarter Pounder.
How about a Big Mac?
Okay.
Wait. No.
I'll wait.
Where are you headed?
California maybe.
- You?
- Colorado.
Where are your friends?
It didn't work out. I split.
It isn't right, Marcus.
What?
You should tell him the truth, that's what.
We wouldn't be making this trip
if he knew the truth.
- I think you underestimate him.
- Do you mind? He's my brother!
Maybe I know some things about him
you don't.
Maybe so, but don't use
that tone of voice with me.
- You never heard of bike racing?
- No. Is that what you were doing today?
No, that? We were just training
for this big race in Colorado.
We'll ride to the top of the Rockies
and back. It's very dangerous stuff.
One wrong move and you're just
another statistic in the Hell of the West.
I hope you come out of it alive.
Good luck.
You, too.
Would you like a ride?
Where, on your handlebars?
Marcus, look.
How fast do you go?
Sixty. Sometimes faster.
Hope she's the quiet type.
Not a chance. She even walks loudly.
What did she do to her hair? What is that?
This is Becky Chandler.
Becky, this is my brother, Marcus.
- This is Sarah.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
How's your finger?
Sorry about that.
Thanks for the ride. Hell of the West, huh?
Sounds great.
How far are you planning to go with us?
Tell you what, Doc.
I'll go pretty far if it feels good.
All right.
Ready? I'll get you on a machine
and have you buffed up in no time.
I don't like this place. It smells bad.
That's sweat, Randolph.
And it does not smell bad.
Mama said I didn't have to do this.
You're in Daddy's sinister clutches now.
And Daddy wants to see his beloved son
Randolph sweat his ass off.
Dr. Conrad, Line 3.
I'll put you on this bike.
Use this one, Randolph.
Hello?
Who is this, please?
How do you do?
It's just that I called his house last night
and then again this morning...
...and no one answered, so...
...being a hysterical person,
I started to worry.
There's nothing to worry about,
Mrs. Sommers.
The three of them went on a camping trip.
Marcus, David and Sarah.
Who is Sarah?
The girl he lives with.
I wanted to tell him something...
... but it can wait.
Come on, Randolph. Move it.
I'll have him call you when he gets back.
You can go faster than that, damn it.
It was nice "meeting you," Mrs. Sommers.
You're supposed to be picking a sport.
So, pick a sport.
I like bowling.
Bowling? Bowling is not a sport.
Bowling is just a big video game.
Don't get all defrosted, Dad.
Don't do what?
You heard me. Don't get all defrosted.
How does your mother put up with you?
Now, look, Dad. The way I see it,
there are no black bowlers.
Basketball, yes. Football, yes.
Golf, we got one guy.
But bowling, we got zip. Think about it.
Boy, bring your ass over here.
We stayed in this same place
two years ago. Remember?
- What do you think?
- I think you better remember.
I think you ought to use
a different tone of voice with me.
It's just the way my parents are.
They're too nice.
I bring a guy home
and they fall in love with him.
So there were three guys I broke up with,
hanging around my house...
...watching TV with my dad,
eating my mom's cookies...
So I freaked out.
That's what I do.
When in doubt, I freak out.
You must fall in love easily. Three guys?
Oh, that wasn't love.
Not love love.
I knew it was going to be like that.
I think she's kind of nice.
What does it say on that T-shirt?
- That's Latin.
- Latin? What does it say?
"Once you've got it up, keep it up."
All right! Where can I get one?
- Let's do it like they do it in the Olympics.
- How do they do it?
You know, exchange T-shirts.
What are you doing?
If it's the Olympics,
you have to play the national anthem.
Only if you win.
Excuse me. You're not going to see that.
So, about that tone of voice...
What's going on?
Shake and break.
What's that?
If you're making a solo breakaway
and you've got a wheel sucker hangin' on...
...you shake and break to shake him off.
Wheel sucker? What's a wheel sucker?
Someone who drafts all the time...
...and won't take his turn up front.
Hey, you wheel sucker!
Get up there!
You want to get them?
We got them! We got them!
Watch this, Dave.
Give it a race, guys.
You boys ought to get yourselves a horse.
Oldest trick in the book, Dave.
That was great.
Second oldest trick in the book.
Look at those buns.
What is that?
Looks like we've got a flat.
We've got to stop.
It's okay.
Sarah!
Jerome!
- Look at you.
- How are you doing?
- It's good to see you.
- It's good seeing you.
I said to Jerome, "Jerome,
that sure looks like Marcus's van."
Our old team van.
- Hello, Geronimo.
- Hello, Muzzin.
Where is he?
Riding.
He's great when it comes to training,
but what's he like in the clutch?
You said you wouldn't start nothing.
You know, Jerome,
women are a real mystery.
In bike racing, the best man always wins.
But what is it about some women that
makes them fall for quitters like Marcus?
You know the bigger mystery, Jerome...
...is what makes "some" women ever fall
for a rabid dog like you, Muzzin.
Hey, come on, you two. Cut it out.
You tell him, Sarah.
He knows I'll win.
But you tell him that I'll make him bleed
before I beat him.
I don't deliver messages.
Sometimes I don't even hear them.
He'll quit.
I'll make sure of that.
I'll make him die in the mountains.
Jerome, I consider you a friend.
Would you take this damn Cannibal
out of my face before I kill him?
I'm Jerome. You're a damn Cannibal.
That's a big rock.
Let's get out of here.
We got a race to win.
'Bye, Sarah.
Well, I'll be a Fig Newton!
I'm standing next to a lady with a past.
Then Jerome says:
"I'm Jerome.
You're the goddamn Cannibal...
"...and this is a big rock." So they left.
Sarah was so tough. So cool.
You missed it all.
I'm keeping this rock.
I'm taking this rock to college.
We're seven minutes to the start...
... of the famous Morgul Bismarck stage
of the Hell of the West.
We're getting the race caravan organized
and ready to begin.
Here come some of the press people.
More vehicles coming through.
Team cars, let's keep the roadway clear.
Mexico, Great Britain, Italy,
Norway team cars coming through.
Press people, please report
to your vehicles immediately.
We'd like to introduce to you
some of the riders...
... who will participate in today's event,
beginning with the U.S. National Team.
And ladies and gentlemen,
the Soviet National Team...
... led by the defending Olympic champion,
Sergei Belov.
And finally, ladies and gentlemen,
the 7-Eleven team...
... led by our own 1980 Olympian and
winner of the Hell of the West last year...
... Barry "the Cannibal" Muzzin.
Shake that, Belov.
And now, our honorary starter for today's
Hell of the West, Stage No. 1...
... ladies and gentlemen, the greatest
racing cyclist in the history of the sport...
... Mr. Eddie Merckx.
We will be starting
on the sound of the pistol.
Riders, ready?
Timers, ready?
We're under way,
the Hell of the West, Stage No. 1.
Let's hear it for a big sendoff.
The Hell of the West, Stage No. 1.
We are under way.
This first circuit of the Hell of the West
is the dreaded Morgul Bismarck.
It's a world championship court
which offers little shade...
... steep hills, fast descents...
... and the gut-wrenching climb to the finish
that sits here, atop the devastating Wall.
Riders who have raced here before
seldom look forward to coming back.
And newcomers to a race of this stature,
unused to riding in a large pack...
... will soon find out why.
This is a race of seven laps,
totaling 91 miles.
A grueling test for any rider.
Sommers, look out!
Watch your line!
Move over, Sommers! Move over!
Here we go, Dave.
Enough of this Sunday stroll.
Let's hurt a little bit.
10-4. We are rolling in
an ambulance right now.
Three laps down and four to go.
Four to go, four laps yet to go.
Barry Muzzin in the 7-Eleven team
followed closely by the Soviet team...
... and Marcus Sommers of ShaverSport.
Each lap yet to come on this grueling
course will take its toll on the riders.
Only the toughest will be
among the first 48...
... who will go on to contest Stages 2 and 3
of the Hell of the West.
Shit!
Tough break, Marcus!
Marcus has got a flat. Pull up. Quick.
Okay, pull up. Slow up. Come on.
Come on, Sarah.
Come on, baby, they're leaving us behind.
Come on, honey.
You got it. Good. Good girl. Now, push.
Push.
Look.
Move it! Move it!
Come on! Pick it up!
You want back in this race!
Pick it up! Come on!
One lap to go! Bell lap coming up.
One lap to go! One lap to go!
Here we are!
Here you go!
Marcus, water! You need this.
Water! Water!
You're 52, David. You've got to move up.
You've got to move up!
The caravan is in sight,
ladies and gentlemen.
They are around the corner,
at the bottom of the Wall.
Here they come.
And in a remarkable recovery,
Marcus Sommers has regained position...
... near the front of the lead group
after a flat tire way out on the course.
Muzzin, Sommers and the Soviet, Belov,
fighting it out as they come up the Wall.
A real neck-and-neck battle
as they come through.
It will be a three-way sprint for the first.
The Americans, Sommers and Muzzin,
and the Soviet, Belov.
Right now it's Muzzin in front,
Sommers, second.
Sergei Belov of the Soviet team
charging up in third.
And it's Marcus Sommers, the winner!
Muzzin, second. Sergei Belov, third place.
Ladies and gentlemen,
a tremendous finish!
Sommers, Muzzin and the Soviet, Belov.
Fourteen, 15, 16 riders across the line.
The winners are already in.
We're counting the last riders to qualify.
Only the first 48 finishers today
will be able to race tomorrow.
- Where's David? How far back?
- I don't know.
Only three more riders will stay
in the race.
The rest will have to wait until next year.
- Is that him?
- It is.
With the field closing in fast behind them...
... two riders, the final two
that will qualify...
... and the field is eating them up
coming up the Wall.
Struggling up the Wall for the final time
in this grueling Hell of the West.
And they're down!
One rider is back up.
He's on his bike and he's going to finish.
Run with it!
Get going! Pick it up!
- Can he do that?
- I don't know.
That's it. Run!
Come on, David! A little more!
And in a remarkable finish, David Sommers
crosses the line 48, carrying his bicycle.
- Can he do that?
- Is that legal?
I think I screwed up.
It's okay.
It's official, ladies and gentlemen...
... David Sommers becomes the 48th
and final qualifier...
... to ride Stages 2 and 3
of the Hell of the West.
- Two more stages.
- It was a real close race, wasn't it?
No shit!
Tell us what it was like
to have ridden 90 miles.
It's a big day for American cycling to have
two Americans beat an Olympic champ.
You must feel some pride?
- Come on, walk it off.
- I'm all right.
I'm not riding for America, lady.
I tried riding for America.
I spent four years working at shitty jobs
so I could train...
...and make the Olympic team
and ride for America and look at me.
Then some fat-asses in Washington
started having opinions.
The Olympic Committee started
having opinions.
You, you bitch, I know you.
You started writing your opinions.
So we boycott the Olympics.
I was in the best shape of my life
in the summer of 1980...
...and I got beat by opinions.
Is that why you're boycotting
the victory ceremony?
What victory? There's two stages left.
Still, the fact remains...
Bitch, you wouldn't know a fact
if it banged you all night long.
In first place, the leader of
the ShaverSport team, Marcus Sommers.
Okay. I got one.
I got one. It's about David.
David was only 10 at the time.
He comes into my bedroom
looking real serious.
Remember this? He wants to know
what's oral sex.
Nobody wants to hear this.
Yes, I want to hear it. Go on.
You say things about me,
I can say things about you.
So he says, "What's oral sex?" I tell him:
"Oral sex is the opposite of written sex.
"If you read about it, it's written sex.
If you talk about it, it's..."
Oral sex!
Three weeks later,
he goes to a birthday party...
...up on the third floor for Sheila Fletcher.
Who's Sheila Fletcher?
Comes back in 15 minutes.
Mom and Dad want to know
why he came back so quickly.
"Because", he said, "it was boring.
"Everybody was just standing around
having oral sex."
You got to know my mom.
She flew out of the apartment.
- Is your name there?
- Yeah, somewhere.
- David!
- What?
You're only two minutes and 11 seconds
behind in the standings.
- Is that all?
- That's good.
Marcus, how many rooms for the leader?
One for us, Tom.
David, how many rooms do you need?
Two.
And one for us.
- How is your leg?
- It's fine.
Remember, we are racing tomorrow.
See you then.
We are going to win.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
You know,
I think this whole thing was destiny.
What whole thing?
You and me. This trip. Everything.
I mean, there I was at McDonald's.
And I wanted a Quarter Pounder.
The girl goes, "We're out.
"You'll have to wait.
Do you want a Big Mac?"
Just think. If I hadn't waited
for that Quarter Pounder...
...I wouldn't be here with you.
That's destiny.
There's really something
you should know about me, Becky.
You don't have a girl back home, do you?
No.
- You're not gay, are you?
- No. Hell, no. It's just the opposite.
Then what?
I probably shouldn't be telling you this...
I think I'm going to die.
Thank God I'm not the only one.
I think I'm going to die too
if we don't do something really quick.
I'll be right back.
Stay right here. Promise?
They're playing our song.
- David, are you all right?
- It's just my knee.
We don't have to do this
if you don't want to.
Yes, we do.
Where are you going?
I want to go over the course with David.
Come back to bed.
The race isn't until noon.
What a beautiful morning.
I love you, Marcus, so much.
You're out early!
Look, they got four of these flags
scattered around the course.
Each time you win a sprint to one of them,
you gain 30 seconds on your time.
Do you understand?
I'm not an idiot, you know.
- I don't want you to ride like an idiot.
- What do you mean?
You're two minutes and 11 seconds down.
If you win all four of these sprints,
you'll be only 11 seconds back.
Because nobody knows you, if you do
something stupid like take off by yourself...
...they'll let you go.
What's the big deal?
You don't need me. You're winning.
The big deal is we're brothers.
How is he?
He won the first stage.
You should've seen him.
The son of a bitch told me I couldn't come.
He didn't want me there. He did it, eh?
I think it's begun.
I don't suppose he'd consider
not racing today.
I know he's against it but his mother...
Somebody should call her.
Shit.
I had a bitch of a workout, Dad.
You okay, Dad?
No.
Come on, Dad. Cheer up.
It's not your fault.
Every black man can't have a son
who's Julius Erving.
You're soaking wet.
I sweat.
Funny, doesn't smell like sweat.
I used a deodorant.
Go take a shower.
I have to make a phone call.
Good.
Then can we get something to eat?
Yeah, Randolph,
then we can get something to eat.
One look at the lunarscape of the
spectacular Colorado National Monument...
... and you understand why it has come
to be known as "The Tour of the Moon."
The view and terrain are like nothing
on earth, with bright red rock formations...
... tunnels, numerous sheer cliff drop-offs,
and rapid descents.
The race totals 83 miles...
... and in 1984 was won by
America's Olympic Champions...
... Tommy Carpenter and Alexi Grewal.
Okay, get ready.
Do it, David.
Okay, here we go.
- Oh, God!
- It's the breakaway.
David, no!
Goddamn it! It's too early.
No. David, you dumbbell.
Let them go, Tommy. They're nobodies.
They'll die on the hill.
Let them go!
Here comes the breakaway group
up the hill.
The first rider past the flag will gain
30 seconds on his time.
There goes No. 7, Ulie, of the Kelly's team,
starting the sprint for the flag.
But here comes David Sommers
of ShaverSport.
It looks like these two are both
going for that 30 seconds.
Ulie's in the lead.
But Sommers is coming up hard of breath.
And it's Sommers who wins that
very valuable 30-second time advantage.
Let's reel them in.
The breakaway group's coming up
to the second flag.
David Sommers, who took the first one,
riding very strongly at the front again.
And David Sommers indeed takes
the second time flag.
And it looks like he's going
to keep right on going.
The way the chase group is coming up
hard behind them...
... he's going to need all these time bonuses
that he can take.
We got them.
Where's Sommers?
Where's the other one?
You son of a bitch!
Marcus, I taught you that move.
We got us a race, Muzzin.
Tommy, Jerome, come on, let's move it!
Hold your line!
What's the matter with you, man?
Hey, Marcus, look out!
What are you doing?
Oh, no.
Marcus, I'm right here.
Okay, here I am, Marcus.
Sarah, what's wrong?
Hang on. Hang on.
Oh, God, Marcus.
Becky, help me!
We're here.
Hold on!
Oh, God, Marcus!
Becky, hold the wheel.
I got him!
Watch your line!
Hold it against his mouth.
Make sure he can breathe.
What is he doing?
They're coming down to the finish line,
and David Sommers is still the lead.
But the chase group is breathing down
his neck and getting closer every second.
The field's in sight,
coming down to the finish.
David Sommers is still out in front.
But the pack is coming hard on his heels.
It's going to be a miracle if he can hold on.
No, they've got him!
David Sommers has been swallowed up
by the chase group. Here they go.
They're getting ready to begin the sprint.
Muzzin makes the move on one side,
Belov on the other. They're neck and neck.
Muzzin and Belov, Belov and Muzzin.
It's going to be a fantastic sprint.
And it's going to be... It looks like Muzzin.
Barry Muzzin and Sergei Belov.
And its going to be Muzzin, Barry Muzzin.
Sergei Belov, second.
David Sommers holds on for third.
The rest of the field coming through...
David, you uncorked the big one today.
Where's Marcus?
Please, get out of my way!
It's Marcus. We've got to go!
So, how much time did you make up?
Two minutes.
We did it, huh? You did it.
Marcus, what the hell is going on?
Remember when we were
out front, talking?
I told you that you were free of diseases.
But you never told me anything
about yourself.
I wanted you to come with me.
I wanted us...
Remember, the two of us,
the Sommers team...
Did it ever occur to you
that you could've told me?
That maybe I might pull through for you?
How many goddamn brothers
do you think I have anyway?
Son of a bitch.
It's a good thing you dropped out
of pre-med.
Your bedside manners are atrocious.
How can you be sick anyway?
Look at yourself, what you've got...
You have a moustache and everything.
I had this all figured out.
How to handle this, if it's me. But not you.
I don't know what to feel, Marcus.
Am I supposed to feel happy
it's you and not me? Is that what?
Then what?
Be strong, now, okay?
Okay.
Thank you, Becky.
You have to finish the race.
You're crazy, you know that.
I think you've eaten too many bananas.
- It's not over.
- It's over for me. Don't you understand?
The race isn't important now. It's you.
What will you do for me?
We'll take you to a hospital...
I don't know how much time I have left.
Maybe a few days, maybe more,
but there's nothing they can do for me.
Come on. Help me with this.
I want to sit up.
I'm not trying to be a hero, you know that.
It's just that I won't let them turn me
into a chef's salad, either.
Then I'll stay here with you.
But I can't race tomorrow.
That's just great. Years from now,
you'll tell your kids:
"There was this race in Colorado
and I could've done great...
"...if my brother hadn't gotten sick."
You won't use me as an excuse.
I'm not listening to you anymore.
Goddamn it, David!
I'm still alive, so don't ignore me.
What happened to Marcus?
He had some trouble.
I hope he feels better, Geronimo.
Thanks, Cannibal.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Why?
You sound half-human.
I am half-human.
I was in your office when you
and Dr. Conrad were talking.
Do you remember what you said?
"I don't want to ruin it for him," you said.
"I love him too much for that."
You remember?
No.
I swore that one day
I was going to say it to your face.
Come on, you have to look at me.
Are we going to do this the hard way?
I love you, too, Marcus.
What's our plan?
Stage 3.
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to Golden, Colorado...
... site of the third and final stage
of a race they call the Hell of the West.
Looks like we're in
for a great day here today.
Before we get started, I'd like to introduce
the main contenders in this competition.
Beginning with the rider
in third place overall...
... 11 seconds behind the leader,
David Sommers.
In second place overall,
from the Soviet Union...
... only two seconds behind the leader,
Sergei Belov.
And ladies and gentlemen,
last year's winner of the Hell of the West...
... the race leader today going into
the third and final stage...
... Barry "the Cannibal" Muzzin.
We'rejust minutes from the start
of the competition.
All caravan drivers,
please report to your vehicles.
All officials, please report to your vehicles.
Here's a surprise.
The Russians are starting things early.
Belov is sending a teammate up the road,
forcing the others to do the chasing.
That will take some of the sap out of them
if they're not able to hold the pace.
The weaker ones will get burned off and
won't be able to make the climbs.
Over 100 miles to go and the Russians...
... are really making things pop
right off the bat.
Belov must have a lot of confidence in
his ability to start a breakaway so early...
... in a race like this.
It's no fun up front, is it?
I must be hallucinating.
That looks like Randolph.
It is Randolph.
Who's Randolph?
Sarah, pull over.
Mr. Sommers, don't!
Do you want to go with us?
Go around.
We'll follow you.
Come on, let's go, Randolph.
You must be Sarah.
- Yes. Mrs. Sommers.
- How do you do?
- Hi, I'm Becky.
- Hi.
Okay, let's go.
Golden to Mount Evans race is the third
and final stage of the Hell of the West.
It's also the most difficult. It starts at
the Coors Brewery in Golden, Colorado...
... and begins a spectacular climb
over 6,000 feet into the Rocky Mountains...
... finishing nearly 12,000 feet
above sea level.
And that's over the highest paved road
in North America.
Not many of these cyclists
have ever raced at this altitude.
In Europe, for instance, the courses
through the Alps are much lower.
It's a torturous course.
Even the fittest athletes can't get
enough air to maintain a normal speed.
Notice anything unusual, Randolph?
Yeah, I have jet lag.
Hardly any black riders out there.
Think about it.
I don't have a bicycle, Dad.
Your birthday's coming up.
I want a bowling ball.
I'm still here, Belov.
Right on your red ass.
Think about this, Belov:
I'm behind you,
but I'm really two seconds ahead.
Are you nuts?
He doesn't understand English.
He understands.
Don't you, Belov?
You know why you won the Olympics?
Because I wasn't there.
Well, now I'm here.
Only I'm not here. I'm two seconds ahead.
He does understand English.
Up, Dave. Up.
Up, Dave.
That a boy.
Get him, Belov.
You go get him.
Ten miles to go and David Sommers
is trying to steal this race from them.
He's been very aggressive this last mile,
forcing them to chase very hard.
These last few miles many riders will drop
as the lack of oxygen grows more severe.
He's going all out early.
Should I pull over and wait?
No. Let's go up to the finish line.
It's his race, let him ride it.
Here we go, Sommers.
Okay, we got him.
Just sit back and you've got second
locked up. Okay?
Okay.
Shit!
I gave you a chance, Sommers.
Now all bets are off.
It's David Sommers in the lead,
coming around the corner.
But even if he crosses the line first...
... Muzzin still has
an 11-second time advantage overall.
If Muzzin crosses the line
less than 11 seconds after Sommers...
... Muzzin will still be the winner
of the Hell of the West.
Sommers is finished.
He'll become the overall winner...
... if Muzzin doesn't cross the finish line
in the next 11 seconds.
Muzzin didn't make it.
David Sommers wins the final stage...
... and clinches the overall victory
in the Hell of the West.
A fantastic performance
by this young newcomer.
He has beaten the veterans this year
and made quite a name for himself.
Young David Sommers, a fantasticjob!
Let's give all these riders
a big round of applause as they come in.
What a finish here today!
Mrs. Sommers, would you come up?
How about some smiles?
Next year.
Come on, look over here.
Come on, give us a smile.
Over here. Look out.
That's it. Picture, please.
That's it, that's it. Thank you.