Subtitles ripped by tiger6ex
(c) BitShock.org TEAM
(ALARM BEEPING)
I know what I have to do today, Maryam.
MAN ON RADIO: HomeIand Security
officiaIs say the current high aIert
is directIy reIated
to the discovery Iast night
of homemade expIosives
at a warehouse in Los AngeIes
owned by a MusIim maIe
The Iocation of the warehouse
and the identity of the owner
have not yet been discIosed
by the Department,
but unnamed sources
in HomeIand Security
-Why am I a MusIim?
-What?
Why did you have to
name me Mohammed?
I named you after our own prophet.
And you're MusIim because I am MusIim.
Everyone at schooI is Jewish or Christian.
AII the same.
AII beIieve in one God.
What if I wasn't born MusIim?
It is your journey, habibi
You have a great heart,
just Iike your mother.
BIess her souI in heaven.
Can we get a Christmas tree?
(WOMAN CHA TTERING ON PA)
Mohammed, we have to get there.
WaIk fast.
Sabir.
There. Mohammed, Sabir's here.
Mohammed?
Mohammed. Mohammed.
Mohammed.
Hammo. Mohammed.
Mohammed!
I have a possibIe 10-107 in progress.
(MUSTAFA SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
Mohammed.
-Sorry, ma'am. I'm sorry.
-It's okay.
I'm reaIIy sorry.
-I'm sorry.
HaIt. FederaI agents.
-I'm Iooking for my son.
-Stay caIm.
AII right, get him up. Get him up.
-Sir, I'm Iooking for my son.
-Come on.
Come with us. Come on, Iet's go.
MUSTAFA: I was Iooking for my son.
I didn't do anything.
Where are you taking me, sir?
(AIRPLANE PASSING OVERHEAD )
Mr. Marzoke, I'm Agent Stevens, FBI.
FBI? Where is my son?
Look, your son is safe in the other room.
Why were you running
around the airport yeIIing, sir?
I was Iooking for my son.
Do you read the papers, sir?
You reaIize we're on high aIert?
I thought I Iost him.
What is your business
at the airport today?
I'm picking up my cousin.
-And what's his business in the US?
-No business, just personaI.
We did a search of your vehicIe,
Mr. Marzoke.
We found aII of these items.
CouId you identify them, pIease?
WeII, I Iisten and I read the Quran.
Is that a crime now?
The Quran.
These receipts...
What are these?
Money transfer. Donations.
Donations. I see.
Donations to the Sharia Foundation
in Egypt.
Why do you make donations
to the Sharia Foundation?
Sir, I'm a MusIim.
One of the five piIIars of IsIam
is to give zakat
I don't know if you know about zakat
It's an IsIamic Iaw.
When was the Iast time you were
at the Muhammad AIi Mosque?
-Muhammad AIi?
-Yes. BeautifuI pIace.
AIabaster, the taII minarets,
the view from the top, the pyramids.
-You've been there?
-Last month.
You have a very rich cuIture, Mr. Marzoke.
Now imagine if some fundamentaIist
Christian nut jobs from the US
fIew a jet passenger pIane
into the Muhammad AIi Mosque
or another one
of your renowned monuments,
kiIIing thousands of innocent Egyptians.
I'm sure that you'd be busting
every infideI stupid enough
to go around screaming EngIish
in the Cairo airport, wouIdn't you?
Let me give you a word of advice.
You be very mindfuI of how you act
and speak in pubIic.
When we're under high aIert,
peopIe get trigger-happy.
You got it?
It's okay, Mohammed.
-Are you aII right?
-Yeah, it was just a big mistake.
A big mistake.
-You hungry, Sabir?
-Later, Iater.
I want you to trace these transfers.
Where he sent them from,
who he sent them to.
Get me bank statements,
e-maiIs, Iibrary accounts,
subscriptions, postaI records.
The whoIe nine yards.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Piece of shit.
God, I hate this dump.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Can I heIp you, sir?
I toId this asshoIe 100 times,
no sauce on my faIafeI.
I'm supposed to ask you
to not use words Iike that in here, sir.
This is stupid.
LEILA: AbduIIa, pIease make
the gentIeman another faIafeI.
No sauce this time.
Are you serious?
(SIGHING)
-LeiIa.
-What's up, Fikry?
It's hot, man. Air conditioner working?
Yeah, sure.
It just makes that noise to mess with you.
Smartass.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(ROCKMUSIC PLA YING)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
-Fikry.
-Mustafa.
Next time, Pops,
if you're gonna punch in Iate,
just give me a caII, okay?
It's been a rough day.
Don't start with me, okay, pIease?
-Where are you going?
-I have a Iife, too, remember?
-Okay, don't forget to be home earIy...
-I know.
It's a speciaI night. I know.
Be home earIy for dinner.
GIRL: Hey, what's up?
LEILA: Let's get out of here.
-Mustafa.
-Fikry.
What's wrong?
I get this feeIing sometimes
Iike I'm going to expIode.
Don't do that.
We've had enough expIosions.
AbduIIa, Sam is coming by Iater.
Have his coffee and bakIava ready for him.
-Again? For free?
-Just have it ready.
You know, that guy never
pays for anything, never!
He thinks I work for him.
MURAD: Oh!
It is hotter than heII.
What's up, Fiky Frik, Big M?
AbduIIa in the house.
Turn on the TV. You seen this?
I want to show
what these bastards are doing now.
Despite repeated requests,
American authorities
have not made avaiIabIe
any evidence of expIosives or weapons
See, that's what I'm taIking about.
You see that?
You know, they cook aII this stuff up.
AII this heightened-state-of-aIert buIIshit.
It's aII buIIshit, red, green, fuchsia.
I mean, they just want peopIe
scared shitIess of peopIe Iike us.
Murad, you see a conspiracy
in everything, man.
Mustafa, you teII him. I've tried.
ActuaIIy, I got arrested
today at the airport.
-What?
-What happened?
Nothing. A mistake. I'II teII you Iater.
A mistake? That's some serious shit, M.
I mean, they can make
your Iife heII in this country
if they get you on one of their Iists.
They wiII Iock your ass up
in one of those ships off the coast
in internationaI waters
and they wiII torture your ass
untiI you sign a confession.
Murad, I got bigger probIems
than torture ships, Murad.
Keeping this pIace afIoat,
that's my torture.
Maybe this pIace fIoat
if you don't give away
so much free food, huh?
Thank you, AbduIIa. He's right.
I need to make money, reaI money.
Why you need money
so badIy aII of a sudden?
Because I wouId Iove to open
a new restaurant, a reaI restaurant,
with reaI Mideastern food, Iike back home.
There is a pIace on Washington I Iike.
That's gonna cost some serious G, M.
So? Why not? Maybe I'II get a partner.
This is America.
Maybe I'II partner with someone Iike Sam.
-Sam the Jew?
-So?
So? Sam the Sephardic fucking Jew.
Murad, business is business.
Fikry here is Christian.
You're doing business with him.
-He's not a Iand grabber.
-What's Ieft for an Iraqi Christian to grab?
Murad, Sam is Jewish,
but that doesn't make him a Zionist.
I trust him and he's a good businessman.
That's what I need.
-You asked him aIready?
-Yeah, he's researching the numbers.
Sure, sure, he's researching the numbers.
Of course he is.
He's gonna research those numbers,
he's gonna go behind your back,
he's gonna buy that buiIding,
he's gonna jack your idea.
I'm teIIing you,
he wiII not partner with a MusIim.
You feeIing me? You're gonna end up
being his empIoyee bitch.
If you don't mind, guys, I've had enough of
''It's hard being a MusIim'' for one day.
I need to change,
and there is an important
visitor coming by Iater.
So be nice to him.
More important than us?
Easy on the sauce, okay?
Everybody compIains.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Just easy on the sauce.
MAN ON RADIO:
The ongoing investigation
into what is now being referred to
as a terrorist arms depot in Los AngeIes
has netted severaI suspects
and authorities say arrests are imminent
Some of the expIosive materiaIs
have now been identified
as being both Iraqi
and US miIitary in origin
Taxi!
-Hi.
-Yeah, okay. Get in, Iady.
-HeIIo.
-To what do I owe this surprise?
-I'm free untiI evening rehearsaI.
Thought I'd give you a Iift
to your appointment.
Oh, weII, I guess it pays
to sIeep with a cab driver after aII,
especiaIIy one with a seven-episode deaI
on a new series.
Yeah, which is why I thought
I couId finaIIy...
Afford this.
Omar.
You're doing this
because you want to, right?
-Not because...
-Kate, I want to.
(WOMAN CHA TTERING ON PA)
-Good night.
-SaIwah?
Yes.
I haven't seen you in forever.
Oh, weII, I've been here.
Hey, um...
-Yes.
-Do you want to someday, if you're free...
Do you want to have dinner with me?
Do you Iike Japanese?
I'm a heII of a sushi chef,
if I do say so myseIf.
Oh. No, I...
I have to teII you I'm going to get...
I'm... I'm...
(CLEARING THROAT)
I'm going to be Iate.
(CLATTERING)
(MIDDLE EASTERN MUSIC PLA YING)
(DOOR OPENING)
Our movie star!
What's with the air conditioner?
It's boiIing in here.
What, you expected it to work?
I Iike it. When I'm here
I can reIate to my peopIe in Iraq.
Kate, SaIwah caIIed. She's Iate.
I can run some errands.
Just teII her to caII me, okay?
I want to teII SaIwah myseIf, okay?
What's up, my homie-omie?
-How did we do?
-$900, more or Iess.
That's it?
Your other business... Are you busy?
We have first run-through tonight,
camera rehearsaI.
Pick good roIes. Be smart.
Think about the future.
It's funny you say that.
I just proposed to Kate.
What, are you getting married?
Fantastic, Omar!
Omar is getting married.
Huh?
Fresh bakIava and tea on me.
I make it myseIf.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Come here. Come here, come here.
CongratuIations.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
MURAD: So, yo, big shot,
you making enough money
to support a wifey now?
I Ianded a good roIe finaIIy,
and on a good show, American Safety
Don't teII me, they're gonna have you
pIay a terrorist again.
No, not this time. A doctor.
Hey, that's a good part for you.
Yeah, no more Arab bad guys, inshaIIah
Yeah, inshaIIah,
but don't get your hopes
up too high, homie,
because as Iong as the Jews
controI HoIIywood...
That's a myth.
-TaIent wins in this town, that's aII.
-For reaI?
So then how come there ain't
no successfuI Arab actors?
-There are.
-Who?
-Omar Sharif.
-He's a Jew.
He's not a Jew.
He was Christian and became a MusIim.
-He's a Jew.
-He's not a Jew.
He's a Jew. They're aII Jews.
Name a known actor who's not a Jew.
-Antonio Banderas.
-Big Sephardic Jew.
He's not a Jew. Anyway, you'II see.
I'm going to be the Antonio Banderas
of the Arabs one day.
Yeah, one day the GirI Scouts
are gonna seII cookies
for the MusIim brotherhood, too,
you know.
Murad, you watch too much AI Jazeera.
It feeds your constant fear of the West.
Yeah, and Zionist American propaganda
feeds your constant fear
of your own MiddIe Eastern peopIe.
-Check that shit on Fox.
-Fox.
Murad, enough aIready. Read the sign.
''No poIitics or reIigious discussion
aIIowed in this estabIishment.
''The management.'' That's me.
That is, but that sign does
not say ''discussion,'' M.
Whoever made that sign Ieft that shit out.
Ya Ya make it.
His EngIish Iike mine, not that good.
-But he's cheap.
-What do you mean, ''his EngIish''?
He's iIIiterate in Arabic aIso, man.
Oh.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
You know the way.
You were saying, M, about reIigion?
I have to get the Iight on for them.
I'II get you the Iight. I'm sorry.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(PRAYING IN ARABIC)
SaIwah, Kate was here. Give her a caII.
I need to set up.
Sam is coming any minute.
You hungry?
MURAD: I Iose, and now I got this.
Hey, Sam.
Look at this guy.
-Sam, how are you?
-Mustafa.
Have a seat. SaIwah's setting up.
-SAM: How's it going, Fikry?
-Good, Sam.
-Omar.
-Hey, Sam.
MUSTAFA: AbduIIa,
coffee and bakIava for Sam.
So, Mustafa, you try those dates
we brought in Iast week?
-The best, right?
-SoId in two days.
Funny, we were just taIking
about those beautifuI dates
that they used to grow in Iraq
before the US government
decided that oiI was sweeter.
You're feeIing me. I know you are, Fikry.
It's aII about the oiI.
It's not about this democracy shit
they keep feeding us.
It's about the oiI.
And IsraeI.
Sam, I'm ready for you.
Excuse me, gentIemen.
(DOOR OPENING)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Sabir, you made it!
Sabir, my cousin, came from Egypt.
(ALL EX CLAIMING)
Hey, Sabir.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
-You rested?
-Later, Iater.
SaIwah's here. Let's go in.
SaIwah, Sabir is here.
Ow! Ow!
SaIwah.
Sorry, Sam. Sabir came
aII the way from Egypt to see SaIwah.
-Remember him now?
-Yes.
-Hi, Sabir.
-HeIIo.
Nice to meet you, Sabir.
What brings you to LA?
Mustafa and I have business.
Okay, you guys finish. Let's go. Let's go.
What was that about?
He's my future husband, supposedIy.
I didn't know you were engaged.
Hmm.
I didn't either.
I don't get you.
Our famiIy aIways taIked about
me marrying my first cousin.
It's a tradition.
I'm sorry.
Ow.
Mustafa's not Iike that.
He doesn't hoId onto
oId tribaI notions Iike that.
Mustafa thinks it's his duty.
You're joking.
(MEN SPEAKING ARABIC)
They arrest MusIims
and jaiI them aII the time.
You know what I'm saying?
No charges, no evidence.
They just, poof, disappear.
Yeah, we hear how badIy Arabs
are treated in this country.
What happened today
was very, very frightening.
You know, Sabir,
9/1 1 was not a smaII thing.
We and everybody eIse wiII pay the price.
Yo, M, who ''Everybody eIse''?
It's the Arabs
that are paying the price, brother.
Murad, you act as if
we're the onIy ones, man.
It's part of a hazing process, you know?
It happened to the Irish,
the Japanese before us.
We're the newcomers now, that's aII.
Yeah, but it happened here in this country.
See, the fucking probIem is
the peopIe in the MiddIe East
are paying the price so that Americans
can Iive their American dream.
SUVs, subsidized gas, fucking fast food.
I don't understand
why you want to Iive here at aII.
When you get married and settIe,
you wiII see.
This is a good country.
And a good peopIe, too.
Thank you, SaIwah. This is for you.
Thank you.
Mustafa, do you have a minute
to taIk about business?
Yes, Sam. Come in the back.
I'II teII you what the probIem is.
It's the fucking Iand grabbers.
Here I thought it was
the fucking IsIamic terrorists.
Murad.
Sabir, go to SaIwah.
Have a seat.
So, you Iike doing this?
Sabir, I'm sorry. This is...
This is very strange for me. I...
I need to get to know you. I...
I need to take some time,
but right now I have
another cIient coming in.
Sam, this pIace...
Every time I fix something,
something eIse breaks.
Yeah, I know, I know.
Okay, Iisten, Mustafa,
I had an inspector check out that buiIding
and my accountant ran the numbers.
-Yeah?
-And it Iooks pretty good.
That's great, Sam.
I promise you,
we'II have the best Egyptian food in town.
-We're gonna make a difference.
-I agree. I agree.
I brought you cookies from Egypt.
I'm sure they're deIicious.
Try one. You'II Iove it.
I can't. I watch my diet.
But I'm sure the famiIy wiII Iove them.
(MIDDLE EASTERN MUSIC PLA YING)
-Atmosphere is important, right?
-Sure, sure.
We can't have certain eIements around.
I understand.
Not in the new pIace if we want it to work,
because it's not a sociaI cIub.
-I mean, you understand.
-I understand. Sure, Sam, sure.
-No eIements, no probIem.
-Good, good.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
The Mohammeds.
AII these guys named Mohammed.
They need room to pray.
-You know what your probIem is, Fikry?
-FIKRY: No, what is my probIem? TeII me.
You're what we caII a seIf-hating Arab.
That's ridicuIous.
You say that because I'm a Christian,
Iike I'm not even Arab.
MURAD: I didn't say
you're not an Arab, Fikry.
Let me teII you,
when I waIk down the street
the rednecks yeII ''toweIhead'' at me aIso.
Yes, yes, yes,
I'II teII you what my probIem is.
My probIem is that my country
has been invaded by peopIe
of my own reIigion.
And now the Jews and the MusIims
have stoIen even my victimhood from me.
That's my probIem.
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
-Hi, Sam.
-Hi, Kate.
So my cousin's, Iike,
in the Marines in Afghanistan, okay?
And he brought back this hash.
I mean, this shit's coId-bIooded.
Been meaning to ask you something.
How come every time I turn on the news
there's some MusIim dude
who's pissed off and kiIIing everybody?
Why do you hate America so much?
Maybe if you'd educate yourseIf,
you wouId know the whoIe story.
So teII me the whoIe story.
It's Iong. I don't remember it aII.
It's, Iike, 1,400 years oId.
So teII me what you know.
I want to hear it.
AII right. Pass the rocket.
Once upon a time before the oiI, the sheiks
and aII of the Saddams and Osamas,
in the middIe of the Arabian Desert
was this cooI dude named Mohammed
His homies caIIed him ''the honest ''
He used to kick back and meditate
And one day an angeI appeared to him
with a new reveIation caIIed IsIam
It means ''Submission to God ''
The God of Abraham, Moses and Jesus
Back then, the IocaI yokeIs beIieved
in a bunch of different gods
But when the angeI gave Mohammed
the message that there's onIy one God,
they dumped the whoIe
idoI-worship thing
See, according to Mohammed's prophecy,
God wouId free everybody from sIavery
Dudes, babes, rich, poor,
bIack, white, whatever
Everybody was equaI
They were aII over that in a heartbeat
So freedom and IsIam began
to spread throughout Arabia
And it kept on spreading
to India and aII the way to China,
then across North Africa to Spain
This was the start of IsIamic civiIization
Back then MusIims were, Iike, top dog
when it came to art,
science, Iiterature and poetry
So pretty soon the buzz hit the West,
onIy back then Europe was, Iike,
a bunch of barbarians
busy barbecuing pIague victims
But you know what? They didn't dig these
dark dudes with sand aII over their feet
And that's, Iike, where I think
the word ''sand nigger'' comes from
So they said no way to IsIam
This brought on the period
known as the Crusades,
which was, Iike, a downer for everybody,
especiaIIy MusIims Iiving in JerusaIem
who got royaIIy reamed out
by Christian armies fighting
to take back the HoIy Land for the Pope
But finaIIy, this other reaI cooI Kurdish
MusIim dude named SaIadin shows up
and unites the Arabs
to fight the Europeans
and take JerusaIem back
See, difference is, under SaIadin
there's, Iike, this time of peace
with Jews, Christians and MusIims
aII kicking it together,
which is dope, because JerusaIem 's,
Iike, a hoIy pIace for aII three reIigions
But guess what? That didn't Iast
The Europeans came back even stronger
with, Iike, a divide-and-conquer thing
They gave the Iand the PaIestinians
were Iiving on to the Jews,
and that became the new IsraeI
And once the Euro-honkies spIit,
there was, Iike, constant fighting
between the IsraeIis
and Arabs over JerusaIem
'Cause both the IsraeIi and Arab radicaIs
wanted to have it aII
If they'd just chiII,
they'd see JerusaIem is a spirituaI pIace,
the Iand of miIk and honey
But, no, because now
some Americans come in
to check out what aII the fuss is about,
and they discover oiI
And to keep the pumps happening,
they prop up these greedy dictators
who seII onIy to them,
and they don't heIp the Arabs,
onIy IsraeI, which pisses the Arabs off
So then you get the IsraeIis
and PaIestinians
fighting over JerusaIem
and bIowing each other up,
whiIe the worId just watches
and pIays it aII Iike some kind of game
And that's why the MiddIe East
is a fricking mess
'Cause there ain't no more cooI dudes.
Whoa.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
-Omar, how's it going?
-Great. Looking forward to this.
-Good.
-You wanted to see me?
Yeah, there's some script changes
I wanted to taIk to you about.
Look, I'm sorry to say this,
but the doctor roIe has been cut.
-Cut?
-Yeah. Let's taIk over here.
Um...
Okay, Iook,
they rewrote the entire episode Iast night.
It's practicaIIy a new show.
-I don't beIieve it.
-Omar, I Iove your work.
I want you to stay, but I'd have to ask you
to change roIes at the Iast minute.
I'II do it.
ReaIIy?
You're the best.
AII right, weII, here are the new pages.
And take a Iook at the roIe of AIi.
-AIi?
-Yeah, we'II run through it shortIy, okay?
Can you get Omar
someone to heIp him suit up?
WOMAN:
HoId the noise, pIease, peopIe.
DIRECTOR: Action, Omar!
OMAR: Everyone on your knees.
You're being taken hostage.
Um. Okay, cut, Iet's cut. Can we cut?
MAN: Cut!
You okay? What's up?
I don't understand. Why wouId
a terrorist take over a hospitaI?
Terrorists want to strike fear
in the heart of America.
That's what the episode's about.
So they're at a hospitaI.
There's a Iot of peopIe,
very IittIe security, okay?
But you know this hospitaI
is in a quiet IittIe community.
It's a show, Omar.
We give our heroes of American Safety
heroic things every week, aII right?
So, just give me more accent,
and, you know, scary, aII right?
Okay, everybody. Back to one.
MAN: We're back to one.
OMAR: Everyone on your knees!
You're being taken hostage!
We are the soIdiers of AIIah!
Great. Cut! AII right.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MUSTAFA: Meet your second cousin.
This is Sabir.
MOHAMMED: What's up?
MUSTAFA: Everybody. Let's eat.
MUSTAFA: Yeah, come, Iet's eat.
SABIR: So your friend Murad...
He teIIs me you're thinking
of opening a new pIace.
Maybe with this man Sam.
-I think he's a...
-A Jewish man.
I just see him as a good businessman.
It's true. They're good with money.
But he can use this against you.
Just turn on the TV,
see what they're doing.
Sabir, not too Iong ago in Egypt,
Jews and MusIims had business together.
But how much interest did they charge us?
Mohammed, put that away, pIease.
It's broken anyway.
You broke it?
Do you know how much this cost?
So, Sabir,
you own your pharmacy in Egypt.
SaIwah here is a nurse.
A nurse?
So why do you do this saIon work?
It's extra money.
Um, I'd Iike to ask, how do you feeI
about women working?
After marriage, I mean.
To be honest, it's better
for women to stay at home.
So you beIieve that women are born
to raise chiIdren and to be wives,
but not to find their own work?
SaIwah, what Sabir tried to say here,
to have a strong famiIy
is very important for a mother...
Okay, okay, Iet me ask Sabir directIy,
if I may.
If we were to be married,
wouId you expect me
to give up my saIon and quit nursing?
I don't think it wiII be an issue.
I'd prefer to stay in Egypt.
I don't think America
is a good pIace to raise a famiIy.
Excuse me, pIease.
SaIwah, it is aIways hard at first.
You guys just met.
Oh.
So I shouId wait and move back
to Egypt when it's Iess hard.
He wiII change his mind
when he gets to know you.
I don't know how to say this,
but you're aImost 30.
(LAUGHING)
That's nice. That's very nice.
Just Iet me finish.
You are a MusIim woman
Iiving in America.
So I don't have a Iot of options, you mean?
Because I am a MusIim,
I have to marry a MusIim?
That's not for you to decide.
I want you to have your own kids,
your own home.
-I want you to be happy.
-You want me to be happy
or this wiII make you happy?
This is what our father aIways wanted.
Listen, get to know him.
Just give him a chance.
You heard how he referred
to me at the cafe today?
''I have business with Mustafa.''
That's how he thinks of me, business.
(SIGHING)
WOMAN ON TV: In Los AngeIes,
HomeIand Security officiaIs
have made severaI arrests
in connection with the recent terror threat
that has raised the aIert IeveI to code red
No names have been reIeased,
but one officiaI said
that more arrests were forthcoming
and that, quote,
''A far Iarger IsIamist network has been
uncovered than originaIIy suspected ''
I can't beIieve this shit, M.
What's wrong with you, Murad?
PaIestinian this, PaIestinian that.
Fuck them ! I'm tired of their buIIshit.
They are ruining our Iives, those bastards.
And now, Arab dictators are controIIing us
in the name of the PaIestinian cause.
Why don't we just hand the Iand over
to those motherfuckers,
because they're just going to take it.
Come on, man,
you can't say that about the PaIestinians.
-Why not?
-'Cause it's unfair.
And it's poIiticaIIy stupid, especiaIIy now.
They've been kicked out of Lebanon,
they've been kicked out of Jordan.
If they Iost their Iand,
where wouId they go?
I'II teII you where. FIorida.
Take aII the Jews,
because there's a Iot of them in FIorida,
move them to IsraeI,
and take the PaIestinians
and Iet them Iive in FIorida,
or maybe Cuba.
No, I teII you what,
I have the perfect soIution
to the probIem in the MiddIe East.
AII the PaIestinians shouId convert
to Judaism and become IsraeIi.
He's meIting.
You've gone out of your goddamn mind.
No, aII the Arabs
shouId become Jewish, man.
That'II soIve the probIem once and for aII.
Why wouId anyone want
to be Arab these days?
But to be Jewish, that's cooI, man.
You get the support of everyone.
You guys stiII going on about that?
Oppression's stiII going on,
Sephardic Sam.
Why shouIdn't we be going on?
Murad, the truth is, the fact is,
you Jordanians kiII more PaIestinians
than anybody eIse.
BuIIshit. BuIIshit.
You know what? You bageI munchers,
you steaI their Iand,
you destroy their homes,
you shoot missiIes from the sky
into streets fuII of innocent peopIe...
You prefer to bIow up buses
and airpIanes fuII of innocent peopIe.
-Jesus, enough.
-Murad, caIm down.
-Look at him.
-Sit down.
I'm sorry.
I just came by to apoIogize
for waIking out yesterday.
-Mustafa.
-Just sit down.
-Not now, AbduIIa.
-Mustafa.
But it's this...
This infIammatory shit,
which I guess you watch 24 hours a day.
You're goddamn right I do.
I watch it 24 hours a day
because I Iike to stay informed,
accurateIy informed.
Misinformed.
American propaganda !
-No more TV. That's it.
-That's aII I'm saying.
That's aII I'm saying. No more TV.
-Does AI Jazeera have parentaI controIs?
-What?
I try what you say,
but they pray inside, the Mohammed.
He's a Mohammed,
I toId you, don't disturb them.
You want peace, but the ignorant
are brainwashed by the crap.
There's no peace
'cause there's no fucking justice.
Occupation and oppression
is why there's no peace!
What kind of peace
do you get from the great Arab tradition
of sending suicide bombers
into hoteI Iobbies
and coffee shops fuII of innocent chiIdren?
You're kiIIing the innocent chiIdren!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Enough! Enough!
You guys want to fight? Outside!
Don't touch him. Outside!
ABDULLA: Mustafa.
MUSTAFA: Go around them.
ABDULLA: They don't Iet me in.
MUSTAFA: I toId you, don't bother them.
I tried. I tried two times.
This is Habibi Cafe, man, not Hebrew Cafe.
Mohammed, what are you doing here?
It's Friday.
I thought we were meeting at the mosque.
I don't want to go to the mosque anymore.
Mustafa.
What?
Mustafa, Mohammeds won't Iet me in.
They pray inside and I can't get in.
Okay, have a seat. Have a seat.
Come. Give it to me.
MUSTAFA: I have to do
everything by myseIf.
-I tried three times. You try now.
-Okay.
Listen to this. Listen to this.
''Buy a Christmas tree from IsraeI,
where Christ was born.
''We ship to your door.''
They're seIIing PaIestine off
piece by piece, these motherfuckers.
(PRAYING IN ARABIC)
-Dad, are you okay?
-Yes, Mohammed. Yes, I'm okay.
What's the story about you
not going to the mosque?
I toId you,
I don't want to be a MusIim anymore.
Why, Mohammed?
And Murad said we can get
a Christmas tree by maiI.
Mohammed, for God's sake!
You are MusIim. We are MusIim.
We don't ceIebrate Christmas.
We ceIebrate our own hoIiday.
-We ceIebrate Ramadan.
-But Ramadan doesn't have a tree.
And Murad said we can get one
from those motherfuckers in IsraeI.
MURAD: You teII me what's happening.
Murad, what did you say
in front of my son?
Yo, chiII, M. What? I'II show you.
Read for yourseIf, a baby Christmas tree.
OnIy the Jews can make money off
the Christians by steaIing from the Arabs.
Stop with the Jew thing. I'm sick of it!
Mohammed, when Christmas
comes around, I'II buy you a tree.
Fikry, nobody's buying a tree
for Mohammed.
Yeah, buy it from JerusaIem for $29.99,
get it bIessed by a fucking rabbi.
That's it. Murad, outside.
Oh!
Fikry, Fikry, stay away.
I'm taIking to you as a friend, Murad.
You have to stop spreading aII this hatred.
And no more swearing,
especiaIIy in front of Mohammed.
I didn't swear.
You swear aII the time!
You don't hear yourseIf?
You're too angry.
Nobody Iistens to you when you're angry.
You're goddamn right I'm angry.
I am swoIe up.
Aren't you?
Look at what's happening to our peopIe.
That's it.
I'm warning you, if you don't stop,
I don't want to see you here.
What?
You're on their side now?
Fine. But I'm gonna
teII you something, Mustafa,
you are too accommodating.
You forget who you are.
You want to fit in maybe.
You, the Jew. The Jew, you.
You can't have it both ways.
Come on, come on.
(MIDDLE EASTERN MUSIC PLA YING)
(WOMEN CHA TTERING)
So you wear this when you get married?
It's supposed to make you exotic
for your husband.
(LAUGHING)
Omar toId me, SaIwah,
about your marriage.
(SIGHING)
You know, I don't even know the guy.
I haven't seen him since I was 12.
I hardIy remember that.
How can Mustafa expect you to marry
a man you don't even know?
It's tradition, you know.
The famiIy arranges it
to protect the woman.
Listen, it's none of my business, SaIwah,
but you need to marry a man
that you Iove, a man you want to...
I mean, isn't there somebody
that you'd Iike to, you know...
Shh!
-Kate.
-No one?
I reaIIy don't beIieve it.
Let's face it, SaIwah,
you're not the Virgin Mary.
Okay, okay, okay.
AII right, there is this doctor
at the hospitaI.
He's very nice. He's very cute.
And he kind of asked me out
for Japanese food at his house.
Okay, weII, there you go.
I think you shouId do it with him.
Kate, stop it.
I'm not gonna just do it with him.
WeII, do you Iike him?
So go out with him.
Why not? Because you're MusIim?
Look, even Omar struggIes
with the differences between us,
but it doesn't matter.
What do you mean?
He never toId his parents
we were Iiving together,
but aII that tradition stuff,
that just goes out the window
when there's Iove.
(MEN PRAYING IN ARABIC)
Mohammed, what is it?
You don't want to pray with us?
You want to taIk about it?
Did MusIims reaIIy kiII
aII those peopIe in the twin towers?
Listen to me, habibi
There are good MusIims and bad MusIims,
Iike aII other reIigions.
And the ones who fIew those pIanes
were bad and ignorant of IsIam.
Who's a good MusIim?
Muhammad AIi is a good MusIim.
He's a bIack guy, not an Egyptian.
Your dad is a MusIim and Egyptian.
Don't you count me?
CIosed? Where is LeiIa?
-Mr. Marzoke.
-What's going on?
We'd Iike to bring you in
for further questioning, if you don't mind.
-What for?
-We'II get into that.
No, go into it now.
Mr. Marzoke, I couId arrest you,
if that's what you want,
or you can come with us voIuntariIy
and show your wiIIingness to cooperate.
No, go ahead, arrest me.
I want a record of this.
I'm not gonna disappear
into one of your ceIIs
and nobody knows where I am.
I don't know where you get your ideas
of how we operate, sir,
but it's not Iike that.
I'm back, LeiIa.
Who's that? Do you work here, sir?
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Do you speak EngIish?
Do you have residency papers, sir?
Sir, what are you doing here?
-You!
-You have to come with us.
Leave him aIone! He didn't do anything!
-Take the kids away.
-Back off.
-He's not resisting. PIease, pIease don't.
-I have to take you in.
if the infideIs attacks our God,
it is our responsibiIity to defend Him
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
Are you ready? Ready!
That is tight. That is hot.
They're running this on prime time, dude.
You are gonna bIow the fuck up.
Give me.
Now remind me,
who got you on this MOW?
-You did, Dez.
-Give me some more. Give me some more.
Thank you.
Thank you, but I'm saying
it's another bad-guy Arab.
You know, this thing that happened with
American Safety
Dude, I got cIients
who'd gun down their granny
for one episode of this hot-shit series,
American Safety
And how many did you book? Seven?
Who is your fucking manager?
Dez, I'm gratefuI for the work,
for the MOW, too, reaIIy.
AII right.
I don't know, this kind of image
they want me to pIay, it's demeaning.
Worse, it's Iike, I don't know,
crushing my souI.
Omar, you'd better not even be thinking
about baiIing out on me on this.
Okay, they changed the roIe on you,
but you did the right thing.
You roIIed with it.
You turn around and back out now,
I'II never be abIe to book you again.
I fucking mean it.
We square?
Good.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Terry, get me Saperstein.
-Sorry, it's my fiance.
-No, it's cooI.
Kate, I'm Ieaving. I'II caII you.
What? Mustafa?
-AII right, teII SaIwah I'II be right there.
-You are bad, dude. You are bad.
Oh, yeah, I'm an accessory.
(LAUGHING)
But it'II happen again.
That's right. That's right.
I hear you. I hear you.
Dez...
Uh...
Hang on for one second.
Yeah?
I mean it.
After this, no more.
It's kiIIing me.
Omar.
Okay. AII right.
No more terrorists.
I'II see what I can do.
Okay? Go.
Go, go, eat your faIafeI, shish kebab,
whatever you want to caII them.
And have some espresso, too. Get a Iife.
Shit. Terry, I Iost him.
Yeah, get me Sap on the phone.
Sap? Sorry about that.
Yeah. Yeah.
SaIwah. What is it?
Come in. Come in, pIease.
SaIwah, are you okay?
MAN: Okay, Mr. Marzoke.
Come with me, pIease.
Sorry for aII the noise, Mr. Marzoke.
Where am I?
We maintain a presence
in a number of Iocations.
So, Mr. Marzoke,
you don't appear to have
much of a financiaI acumen
for someone who runs his own shop
and owns a car service.
As a matter of fact, you're in the red.
You're very near forecIosure.
-I'm struggIing. Is that a crime?
-No, no.
But since you are struggIing, as you say,
we were wondering how you couId afford
to make such sizabIe
monthIy wire transfers
to a terrorist organization.
I don't send the money to terrorists.
WeII, ''terrorist'' has a broad definition.
The Saudis don't consider HAMAS
to be a terrorist organization, for exampIe,
but the US government does.
I'm not a Saudi.
You send money to an entity
caIIed the Sharia Foundation.
Now, there is a charitabIe organization
caIIed the Sharia IsIamic Foundation.
And they've been known
to finance jihad studies
in madrasas worIdwide.
I toId you before, I just make zakat
No, these are not zakat
The Sharia Foundation is not a foundation.
It's a storefront operation.
OstensibIy it exports Egyptian music,
movies, the Quran on tape,
things of that type, but unofficiaIIy
it's a cash deIivery service.
It's not iIIegaI.
I don't use banks
because banks charge so much money
and it takes weeks
before the money cIears.
I know the man who owns the business.
I trust him more than banks.
-Where does the cash go?
-I know the man.
This man brings the money door-to-door.
-Where does it go?
-And in 24 hours the money is there.
-Answer me!
-A bank cannot do that.
Where does the cash go?
The government takes money from you,
taxes you...
-Answer my question. Where does it go?
-To my cousin, sir.
Why?
Because my father soId our Iand for me
so I can own my business here.
He soId it to his brother, Iike a Ioan,
with the promise that we'II buy it back.
Buying it back was my responsibiIity,
to make a Iife here,
to bring my sister over.
My father didn't Iive
to see the Iand come back.
Because aII these years
I've been trying to buy the Iand back.
And every night when I go to sIeep
I can hear my own father's voice saying,
''Mustafa,
''what happened to your promise?
What happened to your Iand?''
So you sent your money
through a hawaIa service
to buy your Iand back.
Why didn't you say that before?
Why did you teII me
it was a charitabIe donation?
Even my sister and my kids
don't know about this, sir.
Where I come from,
it is a shame for a man to Iose his Iand.
(GRUNTING)
LEILA: Dad's here. Dad!
LeiIa, Hammo.
Everything is okay. It's okay.
Daddy, what are we gonna do?
We're gonna Iive our Iives. You hear me?
I stiII beIieve in this country.
It wiII get better, okay?
-Thanks for seeing us, Sam.
-It's okay. It's important.
-Ben coming?
-No, he wanted us to taIk to you first.
Look, as far as I'm concerned,
nothing's changed.
We ran the numbers.
We projected that the pIace
wouId be into profits in two years.
This is not about profits, Sam.
Okay, you soId merchandise to this guy
for a coupIe of years. So what?
You don't know him. He's an Arab.
So it's not impossibIe
he's sending money to terrorists
who want to destroy IsraeI, is it?
You watch too much TV, David.
Okay, okay, Iet's not caII it terrorism then.
Let's say he supports
the Iiberation of PaIestine, okay?
It's not so far-fetched.
I mean, most of them do.
Sam, we haven't made a commitment yet.
I shook his hand.
I toId him that we couId make this work.
Besides, it's good business. We aII agreed.
So it's good business.
Why do we need him?
We have the capitaI.
-WeII, first off, he brought it to me.
-So offer him something.
Let him be the manager and the chef,
but don't cut him in as a partner.
He'II be gratefuI for anything you give him,
you'II see.
Okay, I've Iistened to what you had to say,
but Ben has the Iast word.
Why is there anything
to discuss with Ben?
I mean, who,
who anywhere in the entire worId
wouId want to have their money tied up
with some MusIim guy
who's under investigation
by the FBI, for Christ's sakes?
I mean, just answer me that.
MUSTAFA: What did you teII Sam?
I didn't teII him anything.
He didn't ask.
He voIunteered his Iawyer, Mustafa.
SaIwah, I can't afford a Iawyer.
I can't even pay Sam back for the baiI.
You need a Iawyer.
They're stiII investigating you.
They've frozen aII of your accounts.
Do you think that your probIems
are none of my business?
I thought I couId work it out.
By marrying me off to Sabir.
Shh!
You thought that if I marry him
you'II get the Iand back.
It's not just the Iand, SaIwah.
No, it kiIIs the two birds with one stone.
The Iand and your duty
to see that I'm married.
This is your Iand now.
And you can choose to Iive
with one foot over here
and one foot over there
if you want to, but not me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come, Sabir, come.
I think maybe this deaI our fathers made,
maybe it's a kind of curse for aII of us.
-No, Sabir.
-Wait. Let him finish.
AII my Iife I hear
how you are here in America,
a big success.
So I come here
with a IittIe bit of resentment, Mustafa.
-Why?
-No, it's true.
I come here resenting what you have.
Resenting America even.
But I Iook around and I see maybe
a famiIy that's not so happy.
I see your troubIes.
And I think maybe
what they say about MusIims
who come to Iive here is true.
They must give something up to Iive here.
But is it worth it?
I...
I got this fixed for Mohammed.
Good night.
-Thank you, Sabir.
-Good night.
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC ON TV)
OMAR: Are you ready? Ready?
MAN ON RADIO: Authorities have identified
and reIeased photographs of suspects
in the ongoing terrorist investigation
in Los AngeIes
that has resuIted in the nationaI aIert IeveI
being raised to code red
The four MiddIe Eastern
Omar, it stresses you out.
Okay.
Everyone at the bank saw your TV ad.
Great.
Omar the jihadi.
Come on, they were impressed.
Everyone says you're gonna be famous.
It's not so bad, you know.
You have a great roIe on American Safety
We shouId be ceIebrating.
You know, this American Safety job...
-I wanted to teII you...
-What?
You're starting your first episode today.
-Aren't you excited? I am.
-Yeah.
You're right, it shouId be ceIebrated.
We'II have another reason
to ceIebrate soon.
Omar, you're aII right with this, right?
You're not gonna judge me
differentIy Iater?
No, I just want our chiId to Iive in a pIace
where nobody wiII think
twice about his name,
where ''Nasser'' is just as American
as ''GiuIiani'' or ''Lieberman.''
It's gonna happen, Omar.
It is, okay?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-Dez.
-Omar, are you Iistening carefuIIy?
I just got back from
a IittIe breakfast meeting.
This is hot shit, homeboy.
This is big This is awesome
I'm taIking major studio, Ieading roIe.
Are you ready?
You got an audition in two hours.
-I got the script for you right here
-Dez, thank you. Thank you.
This is the kind of thing I wanted.
-You're gonna naiI it
-Yeah, I wiII.
-I'II naiI it, I promise. I'II naiI it.
AII right then
(LAUGHING)
(METALLIC POUNDING)
(GRUNTING)
Son of a bitch.
Hey, Murad. Come in.
Yo, M, you aII right? I heard.
Yeah, Sam caIIed his Iawyer for me.
-The Jew did that?
-Yeah, the Jew did this for me, Murad.
You know, about yesterday,
I just wanted to say that...
Murad, forget it.
We're friends for a Iong time.
Okay?
-I just want respect.
-You shouId have respect.
But we shouId respect other peopIe
or we're never going to puII ourseIves up.
You hear me?
-I do.
-Good.
Listen, I need to fix this pIace up
and seII it.
I need to put my Iife together.
Go have some coffee or tea.
Fikry here has started.
-Thank you.
-Murad.
Fikry, how are you, habibi?
What are you doing here?
-What are you doing here aIways?
-I was waiting for you.
-Can you fix it?
-I fix.
Not Iike you fixed the sign.
-What's wrong with the sign?
-WeII, you missed one word.
I give a good price!
What, you want one-word refund?
MUSTAFA: Thank you, Mrs Jensen
TeII Sam I appreciate it
Look, it shows that we soId the Iand
with the option that we can buy it back.
That's why I've been
sending money to Egypt.
So it's a deed.
Okay, we need to get it transIated.
But how Iong wiII it take?
I need to seII this pIace.
I need the money so I can
buy the new pIace with Sam.
I don't think you understand, Mr. Marzoke.
They have frozen aII your assets
untiI the investigation is over.
I advise you not to even try
to Iiquidate any property right now.
But this is my money.
You give me a few days.
(ESPRESSO MACHINE HISSING)
-WOMAN: Hi. Can I heIp you?
-Hi.
-One coffee, pIease.
-No probIem.
Hey, check this guy.
I saw him before, man,
Iike on the news or something,
but with the whoIe raghead business.
-You mean Iike the terror aIert thing?
-I don't know, man, but...
He just Ieft his backpack right behind you.
Hey, man.
-Is that your bag over there?
-Yeah.
Maybe you shouIdn't
be Ieaving it Iying around.
What?
You think I'm a suicide bomber?
Look, I've seen you before, man.
Yeah?
Where, on TV,
beheading an innocent reporter maybe?
WeII, you've got me pegged, man.
I am a terrorist.
And if you don't get out of my face,
my fucking face,
I'm gonna bIow this pIace up!
But first, I'm gonna have my coffee.
AII right? Okay?
Thanks.
Good evening, Iadies and gentIemen
This is TVLA 4 breaking news
Authorities have identified these men
as part of an ongoing
terrorist operation in Los AngeIes
AII are beIieved to be at Iarge
in the US or trying to enter
What's reaIIy going on?
I mean, what is reaIIy going on?
Do they cast actors for this crap?
Pretty soon everybody's gonna be
scared shitIess of anyone with a suntan.
MAN ON TV: It's a good time
for Americans to stay aIert
Murad, we aIready taIked about this.
No more news. Watch a movie.
I want peopIe to waIk here and Iook,
nice atmosphere.
No bad eIements. Okay?
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
OFFICER: You!
PIace your hands
behind the back of your head,
interIace your fingers and stand up.
Put your hands behind your head.
OFFICER: AII right, Mr. Nasser, you can go.
But I want to say this,
under the circumstances,
we take what you said very seriousIy.
Doesn't matter what the situation was
or how angry the other guy made you.
Do something Iike this again
and they're not gonna be
so forgiving next time.
-Got it?
-Yeah, sure.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
OMAR: Hey, wait.
I'm sorry I'm Iate. I apoIogize.
Omar, there's nothing I can do.
They're gone. It's over.
-Can't we rescheduIe?
-They cast the roIe. They shoot next week.
Look, I'm sorry.
They reaIIy wanted to see you,
but it's a done deaI.
I'm here.
LeiIa, where is Mohammed?
I thought he was with you.
No, you were supposed to bring him here.
-What about Sabir?
-They were both gone when I got up.
Phone home, see if they're back
and try SaIwah.
Okay.
You have to repIace aII these pipes.
They are no good.
Come on, Ya Ya.
MURAD: Yo, Omar.
We were just taIking about you.
Just saw your TV ad for your show.
I thought no more terrorists, man.
Hey, don't Iisten to him.
You're doing great.
You're gonna be a big star.
I have to run. We're shooting.
-How did we do?
-$750.
Omar, I know you're busy with acting.
That's great,
but I need a fuII-time driver, man.
I need the money.
You don't want me to drive for you now?
You focus on acting.
Let me take the cab off your hand.
I need... I need it, man.
Look, it's reaIIy a bad time for me.
Can we taIk?
Listen, I've got some probIem here.
Ya Ya's here fixing the thing.
I need to fix aII this situation.
-Mustafa, you're okay.
-Hey, Sam, how you doing?
Have a seat. We'II get you a shisha.
AII right. Won't say no to a shisha.
Look, Mustafa, it's very important,
something I didn't teII anybody.
Listen, thank you
for what you did yesterday.
Taking SaIwah to Sam,
it made aII the difference.
LeiIa, shisha for Sam.
Listen, Iisten.
Come back, we'II taIk, okay?
Ya Ya, taIk to me!
MURAD: Oh, whoa, Sam.
Don't suck so hard.
You need to treat it Iike a nippIe.
A nippIe.
Sorry.
You see that?
GentIe.
You Iike?
I knew that you wouId Iike that. Me, too.
Yes, you Iike
big fat juicy nippIes, just Iike me.
That's why I Iike Jewish women.
That's funny.
I got the idea
that you didn't Iike Jewish peopIe at aII.
No, man. What...
You're not feeIing me, Sam.
I Iove Jewish women.
The best sex that I ever had
was with a MusIim woman
and a Jewish woman at the same time.
You know how MusIims and Jews
fight over JerusaIem?
That's how they fought over my dick.
And I ain't buIIshitting you.
You need to hit that shit, Sammy.
WeII, somehow I think it wouId be hard
for me to get a MusIim woman into bed.
No. No.
Just convince them
that you're doing it for peace.
That's how you get them.
Peace, my friend.
Everybody fucks everybody eIse for peace.
I guess you got a point there.
-MUSTAFA: You okay, Sam?
-Yeah.
Yeah, Murad was just giving me
some new insights
into smoking a shisha.
MUSTAFA: Thank you, my friend,
for yesterday.
SAM: Oh, no. I'm sorry it happened.
(SAM COUGHING)
You okay? You seem...
I guess AngeIa toId you
they froze my money.
Yeah, yeah.
Mustafa, Iisten.
Maybe the timing isn't right.
-Yeah?
-Sam, you put the deposit on the buiIding,
I pay you my share
when I work my situation out.
-We'II have it in writing.
-No, yeah, yeah...
Look,
there are some compIications
that we have to address.
Your circumstances have changed, right?
-This is onIy a cash fIow probIem.
-No.
No. No.
Okay, Iook,
this is hard for me.
You know I'm in business
with my famiIy, right?
And my famiIy is run
Iike a corporation, beIieve me.
So untiI your IegaI situation is cIeared up
they want to offer you a different deaI.
They put up the totaI investment,
you run the pIace.
You want me to run the pIace for you?
Like a manager?
-No. No.
-Sam, we are partners, you and me.
Mustafa, don't take this the wrong way.
I have to teII you what they're saying.
You want me to work for your famiIy.
It's not what I want.
I'm getting outvoted here.
Do you understand?
What about our chance?
Let's just see what happens, okay?
Let's just see how it goes.
Okay?
Omar, you're Iate.
We've been trying to reach you.
-Yeah, Iook, I had a probIem.
-What do you mean?
Omar, what's up? We're waiting.
Those Iines, I can't say them.
You did them in rehearsaI
and you were cooI with it.
-No, I'm not cooI with it.
-Okay, but we're shooting, okay?
The show airs in a week.
They wiII seriousIy have your head
if you just waIk out in the middIe of this.
The scene has no sense.
The Iines are stupid.
Character isn't reaI.
I don't understand what he's trying to do.
Okay, he's a terrorist. He's fuII of hate.
That's aII you have to pIay.
No. That's what I'm saying.
That's exactIy wrong.
Wait, what's happening?
Omar has probIems with how his
character's being portrayed in the script.
It's a bit Iate for that, isn't it, Omar?
-Let's get on with it, bud.
-Don't caII me bud.
-Read the Iines and see how they sound.
-I have read the Iines.
And since I'm producing this show,
you're either gonna do the Iines
as they're written or I'II repIace you.
I don't care how Iate in the day it is.
Are you stupid
or don't care if it's propaganda or not?
AII right.
I'm gonna have to ask you to Ieave.
No, you Ieave. I'm taIking to her.
-Get security.
-MAN: Hey, over here.
-BeIieve this?
-I can't...
I mean, he's... I don't know what to do.
What's up?
Now, I'd advise you to go on your own
and not make them force you, okay?
AII right, everybody, back to work.
This is over.
-No, no, it's not over. It's not over.
-Hey, hey. Get this maniac off of me.
-Listen to me. Wait a minute.
-Get off of me.
-Wait, wait, wait. I want to...
-Listen.
-Wait!
Freeze!
MAN 1 : Get out!
Johnny, get out of here.
MAN 2: Down! Down!
MAN 3: Omar, chiII out, man.
JOHN: I was surprised
when you said you wanted to do this
Last time I saw you,
you practicaIIy sprinted away from me
SALWAH: I don't know what to say
TeII me about you.
I mean, you're a mystery to me.
-You're Egyptian, right?
-Yes.
Uh...
I was born there. That's aII.
(LAUGHING)
Okay, weII, I came here when I was 12.
And I went to schooI and to coIIege here.
So, reaIIy, you know, this is Iike my home.
Yeah, but stiII,
it must have been hard for you,
the transition from Egypt to America.
Uh...
No, not reaIIy, you know.
I wanted to fit in, so...
WeII, you know, Egypt's right at the top
of my Iist. You okay?
(COUGHING)
I Iove Egyptian history.
I Iove MiddIe Eastern music,
MiddIe Eastern food.
Every time I'm on the Westside,
I go to that...
What's the name of it?
It's an Egyptian pIace.
-Habibi's?
-Habibi's, yeah. It's a great pIace.
-That's my brother's pIace.
-Come on.
-ReaIIy? That's amazing.
-Yes.
What does it mean, ''habibi''?
''My Iove.''
Do you want to eat?
No.
We're at Coyote FiIm Studios
in East Los AngeIes,
where a gunman has seized
a number of hostages
Eyewitnesses say that the man,
an actor, Omar JamaI AbduI Nasser,
attacked members of a fiIm crew
and is hoIding the director, the producer
and others against their wiII
A security guard has been
reported to be shot
(KATE GASPING)
-Is this guy fIying soIo?
-He's a disgruntIed empIoyee.
He got picked up earIier for a simiIar thing.
I got a man
trying to penetrate from the roof up there
and another seeking
a vantage point from over here.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Why didn't you just Iisten?
Omar, pIease. It's just a TV show, okay?
It doesn't mean anything.
It means everything.
MAN ON TV: We're Iive at the studios
where the new TVseries
American Safety is fiImed
An Egyptian-born MusIim actor
and part-time cab driver Omar Nasser
-is stiII hoIding
-I don't understand.
the fiIm crew hostage at gunpoint
-How can this be?
-He didn't do it.
Change the channeI.
Put it on an Arab station.
-Hey, hey, hey!
-Leave it, Murad.
I just asked him to give up driving my cab.
That can't be it, Mustafa.
There has to be a probIem, man.
The probIem is this young generation.
They Iisten to their heart
and forget about their brain.
MURAD: You just wait.
If there is another 9/1 1
it wiII be safer for aII of us
to go back to Iraq with Fikry.
officers inspecting the roof of the studio
where Mr Nasser is hoIding the hostages
We don't know if poIice are preparing
any kind of assauIt on the studio,
but I've been assured
by the office authority
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Anybody working here?
LeiIa, see what he wants.
No, no, no.
-No, no, no. I'm sorry.
-What's wrong?
Wait.
I won't hurt you.
(GASPING)
No, stop.
Stop, pIease. I'm sorry, I...
-What did I do wrong?
-I thought...
I thought I couId do this,
but I can't.
It's...
It's not you. It's me.
You wouIdn't understand.
MURAD: I can't even beIieve it.
I don't beIieve what I'm seeing.
You Iiked it with a Iot of sauce, right?
You know what?
I come in here
and spend good money for service,
not to take a Ioad of crap off you.
Sir, you're taIking to my daughter.
I come in here aII the time.
Your daughter is rude to me.
I don't have to put up with this shit.
Sir, I'm asking you
not to speak Iike that here.
Or you'II what? Come on.
Look at you peopIe.
You're fucking pathetic.
-Who are you caIIing pathetic, bitch?
-You, and aII of you,
sitting around
bitching and moaning aII day
about how Arabs are treated,
fighting amongst yourseIves.
If that's the best you can do,
you deserve to have your asses kicked.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
WOMAN: You've got to Iet it go.
You can't win Iike this.
You'II just end up getting hurt.
I'm aIready hurt.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hanging in there? Good.
You want some water?
Keep the pressure on your Ieg
and keep stiII.
-Kate?
-Omar, what are you doing?
MAN ON TV: His name
is stiII being withheId
-What did the doctor say?
-He said...
-Put down the gun, Omar!
-No!
Put it down, Omar.
You're going to get hurt.
-Omar?
-The SWAT guys are on their way.
They wiII not hesitate to kiII you.
You have my word on that.
I was gonna Iet them go. It's an accident.
I beIieve you. I beIieve you.
I'm gonna put down my gun.
Now...
You step away from them.
You put your gun down now.
You can't arrest me.
I was gonna Iet them go.
Nobody's gonna do anything.
We're just gonna taIk.
I'II Iisten.
Omar?
My fiance, she's...
(GUN FIRING)
MAN ON TV: I've just heard a singIe shot
that sounded Iike a discharge
from a high-powered rifIe,
possibIy one of the sniper rifIes
PATRON: You deserve
to have your asses kicked.
MURAD: I'II kick your ass, you sand nigger.
PATRON: Me, sand nigger?
50 Cent wannabe,
trying to Iook Iike a bIack man.
You think peopIe in this country
think you're cooI?
Damn right they think I'm cooI.
You understand?
They don't think you're cooI, asshoIe.
Sir, I toId you, watch your Ianguage!
Excuse me,
I'm Iooking for Mustafa Marzoke.
I am Mustafa Marzoke.
What is your reaction
to your empIoyee, Omar Nasser,
being kiIIed by poIice tonight?
What?
MAN ON TV: EMS are coming out
with someone on a stretcher
Yes, we're getting reports
that the gunman, Omar Nasser,
has been shot and kiIIed by poIice,
and that aII the hostages are aIive
In fact, I am seeing the hostages now
No, no, no!
-They fucking murdered him !
-Stay.
Get the fuck out of my face!
Get the fuck out.
You peopIe, you fucking murder us.
You fucking fiIm our suffering
for your entertainment! Fuck you!
Murad, Murad, Omar is dead. He's dead.
What murder?
He takes peopIe hostage with a gun.
-What do you expect to happen?
-Fuck you!
-And fuck your American media !
-No, fuck the Arab media !
TeII me about your empIoyee,
Mr. Marzoke.
Did he have extremist poIiticaI
or reIigious views?
What? No.
WOMAN REPORTER: Do you
know if he has any connection
to any of the other MiddIe Eastern men
being arrested tonight by poIice?
He was our friend. Go away, pIease.
-Fucking cameI cocksucker.
-Go away! Go away!
(ALL SHOUTING)
-Out! We're cIosed!
-Okay. Okay. AII right.
PIease.
We're cIosed!
Out!
(SOBBING)
It's aII right. It's okay.
Mustafa, I heard about Omar...
Oh, my God.
Oh, my...
Who did this?
I did it. I did it aII.
What?
Mustafa...
You don't need to worry about me
or the Iand.
Do you understand?
You're reIeased from aII of that.
You've done your duty.
You've done more than enough.
You've made a new Iife for aII of us.
BEN: Sam, I've aIways respected
your decisions
and Iet you run the famiIy business,
but this time,
the famiIy thinks you're mistaken.
So I hear.
Then you're prepared
to get us out of this arrangement?
Ben.
I've aIways beIieved in our purpose.
I've aIways tried
to keep that foremost in my mind,
but if anyone asked me
to appIy that beIief,
or even money for that matter,
to the destruction of other peopIe's Iives,
I wouId draw the Iine.
WeII, I know Mustafa.
And I know that he is
the same kind of man.
We are tied together
by the same forefather.
More importantIy,
I beIieve we are tied together now, here.
We're Americans.
We can make a difference.
We can change things,
maybe show that catastrophe
isn't a foregone concIusion.
The everyday act
of breaking bread together
is more powerfuI than aII the hate.
MUSTAFA: Let's do it!
What's this? Wait. It's supposed to say,
''American MiddIe East.''
Ya Ya, what happened?
I write the way you teII me on the phone.
-What?
-I write the way you teII me on the phone.
I don't know what he said
or what you wrote,
but it's ''American MiddIe East.''
What's the difference?
He gave us a great price.
I can't argue with that.
SAM: Our investors.
MUSTAFA: Here come Fikry and
Murad and the four Mohammeds.
SAM: What are they doing here?
Murad, I thought no SUV.
-It's a hybrid, bitch.
-Mother bitch.
-Mustafa, Iook, we taIked about this.
-You know, good Iuck for us.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
we taIked about this, right?
This pIace is gonna be different.
It's a business, not a sociaI cIub.
-Sure, Sam. Sure.
-Let's just get them in.
-Whoa, we were here first.
-No, we come before you.
-No, you didn't.
-David, David, it's okay.
No, it's not okay.
Mr. BIoom is an investor.
He was here first.
Yo, March of the Penguins,
step off, boy, aII right?
-Murad...
-Just because you spend...
(ALL SHOUTING)
HeIIo, young man. Who are you?
I'm Mustafa's son
and my name is Mohammed.
Good. Let's go inside, shaII we?
-Are you hungry?
-Yeah, Iooks good.
Don't pay attention to them.
They don't know what they're doing.
Subtitles ripped by tiger6ex
(c) BitShock.org TEAM