I think I'm in a frame.
- Who's putting you in?
- I don't know.
All I see is a frame.
It's that Rheiman murder
out in Palm Springs.
You tricked with them?
Once. Just once. Favour to Leon.
- Two-timing bastard.
- I'm nice. I can't help it.
You check around for me?
Why don't you ask
your new friend Leon?
I may just do that.
You trick for other people,
cheat me out of money,
and then when you need a favour,
you come back to me.
If I help you...
you'll have to help me.
How?
You'll have to come back to me,
work strictly for me.
Wait a minute.
It's got nothing to do with that.
Like shit it doesn't.
I made you, Julie.
I taught you everything you know,
how to dress, how to behave,
how to treat women, how to make love.
Then you say, "I'm too good for you,"
and cut me out.
It ain't right, Julie.
Things are different.
I'm more than I used to be.
I'm getting older, Anne.
I got to keep moving forward.
Please, Julie, save me the speeches.
- How's your Swedish coming?
- I'll be ready.
She's flying in
from Stockholm on Thursday.
She apparently has certain
sexual idiosyncrasies.
Are you going to come back with me?
- You did it, didn't you?
- What?
The Rheiman killing.
Don't worry, Julie.
It doesn't matter.
Thank you.
It's been a wonderful evening.
- Can I see you again tomorrow?
- How about this one?
There was a sexy
girl from Borgan Place...
Do you live alone?
It's such a sweet face.
- No, not yet.
- Why not?
- Let's just kiss some more, OK?
- What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong. I just don't...
want to make love.
I love to be with you.
I love it when you kiss me
and when you touch me,
but when you make love,
you go to work.
If it's your period, I don't mind.
Don't give me that.
You know what I'm talking about.
I can't give you any pleasure,
and you can't fool me any more.
You don't know what you're saying.
Yes, I do...and so do you.
Yeah, I know.
You're talking about me giving up
what I am, what I do.
Is that so shocking?
I care about you. I really do.
That's still not enough.
It's all I'm good at.
That's not true.
It doesn't matter.
I can't quit anyway.
If I quit, I'm out on a limb.
Well, then we'd be even.
I'm already out on one.
People I know
take care of each other.
I need their protection.
I'm being framed by somebody.
I don't know who.
There was a murder, Palm Springs,
a couple weeks ago.
Police think I did it.
It was a woman. A woman I met once.
I wasn't there,
but my alibi completely denies it.
- Why would anyone do that to you?
- I can't figure that out.
- It doesn't make any sense.
- When was the murder?
A week ago Tuesday.
- Weren't we together that night?
- Baby, I wish we were.
All right,
boys, stand full-face, please.
This is bullshit. These cops...
Number three, take off your glasses.
Number two, straighten up.
Turn to your right.
No, Number three, to your right.
Jerk.
How much you getting paid?
What are you talking about?
I'm just a con.
So am I. I'm getting 15.
- You are?
- Yeah. 15 bucks.
Now left, please.
Left.
Thank you.
- The wino's getting 20.
- You're kidding.
You ain't getting paid,
you're getting screwed.
Shit! What the fuck's going on?
I want to speak to my lawyer!
You'll see your lawyer.
Get in line.
Make sure I speak to him.
Number one, turn to your right.
I know my rights. This isn't Russia.
We have a constitution here.
- I know my rights.
- Thank you. You can leave now.
How about this fuckin' jerk
here, three.
You getting paid, too?
What the fuck is going on?
Well, what do you think?
- Not bad.
- I'm gonna steal your thunder.
He's teaching me how to dress.
This is Lieutenant Curtis
from Palm Springs.
He's...
- He's in charge of this case.
- Wait a minute. I thought you were?
No, I'm in charge
of pimps, prostitutes and hustlers.
Pretty low on the pole.
Good joke, huh?
You've been identified, Julian.
- Julian.
- By whom?
Who could possibly identify me?
You parked 50 feet
from the Rheiman house
around 10:00 on the 22nd,
proceeded up the street
and entered the house.
- Someone saw you.
- I request formal charges...
I don't understand.
Who would say this? I was not there.
Then she identified
subject number one.
Then she wasn't sure
which one of you it was.
- You got the license number?
- She didn't see it.
- Shit!
- Right.
Here.
We looked around your house.
We had a warrant.
- We know.
- You recognise these?
- They were under your mattress.
- So what?
They had Mrs Rheiman's fingerprints
all over them. That's so what.
- Did you find the jewels?
- What jewels?
I read the paper, too.
Jewels stolen from Rheiman's house.
Whoever planted that money
probably planted the jewels.
There were no jewels.
Didn't you ever wonder
this may be a frame?
- It occurred to us.
- It occurred to you.
- Did you check Rheiman?
- He has an alibi.
- Big deal.
- You're grasping at straws.
What about Leon James, the black guy?
- He said you were high-class.
- What do you think?
I think you're guilty as sin.
I think you went to the Rheimans',
did a trick,
played some rough games.
You got drugged or stupid or both.
You beat her, killed her,
stole the money and the jewels.
Then there's no use talking further
until you press charges.
Whether we think Julian's guilty...
we're not going to arrest him.
If you're being framed,
you're gonna be more use to us
floating around.
Can we go now?
Just one more thing, Julian...
don't tell cons
they get paid for line- ups.
Some cops don't have
a sense of humour.
Hi. I'm here
to see Mrs Williams.
- I'm Julian Kay.
- I'll take care of this, Wilma.
- Julian, why are you here?
- Can I talk to you?
What about?
Were the police here?
There was a detective here.
I was very surprised
you used my name.
I'm very, very sorry
about that, Lisa,
but this is very important to me.
I told him the truth.
Lisa, you didn't,
I was with you until after midnight.
That's not the truth.
Julian, I can't...
you weren't here.
What is it, dear?
This is Julian Kay,
the one who is helping
with the decorating.
The boy who said he was with me
the night of that murder.
Mr Kay, it's bad enough
you made a fool of my wife
But then spreading lies...
- Leave us alone.
- I wasn't lying.
Whatever you did, you won't
to get out of it by dragging...
I just came here for the truth.
- I know you're lying.
- How do you know I'm lying?
Because I was here with my wife
the entire evening.
Thank you, Mr Kay.
You're not very good at this.
- What?
- Following people. You're lousy.
- What are you talking about?
- Who's paying you?
- You're not a cop.
- I'm calling the police.
You want to call? Go ahead, call.
What have we got here?
Floyd...Floyd Wicker. Nice name.
Born 7-23-52.
Hawthorne Avenue, LA.
Driver's license, American Express,
Mastercharge,
picture of girlfriend...
So-so,
eyes too close together, Floyd.
What else have we got?
California State
Congressional Library pass,
California State identification,
California...
State Senate pass...
Senator Charles Stratton.
- Who the fuck are you?
- You can read.
Here.
You work for Senator Stratton?
Yes.
- Why are you following me?
- I was told to.
- By the senator?
- Who else?
Why didn't he ask me
about my private life himself?
Huh? You don't know. You don't know.
Well, Floyd, I'm gonna
make this easy for you
so you don't forget.
This is my telephone number.
Now, you tell...the senator
if he wants to talk to me...
he can just give me a call,
all right?
Now, you fuck off
and leave me alone!
I received your message, Mr Kay.
- Thought I'd see you.
- Good evening, Senator.
- A vodka tonic.
- Yes, sir.
This is heartwarming.
Nice to see you haven't lost touch
with your constituency.
I'm not talking as a senator,
but as a husband.
That's too bad. I'm not a wife.
Very funny.
What do you want?
- Want?
- I know who you are.
I can't stop my wife being a fool,
but I can stop her
from being blackmailed.
- I don't know what you mean.
- You don't?
The police think you're involved
in a murder in Palm Springs.
Three days later,
you seduced my wife at a fund-raiser
to blackmail me into helping you.
- You're crazy, mister.
- Am I?
Last night, my wife asked me
about the Rheiman murder.
Didn't make any sense
till I heard about you.
You talked to Michelle about this?
You're not gonna blackmail me.
You don't know anything about this.
But I do know a whore when I see one.
How much?
Not to see your wife again?
5,000.
You'll have the cash in the morning.
I'm seeing Michelle
because I want to see her...
and because she wants to see me.
I don't want a dime from you.
That may be even simpler.
You live off the good graces
of a few people,
like Mrs Andros,
who was at the door a minute ago...
and of places such as this.
You're just a hanger-on.
Unless you want to find
a new crowd to hang onto,
don't see my wife again.
- How you doing?
- Not bad. How about you?
I'm looking for Leon James.
Seen him around?
Yeah. He's probably at Probe.
OK. Thanks. Take care.
Hey, Julie.
Hey, Jason.
I haven't seen you lately.
What brings you here?
Have you seen Leon around?
Oh, yeah.
He was showing off his new boy.
I think he's over there someplace.
OK, thanks.
Hey, Julie!
I thought that was you.
I've been looking for you.
I want to talk.
- Let's go out back.
- OK.
What you doing here?
You...coming from a funeral?
I hear you're
showing off a new boy.
I'm gonna make sure none
of these fruits snatch him from me.
You heard anything
about the Rheiman killing?
That's all I've heard about.
Cops on my ass like white on rice.
- They're giving me the third degree.
- Everybody else, too.
I may need your help.
I don't have an alibi.
You're the one that sent me.
You need one?
Yeah.
I'll see what I can do.
Who do you think killed her?
If I was the police,
I'd be more interested in Rheiman.
He's a freak, you know.
He's a freak...
but he's got an alibi.
An alibi?
Julie, I got something working
tonight, a little thing.
I'll cut you in on it
if you're interested.
Straight?
This time of night? Are you serious?
Leon, I'm sick of doing your shit.
No more fag stuff.
No more kink. Nothing.
- Finito! Got it?
- I heard about your problems.
What problems?
Your clientele, Julie,
your rich pussy.
They won't touch you.
They say it's too hot.
- They're looking for new boys.
- Fuck 'em. Fuck 'em!
Hey, Julie, listen...
you ask me to help you
out of a tight spot,
I'm glad to do it.
But I ask you to do my trick,
you say no.
Now, how you expect me
to help you, huh?
You give me the alibi,
then we'll talk about tricks.
- I have to talk to you.
- Hey, baby.
God, I'm glad to see you.
Are you OK? You look so worn out.
I didn't sleep much.
- Want to go for a walk?
- Yeah.
I'll get my shoes.
What's wrong?
Are you gonna tell me about it?
Hey.
Hey...you.
Come on, tell me.
When I said I didn't want
to make love to you,
I didn't mean it. I want to fuck you.
I always want to fuck you.
- Is that what you came to tell me?
- No.
Charles asked me to leave
for two months,
till the primaries are over.
I'm going to Rome.
Two months...
I'll be back. Wait for me.
I don't know if I can.
The police searched my apartment.
- Maybe Charles...
- That's not what I'm saying.
I don't know what I'm saying.
All my life...I've been
looking for something.
I don't even know what it is.
- Let me...
- Maybe you're what I'm looking for.
I gave Charles my word.
I've got to go.
It'll be all right.
Yeah.
I have to leave.
Shit!
I don't know.
I haven't seen him since yesterday.
- Tell me.
- I don't know. Honest.
The police have been
here all morning.
- Another cop's in his room.
- Does he call in?
I'm not supposed to tell.
OK. Next time he calls in
I've gotta talk to him.
Ask if I can meet him.
Do you know a blonde kid
that hangs around with Leon James?
Nah. Couldn't tell you.
Anne, I'm sorry.
I've got to talk to you.
I can't now.
I'm looking for somebody.
Perino's? Look, I don't have time.
Yeah, all right, Perino's. Yes, 8:30.
Jill, this is Julian.
Yeah, I know.
You got some messages for me?
Michelle?
Tell her to meet me at Perino's.
Son of a bitch, it's Rheiman.
Mr Julian.
You can't come in like this.
I was working. I forgot.
- I'll get you a jacket.
- No, it's OK.
Julie, you look like shit.
What's wrong?
- Everything. Straight bourbon.
- What are you doing?
The way you look
you couldn't get a maid to fuck you.
Anne, the cops are after me. They're
framing me for the Rheiman murder.
- Where have you been?
- Looking for somebody.
Last night?
Mrs Farfter came in last night
on a flight from Stockholm.
There was no one there to meet her.
She was furious.
I've got hell to pay. What happened?
Did you hear me?
I said the cops are after me...
for murder.
So you stand me up.
Jesus Christ!
What do you want?
Are you gonna help me?
I've checked around, Julie.
You are in trouble.
That's why I need your help.
You never did anything for me.
Never did anything for...
- I'm your number-one boy.
- And you fight me every turn.
You ask favours, then blow a gig
I worked six months to arrange.
- I explained that already.
- I'm through, Julie.
You'll have to fend for yourself.
I don't care
what happens to you any more.
Excuse me. I'll be back.
Julian, thank God you got my message.
I've been looking for you.
It's all right, baby. It's OK.
No, it's not all right.
Charles talked to the DA.
They found the weapon.
They're going to arrest you.
That can't be. It can't be.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
What can I do to help?
- Nothing.
- There's gotta be something.
Don't you understand?
I'm in big trouble.
- Just stay away.
- No.
There's gonna be a scandal.
You know what a scandal is?
You know what that's like?
Stay away from me.
I'll ruin your life, your husband's.
It's all over.
Not if you're innocent.
How do you know I'm innocent?
Look at me, right in the face
Can you tell me without hesitation
you know I'm innocent?
Yes.
Listen, forget me.
Is someone in there?
I never loved you.
- Julie?
- Let me in. It's important.
You look terrible.
You want to clean up, shave?
I'm sorry to bug you this late.
I've been looking for you.
I'm listening.
You got my alibi ready?
I'm gonna need it today.
It's not ready yet, Julie. Tomorrow.
I'm still piecing it together.
It's not easy.
I'm trying to get it right.
- Why are you framing me?
- What?
Judy Rheiman's murder...
you were behind it. You, Rheiman,
your cute little blonde
boyfriend in the bedroom there,
who planted the jewels in my car.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
What the fuck is that, then?
He's the one that
actually killed her, isn't he?
Leon, what happened?
You sent him out there
with Rheiman and his wife,
he got rough and he killed her.
Shut your fucking face!
I never saw that shit
before in my life.
I want to know one thing.
What will it cost
to get you off my back?
You ain't talking money,
you're talking murder.
- How much?
- I feel sorry for you.
How much?
It don't make no difference
how much, Julie.
The other side will always pay more.
Got it on real tight, huh?
You're real proud
of yourself, aren't you?
The police found the murder weapon
a block from your apartment.
That bitch in Palm Springs
is gonna change her mind
any time now and identify you.
Police want you real bad, Julie.
Now they got you.
Look, I'm worth maybe...
20, 30 grand. It's yours.
I'll break your new boys for you.
I'll work just for you.
Just for you, Leon,
40/60 split.
It's fair, 40/60.
40...
30/70. I'll...
I'll do fag tricks. I'll do kink.
I'll do anything you want me to!
Leave me alone and get out, Julie.
Why me?
Why did you pick me?
Because you were framable, Julie.
You stepped on too many toes.
Nobody cared about you.
I never liked you much myself.
Now get out.
Who's down there?
Your new boyfriend? You motherfucker!
Oh, my God!
Don't let me fall!
Please, Julie, help me!
Don't fall. I need you.
Give me your hand.
- Reach up.
- I'm trying.
Help me. Help me, please!
God! Don't fall!
Julian!
Would you answer a few questions?
- Who was involved?
- How old are you?
How long had you
been seeing Mrs Rheiman?
- Any Hollywood notables?
- How much money have you made?
Julian, give me an exclusive.
How much do you get for a trick?
Give me a break, Julian.
Do you feel
you're being framed, Julian?
Were you ever afraid of the husbands?
I wish I had arrested you earlier.
It would've been easier
for everybody.
You'd better end
this pretrial publicity.
We're moving him
to Palm Springs soon.
You have anything to say, Julian?
Julian?
No.
Hello, Julian.
Going away on your trip?
No. I decided not to.
- Does your husband know you're here?
- No.
Why did you come?
I didn't think
I'd ever see you again.
Don't come back, Michelle.
Are you satisfied with your lawyer?
It doesn't matter.
Don't go.
Michelle Stratton is paying
for my services, Julian.
I think you know this is
a matter of some secrecy.
Tell her not to bother.
Julian, you'll have to help us more.
You tell Michelle to forget me.
I'm more worried
about your defence, Julian,
than about her private life.
We'll must go into the details
the night of the murder.
The maid saw you trying to save Leon,
so the police are only pressing
the Rheiman case.
The papers and TV
are trying you already.
The police aren't
investigating any more.
We need some help, some facts,
to get the investigation going again.
Then we can find out
about Leon, Rheiman...
maybe the blonde boy.
How about it, Julian?
Lieutenant Curtis?
Yes, Mrs Stratton. This is an honour.
May I sit?
I was told you wanted to see me.
I want to talk to you about
the Julian Kay/Rheiman murder case.
Yes.
I'm paying
for Mr Kay's defence.
I know.
I'm paying for Mr Kay's defence
because I know he's not guilty.
I don't want
an obstruction of justice.
How do you know he's not guilty?
Because he wasn't
in Palm Springs that night.
- No?
- No. He was with me.
I told them, Julian.
I heard.
You didn't have to do that, Michelle.
You could have forgotten me.
I'd rather die.
What will you do now?
I don't know. I can't go home.
The newsmen
are waiting outside for me.
There's dozens of them.
Why did you do it?
I had no choice.
I love you.
My God, Michelle...
it's taken me so long
to come to you.
English