Oribinal English Subs by lemons
Found you!
Come. I'll show you something.
Just a second.
- What are you doing here, Jun?
- Don't go with Jerry!
Go home.
Your Mother must be looking for you.
What's this?
Why are we here?
Because we're alone here.
Jerry?
Hello, Sandra!
- No!
- Get her!
But this is seasonal.
I only did it for Mom.
Besides, I could probably bring her
to Canada in three years.
She won't need to work anymore.
- Thank you, honey.
- Plus...
she will be more relaxed
once we're there.
How about you?
Amiel?
- Mom! You scared it away!
- I'm sorry, Amiel.
- I didn't know.
- Aw, it flew away. Rommel will be sad.
Aww, Mom.
I'm so sorry.
At least you still have one.
But it will feel lonely.
Let's catch another one later, okay?
- There!
- Nobody move. Nobody move.
- Amiel, don't move.
- I'm not moving.
Get it, Rommel!
There's so much on your hair.
Mom, does beer taste good?
Beer?
You're still too young for that.
Wait till you grow up, okay?
Don't think about it right now.
I won't. Papa might get mad
if I ask him again.
Good boy.
Mom, can Rommel and
I play Aunt Lola's piano?
Sure.
Let me see.
Wow. Amiel's so handsome.
And Amiel's mommy is so beautiful.
Wait. Let me memorize your face
so I won't forget it.
I love you, son.
I love you, mom.
Rommel, let's practice?
Game.
Practice what?
We'll still go here even if
I can't see anymore, right?
I should learn my way
around the house, right?
Start practicing now.
Eight steps forward.
One to the left. Go.
Retinitis Pigmentosa, auntie.
There's no cure.
It's genetic.
He got it from me.
I'm the carrier.
It's my fault.
Do you know why
you're named Amorosa?
Because you're so loving.
Don't blame yourself.
it's not your fault.
You are a good mother.
Look at your children.
So, what do you think?
- Do you like the renovation I did?
- Yes, I do, Auntie.
I got this cheap.
I saw it in the ads.
I thought it would be
a good business, right?
Speaking of business,
how's yours and Lito's business doing?
Oh, Auntie.
What?
- We failed.
- Oh my God.
We couldn't save it
so we just sold it.
I told him it's a good thing
we had some money in the bank.
Don't worry.
I will give you this house.
You're like a ghost.
You come out of nowhere.
Are you a guest?
Sir, the gardener's assistant
is never invited to parties.
Once you all leave...
I'll be the one to patch up
the grass in the garden.
You caught two doves?
Of course. You can have them.
- Are you sure? Thanks.
- Yeah, take them.
I'm Rommel, by the way.
Amanda?
Take care of the doves, okay?
- Of course.
- Let's go, Amanda.
That's Mr. Pedro, my Uncle.
I plant the flowers because
they die when he does it.
His hands are too hot
because he's a healer.
Amanda, I'm not deaf.
Why are you making up stories?
I'm telling the truth.
I'm going to take them, okay?
- Thanks. I'll take care of them.
- Okay. Sure.
Don't worry.
I'll name one after you.
And I'll name the other one
after me-Amanda.
You're not yet circumcised,
but you already have a girlfriend.
Stop it, Amiel.
Mom, you look sad again.
Please smile.
Come here.
Rommel, do you remember our promise?
We'll take care of your brother.
No quitting. No giving up.
Yes, Mom. No quitting. No giving up.
We'll take care of big brother.
My son, you always give me strength.
- I love you so much.
- I love you too, mom.
For the best mommy
in the whole world.
Wow! More food!
- Thank you!
My boys.
Amiel, this school you Want
to attend is too far away.
So inaccessible.
Mom, can I stay there while I study?
Are you crazy? Who told you
I'd let you be on your own?
If you really Want to study here...
We'll just live in
Aunt Lola's pension house.
It's near the school.
Come on, Rosa. Let the boys be.
They're grown ups now.
You're turning them into Mama's boys.
Can't you see Amiel's condition?
You know he's blind.
Amiel, this is it, right?
Amiel, my son. You're back.
Big bro, you wanted
a blue rosary, right?
Here, I made this for you.
That's special.
Home for the blind?
Why didn't you tell me
this was a home for the blind?
What kind of mother do you think I am?
Mom, I never said
you weren't a good mother...
but I want to stay here.
Instead of working and earning money,
you're unable to because...
Don't use my work problems
as an excuse.
Mom, my eyes are gone.
It's more costly if you
hire someone to look after me.
And Dad was approved for work
in Abu Dhabi, right?
Rommel's here for you.
- Bro, it's all good.
- Rommel, you're about to graduate.
Isn't it more practical this way?
- No cost...
- Son, I can do something about it.
You don't have to live here.
I don't want to be
a burden anymore.
You'll never be a burden to us.
They're no longer babies.
And what's wrong if they want
to help us financially?
I'll be the one
to get us through this.
I won't let my children make sacrifices
for your failed ventures...
- Mom, Dad, stop it.
- You talk as if I'm a worthless father.
Well, who else got addicted
to gambling and drinking?
It's not my children's fault
that we lost all our savings...
and surely I'm not the one
who got us neck deep in debts.
Mom, please stop.
Amiel got his blindness
from the side of your family.
What happened?
You got into an accident, miss.
- Lito! Lito! Lito! Lito!
- The driver got thrown off.
- Please sit down.
- Help! Hurry!
The van's gonna fall.
Miss, you're hurt.
- Just sit down.
- My boys.
- I've got to get to them.
- Ma'am, just stay here.
Amiel! Rommel!
Miss, who do we save first?
- Who do We save first?
- What do you mean?
- Please save both of my children.
- You need to choose.
The car will fall any minute.
Don't make me choose. I can't.
Miss, who do we save?
The one in glasses or the other one?
Please, Miss. Just stay put.
You might get hurt even more...
- if you don't stop.
- The one wearing glasses.
The one with glasses. Where is he?
Where's the one with glasses?
Where?
Amiel! Amiel!
Amiel.
Mom?
It's late, where's your brother?
He just went out. He'll be back.
Rommel. Cool.
Rommel. I want you to meet
some people, Dude.
My boys down south.
Yeah, sure. Just text me where.
Game?
Bro, this is okay, they're suppliers too.
Mom alert, man.
Dammit! I told you
she knew this place.
Sorry, Bro.
Rommel. Rommel.
Come on. Let's go home.
Mom, why are you here?
Go home.
I'll be home soon.
I don't need you to pick me up.
Ma'am, I'll take care of Rommel.
He's my bro. We're fine. Promise.
Rudolf, look at you.
And you're telling me
you'll take care of my son?
I know your antics. Just stop it.
Rommel, let's go. We're going home.
Mom, please.
Okay.
Fine, let's just go!
Rommel.
Bye, Rommel. Be safe.
You know, if you were in school,
I wouldn't have to do that.
Next school year...
- you're gonna study again.
- Mom!
If you ever pick me up again,
I won't forgive you.
Rommel, aren't you ever
going to listen to me?
You're so annoying!
We had a deal. Have you forgotten?
- What deal?
- No quitting. No giving up.
When you were little.
Don't you remember?
It was our pledge.
You always said "Mom, I'll help you
take care of big brother."
And I always told you,
"Son, thank you so much...
for being the one
to give me strength."
That's in the past.
I already forgot.
Well, I haven't, because even now
it's still you who gives me strength.
We're moving to the
pension house of Aunt Lola.
There you go again.
Didn't I tell you countless times
I don't want?!
Our house is being seized
by the bank.
We've got one week to move out.
Then why there?
Because I need a job.
I've talked to Aunt Lola.
She'll pay me.
I'll manage the inn. I can do that.
This is a great place.
It's peaceful and tidy.
It's better to live here.
Okay, you take care of that.
Cover it with newspaper.
Yes, Sir.
Why is there a crime scene?
Ma'am. Ma'am Rosa. Hello.
Auntie Lola called me about you.
Yes, she did.
By the way, I am Florida Bulaong,
reception and overall supervision.
What should I call you?
Is it Rosie, Rose, Rosetta...
- Rosa.
- Oh yes, yes.
Has Eugenia left already?
Oh, my predessor-hey, predessor.
English.
She's not here anymore. Left long ago.
She went to Australia.
Rommel, take care of the luggage
and help your brother too, okay?
Let's go, Ma'am.
I'll put you inside.
Wow. This is exciting.
New house, new life.
The layout is still the same.
Here's the kitchen.
There are fifteen rooms.
We don't have a lot of customers
this time of year.
It's off peak.
And there are
many competitors around...
and their Bed and Breakfasts have been
renovated to look better.
My daughter, Nadia
Good morning. Hello.
Good morning, Nadia.
Anyways, Ma'am.
Here's Lulu for our laundry
and chambermaiding.
- Good morning, Ma'am.
- Good morning.
Oh, yes. This is Edu,
the very young carpenter.
Good morning.
Where can I charge my phone?
- Lulu. Lulu, assistance please.
- Can I charge my phone?
Yes, Ma'am.
I'll do it for you, Ma'am.
Thank you.
Ma'am, Ma'am. What happened, Ma'am?
Can I help you, Ma'am?
No, I'm fine.
There was an insect.
It's gone now.
Lulu, fix it.
Thank you very much.
Cleaning. Cleaning.
Cleaning. Go, girl.
By the way, these are my sons.
Rommel and...
- Hi, Rommel.
- Rommel.
Snob. Unlike the other one. Friendly.
Ma'am, please forgive my daughter.
Her father's an alien.
And who's the alien's mommy?
Your daughter's funny. Very energetic.
Oh, yes. I'm so proud of her.
Very proud.
Eight steps forward. One to the left.
Rommel, where are you going?
Just gonna go out.
Mom, why do you think Rommel
changed after the accident?
Do you see it?
Yes.
I don't.
Well, it's because
you're blind, isn't it?
More often since you arrived.
Looks like there are
guests checking in.
That's good.
it's not just a café anymore.
I'm already sleepy, Babe.
Let's go to sleep then.
Let's go. Your mother's
looking for you. Let's go home.
Babe.
Babe...
- I thought we're just going to sleep?
- Yeah, in a bit.
- I'm tired.
- No, it'll be fine.
- Babe, I'm tired.
- Come on.
Babe, I said
I'm tired from work, okay?
- Why did you push me?
- You're tired?
What do you want?
Why did you hit me?
This is what you want, isn't it?
Ouch!
- Come on. Please?
- Fine. I'll just take a shower.
Hurry up.
Babe, hurry it up.
Just a second.
- Babe, let's go. Hurry, hurry.
- Why, babe? What is it?
Hold on, Babe.
I'll just put my clothes on.
No, let's go. Come on!
We'll never come back here again.
Thank you. And please come again.
Sir Edu, we saw a dead body
while on our way here yesterday.
That was our neighbor.
It was Carding.
He raped his fifteen year old daughter.
The killer must have been very angry.
His face was crushed.
Many have died here.
They say all of them were rapists.
They say a rape victim's ghost
is the killer.
They say she made a deal with
dark forces to seek revenge.
Wow, Sir Edu, where did you hear that?
From your ancestors?
You're kidding.
- "Dark forces".
- Here.
Pinoy Ghost Tales Volume 8
Later, son.
Don't go in there.
She's always there.
Oh, you rascal, always seeing things.
You're like a cop sniffing around.
Ma'am, are you okay?
I'm okay.
Ma'am that's just the wind.
it's the wind.
Oh, you.
Mom, you'll feel better in a while.
Ma'am what's that for?
Stress reliever?
Yeah. My doctor diagnosed me...
with post-traumatic stress disorder
after the accident.
I can't relax. I can't stay calm.
I get paranoid.
Hallucinations.
Hallucinachon.
Not hallucinachon, mommy.
Hallucination.
It's the same thing, you silly kid.
Ma'am this is Sgt. Villegas.
Mrs. Calderon.
- SPO4 Caldo.
- Hi. Good morning.
- Coffee. Please sit down.
- Thank you.
To what do I owe the pleasure
of your presence, Sergeant?
Yes, Ma'am.
There are a lot of unpleasant
memories in this place.
Just a few days ago,
a man was brutally murdered.
He was accused of sexually
abusing his teenage daughter.
You'll be living here?
Yes, Aunt Lola asked me to work here.
And my children have fond memories
in this pension house.
Please be careful.
There are a lot of murder cases here.
Sir, there's an update on the case.
Let's go. We'll go ahead, ma'am.
Thank you for the coffee.
If there's anything...
just call me in the station.
- We'll be going now, Ma'am.
- So, it's really dangerous here.
Please take care.
Yeah, you too.
Help me.
Rommel?
Amiel?
Amiel? Rommel?
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I'm calling the police.
Who are you?!
Why does God let this happen to us?
Why does He make us choose this Way?
You, Rosa.
He'll be taken away from you. Soon!
Rommel?
Rommel, what are you doing out here?
Why aren't you in bed?
Amiel.
Didn't Rommel go out, Mom?
Oh yeah.
Amiel.
Can you hear anything?
Mom, I'm blind. Not deaf.
You? Do you hear it?
Your bed is calling you.
Go rest. I'll take care of Rommel.
I'll wait for him.
You sure?
Thanks, son.
Miss, which one?
- The one with glasses or the other one?
- The one with glasses.
The one with glasses.
Where's the one with glasses?
Where? Amiel!
Rommel.
- Bro.
- Bro, how are you?
What's up?
Nothing new.
Oh yeah, boys... This is Glen.
This is William.
This stuffs great.
- William's a supplier.
- Are you sure?
Let's go there.
- Where are you going?
- Just here. Come on.
- Dude, nice meeting you.
- Hi, Miss Beautiful.
Can we sit?
Bro, why did you introduce me
to those guys? They're bad influence.
Aren't you gonna talk to us?
Since when have you been
a good boy? Huh?
It's not that.
I just thought, once we moved here,
it would be better if me and my mom...
You know... if we...
Bonded?
To make it up to her?
I'll give you a piece of advice.
The reason your mommy is
unable to move on is because...
you still can't get yourself
to forgive her.
Think about it.
Hey, brother. How are things?
Good, you finally came home.
If mom wakes up and see you
drunk again she'll have a fit.
You know, sometimes I think
I should have been the one...
in your situation.
It hurts too much.
Rommel, what's wrong?
Mom really loves you.
She didn't abandon you.
That's the truth.
Good night, Bro.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Who gave these?
They're from Amanda.
Amanda?
She's outside
waiting for the payment.
Amanda?
Rommel?
Is it really you?
You didn't have a scar
on your forehead before.
You're all grown up.
You too.
Are you still gardening here?
Not anymore.
I sell flowers while waiting
for the next semester.
You know, I never forgot about you.
Rommel and Amanda
have grandkids now.
Wanna see?
Sure. Of course, I do.
- Amanda.
- Hello.
How often do you bring flowers here?
Once a week.
Can you deliver everyday?
Really?
Sure. Is there a specific
kind of flower you like?
- No, you choose for me.
- Okay. Thank you.
So, let's go?
Our grandkids are waiting.
Grandkids?
- Where are you going?
- Not far, mom. Don't worry.
We'll be right back.
Ask permission properly.
We'll just look at the offspring
of the doves I gave her before.
I won't belong.
Don't stay out too late.
Let's go.
That's Rommel's first crush, mom.
She's the reason Rommel
wanted to be circumcised.
Come on! Hurry!
Our grandkids are here.
Wow!
Look. I kept my promise.
I took care of them.
Rommel and Amanda's family
has grown, huh?
I never thought I'd see you again.
I mean them.
Me too.
Once, Rommel got out.
I thought he was gone for good.
But I told Amanda,
"Rommel will come back for you.
He won't leave you.
You'll make many dove children."
That afternoon,
Rommel came back.
And there are now
Twenty-seven of them.
Rosa!
Don't do that.
Rosa.
Mom. Mom.
Mom, what's wrong?
Rommel, I know what happened to her.
She was raped.
Let's help her. Let's save her.
- Mom, it's just a nightmare.
- No. Rommel, please believe me.
The girl who's been haunting me.
She was raped.
She's asking for help. Rommel!
You are so hard-headed.
I told you to drink your medicine.
But you keep forgetting. Here.
Rommel, where's your brother?
Can you check on him
before you go to sleep?
Mom, lie down and sleep.
You're just tired.
Rommel?
I love you.
Go to sleep.
Good morning, Ma'am.
By the Way, I bought candles
for this coming All Souls' Day.
Sir Edu, do you remember
anyone dying here?
Why, ma'am?
Nothing.
It's just that people say
it is bad luck.
It may be why we don't get
a lot of guests in here.
Maybe we need to
have the house blessed.
There was one.
A man died of a heart attack
during a birthday party.
But that was long ago.
A man? How about women?
Ma'am, if you want to know
the history of the pension house...
the previous gardener
knows a lot more.
Sir Pedro.
Anybody ho...
Are you Pedro?
Yes?
The pension house is home
to a restless spirit.
Or maybe it's trapped.
Just like you.
You always have a guardian,
don't you?
I hope one day you'll let it go.
So it can rest in peace.
The girl I keep seeing.
Who is she?
Do you see her with your eyes
or in your head?
Are you just going to psychoanalyze me
or will you answer my question?
Back in 1992, a girl was raped
in that pension house.
After that,
death has plagued this place.
It is said that the raped girl is
the killer of men who abuse women.
Do you know how
to make the ghost leave?
Why would you want to make
an avenger of abused women leave?
If there's anyone who has to leave,
it's you and your children.
She's giving a Warning.
Your son will bring danger.
Amiel? Rommel? Which one?
What kind of problem?
Pedro, what danger?
Pedro.
Do you know where Rommel is right now?
Amiel. Rommel. Amiel!
Rommel!
Mom, what's going on?
Mom.
Rommel, come here. Hurry.
- Are you taking your pills, mom?
- Rommel.
- Wait. I'll get your pills, okay?
- Rommel. Rommel.
Rommel, we have to go. Come on.
Something here is haunting me.
We need to leave.
What's wrong with you?
You're hallucinating again.
We just got here and
you're already getting paranoid.
Listen to me. Listen.
I shouldn't have brought us here.
I made a mistake, Rommel.
Why, mom?
Tell me why it's a mistake.
We're in danger here.
Something bad is going to happen to us.
I feel like our problems are going
to get worse if we stay.
Rommel, listen.
Let's go back to Manila for us
and your brother.
Brother?
Brother.
Where's my brother, mom? Where?
Bro! Where is he?
- Where?
- Upstairs.
He's upstairs.
In his room.
Your brother's in his room.
Upstairs.
Then tell me, mom. Who is he?
Who's this?
Eight steps forward. One to the left.
Rommel, take care of the luggage
and help your brother too, okay?
Hey, brother. How are things?
Why aren't you in bed?
Amiel!
Mom, it wasn't Amiel who survived.
It was me!!!
- Survived what?
- The accident!
Which one are We going to save?
The one with glasses or the one Without?
The one with glasses.
Where's the one with glasses?
Amiel.
Where's the one with glasses?!
Amiel!
Give me your hand. Quickly!
Give me your hand.
The car's going to fall.
Amiel!
Give me your hand, Rommel.
You must live.
- Amiel.
- Rommel.
- Please take care of Mom.
- Amiel.
You didn't choose me.
But I...
I was the one they saved.
It was Amiel who remained in the van.
Who fell off the cliff.
Your brother was just with me.
- In the car...
- Mom, are we going to keep doing this?
You think you're talking to him
when you're alone.
He talks to Nadia.
He brings me my jacket,
food, my medicine.
That's me!
Me.
I've been the one going
to your room every night...
bringing you food,
and your sweater.
I was ready to forgive you.
I was ready to forget everything.
I've always been trying to...
because I love you so much, Mom.
I love you so much.
Why can't you see that?
You don't want to face reality.
Until now,
it's Amiel who is on your mind.
You know what?
If you don't want to believe me,
I don't care anymore.
Rommel. Rommel.
Do you think I'd let you get hurt?
Why not?
You've done it before, haven't you?
Never.
Rommel.
I thought you knew Miss Rosa.
I guess I really just wanted
to fool myself that he's still here.
You know, Miss Rosa, sometimes you have
to face the truth so you can move on.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
It's true.
She's right.
She's just a kid but she already
knows better than I do.
Ma'am, if you want I can ask Edu
to stay here with you.
No need. I'll be fine.
- Okay then. Good evening. Bye bye.
- Okay, Ma'am. Shall we go.
Bye bye.
- We'll head home now.
- Thank you again, Ma'am.
Amiel.
I'm letting you go.
I accept it now.
And to the others still here...
I hope you find peace.
Rommel, you can trust me
if you want to talk about it.
I wish I was the one who died.
I am at fault of Amiel's death.
That's not true.
Don't say that, Rommel.
Yo, What's up?
Bro, I'm with William.
Hi. How are you?
What are you doing here, William?
C'mon. Let's go out.
- Game.
- Let's go. Come with us.
Wait a minute.
Amanda!
Wait, where are we going?
Don't touch me.
- Here. Here.
- Let go of me!
- Amanda!
What's happening?
Let me go.
Okay. Okay. You win.
Okay. Alright. Joke time's over, bro.
You've scared us.
Let Amanda go home, okay?
Man, we're just getting started.
Dude, this is too much.
We'll all regret this in the morning.
Regret my ass!
Do you know how long I tried
to hook up with Amanda?
And you...
you're choosing him over me?!
- Now, I'll show you what you've done.
- Stop!
You son of a bitch!
Stop it!
You won't listen.
I told you so many times
I don't like you.
You don't like me?
Let's see if you still won't like
what I'm gonna do to you.
Amanda!
Rommel!
Stop! Amanda!
Where's her cell phone? Where is it?
Since Amanda chose you over me,
you get to go first.
It's play time.
Let's play. You play or she dies.
Stand up!
Give it here.
What?
What?!
You assholes!
Do you really need
to threaten me like that?
This is a blessing.
- Why would I refuse it?
- That's the spirit!
You're too slow. C'mon.
Alright!
So fine! Smooth!
This is great, Dude.
Rommel. Rommel, please.
Now, you'll find out
who the real Rommel is.
Amanda, Amanda,
I need you to trust me.
When I say run, you run.
Run! Run!
Get her!
Amanda! Amanda!
You asshole!
Rommel?
Pedro?
Get out of here, Rosa.
Save Rommel.
Save the son you have left.
You son-of-a-bitch, Glen!
Do you really need
to threaten me like that?
This is a blessing.
Why would I refuse it?
Rommel.
That's the spirit!
She looks good. Smooth.
This is perfect!
Rommel, please.
Now, you'll find out
who the real Rommel is.
You bastard!
Hello?
Rudolf, Where's Rommel?
He didn't come home last night.
Where is he? Is he with you?
Ma'am, I haven't seen him.
Rommel, where are you?
Rommel, my son, what happened?
Rommel. Rommel. Rommel!
No one says anything to anybody, okay?
Hey, Rudolf!
You try anything, you die.
Yeah, you're dead.
No, man. You can trust me.
The wound should have been deeper.
But this must have shielded you.
That's Amiel's. Take good care of it.
That saved me two times now.
Why were you stabbed?
What did you do last night?
I can't remember.
We need to go to
the hospital to treat that.
Won't they ask where
this wound came from?
Of course. They'll report it
to the police. Let's go.
Mom. No, Mom.
Why?
Did you do something wrong?
Mom, I said I don't remember.
All I know is I was with William,
Rudolf and Glen.
And Amanda.
Did you kill her?
Why would you ask that? No.
Mom, I didn't do anything.
Believe me.
Shit. Shit. Shit. What was that?
What?
Insect.
Just an insect.
You're still drunk, aren't you?
Shit!
- William!
- What is it?
William!
Glen!
Good morning, Sergeant.
Mrs. Calderon, can we come in?
Sir...
We've been investigating
those boys for a long time.
They're suspected of drug use,
drug trafficking and attempted rape.
A Week ago I saw them together.
My sources say one of them
is your son, Rommel.
William, Rudolf and Glen
are in those pictures.
Friends of your son.
Eyewitnesses claim to have seen them
getting into a car with a girl.
Now the girl, Amanda, is missing.
If I'm not mistaken, Amanda's the girl
who delivers flowers here. Right?
Yes.
Do you know where Rommel is?
He didn't come home last night.
Any texts or calls from him?
Maybe his phone's dead.
All I know is he went back to Manila
to visit the family grave.
Sir! Sir, you can't go in.
You don't have a search warrant. Sir!
Ma'am, you don't have dead relatives
in Manila.
Your dead is here.
Your mom? Dad?
Husband and son.
Accident.
Then let us help Rommel and Amanda
so you won't lose him too.
Sir, he's not here.
Sir, the rooms upstairs are empty.
I can sue you.
You don't have a warrant.
You know that, right?
Sir, it was just called in.
The car in front of the bar
belongs to William Tan.
Plus there are reports of a crime scene unit
dispatched to their condo.
One of them is dead. Glen Talabis.
Clean kill. No traceable evidence.
Let's move.
We'll be back. I hope, next time,
you have some answers for us.
Reyes, stay here.
Yes, Sir.
Rommel?
This is not real.
Rommel is alive. He's alive.
Hello.
Rudolf. Rudolf, you lied to me.
Tell me the truth.
I know you were with my son last night.
Tell me what happened.
Who told you?
Rommel.
Weren't you all together last night?
You, Glen and William.
And now Glen is dead, correct?
Rudolf, listen.
You'll all rot in jail
unless you tell me the truth.
Tell me what happened!
Why don't you ask your son?
He raped and killed Amanda.
Go ahead, try to turn us in.
You better hide your son
because I'm coming for him.
And if you insist on messing with us,
I'll kill you next.
You can't do that to my son.
He didn't do anything, Rudolf.
You can't hurt my son.
Rudolf!
Oh, God.
Dude, Rommel's alive.
He was able to talk to his mother.
We're dead.
That bastard.
He must have killed Glen.
What? Are you sure?
I don't think Rommel did this.
Have you seen Glen's face?
Must have seen a ghost
or something.
Since when did you believe in ghosts?
Where could he have hidden?
Maybe he went to the cops, Bro.
We're dead, man.
Then let the cops look for him first.
Here's what you're gonna do.
Here's Amanda's cellphone.
Take this to the police station.
Why me? You do it.
Are you stupid? Don't be a pussy.
I still need to clean the evidence --
Rommel and his mother.
No witnesses.
Go.
Dude.
Rudolf.
Hey! Hey! Watch it, asshole!
Ma'am.
I thought you left?
They made me stay to watch you.
I have something to tell you.
Rudolf was just found dead.
Hit-and-run.
Ma'am, if you know where your son is,
it's best you turn him over to us.
Because the killer is
targeting all our suspects.
Rommel might be next.
My son didn't do anything.
I'm sorry to do this, Ma'am.
But we got this phone
from Rudolf s pocket.
Listen carefully to this
piece of evidence...
connecting your son to all of this.
You son of a bitch, Glen.
Do you really need
to threaten me like that?
This is a blessing.
Why would I refuse it?
You're too slow.
Believe it or not, they're being
murdered by a female ghost.
And if your son is a rapist
and a killer, he's next.
Better turn in Rommel
so we can protect him.
Rommel.
Sir, with all due respect, sir...
I don't think you shouldn't have
threatened Mrs. Calderon...
to give up his son.
Assuming she is hiding him...
we're not even sure he's behind
all of this, are we, Sir?
I wasn't scaring her.
I was giving her a chance
to say goodbye to him...
...because I'm certain
Rommel will be next.
Who's gonna kill him, Sir?
Oh no, Sir!
It might be the ghost, right?
The urban legend in this area.
We're doomed, Sir!
Are you mocking me?
- You're mocking me?
- Sir. Sir, let go.
Don't go with Jerry.
The other side!
Get her!
Sandra!
Choose!
Either you come out
or We kill this kid?
Sandra, don't come out.
Shut the hell up!
- Think about it, Sandra.
- Jun.
- One! Two! Three!
- Four!
Five! Six! Seven! Eight!
I knew you'd come out.
You shouldn't have make us run
after you. Save us the trouble.
Please, Jerry!
Jerry, please don't do this.
Stop! Jun.
Jerry!
Let me go! Please, let me go!
I was helpless.
Sir?
Let's search the forest.
I know where we'll find the girl.
Son?
Rommel?
Rommel.
How is your wound, Rommel?
How did you manage to hide
from the cops?
Big brother helped me.
He blocked all the statues
so the Police wouldn't see me.
Let's go, Rommel.
William might be looking for you.
Rudolf and Glen are gone.
They were killed. You might be next.
I'm innocent. I didn't do anything.
Rommel.
Just tell me what really happened...
so that I will know what to believe.
Mom.
Don't you love me anymore?
Do I need to get sick?
I heard you during the accident...
choosing Amiel to be saved.
- Not me.
- That's not true.
When will you choose me?
Rommel, I didn't choose.
I never chose
between the two of you.
I love you both as your mother.
That day, I called for him first
since I was used to...
taking care of him first because...
I blamed myself for his blindness.
But you, Rommel...
you were always so loving.
I always expected you
to understand.
I never realized I was neglecting you.
I didn't know.
I'm sorry, Son.
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
Please, forgive you mother.
I'm also sorry, Mom.
Mom, we need to find Amanda.
All right.
Come on.
Just a little further, son.
Let's just get past the Police Officer.
Mom. Mom. I remember now.
I didn't want to join them.
But Glen had a knife on me.
Amanda...
I left Amanda in the forest.
Okay, we'll find her.
He's turned around.
Let's go.
- Come on, son.
- Here, mom. This is it.
I know Amanda's here.
I can feel it.
She's been here for over a day.
We need to find help.
I'll call for an ambulance.
No signal.
Rommel, there's no signal.
Mom, you need to go home.
Go and ask for help.
- I'm not leaving you like this.
- Mom, mom, mom. I got this.
Amanda needs us, Mom.
I can't. I can't leave you, Rommel.
Stay here.
- Rommel! Rommel!
- Mom, I'll be fine. Go home.
Call for help. it'll be alright.
Be careful, mom.
Amanda!
Brother, please help me.
Rommel. Let's practice.
Fifteen steps forward.
Three to the left.
Thank you.
Thank you, brother.
Please don't die on me.
Rommel.
Rommel, show yourself.
Stop hiding.
Amanda!
Amanda. Amanda. Amanda.
Amanda. Amanda.
Amanda, wake up! it's Rommel.
Amanda.
- Amanda.
- Rommel.
You came back for me.
I can't move.
You're bleeding, Rommel.
Just leave me.
- I will not leave you, Amanda.
- Please, go. Save yourself.
Rommel didn't leave Amanda.
They grew old and
had many children, remember?
Twenty-seven kids.
Can you take that? Huh?
Amanda. Amanda!
Amanda, wake up! Amanda!
Sir, somebody's in there.
Help!
Sir, please help us!
Sir! Please!
- Get away from there!
- Sir, I'm innocent.
Sir, we need help.
- Sir, please, help us.
- Check the girl. Go.
Sir, she's alive.
- We need your help.
- Call an ambulance. Quickly!
Yes, Sir.
Amanda. Amanda.
Rommel!
Rommel! Show yourself.
Rommel, come out!
Sir, thank you for responding
quickly to my mother's call.
Thank you.
Your mother didn't call me.
Aren't you friends with William?
Where is he?
Sir, he's not my friend.
Sir, he's behind all of this.
Reyes? Reyes, what's your status?
Reyes, What's your status?
Sir, what's going on?
Reyes isn't answering.
Bring them to the hospital.
I'll go to the pension house. Go.
Hold on!
Rosa.
Where are you going?
I'm coming to get you.
Rosa.
- Please hand me the gauze.
- She's going into shock!
Sedate her.
Rosa, stop hiding Rommel.
Where is your son?
Sir, please don't move.
Please don't move.
- I need you to steady, Sir.
- Hello.
Hello, mom?
I'm with Amanda now.
She's still alive.
But We need to bring her
to the hospital.
- Hello, Mom? Mom?
- Rommel...
Rommel, William is here.
Sir. Sir. Sir, we need to go back.
My mom's in trouble. Please.
No, Rommel.
- Turn around, please.
- No, Rommel. Don't come back.
- Sir, my mom will die, please.
- You are not going back here, Rommel!
Don't come back.
Your mom or your girlfriend?
- You're still bleeding. It's not good.
- Son. My Son, listen to me.
You will not come back here.
You don't have to choose.
Just go straight to the hospital.
I'll handle this.
You will never be able to run
to the Police now!
I love you.
I love you, mom.
Open the door!
Do you think you can escape me?
Stand up!
Where's Rommel? Stand up!
You bitch!
You just had to mess with me.
- Where's your son?
-I don't know!
You don't know?
- Stand up!
- Let me go.
I said stand up.
Where is Rommel?
Ma'am.
Thank you.
Sarge? Sarge!
Don't. Please.
No. Don't.
Have mercy. Please, William.
No!
Ma'am, have a safe trip.
- Be safe, Ma'am.
- Mom, shall we go?
You inspired me to go back to school.
Aww, you. Don't drive too fast, okay?
Have a safe trip.
Okay, I promise.
Mom.
Mom, let's go!
- Let's go!
- Goodbye. Bye bye.
- Goodbye.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
- Bye!