ANA AND THE OTHERS
- Hello.
- Good morning
- The paper please.
- The paper, here you are.
- Thanks.
Ana...? I'm Mariana Schuster,
from High School. And she's Silvina.
Hi! How are you?
Yours, isn't he?
Yeah, mine and Rodrigo's.
- Did you marry Rodrigo!?
- It's been four years now.
You look different with your hair cut,
you used to have long hair.
Yeah, I had it cut a short time ago.
Yours is just the same as it was...
Now it's lighter, for the summer.
How are you?
Fine, I'm always in Buenos Aires.
Oh... you know Rodrigo Guzman is also
in Buenos Aires. Do you remember him?
- No, I haven't the slightest idea.
- And I think... Laura too, the curly one.
Laura Solís.
Oh, yes, I think I know who.
- The one that in 4th grade was dating Flaco.
- No, it wasn't Flaco.
- Yes, it was.
No, she was dating Leandro.
Oh Mariana...
I'm sure because I liked him too.
Well, anyway I haven't seen her.
What about you?
No, I haven't married. I have a boyfriend.
I'm a single woman dating.
- Somebody I know?
- No, I don't think so. He's from Santa Fe.
We met there studying.
What's his name?
- It isn't a nice name.
- Why not?
It isn't nice, it's an old name. It's Omar.
- My uncle's Omar.
- Yeah, it's an old name.
Not nice for a young boy.
Old fashioned for our generation.
I love to call him Omi.
But when I get angry I call him Omar.
And you, do you have a boyfriend?
No, not really,
there's always something like it...
but not a boyfriend.
Well...
Can you lend me the newspaper?
Excuse me. Can you lend me the newspaper?
Just to see something...
I want to see the sports section...
Thanks.
You know if the Rowing swimmers are in?
No, I really haven't seen
the sports section yet.
Could I keep the page? If you don't mind.
Because this is my boyfriend.
- No, there's no problem.
- Thank you.
- Are you from here?
- Yeah.
- Because he's quite well known...
- Oh, yes? What's his name?
He's Adrián Serrini.
He's in the swimming team.
Have you been with him for long?
Not really. We met a long time ago but
we have been dating for fifteen days.
He's older than me.
It's strange you don't know him.
- How old are you?
- Me? 17.
- Now he has short hair but he had
long hair before. - Let me see.
He rode a motorcycle,
and lives near the park.
And how did you meet him?
I went to a disco with a friend...
and he and his friend asked us to dance.
Actually, he was with my friend
but I liked him very much.
At one moment I started to talk
to him and we changed mates.
We kept on talking the whole night.
My friend disappeared and we
left together in a taxi.
We exchanged phones but I thought
we'd never meet again.
And the following day my friend and
I went for a motorcycle ride...
in the Roses Park and we
saw him with his friend.
And I asked my friend to stop.
"Please, I want to talk to him!"
But she didn't want to because his
friend had been bothering...
her the whole night and she didn't stand him.
And we didn't stop.
But I wanted to see him another time...
to meet him in the bus, in any place.
I returned to the Roses
Park a thousand times.
Every time I had to go somewhere
I chose that way to find him.
I didn't see him for a whole year.
And this year,
I saw him again in the same disco.
He walked in front of me and I followed him.
I touched him on the shoulder and...
we started talking talking,
and he told me that he remembered me.
Since that moment we've been dating.
It was on the 31st.
And now I'm for waiting him.
He's coming over.
- Which was the club where he swims?
- At the Rowing.
I used to go to the Rowing too.
Diego...
Hi.
How strange, you riding a bike.
No, I do ride. You should see me.
I even swim now.
- Windsurf?
- Obviously.
- Bullshit.
- No, no windsurf. Not yet.
- Is the bike yours?
- No.
It's my sister's... I have to take it back
because she has to go to the gym.
You know how she is,
she needs the bike to go.
- Do you see any of the guys?
- Who?
- Anybody.
- No, not really.
- Mariano?
- No. Are you staying long?
No, just a couple of days.
- Diego!
- Bye!
Marcos, from the club.
Are you staying long?
- You've already asked.
- Yeah.
No, a couple of days.
- Well.
- I'm off.
- So am I. Have to go.
- You look thin...
- Yeah... not as much as you...
Yeah, I'm thinner too. But I've always been.
- Excuse me. May I ask you a question?
- Yes.
Would you know if there was
a photo shop here before?
No, not here,
there's one straight ahead on the corner;
but not here.
Not on this corner? One from the Garridos.
No.
Next block, you say?
There's one next block, Yung Color.
- And then there's this other one.
- No, yeah, I'm looking... well.
I don't remember really,
you should ask somebody older.
OK.
Over there on the other block
there's a newsstand.
I think the old man was born in the street,
so he can tell you...
something or give you a hint.
- OK, thanks. See you.
- Hello.
- Good morning.
Excuse me.
Do you know if there was a photo shop here?
No, there has never been one.
There was a lottery shop...
then a restaurant, now the phones.
Hi. Do you know if there was a
photo shop here some time ago?
Here? Yeah, maybe, but a long time ago.
I've been working here for three years.
It was the Garridos' one.
His son used to work.
- A tall one, chunky?
- Yes...
maybe. Do you know him?
- I don't think he's the same one.
- Mariano Garrido.
- No, nothing to do with him.
- OK, thanks.
Hi, Nati?
...Yes.
Yes, give me the address.
- Is it a long time since you moved?
- No, only a year and a half.
- And was the house like this?
- No, it was horrible when we bought it.
We did a lot, but we want to make
another floor for the bedrooms...
so that here we can do a room for the grill.
We haven't finished yet.
- It's nice.
- Yes, isn't it?
Guess who I ran into today. Diego.
I saw him very good looking.
No, you're crazy, he's fat.
I was surprised, he's changed. He's thin.
- No, he's ugly.
- I liked him.
- Anyway, we never share our likes
or dislikes. - Come on!
We agreed on some though.
But you had better taste before.
Mariano, for example.
I was going to ask you about him.
- Yes?
He's in Victoria, he went to work there.
- Why?
- Just to know.
But why do you ask about him?
Just to know something about him, that's all.
I've seen Martín quite often.
He went to Rosario to study, he's a dentist,
he came back...
and opened an office with a partner.
And Julio. He's working with his father...
Do you want me to get married?
- It's not that I want you to marry...
but it'd be good for you
to be with someone...
then somebody else,
and at some point you'll make up your mind.
- It sounds good.
- I'd hurry up.
See? You wanna see me married.
No, I don't want to get you married,
but it'd be good for you...
to be with somebody and...
...and not be so alone.
But I enjoy being alone.
It's easier.
No. Neither easier nor harder.
You may also say that...
being with somebody is easy.
- Why?
Because one day you make up your mind
and you've found the person...
you want to be with that meets
a couple of conditions that...
could be different in every case.
For example,
what do you like the best from Lautaro?
Uuumm, he's a good cook,
and makes dinner every night.
No, something bigger.
Why did you decide living with him?
- I don't know.
- Well, it doesn't matter. Anything.
The day you made up your mind,
you didn't think twice.
You're not looking anymore, you don't wonder:
"Would it be this one or another?"
I don't get it. Do you still believe that
a person must be looking all the time?
I've also been with this one and another,
but that's that. I can't live like that.
- Like what?
- Wondering, believing that...
there's always somebody better
and that you're missing it.
It never happened to you
to like somebody else?
No, not so far.
You say so far because it
could happen to you?
- Yes.
- And if it does?
- And if it does I'll see when it happens.
- And the house?
- What with the house?
- What would you do with the house?
Ah... is the house the problem?
Do you really think that you'll think
about the house when you decide...
being or doing something with someone?
Well, but if you don't share
a house it's easier.
See, being alone is easier.
- No, no. "Easier" is not the point.
- And what is?
I don't know. I'm lost.
- Look Agos.
- Get down here!
- Who are you shouting at?
- Pablito.
- What Pablito, your neighbour?
- Yes, I told him to get down there.
- Come on, let's play.
- I told him: "Step down."
- Did you say that? And he did?
- Yes.
Blow.
Wait until it burns a little more.
Come over here.
Look.
- Come here, Agostina.
- No!
- Agostina, come here!
- Go.
- Hi.
It looks good on you.
- This is Pablo.
- How do you do?
- You arrived today, didn't you?
- Yes, this morning.
- And?
- Fine, fine, and you?
- Fine, we're coming from the club.
- Which one?
- The "Náutico."
- Which one is it?
- The one up North.
- Ah, near the tunnel.
- Yes.
- Andre!?
- What?
- Are you with the motorcycle?
No.
- C'mon.
- No, really.
I heard you arrive.
- It's not working well.
- You're lying
- It's true.
- That's a lie.
It doesn't have much brake fluid.
Aren't you going to dad's
to pick up something?
No.
C'mon, go.
He called.
There's plenty of leftovers from yesterday.
OK, we'll go in a while.
- Hurry up, he's leaving soon.
- We'll go in a while.
Go.
OK.
Hi, Lau, what's up?
Ana? Yes, she's already here.
What time are you coming?
Around ten?
Would you bring the book I
left in the living room?
In a minute.
Come on. Do you want me to cut it?
- No, tell me.
- So I don't cut your hair.
Yes, cut it but also tell me.
- Are you sure that I haven't told
you anything? - Anything.
- About the priest?
- No.
- Sure?
- Yes.
- I'll tell you.
- Please.
We were in church.
Lautaro was inside waiting,
the people were all sitting.
I was in the car with dad, ready to get off,
but the priest didn't show up.
Mom and Andrea trying to call him,
the man didn't show up and the people...
in the chorus had to leave to
sing in another wedding.
And there was no time left.
In that moment Andrea comes to the car and
asks me whether I preferred to have...
the chorus or the priest to marry us.
Obviously I chose the chorus.
I wasn't resigning the hail Mary.
And we were about to start the ceremony...
with some friends of my mom directing it for
they knew the ritual, when the priest...
came in completely wet, offering the excuse
that he was confused by the time...
he thought it was ten at night
instead of ten in the morning.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Wine, please.
- Yes.
Omar gave me this for the party.
Do you like it?
- Yes, it's so nice.
- But it's not my style.
Well, but I think he bought
it thinking of you.
But don't you think he could've bought
something thinking in my likes?
I mean...
Do you think I can put this chain on?
You're angry with him.
- No... Well, actually...
- Hi.
- How are you?
You know that after your questions
for Mariano I asked around...
and they told me he's gone to Victoria.
But it seems that he didn't go for work,
he went because he had a girlfriend there...
and I don't know what happened that
she left him or something...
so he went for her.
I was told something like this.
His parents knew about the meeting.
I don't know if he learnt about it.
- So.
- Fine.
- What were you talking about?
- About Mariano.
- What about Mariano? - That he went
to Victoria after a girlfriend.
- That's a lie.
- How do you know?
Silvina makes up everything she says.
Yes, maybe.
- Hi!
- Hi.
Hi, how are you?
- You are thinner, aren't you?
- Is that so?
- Yes.
- I've heard that.
- I'm getting Lautaro.
- OK.
Do you want something to drink?
- No, I'll be back in a minute.
- OK.
- We'll take the photo.
- All right, I'm going.
- Come on.
- I'm going.
The last one I saw was a French one,
the one that they are deeply in love...
and he has to go to war, and she's expecting
and finally she marries...
another man.
He came back to her but it's too late.
I don't remember the title.
I saw it in video.
I know it. I didn't like it, neither the
character nor the film in general.
- Really, it rather annoyed me.
- Why?
Because the characters don't follow with
that difficult love in the name...
of what socially should be,
as if passionate or pure love would be...
something to be lost.
What do you mean by pure love?
It's not related to purity but to pure love.
I don't think so.
I don't think that the film justifies that,
just the opposite.
For me it criticizes that.
They don't have a good time.
Obviously not, but that's the thing.
They do nothing to change it and be together.
It's a tragic love,
it has to finish that way.
- Omar!
- Diego!
- How are you?
- Fine. You?
This is Ana.
How are you?
- Fine.
We haven't met but I've heard about you.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
- From who?
- Silvina.
- Ah, you're Silvina's friend.
- We know each other from High School.
And what did she say?
- No, she just mentioned you.
- Well or bad?
- Nor well, nor bad.
- Nothing weird?
- No, nothing weird.
- Ah, you're not very close then.
No, we're just acquaintances.
I thought you were in Santa Fe.
No, let's not talk about it.
Good I came here for a couple of days.
- Why?
- I have some problems.
- Silvina?
- No, another one.
You're dating them both.
Not both. I'm dating Silvina.
And I see the other from time to time.
What's the problem?
The other girl,
the one I see from time to time,
is a bit anxious.
She went home last week and rang
the bell for two hours.
I was with Silvina,
so I couldn't open the door.
She insisted and insisted and Silvina
asked me what happened.
I tried to explain that they wanted somebody
else from a different floor.
- And Silvina, do you love her?
- Yes, a lot.
- And the other girl?
- Well. I like her.
See you later.
- She doesn't love him very much.
- How do you know?
Ah...
Come on, tell me.
No
- Come on...
- No.
- Come on, tell me.
- No. I don't know, just my opinion.
- But he loves her.
- Not so much.
Yeah, he loves her,
but he likes another girl.
It's not only that he likes another girl,
but he's with the other.
Yeah, but it's not that
he doesn't love her...
Maybe he may like another girl but
if he loved her he wouldn't...
be with another girl.
- Who loves whom more?
- What?
Those two, who loves whom more?
She loves him more.
And of those two?
- She does.
- Oh, women always love more.
No, not always. Just in those cases.
Let's check others.
Those two?
She loves him more.
- You believe it's always like this?
- What's like this?
- That inevitably one loves more
than the other. - Of course.
- Why "of course?"
- Because it's unfair.
- What?
- Love.
What's the relation between love and justice?
Of course it's not fair,
but it's not necessary for it to be fair.
I think it should be. If I love someone,
it's fair that he loves me too, isn't it?
- You want everything.
- Everything, why?
You mean you love a person and that's
enough for the other to love you.
- Yeah, I love him, that's a big deal.
- Yes, it is.
But maybe he just doesn't love you.
Maybe he loves another girl. So, what?
- Well, things shouldn't be like that.
- But they are...
But it's a bad thing.
No, it isn't a bad thing,
it's the way things are.
OK.
We had a good time in Bariloche, didn't we?
- Yeah, it was cool.
- Did you ever come back?
Yes, a couple of years ago,
and truth is it was very boring.
You got bored?
Well, the place is great,
but it doesn't compare to those days.
- Well, no.
- Fortunately.
- Why is that?
- I didn't have such a good time.
Why?
Too many people.
- You did have a good time, didn't you?
- Yes.
- Do you have his phone number?
- Whose?
- Mariano's.
- He's in Victoria.
- Yes, I know.
- You've been asking, haven't you?
No, but it's difficult not to
learn about things here.
Yeah, true. What else did you hear?
He went looking for a girlfriend.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Is it true?
- Partially.
He did have a girlfriend in Victoria
and he travelled a lot to see her.
That's how he met the people from the paper.
When he was fired from the paper
here he decided to move there.
But they had already split up.
Got the number?
Last time I saw he didn't have a phone.
I've got the address though.
- Fancy a coffee?
- No, thanks.
- C'mon, I'll make you one.
- OK.
I brought sugar.
- Black for me.
- OK.
- "OK."
- What?
Nothing. I mock you: "OK."
No cookies left.
- No problem. Not too much into sweets.
- Aren't you?
No, not really.
In Christmas I never eat much,
specially the real tasty ones.
Ummm... you never heard that Mariano
and I were apart for quite a while.
Why?
Because I had a crush on you.
I never knew about it.
When was it?
- When we came back from Bariloche.
- Before I left to Buenos Aires.
- Too much?
- Yeah. Well... I don't know. That's life.
Yeah, that stupid.
- They didn't look stupid back then.
- But they are.
No, they're not.
Yes, they're teenage crap. At that age
you're a little silly for some things.
Not anymore?
Yes, it could happen,
but it has to be something important.
That was important. I really liked you.
Ah, you were talking about that.
What were you talking about?
I thought you were talking
about you and Mariano.
- I'm sorry.
- No problem.
- And how was it?
- My crush on you or the thing with...?
- The thing with Mariano.
- Just happened.
- But how? You were very close.
- Yeah, but it happens.
You have a fight and that's that.
Yes, but nobody has a fight just
because with his best friend.
Yes, you fight because you feel that way,
because something gets you...
because suddenly you are jealous of
him you want to have what he has.
But fighting you won't have
what the other has.
And besides what's that about "having
what the other one has?"
There's a third party who should
have a say in this, isn't there?
- No.
- No?
- It wasn't with you, it was with him.
- Were you in love with him?
No, I was mad at him.
Because I was in love with him.
Or because he was in love with you.
I should have asked you for advice,
shouldn't I?
"Ana, do you think I should get into a
fight with Mariano for you or not?"
Maybe yes, maybe I would have let you
know that it wasn't worth it and...
you saved yourself a problem.
- But it's over now, isn't it?
- Yes, it's over.
Well... yes.
- See that house?
- Yes.
What do you see?
- Nothing, a house.
- Don't you like it?
Yes, I don't see anything special.
It's a rationalistic style house.
It's the only one built in this town.
Weird, isn't?
Do you know the story about the "Rulero?"
People say that when...
...a guy killed himself there...
and then the construction was stopped
for a long time. Right?
- Yes.
- Now they say it's cursed or something.
Yeah, that.
Well, bye.
Bye.
So then I'll start reading the writing
regarding the ownership...
of the property you received
from your parents...
to Mr. Fernández, to seal the agreement.
Here it goes.
In Paraná, capital city of Entre Ríos,
January 11 2002, I see before me...
...for one party Miss Ana Torres...
...ID number 20005704, single...
...permanent address Laprida St Nr.
3256 Capital Federal...
and as the other party Mr.
Roberto Horacio Fernández, ID...
Hi
- Sorry. I'm late.
- No problem. Are we late?
A little bit, yes.
- How was it with the writing?
- Fine. It's over.
Sold.
How is it with you?
A little late, but...
- Did you have a good time?
- When?
At that age.
I don't remember.
It couldn't have been so bad, could it?
And who's that?
Pablito, next door kid.
Humm, seems like she's got a boyfriend.
- Ouch! She hit him.
- Always does the same, but he has fun.
Or so we think.
- Hi.
Let's go.
This is changed, isn't it?
It wasn't like this.
No, no it wasn't.
All this part is new.
It's a project to prevent erosion,
the falling off of the hill.
Inside, the core of the hill
causes mass movement.
What's that?
When the soil inside begins
to move and slide.
And it finishes with the movement of
the bank because of the strength...
of the Paraná River.
That's one of the purposes.
The other one is to recover land.
Look from the warehouses to...
the Rowing Club they'Il do landscaping.
This is the first part they did.
Look at the lighting, the decks,
very old decks.
They are being recovered,
there are benches...
so people can be close to the river.
It's very nice.
Something very odd happened
to me in the harbor.
We were sixteen and I went there
with a boyfriend I had then.
We hung around, looked at the river...
and when he was about to kiss me, I fainted.
He caught me, sat me on some nearby steps...
and I came around.
Up to there, everything was normal.
The next year, or the following...
Yes, I think It was two years later...
I went back to the same place with Mariano.
And it happened again. Exactly the same,
I fainted...
in the same place.
Very strange.
- Was it in the same part of the
harbor both times? - Yes.
Diego called you. He wants you to call him,
he'll be at home.
What's this.
Last night pictures.
Andrea went to pick them up.
Oh! How nice.
Do you know the story of this photographer?
The girls placed an ad in
the paper for our party.
But it seems that the only one who
answered was this photographer.
He offered himself to take the photographs
and told Mariana that he was blind...
and that now he was recovering his sight.
Mariana felt pity for him...
and she hired him.
Hey, what's up, Diego?
It's been such a long time. Wait.
- Tell him you're still waiting for me.
- Pick up the phone.
No, tell him that you're waiting for me,
but know nothing.
- I told him you were taking a shower.
- Well, tell him I finished and left.
C'mon, pick up the phone.
Say something to him.
- Something like what?
- What do I know?
I don't tell him.
Please, tell him I left early
and I didn't come back yet...
that I'll be in late,
you let me know and tomorrow I'll call,
or later today.
I don't like to lie.
Liar.
If I tell you that I don't like to lie,
it's because I don't.
But this isn't a lie.
Ah, isn't it? So what is it then?
Hello, Diego. Yes, I'm Lautaro.
Natalia is with the baby.
That's why I'll help you.
No, Ana is not here yet.
OK. Shall I tell her to call
you when she gets back?
OK. Bye.
Stop, stop. You're going to get her excited.
Go to bed, Agos. It's late already.
And who's that?
That's an aunt, that's my brother,
some uncles, cousins...
The only bad thing was that
it was full of old people.
- That's what I hate about weddings
- Sugar?
No, black.
- Are you on diet?
- You see?
Look at this picture.
- Standing still for the picture.
- Posing.
Look at the camera, please.
That's Mariano, isn't he?
Which one? The one in the white shirt?
No, that's Fabrizio.
- No, I mean the voice.
- Yes.
Excuse me.
Do you know the way out to Victoria?
One block, turn left, then straight ahead...
No, she has to turn right
at the traffic light.
In the traffic light turn right.
Exactly, turn right at the traffic light
and there you'll see the signs...
and you're on route 11.
- Do you live there?
- Yeah.
- And do you know the boy who
lives next door? - Yeah.
Come on, Matías!
Yeah! Wait! Yeah, I see him sometimes. Why?
- I'm looking for him.
- And who are you?
- A friend.
- Friend... friend?
Friend, friend.
Because he has several friends...
- Really?
- Yeah. I haven't seen him for some days.
He's got a red car,
but it isn't there either.
- Come on, Matías!
- I'm going! Bye.
- Are you the one who's looking for Mariano?
- Yes.
Come this way.
Hello.
I'm looking for Mariano Garrido.
Mariano's in Gualeguaychú,
working on an article.
He should be back tomorrow or the day after.
- Is there any phone number to contact him?
- What?
Is there any phone to contact him?
Yes, I'll get it for you in a second...
Will you give me a lift up to a friend's?
I've got to fetch something.
OK, get on.
What do you have to fetch?
- A bass drum, for the band.
- You play in a band?
Yeah, with my brothers.
- And when does carnival begin?
- Fifteen days from now.
Not next Sunday, or the next. After the next.
That makes it twenty.
- Twenty what?
- Twenty days.
Well, yeah. Sort of.
Are you on a trip?
Yeah. But I guess I'm getting back.
To where?
To Parana. Do you know it?
Yeah. Once I was there, long ago.
I remember a playground with a huge duck.
- The "Sirirí Duck."
- What?
The "Sirirí Duck" is the name of the park.
- Did you get on the airplane?
- What airplane?
The one next to the duck...
When I went the plane wasn't there.
What are you saying? I know it.
When I went it wasn't there.
I went a long time ago...
- I went two years ago.
- And it was there. I used to go as a kid.
You're from there?
Yes, but I live in Buenos Aires.
- I don't know Buenos Aires yet.
- Ah, you have to.
- Is it nice?
- Very.
Well, some people don't like it.
- What do you like doing?
- Everything.
Then you'll like it.
Do you know any other city?
Yes, Paraní, Gualeguay, Rosario,
Australia, Brasil, Paris...
Ah, been far away.
- But, I've never been to Paris.
- Then you're kind of a liar.
- No. Paris is a city.
- Yes.
And I know it. I studied it this year.
And I don't like you to call me a liar.
- Why don't you call me by my name?
- Because you're a lady.
What do you mean a lady?
- You're older.
- Well, I am older but not an old lady.
- You are to me.
- So anybody older than you is an old person?
No, not everybody.
Those girls?
No.
And what's the difference
between them and me?
You're older, I mean not a teenager.
- Uy!
- What's up?
- There goes Jose.
- Who, your brother?
- No, Josefina, a girl.
- And so what?
I don't want her to see me with you.
- Why?
- Are they through?
Yes.
- Go straight ahead on the road.
- OK.
I'll be right back.
- Hi.
- Is there any pay-phone here?
- Yes...
here you are.
- Thanks.
You have communicated with Mariano Garrido.
Please leave your message.
- Everything's OK?
- Yeah. Let's go.
OK.
- That's the car!
- What?
That's Mariano's car!
Couldn't you go faster?
Are you sure that's the car?
- Yes, it was him.
- Sure?
Yes, it's a red Fiat.
And did you see him?
Yes, it was him. He's blonde, long hair.
Ponytail.
No, I was kidding.
Aren't you going?
Not here.
And what if he never comes out?
We'll wait here, in front of the door.
- But I have to go home.
- Just a minute.
What are you doing? He'll see you!
So? I'll say I was around.
Come on in.
Come on!
So we can follow him when he comes out.
- I don't get this.
- Read it to me.
When banks discuss the government
decisions...
a "per saltum" will happen, which will...
raise the subject to the Supreme Court
and postpone the first way.
Did see the girl that passed by today?
- Yes.
- I like her.
Ah, really? Does she know?
No, I don't think so.
Josefina, right?
No. Me and my friends call her that.
I don't know her real name.
- From school?
- No, from my neighborhood.
- You'll have to say something to her.
- No way.
- What do you mean no way?
- No.
One suggestion...
Let's suppose that I'm her so you practice.
- How's that?
- OK.
OK. You go over there and I stay here.
- Hello, Jose.
- Hi.
I brought the paper so we can read together.
- Ah, but I don't know how to read the paper.
- Why?
Because I don't really like reading.
So you'll be an animal all your life.
No, how are you going to say that?
What?
Tell her something nice,
maybe something you read about.
C'mon, again, go.
Hi, I was reading in the paper about
the football game, shall I tell you?
No, do you think she'll care about the game?
No, let's try inviting her somewhere
or to do something.
What are you doing?
- Do you always say hi like that?
- Yes.
No, no like that. Again, go.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Would you like to go swimming to the pool,
this afternoon?
I can't.
Why?
I have to visit my grandma.
May I go with you?
No. What do I say to my grandmother?
- That I'm your boyfriend
- But you're not.
Not yet.
No, that's too straightforward.
Do it again, go.
- But how many times?
- Go.
Hello.
- Would you like to go for ice-cream?
- I have no money.
No problem, my treat.
And where did you get the money from?
- None of your business.
- No, that's aggressive.
How are you going to say that?
How is she like? Does she pay attention
to you or is she indifferent?
She's hard to get.
Ah. Well, for instance...
I don't know, you'll have to ask my mother.
I ask what?
You say "No problem,
I'll go and talk to your mom."
Go again, from the ice cream.
- Would you like to go for ice cream?
- No, I have no money
OK, my treat.
And where did you get the money from?
My mom, doesn't yours give you any money?
No, my mom says that there's no
reason for kids to carry money.
- Kind of dumb your mom.
- No, no!
Uy, there he is!
You can go, no one is coming.
- But it's red.
- C'mon, go.
It's a minute.
I bet a gum she turns at the corner.
You're not leaving now?
Yes.
Well...
I'm going.
- Bye.