( silence )
( vocalist singing
in Italian )
( vocalist continues
( indistinct announcement
over P.A. system )
( objects clatter )
Man: EXCUSE ME.
IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY, IT'S OKAY,
LET ME HELP YOU
WITH THAT.
( vocalist continues
in Italian )
( man speaking
Italian )
I'M LOOKING FOR
THE CONCERT HALL.
I THINK WE MAY
DRIVE RIGHT BY IT.
THERE IT IS!
VERY FUNNY.
( man speaking Italian )
I THINK
IT'S GONNA BE GOOD,
US BEING HERE.
( woman on radio
speaking Italian )
SHIT.
WHAT?
I CAN'T FIND
MY WALLET.
PUT IT IN YOUR SUITCASE?
NO. IT'S NOT
IN MY SUITCASE.
WHY WOULD I PUT IT
IN MY SUITCASE?
WELL, IT'S GOT
TO BE SOMEWHERE.
MAYBE IT'S
IN THE CAR.
THANK YOU.
( speaking Italian )
SHE'S LOST HER PURSE.
HER PURSE.
( speaking Italian )
WILL YOU JUST
GIVE HER A MINUTE?
UNO... UNO MOMENTO.
UNO MOMENTO.
ALL RIGHT,
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
( speaking Italian )
WHEN DID YOU
HAVE IT LAST?
THE TRAIN STATION, I THINK.
THE EXCHANGE BOOTH.
SHIT.
OH, JANEY, I'M SORRY.
THAT BASTARD AT
THE TRAIN STATION STOLE IT
WHEN YOU DROPPED
ALL YOUR STUFF.
THIS IS 170, NOT 70.
WHERE DO WE NEED TO GO?
WE NEED 70.
HERE WE GO.
IS THIS IT?
I THINK SO.
IT'S NICE.
YES, I HAVE HER CREDIT CARD
NUMBERS ON FILE IN MY COMPUTER.
YES, I HAVE THEM HERE.
OKAY, 5-5-3-3...
7-6-4-5...
8-7-8-7...
9-1-5-7.
5-7.
YEAH.
EXPIRES 12-15.
NO, SHE'LL DEFINITELY
NEED ANOTHER CARD
SENT OUT IMMEDIATELY.
WE'RE HERE FOR TWO WEEKS.
NO, I'M WORKING HERE.
YES, I'LL HOLD.
YOU LOVE HOW THEY ASK?
AS IF I HAVE A CHOICE.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT I'M GONNA
TRY TO DO WHILE I'M HERE?
BESIDES LEARN ITALIAN?
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU
THINK THAT'S SO RIDICULOUS.
I DON'T AT ALL.
I ADMIRE YOU. I JUST THINK
IT'S TOO LATE FOR ME.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
YOU CAN'T TEACH
AN OLD DOG NEW TRICKS.
AND BESIDES,
WHAT'S THE POINT?
THE WHOLE BLOODY WORLD
SPEAKS ENGLISH.
WELL, I...
AM GOING TO FINALLY
TRANSCRIBE THE TAPES.
YES?
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY.
WELL, IF YOU CAN SEE IT
THROUGH TO THE END,
I THINK THAT'S WONDERFUL.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
NOTHING.
NOTHING?
I THINK IT'S
A FANTASTIC IDEA, JANE.
I ALWAYS HAVE.
YOU KNOW THAT.
( object clatters )
JUST DIDN'T SOUND
VERY SUPPORTIVE.
YOU HAVE MY SUPPORT.
I'M SORRY IF THAT
CAME OUT WRONG.
I JUST KNOW HOW
EMOTIONAL LISTENING
TO THEM CAN BE...
HAS BEEN FOR YOU.
I THINK ENOUGH TIME
HAS PASSED.
WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
( indistinct loud voices )
WHY DO YOU THINK
HE KILLED HIMSELF?
WHO?
DAVID FOSTER WALLACE.
I... I...
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU CAN'T GET A SENSE
BY HIS WRITING?
YOU'LL HAVE TO READ IT
WHEN I'M DONE, DARLING.
DO YOU THINK HE
RECOGNIZED A BLANK INFINITY
JUST STRETCHING OUT?
HE GOT TO THIS POINT,
MAYBE, WHERE...
IT WAS JUST DAY
AFTER DAY AFTER DAY.
I REALLY DON'T KNOW, JANE.
JUST SO TEDIOUS.
AND THEN OF COURSE,
HE FELT GUILTY.
MOST PEOPLE THINK LIFE IS
TOO SHORT, AND THERE HE WAS,
ALL THE TALENT IN THE WORLD,
AND IT WASN'T ENOUGH.
JANE, CAN I--
CAN WE NOT TALK ABOUT THIS?
IT'S JUST A BIT MORBID.
( distant siren blares;
distant, indistinct voices )
LOVE YOU.
LOVE YOU, TOO.
DO YOU FEEL ALL RIGHT?
YOU FEEL OKAY?
YEAH.
YOU SURE?
MM-HMM.
( distant siren blares )
( siren recedes )
( passionate gasps )
( distant male laughter )
( distant,
indistinct male speech )
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WON'T COME WITH?
YOU'LL BE SO BUSY.
MIGHT GET BORING ALL ALONE.
I THINK SOMEONE
SHOULD BE HERE IN CASE
THE CARD IS DELIVERED.
TRUE.
AND THEN I THINK I
MIGHT GO OUT, SEE WHAT
THE WORLD HAS TO OFFER.
WELL, IF YOU DO,
LEAVE ME A MESSAGE, OKAY?
SO I CAN WORRY ABOUT YOU.
OKAY.
I'VE LEFT YOU
SOME MONEY HERE.
THANK YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
Jane:
TESTING. TESTING. OKAY.
DO YOU HAVE ANY STORIES
FOR MY BOOK?
Grandmother:
WHAT KIND OF STORIES?
STORIES
THAT YOU'VE PREPARED.
OR I CAN ASK FROM
A LIST OF STORIES
THAT DAD TOLD ME ABOUT?
GO AHEAD AND ASK FROM
YOUR FATHER'S LIST,
GOD REST HIS SOUL.
LET'S START WITH THE WAR.
WE WENT INTO
AN AIR RAID SHELTER.
MY MOTHER, YOUR
GREAT-GRANDMOTHER.
SHE WAS SHAKING.
THE SIRENS WAILED AND...
THEN THERE WAS
THE SOUND OF A BOMB,
AND THE MAN NEXT TO US,
HE SAID, "I WAS IN
A SHELTER LAST NIGHT
WITH MY WIFE
AND MY LITTLE BOY,
AND HALF OF IT
GOT BLOWN AWAY."
THERE WAS BLOOD
IN HIS HAIR.
HE WAS ALL ALONE.
THAT NEARLY FINISHED
MY MOTHER, YOU KNOW.
HERE WE WERE IN THIS
TINY TOWN IN ENGLAND,
MILES FROM GERMANY,
FROM RUSSIA,
FROM ITALY,
FROM ANY FRONTLINES,
AND THIS MAN,
HE HAD BLOOD IN HIS HAIR.
( speaking
rudimentary Italian )
Grandmother: WE WERE RIDING
OUR BIKES TO SCHOOL
WHEN THE GERMANS
STARTED FIRING AT US.
WE JUMPED INTO A HEDGE.
WE WERE TERRIFIED, BUT...
AFTERWARDS WE COULDN'T
STOP LAUGHING.
( chuckles wistfully )
IT FEELS NOW AS IF
I'M THE ONLY ONE
WHO REMEMBERS THAT.
IT'S AS VIVID TO ME
AS IF IT HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
OH, HI, LEONARD.
IT'S JANE.
I DECIDED TO TAKE
AN IMPROMPTU TRIP TO ISCHIA.
OR, UM, "EE-SCHIA,"
AS THEY PRONOUNCE IT.
SEE, I'M LEARNING
A LITTLE BIT. UM...
ANYWAY,
I'LL BE HOME LATER.
I HOPE YOU HAVE
A GOOD DAY. BYE.
Grandmother: THOSE
FRIENDS
ARE ALL DEAD NOW.
THERE'S NO ONE LEFT.
THAT'S ONE OF
MY REGRETS, YOU KNOW.
SOMETIMES I THINK
I SHOULD HAVE HAD
MORE CHILDREN,
NOT JUST YOUR FATHER.
YOU'RE ALL ALONE NOW THAT
YOUR PARENTS ARE GONE.
NO BROTHERS, NO SISTERS.
I'M UPSETTING YOU.
Jane: LET'S TALK
ABOUT SOMETHING ELSE.
YOU WANT TO ASK ME
MORE BORING QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE WAR?
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
( speaking
rudimentary Italian )
THE CASTLE?
CASTLE?
( asking question
in rudimentary Italian )
NO?
NO.
UM...
( speaking
rudimentary Italian )
AH.
( both speaking Italian )
Grandmother: HE'D BEEN SHOT
THROUGH THE NECK.
THE BULLET WENT IN
ONE SIDE AND CAME OUT
THE OTHER.
AND THERE WERE
ALL THESE BOMB HOLES
FILLED WITH WATER,
AND HE COULDN'T TELL
WHICH WAS THE GERMAN SIDE
AND WHICH
WAS THE ALLIED SIDE.
WHEN HE CAME HOME
AFTER SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
YOU COULDN'T REALLY
COMPLAIN TO HIM
ABOUT ANYTHING,
NOW COULD YOU?
I'M ACTUALLY
GOING THERE NOW.
TO THE CASTLE.
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH NOW?
YEAH.
WHY, DID YOU THINK
I WAS ITALIAN?
YEAH.
YES!
THAT'S GREAT, THAT'S COOL.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
WHERE YOU FROM?
LONDON.
NO, IN AMERICA, COME ON.
MAINE.
NO SHIT.
I'M FROM MASSACHUSETTS.
THAT'S CRAZY. THAT'S WEIRD.
RIGHT?
YEAH.
VACATION?
OH.
ARE YOU?
WHAT?
ARE YOU HERE ON VACATION?
SORRY. I THOUGHT
YOU WERE SAYING YOU
WERE ON VACATION.
ME? NO.
SO, COME ON.
MY HUSBAND
IS WORKING IN NAPLES.
WHAT DOES HE DO?
HE IS PLAYING IN A CONCERT
AT THE END OF THE MONTH.
COOL. WHAT DOES HE PLAY?
VIOLA.
MNH MNH MNH!
THE VIOLA!
HE ANY GOOD?
YES. VERY.
HOW DO YOU KEEP YOUR
VIOLIN FROM GETTING STOLEN?
YOU PUT IT IN
A VIOLA CASE. RIGHT?
NO, THAT'S NOT FUNNY.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN A VIOLA AND A COFFIN?
A COFFIN HAS
A DEAD PERSON
ON THE INSIDE.
'CAUSE VIOLA PLAYERS
ARE DEAD, NO?
WHY IS A VIOLA SOLO
LIKE PREMATURE EJACULATION?
( snickers )
BECAUSE EVEN THOUGH
YOU KNOW IT'S COMING,
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO ABOUT IT.
I CAN'T HELP IT,
I'VE GOT THIS WEIRD
AUTISTIC MIND FOR JOKES,
AND I WENT TO THIS
MUSIC-SLASH-NERD SUMMER
CAMP WHEN I WAS, LIKE, 10,
AND I PLAYED THE TRIANGLE.
RIGHT.
AND I'M
AN ONLY CHILD, SO...
YOU KNOW, UNDERSTAND.
YOU LOOK TOO YOUNG
TO BE MARRIED.
ARE YOU A NEWLYWED?
NO.
YOU'RE MAKING ME FEEL
LIKE A STALKER. FUCK.
( speaking Italian )
Woman:
GRAZIE.
UNO.
ALL RIGHT.
UH, HEY,
HAVE YOU GOT 50 CENTS?
IF YOU CAN CATCH IT.
GRAZIE.
WHAT BROUGHT YOU
OUT HERE TODAY?
THE FERRY.
HA! "THE FERRY."
I LIKE IT.
THEY HAVE THIS DEVICE
DOWN IN THE BASEMENT.
IT'S LIKE A TORTURE CAGE.
THEY'D LOCK YOU IN THERE
UNTIL YOU TURNED TO BONES.
BUT CAN YOU IMAGINE DYING
BY JUST SITTING THERE?
THAT WOULD SUCK.
IN, LIKE, THE 1300s,
THOUSANDS OF FAMILIES
LIVED IN THIS CASTLE.
MUST'VE SMELLED
PRETTY BAD,
ALL THOSE PEOPLE
CRAMMED ONTO THIS ROCK.
WOW.
I KNOW.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
EVERY DAY, AND IT
STILL GETS ME.
IF ONLY WE COULD
KILL OFF ALL THE TOURISTS.
( scoffs )
YOU'RE A TOURIST.
NO I'M NOT.
I CAME OUT HERE
A FEW MONTHS AGO
WITH THIS VOLUNTEER
ORGANIZATION DEDICATED
TO STUDYING
THE RELIC POPULATIONS
OF DOLPHINS AND WHALES
IN THE GULF OF NAPLES.
I CAN'T TELL
IF YOU'RE JOKING.
I'M DEAD FUCKIN' SERIOUS.
NO, I JUST DIDN'T WANNA
GO TO COLLEGE, AND THEY
PAID FOR ME TO COME OVER.
FOUR CONNECTING FLIGHTS,
A 72-HOUR PLANE RIDE.
BUT, YOU KNOW...
IT WAS WORTH IT.
MY FIRST TIME
OUT OF THE U.S.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
I'M 19.
IT'S MY BIRTHDAY TODAY.
IS IT REALLY?
UH-HUH.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YEAH, SO, I LEFT
THE PROGRAM AFTER,
LIKE, A MONTH.
FUCK THE RELIC DOLPHINS!
I'M STILL ON THE ISLAND
'CAUSE I HAVE THIS--
THIS AWESOME
LIVING SITUATION.
I'LL TELL YOU
THE SHORT VERSION.
BASICALLY, I USED TO HAVE
ANCESTORS IN ISCHIA,
SO WHEN I COME OVER,
I FACEBOOKED THIS SECOND
COUSIN TWICE REMOVED.
A SECOND COUSIN TWICE REMOVED,
IN CASE YOU DIDN'T KNOW,
IS WHEN ONE PERSON'S
GREAT-GRANDPARENT
IS ANOTHER PERSON'S
GREAT-GREAT-GREAT GRANDPARENT.
I'D LOVE TO HEAR
THE LONG VERSION.
SORRY. ANYWAY...
SO THIS RELATIVE GAVE ME
THE NAME OF THIS GREAT UNCLE
WHO LIVES ON THE ISLAND.
SO I SHOW UP...
HE ANSWERS THE DOOR
AND HE'S LIKE THE OLDEST
FUCKER I'VE EVER SEEN.
EASILY PUSHING 100.
100?
YEAH, IF NOT OLDER.
HE'S, LIKE, DEAF AND BLIND
AND ABOUT FOUR FEET TALL,
AND HE MUMBLES A COUPLE
THINGS TO ME IN SOME
CRAZY DIALECT,
USHERS ME INSIDE,
POURS ME A GLASS OF WINE,
AND LEADS ME
TO THIS BASEMENT APARTMENT.
AND, UH, YEAH,
I NEVER LEFT.
( female vocalist
singing operatic music )
( operatic music fades )
"LOVE TEACHES ME
TO FEED ON FLAMES AND TEARS,
"TO TURN WITHERED HOPE
GREEN THROUGH DESIRE,
"TO RE-ENSLAVE MY HEART
EACH TIME
LOVE FREES HIS
NOBLE FACE FROM
THAT HEAVY DISDAIN."
WHO WAS THAT?
VITTORIA COLONNA.
AH. THE WOMAN
WHO LIVED HERE.
YOU READ THAT
IN YOUR GUIDEBOOK
THIS MORNING,
DIDN'T YOU, JANE?
SNEAKY.
YEAH, I'VE DECIDED
TO LEARN ITALIAN BY
COMMITTING TO MEMORY
ALL THE SONNETS
SHE WROTE TO MICHELANGELO
IN ENGLISH AND ITALIAN.
I THOUGHT
MICHELANGELO WAS GAY.
AH, ACCORDING TO HISTORY
AND THE MUSCULAR THIGHS
OF HIS SCULPTURES, YES.
BUT THAT DIDN'T STOP HER
FROM LOVING HIM.
LET'S HEAR IT, THEN.
IN ITALIAN.
LET'S HEAR THE POEM.
COME ON.
OKAY, OKAY.
( reciting haltingly
in Italian )
( clapping )
WHEW!
I'M IMPRESSED.
THANK YOU.
YOU HUNGRY?
WHY? YOU GONNA
TAKE ME OUT?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT THEN.
OKAY.
Caleb: TWO PASTAS WITH
THE HOUSE SAUCE, PLEASE.
RED, PLEASE.
Man: WHITE OR-- RED.
UH-HUH.
THANK YOU.
GRAZIE.
SO YOU'RE REALLY NOT
GONNA TELL ME WHAT YOU DO?
I WRITE FREELANCE
ARTICLES ABOUT PARTIES
AND FASHION TRENDS
IN   TOWN AND COUNTRY UK.
THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE.
I'M WRITING A BOOK...
ABOUT MY GRANDMOTHER'S
EXPERIENCES IN RURAL ENGLAND,
LIVING THROUGH TWO WORLD WARS.
I RECORDED HER
FOR HOURS AND HOURS.
BUT NOW...
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT DON'T YOU KNOW?
YOU WANNA LISTEN, A LITTLE?
YEAH.
YEAH?
YEAH, NO,
I LOVE TO LISTEN.
IT'S ALL TANGLED UP.
HOLD ON.
OKAY.
Grandmother: AWFUL AS IT WAS,
IT MADE YOU STRONGER.
THESE DAYS PEOPLE
WHINE ABOUT ALL SORTS
OF THINGS,
AND I'M NOT ONE OF
THOSE OLD PEOPLE WHO
THINK MY TIME
HAD THE ONLY JOY
AND THE ONLY PROBLEMS.
WE ALL HAVE OUR OWN
PRIVATE WARS, EVERY ERA.
BUT IT WAS NOTHING LIKE--
IT REALLY BROUGHT
PEOPLE TOGETHER, THE WAR.
WE HELPED EACH OTHER
DURING THAT TIME.
WE HAD TO LAUGH,
WE HAD TO SMILE.
WELL, IF NOT
FOR OURSELVES,
THEN FOR
THE PEOPLE WE'D LOST.
NOW SHUT THAT THING OFF,
WOULD YOU?
GET IT OUT OF MY FACE!
THAT IS LIKE--
IT'S LIKE A WINDOW IN TIME.
THE SORT OF THING
YOU WISH YOU ALWAYS DID
BEFORE SOMEONE DIED,
YOU KNOW?
MY HUSBAND THINKS
I'M NEVER GONNA FINISH IT.
YOU SHOULDN'T CARE
WHAT ANYONE THINKS.
WE MET WHILE
I WAS RECORDING HER.
BONDING OVER GRANNY, HUH?
YOU MAKE IT SOUND PERVERSE.
THAT'S WHAT IT WAS, RIGHT?
( speaking Italian )
I GOT PREGNANT,
SO WE GOT MARRIED.
I LOST THE BABY.
I'M SORRY.
( speaking Italian )
I DIDN'T GO
BACK AFTER THAT
TO THE STATES.
DID YOU, UH,
DID YOU EVER HEAR
THAT STORY ABOUT
THE RED STRING?
I THINK I MIGHT HAVE.
TELL ME.
IT'S LIKE THIS
ASIAN PROVERB.
SAYS THAT ANYONE
YOU'RE DESTINED
TO MEET, LIKE, UH,
YOUR SOUL MATE
OR YOUR FAMILY OR,
YOU KNOW,
SOMEONE YOU BUMP
INTO ON THE STREET,
WE'RE ALL CONNECTED...
BY THIS RED STRING.
IT CAN BE TANGLED
OR STRETCHED,
BUT IT CAN NEVER
BE BROKEN.
THERE'S THIS MOMENT
IN THE TAPE.
I'M SITTING, WAITING,
IN THE AIRPORT BAR
FOR MY FLIGHT,
AND I'M TALKING
INTO THE RECORDER,
RAMBLING ON ABOUT HOW
I'M ABOUT TO EMBARK
ON THIS AMAZING ADVENTURE,
HOW I'M GONNA SHOW
WORLD WAR II
FROM A TOTALLY
DIFFERENT PERSPECTIVE.
BUT?
I DON'T KNOW
IF IT'S THAT INTERESTING.
THAT'S THE WHOLE POINT,
ISN'T IT?
KEEPING IT INTERESTING
FOR YOURSELF.
MAYBE.
MAYBE I JUST WANNA
WRITE ABOUT NOTHING.
EVERYTHING IS NOTHING.
ALL THE BEST.
( chuckles )
( both speaking Italian )
MAKE A WISH, HUH?
MAKE IT GREAT.
OKAY.
BRAVO.
BRAVO. HEY.
( playful growl )
ARE YOU READY?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
AM I READY?
GRAB MY HAND.
GO, GO, GO!
WHAT? WHY? OH, MY GOD!
GO!
OH, MY GOSH!
( shouting in Italian )
WHY? WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
GO!
( man shouting in Italian )
( shouting in Italian )
( indistinct,
panting remarks )
IT'S THE CARIBINIERI!
WHAT?
THE POLICE! COME ON!
NO! NO! NO!
YEAH! YEAH, YEAH!
WE CAN'T GO BACK!
IF WE GO BACK,
WE GET ARRESTED!
OKAY.
RUN!
WE CAN'T PAY
IF WE HAVEN'T
GOT ANY MONEY!
OH, GOD. COME HERE.
OH, GOD.
HEY. HEY.
WHAT?
Would it make you
feel better if I said
I set the whole thing up?
Yes, if it's true.
Is it true?
I paid the check when
I went to the bathroom.
( laughing )
You're horrible.
You're a mean,
horrible person.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, come on.
Quick! Let's go!
Why are we still running?
I don't know why
we're still running.
( gasping )
OH, MY GOSH.
( laughing )
IT WENT UP MY NOSE.
( comical snort )
WILL YOU COME BACK?
MAYBE.
"MAYBE" IS NOT A "NO,"
AND SINCE I DON'T
HAVE A PHONE,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
GIVE ME YOUR NUMBER.
FOR CHEAP THRILLS
AND FUTURE CRIMES
COMMITTED.
( emphatically )
NO.
FAIR ENOUGH.
I'D BETTER GO...
CATCH A FERRY.
HEY.
WHY DO VIOLISTS...
KEEP THEIR VIOLA CASES
ON THEIR DASHBOARDS?
WHY?
SO THEY CAN PARK
IN HANDICAPPED SPOTS.
OH.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
THANK YOU.
( distant,
indistinct shouting )
YOU'RE AWAKE.
NO, I'VE GOT SO MUCH OF
THIS STUFF TO GET THROUGH.
YOU BOUGHT FRUIT.
NICE.
Grandmother: THERE ARE
THE GREAT BIG EVENTS,
THE THINGS YOU THINK
YOU'LL ALWAYS REMEMBER,
AND YOU DO,
BUT THERE ARE
OTHER SMALLER--
PICKING A BLACKBERRY
THAT'S BEEN IN THE SUN,
OR BRUSHING
THE FINGERTIP OF SOMEONE
YOU DIDN'T KNOW
YOU LOVED UNTIL YOU
TOUCHED THEM.
NELLIE WAS
THIS LITTLE COLLIE
WHO WOULDN'T GO ON A LEASH,
SO SHE HAD TO
SIT ON A BICYCLE SEAT.
THEY STAY WITH ME, TOO.
( distant traffic sounds )
JANE. JANEY?
GOT SOME PASTRIES.
YOU STILL ASLEEP?
JANE?
Grandmother:
MY FRIENDS HAD LOTS
OF AMERICAN BOYFRIENDS,
AND THEY USED TO
BRING US NYLON STOCKINGS
AND CHOCOLATES
AND ALL SORTS OF THINGS.
AND WE USED TO GO
TO LONDON, AND...
WE SAW GLEN MILLER
ONE TIME.
OH, WE USED TO GO
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THEY WERE WONDERFUL TIMES.
I NEVER HAD
AN AMERICAN BOYFRIEND.
I LIKED SOME OF THEM.
THEY WERE NICE BOYS,
BUT...
I DIDN'T WANT
TO LEAVE MY MUM AND DAD.
I WISH I HAD, SOMETIMES.
Jane: YOU KNOW WHEN YOU
WERE 19 AND THE WORLD
JUST FELT SO OPEN
AND CAREFREE
AND FULL OF POSSIBILITY?
HE REMINDED ME OF THAT.
OF THAT TIME.
YOU WERE 19 WHEN WE MET.
YEAH.
I WOULDN'T HAVE
DESCRIBED YOU AS
CAREFREE BACK THEN.
NOT AT ALL.
WELL, I FELT NOSTALGIA...
OR SOMETHING... FOR YOUTH.
YOU'RE NOT OLD, JANE.
WE RAN OUT ON THE BILL.
YOU JUST RAN--
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU RAN OUT ON A BILL?
PERHAPS I'M NOT
EXPLAINING IT WELL.
IT WAS...
IT WAS FUN.
IT WAS JUST FUN.
( church bells toll )
HOW WAS WORK?
THE CONDUCTOR IS
ACTUALLY A DESCENDANT
OF WALTER LEGGE,
WHICH IS FASCINATING.
THE THREE OF US
SHOULD PLAN A DINNER
BEFORE WE LEAVE.
I'D LIKE THAT.
JANE?
OH, MY GOD. IT'S--
THIS IS CALEB.
HI.
LEONARD. WE WERE
JUST TALKING ABOUT YOU.
WE WERE. THAT'S SO WEIRD.
SIT. PLEASE,
SIT DOWN. JOIN US.
WELL--
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
OF THAT?
I KNOW, RIGHT?
I'VE ACTUALLY GOT
TO GET BACK PRETTY SOON.
THAT'S OKAY. I ALREADY ATE,
SO I'LL JUST GRAB
A COFFEE OR SOMETHING.
CAN I HAVE THE CHECK,
PLEASE?
( orders coffee
in Italian )
OH, NO, THANK YOU.
JANE?
YOU DON'T SMOKE.
YES, I DO.
SOMETIMES, AT PARTIES.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
WELL, I DON'T
DO IT A LOT.
ITALIAN FOOD'S
SO OVERRATED.
I LOVE IT.
THERE'S NO VARIETY.
ENGLISH FOOD,
ON THE OTHER HAND--
SAY WHAT YOU LIKE ABOUT IT,
THERE'S NOTHING
LIKE A GOOD STEAK
AND KIDNEY PIE.
I WENT TO THIS
PARTY THE OTHER DAY,
IN THIS VILLA
OWNED BY THIS
OLD DRUNK EX-PAT,
AND THEY HAD, LIKE,
A PRIVATE CHEF
AND EVERYTHING...
AND THEY WERE
SERVING THIS, LIKE,
LOAF OF MEAT
COVERED IN SAUCE WITH
ALL THESE OTHER LOAVES.
THIS GIRL CAME OVER TO ME
AND SAID IT WAS CAT.
NO!
NO JOKE.
LIKE A ROASTED MOMMY CAT
AND HER KITTENS.
THAT IS DISGUSTING.
TRUE STORY.
( both chuckle )
WHY DON'T YOU
TELL LEONARD ONE OF
YOUR VIOLA JOKES?
COME ON.
YOU SOUND
LIKE MY AUNT.
COME ON.
LET'S HEAR ONE.
I HAVE ONE.
WHAT IS THE DEFINITION
OF "PERFECT PITCH"?
WHAT?
WHEN YOU THROW A VIOLA
INTO THE DUMPSTER
WITHOUT HITTING THE RIM.
( snickering )
YOU DIDN'T
JUST MAKE THAT UP.
I DID.
WELL, I'M IMPRESSED
AND I'M STEALING IT.
YOU CAN PRETTY
MUCH MAKE THAT JOKE
ABOUT ANY INSTRUMENT.
DO YOU PLAY
ANYTHING, CALEB?
THIS AND THAT, YOU KNOW.
SHALL WE?
WHAT? TIME TO GO,
ALREADY?
YEAH, I'VE GOT TO GET
BACK TO WORK.
Leonard: SO, WHAT'S NEXT
ON YOUR AGENDA, CALEB?
Caleb: UM,
I'M THINKING TIBET.
Jane: OH, TIBET?
REALLY?
YEAH, THERE'S
THIS THING CALLED
THE SHOTON FESTIVAL...
AT THE END OF THE SUMMER.
I'VE HEARD ABOUT THAT.
THAT'S WHERE
THE BUDDHIST MONKS
UNROLL ALL THE TAPESTRIES
ON THE HILL, RIGHT?
THE MONKS, THE MONKS,
THE MONKS.
IT'S SO PRETTY.
HOW DO YOU
SUPPORT YOURSELF?
OH, BIT OF THIS,
BIT OF THAT.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
I'LL WALK YOU.
DOES ANYBODY HAVE
A PEN? YOU GOT A PEN?
YEAH, I HAVE A PEN.
OKAY.
I HAVE A PIECE OF PAPER.
YOU GUYS SHOULD DEFINITELY
COME OVER TO THE ISLAND.
I'LL TAKE YOU
SOMEWHERE FUN,
YOU KNOW.
DON'T KNOCK ON
THE FRONT DOOR.
COME AROUND THE SIDE.
90 REGINA...
ISCHIA.
HERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
AND THANKS AGAIN
FOR YESTERDAY.
OH, NO PROBLEM.
OKAY.
HOW STONED ARE YOU?
COME ON, LEONARD.
IT WAS JUST ONE PUFF.
IT'S NOT A BIG DEAL.
SO YOU'RE SAYING
YOU SMOKE BACK AT HOME?
OCCASIONALLY.
HEY, CAN WE DO
SOMETHING FUN TONIGHT?
SURE.
I'M FINE FROM HERE.
OKAY.
SEE YOU AFTER WORK.
YEP. I'LL BE WAITING.
HEY.
OH, GOD,
YOU SCARED ME.
ARE YOU FOLLOWING ME?
MAYBE. IS THAT WEIRD?
YEAH.
I COULDN'T SLEEP
LAST NIGHT.
YOU TOLD ME
YOU WERE STAYING
NEAR THE PORT,
SO I GOT THE FIRST
FERRY THIS MORNING.
I CAME
LOOKING FOR YOU.
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE
I FOUND YOU.
What are we doing?
I think we're making out.
You're so sexy.
And beautiful.
I CAN'T.
I CAN'T DO THIS.
WHY? WHY?
WHY?
DO YOU DO THIS A LOT?
WHAT?
DO YOU SEDUCE WOMEN?
IS THIS WHAT YOU DO?
YOU NEED TO BE
LESS SERIOUS.
DON'T FOLLOW ME.
Grandmother:
THERE WAS ONE BOY
FROM BELGIUM.
HE WAS LOVELY.
HE HAD A MUSTACHE.
( laughing )
MY MOTHER HATED
MUSTACHES.
BUT HE WAS SHIPPED OFF.
I NEVER SAW HIM AGAIN.
ANYWAYS, I MET
YOUR GRANDFATHER
NOT LONG AFTER,
AND WE GOT MARRIED.
Jane: WAS IT LOVE AT
FIRST SIGHT WITH GRANDPA?
LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT?
STOP THAT THING. WE'RE--
LEONARD.
YOU'RE HOME EARLY.
WHAT DID I DO
TO DESERVE THAT?
I JUST MISSED MY HUSBAND.
JANE, I'M SORRY,
JUST GIVE ME A MINUTE.
A HELL OF A REST
OF MY DAY.
SORRY, DARLING.
HEY, DO YOU STILL
WANT TO DO SOMETHING
FUN TONIGHT?
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
I BROUGHT SOME DINNER.
THOUGHT WE'D
JUST STAY IN HERE.
THE TWO OF US.
I'VE JUST GOT TO
WORK THIS THING OUT
BEFORE TOMORROW.
OKAY.
I'M SORRY.
It's okay.
( viola playing )
Leonard.
Can we talk?
SAY CHEESE.
CHEESE.
YOU SHOULD KIND OF
BE IN THE MIDDLE.
NEVER MIND.
HOLD ON A SECOND.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S WHAT
OUR LIVING ROOM
IS MISSING.
( camera beeps,
then clicks )
WHAT DID YOU DO?
I PUT MY HAND
OVER MY MOUTH.
YOU DID?
WHAT DID YOU DO?
JUST WAVED.
( chuckles softly )
( voices arguing )
( arguing in Italian )
( passionate gasping )
LEONARD?
DO YOU HAVE ANY FANTASIES?
WHAT?
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WANT?
JUST AS YOU ARE, JANE.
JUST AS YOU ARE.
YOU'RE ALL I NEED.
( knocking on door )
OH!
HI.
DID I WAKE YOU?
NO.
I THINK I NEED
TO BE LESS SERIOUS.
YEAH. LET ME
PUT MY PANTS ON.
MM-KAY.
LEONARD THOUGHT
YOU WERE LYING...
ABOUT THOSE CATS.
HE SAID THAT?
WERE YOU?
THEY WERE DELICIOUS.
YOU MAKE ME FEEL NERVOUS.
YOU MAKE ME FEEL CALM.
YOU WANT A DRINK?
( muffled footfalls )
IS THAT HIM?
YEAH, HE JUST SHUFFLES
AROUND ALL NIGHT.
MUST BE LONELY.
Voices on Tape: ♪ AGAIN
AND AGAIN AND AGAIN ♪
♪ AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND AGAIN ♪
♪ ONCE I WAS SINGLE,
MY HEART IT WOULD JINGLE ♪
♪ I WISH I WERE SINGLE AGAIN
♪ AGAIN
AND AGAIN AND AGAIN ♪
♪ BOM BOM
♪ AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND AGAIN ♪
♪ FEWP FEWP
♪ ONCE I WAS SINGLE,
MY POCKETS THEY'D JINGLE ♪
♪ I WISH I WERE...
Grandmother:
♪ SINGLE AGAIN
♪ BOM BOM
I DIDN'T SLEEP
AT ALL LAST NIGHT.
WHERE'VE YOU BEEN?
I WAS WALKING.
ALL NIGHT?
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
YOU LEFT YOUR PHONE HERE.
I HAD TO PLUG IT IN.
WE NEED TO TALK, LEONARD.
I HAVE TO GO TO WORK.
CAN YOU BE LATE?
NO. I CAN'T BE LATE.
LEONARD--
JANE, WHATEVER YOU HAVE
TO SAY TO ME,
I WANNA HEAR IT.
BUT I'VE COMMITTED MYSELF.
PEOPLE ARE DEPENDING ON ME.
I HAVE TO GO TO WORK.
OKAY.
Grandmother:
IF IT WASN'T THE WAR,
IT WOULD'VE BEEN
SOMETHING ELSE.
THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING
ELSE, ISN'T THERE?
BUT THAT'S THE THING.
THAT'S THE THING
ABOUT STRUGGLE.
I'M GOING TO MAKE SOME TEA.
DO YOU WANT SOME?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
YOU GO OUT LIKE THAT AGAIN,
JUST TELL ME. I WORRY.
OKAY.
I CAN'T SEEM TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON IN YOUR HEAD.
DO YOU THINK EVERYTHING
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
ACTUALLY DOES US ANY GOOD?
IN THE LONG RUN?
OR DO WE JUST MAKE OUT
"STRUGGLE" TO BE
SOMETHING MEANINGFUL
BECAUSE THAT'S ALL
MOST OF US HAVE?
I TELL YOU, NEXT TIME
WE COME TO ITALY...
WE NEED TO GET
A PROPER KITCHEN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU
WANT ME TO SAY, JANE.
IF ONE LITTLE THING
HAD CHANGED IN MY
GRANDMOTHER'S LIFE,
I MIGHT NOT BE HERE.
SOMETIMES I WORRY
I'M NOT HONORING HER.
WITH THE BOOK?
NO, WITH MY LIFE.
THIS IS IT, YOU KNOW.
IT ENDS WITH ME.
Grandmother:
IN THE HARVEST TIME
WE ALL WENT TO THE FIELD
WHERE THEY WERE
CUTTING THE CORN.
EVERYONE
WAS CHASING RABBITS,
AND THEN WE HAD OUR TEA
IN THE HARVEST FIELDS.
THE HORSES.
YEAH?
MM-HMM.
THE HORSES BACK THEN,
THEY WERE KEPT BEAUTIFULLY.
DAD USED TO DRESS THEM
ALL UP--
BRASS THINGS AND--
AND LITTLE HORSESHOES.
HE'D PUT BRAIDS ON THEM.
( gasps )
THEY USED TO BE GORGEOUS.
WHAT ARE YOUR PLANS
FOR TOMORROW?
Grandmother :
THERE WAS ONE,
DUKE.
HE WAS A CLYDESDALE
I USED TO RIDE
DOWN TO THE MARSHES
EVERY NIGHT WHEN
HE FINISHED WORKING.
THEY WERE LOVELY DAYS,
REALLY.
Caleb: GO!
Grandmother:
THEY'RE GONE, FOR ME.
Leonard: JANE?
Grandmother:
BUT NOT FOR YOU.
JANE.
YOU KNOW, IT'S
DIFFERENT FOR YOU.
IN SOME WAYS
IT'S EASIER.
YOU HAVEN'T GOT THE WAR.
PEOPLE DON'T DIE AS MUCH
AS THEY DID BACK THEN,
BUT IN SOME WAYS
IT'S MORE DISJOINTED.
YOU'VE GOT TO MAKE
YOUR OWN LIFE,
ONE THAT YOU LOVE,
AND YOU CAN'T BE
AFRAID OF THE...
THE TIME.
TIME IS SHIFTABLE.
THERE ARE MOMENTS
IN MY LIFE THAT
I WOULD TRADE
60 YEARS TO
HAVE BACK AGAIN.
THAT'S THE TRUTH.
YOU'LL KNOW THE TRUTH
WHEN YOU FIND IT.
IT'LL COME TO
YOU LIKE SOMETHING
YOU'VE KNOWN BEFORE
RATHER THAN SOMETHING
YOU'RE LEARNING FOR
THE FIRST TIME.
OH, SORRY.
THAT'S OKAY.
AHH! BOLLOCKS!
WHAT IS IT?
( Leonard groaning )
OHH, YOU FU...!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YOU OKAY?
YEAH. I STUBBED MY TOE.
IT'S BLEEDING.
IT'S FINE. IT'S FINE,
IT'S FINE. IT'S FINE.
YOU FINISHED IN THERE?
YES.
FUCK!
Caleb: I MET THESE BACKPACKERS
LAST NIGHT, FRANK AND ELSA.
SHE'S FRENCH, HE'S GERMAN.
THEY'RE GOING TO TIBET,
AND I'M GOING WITH THEM.
I WANT YOU TO COME WITH ME.
HI.
HOW ARE YOU?
KNACKERED.
LONG DAY?
GOD, WHEN ARE THEY NOT?
I DON'T THINK I'D JUMP
AT DOING ANOTHER
STINT LIKE THIS.
HOW'S THE WRITING GOING?
I'M FEELING INSPIRED.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
I THINK I'VE FIGURED OUT
THE KEY TO FINISHING
THE PROJECT.
ARE YOU LISTENING?
YOU FOUND THE KEY
TO FINISHING THIS PROJECT.
THE WATER HERE
TASTES SO FUNNY.
HAVE YOU EVER CHEATED ON ME?
OH, JANE.
HAVE YOU?
CAN WE NOT?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
WHY DID YOU TAKE SUCH
A LONG TIME TO ANSWER THAT?
BECAUSE I'M SICK...
OF WHAT, LEONARD?
OF IT BEING SO HARD?
YES.
TEDIOUS?
I HATE TALKING
ABOUT SEX WITH YOU.
IS THAT WHAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT?
NORMAL PEOPLE
TALK ABOUT SEX, LEONARD.
AND WE DON'T?
THERE'S JUST
HUGE VACANT LOTS
THAT WE DON'T DISCUSS.
LIKE WHAT?
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO ASK ME?
WHY? IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO TELL ME?
I JUST WANNA CONNECT.
SO YOU DON'T FEEL
THAT WE'RE CONNECTED.
DO YOU?
I LOVE YOU.
I GET IT, LEONARD.
I GET IT.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
THIS BIG, SERIOUS,
GRAVE THING FOR US.
SEX HAS CONSEQUENCES,
LIFE AND DEATH,
MOSTLY DEATH.
JANE, PLEASE.
LET ME GUESS. YOU DON'T
WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT?
NO, THAT'S NOT WHAT
I'M SAYING. YOU'RE JUST--
DO YOU WANT TO HAVE
CHILDREN, LEONARD?
OF COURSE I DID.
NOT "DID." DO YOU WANT
TO HAVE CHILDREN?
SO DID YOU, BUT...
SAY IT.
JANE.
I CAN'T HAVE CHILDREN,
LEONARD.
I NEVER WILL.
AND IF WE KEEP TRYING,
THEY KEEP DYING.
PLEASE, JANE. PLEASE.
AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND AGAIN.
HOW DOES THAT
MAKE YOU FEEL?
IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
HOW DOES IT MAKE
YOU FEEL, LEONARD?
HOW DOES IT MAKE YOU FEEL?
YOU WILL NEVER BE A FATHER.
WE CAN ADOPT.
THAT'S NOT
WHAT YOU WANT, IS IT?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
HM?
'CAUSE I THINK ABOUT IT
ALL THE TIME.
THAT THE ONE THING
YOU ALWAYS WANTED,
I WILL NEVER BE
ABLE TO GIVE YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO DO, JANE?
I JUST WANT TO
KNOW THAT THERE'S
A REASON... FOR IT ALL.
YOU'RE NOT CURIOUS
ABOUT ME, LEONARD.
NOT REALLY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO KNOW?
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TO ASK.
I FEEL AS IF YOU WANT
ME TO BE SOMEONE I'M NOT.
SOMEONE
THAT I'VE NEVER BEEN.
I'M LEAVING YOU.
I'VE BEEN
SEEING SOMEONE ELSE.
SEEING?
CALEB.
THAT KID?
YES.
THAT KID, THAT CHILD,
THAT KID YOU'VE KNOWN
FOR TWO DAYS?
IT'S BEEN LONGER THAN THAT.
PLEASE TELL ME YOU'RE JOKING.
TIME IS SHIFTABLE.
I DON'T GET IT.
LEONARD.
HE'S ASKED ME
TO TRAVEL WITH HIM.
ARE YOU SLEEPING WITH HIM?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
( glass shatters;
car horn honks outside )
I KEPT WAITING FOR YOU
TO SEE IT, TO SMELL IT,
TO SENSE IT!
SO, WHAT?
I FAILED YOUR TEST?
YOU DON'T SEE ME!
I'M SORRY.
FOR WHAT?
I SHOULDN'T
HAVE DONE THAT.
NO.
LOSING MY TEMPER.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE THAT.
YOU HAD EVERY RIGHT...
...TO LOSE YOUR TEMPER.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
IF YOU THINK THAT
THIS IS WHAT'S GONNA
MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER,
THEN YOU SHOULD GO.
YOU SHOULD GO WITH HIM.
YOU'VE BEEN
THROUGH A TERRIBLE...
TERRIBLE THING, JANE.
NO.
THAT IS NOT WHAT
THIS IS ABOUT.
OF COURSE IT IS.
YOU DON'T LOVE ME
ANYMORE, LEONARD.
YOU DON'T LOVE ME!
THAT'S-- THAT'S RUBBISH.
THIS IS YOUR TICKET.
THE DAY
AFTER MY PERFORMANCE,
MEET ME
AT THE TRAIN STATION.
OUR TRAIN LEAVES AT 4:30.
WE'LL GO HOME TOGETHER.
I WANT YOU TO DO
WHAT YOU NEED TO DO.
AND THEN COME BACK TO ME.
NO QUESTIONS ASKED,
NO GUILT.
THIS IS GOOD.
( classical music playing )
( classical piece ends )
( final note lingers )
HI.
YOU WANT SOME?
NO THANKS.
FRANK AND ELSA ARE...
COMIN' OVER
IN A COUPLE HOURS.
FRANK BOUGHT A CAR,
SO WE'RE GONNA...
WE'RE GONNA HEAD OUT
IN A COUPLE WEEKS...
OR SO, YOU KNOW.
WE'RE THINKING ABOUT, UH...
DRIVING THROUGH ROMANIA,
THEN... THEN, UH...
UKRAINE,
THEN DOWN THROUGH RUSSIA,
AND THROUGH KAZAKHSTAN
AND STRAIGHT TO, UH, TIBET.
( speaking Italian )
CIAO.
( indistinct announcement
over P.A. system )
JANE!
YOU'VE GOT TO COME
OVER TO THIS SIDE.
THE TRAIN'S GONNA
BE HERE IN A MINUTE.
Female Vocalist:
♪ IT'S FOUR IN THE MORNING
♪ THE END OF DECEMBER
♪ I'M WRITING YOU NOW
JUST TO SEE ♪
♪ IF YOU'RE BETTER
♪ NEW YORK IS COLD
♪ BUT I LIKE
WHERE I'M LIVING ♪
♪ THERE'S MUSIC
ON CLINTON STREET ♪
♪ ALL THROUGH THE EVENING
♪ I HEAR THAT
YOU'RE BUILDING ♪
♪ YOUR HOUSE
♪ DEEP IN THE DESERT
♪ ARE YOU LIVING
FOR NOTHING NOW? ♪
♪ HOPE YOU'RE KEEPING
♪ SOME KIND OF RECORD
♪ YES
♪ AND JANE
♪ CAME BY WITH
A LOCK OF YOUR HAIR ♪
♪ SHE SAID THAT YOU
GAVE IT ♪
♪ TO HER
♪ THAT NIGHT WHEN
YOU PLANNED TO GO CLEAR ♪
Grandmother: I WOULDN'T
WANT TO LIVE TO BE 100.
Jane: WHY NOT?
I'M NOT TELLING YOU
WHY NOT.
Female Vocalist:
♪ DID YOU EVER GO CLEAR?
Grandmother:
NOW SHUT THAT THING OFF!
Female Vocalist:
♪ AH, THE LAST TIME
WE SAW YOU ♪
♪ YOU LOOKED SO MUCH OLDER
♪ YOUR FAMOUS BLUE
RAINCOAT ♪
♪ WAS TORN AT THE SHOULDER
♪ YOU'D BEEN
TO THE STATION ♪
♪ TO MEET EVERY TRAIN
♪ BUT SHE NEVER TURNED UP
♪ I MEAN LILI MARLENE
♪ SO YOU TREATED
♪ SOME WOMAN
♪ TO A FLAKE
♪ OF YOUR LIFE
♪ AND WHEN SHE GOT HOME
♪ SHE WAS NOBODY'S WIFE
♪ WELL, I SEE YOU THERE
♪ WITH THAT ROSE
IN YOUR TEETH ♪
♪ ONE MORE THIN
GYPSY THIEF ♪
♪ WELL, I SEE
JANE'S AWAKE ♪
♪ MM-HMM
♪ SHE SENDS HER REGARDS
♪ AND WHAT CAN I TELL YOU?
♪ OH, WHAT CAN I TELL YOU?
♪ WHAT CAN I POSSIBLY SAY?
♪ I GUESS THAT I MISS YOU
♪ I GUESS I FORGIVE YOU
♪ I'M GLAD THAT YOU
STOOD IN MY WAY ♪
♪ AND IF YOU EVER
COME BY HERE ♪
♪ BE IT FOR JANE
♪ OR FOR ME
♪ I WANT YOU TO KNOW
♪ YOUR ENEMY IS SLEEPING
♪ YOUR WOMAN IS FREE
♪ YES
♪ AND THANKS
♪ FOR THE TROUBLE
YOU TOOK ♪
♪ FROM HER EYES
♪ I THOUGHT IT WAS THERE
♪ FOR GOOD
♪ SO I NEVER REALLY TRIED
♪ AND JANE
♪ CAME BY
♪ WITH A LOCK OF YOUR HAIR
♪ SHE SAID THAT YOU
GAVE IT TO HER ♪
♪ THAT NIGHT WHEN YOU
PLANNED TO GO CLEAR ♪
♪ SINCERELY
♪ A FRIEND