(Train Station Announcement Polish)
Hello! Hello!
Auschwitz-Museum?
eh, street...
One moment, moment...
- This is... street...
- Thank you.
Hello.
- Good morning.
My name is Sven Lehnert.
I am here because of the civil service job.
Hello.
- Hello, hello...
Excuse me.
Excuse me,
is this your...
Empty?
Totally empty.
But you speak German, right?
Is this a hostel now?
You are Sven? Herold. Welcome.
I will show you around.
If you have questions, simply ask me, okay?
- Okay.
You are the only one doing service here.
In the moment and in the beginning,
You have to do everything's coming up
Later when you are more experienced,
You can guide groups,
Buy bus tickets,
Organize lunch and
Manage analysis groups.
We will see.
We are not a youth hostel only,
We also guide
The young visitors here
In an educational way...
Go to seminar room one, ok?
I'll see you there a little later.
You'll stay in the guest house first.
We usually put the teachers there,
For one or two days,
If there is no room left here.
These are the sleeping halls, but
I'll look for something in the city for you
You'll get to see some daily life there.
But I haven't got the time yet.
(Polish)
- Hmmm... milk.
Milk?
- Yes.
(Polish)
(Knocking on the door)
(Repeated knocking)
- Come in.
Hello, just wanted to say...
- (Polish)
Didn't want to disturb you,
Just... - You live here now?
Yes. I am living here.
Civil service.
From Germany?
- Mhm.
Where from?
- Berlin.
I see!
Why, do you know Berlin?
I am supposed to take care for you
for the time being. - Take care?
You are some kind of servant?
No.
- Assistant for my job?
No, it's only about helping around
With a few simply things.
Like buying things and such.
And I can drive you
To these... history witness talks.
And tomorrow we'll have physiotherapy.
I am not sick.
Who is saying that I need
Physiotherapy?
Mr. Herold. The latter dates you
Haven't attended, right?
This order, that you have to
Take care for me,
Herold said, that you should do that?
But that wasn't an order. That...
I believe, he wants to be nice to you.
Oh, yes.
I know.
I have... that's the reason I am here...
I bought a bottle of milk.
Put it in the fridge
And close the door.
That is great music.
- (Polish)
No, no, no. I...
- You are German?
Yes. I am from Berlin.
Uuuh, German, right?
Fritz, German, Berlin, yes?
Yes, yes, I...
- What are you doing here?
I am doing... civil service.
You know civil service?
Civil?
- Yes, civil service. For one year.
In Germany you can choose
To go to the army or do civil service.
Civil army? - Yes.
- And what are you doing?
I am working in the hostel, near
Auschwitz-Museum, you know?
Civil army Auschwitz?
Sort of, yes.
- I see, ok.
Hey guys!
The German army is here again
in Auschwitz.
Here you can see the suitcases.
The prisoners have been told,
They would be send to the east.
That's why they took all kinds of
Necessary things.
Right after their arrival here
The suitcases have been taken away.
Please have a look at the plates.
Here is the name,
Family name, birth date,
Transport number,
Sometimes the address as well.
What you see here,
Is only a small amount of the
Dispossessed suitcases.
Please follow me.
(Polish)
Unbelievable, how packed this was, right?
- Excuse me?
I said: it’s unbelievably crowded.
So many people around.
Weekend.
You don't go on?
- By bus?
No, I am not here by bus.
I am by myself.
Moved here a week ago.
Civil service.
Civil service?
Why this place?
I didn't want to. I was supposed to...
I had a position, hmm...
In Amsterdam, centre for young people.
But somehow that didn't work out.
And then this came along.
There was an open position here.
And now I am slowly getting
A feeling for it, why. Well...
Oh.
Amsterdam...
Ok, have to rush. Sorry.
- Bye.
(Polish)
(Herold) Please let me ask you,
To write down a word,
A short sentence on the cards,
Been given to you by Sven.
It is all about to find a "place"
Which came to your mind
In Birkenau and Auschwitz
Something in your memory.
"Emotion"... yes, some feeling,
You had visiting the memorial.
And please let me ask you
To concentrate on one feeling.
And with "Wish" please make a wish
Or a short sentence,
For the future, after you have left
The memorial.
(Silence)
Anybody wants to start? Anybody at all?
It is all voluntarily.
Nobody has to do this.
- Yes, I can start.
So I chose the place, hmmm... the room
With the suitcases from block six.
Hmm, there was this cupboard
With lots of suitcases.
My guess is a thousand or some.
And each of them had a name on it.
The prisoners and some also
The priso... or the detainee's number.
Good.
Sven, would you please pin this here?
As "place" I chose the children's clothing,
That was in block six as well,
Jonas mentioned this already.
There was a cabinet
With a small jacket,
Some small trousers,
Baby socks, a rattle
That made me feel very emotional.
As "Emotion" I chose helplessness
And as "Wish" I want,
That this terrible times never
Shall be forgotten.
Please!
Why are you walking so slow?
Wait downstairs.
Here.
Lighter.
The lighter, please.
To the left over there.
Mr Krzeminski? Excuse me.
Mr Krzeminski? I don't want to disturb but
I am working until seven only.
And what's the time? - It is already...
I believe it is almost eight.
You don't have a watch?
- No, I don't have one.
Look at this.
A German without a watch.
A German chauffeur.
Times are a changing.
Mr Krzeminski,
We have to go, ok?
You can leave then!
I don't keep you from going.
Just ask him,
Wether his Grandfather
Has been working here as well.
Ok, then I wish you
A nice evening.
Sven, let's have a word, ok?
One of the colleagues has picked up
Krzeminski half the way back.
He went by foot. In the night.
On the country road.
Sven, if something had happened to him! -
But I have asked him a few times.
He didn't want to come.
- Ok, but then you should have waited!
Or call us here. - But how should I know
That he would try to make it on his own.
Why hasn't he called a taxi?
- Listen, Sven, it's not that simple.
This is a sensitive place.
Former concentration camp prisoner
Dead in car accident,
Because German civil service worker
Left him alone.
That's what the newspapers
Would say.
Yes?
Krzeminski is in his eighties. And he
Is not in the best shape lately,
And this is why you are supposed
To take care. Is this so difficult?
No, but do I have to live with him
All the time?
That's kind of...
We have been talking about this,
I will find a way.
Where are you going?
Don't worry, I will be back.
Ok, we meet tomorrow, 3 o'clock.
- This is your new landlord.
Hello.
- Hello.
Hi. - Hi.
- Sven.
We have met before.
- Yes, at the exhibition.
So much the better.
- Yes.
Well, then... where are your things,
Your backpack?
My stuff is over there in the office. -
You want me to help?
See you later. - You are here?
- Yes I am waiting here.
Hey?
Hey!
Can you switch this off?
This is my brother Krzysztof.
Sven.
Fritz?
- Hello.
You know each other?
- Yes, hmm, I was at his concert.
What is he doing here?
- He is moving in.
Don't I disturb you?
I mean in your room.
Could you please move your stuff?
You have let my room?
- Yes.
Are you sure? - Just take your stuff
and don't start a discussion.
This German guy is going to
Take my room?
This is my place and you haven't paid
Your part of the rent since three months.
Take your things out now.
You are not serious, are you?
- Of course and now get going!
Welcome.
Calm down!
What? How? I, hmm...
Sleep in his room? And he is moving out? -
No, you will take this room.
Thanks, sweet sister mine.
A German in my room.
Should I sleep in his room? - This is not
His room. This is my place.
If this is a problem, I'll find something else. -
No, this is not a problem.
Where do you take me?
- Well, to this, eh... chemical factory.
We have a new trainee's group there
In the meeting facilities.
Rhon chemical. A German group.
They took over the factory.
Good morning.
My name is Stanislaw Krzeminski.
From the 10th of January
I was prisoner number
9.372
in Auschwitz.
In my car from Tarnow
There were 102 comrades...
Sorry.
Four have survived.
Thank you.
You are German as well?
- Mhm.
Isn't it crazy, right? The way these
Polish guys have let this place gone down.
I don't know.
I didn't have a close look.
Well, wouldn't do that if
I were in your shoes.
At least not without helmet and
breathing protection.
Anyway, there's a lot to do.
We have got some other
Things working in the end.
Stop eating!
Come on in everybody!
Questions and answers now...
Mrs Schneider?
Hello Mr Dremmler.
- Hello. This is our history witness.
Mr...?
- Krzeminski.
Hello Mr Krzeminski. I am very sorry
that I couldn't make it to your lecture.
I had to listen to the
Reports by our trainees.
And they are very impressed.
This discussion will stay with them
A lifetime.
- It is only a story.
Oh no. This is an encounter.
And this will stay with them. Please.
Thank you.
- No, we have to thank you.
For my trainees and for myself
This is an exciting beginning,
In our new operation here
In Oswiecim.
I am positive, the few weeks here
Will be unforgettable and
An important part
Of your training.
I wish to say thank you
Once again
That we had the chance
To listen to your story
And I am confident that we will
Hear some interesting questions.
Steffi, can you please begin.
What did you eat in the camp?
We have eaten everything.
Leftovers from the swine feeders.
There was no grass left
Between the barracks.
I stole bread crumbs
From my neighbor.
By day and by night
We have been dreaming of food.
Yes, please. - Did he also get a
Number in the camp?
He wants to know, wether you
got a number tattoo in the camp..
All of us
Have got a number.
Eh... Would it be possible
That you show it to us?
Of course.
Almost gone.
Didn't have it renewed.
"Hey boy, do you wanna go with us?"
What's up? Do you come along?
Where to?
- Surprise.
I simply don't know,
What I want to do. - What?
I am not sure, what I want to do later.
It is just like that.
This is the good thing about this civil-thing,
because it gives me a year to contemplate.
Yes, this may be good. - l believe
Something's gonna happen, you know?
But there must be something you
Really want to do, right?
No. - Everybody has got that.
Like a dream. Dream! - No!
Maybe one or two... all my friends,
The girls from my grade,
They push buggies into church
And then they pick up their
Drunken husbands from the bar.
I simply don't want to do this.
That's your dream?
- Yes, the nightmare! - My nightmare!
And Krzeminski
talks about his camp life.
But the trainees really don't know
What they should ask him.
He gets this envelope from the manager
And says thank you for a thousand times.
She hasn't been there, has no idea
But show off like being so deeply  impressed.
And how bad it all has been...
She doesn't need to know anything
About history, all that matters is business.
Why? - At least they will invest
Here in this place. And this is good, isn't it.
Without the factory all people,
Including Krzysztof,
Wouldn't have a job.
- Krzysztof is working in the factory?
Yes. Not all can depend on the camp.
The tourists come in the morning,
And then they leave for Warsaw
Or they go to Krakow.
Ok, but I don't really believe
They will invest.
They come, that's globalization,
They come to this place, press out the juice...
Attention. Germans!
Are you mad?
You are really sick.
Calm down, dear sister.
- Asshole.
What's this called? - "Zasraniec".
- Zasraniec!
What?
Mr Krzeminski. We have to go
To physiotherapy, Mr Krzeminski.
Is it my fault,
If you come that late?
Come here.
Help me. Hold this.
This is all falling apart.
This new glaze
From that idiots.
Go to Konserwacja
And get me a new suitcase.
Listen, I better get you
To physiotherapy first.
And afterwards I would be pleased
To get a new one for you. - Yes, go ahead.
I have to pack this.
- We have to go now. Please!
Go ahead.
Hello.
Can I help you?
Karol!
Krzeminski's suitcase.
Krzeminski says, it must be something...
With the glaze.
Glaze?
He is ruining the suitcases
with his old methods.
We can forget about this one
For the exhibition.
This is going on since half a year already.
He told me,
It was broken before.
Krzeminski fucks up
The suitcases, right?
Ok, good.
I will tell him.
Oh, and then I need
A new suitcase as well.
He wants a new one.
Give him one.
(Sven tries to speak Polish)
May I... may... help?
Oh, you are from, Germany?
- Yes.
Boah, what's this then?
I have tried it with my
Children and grandchildren
hmm... teaching them German,
but it didn't work out.
Only me and my brother
Speak German.
Ah, you want to Mr Krzeminski?
- Yes.
I just drove him into town.
- Oh!
And I have called last week
To confirm this.
He is doing this intentionally.
I don't think so, because he is
Attending physiotherapy. - Physiotherapy?
This is good!
Please hand this letter to my brother.
And if he's going mad
Just tell him,
I am not getting younger either.
Will you do this?
- I will. - Thanks a lot.
Good.
- Bye.
Lighter.
She said, you shouldn't get mad,
because she's not getting younger either
Is it her birthday?
The lighter, please.
Of course.
What's in this?
How should I know?
It's from your sister.
It's an exercise bike.
- What?
A bike. For indoors.
Take it with you and leave.
It's heavy.
can't carry it by myself
Ok, see you tomorrow then?
Bulb.
- What?
The bulb in the doorway.
Change it.
I am off since twenty minutes.
I'll do it tomorrow, ok?
You change the bulb now.
And where's the fucking ladder?
- Ladder?
I don't understand. I work from 9:30 am
to 6pm, 40 hours a week.
Enough time for you to give orders
I've no choice.
But I also respond to complete
sentences. If that's possible.
if I could do it myself,
climb a ladder,
do the grocery shopping,
drive a car,
believe me...
I wouldn't take up your time.
Please turn on the light.
Yes.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Take this garbage out with you!
Cassette.
Lighter. Lighter please.
Krzeminski...
- A strange guy.
Krzeminski has always lived at the camp.
He won't move out.
I don't get it. He's got family.
Why not live with them?
Or at least somewhere else?
Never change an old tree.
Where did you learn that??
- It's pretty.
German's a nice language.
An old tree like that can topple over.
I almost saw it today.
If he were to fall from that ladder,
it'd be "good night" for him.
Good night.
Hello. Good morning.
Have you learned
some Polish yet?
"Troche". "Przepraszam".
"Dzien dobry". "Dziekuje".
"Tak, tak, tak".
Very good.
Just four words.
Don't listen to him..
My pleasure. Hello.
Tadeusz.
- Thaddeus.
Boguslawa. - Oh?
- Boguslawa.
We have it all for your here.
A garden, a room, good food.
In this one-horse town?
Stanislaw.
At least it is not the camp.
You never understood my point.
What a pity.
Stay stubborn then.
You are good at that.
You are right.
I am good at that.
Please turn off
this sentimental nonsense!
She says I should move in with her.
Why not? Her place is nice.
In the country.
My place is here.
I have a duty
she doesn't understand that.
She doesn't understand,
that I'm needed here.
Good night.
Thank you for driving me.
You are welcome.
Wonderfull!
Get up. You hear me?
Ok. Ok.
Enough! Can't you get up once
On your own and go to work?
How late is it?
- Twenty past five!
Shit!
- Shit.
Get going!
You have waken up Sven.
Go to work!
Everything okay?
Sorry, I didn't want to wake you up.
- Doesn't matter.
I want to ask you a favor.
In a few days, the German trainees
will put up a memorial stone at Monowice.
It's from Rhon Chemie
who supports us here too.
maybe you could
take care of the project.
Sure.
You should read up
on the historical background a little.
and assist them when they're there...
No problem.
Have you been there yet?
- No.
It was a subcamp, for forced laborers
at IG-Farben.
Come on!
It's nice here.
This is Monowice.
Auschwitz III.
What was? Where? All over here?
- Yes.
This was the camp street
where you're riding now.
And the barracks were over there
where the houses are now?
Yes.
Wild. It looks like a normal village.
Wait! Look at this.
They want to put up
the memorial here.
How many prisoners were here?
- What?
- Around 30.000.
Come on , Sven.
No tours today.
Look here! A Bunker
-Come on.
The subject bothers you.
But how is it for you?
I'm sorry. I mean...
You lived here all your life and...
So?
Is it commonplace for you
to ride through Monowice?
or is it somehow...
Yes, but I...I was born here
I live here. My life is here.
Yes I know, but...
You live where humanity's
greatest atrocity took place.
You're living here now too.
How... do you feel about it?
You're German.
What do you think?
I don't understand the question.
Should we go? .
Want to go see a movie?
- You wouldn't understand a word.
So what?
Maybe another time.
- Okay.
But...
I don't understand...
Preserve! Not repair!
This is the most important
Basic principle.
Conserve,
Not repair!
He's never been to university.
Somebody's gotta talk with him.
I cannot take responsibility
Any longer.
He's not gonna get any
Suitcases any longer.
No more suitcases.
What?
- It's over!
I don't understand.
Why no more suitcases?
I don't know either.
They said something like....
there are problems at the moment...
it's going slowly...
They need to look into it.
I don't know.
I didn’t understand the whole point of it.
Just as well.
Some time off.
You can visit your family
Or drink a beer with colleagues.
Horse betting.
- Don't bother me with that.
Good Morning.
Yes?
- Hello.
Everything's alright with the suitcases.
- Oh yes?
I'll be on my way.
- Alright fine.
Stay still!
Can you wet this?
Don't move!
Hold this. Face towards me.
Are you able to patch this... ah!
Look at me!
Can you cut the bandage
and pull it out?
Thanks. - Do you need more?
- Yes.
What happened?
- Nothing.
Don't be childish.
- You hurt me.
Just leave me alone, you idiot!
I have lost my job.
Why?
Germans kicked me out..
They're firing people.
Damn it.
What should I do?
Don't worry about it
I am fed up with this.
I'll let you be.
Wait.
We're a little late,
everyone's here already.
They won't start without me.
Mr. Krzeminski.
Good morning. How nice of you
to join us.
Mr. Friedrich
One of our board members
He came from Germany
especially for this.
On behalf of my company,
thank you for your time..
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You already know our mayor.
- Good morning, Mr. Krzeminski.
We're ready then. We can start.
The prisoners feared
the selections the most.
Right here, where you're standing,
On this roll call area
The SS medics used to decide
In a matter of seconds
On life and death.
I saw the bored faces of the doctors
Quite often.
They felt uncomfortable,
Just looking at us.
They only judged us
Based on our value to them.
Thank you, Mr. Krzeminski.
Thank you for your talk.
Okay we can take the picture. Thanks.
Mr Krzeminski, come, please.
No... sorry. I think it's better
if you'd come over here.
It's always very tiring for him.
Fine. We'll take the picture
without him.
What a remarkable man
this Mr. Krzeminski.
What goes on in the mind
of such a person?
Well, maybe you should have
let him finish.
I thought his talk was losing impact.
-What impact?
He should just talk some.
He can decide on his own
for how long.
Not everyone has the strength
to deal with the past,
like you do.
I think what you do is good.
You work here.
Do you know Krzysztof Lanuszewski?
He works for you.
A friend of yours?
- Yes, he’s Polish. About my age.
Yes you just fired him.
- I know him well.
Just like back then.
Thrown away when of no value.
He came too late or not at all.
Our plant cannot accept this.
And your comparison is tasteless.
No, no Krzystof you should have
told me why you lost your job.
You know one minute ago I'm standing
with Mrs Schneider talking about you...
It's not about Schneider.
- I want to help him.
Who asked you to get involved?
- You saw how they treated him...
Schneider is a real bitch
-Yes - She’s a bitch.
Why the sudden interest in Krzeminski?
- He was in the Camp. Let him talk.
That's not the problem.
You're the problem idiot.
You are the problem, Idiot.
- Calm down.
You are not my mother, ok?
I am really fed up with this.
I've had it.
I'm leaving.
I am done. Thanks a lot.
I am leaving.
Just go.
I'll be gone in four weeks too.
What? you're going away?
I applied for a scholarship.
In Brussels.
To become an interpreter
for the agricultural commission.
And...
- And I won't earn a cent there..
And when...
- The exam is in Warsaw tomorrow.
And if you pass the exam?
Then I start in four weeks.
Hey.
- Good morning.
How do I look?
Can i go like this??
Yeah...
It looks like Brussels.
Are you going to wish me luck?
- Of course.
My train leaves in 30 minutes.
Mr. Krzeminski?
Mr Krzeminski?
Oh shit!
Mr. Krzeminski?
Can you hear me?
Mr. Krzeminski, what happened?
What happened?
Here's some water?
- It's fine...
It’s fine. Leave me alone.
Is everything?
- It’s fine. Leave me alone.
It's okay.
Go!
What happened?
What I missed the most,
was not having cigarettes.
But if you pass out like that
nobody'd know.
It'd take forever for someone
to come by. It's not right.
I'm still functioning. Everything is okay.
You came.
By chance. I brought cigarettes for you.
If I had not...
Maybe you're right.
Can you call my sister?
A man like me...
isn't needed anymore
around here.
Well, I do believe,
that you are needed here.
For youth groups, for example.
And for the people you talk to.
It's like...
It's quite different isn't?
Show them "Schindlers Liste".
That has more impact.
Is the suitcase ready?
- Yeah, ready.
Na?
The boss asked me
where I come from.
and when I told him ...
they looked at me uneasily..
Everyone.
Maybe, that's why they chose me.
-Nonsense.
I do...
- I don't think so.
No...
- What?
And I had to sign right there...
the same evening...
I had to sign all documents.
It was strange. A few signatures
take me away from here.
Yeah...
Please don't do that.
- What? What's wrong?
Hey?
Talk to me
I don't understand you.
Yes I know.
How can I explain it?
I don't want that..
- Say what's on your mind.
I'm gone in 2 weeks.
You’re gone in a few months.
And it's different for you.
You don't know what you want to do.
You're waiting for what comes.
That has nothing to do with it.
- Yes it does.
I have only one chance to get away from here,
do you understand?
And I want to go away.
I would like to apologize
for Sven's behavior
and hope that this transgression
does not impair our good relations.
I will make sure that
this does not get repeated.
Krzeminski's work with the department
Is honored. -
But we are part of a museum.
We have to consider
Every single piece.
Mr. Herold, excuse me,
but it's obvious...
that his work is being taken away.
It's his job. - Sven It's enough.
It's important to him. - Enough.
- Who says "sensitive place"!
Are you deaf?
I am sorry, Mr. Krzeminski.
Mr. Krzeminski...
I'm really sorry.
I know I shouldn't have lied to you.
We just had one hour,
to take the bags,
the suitcase
and other things away from the prisoners
on the ramp.
I have promised...
these people, these families,
children... that they
would get their suitcases back.
Go now.
I would like to be alone.
Didn't you hear me?
What's this about?
What are you doing?
- I'm going back to Berlin.
What? - I'm going back.
It's too complicated here.
What's too complicated?
I went shopping for dinner.
So?
Wait here please.
Excuse me, do you speak English or German?
- Yes german.
Wonderful. The youth center?
Uliza Prschesy...
It's called "Ulica Przemyslowa".
Bus no 1 over there.
You know your way around??
- Yes. - Thank you.
Let's go to bus no.1 over there.
It's over there. -There?
-I'll come with you for the moment.
It's very kind of you. - No problem.
I forgot something anyway.
Our civilization, our culture
will be ultimately be judged,
on how we deal with this dark period
in history, right?
The systematic killing of millions of people
places a challenge before us.
I need to get to the ticket machine.
I think it's exemplary
what you're doing here.
Especially for our students.