- Bonjour, madame.
- Bonjour.
I want a small suite, please. Must be quiet.
I have a very charming one
facing the courtyard.
Will Madame please sign her name?
Merci, madame.
To save inconvenience later,
- will you kindly leave your passport here?
- Passport?
- I showed my passport at the airport.
- I'm sorry, but it's a government regulation.
Oh.
Travelling's becoming
quite complicated, isn't it?
Merci, madame. S'il vous plaît.
- Bonjour, madame.
- Will you show madame to 54?
Par ici, s'il vous plaît.
Is there anything wrong?
Not at all.
Everything will be all right, I assure you.
- Mrs Brown.
- Thank you.
- Trente-cinq francs.
- Don't you speak English?
Pas Anglais, monsieur.
Merci, monsieur. Merci.
- Don't I get anything back?
- Merci, monsieur. Merci.
No, no, money. Er... change.
- Er... back.
- Merci, monsieur. Merci beaucoup.
Oh, don't rub it in.
You want me to wait?
Merci beaucoup.
Amazing! You know,
I'm going to like Bolshevism.
Why, could you earn your own living?
No, that's the bad part about Bolshevism.
But it has merit.
Without the Revolution,
the Grand Duchess would be in Russia
instead of providing such a delightful salon.
And perhaps I should never have met you.
One for Your Highness.
- Who is this Mr Halton?
- I've never seen him before.
I think, an Englishman. He brings
best regards from Captain Buckler.
Captain Buckler? Oh, yes.
Let him wait in the reception room.
I'll be a few minutes.
The Grand Duchess will be delighted
to see you, but it will be a few moments.
If you will be so kind as to step in here.
- Rue de la Tour, 314.
- Pardon, madame.
- Oh, Rue de la Tour, trois quatorze.
- Ah, oui, madame.
Whom may I announce, madame?
Oh... Just say an old friend.
Listen, my man, this is very important.
How can I reach Miss Field?
What's that you say?
3467. What is it you want?
- Pardon me.
- Who's playing the piano?
- The Englishman.
- I'd forgotten him.
Pardon me.
There is a lady waiting to see you.
- Who is she?
- She said, an old friend.
Tell her to leave her address
and don't let her in again.
All I want is a cup of tea and a sandwich.
- Now!
- Mm-hm.
- It isn't possible.
- It is I.
Oh!
You look marvellous. You know, I haven't
seen you, not since I opened the salon.
- And I haven't heard from you in...
- In six years, Anna.
Six? Why didn't you write to me?
You know I always like
to keep track of my friends.
That's why I didn't write to you.
Oh! Oh.
Well, now, tell me everything.
How was Rome?
Rome? I haven't been in Rome for years.
Has your husband been transferred?
Husband? Oh, you mean Savoldi?
- That's right.
- Oh, I didn't marry him.
- I broke the engagement.
- Why?
- Forgotten.
- Oh.
- What are you doing now?
- At the moment, I'm in Paris.
By the way, I'm not in Paris. Can I trust you?
I swear.
Anna... I’m in a rather difficult situation.
- Serious?
- Very.
I really came to Paris to ask your advice.
- You know I always give sensible advice.
- Yes, I know.
Driving up here, I realised that
I don't want any sensible advice.
I want no sense, no logic, no reason.
It can't help me at the moment.
- What's going on in Paris?
- Well...
Will you excuse me?
Hello. Hell...
Oh, it's you.
Look, may I call you back in ten minutes?
- Do you want me to go out?
- Just a moment.
You're so understanding.
- How do you do?
So kind of you to see me.
I bring you best regards
from Captain Buckler.
- Captain Buckler?
- You remember Willy Buckler.
He always talked so much about you, and...
He told me, "If you want an amusing time
in Paris, go to the Grand Duchess and..."
And... here I am.
And there you are.
- So you want an amusing time in Paris.
- Well...
Well, we must see
that you have a very amusing time.
Sit down, please.
- Have you been in Paris before?
- Not since the war.
- How exciting for you.
- Yes, I'm thrilled.
And I'm so glad to meet you.
Thank you.
Be seated, please.
- You're going to see Paris at its best.
- I'm so glad.
Let me think. What could I suggest?
Oh, first of all,
you would like to see the Louvre museum.
The what?
One of the most interesting
picture galleries in the world.
You've heard of the Mona Lisa.
Er... yes, I, er... I believe I have.
Oh, you don't care for pictures?
Oh, I know. The Eiffel Tower.
You mean that...
that steel thing, stuck up in the air?
Do you know what I'm afraid of?
- What?
- I'm afraid you'll suggest Notre Dame.
I was just coming to that.
Madame. Even if you could give me
the history of each stone separately,
- I'm still not interested.
- Oh.
I've found, through life,
the days take care of themselves.
- It's the evenings that are so difficult.
- Oh, how stupid of me.
You want me to arrange a party for you.
A nice, large party.
- Not too large.
- Six?
Four?
Two?
Two is the best suggestion.
Why do you stare at me like that?
He's completely off his head.
What are you talking about?
Buckler. He described you
as "hard as nails".
Much older, and, erm... beginning to, er...
- Beginning to spread.
- How unkind of him.
I hope you don't think the description fits me.
If he'd said
one of the loveliest women in the world,
I'd have recognised you anywhere.
Encouraging. Thank you.
Now, I wonder which one of my friends
you would like.
- May I make a suggestion?
- Please.
It would make our mutual friend Buckler
very happy if, er...
- if you would dine with me.
- I'm engaged.
Oh. Well, then, don't bother any more.
I'll have a couple of boiled eggs,
a detective story, and go to bed.
Madame. Have you ever been
at the mercy of loneliness?
Have you ever been a stranger
in a strange city?
- Often.
- What did you do?
I cried.
Well, that's what I shall do.
Café Danube. Nine o'clock.
Eight-thirty.
Nine o'clock.
But, Your Highness...
Oh, by the way, I'm not the Grand Duchess.
What?
Quarter to nine.
Mr Halton.
- How do you do?
- You are the Grand Duchess Anna.
- Yes.
Captain Buckler described you so accurately
I would have known you anywhere.
Oh, thank you so much.
Captain Buckler. I imagine he wants me
to arrange something for you.
Who would you like to meet?
What would you like to do?
Er...
I'd like to see the Louvre museum.
- The what?
- Yes, the Louvre,
the Eiffel Tower,
oh, and most of all, Notre Dame.
Are you sure you're a friend
of Captain Buckler's?
Mm-hm.
Well, well, well.
Afraid I can't do anything for you.
Oh, yes, you can.
Tell me the name of the lady
who was here a moment ago.
Lady? I don't know.
- Was there a lady here?
- Come, come, you know there was.
Really, I don't know. I swear.
All right.
Goodbye, Your Highness.
Mr Halton.
Why do you want to know her name?
Because I'm dining with her
at a quarter to nine.
You are a friend of Captain Buckler's.
What a lovely song. What's the name of it?
It has no name.
I just made it up for you, madame.
- And for you, monsieur, thank you.
- Thank you.
You must have been
very successful with women.
What makes you say that?
Nobody could order such a delicious dinner
who wasn't.
Am I a success with you?
Tremendous.
- I wonder if I am.
- Why do you doubt it?
Because, here we are at the dessert
and we know nothing about each other.
You won't tell me your name
or even let me tell you mine.
Oh dear. Didn't we settle all that at the soup,
and again at the salad?
Why spoil such a
perfect evening with names?
I don't want to know your name.
Whatever it is, I know it wouldn't suit you.
Thank you.
I should hate to risk it.
Besides, I know all about you.
You do?
Providence gave you
grey eyes, brown hair...
a charming smile.
Great attraction.
Everything else is unimportant.
I'm content.
You're married?
Back to the soup and the salad.
Why be so curious?
Jealous.
Just terribly jealous.
I thought we were going to have
an amusing evening
but now it's become serious.
Desperately.
Who are you? I must know.
- Isn't it obvious?
- Not to me.
- We meet at the Grand Duchess's house.
- Why were you there?
You meet me at five o'clock. And at ten
minutes past five, I agree to dine with you.
A complete stranger.
The shortest story in the world.
Now tell me the true one.
Very well, then. Perhaps it's dangerous
for you to be with me.
Perhaps I have a husband
who'll come in and shoot you.
Perhaps I'm a spy. A thief.
The police may come in and arrest me.
Both of us.
You're none of those things.
If you were, it wouldn't matter.
Now, or any other time.
I must have done something very nice
in my life to be so beautifully rewarded.
Do you really mean that?
And so much more.
You're an angel.
Angel, that's what I shall call you.
Angel.
You're cold.
Frightened.
- Of me?
- Much more serious.
I'm frightened of myself.
What a strange evening.
I dined with you to be amused, to laugh.
To laugh at you. And...
- And what?
- And say goodbye.
Could you?
I don't know. You must give me time.
Please, a fortnight. A week.
Next Wednesday at five o'clock
at the Grand Duchess.
Wait for me. If I come, I won't ask any
questions. I'll go wherever you ask me to.
- And if you don't come?
- Then you must forgive me.
Never look for me. Forget that I ever existed.
Swear.
Promise that you'll do that for me. Please.
If I did, it would be a promise I couldn't keep.
I don't care who you are or what you are.
- All I know is...
- What?
I love you.
You'll never go out of my life.
I'll never let you go.
Er... Merci beaucoup.
Angel!
Angel.
- No other statement, Sir Frederick?
- No other statement, no.
- How's everything, Wilton?
- The Foreign Secretary is on the telephone.
Get me the minutes of Thursday's meeting.
Article 6, section 5b.
Also of Friday's meeting,
all of article, erm... 2.
Well, Mr Wilton? How are you?
- Glad to see you back, Graham.
- Thank you.
- How's everything at Geneva?
- Oh.
- Is there going to be a war?
- Well...
It looks as if Europe is going to have peace.
At least, for the next three weeks.
We had rather a hard fight, you know.
21 nations lined up against us. But we won.
- I hear France was making difficulties.
- Well...
- What can you expect from the French?
- Yes.
You realise the French delegate
hasn't even a manservant?
Appalling.
But the Russians
were the surprise of my life.
We had two Soviet delegates to dinner.
You may not believe it, but I assure you
they were properly dressed.
- Tail coats. White ties.
- Well, well, well.
- Maybe the Russians are going places.
- Oh, well, I...
wouldn't come to hasty conclusions.
They still dunk.
- I shan't need you any more tonight.
- Good night, sir.
Graham!
It would be outrageous,
you can't disturb the master at this time.
The telegram may contain matters of state.
But how would you justify it
if it were only a personal matter?
You'd be criticised very harshly.
My dear Mr Wilton, may I remind you
of what our master always says?
A statesman must have
the courage to be unpopular.
- What is it?
- A telegram, m'lady.
Oh, thank you.
- Oh!
- Aah!
Who's that? Who's that?
Oh!
Hello, darling.
I didn't want to wake you up.
You were sleeping so peacefully,
I hadn't the heart to disturb you.
You're always so considerate.
Oh, I watched you for a long time.
- You had the loveliest expression.
- I was dreaming.
- About me?
- Oh, naturally, of course.
I dreamt you were a great success
at the League of Nations.
Well, I was! Sweetheart,
your husband defeated 21 nations.
Oh. You must be worn out.
- Not at all. I feel better than ever.
- Good.
- What else did you dream about?
- Let me see.
Oh, yes. I came into the League of Nations,
dressed in the most striking Paris gown.
All the delegates rose to their feet,
staring at me.
But I walked straight to you.
I wanted to kiss you.
But you were talking. So I walked out.
I went to Egypt,
and from Egypt I went to China,
from China I went to Arabia.
I circled the whole globe.
Finally, I came back
to the League of Nations.
But you were still talking.
So I took you away. I took you to Paris.
We walked in the park at night.
You had your arm around me.
Suddenly, I sat down on a bench.
I was cold. Frightened.
- Of me?
- Huh?
Oh. I got mixed up.
I dreamt that yesterday.
Now, let me see. Oh, I have it.
I lost you in Paris.
Next thing I remember, we were here
at home and you were beating me.
Oh! What did you do?
I'm afraid to tell you.
I liked it. And then you started to kiss me.
And you liked that too?
Better than ever before.
You carried me upstairs.
- And?
- There was a knock at the door. I woke up.
- Oh. How cruel.
- No, how wonderful.
It's true the dream is over.
But it doesn't have to be.
Oh, I'm so glad you're home, my darling.
- Tell me, who knocked at the door?
- Oh, Graham.
- At this time of the night? Why?
- A telegram.
- Was it so important?
- I didn't open it, it was for you.
- Where is it?
- There on your table.
Bad news?
Very disturbing.
What's worrying you?
- France?
- No.
Yugoslavia.
- I hope you don't mind, I...
- That's all right, dear. I understand.
I understand perfectly.
- Night, dear.
- Good night, dear.
Good morning, sir.
Morning.
How's the weather today?
Not bad, sir.
Why, Wilton!
Darling, some thrilling news
from Mrs MacGillicuddy.
Wilton, this is the nicest thing
you've ever brought to the table.
- My congratulations.
- Thank you.
- And mine.
- Thank you, m'lady.
What a pretty girl.
All her friends think
she ought to act in the films.
You see, sir, she once was photographed in
a newsreel
at the funeral of Admiral Bennington.
She was standing on the pavement
just as the hearse went by.
I hope I don't seem disrespectful, sir,
but in my opinion, she stole the show
from the late Admiral.
- That's love.
- I'm sure she loves you just as much.
Oh, she worships me, sir.
But it was by no means an easy conquest.
The young lady didn't believe
in the institution of marriage.
- But you persuaded her.
- Oh, no.
Begging your pardon, sir, it was you, sir.
And you, m'lady.
- We?
I took the liberty of citing you both as an
example of how beautiful marriage can be,
and that convinced her.
- Did you hear that?
- Maybe we should stage a rousing quarrel,
so we won't feel quite so responsible.
- That's a lovely idea.
- What shall we quarrel about?
Well, I might say I'm a neglected wife.
No, darling. I'm afraid we couldn't quarrel
about that because I'd agree with you.
Oh, anyway, it's bad.
Complaining wives are such a bore.
We can find something better.
I have it. You're jealous.
A very charming woman is in love with me.
- I could believe that.
- Thank you.
But I wouldn't quarrel about it.
I would do just the opposite. I would try to be
twice as charming as the charming lady.
I'm sure it wouldn't be difficult for you.
- Oh, you're an angel.
- Thank you.
- Frederick?
- Yes, dear?
Someone is in love with me.
I'm crazy about him.
I've decided to leave you.
I'm already packed.
I wonder what you would do.
I certainly wouldn't quarrel.
It would be too late.
Darling, isn't it a shame?
Here we are, two intelligent people,
and we can't find anything to quarrel about.
- We're complete failures.
- Perhaps we are.
I'm sure we are.
We might just as well face it.
We're a hopelessly happy married couple.
Hm.
- What's that?
- Oh...
Just... just something I made up.
That's nice.
It's beautiful. Darling,
I didn't know you had so much talent.
- Let's hear the rest of it.
- Oh, no, no.
- Come on. Don't be timid.
- No.
- Let's hear it.
- I'm not in the mood.
- Temperamental artist, eh?
- No, not exactly.
But you see, I don't know
what the end is going to be.
You've certainly found a lovely beginning.
- Almost too lovely.
- Oh, you must finish it.
It's not so easy. Well, I don't know.
The beginning is so beautiful,
I wonder if the end matters.
It's an old tune, but it's still good.
Of course, I play it badly.
But you danced divinely.
- I'm not such a good dancer.
- You were a rotten dancer.
You stepped on my toes
and you ruined my shoes.
But still, I say you danced divinely.
Ah.
What's the matter?
You took me back to Vienna.
Now, was that nice?
What was the name of that little hotel?
Hm. I don't remember the name
or how we got there.
- All I remember is...
- It was glorious, wasn't it?
- And what a hotel.
- Let's forget it.
Oh! Oh, no. I could never forget it.
The service was too awful.
They had every inconvenience.
Do you realise there was no lift?
We climbed four flights of stairs.
Sometimes two at a time.
What a hotel.
And when we got to the top of the stairs,
what did we find?
Two small, badly-furnished rooms.
- Were there two?
- Certainly, there was a sitting room, darling.
Oh, Christopher, I'm so excited.
This is the thrill of my life.
I don't wanna miss a thing.
You must tell me who everybody is.
- Afternoon, Mr Breckinbridge.
- Oh! Is that Mr Breckinbridge?
- Yes, yes indeed.
- Oh, my.
Very modest man. You wouldn't dream
he's Lord Straighton's butler.
How do you do, Mademoiselle Maupois.
- Lady Fellingham's personal maid.
- You don't say.
This is so fascinating,
seeing all these people in the flesh.
- Love me?
- Insanely.
Hello, John. Interesting case.
He was Lord Aldergate's valet for 20 years,
but it didn't last.
They differed in their political views.
Situation finally became impossible when
Lord Aldergate joined the Labour Party.
- Hello, George.
- Hiya, Toots.
Oh, hello!
- Who's that?
- Er... an American chauffeur.
Now, let's see if I can find Lady Barker.
There she is.
In the black dress,
in front of the staircase.
What has happened?
She seems a bit upset.
- It's nothing serious?
- No, no.
- Just a headache, but it's annoying.
- I'll go with you.
No. I'll lie down for an hour and be all right.
- You go back to your guests.
- Pardon me. May I?
- It's for Consolidated Press.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- I'd rather not.
- One second.
- Please, no.
- I'm sorry. Some other time.
- Thank you, sir. Yes.
I hope you don't mind
but I'm not in the mood for a picture.
- I know I don't look well.
- That's all right.
Are you sure I can't take you home?
Positive. You stay and have a good time.
- Take her Ladyship home. Drive carefully.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, how is your wife?
- She'll be all right. Just a headache.
- Don't forget Saturday.
- No. One o'clock.
One o'clock. Right.
- There's your ticket, old man.
- Oh, thank you, Tony.
- I wonder if you're right about Landslide.
- I think she's the best bet of the day.
Oh, I'm getting a lot of interesting fellows
together for Saturday.
Good. Which one is Landslide?
Oh, yes. There she is.
- Who's going to be there on Saturday?
- The Duke of Amesbury,
Earl of Avonborough, Argentine
ambassador, about 20 of us.
Pleasant luncheon?
Yes, very nice, very nice indeed.
I'm glad of this opportunity
to meet you, Sir Frederick.
- I've been looking forward to it.
- Thanks.
I've a feeling you and I might find
some very interesting things to talk about.
I'm quite sure we could.
Yes, these are very exciting times.
- Sir Frederick...
- Yes?
I wonder if you know who I am.
Well, certainly. Devon's told me
about you. You're his house guest.
- You were in India for quite a while.
- Right.
I still wonder if you know who I am.
Mr Halton, aren't you?
Yes. Doesn't that name
mean anything to you?
I'm sorry. I'm at a complete loss.
Sir Frederick, you once deliberately
stole my overcoat.
- I beg your pardon?
- But I helped myself to a pair of your gloves.
This... sounds like a mystery story.
No, no, just a war anecdote.
Oh! What was your regiment?
- I was in the Warwickshire. 10th Battalion.
- I was Leicesters. Machine guns.
I don't think the two regiments
ever came together.
Neither did we. But during 1916 and 17,
you went to Paris several times on leave.
Yes, that's right, I did.
You were very young.
- And she was charming.
- Who?
Paulette.
Do you mean...
Paulette Fouchardière?
Paulette Fouchardière.
Modiste. Third floor.
Hem stitching and embroidery.
Are you Poochie?
Yes, Schnoogie.
Well!
Let me have a look at you.
- You didn't have a moustache then.
- No.
Your picture was on the small table...
- Next to the little silver box...
- With the bird on top.
- And when you opened it...
- It played O Sole Mio.
Ah, she was lovely, wasn't she?
- Paulette Fouchardière.
- Mm.
Oh... what a rotten trick Napoleon
played on her great-great-grandfather.
Mm. If Napoleon had kept his promise...
- After the Battle of Valenciennes...
- Which Grandpapa really won.
Grandpapa would have
married the Duchess of Parma.
And Paulette would have become
the Princess of Naples.
I wonder whatever became of her.
To the Princess of Naples.
The Princess.
That's very kind of you, Lady Burnstead.
We'd love to come.
Your parties are always so delightful. But,
you see, we intend to leave next Saturday.
Yes, I'm terribly excited.
It's our first trip in ages.
Well, thank you so much.
My compliments to Lord Burnstead
and little Beatrice. Goodbye.
- May I come in?
- Of course.
- Hello, sweetheart.
- Hello, darling.
- Dressing already?
- The opera starts at eight, doesn't it?
- Oh, the opera, huh?
- Darling, you promised.
And I'm going to keep my promise. You love
opera, I hate opera, why shouldn't we go?
Have a nice luncheon?
I discussed the naval situation
with the French attaché. It looks promising.
You must have taken the navy all around the
world and discussed each ship separately.
Why? What time is it?
Oh, good heavens!
I meant to leave right after lunch, but...
Oh, I've lots of amusing things to tell you.
I met an old friend.
We were in the war together.
We began reminiscing.
We had a couple of drinks.
Good old Poochie.
- Good old what?
- Erm... Poochie, dear, Poochie.
Huh! What a curious name!
That's what we used to call him in the war.
Poochie Halton.
His real name is Anthony.
He once practically saved my life.
Great fellow, great fellow.
Don't you think you'd better get dressed?
We don't want to miss the overture.
Oh, no, we don't want to miss the overture.
We might as well see the whole thing
through from the bitter beginning.
Quite a fellow, this Halton.
Oh...
I say, did you ever hear of
a Grand Duchess Anna... Dmitrievna?
Anna Dmitrievna?
She's a Russian emigrée. Lives in Paris.
Yes, I've heard of her. Why?
This fellow Halton
told me the most fantastic story.
He's an extraordinary fe...
Isn't this my nailfile?
- I don't know, darling.
- It is, dear. It is.
- How do you suppose it got here?
- I haven't the faintest idea.
Graham, would you be good enough
to hand me my nailfile?
- You're going to the opera, sir?
- Yes, that's where I'm going.
If I may say so, sir, my favourite opera
is Cavelleria Rusticana.
It's only one act, but it has everything.
Love, jealousy, hate, murder,
and all in 35 minutes. I timed it once.
The one where the husband suspects
his wife of singing with another man?
And catches them.
Right in the middle of a beautiful duet.
- He kills her, doesn't he?
- Not immediately, no, sir.
- He joins them in the most exquisite trio.
- Naturally.
After Cavelleria Rusticana,
my favourite is The Barber Of Seville.
- The barber's song is particularly beautiful.
- How does it go?
Dee, da da da, da da da, da da da, ta ta
Tiddly-ya, tiddly-ya, tiddly-ya
Ta, ta ta ta, ta ta ta, ta ta ta ta ta!
Tiddly-ya, tiddly-ya, tiddly-ya,
tiddly-ya, tiddly-ya, tiddly-ya...
Graham, whoever persuaded you to become
a valet must have been a music lover.
Oh, thank you, sir.
- Shall I draw your bath, sir?
- Please.
You were saying something a while ago
about this Grand Duchess Anna.
Yes. Well, this fellow Halton's
gone completely mad over a woman.
A very nice fellow. Lived four years in India,
some fine government work.
The man has a splendid career ahead of
him. I hope he doesn't do anything foolish.
- You mean because of this woman?
- He can't seem to get her out of his mind.
Do you know where he met her?
At this Grand Duchess's salon.
Remember the novel,
An Afternoon In Paris?
- Yes.
- It's undoubtedly the same kind of place.
Oh, I see.
And that's where he met the woman?
Gives you a pretty accurate picture
of a lady. Obvious, isn't it?
Oh, it's probably just an adventure.
Not with him. Why, that man's been looking
for her in every possible place in Paris.
What's more, he's going back again.
His mind is made up.
Nobody can talk him out of it.
Dear, Mary Glenbrook over there.
Hmm, everybody seems to be here tonight.
Everybody seems to be looking at us.
At you, rather.
Do you suppose your friend is here?
Halton? No, he couldn't come.
He's telephoning tomorrow.
He's trying to cancel an engagement
and have lunch with us. All right?
- Yes, why not?
- They certainly are looking at you.
You know, a man shouldn't take a woman
seriously unless he can be proud of her.
At least she should be fit
to sit at the head of his table.
Not someone you just meet in Paris
in the afternoon,
and the same evening
she dines at your apartment.
- She went to his apartment?
- Certainly.
Darling, look. The Duchess of Loganshire,
over there to your left.
Naturally, he didn't say that.
He tried to romanticise the story.
A night in the park, a bouquet of violets.
The lady disappears.
Hello, old boy. So glad to see you.
It's been a long time since I've had
as many drinks as I had yesterday.
As a matter of fact,
I had a few too many myself.
I'm awfully glad
you got out of that other engagement.
You know...
Well, it's funny. I... I’ve only known you
since yesterday, and... yet I...
I feel the same way. It is funny, isn't it?
Well, come on, let's sit down.
I've been following your career
in the papers, old man.
I admire what you've done.
I admire your courage, your wit, and the
daring with which you tackle your problems.
I'm...
I'm proud to be in your house.
Thanks.
You know,
I've been thinking about you a great deal.
Now, I hope that little story of mine
hasn't worried you.
It's an unusual story.
I shouldn't mind reading it in a novel.
But I'd hate to be the hero of it.
Or even have...
...have a friend of mine...
Well, thanks, Barker.
Believe me, a man shouldn't go out of
his way to create handicaps for himself.
I imagine that's what Brutus told Caesar,
when Caesar said,
"Brutus, I've just met a little
Egyptian girl by the name of Cleopatra.
"She's driving me crazy."
If I remember my history correctly,
Caesar got over it.
Right. But my dear man,
Cleopatra wasn't Angel.
If Caesar had ever met Angel, it would have
changed the history of the Roman Empire.
It would have collapsed 200 years earlier.
Well, what are 200 years in history?
25 pages.
But one hour with Angel...
60 minutes.
3,600 seconds.
Well, I give up. It's always ridiculous
to reason with a man in love.
And I'm afraid you are a man in love.
I don't know. It may be more than love,
or less than love.
Well, man, make up your mind. What is it?
It's... It's a certain feeling.
It's a secret that belongs to two people,
and to those two people alone.
Something you can't...
Good heavens, haven't you ever
lost your head over a woman?
Haven't you ever felt that at last
you can stop searching? You've found it.
Yes, I have.
And you're going to meet her.
Halton, I'm afraid you and I
expect different things from love.
Probably from life.
I don't measure in terms of seconds,
but of years.
- How about a gin and tonic?
- Not a bad idea.
- It's a charming place you have here.
- Like it?
I say, that's a lovely picture.
- That's your wife's photograph, I suppose?
- Naturally.
- Mr Halton has arrived, m'lady.
- Thank you.
- Here...
- How do you do, Mr Halton?
How do you do?
My husband told me so much about you.
Won't you sit down?
- Cigarette?
- Thank you.
Thank you, dear.
- I hope I didn't come down too soon.
- Of course not.
Reunion of two old friends.
Are you sure I didn't interrupt?
We'd just finished
a most interesting discussion.
The newest subject in the world. Love.
Oh. Love.
- But we disagreed completely.
- Really?
Yes, we see the same thing,
but with entirely different eyes.
It's amazing.
It's like two men looking at the same lamp.
One says the shade is blue.
The other one swears it's green.
- You forget, Barker...
- Frederick.
Oh, I'm sorry. Frederick.
We both could be right, you know.
Perhaps the lamp shade is blue.
But when you light it up,
it may be the greenest green in the world.
- Don't you think so, Lady Barker?
- Gentlemen, the sun is shining so brightly.
Don't you think it's rather early in the day
to be talking about lamps?
I'd rather talk about you, Mr Halton.
- You have been in India?
- Yes.
- Are you going to stay in England?
- He's going back to Paris in a day or so.
- Oh.
- Well, I may have to change my plans.
- That's interesting. When did this happen?
- Oh, as a matter of fact, today.
Yes, I may have to stay a little longer.
How fortunate for you to be here at the best
part of the year. There's so much going on.
There's the ballet, and next week
there'll be the Wimbledon tennis.
Oh, darling, I am afraid
we are going to miss the matches.
- Frederick and I are taking a little trip.
- Oh.
Did you make up your mind, dear,
where you want to go?
- Mmm, I've several very interesting ideas.
- I'm dying to hear them.
And now, shall we have lunch?
Mr Wilton, what do you think
of this fellow Halton?
Oh, nice fellow, but I should say a trifle dull.
He talks about Paris, Paris, Paris,
and again Paris.
- Give me the crumb tray.
- What is it?
The crumbs at her Ladyship's place.
She seems to be playing with the bread.
- Her Ladyship seems to be a bit nervous.
- No, merely bored.
And how this Halton brags! He knows a man
who knows every stone in Notre Dame.
Would you call that an accomplishment?
And who cares
how high the Eiffel Tower is? Do you?
Mr Wilton, we're used to
such brilliant conversation in this house,
that sometimes I wonder
if we're not a little spoiled.
Yes, quite true. There's always the danger
of one's becoming blasé.
Sir Frederick told a delightful joke.
The Scotchman who wanted to buy a piano?
- And ended up by humming.
- Good. He tells it superbly.
Things seem to be brightening up. I'm glad.
They must be finished.
Hello? Oh, it's you, Emma.
Well, we're at luncheon.
I'm pretty busy just now.
Yes, I am angry. Frankly, I'm furious.
Unless you can explain where you learned
the rumba, I'm through. Goodbye.
- Whose plate is this?
- Her Ladyship's.
Hardly touched. Can there be
anything wrong with the meat?
I hardly think so, Mr Wilton.
Perhaps she just had a late breakfast.
- Whose plate is this?
- Mr Halton's.
But he hasn't eaten, either.
It's obvious that he tried.
Maybe there is something wrong.
Let's see Sir Frederick's plate.
No, it's not the meat.
I tell you, Mr Halton talked so much...
Or maybe he doesn't like veal.
That's quite possible.
At any rate, make a note.
- If Mr Halton should come again, no veal.
- Very well, Mr Wilton.
- Splendid. Don't you think so, darling?
- Yes, beautiful.
- Thank you.
- The fact I like it doesn't mean anything.
- But Maria, she's a composer.
- Frederick!
- She composed the loveliest song.
- Please!
- Play it, darling.
- Why don't you?
Don't make us coax you.
All right. Now, let me see, how does it go?
You know, I think I've forgotten it.
Oh, that's too bad. It really was very nice.
Now, how did it go?
I heard a delightful tune in Paris.
I wonder if I remember it.
Gentlemen, you're both working too hard.
I insist that you relax, please.
I'll play you something even better.
Oh, Frederick went out.
It's a lovely waltz, isn't it?
First time I heard it,
I was dancing with Frederick.
Takes me right back to Vienna.
It was our first dance together.
I think it has a beautiful melodic quality,
don't you?
Hello, Angel.
- I beg your pardon?
- Angel.
What do you mean, Mr Halton?
- It seems incredible.
- What seems incredible?
That I should find you here, in this house.
His wife.
It's like a dream.
I still don't understand you, Mr Halton.
I don't understand you.
We're alone, Angel. Darling,
how long are you going to keep this up?
Mr Halton, you're obviously confusing me
with another woman.
Oh, no, I'm not.
There can't possibly be two of you.
I'm afraid there must be.
I haven't been in Paris for...
Oh, for the last six months.
- You haven't been in Paris for six months?
- I told you so. That should satisfy you.
It seems to be a terrific coincidence. The
lady with whom you had your adventure...
- Wasn't it more than that?
- Maybe it was.
- At least I thought so.
- Maybe the lady thought so, too.
But it's impossible for me to read the mind
of a woman I never saw nor heard of.
In other words, to you it was.
Just an adventure.
Now, Mr Halton, I insist that we settle this,
once and for all.
Look at me.
Look at me carefully.
And I'm sure that you will realise
as clearly as I do,
that I am Lady Barker,
and nobody else.
The resemblance is amazing.
I could have sworn it was you.
You have exactly her hair.
Her eyes.
Her skin.
Her lips.
But when I listen to you...
...I begin to see the difference.
You're not Angel.
I am greatly relieved.
- Will you forgive me?
- Naturally.
You know, Mr Halton, this resemblance will
always create embarrassment between us.
It's unfortunate, but for my own comfort
and peace, and certainly for yours,
don't you think you might find some excuse
not to come here any more?
You have a lovely home, Lady Barker.
It's in exquisite taste.
I suppose this is the kind of house
every woman dreams of having.
And you're the wife
of a charming and famous man.
- You must be very happy, Lady Barker.
- I am.
Don't be afraid. I won't play it.
I shall never play it.
I hope I never hear it again.
Thank you.
Maria...
I told you in Paris never to look for me, never
to recognise me wherever you find me.
- The whole thing must be forgotten.
- I told you I'd never keep such a promise.
All I know is that I love you,
and I'll never let you out of my life.
I will fight with everything at my command
if you should try to destroy my home.
Why did you ever come to Paris?
Tell me, why?
Why did you leave me and go back
to London? It doesn't seem to make sense.
None whatsoever. But it's the privilege
of a woman not to make sense.
Men who expect women to be logical
are failures in love.
Have you ever been in love?
Not with you. I never told you I loved you.
Never.
Can't you remember what I said?
Every word.
Every syllable.
You said you had grey eyes.
Brown hair.
Charming smile.
Great attraction.
You still have. That's why I want you to go.
Oh, go. Please, go. Every moment
you are here, my home is in danger.
Go, I beg you, I tell you.
Maria...
Angel...
Come in.
- Wilton, will you find Sir Frederick?
- Yes, m'lady.
At the present moment,
I am definitely against it.
Is Hamilton with you?
Come in.
Has he sent the papers over?
Good. No, I'm not disturbed,
but I'd rather worry now than later.
Right, thank you. Goodbye.
- I beg pardon, sir...
- Just a moment.
- What is it?
- Her Ladyship is asking for you, sir.
Oh, all right.
I'm expecting a call from Mr Hamilton.
Let me know immediately.
- I'm very sorry. Just one of those things.
- Darling.
- Hmm?
- I'm afraid Mr Halton has to leave.
Is it so late?
I'm terribly sorry, Tony. I was called
to the telephone. Do you really have to go?
Well, I don't know...
- How about another drink?
- I tried to persuade Mr Halton to stay.
But I'm a complete failure.
Failure? Lady Barker, really, I...
I had an engagement but now I must stay,
long enough to turn failure into success.
Good.
- I would like to have a drink, too.
- You? Whisky, darling?
Just a little. Just enough
to drink to our friend, Mr Halton.
Thank you, dear.
Here's to you, Mr Halton. And to Angel.
Mr Halton told me the most amazing thing
that happened to him in Paris.
Everything I told you. Do you mind?
Not at all.
Always good to get a woman's point of view.
It's a thrilling story and I listened
to every word with great suspense.
Mr Halton, you described every detail
with such love and care.
Yet you omitted the most important part.
You failed to describe the woman.
- Yes, what does she look like?
- It's difficult to find the exact words to...
Now, I think you are being unfair.
You can't leave us like the daily instalment
of a newspaper serial. To be continued.
You have aroused our interest.
Frederick and I are entitled
to know a lot more about the lady.
Now, I insist, Mr Halton.
What did she look like?
She was radiant... Exciting.
- These are generalities.
- You're talking like a poet.
I see. You want the matter-of-fact
description of, shall we say, a detective?
That's exactly what we want.
Well, then...
Her eyes were brown.
And her hair was dark.
May I be permitted to change your toast?
To the most charming hostess.
Yourself, Lady Barker.
Thank you.
Well, I must be going.
Thank you for a lovely afternoon.
Goodbye, Lady Barker.
Mr Halton, since I've had the privilege
of enjoying your confidence,
may I indulge in a little advice?
Do.
- Mr Hamilton on the telephone?
- Yes, sir.
Yes, Hamilton?
Yes, will you read it to me.
You wanted to give me some advice,
Lady Barker.
I'm afraid Angel is far from blameless.
But I think you should forget her,
and perhaps even forgive her.
- I've already forgiven her, but...
- But what?
- Paris. I'll be in Paris next Wednesday.
- It'll be useless.
- If there's one chance in a million...
- There's not.
- I'll wait at the Grand Duchess's.
- Torturing yourself.
I'll be there Wednesday at five o'clock.
I'll be there hours before.
All right, Hamilton. Goodbye.
- Well, goodbye.
- I'll see you out.
Goodbye, Tony.
- These papers came from Mr Hamilton, sir.
- Oh, good.
By the way, I'm going to Geneva.
- Didn't you tell me Mr Hamilton is going?
- I've changed my mind.
Oh, I thought
it was only a sub-committee meeting.
It is, and I'm sure Mr Hamilton would
handle it, but you know me, Greenwood.
- I'd be uncomfortable if I didn't go myself.
- I see, sir.
In that case, you won't require
the other reservations.
- Which other reservations?
- For your trip with Lady Barker.
I'd forgotten all about it.
- Frederick, you're not working, are you?
- I'm sorry, but something unexpected...
Frederick! Is this where we are going?
Why, that's wonderful!
Oh, darling, I can hardly wait.
Let's have a glorious time.
Let's be foolish again.
Oh, I can't tell you how much...
Why, what's the matter?
Well, dear...
Don't tell me. Don't tell me we are not going.
- Don't tell me now.
- You see... I don't know... You see...
- It's all right.
- You must understand...
Don't explain. It's very clear.
You have to do your duty.
- You know...
- I know. I know very well. Too well.
I can recite all the reasons.
I know them by heart.
- Oh, I beg your pardon.
- It's all right, Mr Greenwood. Come in.
You go back to work.
Don't let me disturb you.
Thank you, darling.
- About the reservations, sir.
- Oh, yes?
The Geneva plane stops in Paris only 20
minutes. You'll require at least four hours.
More. I've a good many things
to discuss at the embassy.
I thought so, sir. The airways people
suggest a private plane.
They can put one of their newest machines
at your disposal,
the same plane
that Lady Barker chartered last week.
Lady Barker chartered a plane?
That's what they said, sir.
It, er... It must have been Wednesday.
You were in Geneva.
Yes, of course, I remember.
That's all right, I'll let you know later.
Very good, sir.
Give me Croydon 2046.
Is that Imperial Airways?
I want to speak to the manager.
Sir Frederick Barker.
Oh, good evening.
About that private plane.
Is it the same one that Lady Barker took?
Mm-hm.
She says it's not so fast.
Oh, you say it made Paris
in one hour and forty minutes?
That's very good.
I'll take it. All right, thank you.
Finished your work?
Quite.
- Frederick?
- Yes?
When are you leaving for Geneva?
On Wednesday morning, by plane.
Doesn't the plane stop in Paris?
Yes, I believe it does.
Couldn't you take me along as far as Paris,
and pick me up on your way back?
That's an excellent idea.
I really need some new clothes. I haven't
done any shopping for quite a while.
Besides, it'll do you good to get away
from London. Be a change for you.
Yes, it would.
I shall make arrangements for Wednesday,
shall I?
Thank you.
Hello? Oh, Sir Frederick.
Are you? Geneva?
When are you leaving?
Mm.
Yes? Yes, this is Lord Davington's house.
You wish to speak to Mr Halton?
Who's calling, please?
Just one moment, Sir Frederick.
- Attendez.
- Oui, monsieur.
- Bonjour, monsieur.
- Bonjour.
I'd like to see the Grand Duchess,
if you please.
Thank you, monsieur.
Come in.
I'll come in a moment.
Now, Mr Halton, I wouldn't be impatient.
If a lady makes an appointment for five
o'clock, you shouldn't expect her until six.
The kind of lady who comes on time
really wouldn't be worth waiting for.
If you get bored, there's the cocktail bar.
You might find some interesting people.
- Thank you. I'll wait here.
- Just as you like.
You may be sure we'll let you know
the moment she arrives.
Angel. Charming name, Mr Halton.
Bravo.
- Sir Frederick.
- Yes.
I am the Grand Duchess Anna.
How do you do?
Will you step this way, please?
- Will you sit down?
- Thank you.
To what do I owe the pleasure of your visit?
Well, at a party a few days ago,
your name was mentioned.
And the charm and glamour of your salon.
Oh, thank you very much.
I hope you won't be disappointed.
It's after five. You might find some
interesting people at the cocktail bar.
- No, I think not.
- Or a little roulette?
Or if you've no plans,
I might arrange a little dinner.
You're very kind, Your Highness.
But, you know, at this party I just referred to,
a certain young lady was mentioned...
and her description roused my curiosity.
I'd be glad to do anything I can to arrange an
introduction, if you give me the lady's name.
That's the difficulty.
Her name seems to be rather a mystery.
But I wonder if this might give you a clue.
The person describing her
referred to her... as Angel.
Angel? Angel, that's a strange name.
Rather charming. But I'm afraid...
Erm... look here, Your Highness. Is there any
way in which I might refresh your memory?
Really, I have an excellent memory, but
I don't seem to remember that name at all.
Perhaps this might help, Your Highness.
I would contribute generously
to any charitable institution you might name.
Oh. Well... l... er...
Or perhaps it would be better if the
contribution were placed at your disposal.
Oh, that's very kind of you. We always have
the needy with us, but unfortunately...
Come in.
Pardon me, Your Highness.
Your Aunt Sonya is here.
Always these interruptions!
- Well, she'll have to wait. I'm sorry.
- Yes.
Just a moment, Gregori.
Perhaps I'd better see her.
She's an elderly lady. Would you mind?
- I'll be back in a moment.
- Not at all.
- Hello, Frederick.
- Hello, Maria.
- Strange place to meet you, isn't it?
- Rather strange.
- May I ask what you are doing here?
- Curiosity.
The lady known as Angel
caught my imagination.
You mean you stayed in Paris? You
actually missed the conference in Geneva?
Merely to find out if Angel is a brunette.
Well, Frederick, that's marvellous.
I can hardly believe it.
You let all Europe wait
just to find out if a woman is a brunette.
Or a blonde.
As a matter of fact, she is a blonde. You
remember Mr Halton described the lady?
- Yes, he seemed rather uncomfortable.
- Shall I tell you why?
Before you came in,
he described her differently.
- Would you like to know what he said?
- Very much.
He said she had blonde hair, blue eyes,
my figure and a slight foreign accent.
Sounds like a description of you.
It does, doesn't it?
It annoyed me that there should be
another woman who looks exactly like me.
It disturbed my vanity. You know how
women are. So I came here to find out.
Did you see her?
Oh, yes.
As a matter of fact, she's in the next room.
And does she look like you?
Exactly.
You were in Paris last Wednesday.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Why didn't you ask me?
Did you ever ask me what I do
when you go to Geneva,
and you have your conferences,
your committees?
- Did you ever ask me anything?
- How many times have we been here?
- Are you interested?
- What life have you been leading?
- What kind of woman are you?
- Does it really worry you?
As much as Yugoslavia worries you?
How many times
have you been here before? Answer me.
Frederick, you're getting nervous.
To think that my wife, whom I trusted,
whom I was proud of,
to think you could come to a place like this...
Frederick, you're jealous.
Angel. You are Angel.
Now, why should I be Angel?
Why should I be so foolish?
Why should I do such a thing?
Don't I have a lovely home,
a celebrated husband, the best servants,
every comfort, social position?
Is there anything more a woman could ask?
Why should I be Angel?
What reason could I have?
Perhaps you can think of one.
Frederick?
Now, Frederick, if you go into that room,
I'm afraid our marriage is over.
If you find Angel in there,
you'll be happy that I'm not Angel,
and you'll want to continue our old life.
That would not be satisfactory to me.
And if I don't find Angel?
In that case, you'll want to see
your lawyer as soon as possible.
On the other hand, if you don't go in at all,
you'll be a little uncertain,
you won't be quite so sure of yourself.
Or of me.
And that might be wonderful.
- Did you tell Mr Halton the lady was here?
- No, Your Highness.
He must have seen her come out of the taxi.
Who told you I came?
I understand Frederick's here.
He's in the other room. Or maybe he's gone.
I don't know. Anyway, it's all over.
Silly how upsetting a little thing like
saying goodbye to one's husband can be.
Silly, isn't it?
- Hello, Tony.
- Hello, Frederick.
You know the... that story you told me
about Angel interested me so much
that I couldn't resist coming here.
Well... I’ve met her.
You see, Maria, in the last few moments,
I've thought more about our married life
than in all the years we've been together.
And all I know is...
the train to Vienna leaves at ten.
I... I don't know how you feel about... Vienna.
You've plenty of time to think it over.
Well...
I say goodbye to Angel.
And so must you, Maria,
if you decide to meet me at the station.