[whoosh of gate opening]
[distant hisses and creaks]
[gasps and groans]
[yelps]
All right, get out of the way,
get out of the way!
Come here, come here.
[bodies and boxes
tumble and crash]
Come on, come on, come on!
This is Scott,
slow down the evac!
We are coming in too hot!
Colonel, come in!
My god, where are we?
[shouts of pain and confusion]
Get them off the gate!
Look out!
Where are we?
Why didn't we come
through to earth?
There was no time to explain!
Off to the side!
What's going on?
[clamor and panic,
cries of pain]
This is Scott, come in!
Colonel,
come in!
I need a medic!
Over here!
Can you move
your fingers?
I think
my arm's broken.
Okay, just hold
your arm there,
And we'll put it
in a sling, okay?
Ah!
[clamour slows,
voices echo dreamily]
[echoing]:
Keep calm, keep calm.
[real-time speed resumes,
soldiers grunt from impact]
Clear this area,
There could still be
more incoming!
Oof!
[coughing]
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Oh, god.
Move...
Where the hell are we?
Greer...
Where's colonel young?
He was right behind me.
[gas jets hiss and fume]
[crowd screams in panic]
Move, move, move.
Quiet!
Stay calm!
Excuse me...
Keep it down!
Move, move, move, move.
Colonel...
Colonel?
Don't move.
Where... Where are we?
I don't know, sir.
Are you...
Sir...
You're in charge, all right?
You're...
Sir...
Tj!
I'm coming!
Clear the crowd, people,
coming through!
Let's go, move,
move, move!
[clamor and shouting]
Is he okay?
I don't know.
Wallace!
What is this place?
Look, I-I just did
what rush told me to--
Where is he?
I don't know,
he went through ahead of me.
Rush! Rush!
Eli, help me find him.
[stammering]
well, I--
[engines whine to life]
[people shout in confusion]
[engines drone and surge,
then fade]
What in the hell
was that?
I don't know.
Sergeant...
I need you to get
these people settled,
And you find out
who and what we've got.
Nobody leaves
this room.
Yes, sir.
Eli!
Now!
The Core of the planet
is the power source.
You have to channel it
into the weapon
To destroy the enemy ship.
Can't do it, dude.
Uh, doin' it.
It's one of those
programmer's jokes,
A problem that
can't be solved.
- Already solved it.
- No, you didn't.
Just shut up!
And watch this...
What the hell!
What happened?
Noth--
Nothing happened.
I'm back at the beginning
of the level.
- You're so full of yourself.
- No. No, no, no.
It worked.
The firing Code locked in.
Whatever.
That was extremely
unsatisfying.
Eli Wallace?
Actually, uh,
eli's not here right now...
[stammers]
Okay, okay, whatever you guys
think that I did,
I swear, you've got
the wrong guy.
Do I look like someone
who would be standing here
If I didn't already know
everything there is to know
About you?
Yeah, not really.
Right.
Who are you?
Dr. Nicholas rush.
May we come in?
Why?
You've spent a great
deal of time recently
Playing an online
fantasy game
Called "prometheus."
Big brother's
got nothing better to do?
Last night,
You solved
the dakara weapons puzzle.
Yeah, a month of my life
went into that.
You know what happens
when you solve that thing?
Nothing.
We're here.
That happened.
To complete that
particular puzzle,
You had to solve
a millennia-old
Mathematical proof
Written in
another life,
For that,
You've won
something of a prize.
Well, whatever it is,
I'll take
the cash equivalent.
There isn't one.
It's a non-disclosure
agreement.
Non-disclosure?
So you guys really embedded
A top secret problem into a game
Hoping someone like me
would solve it?
Yup.
So, what do you need
me for now?
I assure you,
It'll be worth your while
to sign it.
And if I don't?
We'll beam you
up to our spaceship.
[laughs]
Right.
Uh, I-I think I want my lawyer
to look over it first--
And by "lawyer,"
I assume you mean "mother."
So we'll just agree then
That I will call you.
[whoosh]
What the...
Welcome aboard
the Hammond, eli.
Yes, that is the planet earth,
And yes,
you are on a spaceship.
We need
your help, eli.
To be honest,
I don't know how long
it's going to take.
I should call my mom, uh...
Tell her where I am.
That's probably
not going to work up here.
Right.
You can speak to her
on the way.
There's a cover story
you'll have to follow.
I'm sorry, um...
On the way to...
To another planet
21 light years from here.
I can't go. I...
I have things that--
We know about
your mother's condition.
Well, you just know everything,
don't you?
We also know
you are currently unemployed,
And that your mother's
medical coverage is...
An ongoing issue.
We'll see
she gets
The best available care
while you're gone.
And if I don't sign, what,
you going to erase my memory?
[chuckles]
Something like that.
Can I get some pants?
I...
Hello, I'm Dr. Daniel Jackson,
And behind me is a stargate.
It was originally built
millennia ago
By an alien race
who we call "the ancients."
Over the next few hours,
we'll be touching on
Some of the things
you need to know...
...There are 39 symbols
Representing
star constellations
As seen from earth...
...When a connection is made
between two stargates,
An unstable energy vortex
emerges from the gate--
Whoa!
...And settles into
the event horizon
Or "puddle"
as we like to call it...
Later, it was discovered
that using an eighth symbol
Would actually
dial another galaxy...
...In hundred of thousands
of light years
Via an interstellar wormhole...
...It is believed
An unprecedented
amount of power is required...
[lecture starts to blur,
and Jackson's voice overlaps]
...Mysterious ninth chevron...
The first six symbols...
...Establish on a planet
discovered two years ago...
The entire purpose
of the project
Is to hopefully one day
dial the nine chevron address
Found in the ancient database.
Hi! I'm Dr. Daniel Jackson.
Now, you've heard the term
"hyperspace" for years...
Where are you?
It's top secret.
Eli!
I'm serious, ma. I can't say
anything more than that.
I don't understand.
Why could you not at least
tell me you were leaving?
I'm sorry,
But did you get
the letter from--
Yeah, the air force,
I got it.
Are you in a plane now?
You sound like
you're in an airplane.
Uh, no,
it's nothing like that.
I want you to know that
they're going to look after you.
You didn't have to do this.
This is good.
Really, it's the kind of thing
I always dreamed of.
Hi.
You mind?
No, go ahead.
Thank you.
First time on
a spaceship, too?
Me?
I've been on lots of, uh...
Various...
Eli Wallace.
I know.
You've heard of me?
I have.
Wow, that almost never happens.
And you are?
Chloe.
I work for Alan Armstrong.
Senator of California.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I have heard of California.
[laughs]
My last job was
in the burger and fries field.
How'd you line that up?
I was a political science major
at harvard, so...
Mm, I hear it's a good school.
For a while there, I was at--
Mit.
I know.
Really?
What else
have they told you about me?
What?
Uh, I've seen
this writing before.
In the game?
Yeah.
[pushes button]
[mechanism whirrs]
Sheesh...
We're on a ship?
The Design
is clearly ancient,
In the truest
sense of the word.
Launched hundreds
of thousands of years ago.
Dr. Rush?
Faster than light,
Yet not through
hyperspace.
What are you doing?
Who knows how far
it's travelled.
Dr. Rush...
We've got
a lot of wounded.
We need to get home.
[clanking and thudding
from ship's mechanisms]
Lt. Scott, come in.
Go ahead.
We've got a problem.
One of the air vents
just shut down in here.
Copy that.
Yeah, the air's
getting pretty thin
In here, too.
What does that mean?
That the life-support system
is failing.
We should probably do
something about that.
Well, it's always
just one more year.
It's a command.
Where?
It's a lot safer
than other places I've been.
You've put
your time in, Everett.
When this tour's over,
I promise--
You know what?
Never mind, don't bother.
You always end up
Choosing somewhere
other than here.
I am not choosing
my job over you.
How you can even
say that to me?
[voice echoes dreamily]:
I love you,
But I can't wait anymore...
[dishes clatter]
Everett?
Are you okay?
Sweetheart, baby,
look at me.
[hollow, echoing silence]
Colonel?
[grunting and gasping]
Oh, my god...
Can't you
do something?
He's having a seizure.
There's nothing I can do.
[wormhole whooshes open]
[couple panting and moaning]
Scott, this is colonel young,
come in please.
[gasping and shouting]
Our guests have arrived a few
minutes early, lieutenant,
What's your position?
No, not yet.
Not yet.
Lieutenant,
drop whatever you're doing
And get your ass up here.
I'm on my way, sir.
Bye.
Holy...
Senator...
It is my honor to welcome you
to icarus base.
Colonel.
This is
my executive assistant, Chloe.
It's a pleasure
to meet you, sir.
The pleasure's mine.
She's also my daughter.
You must be the...
Contest winner, yeah.
That is a big gun.
Rail gun.
500 rounds
per minute.
This is lieutenant Scott.
He's been assigned to you,
Mr. Wallace.
Shall we go inside?
Unbelievable.
Yeah, it is.
It's weird how fast
You can start to take
something like this for granted.
So, if a stargate
can instantly transport you
To another planet,
Why did we fly here
on a spaceship?
Something to do with
How this one's
tied into the planet for power.
Apparently, it's been modified
to only dial out
Because incoming wormholes
are too dangerous.
You're the genius.
You can probably
tell me better.
All I did was solve a puzzle
in a video game.
You figured out something
Doctor rush has been trying
to figure out for months,
Which, by the way,
A lot of people
were glad to see.
And, of course,
you know colonel Telford.
Ready for this,
colonel?
You just give the word, sir.
Oh, I gave it
quite a while ago, colonel.
I'm just here to see
How my $1.6 billion
is being spent.
[chuckling]
Very good...
Thank you, everyone.
Dismissed.
Now, as you know,
up until now,
We have been unable to channel
The precise
amount of power necessary
To unlock the stargate's
ninth and final chevron.
However,
Thanks to some ingenuity
from young Mr. Wallace here,
That problem has
finally been solved.
We've heard
that before.
This time we're sure.
That's what
I figured out?
I embedded
The mathematical problem
we had to solve
Into the game.
I then engineered your solution
Into a practical,
workable application.
What say
we get on with it?
Absolutely.
Sergeant Riley...
Chevron one encoded.
Sir...
[gate creaks and clanks
as it dials]
We're dialing now?
A test, to see
if we can make a connection--
Chevron one
locked.
If we do,
We'll send an automated
reconnaissance drone through.
We'll see
what's on the other side.
Chevron two
locked.
And then
they'll go?
No, first,
we close down again,
Assess the data we receive,
And then perhaps
send the away team.
If it works.
Chevron four
locked...
Until then, they're just
interested observers like us.
Chevron five
locked.
Chevron six encoded.
Chevron six locked.
Chevron seven encoded.
[clanking]
Chevron seven locked.
[beeping]
Chevron eight
encoded.
Chevron eight locked.
Chevron nine encoded.
[electricity sparking]
W-what's going on?
I don't know,
we never got this far before.
[banging and clanging
from machinery]
Chevron nine...
Will not lock.
We matched the power
requirements down to the emu.
It must work.
Power levels in
the gate capacitors
Are going
into the red.
Shut it down.
No, wait, wait, wait...
We're reading fluctuations
in the output from the Core--
Shut it down now.
[power winds down]
It should have worked.
Well, it didn't,
And drawing power
from the planet's Core is--
Dangerous,
yes, we're all aware of that--
Regardless of
what's been spent
Or what's at stake,
My first priority
Is to ensure the safety
of the people on this base.
Of course.
Of course...
Eli...
We'd best run through
your equations again.
You'll excuse me.
You are not seriously
putting this on me?
Not my fault.
People, you have to
calm down.
Seriously,
You have to calm down...
[systems power up]
[applause from crowd]
Yeah,
we got power!
Can I have
everybody's attention, please?
[clamor continues unabated.
All right, please listen!
Hey, listen up!
What is going on?
We're on an ancient spaceship.
What?
That's all I've got.
Now, what
that means is--
It means we need to use
the stargate
To get us all back home.
That is definitely on the list
of things to do, sir,
But I think right now--
You can consider that
an order--
We are working on it, sir.
Hey, I need to
speak to the person
Responsible for this.
Where is Dr. Rush?
Just shut up
for a second, will you?
How dare you talk to me--
Dad?
Dad, please...
Water?
Over here...
Sit down.
My pills...
[coughing and gasping]
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to
explain the situation.
We are on a ship,
But we have no idea where we are
in relation to earth.
Now, with respect, sir,
The reason you might be having
A hard time
breathing right now,
Is because the ship's
life-support system
Is not functioning properly.
[murmurs of panic
ripple through crowd]
Dr. Rush
is working on that right now.
[murmuring increasing]
Brody and park?
- Here!
- Here.
Okay, good,
you two are with me.
But these consoles
just came on.
No. Nobody touch
anything yet.
Dr. Rush needs your help.
Everybody else...
Just stay calm, stay put.
Please.
Stay put?
Wait, what
do you mean,
You're just going
like that?
There has to be a mistake
in here somewhere.
Seriously, who uses
a whiteboard anymore?
You have computers,
like, everywhere around here.
Power flow
was in the target range.
Why wouldn't
the address connect?
Wrong address?
There is only one,
Found in the ancient database
on atlantis.
With no other instructions.
No, but that's not the issue.
It has to be your proof.
My proof works.
You know how I know
that it does?
Because you said so.
Gentlemen,
how's it coming?
[scoffs] whoa, whoa,
what are you doing?
- Starting from the beginning.
- Wait! Save, save, save!
- I can't--
- Mr. Wallace, I would like you
To join me for dinner
in the officer's mess.
Thank you!
I'm starving--
We're quite close to
a breakthrough, actually.
I'd like eli
to keep working.
Well, we've been here
for six months.
It can wait a few more hours.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, uh, colonel,
You really have
no idea
Where this ninth-chevron
stargate address
Is going to send you?
No idea at all.
Hmm.
But the ancients built
the stargate with nine chevrons.
It's got to go somewhere.
[throws pen in disgust]
[sighs]
...We've also known
for some time
That the only way to
unlock the ninth chevron
Was to solve
the power issues.
Well, if anyone's
going to solve it,
I think eli will.
Yes, that's right.
It's true...
I am math boy.
[giggles]
Dr. Rush...
Dr. Rush!
I would like
to propose a toast.
Oh, no, that's
really not necessary.
- Not to you.
- Oh.
When the proposal
for this project
First crossed my desk,
I did not want
to approve it.
Oh, my god...
It seemed clear
to me at the time
That there were enough
Terrestrial
matters of importance
That needed
that kind of money.
Now, being
a proud father
Of a beautiful
young woman is one thing.
Having that young woman exceed
Every possible
expectation
Is quite another.
[opera plays on stereo]
It was my daughter, Chloe,
Who reminded me that
there was no greater endeavor
Than seeking an understanding
of who we are
And the mysteries
of the universe
In which we all exist.
[whispering]:
Not in those exact words.
It was also her idea
To embed the ancient
proof in a medium
That would give us access
to brilliant young minds
That we would have otherwise
overlooked.
And so,
To all the brave men and women
who have volunteered--
[distant explosion]
Okay, what was that?
[intercom crackles]
This is young.
[louder, closer explosion]
The base is
under attack.
All non-combatant personnel
report to your designated areas,
Everyone else
to your battle stations.
This is not a drill.
Senator, I need you
and your daughter
To go with lieutenant Scott.
- Eli, you as well.
- Oh, yeah, uh...
[murmuring in concern]
[argument in process]
What's going on
in here?
The life-support system
is on,
But for some reason,
it's not working properly.
I'm attempting to reset it.
He has no idea what he's doing.
Step away from that thing.
That screen says
That what you're doing
is going to overload it--
- Eli, please!
- Is that what it says or not?
You only think you know
what it says in this screen
Because I embedded
A rudimentary version
of the ancient language
Into the game.
This is not a game.
Don't touch it,
rush.
When the oxygen
aboard this ship
Falls below critical level,
It will become
increasingly difficult
To concentrate.
What you're doing
could blow the whole ship.
Are you sure, eli?
Back off now, or I will shoot!
Lower your weapon,
sergeant!
He already screwed us once.
I'm not going to let him
do it again!
I need to get through, people.
Stand aside.
[alarms wail]
Sergeant, we're under attack.
Don't know who,
don't know why.
Consider
the charges dropped.
Go take your anger out on them.
Yes, sir.
What do we got, colonel,
lucian alliance?
That would be
my guess.
They haven't
introduced themselves.
They started shooting
The minute
they came out of hyperspace.
Our shields are holding,
but we're not the target.
What's heading our way?
A full squadron of gliders
and a troop transport.
We cut them down some,
But the rest will be
on your doorstep
In less than three minutes.
Telford, did you copy?
Roger that.
If we can get to the transport
before they land their troops,
We stand a chance...
I am going to press
that button.
It's going to fix
the life-support,
And then you and I
and everyone else
Will be able to breathe
And think
Much better.
[whispers]: Don't do it.
Okay, look,
Sergeant...
I know we are in
a tough situation here,
But I am giving you
an order.
Lower your weapon.
So?
Well, I suppose
that would have been too simple.
Apparently, that did nothing.
This may take
A little more time, tj.
Hang in there.
Copy.
Does colonel young
know about this?
He knows.
Two weeks ago, you told me
That this was the best
experience of your life.
Something must
have happened.
The scholarship came in.
I guess I've just been
too afraid to admit
What I really want.
Well, you didn't tell me
you had even applied.
There's nothing else going on.
You know I'd tell you.
Unless you were
protecting someone--
I'm not.
Like I said,
I just hadn't made up my mind.
[rapid gunfire and explosions]
[alerts beep]
Dr. Rush?
I'm reading a dangerous
energy spike in the Core.
Eli...
Eli, I need your help.
With what?
The ninth chevron.
What? We need to get
the hell out of here!
Look, it took us two years
to find this site.
The properties are unique.
This may be our last chance.
[explosion rumbles]
If this bombardment
continues,
The radioactive Core's
going to go critical.
Y-you mean the planet,
it-it's going to explode?
Yes.
Okay, okay, okay,
um, um...
If my math works--
- We can't assume that--
- I said "if."
Then if it works,
Then it's not
a power supply issue,
It's the gate address.
We've known the first
eight symbols for years.
The ninth has to be
the point of origin.
So, what if
we're not on the planet
You're supposed to be
dialing from?
This is
where we are.
Okay, what if we are not
supposed to be here?
Icarus base, Telford.
We can't hold 'em back.
[soldiers shouting]
Let's go!
Go!
Fall
further back!
Sergeant Riley,
dial the stargate to earth!
Take cover!
Come on, come on.
[explosion rumbles]
[stargate dialing]
[Riley]:
Chevron one locked...
Okay, follow me,
the symbols on the stargate
Are constellations
as seen from earth,
That's what you said--
Yes, yes--
Okay, so, what if earth
is supposed to be
The point of origin?
The only viable
power source
Was here, light years away.
What if that
doesn't matter?
What if it's the only
combination that will work,
Like a Code.
A Code?
Yeah.
Chevron four
encoded...
Stop the dialing sequence.
I have my orders.
Get out of my way,
get out of the way!
We can't risk dialing earth.
[beep, stargate dialing]
[alerts wail]
Come on, let's go.
[coughing]
[crowd clamoring in panic]
[explosion rumbles closer]
[gasps]
Dad?
Dad!
Chloe!
Dad! My father!
There could still be people
trapped on the other side.
All right,
let's go, people!
You need to move it
to the gate-room!
This is Scott.
I got about a dozen or so people
cut off from the gate-room,
South-east corridor.
Oh, god. Dammit...
[col. Young]:
Oh, my god.
Is that
Dr. Simms?
Stay with me, okay?
He was helping pull people
back from the surface.
[sniffling]
Simms, can you
hear me?
Tj...
Tj--
No!
Hey, Tamara...
Hey...
Tamara...
Come on, we got to go.
[chevrons locking]
That is impressive.
Power's fluctuating
at critical levels.
[alerts wail]
Colonel, I'm detecting
a massive build-up of energy
From the planet!
Recall our fighters.
Radio colonel Telford
he's got two minutes
To get his people aboard
before we jump to hyperspace!
[explosions rumbling]
What's everybody doing?
I ordered an evacuation!
He didn't dial earth.
It's the ninth chevron address.
What?
The attack started
a chain reaction
In the planet's Core,
There's no way of stopping that,
And any blast
could easily translate
Through an open wormhole.
It's too dangerous
to dial earth.
You could have dialed
somewhere else, anywhere else.
- This is our only chance--
- shut it down.
- We can't, it's too late--
- Riley!
System's not responding, sir.
I need to get these people
out of here.
We have a way out.
We don't know what's on
the other side! Dammit, rush!
Can't be worse
than here, can it?
[explosions rumble]
Nobody move!
Await further instructions.
What's that?
Well, it doesn't
look like life-support.
I realize that.
Whoa...
What are we looking at?
It's a star map.
That's
the milky way.
I believe it's
a visual log
Of the ship's
journey.
So this is
where we are now?
No.
That's where the ship
originally embarked from.
Earth.
It's leaving the galaxy.
It did.
Long ago.
That was pegasus.
So those points
are more stars?
No, they're galaxies.
Rush...
Where the hell are we?
Several billion
light years from home.
Scott...
Stand clear.
You could take down
the rest of the roof with that.
We don't have time to argue.
I need you to lead the evacuees
through the gate.
You need to go with him.
No, I-I'm staying here
until I know my father's okay.
Make sure
everyone carries
As much of the expedition
supplies as they can.
Why?
'cause you're not going
to earth.
Rush dialed the ninth chevron.
Go.
Go!
[explosions rumble louder,
closer]
Once I'm through,
Follow one at a time
on a three-count!
Okay, people.
Make way.
You good?
Okay, let's go.
If you can hear me,
Stand back!
Okay, get down.
Fire in the hole!
[explosion rocks,
Chloe yelps]
Dad?
Put your weight
on me...
Keep calm, everybody.
I got you.
Please...
[explosion shatters
and Sparks]
Everybody, stay calm!
Don't push!
Oh!
[gulps and holds his breath]
Dad!
Ah!
Careful, careful...
You're okay, sir.
Are you okay?
I'm the last one.
I'm all right.
Greer, go.
I'm right behind you.
Hammond, this is young,
come in.
Hammond, this is young.
Come in.
Let's go, let's go,
let's go, come on, people.
Let's do it,
let's do it.
Sir!
Go!
Sir...
We've got colonel Carter.
On screen.
General,
we barely got away.
The planet was destroyed.
We managed to beam most
of our people off the surface
Before jumping to hyperspace.
We also believe
That the enemy forces
were destroyed.
Any word
on how they gained intel
On our base?
No.
What about casualties?
12.
80-plus m.I.A.
The Bunker-shielding technology
Prevented us from beaming out
anyone inside.
How many people made it
through the gate to earth?
None.
None?
Our sensors indicated
that the stargate was active
For a full six minutes
before the Core went critical.
Well, they didn't come
through here.
Then where'd they go?
Okay, listen up!
Everybody who is able,
We are going to search this ship
top to bottom.
Teams of three.
Weapons?
23, including
handguns.
One per group?
Yeah.
Flashlights, radios--
only when necessary.
Once those batteries are dead,
they are dead.
Regular check-ins with Dr. Rush
in the control room
Every 10 minutes,
And keep in mind,
As far as we know,
This bucket is really
freakin' old,
And there may be areas of damage
where life-support is unstable,
And, look, be smart, okay?
Don't touch anything
That looks like
it might be dangerous.
How are we
supposed to know
What's dangerous?
Becker, right?
Yes, sir.
I work in the mess.
I mean, I did.
Well, don't touch, just look.
You're, uh...
You're James, right?
Yes, lieutenant.
You and Riley are with me.
Subtle, man,
Subtle...
[Scott]: If it's
okay with you, sir,
It might be best,
Given your obvious skills,
If you could hang back here,
Help keep the rest
of these people calm.
Don't patronize me, son.
No, sir.
I'm a part of it.
Colonel,
I'm in.
Are you all right?
I'm solid, lieutenant.
I'm trained for this.
Look, I-I
didn't mean to--
Look, not now.
Rush, this is Scott,
come in.
Rush, this is Scott, come in.
Hello.
This is eli.
Where's rush?
Uh, bathroom, if he found it.
Uh, I'm at what looks like
a bulkhead door.
It won't open.
I was hoping rush
could open it from there.
Should I find him?
No.
Here, give me a hand.
What happened to being smart?
This could be
the engine room
For all we know.
We got to at least
open a few doors.
Do we?
Do we really?
Hang on.
No, keep doing
what you're doing.
I think I found
where you are.
The door is flashing red.
Can you open it
from there?
Red is usually bad,
isn't it?
Maybe it means
the door is stuck.
Just try it.
Okay.
You should probably step back.
[air whooshing out]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, not good!
Not good, more red, uh...
Close it!
- Close it now!
- I'm trying!
Yeah, okay, we established
why that hatch was closed.
Yeah.
A lot of others are closed
for the same reason.
We're only occupying a fraction
of the ship right now.
It goes on forever,
But if there are
damaged areas of the ship
That aren't sealed,
That could be our problem.
Oh, hey, good timing.
We just found--
hey...
Really?
This is Dr. Rush.
Meet me in the gateroom
immediately.
Everyone.
[murmurs ripple through crowd]
What's going on?
In this case
Are five ancient
communication stones.
They work over vast distances
In real time.
We can talk to
the people on earth.
Yes.
[murmurs of excitement]
You physically
take control
Of an individual
at the other end.
I brought these with us
In the event
we ended up somewhere
Out of range
of normal communication.
So let's use them.
[murmurs of assent]
I already have.
[murmurs of surprise]
Are they
sending help?
No.
Why? Why are they not
sending help?
The only means
of dialing this gate
From our galaxy
Was destroyed in the attack.
We're cut off.
I want to use one of
those stones now.
I have spoken with
general o'Neill--
I am a United States senator!
I've explained
our situation clearly.
In light of my knowledge
and experience,
He has placed me in charge.
He did what?
[loud murmurs of outrage]
I have faith in our ability
To repair the ship,
And to work together,
But if we're
to survive this,
We need leadership
And a clear
chain of command.
We only have a few
hours of air left.
I want to speak to
the general myself.
- Senator, please.
- Give it to him!
[angry shouts of agreement]
[gasps in pain]
[groaning]
Dad? Dad!
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Tj?
Excuse me, excuse me.
Okay...
Okay, he's still breathing.
Oh, my god!
I saw him
taking some pills?
Warfarin,
for his heart.
Blood-thinners are
the last thing he needs
If he's bleeding internally.
Um...
Please do something!
Look, I told you,
I'm just a medic--
Everyone, please,
There's no need for us all
to congregate in the one place.
Ms. Johansen,
Please find
adequate accommodation
For the injured,
and everyone else--
No, I don't recognize
your authority, Dr. Rush--
We have found quarters nearby
much more comfortable--
As an ioa representative,
I think you need to--
Please go there, and stay there
Until you're asked to do
something useful.
Something useful?
We do not want to settle in!
We want to get back!
Right?
[shouts of agreement]
We should be working
on getting home.
Exactly.
I'm not sure
if that's even possible.
What?
You haven't even tried!
Maybe you should
actually do something
Instead of standing around
talking about being in charge.
If that's even true.
Everybody!
Everyone, calm down!
Now, the fact is,
Colonel young put me in charge,
And I expect
All sg personnel
to follow my orders!
As for the rest of you,
You get out of line,
we will lock you down.
Now, Dr. Rush
Is right
about a couple things.
First off,
we all have to work together...
And second of all,
we don't all have to stay here,
So let's...
Let's move out.
Come on, move.
It's okay.
[murmurs of agreement]
you heard him...
[sighs heavily]
I think we need you...
So I've got your back
for now,
But if I were you,
I would find some way
to dial that gate back to earth.
I've got some
testing equipment
Over here.
Looks broken.
We'll get back to that.
What about
all these ancient crates?
If it's not ours,
don't touch it.
Did no one think
of labeling anything?
Every case
has a bar Code.
All right, anyone find
a bar Code reader?
Guess that got left behind
along with the food and water.
Uh-uh, we got food.
Yeah, protein bars,
And this powdered stuff.
Look, everybody.
Seeds? Volker,
you've got to be kidding.
I got a case
of blank paper.
Maybe we should start
a suggestion box.
What are you staring at?
You were in detention.
Yeah.
For good reason.
What did you
want him to do,
Leave me there?
Of course not.
I was just wondering
what to do about it now.
That's not up to you.
We'll see.
No, no, no.
Don't do it.
[static crackles from comm]
Greer, I need you
to help check
For any open bulkhead doors
That lead to
damaged parts of the ship.
Rush will direct you.
Copy.
[rush]: There should be
an elevator directly ahead.
Copy that.
Are you there yet?
This is Scott.
Radio silence, please.
Hey...
Hey.
What's going on?
We almost lost you.
You were thrown
clear across the room.
[groaning]:
Where are we?
Sir...
[weakly]:
Where are we?
We're on a ship.
It's ancient.
Rush says
it's thousands of years old,
And we're pretty far off
into the universe.
What's he doing to get us home?
He says he's working on it,
But we have bigger problems.
The life-support system
isn't working properly.
If we can't
get it fixed,
There's not much time.
You should also know that
He used the communication stones
to contact earth,
And he said general o'Neill
put him in charge.
I don't think so.
I don't think--
oh...
Sir, you shouldn't be trying
to get up just yet, okay?
I don't think
I have a choice, tj.
I can't feel my legs.
- Whoa, jeez!
- Whoa!
What is that thing?
Come here,
I'll show you.
It's a...
It's a camera.
It's a flying camera.
I'm calling it a kino,
you know, after the Russian--
Yeah--
Well, I figure
maybe we can use it
To check out the damaged
areas of the ship.
- That's good.
- Yeah.
That's good.
Where's it going now?
Oh, I don't know,
it's just doing its thing,
But there's lots more of 'em.
[chuckles]
Yeah, it's cool.
Yeah!
Do you want one?
It's not
a gumball machine, eli.
Okay.
Okay!
Okay, so you figured out
where they keep the kinos,
What else have you
figured out?
Give me a break, man.
This is my
second spaceship,
And my first
was yesterday.
I know.
Icarus was my first
sgc assignment
After training.
I haven't
been at this
Much longer
than you have.
Huh...
Did they beam you
out of your house?
No, you
got me there.
Got any food
on you?
No.
Tylenol?
Headache?
Yeah.
Me too.
Neuroproaxia is
a temporary paralysis
That can follow
a concussive injury.
You don't know?
You'd need an mri
And a qualified doctor
who knows how to read it
To know for sure
if there's spinal damage.
We don't have either.
Hopefully, it's just
the nerves in shock.
Best I can do is insist
that you remain still.
Your tour was over
two weeks ago.
You should be
in some classroom
In san Diego.
Seattle.
That's where my scholarship was.
I'm sorry.
That part's not your fault.
Tell rush I want to see him.
Yes, sir.
What's that?
Flying camera ball.
I'm calling it
a kino--
Don't ask.
That's marvellous.
It comes
with a remote.
I thought we could
use it to look around.
What do you have?
Uh, well, it's not
so good, really.
These processing nodes
are scrubbers,
Responsible for
cleaning co2 from the air.
Here, here, and here.
It's indicating
malfunctioned.
Others are failing.
Greer, this is Scott.
I'm heading for the gateroom.
Meet me there.
Look, I'm just saying
That she better
stay out of my face.
I'll remind her of your
personal space issues
Next chance I get.
Dr. Rush?
Colonel young wants
to see you right away.
There should be a kind of grate
covering the node.
[latch beeps]
[goo slops]
[rush]: What do you see?
A problem.
We see a very big problem.
What happened?
You collapsed.
We brought you here.
What's going on?
I'm not sure.
I've been here with you.
You need to know
what's happening, Chloe.
This is important.
Dad, I was worried about you.
Okay.
And I'm scared.
One step at a time, Honey.
One step
at a time.
[winces]
My pills...
No, daddy, you can't take
any more of those.
Your ribs are badly bruised.
You will bleed
internally.
If I don't take those pills,
A bruise is going to be
the least of my problems.
I know.
Don't worry about me.
Go. Find out what's going on
out there.
No, I want to be here with you.
And I want you here,
But right now,
I want to know what's going on
Just a little bit more.
I'll be here when you get back.
Okay.
What's going on?
I don't know, man.
The air filter's full of crap.
Come on,
They want us to keep looking.
Let's go.
All right, okay.
[device beeps]
Alkaline.
Everyone's heart rates
are elevated,
People are reporting
headaches, it has to be.
What?
The used-up residue
Of whatever magic compound
the ancients used
To scrub co2
from the air.
So now we have
two big problems
Relating to
the life-support.
Our first priority
must be
To seal off any
of the leaks.
If we can manage that,
Then we can maybe
buy ourselves a day or so
Before the build-up of co2
kills us.
As it stands,
how much time do we have?
I don't know.
Couple of hours
at most.
[barks a laugh]
awesome.
Brody, there was
Some medical-grade soda lime
In the supply manifest?
It never made it.
That's a pity.
Well...
In a ship this old...
There's bound to be systems
past their designed life.
Okay, let's say
we find the leaks.
Can you fix this?
I doubt this stuff
can be cooked off.
Perhaps if there were stores
of this substance
In a clean form,
Or something else capable
of co2 sequestration,
Calcium carbonate,
lithium hydroxide,
Then yes, "if."
Okay, well,
that's not going to matter
Because you're going to get
the gate dialed back to earth
Before this becomes
an issue, rush, right?
Lieutenant...
That's the kind of thing
You're taught to say
in officer training
Presumably
for the benefit
Of those that don't know
any better.
[whispers]: Please.
What makes you think
I won't try?
Greer, I found what looks like
a shuttle.
Looks like there are
two shuttles
Attached to individual
docking sleeves.
We're all going to die.
Shut up, Franklin.
I'm just saying what
everyone's got to be thinking.
I said, shut up,
Or else
you're going to be first.
This the door?
Yeah, yeah, that's it.
Can you close it?
It won't close.
We can't close it
from here, either.
There's something wrong
with the mechanism.
I think I found the leak.
There's another door
on the back of the shuttle,
But there's no control.
Then maybe we can
close it off locally.
The shield keeping
the air inside
Is obviously not
100% effective.
It probably wasn't designed
to compensate
For the amount of damage
the ship has sustained.
Is there a way
of boosting it?
At least in the areas
we need it?
We haven't
found a way yet.
It seems to be operating
at maximum capability.
[door hisses closed]
[coughing
and struggling to breathe]
Open the door!
Well, that's
not good.
That's very good, sir,
a very good sign.
I don't have time for this,
do I?
Two problems.
We're venting atmosphere
from a damaged shuttle,
And even if we could
seal it off,
The life-support system
in this ship
Is past its expiration date.
We'll build up co2
to lethal levels within a day.
Well, that explains
the headache.
You already had one.
They'll find a way,
that's what these people do.
Well, most of
these people
Aren't even
supposed to be here.
How did the ship get damaged?
We don't know.
It certainly looks like
it's been through a battle,
At least the parts
we can access.
We're still cut off
from most of the ship.
It's huge.
They tried jamming something
into the shuttle doorway
To keep it open long enough
To let the person inside
get out...
But it just opens again.
Some sort of
safety mechanism.
Like an elevator.
Rush says he can't override it.
How long do we have right now?
As it stands...
Rush says
if we don't get it closed...
....We've got just over an hour.
Bad air's
better than no air.
Guess a day's
better than an hour.
Someone's
got to go in there
And close this door.
My head is pounding.
Heartbeat has accelerated.
It's getting harder
and harder to breathe,
As our very lives
are being vented out into space.
That is going to
get old very fast.
This needs
to be documented.
No one's
going to see that.
How do you know?
We made it here.
Someone else could, too.
If we die,
Maybe this can help them
to find out what happened to us.
Yeah, well,
we're not dead yet.
[quietly]: I'm starting to have
slightly blurred vision--
- Eli!
- What?!
So how are we
going to decide who?
I assume we're not
going to get any volunteers.
What's another day
going to buy us?
Time...
To find a way
to survive.
May I see the list?
I marked the names
of anyone injured.
Right.
We have to find out
peoples' skills,
Background, experience--
Doesn't take any special skills
to die from asphyxiation!
Look, what I'm saying is,
It shouldn't be someone
With potentially
valuable knowledge,
Or abilities we might need
to help us survive beyond this.
Are you really
suggesting what I think--
Doc, half the people
on this ship
Already want to kill you.
I don't care.
You can't ask someone
to sacrifice themselves,
Period!
Politicians ask
military personnel
To sacrifice themselves
for the good of others
All the time.
If someone doesn't go in
there and close that door,
We're all going to die.
Period.
Franklin
is still working
At the airlock controls locally,
But it doesn't look good, sir.
Camile's explaining
the situation
To everyone else on board.
I'll do it.
Sir?
This isn't the kind of thing
I can ask somebody else
to volunteer for.
If we're going to
make it past this,
We're going to
need you, sir.
I don't know about that.
You're doing a pretty good job
without me, lieutenant.
Yeah?
Well, look at the mess we're in.
If that's not proof
that we need you, then--
Look, I'm not sure
anyone should do it.
I don't want someone
sacrificing themselves for me.
I say we figure this out
together
While we still
have time,
Or we all die trying.
I want you to both
listen to me.
It needs to be done,
and I'm doing it.
Look, sir,
you can barely stand.
Help me.
Look, the paralysis
is temporary,
You know that now.
You will recover--
Lieutenant,
I need your help.
No, sir.
I gave you an order.
I know.
You can have me court-martialled
when we get home,
But I am not going to
help you kill yourself.
My father's not in his room.
We'll find him.
He does not leave this room.
He can't have gotten far.
I told him
what was going on.
Greer, this is Scott,
come in.
Greer...
Greer, do you read?
Senator Armstrong is missing.
He may be headed your way.
He's here.
He's got a gun.
I don't want to shoot you.
I don't think
you want to shoot me.
Get out of the way.
Just give me
a little more time.
Let me try
and fix this.
I don't have much.
[eli]: Guys, I'm not seeing
any change,
Whatever you just tried,
It's not working!
The problem's obviously
mechanical.
You can't fix it.
Tell me what to do.
Dad, no, wait!
Dad, no!
No!
No! No...
[heavily muffled pleading]
Open the door!
Open the door, please!
I can't!
[crying]: Please
open the door...
He was dead
on his feet.
Dad, no!
[crying]: Please
open the door...
[sobbing]: No...
Eli!
Not him!
There's nothing
I can do for him here.
Help him!
Open the door, please!
[sobbing uncontrollably]
No!
[crying]: No...
No...
[sobbing]
He can't leave me...
Chloe...
Chloe!
Well, at least
he bought us a day.
[shouting in rage]
You!
You did this!
You killed him!
You've killed all of us!
Chloe, stop!
Little help here...
Hey, hey, relax.
Hey, hey, Chloe...
Just get away from me!
All of you!
M-miss Armstrong...
You're in shock.
Believe me, I understand.
Everyone
deals with tragedy
In different ways.
You're looking for
someone to blame.
I'm not looking.
Hey...
I'm sorry about your father.
I truly am.
He was a good man,
And he certainly
wouldn't have been my choice,
But you must realize,
None of this was my fault.
I didn't create the situation
that forced us here.
There was
no other way.
[crying]
Miss Armstrong...
I know you don't
want to hear this just now,
But...
But this ship...
This ship could be
the most important discovery
Mankind has made
Since the stargate
itself.
You know the icarus project
Was something
your father truly believed in,
Enough to risk
his career
To support.
What difference does it make
if we all die?
A number of people died
during the attack on the base.
Some of them I knew very well.
I'm sure some had
more value than others.
As human beings,
All of them were invaluable.
Look, my point is,
I promise you,
I will do
everything I can
To make sure no one
gave their life in vain.
No one.
Please give me a chance.
Colonel...
We've lost
senator Armstrong.
Oh, my god.
He's bought us
some time.
To do what?
We're working on it.
First up is trying to
dial the gate back home.
Should you even be
on your feet?
No.
Well, I am on my feet,
and right now
We're trying
to get home.
Camile,
I need your help.
You know these people.
I need you
to spread the word.
Try to keep things
as positive as you can.
I can do that.
Good.
I can't believe
my dad is gone.
I watched him die,
And I still
just can't accept it.
Tell me about him.
Why?
Man died so I could live.
I'd like to know
a little more about him.
No matter
how tired he was,
Or how long he'd worked,
Or what was going on
in his life,
He always had time
to listen to me.
I'd go on and on.
He never preached.
He never told me what to do,
Even though sometimes
I wished he would.
He would just listen,
And then he would tell me
that he loved me.
The best part
Was if I'd had
a fight with my mom.
He never took sides.
[chuckles softly]
Oh, god.
My mom...
He was her whole life.
She probably thinks
we're both dead.
All I know
Is that he wanted you to go on.
I know.
I got to get back
to the search.
You going to be okay?
I don't know.
Fair enough.
What?
What are you
doing?
I... Just
watched a man die.
Okay?
Don't you even care?
Of course I do,
And I'm also trying learn
as much as I can,
As quickly as I can.
That is,
In addition to running
Nine separate searches
in the database
In the hope of solving
our life-support issues.
Right.
Found anything?
Destiny.
As in ours?
The name of the ship.
Translated from ancient.
I've also learned
that they were never here.
I thought
this was an ancient ship.
It is,
But they sent it out unmanned,
Planning to use
the gate to get here
When it was far enough out
into the universe,
But they probably
learned to ascend
Before that time.
Learned to what?
Ascension.
It's a process
Whereby consciousness
converts to energy
That no longer requires
physical form.
That wasn't
in the video.
Well, there's
more than one video.
We should get back to work.
Sorry.
Sir, I think I got it.
It wasn't even
that hard to find.
It's right here
in the dialing program.
You're sure?
Yes, it's
an eight-symbol address.
You mean you can
dial this thing back to earth?
There's no point
of origin indicated,
But still, there's only
36 symbols on this gate.
I'm assuming
the ninth symbol represents
Some x-factor
distance equation.
Well, I don't care.
Start dialing.
Sir, don't we want to bring
Dr. Rush in on this?
Well, you said this wasn't
that hard to find?
No.
Well, then he probably
already knows
And didn't tell us.
[alert starts to beep]
Oh, no, no, no, no...
What?
Someone's dialing the gate.
Colonel young...
You're up.
Nice to see you, too, rush.
I did order you to report to me.
What are you
doing?
We're trying to dial earth.
That would be
a mistake.
Riley thinks he's found
the address for home.
His understanding
of ancient
Is marginal at best.
With respect,
doctor,
I know enough to recognize
a reference to earth.
He says the address
Wasn't that hard
to find, rush.
No, no, this is a complete
waste of power we may need.
We have
the address back,
All we need is
the right point of origin.
And we've got 36 tries.
We barely have enough power
to operate the Main systems.
This ship
Simply doesn't have
the capability to dial earth.
You see, that's news to me.
He didn't
tell me that either.
Well, I've only
just learned myself,
And you know
what I've been doing.
Even if
it doesn't work,
The people aboard this ship
need to see us at least try.
So, what, you're going to drain
what little power we have
For the sake of morale?
How ridiculous.
[ships groans and clanks]
What was that?
Anyone near
the observation deck?
Colonel...
It looks like
we've dropped out of ftl.
Because we were
draining power?
No, no.
If I'm right,
The gate should begin to dial
any moment.
How did you know that?
The ship detected
a stargate
On a planet within range
that may have what need.
What?
How the hell
Are there even
stargates out here?
The ancients sent out
a number of unmanned ships
Ahead of this one.
They're programmed
to gather data,
Resources,
To manufacture
stargates,
And deposit them
in habitable worlds.
Any relevant information
is relayed back here
To help
plot the course.
You're telling me
That this ship knows
we're in trouble?
Yes, because I told it we were.
Essentially,
We're flying on auto-pilot.
This ship may have stopped
When it was within range
of a stargate
Regardless of our need,
But I have reason to believe...
So, what we need
Is on the other side
of that wormhole.
An educated
guess, yes.
There's only one way
to find out.
Sir, you can't
do that.
We have no idea what's
on the other side.
We can use the kino
to find out.
I expect that's the purpose
of this device.
I'm getting
readings over here.
What have we got?
Temperature,
gravity,
Atmosphere composition,
Barometric pressure...
Oxygen nitrogen,
very little co2,
Extremely low humidity.
Habitable, but just barely.
Good enough.
Looks like
four other addresses
Came up here, too.
They could be
other planets within range.
Maybe we should
think about
Dialing them up
and seeing--
No, no, they're locked out.
The ship chose this one.
The stargate is open,
All we have to do
is step through.
What we have to do
is put a team together.
Dr. Rush...
Looks like our time
might be limited.
What is it?
It's a countdown.
Just over 12 hours left.
What happens then?
I suspect
We jump back into ftl.
[shutter snaps]
Palmer is a geologist.
Obviously, she should go.
Franklin and Brody are the best
of the rest of what we have.
Thanks for the
ringing endorsement.
He didn't even
mention me.
Franklin goes,
the others stay.
We're still going to need
good people
Working on the problem
from this end.
I'd like to go.
Really?
If I can help, then--
Colonel young, please--
What?
You don't think
I can handle it?
He's going.
I've been off-world before.
You have made a habit
Out of pulling our asses
out of the fire.
Eli, you want to go,
you're going.
The only one
I'm questioning right now
Is you, Dr. Rush.
[scoffs]
Well, besides Palmer,
I'm the only one who knows
what we're looking for.
We have 12 hours
to find what we need
And then get back on the ship.
You're sure you can't stop it?
No, we're just along
for the ride for now.
Then we may all be better off
on the planet.
Well, that's another reason
why I should go.
Someone to assess
Whether long-term survival there
is even an option.
All right.
Okay.
I want everyone clear
That Scott is in charge
of this mission.
Let's gear up,
Let's find
whatever supplies we have,
And move out.
Sir...
About eli--
He volunteered.
He's not trained
for this.
Just like a lot of the people
we got on this ship.
I'm going to need to know
what they're made of.
He'll slow us down.
Well, if he does,
You send him
back to the gate.
If we're going to make it,
And I'm not just talking
the next few hours,
We're going to need
everyone on board to step up.
Lieutenant...
Keep an eye on rush.
We'll be back, sir.
Good luck.
Transcript by Leapinlar
www.opensubtitles.og
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com