Whoa, look at Rachel's balloon.
Look at that balloon.
All right, she's gonna let it go on three.
One, two, three.
Oh, I got attacked by a balloon.
What's up with that?
Hey, Nate, you got a cake nose!
Dadda?
Daddy, wake up.
I wet my bed.
Okay.
It's all right.
There we go.
Okay.
Is that okay?
Go back to sleep.
It's bed time, okay?
Is Dadda awake?
No, Dadda not awake.
Dadda, there's snow.
- Snow?
- Come see!
- Where?
- Over there.
Is it getting you?
Snow.
It's getting snow all over.
Do that again.
- Hey, buddy.
- Yeah.
- You wanna go outside?
Want to build a snowman?
- Yeah.
- Then let's go.
Seven...
11...
aren't ya?
Who's my little guy? All right, I got you. Two arm.
Love you.
- Hey, you know what?
- What?
I think Charlie might be a little cold in the snow.
- Should we leave Charlie behind?
- Yeah.
- Bye, Charlie.
Bye-bye, Charlie.
- Yeah.
- Bye-bye, Charlie.
- Are we gonna make a snowman?
- Yeah.
- Are we gonna go sledding?
Oh, it's really cold, Nate.
Are you gonna sit beside me?
I can't. Daddy's gotta drive.
Let's put your little arm through. There.
Is Charlie okay?
I'm sure Charlie's just fine.
Are you sleeping?
You wake me up, and now you're going to sleep?
Look, there's Angie.
Hey, Ethan.
Get your blanket, here.
There you go.
What do we want for dinner tonight, huh?
Pizza.
Look at that huge mountain.
There's a dump truck.
Vroom, vroom!
Look at that.
What do you think, champ?
Nate, hey. Buddy, wake up.
Shit.
Nate.
Nate!
Come on, buddy! Let's go!
Can I get you anything else, Frank?
No, I'm just gonna sit here and avoid the weather.
Don't blame you a bit. Paul?
Tabasco.
How could I forget?
Angie's, you got her.
I'm late for work again.
It's the second time this week.
We need to keep last night to ourselves.
You think?
Jane's gonna kill me.
Hmm.
Hey, maybe we should keep this
morning to ourselves as well.
I'm not gonna fall for that, Rusty.
Come here.
Cindy!
- Cindy.
- What?
Maybe you should put some panties on first.
Oh, shit.
- Cindy, it's Angie.
- I'm coming.
Hey, Angie.
Cindy, I need you to get dressed.
How far did you track that deer?
100 yards, maybe half a mile...
- I don't know.
- Which direction?
North. Northeast, towards the ravine.
And how long were you gone?
10 minutes, maybe.
Maybe?
No more than 20.
I want the dogs all over that trail, go.
Now, Charlie!
Hey, heard over the radio.
Gotta talk to Bill. Where's Rusty?
Rusty... haven't seen him since Trevor's last night.
Come on. Come on.
Fuck me. Come on.
Come back to Daddy now.
I guess I'm not going in to work.
Got a good excuse now.
This radio work?
Yeah, sure.
♪ If you're happy and you know it ♪
♪ Then your face will surely show it ♪
♪ If you're happy and you know it, shout hurray. ♪
Nate.
Nate!
- Hey, Rusty.
- Hey, Charlie.
- What's going on? Where's Ethan?
- He's up in the woods.
- Okay, where? What direction?
- No, no, no, no, no.
I need you to check in right there, right now. Go.
All right. You fucking believe this?
- Rusty.
- Hey, Bill.
Nate!
I need some help!
Fucking...
- Ethan.
- Where were you?
Fuck, man, I didn't have my phone on.
Where you heading?
Northeast part of the trail, by the old campsite.
I already hit it once. Mabe I missed something.
Okay, I'll head south. We'll meet back here
- in two hours, okay?
- Yeah.
Hey. Cindy?
Angie's with her.
How old's Rosie now?
Um, she's coming up on three and a half.
She's a Pisces, right?
Pisces? No. She's a Libra.
Natey!
Excuse me, ma'am.
Volunteers can report to Officer Parks right over here.
Okay, we're not volunteers.
- This is Cindy Mills.
- You know, the mother.
Oh, would you like some coffee or something?
Coffee? I don't want coffee. I want to talk to Ethan.
We should talk to Bill first, find out what's going on.
Where is he?
You...
son of a bitch!
- You motherfucking son of a bitch.
- Cindy.
- You went and fucking lost him?
- Cindy, calm down.
- All right, look...
- No, I don't want to calm down!
- I wanna know where my son is!
- We all do!
- Don't make this about you, Cindy.
- If he's dead...
Now don't fucking...
If he's dead, I will kill you.
If he's that, I'll save you the trouble.
Get her out of here please.
Oh, God.
Nate?
Nate!
Why is nobody screaming his name?
Back to work.
- I mean, he's gone, right?
- We don't know that yet.
I can take myself.
How many rangers do we have out here?
We have enough. We have all we can manage.
We need to get more people out here.
Go home and put on a warmer coat.
When it gets dark, he won't survive it.
We know that, Jane. We're doing everything we can.
Just... just hang tight.
- Nate!
- Tom.
Tom, I need a report on grid four.
Here, drop me here.
Oh, please, God. Please, please, please.
Please, please, God, don't take him away from me.
Please.
Come on, let's go.
Ethan.
- Ethan, I'm so sorry.
- What's going on?
- Bill says it's getting dark.
- What the hell is going on?
- So he thinks...
- What, everyone's leaving now?
Hey. What's going on?
You're sending people home now?
I'm sorry, Ethan, we just can't
keep this up in the dark.
What the fuck? My son is still out there.
I know that, but it's just not safe
for the search teams any more.
Not safe for the search teams? He's three years old.
I can't risk anyone else.
Fuck your risk. Nobody goes home.
You, stop. We're not shutting down.
Put the tent... put the stuff down,
and put the tent back up.
Pack it up, Charlie.
You listen to me, you put the fucking tent back up.
- Ethan! Ethan.
- What?
Gotta let Bill do his job.
Rusty, Bill's job is to help me find Nate
while there's still time.
And there's still time, right?
- Right?
- Yes.
Yes, Ethan, there's still time.
Now, I gotta send these other people home,
but... but I'm staying,
and we're gonna take turns searching,
and we're gonna search all night.
That's right.
Okay? Ethan?
Yeah. Yeah.
You really think those shoes are the best choice?
I wasn't really thinking.
- Hey.
- What?
I'm getting you all wet.
Always.
That's not what I meant.
Mmm, then that's too bad.
You should have seen Ethan, Rox.
- He was devastated.
- Yeah, well.
- What?
- He lost his kid.
It's a natural reaction in the scheme of things.
- He should feel devastated.
- Should?
What do you want me to say, Jane?
Just say what you think, Rox. You always do.
Fine. Ethan shouldn't have left Nate in the truck.
It was stupid and careless,
and what the fuck was he thinking?
It's his own fault.
You could have some compassion.
I do. I do have compassion, a truckload of it, for Nate.
That'll be $4.86.
Shit.
It's basic.
You think medium would taste better?
- Hey.
- Yeah?
You still buddies with Ethan?
Yeah. So?
Yeah, well, he owes me.
Wanna spot me some beer?
She'll probably give you a blowjob for it, man.
I can fucking hear you!
You're a good man.
Come on, Nate. Nate.
All right.
Come on, Nate.
Come on.
Nate!
Hey, hey.
Nate, it's Daddy.
Hey.
Take care, Brian.
- You, too.
- See you, man.
District attorney Jack Craft will be holding
a press conference later this morning in Angels Crest.
It's expected that Mr. Craft will address the case
of three-year-old Nathan Denton,
who was found frozen to death last week
after his father Ethan Denton had left him in the truck.
I told them not to let anyone in yet, but... you okay?
Yeah. It's smaller than I remember.
- What?
- The coffin.
- You went to the funeral?
- No. I'll... I'll be fine.
Maybe we should just postpone.
No, no, no. How much time do we have?
- 10 minutes.
- Jack.
- Yes.
District Attorney, any comment on the accusations?
Mr. Craft, can you separate this
case from your own past?
The state is filing charges against Ethan Denton
for the death of his son Nathan Denton.
Now, we are not claiming that Ethan Denton
deliberately killed his son.
However, his decision to leave the boy
alone in a truck during a blizzard
directly led to his death, and therefore constitutes
an act of criminal negligence.
Jack, are you the right man to be prosecuting?
- Thank you.
- Jack, Jack, without being personal...
Jack, any correlation between this case...
I'm so sorry.
Ethan, we need to talk.
Okay.
You keep in mind that I have never
hated my job more than I do right now.
- Okay.
- I gotta take you in.
For what?
Now, you'll be able to get a lawyer.
Right now?
- Right now.
- Okay. Okay.
- Did you see Bill, Angie?
- Yeah.
Has everybody lost their minds completely?
- It was an accident.
- Calm down, Jane.
- Nobody's saying it wasn't.
- Ethan is a great kid.
Why am I the only person who's angry about this?
He just should have taken better care is all.
Hey, sweetheart.
I'm so sorry Mommy took such a long time.
♪ I wish I had a dime ♪
♪ For every bad time... ♪
Hi. I'm Jane Childs. I don't believe we've met.
I'm Joanne Mills.
It's nice to meet you. Are you a friend of...
I'm Cindy's mother.
Oh, oh. I didn't realize Cindy had...
I mean, of course I realized she
had a mother, but I just...
It's so good to meet you. It's so good you're here.
For Cindy.
Can I get you anything?
Do you know where Cindy is?
What's that?
It's medicine.
You have a tummy ache?
Yeah, something like that.
So, you gonna go to the bathroom or what?
- I know how to go myself.
- Good for you.
I left Paul Jr. In the car once overnight
when he was about Nate's age.
Really?
Crying like a banshee the next morning,
but no worse for the wear.
- Never told Donna.
- Smart.
Of course, it was summertime.
Wouldn't have left him out there in the winter.
Yeah, so long as it was summertime.
You poor thing. What you must be going through...
I can just imagine.
But you rest assured,
Nate is in a better place.
Cindy, Cindy. I'm very sorry.
- She's just not herself.
- Oh, God!
Sit down.
You came, huh?
I missed the funeral because
you gave me the wrong time.
You have very nice friends here.
The woman sewing coffee, she introduced herself.
She was very nice.
Jane?
- Yes, Jane.
- She's a dyke.
Jane says we need some more napkins.
I'm getting them. I'm getting them.
Hey, hey, whoa.
I'll help, okay? It's cool.
It's not cool.
I've been trying to call Ethan's dad
for days, leaving messages,
and I just don't understand why he's not here.
Ethan needs someone.
No, Ethan doesn't need his dad right now.
- How do you know?
- I know Ethan.
Look, maybe it's you that needs someone.
All right.
What?
I've gotta go.
Rose?
Rosie?
Guess what.
I washed my hands.
Good, baby. Good, sweetheart.
Oh.
Hey, what's this?
What's this you're wearing?
I thought it was a wedding.
Oh.
Yeah, baby, it's...
it's not a wedding.
You still play ball?
That's too bad. You were good.
Oh, thanks, man.
We got a softball league.
Play against the fire department.
It's not real or anything, but, you know, it's something.
Right.
You ever think of a career in law enforcement?
We could use an arm like yours.
Ethan Denton made bail this morning
after pleading not guilty to the charges against him
- for his role in the death...
- Not guilty, my ass!
I hope that jury fucking puts him away.
Whatever happens, it's in the hands of the Lord now.
That's supposed to be comforting?
What are you doing with my beer?
You've had enough, Cindy.
You have your god, I have mine.
Denton will not be making a statement at this time.
When will he be ready to make a statement?
Hey, hey, hey.
We're on your side, Ethan. Come on, just give us...
Ethan.
Hey, hold up. Come on... Ethan.
Shit.
Hey, man.
Where you heading?
Nowhere.
You can crash at my place if you want
or at the garage.
We're closed down for the week.
Whose idea was that?
Mine.
- Hungry?
- No.
- I can pick you something up...
- Where were you that morning?
What you talking about, man?
Come on, where were you? Don't be stupid.
You know what I'm talking about.
Come on.
You come on. Where were you?
You know where I was. I was with a girl.
- Yeah? What girl?
- Come on, man.
No, come on. What girl?
Give me a break, man. Come on.
Tell me what girl.
You don't know her, all right?
- What girl?
- Stop it.
- Stop it. Come on.
What girl?
Say it. Say it!
Cindy.
- Cindy, all right?
- Cindy.
You know how close Nate was to the truck?
Less than a quarter-mile.
- Dude, are you looking at my screen?
- I never, ever...
You were looking at my screen, man.
Beer.
Think they let you game in prison?
I'm just saying, I mean, no work, no bills,
just you and the console.
For five years?
Some games take five years, man.
Maybe I'll get lucky and they'll let me out after three.
For good behavior?
- You want me to pause it?
- Yeah, pause it.
- Fuck. Fuck.
- Oh, shit!
You crazy bitch!
Get the fuck out of here!
Get out of here!
Yeah, come on.
Come on.
Not guilty, my ass!
Is your dad alive?
No.
I bet he was a good dad, though, right,
when he was alive?
You being a lawyer and all,
I imagine he'd be real proud.
Something like that.
My dad's not dead.
He's not proud, either.
As a matter of fact, he's not even here.
I don't blame him.
He probably doesn't even know.
That's why he's not here.
My dad is a shit dad.
But if he knew,
I know he'd be right here,
digging up this grave with his fingernails,
lifting Nate
out from the earth,
giving him mouth-to-mouth.
He'd try and bring him back to me.
He would.
Because what dad could just stand there
and watch a boy live through this?
I'm very sorry for your loss.
What are you doing here?
- Here you go, number 21.
- That was fast.
Smells good.
What can I get for you?
What's the special?
It's open-faced turkey sandwich
with mashed potatoes and gravy.
That sounds good.
- To go?
- No.
I'd recommend it.
Well, actually I was hoping to
speak to you, Ms. Manning.
One turkey.
- I'm busy. To go.
- Well, maybe another time.
Oh, I'm always busy.
Here you go, Frank.
Sir.
Yeah.
You have any kids?
Once upon a time, yeah.
Jane.
- Hi.
Come in.
This is my partner Roxanne.
- This is Melody.
- Hi.
Hey.
Good to meet you.
Mel.
Okay, so, uh, let me show you up to your room.
I got it.
Okay, okay.
Right up the stairs here.
These are Roxie's paintings, all of them.
- You're reading too much into it.
- Yeah, right.
Well, what do you want me to say, Roxanne?
He was raised by my ex-husband.
Oh, you know me, bean pole.
- I'm just venting.
- Yeah, thanks for the support.
What? I'm hungry. I want that.
- Not for us.
- What?
I'll be back before you know it.
Oh, no. No, you're not leaving me here alone.
You're not leaving me here to
babysit your homophobic son
and his knocked-up little girlfriend.
- Bye.
- Jane.
Hey.
Hi.
Why don't you take a little break,
let me fix you something to eat?
You know, I locked the door when I got out.
- I locked the truck.
- Of course you did.
And I had the heat on high.
I closed the door really fast
when I got out s-so that it w-would stay warm.
He was still warm when I left him.
He didn't know how to get out of his seat.
That's the thing... he didn't...
didn't know how to do that.
- I know, baby.
- You know?
I know.
It's not your fault.
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
I couldn't think of anywhere else to go.
Rosie's fast asleep.
- How about I get you a cup of coffee?
- Yeah.
I was with Cindy that morning.
I know.
I saw you there.
Thanks.
Oh, so you think that if you hadn't been there,
maybe things would have been different.
That DA came by here.
The thing is,
I never thought that Ethan
was that great of a dad.
No?
No. I mean, I know he loved Nate and all,
but there were always little things,
like he would let him out of his
sight for a moment too long
or he would drink beer in the truck.
And I never said anything.
Never.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
They're young.
I'd better not have to fucking listen
to that every other night.
We won't. They're leaving soon.
He just wants money.
Yeah, well,
what did you expect... love?
You left him when he was 10 years old.
I know.
Can I help you?
Uh, I was just gonna take a closer look.
That's why we have display models.
I'm sorry. I'll put it back.
Here, let me do that.
Hey, you haven't had a recall
on this item or anything, have you?
We wouldn't be selling it if there was a recall.
Do you get many complaints?
Like about... see this part, like the...
Or this, the latch, not staying buckled?
- Not that I know of.
- Anything?
Look, why don't you just go online
and look at some consumer reviews or something?
You know, that's a real good idea. Thanks.
Can I have a price check for Similac
on aisle three, please?
I just need just a little bit of clarity here,
because I'm trying to figure out what's happening.
The insurance claim was denied?
- We don't actually know.
- I think so, yeah.
Ethan and Nate stayed with you guys, correct?
Yeah, the water damage destroyed the kitchen.
It was inconvenient for them to
stay there during construction,
so, yeah, they stayed with us.
- Well, who paid for the construction?
- Ethan did.
He worked overtime to pay for it.
He's a very hard worker.
Because the insurance claim was denied?
I'm not actually sure.
Of course it was denied.
The faucet in the tub was left on
for hours. It was negligence.
Thank you.
- What?
- Nothing.
What? Speak your mind for once, please.
- It's not really the time.
- Why not?
Who gives a fuck what this guy thinks? Say it.
Ever since I told you George was coming,
you've been a total cunt.
Well, just give me one more question, you guys,
and I'll get out of your hair.
How long did Ethan and Nate stay with you guys
after Ethan flooded the house?
Ethan didn't flood the house. He wasn't even there.
Cindy was.
- You like it black?
- I do, thank you.
Okay.
Oh, I'm sorry if I woke you.
Let me introduce myself. I'm Jack Craft.
- This is the district attorney.
- Nice to meet you.
I need coffee.
I had her when I was very young.
Clearly.
Miss Mills, I don't know if you're aware of this,
but the state is prosecuting Ethan Denton
for his role in Nate's death.
It's Cindy.
And I know all about the trial.
I was wondering if you'd be willing to help me.
Like what? Testify?
No, no, no. That's getting way ahead of ourselves.
I was just trying to get some background information.
Like what?
Like, you know, what kind of father Ethan was,
you know, from your perspective.
- My perspective?
- Yeah.
You may not be aware of this, but...
Fuck.
But I have an itsy bitsy problem with alcohol.
That's why Nate lived with Ethan in the first place.
You're not the one that's on trial here; Ethan is.
You may be an alcoholic,
but you're not the one who chose to drive your son
into the woods in a snowstorm.
You didn't, totally sober,
make the decision to leave Nate in a truck
to track a deer...
a fucking deer.
Excuse me.
Ethan's actions would be more understandable...
not less negligent, but more understandable,
had he been drunk at the time.
That's a twisted fucking argument.
Now, maybe he chose an inappropriate babysitter.
Maybe he's done a lot of fucked-up
things during his life.
Maybe this isn't the first time that he chose hunting
over taking care of his son.
All I'm asking is for you to think about it, all right?
If something comes to you, if you remember anything,
you simply write it down.
I've taken too much of your time.
Not at all.
You ladies have a good morning.
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
God be with you.
He seems really smart, doesn't he?
I guess.
I think he's gonna put Ethan away.
Maybe.
Why didn't you give Nathan the
birthday present I sent him?
I... I was going...
I didn't have a chance. I was going to.
Just, uh... I saw it in the closet and I wondered.
- I was going to.
- I believe you.
What did you give him?
Made to order.
Oh, best thing I ever put in my mouth.
- You want some?
- I don't do dick.
- Hey, Ange.
- Hey, Rusty.
Can you take some food over to the garage for me,
for Ethan?
Oh, now's not really a good time.
No? Okay, I'll have Rox take it over for me.
So, can I get you guys anything else?
- Ethan.
- Hi. Hi.
- What are you doing here?
- I got...
Oh, this is Melody. She's the uh...
Knocked-up little girlfriend of Jane's homophobic son.
Yeah.
Hey, that's a cute seat.
I was thinking of getting one.
It's a piece of shit.
So, Ange wanted me to drop off some food for you.
I'll be right back.
- What do you use?
- Bolt action, 30-30.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Can I buy you a cup of coffee?
Not in this lifetime.
Just a heads up then... you'll be getting a subpoena.
All right.
I'm not testifying against Ethan.
You were with him when he found Nate.
All I expect you to do
is describe that experience, that's it.
- I can do that.
- All right.
I can tell about how I never saw
a person so wrecked as Ethan
when he dug up his son from the snow.
I can tell the jury how much bullshit this trial is
and how losing your own kid
doesn't give you license to shit on the rest of us.
I'll ask you how Nate was found, what he was wearing,
how he looked when you saw him,
the state of his toes, color of his skin,
how low the temperature got.
You answer all my...
Hey, man.
Hey.
I... I just came by to say... I'm sorry.
You know, I'm just really sorry.
For what?
For not being there when you called.
For Cindy.
It doesn't matter.
It really doesn't matter.
What you doing there?
I can't figure the goddamn thing out.
I read online all these complaints about it, right?
Like, this one woman, she said that
the buckle would just come undone.
Like, it would just pop open
after she buckled her kid in.
So I kept taking the damn thing apart
and putting it back together, and I can't find the glitch.
What glitch?
You know, the glitch... the glitch that,
you know, makes the buckle come undone.
Okay.
I have to... I have to get this kind of evidence,
you know, because...
Huh?
Hey, why don't you come crash
at my place for a while?
No, no, no.
No. I'm really fine here. I'm fine.
Yeah, yeah, you know, I can see that,
but, you know, I thought maybe
you could use a fresh pair of eyes, you know.
We can bring the car seat, work on it together.
You'd work on it with me?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
Come on. We'll go get some food,
camp out at my place.
It'll be great.
- I don't know, man.
- Dude...
this place reeks anyway, man, you know?
Man, come on. I don't even know
what this is, you know?
It was once upon a time bacon, but now...
Jeez.
All right. Thanks, man.
All right. I'll get the seat.
- You got it?
- Oh, yeah.
So, when'd you last take a shower?
- I don't know. It's been a while.
- Oh, yeah?
First thing I'm gonna do is take a hose
to that skinny-ass body of yours.
- I just gotta lock up.
- Okay.
See you there.
Whiskey?
- Hey, Cindy.
- Hey.
What are you doing here?
Same thing as you, I guess.
Have you seen Ethan?
Not really.
I thought you two were close.
No, Jane's the one.
But you used to take care of...
Sometimes, yeah.
Was he good for you?
- The best.
- Good.
He was a good baby, too. He didn't cry too much.
We'd build forts in the living room
with pillows and blankets and shit.
He loved that. Yeah.
That must have been fun.
No, not really. I'd set the pillows up,
he'd pull them down, throw them all over the place,
then want me to set them up all the fuck over again,
but it was fun for him.
It's on me.
To know that Jesus is your savior,
but he's also your friend.
You can put your trust in Him.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Can you hear me, O Lord?
♪ Can you hear me? ♪
When I ask You to be my friend.
♪ Be my friend... ♪
There's only one way to come to Jesus...
Where have you been?
At work, I told you that.
I was listening to that.
My house, my rules, your words.
What's wrong with you?
What's wrong with me?
What do you think?
I defrosted a casserole for dinner.
I don't want a fucking casserole.
Then what would you like to eat?
I don't want anything to eat.
I want you to just stop fucking doing
my fucking laundry any more, either!
You ungrateful shit.
Slut.
Look at the way you live.
My baby's dead.
You were Nate's mother,
and you let that boy take him away.
No, that's not my fault.
You let that boy take him away
and let him freeze to death.
- That's not my fault.
- It was your choice.
In what universe was it my choice?
I wasn't even there.
It was your choice to let Ethan have him.
What did you want me to do?
What was I supposed to do?!
You should have let me have him.
Cindy?
Hey. Wanna wear this?
That was Ethan's, Angie.
- I'm sorry.
- Let me see it.
It used to smell like him.
Oh, God, I miss him so much.
We all miss Nate.
No, not Nate.
Ethan.
- Try my tea.
- No.
- Do it.
- No, no.
Hey, stop it.
Oh, I know. Rachel.
Ethan.
- Hey, how are you?
- Good.
Paul, I haven't seen you in a while.
- Good to see you.
- Thanks, man. You, too.
Ethan, I am terribly sorry...
but we have no more turkey.
- Uh...
- We got ham.
- You got ham?
- Ham it is.
- Ham.
- One ham!
Put it in.
Put the poop and pee in.
Okay, now mix it up.
There's poop and pee in it.
- Oh!
- We're pretending.
May we have French fries please?
All right, then, little ladies.
You'll have to sit behind the counter
and take your order like regular customers.
Someone's in here.
It's me. You okay?
Trying to take a shit in peace.
Sorry.
Whoo! Can Nate play?
No.
Why not?
He's not here.
Is he at your house?
- Where is he?
- I don't know, okay?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm not mad at you.
Nate's just on a trip.
Okay?
I want to go on a trip.
It's too cold. Come on.
Why don't you get in the car seat over there?
- Can we get some biscuits and gravy?
- Yeah, that's fine.
Not too tight, is it?
- Nope.
- No? All right.
Hey, sweetie. Where's Rosie?
We can go on an adventure.
Yeah, we're going on an adventure.
Rosie!
Rosie?
Hey, Ethan, stop!
What?
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
What the hell were you thinking
taking Rosie without asking me?
We're just going for a drive. We're not going far.
The hell you are. You're not going
anywhere. Come on, Rosie.
Come on out, baby. Get out of the truck.
Calm down.
- She's like my sister.
- Well, Nate was your son.
Rosie, come on, come on.
- She can do that?
- Do what?
Unbuckle herself, get out of her seat like that?
- Yeah.
- For how long?
How long has she been able to
get out of the seat by herself?
I don't know. A while!
Fly away!
Look how high it's going!
What's wrong, Mommy?
Nate's gone. That's what's wrong.
Come in.
Cindy Mills is here to see you.
Oh, good. Cindy, how are you?
Have a seat.
- I wanted to give you this.
- Good.
I bet this is gonna be great. Thank you.
- Read it.
- All right.
"Didn't go to birth class at hospital."
"Drove drunk while baby was in the car."
"Drank vodka while breastfeeding."
"Smoked heavily around baby."
It's all I could come up with.
Well...
Go away, Rusty. Go.
Oh, God.
Fuck.
Rusty knows how to work the dryer, right?
You were right to take Nate from me.
I'm a shit mom.
And now you're a shit dad, too.
Please stay.
Stay.
Cindy?
I'm so, so sorry.
Hi. Celina Cervantes please.
It's Ethan Denton.
- What's going on? Am I late?
- No, no.
- Cervantes just called.
- Uh-huh.
Denton boy wants to change his plea to guilty.
He wants to change his plea.
- It's good news, right?
- No.
Okay, would you mind if I left a little early?
Yeah, I would. I would, actually.
My son's got a game.
Well, take it off, then. Go ahead.
- Thank you.
- Uh-huh.
Thank you.
Where are you going?
Home.
Before you go...
can you tell me something about him?
Just one thing?
He'd carry his walkie-talkie around all the time,
like it was his cell phone.
He was always expecting a call.
This is Ranger Bear
calling Ranger Pup.
Do you read me?
Hey.
Rusty said you moved back home.
It was time.
Is George still around?
No, they left.
- I'm sorry.
- Me, too.
Rox says they'll be back, but I don't know.
He came to you when he was in trouble, right?
Yeah.
He'll get in trouble again.
Thanks.
You know what?
I think Judge McKay is gonna be lenient.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's what...
what Celina says.
She's guessing 30 days and community service.
That's not so bad.
It's okay, right?
I'll just see you later at the diner.
- Okay, I'll see you then.
- Okay.
Ethan, this is Celina again.
We need to go over your statement before tomorrow.
What you say to the judge might very well have
a direct effect on your sentencing.
♪ There is a light ♪
♪ That never goes out ♪
♪ Though dark and deep ♪
♪ Buried by the night ♪
♪ There is a smile ♪
♪ A never-ending hope ♪
♪ Though broken down ♪
♪ Lost on the road ♪
♪ And now you left my side ♪
♪ It makes me wonder why ♪
♪ Why I'm alive ♪
♪ Shine, shine bright ♪
♪ Light of my life ♪
♪ Everything I got to give ♪
♪ I give it all to you ♪
♪ Every tear out of your eyes ♪
♪ I would cry for you ♪
♪ I'd die for you ♪
♪ Won't you let me? ♪
♪ Swing higher now ♪
♪ Child of mine ♪
♪ Fly to the clouds ♪
♪ Higher than high ♪
♪ Our shoes are tied ♪
♪ Let's go for a ride ♪
♪ The wind in our hair ♪
♪ Enfolds sunlight ♪
♪ And the frozen world ♪
♪ Will all be left behind ♪
♪ My treasure, it's a treasure hunt ♪
♪ Let's see what we can find ♪
♪ Playing hide and seek ♪
♪ And swimming in the creek ♪
♪ Well, my brother and son ♪
♪ It's the world we're hiding from ♪
♪ So shine ♪
♪ Shine bright ♪
♪ Light of my life ♪
♪ Every tear out of your eyes ♪
♪ I will dry for you ♪
♪ I'd die for you ♪
♪ Won't you let me ♪
♪ Drift ♪
♪ Drift away ♪
♪ With you? ♪