Five,
six,
seven.
Listen, stay away, stay away,
let's get out of the round.
Just stay away.
Jake. Jake!
Jake!
That's it, punch him.
Come on.
One, two, three,
four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten.
He's out.
- You look like you got your ass kicked.
- That's an early birthday present.
Oh, yeah? So when you started crying,
was that part of the present?
Son of a bitch.
Started crying? I would never cry.
He was down for eight, crawled back up.
I felt so sorry for him, I took a nap.
Hey, Jake.
Jake!
- You do the work on H-2?
- Yeah.
Well, your cross-weld seams got bubbles.
- They looked fine.
- Do 'em over.
Jake, there's some guy from the Naval
Academy out there looking for you.
- That's funny.
- I'm serious, man.
He's out there looking for you right now.
- He say what he wanted?
- No.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm Jake Huard.
Lieutenant Commander Burton,
United States Naval Academy.
Your application
made for some interesting reading.
- Thank you.
- I kept going over it,
to figure out why a congressman
would give a nomination
to someone with
such mediocre grades and test scores.
- He didn't want to give it to me at first.
- That's what he told me.
He also said you were
the biggest pain in the ass he'd ever met.
- I had to go back a couple times.
- How many?
34 straight days, sir.
We've had some spots open up
in this year's class.
Couple kids decided last minute
they'd rather have fun at college.
Induction day is tomorrow.
I'm gonna be honest with you.
This is not an ideal situation.
You'll be way behind the other students.
They've had months to prepare.
That's all right, sir.
- Well, then, congratulations.
- Thank you, sir.
I'll see you tomorrow at 0630.
I don't get it. I mean, I don't know
why you want to go to that place so bad.
I mean, we're rivets. We build ships.
Can you remember when my mom
used to take us there when we were kids?
Yeah, and we all wanted
to wear the uniform and be the hero.
But we were little kids then, Jake.
- Well, I never stopped wanting that.
- So, this place isn't good enough for you?
No, that's not it.
I just don't want to build ships.
And what happens if that doesn't work out?
It's gonna work out.
I mean, I got dreams too, man.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Like going to Sir Frankie's tonight
and getting shitfaced.
Tonight's your night.
We got plenty of room over at the VIP table
if you guys wanna join us.
All right, Romeo.
These girls are all over your Navy buddies,
man. Look at this place.
- Oh, yes.
- Al right.
- To Jake.
To Jake.
Listen, guys. You're my best friends
for as long as I can remember.
That's why I gotta get outta here. If I can't
find better guys than you, I'm in trouble.
See you at Christmas.
Be good.
Yo, wait up.
Look at her. You see the girl over there
with the long black hair?
Yeah.
Couple of us chipped in.
- What, she's a hooker?
- No, she's not a hooker.
She's an escort.
Get outta here.
Look, I swear on my mother.
OK? Just go talk to her.
She ain't gonna bite you.
That cost too much.
Hi.
I'm Jake.
Ali.
So, look... This is probably, like,
business as usual for you,
but I've never
done anything like this before.
Uh...
Look, so you can just keep the money, I...
What are you talking about?
I swear on my mother.
- You're not a prostitute.
- Uh, no, I...
I am.
But I'm really late
for my next appointment, so...
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
I'm sorry. OK?
They did say you were really expensive.
Why did you think your friends
were trying to get you a prostitute, Jake?
You trying to lose your virginity?
Uh, actually...
You were supposed to be
my going-away present.
I'm going to the Naval Academy tomorrow.
- You are?
- Yeah.
It's a fairly rigorous selection process.
Yeah, I know that. I've heard.
Well, if you're interested, maybe
we could get together. I'll give you a tour.
You know, I would love that.
I'm... kinda feeling a connection here.
- You are?
- Yeah.
I mean, with me
so close to going to war, and...
You're going to the academy.
Well, yeah.
I think we should ask ourselves:
Can we afford to pass up
what is possibly our one night together?
- I'm gonna do something about it.
- Is that right?
- I... Just think about that.
- AJ, chill.
All right, all right, all right. AJ. AJ!
What? I'm just saying hi
to your new friends.
OK. All right.
You all set?
You sure this is what you want to do?
You're close to getting your hours.
I don't want to join the union, Dad.
Well, tell me.
What the hell is it you do want?
I mean, come on, Jake.
Who we kidding?
You don't listen to me or anybody here,
and you're gonna take orders from them?
I'm sorry
I didn't give you two weeks' notice.
Jake, Jake.
I'll give you a ride.
I'll see you at Christmas.
- Go get 'em, son.
- I love you, Mom.
All right, smile, now.
20 months ago.
50.000 young men and women
inquired about applying to this academy.
But this morning. Only 1207 of you
passed through these gates.
Some of you have
only known success your entire life.
But this year. Your plebe year.
You will know failure.
Welcome to the academy.
Because failure
is a far greater teacher than success.
Our standards
are both high and uncompromising.
Some of you will fail to meet them.
We make no apology for that
because the mission
we have been entrusted with,
transforming you
from civilians into naval officers,
is too important.
Left. Left. Left, right, left...
- Lock those elbows, Nance.
- Ma'am, aye aye, ma'am!
Come on, move it, meatheads, run!
Go, go, go!
Keep that rifle up.
You look surprised, Plebe Huard.
Ma'am, yes, ma'am.
How many buildings at the academy
are named for admirals?
- Ma'am, I'll find out, ma'am.
- That's one of your rates.
You're required to know that information.
Especially if you're gonna be offering tours.
Ma'am, yes, ma'am.
- Now drop and gimme 20.
- Aye aye, ma'am.
What is that smell?
- Is that you, Estrada?
- Sir, no, sir.
You been taking Puerto Rican showers
instead of regular ones?
- That what you're doing?
- Sir, no, sir!
You stink.
How about your beard?
Plebes are supposed to be clean-shaven.
Sir, I shaved this morning, sir.
I just have a thick beard, sir.
I want you to shower and shave
every three hours after lights out.
And no more cologne.
Do you understand, Estrada?
Sir, yes, sir!
At ease.
Attention on deck.
Midshipman Lieutenant Cole.
Get in.
Sir, aye aye, sir.
- Zip it up.
- Sir, aye aye, sir.
I want you all to remember
what that bag looks like with a body in it,
'cause if you become officers, this is where
they're gonna put your mistakes.
- Do you understand me?
- Sir, yes, sir.
All of you came straight here
from high school.
But not me.
Before I got here,
I served three years in the Marines.
Which means I'm more than
just a senior at this academy.
I am someone who knows
exactly what it takes to become an officer.
And I will accept nothing less from you.
If that's not what you signed up for,
there's nothing wrong with that.
Just let me know now.
Just raise your hand.
All right.
Let's go for a little jog.
Go!
Go, go.
Move it!
Come on, Huard.
Let's go.
Risa, what are you doing?
Come on, let's go.
Move it. Oh, God...
Come on, let's go, let's go.
Faster, come on.
Let's go, let's go. Move it.
Come on, let's go. Move it, move it.
Yo, move it, move it.
You letting this girl beat you, Nance?
Move it, go.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
- Come on, Loo.
- Don't let him beat you, Loo.
Don't let him beat you.
- Come on, Huard.
- Come on, Loo, move those feet.
Move those feet!
Run it out, Huard, run it out.
- Good job, Loo. You too, Huard.
- Let's go, Estrada.
- Come on, Risa.
- Estrada, move. Move!
Finish line's right here.
Run. Keep doing it.
Come on, just a little further.
- Let's go, Echo Company.
- Run it out, guys, run it out.
That's right, come on.
You're almost there.
Let's go now.
All right, a little bit more.
Good job.
- What's the problem here?
- Sir, I'm trying, sir.
- Stop trying and do it.
- Aye aye, sir.
Come on, you butterball, move it.
Move it.
There's a big juicy steak
waiting for you, and yams.
Holy shit! You are pathetic.
You're the only one
who can't make it up this thing.
From now on,
I'm gonna start calling you Twins.
You know why, Twins?
Because I'm carrying the weight
of two human beings, sir.
You're smart, too.
So you should be able to figure out
that if you don't get your fat ass
up this climb by the end of this year,
your fat ass is gonna be separated.
What the hell are you doing?
Just reminding myself
of what I'm fighting for.
Hey, Huard.
Don't worry. That book's
gonna be all in your head soon.
Yeah, I hope.
You should learn to make your bed first.
What?
Fold's gotta be 12 inches from the top.
Loo.
Nance.
What the hell? We only been here a week.
- Estrada.
- Nice!
Oh, this is from that chick
that I met at the shore this summer.
Ho ho!
Sorry, Carmen.
Before you achieve,
you must believe.
Before you achieve, you must believe.
Hey. Doctor Phil.
Shut your hole.
20.
54º, 85' north.
15.
166º, 10' west.
- Let me help you.
- 10.
I got it.
- There's a headwind here...
- I got it.
40º, 80' north.
Five.
Come on, Jake.
Time.
Drill's over, Huard.
Next squad, you're up.
Make me a believer.
One, two, three, four...
Mike Tyson once said,
"Everybody's got a plan until they get hit."
You can say what you want about Tyson,
but that's the smartest goddamn thing
I ever heard anybody say about boxing.
Centre that weight.
You got no balance, I'd push you right over.
Aye aye, sir.
That is why we teach boxing here.
You see, the powers that be
want to see how you react
when you get popped in that mouth.
They want to see how you hold up
when your little plan goes to hell.
Get that chin down.
Want to get knocked out?
In 40 seconds
you're on the focus mitts with me.
Pretty good, Huard. You boxed before?
- A little bit.
- Yeah, you can tell.
Jab's good, straight right's pretty crisp.
Yeah. You hook like a girl, though.
I hook like a girl?
- Hey, Loo.
- Hey.
- You finished your calc homework yet?
- Ah, jeez...
- I just wanna check my answers.
- Nice try, Estrada.
- I didn't get a chance to finish mine.
- Look, I made the time.
- It's just a homework assignment.
- Sorry, man.
You know how you're gonna die, Loo?
Friendly fire.
- I'll help you.
- No offence, but I wanna pass, Huard.
What is this?
Restricted diet means no pogey bait,
Twins!
Shove off.
You do understand what "shove off"
means, don't you, Huard?
Oh, I forgot. You're a wait lister.
Well.
Since you're here, why don't you
clean up your shipmate's mess?
Psst.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
What are you looking at? Porn?
It's not porn.
- Was that parade for you?
- I'm from kind of a small town,
so me getting in here was a big deal.
I hadn't even decided to come when I
found out they were throwing me a parade.
No wonder you get mail every day.
There've only been two times in my life
my father ever told me he was proud of me.
Fourth grade, I knocked out this bully
who'd been picking on me.
And the day I received
my acceptance here.
Hey, you guys looking at porn?
Yeah.
Someone explain why I can't hook up with
those girls until after my plebe year?
Hook up?
Oh, man, we can't even kiss 'em.
I'd explain it.
By giving your calc score today.
Hey, hey. I got 57. That's an F+.
- Huard got a G.
- Oh, man.
All right, all right.
Hey, relax, Huard. I'm just playing.
Hey, Huard. You gotta use more polish.
That's never gonna pass.
Worry about your own, Marianne.
I'll worry about mine.
You just don't get it, do you, Huard?
We're all tied together here.
- I don't need your help, Loo.
- Yeah, you do.
Hey, I know we're four guys in a shower,
but can we keep
the testosterone to a minimum?
Hey, Jake.
Help is like sex.
Take it from whoever
and whenever you can get it.
Nance, how's the cow?
Ma'am, she walks, she talks,
she's full of chalk.
The lactic fluid extracted from the female of
the bovine species is highly prolific to the...
fifth degree, ma'am.
- Good job, Nance. Serve yourself.
- Ma'am, thank you, ma'am.
I'll give you an easy one, rivet.
The Triton Light
has water from how many different seas?
- Sir, eight, sir.
- Are you sure?
'Cause you look
like you're guessing, Huard.
Sir, I'm sure, sir.
So you wouldn't have a problem
betting your companymates' dinner
on your answer?
Sir, no, sir.
What about their lives?
You said you were sure about the answer.
Well, if you're sure,
stakes shouldn't matter.
Loo. The Triton Light
has water from how many different seas?
Sir, seven, sir.
You just killed
everyone in your company, Huard.
Everyone scrape your plates
back onto the platter.
The worst officer is someone who guesses.
Someone who's too afraid to admit
that they don't know the right answer.
Those are the officers
who get people killed.
You bet everyone's meal, Huard.
Enjoy.
Sir, the uniform for noon meal formation
is Working Blues. Stripers carry swords.
The menu for the noon meal
is baked chicken, roast beef,
mashed potatoes, vegetables,
cannonballs and hard sauce.
You now have ten minutes, sir.
You don't stink so bad, Estrada.
- You been taking your showers?
- Sir, yes, sir!
All right, Estrada.
You can terminate Operation Disinfect.
Sir, aye aye, sir!
Carry on.
Finally, a goddamn night of sleep. Oorah!
Estrada, we need to talk.
- You mean talk, or talk talk?
- You lied to Whitaker.
- What the hell are you talking about?
- You didn't take a shower last night.
So what?
Look, man, I been taking those goddamn
showers every night for the past six weeks.
- So what if I missed one?
- You gotta turn yourself in.
Why?
'Cause Whitaker's a racist prick?
No, man.
I shouldn't have had to take those showers.
It's not the showers.
It's the first thing we learnt.
- Midshipmen are persons of integrity.
- Get off your soapbox, Loo!
Loo, it's a shower.
We can take care of this.
- You think I want to do this?
- Eat me, poster boy.
- Just tell the truth.
- Attention on deck!
- Is this room ready for inspection?
- Sir, yes, sir!
Sir, I need to speak to you, sir.
Loo.
You mother...
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey! Loo. Loo.
Estrada, outside. Now.
- Come on, Huard.
- Let's go, Risa. You can do this.
We're gonna drown because of you, Risa.
You're crying?
Your ship is sinking and you're crying?
You're the reason
they say women don't belong here, Risa.
It's girls like you who give us a bad name.
- She gets the point, ma'am.
- What was that?
Ma'am, I said
I think she gets the point, ma'am.
Risa, out of the tank.
You got a problem with the way
this company's being run, Huard?
Sir, no, sir.
You've got enough problems of your own
without worrying about Risa's.
You want to hit me, Huard?
- Go ahead.
- Cole, this is my drill. I'll handle it.
All right, gentlemen. That's enough.
Nice work, there, Cole.
Nice work. I like that.
So you all think you're Rocky Marciano
'cause you can tag your roommate
with a weak-ass right.
So I had your commanding officer
come in here today
to show you what real boxing is about,
'cause if you make Brigades
next semester,
that right there
is what you'll be looking at.
Midshipman Cole
looks like he can go another round.
- What do you say, Midshipman?
- Let's do it.
Uh-oh.
Anybody want to come in here with him?
Huh?
I hope you're this quiet
when you're sneaking up on the enemy.
Loo.
Loo. How about you?
You and your mouth were Golden Gloves
champ at 185 in San Diego.
Come on, champ.
Sir, I would, sir, but I don't want
to give away my secrets until the Brigades.
Pussy.
Come on.
This man has been making your life
miserable for the last two months.
It's your chance for a little payback.
Anybody gonna come in here with him?
I'll do it.
- You're not in his weight class, Huard.
- I'll wear an extra T-shirt.
You're not in his class class, either.
- Come on, son.
- All right, yeah!
All right, Jake. You can do it.
You can do it, Jake.
- Sure you want to do this, Huard?
- Yes, sir.
All right, gentlemen. Let's box.
All right, all right. It's a slip.
It's OK. It's OK, Jake.
It's OK, Jake.
Let's box.
This ain't one of them smokers
from the shipyard, Huard.
All right. You all right, son?
Let's go.
Come on, man.
Stay in there. Stay in there, Jake.
All right, all right, that's it.
That's it. That's it.
Hope you didn't bet
anybody's meal on this.
All right, that's it.
Get his gloves off.
Boy's got heart, which is more
than I can say for all of y'all. But heart...
What the hell are you doing?
- Let him go.
- Show some discipline.
- Get out of the ring.
Set an example for these plebes.
Settle down. Now!
Get your gear off.
All right.
147 to go.
- When are you taking off?
- I'm not.
I gotta stay
and work on my time for the O-course.
And, to be honest, I'm afraid
if I walk out of here, I won't come back.
So, you have a good Christmas.
I'll see you after leave.
Hey, Huard?
I said, I'll see you after leave.
Sir, yes, sir.
Hey, how are you?
Hey, it's Popeye the Sailor Man.
Easy, easy, easy...
- Cheers!
- To Jake.
- It's great to have you back.
- That's right.
You say they kicked some guy out
for not taking a shower?
Yeah. Yeah, they threw a couple out
for hooking up with girls, too.
That sounds like bullshit to me, man.
I don't know why you put up with that crap.
Well, it's not a job. It's an adventure.
I'll drink to that.
I'll drink to you drinking to that.
Hey.
The fight's about to start. You hungry?
- No, thanks.
- You sure?
So AJ said you guys
are a couple weeks behind.
- Yeah, a little.
- I was wondering if you could use me.
Well, I don't have any short time stuff.
Yeah, well, I wasn't really
thinking about short time stuff.
Are you sure this is what you want?
OK.
I'll talk to Mike tomorrow.
See what we can work out.
Thanks.
Should be a good fight.
So I told Mike you would meet him
over at Sir Frankie's at five.
Ah, that's all right.
I think I'm just gonna go home.
What?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing. I'm just tired.
So how much did you collect?
It's just for shits and giggles, man.
How much?
A little over 500.
What's up?
AJ leave early or something?
You all right?
What kind of father
wants his own son to fail?
- What are you talking about?
- You gave me my job back.
- You asked for it back.
- And you said yes.
- This is a good thing here.
- Yeah, not for me.
You knew how bad I wanted to go
to the academy. You never said anything.
Why? Would it kill you
that I might actually do better than you?
You want the truth? I didn't want you to go
over there because I knew this'd happen.
You'd be back here,
pissed off 'cause you didn't make it.
Look, Jake, I know you promised
your mother that you'd go to the academy.
And you tried, but it just didn't work out.
Yeah. Maybe it would have
if she was the one who was still around.
Look, I know I haven't been the best father.
And you can blame me for a lot of things,
but this ain't one of them,
'cause when it's all said and done,
I didn't quit. You did, Jake.
- What are you doing here?
- You know, just scoping out johns.
You want a beer?
Nah.
How's your leave been?
It's been a blast. How's yours?
OK.
You looking forward to heading back?
Come on.
I thought you were gonna dance with me.
I'm sorry. Do you mind if I cut in?
This is nice.
I don't think I've danced since high school.
- No spring dances at the academy?
- No.
Uh-uh. Never gone.
Yeah, you can tell.
Really? Says the guy
who keep stepping on my foot.
Ow!
Sorry.
Why don't you go to the dances?
Some guys at the academy
don't view women as their equals.
It's worse if you start dating them.
It's no fun being underestimated, is it?
It's worse when you do it to yourself.
Excuse me.
I will see you tomorrow, Plebe Huard.
Watch your feet.
- Delta Company.
- Sir.
One missing and unaccounted for.
Midshipman Fourth Class Butcher.
- Echo Company.
- Sir, two missing and unaccounted for.
Midshipman Fourth Class Casarico,
Midshipman Fourth Class Huard.
Ma'am, Midshipman Fourth Class Huard
is present and accounted for, ma'am.
- In case you forgot, we wear uniform here.
- Sir, yes, sir.
- Put yourself on report.
- Sir, aye aye, sir.
- Memorial Hall in ten, Huard.
Dead at 23.
The best officer I ever served under.
I'm sorry about your friend, sir.
Why? He's not.
Why are you here, Huard?
To serve my country, sir.
You say that here...
where people actually died
for their country.
You don't think I took Psych 101?
You're here to answer the question
that's gnawed at you
ever since you saw this place
from across the river.
Well, let me spare you the suspense.
You ain't good enough.
I've heard that my whole life.
But I'm still here.
All the other company commanders here,
they're playing soldier.
But I've been a soldier, Huard.
I've seen what good officers are like.
And I know what bad officers are like.
So there ain't no way
I'm letting someone finish this year
who's not worthy of this academy.
I'm not quitting.
Wakey wakey!
Come on, Loo. Move, butterball!
Plebe Huard.
How many missiles are the Ohio class
of ballistic missile submarines
capable of carrying?
Sir, I'll find out, sir.
Who was the youngest midshipman,
and how old was he?
Sir, I'll find out, sir.
I'm sure you will, Huard.
Keep filling.
Stop.
Congratulations, Loo.
You can join Huard
on marching tours this weekend.
Carry on.
Understand this.
When Plebe Huard
doesn't know his rates, none of you do.
A company is only as strong
as its weakest plebe.
You should get out too, Nance.
He's just gonna drag you down.
He's right, you know.
Can I borrow your starch?
Look, I don't get it.
Why are you still here?
- You want to know why I stay in this room?
- Yeah.
'Cause, Jake, you're my Mississippi.
I'm your what?
People who live in Arkansas,
you know what their favorite state is?
No.
Mississippi. 'Cause Mississippi's
the only thing that keeps Arkansas
from being the worst state
in the whole country.
- I'm Mississippi.
- Well, you sure as hell ain't California.
Listen, Cole and Whitaker
are so busy trying to run you out
they forgot all about me.
As a matter of fact, they've forgotten about
every other plebe in this whole company.
That's why I stay in this room, Jake.
'Cause if Mississippi quits,
then all of a sudden Arkansas
is the worst state in the whole country.
Hey, where's my starch?
- All right.
- Come on, chop chop.
You're looking good, Huard.
Pretty soon you'll be able
to keep up with my six-year-old daughter.
When can I start boxing again, sir?
When I make admiral.
You knew better than to pull
that mess you pulled in my ring, son.
Eyes on the ring.
Brigades Tournament
begins in eight weeks.
Training starts this Friday.
Brigades is the biggest event
in this academy all year. You know why?
Because the boxing ring is the only place
in this academy where everybody's equal.
Doesn't matter what your rank is,
how many stripes you got,
the only thing that is guaranteed
when you step inside these ropes:
You're gonna find out who you are.
This doesn't look like your room.
What are you doing here, Huard?
I'm training for the Brigades, sir.
All right, Huard.
Let's see how you're doing.
Sir?
Show me how
you're gonna win the Brigades.
Ding ding.
Don't worry, Huard.
I'm not your company officer in here.
I'm just a guy
looking to punch you in the mouth.
Well, you can take a punch.
I guess we knew that already, didn't we?
You can actually land a punch, too.
- You're pretty good, Huard.
- Thanks.
Against a 36-year-old
out-of-shape lieutenant.
Not bad, Huard.
You know, most of the boxers in the
Brigades are nationally ranked amateurs.
Think you're gonna beat 'em
by hitting the bag for a couple hours?
I'll do what I have to.
Really? Without anyone training you?
You think you're gonna be the first plebe
to get through here without anyone's help?
I don't need anyone's help.
No one thinks I'll make it anyway.
Who do you think convinced the board
to take a chance on you?
This ain't the shipyard, Huard. You can't
just will yourself through this place.
Sorry. I'll be done in a minute.
Here. Recent studies show that auditory
retention surpasses that of visual retention.
OK.
OK. Turn off the light
so I can get some sleep.
What is the latitude of Annapolis?
The latitude of Annapolis is 38.58º north.
Thanks.
- Ma'am.
- Plebe Huard.
- Everything OK?
- Yes, ma'am.
You know I'm training for the Brigades.
That's great, Huard. Good luck.
Maybe we could work out together.
Uh, no. I think I'm already
in pretty good shape, thanks.
Ma'am.
I need your help.
What? Think you're gonna be
all alone in that ring?
Come on. Come on.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
- Damn it.
Before you achieve, you must believe.
Let's go, Arkansas.
Come on, Huard.
I've seen better footwork at Payless.
Come on, get back in there.
Better footwork at Payless?
- Jake.
- What?
You're trying to get into
Cole's weight class, right?
Yeah.
What's this?
Well, you're not gonna get there
by just eating the stuff they serve you here.
What you need, my friend, is the patented
Marcus Nance North Beach Diet,
which, I'm proud to say,
has been perfected
after 18 years of dedicated research.
- So you're gonna get me to 185?
- Hey.
I'm not only the president
of the Marcus Nance North Beach Diet,
I'm also a client.
Come on, get down in the mud.
Come on. Come on, buddy.
Up, up. Over, over.
Go, Arkansas. Come on.
Let me see you run.
How long have you been
in the Navy? All my bloomin' life.
Just hook it over and we're done.
Hook it over and we're done. Here we go.
What happened to all my ball machines?
- Come on, Huard. Dance for me.
- Hit me once and you can talk like that.
- I have. I think I hit you about five times.
- Ooh!
Make that six, Huard.
Three. That's three. Gimme one more.
That was for momma.
Gimme one for daddy. Get up there.
How bad do you want it?
Not quite there, huh?
Come on. How bad do you want it?
OK, that's good. Stop.
I never could have done it.
What?
Made it through plebe year
if I could see my home every day.
Well, if I couldn't see it every day,
I probably would have quit a long time ago.
You know, my mom
used to take me out here.
We had a Sunfish.
We'd park it down there.
She was the only person
who ever believed I'd make it here.
She must be very proud of you.
She would be.
I'm sorry.
She's what's getting you through?
Well... She's what got me here.
But she's not the one
who's getting me through.
Matt Cole, 197.
All right, Midshipman. You step down.
Anybody else for heavyweight?
- All right, I guess that's it, then.
- One more heavyweight.
- Huard, what are you doing?
- Weighing in.
Jump rope contest is next week.
My daughter's looking forward to it.
- Anybody else?
- Sir.
You said the Brigades
were open to all midshipmen.
I want to fight.
Fine. I'm gonna draw up a permission slip
for your parents to sign. Hit the scales.
Jake Huard, 185.
Next up, heavyweight division:
Midshipman Loo
versus Midshipman Huard.
- Let's go.
- Loo! Loo! Loo! Loo!
You both received your instructions
in the dressing rooms.
I want you to keep it clean.
Any questions?
Payback's a bitch, Huard.
You set the pace out there, Huard.
Come on, Jake. One more.
Hmm? Come on, hit me one time.
One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten.
You're out.
What is the latitude of Annapolis?
- Who were the first three admirals?
- How long have you been in the Navy?
Sir, the latitude of Annapolis
is 38.58º north.
Sir, the first three admirals
were Dewey, Porter and Farragut.
Sir, I've been in the Navy
all my bloomin' life, sir.
My mother's a mermaid,
my father's King Neptune.
Every bone in my body is a spar.
And when I spits, I spits tar.
I's hard, I is, I am, I are.
All right. Everybody on your feet.
Everyone but Huard is dismissed.
How about some more up-downs, Huard?
What? I'm a plebe. I love rolling
on the ground and freezing my ass off.
Y'all trying to make me proud
out here tonight, huh?
- Oorah!
Good. Time.
- Nicely done, Huard.
- Thank you.
Good job. Your left hook's getting there.
- It's getting there?
- Mm-hm.
- But it's not there yet?
- Not yet.
- Really?
- Almost.
- Why don't you show me? There.
- OK.
- Not bad.
- All right.
- Show me how to...
- It's just... the little things.
Like, really get your weight behind it.
You know what I mean?
Ooh! I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry.
Oh...
- Jeez.
- Let me see. No, it's OK. I'm sorry.
- Is it bleeding?
- Uh-uh.
- Huh?
- Mm-mm.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
- I'm OK.
- No, I mean about...
About stopping.
Oh.
Well, why are you sorry?
I was the one who stopped.
What did you say?
It was getting a little hot.
I had to push you away.
You know what? I think I hit you
over the head a little too hard there, Jake.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten.
You're out!
You OK?
Nice smile, Huard.
Can't wait to see
what Cole does to it in the finals.
Good fight.
No way.
It's impressive, to be able to say
you helped build something like this.
Take ten.
Hey.
The ship looks great.
Yeah, it might float.
So, I know you're probably busy, but...
I have a fight next week. Saturday.
It's the finals in the Brigades.
It's for the whole academy.
We're still a little behind.
Yeah. I get it.
All right.
I guess I'll see you soon.
Yeah, sure.
- Take care of yourself.
- All right. You too.
The required time for plebes
is five minutes.
Failure to meet that requirement
will result in separation.
There will be no retest.
Good luck.
Keep going.
This is nothing.
You're there. You're there.
Put it over. Put it over.
Hook it over.
Come on. You got it.
Come on, duck down. You got it.
Come on, that's it. Let's go. Let's go.
That's it. You got it.
Come on, Twins.
Show Whitaker. Show him. Let's go.
Yeah! That's it.
Last one. Last one.
- Nice! Good job, Nance.
- Good job, man.
Nance.
5:04. You're four seconds over.
Sir, give him another chance.
He can make it.
5:04 is 5:04.
It's four seconds.
You know how far he's come?
Hey.
They gave me the key to the city.
You know that?
You think I have to give it back?
Hey, this isn't over.
We can talk to Burton.
Remember how I told you about
that bully I beat up in the fourth grade?
Mm-hm.
Truth is, he tripped when he hit me
and knocked himself out on the pavement.
Next day, he kicked the crap outta me
till I cried like a baby...
All right, come on, Arkansas.
You can't do this to yourself.
I let 'em down.
I let my parents down...
You didn't let anyone down. We're gonna
work this out. It's gonna be fine...
Just stop it, Jake! OK?
It's over.
I don't belong here, OK?
You belong here.
I just need some time alone, all right?
OK.
All right.
Switch.
Thanks.
You're ready, man.
Somebody jumped.
He's still breathing.
Go get some help.
Jake! Get him off. Get him off!
Get off, Jake. Get up.
- You did this!
- Jake, take it easy.
- You happy?
- Cool off. Cool off, Jake, come on.
Take it easy. Just take it easy.
It's not worth it, man.
Cool off, man. You gotta cool off.
So you're quitting?
What about your review board?
I hit my superior officer.
We both know how it's gonna end.
I asked for more time
to prepare my statement for the board.
Your appearance
has been moved to Monday.
After the Brigade finals.
I'm giving you
what you wanted all year, Huard.
Hey.
Doctor says you're gonna be all right.
Jake.
Yeah?
What time's the fight?
There are more important things
than the fight right now.
Listen, Jake. We're both lucky.
We got second chances.
I'm not gonna waste mine.
Neither are you.
When you step in that ring,
you have three rounds
to find out who you are.
Show 'em who you are, Mississippi.
Hey, rivet!
Don't let me down. I got money on you.
OK. Here we go.
Good luck.
Here we go.
OK. Fighters to the centre.
OK, gentlemen. You received
my instructions in the dressing room.
Obey my commands. Touch gloves.
Come on, Jake!
- All right, let's go, Huard.
- Come on, Jake.
Wreck this guy, Cole.
Watch that jab.
Come on, Huard. Step around.
This kid Cole is probably
my best recruit in the last ten years.
Playtime's over.
- He's gotta pace himself.
- Attack him!
- That's it.
- He's gotta slow it down.
Here we go. Yes!
Put him down. Put him down!
- That's right.
- Oh, my God.
Where's your smile now,
Huard?
One, two, three...
- Take the count.
...four...
- Get up, Jake.
...five, six, seven, eight.
Attaboy, Jake.
Box.
Here we go, baby.
Stick and move. Stick and move.
Put him down. Put him down.
Stay off the ropes, Huard.
Break. Break, break, break.
Defense, Jake. Hands up.
Get outta that corner.
Get outta the corner!
Break. Break!
All right. Take a deep breath.
Relax. You OK?
Relax, you got this. OK, come on.
Remember,
you're boxing in there, not brawling.
Look at me, Jake. Look at me.
I want you to watch him, OK?
Keep your hands up.
Make him come to you.
You hear that?
You are dominating this fight.
You're the champ, OK? Two more rounds,
baby. Finish off this prick.
- All right? Do not charge him.
- Let's go, Jake.
Come on, Jake. Come on, let's go.
Box.
Be patient. Just let him come to you.
Here we go.
- Put him down.
- Stay off the ropes, Jake. Come on.
How's your man Huard doing,
Lieutenant?
Come on, Cole.
Come on, Huard. Let's go.
Move in on him, Jakey.
- Yeah, Huard.
- No, no, attack him.
- Get off the ropes.
- Yeah.
Watch it. Watch out, Jake,
you're leaving yourself open.
- Hands up. Hands up!
- Careful.
Touch gloves.
- You've got this.
- Go, Cole. He's got nothing left.
Let's go, Jake.
That's it, Jake.
Make him come to you.
- Nice. Nice!
- Nice, Jake!
- Cole, get outta there.
- Go! Yes!
- Yeah! Stay down.
- Yeah, Jake!
- One, two...
- Get up, man.
You're the champ. Come on.
...five, six, seven, eight.
- He wants some more!
Box.
There you go! Step around.
Here we go.
You got him, Jake. This is your time.
- Cole! Come on!
- Yes!
What the hell are you doing?
- Come on, Huard.
- Work him. He's going down.
Just work the body.
Let's go. 30 seconds.
Go for it.
Come on, Jake.
He's getting tired, Jake.
You've gotta go for it. Go for it.
20 seconds, Huard.
Come on, Huard. Yeah!
Keep your rhythm. Keep your rhythm.
Get outta the corner.
Ten seconds, Jake.
You gotta take him out now.
Come on, Huard.
- Go after him, Jake.
- Go, go, go!
Break. Break.
Great fight, Jake.
Yeah, that kid Huard's a tough kid.
- Go on, Jake!
- That's my boy right there.
That's my boy.
OK. Fighters to the centre.
Fighters to the centre. Let's go.
- Out the way.
- Let me get a shot.
Sorry, man.
I told you. Hell of a fight.
Yeah, number one, baby.
Yeah, number one.
You did great.
- Good job, man.
- Good job, Huard.
- Good job, Jake. Good fight.
Midshipman Huard, please stand.
Mr. Huard, this review board
finds you guilty of insubordination.
Sir, yes, sir.
However, based on the recommendation
of your company commander,
this board has decided to retain you.
Your punishment
will be 95 days' restriction and 95 demerits.
Punishment will commence immediately
upon your return from summer cruise.
Is that understood?
Sir, yes, sir.
Congratulations, Midshipman Huard.
Thank you, sir.
Class of 2008.
Congratulations.
You just completed your plebe year.
Plebes no more!
Your summer leave starts...
Now!
Three more years, man.
I'll see you, man.
- Congratulations, Jake.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Any plans before your summer cruise?
- Uh, yeah.
I think I might go over to Sir Frankie's
and see if there are any escorts around.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Save your money.
- Plebes no more.
- I'll see you at Sir Frankie's.
- You got it.
Sir.
I want to thank you.
- For what?
- For helping me with the review board.
It wasn't about you, Huard.
That was about this academy.
Good luck out there.
Sir.
What do you think would have happened
if that fight went another round?
You really want to find out?
Come join me in the Marines.