Hi, Noah.
Hello, Anna. How are you doing?
Fightin' 'em off, Noah.
Fightin' 'em off.
Somebody threw a rock
through Uncle Ben's window
and pinched a pair of binoculars.
Any comments?
I came across the bridge.
I have nothing
against Uncle Ben.
It's too dark to pitch rocks.
That's the one thing
I need, binoculars.
And cops are not
my favorite people.
Take it easy.
That's the talk, Anna.
Hi, blanche, why don't you give
the man back his binoculars?
Of all the back-handed remarks.
That's what I'm always telling
you about her, eddy.
You never know where
you stand with her.
He knows where he stands.
Both of you
better watch your step
if you want to stand
in good with me.
Where is everyone tonight?
The streets are like graveyards,
houses like tombstones.
Everything's
slowed down to a stop.
When your train is
going too fast,
God puts the brakes on
to give you a chance to think.
I don't want to think,
I want to drink.
Do it again.
You ain't paid for
the first one, baby.
Ain't my credit good?
With me, sure.
But I've got
the landlord to think of.
Take out for the first one,
Noah, and leave the bottle.
I'm choosey who I drink with.
Some people have
absolutely no manners.
I'll take a rum cola, Noah.
Let her have it, Noah.
Thanks, eddy.
But drink it right here
at the bar.
Oh, don't let
me spoil the party.
This is for the party.
Such a mercenary atmosphere..
How about a little conversation?
Converse.
How you been?
It worries you, huh?
Yeah, I've been
thinking about you.
You know, I've been watching
you for over a year now.
How am I doing?
You get along with the fleet, but so far
they haven't named any ships after you.
I don't mix with admirals.
Look, I run
an exclusive place uptown.
We don't cater
to sailors in my place.
Just captains of industry.
I'll dress you up
in the right clothes,
and you'd look natural on the
arm of some tired businessman.
What do I have to do?
Be a hostess.
You can talk plainer than that.
That's all. Like I said, my club is
real exclusive. No rough stuff.
You just sit and drink
with the customers.
Rake-off on every drink.
Of course, you'd have to learn
how to smile a little.
What goes with the smile?
Mingle, like you do down here.
Except you get paid for it.
Get paid for what? So far
you haven't said anything.
Look, I run an exclusive club.
What's different about your
place makes it so exclusive?
For one thing,
the law won't bother you.
You've got it made.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah,
I'm coming up in the world.
Not in mine.
I'd like to remedy that.
What's your prescription,
doctor?
Me.
I'm not all business. I take a little
pleasure myself once in a while.
Now, working in my place, it's only natural
we'd spend a little time together.
I'd rather do time
than spend it with you.
A couple of
years softening up in the can.
You're scaring me
to death, louse.
Now I'm getting mad.
Ow! You rotten little bum!
What'd she do to you, eddy?
Burned me on the neck
with her cigarette.
He almost tore my arm off.
Well, now you know where you
stand with each other.
I'm not wastin' my time
with no waterfront tramps.
Well, excuse me for lmn'!
Not you, but you.
Better change your mind
and stop being so particular.
Someday you may need a pal.
I'd rather pal with rats.
Keep it up, and you will.
Are you gonna stick
around here all night?
Well, you don't have
to get so tough about it.
I'm only going to stay
for a little while.
Gee, my feet are killing me.
You got a smoke?
You know they still sell 'em
in every drugstore.
Yeah, I know.
But I'm cuttin' down on tobacco.
Gives me the heartburn.
Thanks, kid.
Hey, Noah, I'm dyin'
for a drink.
I'm dyin' for a cash customer.
Hey, Noah.
How'd you like to buy
a nice pair of binoculars?
Go ahead and take a look through 'em.
See what you could see.
Without looking through 'em, I can
see from 1 to 10 at hard labor.
Give 'em back to Uncle Ben.
I didn't break that window.
And I didn't steal
no binoculars, either.
I was walkin' down the street,
mindin' my own business,
and there was that
hole in the window
and the binoculars sittin'
right there on the edge.
They fell in my hand.
I found 'em.
Hey, Anna, do you think there's a
reward for findin' lost articles?
I'd sure like to be found.
Yeah.
Gee, you look
a million Miles away.
Get lost, will you? Get lost.
I was only tryin'
to cheer you up.
Stay in the dumps. Who cares?
Hey, where you gonna
sleep tonight?
Why should I tell you?
All right, be huffy.
I don't care where I sleep.
You better go on home, Anna.
I'm locking up.
Here's a couple
of sandwiches for the road.
What about something
to wash 'em down with, Noah?
Here, get yourself
a cup of coffee someplace.
Do you know where
a lady can sleep for 4 bits?
Sell anything today, Frank?
Well, yes and no.
Had a couple of very interesting
prospects, Stanley.
Yeah, but did you
sell anything today?
You know, you have a nasty habit
of reducing everything to money.
That's what money.
Did you take in any?
You make money your God and it'll
plague you like the devil.
I'm plagued with all the junk you
got cluttering up this yard.
Hey, give me a hand with this.
You have absolutely
no imagination.
Can't you see this is a
treasure trove of antiques?
I say it's junk.
Yes, but don't you know when
junk gets old enough,
it becomes antique?
Now you take this little
masterpiece, for instance.
Now I can't leave
this out all night.
Might tempt some honest man
to become a thief.
Hello, darling.
Hi, Stanley.
Did you have a hard day?
You said it. Monday's
always a back-breaker.
I know.
You sit over on the couch.
I'll help you
with your slippers.
Stella,.
Look at that rip.
Every time I raise my arm,
it tears again.
Take it off. I'll sew it up.
Well, you sewed it up yesterday.
I'll patch it from the inside.
You're getting careless
in more ways than one.
How many times have
I told you to wash your hands
after handling that junk?
What for?
Dirt never hurt nobody.
It's healthy.
All that stuff
about dirt and germs
is just a lot of bunk.
Ain't it, Frank?
Hey, ma, hurry up
with the dinner, will you?
I'm starved.
Oh, Frank, special delivery
came for pa today.
I saved the government 15 cents
by bringing it up myself.
When congress hears about this, I'm
sure we're gonna get a tax cut.
I'll take it up to pa.
Why ain't he down here?
It's time to eat.
He's got another
one of his headaches.
Headaches. He's got a hangover.
It's more than that.
He's got some kind of psychosis.
Psychosis, bunk.
He just likes to hit the bottle.
That's not true..
Hey, wait a minute.
Who's that letter from?
Hey... hey, who'd have anything to write
to Joe that was special delivery?
It's from bessemer, Alabama.
Probably one of his old cronies
puttin' the bite on him.
All folks down South think
California's the gold country.
Well, he ain't gonna
get any of my money
to send to those Alabama Hicks.
That's easy, you ain't got none.
You little nickel snatcher.
Look, I got a business, eh.
I put the money I make
back into the enterprise.
Enterprise? Don't make me laugh.
You just use that
not to take a job.
Well, I'll ignore that
unkind remark and tell you
why I wouldn't give the old man
a dime to send to Alabama.
Why? It's the principle
of the thing.
Everyone's got
to make their own way.
That's democracy,
everyone for himself.
That ain't democracy. Democracy is,
"all for all and one for one."
and you're the one.
I was until you had
to go and make it 2.
It ain't
a question of democracy.
It's a question
of pampering people.
Nobody never got
nowhere with pamperin'.
You take us, for instance.
Now where'd we be if we'd
stayed down in Alabama?
Where do you think we are now?
In California.
What's that got us?
I don't know where it got you.
I know where it's gonna get me
as soon as this tight
money situation eases up.
You just try walking out on me.
Ain't that a woman for you?
Always makin'
the thing personal.
Where was I?
Easin' the money situation.
Oh, yeah. The country ain't never
going to balance the budget
as long as they keep
on gmn' stuff away.
Now, you take this here new thing,
this here foreign giveaway program.
Do you think that's right?
Sure that's right
because I heard a guy...
who the hell is telling
this thing, me or you? Me.
That's how much you know.
I heard a guy
talkin' only last night...
now you see? You see?
What's the use?
Trouble with you is,
you listen to too much talk.
Trouble with me is,
I listen to too much you.
Listen, now if you really
want to know
why we shouldn't send money to
those southerners, I'll tell you.
Why, Frank?
Because it's pamperin'.
When they get hungry,
they'll find a way to eat.
And the only way
to eat is to work.
And the only ones who eat without
Workin' is the politicians.
And just as soon as this country
gets back on its feet again,
that's just what I'm
a politician.
And that's when the country
will really be on its butt.
Eh, I sure did marry beneath me.
That's another trouble women.
Hey, ma, when are we gonna eat?
Now.
If you don't get some solid food inside
you, instead of all that candy,
you'll give birth
to a chocolate marshmallow.
Dinner's ready, Joe.
We're waitin' for you.
All right, Theresa. I figured it
was about time. Thank you, Katie.
Did you have a nice nap, honey?
I got a little sleep.
Well, you're
feelin' all right, then..
No, Theresa, I feel terrible.
Every time I try
to read this letter,
the words just
jiggle around like bugs.
Here, you read it for me, Katie.
Of course, Joe.
Are we gonna hold up my
dinner for this mess?
I want everyone to keep quiet
and listen to it
because it's from my old
friend, Otis slocum,
and it's bound to be good.
If he wants our old clothes,
he's out of luck.
We got 'em on.
Shh, let Katie read the letter.
"My dear friend Joe lucasta, I hope you
are fine and rich in California."
here it comes..
"I just sold my farm
because the doctor says.
"I work too hard
and got to take it slow
"and stay off my
feet from here on.
"All my boys and girls got
married, all except Rudolf..
Rudolf's getting painfully
restless for a woman."
tell him to take a cold shower.
Shut up, Stanley..
Read on, Katie.
"Good healthy women
are scarce down around here
"owing to so many
of the young folk"
"leaving this
part of the country."
"So I gave Rudolf
his share of the farm"
"so he can get
himself a good wife"
"when he comes west.
He's bringing $4,000, Joe."
"And I want you to pick him
a good, strong woman,
"clean and God-fearing..
"I know you will do this,
for old times' sake.
"So bless you, Joe, and be
good to my boy Rudolf.
Otis slocum."
what does that farmer think?
You can buy a woman
like you buy a pig?
Sometimes pigs is a better buy.
When are we gonna eat?
I'll bring you
yours in a trough.
$4,000.
That's a whole lot of money for
a jerk to be carryin' around.
Yeah, really too much.
$4,000 is a lot of money.
We need it bad.
Frank, you can't stoop that low.
Well, if he's willing
to pay for a woman
and we get him one,
we ain't cheatin' him, are we?
It's business.
That's what it's like.
Yeah, and I gotta get a whole new
wardrobe after the baby comes.
And we gotta get
a new bed for Stella and me.
I'm tired of nailin' that thing
together in the middle of the night.
This family could
use a second car.
There's a swell Ford
down at the used-car lot
for only $800.
It's convertible, too.
Stop it!
Stop spending Otis slocum's money.
I won't let you.
Well, you ain't got it yet.
Besides you don't have to do nothin'.
We'll do it ourselves.
I said, no!
He just said you don't
have to do nothin'.
If we don't get it,
somebody else will.
What chance has
a dumb son of a gun got
keepin' that kind of money
in this town?
Don't let them do anything.
It's disgusting.
We ought to be able to get some
real nice girl for Rudolf.
All the girls I know
are married or got kids.
There's Irene's sister.
But ever since she went to San Francisco,
she wouldn't look at no farmer.
How about tom's daughter?
What the devil's going on here?
Give me some meat.
He'd pay us to take
her off his hands.
Who did you say, Stanley?
Tom's daughter.
Say, by George,
you've got somethin' there..
She'd take anything in pants.
You talk to her tomorrow,
will you, stell?
I'll call her tonight
right after dinner..
That's the best
time to catch her.
Good, be sure and do that, eh.
Mmm-hmm.
You've got it all figured out..
It never struck you that Rudolf
might have his own ideas
of what he wants in a wife?
You're right, Katie.
You're absolutely right.
We've got to get
the guy somethin' good..
We can't take a chance on
a false number. Uh-huh.
Oh, what's the use?
I know who we'll get for Rudolf.
Who, ma?
Anna.
Who did you say, Theresa?
I said, Anna.
Have you gone out of your mind?
No, Joe.
It come to me like a big light.
Here's our chance
to give Anna a fresh start.
I made a rule, we don't talk about
her in this house no more.
And I keep that rule, Joe.
We don't talk no bad about Anna.
This is good for her.
This is good we can do Anna.
She ain't no good,
but she'd do for him.
You're speaking
of your own sister.
So what?
She's nothing but a slut.
Don't you say that, Stella.
There's no one got
a right to call her that.
Pa didn't kick
her out for nothing.
You shut your mouth,
or I'll slap you down!
You just try.
Nobody's gonna slap
my wife down but me.
You and who else?
Right. Let's settle this thing.
Let's all keep our heads.
Now here's our chance to look at
this thing from the human angle.
What?
Well, we've all got
different angles.
Let's just put them all
together and do as I say.
Now anybody can see
that ma is right.
She's absolutely right..
Anna's the girl we ought to get for
Rudolf, so we'll just get her.
Never! Never in this world!
Maybe she's changed.
She don't look a day older.
How do you know?
Stanley?
A friend of mine saw her. I... i
didn't want to tell you, ma.
Tell me what?
Nothin' ma. Anyway, she's... she's
lookin' just great.
What if she won't have Rudolf?
Stop that talk.
Didn't you just hear
Katie read the letter?
Didn't you hear Otis tell me to
find his son a God-fearing woman?
Joe, you've got
to give Anna this chance.
No!
No, Theresa!
Have you gone crazy?
But, Joe, she...
I swore it then, -
she don't come
back in this house!
She don't come
Well, I guess he means she don't
come back in this house.
No. No. Joe wants her back.
It's just that stubborn,
bullheaded pride of his
that hates to admit
he's done wrong.
You don't know
what you're doin', ma.
They only want her back
to sell her like an animal.
I don't know what
you're talkin' about, child.
All I know is I want
Anna back, that's all.
I'll make Joe go fetch her.
I'll break him down, you'll see.
Do you think she can
make that old ox see the light?
If she don't, I guess I'll just have
to have a little talk with him.
If I don't get
that new wardrobe,
I won't be able
to step out of this house.
I never dreamt people
could be so inhuman.
At least we're not hypocrites.
Well, who's a hypocrite?
You. You're not so keen on lmng
under the same roof
with that streetwalker.
That never entered my head.
I'd like to meet Anna.
I've a feeling she's got a
lot of her mother in her.
And I never met anyone sweeter
and nicer than Theresa.
Let go of me, Theresa.
I won't let you go
till you promise me
you'll let Anna come back.
Get away from me, Theresa!
If we don't give her this
chance, we may never get...
oh, ma. Are you hurt, ma?
You girls take ma upstairs.
Let her rest.
He's got to give Anna another chance.
He's got to.
It's all right, ma,
you leave him to me.
Go up with them, Stanley.
I wanna talk to him, too.
I ain't talkin' to none of you.
I'm gonna talk
and you'll listen...
you get out of my house!
We only want to get
some sense into you, pa.
You two, get out!
We should throw you out.
Who's paid the rent for 2 years?
Shut up!
Don't tell me to shut up.
Cut that out. Now beat
it, like I told you.
Go on!
Gee, I hate to see that, Joe.
That's bad,
your own son
raisin' his hand to you.
That's bad upbringin'.
You ain't done
so good by Stella, either.
I had a hard job
housebreaking that woman.
Seems like the only one you showed
any loving care for was Anna.
You was real fond
of her, wasn't you?
I was.
Yeah, she turned out to be
your prize mistake.
Well, that's the pity of it all,
"It's an ill wind that don't
carry a silver lining."
now we can make some good out
of all this bad, you and me.
I know what you're drmn' at,
so you can save your breath.
Oh, sure.
You ought to know I ain't
the one for wastin' words.
There's much quicker ways of
gettin' things done than talk.
Now why was it
you kicked Anna out, Joe?
Why did you do it?
I did what the hymnbook told me.
The hymnbook?
Now you ain't
a religious man, Joe.
Can't even get you
to go to church on Sunday.
You rather lay in bed.
No, it wasn't the hymnbook.
Now, ma says it was your pride.
Now you could have never took
no pride in this family.
So what was it, Joe,
that made you kick her out?
And why won't you have her back?
'Cause I ain't gonna let you
spend Otis slocum's money.
There ain't nothin' in this world
I hate more than I do a liar.
That ain't a lie.
It's the truth.
You just heard from Otis today,
yet you kept Anna out of this
house for all this time.
I'm gonna give you one last
chance to say the truth, Joe.
So come on, out with it.
It'll save you
a whole lot of sweat.
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
There ain't no truth
but what I've already said.
Oh, yes, there is.
You're afraid.
You're afraid to admit
you done wrong.
That's what's eatin' your guts.
I did right, I tell you!
I did right.
What are you
hollerin' about, Joe?
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Look at you, trembling like an old fool.
What are you trembling about?
Because all the things you say are lies.
All lies.
Then prove it!
Prove it by bringin' her
back and showin' all of us
you can act
like a father to her.
A nice, kind father, Joe.
No. No.
Yellow, huh?
Then I guess I'll just have
to give you a little courage.
This is where
you need it, Joe, right here.
Let's get downtown and get you
on that bus for San Diego.
I can't do it.
I can't do it, I tell you.
But you gotta, Joe.
M-maybe tomorrow.
No, tonight.
Stanley, what was the name of
that place your friend saw Anna?
Noah's wharf cafe.
Is he gonna go?
Your son asked you
a question, Joe.
I ain't got the fare.
Here, give me some fare,
Stanley.
Easy. That money's
Katie's as well as mine.
Am I gonna have
trouble with you, too?
Come on, Joe.
Frank, is he going?
Yeah, ma. He had a change of heart.
Is he really going?
That's my good Joe.
Come on,
you're holdin' up the parade.
Yeah, when you gotta go,
you can't stay.
I knew you'd do it, Joe.
God bless you.
We're gonna have
our little Anna back again.
Come on.
Lester, boy,
your fate is in my hands.
Hey, Noah!
I'm closed.
Come on, man.
Open up for a hot sailor
on a cold night.
Hey, Noah, it's Danny Johnson.
Let him in.
Now I'll never get to bed.
Hi, Noah. Hey, wait a minute
don't shut that door.
There's a lonesome gob
out there.
Lester, what are you gonna do?
Stand in the breeze all night?
Come on in.
Hello, baby.
Hiya, Danny.
Is it good to see you!
Hey, don't handle me
like a sack of potatoes.
Hey, you lost weight, baby.
Yeah, among other things.
But you're still a fine-looking chick.
Thanks.
Hey, Lester, look what I found.
Well, you sure
don't lose no time.
No, this is the girl I've been
tellin' you about. Oh, pardon me.
And pardon me. Is this
the last of the convoy?
Yeah, Noah, it's
the last of the convoy..
This is Lester. He's the cat with
all the loot. He's treasurer.
Lester, I want you
to know Anna lucasta.
Once you've met Anna, you've
come up against the main event.
How are you?
How do you do?
It looks as though
you've met someone in Lester.
Now you know that I only know
the best kind of people.
Come here and tell me something.
Why didn't you write me?
We docked in long beach
and took a cab
all the way here
to find you, didn't we?
That's right, but it sure
was worth the cab fare.
Hey, your friend's
got the makings.
Yeah, I towed him along to
bring out my finer qualities.
He says I'm a gentleman
in the rough.
I sure am rough, ain't I,
baby, and don't you love it?
May... maybe I'd better go
and write myself a letter.
No, man, stay
and enjoy yourself.
Enjoy myself?
Well, uh, maybe I
could order some drinks?
Hey, now, that's a good idea.
Why couldn't you
have thought of that?
'Cause my mind's racing
way ahead of that, baby.
Yeah, but we've got company,
remember?
Did you say something
about a drink, sailor?
Pardon me for buttin' in.
Don't apologize.
You're too
good-looking for that.
Now come on. Don't get him
all steamed up, baby.
This is his first cruise.
But not my first port.
Now come on, folks, what'll it be?
And let's make it snappy.
Just bring out a big,
fat bottle.
Beer for me.
What did that cab set us back?
What's the difference?
It was worth our while,
wasn't it?
It must have cost us $20
getting here.
And I kept sayin'
to myself on the ride,
"maybe she hooked some bigshot.
Maybe she left town
or somethin'."
quit your jazzin'.
I ain't jazzin'. Ask Lester.
But no more problems now, baby.
I found you, and you ain't never
gonna slip away from me again.
You can bet your boots on that.
Now truthfully,
what does that do to you?
Does that bring out
my finer qualities, Lester?
Well, it sort of...
what does he know?
He likes everything plain.
He's got no taste.
Wait a minute, there's something
else that goes with it.
Ah, here we are. Dig.
Hey.
Danny, this looks like
it's been worn before.
Now let me see
if I can find the rest.
Hey, wait a minute.
Hey, where's papa?
Lester, where's papa?
If you left papa
on the ship... here he is.
Where do I wear that?
You don't wear him, honey.
He's someone you're gonna
get to know real well.
Another one of your
west Indian puzzles.
How do I take him apart?
You don't take him apart. You treat him
with respect, and he'll do you favors.
Like right now, he's planning
something really big for you.
Do you know what
he's talking about, Lester?
Oh, it's a mighty big plan.
Tell her who papa is.
Uh, that's a model of agoue,
the Haitian God of the sea.
Seems he's good to sailors.
Looks like papa and me
has got something in common.
Oh, come on,
be serious, will you?
You see, my cruise is up
in a few days.
And I ain't about to sign up
for another 4-year hitch.
What did they do? Give you the rush?
Give me the rush?
Did you hear that?
Ain't it ridiculous, papa?
The admiral himself
begged me not to leave,
didn't he, Lester?
He cried like a baby.
What do you do now?
Now I get me a hack,
and I go back to hackin'..
And pretty papa here is gonna
ride the radiator cap.
There's the little matter.
Of a previous drink
for the lady.
Lester, pay the man, will you?
Here you are, honey.
Here's looking at it.
Happy times.
Where did you say
you are you from, Lester?
Hartford, Connecticut.
Oh, a real blue blood.
You know, this cat
can even speak French.
No kidding? Yeah.
Say something in French, Lester.
Oh, I only know a few words.
I bet they're the right ones.
Yeah, but like I was saying...
yes, what were you saying,
Danny?
About the big plan.
You're gonna go back to hackin'.
That's only half of it, honey.
You know
how it is in the Navy, honey.
You get pushed around
from pillar to post.
I figure now that I'm out,
what I need is an anchor.
Around your neck.
Ha-ha-ha, funny. Funny, funny.
I know what you think,
you think like everybody else,
you think that all I do
is hang in joints like this
with broads, and boozin',
and lovin', don't you?
Mmm-hmm.
That's only part of it.-
the side that wants a home
with someone in it.
Someone you come home to after a
hard day's hackin' and say...
"hack me a hunk of steak."
what do you mean?
She means you're
lookin' for a cook.
What're you tryin' to do?
Louse this thing up?
What "thing"?
What are you leading up to?
Look, I'll give it
to you straight, baby.
A home without a woman in it
is just a pile of cold bricks.
Now what do you say me
and you get together, huh?
Are you asking me
to marry you, Danny?
Well, something like that.
What's something like marriage?
It's practically the same thing.
What's the same thing?
Look, honey, havin' a preacher
say a few words over you,
and gmng him $2,
anybody can do this.
Let's me and you
be different, huh?
How different?
Well, look, honey, take on
the islands, for instance.
Lester will bear this out.
When a cat meets a chick
and they dig each other,
they put a coconut
in middle of the ground,
a guy comes along
with a knife and goes, Chuck.
And like that, they're married.
Did you bring any coconuts
in that bag, Danny?
Why don't you marry her, Danny?
Lester, the talking lamp is out.
Take it easy, Danny.
I was only putting you on.
You said it so funny,
you gave me goose pimples.
You shouldn't
scare me like that.
What's wrong with you?
Have you gone nuts?
Sure I'm nuts. So are you nuts.
The whole world's nuts.
Come on, Lester, let's dance.
Oh, I can't dance.
What's the matter?
You got goose pimples, too?
No, I just can't dance.
Oh, sure you can dance.
I sure wish I could.
I know you can dance
if you want to.
Lester.
Break it up.
Break it up. Break it up!
No dancing allowed. Besides, there are
those who would like to go to bed.
Hey, you know,
that ain't a bad idea, baby.
Hey, what do you say, papa?
Hey, what do you say
about that, huh?
But we haven't finished dancing yet.
Don't close up.
Come on, Lester,
buy us another round.
Yeah, and smile, Lester.
Don't you want to be happy?
Lester doesn't know whether he
wants to be happy or good.
But we do, don't we, baby?
We sure do.
Well, here's looking at you.
Yeah, happy times.
Noah.
Well, what's with you?
What can I do for you?
Anna, I came up to see you
and to talk to you.
You handed me enough
to last me a lifetime.
You're on my territory now.
I don't have to take anything
from you here, so beat it!
Hey, who is this old guy?
Boys, you've got strong nerves.
Meet my old man.
What's on your mind, pop?
I'd like to
talk to my daughter alone.
Let's go, Danny.
No, don't go. Stick around.
Well, you can't refuse
to talk to your father.
Who says I can't? It's a
free country, ain't it?
He told me what he thought of
me when he kicked me out.
I'm here to ask you to forget all
that and to come home with me.
Why the change of heart, pa?
You think I'm loaded
with loot or something?
Don't talk that way
to your father.
Who says she can't?
What are you butting in for?
We still have free speech.
It isn't only me
that wants you home.
It's the whole family.
There ain't nothing wrong
with ma, is there?
Anything wrong?
No. No, she's well.
It's just that
she wants to see you real bad.
Won't you come home with me?
I can't.
Why?
Why the hell do you think?
Why are you
buggin' her, old man?
Can't you see you're
getting her all upset?
Now, you just keep
out of this, sailor.
This is none of your business.
Who says so?
I know what she's thinkin'.
And so would you,
if you'd use a little sense.
She don't
belong at home no more.
You should've thought of that
before you kicked her out.
What right have
you to say that, Danny?
She belongs at home
if they want her.
Have you anything
better to offer?
Will you quit buttin' in?
At least Lester ain't
depending on papa agoue.
If you want the advice of your number
one gin peddler, Anna, you'll go.
At least it'll give you
time to think.
Who wants to
spend a lifetime thinkin'?
You might try it for 5 minutes!
Anna, I have a bus ticket
for you here in my pocket.
Won't you come home with me?
Stanley married one of them
foster girls, didn't he?
Katie, she's a nice girl.
You'll like her, Anna.
I guess mama still makes spoon
bread and peach cobbler.
And she sure keeps the linen
nice and fresh.
Won't you come home with me?
Well,
what have I got to lose?
Nothing but your mind
from boredom.
At least it's 3 squares
and a place to flop.
You can have them with me, baby.
I was many months
without them, Danny,
while you were
riding the billows.
Can we go up and get
your things now, Anna?
Take it easy, pa.
I've got them all on.
I'll think about you, Noah,
whenever I get thirsty.
Yeah, you do that,
and you send me a postcard, you
know, like "'x' marks my window."
will you frame it, Danny?
I'll tear it up.
Good hackin', kid.
And take care of Lester,
will you?
Let him bring out
your finer qualities.
Well, I hope you're
satisfied, bigmouth.
You loused up my whole evening.
She wasn't
thinking about an evening.
She was offering
you a whole lifetime.
Oh, Lester, boy, how did
you ever get in the Navy?
Well, I see you bought the car.
Not exactly, Frank.
I got it on a 7-day trial.
Well, not too big,
not too small.
I approve.
How do you like it?
You still sell the same junk.
Hey, Frank, come on.
We'll be late.
Oh! Stanley, it's beautiful.
Can we use it to pick up Rudolf?
It ain't exactly mine just yet.
Get in.
It will be by the time we get
Rudolf back to this house.
♪ Oh, you better mind ♪
♪ You better mind ♪
♪ You've got to give
an account at the judgment ♪
♪ You better mind ♪
♪ You better mind how you talk ♪
Ma, do you think
that sign of Frank's is gonna
inspire Rudolf's confidence
in this family?
I think it's a very pretty sign,
Excepting I believe he would've
inspired more confidence
had he painted George
Washington's picture up there.
You feel pretty
good today, aren't you, ma?
Oh, with Anna back again,
I got a feelin' everything's
gonna be good for everybody.
Ma, I think I'll quit my job and
go into business with Frank.
Whatever makes you happy, son.
Then I guess I better look
for a steady job tomorrow.
I thought you two was the happiest
couple in the neighborhood.
She's always pickin' on me.
I can't do anything right.
Oh, it's not him alone, ma.
He's following Frank
and Stella's lead, as usual.
What about?
You know what they're
planning to do
as soon as they get
Rudolf into this house.
Well, we all.-
that Rudolf will like Anna
and she'll like him.
You're for Anna,
ain't you, Katie?
You act as though you like her.
Of course I do.
She's an intelligent and attractive
girl and very considerate.
But I'm not going to be
mixed up in any scheme
to use her
for other people's gain.
You talking to me, Katie?
No, she's slammin' me,
because I think
like Frank and Stella,
that if we make Anna respectable by
marrying her to this country hick,
we certainly rate a few of
the potatoes he's carrying.
Well, Katie, if they get married, I'm
sure they'd both want to help out.
You ain't suggested that
to her, have you, ma?
Of course not.
I'm waitin' to see if Rudolf's
good enough for Anna.
You just live in the clouds,
don't you, ma?
I feel like I was in heaven
ever since Anna come home.
So good just to hear her voice,
even though she
does say frisky things.
She made me laugh fit to bust
the other night in bed,
telling me all
about them funny people
she waited on in that
restaurant in San Diego.
So that's what
she was slingin', eh, hash?
Yeah, Stanley,
that's how she lived.
I always knew
Anna was good at heart,
and wouldn't end in the gutter
because she made one slip.
Do you think
she only slipped once, ma?
I know Anna's good.
Ain't nobody
can tell me different.
I know that the first night she
come home, cradled up in my arms,
and cried herself to sleep.
I knew her heart was just as
good and sweet as it was
when she was a little baby
in that same bed at my breast.
One time, she woke up, -
"is it rainin'?" And I said,
"yes, honey, it's rainin'."
she said, "that's nice."
went off to sleep again,
just like a little baby.
Joe, why ain't you down at the
station to help bring Rudolf?
I ain't got the heart
to meet him, Theresa.
Glued to a stool
at Mike's saloon.
Yeah, that's right.
Now you keep sober
and tidy up a bit
to meet your best friend's boy.
Let me alone.
Come on, ma.
Let's get the dinner.
What's the matter, pa?
You're nervous
as an old dog with ticks.
The lord strikes down
them who mock their parents..
Don't bring me
that hymnbook hi-de-ho.
I'm too fast for that mess. Ah.
What's the matter, pa?
Stanley riding you
about your hymnbook?
Where did you get that?
Ma gave it to me.
I thought I'd read for myself your
gospel about dying and going to hell.
There's a whole lot in here
about heaven, too,
and how to get there.
I missed them.
"Beulah land."
my pappy and my grandpappy
used to sing.
And sing.
♪ Beulah land ♪
♪ Walk in beulah land ♪
They used to sing and sing until they
didn't have a bit of breath left.
And no more gin.
Don't you call
my pappy a drunkard.
You, you heathen!
What's the matter, Stanley?
Why do you always
have to bring people down?
We just got pa to singing.
Come on, pa. Give out some more
of that dwelling in beulah land.
I forgot the tune.
But you were just singing it.
I forgot it, I told you.
Come on, Stanley, let's dance.
Not with my feet.
How about you and me, pa?
No. No.
You taught me how.
Remember?
Let's dance, pa.
No, don't put your hands on me.
How dare you!
Have you gone crazy?
Pa!
♪ Beulah land ♪
Anna, would you like a cup
of coffee or something?
No, I-I'll wait for dinner.
You're putting on a mighty big
spread for that gentleman caller.
Well, it's the least we could do
for the son
of an old friend of pa's.
And Frank and Stella drive all
the way down to union station
to pick him up?
Simple courtesy.
That's a new word for it.
You shut up.
You're not going to shut me up.
Take it easy, Katie. I know
what Rudolf's coming for.
Ma told me.
They're not interested
in making you respectable.
They're just out to
get Rudolf's money.
Are you out of your mind?
Oh.
So the guy's got dough?
How much?
His father gave him...
$45.
$4,000.
Well, you can't do it, Anna.
You can't.
Why not?
Don't you want to see me
respectable, like Stanley says?
You'd only be
cheapening yourself.
Well, I'm not too
expensive anyway, Katie.
Where's Rudolf?
Yeah, where's Rudolf?
Did he come in? He came in.
What did you do with him?
Oh, I took him out and bought
him a couple of beers.
He got real drowsy.
Then I took him down to the
hotel and watched him unpack.
He's all set now
for a long night's sleep.
Tomorrow morning, I'll go buy him
breakfast and take him to church.
Ain't he coming up to dinner?
No, he's not coming for dinner.
Say, what's the mystery?
You two been
cooking up something.
We've got to get a whole new
approach to this thing, Stanley.
This Rudolf ain't
all we bargained for.
What's the matter with him?
Plenty.
Our Rudolf graduated
from agricultural college.
Graduated from college?
With honors.
With honors?
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, that boy's daddy
sure done us a dirty trick.
We're still gonna marry him
off to Anna, aren't we?
Not a chance.
He's too clean-cut.
He'd see through her
in a minute.
Then how are we gonna
get the dough?
That's the problem.
Are you sure he's got it?
Oh, hell, yeah.
He's got a wallet in his breast pocket
there that makes him walk lopsided.
If only we hadn't listened
to ma about getting Anna.
We should have got tom's
daughter, like I said.
Listen, brainstorm,
Frank mentioned to rudolf
that Otis said he was
anxious to get married.
What do you think he said? What?
"Oh, that was pa's idea. I came
to California to get a job."
well, we got to
keep Rudolf away from Anna.
Can't have her disgracing us.
Mmm-mmm.
I'm afraid
that won't be so easy.
Why?
Because now she's
hot after Rudolf's dough.
Who told her about the dough?
You big blabbermouth!
It was Katie, she gave
the whole thing away.
Look, can't I leave
you two alone for a minute?
The moment my back's turned,
some one of you
gums up the works.
Oh, ma, they're back.
Got to get a brand-new approach.
Yes, sir, I know
just what it's gonna be.
I'm gonna take
the investment approach.
Get him to invest his money
in something special.
I've got to approach him
through his interest.
What is Rudolf's interest?
Agriculture.
Mmm?
Frank? Yeah.
Where's Rudolf?
Oh, uh,
he was all played out, ma.
That's a tough trip
from Alabama.
When are we gonna eat?
He was too tired to
come up to meet us all?
To meet Joe,
his father's oldest friend?
Well, uh, I explained to him that
Joe ain't been so strong lately,
and he agreed that
tomorrow would be soon enough.
When are we gonna eat?
I never was so disappointed.
Got a real Southern
dinner for the boy.
I think he's acting careless.
I don't think he's showing
the proper respect.
Well, you're right there, ma.
He ain't showing respect.
But then...
well, you know
these Southern hayseeds.
Did you tell him
we were expectin' him?
I sure did.
But what can you do
when a guy is all tired out
and don't want nothing but bed?
He was sure worn out,
wasn't he, stell?
Could scarcely walk.
Someone's at the front door.
See who it is, Stanley.
Oh, Frank, I think it's Rudolf.
Well, let the boy in, Stanley.
Won't you come in?
We's all mighty
glad to see you, Rudolf.
Oh, thank you, ma'am.
I would have
knowed you anywhere.
Why, he's the spittin' image of
his pappy when he was his age,
so neat and good-looking.
Now, Mrs. lucasta, you're
gonna get me all fussed.
Oh, you mustn't feel like that.
Got to make yourself at home,
and let me treat you like
I would my own son Stanley.
It ain't right what Frank said,
that you're too tired
to eat, is it?
Too tired?
Uh-huh..
Oh, no, ma'am,
I'm never too tired to eat.
That's the way I like
to hear my sons talk.
I'm Katie.
Oh, hi, Katie. How are you?
Excuse me. I have to
get back to the kitchen.
Come on in and sit down, Rudolf.
Make yourself at home. Come on.
Thanks, Frank.
Uh, where's Anna?
Keep her up there.
Well, Rudolf.
Oh, I hope I'm not
interrupting dinner, Frank?
But I just didn't feel right not
coming over to pay my respects.
Oh, think nothing of it.
Have a shot? I mean, a drink?
No, thanks. I still feel those
2 beers I had with you.
Well, it takes a wise man
to know his own limitations.
That's a good paraphrase
of socrates, Frank.
Socrates? Oh, yeah,
socrates. Sure.
I had to read him in college.
Uh, say, have a cigar, eh?
Uh, no, thanks.
No? But if you don't mind...
oh, go right ahead.
Help yourself.
Thank you.
Say, Rudolf, uh, what did they teach
you in that agricultural college?
Most anything I wanted to learn.
Things like plowing
and hoeing, I suppose, huh?
Plowing and hoeing? I knew all
about that when I was 10.
You did, eh?
Well, of course, I suppose there's
always, uh, new inventions,
oh, like mechanical plows and
mechanical hoes, uh, electric...
well, ever heard
of a tractor, Frank?
A trac... oh, tractors,
sure. Oh, my, yes.
A tractor.
Yeah, you know, I was talking
with a guy the other day.
Smart fellow he was, too.
And, uh, he had a brand-new
approach to these, uh, tractors.
What was his name?
His name?
Oh... oh, well, you see, uh, he was
just an inventor. You understand.
They like to keep these
things secret, you see?
Nobody's gonna steal his name.
Uh, no, I... i suppose not.
Well, uh,
let's see.
What was his name? He, uh,
not mccormick?
No, no, no.
Uh, it wasn't deere, was it?
Deere?
How do you spell that?
D-e-e-r-e.
That sounds like it.
Yeah, that's what it was,
Mr. deere. I remember now.
He ought to know.
Along with mccormick, he's the biggest
manufacturer of tractors in the world..
He... uh,
oh, well,
no, that wasn't the man.
Uh, you... you see,
this was just an inventor.
You understand?
A private inventor.
Oh.
Well, pa taught me
one thing real early.
Keep away from new inventions
until they're foolproof.
Pa made his money with the
old-fashioned plow and hoe.
Yeah.
Boy, your old man
is a character.
Mmm, yeah.
Well,.
Uh, Rudolf, what is your, uh, special
agricultural interest, son?
Well, Frank, I'm interested
in everything that goes into
and comes out of the earth.
Uh-huh.
But in college, I... i did some special
kind of work with fertilizers.
Yea...
fertilizers?
That's just plain ordinary...
that ain't nothing but manure.
You ought to know
someone in that, Frank.
Pretzels, Rudolf?
Thank you, Stella.
Isn't anybody
going to introduce us?
Oh, uh, that...
That's... that's Anna.
How do you do, Anna?
Y-you a neighbor?
A neighbor?
Oh, did I forget
to mention I had a sister?
I've been away
for such a long time,
they've hardly
got accustomed to me.
Shouldn't take long
to get accustomed to you.
It don't, as a rule..
Say, Rudolf, uh, how would you
like me to take you around
and explain to you about all
these antiques I got here?
Oh, I-I'd like to, Frank.
Good, come along.
Later?
Oh. Well.
Where have you been lmng?
There's something about the
sea that I've always liked.
Have you ever been to San Diego?
No, that's the large
naval base, isn't it?
Mmm-hmm.
Lifeblood of the whole town,
the Navy
and the merchant marine.
What... what did you
do in San Diego?
Uh...
Well, wasn't that ma I heard
calling us to dinner?
I didn't hear anybody.
Uh, well, I'll go hurry her up.
What did you say
you did in San Diego?
Well, I didn't go to college.
Stanley says you graduated.
Yeah, just last month.
That's a good-looking
ring you're wearing.
Keepsake from some
college girl, I'll bet.
Oh, no, no, no,
that's my fraternity ring.
Yes, that is an expensive hunk
of jewelry you've got there.
Got to be careful with your
valuables in this town.
I wouldn't carry
too much cash around with me.
Yeah.
We've got some bad
people in California.
Say, how'd you like to get a couple
of beers before dinner, Rudolf?
Come on, let's go have one, huh?
Oh, no, thanks. I feel fine.
You do? What the hell...
just fine..
Uh, except that it... it is a
little warm in here, isn't it?
Why don't you
take your coat off?
I-I-if you don't mind.
Be real casual.
Thank you.
What you totin'? A gun?
No, that's my wallet.
Say, Rudolf, I recently came into
possession of a burglar-proof safe.
I can take this and...
put it in the bank.
Yeah, I plan to
deposit it tomorrow.
I'll take you down to my bank,
introduce you to the manager.
Oh, that's Joe.
I guess you remember,
I told you,
he wasn't
very strong these days.
Hello, Mr. lucasta.
I'm awful glad to meet you.
I've heard about you
all my life.
Otis.
No, I'm Otis' son, Rudolf..
Rudolf?
Rudolf.
Well, how's my old friend, Otis?
Oh, pa's just fine, Mr. lucasta.
He... he sends you
his very best wishes.
Otis told me
to get you a good wife.
So Frank said. That's like pa.
He... he still think
I'm in short pants.
You wanna watch out
for the women, son.
Oh, sure.
And the wine..
If one don't get you,
the other one will.
Watch out for your money..
Don't let nobody get hold of it.
No, sir.
You better put it...
you better...
you better put it down, Joe.
Come on now, sit down.
Let me go!
Can't you see I'm talking
to my old friend Otis?
Well, it's too
bad he can't hear you..
He's a thousand Miles away.
That's Otis. That's Rudolf.
You let me alone.
I'm telling you, I'll fight you!
Just take it easy, Joe.
Let me go!
Leave him alone, Frank.
Pa, would you like to
have a cup of coffee?
You. Don't you talk to me.
You get away from me,
or I'll slap you...
Stanley! Yeah?
Come here.
Let's go.
You'll have to
excuse Joe, Rudolf.
He has a psychological problem.
Yeah.
He just can't seem to
find the bottom of the bottle.
I never considered myself much
of a dancer till tonight.
It must be you. Was that
the mambo we were doing?
Ha. How do you like that!
I can do the mambo
and never had a lesson.
Where'd you like to go now?
I'd like to go home..
I... i haven't had as much
fun in my whole life,
as I've had
this past week with you.
The night's gone so fast, I... i didn't
realize it's past... past 1:00 already.
Is it really?
You sound tired. Are you?
A little.
Oh, I'm sorry, honey..
I... i kept you out late
every single night, haven't I?
To you, I guess all
these places are familiar.
But me, I've been having a ball.
It's good to be with you, Anna.
Gosh, I never thought I'd be lucky
enough to run into anybody like you.
I'm glad
you enjoyed your vacation.
Vacation? I've come
to California to stay.
I've got my eyes
on a job already.
Where?
Valley junior college.
I sent my credentials..
I-I'm just waiting to hear now.
But I thought
you wanted to farm.
Modern farming.
Oh!
You know, it's a mystery to me how you
ever got yourself into that dress.
It looks like
you were poured into it.
Now, what do you mean by that?
Have I said anything wrong?
Well, it isn't necessary to tell a
girl how she fills out a dress.
Well, I haven't said anything
I wouldn't to my own sisters,
and they never took offense.
Well, I guess it's probably
just my dirty mind.
Don't say that about yourself.
You're just a little prudish,
and I like it.
Have it your way, brother.
Then we can be friends?
That shouldn't be difficult.
Gee, your hands are soft.
Soft and cool,
like... like... like topsoil.
Rudolf, what are you?
Just a college cutup?
Well, if that's
the way I strike you,
sure, I'm just a college cutup.
Well, you can't be serious, telling
me that my hands are like topsoil.
You make it sound silly, and
makes me out a plain ass.
Well, I didn't
mean it that way. It's...
well, you're such a funny kid.
I never met
anybody like you before.
Well, I never met anyone like you.
I sure never did.
You seem to be
looking right through people,
and reading their thoughts.
According to you, I don't
always read them right.
Oh, I think that's because
you don't trust people.
Someone must have hurt you.
More than one, brother.
Why... why should anyone
want to hurt you?
Let's go.
Here. It's getting
a little cool.
Thanks.
I been talking with your mother.
She seems worried about you.
Why?
She's afraid
you might leave home again.
I didn't intend
to stay this long.
Then you haven't found me
altogether unattractive?
I like you.
That's a beginning.
That's where it ends.
All week long, I thought we were
getting to know each other
a little better every day.
Even if we didn't talk,
I felt it,
that we were beginning to mean
something to each other.
Then, back on the dance floor, while I
was holding you close in my arms,
I knew I suddenly lost you.
What is it, Anna?
Please tell me.
When I was little,
pa was real good to me.
He changed when the boys started
walking me home from school.
One of them, Charley, was a
good dancer, so pa hated him.
So he made us break up
the night of the school prom.
I left the house after dinner and
came over here to this park.
I had a feeling Charley would
come here, too, and he did.
We sat on this bench
holding hands.
There wasn't much
we could say to each other.
And then pa came tearing into
the park like a maniac,
calling me
every name under the sun.
He took hold of Charley
and hit him hard.
Then he took hold of me..
I...
I've never seen a look like
that on a man's face before.
He... he dragged me back to the
house, forced me to pack my bag,
took me down to the bus
station, gave me $20,
and told me
never to come home again.
I don't remember
buying a ticket to anyplace.
I was crying so hard.
I just remember
getting off in San Diego,
not knowing how to go about
finding myself a place to stay.
Well, the fleet was in and a
friendly sailor picked me up.
He took me to dinner,
stole my $20,
and that's the last act of
human kindness I experienced.
I'm not cold anymore.
The wind must have changed.
Don't go in yet.
You'll miss your bus.
I can't leave you like this.
I'm sorry I spoiled
the evening for you.
You didn't.
I'm glad you told me
the things you did.
It made you seem closer to me.
That's not why I told you.
I know.
You want to be honest with me.
Well, I'll be honest
with you, Anna.
I love you.
I want you to be my wife.
Look, you don't like this town,
we don't have to live here.
Well, we can go back home.
I can teach there.
We can go anywhere,
as long as you're with me.
Hallelujah!
Don't say nothing, honey.
Just let me hug you.
And God bless you
for loving my Anna.
Don't be a fool, ma.
Don't make
something out of nothing.
You can't tell me,
honey, you don't love him.
I saw the way
you was kissing him.
I learned how to
kiss a long time ago.
But don't you love me, Anna?
Even a little bit?
Sure I love you,
more than a little.
But not enough to marry you.
Honey, you told me
the other night in bed,
you'd get married
if the right man came along.
People say
funny things in bed, ma.
But I know you meant that, Anna.
You wasn't being funny.
Whoever heard of
such a crazy thing?
A guy walks into your house
and says hello,
and the next thing you know, you're
marrying him off to your daughter.
Nobody's marrying me
off to anybody I don't want.
And it don't take 10 days to fall
in love, it takes only 10 seconds.
I knew that
the minute I saw your face.
But everybody
isn't like you, Rudolf,
with nothing but goodness in
them to show in their faces.
I know you're good, Anna.
She is good..
Can't you see
what's happening, Anna?
God has sent this lovely boy
into our home just for you.
He's sent him
in answer to prayers,
'cause you never had
a fair chance.
And the boy's fell in love
with you from the start.
That's God's doing, too..
God's gmng you your chance
for love and happiness.
You ain't gonna break his heart
and Rudolf's, too, are you?
God can stand anything, ma,
but Rudolf ain't so husky.
Oh, come on. Stop fightin'
me, will you, Anna?
Are you deaf, dumb, and blind?
Didn't you hear anything
I told you in the park?
I heard what you said.
Every word.
And it makes no difference.
What are you gonna do
with a guy like this?
Love him, child,
and make him happy.
Well, your ma's got
the right idea.
Now come on, knock that
chip off your shoulder.
Say you'll marry me.
At your own risk, Rudolf.
I'll take it.
What the hell's goin' on here?
They're going to be married.
Who? Anna and Rudolf?
Who do you think?
Well, what do you know!
Congratulations, Anna..
Congratulations.
Thank you, Stella.
Ma, it looks like we're
gonna lose our little Anna again..
You may kiss
your brother-in-law, stell.
All right, all right.
What do you want to do? Give the
impression our women are loose?
Where you kids
gonna spend your honeymoon?
Where Anna wants to.
I know a nice little
place in San Francisco.
How would you know?
You've never been
to San Francisco.
A fellow told me about it.
Come on, let's
everyone come inside.
And have a drink to celebrate.
I don't know if
I've ever been so happy.
♪ Wade in the water ♪
♪ Wade in the water, children ♪
♪ God's gonna
trouble the water ♪
Frank, run upstairs
and tell katie
to give you the bride and groom.
The bride and groom?
Yes, she'll find them
underneath my bed.
Hey, ma, lay off the liquor
until after the weddin'..
Anna's upstairs dressin', Rudolf's
down at the hotel waiting.
They're not underneath any bed.
I'm talking about the little bride and
groom that goes on top of the cake.
Why didn't you say so?
Hey, Katie.
Katie? Yes?
Get the bride and groom
from under ma's bed.
They're in a cardboard box.
In a cardboard box.
All right..
Never can understand
a woman's brain.
If they don't want to
understand somethin',
nothin' on God's green earth
will make them.
Just tell them there's a bride and
groom in a box under a bed,
they know exactly what you mean.
That's easy, Frank. Women just
play dumb, men are born that way.
Oh, how do you feel, Joe?
I thought you was too sick
to get out of bed, Joe.
I feel a little better.
Joe, you've come to yourself.
Maybe you'll change your mind
and take Anna up the aisle.
No, Theresa, I ain't
never gonna feel that good.
You go on back to bed
and stay there.
I come and go as I please.
Right now, I'm pleased to look
at your weddin' preparations.
All set for an orgy, ain't you?
If you've got it in your head
you're comin' down to church
and raise a lot of ruckus,
you better get it out.
'Cause one peep out of you,
and I'll take you out
and dunk your head in the sink.
Don't talk crazy. Why would Joe
want to break up the weddin'?
You wouldn't understand, ma.
You're too young and cute.
Frank, answer the door.
I gotta get these funny-looking
things out of my hair.
Oh, hey, ma. Uh-huh.
Put this away
in a safe place, will you?
Rudolf, what are you doin' here?
Waitin' around in that hotel
room just made me nervous.
Is everything going all right?
Oh, sure.
How's Anna?
Just dancing with joy.
Is she nervous?
Well, nice and nervous,
you know.
Well, where's Stanley?
No, he wouldn't be in there.
I sent him out
to get the car washed.
He should've been back
an hour ago.
What if he doesn't show up
on time?
Well, then I'll act in the double
capacity as your best man.
Be sure that everything
comes out all right.
You got nothin' to worry about.
Hello, Mr. lucasta. I hope
you're feelin' better today.
I've been feelin' dizzy
all the morning, son.
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry
to hear that.
I got a wire from my father
this mornin'.
He sends his best wishes
to everybody,
and his special regards
to you, Mr. lucasta.
Yeah, I can see your pa
drmng your ma
to their wedding
in that old high cart,
as though it was yesterday.
Well, I hope Stanley
didn't have a flat tire.
Oh, no,
the car's carryin' a spare.
Matter of fact, that's the
only good tire on the car.
Maybe I better give you the
ring and papers, just in case.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Uh-huh.
Rather small...
I mean, uh, little.
Uh, that is, rather neat.
It's not too expensive,
but excellent taste.
License, huh?
Yeah, let's see, uh-huh.
What is that? Oh.
Say, you know,
these health certificates, uh,
that's somethin' new
since I was married.
Yeah. All nice and healthy.
You're a healthy boy, all right.
You know, I was talkin'
with a guy the other day.
Smart fellow he was, too.
This is what he said.
He said, "the trouble
with most modern marriages"
is that they're all
contracted in ignorance."
and he was right, too.
He was 100 percent right.
Yes, it's wonderful how many
ignorant people get married.
Ain't it the truth!
Katie, how's Anna, Katie?
Just fine.
Can I see her for a second?
No, it's bad luck.
But I've got some
important news to tell her.
I'll tell her.
What is it?
Valley junior college
has confirmed my appointment.
I just got a letter from
the... the head of the school.
They want me to start teaching
in the fall term.
That's wonderful, Rudolf. I hear
that's a very fine school.
A real live Professor
in the lucasta family.
Well, who'd have thought it?
Anna will be so thrilled
when I tell her.
Let me tell her. Right now,
you've got to get out of here.
Your bride will be down, and you
mustn't see her before church.
Goodbye now, Rudolf.
Oh, goodbye, Katie.
Isn't Stanley back
with the car yet?
Oh, I sent him down
to get it washed.
He's probably taking a joyride.
Guess I have to knock some
responsibility into that boy's head.
I tell you, Katie, this day is
almost too much for a man to bear.
Ma's cake would've
burned to a crisp,.
If I didn't get a premonition
in the middle of the night
to come down
and shut off the oven.
Oh, sacrifice, sacrifice, sacrifice.
That's my middle name.
You're certainly
in the groove today, Frank.
The preacher ought to let you
say a few words in church.
Ain't that some bride?
Now, who would think 2 women could
look so different in the same dress?
When I wore it,
you looked different yourself.
There was some sort of line to
show where your chest started.
There's Stanley.
Hey, ma. Step on it.
All right, all right.
Stella,
you sure do make pretty hats.
But, ma, you got it on
upside down.
Oh, who'd know the difference?
Is it all right now?
You look just lovely.
My little baby.
This is all I've been lmn' for.
Mom, I love you.
All right. Let's break it up
and get goin'. Come on.
Come on, ma.
Don't cry, mama, don't cry..
Well, as the man said, "4 score
and quite a few years ago",
our forefathers brought forth on
this continent a new nation..."
May I help you?
I came to see the Dean.
Have you an appointment, sir?
No, I don't have an appointment,
but I think he'll want to see me.
May I ask what it's about?
I have some information concerning
that teacher he's going to hire here.
What's his name? Rudolf slocum.
What are you laughin' about?
I thought Frank would never
give you the ring.
He sure hated to part with it.
How's that, Mrs. slocum?
Couldn't be better..
We've done it. We really
are traveling together.
Let's get away quickly, shall we?
Let's not waste a minute.
I have to go to the hotel,
check out, get my clothes.
I'll be back in 20 minutes.
But I don't want to wait
for that. Can't we go now?
Your folks have gone to a lot of
trouble for the celebration.
We should stay, wait until they
get back, and cut the cake.
Sure, let's all sit down
and have a piece of cake.
We're not gonna have
our first argument
just as soon as
we leave the church, are we?
I don't have
an argument left in me.
Oh, we're never going to.
We're going to be happy
all our lives together.
I'm sorry. I guess you're right.
Of course I am.
I'll be back before you miss me.
Rudolf!
Hold me. Hold me
tight enough to kill me.
Hi. Anybody home?
You're early. The guests
haven't started to arrive yet.
Mind if I wait inside?
Yeah. Make yourself at home.
Thanks.
Hello, baby.
Don't take your coat off.
Why?
You've got to
get out of here right away.
What's goin' on here?
And what are you dressed up
for, a fancy dress ball?
I've just been married.
Ah, come on, Anna.
Don't shake me up.
Hey, it does look like
somebody's been married.
It couldn't be you, could it?
Why not?
I just got this letter
you sent me.
I beat it down here,
like you asked.
Danny, I thought after 2 days here,
I wouldn't be able to stand it.
That's when I sent you that
letter to come down and get me.
But a lot has happened
since then.
Oh, go on. You ain't married.
Hey, wait a minute.
Hey, who was that guy
that just left?
My husband.
Well, what do you know?
What do you know?
Hey, what happened? Did that
funny old man of yours
try to put somethin'
over on you?
No, it's on the level, Danny,
and it's of my own doing.
Who is this guy?
Where'd he come from?
He's the swellest guy
I've ever met.
When did you meet him?
When I came home.
What did he do?
Put somethin' in your drink?
I don't know,
but I'm sure floatin'.
Ah, come on, baby. You're talking
to Danny Johnson, remember?
Well, you're a swell guy,
too, Danny.
Thanks a lot, but you don't
have to con me, Anna, ever.
Come on, what's the gimmick?
Is the heel loaded?
I wouldn't care
if he didn't have a nickel.
Oh, then he is loaded.
That makes all the
difference in the world.
What is this stuff?
Look. Danny, you're a
good sport, aren't you?
It all depends.
What's on your mind?
Will you beat it? Will you get
out of here before he sees you?
Are you ashamed of me?
No. You know better than that.
I'm in love with the guy.
You used to tell me that,
too, baby.
I didn't. I couldn't have. I...
I didn't know
what it was until now.
You sure made me feel like it
every time we came into port.
Well, I was always glad
to see you, Danny.
I even missed you when you
were... when you were away.
But, we were 2 kids out to get our kicks.
To hell with tomorrow.
That's the way to live.
What's your plan?
Marry a guy who kisses you
goodbye at breakfast,
goes off to the office while you
stay at home baking pies,
then he plays the fiddle to you?
That's horrible!
Rudolf isn't a bit like that!
Rudolf? You married
a guy named Rudolf?
Anna, that's not a name.
That's a cigar.
I'm sorry you don't like
his first name,
because his last name is slocum.
Rudolf slocum?
He sounds like a farmer.
That's what he is.
Oh, no, I don't believe it..
I... i just do not believe that
you would marry a farm...
you know what I ought to do? I
ought to punch him in his mouth.
In fact, that's what I'll do.
I'll wait here,
when he walks in the door,
I'll beat his brains out.
It's very simple.
You're getting out of here.
Right now.
And leave you with this farmer?
Don't be silly.
He's not your kind.
You'd go crazy in a week
without the lights and swing.
That's why I'm here.
That's what I'll give you.
I'm through with it.
I don't want it anymore.
You can't get away from it! Anybody
looking for it can see it in your eyes
like I did the first flash
I got of you.
You don't belong to one man.
You'll never belong to one man.
You can't!
Yes, I can.
I know I can. Damn you!
I know what you're trying to do.
You're trying to scare me!
I'm trying to save you
a lot of grief, baby!
You and me, we're real people,
Anna. We're the real stuff.
Many's the time
we set the earth on fire.
You stick with me
and we'll burn it up!
Are you... Are you finished?
Yeah, I'm... I'm finished.
Now will you leave?
Yes, I'll leave.
And please don't try
to see me anymore.
I'll remember that.
I'll remember that when you
come crawlin' back to me.
When you do,
I'll probably take you back
because I'm just about
as weak as you are.
Oh, Anna...
goodbye, Danny.
This ain't goodbye, baby.
How do you do?
Nice car you have outside there.
Thanks a lot.
Danny just came down
to offer his congratulations.
Is that so? Yeah.
Congratulations to you,
too, pop.
You ought to be
a very happy man today.
I've seen you someplace before.
Yeah, in San Diego.
Yes, you were the sailor that
was kissing her at the bar.
Well, you know how it is, pop.
What's a little kiss
between friends?
Nothing. Nothing at all,
with folks like you.
I'm sorry we don't have time for a sermon.
I've got to get dressed.
And Danny's anxious
to be on his way.
Beat it, Danny.
You'd better hurry, daughter. You
don't want to keep Danny waiting.
Uh, he's not waiting for me.
Go ahead, Danny, beat it!
You better wait, Danny.
She'll be needing someone.
What for?
To take you away.
I'm drmng away from here in a few
minutes with... with my husband.
You think so?
You think he'll still want you
when he knows all about you?
He does know!
I told him everything, pa.
I mean, everything.
Honest..
I... i tried to talk him out of it,
but he wouldn't listen to me.
I know it's hard for you
to believe that,
because you despise me so.
But it's true.
Won't you please try to
let me make good now?
And if I mess it up,
I won't bother anybody anymore.
Nobody will ever see me again.
I'll know what to do
and where to go.
You're just what you are,
and nothin' on God's green
earth will ever change you.
Now wait a minute, pop.
Why so fast on the trigger?
Besides, what's the
percentage in you bustin' up
your little girl's wedding?
Shut up, Danny. Pa, I've got
happiness in the palm of my hand.
And if you mess it up,
I swear I'll kill you!
And I don't care what happens because
there'll be nothing to live for.
Baby, you don't have to.
If you want his mouth hushed,
I'll fix it so Rudolf
won't understand a word.
Rudolf don't have to
hear a word from me.
I don't have to tell him.
What have you got on your mind?
Theresa told me
he was getting a job
somewhere near here, teaching.
He is. Is he?
You got somethin' to say,
old man, you say it!
I don't have to say it.
It's been done.
What's been done?
I paid his Dean a visit.
We had a nice talk.
He agreed
he shouldn't hire a teacher
whose wife might teach his students
something they can't get from books.
You crazy old idiot.
You're not protecting him.
You're destroying him!
And wherever else
he tries to get a job,
I'll go and see that Dean, too.
Weren't you satisfied
with messing up my life?
Must you mess up Rudolf's, too?
You don't care
what man's making love to you,
just as long as it's a man.
Go back to your 3 square meals
and your flop with Danny!
Let's go. I don't
like the way he's acting.
Get me out of here!
Get the hell out of here!
Go on, take her out of here!
Put her in your damn car
and drive her to hell!
Yeah.
I'll take it.
Money.
And burn this.
You gettin' good and lost, baby?
I never want to be found.
Hi, blanche.
How's the world treating you?
Hi, Noah. How are all the animals
in this smelly old ark?
Meet the world's greatest
lover, Danny Johnson.
Danny, meet Noah.
Blanche, meet Danny.
Danny, meet Anna.
Don't just stand there, man.
Bring out the best.
Ain't nothin' too good
for my old lady.
What are you using for money?
If I had money,
I wouldn't be here.
Come on, you know I'm good for it.
Bust loose, will you?
Yeah, bust loose with the cork
and let the gin flow.
What's the matter, Noah?
You paralyzed?
You've both had enough already.
Enough? I never get
enough of anything.
I just got started.
Great idea you had,
comin' here to your friends.
Your friends
wouldn't even let us in.
Oh, Anna, if you wish, you may
stay at my place tonight.
Never mind. I.-.
"Let's all pitch in together."
I'm pitching in with Danny.
Didn't I promise to love you
forever and ever?
Or was that some other guy?
I'm thirsty.
Hey, Noah, come on,
a couple of beers, huh?
Beers? What's the matter?
You gone cheapskate
or somethin'?
You been flingin' the dough
pretty good.
Come on, spend it.
Mine's double gin.
You ain't gettin'
even a beer, Anna.
Give it to me.
What are you doing?
Look, I'm no mooch. When I'm broke, I quit.
So does the broad with me.
But I can't stop now.
We've got to keep going.
Honey, I'm with you all the way,
but we've used up
this town and that's for sure.
But we've got to go, go, go,
Danny. Time's a-wasting.
Honey, get your hooks out of me!
I'm trying to figure it out.
I'm thinkin'.
I smell wood burning.
Well, that's funny.
That's real funny.
Well, come to the party, man.
You're driftin'.
You know, sometimes I can't
ever figure out
how I got mixed up with you
in the first place.
I never asked you for nothin'.
Oh, no, not much. Just every
stitch on your back,
booze by the case,
and spending money like I
was printing it myself.
It's not fashionable to go
broke in this town, Danny.
You're out of style.
I told you, Anna,
to quit pushin' me.
Who's pushin'?
That's what you need
is a good push.
You...
No. That's what you'd like,
isn't it?
I'm not about to go to the chair
for beating your brains out!
That's exactly what I'd do
with another night of you.
Go ahead and laugh!
You know what she did?
She busted up my cab.
Papa agoue was riding
the radiator cap
and she knocked his head clean
off and busted my luck with it.
If she busted your luck, why do
you keep tagging along with her?
6 months pay gone down the
drain in one lousy week.
And for what?
Oh, hit the road. Who needs you?
You bet I'll hit the road, baby.
I must have had rocks in my
head to carry you this far.
And I'll take this,
if you don't mind.
I don't figure on
keeping up the payments.
It's nothing
but a piece of junk, anyway.
It stopped running
the moment I kissed you.
You kissed me, all right, baby.
You're the kiss-of-death broad.
That's you.
Danny Johnson's
got a lot of traveling to do,
and a lot of lmn' to do,
and I'm checkin' out.
And don't bother
writing me any letters
because from now on,
I'm sticking to women
who have only one thing.-
me.
Danny.
Anna, I was just talking
to eddy over at the chambers.
Seems like he's given the gate
to one of his girls
and now she's tryin' to make out
like he was beating her up,
at the very same time
he was down here
gettin' a hole
burned in his neck
by that cigarette
you pushed into him.
You remember that night,
don't you?
Heaven knows you never give me
no reason to do you no favors.
But when I see somebody throwing
themselves away like you are,
it's just my natural instinct
to try and save them.
And I don't care what you say,
eddy's a swell guy.
He needs you
for a witness to prove
he wasn't even
in the chambers that night.
So if you go to him and tell
him you'll stand by him,
you could have his shirt.
In fact, you could
move right into the job
he just threw that broad out of.
No, thanks, blanche.
Now you look here, Anna.
You can't go around kicking every
man who likes you in the pants.
Pretty soon,
there'll be none left.
Why don't you go haunt
some other bar?
Oh, don't you rush me.
Anna,
you can't fight
eddy off forever.
And besides, you'd be doing me
an important favor with him.
Huh, Anna?
Good night, blanche.
All right, I'm leavin' already.
Anna, there's a nice breeze
comin' right off the ocean.
Oh. Oh, well.
What's with you?
It would look
ridiculous on me, anyway.
Planning on shipping out, huh?
Rio..
What?
Rio de Janeiro.
You know, Brazil.
That's the spot.
Brazil?
I saw that on a map once.
That's at the bottom
of the world.
No, it ain't.
Same distance below the equator
that we are above it,
and the climate's even nicer.
You been there?
Oh, yeah. Lots of times.
I got a cousin that runs
a soft drink joint down there.
Let me see. The iberia leaves tomorrow
night, the hispanita on the 20th. .
Hey, I know
the mate on the hispanita. .
He'd let me
work my passage over.
Take me with you, Danny.
I intend to.
First I got to work your fare.
I can work. I can do anything.
I'll shovel coal.
Honey, ships today use oil.
I'll have to buy your ticket.
Sell your cab.
Can't. It's in hock up
to the hilt.
Wait a minute.
The hispanita on the 20th. .
If I work
around the clock hackin',
we could make the one
on the 20th.
No, let's take the one tomorrow night.
The first one that's leaving.
Honey, relax. We'll go.
2 weeks won't make a difference.
It will to me.
My cousin must be
really busting them up
down there.
Imagine, a place
with booze on every corner,
and they're just
getting used to soda pop.
It'll be a good business
to break into.
On the cuff? Thanks.
Maybe if we went down
to the wharf,
the skipper on iberia
will give us a break. .
Not on your life. I know him.
Better chance cutting bait with
a shark than get his favor.
Maybe I could sweet-talk him.
That's out.
I don't even want you
to joke about it.
I wasn't joking.
I said, we'll go
when I can pay your fare.
Let's get out of here
tonight, Danny. I gotta.
Now let me think.
Maybe I can hit
Noah on the head.
He ought to be good
for about $20.
For $20, you'd have to kill me.
That's funny. Funny.
I've got money.
You been holding out on me?
No, it's the money Rudolf
gave me to buy my trousseau.
Where is it?
I hid it in my room.
Come on, baby, there's
still gas in the cab.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
Nothin'.
It's yours, ain't it?
I mean, he gave it to you?
Honey, Brazil.
And we'll never come back
to this place again?
What for? We only have bad
times to remember here.
I wish we were on that boat now.
Soon, baby, soon.
Come on.
No, I better wait here.
Oh, it's Sunday.
They're all in church.
Come on.
Why,.
It's not here.
Are you sure you put it there?
I thought I put it in my doll.
Aw, honey, this is no good. You can't
find it rummaging around like this.
Relax and take your time.
Close your eyes and think.
Honey, will you... honey, will
you sit down and listen to me?
Ah. Now,
with that kind of money, baby,
we can buy 2 tickets
and travel cabin style.
Who's that?
The old man must be in his room.
Let's get out of here.
You better give a look.
He's just sleeping off a drunk.
He sounds sick to me.
He ain't sick or drunk.
He's dying, Anna.
I couldn't even hear
his heartbeat.
I tell you, Anna,
your old man is dying.
Just a month too late.
A lot of good
that's gonna do me now.
That's a terrible thing to say.
You go over there
and say something to him.
You hold his hand, make it up if
you have to, but do something.
I'll go call the doctor.
Where's the phone?
In the lmng room. I'll go.
No. You stay here. I'll go.
Angel.
Did you have a good day
at school today?
Did teacher give you
some homework?
I'll help you
with your homework.
My little smart baby.
Someday you're gonna grow up
and be a real fine lady.
Anna,
If I'm not Workin' next Sunday,
I'll take you to the z-z-zoo.
Remember that old elephant?
He... he remembers you.
Remember how he took the
peanuts that you gave him?
That's because he likes you,
and he knows that
you like him, too.
E-e-elephants are smart,
that way.
Anna,
my little... little... little
baby.
Oh, good Jesus,
sweet, sweet Jesus,
look after and watch over
my little...
baby.
Pa. Pa..
The doctor's on his way.
He... he kept
calling me "angel,"
like he used to
when I was little.
I didn't know
what to say to him.
All I could do was sit here
and watch him die,
while he prayed to Jesus
to watch over me!
What's got...
What's got into that boy?
Well, he can't be that hungry..
Oh, yes, the preacher did
make an extra-long sermon.
Gotta speak to that man.
He sure takes good care
of the soul.
But the state of stress
the world's in today,
a man's got to have
a pretty good pair of kidneys.
You know, I was reading in the
medical journal the other day,
the doctors say
the chief trouble
with modern-day cmlization
is the headache.
And you know what a headache is?
It's a message.-
"don't send down
no more garbage."