Thank you.
This won't hurt a bit.
...labour pains...
...the routine use of drugs...
...may be determined...
...when the physiological,
sometimes fatal...
When contraction problems
occur-
- the pain can be relieved
with suitable drugs.
Thus the pain will disappear
or decrease.
In case... In case of a painful
but quite normal labour-
- the effect of the medium on the child
should be taken into account.
Relatively little is known about
the effect of certain anaesthetics.
Further research is needed.
The aim of obstetrics
is a healthy child-
- and minimum inconvenience
to the mother.
Now I submit my thesis
for your expert criticism.
Mrs Kivi's research shows...
...we still have a long way to go...
...Clarke & Russell, 1967...
...delivery without danger...
...an insuperable barrier
for our human knowledge...
We rely too easily on the statistical
and mathematical basis-
- provided by modem science.
We may thus forget-
- that pain, too, is
a manifestation of our culture.
...Mrs Kivi is hereby awarded her
Doctor of Medicine degree.
My name is Anna.
My housekeeper is called Helena.
My daughter is called Liisa.
Helena has been working for me
for a couple of months now.
I got my M.D. Yesterday.
I felt like laughing.
I've been writing my doctoral thesis
for three years.
I was divorced several years ago.
I bought the flat
so I could keep it.
I haven't asked for maintenance-
- because my ex-husband
earns less than I do.
I am an anaesthetist at the
Turku University Central Hospital.
Although I'm used to this life,
I don't like it.
- Ice cream?
- No, thanks.
- I want some.
- You'll get a tummy ache.
- Come on.
- Stop that whining.
- Ice cream?
- What have you got?
- Do you still feel nauseous?
- Why?
The pill doesn't suit everyone.
- I don't take it anymore.
- Why not?
- I don't need it.
- Suit yourself.
- You promised to pay for it.
- I forgot. You'll get the money.
Do you have your period?
You're so moody.
- I'm fine.
- Maybe there's a storm coming.
- What are you looking at, Mummy?
- I don't know.
More people seem
to be coming here this year.
Is Arvo coming this summer, too?
- Was he here last year?
- Don't you remember?
Yes, I guess he was here
for a couple of days.
There must be
some way of getting off the island.
Oh, God, we've got to get there first.
- Hello.
Spring arrived late this year.
The worse the winter,
the better the summer.
May I introduce myself.
We're neighbours.
- Kalle Koivu.
- Kivi. How do you do?
Koivisto here said that I can join you
if you don't mind.
My son was supposed to come and
pick me up. He must have forgotten.
- Young people often do.
- Of course, if Koivisto said okay.
You go first, Liisa.
- I rented Virtanen's place.
- I'm glad we won't be alone.
Can you give me a hand, Koivisto?
Hi. Do you have children?
I have a son, Veikko, who was
supposed to come and meet me.
- Do you care for some?
- Sure.
- Helena!
- I'm an adult. You're not my guardian.
- I left my typewriter in the car.
- I'll get it.
Thank you. It's in the boot.
Here's the key.
- Who is that man?
- He's a former MP.
Former...
A year ago on the same boat.
I came to the island with Arvo
in early spring.
It was cold.
The countryside was barren.
I was full of anticipation and joy.
We had fun together.
Nature was still dead.
Arvo embraced me playfully. Koivisto
turned his back on us, being tactful.
Arvo whispered something in my ear
and laughed.
My life seemed better then.
I hadn't noticed anything yet.
It's stuffy in here.
We must give it a good airing.
What are we going
to the neighbours for?
I'd like to go.
- Helena, you'll be sleeping here.
- I see.
You go and warm up the sauna.
I'll start planning my lecture.
Where's the typewriter?
Oh, here it is.
- Whose are these?
- Don't know.
- Are these Arvo's?
- Maybe.
Helena can wear them. Don't just stand
there. Go and scrub the sauna floor.
Veikko!
Hi there!
Don't run away.
- I'm Veikko.
- So what?
Oh, you're here already.
We're not quite ready yet.
- Do you smoke?
- Of course.
- But Anna doesn't approve.
- She can't stop you.
Well, no, but...
- Are you going to be here all summer?
- Where else would I be?
For me this is work, not fun.
- Does she pay you well?
- 250 a month.
- In Sweden you'd earn a lot more.
- I don't want to go to Sweden.
- Let's go for a boat ride.
- I have work to do.
You seem a bit uptight.
Give me the buckets
and get lost!
- Try to concentrate on the buckets.
- Don't get mad.
- What kind of a woman is that Anna?
- The same as everybody else, I guess.
- She goes on a bit too much.
- How do you mean?
Why do you keep asking me?
Go and ask her yourself!
- Okay, I will.
- Take the buckets like you promised!
That cigarette tasted really foul.
- Give me a kiss.
- No way. Keep your hands off me!
Come on,
we have to get the fishing nets out.
- Hi!
- Hello.
- So you're Kalle's son.
- Yeah.
Helena's going fishing now.
Take those nets.
- Try to row straight.
- I'm trying. This is not easy.
- I'm no fisherwoman.
- It won't kill you to learn.
Can't you row a bit more?
For Christ's sake.
You must know something about this.
- What are you doing?
- Just testing if you're awake.
Row back home now.
Don't swim too far out when you're
here alone. The water is still cold.
Beware of the snakes.
Liisa's used to them but you're not.
Stop smirking at everything I say!
It's a long way to the doctor.
- Do you like my mummy?
- Yeah, why?
- Many people don't like her.
- Why not?
They say she's stuck-up
but she doesn't care.
- Is your mummy nice?
- Yeah, though sometimes she gets mad.
It's nice when she talks
about all sorts of things.
- What does she do?
- She just works all the time.
- Then she's got Arvo.
- Arvo?
Goddamn idiots get to rule
and decide things for us.
People like me-
- who have been
working hard for years-
- get booted out.
The public votes for
all kinds of TV pundits-
- who know nothing about anything.
- They just babble on.
- Don't talk bullshit again.
I apologise for my son.
His vocabulary is somewhat limited.
I've never had time for politics.
I've worked all my life.
Don't think
that this is just a woman talking.
Most of my male colleagues
feel the same.
We work hard. Politicians have
their own business and I have mine.
- Are you angry?
- No, I just feel a bit funny.
You looked angry.
Helena, where do you go out
dancing during the winter?
Or do you prefer to
have fun at home?
You only live once.
Better make the most of it.
- Where are you going?
- Come and show me around.
- Kalle is a bit drunk.
- I'll go and talk to him.
What the hell are you doing?
First you ask people over-
- then you pass out stinking drunk.
- You think Anna will come here again?
- Hi!
We'd better go.
Liisa!
You're not much of a dancer.
I'll go now. Bye, then!
Helena, come on!
"How can you be a communist"-
- "when they've caused
so much suffering in this world?"
How can you be a doctor-
- when they've killed
so many people?
"What about Czechoslovakia?"
Goddamit!
"How are you going
to change the world"-
- "when you can't
even change yourself?"
Look at the socialist countries.
Everything's all right there.
"Moscow is pulling your strings."
Not my strings!
"Such communists don't exist."
But I do!
I still don't approve of everything
that the Soviet Union does.
That's why
they're working against me!
- Who says all that?
- That bitch!
Communism is just the same old shit.
To tell you the truth,
you're too old to keep up.
I don't give a shit
about your communism.
I don't want to suffer
like you've suffered.
"How can you approve of such
an inhuman system as communism?"
I'm not responsible
for Stalin's crimes.
"Of course not,
but you kept quiet about them."
Do you condone
the crimes of capitalism?
You keep quiet about them!
They've taken our boat.
- Helena! Are you asleep?
- No.
Come here, then.
Sit down.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
- Rather quiet here, isn't it?
- I like the birds.
You can sleep here in this bed.
It's warmer here.
I won't bite. Here you are.
We can sleep late tomorrow.
I'll switch off the light.
Good night.
Come closer.
The night is not over
though the sun is rising.
I like the silence.
After a sleepless night,
I can drop off again in the morning.
- There was nothing there.
- I knew that.
- How did you know that?
- I've been here before.
I don't smoke.
- It wasn't me you came to fetch.
- What do you mean?
There's younger talent around.
Or do you prefer more mature women?
There's all sorts of women.
How can one remember them all?
I want to try different kinds
before I get married.
I'm the marrying type.
Do you believe me?
Though
I don't want to settle down yet.
It's different
when you're really in love.
- Drink and get laid and get married.
- What did you say?
Just something
I heard a long time ago.
Before you were born.
Give me a light.
I don't feel well. I haven't eaten
anything. Let's get back.
Or?
- Take out the seaweed, too.
- I will, I will.
It's always a bit tricky.
You can throw
the small fish to the seagulls.
Is the pike dead even though
its heart's still beating?
Silly you...
- Have you seen one of these before?
- No.
- What is it?
- A pike's heart.
Mummy! An overseas call.
Hello? Hi!
I expected you to call earlier.
No, I understand.
What did you say?
We've got new neighbours.
New neigh... I can't hear you.
I see.
You know I can't do that.
Don't be daft.
Yes, they're still here.
Buy me some perfume on the plane
if you have the time.
Get some passport photos
so I can see if you've changed.
I'm cleaning fish.
My hands are all bloody.
You think that's disgusting,
don't you?
Yes.
Bye, then.
The light fascinates me.
The light scares me.
Out here on the islands everything
is timeless or very small.
Our days are simple,
fishing, eating, sauna.
And beyond all that
there's light, water, rocks-
- islands like little grey flecks
on the horizon-
- ships that come and go.
It's a time of yeaming
and retrospect-
- regret and sorrow.
When I was young, it was wartime.
We weren't free to live.
I envy them.
I'm afraid of them.
My eyes hurt.
I can't even read without glasses.
Soon I'll only be able to see in the
dim light of the operating theatre.
- Hi.
- Hi. Grab a glass.
Can you drive me to the ferry
tomorrow morning?
- Sure. What time?
- Six o'clock.
- Want to shoot dad's empty bottles?
- That should keep you busy.
Let's go over to the corf.
You came after all.
Why are you sitting indoors
on a lovely evening like this?
I can't stand being idle-
- so I'm sitting here drinking.
It's different for you.
You come here for a day or two
and then go back to work.
- Don't you have a job?
- No, I don't.
I'll be all right
for the rest of the year-
- but then
I'll have to start looking for a job.
- Don't you have any friends?
- Sure.
Former friends.
It's easy to hate
but hard to like someone.
I'm off tomorrow.
I'll be back for midsummer.
- Have a drink.
- No, thanks.
- Hello!
- What are you doing? I'll get all wet.
- Sorry, I'll get you a towel.
- Don't bother. Put the pike back.
Can I come and sleep over
at your place? I'm so cold.
No, you can't.
Go and sleep in your sauna.
- Good night.
- I love you.
Why haven't I got
any brothers and sisters?
- I don't have a husband.
- You've got Arvo.
You can't have a child with just
any man. You both have to want it.
- Did daddy want me?
- Yes, he did.
- And you agreed?
- Yes, I did.
Good night. Go on now.
Call me every night around nine.
See that Liisa doesn't swim too much.
Where is she now?
You do know that the best place for
fishing is there by the small cape?
Are you listening to me? Make sure
the house stays in one piece.
Are you leaving the typewriter here?
I can write the lecture when
I come back. There's no great hurry.
- Let's play something.
- Not right now.
- I'll go and build a hut, then.
- Don't be too long.
- What are you doing tonight?
- Why do you ask?
- I may be coming to town.
- By all means.
- To meet you.
- I'm flattered.
You should be.
I could come tomorrow.
- I've got to work.
- At night, too?
That's when I sleep.
Thanks for the offer.
It's no offer.
Be a good boy and give me the bag.
See you at midsummer!
Goddamit!
- It's tiring to watch women at work.
- Go get some water, then.
- Lf you come with me.
- I've got other things to do.
- There you are.
- Thanks.
- How about a little boat ride?
- You drive too fast.
- I'm a terrific driver.
- You?
I hate this goddamn wilderness.
I want to go to town and see people.
- You've got me here.
- Piss off!
Let's be friends.
You've got Anna's bracelet.
- So what?
- Hand it over. You've stolen it.
No way! What do you want it for?
- Liisa is a nice kid.
- Do you like children?
Hard to say.
As far as I know, I don't have any.
- You only like yourself.
- Well, someone's got to like me.
- Would you like to see something?
- Don't reveal everything at once.
Read this.
"I can't really say what I mean
but I need you."
"I am strong only through you."
"Every day I try to forget
that I'm no longer young but..."
- What is this?
- Anna's letter to her boyfriend.
- Why did you give it to me?
- It's cold!
You said
the water was twenty degrees.
What are you doing for midsummer?
I guess I have to join
the family in the country.
I don't bother about holidays,
except for Liisa's sake.
What are you doing tonight?
First I'll have a nice dinner and
then go home. I'm expecting a call.
- Want to join me?
- Why not, as the family's away.
Let's go, then.
- Kivinen, the cancer patient, died.
- Who?
- It wasn't you that operated on him.
- I was there.
We still have to eat.
Don't tickle. Leave me alone!
Women get tense
when they're not getting any.
- I'm not tense.
- Really?
I'm not! I am what I am.
- What are you?
- I'm a housekeeper.
A tense housekeeper. What are you
going to be when you grow up?
A soldier. I'll shoot all the men.
Stop that!
- You're rather good-looking.
- So what? Go get my clothes.
- Why?
- Go and get my goddamn clothes!
All right, then. I'll swim home.
Don't drown.
Perhaps I'll meet someone some day.
I've been working hard all my life-
- first to be able to study
and then just because I'm a woman.
- But women are emancipated now.
- Emancipated?
You've got
much more freedom than we have.
I'm responsible for the family
and all that. Most women...
- I've got a family, too.
- You're an exception.
There's so much in life
one must try to ignore.
Don't worry about things like that.
You're doing all right.
You've got a good job,
a decent salary-
- and a daughter,
who must be dear to you.
Of course, sometimes things seem...
A patient dies or you start thinking
about all the suffering in the world.
You've got to drown such feelings
so that you can go on living.
We all have our disappointments
that we want to forget.
This is my way. I'm alone in town.
I want to have a good time.
There are plenty of admiring nurses
who don't blab-
- and lady doctors that do.
But they all want
to talk about patients.
I don't want that when I'm off duty,
especially not in bed.
The good thing is that they're safe,
no fear of gonorrhoea.
But I'd rather go boozing.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Hello? Oh, hi.
When are you arriving?
What did you say?
"Communists mock to conceal
their ideas and intentions."
"They declare openly that
their aims can only be achieved"-
- "by violently disrupting
the social order."
"Let the ruling classes tremble"-
- "when
the communist revolution begins."
- What is that?
- The Manifesto.
- We don't read that at school.
- That's why I'm reading it to you.
"The proletariat have
only their chains to lose"-
- "that they may gain the whole world."
- Haven't you got any children's books?
- This is for children, too.
I'll show you
how to make a useful knot.
Here's a nice piece of rope.
This is how it's made.
Isn't that a fine knot?
Then you tighten it like this.
It won't come undone.
- I'll tie up the boat with it.
- You do that.
Where was I?
"Walk in my sleep? Rubbish."
"Take a look at your nightshirt."
"It's tom. How is that possible?"
"It got caught in our barbecue fork."
"Poor me, I do walk in my sleep.
What to do?"
"We'll tie you to the bed."
Veikko, what on earth are you doing?
Leave the birds alone!
Bloody hell! Are you crazy?
That was dad's gun.
- Why don't you have a job?
- It's more fun here.
It's only fun in the summer.
- Why are you like that?
- Can't I even speak anymore?
- What do you think about Anna?
- Anna?
She's quite a fetching bird.
What were you talking
about on the boat?
I don't remember. Why?
I've noticed
that you're hitting on her.
- She could be my mother.
- And that's all she could be.
There's your precious Anna's bracelet!
Go to hell, you toffee-nosed bastard!
- Have I hurt you somehow?
- You think you can do as you like.
I want to get out of here.
I don't want to be here with you lot.
Don't cry.
I'll get something for your foot.
I'm still in town, though I'm
meant to be on holiday already.
It's quiet here in the flat,
only clocks ticking.
Every day I try to forget
that I'm not a man.
It's a man's world even though some
women like me attain a good position.
Everything around me is cold.
I try to live and be free
but something keeps me down.
I'd like to talk to you but even when
you're here you're so far away.
Here on paper it all seems so silly.
You are coming, aren't you?
- Why haven't you got a wife?
- A wife?
She got what's coming to all of us.
Your mum's got no husband.
Mummy and daddy were divorced when
I was little. Daddy was an awful man.
Everybody said
mummy shouldn't live with such a twit.
- Who's everybody?
- Well, everybody.
Besides, mummy says
one's better off on one's own.
Maybe so.
- What does your dad do?
- He's a technician or something.
I'm going to be a doctor.
They do such valuable work.
So your mum wants to live alone...
- Are you hungry?
- I'll make something for both of us.
People seek security
in all the wrong places.
They wear themselves out
doing that.
And the others-
- those who have enough courage-
- and dare to say what they think...
...they get booted out.
- Were you booted out?
Yes.
But I don't like to admit it.
You see,
I've become tired and restless.
And I'm alone.
Stop that.
You're supposed to be tidying up.
You shouldn't mess up
other people's beds.
What's the matter with you?
I just don't feel like doing it now.
We're a bit late, I guess.
- Where's Liisa?
- With Kalle.
- Did you pick up the things I ordered?
- No.
What are we to do?
It's a public holiday.
- I can't do everything.
- What have you been doing, then?
- Did you hurt your foot?
- No.
I'll sit here.
I look at myself in the mirror.
Am I alone?
Am I old and ugly when the others
are young and beautiful?
What is the colour of water?
When the sky is dark,
the water becomes grey.
When the sun is shining,
it reflects the light.
Is someone rising out of the water?
When it's windy,
the water seems to come up to me.
When I'm swimming, I want to
experience the pressure deep down.
I should explore the sea
instead of dreams.
I don't dream at night,
only in daylight.
The sauna floor is still filthy.
You're not here on holiday!
I don't pay you to lark around
with Veikko. Is that clear?
Stop crying.
I didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
You're capable but...
I'm irritable. I don't feel well.
Take the rubbish away, and
we'll have a bottle of wine together.
Bloody hell!
The goddamn idiot had the nerve
to throw me out!
I told him
I'm not going to relieve him-
- just to get a chance to booze
in that rat-hole! No way!
And that bloody old hag
just sits there.
Bloody hell! I'll tell her.
You dried-up old twat!
- She'll hear you.
- She can't hear a thing.
She just chats on about herself.
Goddamit!
I'm leaving this place right now!
Take me to the ferry.
Keeping a bloody comb in your pocket!
- I'll throw this in.
- Chuck this one, too.
No.
I'll take the boat and drive off fast!
- Do you want the keys?
- No!
Keep your mouth shut
or I'll throw you in, too!
You rotten toffee-nosed bastard.
The bitch is in there, look.
Where are you going?
Bloody hell, that was great!
- Don't bum the house down!
- You can always build a new one!
I'll set the whole island on fire!
- Son!
- The whole island will bum.
- Nice going. More!
- Coming.
Olé!
That was a pathetic little bang. More!
That was even worse.
You're no good.
Let dad show you.
Don't start a row now!
You're here already.
- You like it here.
- There's only the neighbours here.
- Come. Let's go over there.
- No.
You seem so far away. We haven't
seen each other for a while.
I guess that explains it.
You've got a nice tan. It suits you.
- Listen, Anna.
- Yes?
- It's no use.
- What is?
You and me trying again.
It's not your fault.
In your world there's only room
for your own problems- and you.
There's no place for me there.
You're not concerned with
what's going on around you.
You're only concerned with you.
- I want to have a wife.
- But I love you.
Love?
Good night!
What are you doing,
thinking about me?
- Just thinking. You fool.
- Crazy woman.
Arvo, come and have some coffee.
I can't sleep.
Come and have some coffee!
- Would you come to town with me?
- Why not.
- I just need to find a place to live.
- It'll work out somehow.
Listen. The birds are singing.
- Can I ask you something?
- Sure.
- Do you love me?
- Of course, all the time.
I know you've had other women.
I don't care about that anymore.
But sometimes it hurts.
There you go.
Maybe you'd have felt more free
if I had someone else, too.
But I can't, I'm afraid.
I'm afraid of so many things,
darkness, disappearing, death.
Isn't it funny
that I should be afraid of death-
- when I put so many people
to sleep every day?
When I was a child, we used to rent
a house in the country for the summer.
I slept alone in a big room.
I remember when the Americans let off
a nuclear bomb, or was it an H-bomb?
The papers said that a litre of water
contains as much energy as the bomb.
The whole world
might become one huge fireball.
I couldn't sleep. I was so afraid.
Nobody could tell me what to do.
I've never met anyone who could
give me advice I could follow.
Except you...
sometimes.
You and I will never work out.
You're too afraid of yourself,
and everything else.
I'm not much better myself.
I've only got my work.
That's why
I want to have somebody, too.
I'm tired.
Come here.
Can you draw the curtains?
Don't worry, I'm not after anything.
But supposing I am?
Let's just sleep.
Did you ever read my letter?
I'm sure you didn't.
Did I write about the water? When I
was young, I used to swim for hours.
The summers were much longer then.
Now they seem too short.
I never have time
for summers like that.
I'd still like to swim,
way, way out.
Mummy!
- Hi there. Did you sleep well?
- Yes.
Helena and Veikko have gone missing.
- They went out to sea.
- They'll be back.
I'm so thirsty.
Can I have some water?
- I'll get you some.
- Thank you.
Here you are.
- Hi.
- Oh, it's you.
I'm glad you're here.
Mummy's missed you.
I spent the night at Kalle's.
- Are you staying here all summer?
- I wish I could but I'm too busy.
I'm going to lie down if you get up.
- Who's that?
- The neighbour.
- Hangover?
- You bet.
Liisa's got a good memory.
I'm going out.
Don't swim too far out!
Arvo's got a nice boat.
Why don't we go out sailing with him?
Mummy,
why don't we go out sailing with him?
It'd be nice to go out there.
I bet everything's different there.
- Go and change now.
- I was just going.
- I'll join you.
- Not now.
- You want some coffee?
- Yes.
I'll do what I like in my spare time.
It's none of your business.
I think you've got confused somehow.
- What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
What about the two weeks' notice?
Go and plot out your lecture,
you broody old hen.
- You can keep your bag.
- Helena!
Veikko!
There you go.
What about your pay?
You'll need money.
Go and get it then if you have any.
Have you quarrelled with Anna again?
- Why are you carrying a bag?
- I quit.
- You promised to come to town with me.
- What's the rush?
- At least I'm not stingy.
- Thanks.
- I'm off, then.
- Tell me why.
No. I can't explain it.
You can stay in my flat
for the time being.
- I'll just go and get my things.
- Suit yourself.
You can have it.
- Am I disturbing you?
- No, I'm just writing a lecture.
Kalle's wife died of cancer
but Kalle says she died of boredom.
Go out and play for a while, dear.
There's just the three of us here-
- like on a deserted island.
Young people don't understand.
Except for Liisa.
You're rather attractive, actually.
I understand
why Veikko is interested in you.
But we all feel our age.
You can't cope like you could
when you were younger.
For example, I haven't been
to bed with anyone for ages.
It's partly the booze, I suppose.
But when my wife died,
I lost interest.
People of the deserted island.
- I'll tie up the boat.
- No need. I'm going alone.
- What do you mean?
- I'm going alone. You stay here.
- Anna gave me her key. I'll be fine.
- You're insane.
We had fun
but we have nothing in common.
How do you know that?
- When are you coming?
- In August.
Can I have a lift?
- Let's go fishing, Mummy.
- Can't we do that tomorrow?
- No.
- I don't feel well.
Is that Arvo's boat that's turning?
It's not turning, no.
Look now!
I can't see anything.
Translated by: Kati Wnk
www.sdimediagroup.com