Could you turn on the light for me?
No problem, mister.
Lady not here.
Me clean. No understand.
No understand. Lady not here.
Just look at this.
Someone tore 6 pages
out of this magazine.
Can you imagine?
Talk to the manager.
-Where is he?
Try the meat section.
-The nerve of some people.
All done?
Thank you.
Man...
Telephone.
Who?
-Me not know name.
Was it Frank, Herbert,
Mr. Ostermayer maybe?
It doesn't matter.
See you next Friday.
Thanks. Good-bye.
Huber is sick again.
Can you turn it down a little?
Can you get it?
-OK.
Hofstiitter.
Mom, can I stay over
at a girlfriend's tomorrow?
Which girlfriend?
Anna.
You don't know her.
Alright, but ask your dad too.
Slavicza has wreaked havoc
in my CD5 again.
I can't find any of my Schubert.
Dad, can I stay over
at a girlfriend's tomorrow?
Who is she?
-Anna. She's in the same grade as me.
What do you have planned?
Listen to music, study math.
Where do they live?
-They've got a house.
What do you think?
-it's fine with me.
OK.
We ought to look for a new place.
This development's going to pot.
Bun appetit.
What do your friend's parents do?
Her mother has a shop.
I don't know about her father.
I'm off. Bye.
Sleep tight.
-Have a good shift.
She's not here, she's on duty.
Rudolph Hospital.
Good-bye.
Who was that?
-It was for Mom.
Room 408, Ms. Machant.
Machant - unchanged.
Kovac too - unchanged.
Guess who called me yesterday.
-Who?
Schneider.
-Schneider who?
Dr. Schneider.
What did he want?
Blah, blah, how I'm doing,
what's new, is everything OK?
Whether I still go swimming
once a week? Shit like that.
I told him I don't really have
time for this...
Mrs. Reichold?
Vomited twice.
She's not doing too good at all.
Then suddenly he goes:
Mrs. Keinrath, I'll get back to you
in a couple of hours. Bye.
His wife probably walked in right then.
Mrs. Zipfer...
Being discharged tomorrow.
Granddaughter's picking her up...
-Really? Nice girl. I like her.
So then a few hours later
he really calls...
A man's last suit has no pockets.
We've lost sight of that,
thus our current global state.
Let's go to sleep, shall we?
A man's last suit has no pockets.
No.
I don't feel like sleeping.
I'd rather think.
If I don't, no one will.
What do you think about?
You don't know beforehand.
You can't will yourself to think,
you gotta let it happen.
Then ideas just come to you.
You try that
when you've got some time.
I'll make us some more coffee.
Has he fallen asleep?
No, not really, he's just dozing.
It's quiet tonight.
Morning.
-Morning.
How was it?
Quiet.
Morning.
What are you doing in Vienna?
I wanted to see you again.
How did you know I work here?
I called your number.
Was that your daughter?
I didn't think
we'd see each other again.
How long are you staying?
I might be able to come back tonight.
I'll wait here.
What kept you?
-Things were chaotic last night. Bye.
Hello. You're late.
Coffee?
-Yes, please.
It was really chaotic.
The obscene elevator scribbler
struck again...
Yes, I noticed.
I'm on duty again tonight.
But we've got concert tickets.
I know, but Uschi is sick
and Monika's on vacation.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you call your sister?
She always says she's so lonely.
She locked herself out again.
What a scatterbrain.
I'm going for a jog.
Can you turn it down?
Your mom's sleeping.
Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Listen to this:
Apartment in a brand-new building,
centrally located, 120 sq m,
open design, big terrace,
quiet courtyard.
What do you think?
Sounds good.
-Shall I call them?
Could we look at it?
Hofstiitter. Yes, thank you.
Good-bye.
Tomorrow at 1 p.m.
The obscene scribbler
struck again...
You told me already.
When?
-This morning.
Did I?
He plays with such intense passion.
Are you almost done?
Just a second.
Enjoy the concert.
-Thanks.
And say hi to Edith.
-I will. Bye.
Good evening.
Can you connect me with Mr. Tomas...?
I've forgotten his last name.
It was the seventh floor, room...
Forget it.
Wanna grab a bite?
Let's go straight to your place.
-OK.
A glass of wine?
You had it developed already?
Yes.
Do you like it?
Wait.
May I blindfold you?
How long can you stay?
Till tomorrow morning.
Then let's go out to dinner.
What's wrong?
Do you know her?
I don't think so.
-Nope.
Yes you do, you know her.
I do not, how should I?
-You're lying.
You're back at her house?
And your friend's parents
let her stay out that late?
I'm back at the hospital.
The man you saw me with
was a colleague.
We went for a walk.
See you tomorrow.
Go down on me.
-Is that what you want?
The room-service waiter
watched you eating me out.
He was young, dark hair.
I wanted him to watch us.
I saw him come in.
Give me the camera.
I love you.
I've never fucked like this before.
Do whatever you want with me.
Spread your legs.
Now stroke yourself.
No, I can't.
Are you married too?
Children?
How old?
Five and seven.
How long are you staying?
My plane leaves tomorrow morning.
I can't come tonight.
Please don't stop.
Here's my number at the hospital.
Call me there instead,
if you want.
I'll miss you.
I better be going. Take care.
How was it?
Quiet.
And your concert?
-Good.
We're looking at that place today.
-When?
At one.
I better get some sleep then.
What about breakfast?
-I ate at work.
Sweet dreams.
How was it?
What?
-With your girlfriend?
Uh, OK.
We're looking at an apartment.
Want to come?
No, I have to study.
We have to leave in fifteen minutes.
I'll be ready in a sec.
I don't understand this.
-Maybe he forgot.
Let's go home.
Let me call him.
This is Hofstiitter.
We had an appointment at one.
Why aren't you here?
We're waiting for you.
We've been waiting for 20 minutes.
Why didn't you cancel?
What did you say?
What about my time?
He's not coming,
he already rented the place.
He has no qualms about wasting our time.
I won't stand for this.
I'm calling his agency.
The nerve of that guy.
Answering machine.
-it's Sunday.
I'm not letting them treat me this way.
Can we just go home?
The nerve of him. He's not normal.
You don't care.
-What makes you think that?
I'm no sucker.
And you don't even care.
That's not true,
but it's no use, it's Sunday.
I make an effort and no one cares.
What do you mean?
-I make an appointment, no one shows.
I get concert tickets,
you have to work.
What?
We discussed this.
A colleague got sick, it's not my fault.
I told you 2 months ago...
-You are so egotistical.
That's your opinion.
-Can we please just go?
Can I go to my friend's again?
What about your homework?
-I'm done.
What do you say?
-Fine with me.
Alright, but be back by eight.
I left something in the car.
Where are the keys?
Over there.
Thanks.
I'll be right back.
Hello, it's me, Eva.
You're there at the hotel
in our room.
What are you doing?
Looking at your pictures.
What do you plan to do with them?
Take them with me.
They turned out nice.
Come here.
Are you still there?
If only I could...
But I can't.
21 channels and nothing but crap.
What a joke.
These German film titles.
"The Dummy Crisis".
You scared me.
You're so nervous today.
-You just startled me.
What if we go to the movies tonight?
The movies?
Why not?
We haven't done that in a long time.
I've circled 3.
This one got good reviews...
Alright.
Are you OK?
-Why shouldn't I be?
There's something wrong...
-No, I'm fine.
What time does it start?
-7:30.
Don't move, I'll get a broom.
I'll call Iris to tell her
we're going out.
What was that?
Over there I think.
Did she scream for help?
Huh]
Probably just a marital quarrel.
Probably.
Back to the real estate section.
High time we got out of this place.
That weirdo again.
-Did he say anything?
They never say anything.
I'll have it traced next time.
Let's go to bed?
Do you want to go first?
No, go ahead.
Could you turn on the light for me?
No problem, mister.
You shouldn't be smoking
when you're pregnant.
I'm not pregnant.
Not pregnant?
I just said that because of Marco.
He wants a baby so bad.
We'd get married.
And he really thinks you're...
We even bought wallpaper
for the nursery.
How long has this been going on?
Two months.
I don't believe it.
Men are so stupid.
What's so funny?
I figured I'd tell him
and get pregnant right after.
I ovulate this weekend.
It could work,
people have premature babies.
Two months...
All I can say is "good luck".
Just look at this.
Someone tore 6 pages
out of this magazine.
Can you imagine?
Talk to the manager.
-Where is he?
Try the meat section.
-The nerve of some people.
Bottle receipt?
19.20, please.
Thank you.
Hey baby.
I'm on ladder now,
I call you right back.
I'm on ladder,
I call back. OK, ciao.
What a fox.
You think she screams
when you screw her?
Or does she just lie there?
I dunno, I first have to try her.
Shit.
I forgot.
Moment.
Marco, what's wrong with you?
You said you'd call right back.
You made me wait
like a fool for an hour.
If I say I'll call right back,
I call right back.
You don't love me.
Where are you anyway?
Who with?
And who else?
Nobody. Robert and me.
And billboard.
You know.
I come soon.
Ciao.
She is jealous woman.
-She's got good reason to be.
What reason? No reason.
I love her with my life.
-You people amaze me, man.
Hey, you marry with Astrid,
you know
whole life you fuck one woman.
Then come this woman,
she want fuck you,
you fuck her, no?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Simple, no?
You have only to use logic.
Where is he?
Hey man, that your car?
-Yeah, so what?
No standing, man.
I ain't allowed to be here?
You block my parking.
-I ain't allowed?
Move the car.
Don't shit your pants, Yugo,
you got plenty of room.
Move the shit.
-What did you say?
Move the shitcar.
-What did you say about my car?
Move the shit.
-Why so nervous, boy? Got a problem?
You asking for problem?
-A Yugo twerp ain't no problem for me.
Hello honey.
Honey,
sorry I was so angry on the phone.
No problem.
You're not angry with me?
-Naw, forget it.
I have question too.
-What?
You wanna go dance tonight?
-I'd love to.
You like go Yugo disco?
Tonight I can't come.
Say it to me tomorrow. I call you.
-Honey, you hungry?
We go out, eat there.
Gotta go.
I call you. Ciao.
You like her?
-Astrid?
She good woman. Strongwoman.
When we fuck, she's really loud.
I love that.
I'm wild about her.
When she comes,
she makes the strangest sound.
Never heard anything like it.
What sound she make?
It's hard to describe. Like yodeling.
Yodeling?
Not yodeling, but kinda like it.
I can't describe it.
Wow baby, I need a drink.
You must to try Bambus.
I'll get one for you.
You like this place?
-it's totally wicked.
Not same like yodeling?
Baby, there you are,
I look everyplace.
We go have drink.
What are we drinking to?
-Toast to my son.
Sonia is so good woman.
When doctor say she got pregnant,
no more cigarettes, no alcohol...
Nothing.
-That's great.
Isn't it boring not being able
to drink or smoke?
Not if you know why you're doing it.
Is cool song. C'mon, let's dance.
You sure got a sweet boyfriend.
-I know.
Saw you shakin' your fanny
with the Yugos.
Yeah, I dance if I have to.
Look, we put up these billboards too.
Right Marco? That's our work.
All billboards is our work.
What do you wanna do now?
-I have idea.
What?
We drive to place I know.
Good idea. You drive, I roll.
Go easy, is strong shit.
Here, Sonia.
Hey, she is pregnant woman.
Sorry.
I forgot.
You're so skinny.
People always think I'm pregnant,
but I'm not.
I think you're perfect.
Love handles.
Not like the floozies
on those billboards of yours?
They're not bad either, huh?
Yeah right...
Hey Astrid, my favorite song.
I teach you lyric.
"Long time ago..."
Uh, forget it.
He sing about a man who
leave his wife and become a rich man.
He lose all his money,
and then he go back.
Why he go back?
Nobody know. Just he know why.
And now
he say he make big mistakes.
Now he come back to see wife
before he die.
"...before I die." You like?
-Great lyrics.
Pretty, but sad.
-Is same like real life.
What's so sad about it?
First he leaves her
and then he's all remorseful.
It's just a song.
You're not leaving me,
though, are you?
Not anytime soon.
Listen, listen. Song continues.
Baby, what's the problem?
Baby, tell me.
You couldn't take your eyes off her
all evening.
You and your Astrid.
Baby, baby.
Do I do that to you?
You think I'm stupid?
You think I'm blind and don't see it?
I don't do that to you.
-You and your silly head...
You don't love me.
But baby, I love only you.
You don't call when you say you will.
I always call if I say so.
Baby,
I told you already I was on ladder.
Astrid is Robert's girlfriend.
My woman is you, only you.
Really?
You are mother of my child.
Let's go upstairs.
What you doing?
Gymnastics.
I hear baby.
-Marco, that's impossible.
It's this big.
Like a worm.
Yes, yes I hear, small sound.
Marco, that's impossible.
Bottle receipt?
-No.
6.18, please.
Bottle receipt?
Have a nice weekend.
Hi. Which pizza do you want?
Provenciale, Cardinale,
Diabolo, Margarita?
Provenciale. OK. Kisses.
You catch that ovulation window?
I dunno yet.
You oughta be able to tell right away.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
-Nothing.
Something is wrong.
-it's nothing.
Tell me what's the problem.
-You know exactly what it is.
I don't know if you don't talk?
-Whose number is that?
What number?
The number in your pocket.
Do you think I'm stupid?
In pocket from my jacket?
-Yes.
In my jacket is problem?
Telephone number in my...
-Yes.
Come. I show you...
No, I don't want to.
-Come.
No.
-Come now.
I show you problem.
-Let me go.
Look: 9670.
Hi, Sonia wants say you something.
There, you want talk? Talk.
What's up?
Fine thanks.
Visiting her grandpa at the hospital.
What do you want from her?
Yeah sure...
Bye.
Honey...
Honey, sorry.
Honey, please say something.
I thought you didn't love me anymore.
That's not true.
But sometimes is difficult, Sonja.
-Then you're not angry?
C'mon, don't cry.
Come here.
Robert must think I'm completely crazy.
We go for walk.
I go for walk with Fipsi.
-OK.
Fipsi, going for another walk so late?
First walk only last 10 minute,
poor Fipsi.
OK, see you.
See you.
I don't know any Marco.
My name's Mario. Bye.
OK, ciao.
-Ciao Marco.
Ciao Fipsi.
Come by tomorrow.
Mario won't be here
and we can be wilder.
-I dunno...
I call you, yes?
I want to go for walk,
but turn into marathon.
Hello honey.
I'm tired.
We do it tomorrow, OK?
Hi. It's Sonia. ls Marco there?
Nothing.
It's just he forgot his cell phone.
Bye.
Hello, awake already?
Mario?
Yes he's right here, but who are you?
Hello?
Baby, brush.
Finished.
Is good, yes?
-Nice.
You don't like?
-I do, it's great. Fine.
I do job like pro.
-Yeah, great.
I feel like smoking cigarette.
-Go ahead, have one.
It's OK?
-We can open the window afterwards.
You allow me?
-Yes.
I do just one time.
Maybe we should have taken
the teddy bear wallpaper?
No, that's too dark.
Baby must to have light.
Better this one.
Better I smoke on balcony.
Baby...
You sleeping?
I go for walk with Fipsi.
-OK.
Baby?
Shit.
Marco Jukic.
My girlfriend swallow pills.
Mitterhofergasse 2,
apartment 5, section...
Uh, apartment 32, section V.
Moment, I must to look...
Different pills...
Mogadon and Halcion.
Moment.
Yes, breathing, breathing.
Come quick. Please.
Sonia, wake up.
Yes, yes.
Breathing, yes.
In bed,
on back, yes.
Hi Kurt. Hello.
Patient ingested a mixture
of Mogado, Halcion,
and alcohol.
We found her lying unconscious
on her bed.
Please, not going to die, no?
-Don't worry. Wait outside.
Here are pills she swallow.
-I know, thank you.
We have a room for you now, Doctor.
We'll wake you in time.
I'd like to leave this.
For Eva Hofstiitter.
I'll see her in the morning.
Internal medicine ward.
I know Eva.
Don't take shit from nobody,
remember that.
Surprise.
What's that for?
I shot it for you.
I bought a convertible.
A Le Baron. Color: petrol.
Great.
Want to see it?
-No time. I'm waiting for someone.
It's down in the garage.
You can't park there.
What?
-You don't live here anymore.
What's so hard about going downstairs
to check out my new wheels?
You read about the
new car smuggling ring?
Turks and Polacks,
they'll rob you blind.
Better not mess with me.
Let me show it to you.
You know I don't care about cars.
OK. Maybe next time.
We can go for a little drive.
Please leave.
Way to go Mario.
There, blow up the asteroid.
Get lost, now.
-In a minute.
I said now.
Sorry about the vase,
no hard feelings, huh.
I don't give a damn about the vase.
Get out of my apartment.
Why so nervous? I won't hurt you.
Don't take no shit, right Mario?
Get out of my apartment.
Get your foot out.
You don't get it, that's the problem.
Get your foot out of my door.
-Alright.
Look at you,
you're totally hysterical.
Totally hysterical.
You're a thug, a common thug.
Hey man, that your car?
-Yeah, so what?
No standing, man.
I ain't allowed to be here?
-You block my parking.
I ain't allowed?
-Move the car.
Don't shit your pants, Yugo,
you got plenty of room.
Move the shit.
-What did you say?
Move the shitcar.
-What did you say about my car?
Move the shit.
Why so nervous, boy?
Got a problem?
You asking for problem?
-A Yugo twerp ain't no problem for me.
Rabitsch speaking, hello.
Just a second.
Don't you dare scratch my car.
So, what do we have for you?
Let's see, there's
tomorrow.
How about ten o'clock?
Then maybe
two o'clock. OK?
House number 53,
I'll be waiting inside the apartment.
Thank you. Good-bye.
Come here.
Don't be scared.
Wow, you got nice car.
Thanks.
How about the two of us?
How much?
Blow job - 50,
you want more, you pay a little extra.
I got an alarm system too,
to keep Polacks off my car.
So, what about us?
Too expensive.
What you want anyway?
-I wanna fuck.
Normal fuck?
-Yeah, normal.
How much you pay for fucking?
-Nothing.
Nothing.
Because I don't need this.
I can have any woman I want, for free.
Now get lost.
Stinkin' slut.
Stinkin' sluts, every last one of 'em.
Great, the agency gave me
my own apartment.
Mom, you gotta see a doctor,
I can't help you there.
Next week looks bad, I'm so busy.
I'll call you. Bye.
Hello, Rabitsch.
Mr. Gruber, we spoke on the phone today.
Come in.
Feel at home.
Come in. Feel at home.
When is it due?
-In two weeks.
I have a son, this tall.
With a little tasteful decoration...
We'd have to tear out the tiles.
Once you move in,
you'll give the place
your own personal touch.
Bathtub for two.
Do you like it?
I bet you like that.
This is for the washing machine,
the sink...
This would be the entrance hall.
How cute. What's its name?
Sammy.
Living room...
A bit dark, isn't it?
Yes well,
it's kind of a hazy day today.
No foreigners in this house,
family friendly,
dog friendly, animal friendly.
As a matter of fact,
the vibrations here are better.
What's that odd-looking thing?
Well, that's a cute little idea.
A round window,
to let in extra light
because this would probably
be the TV area.
What about the nursery?
It'll be cramped.
The nursery...
It is kinda small, huh?
It's a two-room apartment.
That's what the ad said.
We thought it would be bigger.
And here's the extra bonus:
An 80 sq m terrace in heart of the city.
You can't even just walk out onto it...
And this wall protects your privacy.
You can grow ivy on it,
or Virginia creeper or whatever...
Do you like it?
-No.
Because we hope
one day he'll have a big family
with lots of kids
running around all day.
Does it face south?
-Southeast.
That office building is awfully close...
Sit.
Down.
Nice dog.
Can I give him a nibble?
Is that a Le Baron?
3.0 L V6.
Horsepower?
-140.
Come. Heel.
New vase.
-I don't want to see you anymore.
And something for the vase.
Sorry about yesterday.
Thank you.
Mario wet his bed again.
He didn't get that from me.
Where is he, in his room?
-Can't you hear him?
Could you stop coming here?
Nicole, I want to talk to you.
Like normal people.
But you won't listen to me,
that's the problem.
OK, then talk.
I sold an apartment yesterday.
The third one this week.
Do you know what that is?
It's an agency record.
That's what you wanted to say?
-I just want to talk to you.
I don't want you around.
I'm tired of being beaten
every other day,
of getting in trouble for
forgetting your beer,
of getting raped...
-Don't start this shit again.
I was mad 'cause
you didn't wanna fuck.
I'm tired of fucking
whenever you feel like it.
You don't understand
what goes on up here.
Then tell me and then leave.
Listen Nicole.
These are hard times for you,
I know,
what with the separation and all...
But you have to come to grips
with yourself.
You're just distraught.
Come to grips with myself?
Yes.
I'm distraught?
How are you?
What are you doing?
Yes, I'm waiting for you.
Can't wait to see you.
No, he's here.
Look at this.
I think he hurt himself.
Can I call you back?
What have you done.
-Look at this.
Wait. Sit down.
Hold still.
What's that?
-iodine.
Does it burn?
-Naw.
Your present, I almost forgot.
Want me to get it?
I don't want any presents.
Daddy hurt himself.
Doesn't matter.
Minor cut, nothing serious.
Come down with me and
see my convertible.
I don't care about your convertible.
Then I'll bring it up. I don't mind.
Is that OK?
Does it hurt?
Here.
Give it to your new girlfriend.
-Come on.
You like the color?
It was either silver or petrol,
but I figure petrol is cooler.
Let's go for a drive.
Alex, I don't want to.
That's OK.
You'll come around.
Look.
Alarm system.
Sure you don't want to?
Next time.
Bye.
Come over here.
Come on.
How are you?
Fine.
Thought about it?
You and me, baby?
Blow job - 50.
Fucking - 200.
Hey, do I look like someone
who has to pay for a fuck?
Do I look like someone
Look at me.
Do you really think I need that?
Go ahead and think it over.
Come quick, there's idiot here.
What are you doing here?
Just standing.
Ain't nothing against that?
This here is a no parking zone.
-Yeah? I hadn't noticed.
Hey, are you crazy?
You can't piss in my car.
What car?
It's as good as gone.
You heard the man: no parking zone.
Lousy, fuckin' bitches.
Shit.
I know.
I had another appointment.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
Bye.
Assholes.
There they are, those jerks.
Hello, Rabitsch.
Sorry, I had another appointment.
Come in.
Sorry.
Well?
We'll think about it.
Think about it.
Good-bye.
Sorry, we won't be taking it.
It's too expensive.
Go fuck yourself.
I beg your pardon?
C'mon, let's get out of here.
Won't understand this.
Maybe he forgot.
The apartment's already taken.
What do you want from me?
It's taken.
Don't you think
I've got better things to do?
The apartment is gone.
Time is money, man.
Your time ain't worth
diddly squat to me.
Somethin' wrong?
I said it's over...
-Gotta talk to you.
I don't want to talk.
Get your foot out.
Alex stop it. I'll scream.
In front of Mario?
He's at my mother's.
Then we got the place to ourselves.
Help!
Stop being ridiculous.
I just want to talk.
You left this in the car.
I don't want it.
Give it to your new floozy.
Very funny. Now take it.
Or I'll get angry.
Look Nicole.
Let's be reasonable.
I hit you again,
but that's not what I want.
You just don't get it.
This is our Chinese restaurant.
I always used to get the chicken.
Swimming pool.
Look,
remember that old jacket?
Amazing.
Look, I still had long sideburns here.
And this is
carnival 1997.
I puked for three days after that.
I missed an appointment this morning.
Kept those jerks waiting half an hour.
Who are you calling?
That's the police.
Are you dense or something?
We don't need the police,
I'm not hurting you.
Where was this?
Maybe in Schwechat?
We sure make a great-looking couple.
Cheers.
Nicole, your problem is you don't talk.
I've got my flaws too.
Look, I don't have a new girlfriend,
I just said that.
Women are stupid anyway,
except for you.
I've got someone new.
-I know, consider it forgotten.
No problem, I forgive you.
I'm dying to see
how this looks on you.
If I try it on, will you leave?
Yeah, put it on... Please.
Great.
Fits great.
I'm cold.
OK. Get dressed.
Thanks.
Can you go now?
Not until you get it through your head
that I love you.
That just doesn't seem to sink in.
Good evening.
I'd like to order some food.
Mitterhofgasse 2,
section IX,
apartment 27.
Hold on. I'll call back in a second.
Help!
It's me again.
Yes.
I'd like a pizza Capricciosa
and a Del Amore.
Excellent.
Bye.
Sorry, but you leave me no choice?
Do you want to throw all this away?
And this?
What more do you expect me to do?
I'm sorry.
Everything's going wrong,
I don't know why.
It's 'cause you won't listen to me,
Nicole, I love you.
You're the most kick-ass woman
in the world.
Can't you just leave me alone?
That's beside the point.
OK, I made a mistake,
but I've changed.
You must have noticed.
Why do you think I'm doing all this?
The roses, lingerie,
vase, the convertible.
What can I do
to make you understand?
You always blow things.
I plan a nice evening
and you go and ruin it.
How do you expect us
to go on this way?
I don't, we're through.
You're the one who doesn't get it.
Is that him?
Don't you dare hurt him.
I don't have to take this.
Sorry man, I come see...
No problem, come in.
Nicole's here.
How cute, what's its name?
Hi there, Fipsi.
I don't stay long...
-No problem.
Lock the rat in the bedroom, Yugo.
Close the door.
Move.
Hi.
Sit down.
That's him.
The Yugo with the ridiculous Renault?
With knife you big strongman.
Bravo.
Bravo, your man is realman.
I'm strong without the knife, boy.
Get up.
Don't.
Stop it.
Get up. Or ain't you got the balls?
Got the message, boy?
You're such an asshole.
Get out of my life,
out of my apartment.
I don't need your roses.
I hate you.
But Nicole, that's not true.
You're bleeding.
Is it broken?
-No, I need napkin.
Come to the bathroom.
He's such an asshole.
I'm sorry.
You die.
I don't have to take this.
He's always been an asshole.
I'm so sorry.
He'll always be an asshole.
At least nothing's broken.
Does it burn?
-No.
I don't fuckin' have to take this.
What the fuck...
Fuckin' piece of shit.
Never again.
Shut up.
Piece of shit clunker.
Assholes.
I don't believe this.
Damn it.
The gentleman has already checked out.
Gone for good?
He checked out an hour ago.
-He must have taken the earlier flight.
May I go up to his room,
I forgot something.
I'll send up a maid.
Can I take care of it myself?
It's personal.
I'm afraid I can't do that...
Please, it's very important.
Please.
Here you go.
-Thank you.
Is it broken?
My arm, yes.
That lunatic ran a red light back there,
am I glad nothing worse happened...
There should be some pictures
in the car.
I dropped them.
I'll have a look.
Thanks.
It's me.
Please stop shouting at me.
I'm in a hotel.
No, I'm not alone.
I'll be staying here tonight.
No, I don't want a divorce.
I just have a lover.
Let's talk about it tomorrow.
Good night.
It's me again.
Wait.
I forgot to mention I have the car.
You'll have to take the subway tomorrow.
Bye.
Everything's the way it should be.
We have a good life together.
Dead?
Car accident?
Thank you. Bye.
Here you go.
Want a sandwich?
Hey baby.
Nurse give me vase.
I ran into door.
Was so nervous.
Dying isn't hard at all.
Strange.
Baby, why you did this?
Is no reason to.
Because I lost the baby.
But baby, no problem.
We make new baby.
You say baby so small like worm,
so small.
How's Fipsi?
Bye.
Well, do they know what I have yet?
Still haven't found a thing.
You're a mystery, Mr. Riedel.
-Not to me, I know what I have.
I think you're making a fool of us all.
People make fools of themselves.
I know you from housing.
We live in same housing.
Hello.
I want ask question.
My girlfriend in hospital.
She swallow pills...
Doctor say
she must to make psychiatry...
No, no.
She'll just be talking with
a therapist
to find out what happened.
But she is not crazywoman,
just lose child.
Don't worry, it's routine procedure.
In summer we marry, you know.
How nice.
Good luck.
Good-bye.
-Ciao.
Translation: Kimi Lum