THE KID WITH A BIKE
Hang up, Cyril.
It's like last time.
The number's not in service.
Hang up.
Give it here.
You dialled it wrong!
Let me do it.
Ok, but put the loudspeaker on.
If you get that message again,
hang up. Ok?
Yes.
Go on.
The number dialled is not in service.
You heard?
Go and play.
I'll call the janitor.
We did that. You heard him.
Your dad's moved out.
You must accept it.
He'd have brought my bike.
Ask the janitor where he is.
He doesn't know!
Give me the phone!
No!
Get off me!
Cyril!
Alain! Catch him!
Cyril, get down from there. Let go!
Let go! You'll hurt yourself.
Let go, Cyril!
Calm down!
Just calm down, ok.
Finished?
Come on.
Where are you off to?
The toilet.
Use the urinals.
It's a big job.
- You told the supervisor?
- Yes.
Go on then.
Is this the Val-Potet bus?
- No, number 2 there.
- Ok, thanks.
Janitor.
It's Cyril, to see my dad.
Cyril?
Cyril Catoul. 5th floor.
Your dad left a month ago.
His name's here.
He's gone.
- Can't I go up?
- No one's there.
But I'd like to...
Medical practice.
Hello?
I fell off my bike...
Ground floor,
the blue door before the lift.
Dad!
Dad, are you there?
What's going on?
No one lives there.
My dad does.
The place is empty.
Just ask the janitor.
Don't stay here. Go back down!
Go on!
Just go back down, ok.
Cyril!
Wait!
You fell off your bike?
- You got lost in the building?
- A bit.
It's simple enough.
- Where are you hurt?
- My leg.
- Is it bleeding?
- No.
- Did you bang your head?
Give me your name.
We're his counsellors.
He ran away from school...
Be reasonable. Come with us.
Did you hear me? Come on!
Let go of the lady!
Come with us!
Not so tight, that hurts.
Leave the lady now.
I'm staying at Dad's!
He's moved out.
My bike's here too!
You can hold me but not so tight.
- Come on, Cyril.
- No!
I can let him see the apartment.
You heard the janitor?
We'll go and see
your dad's place, ok?
Sorry about that.
Coming now, Cyril?
Cyril...
The director wants to see you.
Get up. I knowyou're there.
The others are already at breakfast.
Going to get up?
- What time is it?
- Ten to nine.
It's Saturday.
I have ten more minutes.
The director wants to see you.
You have to go.
You're not getting up?
I'll tell him
you won't see him then.
Remember the lady you held
at the medical practice?
She's here to talk to you.
Do you hear what I'm saying?
I've got your bike.
- You sawmy dad?
- No.
How did you find it?
Get dressed.
You told the janitor
it was black with a chrome fork.
So I looked for one like that.
Where was it?
I saw a boy riding it on the estate,
so I bought it off his dad.
Bought it?
He said your dad sold it to him.
He's a liar.
He stole it and sold it back to you.
Or it's not mine.
It's scratched there. It's mine.
He stole it from my dad.
- Howmuch did you pay?
- Never mind.
Maybe your dad needed money
for bills.
He'd never have sold it.
- Thank the lady.
- Thank you.
Watch this!
Bravo!
Watch.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye. Thank you.
Coming for breakfast now?
Cyril, watch out!
Cyril, come back!
Can I stay with you at weekends?
I'll need to ask the director.
He'll agree,
he needs foster families. Ask him.
No, I'm already late for work.
I'll call him. Goodbye.
You say that but you won't.
I will.
Goodbye.
I don't knowhim.
But he told me he came here.
Maybe he said where he was going.
I don't remember him
so even less what he said.
Let me by.
He had a golden helmet. That's rare.
I don't remember. Cut it out.
Yes.
I'm riding my bike
around the neighbourhood.
A boy tried to steal it.
Maybe the one you bought it from.
What colour was his hair?
Tell me anyway.
It wasn't him.
I'll ride a bit more, then come back.
You were with him?
Yes, one Sunday morning.
I remember him
but didn't knowhe'd moved.
I can't help you.
Ok, goodbye.
- You're his son?
- Yes.
- He didn't say where he was going?
- He did but I forgot.
He filled his motorbike here.
He had a golden helmet.
Was it an old BMW 750?
Yes, green and chrome.
He put up an ad for his motorbike.
In the shop windowthere.
When was that?
About a month ago.
Where he was moving to?
Why would he tell me?
Maybe there's an address
on the ad.
For sale: BMW750 motorbike
and child's bicycle
Guy Catoul,
Bergerie block, 5th floor, Val-Potet
Cyril, turn the tap off, please.
Excuse me...
I'll be done in five minutes.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Cyril, say goodbye.
I hate water being wasted.
What's wrong?
Is it that boy
who tried to steal your bike?
Someone spoke to you about your dad?
You're off to a great start here!
Tell me what's wrong.
I can't guess, Cyril.
You heard the psychologist.
Coming to your dad's neighbourhood,
you'd think about him too much.
Maybe I should just have you
on Sundays.
We could go to the country
or the sea,
then I'd drive you back.
What do you think?
Cyril, look at me.
I'd like to see the man
you got my bike from.
Why? To tell him he's a thief?
No. My dad sold it.
I saw an ad at the petrol station.
What'll you say to him?
I'll ask him about my dad.
I still have his number.
Shall we call him?
Yes.
Turn the tap off.
Don't use up your credit.
Mr Gurza.
04336...
Hi.
Cyril... Gilles, my friend.
Hello.
What's the number?
043366310.
Hello... Mr Gurza?
I'm calling about my bike.
This is Cyril Catoul.
When my dad sold it to you,
did he say where he was moving?
Yes, Guy Catoul's my dad.
Did he say where he was moving?
He really didn't say?
Goodbye.
- Why aren't you coming?
- I'm scared.
With me, you won't be.
I'll watch you both.
Here, Cyril.
Go on.
I'm going alone!
No, it's dangerous.
I have to be with you.
- Stay here!
- I'm going alone!
- What if there's a problem?
- I don't need you!
Samantha!
Stay here! Calm down.
He wants to go alone!
No, not on your own!
Sit down, Cyril!
Sit down!
Can I sit down?
What is it?
I want my dad.
It's warm.
What is?
Your breath.
Let me.
Turn the handlebars.
Give me your bag, Cyril.
Goodbye.
See you on Monday.
- Who gave you his address?
- The police.
What did the director say?
He hopes it'll go well.
But he couldn't get the address.
He could have
but he wanted to let your dad
take the first step.
So did the psychologist.
But my dad told you
he wanted to see me.
Not that he wanted to,
that he agreed to.
- Same difference.
- No.
If he'd wanted to,
he could have called.
No one's stopping him.
Don't be upset if it's not the way
you dream it'll be.
I'm not dreaming.
Another sandwich?
No.
Some water?
Please.
Thank you.
- What?
- Thank you.
I couldn't see him.
He'll probably come that way.
He's not coming.
You should have given him
your number just in case.
Let's go to his place.
What if he's on his way?
He's 40 minutes late.
Let's go to his place.
I'll just check that street.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello.
Could we talk to Guy Catoul?
He's not here. Who are you?
He's my dad.
He was supposed
to meet his son at 10.
He wasn't there so we came here.
Where can we find him?
Who are you?
Cyril stays with me at weekends.
You know Guy?
No, I sawhim once
to fix the appointment.
He's prepping my restaurant kitchen.
The 'Acacia', by the bridge.
- This side of the river?
- The other.
Thank you. Goodbye.
It's too loud. He can't hear us.
There he is!
Dad!
He's gone in the back.
There's a door in the alley. Come on.
I'll climb up.
I can see him!
He's bringing the bins out.
Dad!
Dad! I'm here!
- What's up?
- I've come to see you!
Do I jump
or can you open the door?
Go round the front.
Round the front.
I'll wait here.
Come on in.
Want a drink?
- Want a drink?
- Yes.
- What?
- I dunno.
Coke, peach juice,
pear juice, water...
Peach.
- What?
- Peach.
Peach.
Is the woman nice?
She's ok.
It's good she can have you weekends.
- Going to be a hairdresser?
- No.
I have work to do in the kitchen.
Come on.
She bought my bike back.
That's great. I had to sell it.
I was in the shit.
That's ok.
When are you coming for me?
- Where?
- At the home.
They're not nice?
You said it was only for a month.
It's not easy for me.
I wanted to call
but why bother if I couldn't come?
That's ok.
You changed your number?
I sold my mobile.
I can't have you back with me, see.
Not yet anyway.
I need to put some money by.
I need a flat and all that.
When will that be?
I don't know.
Samantha got me a mobile.
You could call me at weekends.
Want to note the number?
Just a second.
Go on.
0479...
69...
56...
23.
What's the number here?
There isn't one.
Well, you mustn't call.
My boss doesn't want that.
I'll call you.
What's that?
Sauces.
Choron and Caribbean.
Time to go. I have work to do.
Can I stir it?
Go on. Careful, it's hot.
Off you go.
I have stuff to do before we open.
Give me the spoons.
When do you open?
At midday. In half an hour.
I'll come with Samantha.
You can't, we're full.
- Are you hungry?
- Yes.
What do you want? Sausage?
Crisps? With paprika or salt?
Paprika.
Let's go.
- Want one?
- No.
When'll I see you?
I'll call you.
Next Saturday?
I'll try. I'll call you, ok.
If you can't reach me,
I'll come back here.
Hold on...
Can I have a quick word?
No, wait here.
I didn't come because I can't.
It's too much.
I can't look after him.
Nowhis gran's gone, I'm all alone.
I can't. It's too much for me.
I could bring him an hour
at weekends.
No, seeing him stresses me out.
He likes you. Look after him.
He wants you, not me.
He'll forget me.
I'm starting over.
With him around, it won't work.
I just can't look after him.
Even once a month would be good.
No, please, take care of him.
I don't want to see him again.
Tell him I can't.
You should tell him yourself.
I've tried but I can't.
What did your dad say?
That he'd call, maybe Saturday.
I gave him my mobile number.
Come with me.
- Why?
- Come on!
He heard us.
- What is it?
- You have to tell him, not me.
Tell him.
Don't try to see me again.
Stay at the home or with her.
You'll be ok.
You won't be calling me?
I don't know.
No.
No! Cyril!
Stop that!
It's all right...
We're one short. Want to play?
After I take the shopping back.
I'm going to play five-a-side.
There's...
4 euros 60 left.
Put it on the counter.
Thanks.
Howmuch was it?
I dunno.
Work it out. I gave you 10 euros.
- 5 euros... 40.
- Yes.
- Give it back!
- Come and get it.
Attack, Pitbull! Go on, attack!
Go on, attack!
Make him cry! Go on, Pitbull!
Go on, bite him!
- That's good!
- Go on, bite him!
Go on!
Ok, Pitbull, you win!
Enough, I said!
Enough!
Come back down. Come down!
Wait!
Give me your hand.
You're wicked, Pitbull. Respect.
Shake his hand.
Respect.
I'm going with him.
Logan!
Wash my car. Nabil has the key.
Going to the estate?
- Yes.
- Me too.
It's flat.
It's full of nails and glass here.
I'll get the garage apprentice
to mend it.
I have no cash.
It's ok, I have some.
- It's a nail...
- Yeah.
Leave it in
so he knows where the hole is.
I'll carry it to the road.
Don't puncture the other.
Where do you live?
At Samantha the hairdresser's
near the square.
You're related to her?
No, I just stay at weekends.
Is she nice to you?
Yes.
- Smoke?
- No.
You're at the home in Theux?
- You knowit?
- I spent 3 years there.
We're made to get along.
Let me see your eye.
Hold my cigarette.
There's a speck of dirt.
Don't touch!
- Like PlayStation games?
- Yes.
Got one?
No, I use an old PS1 at the home.
I have a PS3
and the new Assassin's Creed.
Want to play?
All right.
What happened?
The TV remote fell
and I tried to pick it up.
Pitbull, pick up the remote.
Where's Grandpa?
At the chemist's.
I bet he stopped at the bar.
What channel?
Four.
Will you be ok?
Thank you.
Come on, Pitbull.
Pitbull.
Sit down.
Sit down here, Pitbull.
- You like me calling you Pitbull?
- Yes.
I'm Wes... Wesker,
like in Resident Evil.
- With the glasses!
- I always wore them before.
Hold on.
Don't say you're with me!
Yes.
No, I...
I didn't go and play with them.
I met other boys.
We're riding our bikes.
No.
Yes.
See you later.
- The hairdresser?
- Yes.
Mention me
and she'd have said, 'The dealer?'
Everyone around here thinks I deal.
The fuckers!
Seen me deal dope?
Did I offer you any?
No.
Here.
- It's cordless?
- Yes.
Want a drink?
Coke, Fanta, beer?
Fanta.
Dagger or sword?
Sword.
Press R2 and pick sword.
- Her again?
- Yes.
Don't answer. Ignore her.
Turn it off.
There...
Go on, play.
Faster or I'll slaughter you.
Dodge him!
You have to waste that shit.
Here, Pitbull.
Wait!
No other guy in the gang
has ever been here. Just you.
To our meeting.
Go on, play.
Watch out there.
There. Nice move.
Go on.
Bad headbutt.
Here.
Thanks.
- Thanks.
- See you.
I'll ask Samantha for 10 euros.
I don't need her money.
I'm glad to help you out.
I'm hungry, aren't you?
Kind of.
Good evening.
What is it?
I told you,
a job we could do together.
What kind of job?
I need to be able to trust you.
You can.
- Sure?
- Yes.
I'm not sure, Pitbull.
You seem a bit sly.
Hey, Pitbull...
You seem a bit sly, right?
I'm kidding! I trust you. Totally.
Here.
Want to move to my place?
I'm at Samantha's.
Change foster home.
There's a free room.
My grandparents would agree.
- Want me to ask them?
- Ok.
It's Samantha!
I'll handle it.
See you Saturday.
I've been looking all over for you!
He had a flat.
I took him to the garage.
Shut up!
Your bike.
- I'll ride back.
- You're coming with me!
See you.
Keep away from that dealer!
He helped me.
Why didn't you call?
Why didn't you answer your phone?
Why didn't you answer?
Tell us.
I didn't hear the phone.
- Liar!
- Liar yourself!
Apologize!
Apologize for that!
Apologize, Cyril.
Apologize or you won't come back.
Don't say that.
No one can say a thing.
He's running rings around you.
Last week, he had a fit of nerves,
today we look for him for hours
and he insults me?
Apologize or don't come back.
You've no right to say that!
It's him or me.
You hear? It's him or me.
Him.
Gilles!
See, it's off.
It was while I was pedalling...
Never mind. You could have called
when you got a puncture.
Get the water.
I don't knowwhy you didn't call.
Why didn't you think
I could help you?
Or that I'd be worried about you?
I forgot the forks.
Answer me!
I don't know. I didn't think.
Wait for me.
Enjoy.
Why did you want me to come here?
You're the one who asked.
But why did you agree?
I don't know.
Promise me one thing, Cyril.
Keep away from that guy.
Don't let him come near you again.
You promise?
Yes.
He lowers the shutter...
He locks it...
Turned your phone off?
I'm doing it now.
I'll leave it at Samantha's tonight.
There.
He comes over to the corner...
He passes you...
He's carrying all the unsold papers.
He puts them down...
He opens the car boot...
He bends to pick them up...
No!
The bag on his wrist first.
Right...
Empty it out.
No!
Right...
Ok.
Look at me.
If you forget the bag
and his pockets?
- I won't forget.
- What does that mean?
I knowwhere the money is.
And that means?
They'll suspect you because
you worked at the newsagent's.
That means you'd be betraying me
to the cops!
- Want to put me in jail?
- No.
- What comes first?
- The bag.
- Second?
- His jacket pockets.
And third, his belt thing.
Come on...
Practise with this.
It won't kill him?
No, but hold it at the bottom.
Grip it tight. That's good.
Pitbull!
Tie this on me.
Howmuch do you want? 500 euros?
No, nothing.
So why do it?
For you.
Stop that, Cyril!
What are you doing?
- You stay in if I say so!
- Why?
I don't want you out alone at night!
Go to the movies with Mourad.
I'll only ride my bike.
Who with? The dealer!
He hasn't got a bike.
He's always around,
trying to hire other kids.
He knows you're new!
I'm going out!
Stop it!
That's Mourad.
Come on.
Go to the movies
with him and his parents.
Mourad wants to be your friend.
His mum told me.
Come on...
No.
- Hello.
- I've come for Cyril.
Come in.
He doesn't want to go.
Come and ask him.
Why won't you come?
- Come on...
- No.
It's in 3D, it'll be fun.
I don't want to.
Go on, Cyril.
No!
Come on.
Ok... Bye.
Bye.
Coming to the match tomorrow?
Yes. What time?
- Two o'clock.
- See you then.
Apologize to your parents.
Cyril!
Cyril, get down!
Get down!
Calm down, ok!
You're not my dad or my mum!
I want to go back to the home!
If you want to go back, fine!
Call them and I'll take you.
I'm not staying with you!
Open up!
Cyril, come back!
Hello, this is Samantha,
Cyril's foster family.
Can I speak to a counsellor?
Yes.
All right.
Dad, I can't lock the shutter.
What's going on?
Did he see you?
- I think so.
- You think so?
I had to turn to him to hit him.
Take this!
Why?
Take it!
It was your idea. You did it alone.
If you say I was involved,
I'll kill you! Got that?
Now get out!
- But...
- Get out!
Did you forget what I said?
I have something for you.
Where's it from?
I stole it but no one knows.
One meatballs with extra chips! Guy!
Coming up.
I won't tell the cops
I gave it to you.
Clear off!
I won't tell.
You'll put me in jail!
- I won't tell...
- Shut up! Climb!
Jump!
Are you ok?
Yes.
Don't ever come back here!
The police are after you
for the newsagent.
We have to go. Put your bike away.
I'll get my keys.
Samantha...
I'm sorry I hurt your arm.
I'd like to live with you.
All the time.
All right.
Give me a kiss.
As the money has been found,
the damages requested
by Mr Surlet and his son Martin
amount to their hospital fees
and the loss of earnings
caused by six days closure,
namely a total of 1,750 euros.
As the accomplice, Steve Deschamps,
is insolvent and currently in prison,
Ms. Samantha Puccio,
guardian of the attacker,
Cyril Catoul,
will pay the victims
the full sum
in 20 monthly instalments.
Do you have anything to add?
No.
And you?
Will you make a full apology
to Mr Surlet now?
Yes.
Will you accept his apology?
Go on then.
I apologize to you
for the money I stole
and for hitting you on the head,
you and your son.
I accept your apology.
You can stand
and shake Mr Surlet's hand.
Then we'll sign the agreement.
Why didn't your son come?
He won't accept your apology.
Change gear! A higher one!
- What gear are you on?
- No idea.
- What numbers on the handle?
- Eight.
That's twice mine.
- Can I try it?
- Sure.
I hadn't ridden a bike in ages.
- Time for a sandwich?
- Yes.
- Tuna?
I'll have cheese.
What'll we do this evening?
I don't know.
Let's invite Mourad and his parents
for a barbecue.
Where?
In the back yard.
I have the full kit in the cellar.
- Shall I invite Mourad?
- Ok.
Hello, it's Samantha.
Cyril and I would like you
to come to a barbecue.
Mourad, you and Jeannot.
Yes, bring them along.
All right.
At 6 o'clock.
Yes.
His two cousins are here.
- My age?
- More or less.
- How about you?
- What?
You're not inviting a friend?
Mind your own business!
Excuse me...
There's no charcoal?
Not until tomorrow.
They're out of charcoal. I can get
some from the petrol station.
I'll give you some money.
I hope they have some.
It's 5 or 6 euros.
I'll see you at home.
Yes.
There you go. Goodbye.
Hello. A bag of charcoal.
5 euros 80, please.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- There you are.
- Goodbye.
Hello.
Leave him. Get back in.
Martin!
What'll you do nowwithout that bat?
Go on, hit me!
I apologized...
Screwyour apologies!
Go on! Try to hit me!
I don't want to.
Just do it!
Come down, asshole!
Dad!
He climbed up
and I threw stones at him.
- Sure he's not moving?
- Yes.
What did you do that for?
- Where is he?
- Near a trailer...
Hold on...
Hold on.
If he's dead,
we'll say he insulted us
and you ran after him.
He climbed a tree to get away
and fell.
Did the stones hit him?
His hand's cut
but it doesn't have to be a stone.
It could be a branch.
Yes.
Get my mobile from the car
to call an ambulance.
You have concussion.
I should call an ambulance.
No.
Subtitling: CMC - Paris