Hurry up, it's a big day.
You don't want to make the
bride wait for you, do you?
The usual, boss.
Put it on my mom's tab.
All right, no problem
I was 16 that year
Chang Yu-Sheng's voice was
still heard on TV shows.
Jacky Cheung sold more than one million
cassettes for the "KissGoodbye" album.
The bookies hadn't started watching CPBL
and the classic Dragon-Elephant games
were always sold out.
That year
a girl with tanned skin won the
championship on the local talent show
for five consecutive rounds.
That year...
Those years.
My name is Ko Ching-Teng.
My friends called me Ko-Teng
I went to Jingcheng in Changhua City
for junior high school.
As for high school, I stuck
to the same one, too.
This is Hsu Bo-Chun.
He has been my best friend
since junior high school.
He's always getting a boner
that's why we named him "Boner".
Fuck!
Fuck what?
You are dead meat. Don't run.
This is A-Ho.
We have been in the same class all the way
from elementary to high school.
There is a fat guy in every story.
A-Ho is the fat guy in our story.
Stop bugging me.
Why not?
Good morning, Sir.
Good morning.
Your hair is too long.
It's time to get a haircut.
Gosh, can you stop that?
What?
Stop doing that
I have told you a million times!
Why not?
You totally wasted my food
I only had one bite of that hotdog.
So...
Don't you know how to catch?
Cock Tsao.
Why are you such a jackass in the morning.
You know what?
I won a Grant Hill 1 to 40
limited edition card yesterday.
This is Tsao.
We have been classmates ever since junior
high and he has always been an ass.
We called him.
(Cock, Cocky, Dumbass Tsao
or "Tsao motherfucker")
Show off?
We can switch then for your
1 to 100 Penny Hardaway cards.
No way!
Piss off, then.
The only thing that these
boys shared in common with...
was that they all had a crush
on the honor student in the class.
Shen Chia-Yi.
From my point of view.
Shen Chia-Yi was only slightly prettier
than the other girls.
Don't know what the guys were thinking.
Shen Chia-Yi.
Yes?
Did you watch Rose Night yesterday?
Are you talking about
the Taichi Gorge photo?
Yeah, the picture was horrifying
I got goose bumps all over.
The story sounds terrifying but...
I can't really tell from the picture though
I think it was the shooting
angle that does the trick.
You think so?
Now, start doing the exercises
for lesson five and six.
Continue after the assembly
if you can't finish.
Focus on your own exercises.
No discussion.
This is Liao Ying-Hung.
His surname, Liao, is a verb in Chinese.
And it means to scratch.
Since it's a verb
we should make good use of this verb.
Thus, we gave him a nickname.
"Groin" (Scratching Groin)
"Groin" likes Shen Chia-Yi, too.
That's because he likes
every girl in the class.
It's early morning and
everyone looks half asleep.
Stand straight.
Wake up!
Stop moving.
Stand up.
Attention.
Salute.
Good morning, Miss Chou.
Good morning, everyone. Sit down.
In year 1974, it was
still the Qing dynasty.
So it means that.
It was the thirty second year that China
was ruled under Emperor Qianlong.
There was really not that much difference
between junior high and senior high.
Just a matter of how deep you are in hell.
Endless studies, exams...
it's all very boring!
There is the character, the
time and then it's the place.
Where is the place?
The place...
But, we can always find a
way to entertain ourselves!
Hsu Bo-Chun
stand up and read the next section.
Stand up and read.
You don't even know where we are.
Hello... are you in the classroom.
Ko Ching-Teng
what are you laughing at?
You read it.
(Reading paragraphs from the textbook)
Stand up and read.
It's not very convenient.
What do you mean "not very convenient"?
Stand up.
Jerking off.
Jerking off right in the class
I have been a teacher for so many years
I have seen students who cheat
get into fights
black mail.
Or even those who beat up teachers!
I have seen all kinds
of problematic students
but just no perverts like you!
I didn't even ejaculate.
And that's an excuse?
Yeah.
We were just fooling around...
You, too.
Your parents spent so much money
to send you to school
and you guys don't even
cherish how lucky you are.
What's jerk off?
Jerking off in the classroom.
Hey?
I don't know.
Shen Chia-Yi
come out here for a second.
from now on, Ko Ching-Teng
will sit in front of you.
Keep an eye on him for me.
Don't let him be a bad influence on others.
Give him a push on his schoolwork, as well.
Okay?
Hsu Bo-Chun.
In the future
you will sit in front of Hsieh Ming-Ho.
The same goes for you.
Don't goof around again.
If you do, I will ask your
parents to come to school.
Get it?
Got it.
Now, go to your class.
Thank you, sir.
Even though Shen Chia-Yi and I have been
in the same class ever since junior high
the distance between an honor student
and a bad student
always stayed the same.
It's shitty luck to sit
in such a shitty seat.
Who has bad luck now?
You are sitting in front of me now.
You better stop your childish pranks.
So you don't bring me unnecessary troubles.
It must be nice to be an honor student.
Just because you have good marks
doesn't mean you can boss people around.
Who cares about what you think?
Don't mind him, don't let him bother you.
That's right.
He just likes to masturbate
in the classroom.
Fuck.
The reason you like to goof around is because
you don't concentrate on your studies.
Yeah.
You're so clever, you are such a smart ass.
A nerd like Shen Chia-Yi
likes to poke her nose into other people's
business whenever she gets a chance.
All you do is drawing these
retarded figures every day.
Where's the future in that?
It's none of your business
I'm pretty much minding my own business.
I just want to have a good laugh.
Moron.
How come every retard you drew is bald?
Do you discriminate against
bald heads or retards?
Mind your own business.
Man, you are as slow as a turtle!
Bye.
Ko-Teng.
What?
Stop giving Shen Chia-Yi a hard time.
Yeah right.
That's all.
That's all???
Every man wants to be the strongest man.
Including me.
One day
I will be as strong as my master.
You are D.E.A.D.
The fact that I am so reckless
has got something to do with my family.
Ma, shampoo is out.
Hey, put some clothes on.
You're a grown-up now
I know, it has grown so big, right?
My father also likes to walk around
butt naked in the house.
The school called today.
What's the big deal about coed school?
Concentrate at school.
Stop goofing around.
What did I do?
Eat first, while it's still hot.
Talk later.
Why are your grades always
in the bottom percentile?
Is it because you are thinking about
girls all the time, is that why?
No, I am not interested in girls!
I'm not interested in guys, either.
Speaking of girls.
Each one of my good friend
liked Shen Chia-Yi in a different way.
Groin, what are you doing?
Shen Chia-Yi
I have just invented a new magic trick
I want you to be the first one to see it.
Hu Chia-Wei, do you want to see it, too.
Is it a prank?
No way. It's amazing.
Look closely.
Basically, Groin was on the right track.
It's to cheer the girls
up and make them laugh.
Nothing in this hand, either.
Look closely.
Groin, you are such a bore.
Besides Groin's retarded magic.
Tsao had a very different
way to make girls happy.
Shen Chia-Yi.
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
And no one gets it.
A-Ho liked to read what grown-ups read.
So he knew many things that we didn't.
Shen Chia-Yi.
Do you remember the Air
Supply album that I lent you.
Um... I remember.
They are coming next month.
Do you want to go if I have tickets?
To Taipei?
We can take the train.
Hu Chia-Wei.
Do you want to go with us?
Yes, sure.
Sounds fun.
The adult's way is the most subtle way
to chase after Shen Chia-Yi.
Who is Air Supply?
Someone said.
Showing one's clumsy side
is also another way to pursuit girls
I think.
Boner has tried this many times.
Hsu Bo-Chun.
Can you stop playing?
And it proves that his
way doesn't work at all.
Me? Yes, there's also a girl I like.
But it's unlikely that we can develop
anything at that point in time.
That's fine
I will grow up.
One clay, I will turn to be
the man that deserves her.
That day.
Nobody knew if the English teacher
had lost money in the stock market
or her menstruation period went wild.
She had a shitty face.
She looked like she was
about to kill someone.
Stand up.
Sit down. Let's begin
I thought
it would be great fun to see the
smart ass student, Shen Chia-Yi
makes a blunder
I meant.
"I thought."
Stand up if you didn't bring your textbook.
Ko Ching-Teng
we have gone through a
third of this semester.
And you don't even have your English
textbook with you, which we use every day.
Are you serious about getting an education?
Chair.
Don't you know private
schools are expensive?
If you don't even have your textbook
then why do you even
bother coming to school?
Here to eat your lunchbox?
Lunch is essential!
Of course I have to eat it.
You think you're very funny, huh?
Have you no shame?
Raise your arms higher.
Raise them higher.
So weak! Didn't you eat?
Go do 10 rounds of squat jumps outside.
Did I ask you to put your hands down?
Higher!
(Reciting English textbook)
my friends
that in spite of the difficulties
and frustrations of the moment
I still have a dream
that in spite of the difficulties
and frustrations of the moment
I still have a dream.
It is a dream deeply rooted
in the American dream
I have a dream
that one day this nation will rise up.
(Shen Chia-Yi would be kind of cute
if she wasn't such a prude)
and live up the true meaning of its dream.
What are you thinking?
You've been weird all day long.
Nothing.
Do you need an exorcism?
You are thinking too much.
Head office announcement
Jay Chou in third year
please come to the head office now.
Sweet.
What?
Thank you for yesterday.
No big deal. I have no shame anyway.
Thank you.
Why not just buy me a drink?
It's weird to hear you
keep on saying "thank you".
Can I ask you a question?
Go ahead.
Why don't you want to study?
It's not like I don't want to
I am afraid if I really tried
I would be so good that I
would even scare myself.
You better watch out then if I do study
I would beat you immediately.
Wanna take up the challenge?
Sure, why not.
Ko Ching-Teng.
What?
This is a quiz I made up myself.
Take it and do it at home.
Bring it back tomorrow.
Are you for real?
A quiz made out of love.
And here is a math exercise book.
See the questions I've highlighted in yellow?
Do them three times.
You will probably score at
least 50% in the next quiz.
Only 50%
I didn't say it's easy to get good grades
I will give you some harder problems
after you finish the basics.
What do I owe you?
Why should I listen to you?
Because I don't want to look down on you.
Yeah right!
You can be so stuck up just because
you have good grades.
Go on then, I don't really care
I don't look down on people with bad grades
I look down on you because
you pick on people with good grades
while you don't even try to work hard.
Put on some clothes.
Otherwise you'll catch a cold.
That's impossible.
My master is Bruce Lee.
Swallow your food before you speak.
Why is our tissue paper
running out so fast?
What?
Your quiz.
You made so many mistakes.
You did the problems without reading
the exercise book, didn't you?
You can find the answers for these
two problems in the exercise book.
This one is harder.
It's not the kind of problem
you can solve with a formula.
You need to use these theories.
You go home and read the parts I circled.
It's such a pain to study.
That's why people who are
good at studying rule.
Why are you helping Ko Ching-Teng to study?
Did you see his grades?
It's none of your business.
They are really bad.
Still, it has nothing to do with you.
Miss, this is yours and this is yours.
Thank you!
It's so not you
I hate people who are lazy and have
no sense of self-awareness at all.
Ok
I'm not talking about you.
You sure?
It's so boring to study
I don't understand
why Shen Chia-Yi can do this every day.
Do you have any idea?
Let me tell you.
Being able to solve these
tricky math questions.
Does nothing good in life!
Here.
Why do you work so hard?
No, I just study when I feel like it.
If you want to study, study hard then.
What do you mean "when you feel like it"?
Fine, I will think about it.
Eat porridge.
Don't finish it too quickly.
By the way
there was a new shipment in the store a few days ago.
The whole package was unopened
so the store owner wants to
sell the whole thing together.
Do you think I should buy the whole
package of SKYBOX or two boxes of CC?
SKYBOX is too expensive.
So, two boxes of CC?
How many times did you jerk off yesterday?
Why are you so tired?
Jerk off your ass.
Mind your own business.
Fuck!
Get up and eat your meatballs.
If you don't eat it, I'm
going to finish yours, too.
Shen Chia-Yi, check out my new magic.
You idiot.
Not bad!
Gross!
It's the best this year.
Isn't it?
What are you guys doing?
It's a new magic.
For real? Show me! Show me!
I will show you.
It's gross.
Just pretend that you are
drinking, but don't swallow it.
You suck.
You are so gross.
Make correction
10 minutes.
Because I am so damn smart
5 minutes is more than enough.
Don't study in the toilet
I am going to pee in my pants.
Ma, stop scaring me.
Why would I?
Dump it out and come out.
Hurry up.
Why are you up so late?
What the hell are you doing in there?
I am studying English
English is useless for you
I FUCK YOU
Go to sleep
I sleep late because I
study English very hard.
Hsieh Ming-Ho
87%
Not bad, not bad.
Keep it up
Chang Chia-Chi
44%
Work harder.
Ko Ching-Teng
75%
You have been studying hard lately?
Not really, I am a genius.
Then, be a genius from now on.
Okay, Class dismiss.
Remember the test next week.
Genius?
Are you serious?
It's not a big deal that you know
how to solve these problems
I bet you
in 10 years time, I wouldn't
even know what log is
and it makes no difference to my life.
Emmmm...
You don't believe me?
I do.
Then, why do you still work so hard?
You don't expect returns
from everything you do.
You really like to pitch high
notes like adults, don't you?
It will be no help to your life whatsoever
if you continue to be so childish like this.
How would you know
if you've never been childish ever?
You know something is
meaningless without trying it.
This is shit.
Next group
I heard you will become a
zombie if you are bitten by one
I don't buy that.
This must be some rumors.
But he had to learn this
from somewhere, right?
What are we going to do?
Hey.
What?
Have you heard that rumor lately?
You mean the one that every
girl wants to date me?
Moron.
Okay, what is it?
I heard some stowaways
from China were drowned.
And they had became zombies
after their bodies were washed up on shore.
Oh! Those zombies
I've heard about them.
They jumped, jumped and
jumped all the way here.
Shit.
Are you for real?
Of course.
With whole bunch of people jumping
around up in the hills at night
what do you think they are?
Yes, I remember seeing that on
the newspaper a few days ago.
If they jumped harder
they should have reached
Baguashan Mountain by now.
So, do you want to see them?
No way
I don't think you can see
them even if they are real.
Maybe they got lost in Baguashan Mountain
and jumped directly into Changhua city.
Don't think it's impossible.
Zombies don't have a sense of direction.
What?
You and Shen Chia-Yi seem
to have a lot to talk about lately.
Do me a favor.
No way.
Don't tell me you want
to write a love letter?
You write it
and I copy it
I don't think one drink is enough
if she says yes
I will buy you one year worth.
Plus a Grant Hill 100:1 All-Star Card.
Alright, deal.
Ko Ching-Teng.
Are you going to cram school tonight?
What for?
You are so dumb, how can you not go!
Mind your own business.
Starting tonight
you stay here and study after school.
Stay at school?
What's your problem?
I will stay, too.
What the hell?
It turned out that Shen Chia-Yi
stayed behind to study
when she didn't have to go to cram school.
So, you asked me to stay
behind at school with you
only because you are afraid
of those zombies, right?
I am just worried you're getting stupid.
Right.
Tsao asked me to give you this letter.
My dear Shen Chia-Yi
I like you very much.
As the song goes,
"Nothing's gonna change my love for you.
Making love out of nothing at all"
barely expresses my feelings for you.
This is your handwriting.
Ko Ching-Teng
I must say
you suck at writing love letters.
What do you mean?
I am that close to William
Shakespeare, okay?
Since you have the time to write
love letters for someone else.
Why don't you use the time
to memorize some English vocabulary?
Ok.
Even though I am cute, smart
and incredibly humorous
don't fall in love with me easily.
Because I am a lone wolf
traveling in the wild wind.
Oh, thanks
I'm not interested in guys
who are dumber than me.
Shen Chia-Yi doesn't like
guys that are dumber than her.
Dumb?
Come on, I let you win on purpose
I don't study hard cause
I don't want to beat you
and I don't want to hurt your feelings!
Pardon me.
Save your kindness, mister.
You are welcome to try to beat me anytime!
I dare you to bet with me.
Let's bet on...
Your hair.
How?
If you beat me in the next midterm
you can do whatever you want to me.
But, if I won
you will have to wear a
ponytail for a month.
Sure, whatever.
It's not like you would win anyway!
I was struck by her cocky
confidence right away.
Hey, you.
Why on earth you need to
study freaking English
in the middle of the night?
I fuck you
I fuck you too
I fuck your mother.
What's wrong with you?
Fuck you fuck you
I love you
I LOVE YOU
Hey, Ma'am.
A super hot and charming jar head, please.
Idiot, how can a jar head be handsome?
Of course there is.
Give it a try if you don't believe me.
Here, I don't owe you any more.
Stop that.
Rumor has it that Inoue Takehiko
has died a couple weeks ago!
I heard that he died in a car accident.
Really.
No wonder I felt something was different
in his drawing style.
More powerful that is,
how can such a genius die just like that.
Don't you think...
Think What?
Don't you think Shen Chia-Yi likes me?
If not, why would she
wear a ponytail today?
Maybe!
How did Shen Chia-Yi
know I like girls who wear ponytails?
You too?
I always like girls who wear ponytails.
So do!
I don't know why Shen Chia-Yi wore a ponytail
that day even though she won the bet.
However, ever since then
studying hard had become an
enthusiastic thing for me.
The class funds went missing.
It was still here when the class leader
checked about an hour ago.
Now school is almost finished.
Who else could have stolen that money?
It must be someone sitting
in this classroom!
Whoever stole that money,
you better turn yourself in right now.
Otherwise, don't blame me for
being too harsh afterwards.
Fine.
It's okay if no one wants to admit it
I guarantee that the thief is
sitting right here in this room.
The person must thinks that
he can get away with this.
Good
very good.
Now, take out your pen, everyone.
And write down the name of the person that
you think it's most likely to be the thief.
The top three named
will have to bring your bags forward,
and I will check them personally.
Now!
Take out your paper right now.
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
What are you doing?
Sir.
Who do you think you are to have
us suspect our own classmates?
Now who is the supervisor? Are you or am I?
You are, sir.
But you are an ass hole!
What did you say?
I said you are an asshole.
Ko Ching-Teng, Tsao Kuo-Sheng
I think you guys are bluffing
bring your bags now and I
will check yours first.
Excuse me, Sir.
You have no right to do that
I have no right to do what?
You can't ask us to write down names
and vote on such a thing.
You can't ask us to suspect
our own classmates.
We can just all pay the fees again.
It's no big deal.
Exactly.
We can just pay again.
Being an honor student doesn't mean
that you can say whatever you want.
Bring your bag over here.
No way.
We are not thieves.
Douche.
What did you say?
I said you are a douchebag.
Bring your bags over now, all of you.
No.
Sir
I now suspect that you have no balls.
Take your pants off now.
What did you say?
Take your pants off.
Bring your bags over.
Fine, here you go!
Stop staring at me.
It's very embarrassing. I feel so ashamed.
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
You kicked ass!
Don't need to be too serious about this.
Shen Chia-Yi.
Relax a bit.
Just pretend, it's no big deal.
Those teachers are not watching anyway.
It's kind of nice to be a bad
student once in a while, isn't it?
I am so ashamed.
Ever since I knew you from junior high
that was the only time
I was amazed by how tough you really are.
Shen Chia-Yi, you rock!
You look so pretty even when you cry.
Yeah.
Super duper cool.
Unbelievably cool.
Unlike quizzes
you never find a correct answer in life.
No one really knew who stole our money,
but no one really cared.
All I remembered from that
day was Shen Chia-Yi's face
beautifully and delicately
engraved in my heart.
Six years ago, when we first stepped
in to Jing-Cheng high school
we were all young and immature.
Although we had great
dreams about our future
we weren't really sure what we were going
to learn and encounter during these years.
Thanks to the teachers who led us and
furnished us with abundant knowledge.
Thanks to all the peers
who accompanied us throughout the years
with bitter and sweet memories.
Ching-Chen high school
represents our young and crazy days
it gave us the most
wonderful times of our life.
From now on
it's time for us to spread our
wings and chase our dreams.
So long, my friends.
How I envy you.
You have so many guys chasing
after you throughout the years!
Yes, it's quite nice to
be liked by someone.
But...
Don't tell me that you feel annoyed
because you are too popular.
No
I just think that I am a very lucky girl.
So, have you decided?
Decided what?
Decided whom you want to be with.
Come on, you can't even tell me?
Ok, if...
I will be really happy.
Happy graduation.
Finally, the colleague entrance exam came.
To me, the exam was more like a test for
Shen Chia-Yi's special training programs
rather than an exam for college.
We spent most of our time at the beach
during the summer before college.
They are so childish
I know, so childish.
You don't really like
childish guys, do you?
No.
Who do you think
is the most childish one among them all.
Ko-Teng, maybe?
How about me?
You are so childish.
Now that we have graduated
have you thought about
what you want to do in the future?
I want to work in the Hsinchu
Science and Industrial Park
so I can get stocks for
bonuses and tons of money.
And then I can marry Shen Chia-Yi...
or Hu Chia-Wei.
Who wants to marry you?
I want to study abroad.
It'll be such a waste of money, okay?
Oh, fuck off.
Study abroad?
I want to study abroad, too.
Maybe I will apply for government
scholarships and get an MBA degree
I want to keep on playing basketball.
And maybe one day make my way to NBA.
What about you, Chia-Wei?
Me?
I think I will find myself
a rich man to marry.
Go away.
What about you, Shen Chia-Yi?
I don't expect much about
my future, really.
Ko-Teng, it's your turn
I want to be a kickass person.
What are you talking about?
What is a kickass person?
I want the world to be a little
bit better because of me.
And you are the only person
that is going to make my world better.
Hello. Yes?
I am a nerd
I am a bookworm.
Ever since junior high and high school.
All I did was studying
I still screwed it up.
No matter which university you go to
there is something that
I want to say to you.
Please.
Don't tell me you like me now
I do like you
and you knew that already.
What do you want to tell me, then?
The results were out.
A-Ho got into Economics Major
in National Tsing Hua University
which means he made one step forward
to his overseas dream.
Groin got into Information Engineering
at Feng Chia University
to become one of those
Science Park smart engineers.
Tsao got into Chemical Engineering
at Cheng Kung University.
So I guess it's most unlikely
that he would make it into NBA.
Although Shen Chia-Yi didn't
do as well as she expected
she still got into University of Education
I could totally imagine Shen Chia-Yi
being a teacher, it really suits her.
Here, for you.
What is this?
I drew it myself.
Not my best work
but I think it's okay.
Thanks.
Shen Chia-Yi, promise me something.
Don't let boys get you too
soon after you go to college.
Ok?
What are you talking about?
You Are the Apple of My Eye.
Oh, yes, as for the masturbating Boner.
He decided to stay
and take the college entrance exam again.
Take the entrance exam
next year with me please!
I have also come to the
next stage in my life
a school without Shen Chia-Yi
I never thought that Shen Chia-Yi would not
be the first girl that I hold hands with.
Instead of her, it was a girl named...
Named...
Hello, my name was Hsu Ke-Shin.
Hi, my name is Ko Ching-Teng.
There were many weird
stories in the dormitory.
Most of them were ghost stories.
But
there's one story about
a four-legged beast.
It was definitely real...
My roommates came from all walks of life.
Hsiao-Lun was a muscle maniac, who did
nothing but lifted weights all day long.
The ultimate weirdo is Yi-Chi.
He was never in the classroom
because he's always reading Manga.
Chien-Han, who started to prepare for
graduate school from the day he arrived
was studying twenty four seven.
Luckily, we had some common
interests to talk about.
See, Iijima Ai is way too old.
Her tits have turned dark.
Emmm... Madoza Ozawa
looks hotter and yummier
Anna Ohura is not too bad, either
I have some nice stuff
called the Human Sex Program.
Let's watch it together later.
Don't you think it's too weird
to watch cartoon characters having sex?
There're ones with dogs and eels, too.
That was the time before
mobile phones were common.
At night, all the guys acted
like they casted a spell.
Everyone one of us
was lining up in front the telephone booth
I miss you so much my
sweetie little pumpkin pie
I miss you 10 times every
hour on a regular basis.
It's true.
So do you miss me this much, too?
How many times per hour?
10 times at least?
Hey.
You are not asleep yet, are you?
No, not yet.
Go to sleep
I talked to Shen Chia-Yi every night.
Sometimes, she fell asleep in
the middle of our conversations.
Sometimes I spent all my money on phone
calls and left no money for food.
Welcome party? Next week.
Next week.
Listen.
Can you please not dance with anyone?
Why not?
Because...
Ok, I know we are not
seeing each other yet.
But those guys who you don't even know.
Can you not let them hold your hands?
I haven't even held them myself.
What about you?
You didn't dance with anyone?
I don't believe you didn't
hold any girl's hands.
Oh, well... yeah, but only a little bit.
That's because...
I imagined that she was you.
Oh please, I don't believe you.
Really.
Then I can also imagine the
guy I dance with was you.
No man, I'm for real.
All right, I am serious.
Don't let anyone hold your hands.
Bye.
Finally, it was the first Christmas
after we entered college.
Hey.
Is this considered a date?
Why ask me?
Why is it so cold in Taipei?
Hurry up, my turn for a picture!
Hurry up! It's leaving.
Oops, I didn't get it.
You.
Come back.
Ko Ching-Teng.
Do you really like me a lot?
Yes, I do.
Very much
I always feel that you
give me too much credit
I'm not as good as you think
I feel weird about the
fact that you like me.
What's so weird about it?
There is another side of me
that you don't know about
I am very sloppy at home.
Emm...
I get very grumpy when I wake up early.
And I get pissed off with my little
sister at times just for minor stuff
I am... you know.
Very ordinary.
Maybe, the person that you like
is in your imagination
I am not that imaginative.
Look.
Think carefully.
Do you like me that much?
Hell yeah.
You are so childish.
You didn't even think through it.
Think about it carefully
before you tell me.
What did Shen Chia-Yi mean?
Was she trying to turn
me down in a nice way?
I was afraid.
For a long time,
I always thought that I am a confident guy.
At that moment, I realized that
I was really a coward in
front of the girl I liked.
What do you wish for?
Write your own, no peeking.
Come on, I just want to have a look.
Shen Chia-Yi
I like you very much
I like you a lot.
One day you will be mine.
One day, I will make you mine.
Do you want to know the answer?
I can tell you right now.
No
I didn't ask you.
So you can't turn me down.
You really don't want to know?
Please don't tell me now.
Just let me keep on liking you.
Every guy wants to show his strongest side.
Especially in front of the girl he likes.
So what should I show to Shen Chia-Yi?
It took me a long time
before the answer suddenly hit me one day.
Why can't you just go pee in the toilet?
Man, it's far.
Hey, are you going out?
Empty this for me on
your way out, will you?
You fucking serious?
Come on, just do me a favor...
Don't you guys think.
It's time to battle?
Come on.
Let's fight
I am organizing a competition.
Anyone wants to join me?
Anyone wants to join the competition?
Anyone wants to fight?
Fighting competition, anyone?
Do you want to fight in a competition?
Do you want to fight in
a combat tournament?
Anyone wants to fight?
Anyone wants to join?
Can I stay until you guys finish?
What's the big deal with
the regular sports?
Combat is definitely cooler.
Seriously, you have to be here
I just put out posters.
It's going to be a full house.
Why do you want to organize
such a dangerous competition?
Don't you guys need to study
and look after your marks?
Exactly! People study way too hard.
That's why they need to exercise
I want to give them some trainings.
It's just a fight.
Fine, if you really want to put it that way
I really don't get you sometimes.
You can nail this easily
I thought everyone in college was a pussy
I was wrong.
There was a tough guy named Chien-Wei.
He was the second chair of the
taekwondo club, a black belt.
He looked cocky.
And he looked tough.
Just the kind of guy
that I was looking for.
We follow the rules of the highest
martial arts order in the world.
No killing.
You cannot go outside of the boundaries.
No kicking on penises.
You lose if you are knocked down and unable
to get up after the referee counts to 10.
Ready!
Put it on.
What the hell?
Wear it so I know I won't kill you.
Go fuck yourself.
Go
I am going to kill you.
Punch him with Gazelle punch.
Stand up.
Ko-Teng.
Hurry up.
Fight back.
Ko-Teng, fight back.
Beat him up.
Stand up and beat him, stand up.
One... Two... Three... Four...
Five... Six... Seven.
Ko-Teng stand up.
Stand up now.
Time is running out.
Ko-Teng.
Fight back.
Who is that? She's so hot.
Hey! I didn't see you
when the game was over
I thought I was knocked out...
Did you see that guy?
He kicked my ass so bad
I couldn't get away from him.
Was it fun?
Not bad!
I was so excited when I saw you!
Answer my question, was it fun?
Now what?
Why did you insist on organizing
such a weird competition?
What's the meaning of it?
Don't you think it's super cool?
That kind of...
win or lose between two men.
It's just violence.
Ko Ching-Teng.
You organized a game to get yourself hurt.
Why are you so childish?
Childish?
Right, childish.
Very childish.
Let me ask you something.
What exactly did you learn from this game?
"Learn"?
Why do I have to learn something
from everything that I do?
At least you learned that having a competition
like this will get yourself hurt.
And it is totally unnecessary.
You are so childish.
See those bruises on your face?
You deserve it
I am childish?
Do you know this competition
is a fantastic experience for me?
Can't you just be happy for me?
So you are going to do it again?
Of course I will do it again.
Why not?
Grow up will you?
Why do you always look down on things
that matter to me?
Things that matter to you
are things that hurt you?
Fine
I am childish.
And that's why I would go after
such a good school girl like you
I am this naive so I could
chase you for so long.
Stop trying then.
Idiot.
Right! I am an idiot.
Moron.
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase
after you for such a long time.
You don't understand anything.
No, I don't understand anything.
The cruelest part in “growing up”
is that girls are always more
mature than guys of the same age.
No guys can handle girls at their age.
What? A big fight?
Does that mean you are not going
to be a couple after this?
What's your problem?
For real? Not plans of making up?
Oh yes, so I have a chance now?
Tsao took off right away on his motorcycle
and rode from Tainan to Taipei.
He was ready to confess
his love to Shen Chia-Yi.
A-Ho, on the other hand, bought
a ticket for the next train.
It turned out that
the train is faster
I know we have always been good friends.
But somehow I always knew
that Ko-Teng is the one.
Being childish is something that
I can never learn.
Even though you said you
hate childish guys.
Every time when you called Ko-Teng childish
I can tell how much you like
that childishness in him.
Why are you telling me this now?
If I don't do anything now
you guys will get back together eventually.
Right?
I am sorry.
Since you guys are not in good terms now,
I would like to take my chances.
When Tsao saw A-Ho and Shen Chia-Yi walked
across the street, he took off again.
This time, he rode his way
around the whole island.
When Tsao made it to Tainan
he took the wrong exit so
he went straight to Chiayi.
Then he thought why not just take
another round around Taiwan.
This time, he stopped to picked me up.
What?
Fuck.
What do you want?
Hit me back.
What's your freaking problem?
Idiot?
I was heart broken
I had lost Shen Chia-Yi.
There was nothing left in me
I met quite a lot of girls
after I lost Shen Chia-Yi.
It's just that they all
happened to be Japanese.
For that, I felt there was
something missing in my heart.
Sakuragi Hanamichi was right.
You can only use one hand, your left hand.
Because you need your
right hand on the mouse.
What's the point of us
masturbating all day long?
Who cares?
As long as I get to ejaculate, who cares!
I am coming, I am coming, I AM COMING!
Even though getting a diploma
might not be crucial
but a bachelor degree
seems to be not enough
I admit that I might be childish,
just like how Shen Chia-Yi described me.
A-Ho has been a really good friend of mine.
But I just couldn't bring
myself to congratulate him.
It'd be nice to plan things ahead.
We should start thinking
about graduate schools.
If you really want to be a teacher.
Then getting a Master of
education would be nice.
At least people will pay
you more in the future.
A-Ho was with Shen Chia-Yi
for only five months.
But that was more than enough
to make me jealous like hell.
Fuck, what's happening?
Shit.
Fuck, what's going on!
Ghost! Ghost!
Let's get the hell out of here!
Shit... ghost? Where? Where?
This is crazy, man!
My mom just called and said that the
hotel next to my house just collapsed.
You are from Taipei, aren't you?
So the epicenter is in Taipei?
It's too crowded here, the
system is probably overloaded.
Try to give it a shot at
somewhere less crowded.
Are you sure?
I don't know.
Hello.
Ko-Teng?
I am safe, don't worry.
Everyone is out on the street, though.
Thank god
I heard that the epicenter is in Taipei.
And the whole building collapsed
anyway.
Good to hear that you are safe.
Thank you.
Alright then
better go.
Wait a minute
I am touched, really.
Yeah right.
You are the girl that I chased for years!
Who else is going to share
this memory with me
if you are gone.
Hey, come on.
You didn't even try to contact
me in the past two years.
You didn't call either.
How dare you mention it.
So, what have you been doing lately?
Nothing much, really.
Same old thing, studying.
What about you?
Still skipping classes?
Of course
I never liked studying anyway
I only studied because of you.
Wow! So sweet.
We had a long chat that night,
talking about the old days.
The old days when I tried
everything to get closer to her.
So, do you have a boyfriend now?
It's none of your business.
I...um...
I... was with A-Ho for a while
I know
I heard.
Why did you guys split up?
I didn't want to ask him cause that
just made me want to kick his ass.
Was he mean to you?
Not really
I just felt that he
didn't like me that much.
No, A-Ho was crazy about
you, head over heels!
Having being loved by you makes it
harder for me to feel other's love.
You are kidding me right?
Don't ruin it now.
Hey, Shen Chia-Yi.
Can I ask you a question?
Why didn't you want to
be with me at that time?
You know...
People always say that the most
wonderful time of a relationship
happens before it really happens.
When two people are together.
The magic vanishes easily.
So I thought it'd be better
if I let you chase me longer.
Otherwise, if we got together
right away, it'd be less fun.
Man, that's slack!
Shen Chia-Yi.
Do you believe in parallel universe?
Maybe in that universe, we are together.
How I envy them.
Thank you for liking me.
Yes.
Thank you for letting me
like you in those years.
You are always the apple of my eye.
Then it came to Senior year.
Everyone around me was
preparing for grad schools
I had no idea what I
wanted to do at that time.
Everyone was studying so
hard and it made me nervous.
So I decided to join them in the library.
And out of the blue, I started
to write stories on my blog.
Tsao didn't make his way to NBA.
He ended up selling second hand cars.
And it turned out he's pretty good at it.
On average, he sells one
car every other day.
Unbelievable.
The engine never lies.
Here.
Put your foot on the gas gently.
Hear that sound?
It's this powerful before we upgrade it,
can you imagine if we do?
I bet it is going to run over
2000 rpm when it hits the road.
The horsepower is beyond your imagination.
What do you think? You like it?
I like it.
Well then, how about we take
this beast out for a ride?
Okay.
GO
Groin passed the government worker's exam.
He is now working as a librarian.
Which he gets to play perform magic
to young innocent girls every day.
See this book? Blow on it.
Now, pay attention.
Are you nuts?
Stop there.
A-Ho became an insurance sales man.
He loves driving his car.
Every day he spends about 12 hours in it,
even though it's tough
I do believe he will succeed one day.
After all he is the only person
who has officially dated Shen Chia-Yi.
Hello, is this Mr. Lee?
Yes, speaking.
Hi, remember the insurance plan
that I talked to you about last time?
I have already gathered all
the information for you.
Just wondering when is a good time
to pay you a visit in your office.
Boner flew to America for graduate school
immediately after his military service.
Boner's English sucked
I don't know how the hell
he had the guts to go to the States.
Perhaps he wanted to masturbate
in a different country.
If you can't stand it, just
come back, understand?
Ma, stop talking nonsense
I am serious.
If it's too hard, then just come back
I will not blame you, I promise.
Fine, I got it.
Okay, it's dad's turn to say good-bye now.
Two years gone by while Boner was overseas.
Oh, yes, and there is Hu Chia-Wei.
That girl who always drew
retarded stuff in her books.
She now has another name.
Wan Wan.
So it proves that those
who realize their dreams
are often not the most
clever ones in school.
But they are definitely those
who persist till the end
I am very glad that I was wrong.
When Boner came home with a foreign degree
I received a phone call.
Hello.
Hello, old friend, are you busy?
Of course I am busy
I don't care, there is something that
I want you to be the first to know.
What is it?
You got time for me to go after you again?
Not this time, I am afraid.
Why?
Hurry up!
It's a big day today.
You want to make the bride wait for you?
Cheers.
Regret it now?
I was so available back then,
but you guys all went for Shen Chia-Yi.
So does that mean I still have a chance?
You suck!
I got to tell you something
I wasn't really serious about chasing
after Shen Chia-Yi before.
Why?
I just didn't want to miss out.
Everyone went after her, so I did, too.
In comparison to me
I must say, you guys are shameless.
She is the bride today, but
none of you is the groom.
How dare you guys show
your faces at this wedding.
Shameless!
Hsu Bo-Chun.
Kiss my ass.
Just drink!
Oh, please, I have dated her, haven't I?
That was a scam.
Exactly, cheater!
Hey, let's make a bet.
Let's do paper, scissors stone.
The loser
will have to trip the groom
when they walk in later.
What the hell was that? It's embarrassing!
You guys are mean.
Can't you just show some love to the couple?
You won't understand.
If you really like a girl.
It is impossible to see her marry
to another guy and still bless them.
That's right.
True love means someone should sneak up
and stabs the groom in the back.
Correct.
Trip him!
But I am wrong.
In fact, when you really like a
girl, you'd be happy for her.
When you see her finding her Mr. Right.
You will want them to be together.
And to live happily ever after.
Come closer.
One more, ready
1,2, 3, go.
OK
Congratulations, happy marriage.
Come, quickly
I want to stand next to Shen Chia-Yi.
We should take more photos.
How do I look? Get a pretty one for me.
All right. Here it comes.
Ready.
Ok, one, two, three, go.
One more, one, two, three... done.
OK
Thank you.
Hey, man, we have a suggestion.
About what?
See, the thing is that we
have loaded you with cash.
Don't you think we have the
right to kiss the bride?
Well, I am fine if she says fine.
Well, fine.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
You can kiss the bride.
But you have to kiss me first.
Kiss me the way you want to
kiss her, so that's fair.
Bullshit!
What kind of rule is that?
Yeah, no way.
Don't be stingy.
That is not right.
Well then... sorry.
Ha, ha... Look at yourself, guys.
What?
Thank you for yesterday.
Are you for real?
A quiz made out of love...
You made so many mistakes.
You did the problems without reading
the exercise book, didn't you?
Shen Chia-Yi.
You were so cool when you shouted at him.
You look so pretty when you cry, too.
Even though we are not
seeing each other yet.
But those guys who you don't even know.
Can you not let them hold your hands?
I haven't even held them myself.
You held this game and got yourself hurt.
How can you be so childish?
Childish?
Yes, childish.
Very childish and totally immature.
Idiot.
Yes, I am an idiot.
Moron.
Only a moron can keep on trying
to chase you for such a long time.
You don't understand anything.
You're right, I don't!
Sorry
I was the immature one.
Being able to solve these tricky math
questions does not help anything in life!
You want to bet?
I won't even know what “log”
means ten years later.
And it doesn't make my life any harder.
Emmmm.
You don't believe me
I do believe you.
Then, why do you still work so hard?
You don't expect returns
from everything you do.
Do you want to know the answer?
If Ko Ching-Teng comes
and confesses to me I will be very happy.
Shen Chia-Yi
I like you very much.
(Ok, let's be together)
How I envy them.
Thank you for liking me.
Well then, I am just going
to keep on acting childish.
Sure, why not!
(Happy Marriage, to the apple of my eye)
Hey, Yankees.
Yeah!
A- Chian.
Hey, Ko-Teng.
Have you thought about writing our story?
Of course I did!
I just haven't come up a
good name to start with.
Hey, can you leave out the part
which I was masturbating?
Sorry man... that has to be in the story.
If you really are going to write it.
Don't forget to let your
readers know how handsome I am.
By the way, can you put in some
dating advertisements for me, too!
Come on, I thought you
are going after Wan Wan?
Haha, doesn't really matter.
This is the last image
we shot before wrapping up shooting.
The director conspired
with the make-up artist to prank the cast.
And painted Michelle Chen's face into...