That's not fair. Come on.
You said yesterday.
That's not my fault.
- Come on you lot, chop chop.
- Chop chop! Chop chop!
Anyone seen my overalls?
There's some clean ones
in the back, love.
Oh, thanks.
Andy, Josh, it's ten past.
(TRAFFIC REPORT ON RADIO)
- Where's Andy?
- I don't know.
- Who's moved my rucksack?
- Me, but it was in the way.
Right, Jade, I want you in the car.
Come on, get your shoes on.
And you, love, come on, let's go.
- I'm tired!
- All right.
And I'm hungry.
Andy!
We are going now.
I'm coming.
- Have you got your bus fare?
- Yeah, see you later.
(CHILDREN SQUABBLING)
- Come on, Chris, you're always late.
- See you, love.
Got your recorder, Jade?
Mum, it's not recorder day today,
that's tomorrow.
(TOOTS HORN)
(DOGS BARK)
TV: # Become good friends
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
(WEST COUNTRY ACCENT) Mae, get that.
(FOOTSTEPS)
- Is your mum in?
- She's inside.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Mum.
Oh, bloody hell, not you again!
That's right, me again.
Well, what's that?
A warrant to search
the house and the garden.
Excuse me.
Mum, what...?
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
- Well, what are they all... - They just
come in with search warrants.
(CLATTERING)
Mind my house, you great lummock!
What, then, are the signs of abuse
which social workers
should look for in children?
These may be physical,
unexplained cuts and bruises.
But they may also be behavioural.
Is the child withdrawn or aggressive
or unusually introverted?
Is there an unspoken atmosphere of
fear in the house?
(RINGING TONE)
It's me.
That interfering bloody arsehole
bitch is here again.
She'd got a search warrant this time.
You better have your story straight.
And anything you need to do,
you better get done.
Hm?
(FOOTSTEPS)
(LOCAL TALK RADIO)
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello. Speaking.
Oh, right.
So you want me to come in now?
Er...no, no, fine. Erm...
Half an hour?
Ok, then, bye.
That were the police.
- They need an appropriate adult.
- A what?
You know, it's that thing I
volunteered for.
You lot don't listen to a word
I say, do you?
- Janet Leach?
- Yeah.
This way, please.
Detective Superintendent
Bennett's waiting for you.
(CLAMOUR OF VOICES)
Janet Leach,
the appropriate adult, sir.
Sorry for calling you in
at this time of day.
Probation and Social Services
had no-one available.
- Do you mind if I ask who it is?
- It's a 52-year-old man.
With learning difficulties?
Well, all I can say is that we've been
advised to have an appropriate adult.
Oh, yes.
- You have done this before?
- Oh, no, but I have done the training.
Ah.
Carry on.
Howard Ogden, solicitor.
This taped interview is being
conducted at Gloucester Central
Police Station.
I'm DC Darren Law
and my colleague here is...
- DC Hazel Savage.
- And could I have your name, please?
Frederick Walter Stephen West.
- And your legal representative...
- Howard Ogden.
And acting as your
appropriate adult...
Oh, Janet Leach.
You're here to observe the interview
is conducted fairly
but also to advise Mr West and
facilitate communication with him.
- I understand.
- Super.
The date is Friday 25th February
1994, the time is 16:57.
Before we set off
I've got to remind you, Fred,
that you're still under caution
and that you don't have to say
anything unless you wish to do so
but anything you do say
may be used in evidence.
- Do you understand?
- Yeah.
OK.
You were arrested earlier today
by my colleague here
in relation to the murder
of your daughter Heather.
Could you tell me on your own words
what you know about that?
Well, Heather wanted
to leave home, see,
and she'd been knocking about
with this girl with a red mini.
That's a mini skirt not a Mini car.
(SNIFFS)
And we were pretty sure
she was a lesbian, like,
so me and Rose said, "Hang on a sec,
you'd better think about this, girl,
you know, give it a night, at least."
So next morning come up and...
she looked real rough.
She'd been crying and...
So Rose says, "Let her go."
She said, "I'll go to the bank and
draw out 600 pounds,
she can have that and go".
So, Rose goes off and I'm left in the
hall with Heather and her suitcase.
She's got her hands on her hips, you
know, the big lady, like...
I say, "How about
you get a flat up the road?
You can have girlfriends up there."
And she said, "If you don't let me
fucking go...
I'll give all the kids acid."
That's LSD, like.
"And they'll jump off the church roof
and kill their selves."
And I said, "Well, that ain't very
nice, girl,
you threatening to do that
to your own brothers and sisters."
And she's got this smile on her face,
like a sort of smirk,
like, "Try me and I'll do it".
So I just lunged at her
like that and then
I grabbed her by the throat,
like that,
and held her there for...
I don't know how long
but it was real quick because...
It's surprising how long you can hold
someone by the throat until they...
until they...
But I can't even remember to that
extent what happened next, but
the next minute she's gone blue.
And I'm looking at her from head to foot.
You know, what the heck's gone wrong?
I put her on the floor and I'm blowing
in her mouth, pumping her chest,
but she kept on getting bluer
and I didn't know what to do.
I hadn't meant to hurt her
and Rose is due back any minute.
I'm thinking, jeez, I've got to do
something and...
I was scared.
So I was going to put her
in the Wendy house.
Then I thought I'd put her
in the dustbin,
but I couldn't get her in there, so...
I get this ice saw.
You know, with the two prongs at the
top and the serrated edges,
you use them for
cutting blocks of ice
and I cut her legs off, and...
I mean, that was...
unbearable.
Yeah, I can still hear
that in my sleep.
And then I cut her head off, and...
Well, I closed her eyes first, cos
well, you're not going to take a
saw to your own daughter
when she's sat there
looking at you, are you?
And then she fit
neatly in the bin, so
I push it down the end of the garden,
behind the Wendy House.
Then I take her suitcase
and stuck it behind the vet's on St
Michael's Square where everyone
chucks their rubbish.
Then I got Heather from behind
the Wendy house and...
buried her.
And I been meaning to come down here
and get all this sorted out before,
but I never got round to it.
Can I ask if the appropriate adult's
all right?
Oh, quite all right, thank you.
DC SAVAGE: Let's get this clear.
- You're saying you killed your
daughter. - But not intentionally.
DC LAW: What sort of grave are we
looking for?
Just a hole about four foot square.
SAVAGE: And what's in this hole?
- Well, Heather.
- How many pieces?
Three pieces, two legs,
a head and a body.
LAW: That's four pieces.
Are you happy to come to the house
and point out where she is?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell us all this
before, Fred?
I wasn't ready.
Or is it cos we're carrying out a search
and you were afraid we might find her?
No.
You see, all this is causing
stress to Rose and I don't want that,
and the thing I'd like
to make clear is that Rose,
knew nothing about any of this.
The time is 17:08 by my watch
and the interview is ended
whilst arrangements are made
to visit 25 Cromwell Street.
This notice explains
what happens to the tapes.
-Can I have a word?
- Yeah, sure.
- Is Rose here?
- No.
- I've a feeling she's in the building.
- She's not here.
I just wanted to make sure you're OK.
Er... Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
(SHOUTING)
She is here.
I thought they were taking her
straight to Cheltenham.
- This way, Mrs West.
- You're unbelievable, you lot.
You're fucking unbelievable!
(RINGING TONE)
- Hello.
- Oh, hi, love, it's me.
Is everything all right?
JOSH: Yeah.
- Have you had tea?
- Sort of.
You might have to put Jade to bed.
Where are you?
I told you, I'm at the police
station.
I'm helping the police with an
investigation.
What investigation?
Yeah, the press office
are working on it now.
I can't talk about it. I'm really
sorry, love, I've got to go.
I'll see you later, all right? Bye.
(FRED'S VOICE)
(LAUGHTER)
DC LAW: What, overalls?
FRED: Standard police issue, are
they? Nothing but the best.
Damn stuff drive you mad, it does.
- What's that, then?
- Fibreglass.
Been spraying this bloke's loft over
Stroud way.
We don't have back-scratchers
in the station, Fred.
- Is the car ready?
- Don't I know you from somewhere?
- Erm... I'm sure you don't.
- You don't half look familiar.
(CHATTER)
LAW: I'll be in the first car with
Mr West and his solicitor Mr Ogden.
Ain't just Heather
I buried in that garden.
- There's more.
- More?
You wouldn't believe it.
Not that you can let on to the
police I told you that, eh?
You have got to keep everything I
say in confidence.
But you're a good appropriate adult,
you'll already know that.
DC SAVAGE: Mrs Leach.
OK?
All ready?
Let's go.
Right arm, please, Fred.
- Where's Rose? - On her way to
Cheltenham Police Station.
She's also under arrest.
- That's a waste of her time and yours.
- Come on.
The work I put into this place!
Knocking through here
and building on there.
Years of back-break
to get it looking tickety-boo.
I need to remind you you are under
caution, Fred, you understand?
Yes, thank you, Hazel.
Now you show us where you buried
your daughter Heather.
The problem is remembering
what you did when...
I'd try there.
- Is Bernard still around?
- He's gone home.
- Get him back.
- We need a pathologist.
See there?
What?
And there?
What am I supposed to be looking at?
OK, we're going to get a forensic
team to start examining that area.
We'll go back to the station now,
apply for an extension of custody
and resume our interview tomorrow.
Is there anything else
you wish to say?
Yes. Will the appropriate adult
be present?
Can you attend?
Erm...
Yeah, if you want me.
That's sorted, then.
She's been very helpful so far.
(CHILDREN TALKING)
(CHILDREN'S VOICES)
- I said yeah.
- Ssh!
Come on, you said yesterday,
that's not right.
MIKE: Been on that job over at Barnwood.
They've had cowboys in before.
What a mess,
I'm having to re-skim it all. I told them,
I said, "This'll take weeks."
- Hey, cut it out, you two.
- Hey!
(CHILDREN CHATTER)
- Mike...
- Hm?
- Have you taken them?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Gloucester Police Station,
the date is 26th February 1994.
The time is 10:38.
I'm DC Law, my colleague here is...
DC Savage.
- Your full name, please.
- Frederick Walter Stephen West.
- And your legal representative...
- Howard Ogden.
- And acting as your appropriate adult...
- Janet Leach.
I've to remind that you are still
under caution. Do you understand?
- Yes and me and him just had an
argument. - Discussion.
I'm telling you now what I just told
him. Heather is not in that garden.
She's alive and well and possibly at
this moment in Bahrain.
She's been recruited to work
for a drugs cartel as a drugs runner.
They treat her like a queen.
She gets in touch now and again
to tell me she's all right.
She's using a false name.
I have no idea what that is
and I will not let her tell me.
Now, whether or not you believe in
that is entirely up to you.
But that's why you found nothing and
you won't,
not even if you dig till Kingdom Come.
And I don't care how much money and
time you waste, cos you wasted mine.
- Not just now but in the past.
- There were previous allegations.
- There was nothing in them.
- Rape and buggery of your children.
- Which was never proven.
- You had me in prison,
spat at by other prisoners,
my younger kids put into care,
where they still are, poor lambs,
trying to force me to admit
that I assaulted them...
- Trying to get to the truth, Fred.
- You turned my house upside down.
- And we'll do so again and the garden.
- 3,000 pounds that cost me...
And we'll keep on searching
until we find Heather.
All because of some remark
about her being under the patio!
A remark made by your own daughter.
-Anne Marie said it was a family joke.
- A jopke. There you are!
To social workers who, like me,
have had concerns about your family
for a considerable time.
You're the beautifulest woman in
Gloucester when you're angry, Hazel.
I'm just trying to get to the truth
this time, Fred.
- You're being personal and vindictive.
- I'm being neither.
Against me and my Rose,
who loves our family,
who'd do anything for them.
Why are you saying this now, Fred?
Last night you took us to the house
with Mr Ogden and this lady,
and you showed us a grave.
You inconvenienced me.
So, are you trying to inconvenience
DC Savage to get back at her?
You really saying there's
nothing in that grave?
Why are you smirking?
Who's smirking?
You said yesterday
you wanted to get all this...
sorted out.
Then I spent the night in a cell thinking
what I want is Rose back in our home.
I want my children back, I want my house
and garden reinstated. We are a family!
Well, let's just ask Mrs Leach, as...
an independent lady, what she thinks.
Erm...
Well, he's clearly contradicting
what he said last night.
Did you hear that, Fred?
And I saw the smirk.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
For the benefit of the tape,
PC Roberts has entered the room.
Nothing more hurtful than someone
saying you don't love your kids.
Bet you feel the same way.
Bet you're a mother.
- That's completely irrelevant.
- Ah, but it's not, you see,
cos I think you understand how deep
my feelings are for my family.
Don't you?
(DOOR OPENS)
Time for a cuppa, I'd say, Hazel.
We can... We can take
a refreshment break shortly.
But first I'd like to discuss the
information
that Detective Superintendent
Bennett's just sent from your house.
What information?
They've found some
bones in the garden.
Well, like I said, I...
I want to get all this sorted out.
Our pathologist is confident
they're human.
If I accused you of...
inconveniencing me,
then, Helen, I...
apologise.
Are you sure you buried Heather
all in one place?
You what?
- You didn't scatter any of her body
around the garden? - No.
Cos they found another body part
in another part of the garden.
Well, I can't think how that could
have got there.
What, are you suggesting
it wasn't part of Heather?
It must have been.
It was a thigh bone.
They've already found
two thigh bones.
Heather didn't have
three legs, did she?
Well... do you have any knowledge
how this other bone
could have got there, Fred?
Yes.
Shirley.
Shirley who?
Robinson.
The girl that caused all the trouble.
The girl with the red mini.
Thank you, yes.
You see, she lodged with us, and...
...I had an affair with her
and she got pregnant and...
she wanted to marry me and she said
she was gonna tell Rose and...
there was a bit of an argument,
got out of hand somehow and...
she ended up getting strangled.
And where was Rose at this time?
- In the hospital having a baby.
- Which baby?
Erm...
Babs. No. Er...
No, not Babs. Erm...
Young Rosemarie.
I'd come back from seeing Rose
in the hospital and... (SNIFFS)
Shirley and I had this row
and I killed her.
How?
Strangled her with a piece of flex.
Buried her in the garden?
Yeah.
And her with a baby inside her, too.
Can't tell you how that's haunted me.
I mean, about the baby and...
(SIGHS)
In killing Shirley, the...
... the baby would have died, too.
(SOBS)
I think we'll end there.
Does anyone have
anything else to say?
The time is 11:06 and
the interview has ended.
Excuse me.
We've decided to leave the
interviews for today.
- Oh, OK.
- Erm...Fred needs some clean clothes.
I wondered, could you go to the
house with Mr Ogden and get them?
Erm... Yeah, all right.
And whilst you're at it, could you
get some for Mrs West, too?
- We're still holding her at
Cheltenham. - OK.
Erm...
Does he really have
learning difficulties?
So why do you need
an appropriate adult?
Detective Superintendent
Bennett's concerned
there's no suggestion, Mr West had
difficulty understanding any of this.
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
Can you give us anything at all?
Can you give us
any information atall?
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
In you go.
PC: This way.
Right at the top, I think.
174, 174 Quebec Lima, over.
Quebec Lima, go ahead, over.
Can you do anything to improve access
to the rear of the property?
I'll look into it now, over.
OGDEN: Upstairs, I think.
342, 342, Quebec Lima, over.
Can you meet DC Kaminsky by the back
door? He's got a message for you.
You did know she works
as a prostitute?
- I'd worked that out.
- Mm.
Clothes.
No, there's nothing in here.
(VOICES IN GARDEN)
I thought you'd already
searched in here.
- We're not the police.
- Who the fuck are you, then?
- I'm your dad's solicitor.
- Well, who's this?
Janet Leach, I'm acting as
your father's appropriate adult.
His what?
We've been sent to pick up
some clean clothes.
Where is Dad?
Cos no-one's told us anything.
Gloucester Police Station.
I'm afraid he's been arrested
on suspicion of murder.
Murder of who?
If it's murder
then it'll be Mum, not Dad.
- Don't say that about Mum!
- I'll say what fucking I like!
Don't listen to him.
Mum's all right.
Dad's the one.
Tell Mum I hope she's all right
and we want her home.
Please will you do that for me?
(ENGINE RUNNING IN GARDEN)
(SHOVELS CLANGING)
- Mrs West.
- Jesus! You.
This lady's brought you
some of your clothes.
What?
You've been to my house,
rooting round in my things?
- The police asked me...
- Fucking cheek!
We were just quickly in and out
and we saw Stephen and Mae,
and Mae said that
she hoped you were all right.
By what right, by what right,
you nosy fucking bitch,
do you go in my house
and speak to my children
and poke about among my
private things?
- Rose...
- Jesus Christ!
Rose, calm down.
Who are you, anyway?
- Who are you?
- She's helping us, Mrs West.
She's got no right
touching my clothing
and you've got no right
arresting me!
- All we want is to get to the truth.
- No, it ain't.
You want me to say Fred killed our
Heather and I helped him.
- Did you? - No, I did not!
How many fucking times?
You've got nothing on me
and you know it.
- Take her back to the cells, please.
- Right.
(RUMMAGES IN BAG)
Don't...
touch me.
Oh, what are you so fucking scared
of, you little mouse?
Little mousey-mouse,
wouldn't say boo to a fucking goose.
I bet you're
a dirty little lezzie, too.
Mrs West!
Innocent, isn't she?
I said don't touch me, didn't I?
I told you not to fucking touch me.
- Sorry about that.
- It's all right.
Look, have a seat, I'll get you a
glass of water.
Occupational hazard,
I'm afraid, that kind of abuse.
It's not that.
What is it, then?
Things have happened
and been said that I hadn't expected.
What things?
Has Fred said anything privately
to you about any of this?
I can't tell you.
I owe a duty of confidence.
Of course.
But if he does try and give you
information privately,
you can advise him to speak to me.
I know, I've done the training.
You'd better get home.
What are you doing? It's Sunday.
I know. They need me to go in again.
What?
The police.
Bloody hell, Janet.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
I'm just going in now.
Coping? Of course I'm coping.
Who says I'm not?
Pull out? No!
So, you're saying if I carry on,
you won't support me?
OK, fine!
(CHATTER)
I want that statement on my desk first
thing in the morning, you understand?
Excuse me.
Can I ask? Have you said
something to her?
What?
The organiser of the
appropriate adult register.
Yes, yes, I have.
Did you tell her that
I wasn't up to this?
No, I did not.
Cos she rang me and asked me
if I wanted to pull out.
I explained it was a very difficult
and distressing case.
She's perfectly entitled
to give you that opportunity.
Well, I won't.
Are you quite sure
you still feel able to carry on?
Yeah, absolutely.
Very well.
Janet! There's been a development.
What?
Fred's indicated that there's
another body in the garden.
- Who?
- A girl called Alison Chambers.
I suspect he's told us
cos we'll find the body anyway.
I want him to point out the grave.
Can you come to the house?
Er... Yeah, of course.
(CLANGING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
So, here, Fred,
this here's where we found bones
that you say may belong
to Shirley Robinson.
Where did you bury Alison Chambers?
Well, now...
- Now you're asking.
- Yes, I am asking, Fred.
Let's see.
No. I don't think I can get it.
Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on.
I'm picking something up.
- Yeah, that's her.
- Alison?
Yeah, she's trying
to tell me something.
What's she trying to tell you, Fred?
Where she is, but I...
I don't think I can understand
what she's trying to...
Yeah, hold on, hold on. Erm...
Yeah. Try there.
Now that's your lot,
you'll find no more.
What about...
Rena?
- Rena?
- Your first wife.
And what about Charmaine?
- Charmaine?
- Why are you looking at me like that?
Rena had a daughter Charmaine,
who became your step-daughter.
Where are they?
Well, you lose... you lose
track of people, don't you?
You said you'd lost track of Heather,
but you killed her
and buried her, in this garden.
And you did the same to Shirley
Robinson and Alison Chambers.
You won't find Rena and
Charmaine here, and that I swear.
And even if you don't believe me,
I know the appropriate adult does,
cos she understands me
in a way that you lot don't.
Isn't that so?
How could I understand you?
You've killed people.
Because you're a woman
who can see beneath the surface.
And a woman who knows remorse
when she sees it.
Not like you lot.
The police have found two more
bodies in the garden in Gloucester
where the remains of the
missing schoolgirl Heather West
were discovered on Saturday.
Her father is charged
with her murder.
The two new bodies
are thought to be of adults
but police say identification
will be difficult.
They're checking registers of
missing people.
Our West Of England reporter Steve
Scott has the details...
Can I use that table?
I can't concentrate in there.
Oh, yeah.
..the city's biggest-ever
criminal investigation.
Is this the thing
you're involved with?
Forensic teams have unearthed
three sets of human remains...
It is, isn't it?
It obviously is, Josh.
She can't talk about it.
Do you think there are more bodies?
I bet there are more, though,
most people do.
Police have confirmed the man's wife
has been released without charge.
Indications are that the police
operation at 25 Cromwell Street
could go on for many more days yet.
What's that number again, please?
DC SAVAGE: Jacqui will show you out.
I know this is distressing but that
information could be really useful.
We'll be in touch if we
have any news at all.
- Ready for another session?
- Yeah.
Who was that?
Mr and Mrs Gough.
Gloucester couple whose daughter
lodged with the Wests 20 years ago.
We found some belongings in the
house we think may be hers.
You think she could be
another victim? - Yup.
Where's this going to end?
There are three bodies and that's
it. I said I'm willing to sort all
that out.
I know I'll never go home again
but I want my garden reinstated
and I want Rose and
the kids back home.
- She can't go back home!
- Why not? You've released Rose.
She's with Mae and Stephen,
the younger kids are in care.
We're still searching the property
and the fact that
we've released Rose
doesn't mean that
we belive she's innocent.
This is all wrong, see.
Did Rose know about your
relationship with Shirley Robinson?
No, she didn't.
Living under the same roof? Rose
must have known she was pregnant.
- She didn't know I was the father.
- I suggest that she did.
I suggest she was jealous.
I suggest she helped you to kill her.
- We've found Shirley's body, Fred.
- I know.
It was me who
showed you where it was.
So, can you explain
why the baby wasn't inside her?
What?
The baby has not been left
intact in the abdomen.
I need to take a break.
DC LAW: The time is 11:45,
the interview has ended.
- Back in a minute, Fred.
- Can you sign this off, Mrs Leach?
I need to speak to you.
DC SAVAGE: Yes, Mr Ogden, of course.
I need to see that report.
That would have been Rose.
What would?
The baby.
Are you saying that Rose removed the
baby from Shirley's womb?
Oh, no, no.
No, no, Rose is a mother,
she'd never do a thing like that.
I can't do this.
Don't go, please.
Give me one good reason
why I should listen to this crap.
- I know you've suffered.
- What?
- You don't know anything about me.
- I can see it in your eyes. I know
you've not always been properly
loved and respected by men.
I've had enough of this.
You need to tell
the police everything.
If you've killed other women,
they need to know. The girls'
families need to know.
I'm not admitting nothing else
to Mr Ogden or the police.
- I'm going and I'll not be coming
back. - You're my appropriate adult.
- I don't give a shit!
- Please, please!
Please, Janet, please stay!
You're the only one I can trust.
On one condition.
You tell the police
who else you've killed.
All right.
In writing, so you can't back-track.
I'll get Mr Ogden in.
- Mr Ogden.
- Yes?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Mr West wants to make a statement.
- Saying what?
- Who else he's killed.
Really?
Well...
What exactly do you want to say?
Go on, Fred.
Here, Janet, come and sit here.
OGDEN: So, what shall we put?
Go on.
"I, Frederick West,
authorise my solicitor..."
(REPEATS)
"Howard Ogden..."
Howard Ogden...
"to advise Superintendent
Bennett..."
Superintendent Bennett...
Of?
Of a...
a further...
... eight killings.
Eight?
All right, nine.
Well, is it eight or nine?
Erm...
Shall we just put "approx"?
That's it, "approx".
Good girl.
"Of a further nine...
... approx, killings."
- Is this his signature?
- Yes.
These don't sound like his words.
Well, we drafted it for him,
following his instructions.
We?
He made this admission following
a conversation with Mrs Leach.
I also got him to draw a map.
He said some bodies are in the garden,
some are under the cellar floor
and there's a body in a field.
It's all a bit vague.
Others to be identified.
We've made a start,
trying to identify who they might be.
It's a huge breakthrough, sir.
Why did he come out with all of this?
I told him that if he didn't start
telling the truth,
then I wouldn't help him any more.
That could be seen as
putting him under duress.
How?
I was just being honest
and I told him it was you
he should tell, not me,
because what he tells me I have
to keep in private, confidential.
You've done exactly the right thing.
I won't have to go to court, will I?
Oh, I doubt that very much, Mrs
Leach, you're the appropriate adult.
You're here to assist Mr West.
See, the problem I have down here,
is the high water table.
No matter how much concrete you put
down, you still get seepage.
Let's see what I can do for you.
Hm...
- I don't know.
- What don't you know, Fred?
If I can feel... If I can feel them.
I can feel their spirits
reaching out to me but...
... I'm getting the same message from
all of them.
They're trying to tell me they're...
they're better off where they are.
They don't want to be disturbed.
This is a pile of crap!
Either there are more bodies here
or there aren't.
He's told us that there are.
He'd better not have come up
with those nine to impress you.
- I don't think he has.
- Be wary of getting pally with him.
I'm not getting pally with him,
I'm just trying to help.
Dig the floor up. Take the house
apart brick by brick if you have to.
This is getting out of hand.
People will start thinking
he's taking the mickey out of us.
(DRILLING)
Thanks.
- Janet Leach?
- Yeah.
-Can we have a quick chat?
- What about?
- What you're doing with the police.
- Janet? Hi, Kirsty Stevens.
- Fuck off, Kirsty, I'm talking to her.
- Janet, before you make any decisions,
please talk to me.
- What do you mean, decisions?
- Cromwell Street.
- You clearly know the inside story.
- Who told you that?
We have our ways.
I've got nothing to say to you.
(TV NEWS ON)
It's me.
Hi, how's things?
Look at this, it's a Jag XJ6
4.2-litre coupe.
- What?
- Yeah, there were only 6,000 made.
It's got full leather, automatic
transmission, top speed of 120.
- "Immaculate throughout."
- You're not thinking of buying a car?
- He only wants four grand.
- We haven't got four grand.
- We can get it, easy.
- How?
The newspapers.
Look what came through the door.
What?
They want to buy your story.
- It could be worth thousands.
- I can't talk to the press.
I bet everyone else is.
- Who?
- I don't know. The police?
How else does all this stuff
get in the papers?
It's a hell of a story, Janet.
It's just been on the news
about there being more bodies.
Mike, this is ridiculous.
I'm doing this because it's vital,
not to make money.
That's bonkers, if you ask me.
Well, I'll... I'll have to rustle it
up from somewhere else, then.
Is he all right?
- What do you mean? - It's the sort of
thing he starts doing,
talking a lot, buying
stuff he can't afford.
No, he's fine,
he's taking his medication.
Yet another takeaway.
Yeah.
- We had to eat something.
- I'll give you the money.
How long's this going to go on?
I don't know, love.
(BIRD CALLS)
(VEHICLES APPROACH)
Oh, it takes me back, this, you know.
Right back to boyhood.
Every inch, every blade of grass.
That's Letterbox Field there.
We've come to search for the remains of
your first wife. We're not sightseeing.
I know. Lovely to get out of that
police station, eh, Janet?
Smell God's fresh air.
Try there.
Ok, lads. We're over here.
That's the spot there.
Mark that, then, Darren. That's it.
So, if you take that as your
starting point...
Wouldn't mind a wander
over there, too, Janet.
Why?
- For old times' sake.
- What's so special about over there?
See, I love Rose and
I loved Rena, too, but...
...Anna was the one.
Who's Anna?
The true love of my life.
Anna was having a baby, too, but...
That was a baby I wanted.
I don't understand.
Are you all right?
I was just asking Janet
about my fish.
Fish?
My tropical fish,
who's feeding them?
Let's get you back to the nick.
Mike, have you bought it?
Yeah. It's not the one I went after,
in the end, it's another.
- Beautiful, isn't it?
- How much was it?
It's just immaculate.
The bloke I bought it from,
he's a Jag specialist.
How much was it?
- Nine grand.
- 9,000?
You can't spend
that kind of money on a car.
It's fine, I got it on HP.
We don't even need another car.
What is going on in here?
We've got a new TV and a new video,
too. Even better deal than the car.
I got this new unit to put them on, but
they haven't supplied enough fixings...
Mike, Mike, this is ridiculous,
we're...
- Mike, Mike!
- What?
We're not getting
a new TV or a new car.
Have you been taking your lithium?
- Yeah, of course, yeah.
- Are you sure?
No, you haven't,
you've been missing days.
You can't afford to miss
any days, you know that.
Right, kids, upstairs. Go on. Go!
Mike, the car is going back,
and the TV and the video.
- Why?
- Just sit down. Just sit down.
- No. Why?
Just sit down, go and sit down.
Come on, love.
Come on.
I'm going to have to get you into
the hospital.
I'm going to go and
call them now, all right?
- I warned you.
- Just stay out of this, Josh.
None of this would have happened
if you'd been thinking of us.
You'd far rather spend time
with that murderer.
Just leave it, will you, Josh?
Oh, hello, yeah, my name's Janet Leach
and I'm calling about my partner.
Yeah, he's bi-polar and he's going into
a high and I need to bring him in urgently.
He's finally dropped off.
He's clearly got very
over-stimulated, though.
It could take days, maybe weeks,
to get him fully stabilised again.
I see.
- Do you need me to stay?
- No.
Would it be all right if I came back
this afternoon about half-four?
Fine.
(ON TAPE) ROSE: I'm admitting nothing
cos I've got fucking nothing to admit.
MAE: So it's all Dad.
That's what I'm saying, Mae.
I'm as shocked about this as you are.
DC LAW: Rose has denied it to us,
and to her daughter.
We've got nothing else on her.
So, unless Fred drops her in it...
Janet.
- Ready to crack on?
- Yeah, but erm...
- I need to leave at four, I've got
an urgent family matter. - That's Fine.
Did you engage them in
sadomasochistic acts?
They were adventurous young girls.
So, how did you end up killing them?
You even got the killing wrong.
You're trying to make out that I just
went out and blatantly killed people.
It weren't like that.
Enjoyment turned to disaster.
We're all having difficulty
understanding this.
Especially how these things can have
gone on without Rose's knowledge.
- Rose was out.
- Out where?
Shopping.
Whilst you had sex,
murdered and buried them?
She must have had
an awful lot of shopping to do!
She does.
It's a fair old walk to Tesco.
Mary Bastholme.
Carol Cooper.
Lucy Partington.
Shirley Hubbard.
Those women didn't
stay at your house.
I don't believe they were
known to you,
they just disappeared
from local bus stops.
(INTERROGATION FADES OUT)
- Do you know where you were, then?
- One more time...
Did Rose know about
these sexual encounters?
Did she participate in them?
- Did Rose kill Charmaine?
- Rose didn't kill no-one.
I killed Charmaine when
I come out of Leyhill Prison.
For the last time,
Rose had no part of this.
Your loyalty's very touching.
Do you think she feels
the same about you?
- Rose loves me.
- You're so confident about that
you didn't mind her
having sex with other men?
- That's correct.
- So long as you knew about it.
- I always knew about it. - So you knew
she was seeing male clients
at another premises in Gloucester?
- What?
- 22 Sunderland Street.
- That's rubbish! - We spoke to men
who met her there for sex.
Do you find that upsetting, Fred?
There were things in Rose's life
you didn't know about.
Sexual relationships
she kept to herself.
- No, I don't, cos you're making it up.
- No, I'm not Fred.
I bloody well know you are!
Rose is all mine,
she always has been.
And I would know,
I'd know here if that ever changed.
Rose is my love, that was she is, and
I ain't having you lot telling me otherwise.
- Sit down, please, Fred.
- Fred, you're not helping yourself.
The interview is ended
at 15:47 by my watch.
This suggestion that Rose West was
seeing men without Mr West's knowledge,
any further disclosure about that?
- You'd better come to the office.
- I want to be giving the correct advice.
- Don't rush off, Janet.
- I have to.
That's bullshit about Rose seeing other
fellas in some place I don't know about.
I'm afraid I can't stay
and discuss it now.
A man needs to know
his wife has no secrets.
Would you keep secrets
from your husband?
- I'm not married. - There's
a lucky fella in your life. I can tell.
- Mind your own bloody business.
- Please don't go. Please.
There's something I want to tell you.
It's about Rose.
What about her?
She was involved.
In how many of them?
Lots.
The things I could tell you about
what she done to some of them girls.
I may have started it, but...
..she took over
and did whatever she liked.
I mean it. She did took that baby
out of Shirley's body, not me.
That's the kind of woman she is.
If all that is true, how can you
hold that back from the police?
For the sake of the family.
I don't understand.
We made a pact, see, that I would
take all the blame to myself.
On the day the police
come with the warrant,
I was out, Rose called me to warn me.
When I got home, the police give us
five minutes alone and we agreed then
that I'd tell them it was all me.
And I know you think it's wrong
that Rose gets away with it
and I pay the price, but
that's the plan we made.
So she could look after the family
and that plan is working, Anna.
- Why did you just call me Anna?
- Sorry. Janet.
I get confused.
My mind's spinning with all this...
I'm losing everything.
my family, my wife...
home.
And you,
you're helping me through
the most terrible time in my life.
You're my only friend.
- I'm not your friend, Fred.
- You are.
We're going on
a journey together, Janet.
Neither of us knows
where it's going to end but...
... we're on it together.
I have to go.
Mrs Leach.
Yeah?
We won't be needing you any more.
What?
Your services on the inquiry
are no longer required.
- Why?
- I'm not obliged to give reasons.
You can't just drop me
without any explanation.
- Yes, I can.
- No, you can't, not now.
What do you mean, not now?
I can't answer that.
Well, clearly you found
all this very distressing but
thank you for your help.
I tell you, I'm sick of this, the
fucking trouble your father caused me
and those fucking police,
yammering on at me.
What I done when, what your dad done
when, who stayed in the fucking house.
Well, I'm not taking the blame
for fucking nothing.
What you believe don't matter, Hazel.
It's what you can prove that matters.
(SHOUTING)
I need you, Janet. Please.
I thought I'd frightened you off.
What are you doing?
I get the feeling that there's more
that he wants to tell me.
I think there are more bodies.
I didn't kill Anna.
Believe me, Janet.
She guided me through you.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
- Rose isn't even here.
- No, but she's in here. She's in here.
For your own peace of mind, stop.
I can't.
Sync and corrected by:
www.addic7ed.com.
itfc subtitles