Swannie.
Come over here.
Come to me.
Nice, Swan.
Come on.
Come to me, Mr. Swan.
You'll frighten it!
Help!
Go get my parents.
Go!
I've killed him.
I kill...
ohh.
Ohh.
Nathan!
Oh Jesus.
- Where's Claire?
- Call 911!
- I don't know what happened!
- Where is she?
- He came out of nowhere!
- Nathan...
Do you think he can hear me?
Where's Claire?
Where is she?
I'll look for her later!
I was dead.
I mean,
I was really dead.
Really.
Tell me about it.
What's it like to be dead?
I'd got loose.
It were as if I was
getting out of my body.
My body was staying here,
and I...
I was flying.
You were floating?
Yes.
I heard that dog,
and a woman screaming.
They were around me,
panicking and...
then I heard that noise.
It was like a whistle.
A very, very loud whistle.
I saw... a light.
A light?
Yes.
It was alive.
It was alive
as if it were waiting for me.
I was in the light.
I felt good.
- Didn't you want to come back?
- No.
But you did come back.
Yes.
Why did you come back?
I just did.
Something made you come back.
Is there something you're holding back?
Yes.
Hey, would you like
to hear about Jesus Christ?
Here you go.
Would you like to hear
Excuse me, would you like to hear
about Jesus Christ today?
Like to hear about Jesus Christ?
- Okay.
- Thank you very much, sir.
Would you like to hear
about Jesus Christ? Have a great day.
about Jesus Christ today?
But what made him come back?
Won't you answer?
Nathan?
Right turn.
It doesn't recover.
We're dropping the...
Speed, 220 knots.
Wings lowered.
Flap up.
Flap up! Flap up!
Power! Power!
Oh, shit!
No!
Of the 45 passengers on board,
nine belonged
to the same family.
All from Haiti.
So?
So they're afraid of getting
fucked over by the Warsaw Convention.
I explained to them
that doesn't exist here,
but they're scared,
even still.
They set up a committee.
I met their spokesman.
They gave me this.
What does the NTSB say about this?
The NTSB isn't getting involved.
Neither is the FAA.
They've all washed their
hands of it.
The airline is registered
in the Virgin Islands,
the tour operator in the Caymans.
The crew is from Russia.
They still don't know...
if the plane crashed in Haiti
or the Dominican Republic.
Every day it's a different story.
But the plane was due
to land here in the US?
Seems like everyone forgot that.
The FAA isn't going
to go poking its nose in.
Too much work, too much hassle,
too much everything.
Nathan?
I don't like the smell of it.
If the FAA won't get involved,
that means a lawsuit like this
could drag on for years.
That means hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
And it means we can forget
about the Hague Protocol.
I don't like it.
Excuse me,
since when are we afraid of cases
that drag on for years?
These people are going
to get fucked over
on the pretext that no convention...
It was the same shit in Unterlinguen.
In Kinshasa too.
A judge will show up
with his calculator and say what?
"All right, let's imagine
some two-year-old kid
"who has lost his mother.
"We'll say she'd have devoted
how much of her time
to him, per day?"
- Michael?
- Three hours, tops.
That's a good mother.
Up until the age of 18,
which gives us three hours
a day, times 365 days,
times $8 an hour,
plus the usual interest...
that totals a little less
than $100,000 at best.
- And the plane wasn't even full.
- See?
How far will that get you?
You can't even take your mistress
on a weekend trip.
Nothing.
All right, fine.
But tomorrow morning,
these people are going
to be in my office.
- What do you want me to tell them?
- Send them to me.
I'll explain everything.
They'll understand, don't worry.
Anything else?
Your appointment is here.
Who is this guy?
Remind me.
Joseph Kay.
Heads up a department at St. Louis.
- I'm not sure what he wants.
- Heads up a department?
Something like that.
"Something like that".
"I'm not sure what he wants".
What's that supposed to mean?
Why send him to me?
- You were recommended.
- By who?
- Who upstairs?
- Ross.
I see.
- Your daughter called.
- Oh, yeah?
She left you messages at home and...
Yeah, I know.
I forgot.
She wanted to talk
about the vacation.
She wanted to know,
was it, "Like the usual?"
This was my daughter
who called or my wife?
Your daughter.
Okay, I'll call her back.
Yes?
All that glucose...
Worries me.
I can examine you if you want.
I'm a doctor.
All right...
what can I do for you, Dr. Kay?
You work at St. Louis, right?
I don't know if I'm the right...
Nathan, I believe you
have misunderstood me.
I'm very serious.
You mustn't take
hypoglycemia lightly.
In fact, you shouldn't
take any symptom lightly... ever.
You can't imagine the number
of cells you burn up every day.
Of course, you'll tell me
you're also manufacturing...
- I don't want to interrupt...
- But it's not so.
Neurons can't be replaced.
Some die every day.
Every day a few more.
All that glucose you're pumping in
is just cheap energy.
Very bad for you,
very bad for the neurons.
Thank you for your concern
about my health, but I'm fine.
Now why don't you tell me
what you want from me?
That slight shaking in your hands,
have you had that a long time?
It's a morning thing, right?
When you wake up?
You work too much.
Sure.
Excuse me.
Oui, mon ange.
Yes, sweetheart, I know.
Yeah, yeah.
Daddy will call you back,
but now I'm...
wait, hang on.
Would you excuse me a second?
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
Honey, I can't talk to you now.
Rachel, check out
that guy for me... now.
Of course you're coming for vacation.
Sure you are.
No, honey, I can't come get you.
We'll do just like last time, I...
We'll see.
Okay, I'll call you back.
Love you.
Don't ever do this to me again.
Ever.
I've got a screwball in my office.
He may be a screwball,
but he wasn't lying.
He's head of a department at St. Louis.
Ross didn't tell you anything else?
No, nothing.
They say the swan sings only once,
just before dying.
Yes, I know.
He senses he's going to die,
so he sings.
It's not because of the pain.
On the contrary,
he sings because he's glad.
He's glad to die.
- The number of legends about swans...
- Dr. Kay.
They also say swans
guide and keep company
with the dead,
to help them cross the threshold.
That's my favorite...
a very old Celtic legend.
- Yes, I know it.
- You do?
- Yes, my wife told me about it.
- Your wife told you about it?
Right.
You mean your ex-wife?
We all live in glass houses.
So I see.
Why don't you finally tell me
what I can do for you?
I believe I'm the one
who can do something for you.
But you'll see for yourself.
Certain experiences
can be very unsettling.
I'll see what, for God's sake?
What experiences?
I'm merely pointing out
the need to be prepared.
Is that a threat?
No, it's not a threat.
It's a message.
But I'm not quite sure
you're ready to hear it.
How come you know
so much about me?
Did you have me checked out?
Did you...
was it Ross
told you all that stuff?
"The need to be prepared".
What's that supposed to mean?
I don't know this Ross person.
I've never met the guy.
And I think you know
what I want from you.
I think you know very well.
Hello?
It's me.
Claire, hello.
Yeah, I'm here.
Is Tracey there?
Yeah, sure.
You want to talk to her?
She called me today.
She wanted me to call back.
I know, she told me.
Um, Tracey's asleep.
She's in bed.
Already? Is she okay?
What's wrong?
She waited for you to call all day.
She's drawing things
I don't understand
and waking up at night.
No, she's not okay.
Is there anything I can do?
Let's talk about this
another time, okay?
I'll tell her you called.
Okay.
Nathan.
Nathan!
Listen, I came to apologize
for this morning.
I was a little heavy-handed
and I wanted to apologize.
I have something to show you
not far from here.
Nathan, wait.
Listen.
I have something to show you,
I just don't know if you'll be able
to handle it, that's all.
I'm fed up with your mysteries.
I'm tired.
Nathan, it'll take
five minutes of your time,
no more.
And then I'm out of here.
You'll never see me again.
I give you my word.
- You give me your word?
- Yes.
I give you my word.
You know who I am,
you know where I work,
you're a lawyer.
If I do anything wrong,
anything at all which...
It wouldn't take you five minutes
to blow my career out of the water.
Nathan, believe me,
it's important.
You have to see it.
I swear.
It's important.
Come with me.
Five minutes.
10 minutes... no more.
And then... I'm gone.
You brought me here
just to tell me this?
What the hell does it mean?
Or is that all part of the message?
You come out with these
little riddles of yours
and expect me to...
You see that guy,
the kid in the orange jacket?
Do you see him?
Yeah, I see him.
So what?
Name of Dennis.
10 years ago to this day,
his father died here.
He was waiting for a train
as he did every evening.
He had a good job, happy family.
And one evening, he'd had enough.
And when the express came by,
he jumped.
Was he a friend of yours?
And these last few days,
Dennis has come here
every evening.
- Every evening.
- Do you ever answer a question?
Look at him.
- Why should I?
- Look at him.
Because in about two minutes,
Dennis there will be dead.
What the f...
You're crazy.
Completely crazy.
You gotta take the Chambers Street Exit,
right across the platform.
Look!
He's got a gun!
Listen, don't do it!
Please,
put the gun down!
Is this your first time?
You seem kind of young.
He's here to see Dr. Kay.
- Okay.
- He'll come get you in the day room.
- This way?
- Mm-hmm.
I... I think what you're
doing is wonderful.
You came to see him?
He'll be here.
Just have to wait.
Come here.
What's the matter?
Something wrong?
Myocardial metastases.
Cancer of the heart muscle.
Super rare, right?
They wrote an article
about me in a magazine.
It's in my room,
if you want to see it.
Apparently, I could croak
from one day to the next...
from one minute to the next.
- Jeremy.
- Nathan.
What do you do, Nathan?
I'm a lawyer. Do you know
if he's going to be long?
The first doc I saw,
you know what he called it?
"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy".
Wow.
Can you believe that guy?
You and me,
we're gonna slap that...
that son-of-a-bitch with a lawsuit.
What do you say?
Legally, that's not exactly my bag.
Jeremy, hello.
- Up already?
- Yeah.
- Happy birthday.
- Yeah, thanks.
You've made a new friend.
- Are you the new volunteer?
- He's a lawyer.
He and I are gonna throw
a doctor's ass in the slammer.
Oh, well... see you later.
Bye.
You smell that stink?
Like something's rotting?
Behind the stink of detergent...
can't you smell that?
It reeks of death around here.
Why do you think
she puts up with it?
She had a kid who died.
That's why.
All of us in here
are going out in body bags,
and she knows that.
She thinks that when we see
her little darling up there...
we'll tell him
how mommy's doing.
And we'll take care of him.
Make sure he eats his dinner
and goes to the potty up in Heaven.
Volunteer, my ass.
What about you?
You got a message to send, too?
Who you got up there, huh?
I'm going soon,
so make the most of it.
Some "dearly beloved?"
- Or maybe...
- Excuse me.
Hey!
Hey, come back.
I didn't mean it like that.
I don't know how to die.
None of us know how to die.
But maybe...
somewhere deep inside of us...
a part of us does know how.
Maybe it's not as terrible
as it seems.
Try and rest.
You know, Nathan,
the dying have taught me one thing...
that you can look death in the face
and go on living.
Our mission here is
to keep them company.
Keep company with those
about to die
so that they can depart in peace.
Great, but what's it
got to do with me?
Me, my.
My little consciousness,
my little comforts,
my little life.
What about others, Nathan,
do you ever think about them?
And Dennis?
Have you thought about Dennis?
If you knew he was going
to blow his brains out,
why didn't you do something?
Why didn't you try to listen to him?
Who kept Dennis company
so he'd "depart in peace?"
Anyway, how did you know
he was going to die?
This time I want an answer,
none of your...
- I saw it.
- You saw it?
- Yes.
- How did you see it?
Was it written on his face?
- Yes.
- Yes?
Listen, I'm beat.
I didn't sleep last night because of you,
- and I've got to be at work...
- Nathan,
people who come here,
they've already traveled
a long road
paved with suffering.
But they have had time
to prepare themselves.
But often death comes...
unexpectedly.
It can't be predicted.
Yes, I know, yes.
For instance, say you cross
the street at the wrong moment,
or the body just gives out...
just like that.
Snap your fingers,
you're dead.
We see that every day.
And those people never have
time to untangle the knots.
They never have time
to prepare themselves.
And so?
And so...
the role of the Messengers
is to give those people too
a chance to be reconciled.
- "The Messengers?"
- Yes.
I don't understand.
There are people out there
who know in advance
that someone is going to die.
Let's say they...
"got the message".
And in those cases,
their job is to help that person
depart in peace... reconcile.
- And you're one of these "Messengers?"
- Yes, I am.
- You know who's going to die?
- Yes.
- You see it?
- Yes, I see it.
And you help them depart in peace.
Nathan, I realize it
may be hard to believe...
But Dennis didn't depart in peace.
- No.
- Why?
We don't always succeed.
Sometimes we get there too late.
No one has power over
the hour of death.
No one.
I don't believe you.
Have it your way, Nathan.
But these things can still exist
whether you believe
in them or not.
I know when someone's
going to die... I see it.
And I make every effort
to prepare them for what's coming.
Well, I think I've
heard enough for today.
What exactly are you
trying to tell me?
Are you trying to tell me
I'm going to die soon? Is that it?
I told you everything.
You know everything.
Go fuck yourself.
Hurry up.
Sam.
Sam, hurry up.
Bring that over.
Hurry up.
Breathe, breathe,
breathe.
We need a neck brace and a splint.
Get that here.
Look straight into the light.
Don't move.
The smell of the ghosts.
Follow the smell of the ghosts
and you'll find the flower.
Nathan on phone:
What did you say, sweetheart?
It's a cactus.
It makes a flower once a year,
at midnight.
Only once.
At 12:00 noon, the flower dies,
and it smells like ghosts.
The flower smells like ghosts?
Yeah,
but it's real nice.
Mommy says ghosts smell good.
The Night Blooming Cereus.
Yes, I remember.
Mommy told me about it too.
An Indian legend.
Honey, can I talk to Mommy?
She says she'll call you back.
Tracey?
Hello?
I had everything checked out,
everything...
brain, heart, lungs, blood.
I got my urine tested,
my saliva, my sperm...
they tested everything
and they found nothing.
Nothing at all.
There's the file.
Take a look.
A little hypoglycemia
and nothing else.
Nothing else at all.
I'm very glad to hear that, Nathan.
- I'm happy for you.
- So as of this minute,
you are out of my life.
No phone calls,
no visits, nothing.
If I ever see you again
here or any place at all,
it'll mean the police...
got it?
May I show you something?
- No.
- It's a photograph.
Anna Rachevsky.
Very cute.
Now leave.
From a Russian family.
That photograph was taken
the day she arrived in New York.
I don't give a shit.
Not much money,
father out of the picture.
She wanted to go to college,
but the closest she ever got
was working in
the cafeteria at NYU.
Her boss treated her
like an animal.
The students didn't even notice.
Except one.
He was a foreigner too...
a Frenchman.
She welcomed the kindness
he showed her.
But later, she was fired.
He lost touch with her.
End of story.
Anna Rachevsky, right.
- Coming back?
- Yes.
She works at the Greenwind diner
in Queens.
Late night shift.
Not very well paying.
She's had a child...
a son.
You should stop by and see her.
I'm sure she would
enjoy that very much.
I'll do that, maybe, yes.
Good.
What?
Have you understood me?
No.
What?
What was it this time?
What did you see?
Tell me.
A blinking light?
Some kind of Christmas tree
that begins to...
No, actually, Nathan,
it's a bright white light
that surrounds the person.
But that's not the most
important thing.
What's the most important thing?
The most important thing
is suddenly you'll just know.
You'll know she's going to die.
Nathan?
What are you doing here?
Doing?
Well, I...
I'm just here.
You're as handsome as ever.
Well?
What? No, I just...
actually I was passing through.
You doing okay?
You were passing through here?
Yes, I was going back
to the city.
I was in Queens
and I was going home.
I was dying for a cup of coffee,
and here I am.
You go heavy
on the sugar, huh?
Yes. You're looking well.
- What?
- I said you're looking well.
How's your health?
Okay?
You look like you're
in fine health.
Yes, fine.
It's strange for me,
seeing you again.
Excuse me.
- Are you married?
- Divorced.
Oh.
I never had the time.
He walked out before marrying me.
He still found the time
to knock me up first though.
A good thing too,
you might say.
A little boy.
- What's this?
- It's for you.
These are my numbers.
This one...
is the direct line
to Rachel, my assistant,
and that's my cell phone.
And don't hesitate to...
if you need me for anything,
if anything should come up,
call me. Okay?
If anything comes up,
I call you.
Okay.
And what could possibly come up?
- How old is your daughter?
- Seven.
Do you speak French with her?
- No, not much.
- You should.
I know.
Look at me,
I hardly speak Russian anymore.
But when my father came back,
he talked and talked.
He wouldn't stop talking.
- Did I tell you my father came back?
- No.
You know, we didn't hear
from him in years.
- From your father?
- Yes.
He disappeared into air.
But then two weeks ago
we got a letter.
And in this letter
there was a picture of him
and his phone number
and address.
He was driving a cab
in Toronto.
And on the very same day,
he got a letter too.
And in it was a picture of me
and my phone number,
and a round trip ticket to New York.
See? So for the past two weeks
I believe in miracles.
- And the letters were?
- We don't know who sent them.
We tried,
but we never found out.
A Dr. Kay...
at St. Louis Hospital,
does it ring a bell?
Fuck Ocean City,
Here's a long one.
"Dear, Jeremy,
I turn 17 today too".
Oh, his mother's
the one...
Who asked you?
Huh?
"We don't know each other
and you may think this is weird,
but ever since I heard
your story on the radio,
I think about you often".
"I wish you a very,
very happy birthday.
Write me if you want.
Love, Jennifer".
Right, yeah.
I love you too.
Next time, send me a snapshot
of your cute ass, Jennifer.
Bye, bye.
Happy birthday.
Oh, a baby Jesus.
Great.
Jeremy.
- "Dear Jeremy, blah blah blah".
- Jeremy.
"with our hope you'll be able to leave
the hospital very soon".
Jeremy, can you look at me?
Asshole,
I'm going to die in this hospital!
That's why I'm here,
don't you fucking get it?
Jeremy, what's going on?
What's going on is
that my dumbass mother
went on the radio
to tell the world
that her poor little kid
was having a birthday soon
and the poor angel was dying
of a very serious and rare disease.
And then dozens of assholes
I don't even know,
they're just writing me
to wish me a happy birthday,
and... fuck.
Fuck.
Goddamn it,
why did this have
to happen to me?
I'm 17.
I'm 17 fucking years old,
I don't understand.
Jeremy, you shouldn't
talk like that.
Oh, really?
So what,
I should just sit here
with my mouth shut?
You know what my mom said
when I told her I was gonna die?
She just looked at me
and she was like,
"Oh, no, Jeremy, I forbid
you to say such a thing".
Well, I'm gonna die.
I know I'm gonna die.
And how does that
make you feel, Jeremy,
knowing you're going to die?
I think about all the good shit
I'm gonna miss out on.
And that makes you angry.
Yeah.
And also I just...
I don't know.
I want people to see me
like I normally am.
You know?
I want people to listen to me.
I just want someone to listen.
I agreed to see you because...
you've got a solid case.
I'm sorry,
I don't understand.
I don't speak Creole.
She says she lost both
of her sons in the accident.
She says she knows
you can help us.
- She says...
- Madame, please.
...she's praying for you.
She also said
you have a big heart.
- Tell her she's wrong.
- She can see it.
- She's wrong!
- If you refuse to defend us,
the other lawyers will find out,
and they will refuse too.
- All of them.
- Please, sir, do something for us.
No.
No, that's not true.
Okay.
But you've got a solid case.
Pass it, pass it.
- Alonzo!
- Take it home!
Woman on TV:
"He asked whether the man
"When he heard he was
under Herod's jurisdiction,
"he sent him off to Herod,
who was himself
in Jerusalem at that time".
Man on TV:
"When Herod saw Jesus,
"he was very glad,
"for he had been wanting
to see him for a long time.
"Because he had
heard about him
"and was hoping to see Jesus
perform some sign.
"Herod questioned him
at some length,
but Jesus gave him no answer".
You know, she came
She told me again what a wonderful
husband you were.
Up there,
she sees everything
you do for me.
The Blessed Virgin was
here too, you know.
Oh? The Blessed Virgin
was here?
Yeah.
She watched us
through the window.
You see,
there on the buffet...
that's her hand.
She left that there for us
to let us know
she's thinking about us.
That's your wife's hand.
You could kiss it, you know.
No.
Please.
It's not a mother's job
to bury a daughter.
No, it isn't.
But you have to let the dead
lay with the dead.
You have to.
I saw Anna.
She said she'd never heard of you.
But the picture, the plane ticket...
I know it was you.
What's your game?
Why are you toying
with these people?
I simply did what I had to do.
The father found his daughter again,
and the daughter, her father.
Anna's still going to die.
But hopefully she'll die
more at peace with herself.
It's not a game.
But if she's going to die,
protect her, do something!
There's nothing else
I can do.
I told you, no one has power
over the hour of death.
Anna!
- I think it's for you!
- Who is it?
I think it's Mr. Handsome.
Who is it?
- Nathan?
- Hi.
- What are you doing here?
- Am I disturbing you?
No, of course not.
Come in, come in!
My cousin had
a baby this morning
and we're celebrating his birth.
You must have passed Micha.
He's the daddy.
He just went out with Ivan,
my brother.
And this is Marina, Stephanie.
You've met Judy, my sister-in-law.
Come on, I'll introduce you
to my mother.
Mama.
This is Nathan,
a good friend of mine.
Nice to meet you.
It's okay.
I'll handle it!
We're wired to the building next door.
Maybe they cut something off.
Hey, look who's here!
This is my pride and joy.
This is him!
Papa, this is Nathan.
- Hi.
- Glad to meet you.
We met when I was
working at the university.
Excuse me,
the light doesn't work.
Anna, wait,
you shouldn't touch that.
I've seen Ivan do it.
It couldn't be so complicated.
Stop, please.
It's dangerous.
We cannot just stay
in the dark, can we?
Listen to me, I'm serious.
You have no idea
how many people...
No. Hold this for me!
Hold this!
Just a second.
Okay.
Here.
Ahh.
You see?
It works now.
Anna, I have to tell you...
No, please.
Fine. Okay.
You're right.
We'll take care of it later.
Let's have a drink.
I had a check-up recently...
- A what?
- A check-up.
Oh.
And I said to myself...
let's say,
maybe it would be
a good idea if you did too.
Had one.
A check-up.
Me?
Why?
You never know.
If you want,
I got the address...
You want to marry me,
but first you want
to make sure
I'm the picture of health.
is that it?
I was kidding.
Have you ever tasted
Georgian vodka?
No. Will you think about it?
What, marrying you?
If you take me to Paris,
no problem.
Really, I'm fine.
I swear.
I can't see why
you're so worried.
Your health.
Ivan?
Just a moment.
Ivan.
Papa, don't touch that.
Papa!
I have a right to it, my son has a right,
so does my father.
- No.
- Listen, he worked all his life
and now he's up there
and he needs care,
so don't tell me there's
nothing you can do.
You're going to treat him...
If you will kindly listen,
I will explain to you...
I'm going to stay at his side
as long as he needs me.
No, I will not kindly listen.
Excuse me, can I see
your supervisor?
I'm the person in charge.
Everything's fine.
It's okay.
Your father is
a Canadian citizen
and the program only applies
to American residents.
He is insured in Canada.
He has insurance.
- Oh?
- Yes.
In that case,
he's sure to be covered.
In the meantime, for us,
it makes no difference.
- If it's a deposit you need...
- It's all right, don't worry.
- For you it makes no difference?
- No. It makes no difference.
Fine.
You go tell him.
You go up
and tell him yourself.
He's an adult,
you're an adult.
- Mrs. Rachevsky?
- Just a second!
So you go up and tell him
he left Russia for this.
That he came and find his children
in America all for this!
- Mrs. Rachevsky.
- What? What?
I'm sorry.
What?
"No one has power over
the hour of death," you remember?
Bullshit.
Pure bullshit.
I saved Anna.
I got there in time
and prevented her
from touching
that goddamn circuit box
and she didn't die.
It was her father who died.
Not Anna...
her father, asshole.
Nathan, calm down.
What kind of game
are you playing with us, huh?
You bring the father
and daughter together
and send me over there.
You knew I'd go there.
You knew full well.
You send me over there
just so I'll watch her die?
Is that it, motherfucker?
- Listen to me...
- You think you're God,
but you're nothing but a fucking pervert
and a shitty doctor.
It's like that
at your hospital too, isn't it?
You watch your patients die
one after another.
That's how you get your kicks,
how you get your...
Nathan, tell me what happened.
Tell me.
It was her father who died.
That's what happened.
Anna is fine.
Anna isn't going to die,
and neither am I.
And there's no, like,
light or halo or shit!
Is he still asleep?
Sounds like it.
Nathan.
Nathan!
Claire?
You okay?
- Claire?
- Thank you for calling 911.
All of our operators are busy.