This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Only the council keeps
favoring unanimous voting,
and should any proposal
meet your disapproval,
it has always ended up being rejected.
Not only does this impede
our country's development,
but, as it is but an expedient to
protect the powerful nobles' interests,
I propose voting regulations
for the council of nobles...
move to a majority vote.
Right!
That's right.
What she said is right!
Nine to one?!
~ Episode 44 ~
Nine approved,
and only one was against it.
But, as the council
favors unanimous voting...
It was rejected.
Nine approved?!
Lord Sejong,
Lord Misaeng, Lord Hajong...
They must be amongst those nine.
Yes, Milord.
It is indeed as you suggest.
Mishil does it again.
Seems like she was behind all this.
They certainly could not
let the taxation reform pass,
but they also wanted
to escape any criticism...
their refusal to accept
it would have incurred?!
But, Her Highness proposed to
change the council's unanimous vote...
to a majority vote, proposal which
is being deliberated upon at the moment.
Majority vote?!
Well... I am sure it will not pass.
They could not reach a
unanimous vote on the reform,
majority vote?!
Would something like that ever pass?
It will not pass, but it is
by no means a bad stratagem.
Why?
Still, think of how disheartened all the
nobles wishing for those reforms will be.
So we must foment even
more disheartenment, you mean?!
And that disheartenment
must be directed at the council.
They're quite the fruitless
parade, are they not?
- Right?
- Indeed!
Those feelings...
"They are of little worth..."
Such feelings is what we must foment.
Make your choice.
Her Highness's proposal to change
our council's voting procedures...
was approved by two,
and rejected by eight members,
therefore leading to its rejection.
Think this will mean a
triumph for Your Highness?
I merely reciprocated,
Your Highness.
I ought to...
Think of how propitious the
passing of that reform would have been.
How lamentable.
Nine to one?!
I had no expectations on
the matter, none whatsoever.
There was no way it would pass!
Then...
What brought you all the way here?
Was not "expectations"
what led you here?
Ohh... that!
With all the land those
council members possess,
there was no way they would
pass such reform from the start.
From the start...
Even knowing that,
I still had some expectations.
But we once again found out, uh?!
As long as unanimous voting
dominates the council,
nothing in this country
will ever change!
What are you trying to say?
Did I ever say anything
about your clan?
Is being in possession of
plentiful land and assets a crime?
Wangyun Rang was not
talking about that.
The reason certain clans might be
in possession of larger territory...
is either because their efforts
led to such expansion,
or because their meritorious
service granted them such benefits.
Is that a crime?
Even petty nobles with very little
land boast the same kind of fealty.
So does this discriminatory
treatment show any fairness?
There is a clear
difference between people,
do we have to equally divide land now?
What is wrong with you two?
Are you telling me Deokman was
the one proposing for majority vote?
Lord Seohyeon and I did approve,
but as all the other council
members were against it,
the motion was rejected.
Was it not impossible
from the very start?
Did not the council use unanimous
voting for the last seven centuries?
I am sure Her Highness herself
knew the motion would not pass.
Yes... As even that was rejected,
all the lesser nobles who
participated voiced their disapproval.
It is likely that is what
Her Highness wished for.
Are you telling me she did this to show
how fruitless the council has become?
It is very likely those
were Her Highness's intentions.
Right...
She managed to show that anything
which would go against...
the powerful nobles'
benefit would never pass.
Sire.
Are you all right?
Should we escort you to your berth?
I am fine.
Fret not.
Are we not mutually engaging
in one subterfuge after another?
Majority vote?
What a most discerning move.
Yes, as any proposal would find
it arduous to pass with this system.
Is not unanimous voting
a seven century-long tradition?
However,
it is a vestige of the past which
no longer suits our current situation.
All it has become is a subterfuge
to favor the powerful nobles' interests.
And that is because no reform
would be approved unanimously by them.
That is certainly true.
Still.
Still, Your Highness...
Do you realize that
same unanimous voting...
is also benefiting you?
What?
Should the nobles propose a motion
to oust you from any decision making?
With a majority vote,
only six votes of approval...
would be required to force you
out of any further deliberation.
However, since it is
still unanimous voting,
be it Lord Seohyeon or Lord Yongchun,
would not a single vote against
the motion cause it to be rejected?
And that is why you
continue enjoying your status.
I see.
I was indeed gaining benefits myself.
Our statute and institutions...
They are always a perilous
sword with two edges.
Not only their foe, but even those
wielding it may injure themselves.
Then,
is using such statute and institutions
to contend with your foes...
such immoral behavior?
Statute and institutions...
Again... again...
I almost risked telling
you everything, once again.
How sagacious your sincerity can be.
It almost caused me to once again
fall for that trap of yours.
If I may...
Hey! Minions!
Aigoo... What now?!
The council rejected both proposals.
- Uh?!
- Ehh... You pathetic dolts.
You are the true minions...
Wake up, will you?
Looks like expectations
completely floored them?!
They are really angry, uh?!
That is too bad.
What a shame!
You dolt, how much land
does your clan possess?
Why are you suddenly
curious about that?
*1 sok = 15 square meters
Aigoo... look at you.
Over five thousand sok*?
Uh?!
Had this amendment been passed,
your clan's lives
would have been improved!
Ehh... You ignoramus.
He doesn't even realize
what can benefit him.
You pathetic dolt...
Tell me about it.
Does he have some issues up there?
Just stay put, uh?!
That's kind of true...
Aigoo... you're so hopeless.
Wake up, you dolt.
Let's go.
Couldn't smell money
if it was under your nose...
Ehh...
I just thought that...
Why did you hit me?
Now that I think about it, you dolt,
is that how you address
your direct superior?
Well deserved, wasn't it?
You dolt.
So it should have passed, uh?!
On second thought, the taxation
reform was not such a bad proposal.
Is that not right, Seokpum Rang?
So...
Are you saying it should
have passed successfully?
Why are you suddenly
raising your voice?
It is because of the
drivel you're uttering!
Listen, Seokpum Rang.
Had this amendment passed,
it would have meant benefits
for your own clan as well.
The same goes for mine.
Don't you realize it is but
a subterfuge by Her Highness...
to make Lady Mishil's followers sway?
However, both you and I incurred
heavy losses during the last crops crisis.
It might not mean much
for the powerful nobles,
but one of the pillars holding
our clan was lost in the fray.
Nothing I said was uncalled for.
Careful with your parlance.
The reason we are still here,
and still own any land at all...
It all happened because of
Her Highness Lady Mishil's benevolence.
Have you forgotten?
Seokpum Rang!
Seokpum Rang!!
I really...
Ever since the princess
came back to Seorabeol,
there has not been
a single day of tranquility.
Why, is anything the matter?
All the petty nobles who
participated at the last council...
are gathering here and there
and making such a commotion!
From their point of view,
it is understandable.
It makes no sense!
Unanimous voting is a seven
century-long tradition of ours,
so how and why would
you suddenly abolish it?
No.
In the end,
it must be indeed abolished.
No... In truth, the council itself
is a rather fruitless apparatus.
Your Highness!
What?
"Rather fruitless"?!
What is that supposed to mean?
Yes. Should I achieve
my grandiose endeavors,
it will be the first thing
I will abolish.
Of course, now is not the time.
What did you just say?
Lord Chunchu!
Do what with the council?!
Is that not the case?
Was I speaking in haste?
But in the end, should we not rid
ourselves of the council altogether?
Shouldn't we?
Right... I do think so myself.
However... The council is a
seven century-long tradition of ours.
Abolish it, Your Highness?!
Our path shall from now on
be laden with sudden upheavals.
Hence... I was indeed thinking
whether we should rid ourselves of it.
What our nation needs now
are rapid decisions,
and the ability to rapidly
make plans come into fruition.
Yes... So you spent
the night preparing this?
No, I just could not catch sleep.
I took the time to devise such plans,
may you take a look.
What a cowardly
and baseborn artifice...
Yes, it certainly is.
"It certainly is"?!
But, it should be much more cowardly,
baseborn and spurious, Milord.
Yes... I shall find the kind
of solution you are looking for.
The more ignoble
and squalid, the better.
Enough that anyone reading it
would be disgusted by its vulgarity.
But, Mother...
What would that be?
Is it the morrow?
Or the day after?
Tomorrow.
What is perturbing you?
Sister...
Must we really do this?
Why?
Are you feeling uneasy about this?
Why would any of this
perturb my mind?!
I just...
Just?!
I just think this behavior
does not suit you, Sister.
Whatever disdain
your peers accord you,
I believe the annals of history will
consign you to a luminous legacy.
However, this can besmirch everything
you have accomplished so far.
It certainly could.
The world does indeed fear you,
and shows you contempt,
but never have you acted
against principle.
But when it comes to this,
I hardly think it is the case.
No... Once...
I once did do something
against principle.
Sadaham...
My devotion for him convinced
me to abandon everything...
and plan to together elope.
That was against my every principle.
Yes...
It was that which moved me
to never repeat such behavior.
So, why do it now, of all times?
I now share the same
sentiments as those days.
Quite similar to
what I felt for Sadaham.
Similar as in...
Enough that Mishil will abandon
principle to follow her dreams,
and should even failure
be bestowed upon her,
she will go out in style.
Well, to that extent?!
What? Piltan Rang and
Wangyun Rang's fathers?
Yes. As they both own less than
five thousand sok of land,
they could have become
recipients of your taxation reforms.
That is good to hear.
Where are they?
I shall meet them right away.
The Pungwolju just told me.
I am whelmed with
gratitude for your support.
~ Lord Jujin ~
(Piltan's father, Sangju commander)
You need not flatter us.
We should rather be the ones to
extend you our sincerest gratitude.
Do not even mention it.
We can only be in awe at
the concern you have shown...
for the lesser nobles
and their situation.
No...
It is nobles of purpose
such as yourself...
who should aid this country to go
through the reforms it so fervently needs.
The council has become
nothing more than a pretext...
for the powerful nobles
to maintain their supremacy.
From here on in,
I will need your support.
- Yes, Your Highness.
- Yes. Your Highness.
So, how did she seem?
She requested our support
to reform the council of nobles.
Reform the council?!
Yes.
Saying it has become a mere
pretext to continue your supremacy...
Lord Jujin.
You know, right?
That this is nothing but
a subterfuge by Her Highness...
so that the nobles
will foment dissension.
You cannot let this sway you.
There is nothing
that would sway me,
but as I am staking my life on this...
No.
You have a responsibility to
maintain public order in the capital.
How could that ever
go against principle?!
I am counting on Your Excellency.
Did you come here
yourself, Your Highness?
I thought Lord Misaeng would come...
It is... our first meeting, I trust?
I have heard a lot about you.
Seems like you granted us valuable support?!
And what could I possibly have done?
I merely conveyed to Lord Misaeng
talebearing I learned during my journeys.
And that is why I hold your
endeavors in high esteem.
And hope this mutual
respect will continue.
I cannot express how grateful
I am to hear that, Your Highness.
Any further instructions
you would like to give us?
I hear you and Bidam are close.
Take Bidam with you,
and leave the capital on an
excursion for the next two days.
For excursions, you mean...
Just that.
Find a pleasant spot
up in the mountains,
enjoy fresh water and the
gentle breeze, and then return.
But, should Bidam refuse to come?
Then...
I suppose you will have to
bring him along against his will?!
A guest is seeking your audience.
Lord Seolwon.
What brings you...
Was paying you a visit a mistake?
Still, I remain your guest.
Will you leave me out here?
Ahh... Well...
May you enter.
Is that not right?
If it's politics, that is something
my mother and Her Highness worry about.
Do we need to foment
ill will amongst in-laws?
I certainly concur.
- Here...
- Yes.
We neglected each
other for way too long.
Let us meet frequently,
and freely confabulate!
Yes, we should try...
Father, you are here?
Ohh... Right, Yeongmo.
Here... Have a seat.
What brings you here,
at this belated juncture?
I wanted to meet your
father-in-law, you and your spouse!
Right...
When is the child due?
What happened to my Yeongmo?
Uh?!
What is perturbing you?
Lord Chunchu is your nephew.
And he's our grandson-in-law.
And?
What are you trying to imply?
I do appreciate the fact Lord Chunchu
and I have become in-laws,
but it puts me in a
rather awkward position.
In regards to Lord Sejong, you mean?
Yes.
Even though I had no selfish motives,
he still refuses to believe me.
Lord Yongchun.
Are you not trying to help
Lord Chunchu to the throne yourself?
What are you trying to say?
Even though we did not
intend for it to happen,
are we not on the same boat anyhow?
Ahh... I told you we
can go inside and talk.
Get moving...
What is it?
What do you want?
What are you taking me for?
If you have anything to say, do it now.
Ahh... really.
What is it?
What's the matter?
Ahh... It's driving me crazy.
It'll never work... never.
Hey.
Will you leave with me on an
excursion, or keep drinking?
What?
Would be too cumbersome
to leave, wouldn't it?
So let's just drink, uh?
I saw you can handle it quite well.
Have a death wish?
Start talking.
It's just that I don't think
I can do this while sober.
Let's just have a drink...
Just one.
My apologies.
Ahh... Don't even mention it.
But, you sure can handle the bottle.
I am renowned for my drinking prowess,
but it indeed seems like I found a peer.
Right... Let us have one more.
Yes, all right.
Here...
To the prosperity of our clans,
let us have a toast.
I did hear about it,
but how can I...
It is for Her Highness's sake,
and for the sake of our country.
Seokpum Rang's dexterity
with the blade is peerless.
Is that not the reason
we are entrusting this to him?
Let us begin.
What are you waiting for?
Begin at once!
Did you meet Lord Yongchun?
Yes.
Did you do it?
Yes, I did.
Did you bring that?
I did bring it...
But, why this...
Yes.
Give it to me.
Your Highness.
I always tried to accord
you my understanding,
and so I have done all this time.
But this is something
I cannot understand.
Why would you...
The reason I left that behind
was to earn your trust,
and to placate your anxiety.
So why did you ask me
to bring this only now?
For I now wish for it to placate mine.
What are you trying
to say, Your Highness?
Could this not end up
in failure, after all?
Then...
Yes.
It is Bidam.
This might be a very long night.
Just like that night.
It is a summoning for
an urgent council meeting.
I must convey it
directly to His Excellency.
He still has not awakened,
so let me do this.
May you confirm that
you received the notice.
I sent the meeting notice
to Lord Yongchun's abode.
Directly to Lord Yongchun?
Ahh... No, as he was inebriated
last night and wished to sleep,
I only left it to his servants.
Is that so?
Was the confirmation signed?
Yes.
Lord Seohyeon.
Milord, you must wake up.
It is a list of all the nobles
who wish to give you support.
I met with Piltan Rang's
father, Lord Jujin.
He did seem to approve
our taxation reforms,
but I still cannot be sure.
Lord Jujin commands elite troops
from the closest post to the capital,
so we must make sure
he joins forces with us.
He might not be of high nobility,
but considering his long-standing...
relationship with Lord Sejong,
we cannot be sure.
That is why I plan to
meet Piltan Rang as well.
Also, Wolya Rang, make sure
you keep control over...
the restoration movement
sects in this area.
Lo...Lord Seohyeon.
Lord Seohyeon!
What is this?
What...
What did you fill those drinks with?
I...
Are you out of your mind?
Have a death wish?
Keep quiet, will you?
All this is driving me crazy.
Take these off.
You crazy bastard...
Stop!
Just stay put, uh?
Let me think for a moment, uh?
You really must be insane.
Why did you tie me?
Calm down.
Just calm down.
Come here.
Closer... Come closer!
I said come here!
They will have a council meeting
to oust Her Highness...
from any decision-making process.
With me and Lord Yongchun...
Why would they do this?
Bring my official garments.
I must hasten there.
Yes.
What is that supposed to mean?
The council will discuss what?
Ousting Her Highness from
any further state deliberation.
How could this...
They are discussing it now?
Yes, I saw the council members gather.
But, the council still
uses unanimous voting.
Lord Yongchun and
Lord Seohyeon will be present,
so there is no way it would pass.
Yes...
But how could this happen
right under our noses?
No.
There is something peculiar about this.
The council...
Seems like we are not all gathered yet.
Lord Yongchun and Lord Seohyeon
are still missing.
Is it not time to start
our meeting already?
The Sangdaedeung is here,
so let us commence.
What?
Should not the council
reach a unanimous vote?
Yes, it indeed shall reach one.
Who ever said otherwise?
So how can we start without
Lord Yongchun and Lord Seohyeon?
Eight council members are present.
Would not an unanimous vote
amongst the present suffice?
H...owever...
There is no such precedent,
how...
Are we going to postpone
such paramount decision...
just because a few members
could not come on time?
Not to mention the fact that
they gave us confirmation...
that they received our summoning.
From this meeting onwards,
let us seek a unanimous vote
amongst the members present alone.
Indeed!
Why should we await them?
I concur.
There is no code suggesting that
the entire council must be present.
Merely that a unanimous vote
is required for a motion to pass.
I concur.
Yes, I agree as well.
I agree.
Yes... I concur myself.
Then, we shall hereby
commence this meeting.
What?
They started the meeting
with only eight members present?
Yes, it is currently taking
place at Yeolseon Hall.
Her Highness's right to deliberate
is the motion discussed?
Yes...
What now?
Does it make any sense?
They dare start the meeting without
Lord Seohyeon and Lord Yongchun?!
It... cannot be...
Pungwolju.
I've been told that Lord Seohyeon
spent the eventide...
drinking with Lord Hajong.
Is that true?
They cannot have done
so to leave them out,
and pass that motion with
only eight members present?
Those ignoble cowards!
How could Hwarang alumni
display such appalling behavior?
So... So where are Lord Yongchun
and Lord Seohyeon now?
Leave on an excursion
far away from the palace?!
Mishil said so?!
I told you.
She said keeping you away
until the morrow would suffice.
So why did we not leave,
and you tied me here instead?
Tell me!
Answer at once...
What are you trying to scheme?
You are here because I
could not scheme a thing!
Should I not make
decisions on my own?
Decisions... what decisions?!
First... Who are you?
Who could you possibly be,
to arouse so much interest in Mishil?
I might have dabbled in that
kind of work once or twice,
but it's the first time Mishil
comes forward firsthand.
Second...
She said today and the morrow.
It's clear something
is going to happen, uh?
What could it be?
It can't be...
Is Mishil going to...
Unclasp me...
Do it now!
I told you it's not
such a simple matter.
You still...
It's driving me crazy as well, uh?
Having to tie you up like that
means risking my life,
and letting you go would
make me a foe in Mishil's eyes.
Want me to end
your problems right now?
Unclasp me right now!
Then, convince me!
Convince me that unclasping you...
and becoming a foe in her eyes
will be the right decision!
Move out of the way!
I must join the meeting.
What are you trying to do?
I said move!
Move...
What is the matter?
Are you late as well?
They are blocking the way on purpose.
Then, are they keeping
us out so they will...
pass the motion all by themselves?
Seems so.
We must stop this.
How could they engage
in such coarse subterfuges?!
You knaves!
Move out...
- You knaves!
- Out of the way!
I said move, you knaves!
Did you gather everyone?
Yes.
Is that true?
That they made them drink,
and today staged an urgent meeting?
Wow... What cowardice...
Not to mention that they only
started the meeting with eight members.
As if they were market scoundrels...
It makes no sense.
- Your Excellency!
- Your Excellency...
Lord Yongchun and Lord Seohyeon
arrived at Yeolseon Hall.
Is that so?
Forget it, then.
No need to go.
However, the two are trying
to enter the meeting,
but troops are blocking their entrance.
Troops?!
Pungwolju, must we keep allowing this?
How could we allow
something like this to happen?
Jukbang, Godo.
Report all this to
Her Highness immediately,
and request further instructions.
Yes!
Also, Royal Palace Guard,
everyone follow me.
Yes!
Let's move.
Isn't their behavior contemptible?
How could they leave
Their Excellencies out,
and gain their unanimous vote that way?
I cannot... believe this.
Mishil... Mishil...
How could she stoop to this level?!
It is impossible.
So this is all Mishil could do?
You overestimated her, Your Highness.
We should not squander time here.
We must stop them at once!
It is all the better, on the contrary.
With this taxation reform
incident, public fervor...
and the support of petty nobles
are moving towards Your Highness.
And if you add a grave
affront against procedure,
like seeking a unanimous
vote with only eight members,
and even prohibiting the other
two members from participating.
What would possibly happen?
Yes...
Even if this motion might pass,
opposition will surpass
everyone's imagination.
Everyone says Mishil
always stresses just cause.
However, Mishil is
just a person like all of us,
so anxiety and impatience
led her to do this.
No... It cannot be.
She would never do this.
Mishil would never
cause her own downfall.
Princess Deokman sold military
supplies without the council's consent,
endangering our nation's defenses.
Also,
her unfair taxation amendment proposal
spread unrest amongst the nobles.
This is all to render
this council powerless...
and eventually abolish it,
an artifice concocted by Her Highness.
Hence, we request that
Her Highness be ousted from...
any decision making, and only
concern herself with matters...
related to the royal family.
Apprehend them at once!
Yes!
Her Highness is in danger!
I asked you...
why would she be in danger?
Explain it to me.
I ought to...
We have no time to waste!
I am the only one who can solve this.
The only one!
What?!
Yushin, Alcheon, Chunchu!
She must have fooled them all.
I must go, I must!
That's why I told you
convincing me would be best.
What is Mishil trying to do?
And what is your relationship with her?
Now... Unclasp me now.
I must go, hasten!
Lord Jujin's troops from Sangju
are heading for the capital.
What?
Fine.
Yes.
Lord Jujin...
Does not Lord Jujin
command a huge battalion?
Why is he suddenly...
It can't be...
It can't...
Your Highness!
We received a report.
How did it go?
Alcheon Rang took the troops,
and forcibly entered Yeolseon Hall.
This cannot happen.
We must stop them.
You now understand
what her plans are, don't you?
It's a coup she is preparing!
What?!
She will stage an insurrection!
I knew this would happen.
I said it would be a coup,
and they did not believe me.
How can they be so foolish...
Wh...Wh...What?
I am sure.
Sure as anyone can be.
Hey! I said unclasp me!
In...In...Insurrection?!
A... military coup?!
Master, troops from Sangju
are heading for the capital.
You... You... really
were saying the truth...
Unclasp me, you bastard.
Do it now!
~ For ~ Against ~ Against ~ For ~
How do you explain all this?
How dare you wield your
weapons inside this sacred place?
You knaves!
You dare enter Yeolseon Hall armed?
Pungwolju and a
Royal Palace Guard...
Your being here is high treason!
They just entered.
Yes.
Then...
We shall begin.
No armed courtier has ever
entered these sacred walls before.
*2nd century Shilla Courtier who
staged a failed coup, and escaped to Baekje
Also, even traitor Gilseon*...
could not violate this council.
But you dare wield your swords
and force your way in?
However, as troops were blocking
Their Excellencies' entrance...
You knave.
Did any of them wield a sword?
They are traitors who violated
Yeolseon Hall wielding their weapons!
Apprehend them all!
Yes!
Drop your weapons!
Royal Palace Guard, drop your weapons.
Drop them at once.
Your Excellency, we must not let
this escalate into a confrontation.
May you abate your wrath.
Drop your weapons!
Now!
Your Excellency,
I shall be responsible
for any misdeed committed.
But should we not
solve this impasse first?
How dare you speak after what you did?
Yes, I shall accept any punishment.
However, I suggest we both
drop our weapons,
and let Their Excellencies
be escorted out of here.
Drop your weapons at once!
Drop yours as well.
Your Excellencies,
may you leave the premises.
Here... May you leave.
You knaves!
What are you doing?
Stop at once!
Stop!
Protect Their Excellencies!
Follow me, Your Excellency.
Protect the council members!
Here it is.
Right between the
eighth and ninth rib.
However, it must
not be a deep wound.
Yes.
No... No!
Father!
His Excellency has been wounded!
They hit the Sangdaedeung!
His Excellency was wounded!
The Sangdaedeung has been stabbed!
The Sangdaedeung has been harmed!
His Excellency is down!
His Excellency has been wounded!
What did I just hear?
Th...They wounded...
the Sangdaedeung.
His Excellency the Sangdaedeung
was attacked in the capital!
This is an armed insurrection.
To stop this coup from happening...
Battalion!
Let us march for the capital!
It's a coup.
Mishil's coup.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Main Translator and Timer: MisterX
Timing QC: wichitawx
Editor/QC: thunderbolt
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
~ On The Next Episode Of ~
QUEEN ~ * ~ SEONDEOK
Staging a coup was
her only way to achieve that.
They attempted to murder the
Sangdaedeung at Yeolseon Hall.
Her Highness instigated it?
Princess Deokman staged a coup.
You must find refuge.
The Royal Seal...
You will forgive me,
but all we need is for Your
Majesty to become their bait.
If we can capture Her Highness,
all our goals will be fulfilled.
That is the safest place.
We cannot do that.
How could you go there yourself?
Stake your life and protect me.
Where is Her Highness?
Looks like he infiltrated
the Board of Military Affairs.
Really?
Watch dramas legally @ dramafever.com
STOP illegal streaming sites