Director:
Screenplay:
Art Direction:
"Do you know, Father -
what happens only on one day
all over the world?"
STOCKINGS
"I insist on an immediate search!"
"... in any case I'm not as easily
swayed by a pair of beautiful eyes,
as my father is!"
"...how could someone
come up with such an idea?"
"I was so desperate and in need -
...and I once read it in the
newspaper -"
"We are not victims yet officer -
let her run on!"
"As constable I must pursue
the matter further!"
"-there you have the difference
between old pros and an amateur!"
"...a handkerchief!"
"Nave mercy on me - I swear,
it was my first time -"
"I was behind with the rent -
I should be thrown out tomorrow -
onto the streets..."
...and I have such
fear of the streets!"
POLICE STATION
"No, no - let me at
least get my papers..."
"...it's just near here:
Kirchstrasse 11 ...
...you can come up there with me!"
"None of this belongs to me
anymore...
...tomorrow I must be out of here!"
"I am so bad..."
...please, get me a cognac...!"
"Would you also like one..."
"You wanted to get your papers.
Please do so!"
"The excitement was
too much for me... Officer -
...I feel so ill!"
"I will let the ambulance
take you away!"
"You please me… you really do!"
"Come in, your supper
is waiting, my boy!"
"l was with friends
having a beer - "
"What's going on, boy -
is something the matter?
"Is the street work perhaps
too tough for you?"
Identification papers
Albert Holk
"Consul General, here is your
passport and plane ticket to Berlin!"
"There's a letter for you from
Paris - from him!"
"My dearest Else..."
"Let the boy sleep, whilst he
has a free Sunday!"
"l have brought you back
your present, Miss..."
"...or do you believe
you can pay me off?"
"- perhaps because I didn't
take you to where you belong!"
"So was that not meant -"
"I was until yesterday evening
a dutiful constable -
...and now -"
"You must stay with me -
forever - as my wife -"
"Do you even realise what you've
said? - policeman and thief -"
"Thief? Desperate people may
do wrong but that doesn't
make them bad!"
"Go, go! It's better for us both -
l won't see you again!"
"- Won’t you go?"
"Do you truly believe that
l need to thieve?"
"Is this need?!"
"- If the officer still wishes to marry
me – please…"
"Don't give up on me!
Don't let me down!!"
"Good evening!"
"Leave it mother, our boy knows
what he's doing - he should be
allowed to have some fun!"
"- I have - killed - a person!!"
"Mother -
"...the law's the law!"
"She will testify - it was self-defence -
she will testify!!"
"My name is Else Kramer and l live at
Kirchstrasse 11 ."
"l want to tell you everything: l was at
Bergen the jewellers and..."
"The HoIks can go for the time being,
however it is the authority's decree
that...
...the woman be taken into custody!"
"I'm waiting, dearest one -"
Film Restoration:
Martin Koerber
Intertitles Translation:
Jonathan Lomax
Digital retouching, Restoration,
Remastering and Subtitling:
IML Digital Media Melbourne
IML Digital Media 2005