THE EMPEROR AND THE ASSASSIN
King Ying Zheng.
Have you ever forgotten...
the commandment
of your Qin ancestors...
to unite all under heaven?
No, never.
Ying Zheng wouldn't dare!
King Ying Zheng.
Have you ever forgotten
the commandment...
of your ancestors
to unify all under heaven?
No, Ying Zheng has never forgotten,
not for a moment.
Gong Li
Zhang Fengyi
Li Xuejian
Screenplay By
Chen Kaige - Wang Peigong
Director of Photography
Zhao Fei
Production Designer
Tu Juhua - Lin Chi
Sound By
Tao Jing
Edited By
Zhao Xinxia
Music By
Zhao Jiping
Costume Designer
Mo Xia Omin - Huang Chuo Ping
Art Directors
Yang Su Ton -Ji Wei Hwa
Propmaster
Yi Jin Zou
Associate Director
Zhang Jinzhan
Associate Producers
Philip Lee - Sunmin Park
Production Supervisor
Zeng Qanghui
Qin Invades The Kingdom Of Han
Executive Producers - Han Sanping
Suguhiko Kadokawa - Hiromitsu Furukawa
Produced By - Chen Kaige
Shirley Kao - Satoru Iseki
You're a great warrior.
You should be promoted
and continue to fight for Qin.
What's your name?
King Ying Zheng.
- Your Majesty!
- Don't move.
You die a brave warrior
of Qin.
Directed By
Chen Kaige
Chapter One: The King Of Qin
The Queen Mother's Quarters
Prime Minister Lu Buwei
at the Queen Mother's service.
If I am not mistaken...
it has been almost seven years
since we last met.
The Queen Mother has a fine memory.
That was when he first entered
into your service.
And look at his achievement.
Today he bears the title
of Marquis.
It's not the fault
of the Marquis.
After all, he used to be
your retainer.
Where would he be today if you had not
given him the opportunity to serve me?
Marquis or not...
he is still your servant.
How true.
However...
I do enjoy his company
a great deal.
It is time my son
should get married.
The Marquis has found
a lady for him.
She is a princess
from the Kingdom of Han.
The princess calls me
her uncle.
Are you aware...
that your son
is going to eliminate Han?
Really?
If Han is eliminated,
won't my homeland of Zhao be next?
What will happen to my position
if Zhao is eliminated?
I have no interest except
the well-being of the Queen Mother.
But if Qin eliminates
the other six kingdoms...
who will pay tribute
to Her Majesty?
Clever, aren't you?
Take good care
of the Queen Mother for me.
Trust me...
I have no interest
in politics.
But I must ask...
once the six kingdoms
are eliminated...
what use will the king
have for you...
the prime minister?
Then allow me to congratulate you
on your son's marriage.
The King's War Council
All of Han is in our hands,
except for the capital.
The city has been under siege
by our troops for almost 30 days.
The Han people have lost
their will to defend.
But our provisions
can only last for seven days.
Therefore, I beg you to make
a final decision as to war or peace.
If we destroy Han,
the whole world will be shocked.
What if all six kingdoms
join forces against us?
It's in our best interest
to preserve Han.
I disagree.
We have amassed enough troops
to take the Han capital with ease.
There's no reason
to accept a stalemate...
when you can have victory.
Li Si, you are not
the prime minister yet.
- Han Ambassador.
- Present.
You are free to return to Han.
Yes, Your Highness.
The king and the nobles of Han
will be eternally grateful to you...
for preserving Han.
That's fine.
Prime Minister,
I want a drink.
Bring me some wine.
This is not a toast...
this is a punishment.
Why am I punishing myself...
when I should be celebrating?
Because...
we have 250,000 troops ready...
to attack the Han capital!
But instead...
I have been advised
not to destroy Han.
That it is in our best interest
to preserve Han.
I should be punished
for keeping my silence.
Li Si, repeat what you have said!
Your Majesty...
are you also punishing me
with this drink?
No, I'm punishing myself...
for allowing you to remain
prime minister until today.
It doesn't matter who is king.
I will always be...
the prime minister.
In the name of Qin,
kill Lu Buwei!
I dare you.
Prime Minister.
Please!
I have no choice but to dismiss
Prime Minister Lu.
Li Si...
issue the following decree:
Remove Mr. Lu's title...
but give him 5,000 tons of grain...
100 pounds of gold,
10 good horses.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I ask to be dismissed
as the commanding officer.
I'll stay at home
and await my punishment.
You're going to take the Han capital
in seven days.
But if you fail,
how should I punish you?
Cut off my head!
But Your Majesty, I hear that
you will marry a Han princess.
I don't want your head...
I want your horse.
You have a wonderful steed.
How do you judge a good horse?
By his teeth.
Wrong.
By his eyes.
You can tell everything
about an animal...
from his eyes.
Marquis?
Yes, Your Majesty?
I understand that
you'll be my uncle?
This is the Queen Mother
and the prime minister's idea.
You're always so busy.
Please come riding
with me today.
I'm afraid of heights.
I can't ride.
Afraid of heights, are you?
Even on a horse's back?
Your Majesty, it tickles.
General Fan.
His Majesty asks the Marquis,
is it high or not?
As high as high can be.
Cross!
Remove your robe.
How much is two times three?
Two times three is six.
How much is three times three?
Whatever His Majesty
wishes it to be!
Marquis, what's wrong?
The Queen Mother is worried.
I've just been entertaining
His Majesty.
That way he'll trust me.
Lady Zhao has arrived.
- Good morning, Lady Zhao.
- Good morning.
Good morning, My Lady.
When you think of it...
my son's marriage
is quite unfair to Lady Zhao.
When we were hostages
in Zhao...
Ying Zheng's father
could not do housework.
Nor could I.
So we hired her to help out.
She was only this high.
When she had free time,
she would help Ying Zheng herd horses.
She was such a nice girl
and beautiful.
No wonder my son
loved her so much.
She possesses a strong will
and a somewhat wild personality.
It might be hard to reign her in.
Do you think she has
changed her ways?
No.
When we were allowed
to return to Qin...
she had no intention
of coming with us.
Ying Zheng started to cry.
She laughed and said...
''What are you crying about?
I'll go with you.''
So she joined us.
Your Majesty...
I've come to say farewell.
Where are you going?
I'm going home to Zhao.
Why are you leaving me?
Why?
Your daily visits seem
more like an obligation.
Is this what our love
has become?
Do you still know what I want?
How I want to live?
You don't.
I must smile all the time...
speak softly and walk gently
with my head down.
I feel like an object
on display in your palace!
I want to speak in a loud voice.
Cry when I feel like crying.
I don't want to be nice
to everybody.
I can't live like this...
but I have for so long.
I'm leaving.
Do you remember
when we were young?
When it snowed in the winter...
we frolicked in the hay.
We were cold and hungry,
but we were happy.
We would fall into the hay.
It was so warm...
we would fall asleep...
in each other's arms.
You used to be an innocent boy
from Zhao.
Now you are a king.
You are no longer
the person I once knew.
You are right.
Now I understand
why you want to leave.
I was only waiting
for the day when...
I would be king of all
under heaven...
then I would marry you
and make you my queen.
I thought that this
was what you wanted.
Let's go back to Zhao.
Then we can be together again.
The way it was before.
I know this is only a dream.
Day is breaking.
Please accompany me
to the Imperial Map Hall.
Then you may go.
Unfurl the map.
Your Majesty, this is the map
of the unified empire.
You painted this map?
Yes, Your Majesty,
it is their work.
You've done a fine job.
Are you from Qin?
Your Majesty,
they are from Han.
I see.
Yes, Han will soon be eliminated.
You are crying for your kingdom.
You are loyal subjects of Han.
All the people of Han
are crying now...
because your king orders gifts
to be presented to Qin--
1,000 horses,
10,000 pounds of gold...
1 million sheaves of silk.
I don't want these gifts.
They belong to the people of Han.
Han will cease to exist.
But...
a greater empire will emerge.
Qin and the other six kingdoms...
as far as the eye can see
will be unified.
All people under heaven
will be its subjects.
The empire will have
only one ruler...
one benevolent ruler.
Once unification is achieved...
he will protect...
all his subjects.
The empire will be divided
into provinces...
under the administration
of good officials.
Grain will grow everywhere.
There will be peace
and prosperity for all.
Roads will extend
to the remote border areas...
and the Great Wall will stretch
across the northern border...
to keep the barbarians out.
And to commemorate
the unification...
stone tablets will be erected
by the sea.
Lady Zhao, please stay with us!
Your Majesty!
Our army has commenced the final attack
on the Han capital.
Your Majesty!
Let me go!
Ying Zheng!
How dare you!
Let him come to me.
Kneel before His Majesty!
I am the Prince of Yan.
I won't kneel before the king.
Carry on.
Lady Zhao, don't leave.
I request that Your Majesty stop
the Qin invasion of Han...
and leave the six kingdoms
in peace.
Otherwise--
Then what?
Within five steps...
blood will be shed,
yours and mine.
Even if you kill me...
someone will complete
the unification.
If not me...
then maybe you.
After 550 years...
what has become
of the hundreds of kingdoms?
Today there are only seven left.
Small kingdoms
want to become bigger...
the bigger ones want to annex
the smaller.
This war has lasted
for 550 years.
The people have been living...
in hell.
As long as
the six kingdoms remain...
the world will never know peace.
The six kingdoms must be eliminated.
Nobody can stop the unification.
Nobody.
The truth is as long
as Qin remains...
the world will not know peace.
Don't come near me!
Don't move!
I know you are unhappy
as my hostage here in Qin.
I could let you go back
to Yan...
but the King of Yan will simply
send you back here again.
He will do this
until Yan is eliminated.
Why break your father's heart?
I have raised my sword
before Your Majesty.
Why don't you kill me?
You are my brother.
Your Majesty, bowl!
Your Majesty, bowl again!
Qin Eliminates Han
A great feast for our soldiers!
Now it's time to consider...
how to take Yan.
Once Yan is eliminated...
the northern territories
will be united.
Once we control the north,
unification will be close at hand.
But I must have a reason
to attack Yan.
Otherwise,
the southern kingdoms...
unite against us.
Why don't you let
the Prince of Yan go back?
Go back.
Where to?
Back to Yan.
If you let him return to Yan,
he'll send an assassin to kill you.
As soon as the assassin makes
an attempt, everyone will know...
and you'll have your reason.
Yan may even surrender
without bloodshed.
How can we make him
send an assassin?
Find someone he trusts.
Who?
Do I have a beautiful face?
Most beautiful.
What if it is branded?
My Lady must be joking.
Prison warden
at your service, My Lady.
Please rise.
Warden.
Present.
Who are those prisoners?
Common criminals, war prisoners.
- Is branding difficult?
- No.
Is there someone you want released?
I can take care of it.
I want you to brand my face.
What did My Lady say?
I said, I want you
to brand my face.
My Lady has scared me to death.
I never d-a-r-e
do such a thing!
You dare to disobey me?
My clothes, do they look nice?
Yes, they do.
Don't get them dirty.
No, I won't.
Do you have a heavy hand?
No, I don't.
Does it hurt?
No.
Even if it hurts...
don't scream.
I won't scream.
I won't.
What have you done?
Let me look.
I'm going to kill that warden!
Don't punish them.
It was my idea.
What?
If I didn't do it,
Prince Yan wouldn't trust me.
So you are the one
who will go to Yan with him?
That way I can make him
send an assassin.
Once I succeed, there will be
no need for bloodshed.
Do you think
this is child's play?
War is everywhere.
Dead bodies are piled
as high as mountains...
blood flows like the rivers.
Didn't you say that you would
protect the people of all kingdoms?
Didn't you promise to let them
live in peace?
You said that and I believed you.
As long as you see this mark on my face,
you will never forget your promise.
My face...
is it ugly?
It's beautiful.
For the past few years...
we've been drifting apart.
You are the King of Qin.
I didn't know what
I could do for you.
That was why I wanted
to return home to Zhao.
Now I know that you are...
different from other kings.
You have a great cause.
Finally, I've found a way
to help you.
Sorry to keep you waiting,
my lord.
Where's the king?
The king is otherwise occupied.
His Majesty has asked me
to drink with you.
- Ridiculous.
- Just a moment.
His Majesty has something
to show you.
If you don't have a look,
you will regret it.
This way, please.
Turn around.
This is the unification map.
Han is part of the unified country.
So is Yan.
So are all six kingdoms!
His Majesty has asked me
to tell Your Highness...
Yan is sure to be eliminated.
Your Highness is welcome
to stay here in Qin.
You can no longer be
the Prince of Yan...
but my king will grant you...
a position as a Qin official.
Also, His Majesty
has a message for you.
Your friend, Lady Zhao's face
has been branded...
because she repeatedly asked
to return home.
The brand cannot be removed.
Please think it over.
Please tell the king...
Yan will never surrender.
I want to receive
the Yan assassin...
right here in the Unification Hall.
I want you to find me
a real assassin.
I'll order the guards
to stay away.
Nobody will be armed...
except the assassin.
Who would have thought...
I'm going to Yan...
to find someone to kill you.
I'm invincible.
No one can kill me.
The assassin will know
it is wrong to even try.
Keep this to protect yourself.
Good-bye.
My amulet...
please take it too.
Wait.
Now you may go.
Please, don't look at me.
What does this bridge...
remind you of?
Remember when we were children...
and you would make me cross
that narrow bridge?
I have made a replica
of that bridge here...
so that we can always
remember our times together.
I am the Prince of Yan!
If you want to kill me,
then do it right here.
Goddamn Ying Zheng!
Shepherd!
Is this the Kingdom of Yan?
This is Yan.
Goddamn Ying Zheng!
I'm going to kill you.
Goddamn you!
I must kill you!
Chapter II: The Assassin
Jing Ke...
I have someone I want you to kill.
Who is it?
A sword maker...
who owes me.
Just him?
Kill his whole family.
How much?
Five thousand.
I want ten thousand.
Mommy.
Daddy.
You've killed my whole family,
haven't you?
Then kill me too.
You can't see.
I won't kill you.
Kill me.
If you don't...
I'll be begging
for the rest of my life.
There's no dignity in that.
That's true...
but I won't kill you.
The Homecoming Of Prince Yan
Gentlemen...
Yan may soon be eliminated
by Qin.
I must find an assassin
to kill the King of Qin.
If you are afraid
to accept this task...
you may take your leave.
Leave? We would rather die!
All right then, cheers.
Jing Ke! You madman.
The buns are ready.
Got you! You little bastard!
How many times did you steal?
Many.
Many?
Then there is nothing to say.
Water.
I need water.
Give him some water.
What?
You pay up for him...
and he'll get his water.
Get out, you scum!
Give him some water.
Are you looking for trouble?
We've got water.
Get down and beg
and he'll get his water.
If you let him go, I will.
Fine. On your knees
and I'll let him go.
Crawl through my legs
Let him go.
That's not enough.
I can let him down...
but that's my decision...
not yours.
You have to kill me.
Kill me and the boy goes free.
I won't kill you.
Come on!
Kill me! Come on!
I won't.
You have no choice.
Kill me!
Come on! Kill me!
- Did you kill that man?
- No.
If you didn't kill him,
then why are you here?
This is your last day alive.
Do you have anything
you want to say?
Fine. You're a tough man,
aren't you?
Get him ready.
Scared?
Then scream.
Come on! Scream!
Scream, scream!
All right.
Let's play for a while.
Lady Zhao has arrived.
Hold it.
Your Ladyship.
Release him.
Hurry, release the prisoner.
Faster!
This man has no fear of death.
Everyone cries for mercy
on the torture log, but he didn't.
I should have gone over to the jail
to welcome you myself.
Sorry you had to suffer.
Please sit.
So, the two of you have met before.
So you're the great assassin,Jing Ke.
The prince has been searching for you.
Who would imagine?
The great assassin
has become a sandal peddler.
Lady Zhao and I need your help.
I'll let the lady tell you.
We want you to kill someone for us.
Do you know who we want you to kill?
The King of Qin.
Otherwise, Yan is finished.
All six kingdoms will be eliminated.
I don't kill people.
You're an assassin!
You've killed many people!
Not anymore.
You will be rewarded.
Tell me what you want
and it's yours.
If you kill the King of Qin...
you're assured a place
in Yan's ancestral temple.
I won't kill.
Then go back to the prison and die.
This beautiful woman has been branded
by the King of Qin.
She saved your life.
You owe her.
I won't kill.
Guards!
Take him back to prison.
That's the man I want.
No matter what, you must make him go
to Qin within three months.
He must kill the King of Qin.
I can't force him.
He doesn't even fear death.
You'd better find someone else.
He has three months to live.
So do you.
Don't forget, you're my hostage.
Jing Ke...
I know what you are thinking.
You think I saved you
to make you kill someone?
You are wrong.
I was told that
you were a cruel assassin.
I don't believe it.
I saw you save that child.
I don't know about our past...
but now you can go.
Please go home.
Scream if you can't take it.
Scream.
Hey! Trying to kill someone?
That's not a sword!
I'm sorry.
You don't know me.
But I do.
Nobody does.
And I don't know you either.
I come from the Kingdom of Zhao.
I was born and brought up in Zhao.
Then I followed some people to Qin...
and finally I came to Yan.
Why is your face branded?
What crime have you committed?
I wanted to return to Zhao.
Was it really that important?
Zhao is my home.
You are not a criminal. Wanting to
return to Zhao is not a crime at all.
But killing is.
I've killed many people.
I am the criminal.
I once killed a girl.
She was from a family
of sword makers.
The girl was young,
still in her early teens.
She was pretty and pure.
But she was blind.
You've killed my whole family,
haven't you?
Then kill me too.
You can't see.
I won't kill you.
She kept asking me to kill her.
But I didn't want to.
At dawn, I hear my mother...
making breakfast.
When the sun comes up...
I hear my father making swords.
After sunset, my brother sings
as he brings in the cows.
He always brings me a flower.
If I can't hear
these sounds tomorrow...
I would rather die.
I couldn't kill her.
Who are you?
Even a killer...
has a name.
I've lost my strength.
Help me remove the dagger.
Actually, she wanted revenge.
She had a sword hidden
behind her back.
She couldn't live without love.
She was right.
Oh, no!
You're left-handed.
My name is Jing Ke.
You should tear down this house...
build a new one.
Plant some trees.
If I can come to see you, I will.
If I can't...
don't blame me.
Try to start a new life.
I want you to have this.
The King of Qin
has started troop movements.
There are 400,000 soldiers
at the Han Zhao border.
The people of Zhao are terrified.
The Marquis says that
when Zhao is eliminated...
the next target will be Yan.
Your medicine, my lord.
Qin Palace
This battle-ax...
should only be used by the king.
Of course,
the Prince of Yan knows...
that this gift
might cost me my head.
But I can't refuse
such a fine gift.
Please thank him.
My lord, the king is waiting
to see the Queen Mother.
No.
Tell him that
Queen Mother is sleeping.
Wrong.
Let's try again.
Daddy.
Our poor children.
Must they hide away here
in the palace all their lives?
Chapter III: The Children
Ying Zheng has a good appetite.
You've always loved meat.
But we didn't always have meat.
My queen, are you criticizing
the king for eating too much?
His Majesty is the master
of all under heaven.
He can have whatever he wants.
Daddy.
Pardon me, Your Majesty.
This is my nephew.
The queen adores him and has allowed
him a short stay in the palace.
Like all small boys,
he likes to run about.
Come here.
Come. The king is calling you.
What a fine boy.
I see why the Queen Mother
adores him.
Open your mouth.
Go on.
It was a nice dinner.
I have something to take care of.
Good-bye, Mother.
Good-bye, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
The Marquis' rebels were armed.
They could have killed you.
Your Majesty's wisdom
prevented this.
The Marquis is staging a coup.
I must deploy the royal guards!
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
I will--
General Fan, let go of my hand.
You think that I am scared.
Marquis.
I want the Queen Mother's seal.
The order must come
from the Queen Mother.
The Residence Of Former
Prime Minister Lu Buwei
The seal is real.
The Queen Mother has declared...
as soon as we succeed, you will be
reinstated as prime minister.
So I will be the prime minister?
Then who will be the king?
The King of Qin?
You...
or your son?
Marquis...
you used to be my servant.
I am advising you
to give yourself up.
With the support of the Queen Mother,
your life may be spared.
Otherwise...
I don't mean to boast...
but who can overthrow the king
except me?
I understand.
We will see who will be king...
my son or yours?
What do you mean?
A disgraced prime minister...
has the nerve to kill me?
I don't think so.
Get me my chariot.
I am going to the palace.
Marquis!
The Queen Mother has declared...
Ying Zheng is no longer
the King of Qin!
Whoever captures him...
will be rewarded.
Charge!
Retreat!
Retreat to the west!
Marquis, do you surrender?
Do you surrender?
- No!
- Charge!
I surrender...
only if you promise...
not to kill my men!
I have failed all of you.
Obey their orders.
Do not resist.
The king will spare you.
Lay down your weapons.
Stand up!
Ying Zheng, you murderer!
You murderer!
Mother, hand those children over.
They are my sons.
I'll never give them up.
So be it.
I'm not mistaken...
am I?
Mommy! Mommy!
Ying Zheng.
Who did you have in mind
to replace me...
the older one or the younger?
Ying Zheng, listen to me!
Mommy, Mommy!
I'm begging you!
They are your brothers.
Goddamn you!
I hate you!
You've murdered my sons!
You animal!
I'm so sorry.
But our children...
are dead.
So they're gone.
Then there's nothing more
to worry about.
I've failed you.
No, it is I who failed you.
And failed our sons.
All our efforts
have come to nothing.
People will say
it's my lust for power...
that brings me to my death.
But what I wanted most...
was to share my life with you.
That could have been...
were you not...
the Queen Mother.
As it is...
we will have to wait
until our next life.
Don't cry.
We've done nothing wrong.
Farewell.
Are you guilty?
I'm innocent!
You committed adultery
and fathered illegitimate children!
You plotted against Qin
with foreign kingdoms.
You deserve no mercy!
It's true.
I had children with your mother.
You claim to be a filial son...
but how could you know the loneliness
of the Queen Mother?
I plotted with foreign kingdoms?
Were you not raised on the milk
of the Kingdom of Zhao?
Treason?
Am I the traitor?
No, it's you who are the traitor.
When the Qin Prince
was a hostage in Zhao...
Lu Buwei gave him a woman.
But the woman was already pregnant
by Lu Buwei.
She gave birth to a boy.
Later...
the Qin Prince became king.
When the king died, the little boy
inherited the Qin throne.
Do you have to ask me
who your real father is?
What a pity. You have been
the King of Qin for such a long time...
but you don't even know
who your real parents are!
What a joke!
The King of Qin is not even
a descendant of Qin?
You are the son of Lu Buwei
from Zhao.
Who's the traitor here?
Nonsense!
You're crazy!
Ying Zheng...
you're a bastard from Zhao!
Go and ask your father!
You may take your leave.
Master of Rites.
Present.
Who is my father?
Your Majesty's father
was the King of Qin.
Your Majesty has no other father.
I see.
Thank you.
Qin Ancestral Temple
Lu Buwei, are you guilty?
Of course I am guilty.
If the King of Qin, Ying Zheng,
is my son...
then he could not be
the King of Qin.
That's why I am guilty?
Right?
The King of Qin is not your son.
His father was the King of Qin.
If that is true...
and the king is not my son...
then why do you want to kill me?
Right here in
the Qin Ancestral Temple?
- Prime Minister!
- Stop!
Say no more.
Just go ahead and kill me.
Your Majesty...
the prime minister had made
great contributions to Qin.
I beg you to show mercy on him.
Prime Minister...
just tell the world...
that I am not your son.
Kill me, and the world will know...
that you are not my son.
And only by killing me
can you make people believe...
that you are not my son.
Because...
a son would never kill
his own father.
No!
No.
I will not kill you.
I just want to tell the world...
that I'm not your son.
- And when unification is achieved--
- No matter what happens...
don't you have a father?
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Because I wanted you to be king.
King of all under heaven.
I cannot kill you.
I want to see you grow old.
I want you to help me unite
all under heaven.
I want you to finish your book
'' Lu's Spring and Autumn.''
I want everything under heaven...
to know and remember your name.
Remember your name.
King Ying Zheng...
have you forgotten the commandment
of your Qin ancestors to unite...
all under heaven?
I have not forgotten!
Have I forgotten?
From the moment I was born,
I was a hostage, who supported me?
The people of Zhao spat
in the king's face and whipped me!
Where were the Qin people
at that time?
Where were my Qin ancestors?
I had no food, no clothes.
What did the Qin people give me?
This man...
he raised me
and took care of the king.
He brought our family back to Qin.
I was sitting on his knees...
when he taught me my first word.
That first word was ''king.''
He who taught me
how to be a king!
I cannot kill him.
No one can kill him!
Your Majesty, then kill me.
But even if I die,
people will ask the same question.
I cannot kill him.
I can't.
Please don't make me.
King Ying Zheng...
have you really forgotten
your commandment?
Your Majesty!
Father.
Issue the following decree.
Lu Buwei is a traitor.
He is to be stripped
of all his titles.
Kill his entire family.
What's going on with Jing Ke?
I can't wait anymore.
He must go to Qin now.
He is not the man he used to be.
He'll never go.
He listens to you.
If you ask him to go, he will.
But I won't do that.
If Jing Ke won't go to Qin...
I'll have to imprison you...
and wait for Ying Zheng
to save you.
All right, then.
Imprison me.
As you wish.
Release her.
You stay and she goes free.
You should see our new house.
Get him! Come on!
Go home, boy.
Pick up your sword.
If he won't kill you, kill him!
Go home.
Kill him!
Kill!
Your Majesty, General Fan fled
last night. His whereabouts are unknown.
Issue the following decree
to the other kingdoms.
Any state that harbors General Fan
is the enemy of Qin.
Whoever turns him in is our ally.
Kill his entire family.
General Fan,
I'd like you to meet Jing Ke.
Yes.
You are from Qin.
You know the King of Qin.
What kind of man is he?
He truly is a king...
but he has killed so many people.
Is that the reason you left him?
Yes.
Long live the king!
General Wang.
Present.
I want revenge.
Yes.
Destroy Zhao!
Zhao Ambassador!
Your Highness, My Lady,
I beg you to save Zhao!
What's the situation
in the Zhao capital?
The King of Qin
is leading the attack.
The Qin army has already reached
the city wall.
They've taken all the provisions.
Without food...
the people are desperate!
They eat...
meat off the dead bodies.
The King of Zhao has ordered that
we die before surrendering.
I am afraid we can't hold
very long, and--
What?
The King of Zhao is holding
all the city's children...
boys and girls...
captive in the ancestral temple.
On the day Qin troops
take the city...
all of them will be led
to the city wall...
and sacrificed.
The Zhao king will destroy
the future generations of Zhao.
My Lady...
in a few dozen years...
there will be
no more Zhao people.
We're finished!
The world is finished!
Goddamn Ying Zheng!
I said he was evil!
General Fan!
Present.
The prince has promised
to try and save Zhao.
I am leaving now
to see the King of Zhao.
I will beg him
to spare the children of Zhao.
I also want to see
the King of Qin.
He's changed completely...
since you left.
Our king will listen to me.
Chapter IV: Lady Zhao
Jing Ke.
I'm going to Zhao.
You're going to Zhao?
Is there nothing you wish
to say to me?
You don't want to bid me farewell?
I won't send you off...
because I don't want to lie to you.
You can't save
the Kingdom of Zhao.
But I know you must go...
because you are from Zhao.
Zhao...
is your homeland.
Do your best.
Zhao Outpost - Twenty Miles
From The Capital
My Lady!
The Qin troops have surrounded
the Zhao capital.
The roads have been cut off.
It's impossible for us
to enter the city.
Where is the Prince of Yan?
Where is he?
Zhao is finished.
We must retreat.
Prince, it's getting dark.
We could launch a surprise attack.
Outside The Zhao Capital
I've conquered almost all of Zhao!
We are preparing to attack the capital.
Tomorrow that capital will be ours!
What about the assassin from Yan?
I am so naive.
I thought because of you...
there would be no more bloodshed.
But what did I find
when I arrived in Zhao?
Dead bodies everywhere!
Your army had done nothing
but kill.
The villages have been destroyed,
the towns ruined.
You did all of this! How are you
different from other kings?
But this is Zhao.
Zhao is a different case.
You promised me...
that you would protect
all people under heaven.
Look at my face.
Do you remember now?
Zhao is different!
The Zhao people bullied my father
and insulted my mother.
They made me herd horses.
But your mother is from Zhao.
So many Zhao people
have helped you through hard times.
Your own name used to be
Zhao Zheng.
Your Majesty...
you cannot be the ruler
of all under heaven...
as long as you have hate
in your heart.
The ruler of all under heaven
should love all people under heaven.
No matter which kingdom
they are from...
they are your subjects.
The King of Zhao has given orders
to kill all the children of Zhao.
Go save the children of Zhao.
If you save them...
you will win the love
of the Zhao people...
and the love of all people
under the heaven.
Can you promise me?
I promise you.
Lady Zhao, I won't let you go.
I'll never let you go again.
I am from Zhao.
I can't bear to watch Qin troops
destroy my homeland.
My Lady, this
is a military campsite...
but the prince didn't take
this route when he came.
The prince must have retreated.
We must go directly to the capital.
Children...
the time has come.
Children!Jump!
Jump!
My child, go quickly!
Go quickly!
Zhao will never surrender!
- General Wang.
- Present.
Are these the last
of the Zhao children?
Yes.
Let them go.
Take this.
- General Wang.
- Present.
When my father and I
returned to Qin...
the King of Zhao
sent soldiers after us.
He was afraid I would take revenge.
Right now, I'm also afraid.
I understand.
Wake up, wake up!
My Lady, over here!
- More dead bodies!
- No!
It was Qin soldiers.
They buried
all these children alive.
My Lady, are you all right?
Goddamn Ying Zheng.
Goddamn you, Ying Zheng!
You are sick.
You've been sleeping
for five days.
So long?
You died, but then
you came back to life.
But I do not want to live.
I want to go back to Zhao.
I want to be with those children.
I know.
Your Majesty, General Fan
has been found in Yan.
Order Yan to deliver
the traitor's head.
- Your Majesty--
- Shut up!
The Queen Mother is dying.
Mother.
You've finally come.
I've just returned from Zhao.
I've killed all our enemies.
We have been avenged.
Goddamn you!
I must tell you.
The King of Qin and I
created this whole plot...
to send an assassin to Qin.
At that time...
I was his lover--
we grew up together.
When we were young...
my father was always drunk.
Often Ying Zheng
would carry him home.
It was a big burden
for a small boy.
He took good care
of his mother too.
Everybody liked him.
He used to be such
a good person.
Now...
he's a ruthless killer.
Ying Zheng knows everything.
He will be prepared.
If you go--
I won't let him kill
any more children.
Never again.
Do you think I can stand up
to the King of Qin?
Yes, but you still need
one more thing for your journey.
Without it,
you won't get to see him.
I've come here to borrow it
from you.
You don't need to borrow it.
I'm giving it to you.
It's a gift for a worthy friend.
Because...
you will never come back.
You don't think I know that?
You know that.
Of course I know.
Do you know why the King of Qin
wants my head?
Because I alone know the secret
that can destroy him.
But I can't tell you
what it is.
If you see him...
I want you to tell him that...
I've not told a soul
about his secret...
and that his secret
will die with me.
I am going to get more wine.
Jing Ke...
do you know which direction...
my door faces?
It faces Qin.
Correct.
Your Majesty...
the Prince of Yan has sent
this map.
This the richest area...
of Yan.
The land is so fertile--
We succeeded.
No.
The King of Qin will react
as you have.
He will focus
all his attention on me.
Therefore, my assistant should make
the first move.
Not me.
But I will not have a weapon.
Try again.
Your Majesty.
The Prince of Yan
has sent this map.
This is the richest area of Yan.
The land is so fertile.
The wind is whistling
Over the cold Yi River
The brave hero leaves
He'll never return
Chapter V:
The Emperor and the Assassin
His Majesty!
Come closer.
Sit with me for a while.
How old are you?
I'm talking to you.
Your Majesty, I'm 15.
Already an adult.
Old enough to do great things.
I was younger than you...
when I was in Zhao.
Those were the good old days.
I never had enough to eat
or enough to wear.
But I was determined
to become a king.
My girlfriend told me that...
one day I would surely
be a king.
Indeed, those were
the best times.
Your Majesty, the envoy
from Yan has arrived.
Will you receive him tomorrow?
Yes.
Who is the envoy?
His name is Jing Ke.
Our spies in Yan would say
that he is a great swordsman.
Let him come with his sword.
But be prepared.
Yes.
Yan envoys, please halt.
The swords of the envoys
need to be inspected.
Your assistant cannot
carry his sword.
Please.
Your sword will be returned.
Long live the king!
It was a fly.
Is this the map
you will present to the king?
Yes.
The box...
contains the head
of the traitor.
The king summons
the Yan envoy.
The king grants you permission
to carry your sword.
Here is your sword...
please.
The king summons the envoys!
Long live the king!
What's wrong with your assistant?
We are from a small country,
isolated and unsophisticated.
I said he would be scared.
You see he really is.
Don't be afraid.
We'll go home after
we pay homage to the king.
The king will only receive
one envoy.
Now you've done it.
Jing Ke.
Your Majesty!
What's your name?
Jing Ke.
- Raise your head.
- I dare not.
Raise your head!
Why are you crying?
My secret is scared,
and I am scared too.
I'd like to go home.
Have you brought me
General Fan's head?
Yes.
Come up here.
Please forgive me,
Your Majesty!
I don't want to carry a sword,
but they forced me to.
They sent me here to kill you!
Did you hear what he said?
The King of Yan...
intends to kill me.
Destroy Yan! Destroy Yan!
The map...
is it fake as well?
Fake?
The map is real.
Your Majesty,
the Prince of Yan has sent this map.
This is the richest area
of Yan.
This can be yours.
The land is so fertile--
Stand back!
Draw your sword!
My king!
Not even a single one of you...
tried to stop him!
Get out of here!
Goddamn you!
Why are you laughing?
Why did you want to kill me?
Do you know what I want to do?
I want to establish
a great empire.
Qin and the other six kingdoms
will become one great empire.
General Fan asked me
to deliver a message to you.
Your secret--
He has not told a soul.
He's not like you.
He kept his promise.
Don't die.
I haven't won yet.
You've come back to me.
I've come back...
only to take Jing Ke's body
back to Yan.
If you don't allow me...
then you can kill me too.
Take him back to Yan.
Give him a proper burial.
My love!
King of Qin...
have you forgotten the commandment
of your ancestors to unify...
all under heaven?
In 221 B.C., the King of Qin conquered
all six kingdoms by military force...
to become the First Emperor
of unified China.
His success was short-lived...
as the Qin Dynasty lasted only for 15
years and was overthrown by the Han.
His tomb remains in Xian, guarded by
thousands of terra-cotta warriors.
subcaptions encoded by: NoRMITA.326