[ I've beentemporarily suspended. ]
[ So you cannot use my nameto reserve an operating room. ]
[ Use Park Sun-woo'sname instead. ]
[ Dr. Cha Tae-jin will do everythingto stop this surgery. ]
[ I will pretend to give upthe surgery reluctantly. ]
[ Kang Eun-hyun. ]
[ Before the surgery starts, ]
[ you have to get the informationon what kind of side effects ]
[ he will inflict on Dr. Oh. ]
[ Can you do that? ]
[ I'll try my best. ]
[ Lee Hae-jo, be thesecond assistant in this surgery. ]
[ Yes, sir. ]
[ When the time comes... ]
[ you will comeoutside to send... ]
[ the tumor tissueto pathology. ]
[ Before Lee Hae-josends it to pathology... ]
[ I will check Dr. Cha Tae-jin'sprevious records... ]
[ and I will find out whicharea he'll operate on. ]
[ Then I'll tellDr. Lee Hae-jo... ]
[ which part of thecranial nerve he will touch. ]
[ Change the surgical... ]
[ equipment right before... ]
[ Cha Tae-jinmakes a move. ]
[ This is customized equipment... ]
[ to prevent damageto cranial nerves. ]
[ Min Sung-joon. ]
[ Can you accuratelypinpoint which area... ]
[ he'll operate in such... ]
[ a short amount of time? ]
[ It's not a matter ofwhether I can or cannot. ]
[ I must make it happen. ]
[ What if there are... ]
[ changes to the plan... ]
[ what do we do? ]
[ It'd be best... ]
[ if everything goesaccording to plan. ]
[ But even ifsomething goes wrong... ]
[ and the worst casescenario happens... ]
[ I'll be fine. ]
[ I'm prepared for it. ]
Mom.
We'll give youanesthesia now.
Okay.
I clearly told you not to gonear an operating room...
and that you cannotdo any surgeries.
Stop this surgery at once.
What if I don't?
What is your reason...
for booking thesurgery room secretly...
at dawn under the nameof Dr. Park Sun-woo?
You would probablyknow that already.
As the chairman, I do not permit this.
If you insist...
on this surgery,
you will have toleave this hospital.
Even if this surgery...
is my final one here...
it doesn't matter.
You don't care...
that the wholeworld finds out...
Cha Yeo-wook is your son?
Same thinggoes for you...
we all have secrets.
Dr. Kang Eun-hyun too.
[ Dr. Kang Eun-hyun. ]
[ Before you see Dr. Cha... ]
[ there is somethingyou must know first. ]
[ Yeo-wook is... ]
[ not Dr. Cha Tae-jin's son. ]
[ What... ]
[ do you mean? ]
[ Dr. Cha knowsabout this too. ]
[ We will useYeo-wook's matter ]
[ to discreetly turn over ]
[ the surgery toDr. Cha Tae-jin. ]
[ Kang Eun-hyun. ]
[ You take care of this. ]
[ What do I... ]
[ need to do? ]
If you don't stopthe surgery...
I will use physical force.
You are willing to do that?
No use in hiding it.
Dr. Kang Eun-hyun.
I have something to sayto Dr. Min Sung-joon.
You have something...
to say to me?
Yes.
I heard you will performDr. Oh's tumor surgery.
How dare you decideon this without...
consulting withthe chief resident.
Not to mention you'recurrently suspended from work.
I am really curiousas to why...
you are here.
A chief resident...
dare talk back to...
Didn't you kick meout of the operating room
and made Cha Yeo-wookas your assistant?
A few days ago, the patient you operated onexpired from the shunt surgery.
I will formally file acomplaint on the matter.
Choosing an assistantis a right of the surgeon.
That's only...
when there areno complications
with the patient.
Chairman Cha Tae-jin.
Korea University Hospital is not
Dr. Min Sung-joon's hospital.
As chief resident,
I have a lot of concerns.
I hope you act on this.
You will formally..
file a complaint?
Yes.
As chief resident, I amquestioning the shunt surgery...
done by Cha Yeo-wook.
Once you challengethe shunt surgery...
Dr. Min Sung-joon and...
Dr. Cha Yeo-wook will...
be put in a veryprecarious situation.
This will cause...
a public uproar.
As the chairman,
I don't want to throw
this hospital into chaos.
Nothing good willcome out of this.
Cha Yeo-wook is innocent.
Because he was draggedinto your surgery,
he will have to beara huge burden.
He might even getdismissed from the hospital.
Just like someonefrom the past.
Min Sung-joon.
You're not a 3 year old kid.
Don't make matters worse.
Cha Tae-jin.
Before this getsany bigger...
stop this surgery at once.
This is toprotect my son.
Dr. Kang Eun-hyun.
Yes.
I'm sure you understand...
as well as Dr. Min Sung-joon.
I will performDr. Oh Eun-hee's...
tumor surgery.
Prepare...
to assist me.
Cha Tae-jin.
Min Sung-joon.
I don't wantto embarrass you.
Let go of me before...
I call the police.
What...
happened?
Why did you come here?
I thought you'd bein a tough situation.
Once Dr. Min'ssurgery succeeds,
you will be put...
in a difficult situation...
Today is thelast opportunity.
The last opportunity to...
completely put an endto accusations.
You helped me...
at the right time.
What do youplan to do...
to Dr. Oh Eun-hee?
She won't be ableto control her rage.
You will manipulateher personality?
Like a prisoner, she will live...
in a mental hospitalfor the rest of her life.
She became prosopagnosicafter her last surgery.
If she gets that kindof serious side effect...
I'm not interestedin this hospital.
This is just...
a place to createmy brain map.
It's the only one...
of its kind.
So even if it's not...
in this hospital,
I can also achieveit elsewhere.
After removing vDr. Oh Eun-hee,
let's lay low for sometime
and I will help youbecome the owner of this hospital.
Now, Min Sung-joonis nothing.
He and Oh Eun-hee...
will be kickedout of this hospital.
Father.
Is everything ready?
Yes.
We've already givenher anesthesia.
I will be doing...
your mom's surgery.
What?
Why are you startled?
Isn't Dr. Min...
- supposed to do it?- I've spoken...
with him.
But...
You may leave now.
Doctor.
I'd like to be your assistant...
for today's surgery.
You?
Yes.
It's been my dream...
to assist you during surgery.
Because it's a tumor surgery,
somebody hasto send it to the lab.
Please have...
faith in me.
Then, Dr. Kang Eun-hyunwill be the first assistant.
And you...
will be the...
second assistant.
Thank you.
I will go wash my hands.
Cha Yeo-wook.
Chief.
The surgery...
is in your hands now.
[ He's giving herpersonality disorder. ]
[ Personality disorder? ]
[ It's to control... ]
[ her temper. ]
[ Looks like I haveto go through Cha's... ]
[ past surgery post-op effectsof personality disorder. ]
[ There's not enough time. ]
[ I have to find it fast. ]
[ The area whereCha Tae-jin plans to operate on. ]
[ This approach musthave been used before. ]
Let's begin.
Scalpel.
[ Since we're getting married, ]
[ the least I could dois give you a wedding ring. ]
[ Interesting. ]
[ What are you doing,Oh Eun-hee? ]
[ Dr. Cha Tae-jin,what are you up to? ]
[ Listen carefully. ]
[ To me, you're... ]
[ just my father's pet. ]
[ You dowhatever he wants. ]
[ Like a dog whowags its tail any time. ]
[ Before Dr. Min Sung-joon'sgiant aneurysm patient died, ]
[ you forced him tosign the consent form... ]
[ of the organ donation. ]
[ - That...- Did my father push you to it? ]
[ After the patient's death, ]
[ you made it seem likeit was a medical malpractice. ]
[ You did that. ]
[ Do you plan to... ]
[ blame this on my dad too? ]
[ It was anunreasonable surgery. ]
[ It could have beentreated by medication. ]
[ That's what youbelieve to be true. ]
[ I'll marry you... ]
[ but don't give me... ]
[ things like this. ]
[ It sickens me. ]
I...
don't believe in God.
I've never believed...
from the beginning.
But seeing this happen,
I feel so resentful.
Why must such immoral...
acts happen?
The tumor hasalready been excised.
Let's finish up now.
Yes, sir.
Send that to the lab.
Now, all we needto do is touch...
the nerve to giveher personality disorder.
I don't know how...
to pray.
But...
if you really do exist,
and if you'relooking at me,
please help me.
Please save my mother.
Lee Hae-jo!
Doctor.
And the surgery?
The tumor was excised.
I found the areaCha Tae-jin's going to touch.
After sending the tumor to the lab,go back in as soon as possible.
The area is...
I've sent it to the lab.
The result willcome out shortly.
Good.
Put on your gown.
Continue asthe second assistant.
He has to operate alongthe front side...
and along the mainportion of the brain...
to cause a personality disorder.
[ Hee-yeon. ]
[ The moment I abandoned you, ]
[ I've given up mylife as a human being. ]
[ As the pricefor abandoning you, ]
[ I will live anunfortunate life forever. ]
[ It's all right though. ]
[ I never expected... ]
[ to live... ]
[ a loving and... ]
[ happy like others. ]
[ I've given upmy human life. ]
[ I cannot...
[ live life like a human being. ]
[ No...
[ I won't live likea human being. ]
[ I need to finish this up. ]
[ Nothing will... ]
[ ever be in my way again. ]
[ It travels along the front andmain portions of the nerves. ]
Electric tool.
I acknowledge...
that humans cannotbe brought back to life.
that humansshould not kill.
[ The role of a doctor... ]
[ is not to controla human being's life. ]
On bended kneesbefore a sick person,
I will be a good doctor.
Please help me!
Please stop my father.
Please stop thisterrifying event that is...
happening before my eyes.
We've doneall that we could.
Yeo-wook.
The surgery has ended.
It endedaccording to plan.
All of it.
Now...
the only thing is to wait...
for your motherto wake up.
If there...
is anyone to blame...
blame me.
From the very beginning...
I shouldn't havelet this happen.
Doctor...
If I could turn back time...
if I could...
return to the past...
I would have...
never left your mother.
It's me..
who made herthis unfortunate.
And even you.
Doctor.
You didn't cause anyunfortunate events.
All the thingsthat happened,
are choices...
everyone made.
Can you...
forgive me?
Can I call you...
father this once?
Thank you...
for being my father.
Father.
What are youdoing here?
Lee Hae-jo.
Dr. Cha Tae-jin...
is my birth father.
I found out after my mom wasdiagnosed with Alzheimer's.
That Dr. Cha Tae-jinis my father.
Doctor...
From that moment on,I was consumed with thoughts of revenge.
How to beat that personwho abandoned my mom and me.
How to bring him down.
When I discovered he wasexperimenting on patients,
I realized I can...
never forgive him...
even if he's my father.
I staked my whole life,
and set my mindto seek revenge.
But...
when I found out your father...
lost his eyesight becauseof my father.
For the first time,
I wanted toappear indifferent.
I wanted to look away.
I wanted to conceal it.
I wanted tocover up immorality.
I feel really...
apologetic to you.
I'm sorry for hurting you.
I'm sorry I causedyou heartache.
I'm also sorryfor letting you face...
me like this.
You don't needto apologize.
It's not your fault.
You couldn'tcontrol such events.
You didn't do...
anything wrong at all.
I will not hate you...
for whatDr. Cha Tae-jin did.
Leave! Leave!
I told youto get lost!
Get lost!
Let go of me!
- Let go of me!- Sister, calm down!
Let go!
Get out of here!
Disappear from my sight!
She's gone totally crazy.
She's out of her mind!
Who are you?
I'm Cha Tae-jin.
You...
operated onmy head again?
You might as well kill me!
I can't even recognizethe people before me...
Do you know whatI have to go through?!
I want to die.
I don't wantto live anymore.
Kill me. Kill me!
I can't take it anymore!
Get a hold of her!
Let go!
Mom!
Let go of me!
I don't want injections...!
What's going on?
Why has shegone crazy?!
Why are youasking me that?
Father.
Yeo-wook.
You know that...
I am not your father.
Don't call me that.
Brother-in-law.
What happened?
This isn't anotherpost-op side effect, right?
This is justtemporary, right?
Looks like I have tolook for a suitable hospital.
Look for a hospital?
She's a lunatic.
We can't control her.
Are you...
going to send her...
to a mental hospital?
Yes.
Brother-in-law.
I may not beanything to you,
but I'm still her brother.
Why wouldyou send her
to a mental hospital?!
Are you going to take...
care of yourlunatic sister?
Regardless, I will never...
agree...
to this.
If you don't agree to it,
without Oh Eun-hee,
you are nothing.
What did you say?
If you don't want to bekicked out of this hospital too,
don't mess with me.
Cha Tae-jin.
What did youdo to Eun-hee?
You saw it very clearly inthe observation room.
We excised the tumor.
Are you stilla human being?
Don't you feel guilty?
Guilty?
Cha Tae-jin.
I am...
a doctor whohelps others.
A doctor who determinesa person's life and death.
Oh Eun-hee'stest was positive.
The CT scan and...
MRI clearlyshowed it too.
I did all I couldas a doctor.
By the way.
You know the surgery thatwas revealed to the public?
The shunt surgery youdid with Yeo-wook.
Looks like this willboil over very soon.
A formal inquiry...
will be set upto analyze it.
What did you say?
Prepare yourself.
[ I will... ]
[ let Dr. Cha Tae-jinperform... ]
[ my tumor surgery. ]
[ You and I both know... ]
[ what that means. ]
[ Please help... ]
[ Dr. Min Sung-joon. ]
[ As a human being... ]
[ and as a woman... ]
[ I'm begging you. ]
I'm Kim Yi-joon.
I need to tell you this.
I called areporter regarding...
my uncle's operation.
What do you mean...
by you called?
As a guardian
and a doctor,
I expressed my viewpoint.
There were no...
problems with the surgery.
I've talked withmy family members...
and we decided tocancel the lawsuit.
I didn't want to file a lawsuit...
from the very beginning.
Dr. Kim Yi-joon.
I came to tell you...
that you havenothing to...
worry about.
Then, I'll take my leave.
I thought you're..
with Dr. Cha Tae-jin.
Why are you doing this?
I'm leaving...
in a couple of days.
I'm leaving South Korea.
I wanted to...
do the right thing
at least oncebefore I leave.
Dr. Oh Eun-hee's surgerywent ahead as expected.
She can'tcontrol her feelings.
And she can't recognize people,so she'd be more upset.
The hospital
will get chaotic.
Time will takecare of...
people's anger.
I've been married to...
Oh Eun-hee forhalf a lifetime.
She's cold-hearted and
keeps herselfcomposed at all times.
This kind of woman...
can't control herown feelings.
There's nothingto be scared...
and worry about.
Sung-joon.
Eun-hee.
Are you really Sung-joon?
I've been waiting for you.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
You don't feel weak at all?
No headaches?
- Can you hear my clearly?- I...
am fine.
Do you feel upsetall of a sudden?
Or experience fits of anger?
I feel the same, Sung-joon.
Nothing...
has...
changed.
Thank you.
Do you know?
My love for you...
hasn't changed one bit.
Nothing has...
changed at all.
My heart still beats fast.
I still have...
pain in my heart.
Nothing is damaged.
Heart, thinking, memory...
They're all the same.
I'm all right.
Eun-hee.
I had a dream.
In that dream,
I saw your face.
I recognized...
your face.
What about Dr. Cha Tae-jin?
Was he completely fooled?
Seems like he doesn'tsuspect a thing.
Now...
we just need to...
get the brain map.
Dr. Kang Eun-hyun...
has been consistentlyinvestigating.
I'm sure he will bring over...
the files soon.
We must trust him.
Can we trust him?
Although Idon't want to...
doubt and keep guard,
he is Cha Tae-jin's...
son after all.
When the specializedmedical exam is over,
you will remain aschairman of this hospital.
You can choose...
to purse your specialty.
I will help you.
I understand.
In a calm and orderly way.
Don't feel rushed.
Make this hospital yours.
You're not alone.
Yes.
I want to see...
your mother.
Can you tell me...
where she is now?
Take this.
What is this?
This is fruit of my labor,
the brain map.
If you tell mewhere Hee-yeon is,
I will tell you password...
to open it.
Do you...
trust me?
I'm not yet used to it.
The fact thatI'm your father.
And believingin other people...
I'm not usedto it yet.
Including youin this project...
was a hugedecision for me.
But we can't...
go back now.
This time,
we have to fightagainst those...
who covet our position.
The sun is so bright.
When the sunshines so brightly,
I sometimesfeel so shabby.
How did youkeep yourself calm?
What do you mean?
After finding outwhat father had done,
you ran out immediately
to help in theemergency surgery.
Then you went to my mom
and volunteered tobe the assistant surgeon.
You calmly performed...
your dutyas an assistant.
I'm sure it must havebeen a huge shock.
How did you keepyourself calm?
When my dad returnedafter his surgery,
he said to me...
"I don't know whathappened to me."
"I can't see."
I swayed my handsup in the air.
I wasn't frightened.
You weren't frightened?
If somethingshocking occurs...
Fright, panic...
anger and sadness...
I don't feel them at all.
Everything suddenly disappears.
So I can't feelanything at all.
When I heardthat my father...
became blind onpurpose by Dr. Cha...
I had no...
feelilngs at allin the beginning.
And I slowly startedto think that...
Dr. Cha Tae-jin...
needs to be killed.