Sincronización:
Marga y CarpeDiem
wWw.Asia-Team.Tv
Chicago
Sixteen Months Ago
I'm a cop, you jerk.
You're pissin' me off! You hear me?
No, i'm clean, man. I'm clean.
Shut up.
- Didn't do it, huh?
- Come on, let me go.
Jesus, kenny.
How is it you live In this neighborhood
your whole life And don't
know This alley's fenced off?
I mean, i ain't Even holdin', man.
Yeah, right.
Pick 'em up. Put 'em in your pocket.
Come on, man. Why you doing this?
Do it now, Or so help me
I'll shoot you In the face.
Now you tell me who killed That
little girl Or i take you in.
If i'm not mistaken, You're looking
At a third strike, Am i right?
Come on, man. If i talk, I'm a dead man.
- You know how it goes.
- There you are. Lost ya.
Since when Are you so slow?
Since i found out You're a rat.
Oh, god.
Your friends in the fbi
Shoulda warned you, robbie-Boy.
This is what happens To rats in chicago.
Oh, jeez.
This is w. C.P. Chicago.
The grand jury handed
down 19 indictments
In a massive police
Corruption scandal today.
Wounded hero detective And
whistle-Blower Robert patrone arrived
In court this morning Under the
protection Of the u. S. Marshals.
Alburqueque
Thirteen Months Ago
So what do you think?
I think you've picked The
perfect time To buy a house.
No, i mean what do you
think About the house itself?
Oh, nice bones. Can't say
i'm wild About the decor.
Hey, where's The washer-Dryer guy?
Gone. He finished.
Did you see the backyard?
Did you check out the pool?
I did indeed. Very swinging 70s.
You're, like, A grown-Up now.
You think i've made A terrible mistake.
No, i don't. Why would you say that?
Because i do. I've made A
terrible mistake. I know i have.
I don't know What i was thinking.
I'm not homeowner material.
Sure you are. You're just
having A little buyer's remorse.
- You think?
- Absolutely.
Okay. Anyway, i've got Three bedrooms.
Check this out. One is my bedroom.
One is my office. And the
other one Is i have no idea.
How great is that? I've got an
entire room With no defined purpose.
I could fill it With
cornflakes if i wanted.
Not sure this neighborhood
Is zoned for cornflakes,
but an intriguing notion Nonetheless.
Okay, then sand. I could fill it
with sand. Better yet, bullets.
You can never have Too many bullets.
That's my bullet room.
I have a bullet room.
Well, as long As it's something practical.
Oh, i brought you Coffee and a bagel.
- You suck.
- Excuse me?
Oh, still With the juice fast?
Aren't you crabby enough Without
adding spirulina To the mix?
Bite me, I'm trying to do
Something healthy For a change.
- Why?
How 'bout Because being healthy
Is better than Not being healthy?
Doesn't suit you. Seems oddly out
of character. Kind of unsettling.
Did you ever Stop to think That what's
In character for me Isn't working for me?
I'm 35-Ish. I don't have a
boyfriend. I live by myself.
I go to work, Come home, go to work.
Is it so beyond The realm of reason
That i might want Just a little bit more
for my life, Or is that just too much For
you to wrap Your little pea-Brain around?
I gotta believe this Is
the spirulina talking.
I swear i'm about to
shove That bagel up your-
Anybody home? Hello?
- Sweet pea?
- No, no, no. God no.
What? Who is it? What, who is it?
Sweet pea?
You have to hide me And then
pretend This is your house.
Hide you from whom?
Oh, hello.
Surprise!
I drove all the way From paramus To
help you get settled In your new house.
Oh, thanks, mom. Thanks.
Oh, sweetheart.
Which room should I put my stuff in?
"Item 42... "Financial obligations.
"Entry In witness protection Does
not absolve you From past debt. "
- I don't have any debt.
- Lucky you.
"Item 43... "Linking social security
And other retirement accounts,
"Such as iras, 401s, And
pensions, To your new identity. "
Yeah, good luck Digging my
pension Out of chicago p. D.
Is there anything In what we
just covered You don't understand?
Yeah, I'm a little unclear
Why you're drinking That swill.
I'm a little unclear Why you think
It's any Of your business. Come on.
Time to see Your new home.
I can't wait to see What
kind of castle on the hill
60 bucks a day Gets you in albuquerque.
You should Stop thinking
Whatever it is You're thinking.
Oh, come on, man.
You mean to tell me You have
a partner That looks like
that And you still get pissy
When guys check her out?
Maybe you're the one That needs to
stop thinking What you're thinking.
Hey, let's go. Marshall, you coming?
- I have work to do.
- Suit yourself. Come on, eps.
You're gonna Make yourself crazy.
Well, i've stayed in worse.
Hell, i grew up in worse.
You're paid up For six months.
After that, you should be
Supporting yourself Or have
a damn good reason Why not.
Yeah.
- Aren't you going home?
- Nope.
I don't get it. So what if
your mom Showed up unannounced?
She just wanted To surprise you.
There are two kinds Of surprises,
marshall... Birthday and pearl harbor.
Guess which category The mom surprise falls
under. It doesn't matter. I hate 'em both.
Well, you can't Stay here forever.
No, i can't. But i
think I can do a week.
I bet if i don't show up For a week,
She'll run out Of food and booze, and leave.
Oh, god. Why won't She stop calling me?
Maybe because You left her home alone In a
house full Of unpacked boxes 12 hours ago.
- Good god, I'm so hungry.
- Okay, good night.
Night.
Leave me alone!
What do you want from me?
Uh, i was hoping You could come get me.
- Who is this?
- Who's this?
- Did i dial 442-31-
- Eps?
Yeah. Mary, so listen, I hopped a bus.
Actually, it was More like nine busses, You
know, just to explore Like you suggested.
Good for you.
Yeah, except the guy At the place i'm at
Says the bus stopped Running around 9:00.
You mind coming to get me?
Yeah, sorry, I'm not a taxi service.
Come on. I'm, like, totally lost.
Cops don't get lost.
I'm not a cop anymore. And this doesn't
look Like the greatest neighborhood.
Honestly, I'm a little bit frightened.
Yeah, i'm sure You're terrified.
All right, Give me an address.
I don't know What happened.
They just brought Two dinners.
You gotta try This chilean sea bass
though. You know, It's safe to eat again.
Here's the deal, eps.
I can only imagine What
kind of b-Movie fantasy
You conjured up About how
this Was gonna play out.
But to save you From future humiliation,
You should know A couple of things.
One, wasting my time Is a big mistake.
Two, arrogant assholes Who
think They can get in my pants
Using lame, Romantic
cliches Make me want to puke.
Now pay your bill And let's go.
Thanks.
I'm... sorry...
about The ridiculous come-On.
I, uh-
I don't know.
You know, in chicago That woulda worked.
I think maybe I'm one of those people
You need to see In context to get.
And you were Completely right
About the b-Movie fantasy.
Except in my version, It
ends with me getting loaded
With all my old buddies,
The ones i ratted out,
Tellin' them all About the hot witsec
inspector I nailed in albuquerque.
Why'd you do it?
You want The complicated
answer Or the truth?
I don't know, Surprise me.
I was afraid To go to jail.
Is that The complicated
answer Or the truth?
That's the truth.
And...
it's complicated. The
fbi Had a ton of evidence.
If i hadn't taken the deal,
Someone else would have.
And i'd be The one in prison.
But i know A few of those guys Woulda
told the feds To go screw themselves.
Which leads me to believe That
i just Didn't have the balls
To stand up With my friends
and say, "We did what we had to do. "
- Which was what?
- Which was...
Putting away murderers. And rapists.
And junkies who were Pimping their
kids For a fix By any means necessary.
And for that part of
it, I have no regrets.
So what, You planted
evidence, Gave false testimony?
Yeah.
Look, i don't expect you To understand.
I'm sure you always play
By the book. It just gets-
It just gets frustrating After awhile.
You know, All those rules That
are supposed To protect us,
They just get between us
And the things we want most.
It's kinda hard For me
to take you seriously
with that tinfoil bird In your lap.
As soon as we're finished, I
am gonna eat That entire swan.
I might have to live here.
Every day we make Hundreds of choices.
Most of them innocuous
Either-Or kind of decisions,
Like, "should i turn Right or left?"
Others require A bit more thought, Like,
"should i order The bacon-Cheeseburger,
"Which i love, "Or some low-Fat
Flavorless salad "Which i know
Is better for me But will
ultimately Leave me unsatisfied?"
And then there are Those
really tough choices...
- Hey, squish.
- Hey.
Like, "should i Sleep with someone
"Just because i'm isolated "And yearn
so deeply For any kind of human
contact That my skin Actually aches?"
So, um...
- about yesterday.
- I'm not sleeping With raph.
And now we're not Even friends anymore.
So you can stop Worrying about it.
I'm not worried About it.
And i don't want you
To stop being friends...
But I don't want To compete with
you For his attention Either.
I know. I know, And you
shouldn't have to. I just...
I understand.
You don't have Any other friends here.
Look, awhile ago You asked me To help
you find Some direction in your life.
I want to apologize For not
following through With that.
- Well, it's no big deal.
- It is.
It's a really big deal.
So how 'bout, um, After work we
get some dinner And talk about it?
- Yeah, okay.
- Good.
And in the meantime, It's fine
with me If you hang out with raph.
The slain officer,
Stephen ramirez, Was shot
to death Near his
Northeast heights precinct.
Police sources tell us Before
joining Albuquerque p. D.,
He served with distinction On
chicago's Narcotics division.
Ramirez leaves behind His
wife of 12 years, Elizabeth,
And two children, Zach,
age six, And max, age three.
Hey, it's eps. Leave a message.
Hey, it's mary shepherd. I need you
to call me As soon as you get this.
It's important.
Eps, it's mary again.
Where the hell are you?
Call me.
Hey, what's going on?
Anyone know anything About the shooting?
- Not much.
- He was off duty.
Got shot four times Up close down
on central. Never drew his weapon.
Could have been Someone he
knew. Cops make Lots of enemies.
Yeah, maybe he ran Into
someone he knew From chicago.
What's with the looks?
He's pointing A not-So-Subtle
finger At my witness, Robert eps.
I'm not pointing anything At anyone.
But it wouldn't be The
first cop he killed.
Yeah, well, I'm already
into it. And screw you.
He took one in the back, Then shot that
cop In self-Defense, And you know that.
What are you doing?
Nothing, just considering
All possibilities.
Maybe he shot this cop
In self-Defense too.
All right, That's enough.
We're all On the same team here.
Mary, Talk to your witness.
Find out where he was Last night.
Listen, Chico,
Whatever might have happened Between us
Didn't, wouldn't, And never will.
And the fact is, We're friends.
And i don't have Many friends.
Actually, I don't have any
friends Except for your sorry ass.
So until i find Someone better,
You don't get To just decide
That we're not Hanging out
anymore. Okay, you just don't.
Too bad. Sorry. So shut up about it.
- How do you have keys To my place?
- It's mary's.
Oh, and by the way, um, She said
that it was okay For us to, you know.
No, not that "you know," You know.
Brandi, we are friends, And
i don't want To lose that.
But you have to admit That between
us There's this Kind of attraction.
Oh, please. Okay, so what?
Nothing's gonna happen.
Even if i wanted to, Which just the thought
of it Makes me throw up a little bit.
Okay, you would Never cheat on mary.
Never, ever In a million, billion years.
You're such a boy scout.
You're, like, The most honest,
- Decent, Trustworthy guy...
- I slept with judy.
Fat judy? Your physical therapist?
Well, i wouldn't Call her fat.
Why don't you go hustle Your
flabby ass downstairs And bring me
back The goddamn ballistics report
I asked for In the first place?
Rox, you can't abuse The civilian
volunteers. They work for free.
And yet, we're still
Paying him too much.
We all want The same thing, roxanne.
Yeah, a donut that won't
go Straight to my ass.
Oh, you gotta love her, Right?
Partner's the one Who got killed.
Just wanted to say We're
all thinking about you.
If there's anything
We can do on our side.
- Thanks. It's appreciated.
- How's it going? Got any suspects?
Anyone see anything?
What?
I'll tell you what, You're...
You're one Of those players Who
doesn't show up To the track Unless
they have a horse In the race.
I'm just Looking to help.
- All right.
- Bobby...
Tell me what you know About
this. And don't give me
any of that "I can't
talk about it" Bull crap.
Bobby, i'm just doing My due diligence,
Seeing if anything i know Connects
with anything you know. And it doesn't.
So good luck With the investigation.
God help you, mary, If i find
out You're protecting someone...
Who are you? You know
something about this.
I'm mary shannon. I'm a u. S.
Marshal. I'm sorry about your-
You know. What do you know?
I'm sorry About your
partner. I don't know anything
About his murder. Now
take your hands Off me.
- You're a lair.
- That's enough.
Get back to your desk.
If it were my partner, I'd be doing
the same thing. But just so we're clear,
next time she lays Her
hands on me Will be the last.
Last chance, mary. Either
you tell me What you know
or who you know Or get the
hell Out of my squad room.
Here's what i know. When the heat is on,
You become an even
bigger Asshole than usual.
You dropped this.
Thanks.
Who's that?
According to this, He's
a guy who didn't exist
Until he showed up In
new mexico 13 months ago.
Where have you been, Asshole?
Workin'.
- Is this about That dead cop?
- I called seven hours ago.
Sorry, i was in the middle
Of doing a hot tub install.
I don't bring my cell
Into clients' homes.
You know, just because We slept
together once Doesn't mean You own me.
- Where the hell are you now?
- Home.
- Stay there.
- I'm coming over. Yes, ma'am.
You know, if i knew Killing another
cop Would get you To come to my house,
I woulda done it A long time ago.
That's not even A little bit funny.
Brandi, come on. I need
to talk to you. Open the-
- Brandi.
- Coming.
Hello, raphael. Come in.
Hi. Thanks.
- I need to talk To you.
- Why?
You got another secret You're
dying To get off your chest?
Are you boning Your maid too?
- What?
- She's joking.
Can we just Talk in private, please?
Fine.
You want me to go.
- What happened Was an accident.
- Really?
'Cause accidents Are usually more
like You trip And you sprain an ankle.
Not you trip and you stick
Your penis in someone.
I didn't mean an "accident"
As much as a "mistake. "
Look, it was A confusing time.
Mary was Completely avoiding me.
Every time i ask her To do something,
She asked you To do it for her.
I thought We were broken up.
So you nailed That fat pig,
And you never Even hit on me?
Damn, chico...
i can't think Of the right answer here.
God, you look good.
Where were you Last night?
I took a walk Around old town.
Had a drink alone.
Got home around 11:00,
Also alone unfortunately.
Did you know this guy, The one
who was killed, Stephen ramirez?
Look, i didn't even know
Everyone in my precinct.
No, i didn't Know the guy.
And no, I didn't kill him.
Next time i call you, Call me back.
So how come you avoid
me Like the plague?
Because i like my job, And i don't
want what happened To happen again.
At least you didn't
say It was a mistake.
No, just a choice, And
choices Have consequences.
The consequence Of us sleeping
together Is like it or not
I have to keep My distance from
you More than other witnesses.
- More than you want to?
- Actually, no.
Perfectly happy Staying away from
you. I gotta go. Keep your phone handy.
- What?
- Your boy's About to get arrested.
What? How's that possible?
I have no idea. Stan's on
his way Over to metro now.
All right, Thanks.
- Come on.
- Where?
Police station. Better you
walk in Th get dragged in.
I don't know how The
son of a bitch found you,
But at least he won't have the
Satisfaction of bringing you in.
What the hell is this?
Are you kidding me?
Stay where you are, Both of you.
Keep your hands Where i can see 'em.
Are you outta your mind? You're
drawing down On a u. S. Marshal.
I am gonna burn you For this.
Robert eps, You're wanted For questioning
In the murder Of officer stephen ramirez.
So what's plan b?
I'm telling you, You got the wrong guy.
- Keep walking, Douche bag.
- Don't say a word.
How about When this crazy bitch
Shoots me For trying to escape?
Then should I say something?
Hold up.
Visitors go Around front.
I'm here on official
business. Get outta my way.
And what kinda business Would that be?
'Cause if you wanna
state For the record Your
official connection To my
prisoner, I'd be happy To
let you pass. Otherwise,
you go around front And
fill out A visitation
request Like everyone else.
- Why are you doing this?
- 'Cause i don't like Cop killers.
And right now i'm not
too wild About you either.
Mary.
They're booking eps.
Prick dershowitz Won't even let me in.
I'll take care of it.
I need to call The
u. S. Attorney's office.
I said I'll take care of it.
They just peed On the wrong dog's porch.
This federal court order Gives my
people Complete access To mr. Eps.
That means two marshals
On post 24 hours a day.
Your lead detective Will keep us up to
speed On any developments In the case.
And albuquerque e. S.U. Will take down
The wiretap on this number Immediately.
I can't believe that little
Bitch actually tapped my phone.
- Excuse me?
- Actually he tapped Eps' phone.
Whose number he snooped Off your phone.
Anyway, captain, The u. S. Government
Appreciates your
cooperation In this matter.
I'm saying I didn't know the
guy. Not here, Not in chicago.
Yeah, we know All about chicago.
We found the gun That you dumped
Three blocks away In the arroyo.
That's Some nice police work.
Once we find Your prints on it, The
d. A. Won't be Offering you any deals.
Worst law enforcement idea In the
last 100 years... Male/female partners.
Did you know That nine times outta ten
They end up screwing Or killing each other?
Or both?
Ten bucks Says she did it.
You're a bastard!
Oh, you are tough.
So that's the kinda guy You
go for, A rat cop killer?
Anything other than They both worked
in chicago Tying these guys together?
I'm confident we got The right guy.
Sounds like you're doing Some
great police work. Keep it up.
So where do you wanna start?
This morning You wanted to fry
eps. Now you want to help him?
No, i want to help you.
Thanks. All right, you go
look Into ramirez's case
to see who else Has an ax to grind.
I'll go talk to the widow In the
morning, See what the guy Was like.
You really think That's a
good idea? She's a widow.
I'll be so nice She'll be
happy Her husband's dead
just for the chance To meet me.
Got some information About junior
colleges. You wanna Go over it tonight?
Sure.
What are you doing
With raph's gym clothes?
Hmm, let's see. Laundry
room. Skanky gym clothes.
Detergent. What on
earth Could i be up to?
Hope you don't mind.
Knock yourself out. I'm
sure as hell Not gonna do it.
Oh, that's bad.
Okay, don't get All freaky.
How long have you been Screwing my
boyfriend Behind my back, brandi?
- Brandi, you slept With raph too?
- No!
- Too? Oh, my god.
- What?
- Mom!
- Oh, no, no, Not me.
I just... I just meant
After all This judy thing...
His fat Physical therapist?
Okay, in chico's defense, You guys
weren't together there For a few weeks.
And he feels Really,
really bad about it.
You both knew About this? When
were you planning On telling me?
- what was the question?
- I want you both Out of here.
Disgusting.
Greg, sweetie, Those are
frozen enchiladas For later.
Why don't you Grab
some coffee and relax?
- Mrs. Ramirez?
- Yes.
Hi, i'm mary shannon
From the marshals service.
Just wanted to say On behalf of all
of us We're so sorry For your loss.
Thank you. That's so thoughtful.
Would you look In that top cabinet
And see if i have Any vases left?
Sure.
Did you know steve?
No, no, i didn't.
Everyone i talk to Speaks so highly
of him. He must have been A great cop.
He was.
He was a hero too.
Twice decorated. Once
here And once in chicago.
- Oh, let me Fix you a plate.
- Thank you.
It sounds like he had A lot
of close friends On the force.
Not really.
You know, he was so
devoted To his family,
He didn't have a lot of
time For other people.
- What about his partner?
- Roxanne?
Oh, he loved her. She's a great girl.
Steve and I Always wished She'd
find a nice man To be with.
- She isn't dating anybody?
- Roxy? No.
- But if you know Of anyone...
- thanks.
What the hell Are you doing here?
- Paying my respects.
- Roxanne, we're just-
- Get her out of here.
- But i haven't eaten.
What the hell Is wrong
with you? Coming here!
All right, I'm leaving!
Come on, let's go.
Get it, get it. Get a shot. Come on.
Got it?
Get up. Unbelievable.
Get up.
All right, Take it easy. Come on.
The cause of the scuffle Between
albuquerque detective Roxanne lewis
and the other Unidentified
female Remains unknown.
Your grappling technique
Leaves something to be desired.
You try fighting And keeping Your
face off-Camera At the same time.
Did you find anything
In ramirez's case files?
Yeah, i dug up A confidential informant
He used in a couple Of drug cases.
Thought he might know If ramirez Was
investigating something That got dangerous.
You mind talking to him While i go
make nice With ramirez's partner?
Sure, but keep your left up This time.
Looks like someone
Kicked the crap outta you.
You hit like a girl.
Thanks. You too.
Look, i know What you're going through.
My partner got shot A few months ago.
I almost lost him.
You get the guy?
Yeah.
Good.
You want coffee?
All right.
I want you to know, If it turns out Eps
is your guy I'll hold
him down While you do it.
But i don't think It's him.
Yeah, well, Forgive my
skepticism, But objectivity
Kinda goes out the window
Once you've slept With the guy.
What?
It was on the wiretap.
He said you only Slept with him once.
You thought That was real?
He's always saying stuff Like that.
But if it were true And it got
out, You'd be kinda screwed, huh?
Ballistics got a hit On the gun.
It was stolen From an evidence
locker In chicago Five years ago.
I don't suppose I need to point
out Ramirez is from chicago too.
Ramirez didn't steal
His own murder weapon.
And there's One more thing...
Eps lied About knowing ramirez.
They worked the same
Murder case six years ago...
And that's enough For me to charge him.
You lied to me. You
worked a case With ramirez.
Jesus, does anybody In
this town do their homework?
That case Was the murder Of an
alderman And his entire family.
I probably did work
With ramirez on it Along
with 400 other cops
Over a two-Year span.
The whole goddamn
force Worked that case.
- Marshall?
- Yeah.
- Cooper?
- Guilty.
I still can't believe
What happened to stephen.
Yeah. I was wondering What
kinda things Was he into?
Excuse me?
What kinda cases Did
he talk to you about?
He had you listed As a
confidential informant.
Uh, that was years ago. That's
how we got To be friends.
I helped him arrest This
boy who was dealing meth.
Stephen and i Both really hated What
those drugs Were doing to our people.
You have people?
Excuse me.
Hey, mare. Feel like
joing me For a drink?
How long did you know
Your partner was gay?
What are You talking about?
Are you crazy?
Guy's married For 12
years. He's got two kids.
- How long have you been His partner?
- It's nothing.
Some things are private, You know?
Everyone's got secrets, Right?
You need to tell me Right
now... Was detective ramirez gay?
I honestly Don't know for sure.
I didn't ask. He didn't tell.
- But i did suspect.
- Did his wife know?
Elizabeth? God no. I can't imagine.
A gay cop With a wife Wound
tighter Than a golf ball.
And you didn't think
That warranted mentioning?
I thought his sex life
Ought to remain private.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Is that how you work
Your civilian homicides?
He was a good cop, bobby, With a family.
You think the fact That
he was gay changes that?
Come on, let's go talk To elizabeth.
Ramirez had access To that gun in chicago.
Maybe he lifted it, Kept it at home.
Maybe, maybe not. Let's not Start accusing
people Until we have Proper evidence.
Wow, talk about the cop
Calling the kettle black.
That's funny. Never sounded
racist Till now. My bad.
I wish i knew What to say, bobby.
But you have Honestly got me stumped.
Steve and i Were very happy together.
We were High school sweethearts.
It must have been so hard.
All those years Not being
able To tell anyone the truth.
How long did you have To live like that?
I couldn't have done it.
What is she talking about?
I mean, If i found
out My husband was gay,
- Yeah, i'd be pissed.
- Dear lord, bobby.
Roxanne, Make her
stop Saying these lies.
All i'm saying Is you poor thing.
To spend all those years
With a man who doesn't
Find you desirable, Who'd
rather be With other men-
Stop it. I don't know why
You're letting her to this.
This man was a hero.
He was one of you.
I think the real tragedy Is
it didn't Accomplish anything.
He didn't fool anyone. Everybody
knew, And nobody cared but you.
Who knew?
Don't say that.
Nobody knew.
That would kill him.
Elizabeth,
Did you know That all police
ammunition Is marked For identification?
The fbi Keeps a database, And
they called me A little while ago.
We know that your husband
Was shot With a stolen gun.
But we also know It
was with his own bullet.
No cop would ever load A throway
With department-Issue Ammunition.
You've got kids In the house.
He probably Kept it empty.
Locked away somewhere.
He died like a hero.
That's what He would have wanted.
He died right.
You understand, Don't you?
Hey, it's me.
So this thing With judy.
I guess we were Kinda broken
up Or whatever When it happened.
So i can't be too pissed.
But i don't know.
It feels Like we're trying To
make this Into something it's not.
And the only time We get
into trouble Is when we
start acting Like we're
supposed To be something more.
So i don't know If you're
okay With us just coasting,
but it sounds Like a good idea to me.
And if you want To see other
people, Well, that's okay too.
Just not my sister. Anyway, I'm
not mad anymore. Call me. Bye.
Are you okay?
Yeah, sure, I'm totally fine.
Sorry about the condom.
You didn't Do anything.
Well, I did your laundry. You're the one
Who left the condom wrapper In your bag.
- Idiot.
- You should probably go.
- Oh, okay.
So i'll see you tomorrow.
I can't do this Right now. I just need
some time To sort things out, Alone.
Okay. Fine. You want
to be alone? Be alone.
Mary was right. This is just
a bunch Of high school b. S.
- What?
- Hey, beautiful. What you doing?
I miss you so much.
Yeah, that's why you
call me All the time.
I'm sorry, babe. I've been
busy Working on our future.
We have no future, chuck. We're done.
Brandi, Please don't say that. We do
have a future. Together. And it's here.
The deal is set, And it's huge.
Seriously? It's set?
Yeah. All your dreams
Are about to come true.
You just have To deliver the stuff
Then fly back home. Uh, first class.
Come on, baby, Don't get down. I love
you so much. I need you to do this.
Okay.
Well, free man. Congratulations.
Thank you.
Come on, We gotta pack.
Your cover's been blown. Find you a
new city, New identity, the whole bit.
Yeah, i don't-
I don't think so.
I'm kinda tired Of being someone else.
You're not Safe here anymore.
Eh, i'm tired Of being safe. Me in
this program, It was never A good fit.
I'm taking myself out.
- You're sure?
- Yeah.
- Where will you go?
- Nowhere.
I like albuquerque. I
like Everything about it.
You need a ride?
Nah, i'll take a bus. Who
knows, Maybe i'll get lost.
Perhaps the most Difficult
choices to make Are the ones
that deny us those
things Our heart wants most.
Because as it's been said,
Without reason nor prudence,
the heart wants What the heart wants.
And more often than not,
It will not be denied.
www.tvsubtitles.net