Hey, we need gasoline.
Where's the gasoline?
Hey, hombres, gasoline.
- "Americanos"?
- Yes!
Passports, "por favor".
Airplane papers, please.
No good.
Why the hell did we have to wander
into this place for?
Why couldn't we have wandered
into Monaco or someplace?
When I was a kid,
they called me Fat Morty.
When I was seven years old,
I weighed 280 pounds.
But I was the smartest kid
on the block, man.
And I never ate "goy drek".
I took my bar mitzvah.
I was growing up to be
like a Talmudic scholar.
I was.
Rabbi Wolf.
And now, I am a man
without a country.
Lewis, look what's coming.
American, right? I can't believe it.
A real live American.
- How's the old U.S. Of A?
- I don't know...
I haven't been there in 2 years.
My name is Wolfie.
This is my partner, Lewis Moon.
- Lewis? Lewis?
- I'm Andy Huben.
He's pleased to meet you,
he just has no manners. That's all.
- Would you like a drink?
- No, I'm sorry, I can't.
Wait, wait... Andy, right?
What are you doing here?
This is like the end of the world.
We've chosen to be here.
My husband is in charge of the
evangelical missions in the territory.
You're here to teach the
Lord's word to the Indians.
Perfect, 'cause I got a halfbreed
Cheyenne over here...
is one of the worst sinners
you'll ever meet.
Would you please do your duty
and save his red-skinned soul?
Leslie, this is Mr. Wolf.
- Let's get these boxes upstairs.
- What's wrong? Do I got the plague?
If you got the plague,
then I would tend to you.
But yours is the plague
of blasphemy and fornication.
I've never fornicated in my life.
In fact, I don't think I even really
know what it means.
Is it technical?
Can you believe I dreamed about this?
When I was about Billy's age,
I dreamed about coming to the Amazon.
And here we are.
- Hazel, right?
- It's so good to see you.
I can't believe we are here.
Billy Quarrier, huh?
Welcome aboard, Bill. Hi, Martin.
Mr. Huben, how are you?
I knew you from your picture.
We're very proud we were chosen
to work with you.
My family read your
mission letters aloud.
- My wife, Andy.
- Your little helpmeet.
Hi, Billy, welcome to the jungle.
My name's Andy.
- Hi, Andy.
- Mrs. Huben to you, young man.
I've compiled a little Niaruna
dictionary to get you started.
- Great.
- Uyuyu helps us with the Lord's work.
The Catholic opposition had him.
Now he's ours.
I mean, now he follows
the true path to God.
And they call this degradation
Mãe de Deus...
Poor mother of God.
Mr. And Mrs. Huben, "Bom dia".
- This is Father Xantes.
- How do you do? How was your trip?
"Bom, obrigado".
Martin Quarrier.
"Esta minha esposa, Hazel".
"Please, please".
Allow me to practice my poor English.
Mrs. Quarrier, if I can be
of any help, let me know.
Billy! Don't touch that! Can't you
see everything here is dirty?
Everything.
It's just a bit of pineapple,
Mrs. Quarrier.
Let's go, folks.
You stay right with me, young man.
- The leader of the opposition?
- "No".
We just spent 4 nights
in a filthy hotel...
with awful food and disgusting bugs.
Now we have to rot here for 3 weeks?
That's our hotel.
- The Anaconda.
- That's right.
Far, far away
In sin and darkness dwelling
Millions of souls
forever may be lost
Who then will go
Salvation's story telling
Looking to Jesus, minding not
the cost?
- All power is given...
- Come in.
All power is given unto me
Go ye into all the world
And preach the gospel
And, lo, I am with you, always
- Welcome to Mãe de Deus.
- Glory be the God.
What did he say?
Yes, "to Jesus..."
"To Jesus, to Jesus."
Uyuyu, are you a Niaruna?
No, but speaks Niaruna.
He's been very useful to us.
And a God Christian, right, Uyuyu?
"Obrigada."
We've established good contacts
with the Tiro and Mintipo.
The Niaruna situation,
is quite different.
A few accepted Catholicism, but...
most of them are still wild.
The Catholics abandoned the mission...
so we took it over.
The Niaruna land is coveted by...
ruthless people who have anything
in mind but the glory of our Lord.
Comandante Guzman is just
waiting for a good excuse to...
pacify them.
- What do you mean, Mr. Huben?
- Les.
- I mean attack...
drive them out, kill them if necessary.
Take over their land.
But that's Indian land.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but attacking
them is against national law.
Here in the jungle, Mart,
there is no law.
I see.
You see, many of the tribes here...
think that their shaman, who is...
kind of like their minister,
is a jaguar.
What I mean is that he can become
a jaguar at night...
and travel off into
the spirit world.
- Can he?
- Shamans?
Bad enough your head is filled with
such nonsense, let alone a child's.
All he thinks about are naked Indians
and jaguars and awful snakes.
Come to bed.
Get in bed.
Jaguars.
- Good night, son.
- Good night.
I suppose you think I should take
Billy back home to the States.
I never said that.
Leave you here with these
prostitutes... Is that what you want?
Hazel, what are you talking about?
Hazel...
we have two or three
more weeks here.
You should learn a little Portuguese.
A Catholic language?
If I let you go and it turns out...
you are fugitives...
or the plane is stolen,
or worse...
what can I do?
Look at this, please.
Every day,
all these people get here.
Every day.
They want to settle...
to feed their families.
My job is to stop these people
from taking the Indian land.
But sometimes,
when people are starving...
nobody can stop them.
And some already go to this land.
Niaruna are very dangerous.
What do you think will happen?
You know the answer, you Americanos.
Look, here is Mãe de Deus.
Very small, no?
Not even on the map.
Up there, following the river...
you find mountains...
and then starts the land of the
Niaruna. The savages, savages.
What's the point?
I like these Niaruna very much.
I'm pleased to protect them...
but they don't need all this land.
It's too much for
a few dozen people...
who do nothing from morning to night.
It's inhuman.
Anyway, these Indians
are not very nice.
Their chief, Boronai,
he would kill you like that.
I told you about Boronai.
I just need a little favor.
A foreign airplane passing over
their village...
some little bombs fell out
these Indians will run away.
This way they are safe.
I get it.
You want us to blow the little
brown pricks to kingdom come.
No, no, no.
The idea is not to kill them.
It's only to scare them.
For their own good.
They will find another place.
"Con permiso."
When we get back,
we get our papers, right?
- And a tank of gas?
- I don't see why not.
Hey, preacher, in 2 or 3 days
we'll be gone.
And you get this stinking
toilet to yourselves.
Ei, amigo, trouxe "ayahuasca" para você.
[I've brought "ayahuasca" for you]
Eu acho que é muito bom.
[I think it's very good]
Dá mais um pouco.
[Give a little more]
Howdy.
You mind if I sit down here?
Ayahuasca?
Care to blow your mind?
You better watch yourself.
That there is a very poisonous drug.
The Indians call that Nipi.
That stuff can kill you.
Do you know what this is?
It's a Niaruna-to-English dictionary.
It's the very first of its kind.
You might even be interested in this.
For instance, the Sioux word for
"Great Spirit" is "Wakantanka".
You won't believe what it is Niaruna.
"Wakankon".
The Great Spirit, huh?
Yeah. You find all these
surprising similarities...
between the Plains Indians
and these people.
Shit!
There are greater similarities between
my people and Crow and Shoshone...
and we killed them every chance
we got and they killed us to...
because we were too fucking stupid
to recognize our real enemy.
You got the call, Reverend?
Jesus wants you for his
little sunbeam, right?
You have faith in Lord?
Did you earn it, or were you
stuffed with it like a turkey?
I don't appreciate
been talk to that way.
And as far as my faith goes,
that's something I work out...
day by day with
the help of the Lord.
You really like the Indians.
Their language, their customs...
they interest you.
Yes, they interest me a great deal.
So, why do you want
to change them?
If God made the Indians the way
they are...
who are you to make them different?
Do you really intend
to bomb the Niaruna?
I'd hoped you'd tell me that
wasn't true.
Telling lies is a sin.
The Niaruna you intend to murder are
the ones I came here to work with...
Mr. Moon.
I can't believe you would do that.
- You're part Indian yourself.
- Which part? My prick?
Let me tell you that as an American
I'd be proud...
to have Indian blood. I think a lot of
Americans would be proud to have it.
They would, huh?
Just how much Indian blood would
most Americans be proud to have?
Hey, preacher.
I'm talking to you.
That other guy around here,
the scout leader...
is he your boss?
He is my superior, yes.
And your wife,
she's the big one, right?
The one with dark hair?
- Yes, my wife is the big one.
- And the pretty one is his?
Yes, the pretty one is his.
You screwed her yet?
I'm not gonna take this anymore!
You have a demon in you!
You're nothing but a drunk,
vicious coward!
You want to come outside?
Step outside if you're man enough!
I'm calling you a coward!
You'll get tired of it after a while.
What am I doing?
Preacher, I think you should relax
and give the old pecker a workout.
You might even like it.
Wolfie, he thinks fucking is a sin.
Me and my fiancée
don't believe in sin.
Are you trying to tell me that dropping
bombs on these Indians...
is going to pacify them?
No...
but killing them will.
If they hide in the jungle, at least you
bastards can't turn them into beggars.
Like that fucking Yoyo.
Infecting them with syphilis
and with booze.
Right, Padre?
Tell this poor guy how the priest
got massacred by the Niaruna.
That is not such an amusing story.
It can be.
You see, first the noble savages...
raped both the nuns.
Okay?
Then when they lifted up the priest's
robes and saw they'd been deceived...
they chopped his head off.
"L'chayim."
We found the body eight days later.
- I've written for a replacement.
- Replacement?
Oh, have no fear.
Comandante Guzman prefers
your wealthy mission...
to my humble operation.
You abandoned your Niaruna mission.
The Niaruna are no longer you concern.
On the contrary.
All people are my concern.
Even you and your family,
Mr. Quarrier.
Good night.
In one or two centuries...
everybody will have our colour,
Mr. Moon.
And these Indians you wish to kill...
Yet appears you're an
Indian yourself.
How sad.
Does it not strike you as sad?
God, it's like green hell down there.
I don't know about you,
but it gives me the creeps.
There's the abandoned mission.
We're right on track.
Niaruna.
Sounds like a good Hebrew name.
It's the lost fucking tribe
of Israel, man.
They're Jews, just like me.
It's their turn
to get persecuted now.
In case they forgot what it
as like back in Tel Aviv.
Where are you going?
I'm talking to you, Lewis.
I want my papers back, okay?
We got to drop some bombs
in case Guzman counted.
Where are you going, Lewis?
Lewis, where are you going?
Don't you fuck with me, Lewis.
Don't even try it.
We're going back. Now, Lewis.
We are going back.
Pull out.
Come on.
Pull out, Lewis!
Shit.
You mean the reason we didn't
drop the bombs is because...
some nude, fucking aboriginal
who is probably a fucking cannibal...
was dumb enough to shoot
an arrow at our plane?
A lot of people would say you're
a murdering bastard.
- A lot of people would.
- Yeah, a lot of people.
I ain't like you.
I don't have a stinking death wish.
Hey, Chief, sorry.
No luck today.
Maybe tomorrow, huh?
Nice country out there.
You're going to love it.
We left a few for you.
Did you drink this shit?
Answer me.
Lewis, listen.
It ain't like they're Cheyennes.
It ain't like they're Apache.
They're son of a bitchin'
South Americans.
Listen to me,
they're nothing but jungle rats.
Listen. I'm telling Guzman we fly
tomorrow. Do you read me?
Do you read me?
Ten hut! Shit!
You're out of here.
You're out of here, Lewis.
November 1-3-Zulu,
do you read me? Over.
This is Les Huben, at Mãe de Deus.
Do you read me?
Do you read me? Fuel level in
your aircraft is very critical. Over.
Do you read me, November?
Your fuel level is dangerously low.
How about some last rites,
Reverend?
Moon, can you hear me, over?
You are under the effect of a
powerful drug. You are in danger.
You're running out of gas and time.
Where are you? Over.
I'm at play in the fields
of the Lord.
At play in the fields of the Lord.
Gimme that.
Chief...
Lewis.
I know you can hear me.
You get your ass back here
with that plane, now.
He's gone.
At play...
Crazy son of a bitch.
May God forgive him.
We heard...
a terrible thunder.
You fell down from the sky.
Are you the Thunder Spirit?
Are you Kisu?
We don't want you here.
Go back where you came from.
Go back now.
Aeore, he came from the sky.
I don't care where he came from.
He must leave.
Boronai.
Aeore, don't make him angry.
He can do us harm.
You must leave right now.
This is our village.
Get out!
You are Kisu?
Moon.
He is Kisu Mu from the sky.
Niaruna.
Pindi, quick, bring food.
Kisu Mu wants to eat.
Hurry up, you lazy girl.
We are naked and have nothing.
Therefore,
we must decorate ourselves.
Without our paint...
how are we to be different
from animals?
"Adeus".
Under the eyes of God,
we begin our journey.
Hey, preacher.
You see Moon, you tell him I won't
hang around this town forever.
Tell him the old Wolf
has to cover his own ass.
He's letting you steer?
"Hi."
Bring another bottle of booze.
- What tribe are they?
- Tiro.
They look nasty, but they've been
pacified for a long time.
They're Catholic?
The opposition took advantage.
Anyway, they're a meek
and stupid people.
Then they shall inherit the Earth,
as the Lord Said.
We're here now.
We'll be in Remate, here,
by nightfall.
We'll sleep one more night on
the boat, get up at five...
and by mid-afternoon tomorrow,
we'll be at the mission.
Will we found our mission
in the exact same place...
where the priest was killed?
Yes, it will show the Indians
we're determined. Which is vital.
Some Niaruna will meet us.
A fellow named Kori and his people.
They're Catholic converts
who are used to whites.
They stayed even after
the Catholics left?
Some of them ran back to their village,
but Kori's people stayed.
That's right.
We'll have to win them over
from the Romans, I guess.
You think they are watching us?
It's possible.
Are you scared?
- You bet. Aren't you?
- Nah.
Maybe your faith
is stronger than mine.
"God's will be done."
Stay here, Andy.
Come on, Martin.
"Kori".
We'll have to start all over.
Maybe that's for the best.
Hard work.
Hey, boss.
I'm gonna smoke a cigarette.
Father Silva's grave.
There is more important
business to be done.
It's a shame we need an armed guard
to do God's work.
You want to end up that way?
"God's will be done."
I feel like we're bribing the Indians
to love Jesus.
It's for their own good.
It's the first contact that counts.
How else they come to us?
How else will they learn that
Jesus Christ died for their sins?
"Uyuyu, vamos".
Lord be praised.
It's Kori. Martin!
It's Kori.
They have come back.
Bring presents and food.
Hurry up!
My friends, praise the Lord.
- I come in peace.
- Welcome.
"Please, we need food."
"My people are hungry...
they need clothes."
"Nós temos comida para você
e roupas também."
["We have food and clothing for you]
Bring the stuff, hurry!
"Excuse-me, please".
Andy, bring something
for this lady.
No, it's very bad, very bad.
We don't use it.
"Outro lado."
["Other side"]
Praying the Mother of God -
can you imagine?
We got to get them
to the other side.
"Kori, uma bolacha e também..."
Other side, go on.
This is nuts.
Hazel, come on.
We'll change partners.
- Having a good time?
- I'm having a great time.
- How about he little fella?
- He's having fun.
Hey, Martin.
Give me my wife back.
- You can't have her.
- You can have yours.
Listen, you're a big boy now.
God is counting on you to help
your mother and father, okay?
I'll miss you.
- God bless the Quarrier family.
- God bless you too.
God bless you and keep you.
Lord Jesus Christ be with you.
Have a safe trip back.
God bless the Quarrier family.
God help us.
Son.
Verily, verily I say onto thee,
except a man be Born of water...
and of the Spirit...
he cannot enter
the kingdom of heaven.
I baptize you in the name of our Lord,
Jesus Christ.
- Alleluia.
Billy, where are you?
Billy, were you watching this?
Were you?
Come down here right now,
young man!
Look at you.
Were you watching this, this, this...
You look like a demon!
Shame on you!
Get out of here!
Stop this vile, disgusting...
You're sinners!
You are not married.
You sin against God.
- What are you doing?
- They were...
I'm not leaving! These people need
to be disciplined. They are not...
Dad, do the wild ones
know we're here?
They know.
They know all right, son.
Billy... about your mom...
We have to try and be
patient with her.
We have to try and understand her.
This is difficult for her.
Dad...
Why were they doing that?
They were grabbing each other.
The next time you strike an Indian...
for any reason whatsoever...
it's you who will be sent away.
They are different from us,
they don't understand.
It could be dangerous for us all.
Billy's seeing these filthy tricks!
It won't seem filthy to him
unless we make it so.
- It's very natural.
- Natural?
And if one of these nasty little
savages touches him?
He might enjoy it.
Dad, they're here.
The wild ones.
The wild ones?
Come out, don't fear.
Come here. Come.
This is my house.
It's good here.
Plenty of food.
We don't have to work.
He is a good friend.
He has gifts for you,
you, everybody.
Tell them we have
presents for them.
Kori, can you get them
to lower them?
You got them laughing, son.
You got them laughing, Billy.
You wanna give them their presents?
Go ahead.
Just be careful.
Go ahead. Okay.
Don't be afraid.
Keep passing them out.
Okay, come here, Billy.
Good going.
Moon? Lewis Moon? Moon?
Kisu Mu? Moon?
It's all right. Come on in.
Don't worry. They're friendly.
What do you have?
Rice. Good. Thank you.
Dad, you found the real ones.
I think they found us.
It's more than Mr. Huben did.
It's okay, honey.
Kori, do something.
It's alright. Just relax.
She just wants your sunglasses.
Don't get mad.
My wife.
Friends.
This is nothing.
No, it's not your fault.
Come back.
Good Lord.
Taweeda, where did you get those
things? It's a white man's stuff.
Take it off right now.
What are you talking about?
This is mine. It makes me beautiful.
I don't want to see you
with these things again.
You broke my necklace.
Aeore, the white man have everything.
Niaruna have nothing.
Their gifts are very good.
Tukanu, the whites give us because
they want our land.
We must give the gifts back.
Tukanu, we must have no contact
with the whites.
We must kill the white man.
No, Aeore.
No gifts.
We must take back the presents.
There are more whites than all
the Forest People together.
If we kill the whites
who brings gifts...
all the Niaruna will be destroyed.
Are you Kisu?
I come from Kisu.
If you come from Kisu, you must unite
the people of the Forest.
I agree, Aeore.
Kisu Mu will help the people.
In the day of the Ancestors...
there was no death.
There were no floods, no scorpions...
no famine and no pain.
Jaguar...
was a friend of man
and hunted with him.
Both were creatures of darkness,
for there was no light...
and the Sun lived on the
far side of the world.
Honey, you wet your bed.
Dad, I didn't mean to.
Oh, honey. Can you stand up?
Dad, I'm thirsty.
Niaruna Station, come in,
please. Over.
Niaruna Station, do you head me?
Over.
Niaruna Station, this is Mintipo
Station. Do you read me? Over.
This is Niaruna Station.
Over.
Leslie is on his way, but he weather
conditions are extremely bad.
God bless Billy.
God bless you all. Over.
Mintipo Station?
Andy?
Go ahead, Martin.
Tell Leslie to stay where he is.
Billy has blackwater fever.
He will not leave here.
In the name of the Lord, amen.
- Over and out.
- Martin?
What are you doing?
It's all been arranged.
Come pray with me.
Pray with me.
You're insane?
It's just malaria.
It's just a bad case of malaria.
We're leaving this den of Satan.
Get them on the radio.
Do you hear, Mr. Quarrier?
Are you out of your mind?
It's your only begotten son.
Mutu, come on. He has to rest.
No, Dad. Let him stay.
What is he saying?
Billy you have to rest.
He wants me to name my enemy.
Enemy? You have no enemy.
He says that if I die, it means that
I have an enemy who must die, too.
His only enemy is the mosquito,
Mutu.
No one must be killed.
Dad?
Am I going to die?
Am I, Dad?
Yes.
You're going to die.
May the Lord curse you,
Martin Quarrier.
No, of course not, honey.
Daddy's only fooling.
Tomorrow we'll go down he river
with Mr. Huben.
Then you'll ride on a plane
and you'll be well in no time.
- He's staying here.
- I don't believe this.
This is Billy's home.
The only home he knows.
You're a devil!
You don't know that this
is blackwater fever.
Or even if it is,
that he's dying.
Honey, even the Indians know.
How do they know? They've never
seen blackwater fever in their lives.
They may not know
blackwater fever...
but they know when someone is dying.
Hazel, listen to me.
This thing runs its course
in 24 hours.
We can't get him to a hospital
before that.
And even if we could...
it would be too late.
You just have to get a hold
of yourself...
because Billy is dying...
and I think you know
that as well as I do.
Hazel's right, Martin.
I'll take him out when the sun rises.
No, you won't.
He will die peacefully in his own
home where he belongs.
He belongs in South Dakota.
Leslie's come to help
and you're rude to him.
You're a stubborn and wilful man.
May God have mercy on your soul.
Amen.
Leslie, please.
These people love him.
This is their way.
You're not going to...
Dad.
Yes, son?
Why did God...?
You wont get mad at me?
We won't get mad at you.
We love you and God loves you.
Then why did God have to go
and make mosquitoes?
"The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures...
He leadeth me beside still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the paths of
Of righteousness for His namesake.
Yea, though I walk trough the valley
of the shadow and death...
I will fear no evil...
for Thou art with me.
Thy rod and Thy staff,
they comfort me.
As it is written: "For Thy sake
we are killed all day long.
We are accounted as sheep
for the slaughter.
Nay, we are more than conquerors.
Through him who saved."
Keep going.
Leslie, keep going.
"Verily I say onto you...
except ye be converted and
become as little children...
ye shall not enter into
the kingdom of heaven...
whosoever therefore becomes as
humble as this child...
the same is the greatest in heaven."
You say you have no converts?
Look at them praying.
Behold, the Lord has seen fit to take
our Billy Quarrier...
in order that these poor dark
souls be led into the light.
Let's raise up our voices.
Be not dismayed what e'er betide
God will take care of you
Beneath his wings of love abide
- God will take care of you
- God did not take my son.
Death took my son.
But, if he did...
if God took my son,
the He is not welcome to my son.
Do you understand?
He is not welcome to my son.
May the Lord forgive you.
I'll try to make my own peace
with the Lord, Leslie.
And if I cannot...
well, then I cannot.
Why did they bring back the gifts?
What have you left undone?
I don't know.
I've prayed and prayed and I've
racked my brains, and I don't know.
They don't really trust me.
And they sure don't like
what I teach.
What are they doing down there?
I think they are getting ready
to perform a Nipi ceremony.
The character making the noise
I think is Boronai.
He'll go into the spirit world
and seek a vision.
What did he say?
He's saying that the enemy
sent the mosquito.
When Billy's enemy is killed the Billy
will go far away and sleep in peace.
Not one soul in this infernal pack
realizes that...
God loves them.
They're as savage now
as they ever were.
Get out.
This night, the Spirits carried me
away into the mountains.
I visited the Spirits of the forest...
of the rivers, of the wild pigs.
All of them witnessed the death
of the child.
They told me who Billy's enemy is.
The enemy is this man
with the bright eyes.
- He's my son.
- Were leaving now.
Hazel, get in the boat right now.
Stay with me, Martin.
Hazel, get going.
Get in the boat.
Are you all right?
Keep going.
Get in.
We came to bring you the most
beautiful story in the world.
The white man will come back...
and kill all the Niaruna.
Martin, what are you doing?
Hazel, go with Leslie.
I'm staying.
Oh, no, you don't.
I stay here with you, Mart Quarrier.
Till death do us part.
The Lord bless His servants.
Praise the Lord!
- When do we go back?
- You're not going. It's dangerous.
I'd be ashamed to stay here.
They need our help.
What else can we do?
I keep in touch with Martin
twice a day.
The mission is empty.
The Indians are gone.
Even Kori?
If only Martin hadn't done
so poorly...
Come in.
What happened?
You were attacked?
It's nothing serious.
Maybe it takes more persuasion
for these Niaruna...
than for the Tiro and Mintipo
to bring them to God.
No, not really.
Keep our agreement,
or I'll be forced...
- Forced to what, Mr. Guzman?
- Amazonia is not the garden of Eden.
People here want progress.
We must face the reality,
now or later.
You promised to pacify
the savages, no?
You told me to convert them,
that's better for everybody, yes?
- Including the Indians.
- But to pacify them without violence...
to make them good citizens,
that takes time.
Time...
it goes fast.
You better hurry, Mr. Huben.
You made a deal with him?
What was it?
He gave us a year
to pacify the Niaruna.
- Then what?
- Then he'd do the job in his own way.
I have other missions to look after.
That's my duty.
I can't risk becoming a martyr.
What about the Quarriers?
I thought the Lord
was on our side...
but when this Indian attacked me...
I cried:
"Lord, why hast Thou forsaken me?"
You don't know what it was like.
I couldn't endure it again.
This is no time to be disloyal.
I need you.
Please.
- You know something, Leslie?
- Don't look at me like that.
You've shrunk.
Mrs. Huben, God bless you.
Please come in.
I've never been in
a Catholic church before.
You're most welcome.
You were praying for Billy Quarrier?
Why not?
Also Lewis Moon.
Children and fools, isn't it?
Comandante says that...
our mission work is the best way
to civilize the Indians...
that it's the best way
to avoid killing them.
Do you agree?
There are many ways
of killing people.
When you contacted the Indians...
did you think of what
would become of them?
If they had the misfortune
to be converted?
Did you think of that?
I understand your question...
but I have no answer.
Forgive me, Padre...
but do you truly believe?
My child...
is that a question...
or a confession?
You see.
I love the church.
And...
a man like myself... I need it.
I need it.
Shall we sing?
Oh, God...
Where are we?
Are there no seasons in this place?
Are there no seasons but rain,
and rain and rain?
Are we in hell and just don't know it?
Don't touch me.
You're only comforting yourself.
I can't stand you Christian mercy.
You're a regular little
four-eyed Jesus.
The sociologist...
student of Indian gods and
Indian sluts.
Do you write about your disgusting
wife the way you write about them?
Do something!
Please!
Do anything but for God's sake,
let me know I'm alive!
I cannot talk to you
when you are like this.
I don't know who
I'm talking to anymore.
Martin, please.
Come inside.
I want you to make love to me.
Please, Martin.
The man who killed the
white child has come back.
We need security.
You learned that for yourself.
That's not security.
It's an admission of weakness.
We tried it you way, Martin,
and it didn't work.
I'll go check the racks.
The only time I didn't hate this big,
ugly body of mine...
was when I remembered...
that somewhere inside...
it had to be clean and beautiful.
Or my beautiful Billy
couldn't have come from it.
You shouldn't talk like that.
You have your own special beauty.
I know, I know.
In the eyes of the Lord.
Are you jealous...
because you are barren before God?
Hazel, don't.
You're content that Martin is lusting
after you, I suppose.
Why do you say these things?
Are you saying you're unaware of it?
I mean, what if I told your husband?
- Told him what?
- That...
you don't honour him as you should.
I don't like you, Hazel.
Not when you're like this.
How could anybody like me?
"Patty cake, patty cake,
baker's man..."
Why does it mean?
What do you think it means?
It means: "Go away".
Maybe we should
admit defeat and leave.
Maybe you should.
I'm not leaving, Leslie.
You should know that by now.
Right. Father Silva
was stubborn, too.
Why didn't you scream for help?
I was too afraid, I guess.
You mean you were...
you were naked?
But I wasn't ashamed.
Am I a sinner, Martin?
It was beautiful.
He touched me so gently...
as if he were blind...
and he wanted me.
How do you know?
Martin, don't be such a child.
You didn't...
But I wanted to.
Is that you wanted to know? I never
wanted anything so much in my life.
How it's possible. I mean, an Indian.
That he didn't assault you?
They are not very romantic,
you know...
It was Lewis Moon.
Today we killed two white man
who were living on our river.
We took their things
and burned their hut.
We came to ask you to join us
to fight the invaders.
Let's join our friends.
Aeore, the white man opened
a hole in the earth...
and freed the bad spirit, Xarawa.
Now our people are sick like Boronai.
Our water is poisoned...
all the fish have died and the
animals are frightened away.
The more the white man come,
the more our people die.
The whites came to take our land.
We must kill them...
before they kill all of us.
They must be driven away, that's true.
But they must not be killed.
It was a mistake to kill
those men on the river.
Who are you to say this?
Wait.
Kisu Mu chose me to lead all of us.
We must become a great nation.
Niaruna, Yuri Maha and Mintipo.
All the Forest People must be united.
The whites at the mission
have done us no harm.
They have medicine to cure us.
Martin, Andy.
They're back.
We have gifts for you.
We don't want presents
from the white men.
We don't want you on our land.
We need presents.
Don't go too near.
That's the demon who attacked me.
We the moon is new again,
you must be gone.
I wish to hear these words
from Boronai.
This is what Boronai has said.
Well, well...
If it isn't Lewis Moon...
resurrected from the dead.
Look at you, painted like a devil.
This is your doing, isn't, moon?
What are you up to, Moon?
Answer me.
Martin, what are you doing?
You've destroyed
all of my hard work.
My work here cost me my son.
You know better than
to touch an Indian.
Leslie, he's not an Indian.
It's Lewis Moon.
How much medicine do you have?
My people are dying.
- They have no resistance to flu.
- The flu?
How did they?
They got it from me.
What are you talking about?
I don't want to stay here.
They have the medicine.
- I don't like this.
- Just wait.
Even the smell of the whites
makes me sick. Let's go.
Do you except us to help you do the
Devil's work with those poor savages?
You brought that medicine
for those savages.
- Now they need it.
- Well, they can have it.
- I meant...
- You meant...
you're willing to let the tribe
die in Jesus' name.
Martin, this obscene drunkard
dares speak about Jesus.
Those people are dying
and he wants to make deals.
- You go along with that?
- You're not getting any...
Leslie, please!
We can't save their souls
if they're dead.
- Give me the medicine.
- Why?
You're leading these people
into darkness and corruption.
Shit. Just hand over
the goddamned medicine!
Hand it over!
Moon! I'll give you the medicine!
Let go! Moon!
I'll get you the medicine.
You people better leave here.
- Start with the sulfonamides...
- So long.
If that Aeore had his way,
you'd be dead long ago.
Do you imagine you're
helping these people?
You're not a real Indian
and you never will be!
I'm not taking any chances.
I knew this man was a killer
the minute I saw him.
- What are you doing?
- Calling Guzman.
When did you meet Moon?
And what happened?
- Nothing.
- Then how did he catch your flu?
How could you look at him
when he was naked?
Why is a white man's nakedness sinful
to look upon when a red man's is not?
It's the lustful intent.
Go to your room.
You're giving Guzman a reason
to come in here shooting.
"God's will be done."
That's why we're here.
We're going to fight Mr. Lewis Moon.
Mãe de Deus, this is
Niaruna Station, over.
Take only one.
Just one.
Until you came, our people
never had this sickness.
I do not trust you.
You speak the white man's language.
"Ave Maria, cheia de graça,
o Senhor é convosco.
["Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee]
Bendita sois vós entre as mulheres,
bendito é o fruto...
[Blessed art thou among women,
and blessed is the fruit ...]
do nosso ventre, Jesus.
Santa Maria, mãe de Deus..."
[thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God ... "]
You're not welcome there.
"Rogai por nós, pecadores. Agora
e na hora da nossa morte, amém".
["Pray for us sinners. Now
and at the hour of our death, Amen"]
I'm not here on a social visit,
Mr. Huben.
You've stolen Uyuyu back, huh?
He simply brought me here.
But what is this Indian we have
fought over? A Protestant?
Do you believe so?
Is he a Catholic?
Is he neither?
Is he both?
Answer me, Mr. Huben.
Do you think he knows the difference?
May I?
Who knows what he might learn...
from our poor Indians...
if we were not always
teaching them?
Such an easy people,
light as the air.
Like a leaf, or a cloud.
They not seek for meaning
the way we do.
They just are.
They may be light as air,
but they killed Silva.
Alas...
Christ will never be accepted here.
A pale man from a desert country
where it never rains.
Will you join me?
I have my own provisions.
I can sleep on my canoe.
No, no. You will be
our guest, Padre.
Thank you.
Let's assume this is true.
What will Guzman do?
How do you say?
Exterminate?
That would be a defeat for this
mission. Isn't that what you want?
Not at the expense
of an entire tribe.
The Comandante wouldn't just
annihilate them?
The two man who got killed
were looking for gold.
There is gold in Niaruna land.
Oh, perhaps Guzman forgot to tell you.
For the Indians,
this gold is not a blessing.
You seem so resigned.
How can this be stopped?
You go immediately.
Tell Moon they must disappear
into the forest.
If they resist, they will be shot.
Go.
Uyuyu will take you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye, Hazel.
Everything will go much better
in the States, honey.
Thank you so much.
What did you call me?
You called me a son of a whore?
- You're not going to the Niaruna.
- We're going to the Niaruna.
I'm going.
Now!
If I'm not back by tomorrow,
you better leave.
My glasses.
I need your help.
"Desculpa".
["Sorry"]
I can't find my glasses.
I can't see too well.
Somewhere...
Anywhere...
Oh, God, they could be anywhere.
"Desculpe, não faz mal.
Precisamos ir, vamos?"
We've to go, okay?
Can you lead me?
I need you.
Where is Moon?
What are you doing here?
We gave back your presents.
The village is full of death.
Where are you?
Is that you, Moon?
Is it true that two gold hunters
got killed?
You know this is exactly
what Guzman wanted.
You have to get
these people out of here.
They're too sick to leave.
Oh, when you get back,
give Wolfie my regards.
Tell him to go home.
Tell him maybe I'll see him someday.
Her name was Pindi.
She was my wife.
She had a son.
I think he's mine.
Does he know...
that you're responsible
for his death?
If you'd stayed away from the mission,
this wouldn't have occurred.
I know that.
His spirit has left his body.
When he returns,
he will be the new chief.
How did they come to accept you?
They thought I was a messenger
from Kisu...
because I came from the sky,
Kisu's home.
What kind of god is Kisu to them?
An evil spirit bringer of floods.
Very dangerous.
That's why they fear me.
When I was teaching them about Jesus
they always said...
"Kisu, Kisu".
You mean they believe you're Jesus?
So I taught them that Jesus...
was their evil spirit.
Jesus, Kisu.
What's the difference?
It's all hocus-pocus...
isn't, Martin?
It would have been better for them
to never have known us.
Go on, get out!
Where are you, Martin?
For the last time, Martin.
Answer me!
"Vamos para o barco".
We're getting out of here.
The spirits are angry because the
white man has said that Kisu...
is the only God that Kisu
loves the Niaruna.
The white man has brought us death.
The white man is our enemy.
We will kill the enemy among us.
Aeore tells you he truth.
But this man has come
to warm us of danger.
He does not want your land.
He is not your enemy.
I'm Kisu Mu, I am sent by Kisu.
You will obey me.
But he is a white man,
he must be killed.
No. Kisu Mu tells the truth.
No, we must kill the white man.
If this man is sent by Kisu, seek to
him the way you speak with your God.
He wants me to pray?
He wants you to pray to me.
I can't do that.
I can only pray to God.
I will pray for all of us.
Lord...
I have been far from you,
now I ask you to come near.
These people have been much abused
and I have been part of it.
They are very angry.
Now I ask you to help...
You must not do this.
Do not pray to this man.
He is not a god. Pray to your own god.
You must not pray to this man.
Pray to your own gods in your way
but not to this man or to me.
I said pray to him.
I won't.
I can't.
Pray.
You stupid bastard.
Start praying to me now,
or I'm going to have to kill that man.
Understand? Pray.
Pray.
Why do you tell us to run away?
You should protect us!
Kill them. Kill the enemy.
You are not Kisu Mu.
You're a white man.
"Since my last missive
to Mission Fields...
the devil has inflicted a heavy defeat
on our Lord's forces.
Satan, who never sleeps,
sent an emissary, an outlaw...
to agitate the Niaruna...
and cause them to remain in
blackest sin and darkness.
One day he told us we had to leave
or the Indians would kill us.
We sent the girls out. Then Martin
Quarrier, not heeding my warning...
went to the Niarunas
to warn them of danger.
According to our faithful convert,
Uyuyu...
Martin was killed by the Niaruna,
just as I had feared.
The local commandant closed his eyes
when several murderers...
bombed the village...
where Martin Quarrier's body
was discovered.
No further mission work
will be permitted in this land...
covered by Satan's darkness.
I surely hope there is better news
in the next missive.
To Jesus be the glory."