You need a new flea collar.
How was work?
Boss wants the rent.
Dinner's almost ready.
Stop eating, Jaime!
Or else I'll feed your plate to my turtle.
Put your index finger here...
It's your birthday.
Next week.
Sorry, love. I get dizzy too easily.
Come dance with me.
Your dad won't mind.
He's not my dad.
Thanks, but we're
about to leave, so...
Okay then, y'all have a good night.
What's wrong with you, that boy
was fine. We're just sitting here.
You have some other boy in mind?
Of course not.
I want you to get out there.
It's almost four years
since we lost Manuel, honey.
It's time you moved on.
I don't want to talk about it.
Anyway I'd rather stay home Saturday nights
and watch "Sabado Gigante" with Jaime.
Don't bother the girl.
No, I think we know some
good candidates for her.
Candidates?
Just let me know the day
before the wedding and I'll show up.
How bitter she is. You know my sister, Juana.
How bitter she is.
Women shouldn't
grow old by themselves.
I won't let that happen to you.
I'll move out soon.
Don't be so quiet.
You always get quiet when you're upset.
Any better yet?
I'm fine.
I'll stay.
No. Go, go. You'll be late.
I'll take care of her.
Get her out of the house tomorrow
so I can make her a birthday cake.
What are you whispering about?
Lupe's saying how bad you stink.
Dad, are you okay?
Jason's sorry he couldn't be here.
He's in Tampa again for work and
there's no way he would make it in time.
Dad, what are you doing?
I would have paid for the funeral home.
This isn't right. It's disrespectful.
I didn't want to give her to strangers.
Mom deserves better.
Where's Victor?
He lives closer, he should be here by now.
I can't believe neither of
our families could come.
I'm just glad you're here.
It must have been three years
since we've all been together.
It hasn't been that long.
How's work and your new house?
Good. You know...
Your mother was proud of you.
Dad.
Hey everyone.
Juana, thank you so much.
Well, somebody's gotta
take care of you two now.
Where's my sister?
She looks peaceful.
I would have gotten that for you.
How's my dad doing?
It's hard to say.
What'd she bring?
If it's as good as it smells,
we'll all end up in the hospital.
It's the thought that counts.
I don't even think my mom liked her.
I remember when she used to wear this.
She never even wore this one.
Wasteful. I'll wear it.
I couldn't really use any of
this stuff. It's sort-of late 70's.
Would you like something to drink?
No, thanks.
I guess this would
look nice with something blue.
Did someone already go
through this? I thought she had more.
What are you doing now at BanTek?
You know what LAN networks are?
I set those up for
schools and small businesses.
Is it busy?
Yeah, things are good. It's okay.
I'm pretty hectic, too.
It's that time of year.
We should probably
get back soon, right?
Maybe we'll beat traffic.
There you are.
I remember when
she gave you that hat.
You didn't like it at first.
This was Maria's
favorite time of day.
It's beautiful,
and I never noticed.
What's up?
Are you Jaime?
Connie said I
should wait for you.
It's cool that you
can retire at your age.
My grandfather's still working.
Pull this tight. Okay, you try it.
I've changed my mind, about
what Maria was talking about.
It's time you stopped living with
me and found a new husband.
Where the hell did that come from?
I'm serious.
It's what Maria wanted.
I want you to remarry. Before it's too late.
So you're going to remarry, too?
It's late. You've got work tomorrow.
Where's Connie?
It's past seven.
I have to walk.
He's over in Shiner this week.
You'll be late.
Probably so.
- How was work?
- Fine.
Are you hungry?
Then where have you been
going every day this week?
Looking for other work.
But there's nothing.
And apartments want
the first and last month
before we move in.
We'll find a way to stay here.
I don't think so.
What about Juana?
I'll go to San Antonio.
You'll stay with Eva.
No,
we'll stick together.
Vl'll find a way.
I've never seen
this photo of Manuel.
My son always wore that same shirt.
It's been a long time.
It'll be good to see the
life Victor's built for himself.
A new house.
Are we still in San Antonio?
Let me get that.
Thank you so much, Andrea.
You two can stay
in the boys' room.
Sorry it's not much.
We'd planned on
a three bedroom, but
it's difficult
with only one income.
I didn't want to talk
about it at the funeral,
but BanTek's
had some cutbacks.
They'll try to hire
me back in the Spring.
What are you doing now?
He fixes air-conditioners.
It's not just that.
Part-time.
We can move this stuff over.
Gabe's so cute.
Cute's one way to look at it.
Who's Matthew?
Stop running and get
in here. One! Two!
Matthew's our youngest.
Including the cat.
Gabe, do you remember your granddad?
Hey, let's go out to dinner okay?
What about Tomatillo's?
I'll pay you back by Tuesday.
I meant to bring
Matthew down to you and Mom,
but...
And this job thing is just temporary.
Don't make excuses.
Listen, Victor...
Dad...
We're gonna be late Victor!
Come on. Hook this.
Hey, I just invited Luis.
You'll like him, he's your age.
He lives a few doors down.
She needs to
meet more young men.
Let us know if you like him and we'll
invite him back to the house afterward.
Just make a signal or something.
Don't start.
If you think he's cute, just
say you want more jalapenos.
Yeah.
I'm not going.
You can't be too picky, honey.
You aren't exactly a
spring chicken yourself.
The sitter's here, let's go.
Victor, go put something decent on.
Hurry hurry.
Move it Victor!
You can use a
fork for that if you want.
Have you become that crass too?
Probably.
It looks like finger
food to me, anyway.
Luis, did you know Lupe's from the
same part of Oaxaca as you?
El Coyul.
I used to go
there with my cousins.
It's beautiful.
You know Rio Seco?
I wish I could go
back to visit, in Spring.
There's so much space
not like here.
How would you rate this pork?
It's good,
it's pretty good.
I'm a butcher.
I work at Reyes'.
I used to work at Randall's,
but it's too corporate.
They don't care if you
know what you're doing,
or if you take the time to
learn what the customers want.
I can't handle that.
So I quit.
So you're sort of
a rebel butcher then.
Well...
Lupe,
you want some
more jalapenos?
No thanks.
But it tastes better
with jalapenos. Come'on.
Yeah, they're good.
Sounds like you guys
want more for yourselves.
Here, you can share these.
That's funny you guys
are from the same place.
It's really not that close.
Well, I'll have to bring you some
of the best cuts of meat sometime.
For the whole family.
I think we can all squeeze in.
I'm claustrophobic.
Can you catch the next one?
Hey, don't crush him.
Sorry.
I like your father and Lupe, but they
just hopped on a bus without thinking.
He's going to find a job.
But how long is that going to take?
And what the hell are you
doing spending $150 on dinner?
Can you spare some change, man?
Your dog come in?
Let me show you how to bet.
Come on, we'll split the winnings.
Sorry, man.
Man, I should kick your ass.
Hey asshole, I just-
Jaime? Jaime! Look at this bastard.
Salazar?
What are you doing here?
I thought you
went back to Tamaulipas!
I didn't recognize you.
You look good.
No, I went down
but came back up in '92.
Now I'm visiting my son.
Man, that's great.
My son won't spend thirty minutes with me.
He and his wife still living with you?
No, man.
I couldn't take that shit no more.
I got my own place.
You still see Camarillo?
How is he?
He's dead.
Hung himself a few years back.
He got old fast
after his wife died.
Time flies.
Yeah, time flies man. It really flies.
So who do you like in the fifth?
No, I have to get back.
But we should get together soon.
Yeah, have a few drinks.
Okay, I'll see you around.
It was good to see you.
Good evening.
I brought you a few
of the best cuts we had today.
You didn't have to do that, really.
Well, the real reason I came by was you'd
left your coin purse at the restaurant.
I found it in the parking lot.
That's not mine, Luis.
Really?
Well... would you like to take a walk,
or talk or something.
Actually, Jaime's been sick in bed all day.
I don't know if it's something he ate,
but I'm sort of taking care of him.
Hey Luis! Hello!
Jaime! Get back in bed.
What's wrong with you!
He's never going to get
better if he doesn't rest.
Oh, okay. I hope you
feel better, Mr. Esparza.
I'm feeling better already.
Okay, good night.
I'll have two asadas, please.
You want flour tortillas? Or...
Flour.
There a lot of onions?
No.
Which part of Mexico are you from?
I'm from here, man.
Look...
I'm sorry for wasting your money.
I know you won't say it,
but I can feel it.
Maybe.
But why didn't you bring
your mother her own grandson.
It's one thing
if you didn't want to visit.
But she never even knew he existed.
That's not the way we raised you
to treat family.
And if you lose one job, you can't just...
I never gave up.
It's just not that simple.
But I'll try harder.
You just need to try everything you can.
Yeah, I know.
Hey we shouldn't just sit around
the city while you're here.
We should go
up to Lake Calaveras,
just the two of us.
I'd like that.
But I've got that...
We'll figure something out.
Is dinner almost ready?
Almost.
You've been letting them
watch TV in Spanish?
Where's Gabe?
He's playing out front.
No he's not, I just drove in.
Have you seen Gabe?
He's probably destroying
something out back.
No he's not.
Did he say he was going somewhere?
He got angry
because he wanted money, but...
You're supposed to be watching them.
If you're going to stay here you
have to take some responsibility.
Hi, Maria. How's it going?
No, it's fine.
Have you seen Gabe?
No? Okay, thanks. No, it's fine. Bye.
Well, I've got to go look for him.
What's going on?
Gabe's run away.
He was here an hour ago.
Well an hour is a long time.
Let's not get worked up.
I'll take the car. Jaime, do you think you
can watch Matthew, for just a little while?
Sorry about that.
Come on.
You won't run away
when you grow up?
I can't believe I let this happen.
Andrea seemed pretty upset.
She's always like that. I'm sure he's fine.
What's up?
Hey, it's the guy you rejected.
Andrea is convinced Gabe ran away.
I'll help. It'll be faster on my bike.
Sure, but it's no big deal.
Actually, I'm not really sure how he looks.
Then Lupe can go with you.
Well, if...
He's wearing a red shirt.
Go on. This is your fault, remember.
Hold on.
He wanted money. I think he
said something about rides,
but we didn't know
what he was talking about.
Gabe's fine. He's back home.
He was here but didn't
have any money so he went back.
It was no trouble.
I guess we can go home now.
What do you miss most about El Coyul?
Watermelons. Long summers.
I remember.
I'm surprised I never saw
you, it's such a small town.
Maybe you did and we didn't know it.
You ever think about going back?
Things were difficult there, too.
You used to live with
Jaime, and Victor's mother?
Maria.
My brother hates his mother-in-law.
It wasn't like that. We were close.
I haven't seen my own mother in
six years, and I never knew my dad.
When I left Coyul, my mother held
a ceremony for me, like a kind of funeral,
because she knew we'd probably
never see each other again.
I wish I'd told Maria how
important she was to me...
When I was fifteen, I got so angry at my
Mom I poured salt on all her rose bushes.
She died later that summer.
She used to work on those bushes for
hours, on her hands and knees in the dirt.
It's late.
You don't have to cook breakfast.
I was going to make it.
Don't bother.
Are we going to work on
your math when you get home?
I asked Maria to pick up the kids today.
You don't need us to look after them?
It's easier this way.
They don't want us here.
You shouldn't have to live like this anyway.
It's time you moved out on your own.
Just try to sleep. I'll figure something out.
Sorry for the mess. I usually keep
things neat, but it was short notice.
You can have the guest
bedroom, and Lupe can stay in
what will hopefully be
the baby's room someday.
Make yourself at home.
I'll get us something to drink.
That was too much!
It was so crowded and that
house couldn't keep the bugs out.
How many people were there?
It was Jaime, Maria,
Victor, Alice, Me, and Manuel.
So... what's this I hear about
you and Victor's neighbor?
Probably from the biggest liar.
I don't know this guy,
but you should get out there.
You're not getting any younger.
You have to grab the good
ones before they're all taken.
It's nothing.
Besides, everybody
gets divorced these days.
So I can find someone on
their second time around.
That's how Alice found me.
Well she's lucky she did.
And you're lucky I did, too.
You used to complain
I was dating a white guy,
but you're not complaining now
that you need a place to stay.
No. There's no way.
You'll like it.
I don't gamble. It's just dirty.
Go!
We could've had a trifecta.
You're not reading the backgrounds!
Come'on, who do you like in the third?
I don't actually gamble.
Honestly, it's just... dirty.
It's still dirty.
I've only come here
maybe two or three times.
Hey Luis.
Hi Antonio.
Two dollars?
You seemed stuck-up the first
time we met... but I knew it was an act.
It's strange,
we wouldn't have seen each
other again if that punk hadn't run away.
We wouldn't have met if
Jaime hadn't grown too old for his job,
and if Maria were still living.
Sometimes I don't feel like I'm living.
I never take risks.
Don't you ever want
to do something different?
Do you ever think of moving out
on your own or with someone else?
Sometimes.
But Jaime needs me.
People talk like I'll become
an old spinster, but I don't care.
You'll still like me
if I'm an old maid, right?
Look at the tadpoles.
I can't lose that.
I can see it.
Hold on.
It's beautiful.
Where'd you get it?
From Manuel.
My late husband.
What do you think about El Paso?
I might move there if my
cousin gets me a better job.
You should come-
Luis, don't...
Okay.
I guess it's late.
You know how I feel about you...
I won't ask anymore.
If you want to see me again you can call me.
I don't want to go back to Alice's yet.
Hey. We were worried about you.
Sorry, I didn't think it would be a problem.
Well, it's just inappropriate, really.
Tell her, Dad. She needs to be careful.