Subtitles and Timing brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @Viki
♫ Lonely, lively, or in an ordinary city. ♫
♫ A gust of wind, a surge of rain, a familiar melody. ♫
♫ Helpless, proud, or in an insignificant corner. ♫
♫ How many details, how many scenes, how many clear memories? ♫
♫ Traveling free, no restraints, or devoting myself to missing you. ♫
♫ When I meet you again, when we reunite again, when I can see your pretty self again. ♫
♫ Eternal or ephemeral, the two sides to life. ♫
♫ I want you to hear and see it all. ♫
♫ I want to be with the pretty you, and be together prettily. ♫
♫ I want your company in all the exciting moments. ♫
♫ Brilliant or ordinary; it’s always a lingering question. ♫
♫ Together, I want to try changing myself for you. ♫
♫ I want to be with the pretty you, and be together prettily. ♫
♫ I want to get used to the occasional sadness together with you. ♫
♫ I want to fulfill my crazy wishes together with you. ♫
Pretty Li Huizhen
- Episode 36 -
Associate Editor.
How are arrangements for the poster going?
CC Allen already contacted us earlier.
They didn't give us a reason why they haven't been responding to us before.
In any case, they just rejected our interview now.
And they also said they'd never accept an interview from Immortal again.
I got it.
How is the progress with Taylor Young?
I will hold a meeting with his agent in the afternoon. I will do my best to convince him to accept our request.
Before they reply, we can't also just waste our time waiting.
Huizhen and I will prepare a backup contact list
to contact at any time.
Okay. Let's do it that way then.
I already sent you our plan.
We are very confident in this interview.
We believe we can give readers a fresh feeling.
We can discuss the details together.
We are completely sincere.
I know already. Regarding the details of the interview, we will follow it up more closely. As for the others, we will do our best.
Okay. Okay. We will base our pictorial shoot time based on your schedule.
Okay, you can contact me once you are sure of the time. Goodbye.
Huizhen, how are things with you?
Not one can be contacted. This won't do.
Hello, I am Lin Yimu. Yes, I know.
Hello?
Because the one that contacted you before wasn't me, so I'm not sure about the details.
That's right. It won't work?
Ah, okay. Okay, okay.
Goodbye, thank you.
The models took on other jobs. No one has time.
[Immortal]
Subtitles and Timing brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @Viki
Associate Editor Bai,
do you still remember what you told me the first time you went to my office?
Please give me full control.
No mater what happens, you must stand on my side.
No matter what I do, you must support me.
In the end, I watched you
anger everyone away.
We are family.
Mr. Bai,
I'm not just Immortal Magazine's Editor-In-Chief.
I am the parent of everyone here.
So tell me the truth.
Did you really request the market assessment?
No. Headquarters did it.
I refused many times, but it was useless.
Then why didn't you explain yourself?
Or do you really think that this is a good chance for everyone to find another path?
You're willing to take the blame, but I'm not.
My little flowers, even if they want to find a different job,
they cannot leave with regret and hate.
I know.
You must be thinking that you're doing this for their good.
But this isn't the way you should treat family.
If you don't have the courage to clarify this misunderstanding,
then you can only leave it to me.
Let me think about it.
Fine. Just think about it.
You have to let everyone else understand your heart, too.
I worked at Immortal for thirteen years.
Letting me see this, it makes me feel like my thirteen years were a joke!
I wasn't this disrespected even as a trainee, did you know?
Is there not a single person worth you keeping?
You're finished with work?
Why haven't you left yet?
I'm waiting for you!
Waiting for me?
Huizhen, I'm too tired today. I can't eat dinner with you.
Who said I wanted to eat dinner with you? Give me the keys.
I'm going to drive you home.
Then you can rest in the car.
-Huizhen---I know.
I know if anything happens, I can't help you.
Because of my position and my experience,
besides making some calls and doing some research,
there's really nothing I can do.
But I thought about it. I can spend time with you!
No matter when you need me,
as long as I can do it, I will do it.
Huizhen, you're so good to me.
It's enough to have you.
Aiya, let go. We're at the company! Someone's going to see!
Um... In any case, no matter what happens,
let's take them on together, okay?
Come on, let's go. Someone is going to see us!
-Morning, Huizhen.-Oh, good morning, Yimu.
I feel tired just thinking about the work to do today.
I can't find any energy at all.
-Morning.-Morning.
Morning.
Until now, there's still no progress.
Yes.
-Did you eat breakfast?-No, did you?
I ate three buns.
You can eat that well?
Husheng!
Go and borrow all the clothes that are in this plan.
You all...
Brother Lin Hao!
You're back!
Meili!
Sister Anna! Sister Yaling!
Sister Yaling!
Sister Zhu Ying!
Sister Zhu Ying, you're back! I missed you so much!
Of course, I had to come back.
I worked here for so many years.
No matter what happens in the future, I can't let go so easily.
Honestly!
Don't cry. You're an adult.
Who said I cried? I held it in!
I'm a lot stronger now!
Yes, even if you're strong I can't leave you here alone.
I thought none of you would return!
Associate Editor!
Associate Editor! Look, everyone came back!
Good morning, Associate Editor!
Morning. Meeting in 20 minutes!
To be honest, if I don't hear this voice,
I wouldn't be used to it!
Hello? I am Bai Haoyu.
Okay. I got it.
It was a call from Taylor Young's manager.
Our interview request...
they've agreed to it.
Reportedly, every misfortune that we've encountered now
will have a corresponding good fortune waiting for us in the future.
He encouraged us to not give up easily.
We must last until the end.
Cheers!
This is wonderful! We've made it through another obstacle!
That's right. Our main topic already chose to be interviewed.
This is amazing!
I suddenly feel very moved!
It's too great to be able to work at Immortal!
That's right! I saw our views go up! It's too exciting!
We've really done it! And this feeling is awesome!
No matter how awesome the feeling is, don't get addicted to it.
There's still a difference with New Look, but we can definitely be number one with the next issue.
Of course. Didn't you see?
What is that thing fluttering in the wind? It's our victory flag.
There's a lot of things that I thought were impossible,
but Associate Editor Bai still managed to do it!
I'm impressed.
Hey, talking about that, how come all of you came at the same time? Did you guys talk about this beforehand?
Mm.
It's nothing. I don't really want to say...
I was afraid that you all had some other reasons. I... I really didn't want to come back anymore.
Old Bai personally came to find me and begged me while crying.
I really... don't want to... embarrass him.
Me, too. He waited for hours in front of my house.
Me, too.
Everyone was all personally visited at your house by Associate Editor
and then he personally asked everyone to come back?
Yes. He even personally came to my house and promised
that if we still fail this time,
that he will help me get at least 3 months of separation pay as my compensation.
Really?
So I wasn't that special? I thought I was very special!
Special?! I'm sure that for this matter, you think that you're the most special!
I'm very thankful Associate Editor Bai drew us together.
Everyone, I like being with you all.
I believe that being with you all, we can again get the number one spot
and get back our champion throne!
-Do you have faith?-Yes!
For our Immortal!
One, two, three! Go!
Meili, are you coming with me?
Who wants to take my car?
- I'll take her car instead.- Okay then.
Bye-bye!
Stay safe on the road!
-Bye-bye!-Bye-bye!
Let's go.
I can go alone.
Why are you avoiding me lately?
I'm not.
And you say you you're not?
You don't pick up my calls or respond to my texts. Is that not avoiding?
I...
Xiao Xue, did I anger you?
No.
Did I do anything wrong?
Then why?
It's...
I just haven't thought it through. In any case, it's my own reasoning.
I'm going home.
-I'll take you!-There's no need, I can go alone.
No, it's too late. It's not safe for you to go alone.
I said I can go alone!
I'm sorry, Husheng.
Give me some time to think it over.
I'm going.
Xiao Xue!
Zhen'er! Come, come, let me tell you!
Earlier, I accidentally clicked on that live broadcast of Mogujie
and then I opened a broadcast account
and then a lot of people are sending me flowers and stuff!
There's presents to send, too!
And there's people asking me how I keep my skin so good!
It's interesting!
So amazing?
Wow, how amazing! Qiao'er, you can run your own channel!
What own channel? I just happened
to take a little look. I didn't think it ended up being live.
Then give it a try.
You can teach people to do makeup.
No matter if it's male or female, they'll watch your live show.
Because you are beautiful so you attract boys.
And then you also teach others to do make-up so you attract girls, too.
Then won't you become famous this way? Right?
A famous person?
Forget it... I'm not ready to be famous.
Fine, hurry and get to work; don't talk nonsense.
I prepared bread for your breakfast. It's over there.
This thing is quite interesting.
The coffee is here!
-Thank you!-Come help me!
Coming, coming!
- Hey, whose without sugar is this?- Mine. Mine.
- Oh, thank you.- No sugar.- Then give it to me.
- For your dieting.- Thank you.
Come, come, come.
-Brother Lin Hao.-Oh, thank you.
Who else doesn't have one?
You're not going to drink it?
It's okay, I already had some.
Come and take a look! Diviner really is Chinese!
I wasn't wrong, right?
That's right. Let's look at Weibo. Right now, all the trending topics at Weibo are about that.
Diviner is Chinese!
I heard that Diviner put it on Weibo,
and then... all his fans just directly left messages for him asking him about it.
"Are you Chinese?" and then Diviner answered,
"Yes. I am Chinese!"
Ah... a fire is ignited.
This... This...
♫ In the far east side there is a dragon ♫
♫ His name is called Diviner! ♫
I'm so excited.
Come, come, come!
Cheers!
Xiao Xue, you're here?
Oh.
- You're arranging make up stuff?- I'm almost done. I'll get out first.
Xiao Xue!
It's okay, I'll do it.
-Are you okay?-I'm okay.
What should I do? If it's not Husheng,
then it's Lin Hao or Lin Yimu.
Do I really have to choose one between the two of them?
No, no! What is this?
Do you need it, too?
-Here.-What are you doing? I don't want it!
Then why are you staring at me?
If you like it, then I'll give it to you. Do you like the electric one or the manual one?
-I have both. Take your pick.-I don't want it!
Let me look at your nose hairs.
What are you doing? You're awful!
Associate Editor Bai, you're working on the weekend? You've worked hard.
-You guys often work overtime. You're worked hard, too.-That's what we should do.
Stop writing, hurry and come eat!
You prepared so much for me? I can't eat all that.
You have to eat more to have the strength to work.
It's still hot right now, come and eat.
Eat with me.
Me? I'm not going to eat. I'll interrupt your work if I eat now.
That won't happen. Let's eat together.
-Let's go.-I really won't eat, I still have other things to do.
If we eat together and then everyone sees-
What are you doing?
Guess.
I wouldn't have wasted your time if I knew this, and I especially called you out for food, too.
I need time to rest, too. You can't let me die from overexhaustion.
Then give it a try!
How fragrant!
It doesn't taste good?
Is it too salty? I was in a rush so I didn't really bother to try,
I just-! I just put it out, it might be a bit salty.
Does it not match your tastes?
It's too delicious!
Li Huizhen, why is your cooking so delicious?
It's the first time I came over here. It has such nice scenery.
There's actually such a place in the city.
Yes. I didn't know in the past.
Then I'll take you for a walk later.
Okay! Take this back with you to eat.
I'll take it back first. Wait for me.
Okay!
When I was waiting for you over there,
looking at the scenery in front of me,
and looking at the people around me, I suddenly noticed
that there is some scenery that will only become meaningful if you look at it with the right person.
Then did you find the right person for you yet?
What do you think?
You should say some things. It's so awkward.
I'm shy.
Wow, it's so beautiful looking out from here!
I didn't see this from downstairs.
So the scenery is even more beautiful up here!
It turns out there's so much scenery I haven't seen before.
Do you think it's amazing?
Sometimes, there's some scenery
that we have to personally see. Even though
it's different looking through pictures and movies,
but it's so different when you look at it yourself!
Right?
Wow, the wind is too big!
My god! My hair is a mess!
It looks awful, right?
It looks wonderful.
As long as it doesn't rain it's good.
-My hair is blown all--Huizhen.
Yes?
Marry me.
Let's get married. I'll let you see all the scenery you want to see.
The meaning of this city to me is your existence.
I don't want to separate from you again.
You don't need to respond to me now.
I'll wait. If I can successfully publish the 20th anniversary issue,
when that happens,
as long as you are willing, we'll be together forever. We won't be separated for even a moment.
I will definitely succeed.
When that happens, then give me your answer.
We've been separated for 12 years.
It's been 12 years.
I missed you every day.
Now, I have finally found you.
I won't let you leave me again.
Every time I see you with your family, I always think,
if I can become part of your group, that would be wonderful.
I'm so happy when I'm with you all.
Huizhen,
let's never separate.
Then you must work hard. You must succeed.
Because I want to smoothly marry the one I like.
I want to be with him forever, too.
I've never been so certain of something before.
But to you, I'm sure.
I want to be with you. Let's never be separated again.
Are you willing?
Of course, little fatty Yu! Little fatty Yu!
Your face isn't fat anymore, look!
Perhaps the happiness I feel now,
will attract some future unhappiness.
[Taylor Young's manager]
September 11th, 4 p.m.
Okay, I know that place. Then, see you then.
Okay! Yimu?
Is your magazine company still okay?
It's pretty good. What about it?
I remember that you previously mentioned that you guys are interviewing Taylor Young.
Yes. So?
You didn't hear the rumors?
Rumors?
Hello, I am Taylor Young's manager.
The original plan to accept Immortal's interview request
must be dismissed due to some reasons. I'm sorry.
Hello, I just saw your news.
What happened?
The fight between Taylor Young and that male singer is about to enter the legal stage.
You didn't know about it?
Under these sensitive circumstances, no interviews will be accepted.
How is it? Did you check with them? What did they say?
They've already rejected us.
What?
The interview is gone, too.
But... why did it have to happen now?
There's no hope.
We have to say goodbye to the champion position.
Which means that we can't really interview her?
But we intended to do the interview in these few days!
What are we going to do at the spur of the moment?
Our main star for December, the details of the interview,
what can we use to replace it?
If we can't become #1 this time, are we going to be shut down?
After using so much effort and time, I thought we would have a big interview.
But in the end, we couldn't even find a person.
It's useless to moan about it now.
If Taylor Young really won't do, then we have to hurry and pick a backup.
Hey, is Lucy Liu, the person who's super famous now in Hollywood, alright?
I contacted them before, but because
she's overseas right now, she cannot work with our timeline.
How about Zhao Dian? The youngest designer in New York Fashion Week.
I thought about him long ago. But he's not very famous.
But no matter who it is, we can't just invite them because we want to now.
We found it so hard to choose Taylor Young before.
If we choose another person now, who would agree to it?
Really great. We can't invite Taylor Young. New Look's Laimu Sisters are hopeless now.
Right now...we have already become cannon fodder (nothing).
If we want to beat the deadline for printing, the latest we must finish all the photoshoots
is by next week.
But we don't even have a finished interview right now! What do we do?
If we can't find someone else,
we still cannot
publish a 20th anniversary issue without content.
We're done for. This is our fate. We're all going to lose our jobs.
[Memory]
If it was Diviner?
He's a world famous author.
He also just admitted on Weibo that he is Chinese.
If we can get his exclusive interview, the magazine's sales will definitely rise.
Wait. Associate Editor, you're saying "if," but the process is a bit difficult.
Diviner hides himself so well.
Even if we can find him, would he accept our interview?
What if it is just a one-page interview?
A special person like Diviner,
even if it is just a one page interview without any pictures on it,
that is enough to rise above other magazines' front page titles.
If he really agrees to it, getting the number one spot really won't be a problem!
But... he won't possibly agree to it.
No matter what, I'll investigate through the magazine first.
At the same time, prepare a possible backup list.
How about this? Everyone give me their backup lists.
I'll give it to you after I go through them.
There's little time, you understand.
Hurry!
Diviner?
Oh my gosh! I'm his #1 fan!
Associate Editor Bai has a great eye.
If Diviner successfully accepts our interview,
then that would be so wonderful!
It's too exciting!
Actually, we only just found out that he is Chinese.
How does your company usually contact him?
We contact him through his agent.
Every time, the agent gives us the manuscript. We're just in charge
of translating and then publishing it. We're not sure about the rest.
Then, can you give me his email?
This...
We just want to request an interview from him.
Then I'll tell him for you.
Diviner really gives much importance on his private life.
If I told you the email, I'm afraid it'll affect our partnership.
Okay. Then I'll have to trouble you.
As for if he'll respond or not, I'm not sure.
I got it. Thank you.
Help me check if the Editing Department's package was received.
Okay.
-I'm sorry, there's no such package.-Huizhen?
What did the publishing company say?
The chance of success is low. We can only wait now.
What are you looking at?
Didn't you say you'll have strength if you look at me? I'll give you 100 seconds to look today.
Look! One, two, three, four...
Don't worry, everything will be resolved.
The 20th anniversary issue will definitely be successfully published.
Of course!
You didn't even look who wrote most of the articles in it. Those were my first works.
Continue looking! One, two...
Wait! Are we going to be late for work?
-Hurry!-Let's go.
Stop for a moment.
I'm going to announce an important HR appointment.
The company sent us a new manager.
They say it's our crown prince who just came back from studying abroad.
He's in charge of publishing and editing. He is also our future boss.
Why? Crown prince? That's too sudden.
That's right...
- So there's even such a thing?- Does he even understand us?
He comes in through connections at this time? And it's a young brat, too?
That'll create trouble!
But if we think about it, that might not happen.
The CEO's son, the crown prince.
That also means he's our Editor-In-Chief's nephew.
Then perhaps, we can use that connection
to help our Editing Department.
That won't do. He's the newly arrived crown prince...
We should make sales rise ourselves.
I... I feel that being a web star really makes you really popular. How about us creating two web stars?
Lin Hao!
I think that you have the looks to be a web star.
How weird is he? How unique is he?
Not having any lower limits at all. We are an international magazine, okay?!
I was joking!
If you can really make me a web star is not bad, too. I think that I'm okay for it.
- There's no such kind yet.- Go back to work already.
- What if I got famous, then we...- Let's go back to work.
They have no taste!
Diviner still hasn't responded to me.
It seems like he hasn't even looked at his email,
so you should give up.
He cares a lot about his secrecy.
There's nothing we can do.
Okay, thank you.
If there's any news, please tell me.
Yes, yes, yes, I'm sorry.
Wait one more day for us, okay?
I'll tell you once there's news.
Hello? Okay, I'm sorry.
Please wait a second.
-Bye-bye.-Hello? Ah, hello.
Teacher Li, yes, I'll tell you once there's news!
-Representative?-I'm very sorry.
- Sister Zhu Ying- Okay, we will inform you right away.
The Art Design Department is calling. What do we do?
Drag it out! Think of a way to drag things out!
Sister Zhu Ying, the ads...
They also called me, too. Tell them to wait.
-There's nothing we can do right now, just tell them to wait!-Okay, okay.
Sister Zhu Ying, I also can't be sure about the matter I'm handling. They say that they can't do anything.
Yimu, you know the situation, right?
No one panic right now. Let's just wait, okay?
Drag it out.
While we still haven't any confirmation, don't put it yet. It still can't be printed yet.
Everyone has worked hard.
Let's stop here today. Go back and rest.
But Associate Editor, everyone is waiting for the final check.
The Ad Department and Art Design Department are already rushing us.
Leave that to me.
I will talk to them.
Everyone go back first to rest today. Tomorrow morning, we'll be having a general assembly.
It's been so many years.
This is the first time I got off work in the middle of the day.
What is Associate Editor thinking?
What do you mean?
Instead of suffering here, why not go back and relax?
That's definitely what he thinks.
But... what if the magazine shuts down, what will Associate Editor do?
Does he have a backup?
This industry is so small. If he leaves in failure,
no matter where he goes, he won't get good treatment.
If it's like this, he should still go back. If this all ends,
there's no need for him to stay in China.
Dad, why have you come?
I came to see you. Let's have dinner.
There's no need. I bought food.
How can you eat this?
Look at how skinny you are. Let's go out to eat.
Dad, there's no need. I can just eat this.
How about this? If you don't want to go out, I'll cook.
I'll go buy groceries. Wait for me!
Dad! There's really no need.
Listen to me. The market is just nearby, I saw it already.
I'll come back soon. Wait for me.
I heard from your mom that you refused to go to France with her?
And you resigned from the hotel?
Yes. I want to reconsider my life's direction before I turn 30.
Isn't it quite nice to work at the hotel? You became the Best Employee, right?
How did you know about that?
It was your mom.
Luo Meili. Doesn't she use the spa at your hotel?
She saw the poster.
She was so happy and kept showing me the picture.
She also bragged to her friends.
Is that so? She has a lot of free time.
She still has time to be concerned about me.
Actually, she's always cared a lot about you.
She just doesn't know how to communicate with children.
You've never liked her either.
So, she doesn't know what to do even more.
If she's nicer to you, she's afraid you'll say she's doing it on purpose.
If she keeps her distance, she's afraid you'll say she doesn't care.
It's not very easy.
Both of you take a step back, okay?
Why do I-?
I'm begging you as a father.
Okay, I got it.
She's calling just as we talk about her!
Hello? I arrived.
Don't go. Stay with me for a while.
Yes, yes, I'm with Qiao Qiao. I haven't seen her in a long time.
Okay, okay, I'll tell her.
Okay, have fun. Stay safe.
She went on vacation to America. She told me to ask after you.
She said to tell her if you need anything. She'll bring it for you.
She really hopes that you can accept her.
Do you need help finding a job? Do you have enough money?
Dad, I want to depend on myself this time.
I don't want to depend on family too much.
That's good, too. Just don't make yourself suffer too much.
Even for a normal person, relying on one's family for food and shelter is also no big deal.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dad. I know you're good to me.
Don't force yourself. Tell me if you need anything, okay?
That's right. Thank Huizhen for me.
I have to trouble her to take care of you while you're unemployed.
Don't worry, I will.
Okay then. I'll finish cooking it for you right away.
Dad, if you have time, let's eat dinner together. The three of us.
Okay! I'll arrange the time.
[Fatty Yu! Come out and play!]
[I'm busy working.]
[Hehe, you're afraid you'll lose to me, right?]
You're challenging me?
Subtitles and Timing brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @Viki
♫ I want to wander around in your heart. ♫
♫ It’s better than secretly thinking alone. ♫
♫ I want to accompany somebody and have crazy fantasies. ♫
♫ It’s better than my empty dreams. ♫
♫ I want to brave the wind together with you. ♫
♫ It’s better than quietly looking out a window. ♫
♫ I want to lend my shoulders to somebody. ♫
♫ That way, I won’t waste this beautiful scenery. ♫
♫ In the city, who is bravely wandering around? ♫
♫ The light that shines onto your face is dazzling. ♫
♫ In your palms, there is courage and hope ♫
♫ for the persistence hiding in your heart, Cinderella. ♫
♫ In your heart, loneliness is crying out. ♫
♫ The panic is very obvious. If you’re not pretty, so what? ♫
♫ In your dreams, love is only afraid of pain. ♫
♫ Facing the lonely corridor, you are flustered. ♫
♫ In the city, who is bravely wandering around? ♫
♫ The light that shines onto your face is dazzling. ♫
♫ In your palms, there is courage and hope ♫
♫ for the persistence hiding in your heart, Cinderella. ♫