In association with
With the support of
Mom!
C'mon mom, I've been calling you for
such a long time and you didn't come.
I've been calling you a thousand times.
Why didn't you come?
Yes I did. OK, leave me alone!
Please, darling, don't be angry.
Yes, I did call you.
She fell asleep.
Did I show you
what he gave me?
What?
I didn't even try it on.
The label's still attached.
B plus, 740 Euro.
Underneath you can
see the real price.
1270.
Silk.
When the hunter comes and takes
grannie out of the wolf...
she should be naked. ?
Who?
Grannie.
When the hunter comes...
and takes the grandmother out of
the wolf, she should be naked.
I don't understand.
The wolf eats granny.
After that, he puts
her clothes on.
When the hunter comes and
takes her out of the wolf...
she should be naked.
That's what they told
them in school?
No, darling, Olguta noticed this.
She went to the
teacher and told her.
And what did the teacher say?
That she isn't right.
That she's dressed, because the wolf
took some clothes out of the closet.
She's right.
I have such a bad feeling
about this trip to Budapest.
I don't know what to say.
What's the teacher like?
About my age.
She has an older sister, she's
a secretary for government.
But she is not so nice.
She's an... ordinary woman.
Popa Claudia.
- Is the registration in the car?
- Yes, in the glove compartment.
I should give you
an apple, too.
Let me give you those...
Here are the paint rollers and
there's also some paint left over.
Put them into a wash-bowl and
leave them there for an hour or two.
- Where to?
- The bathroom.
The key...
Here it is.
Where did you leave it? ?
It's on the right side.
It's not on my parking place,
some guy parked his car there.
Where on the right side?
When you exit the building,
there's the 24/7 shop.
It's actually the other way,
about the same distance...
It's better if I come with you.
Wait...
Wait a moment...
You'll get into your bed, right?
I'll be back in a couple of minutes.
And why do you go barefoot?
Don't you have shoes?
Do you want your bum to look like
a warzone after so many flu shots?
You'll get into bed, right?!
Stay! Stay there!
I've told you to
leave it alone.
How many times did I tell you?!
Do you really want to see me upset?
You really like animals...
At least we understand
each other...
Did you bring
me that money?
Of course I brought it.
I told you I'll give it today.
So give it to me.
Believe me, I couldn't
get it any sooner.
I borrowed it from my sister.
If you don't believe me, I'll
give you her number to check.
I'll give you her
number to check.
If you don't believe me...
- Call Nusa, my sister...
- Hold on a second.
Why do you talk
to me like this?
- Why are you talking like this to me?
- Like this how?
Like this. You needed
money, I gave it to you.
You told me you'd give it back
on the 9th... today is the 2nd.
Right? That's three weeks later.
Why do you put
me in this spot?
Why do I have to ask
for something of mine?
- OK, you're right. - Do you think it's
easy for me to ask for this money?
You're right, OK.
Thank you again.
Of course I'm right.
Look what he's doing to me...
- What is he doing ?
- Look what you're doing to me!
This one's broken.
So what? Put some sticky
tape on, and you can use it.
They'll accept it.
Can I have another?
But what's wrong
with this one?
I don't have another
50 note. Take These.
Believe me, it's good for...
...and lowers the
risk of a stroke.
Wait, wait...
- Do they fit the dimensions?
- They fit exactly.
Are you sure?
Positive.
How much?
- What do I owe you?
- Nothing.
Look at me, I'm at least
15 years your senior.
You asked me to help you
and so I did. That's all.
So, I owe you?
That's better.
Where's the one I gave you?
It's here.
Here it is.
No, it's not.
- Do you mind if I check it?
- Please do.
A caliper?
Over there.
Next to the lathe.
They cooked up quite
something about you.
The scheme was
designed on top level.
Toma, Carjan, these folks.
Not Madescu, he's
too much of a sucker.
Just so you know...
I used two old firing pins
from a Browning...
which I adapted for yours...
What if it blows in my face?
No way, it's a perfect job.
By the exact specifications.
The Browning and Beretta firing pins
are made from the same alloy.
I'll reward somehow the guy
I took the firing pins from.
Labor if free of charge.
I got it.
Is 200 OK?
100 is enough.
Normally it costs 15, but
I'm satisfied with this much.
Careful how you place them.
Did I tell you you're not allowed
in the bathroom?
with your toys in the bathroom?
You'll get a good thrashing from
your father when he gets home.
- Don't tell him.
- No?!
Don't tell him?!
Look at this mess!
Leave it, leave it...
I have to mop up first.
It'll drain here, near
the threshold.
Just take a look, you beast,
what you've done here!
Take the toys to your room!
Did you hear what I said?
Take your toys and
off to your room!
Now!
What are you doing? Paddle in the water?
Go away, your socks will get wet.
I'm sorry, it's just
now I noticed it.
A broken pipe would've
been worse.
Broken pipe? And is this
not serious?
Isn't it serious if a child
destroys all our work?!
I'm sorry, I don't know what to say,
I'll talk to my husband and...
Is your place this wet also?
So so.
Anyway, I'm painting the rooms...
I'm sorry, I'll talk
and we'll settle it.
Sorry, I have to clean up.
Good day.
I'll cut off your hands!
You hear me?
One day I'll cut off
your hands.
Like your father weren't enough.
He comes home, wants to eat...
set the table, clear the table.
Look what you've done!
I just cleaned this morning.
Go and change your socks...
- Didn't you say you're coming late?
- Yes I did.
Come on in, Doru.
How are you?
How's the pumping going?
Oh, you didn't even start...
Pusa...
Painting is long off... he's
only now cleaning the walls.
We went to the cemetery.
- And you didn't take the nails out...
- Oh, what a mess.
If I knew you were off, I would've
asked you to come.
From times of yore...
Where are you? You'll have to go to
the home improvement store
and buy a good spatula.
This one's useless.
There are these ones called
Viking, with an elastic blade.
If you want a good finish...
Come here for a moment.
Come here.
Beautiful.
This color really suits you.
And it matches your jeans.
Come on.
- Say 'May his soul rest in heaven'.
- May his soul rest in heaven.
I say you buy everything you need
from the home improvement store...
If you want a good finish.
Oh, you didn't even
take the furniture out.
Or the books.
And I thought you'd already
painted at least a room.
When you take out the furniture
and start working...
you have to strip the whole
wall and start over.
It's really badly done...
Let's go.
The plate and cup are
Chinese porcelain.
Be careful with them.
You could've washed these dishes...
Look for a bag. If he has one...
Help me, please.
Put these inside here.
Anything else?
Yes. This too.
Turn off the light.
We're leaving. Bye!
We actually came by thinking you're
not here and wanted to fool around.
Good bye.
- What's wrong? Do you have a fever?
- No, I don't.
Please, just leave me.
Check your temperature
and take a Paracetamol.
OK, good bye.
Good bye.
No, the other way round.
Like this.
Would you like to see the catalogue,
maybe you like something else.
We can order something for you,
you'd have it in 30 days tops.
No.
Excuse me.
Yes...
Have you decided?
No.
- Do you have covers?
- I'll be with you in a moment.
We also have second-hand weapons.
Like what?
Russian, Czech.
You mean the price?
2100, 2300...
2200.
CZ, the Czech one, is 1700.
And it's a good weapon,
nobody complained.
Fuck you, cocksucker...
Mircea!
Are you stupid, cocksucker?
We can hear your nice
language from here.
Should I show you a CZ?
Just tell me what you'd like.
I need a 12mm.
They're both 12.
- Could you please pack this up?
- Go to my colleague.
- Could you please pack this up for me?
- One moment.
Um, yes, potatoes...
Give me a piece
of chicken, too.
And some mushrooms.
One moment.
And, please, a green salad, too.
Good evening.
Hi.
Weren't you supposed
to call first?
Why won't it come out?
Take it easy, OK?
You might break the edges.
Hey, are you stupid?
Look what you've done!
- You can fix them.
- My ass! You can't mount them like this.
- They got stuck.
- OK, but you broke the tap, can't you see?!
There's one more screw.
- Take it easy!
- Excuse me...
- Are you taking the books now?
- No.
I'll come back next
week for the books.
Where am I gonna put them?
Take those too.
Easy, easy, easy!
Put that away, bend down...
Slowly... not by yourself,
wait for him!
OK, ready.
We'll take that one last.
Take it last... Grab it now,
it won't kill you!
- You take this one and...
- Come on!
Don't take anything
from this room. OK?
- Nothing goes from this room.
- OK.
Nothing goes from this room.
Well, there are those
books over there...
- OK?
- OK.
And, from this room...
again, nothing.
Those boxes are mine.
OK.
What are you doing with those?
Taking them to the car.
No, you're taking them back to
where you got them. Come on.
No, you're not taking these.
So you got to keep those?
Yes, I got to keep those.
I thought thinks weren't settled,
that's why I asked.
- Come here a bit.
- OK.
Here, in the living room...
from the middle to the window,
everything stays.
- OK?
- OK.
So, from the middle
to the window...
you're not taking anything:
CD's, DVD's...
vinyls, books...
I understand.
I heard you we're
wallpapering.
You heard wrong.
I'm putting Raufaser on.
That estuco veneciano stuff?
No, it's a...
paper wallpaper that
you paint over.
That stuff's bad,
from what I know.
But, oh well...
What can I say? Good luck
with your work.
If I said something, that would
mean digging my own grave.
Yea?
Yea, it'd give you the chance
to say I'm always butting in.
Is that what I said?
No, you said worse.
You talked about manipulation.
- Yea?
- Yes.
Come on, faster, boys!
Take them before
we lose all night.
Take these, too.
Yea...
Be careful going
down the stairs.
Good evening.
Good evening. Excuse me,
is the owner home?
Someone's looking for you.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, neighbour.
- What do you say?
- Good evening.
Sir, we apologize. I know that doesn't
mean much in cases like these...
and that's why we'd like to
see the exact damages.
So there aren't any misunderstandings.
Especially for my son, the one at fault.
May I please inspect
the bathroom?
- OK.
- Can I take this?
Yes.
Yea...
You can see the spot clearly.
Come here!
You see what you did?
You like it?
You see?
You see, son, what
hassle you give me?!
My wife told me you thought
there was a busted pipe.
I don't think that's the case.
Move over so these
people can pass.
Do you think there's a busted pipe?
I dunno... you're looking at me like...
That's what I thought at first,
but now it's all clear.
So it's clearly not
a busted pipe.
Right.
Anyway, we're still
at fault. It's not like...
Say you're sorry.
Please excuse me.
- Because...
- Because I'll never do it again.
OK.
You know how much this is
gonna cost us? Do you?!
5 million.
Am I right neighbour?
- About 5 mil.
- Good evening.
- Hello. - What are you
doing here? Go upstairs.
- I told you to leave me alone.
- Don't yell at me!
Please excuse me.
- How is it?
- Go and see for yourself.
There's a stain, no doubt.
- The damage is done.
- It's not that bad.
You know what this means?
5 million means no
money for camp...
and no toys from
Santa this year.
- Of course so...
- Shut your mouth already!
Take it easy!
- Say good evening.
- Good evening.
Come.
And go do your homework.
We've got school tomorrow.
- Go!
- Good evening.
Sorry, that's how it is.
Now, between the two of us,
I hope this 5 mil thing is a joke.
It can't be that much.
Can I look in the kitchen?
Yea. It didn't reach
the kitchen.
So there's no spot
up here, right?
There's clearly no spot.
It's just the bathroom.
Clearly. Just the bathroom.
In my view, it can't be
more than 500 thousand.
- Are you thinking about damages?
- Obviously.
I don't think it's necessary.
I'm painting...
Yes, I see.
That's that. Anyway, I...
Go upstairs, woman!
I'll be there in a minute.
I'll be there shortly.
Come on!
Please believe me...
Look at me: I work
12 hours a day...
Look at my hands.
Do I like coming home, hearing
the kid's been up to no good?
What can I do, kill him?
He's my son...
Once again, sorry.
Anyway, think about it, keep us
posted, and we'll pay for it.
What can you do?
Good evening.
Actually, good luck
with your work.
Good evening.
Excuse me.
Last one, right?
Last one.
Come.
Hey...
We're leaving.
We took those books, too.
Would've asked the boys to sweep up,
but we'd only be raising dust.
Cheers! Good evening.
"Mitica Dragomir
angered football fans."
"According to this law, we can't express
ourselves on the football stadium."
"We can't dispute
this to anyone."
"We can't bring in any banner,
not even the ones that..."
"support the team."
"Among the officials protected by this
law are it's creator, Mitica Dragomir"
"and the Football Federation
president, Mircea Sandu."
"There are some excessively..."
"restrictive measures,
and they constitute..."
"a means of censuring freedom of speech."
"Nobody was against this law."
"There are a few items that would
upset anyone, not just us, the fans."
"The fans are gathering
signatures and are"
"threatening to go to
The Constitutional Court"
"if it will pass by Parliament
in it's current form."
"But even the demonstration
held today"
"brought arguments for
the disputed items."
Who gives you the
right to question
my rights regarding
my own home?
They're impertinent.
No matter.
We're all more or
less impertinent.
Of course I'm right, only...
- Hello.
Is Gina in?
Gina!
I'll wait here.
What do you mean?
Come inside.
Come on.
From the start.
Second part then. Gina!
Hey, Olga!
Why are all your clothes there?
Can you tell me that?
- I'm choosing them.
- So do it.
This is not the piano hour.
Please come here afterwards.
Here you go.
Take these. And don't
pack too many again.
You're not gonna wear them, and
daddy will buy you some more there.
How many days?
3. How many times a
day do you change?
- 2 times.
- 3 times 2 is...
- 6.
- So you need 6...
- 6 blouses and 3 pants.
6 t-shirts, 6 long-sleeved
blouses, 3 pants, right?
And underwear and
socks. Let's go.
Let's go out a bit.
Gina, hold on a bit.
Tell me something.
Just a second.
Yes.
What?
That money...
- 200 Euros.
- Right.
You owe me 100 more.
When, now?
I don't have any money,
didn't I tell you?
Can I wear these
on the train?
Don't you know how
dirty it is on the train?!
Wear this gray training suit.
Go and pack it now.
Well, then?
We'll see. Give me a minute.
I saw that you were calling,
but I couldn't answer.
I couldn't.
What did she say?
- Who? Lulu?
- Yea.
She didn't say anything.
We did have a more detailed
conversation, but...
I'll tell you after...
Anyway, they're leaving in half an hour.
The train is at quarter past 11.
I thought we'd see
each other after.
You could come at about 12,
give me time to return.
OK?
I don't know.
Don't get upset.
Come on, fatty.
Let me get you those.
Hold on.
This for now. Tomorrow
I'll get you a box.
Someone's taking care of it.
- What?
- How long are you gonna be?
- Excuse me?
- How long are you going to...
They're pink, not red.
- What's this about pink boots now?
- I wanna know where they are.
How should I know?
Go back in and look.
You really need me for
every little thing?
You're getting so worked up...
Please excuse me.
Is that the way we talk?
Can I have 2 minutes?!
Look in the bathroom. Don't you
remember you came back all muddy?
I should remember
everything for you.
Yea...
I can't stay. I'll call when
I'm back from the station.
I'll call you, OK?
I was just telling Stoian
it must be you.
Yea?
He got a scare when
the doorbell rang.
I'm with Madam Truica.
You see them?
The shirts...
Washed, pressed. Don't
leave without them.
I made some mashed beans.
You catch that? The smell...
You'd say it was
New Year's Eve.
I went to The Financial Precint
this morning.
My God, what a crowd...
Only about 200 people.
All pensioners.
Everybody piling up...
Right now, it's good. Submit it before
the 15th, get a 5% discount.
That's why they're piling up.
But it doesn't add up
for small figures.
They're piling up for 5%.
What money turns you into...
I didn't submit it.
Only took the forms.
I have to go there again
in order to submit them.
If the crowd's the same...
Pusa.
Yes.
I'm sorry, do you have
something against me?
Listen, Viorel, even though
I never knew your father...
I hold a special
admiration for him.
What did I do? Was I wrong for
helping you out with the bags?
I never touched something
that didn't belong to me.
I borrowed, bought or received
presents, but never appropriated
things that weren't mine,
like you say.
- Mr. Stoian.
- Never...
Look at this house...
and all the things in it, and please
try to remember the following:
If there's any other owner
for these belongings...
that owner is me.
And don't think that Pusa can't see
you trying to emulate other people.
You'd better review
your plans.
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
For starters, stop wearing
dad's raincoat.
Pusa gave it to me.
Mr. Stoian...
Maybe you really don't touch
other people's things...
and maybe you're courting
Pusa because you like her...
but please leave me alone.
I don't like you, and you
should've gotten that already.
It's chemical and epidermal.
And, frankly, I'm bothered
by your sense of humor.
So, please, stay
away from me.
Don't let me catch you in my
room when I'm not home.
Understood?
Pusa.
- Yes.
- I'm leaving.
Wait, wait!
I left my suitcases
in the room.
- What suitcases?
- What suitcases... Suitcases.
- What am I gonna do with them?
- Dunno, take 'em to storage.
Right, the big one and
the plastic one.
Let me show you
something.
Something I made.
Listen, I want this door
to remain closed.
Closed, yes.
This one's violet.
This one's orange.
They're complementary.
What do you think?
They're woolen.
Feel them.
Here.
What are they?
Little hats.
Let me get you a bag
or something.
What's with you?
What happened?
Hello?!
I don't know what to think
of this man anymore.
He's like a girl.
Come on,
put them in.
You should've brought
a smaller one.
- That's what I have.
- They'll wrinkle.
They won't wrinkle.
You should've
turned them over.
- Here.
- Hold on.
Let me hold it.
- Take them out when you get home.
- Don't you have a smaller one?
No.
It's perfectly fine.
Kisses.
Good night.
Kiss you.
Train 1798 from Piatra Olt
is arriving at Terminal 3.
Train 663 for Iasi, with stops in Ploiesti
and Buzau is leaving from Terminal 5.
Brasov, minus 2 degrees.
Minus 11 in The Capital.
Stay tuned to
Radio Info Pro...
Shut up!
- Well, well.
- Hello.
Mornin'.
What a surprise! So that's
why this mutt was barking.
Bitch, if you don't quit
yelling, I'll eat you alive!
I'll show you!
So what's with you
at this early hour?
Can't you sleep?
Yes, I can.
The girls have gone.
Don't say you're
looking for me.
I am.
Come inside.
But...
You're tired.
Why won't you sleep?
Wipe your feet.
Can you tell me what
use I have for...
that cupboard?
Or this one?
Wait till you see the garage:
a regular flea market.
This is what happens
when things go bad.
Let me get you a coffee.
Some time today?
Sugar, one teaspoon or two?
Two.
Besides the fact that you
need sleep, you look good.
Yes, here they are.
3350.
OK? For 3 months...
March, April, May.
Won't you count them?
I will. Now sit down
and drink your coffee.
And, come on, man,
take your coat off!
For God's sake!
You'll be cold
when you go out.
What? Go and sit down.
That's it.
It's cold.
You want me to
heat it up?
No.
Thank God, the
girls are alright.
And they're not
missing you.
How is Pusa?
How is Pusa?!
Pusa is fine. Why don't
you give her a call?
Why would I?
To ask how she's
doing, for example.
I'll call her.
I'm making moussaka.
Dan went to
drive the girls.
You know what I feel most
sorry for in all of this?
You, dividing up
every last inch...
what I did for you, and what you
did years ago, in kindergarten.
This isn't right.
This is how you get to crossing
the street when seeing someone.
Right?
I don't know.
You tell me.
And who is the person?
Guess.
What's that on your lip?
Herpes.
Put some toothpaste on.
You caught me busy.
"And the birdie, in her flight"
"Flew all the way to Bihor"
"And flew all the way to my house"
"And I see my mother and father"
"And I see my brother sometimes"
"And I see my neighbors"
"Because I miss them so much"
"All my life, I liked having
love close by"
"Loneliness is not good"
"Whoever doesn't live life as a couple,
Is always missing out"
"There's no one there for him"
Hey, Lenuta, I see we have guests!
Where are you?
You're starting out a bit early...
"Happiness is like a cure"
"Listen to my words"
"A sad life is never helpful"
"What use is being born
into the world then?!"
"I throw money around
without any care"
"Because I know what I have to lose"
"If I don't live my life now"
"I won't ever live it"
Is Andreea in?
I'm looking for miss
Bratila Andreea. Is she in?
- Who are you looking for?
- Miss Bratila Andreea.
- Is she in?
- Who are you?
- Come again?
- I asked who are you.
- Who are you?, for that matter.
- What do you mean?
What kind of question is that?
Why don't you simply
go and get her?
Come back at 10 o'clock and
speak to our boss then.
Oh, really?! Who are you?
I haven't seen you before.
Why are you covering for her?
Can you tell me that? Why?
If you are smart,
smart enough and
have nothing to hide,
why won't you let me in?
Come back in half an hour
and talk to our boss.
- Why won't you let me in?
- We have work to do. Please come back later.
- You have something to hide?
- We have a store to fix.
I won't bother you.
- Please don't come in!
- I'll just sit here quietly and wait for Andreea.
What are you looking at?
What's wrong with my jeans?
Nothing.
- So, they're fine.
- Yes.
- You like them?
Let's see what you've got here.
Please don't mess it up.
I'm not.
Valentino, Valentino...
Go call Emilia.
And, besides Valentino...
Could you come for
a moment, please?
Tell me, have you ever
thought about
why women started
wearing pants?
Have you?
Hello, how have you been?
Hello. Well, I was just walking
down Calea Victoriei,
and I thought I'd stop by
and have a chat with Andreea,
but I'm out of luck.
Sorry, Andreea doesn't
work here anymore.
- Since about a month ago.
- How so?
Yes. As far as I know
she was trying to get an inspector's
job at the Ministry of Finance.
Are you making fun of me?
No.
What's this nonsense about
ministries and financial inspectors?
It's true.
What? What's true?
It's true: she hasn't worked here
since the end of January.
So I guess you suddenly remembered?
Which January?
Yes.
So, since two months ago?
Can't you see you're trapping
yourselves in your own lies?
How can you call me a liar?
How can I?! Allow me...
Please.
Go in and look,
if you don't believe us.
This is too much!
Miss Cati is in there.
Do you need to
use the bathroom?
Does he need to
He doesn't need to
use the bathroom.
And, if things are the way
you claim, why did she
say that you won't
be in until 10,
and, if I look at my watch,
and it's quarter to 10
and you're here?
Sir, please, leave us alone!
We have to tidy up until 10 o'clock.
And why do you say, at first,
that she left a month ago,
and then, suddenly, you
change your mind and say that
she left at the end of January?
Why?
Leave you?
You want me to leave you?
OK, I'll leave you and go.
And you know why?
Have you considered why?
Think about that.
Is there a problem?
- Excuse me, miss Raluca!?
- Yes?
Why don't you sell ladies' lingerie?
How about it?
So you don't have an
answer for everything.
KINDERGARTEN
Turn right and
follow the line.
Quiet children, and
eyes on your plates!
Hello, ma'am.
Could you...
One second.
There's no one at Miss Helsighia.
She comes in at 12 o'clock.
She's working noons this week.
I came to get my girl, and...
Everyone's at the Ion Creanga theater,
seeing The Giant Radish.
Come, Lumi.
Come on, dear!
Go change.
This way.
We were in mid rehearsal.
Really?
And I'm disturbing you...
What are you doing,
taking her?
I should say so.
What do you think?
We were rehearsing for the festivities,
you could let her stay a bit more.
The festivities?
Are you preparing for
August 23rd?
Could you let her
stay a bit more?
Mrs. Sofronea...
if I were to tell you that
I'm in in the terminal stage...
would that be enough?
Are you being serious?
Are you?
And you, why don't you
come when I call you?
Come on kids, let's resume.
When I call you,
I want you to come.
And 1, 2, 3, 4...
And why are you looking
at me like that?
Put more life into it!
Bye, Nina!
If you don't come at once,
I'm leaving you here.
I'm coming right now.
The water's not running.
Forget about that.
OK, right away.
Please.
- Did I tell you we were in a hurry?
- Yes.
Get dressed.
Can you tell me what
took you so long?
I needed to use the bathroom,
and then the toilet wouldn't flush.
The first one was:
"Alexandru has a new key."
The second one was:
"Ioana's jacket is new."
Did you know that mauve
is my favorite color?
No.
The third one was:
The flower...
Marina's flower
is
orange.
The fourth one was
a question:
What color is
Andreea's book?
And the fifth one was the
answer to the question.
Andreea's book is...
is pink.
Who's Andreea?
Andreea...
is both a girl from our class,
and from teacher's book. Teacher has
a book for getting words.
And I also have a
classmate Andreea.
- And how do you get along with Andreea?
- Very well.
She's almost my best
friend from the class.
Should I give a notice that I'm coming home,
each time I'm coming home?
No, tell me, should I give a notice
I don't know, maybe you'd like me to
give a notice 2 weeks in advance.
Listen to me:
When I come home, I want
to be able to get into the house.
Yes.
Exactly.
Say again?
Enough!
Enough, I don't want
to talk anymore! Enough!
Bye!
Why didn't grandpa
come and get me?
- What did you say?
- Why didn't grandpa come and get me?
Can't you see we can't
get into the house?
- What do we do now?
- I don't know.
Shouldn't you better take
me to mom, at work?
Is that what you thought?
Yes.
- Yes, hello.
- Hi, is Mrs. Mioara in?
- What?
- Is Mrs. Mioara in?
Yes.
OK, I understand.
Your hand.
You think I can deal
with all your messes?
You're very much wrong.
I gave him that money.
There's someone
at the door.
Is that how you figured it?
You give him a little
something for the help.
What are we doing here?
What are we doing here?!
The man has a schedule.
He'll go and leave you hanging.
- Hello.
- Just look at him.
I invite him to the table
and he gets under it.
I have something to ask from you.
Don't tell me the
little one's yours!
Yes, she is.
How are you, pretty?
- What do you say?
- Hello.
Is she the youngest?
No, she's Luminita.
The youngest is Lacramioara.
Very good. I wish her health.
What did you want to ask?
Pusa left and locked the door.
We can't get in, and I don't know
where to leave Luminita.
And I wanted to ask
you, if possible,
to let her stay Here until
Pusa comes back.
Don't you have the key?
I only have the key for
the bottom lock.
They locked the top also, and
left us standing outside.
And whose are these?
Ours.
I see.
But I have things to do,
and can't keep my eye on her.
And I'll have to be
going soon.
Well...
You can have her sit somewhere and do
her homework. She won't bother you.
I mean, Pusa...
I spoke with her.
She'll be back in 3 hours.
Well, come on then.
Come inside.
- It's OK?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- Viorel?! - Yes.
- How are you?
I'm fine.
- And how are you?
- Fine, fine.
Um, what...
- What grade are you in?
- The first.
Yea? What school?
At number 139.
- And what are these?
- Some flowers.
- You made them?
- Yes.
Bravo.
You look good, too.
I'm here with my nephew...
who wants to scam me with
some kitchen furniture.
He's got a business.
So, if I've got a business,
I'm looking to scam you?!
I know you well.
If only I didn't know
you just as well.
Go on, show me.
Three days we've been talking:
the money, the money...
- Allow me.
- OK.
No offence, Viorel, but
I just finished cleaning.
Give 'em here.
I'm getting sick of holding
a rag all day long.
Alright...
Instead of that big cupboard...
- Aren't you hot?
- No.
You're hot, right?
The air...
It's so stuffy in this room.
I'll have to let the air in.
What are you doing?
I'll do all the work
for you.
Relax, don't bother yourselves.
You must be tired.
What can we do?
That's the situation.
I'll leave it here
for you, OK?
... and, instead of that,
we'll have a table.
You can have
4 chairs for it.
Eat like regular people.
You won't have to be
cramped up anymore.
The price. I want to
know the price.
- Excuse me?
- Yes.
Can I leave this bag here?
- Yes, leave it.
- OK?
It's...
How can they be cheaper?
Didn't I say I'm only
charging for materials?
What do you want, then?
For me to pay for everything, and then
have you buy me a drink in return?
Let's come to an
understanding.
Give me a keg of beer at
the end, and that's that.
This is the price.
- What'll be going in the corner?
- The fridge.
- You won't forget, right?
- How could I forget?
Come on.
Dinner's ready. You're driving me
crazy with your cigarettes.
Should I set you a plate?
Are you eating with us?
Dear, don't rush us.
We're coming.
Didn't you say you
wanted to eat?
God, forgive me!
Now, what's most important.
I almost forgot.
Hey...
Did this girl of yours
eat anything today?
- Have you eaten today?
- Yes.
I didn't hear you.
- What did you eat?
- I had a sandwich this morning,
and I had another one at school,
and drank my milk.
Milk isn't food.
I'll give you some
boeuf salad.
Mrs. Mioara, no.
Listen...
- Do you pus mayonnaise in it?
- Of course I do.
Don't give her any. She's allergic to it,
and any kind of preservative.
I made it in the house, with
my own hands. It's fresh.
She's also allergic to eggs.
- Make sure you don't give her
anything with eggs. - OK.
- It's serious, you know.
- I'll give her something else.
Do you want some cherry-brandy?
Let's drink some cherry-brandy.
No, no thank you.
- Leo!
- Yes.
- Let's drink some cherry-brandy.
- I'm driving, thanks.
Come on, what's
the big deal?
I got it: she can't
have any eggs.
I'll find something else
for her, don't worry.
Something else. Anything
except for eggs.
What are we gonna
do with this boy?
- What?
- I need to use the bathroom.
How many times a day do
you go to the bathroom?
- The bathroom's over here, right?
- Yes.
It's occupied.
You should get a job.
Just sit here until
you can go in.
OK?
You see them, right?
- Your backpack, the gym bag.
Don't forget them. - OK.
- Don't forget them.
- OK.
I'm off. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Daddy...
I don't want to stay here.
I don't want to stay here,
I want to go to Pusa.
Leave your dad alone,
he's got business.
Listen...
I have some gumbo stew with
mutton. Can I give her some?
Would she have it?
What kind of stew?
Gumbo stew with mutton.
Yes.
Yes, give her some.
You sit at the table and
do your homework.
- Miss Mioara will help you, and
Pusa returns in 3 hours. - Yes.
We'll manage. We'll have
a great time together.
A great time.
- Yes?
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Don't worry.
Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
- Goodbye.
- Bye, daddy.
PASTRY
DISTRICT 3 POLICE
10TH PRECINCT
Your ID card, please.
You want me to get
you something?
Your ID card, please.
You don't want anything?
- No.
- Broke again?
Empty your pockets
on this desk.
Empty your pockets.
Give this to me.
Come over here.
Over here.
Place your hands
on the wall.
Higher. A bit higher.
Spread your legs.
Good.
Could you be more careful?
Relax, nothing happened.
Sit down here.
Sit down.
- Was it necessary to rough me up?
- Sit down and relax. Nothing happened.
Sit down.
It's expired.
Mister...
- It's expired.
- Yes, I know.
I should have
renewed it in July.
This is a 12 caliber.
Lica! How are you?
We're over here.
Brats, I'm never getting
rid of you, am I?
Sir, this way.
He had a tough
time with it,
with the screws from the lit.
He needed a mouse wrench.
And, when he opened the
plastic lid from the motor,
you know, the one
between rocker cams,
he pulled out a hatful
of cherry seeds.
What?
What? Nothing.
- Tell me. - Don't worry,
finish your work.
How they got in there, I don't know.
He was even ashamed to tell me.
Cherry seeds...
I knew you wouldn't
believe me.
So I told him to keep them so
I can show you tomorrow.
I knew you wouldn't
believe me.
- Have you identified the murders?
- Yes, 4, apparently.
Two men and two women.
- What do you say, boys? Should
we send someone? - Where?
- Coffee?
Yes.
Do you want some?
What, you think we're
getting too high class?
No, boss, but it's
bottled water.
I was thinking that a coffee
can get expensive this way.
Alright.
It's more about Giardia infection
than being high class.
Tap water is riddled with
Giardia in all of Bucharest.
- Listen up...
- All of it!
Ask the mechanic
to add up again.
Ask him nicely to add
up once more.
Boss, he's an honest man.
I wouldn't have stuck my nose
out for him if he was some...
deadbeat or something.
The old man's been fixing
his car there for years.
The man has his garage
in the neighborhood.
Go see if there's
been any report.
Everyone goes to see him, he
never gave any reason for doubt.
You'd never hear that Petrisor pulled
one on him, or something like that.
The phone!
You always do this.
Or should I answer it?
Hello.
Yes, it's me.
Kid, official duty.
To Dragnea. Get it
sealed and stamped.
You know what to do.
Hold on. What's his name?
- Who?
- This mechanic of yours.
- Petrisor. Petrisor Valentin.
- Alright. Gimme his number.
Got it?
This is just for your
peace of mind.
So you don't think that I
added a little extra for myself.
You always do this.
I'm the fool for getting involved.
- Nevermind. - I should have
known from the start.
- Tell me.
- He's arrived.
- Really?
- Yes, he's downstairs.
- I'll be back in 2 minutes.
- OK.
2 minutes.
Let's go.
- Can I turn on my cell phone?
- Yes, you can.
Remain there.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
Can I move from this chair
near the window?
There's a terrible draft
on this hallway.
- There? - Yes, I'm getting
a draft on this chair.
- Yes, sure.
- So I can?
Sure.
I brought you a coffee.
It's got everything
it needs.
Call me when you
finish, OK?
Who did you say
you killed?
The notary public,
Zoltan Istvan
and Dan Livinski and
Rodica Livinski, my in-laws.
- Doru?
- Yes.
Grab something
to take notes.
Yes.
Right away.
Tell me once again exactly
who the victims were.
Tell you their names?
- Zoltan Istvan and...
- Wait a minute.
Ready.
Zoltan Istvan...
and Dan Livinski and
Rodica Livinski.
Rodica is...
the wife of Dan Livinski,
and my mother-in-law.
My ex mother-in-law.
Of course she's
your "ex".
Is that all?
Yes, there was one
more woman.
When I shot Zoli in the
underground parking lot
there was a woman with him,
but I don't know her.
Zoltan Istvan.
And...
I don't think she was his wife.
They didn't seem close.
Is he your relative, too?
He's my ex wife's notary.
They met 3 years ago
at Geoagiu Bai.
4 years as of June.
Where did all these
killings take place?
I shot Zoltan Istvan
in the underground parking
lot of Intercontinental Hotel
yesterday, at about 9,
and I shot my in-laws
at their home,
in Chitila,
at 23a Lunca Siretului street.
Where do these
people live?
Who?
The victims.
My in-laws live at 23a
Lunca Siretului street,
in the Chitila neighborhood.
And Zoltan Istvan has...
an apartment on Fainari street,
at number 17.
It's the street connecting
Lizeanu to Mosilor.
I don't know if he
actually lives there.
It's rather a notary office.
He has another one in Satu Mare,
and another in Debrecen.
I don't know about the
lady he was with.
Why did you kill them?
I want you to know I realize
that what I'm saying...
cannot be qualified
as a confession.
But...
Because you need
it for the record,
I dunno, declarations
and forms to fill out...
I'll try to be precise.
Yes...
Amalia is...
Amalia is careless
like a child...
and she easily...
believes...
what certain people say...
or utter.
I didn't get a divorce because
I wanted a divorce.
Do you understand?
And, when you get a divorce, it's not
like separating from just a human.
I couldn't leave
things like that.
I don't know what
you think, but...
I don't personally
believe that
the justice system
has access to
the complex relationship
between me and my wife.
Who's Amalia?
Amalia is my wife.
My ex wife.
Her name's also Livinski now,
she assumed her maiden name.
What do you do,
Mr. Ghenghea?
I am a specialized
consultant,
metallurgical engineer at
The Bucharest Heavy
Machinery Factory for
The Chemical and
Petrochemical Industry.
And your address?
Where I live?
No. 5, Fetesti Street.
Balta Alba.
Building H27
entrance B, 2nd floor,
apartment 18.
Building?
H27
entrance B, 2nd floor,
apartment 18.
OK.
You're from
Bucharest?
Yes, I'm from
Bucharest.
My mother was
born in Silistra,
in Bulgaria.
And my father was born in Tandarei,
but I was born here, at Polizu Hospital.
I dunno but, I came
to the police...
surrendered myself
and my weapon...
and the officer on duty
grabbed me by the armpits.
I surrendered...
isn't it obvious I
did it willingly?
Yes.
I think that this officer
didn't understand at all.
The man to whom you
were speaking earlier.
- Any more coffee left?
- Yes.
Do you have any children,
Mr. Ghenghea?
Yes, I have 2 girls.
What are their ages?
The youngest is
4 years old,
and the old one is 7,
she's in 1st grade.
Don't get me
wrong, but...
I've listened to you and seen
the way you think you...
know and understand and
are perceiving me, and...
I'm getting scared.
I don't know if you
understand me.
- Should we get his statement?
- I would think so.
Yes.
I understood.
And the others?
Our people left?
OK.
- Well?
- It's all real.
Take his statement.
Here...
Write a statement for us.
"The undersigned",
name, surname,
living in Bucharest,
born on the date...
And so forth. Write down, nice and
detailed, everything that happened.
If you run out of paper,
I'll give you some more.
- Can I have a pen?
- Yes.
Here...
A pen with the
Steaua FC logo.
I'm going to the can.
Produced by
Co-produced by
Executive producer
Production director
Subtitled by
m4lvolio, gbigbi
for KG
Acknowledgements
Special acknowledgements