"I was like grass and I was not torn out."
Fernando Pessoa
Mati...
Mati.
Don't.
What are you...?
- Stop it!
Stop it!
You stop it!
What are you doing?
Stop it!
See?
AUTUMN BALL
I forgive you everything.
Do you still love Jaan?
It really affects me whenever
I get pulled into an environment...
that hasn't been created by a professional.
Then I realise it's truly great.
How can that be? I feel that
I should be the one to...
I should be...
Well, I think that...
For someone who has never studied it
to suddenly create something so...
Well, true style is inherent...
It's interesting how
they've done the facade.
Is it intentional or a work in progress?
Sure seems like something's in progress.
Great party.
Hey Maurer, do you still...
live in that...
housing estate?
- I do
- Why?
Practicing humility.
But seriously?
You're back early.
I'm so tired.
Of what?
They want everything to be...
so cozy.
Warm and comfy.
Who's they?
I cannot stand my friends and
colleagues anymore.
That cynic cornered me again.
Asked me why we still live in
a housing estate.
Does he really believe...
I'm insincere?
Useless layabout.
But really...
Why do we live here
in Lasnamäe?
What?
I'm sure you could still be a
paragon of integrity...
even if we didn't live in this
wretched neighbourhood.
What are you talking about?
Nobody lives here!
Here, there, there!
Nobody lives here?
I'm taking my lunch break.
Baltic consciousness 2006
Literary conference
Those Latvians and their tantrums.
I don't think I have seen you before.
I only came for the food.
Of course, what else.
The presentations are as dull as ever.
It feels so contrived, the way
Eastern Europeans are always...
trying to construct their identity.
Don't you agree?
I agree.
The West finances any old nonsense...
trying to deal with their
overfed guilty conscience.
But all this financing is simply
a continuation of colonialism.
There is no such thing as
the 'Baltic consciousness'.
There is no Baltic anything!
Giving things names is pure violence.
You are looking at me
like I'm a moron.
You know what I'm saying is true.
- What's your sign?
- Aries.
You don't live at all like a writer.
Have you read any Pessoa?
"I made of myself something
beyond my knowledge...
And what I could make of myself
I failed to do."
No, I haven't read it.
Who's Pessoa?
Who's Pessoa!
You're different.
You are... real.
You're a real person.
I'd like to read something
you've written. Will you let me?
I have nothing to show you.
You are modest as well.
Maybe even a genius?
A quiet hermit noticed by no one...
But after your death your
shabby bachelor flat will reveal...
the best texts in the world...
- I'm a doorman.
I don't understand.
What is there to understand?
Maurer?
I saw a one-armed man today.
Yeah.
I'm saying that I saw a man
with a rotting arm near the store...
drinking cologne
and smelling of piss.
For god's sake.
Do we have to discuss this now?
Dear lord!
Listen, I'm afraid of them.
I'm afraid that I might catch
some horrible contagious disease...
just by walking past them.
Is it awful of me to speak this way?
Is it?
Can I speak that way?
Maurer,
can I even think that way?
Can't we discuss
this in the morning?
Two rooms are just fine.
Three would already be a luxury.
Two rooms with a kitchen.
A bathroom.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
I'm a lucky guy.
(in a Finnish accent)
I'm done for today.
I'm not doing your clients.
What clients?
I've got no more
appointments for today.
What about the queue?
What queue?
Kaski!
The fact that you're Finnish
doesn't change a thing.
This here is a business.
Success does not come overnight.
You need enthusiasm.
(voice on the phone)
Slut, I want to see my kid...
Don't call here any more!
You hear me? You're drunk!
Well then...
Yes, it seems to be working now.
Yes.
Then how about...
I mean, I wouldn't say no to a drink.
Such a ladies' drink.
Sweet.
Nice flat you've got here.
Lots of space. - Yes.
You live here alone?
I mean with your daughter?
- Yes.
It's not easy, everything is
so expensive these days.
And you, all alone...
And adults have their
needs as well, don't they?
What are you...?
Oh no, no. I'm just saying...
I'm saying I understand.
Those needs can overwhelm you
so that...
And it doesn't get any easier
with age.
Please stop talking!
Listen young lady,
don't act so...
I could... I'd be able to...
with you...
I'm a complete stranger to you.
We can be honest with each other.
There's no reason to...
You have my number.
If there is anything...
Laura!
Wait!
Hey!
I want to see my daughter.
You're drunk.
This is unfair.
I'll have her
taken away from you.
I know about all those men
who come to your place.
Don't think that I don't know.
Slut!
I'll kill you!
Lotta, come inside!
You'll catch cold!
What is this film about?
That woman over there
is the main character.
Her love is a forbidden love.
- What is forbidden love?
It is love that is not permitted.
Have you read any Pessoa?
"I made of myself
something beyond my knowledge...
And what I could make of myself
I failed to do."
I know one too.
A pig and a duck
had a good fuck...
No, wait.
A pig and two ducks
had a good fuck.
It's an old rhyme from Märjamaa.
I'm sorry...
You're a really cool guy.
No offence. Honestly.
My naughty mouth...
Sorry.
You're a cool guy.
It's nothing personal.
You're a great guy, really.
What a naughty mouth.
I'm really sorry.
If we get a free moment,
we'll pity you.
Sorry.
(in the notebook)
197. Ruth - Libra
198. Kirsi - Gemini...
(last line)
210. Merike - Aquarius
Listen, I was thinking...
If you've got spare time and
have nothing better to do...
could you keep the front
of the restaurant clean?
How do you mean?
I don't know,
with a broom or something.
But I'm a doorman.
Well, we all have our responsibilities.
I'm the manager and your job
is to keep things tidy.
Division of labour.
I was told that cleaning would not
be one of my responsibilities.
So, we seem to have a...
difference of opinions.
And I'm the manager here.
Cleaning is not my job.
Not one of your strong suits?
And where's your jacket?
Where is it?
Employees work.
Reading is for writers.
Hello? - Congratulations,
you lucky bastard - What?
You really don't know?
Everyone else does.
- No, I don't. - You've been awarded
the Cross of Terra Mariana.
And a hundred thousand kroons.
- The Cross, to me?
- Yes, to you.
It was in the paper.
Hey, did you really believe that?
No, I didn't.
I've already called five people.
Everyone believed me!
Fuck off with your stupid pranks!
- Listen, have you heard people saying
that I've gone mad? - No, I haven't!
It's not boredom that ends love.
It's impatience.
The impatience of bodies yearning
to live, yet dying each day.
The impatience of bodies dying
day by day, but yearning to live.
Who can't pass up a single opportunity.
Who wish...
The impatience of bodies yearning
to live but dying each day...
Bodies that can't pass up
a single opportunity
Who wish to make the most of their
limited, diminishing, mediocre lives.
Who can't...
Who wish to make the most of their
limited lives and cannot love anyone...
because everyone else seems limited,
diminishing and mediocre.
Who cannot love anyone...
But it is not boredom...
So poorly printed.
Such a lousy print.
Is it really that much?
Natasha!
- Yes?
How much is "Maaja"?
- Forget it.
- What's "Maaja"?
- The porn magazine!
Doesn't it have a price on it?
It does but the print is so bad,
I can't make it out.
Hold on, I'll find out.
- Forget it.
How much is "Maaja",
that porn mag?
Yes, that porn. It does, but the print
is so bad, impossible to read.
Well, there is,
but it's impossible to read...
Thirty nine kroons.
- Thirty nine?
Okay. I aslo read "thirty nine",
but that seemed too expensive.
Thirty nine, it's quite legible.
What's going on here?
What are you doing? Oh my god!
- I was just...
- I know your sort!
You're not going anywhere!
Pervert!
Look everyone!
There goes a pervert!
Where are you going?
Pervert!
Jump in, I'll give you a lift.
It's always red.
Bumpy road.
You must be wondering
what I'm doing.
I've been watching you from afar
for quite a while now.
And I like you.
You seem sad and...
lonely.
You have... class.
Be my wife.
- Why?
My home needs a fairy.
Or do you despise people like me?
- Like what?
Do you at least want to kiss me?
Lotta.
Do you remember
what I told you about strangers?
You should never accept anything
from strange men.
What does 'pervert' mean?
Try to understand...
It is very important
where and how I live!
I'm an architect, not an estate agent.
- I see. You're a maniac.
Don't look.
Some psychopaths don't like it
when you look them in the eye.
Why did that doorman
look at you like that?
I'm afraid the kitchen is closed.
Give me a bottle of brandy.
Waiter! Bring me
a bottle of champagne!
You're a beautiful goddess.
Like Aphrodite rising from the sea.
You know?
No, I don't. Behave!
People are looking.
- What people?
They're robots.
You know, my wife left me...
for my friend.
Let's drink.
Come on, let's drink.
Hello?
Bottoms up.
Don't be so fucking...
conservative.
So reserved.
It's not a beauty pageant.
Come on, let's drink.
Hello?
Why do you always
wear that same dress?
- What?
- Shut up!
I'm bored with that dress.
Your breasts are
too small for that dress.
Hey, right on!
Thank you for the lovely evening.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry.
I soaked your shirt.
- Hey, where did that woman go!
- What woman?
Get my coat.
Forgive me.
I don't know what came over me.
Give me the keys.
Let's go for a ride.
I'll drive.
Come on, let's go.
Let's drive, we'll go to my place.
- Please stop it.
Where are you going?
Please don't!
Don't go.
- Bastard!
- I'll total this car! Hear me?
Did you sleep well?
Do you want this?
Very good.
Shit.
My shirt is so ugly.
These are...
These are big ones.
Big ones.
Anton.
Why are you dressed like that?
I got a job. It's impossible
to survive as a sculptor.
Your car is parked wrong.
Three rooms is something else.
23 thousand kroons per square metre.
Pretty sweet, isn't it?
It's safe to say I'm a lucky man.
But you... now that you're alone,
you should sell your apartment.
- I don't know...
- Or find a new woman.
Where? And how?
I just can't do it.
Then you should sell the apartment.
I just don't know
how to approach women.
It's very easy to approach women.
You should find out
when she's ovulating.
Women are extremely
receptive during ovulation.
But of course then they're drawn to
men with angular jaws...
and lots of body hair.
Do you have to stick
these things everywhere?
Selfish bastard!
Asshole, look what you've done!
Ovulation? What ovulation?
- I saw it on the Discovery Channel.
- Discovery?
Fuck off!
I don't think I've ever eaten here.
Exquisite cuisine.
Soon I'll have enough money
to buy two skip containers.
What?
Skip containers.
Skip container rental.
For construction waste and garbage.
First I'll take two
4.5 cubic meter ones.
Later when the money
starts coming in...
I'll take 10, 15, hell, 30 cubics!
For tractors, dump cars,
the whole deal.
Think how much construction
takes place in this town.
Think how much construction waste
that creates.
I'm not going to be
a doorman my whole life.
That's all just great...
But I have to get going now.
Please wait!
Hold on!
What's with you?
What just happened?
Nothing happened.
I just have to go.
But I thought...
We had something.
Don't say you didn't feel it.
Yes, I felt it.
So what's wrong?
Theo, I just really have to go now.
Give me your phone number.
No, I'll call you.
Where have you been?
You know how much construction
waste this city generates?
- I asked you a question.
- I'll ask you one as well.
- You will?
- Yes, I will.
Ask away then.
Let's try to be honest,
just this once
- Honest?
- Yes, truly honest.
Without worrying about appearances.
- Honestly?
- Yes, honestly.
Honestly.
I'm bored with you.
Your dry skin. Your cold eyes.
Your petite bourgeoisie egotism,
which to you seems vibrant and natural...
but to me it looks plain stupid.
I'm bored with
your childish craving for attention.
I'm bored with your...
femininity.
And you think I'm the problem?
I couldn't care less about that.
- Do you know what you are?
- Well?
You're like some Bergman character,
not even human anymore. - Wow.
A tiny man bemoaning his god's silence...
squirming in his own little
black and white world.
Maybe that's...
Yeah.
What are you?
What kind of a man are you?
All shiny surfaces and self-admiration.
That's what I think about
your shiny surfaces.
This is...
This shows a complete
lack of responsibility.
You come to work
whenever you please!
If you disappear one
more time, you're gone!
Is that clear?
Where do you think
you're going?
Hello.
- Get out!
- Shit!
Come on,
don't treat him like that.
He's a great actor and director.
- How great?
Rather well-known.
What do you direct?
- Romantic comedies.
- Romantic comedies?
Romantic comedies.
I decided to come after all.
Yes.
Do you despise me now?
These buildings cannot
contain the past very long.
Maybe it's because they were
built thinking of the future.
I just wanted to be happy.
I still want to (be happy).
In every single one
of these fucking boxes...
there is a human being
who just wants be happy.
Whole generations of mothers
and sons, fathers and daughters...
spouses, their lovers,
car owners...
All of them want to be happy.
And their lives drag on like
the wind grinding limestone walls.
And what will be left behind?
Maybe you don't believe me,
but I still love you.
I don't believe.
AUTUMN BALL
Subtitles edited and resynced by sigane
subscene.com/members/sigane.aspx
This movie is inspired by the book
"Autumn Ball" by Mati Unt...
and dedicated to all the men
with a gentle heart and a weak liver...
who stand alone
in the night in their underwear.