Q-u-a-r...
a-n-t...
i-n-e.
Quarantine.
Q-u-a-r...
a-n-t...
i-n-e.
Quarantine.
- You know the cholera?
- Yes, Mother.
You've seen the signs on the houses
where the coloureds live?
Yes, Mother.
- You know the typhus?
- I do, Mother.
You know what they can do to you?
Yes, Mother.
You are not safe.
You may be directing this movie, Howard,
but what you're asking, we can't do it.
Don't tell me I can't do it.
Don't tell me it can't be done.
The gyro forces are too much here.
You send these planes into simultaneous...
It's the goddamn climax of the picture,
Frank, all right? You make it work.
Look, decrease the vertical trajectory,
if you have to.
A LeRhone rotary won't stall at 60 degrees,
I've done it.
Howard, we're still short two cameras.
We need to cut that sequence down...
We're not cutting anything, all right.
I'll get those extra cameras.
Set up for rehearsals in five.
Mr Hughes, I'm Noah Dietrich.
Your office said I might find you here.
Dietrich. You're a man on the come. I read
your résumé and talked to your references.
You know what I'm looking for?
As I understand it, you're looking for
a second in command at Hughes Tools.
Someone to help oversee
the financial aspects of the business.
Yeah. I'm looking for somebody
to run it and do a damn good job.
Look, there's really one thing
you've got to know.
My folks, they're gone now,
so it's my money.
Now, what I choose to do with
that money may seem crazy
to those sons of bitches in Houston -
and I'm sure as hell it does -
but it all makes good sense to me.
You got that?
- Got it.
- Good.
Now, you made, what,
$5,200 a year on your last job?
I'll pay you 10,000.
- Guess I'll be working twice as hard.
- You'll be working four times as hard.
I just got you at half-price, Mr Dietrich.
Welcome aboard.
You're my voice now.
Make 'em understand that.
Look, some of those fine folks down there
still call me "Junior".
- You tell them it's "Mr Hughes" now.
- You bet.
- So, when do we go to Houston?
- We don't. Cholera epidemic in 1913.
2,000 dead. Whole place is
nothing but pestilential swamp.
Typhus, malaria, cholera, yellow fever -
you name it, they got it.
You see that, Mr Dietrich?
You are looking at the largest
private air force in the entire world.
- What do you think of that, now?
- It's your money.
Start 'em up.
I just saw the rough cut of
the new Tod Browning movie,
London After Midnight.
Lon Chaney is incredible.
It's his best performance in a long time. It's
gonna be a big hit. The cards are great.
Hello, Mr Mayer.
I don't know if you remember me.
My name's Howard Hughes.
I was wondering
if I could have a moment of your time.
Yeah, Howard Hughes.
The airplane picture, right?
- Exactly.
- Yeah, I remember.
- Hell's Angels. You heard of it. Good.
- Yes.
Listen, I was wondering
if I could have a moment of your time.
I need a few cameras.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Two, to be exact.
I already bought every camera I could find,
but we're shooting
our big dogfight sequence this week
and I need two more, desperately.
Do you think MGM could help me out?
- With what?
- Cameras.
With the actual cam... We're not usually in
the practice of helping out the competition.
- How many cameras do you have now?
- 24.
Wait a minute.
- You have 24 cameras?
- That's right.
- And you need two more?
- Yeah.
- You don't think you got it with 24?
- No. No, sir.
You know, I think we've got them all...
Don't we have them all?
They're all used.
- All 26 of them.
- I only need two, sir.
- Jesus Christ, sonny...
- Howard.
Howard.
Let me give you a little advice.
- Why don't you take your oil money...
- Drill bits.
Take your drill bit money,
and why don't you put it in the bank?
Because if you continue making the movie
the way that you are,
there isn't gonna be a distributor
who'll want to distribute it.
You're not gonna find anybody
who wants to see the movie,
and you're not gonna have
any more oil money.
So, welcome to Hollywood.
Yeah. Well, I'll be sure
to remember that, Mr Mayer.
- Good luck.
- All right.
He needs 26 to make it work?
He's out of his mind.
I looked down at my pants.
It was a strange situation.
Boss.
Scram, love boat, let's go.
Another soda. You know what I mean.
Milk, please, in the bottle.
With the cap still on.
OK, Howard, what did "His Highness" say?
The son of a bitch won't part with a single
goddamn camera. Can you believe it?
Howard, why don't you try
and make do with what you have?
What I have isn't enough, John.
Not for how I see it. Look.
My name depends on this picture.
If it doesn't work, I'm back to Houston
with my tail between my legs,
making goddamn drill bits
for the rest of my life.
Couldn't you find a way to do it
with the cameras you have?
I mean, jeez, you ought to hear what's
going on with DeMille over at Paramount.
He's shooting this Bible picture, right,
and he's gotta do a crucifixion.
- Johnny.
- He's doing it in Fresno.
- Johnny. Johnny.
- All of a sudden there's...
- Johnny.
- Yeah?
- You're a press agent, are you not?
- Yeah.
And you're supposed to know all the little
ins and outs of Hollywood? Do you?
- Yeah, absolutely.
- Then you leave the big ideas to me.
- Yeah, of course, boss.
- Cigar, cigarettes, Sen-Sen?
Thelma. I thought you were over at
the Brown Derby with Trixie. No, Theresa.
- Margaret, yeah.
- Exactly. What happened to Margaret?
- She lost her shoes?
- Thank God that's settled.
I'm sorry.
Thelma, this is Howard Hughes.
Howard and I were just discussing how he
wants me to pull a camera out of my ass.
- Cigarette?
- Oh, no, thanks. I don't smoke.
Whew. Boy, you are just hitting
on all six cylinders, aren't you?
My God.
Would you do me a favour and just...
Would you just smile for me one time?
Just once?
Whew. Yeah. Yeah.
You see, you got a short upper lip.
Makes for a much nicer smile.
See, I wonder what gives
a beautiful woman like you pleasure.
I mean, say you're just standing there,
right? And I just touch you.
Just like this,
through my fingertips.
Do you...
Do you like that?
Do you?
See, I want to learn what pleases you.
I want to learn everything about you.
Would you let me do that?
Would you give me that job?
I'm off in a half an hour.
- Well, I'm in room...
- 217.
217.
See you there.
Johnny, get on the horn
to Universal and Warner's.
I need two more cameras by Saturday.
Rent 'em if you can.
Steal 'em if you have to.
Abso-tively, boss.
Abso-tively.
Rumours coming from
a lonely airstrip out in Van Nuys.
Sources whisper that young
Texas industrialist Howard Hughes
just won't stop pouring money
into his war epic. And do we mean epic.
137 pilots, 87 airplanes,
35 cameramen, 2,000 extras.
How long will it be before this picture
ends up costing as much as the real war?
Goddamn it.
Why the hell do they look so slow?
This isn't what it was like up there. They
look like a bunch of goddamn models.
Son of a bitch.
Howard?
Without something standing still
behind the planes
we've got no idea of how fast we're moving.
We got no sense of relative motion.
Call over to UCLA.
Get me the best meteorologist they got.
You get him here in an hour, all right?
Hey. You want the good news
or the bad news?
- The bad news, always.
- All right.
We installed the 450 radial
but the struts won't take the vibration.
Minute we fire her up, the struts
start cracking at the attach points.
- Well, what's the good news?
- There isn't any.
Goddamn it, Odie, if the 450's too big,
we just got to figure something else out.
We've done everything.
We've rebuilt her from top to toe.
Now, if we drain the fuel tank, for a couple
of runs, she might make 180mph.
I want minimum 200, all right?
I want a date with Theda Bara,
but that ain't gonna happen either.
Don't be so sure.
So if the struts won't sustain the engine
we need, we got to get rid of the struts.
No, then the top wing falls off.
Then let it.
What?
Who says we need a top wing?
I mean, who says we need anything?
- A monoplane.
- A cantilevered monoplane, right.
I mean, they're doing it in France.
To hell with the top wing and the struts.
- Put in a 550 Wasp engine.
- 100 octane fuel.
- That'd give us a top horsepower of what?
- 700.
We squeeze that to a thousand,
we've got the fastest plane ever built.
You know, I just got to say we've already
spent over $ 200,000 rebuilding this plane.
To hell with it.
Tear it up, Odie.
Go on.
Well.
The cumulonimbus formations
about which you speak...
that look like...
Giant breasts full of milk.
I want clouds, damn it.
Yes, clouds that look like
giant breasts full of milk
cannot exactly be guaranteed
for any particular occasion.
So you might have to...
to wait.
Then we'll wait.
Look, whatever they pay you at UCLA, I'm
doubling it, all right? You work for me now.
Find some clouds.
Find me some clouds.
Welcome to Hell's Angels.
Thank you.
We've been to Chatsworth, Santa Cruz,
Encino, San Diego, Riverside,
Van Nuys and Bakersfield.
It has been eight months.
- Where are my goddamn clouds?
- They move, Mr Hughes.
Clouds move.
That's what they do. They move.
See that? It is costing me $5,271 a day
to keep those planes on the ground.
You find me some goddamn clouds.
Nice day.
Yeah, very funny.
Listen, I got a call from Houston.
They're getting real nervous about all this.
- Stop showing them the damn bills, Noah.
- That would be illegal, Howard.
Shit, no.
Maybe it's a little bit naughty.
Hughes Tools is incorporated in Texas.
They have to see the bills.
Incorporate a new division out here,
all right? We'll call it Hughes Aircraft.
Odie, do we need
these rivets on the cowling?
Yeah, or the reverse thrust would rip it off.
They're gonna give me drag.
Do something about that, OK?
- Wind resistance on the rivets?
- Yeah, I want her slippery.
There are serious tax consequences
to incorporating in California.
- Just take care of it, would you?
- Mr Hughes. Mr Hughes.
Oakland.
We have clouds in Oakland.
- You mean it this time?
- Yes.
Goddamn it, yes. I can promise you.
Clouds in Oakland.
All right, all right,
don't get all jittery now.
Oakland.
We're going to Oakland.
Down and to the left.
That was perfect.
Yes, young Howard Hughes
has pulled it off.
After two years, Hell's Angels
has finally finished filming.
There's going to be one heck
of a wrap party in Hollywood tonight.
The price tag?
A staggering $ 2 million.
So, if every human being
in America buys a ticket,
heck, he might
even make a profit.
First the clouds don't come, then the
planes break down, then the planes crash.
Then the Zeppelins don't work.
Seems we've had everything but
a damn plague of locusts on this thing.
I mean, you have to admit.
Now, honestly, did you ever think
you'd actually finish the damn thing?
Come with me.
Mama, darling,
if I'm a success in this show,
- well, we're going to move from here.
- Oh, no.
Oh, yes.
We're gonna move up in the Bronx.
Lot of nice green grass up there
and a whole lot of people you know.
There's the Ginsbergs,
the Guttenbergs, and the Goldbergs.
A whole lot of bergs.
I don't know them all.
You see, this is what the people want.
Silent pictures are yesterday's news.
So I figure we gotta reshoot
Hell's Angels for sound.
- How much of it?
- All of it.
Before you even ask, I'll tell you. An
additional 1.7 million. We got that much?
- No.
- Well, we'll make it.
Take care of that, would you?
Now get this.
In the halls of 7000 Romaine, it goes on
day after day, month after month.
Howard Hughes is now editing
some 25 miles of film.
Heck, I say release it now and give
the world its first 560-hour movie.
Pat. Mr Hughes needs this reel
in the projection room right now.
Enough is enough, Mr Hughes.
Are you ever gonna let us actually see
this little epic of yours?
Hurry up.
- Who is it?
- Noah.
Come on in.
I've been on the phone to Houston
for three solid hours.
We're fixing every goddamn book we have.
Wait, wait, wait.
Yeah. Run reel ten again.
I think we're duplicating a shot here.
And tell Jimmy I want
ten chocolate chip cookies, all right?
Medium chips,
none too close to the outside. Got it?
Do you remember
that goddamn shot from reel ten?
No. I don't remember anything from
reel ten. I don't know what reel ten is.
I'm a businessman, Howard,
and so are you.
Now, look.
This has been a great ride.
We've had a hell of a lot of fun.
But you're losing
$ 25,000 a day doing this.
Every day.
So, what are my options?
Well, this time I don't know
that you have any.
I'm afraid you got to close it down.
Dig your way out.
I'm sorry, Howard.
I truly am.
Reel ten, Mr Hughes.
Mortgage Toolco.
Every asset.
- You heard me.
- If you do that, you could lose everything.
Well, I won't.
I won't.
All right.
I'll get into it.
Thanks, Noah.
More than half a million good souls
lining the curb of Hollywood Boulevard.
Look at the automobiles,
ladies and gentlemen.
There are at least 45,000 cars here,
making it the greatest traffic jam...
Young Howard Hughes must have
quite a lump in his throat tonight.
Six months after the stock market crashes
and after the death of three of his pilots,
he's finally unveiling
his $4-million baby doll.
It's the most expensive movie ever.
Nothing five-and-dime for our Mr Hughes.
Nothing like tonight
has ever been seen before,
and I can certainly say
it will never be seen again.
500,000 people are crowding the streets
to get a glimpse
of the stars and celebrities.
Three companies of Marines were called
to assist the 250 special police
who are handling this enormous crowd.
This is an industry town, my friends,
and nobody, but nobody,
makes a movie outside a studio.
Sure, some Hollywood insiders
over at the Brown Derby...
And now, ladies and gentlemen, I think...
Yes, yes. I can just see
Mr Hughes's car arriving now.
Mr Hughes escorts
the lovely starlet Jean Harlow tonight.
He discovered her for this picture,
and we think her platinum-blonde locks
and hot-jazz, baby-doll style
are gonna make her a big star.
Mr Hughes.
Mr Hughes, how about a word?
Big night for you, Mr Hughes.
Big night for you tonight.
Very big.
Tell us what it was like
making this fabulous picture.
Yes.
Yeah.
So, four million clams from your own
pocket. Nervous how the flick will fly?
Big night.
You enjoy the show.
Yes, well, let me present the feminine star
of this spectacle, Hell's Angels.
- Miss Jean Harlow.
- Thank you.
I would like to use this occasion
to publicly thank Mr Hughes
for the opportunity he gave me.
Thank you.
Thank you. And now
I'd like to ask Roscoe Arbuckle
to introduce his pet lion cub, Gilmore.
What the hell's the matter with you?
Can't you remember my name?
I'm sorry. Roscoe Turner.
And this would be Gilmore.
We've got him.
Murder. That's what
this dirty rotten politician war is.
Murder. You know it as well as I do.
Stand up, Slim, take a bow.
Reel four played way too long.
Too many coughs.
Get Harry and the team out of the party,
get them over to the office.
I want to cut a few shots tonight.
Find Glenn Odekirk. Somebody write
this down. "Flush rivets." You got that?
- Flush rivets.
Lickety split, boss.
Here he is.
Variety says,
"This one won't miss."
Magnificently photographed...
Scenes that never
have been approached...
Not for a long time have I seen
anything as enthralling...
It cost four million dollars
and it has four million thrills...
The lighter shade. I don't want to look like
Boris Karloff, if you know what I mean.
I read in the magazines
that you play golf.
On occasion.
Well, how about nine holes?
Now, Mr Hughes?
If it would be convenient, Miss Hepburn.
You're not extending enough
on your follow-through.
Follow-through is everything in golf,
just like life. Ha-ha-ha.
Don't you find?
Saw your Scarface picture.
- Violent.
- Realistic.
Movies are movies, Howard, not life.
Now, the stage - the stage is real.
Real flesh and blood. Human beings
right up there in front of you, buster.
Can't look away.
Can't munch popcorn. That would be rude.
- Do you like the theatre?
- No.
I adore the theatre.
Only alive on stage.
I'll teach you.
We'll see some Ibsen, if the Republicans
haven't outlawed him by now. Ha-ha.
You're not a Republican, are you? Couldn't
abide that. How did you vote in '32?
- Well, I didn't.
- You must. It's your sacred franchise.
Heard you were wooing Ginger Rogers.
What about that?
Aw, she's just a friend.
Ha. Men can't be friends
with women, Howard.
They must possess them or leave them be.
It's a primitive urge from caveman days.
It's all in Darwin.
Hunt the flesh, kill the flesh, eat the flesh.
That's the male sex all over.
Excuse me?
Well, if you're deaf you must own up to it.
Get a hearing aid, or see my father.
He's a urologist, but it's all tied up
inside the body, don't you find?
Me, I keep healthy.
I take seven showers a day to keep clean.
Also because I am what's so
vulgarly referred to as "outdoorsy".
Well, I'm not "outdoorsy".
I'm athletic. I sweat.
There it is.
Now we both know the sordid truth.
I sweat and you're deaf.
Aren't we a fine pair of misfits?
Three.
Noble effort.
So I suppose you're wooing me now.
Oh, well.
Not enough. Not enough.
These rivets have to be completely flush.
I want every screw and joint countersunk.
I want no wind resistance on the fuselage.
She has got to be clean, Odie.
Clean. Understand?
- OK, Howard.
- I don't know what else to tell you.
What have you got for me?
The thing is, TWA needs a new plane.
A modern plane.
- Yeah? What kind of plane?
- OK.
The DC-3 has 21 daytime seats
and 14 overnight berths.
- Something bigger.
- Try 50 seats.
- With a ceiling of 12,000 feet.
- No.
20,000. Think about it, Jack.
What does 20,000 feet give you?
- Less turbulence.
- Right, because it's above the weather.
Jack, we want to fly above the weather.
Only 1 per cent of the American population
has ever set foot on a commercial airliner.
Why? Because they're scared to death,
Jack, and they should be.
I mean, 7,000 feet is bumpy as shit.
You know that.
We build a plane
that flies above the weather,
we could get every man, woman and child
in this country to feel safe up there.
An airplane with the ability
to fly in the substratosphere.
Across the country.
Across the world.
Now, that is the future.
- You with me?
- Yeah.
Shoot straight with me now,
cos I don't wanna get into all this
if your board doesn't have the balls for it.
- Would they support us?
- I don't know. They're tight bastards.
- Well, what's your financial picture?
- Not great.
- Last year's deficit?
- 770,000.
- What's it selling at?
- About eight dollars a share.
That's the lowest it's been.
- I could do that.
- Do what?
- Buy it.
- You want to buy the airline?
For crying out loud, Jack. We don't want
a bunch of damn pencil-pushers
getting in the way
of us making our plane, do we?
Give me brass tacks, now. What does
controlling interest in TWA cost me?
- Call it 15 million.
- Whew.
- That is a chunk of change.
- Yeah.
You call Noah Dietrich.
You have him start buying.
Howard, hold on. Are you sure? You want
to think about it for five minutes?
Hell, Jack, I've got a tiger by the tail here,
and I ain't gonna let it go.
Good evening, Mr Hughes.
Welcome. Your table is ready.
- How goes the aviation, Mr Hughes?
- Just fine, Pete.
I'm so glad.
- Good evening, Mr Hughes. Madame.
- It's "Miss".
- Miss. The usual, Mr Hughes?
- Please, yes.
And may I recommend for the lady
our clementine soup,
followed by roast wild duck with currant
glaze and poached pears in rose sauce?
- It's truly divine.
- Yeah. That sounds fine.
Your kind of a joint, is it?
- Wouldn't have thought.
- They're open late.
I go to a hot dog stand on La Cienega, too.
They're open till about four.
Are they?
How marvellous.
Howard. Howard.
Hi. Son of a gun.
Kate, this is Johnny Meyer. I suppose
you could call him my press agent.
Pleased to meet you.
Loved you in Alice Adams.
- You're too kind.
- I'm sure you know Errol, right?
- Mr Flynn. Yes.
- Kate. Kate.
Kate of the clenched-jawed Hepburns.
Enchanting as always.
You should use Lux on your hands,
by the way. I do.
Kate, sweetie, you and Howard ought
to cook up a picture. Co-star with Errol...
My chair.
I think not.
Don't you read Variety. Mr Meyer?
I'm box-office poison.
I'm on the outs, the skids, the doldrums.
Washed up, day-old fish
not worth the eating, so they tell me.
To hell with them. To hell with them,
my dear. Soulless pricks to a man, right?
Johnny tells me you're thinking about
doing a Western, of all goddamn things.
Are you making a Western, Howard?
Yeah. Making a Western.
I'm gonna call it The Outlaw.
Yeah. And you know what it's about?
S-e-x. It's all about s-e-x.
It's a Western.
- You can't have fornication in a Western.
- It's not real sex, Skinny. It's movie sex.
What Scarface did for the gangster picture,
The Outlaw is gonna do for the Western.
Put the sex and guts and blood
right up there on the screen...
- Have any cigarettes?
- Don't mind us.
New York-cut steak, 12 peas,
bottle of milk with the cap on.
You're the only movie star I know
can't afford his own goddamn cigarettes.
I hope your food isn't getting cold over
at your table somewhere, or something.
No, no, no. We're here all night.
Don't worry.
Now, Howard.
Now, Howard, Howard. Howard.
If you're seriously talking about putting
carnality back on the silver screen,
you must swear to let me in
on the casting sessions.
I've somewhat of an eye -
an eye for talent, isn't that right, Johnny?
You ought to give up that prancing
in tights, be a talent scout.
That prancing in tights paid for my new
yacht. You must all come sailing with me.
Catalina, this weekend.
What do you say?
- Yeah, Catalina. Sounds grand.
- Let's have some fun.
I've even managed to coax
the luscious Miss de Havilland
and her equally luscious sister
to accompany me.
Though I fear their mother
will insist on coming along
to preserve their questionable virtue.
We shall assault these twin monuments
of pristine Britannic beauty nonetheless.
- What do you say, Howard?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
I gotta... I gotta go.
If you'll excuse us,
we have to be somewhere.
You are somewhere, Howard,
you madman.
- Somewhere else. Excuse us.
- Charmed, gentlemen.
Do help yourself to the poached pears.
I hear they're divine.
Well. Howard Hughes,
ladies and gentlemen.
Was that meant for me?
My hero.
God, all that Hollywood talk bores me silly.
As if there aren't more important things
in the world. Mussolini, for one.
- Where are we going, by the way?
- Do you feel like a little adventure?
Do your worst, Mr Hughes.
...you limey bastard.
I'm a Tasmanian bastard,
you ignorant prick.
That a way, Errol.
That's Mr Mayer's house right there.
Do you know where Jack Warner lives?
- What's that on the steering wheel?
- Cellophane.
If you had any idea of the crap
that people carry around on their hands...
What kind of crap?
You don't want to know.
Hold onto the wheel for a bit.
That's too hard.
Relax your hand. Relax your hand.
You see, you've got to feel the vibration
of the engine through your fingertips.
- Feel that?
- Yes.
Yeah.
Well, that's good.
Golly.
Well, she's all yours.
- Where are you going?
- I think there's some milk back here.
- You just keep us steady now.
- All right.
- Howard.
- Yeah?
There's a rather alarming mountain
heading our way.
Pull back on the wheel a smidge.
Go on.
Golly.
I don't think I've ever met someone
who actually uses the word "golly".
You all right?
Do you want me to take over?
Just when I'm getting the hang of it?
- You... You want some milk?
- Please.
Utterly smashing.
We'll do it again. I'm free Wednesday.
It's a little early for golf, though,
don't you think?
Oh, no. I live right there.
- Feel like a drink?
- Lead on.
Now, that makes
for a challenging par four.
My decorator picked out
the wallpaper and such.
He's queer as a bed bug, but...
I just hate this room.
Gives me the willies. Ugh.
Feel I'm about to be swallowed up
by the latest issue of Town & Country.
What room do you like?
My study.
Take me there.
You are the tallest woman I know.
And all sharp elbows and knees.
Beware.
Will you fly me to work tomorrow?
It is tomorrow.
Keep your eye on the fuel gauge.
She's got a minimum of fuel to keep
her weight down. Two runs, that's it.
After that, you're flying on vapours.
And then you crash and then you die.
- Right.
- Just give her easy flying.
Don't worry about speed.
And don't think about the record today.
I wish to God you'd let someone else take
her up. You've got damn 20 test pilots...
Hell, why should I let
someone else have all the fun?
See you in a bit.
Contact.
Whoo-hoo.
339.
Goddamn.
347.
Whoo.
Son of a bitch.
- 352.
Good girl.
Damn it.
Goddamn it.
Oh, God.
- There goes our meal ticket.
- Come on.
Howard. Howard.
How did we do?
352 on the last run.
She'll go faster.
Country mouse.
Kate. Katie.
Upstairs, city mouse.
Hello.
- Good Lord, what happened to you?
- Nothing. Hard landing. I cut my foot.
Sit down. I'll take care of it.
You tell me everything.
Well, you cannot imagine what it was like,
Katie. You cannot imagine the speed.
She was like a winged bullet up there.
- What did she make?
- Around...
352.
You did it.
Fastest man on the planet.
- Hot dog. I'm so proud of you.
- She did it, baby.
- You knew she would.
- She was fine. She was just fine.
- Now let me see your foot.
- Yeah.
Good God.
You're covered in blood.
No, no. That's just beet juice.
I crashed into a beet field.
- What?
- Yeah, I crashed in a beet field.
Let me get you cleaned up.
Heavens, what is this?
Electrical tape?
Yeah. Odie just sort of slammed it on there.
But all I could think about was
getting home to see you.
I am so proud of you.
Now, this is going to sting a little bit.
This is useless. Come to the bathroom.
- Don't get beet juice on the carpet.
- I won't.
- Too hot.
- Don't be a baby.
Was the press there?
Some, but...
They're calling everyone.
Should be on the wires by now.
What is it?
Kate?
I've been famous,
for better or worse,
for a long time now, and...
I wonder if you know
what it really means.
Yeah. I had my fair share
of press on Hell's Angels.
I'm used to it.
Are you?
Howard, we're...
We're not like everyone else.
Too many acute angles.
Too many eccentricities.
We have to be very careful
not to let people in,
or they'll make us into freaks.
Kate.
They can't get in here.
We're safe.
They can always get in.
When my brother killed himself,
there were photographers at the funeral.
There's no decency to it.
You know, sometimes I...
I get these feelings, Katie.
I get these ideas, these...
crazy ideas about...
things that may not...
things that may not really be there.
Yeah.
Sometimes I truly fear that I'm...
losing my mind.
And if I did, it would...
It'd be like flying blind.
You understand?
You taught me to fly, Howard.
I'll take the wheel.
Smashing all records, Howard Hughes
outdoes Jules Verne's wildest dreams.
Around the world from New York
to New York in four days,
even beating Wiley Post's mark
by over three days.
New aviation history is written
when his Lockheed monoplane
returns swiftly and safely.
A daring aviator.
A true pioneer of the world's airways.
From New York to Paris,
he cuts Lindbergh's time in half.
Then on to Moscow.
35 hours out of New York, he roars
across Siberia's trackless wastes.
60 hours out of New York, he heads
for Alaska, most hazardous hop of all.
Continuing the terrific pace,
he comes home,
bringing new laurels
to American aviation.
Howard Hughes and his crew may find
more worlds to conq...
You're not gonna believe this.
It just came across the wires.
Howard Hughes
has bought control of TWA.
I thought Mr Hughes
was flying around the world.
Apparently, he did it while he was flying,
over the radio.
I have heard some disquieting rumours
about Mr Hughes.
I'd like to know everything
there is to know about Mr Hughes.
I'd like you to attend
to that for me, thoroughly.
Ah, the Pantages is glittering tonight.
Right over here, Mr Hughes.
This way, over to the left.
Mr Hughes. Mr Hughes,
how was your flight?
Miss Hepburn, Miss Hepburn.
When are you gonna name the day?
- Right over here, Mr Hughes.
- What's your next movie, Howard?
Right here, Howard. How many more
records are you gonna set?
Come on, Howard.
Give us a smile. It won't kill you.
- Raise your head a little.
- Over here. Over here.
Don't forget this side.
Mr Hughes, when are you
gonna fly round the world again?
You going to fly with Kate next time?
Did you get Ionely without her?
Did you talk to Lindbergh
about your round-the-world flight yet?
Mr Hughes,
where is Linda Darnell tonight?
Right here.
Right here, Mr Hughes. That's it.
Are you trying to be
more famous than Lindbergh?
You know,
fame is supposed to be my turf.
LB.
If you don't get more distinguished
every time I see you.
Ah, you look so beautiful.
Is that true?
...Mr Randolph Scott.
They make a handsome couple...
Don't worry about it, Howard.
She's just working the room.
It's her job, baby.
Sultry southern tigress
Ava Gardner dazzles the room tonight.
She's the newest star in the MGM galaxy.
And believe you me...
Jane Eyre has been selling
popcorn for over a hundred years, LB.
Hello.
Could you reach me a towel?
I...
I really can't do that.
I'm sorry.
I'm an idiot.
I'm a complete idiot and I'm sorry.
- Forget it.
- No, no.
I'm a vain, preening ass
without a single redeeming feature.
That's not true.
You have very good teeth.
Come on.
I've got a better idea.
Take me flying.
- Or better yet, I'll take you flying.
- Do your worst, Miss Hepburn.
Don't be so squirmy, Howard.
You're going to get on famously
with Father and Mother.
And I'm sure they'll like you, too.
Once they get to know you.
Hello. Hello.
- Kath, hello.
- Kathy.
Sweetheart, who's that
with the camera right there?
That's my ex-husband, Ludlow. Father
and Mother are just mad about Luddie.
What the hell is he doing here?
He's here all the time.
Hello.
Sorry we're late. Mom.
- Thank you.
- Dad.
- Darling.
- Uncle Willy.
Who've we got here?
Don't feel self-conscious.
Hepburns. Hepburns.
Attention, please.
This is Howard.
Howard, welcome.
Don't worry, he's had his lunch.
He likes you.
That's unusual.
We pay our devotion to the arts here.
A colony we created.
Julian's a painter.
Abstract, of course.
What the hell's the point
of painting something real
when you can just take a picture
nowadays, don't you agree?
Where do you stand on politics,
Mr Hughes?
- Excuse me?
- We're all socialists here.
We are not.
You've met Mr Roosevelt.
What make you of him?
What are you sniggering at?
- What? What was that?
- You just sniggered.
No, no. The dog.
It seems to be crushing my feet.
- Oh, my God.
- Buster.
Hey. Hey.
Don't you like dogs?
I will not have you sniggering
at Mr Roosevelt at my table. Please leave.
- No, no, I wasn't.
- I thought everybody liked dogs.
Perhaps he had a bad experience
as a child.
So, Kathy, does it stick in your craw that
Howard here gets more press than you?
- A bad experience with a dog?
- No, no.
- You are such a shy creature, aren't you?
- Perhaps it was a very large dog.
The press can be a damned nuisance...
- Was it a Doberman?
- It burns my goat.
A Doberman, Mr Hughes, or a dachshund?
- Neither, sir.
- Dachshunds are little dogs.
They should all be lined up
against a wall and shot.
What's that Spanish painting? The...
- The Goya.
- Goya. Of course. Yes.
- Yes. Mexicans. Poor lambs.
- What was that called?
Anyway, that's the vulgar press, I'm sure.
Do you read much, Mr Hughes?
I try to stay up to snuff
on the trade journals, yeah.
Snuff?
These would be flying magazines?
- What was that?
- He's a little deaf.
- Pass the goddamn butter.
- You read flying magazines?
- Take the butter.
- Trade journals on engineering, aviation.
We read books.
Howard has to read the trade pieces, Mom,
because he's designing a new airplane.
Oh, really? Do tell.
Well...
It's quite exciting, actually.
It's a spy plane for the Air Corps.
A twin-engine plane with some,
I must admit,
some rather unique design features.
You see, it has these two booms...
Luddie built a birdhouse once.
You remember that?
- Yes, well, a mere trifle.
- I remember the painting.
- It's called "May 18" or something.
- Hey. Hey.
Anyway, Goya's vastly overrated.
All the Spaniards are.
- Nonsense. Picasso is sacred.
- I'm a urologist.
- It was quite aesthetic, really.
- A sacred monster, that's what Picasso is.
The birds don't care for it much,
but the bats do.
- I'll bet.
- That's such bunk.
- Do speak up, dear.
- Nothing, nothing, Mrs Hepburn, nothing.
Then why did you speak? I can't abide
people who speak but have nothing to say.
Did you go to mechanic school
to learn all this airplane guff?
No, no, I didn't, Luddie. No.
Well, Howard just flew
round the world in three days.
- We've heard enough about airplanes.
- And dogs, apparently.
- Then how'd you make all that money?
- We don't care about money here.
Well, that's because you have it.
Would you repeat that?
You don't care about money
because you've always had it.
- Well then, how did you make...
- Excuse me, I'm speaking.
- OK.
- Thank you.
All right.
Some of us choose to work for a living.
Speaking of which, I have more of that
"airplane guff" to attend to. Excuse me.
Well, seems a rather high-strung chap.
Well, you're a fine bunch
of bullies, aren't you?
Have you talked to Mr Mayer
about letting you do Jane Eyre?
The old Philistine won't budge.
Too arty, don't you know.
Daddy, I'm convinced,
the man hasn't read anything longer than
a Sunday Katzenjammer Kids in his life.
No fair kicking.
You have to use the mallet.
Really, though, darling, you can't retire
from the field of battle like that
- or they'll never respect you.
- Katie, I don't understand.
You were like a different person in there.
They just expect me to be a certain way.
There's only one real Kate.
And that's your Kate.
And over in Hollywood,
aviation tycoon Howard Hughes
seems to be cooking up something big.
Even as he edits
his newest motion picture,
he's been secretly meeting
with the US Air Corps.
We applaud his patriotism and look
forward to his newest mechanical marvel.
Do you know how many Allied ships we
lost this year because of U-boat attacks?
- No.
- 681 ships, just this year so far.
Now, the army needs a new airplane
to fly the troops over to Europe.
These ships, they're sitting ducks.
They're sitting ducks for the U-boats.
- You want to build a troop carrier plane.
- Stop thinking like an insect, Odie.
Not just a plane to carry the troops.
A plane to carry everything.
The troops and the jeeps and the tanks
and whatnot. Here, take a look.
No, other side.
I figure around 200 feet from nose to tail.
Wingspan around 300.
We're gonna need
about 24,000 horsepower.
Now, this, this is just what Kaiser
and the army are looking for.
And don't worry,
they're gonna pay for it this time.
Christ.
What are you getting us into?
Well, it's a big plane.
So I'm calling it the Hercules.
Swell name, isn't it?
- How heavy you imagine this thing is?
- Say around 200 tons.
Well, I didn't say it was going to be easy.
All right, boys,
I want you to rig up something like this.
Should give the proper uplift ratios
while reducing the need
for additional torque support on the front.
We are not getting enough production
out of Jane Russell's breasts.
All right, I want smooth titties, gentlemen.
Smooth titties.
- It's all in engineering, isn't it, Odie?
- Howard.
Do you really think they're gonna let you
put out a whole movie just about tits?
Sure.
Who doesn't like tits?
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Sorry I'm late.
Will the secretary please record
that Mr Hughes has arrived,
and that this session is now called
to order? I yield the floor to Mr Breen.
Mr Hughes, members of the committee,
I have reviewed Mr Hughes' photoplay
entitled The Outlaw
and I can state categorically that I have
never seen anything quite so unacceptable
as the shots of the mammaries
of the character named Rio.
For almost half the picture,
the girl's mammaries,
which are quite large and prominent,
are shockingly uncovered.
For this reason I have concluded the
picture appeals only to prurient interests
and should be denied the Motion Picture
Association's seal of approval.
Really, Mr Hughes.
- Thank you, Mr Breen. Mr Hughes.
- Thank you, Mr Chairman.
Mr Breen,
it's good to see you again.
I haven't seen you all since that situation
with all the violence in Scarface.
The situation here seems to revolve
around Miss Russell's mammaries.
Mr Breen feels that
they are too prominent, yes?
More prominent than other mammaries
have been up on the screen?
Well, I hope to dispel that notion.
Jean Harlow.
Ann Sheridan.
Irene Dunne.
Claudette Colbert.
Rita Hayworth.
Betty Grable.
And the lovely Miss Jane Russell.
Now, all these shots,
save for Miss Russell,
were enlarged from pictures
that received Mr Breen's seal of approval.
Now, as you have probably noticed
by now, they all contain mammaries.
I will ask my associate to join me now.
May I introduce Dr Ludlow Branson
of Columbia University?
Dr Branson
is a mathematician of some note.
Yes, you.
And he will now demonstrate that, in fact,
Miss Russell's mammaries
are no more prominent
than any of these other fine ladies'.
Doctor.
Doctor,
you forgot your callipers.
Gentlemen, Mr Hughes.
Let us commence by calling this
Mammary Exhibit Number One.
Now, you'll see that the length
of the actual cleavage,
if I may, is
five inches and quarter.
Now, if we move to Mammary Exhibit...
Dateline Hollywoodland.
Movie tycoon Howard Hughes
must have the greatest job in the land.
Each and every night the lucky guy
has to escort a different beautiful woman
to a different dazzling event.
The TWA king always talks up his airline
as he escorts a succession...
The Hercules, ladies and gentlemen.
The Hercules.
A plane, a boat, a flying city.
Now, don't forget. Every bill comes to me.
They don't pay for anything.
Those men decide whether or not to fund
the plane, so I need them real happy.
- You do what it takes.
- You betcha, boss.
What about the girls?
How are they in the bomb department?
Well, let's put it this way.
It'll be a regular boob buffet.
I don't think the gentlemen from the Air
Corps will have any trouble scoring tonight.
And inside, 700 brave American soldiers,
a dozen Sherman tanks,
all winging their way over the Atlantic,
free from the threats of the U-boats below.
Could Jules Verne himself have ever
imagined anything so magnificent?
Could he have imagined her mammoth
wingspan, longer than a football field?
Don't you see how this demeans me?
Since when do you care about
the scandal rags?
Every time there's a picture of you with
another woman, it's like a slap in the face.
- Don't you understand that?
- That's overstating it just a bit.
Joan Crawford, Ginger Rogers,
Linda Darnell, Joan Fontaine,
and now Bette Davis, for God's sake.
Look. They're Cracker Jack candy, honey.
They don't mean anything to me.
Very nice.
Well, you're the one that said
that all men are predators, right?
I mean, it's all in Darwin.
Remember?
And am I to expect this behaviour
to continue after the wedding?
What is really bothering you, Kate?
Is it the women? Or the publicity?
Can't you eat ice cream from a bowl
like everyone else in the world?
Don't you dare.
Yeah.
No. Odie, this is not a good time.
For Christ's sakes, we can't make the
Hercules if we don't have any aluminum.
Wait. No, no.
I can hear you better now.
Look, you tell the War Production Board
that this is an essential strategic operation.
Odie, if they're giving aluminum
to Douglas, Northrop and Boeing,
they sure as hell
can give some to Hughes Aircraft.
Don't set the ice cream...
Meantime, we've got to think
of something else.
If we can't get aluminum,
we'll just have to find another way.
Christ, I don't know.
You tell me.
We'll find some alloy that works
just as well. Right. Look...
If we can't get any aluminum,
we'll just have to use wood.
You can't make
a 200-ton plane out of wood.
Why the hell not?
The damn thing is a flying boat, right?
- What do they use to make boats out of?
- Oak.
Think of the Hercules
like a flying Spanish galleon.
Spanish galleons could weigh 1,200 tons.
Good luck today.
We just have to find the right kind of wood.
Something light but strong.
- Morning, Kate.
- Pine, cedar, maybe birch.
Catch.
From my farm.
If you like it,
I can get you a bushel.
Trouble with Mr Hughes?
There's too much Howard Hughes
in Howard Hughes.
That's the trouble.
Beautiful.
Don't you even take Christmas off?
Nice to see you, Bob.
Sorry, I've got grease on my hands.
Have we got something to show you?
Take a look. She's the XF-11
reconnaissance flier. Spy plane, really.
Designed every inch of her myself.
She's got a top speed of 450,
which means she can outrun
anything they throw against her.
After the Japs stole my H-1 design
for their goddamn Zeros,
I figured I needed to do them one better.
Yeah. She's my Buck Rogers ship.
She's a looker.
OK, what have you got for me?
Jiminy Cricket.
Seating capacity for 60.
Wingspan, 123 feet.
Four double Cyclone engines.
Her ceiling's 25,000 feet.
- Gross weight?
- 86,000. Wing loading of 41 pounds.
So less drag on the plane in thinner air.
At high cruise power, you're looking
at a top speed of around 340.
Giving her a range of about 3,000 miles.
- Cross-country.
- Nonstop.
Bob, you know something?
You are a son of a bitch.
Bob, you got something on your suit.
Yeah.
On your lapel there.
You got something on your lapel.
Right there, Bob.
You missed it.
Right there.
Clean it off, would you?
Here. Thanks.
Now throw it away.
No, over there.
Thanks.
So, what do you call her?
The Constellation.
But we can change that.
No, no, no.
It's pretty. I like her.
So, what kind of deal can you give me?
What kind of deal can you give me?
We'll give you the first 40 planes
off the assembly line.
That should give us
about two years exclusivity with her?
Hell, more than that.
United and American don't have
the imagination for a plane like this.
Two years ahead of Juan Trippe, then.
- How much?
- 450,000 each.
That's 18 million for the first 40.
Hell, TWA can't afford that.
The damn airline's flat broke.
Guess I'll just have
to pay for them myself.
Build them, Bob.
Send the bill to Noah Dietrich.
And thank you.
Merry Christmas.
You have just placed the largest order for
airplanes in the history of the damn planet.
Lockheed just sent us a bill for $18 million.
Now now, don't get all hysterical on me,
Noah. It isn't good for you.
- This is a lot of money for some planes.
- Yes. Yes, I know it's a lot of money.
It's too damn much. You think I've just got
$18 million in petty cash?
I should have told you earlier.
It slipped my mind.
- Slipped your mind? For God's sake.
- Right. Well, look...
- How could $18 million slip your mind?
- I'll get back to you. Goodbye, now.
Hey, honey.
What are you doing home?
You're not one for tears
and, well, neither am I.
So it's best to come out with it.
I've met someone.
I've fallen in love and I'm moving out.
If I could make it any more gentle, I would.
But I can't.
So there we both are.
Let's be honest.
It's all been a grand adventure,
but it couldn't possibly last.
We're too alike, you and I.
- You met someone?
- Someone more appropriate.
To me, I mean.
What does that mean,
more appropriate?
Someone more attuned to my needs.
Look at me, Katie.
Stop acting.
I'm not acting.
I wonder if you even know any more.
Don't be unkind.
You...
You want to go?
Go on.
Actresses are cheap in this town, darling.
I got a lot of money.
- Howard, please. This is beneath you.
- No, no, this is exactly me.
You come in here out of the blue and
tell me you're leaving me just like that,
and you have the nerve
to expect graciousness?
I expect a little maturity. I expect you
to face the situation like an adult who...
Don't talk down to me.
Don't you ever talk down to me.
You are a movie star, nothing more.
Don't answer it.
What is it, Howard?
Hey, Noah.
I need you to get to Penney's
and buy me new clothes.
- Penney's isn't open.
- Shit.
- It's two in the morning.
- Yeah, that's right. Ah, well.
First thing tomorrow, then, all right?
I need two suits off the rack.
One light and one dark.
Three white shirts and three pairs
of white tennis shoes. You got that?
- Yeah.
- No, no. Make it Woolworths.
- Woolworths.
- No, no. Penney's. Penney's.
All right, then.
I'll get into it as soon as I can, Howard.
- Noah, do you have a recorder?
- No.
- Are you recording this conversation?
OK.
I trust you.
Howard...
Listen, I need those suits
first thing tomorrow, all right?
- All right.
- Wait, wait.
- Did I say Penney's or Woolworths?
- Penney's.
- Better make it Sears.
- All right, then. Sears.
I'm sorry, honey.
If I don't answer,
he'll just call back.
Stop there, if you please,
Miss Domergue.
Have you had surgery, Miss Domergue?
No.
Do you have scars of any kind?
Wipe off your lipstick.
That's much better.
Now, you understand that you'd be
under contract to me, personally?
Do you know what that means?
Turn around for me.
Very nice.
You move well.
You live with your family, do you?
Yes.
That's nice.
Tell me something.
How old are you, Miss Domergue?
15.
Holy mother of God.
Well, a car picks me up
every morning at eight, and off I go.
I am getting my high-school diploma.
Howard thinks that education is important.
- That's right.
- And then after classes,
I'm off for elocution
and grooming and fittings.
Well, blow me down.
Don't tell me Pan Am's
working out of the Cocoanut Grove now?
- Hello, Jack.
- Hello, Juan.
Helen, good to see you.
- How are you, Howard?
- Good, thanks.
- This is Miss Faith Domergue.
- Sit down. Now, what you doing out here?
Well, I'm out this way to meet
with Douglas about the DC-4.
That's our new plane
and it is gonna be a pip, let me tell you.
- How's the Constellation coming?
- Good.
Great.
So, how about letting me steal a peek?
Don't think so.
You know, I should be cross with you.
You stole Ray Loewy from us.
He's doing our interior design.
That's right.
He was doing ours.
So, what are your colours?
Stop fishing.
So, you have buttons or zippers?
I'm sorry?
Buttons or zippers?
For the drapes on the sleeping berths.
Zippers.
Buttons?
So, I suppose you'll be
expanding on down to Mexico.
- Why do you say that?
- Well, your range is 3,000 miles.
I would imagine you'd expand
from Los Angeles to Mexico.
- And maybe on down to South America.
- Hey, that's a good idea.
- Anyone got a pen?
- Or across the Atlantic.
Now, honey, you've had enough of this
ice cream. You give me that spoon.
You don't want to get your gloves all sticky.
Isn't that too far?
New York to Newfoundland...
to Ireland...
to Paris.
Well,
Pan Am welcomes you.
We're overbooked as it is.
It's such a burden doing it all on your own,
let me tell you.
So, when's the Connie gonna be ready?
- Next year, maybe. DC-4?
- Next year.
Well, we look forward to her, then.
And I to the Connie.
I've ordered the next 40 after you.
It's Miss?
- Domergue.
- Domergue. Yes, of course.
Now, was that a rumba or a samba
you were doing out there, my dear?
- It was a samba.
- A samba, yes.
Howard, I never knew
you were such a good dancer.
Helen, Jack.
Good going, boss. You just gave away
our entire postwar strategy.
- He can't stop us.
- He's Pan Am, Howard.
He can stop anything.
Waiter, give me
the largest Scotch you've got.
I don't know what in the hell you're
so goddamn giddy about. Excuse me.
Jack.
All right. I want you to get in touch
with Mr Joyce and Mr Berg.
Those are my boys in Washington.
Set up a meeting with Jesse Jones,
he's the secretary of commerce.
- Old golfing buddy.
- Slow down.
We're gonna need terminals
in both Ireland and France,
and I want to get tax breaks from them.
If that shit-ass thinks that he owns
the entire goddamn world,
- he's got another think coming.
- Pan Am owns Europe, you know.
He's smart.
We ought to think about Mexico.
To hell with Mexico, Jack.
No one airline should have
a monopoly on flying the Atlantic.
For Christ's sakes, it isn't fair. Look,
he owns Pan Am. He owns Congress.
He owns the Civil Aeronautics Board,
but he does not own the sky.
We are in a street fight with that
son of a bitch now, and I'm not gonna lose.
I've been fighting high-hat, Ivy-League
pricks like him my whole goddamn life.
And listen, fire Ray Loewy.
You goddamn heard me? Fire Ray Loewy.
He's spying for Trippe. That shit-heel
knew all about the goddamn buttons.
Spies in my midst, Jack.
Spies in my midst.
- Hello, Howard.
- Roland.
So, what can I do for you?
I want all the pictures you have
of Kate Hepburn and Spencer Tracy.
All the negatives.
And I want you to kill the story.
Howard, he's a married man.
He's a Catholic.
They're both movie stars.
Fair game all around.
My office knows where I am, Howard.
I'm not gonna kill you, Roland.
I don't do that.
- How much?
- Not for sale.
How much?
Not for sale.
You ever cheat on your wife, Roland?
You ever screw a coloured girl?
You ever steal anything?
You ever hurt anyone?
Good night, Howard.
You ever go to
a Communist Party meeting, Roland?
TWA stock.
How much?
- 50,000 shares.
- Ten.
All right.
This isn't gonna be that easy.
He's been making big contributions
on both sides of the aisle.
And Jack Frye is out there lobbying
everybody in town.
The French and British ambassadors
are all lined up on his side now.
I'm telling you, TWA is serious
about going international.
OK. Point, Mr Hughes.
Very well. You know what I think?
I think it's time for you to introduce
the Community Airline Bill
on the floor of the Senate.
- Is it done?
- My people are finishing it right now.
I also have to get you on the committee
investigating the national defence.
On the committee or chairman?
You know, I could be
much more effective as chairman.
It's a great public platform.
You know, it generates a lot of press.
Wasn't Truman chairman
of that committee?
Yeah, right. Now he's vice president.
Look what he did with it.
No, I think...
I think chairman.
What do you think?
- Chairman. That is interesting.
- Yeah.
Let me show you these specs
for the DC-4.
Ava, what do you think about
"Trans World Airlines"?
"Transcontinental and Western"
just doesn't fit any more.
Now that we're international,
we need a name that reflects that.
"Trans World" is good.
Kind of peppy.
TWA. Right?
Keep the same initials. That way you
don't need to repaint any of the planes.
That's you, always pinching pennies.
Hand me my wrap.
Knock it off.
I have something for you.
Stay here.
- What the hell is this?
- It's a present.
Go on and open it.
A box of trash.
You shouldn't have.
Keep looking.
It's a Kashmiri sapphire.
Best in the world.
I had my boys all over the damn globe
looking for this.
- Why?
- Because.
Look.
It matches your eyes.
I am not for sale.
For Christ sakes, Ava,
it's just a present.
You can't buy me, Howard,
so stop trying.
Don't buy me any more diamonds or
sapphires or any other goddamn thing.
You can buy me dinner.
How about that?
Jesus, Ava.
It's bad enough I have to endure
those filthy gym shoes of yours,
but then I get all dolled up and we have
to go out in this old jalopy without a hood.
Ava, will you marry me?
No, Howard.
- Why not, for heaven's sake?
- In the first place, I don't love you.
In the second place, I'm still married.
Look, you got girls stashed all over town.
You got a damn harem just at the Bel-Air.
Why don't you marry
one of your bungalow girls?
Those are employees.
I'm not going to marry an employee.
Jesus Christ, how would that look?
Good Lord, what is going on?
- Oh, my God.
- Goddamn it.
Faith.
- Faith. What the hell?
- Look out.
Goddamn, what the hell are you doing?
- You OK, lady?
- What are you doing with her?
We're going to dinner, that's all.
Now get out of there.
Get that crazy bitch away from me.
- Don't you love me any more?
- Course I love you, pork chop.
- Ava, look over here.
- Howard.
- Hey.
- Come on, Howard.
Juan Trippe is working with
that goddamn Senator Brewster now.
They're after you, Howard.
If the Community Airline Bill becomes law,
we are finished, my friend.
Pan Am will have a legal monopoly
on international travel.
How can they justify it, Jack?
It's un-American.
Senator Brewster's saying that
nationalised foreign carriers,
like Air France and Lufthansa,
can offer lower rates
cos they don't have to compete, right?
So, hey, let's just get rid of
all that messy competition
and have a nationalised airline of our own,
and why don't we make it Pan Am?
I'm not kowtowing to Washington
or anyone else.
- Howard, I need you up here.
- One sec, Odie.
Look, we are Trans World Airlines,
all right?
Get me something with a circle or a globe
or something round, for God's sake.
Speak up. I know.
I don't give a rat's ass what he says.
I'm not making a single cut.
Tell him I'm releasing without a seal.
All right.
We gotta go public with this.
I'm gonna talk to Hearst,
see what press he can give me,
but sooner or later it's gonna come down
to a vote in the Senate,
so we gotta get senators on our side.
- What do you want me to do?
- Do what Trippe does, for Christ sake.
Set up some offshore operations.
See who's up for re-election.
Let's start making donations.
- So, you want me to bribe senators?
- I don't want them bribed, Jack.
I want it done legally.
I want them bought.
And put a team of investigators
on Senator Brewster.
I need to know everything there is to know
about that shit bag.
Where he goes, what he says
and who he screws.
- Get into it right now, Jack.
- You got it.
Just give me a second.
- All right. What do you need?
- Rudder and elevators.
These are fine. Have Simon and Pete get
back to me on the hydraulic assemblies.
- We need a secondary system here.
- OK.
And listen, we need to take
another look at the wheel.
- Jesus. The damn wheel?
- Yeah. It just doesn't feel right.
Christ almighty, you've seen 8,000
goddamn wheels. Choose one, please.
- Just one of them.
- I know. I know.
- This one?
- I know. This one...
This one's pretty close.
Pretty close.
Odie?
That man sweeping up over there.
Does he work for me?
I mean, have you seen him before?
Name's Nick.
Something like that.
Why's he looking at me?
I don't know.
Fire him. And make sure they use
damp brooms from now on.
Respiratory diseases are expensive, and
I don't want a bunch of damn lawsuits.
OK. But can we at least proceed
with the instrument panel we discussed?
The tool shop's ready to go.
- No. I wanna see the blueprints again.
- Howard,
the deadline is now completely unrealistic.
At this rate, the war is gonna be over
by the time she's done.
Now, I need you here
to help consult on vital decisions
and you're off dealing with movies.
You got a thousand goddamn workers
waiting for you to make a decision here...
Hey. Odie.
Take it easy, all right?
I understand you're under a lot of pressure,
but it's gonna do me no good if you
crack up on me like that. All right? Look.
Take a couple of hours off, all right?
- You relax a little.
- OK.
- See your wife.
All right.
- Be sure to show me all the blueprints.
- All right.
Show me all the blueprints.
I'm serious, now.
Show me all the blue...
Show me all the blueprints.
- Howard...
- Show me all the blueprints.
Show me all the blueprints.
I want to get this done right,
so show me all the blueprints.
Show me all the blueprints.
- Show me all the blueprints.
- Howard.
Show me all the blueprints.
Quarantine.
Q...
U...
A...
R...
N...
T...
I...
N...
E.
Quarantine.
General McEwan. Colonel Bertrang.
Thanks for coming down.
- Odie, you reading me OK?
- Yeah, Howard. You're A-OK.
All right, flight controls are active.
She's all yours.
She's spotless, Odie.
No wiggle on the wheel or throttles.
Take it easy.
- How does she sound, Howard?
- She's whispering to me, buddy.
All right, make her sing.
Well, Odie, she can fly.
Congratulations.
I'm glad to hear it. Retract landing gear and
climb to 5,000 feet on a heading of 2-7-0.
Retracting landing gear and climbing
to 5,000 feet on a heading 2-7-0.
- Jesus, she's fast.
- What's your airspeed, Howard?
- 292.
- All right, take her back to 200.
No damn way.
All right, Howard, we gotta bring her home.
Scheduled time of one hour and 45
minutes has elapsed. Set course for 0-9-0.
- Give me ten more minutes. Roger that.
- Negative. Howard, bring her home.
OK. OK.
Setting course for 0-9-0.
Preparing to descend.
- Jesus.
- What is it, Howard?
The right wing just dipped.
I'm losing starboard engine.
Increasing power to 2800 rpm.
Cutting back.
Increasing starboard engine only.
I'm losing altitude.
Howard, check starboard engine
manifold pressure.
- It's good, but rpms are low.
- Are both starboard props turning?
Hold on.
It looks like they are, but she's pulling me
back and starboard, Odie.
- How bad is your cross control?
- I'm at full left rudder and full left aileron,
but she won't stay level.
Goddamn it.
- Howard, give us your position.
- 2,000 feet over...
Oh, Christ, I don't know.
Beverly Hills. 1,500 feet.
We're going down.
I'm gonna try for the Wilshire Country
Club. Ninth hole. You reading me?
Wilshire Country Club. Copy that.
Howard, reduce engines to one thousand.
I'm going down.
I'm not gonna make it, buddy.
Goddamn it.
Is there anyone else inside?
Is there anyone else?
No.
I'm Howard Hughes, the aviator.
Come on.
Every inch of wiring and fluid connection...
He has burns to 78 per cent of his body.
Nine ribs are shattered.
Not broken, shattered.
As are his nose, his chin, his cheek,
his left knee, his left elbow.
He has 60 lacerations on his face
to the bone.
His chest was crushed,
so his left lung has collapsed
and his heart has shifted entirely
to the right side of his chest cavity.
Jesus, God.
He's getting blood transfusions now, but...
- Whose blood?
- I'm sorry?
- From our stock.
He's not gonna like that.
Mr Dietrich, I doubt he's ever
gonna like or dislike anything again.
I'm terribly sorry.
Orange juice.
It's...
It's not fresh from the kitchen, so I...
I have them make it here so I can see.
Look at me.
I'm a monster.
Yeah.
Orange juice has nutritional value.
There's some flies
outside my window, though.
So...
little Howard likes...
citrus.
Don't he just?
Tell me.
An oil seal ripped off
the starboard rear propeller.
When the pressure dropped,
the prop reversed pitch.
Do you understand me?
Howard, I'm sorry to have to tell you
this now, but there's something else.
- You following me?
- Yeah.
The Air Force cancelled
the contract on the Hercules.
The war's over now,
and they say they don't need it any more.
I have to know what you want me to do.
Should I release the staff?
How far...
from finishing?
- About six months.
- No, no.
In money.
Seven million.
Maybe more.
Build it.
Build it, Odie.
Howard,
a Constellation crashed
outside Reading, Pennsylvania.
The Civil Aeronautics Board
has grounded the whole fleet.
You know, Juan Trippe sent me flowers.
Take a look.
- What did you do with all the others?
- I had them taken out.
They attract aphids.
Aphids are...
They're just awful little creatures.
But...
But these ones...
I wanted to see these ones every day.
Can white elephants really fly?
That's everybody's question.
It's the hull of the world's
mightiest airplane,
a flying boat built
by Howard Hughes.
220 feet long, it towers higher
than a five-storey building.
Power lines have to be cut as it starts
the trip from Culver City, California,
to the Pacific, 30 miles away.
Moving the 60-ton load
is quite an engineering problem.
But you gotta ask, "Was anything this big
ever supposed to fly?"
There goes one wing section.
160 feet long with four engine housings.
Double that, and you've got
some idea of the wing spread.
An airplane that challenges
a mountain for sheer size.
How long can they keep us grounded?
Till they finish investigating
the Reading crash. Could be months.
Jesus. You're already running a
$14 million deficit. How you gonna afford...
We go international,
we'll make it up.
Look, Brewster's CAB bill
just isn't going away.
That bill passes and you bought
all these goddamn planes for nothing.
- We're fighting the CAB bill.
- Yeah.
Meanwhile, how do you suggest
we keep TWA flying?
And don't say, "Just go to Toolco,"
this time.
As it is we're pumping every damn cent
we have into the Hercules,
which, I might add,
the Air Force doesn't even want any more.
Now look, Howard, I'm glad Jack here
is feeling so sunny about things,
but I've seen the books.
And I'm telling it to you straight,
I'm not just crying wolf this time,
we're in serious trouble.
You've got to make a choice.
You want to be bankrupted by
the big plane or by the big airline?
Go see Thomas Parkinson
at the Equitable in New York.
Get a loan against all the TWA equipment
and capital. Use the planes as collateral.
Hell, use the desks, use the pens,
use everything we got.
- Try to get me 40 million.
- And if TWA defaults on the loan?
Well, then Juan Trippe buys us cheap.
Under my bed. You put
a goddamn microphone under my bed.
Honey, listen to me.
I am concerned about you, baby.
- I just want to make sure you're OK.
- And who is in that car?
That goddamn car
has been with me 24 hours a day.
That car is there for your protection.
The only one I need protection from is you,
you sick bastard.
You don't own me, Howard.
I'm not one of your teenage whores,
and I'm not some damn airplane.
Now look, honey,
I'll have them take all the bugs out.
You just have to understand
that I need to know where you are.
- Why?
- Because I worry about you, that's why.
Bullshit.
What do you mean, all the bugs?
There's more.
How many?
I don't know, 12.
12, maybe.
And on the telephones.
Oh, Christ, Howard, on the telephone?
You listen to my phone calls?
No, no, no, honey. I would never do that.
I'd never do that. I...
I just read the transcripts, that's all.
What do you want to know, Howard?
Was I screwing Artie Shaw last night?
Was I screwing Sinatra the night before?
You bet.
Everyone told me you were
a goddamn lunatic but I didn't listen.
It's no wonder Kate Hepburn
dumped your demented ass.
Shut your goddamn mouth.
Get out, you pathetic freak.
Get out.
Is everything all right, sir?
Take out all the bugs.
Except for the one on the bedroom phone.
Sir, the FBI are at the house.
This is outrageous. Everything in these
offices is the private property
of Hughes Productions.
My legal counsel is on the way...
Federal warrant.
Don't interfere with this search, sir.
Dateline Los Angeles.
Howard Hughes has a new house guest.
No, it's not another beautiful starlet
this time. It's the FBI.
Noah, you have got to help, all right?
This is the tenth goddamn time
they have been here.
Rumour has it that federal agents working
for Senator Ralph Owen Brewster
have practically taken up residence
in the aviation mogul's Hollywood home.
Look, they are touching things.
Noah, Noah, they are touching things.
Just keep yourself calm and I'll be
down there as soon as I can, Howard.
Howard?
Howard, hello.
- Owen, nice to see you again.
- Good to see you. Come on inside.
- Emma, you can start the lunch now.
- Yes, sir.
Well, really lovely room.
Nicely decorated.
Thank you.
Here, have a seat.
- Thanks.
- Thanks for coming by.
I just thought you and I should have
a chance to talk privately.
You know, outside the office.
Well...
I appreciate that, Owen.
So, you're coming out pretty strong
against the CAB bill.
- You're coming on pretty strong for it.
- Well, it's my bill, Howard. You know?
Look, I believe sincerely that
America cannot afford to have
more than one international carrier.
So, do you think it's fair that one airline
should have a monopoly on...
A monopoly? No, no, no.
No, no, no. Oh, no.
No, I think one airline could do it better,
see, without competition.
All I'm thinking about are the interests,
the needs of the American passenger.
That's just beautiful.
What is that?
Is that a...
Is that a yak?
Some kind of a yak?
No, that's a llama. My wife picked that up
when we were in Peru a year ago.
Son of a gun.
A real llama.
- From Peru?
- Yeah. A year ago.
Yeah, it was about a year ago.
- Lunch is served, Senator.
- Good. OK.
Come on, let's go have some lunch.
Now did you...
Did you actually get to see any llamas?
No, no.
My wife just liked the painting.
It's a hell of an interesting animal.
I'll have to read up on those.
How do you spell that?
Like Fernando Lamas?
No, no, no. It's...
It's the animal. It's got two Ls.
Here, come on, have a seat.
It's brook trout.
Hope you like fish.
I love it.
Thanks.
I know you're not a drinking man,
so I hope water's OK.
Thanks.
All right, let's get down to business.
Let's talk turkey.
My investigators...
My investigators
have turned up a lot of dirt.
Could be really embarrassing
if this stuff got out.
I'd like to save you
from that embarrassment.
That's very kind of you, Owen.
My committee has the power
to hold public hearings.
I'd like to spare you that.
Would you, now?
Look.
Do you want to go down in history
as a war profiteer, Howard?
Is that what you want?
What do you want, Owen?
You agree to support my CAB bill
and I won't hold public hearings.
- I can't do that.
- Why not?
I can't do that, Owen.
The CAB would kill TWA.
Sell TWA to Pan Am.
You'll get a good price.
You'll get a fair price, I'm telling you.
And then?
Then you won't go public?
Right. That's right. The investigation's
closed. Nobody knows a thing.
It's better for everybody.
You know, Owen, I'm...
- I'm still wondering one thing.
- What's that?
You know the picture of the llama
you got last year?
- Yeah.
- Where'd you sail from?
We didn't sail.
We flew.
- You flew?
- Yeah.
Are you sure you want to do this, Owen?
You want to go to war with me?
It isn't me, Howard.
It's the United States government.
We just beat Germany and Japan.
Who the hell are you?
You tell Juan Trippe something for me,
all right?
Tell him thanks for the flowers.
And he can kiss both sides of my ass.
Well, we have a long list of particulars.
Chief among them is that
he defrauded the American government
of $56 million while we were at war,
when we could least afford it.
While brave men were dying
on the beaches of Normandy,
Mr Hughes was picking the pocket
of the American taxpayer.
I sleep
in this room in the dark.
I'll have him dragged here
to Washington if I have to.
I want to see the whites of his lies.
I have a place where I sleep.
- He has a lot of questions to answer.
- I have a chair.
Particularly about that
monstrous boondoggle of his.
That model airplane he's building.
You know, that flying lumberyard.
That Spruce Goose.
No, we'll get him here.
That's just beautiful.
I like the desert.
It's hot there in the desert, but it's clean.
It's clean.
I need to sleep.
I should drink something first.
Wait a minute.
What if that milk is sour?
If that milk is bad,
I shouldn't pick up the bottle of milk
with my right hand,
and I shouldn't take the top off
with my left hand.
Put it in my pocket.
My left pocket.
Howard, it's Kate.
I need to talk to you.
Can you hear me?
I'm coming in.
Howard, unlock this door immediately.
I can't, sweetie.
You mean you won't.
Howard, please let me see you.
I haven't shaved.
Well, neither have I.
Come on.
You let me in.
I can hear you, Katie.
I could always hear you.
Even in the cockpit, with the engines on.
Well, that's because I'm so goddamn loud.
Howard, I...
I came to thank you.
I found out what you did
for Spence and me.
Buying those awful pictures.
You love him.
He's everything I have.
Howard.
I'm glad for you, Kate.
Go away now.
Would you do that?
Howard, please.
Go away.
Just for now. I'll see you soon.
- We'll go flying together.
- Yes.
Yes, please.
You take me flying again.
Howard, I can take the wheel.
Howard?
Howard, are you there?
Come on, Howard.
Come in with the milk.
Come in with the milk. Come in with
the milk. Come in with the milk.
Come in with the milk.
He is to open the bag with his right hand
and hold the bag out to me
at a 45-degree angle
so I may reach
into the bag without...
without touching the paper.
Repeated from the beginning.
If there is any variation of these
instructions, even to the smallest degree,
the entire process
must be repeated from the beginning.
- Come in with the milk.
- Repeated...
...from the beginning.
- Come in with the milk.
- Repeated from the beginning.
Q...
R...
N...
T...
Q...
U...
E...
I...
T...
N...
E...
E.
I...
Howard?
Hello?
- Who is it?
- Howard, it's Juan.
Juan.
Juan, right. Yeah.
We had an appointment, right? Yeah.
I remember that. Look...
I've got a hell of a cold in here.
A hell of a cold.
So why don't you just take
a seat out there?
Cos you know,
I don't want to get you sick.
I'd never forgive myself if I got you sick.
I don't want to get you sick. I don't want to...
Thank you.
OK, Howard, I'm sitting.
I've brought along our accountings.
Now, Pan Am is trading
at 13 and five-eighths.
TWA at four and a quarter...
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
We both know I'm not gonna sell TWA.
Besides, you couldn't afford her anyway.
Our domestic routes alone
are worth more than twice Pan Am.
Well, considering our stock
is trading at three times yours,
I find that a dubious claim, Howard.
What I...
What I mean is,
you have no domestic routes. All right?
I mean, you get TWA,
you span the globe.
Now, I'm not gonna sell,
and you know I'm not gonna sell.
Here's the point.
Owen Brewster works for you.
Howard, I didn't elect Senator Brewster.
We can thank the voters of Maine for that.
Now, if I appear at his hearings, Juan,
it could get nasty.
Real nasty for all of us.
Well, I think considerably more so for you.
While the good people of America
were losing sons at Anzio,
you produced a dirty movie
and built airplanes that don't fly.
Well, that's just not fair, is it?
I mean, the XF-11 flew quite well
for an hour and 45 minutes.
I mean, I wish you were up there with me,
Juan. It was exhilarating.
Be that as it may, you still have
to answer for the Spruce Goose.
It's called the Hercules.
- And it will fly, goddamn it.
- I certainly hope so.
The American people deserve something
for their $13 million.
I won't sell TWA.
I won't.
I know that, Howard.
I know that.
But I'm going to get it anyway.
You're going to default on
your loan from Equitable
after Senator Brewster
destroys your reputation
and you can't find additional capital
for the airline.
The hearings will also show
Hughes Aircraft to be mismanaged
and incompetent,
and it will go bankrupt, too.
But you won't be insolvent.
You'll still have Toolco.
Perhaps you'll head back to Houston
to rebuild your empire.
I rather hope you do.
By that time,
Pan Am will have bought TWA
and painted all those
magnificent Connies blue and white.
So when you do return,
it will be on a Pan Am plane.
Well...
You seem to have me
in a corner here, buddy.
Not a position in which
I'm very comfortable.
I think you're gonna be less comfortable
at Senator Brewster's hearings.
Very public, Howard.
Lots of cameras and newsmen.
I understand you're not
particularly fond of crowds.
Perhaps we should spare you that.
Well, thank you for your concern, Juan.
I find that
very moving.
It's been a real pleasure.
Noah will see you back to the airport.
Now you...
You fly safe.
Thank you, Howard.
And you take care of that cold.
Don't you worry.
I certainly will.
Bye-bye.
If you let him appear at those hearings,
the whole world will see what he's become.
People should remember him as he was.
He'll have a subpoena in three days
to appear in Washington.
If you can get him out of there by then.
Mr Hughes?
I don't have any shoes.
- Could you get me some shoes?
- Shoes.
Yeah.
How nice of you to dress for me.
Can I come in?
Yeah. Yeah.
You can come in.
Thank you for coming.
Now, let's get a drink.
Wait, wait, wait, honey.
You can't move. You can't move.
You're safe here. You're in the germ-free
zone now. You understand?
- I'll take my chances.
- Oh, no. No, no, honey.
Wait, wait, wait.
Love what you've done with the place.
Now, let me look at you.
When do you go to Washington?
A week.
No, no.
Just under a week.
I don't know the date today,
but I have to be... I have to be...
All right, take it easy.
There's nothing there, Howard.
Mm.
You know, I...
I see things.
I know, baby.
Rinse your face off now.
Put your hands in the water
and wash off the soap.
I'm right here.
I'm not going anywhere.
- Does that look clean to you?
- Nothing's clean, Howard.
But we do our best, right?
Yeah.
- What do you think?
- I look all right?
You look great.
- Will you marry me?
- You're too crazy for me.
I gotta go, baby.
OK.
Thanks.
You'd do it for me.
Hi, Howard.
How are you doing?
The Committee will come to order.
Ladies and gentlemen, I must insist that we
maintain quiet during these proceedings.
All right, Mr Hughes,
will you stand to be sworn?
Do you solemnly swear that in the matter
now pending before this committee,
you will tell the truth, the whole truth and
nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Pardon me for speaking loudly,
but I understand
you have some difficulty hearing.
That's quite all right. Everybody knows
I'm deaf. I'm not gonna try to hide it.
Mr Hughes,
it is the intention of this committee...
Mr Hughes has a statement.
All right. All right. You may proceed
with this statement, Mr Hughes.
Mr Hughes, do you have a statement?
I'm gonna attempt to be honest here.
My reputation's being destroyed, so I might
as well lay the cards on the table.
Senator Brewster,
if you hadn't have gone too far overboard,
if you hadn't have put
the red-hot iron in my side,
I might have been willing to take a
shellacking in this publicity spree of yours.
I might have been willing to sit back
and take a certain amount of abuse.
Simply because, well...
Well, I am only a private citizen,
whereas you are a senator,
with all sorts of powers.
But I think this goddamn circus
has gone on long enough.
That's quite sufficient.
You have called me a liar, sir, in the press.
You have called me a liar
and a thief and a war profiteer.
- The witness will restrain his comments...
- Why not tell the truth for once, Senator?
Why not tell the truth
that this investigation was really born
on the day that TWA
first decided to fly to Europe?
On the day that TWA
first invaded Juan Trippe's territory.
Sit down, Mr Hughes.
On the day that TWA first challenged
the generally accepted theory
that only Juan Trippe's
great Pan American Airways
- had the sacred right to fly the Atlantic.
- You are not here to make a speech.
I asked for silence.
I asked for quiet in this room...
We have in our possession receipts
in the amount of $170,000
acquired from Mr John Meyer.
Mr Meyer works for you,
does he not?
- He does.
- And what is his official title?
Well, I don't exactly know, Senator.
A lot of people work for me.
Can you explain why your press agent
would pay out more than a $170,000
to representatives of
the United States Air Force?
I don't know.
I suppose you'd have to ask him, Senator.
- Well, would you produce him?
- Produce him?
- Will you cause him to appear?
- Well, Senator,
you had John Meyer on
the stand for three days last week.
Well, be that as it may, we would like him
to reappear. Would you ask him to return?
No, I don't think I will.
Will you try to have him return?
Well, no, I don't think I'll try.
You don't think you'll try?
No, I don't think so.
The $170,000 paid out to the Air Force
in the form of hotel suites,
TWA stock,
female companionship...
Now, is it possible
that these could be considered bribes?
I suppose you could call them that, yes.
Would you repeat that?
I said, I suppose you could
consider them bribes, yes.
Well, would you like
to explain that, Mr Hughes?
Well, I'm afraid you don't know how
the aviation business works, Senator.
See, wining and dining Air Force
dignitaries is common in our business.
It's because we all want the big contracts.
All the major aircraft companies do it.
Now, I don't know whether it's a good
system or not. I just know it's not illegal.
You, Senator, you are the lawmaker.
If you pass a law that states
no one can entertain Air Force officers,
well, hell,
I'd be happy to abide by it.
Senator Brewster,
your story is a pack of lies,
and I can tear it apart
if allowed to cross-examine you.
- We're not gonna have this bickering...
- Yes.
Somewhere between two and five hundred,
if you'll just let me...
Now, if you believe that
because of your great wealth and power,
you can intimidate
any member of this committee,
I want to advise you that you're mistaken.
- Now, submit your questions to the chair.
- Now, I'll put this very simply.
On February 12th at the Mayflower Hotel,
did you, or did you not, tell me
that if I were to sell TWA to Pan Am
that this entire investigation
would be called off?
No, I did not. I have asked you repeatedly
to submit your questions in writing.
- How long have you known Juan Trippe?
- I've known Mr Trippe for some time now,
and that's not the question here.
Is it not true that Juan Trippe donated
$ 20,000 to your last campaign?
I mean, he spoke to me
as if you worked for him.
All right.
I have a personal friendship
with Mr Trippe...
Is it true that you accept free tickets
from Pan Am so you can circle the globe
- in support of your CAB bill?
- No, no, it is not true.
Well, who wrote that bill, Senator?
Who actually wrote the CAB bill?
The actual words in the bill,
did you write them?
This is not how these hearings
are gonna be conducted, Mr Hughes.
I have it right here.
Maybe it'll refresh your memory.
"Bill S-987,
to amend the Civil Aeronautics Act."
Now, you introduced
this bill to the Senate.
Lot of words.
You write all of them?
- Did you write any of them, Senator?
- Now look, Mr Hughes.
Now, this entire bill
was written by Pan Am executives
and designed to give that airline
a monopoly on international travel.
And you've been flogging this bill
all around the world on their behalf,
have you not?
I have duties that take me
all over the world, Mr Hughes.
Well, what the hell does a senator
from Maine need to visit Peru for?
I was seeking outlets
for our trade goods.
Buy a lot of lobsters down there,
do they?
Senator Brewster, how many times
have you visited Juan Trippe's office
in New York in the last three months?
Would you like me to tell you, Senator?
All right, this has gone on long enough.
Juan Trippe is a great American.
His airline has advanced the cause
of commercial aviation in this country
for decades.
Juan Trippe is a patriot.
Juan Trippe is not a man
who is interested in making money.
Well, I'm sure his stockholders
will be happy to hear that.
I'm telling you,
we're gonna clear this room.
This is James McNamara
speaking to you
from aboard the Howard Hughes 2000-ton
flying boat, the world's largest aircraft.
This is the sky giant
which has prompted Congress
to investigate
the war contracts of Mr Hughes.
Today, before boarding the craft,
Mr Hughes told newsmen
that this test would
be solely a taxi experiment.
He said he didn't know
what might happen.
He pointed out that the mammoth
flying plywood shell
might ship some water under high-speed
taxi pressure. He said definitely, however,
that he would not take the craft into the air
until next spring.
The thin man from Culver City pronounced
the craft an unknown quantity.
Hi, boys.
All right, none of that, now.
None of that.
As we speak to you, we're about
five feet in back of Mr Hughes,
and we are looking through
one of the side windows in the cockpit.
Professor, why don't you
come on up front here?
In other words,
we are 30 feet high in this aircraft.
Strap yourself in right there.
You ought to be able to see just great.
...just how gigantic this ship is.
Huge crowds jammed
the surrounding shoreline this morning...
All right, boys.
Let's fire it up.
One's good.
Two's good.
Three's good.
Four's good.
Five's good.
Six is good.
Seven's good.
Eight's good.
- Advancing master throttles.
As you probably know by now,
I have to do a great deal of screaming
here into my microphone.
- Prop start up.
- Understood.
- Lowering 15 degrees of flaps.
Howard.
She's gotta hit 70
to have any kind of chance.
Yeah, I know. I know.
I might add that it's a beautiful day over
here off the coast of Southern California.
Crystal blue skies, a warm sun...
25 miles per hour.
30.
35.
One would think these eight power plants
might shake the mighty craft to pieces.
Take it easy, Howard.
...and certainly, it's holding up...
- 40.
- Throttling back for starboard turn 180.
Throttling back for starboard turn 180.
The flight crew itself consists of four men.
Mr Hughes, however, has added 11
maintenance men to this maiden taxi test,
stationed at various places
throughout the ship,
checking points of stress and strain.
How does she sound, Odie?
Sounds good, Howard.
- Professor.
- Yes?
Would you do me a favour?
Would you take a look out that window
there and tell me what the wind is doing?
I would say that we have
a 15-knot wind.
Would you call that a headwind,
Professor?
I would, Mr Hughes.
I must insist that we maintain silence.
We must have quiet during
these proceedings.
All right, Mr Hughes,
will you stand to be sworn?
Mr Hughes,
did you receive $43 million
to manufacture one hundred XF-11
spy planes for the United States Air Force?
I did.
How many functional planes did you
deliver to the United States Air Force?
None.
Would you lean a little closer
to the microphone, sir?
None.
Did you receive $13 million to manufacture
a prototype of a flying boat
known as the Hercules?
I did.
And did you deliver that plane?
I did not.
So, by your admission in this chamber,
Mr Hughes,
you have received $56 million
from the United States government
for planes you never delivered.
That is correct.
Well, excuse me for asking, Mr Hughes,
but where did all that money go?
Well, it went into the plane, Senator,
and a lot more.
More? Do tell, Mr Hughes.
What other larcenies did you commit?
I mean, I put my money
into the plane, Senator. My money.
- See, the thing is...
- Mr Hughes,
your personal finances are not...
Let him speak.
All right, proceed, Mr Hughes.
See, the thing is,
I care very much about aviation.
It has been the great joy of my life. That's
why I put my own money into these planes.
And I have lost millions, Senator Brewster.
And I'll go on losing millions.
It's just what I do.
Now, if I've lost a lot of the government's
money during the war,
well, I hope folks
will put that into perspective.
You see, more than 60 other airplanes,
ordered from such firms as Lockheed,
Douglas, Northrop and Boeing,
never saw action, either.
In all, more than $800 million was spent
during the war on planes that never flew.
Over six billion on other weapons
that were never delivered.
Yet Hughes Aircraft, with her 56 million,
is the only firm
under investigation here today.
Now, I cannot help but think
that has a little more to do with TWA
than planes that did not fly.
- I think you've made your point...
- One second.
Senator Brewster, I have one more thing
to say here to this committee,
and that has to do with the Hercules.
Now, I am supposed to be many things
which are not complimentary.
I am supposed to be capricious.
I have been called a playboy.
I've even been called an eccentric.
But I do not believe that I have
the reputation of being a liar.
Now, needless to say, the Hercules
was a monumental undertaking.
It is the largest plane ever built.
It's over five storeys tall,
with a wingspan longer than a football field.
That's more than a city block.
Now, I put the sweat of my life into this
thing, I got my reputation all rolled up in it,
and I have stated several times
that if the Hercules fails to fly
I will leave this country
and never come back.
And I mean it.
Now, Senator Brewster,
you can subpoena me. You can arrest me.
You can even claim that I've folded up
and taken a run-out powder, but, well...
I've had just about enough
of this nonsense. Good afternoon.
I had to do it.
Mr Hughes. Mr Hughes.
I'd love to see the Hercules in the air.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Excuse us.
Excuse us, please. Thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
- Switch it off.
- The hearings aren't over yet.
The hearings are over.
The airline bill
will be defeated in the Senate.
TWA will begin flights
from New York to Paris.
Then on to Moscow, to Japan,
to Hawaii, to Los Angeles...
to New York.
Fuck.
- Power coming up.
Howard Hughes has just alerted us.
He has asked everyone to hold on.
Tremendous horsepower picking up.
- Let me hear it, Odie.
- 25 miles per hour.
30.
Here we go.
35.
...has moved up to 25. It's 30.
- It's 35.
- 40.
As he pushes the throttle, it's 40.
- 45.
- 45. More throttle. It's 45.
- 50.
- 50. It's 50 over a choppy sea.
- 55.
- 55. 55.
- 60.
- More throttle. It's 60.
- 65.
- 70.
- It's 70.
- 75.
- It's 75.
And something momentarily
has just cut out.
I believe we are airborne.
We are airborne, ladies and gentlemen.
I don't believe that Howard Hughes
meant this to be. I don't know.
And we're really up in the air.
We're really up in the air.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Hughes mammoth aircraft
has flown this afternoon
in Los Angeles Harbour.
It certainly looks, at this moment,
that Howard Hughes
will be around the United States
for quite some time to come.
What we must understand
is that technologies like these
are the way of the future.
That's enough questions for now.
TWA and Hughes Aircraft are delighted
to have you come here
and witness this wonderful sight.
- Excuse us for just a second.
- Sorry.
- So you feel like going to Paris?
- Now?
TWA is starting up flights to Europe.
Thought I might pilot the first one myself.
Ought to be some fun.
- Lots of good shopping in Paris.
- I'll buy you anything you want.
You can buy me dinner.
How about that?
Dinner, then.
We got a date?
OK, baby, you got a date.
I'll be back in a second.
But don't you go anywhere, now. I mean it.
Al right, listen, boys. Something new. Jet
airplanes. You know anything about jets?
- No. But it sounds expensive.
- It will be. But we got to get started.
Come on, walk with me.
Whoever can start utilising jet technology
on commercial airliners
is gonna win all the marbles,
you understand?
Odie, what do you know
about the science?
I know a little. I can work something
to show you. Basic turbine stuff.
Noah, who are those fellows?
Do they work for me?
Everybody works for you, Howard.
Lockheed worked on the F-80,
so let's get Bob Gross on the phone.
- See if he can help us out.
- OK. What, now?
Of course, now. We gotta get into it.
Jets are gonna be the way of the future.
It's 4:30.
I talked to Bob last week.
He's in New York, so it's 7:30.
He won't be in the office.
We'll get Nancy
to figure out what hotel he's at.
The question is,
do you want a telephone call
or do you want
some kind of meeting right away?
We want a meeting,
don't we, Howard?
All right. Well, do you want me to bring
him out here tomorrow, then, Howard?
- The way of the future.
- Howard?
- Howard.
- The way of the future.
- Let's take a walk, Howard.
- Give me a hand here, will you, Glenn?
The way of the future.
The way of the future. The way
of the future. The way of the future.
The way of the future.
The way of the future. The way
of the future. The way of the future.
The way of the future.
The way of the future. The way...
All right, stay here. I'll be right back.
Do you understand, Howard?
The way of the future.
Guard the door. I'll get a doctor.
No one sees him like this.
The way of the future. The way
of the future. The way of the future.
The way of the fut...
The way of the future.
You are not safe.
When I grow up, I'm gonna fly
the fastest planes ever built,
make the biggest movies ever,
and be the richest man in the world.
The way of the future.