The competition for Arirang's 5th Master
will now begin.
Final Episode
Go Joon Young and
Song Yeon Woo,
Arirang's 5th Master contenders,
you may now start the competition.
The mullet will now be prepared.
Where are you running away to?
Go back.
Go and protect your disciple
and your position.
I'll take care of it.
Aren't you curious?
About who'll win?
Sometimes I wondered.
Twenty two years ago,
if you hadn't done that
and competed fairly, who would've won?
You're lying.
Naturally, you think you would have.
The only person who thinks that is you.
You've never considered me your rival.
You've always
looked down on me.
I didn't want to be caught,
that I want to beat Seol Hee.
I want to be Master.
Then
starting now, the judges
will taste the food.
Both of you worked hard.
Explain your dish.
Though it was only for a short time,
the Arirang that I've seen
has many different expressions.
The kitchen staff's expressions,
the seasonal changes of the menu,
and even the customers who come here
every day was different.
During a few months it's like that
so the 100 years of its existence,
it's hard to express it all in one dish.
So if you can't express it all in one dish?
That's why the dish I chose is
carp with jeolpyeon stew.
In this one bowl,
including beef, fish, various vegetables,
and the jeolpyeon instead of rice
were all arranged harmoniously
then with a broth seasoned
with traditional soy sauce
I made a stew.
I wanted to express the integrity
that has protected Arirang
for more than 100 years
amidst fierce strife
in this one bowl.
So
Arirang's long tradition,
fragrance, and sentiment...
All of those things
are contained in this one dish?
My dish is
five colored steamed carp
made with 8 ingredients.
Beef, ginseng, sea cucumber, abalone,
shitake mushroom, bamboo shoot...
With such valuable ingredients
I stuffed the carp's stomach.
Color,
texture,
and taste
all are magnificent.
But if you use such expensive ingredients,
will anyone order it?
Will anyone order it?
There probably won't be.
The expensive price is a problem but
it is also hard to find such
high quality ingredients.
Eight jewels,
like the 5 colored steamed carp made with
8 ingredients is too precious to eat.
Something that has been
prepared with the utmost care.
That
to me, is Korean Cuisine's image.
Yes.
That's so.
In this dish, I wanted to
express the preciousness of Korean Cuisine
that Arirang will protect
for another 100 years
to everyone.
And that is what I,
for 10 years at Arirang,
have seen
felt,
and learned.
Then
while the judges are
discussing their opinions
we ask the two contenders
to wait off the stage.
Seriously..
Stop looking so upset.
Excuse me, but I am only driving because you
complained so much about your heavy bags.
So why don't you just close that mouth.
This transfer was decided suddenly!
Still, it probably wasn't
decided this morning!
Are you not going
to call Joon Young?
If you really love someone
you sometimes have to erase
everything from your head
Where I need to be standing right now.
So you're just going to disapear?
That's what's wrong with you
If you like someone you
should stay by her side.
I also want to live
carefreely and freely just like you
You can't.
You start living like me, I'm
just going to get rid of you
No matter what name you choose to go by
I'm going to keep on
living as Go Joon Young.
The Joon Young who lived
wholeheartly and well
I sincerely love her
No matter what my name is
the fact that she's Dad and
Mom's daughter won't change.
You don't know, do you?
If someone who has
everything is too dignified,
how uncomfortable it makes people feel.
The decision has been made.
Regardless of who won, you can
acknowledge the winner, right?
You expressed the present image of Arirang
so well.
Thank you.
But
the Master that Arirang now needs is
someone who can lead Arirang
into the next 100 years
more than someone who can protect its past.
In Joo,
you are Arirang's 5th Master.
You did well.
Why are you crying?
There'll be so much more to cry about.
It's because she's so happy.
Aren't you being too greedy?
Tears should be conceded to the loser.
Congratulations.
Alright.
Let go of it all.
The venom in your heart and
hatred and greed.
Cry it all away.
You did well, my daughter.
Thank you for doing well, my daughter.
Why are you hiding here?
If I'm near
Mom won't be able to
congratulate her fully.
You're taking this better than I thought.
Truthfully, I already knew the results.
No matter how much I try,
her 22 years of experience
and passion for Arirang
can't be beaten.
Are you jealous?
I'm envious.
But, I like it now.
Being able to cook as much as I want
and live freely.
The title "Master"
does not fit me well.
Truthfully, I knew your skill level
when I ate that lunch you packed for me.
You need to improve a lot more.
You're so great at comforting.
You'd improve if you went abroad
and learned from a great teacher.
A great teacher?
I'm not joking.
"The potatoes are overcooked.
The carrots are soggy."
You'd scold me every day!
I don't want a teacher like that.
Hey, hey!
I'll go in by myself.
True, it's not like we're never
going to see each other again.
Get inside.
In Woo.
Alright, I know.
I'll go check on your grandmother
while wishing her good morning!
If she doesn't look well I'll
immediately take her to a hospital.
And twice a keep go and keep her company.
That's it, right?
I didn't get anything wrong?
There's a person who lost
her life 22 year ago
while protecting Joon Young in the ocean.
Not her foster father?
She's related to us, too.
Who?
In Joo's mother.
Yes, Mom.
Because I was nervous all morning,
I'm a bit tired.
Today, congratulate In Joo a lot.
Alright. Thank you.
Joon Young,
you did really well today.
Even if you're not the Master, to me
you are a disciple I'm proud of.
Yes.
Take care.
1 new message.
Jae Ha
I'm leaving now.
Maybe I'll return after 2 or 3 years.
Ha In Joo, our little...
If you are crying when I return,
you are going to get in big trouble.
Live courageously.
My idol, Go Joon Young, fighting!
Thank you, and
I'm very sorry.
Hyung
loved you a lot.
Hyung is in a lot of pain
because of you.
And I
can't forgive you.
I'm sorry, my child.
I'm sorry Ji Yoon.
My child..I'm so sorry
The person who saved our
Joon Young is In Joo's Mom?
I'm don't know for certain, but
that day In Joo's Mom
fell of the cruise ship that we were on.
Then, while trying to rescue
Joon Young, In Joo's Mom...
Even if it wasn't for Joon Young,
she would have left this world anyway.
Until now,
have you taken care of it all by yourself?
At that time, I promised her
that I'd take good care of her.
Nice and pretty In Joo
is dong well.
Next time, we'll all come together.
All this time,
our In Joo suffered all alone
because of me.
I'm sorry.
And
thank you for saving our Joon Young,
really
I'm so thankful.
Why are you smiling?
What are you so happy about?
You intended to lose from the beginning?
No. I really wanted to win.
I wanted to win by cooking
for the first time since I was born.
Honestly, it was a little difficult.
In Joo had spent time at Arirang,
and she has special love
for it unlike myself.
Please acknowledge her, Grandma.
She only thought about
Arirang all this time.
She probably saw the world differently
than you from the beginning.
What are you going to do now?
Are you just...
I could learn more about Korean cusine and
traditions from people at Arirang. But,
I was happier cooking in Udo.
You were using natural ingredients
from the vast sea to
cook however you wanted.
It was greedy of me to hold you here.
I understand.
No. I'm coming for sure this month.
I never forget.
There are still things to be done in Korea.
Sure, don't worry. You can count on me.
Are you committing fraud?
No. It's not a fraud. We'll definitely go,
and show the best cooking within this month.
Not yet, I told you that.
Then, when? After you lose all your fans?
You're scary.
I surrender unconditionally today.
Where are you running away to again?
Look carefully, Haemil's fan site...
stopped.
President Baek...
Breaking news. Sanarae President acknowledged in the
Haemil incident that the fault was entirely hers.
President Baek Seol Hee announced she apologizes to her ideal son
Kim Do Young and will seek forgiveness to conclude the incident.
Jane.
Is something wrong?
You don't look good.
I...have something to ask you.
That's why I asked you to meet me.
Haemil, I mean
Kim Do Yoon - do you love him?
If you can't answer me decisively,
please let go of Do Yoon.
Am I interfering with his life?
No. You saved his life.
While he was loving you,
he was able to smile genuinely,
cry.
He became human.
But Chef Kim Do Yoon
doesn't have time to wait.
He made public his dishonourable family history and if
people know about a breach of contract because of a woman,
It willl be difficult to recover.
Say that again.
Who is coming?
Kim Do Yoon?
Yes.
Tell him I have an urgent
phone call, have him wait.
Yes.
Haemil's come to my home.
Should I be crying because I'm so honored?
Are you going out?
There's a Female CEO dinner meeting today.
If you have something to
say, say it quickly and go.
What?
Since I confirmed you're
alive, I'm going to go.
You thought that this Baek Seol Hee
would be lying in bed?
You haven't heard yet?
For the first time in 22
years, I beat Sung Do Hee.
I heard.
Congratulations.
You need to go out, right?
I'll leave.
Ji Yoon,
is my son. Not just your brother.
Stop being arrogant and
let him rest in peace.
I told you I don't want anything.
Your son told me I must.
It..tastes good.
Are you mad?
I won't hate Mom anymore,
so don't scold me so much.
Ji Yoon ssi.
Kim Ji Yoon ssi.
Kim Ji Yoon.
I'm going to go to that girl now.
Since you two are close, speak well of me.
I told you I was busy.
I'm hungry.
What kind of chef is always hungry?
Go cook.
Right, you have a lot of money. Go buy it.
I don't want to.
Let's eat together.
Aren't you hot?
Are you kidding?
I'm so hot I could die.
Then take it off.
What if there are reporters?
You think the reporters will recognize you?
Things have finally calmed down
between you and President Baek.
You'll be in a difficult
situation if there's a scandal.
You stand out more like that.
You'll probably cause the scandal.
Get out.
That person?
No way..
I think that's him.
I really think that's him.
Who's the woman he's with?
Is that his girlfriend?
I'm so jealous.
I have a picture, I think it's him.
Go and ask.
I'm right, right?
Excuse me. You're Haemil,
the star chef, right?
No, I'm not.
This is you.
You said you were hungry.
Choose.
I'm not hungry.
There's nothing I want to eat on the menu.
Eat alone.
Let go.
You said there's nothing you want to eat.
I'll cook for you.
What do you think you're doing?
If you don't want to get
more attention, sit still.
If he continues to delay it
might be the end for Do Yoon.
Go Joon Young-
Wow, it's amazing that I can
see Haemil cooking here!
It looks delicious. Can
you make one for me?
No, I can't make anymore.
This dish is one of a kind.
One of a kind?
Are you proposing?
Proposing by cooking.
So cool!
Who is she?
Incredible!
I'm going to go first.
Just grant me one wish.
Now, I-
I'm going to go to you.
You... just don't run away too much.
That's the first time
anyone's said that to me.
"I know you well. I'm
comfortable around you."
"Thank you."
This bastard!
I take back what I said about running away.
You, you come to me too.
I'm having a hard time.
Go Joon Young,
I'm sorry.
We need to talk.
I'm tired.
Why?
Because the great Haemil
proposed by cooking,
but was rejected?
"Star Chef Haemil's ordeal"
It's ranked first on the search engines.
This is Kim Do Yoon's schedule.
Starts next week.
BBC's cooking program,
Haemil's Cooking School,
community service projects.
And a World Tour starting year-end.
Let's talk later.
There's nothing to discuss,
the contracts have been signed.
Jane!
It's your decision of course.
But before you refuse,
you'll need to declare bankruptcy.
I met Joon Young
and asked her to let you go.
You,
Do you know how selfish
your love is right now?
You have to go anyway.
Then what about Joon Young?
She finally met her family.
And what about her dreams?
Don't delude yourself.
Chasing and pushing ahead is not love.
A worthless man who can't
even take care of his own work
definitely has no right.
I'm sorry.
I would like Haemil
to cook foods which can be enjoyed
by all the people in the world
instead of cooking food
for just one person.
I will..
You really struggled.
Master Sun, please come up to the stage.
Please applaud her.
Sung Do Hee, the 4th Master,
will present Arirang's lotus medal herself.
All the time I spent at Arirang,
my dream
has been Sung Do Hee, the 4th Master.
I will now continue her goal and
dream of a precious and priceless
Arirang.
To all those who have stayed by my side:
Master Sun,
our kitchen staff,
the smell of the fermenting sauces,
the fragrance of the herbs in the garden,
and everything of Arirang.
I will keep in my heart
and make an Arirang which
will last another 100 years.
Thank you.
It's already started.
You should hurry inside.
You acted so high and mighty.
How does it feel to lose?
Because you haven't changed much,
I like that a lot.
You never miss
someone's pain.
I'll take that as a compliment.
Right.
Kim Do Yoon, or Haemil, that rot-
that prosperous child
has left.
Thank you!
How worried I was that you
two might get married..
That's great
You threw away your own good fortune.
To him, besides his own brother,
you were first!
Since he's lived his whole life
keeping himself locked up.
If he gets hurt again,
it'll be the end forever.
Well, for me it's fine.
I'm going
Star Chef Haemil, returning
to England alone
Customer, do you want a ride?
Hey, I'm saying don't you want a ride?
[1 year later]
Mom! Today's the day you're
opening the GeumChungJang, right?
I'm out of red pepper
paste and soybean paste.
Can I drop by to get some?
You only want me when you need something?
Am I like that? You know
I'm very busy, Mom.
Anyway, over the weekend, I was going to...
Mom, I'm driving right now.
I'll contact you later.
Kim Do Yoon.
Did you call Joon Young?
No.
Well, maybe it's over if you haven't
been in touch over the whole year.
How about me?
Just organize Saturday's Hong Kong
Food Fair Schedule and bring it to me.
Here...
"Ha Joon Young's Basic
Korean Cuisine Recipes."
She published this with the International
Korean Cuisine Foundation.
Isnt it incredible?
There's more. Apparently there was news that
fake Korean food was prevailing in China.
Joon Young flew over right away
and picketed alone saying,
"Correct the fake name,
cook with Korean recipes!"
She created such a fuss.
Isn't that so like Joon Young?
A demonstration for
overseas chefs every week
and she even published a book.
She does more than that.
She is busier than me.
You knew eveything already?
Enjoy!
Yes.
Enjoy your food.
Are you feeling better?
You've gotten prettier.
Please enjoy your food.
Elder, enjoy your food
We'll enjoy it.
I'll do it.
Yes.
Hey, I'm a CEO, too.
Our restaurant is very busy.
Alright! I'll come soon!
You're going to wear out your cell phone.
What was it... That kitchen
youngster has returned to Korea.
Did you get a call from him?
Why would he contact me?
I have nothing to do with him.
I told you from the beginning
that he was not for you.
Just looking at him, he
looks like he's not steady.
That's why I liked my son-in-law Choi...
Kim Ahjussi!
What are you doing at this hour?
Perhaps, did you quit?
Work was too hard there.
Ahjussi! I introduced you
there only a short time ago.
Can I just stay here, and help out?
Nope. Our motto is
only people who work can eat. You remember?
You can pay back today's free meal.
After you eat, please wash all
those dirty dishes thoroughly.
Aren't you asking a bit much for a meal?
Do you want me to count how
many meals you had here?
Alright. Alright. I'll
wash them thoroughly.
Go find a job quickly.
You'll get really tired
if you stay around her.
She's really tough.
Yes?
Son...
What is it now?
Don't worry, my son.
I'm making a schedule without
interfering with your health.
How long are you staying in Korea?
Can you ask how he feels about
finishing the last show?
I'm leaving tomorrow.
You're really leaving tomorrow?
I told you to stop by Sanarae this time.
Oh, really?
Omo... omo
I'll do it.
How did our Head Chef change like this?
This is betrayal and bias.
Why? It looks nice.
Right. It looks really nice.
That's right. After they went out,
the kitchen atmosphere
became heartwarming also.
Heartwarming?!?
More like chaotic!
Sous Chef, when are you going to feed us
noodles? (When are you going to get married.)
Ask my Do Shik ssi.
Do Shik ssi, when are we going to eat nood-
You're on duty. Anything not pertaining
to work is off limits. Do you understand?
Do you understand?!
Who is making our Head Chef
to raise his voice like that?
Ah, Master Chef!
Today we're opening the GeumChungJang.
Please prepare for what we
discussed without any mistakes.
Yes.
You heard what Master Chef said.
You have just one hour left.
Everyone let's get to work
It's delicious.
You've done well.
You worked hard.
Thank you
Thank you.
Thanks for working hard.
You really became a star now, huh?
Anyways, where is CEO Go?