[Jenna] Previously on Backstage...
May I introduce one of Keaton's
most famous alumni, Maria Schiller.
[Carly] You're the reason Maria got fired.
Or did you forget?
- You kissed my best friend.
- You kissed a backup dancer.
Will you, Julie Maslany,
- let me take you out?
- [Julie] I'd love that.
Are you okay?
No. It's just this.
Sorry, I can't.
We should do a duet at CAMDAs.
Why should Beckett and Carly
be the only ones?
- [Sasha] Because they're the best.
- [Jenna] We can be as good as them.
I can't.
[Jenna]
"Manic Muscle Transformation Cycle"?
What is this junk?
What is he eating?
You don't know anything about it.
I just did that lift
for the first time ever.
I'm not stopping now.
[man] Hope you've all had
a great morning, folks,
and are enjoying the first half
of the CAMDA qualifiers.
As of now, Appleton School of the Arts
sits in first place
with a combined score of 63.
Keaton is right on their tails
with 61 points
and Tumpane rounds out
the top three with 56.
On behalf of all of Keaton,
thank you to our officials
and good luck to all of our competitors.
["Kings and Queens" playing]
♪ Moving through the crowd
Dancing, singing loud ♪
♪ Out there we'll find our place
Tilt our heads and wear the crown ♪
♪ Step into the scene
On the edge of dreams ♪
♪ I know we'll rule this place
Once we pretend to be ♪
♪ King and queens
King and queens ♪
♪ King and queens... ♪
Hey, um, nice... nice sparkles.
"Nice sparkles"?
[sighs]
Well, good luck today.
[footsteps approaching]
Ooh, what was that about?
- Are you two getting back together?
- No. Definitely not.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say you were nervous.
My stomach is a mess.
They say that's a sign of good luck,
right?
- Whatever you need to tell yourself.
- [Julie sighs]
You have nothing to be nervous about.
You're a defending champion.
Sure. But I've never competed in dance.
You're Julie Maslany, the one and only.
There's nothing you can't do.
Except maybe sing.
[chuckles]
Thanks, Scarlett.
I really needed to hear that.
[sighs]
[Sasha] Do you smell that, Jenna?
Sometimes my stomach
gets a bit nervous the day of competition.
No. Not that. Victory.
I can smell it.
We're gonna own these noobs.
[growls] Whoa!
Wow, there's a lot of "whoa!"
- Sure everything's all right with you?
- Oh, yeah, better than okay.
Seriously, J,
no matter what happens today,
I'm so glad we're dancing together.
I really needed this.
This is me.
See you on the dance floor, señorita.
[speaks in Spanish]
Hyah! Whoo!
["Spark" playing]
♪ My eyes are open
But I cannot see ♪
♪ And I'm up and walking
Still feels like a dream ♪
♪ Until our eyes adjust, I guess
We're only feeling in the darkness ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
- ♪ We just need a spark ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh ♪
- ♪ To light up the dark ♪
♪ I can feel you with me
I can feel you with me ♪
- ♪ We just need a spark ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh ♪
- ♪ To light up the dark ♪
♪ I can feel you with me
I can feel you with me ♪
♪ We just need a spark ♪
[man on PA system] Strings competition
has been moved to Music Room 212.
That's the strings competition
Thank you.
[muffled music playing on headset]
Give it up already.
You need to learn when enough is enough.
I just need to listen to it one more time.
You've been tweaking
the same section of reverb
for the past two days.
- It's mixed, mastered. Export already.
- Kit...
[giggling] Maybe.
Bianca, hey, you look stunning today.
- [door closing]
- [laptop clicks]
[sighs]
You're right. I need to learn
when enough is enough.
- The song, I exported it. It's done.
- But I...
You're right. It's done.
[clicks]
Aren't you glad we're in production?
No weird warm-ups, no crazy costumes.
No... whatever that is.
[snorts]
So judges' results won't be posted
till the end of the day.
What do you want to do until then?
I mean, we could go see
what Bianca is up to.
No. Not that.
- But you...
- No, Jax.
[sighs]
I got an idea.
[upbeat music playing]
Hi, excuse me.
Julie Maslany.
Do I have time to run to the bathroom?
[paper rustling]
No.
It's okay. It's probably just nerves.
[audience clapping, cheering]
- Ms. Maria.
- Oh, Julie!
[chuckles] My gosh.
Oh, I shouldn't be seen talking
to the competition.
- Right, I'm sorry. I'll leave you...
- No.
I'm kidding.
- How are you?
- Great.
- Super nervous.
- Mm-hm.
- But great.
- Ah.
Oh, I'm sorry. Julie, this is Katy.
- Katy this is Ju...
- You're Julie Maslany.
I've heard so much about you.
You went to Juilliard's summer program.
How did you...?
Visual artist turned Juilliard-worthy
dancer in like, five minutes?
You're kind of a legend.
You must be insanely talented.
More like insanely lucky.
I saw you dance just now.
You have amazing feet.
- [Katy] And she's nice too?
- [chuckles]
Most of these girls won't even look
at another dancer during competition.
I'm not sure if I'm supposed to say this,
but good luck.
Same to you.
The judges are having
a five-minute water break.
- If you need to use the restroom, go now.
- I'm good.
I'm not nervous anymore.
[sighs]
Twenty six... [grunts] 27, twenty...
[yelps] Agh!
Here.
Cramping.
No, thank you.
Come on, dude, you need water.
I said I'm good.
Sometimes, body builders
don't drink water before a competition.
Dehydration shows off muscle definition.
But Sasha's a dancer,
and dancers need water.
I've worked way too hard
to lose this definition now.
[grunts]
[huffs]
["Fall In" playing]
♪ Is something holding you back? ♪
It's never too late for second chances.
For me and Julie, I'm pretty sure it is.
[chuckles] Let's be honest.
Your chances were slim to begin with.
I finally figured it out.
The break-up with Alya
had more to do with her
than it did with me.
You deserve a fresh start.
So do you.
♪ Completely ♪
♪ You got to charge head first ♪
♪ Fall in completely ♪
♪ You got to charge ♪
[applause]
[boy] Good job!
That was "cirque du so cray"!
- Thank you, I think.
- [both chuckle]
I totally got this.
[Julie] Was that...?
That girl just threw you
some serious shade.
[Jax] That one kinda looks like a balloon.
Surprised he didn't say Bianca.
No way. It's clearly an eggplant.
[Jax] Oh, yeah, you're right.
- Hey, you know who'd love this?
- Jax.
Spoke too soon.
Sunshine, blue skies.
What's the point of it, Kit?
What's the point of happiness
if it's just gonna be ripped away?
That's it. [grunts]
Go fight for her, Jax.
- Wait, what about "enough is enough"?
- I take it back.
Oh, no, no, no, no. Don't get me wrong.
I clearly think
that you've lost a few marbles
and it's probably
not gonna work out, but...
you have to fight for her
like you fought for DJ D.
Yeah, and look how well that worked out.
What you did for Diamondmind
was incredible.
You almost convinced me not to retire.
I said, almost.
Bianca must mean more to you
than some DJ.
Of course, she does.
She means everything to me.
She's the sun, the sky...
[sighs] and the balloon-shaped clouds.
If there's even
a slightest chance she says yes,
you have to keep trying.
You can't give up on her.
I knew there was a romantic
hiding somewhere under that toque.
I'm going to get Bianca Blackwell back.
And Kit...
you're not just some DJ.
Go already.
[indistinct chattering]
Hey, I... I saw you dance.
It was amazing.
Okay, this is not going well.
Look... it's probably too late
and if you wanna shut me down,
you have every right.
But I have to try or I'll never know.
Julie Maslany, will you go
on a second date with me?
I can't deal with you right now.
[Katy] Kit-Kat?
Only one person calls me that.
Katykins.
When you spend two months on a tour bus,
you get nicknames.
- Wow, you're at Keaton.
- Qualifiers.
- I got through.
- Oh. Congrats.
- I should get... [giggles]
- Is Jaxter around?
Never heard of him.
I thought you two were buds?
Oh.
You mean Jax...
Because you called him "Jaxter."
Yeah, uh, he's around.
If you see him first, don't tell him
I'm here. I wanna surprise him.
Oh. [chuckles]
You mean, don't tell Jax that the girl
he kissed over the summer is here
on the same day that he's trying
to get back together with Bianca?
He'll be surprised, all right.
[sighs]
Guess you saw.
Sixth place is respectable.
Especially for your first CAMDAs.
Respectable?
I didn't qualify for finals.
How am I supposed to get into Juilliard?
Because you didn't qualify
in one category?
The most important category.
Do you see where the girls are standing?
Right over there?
That's where I was when I found out
I didn't get into Juilliard.
Just because I didn't get in,
doesn't mean I gave up.
But how do you keep going when
there are no guarantees it will work out?
There is only one guarantee.
If you quit now,
you'll never know what you're capable of.
There's no shame
in getting knocked down, Julie.
The bigger shame,
would be not getting back up.
So...
What's it gonna be?
[indistinct chattering]
- Does Sasha seem off to you?
- Everybody seems off to me.
It's this competition,
it makes people crazy.
Yeah, maybe.
But they're working a bit hard
for warm-up, no?
Maybe we're not working hard enough.
- Whoa! Whoa!
- [Sasha grunts]
[thumps, grunts]
- Jenna!
- Hey, you okay?
I'm okay.
It sounded bad. You want me to get anyone?
Do you need ice?
- I need to sit.
- Here. Come with me.
Carly Catto and Beckett Bradstreet?
You're on deck.
I've been watching you all day.
You're cramped,
you've been overexerting yourself.
- And now this.
- She shifted.
I tried to break her fall.
What else could I do?
I don't think you guys should compete.
Wow.
You're afraid we're gonna beat you.
That's amazing.
Carly Catto and Beckett Bradstreet?
I'm sorry to disappoint you,
but Jenna and I are not dropping out.
No, you're just dropping her.
Catto and Bradstreet. Last call.
That's us.
Come on. Let's go.
- You sure you're all right, J?
- Right as rain.
I just got the wind knocked out of me.
You okay?
I hope so.
- I'm okay.
- [sighs]
- We got this.
[audience applauding]
["Love Don't Fight Fair" playing]
♪ How am I gonna find a four-leaf clover ♪
♪ Down here among the mess you made
Left here on my shoulders ♪?
♪ And I can call these feelings
Into question ♪
♪ Possession is nine-tenths of the law ♪
It's just an expression I heard
Once before ♪
♪ And cold feet
Can only get me so far ♪
♪ I can make no promises
That I won't break ♪
♪ Call it my mistake ♪
♪ And I can't ever watch you
Being scared ♪
♪ I've learned
That love don't fight fair ♪
♪ I can make no promises
That I won't break ♪
♪ Call it my mistake ♪
♪ And I can't ever watch you
Being scared ♪
♪ I've learned
That love don't fight fair ♪
[applause]
[shoes squeak, thumps]
- [girls laughing]
- Jackson?
All right, all right.
Not off to a great start, I agree,
but please, please,
just hear me out.
- I'll give it back. Thanks.
- [feedback squeals]
Bianca Blackwell.
I, Jackson Gardner... love you.
And I am not gonna stop fighting for you.
I made a mistake this summer,
and I would do anything
to go back and erase it, but I can't.
[mic snaps, squeals]
I mean, unless anyone knows where
I can get my hands on a time machine.
Anyone? No?
I betrayed your trust.
I don't deserve you.
But if you just give me one more chance.
Just one more chance.
I swear, I will never let you down again.
You're a goof, Jackson Gardner.
A goof who still has a girlfriend?
Can't you see we're having
a moment here, Kit?
Jax...?
We hung out all summer,
and you never told me once
you had a girlfriend.
Hi. You must be the girlfriend.
I'm the mistake.
Bianca, I don't... I...
All summer? You told me it was one kiss.
No, it was just one kiss, I swear.
I promise.
Stop!
We're over.
We are so done.
[plays chord]
Hey, Miles. Can we talk?
Of course.
Listen, I'm sorry.
- You don't need to apologize to me.
- No, I do.
What happened before, it wasn't about you.
- I was just upset about...
- We both make mistakes.
Mostly me.
So let's start over?
Hi, I'm Miles. Nice to meet you.
- Hi, Miles. I'm Rihanna.
- [chuckles]
["You and I" playing]
♪ Hey there,
Come close to the fire ♪
♪ Feel the desire
Holding all the way ♪
♪ I'm swimming up river
The love I give her ♪
♪ The love I deliver ♪
♪ All in a day ♪
♪ Now you can see my hands are high ♪
♪ I surrender to you
On the floor tonight ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ So don't you leave me hanging by ♪
♪ I believe in yours,
You believe in mine ♪
♪ Don't tell that your hands are tied ♪
♪ I believe in you, in you, in you and I ♪
♪ For your love, girl ♪
♪ I've been falling ♪
♪ Isn't it obvious? ♪
♪ 'Cause it is to me
And my friends agree ♪
♪ They see my hands are high
I surrender to you... ♪
This is it. This is everything
we've been working for.
He's got me. I trust him.
♪ I believe in yours,
You believe in mine ♪
♪ Don't tell me that your hands are tied ♪
♪ I believe in you, in you, in you and I ♪
[applause, cheering]
- We did it.
- You did it.
- Finals, baby, here we come.
- [giggles]
Hey, man.
Respect.
Jenna!
[Beckett] Someone, get a medic!
Someone, get a medic. Hey!
["Love Don't Fight Fair" playing]
♪ How am I gonna find a four-leaf clover ♪
♪ Down here among the mess you made
Left here on my shoulders? ♪
♪ And I can call these feelings
Into question ♪
♪ Possession is nine-tenths of the law ♪
It's just an expression I heard
Once before ♪
♪ And cold feet
Can only get me so far ♪