THE USURPADORA
CINCINNATI In the old and good
times before the 18th amendment.
Open the door and there she is.
I know I earned it, Ray.
For you, Ray.
You are awesome.
You are very curious.
You give one the whole rope
of the world...
And the first thing you do
all is to be hanged.
Come on, Ray.
We had lots of fun.
What do you say?
Fact.
That's great.
We're going to do something.
I know a small hotel
in this street...
Let's Dance.
- Hi, Ray.
- Hello!
- How are you?
- Very good.
- What are you doing here?
- I came in case I saw you.
Who is it?
Ray Schmidt, the girl
Most cheerful of the city.
It seems.
What do you say?
I've been saying no
since before I met you...
and that's five years ago.
He thinks you very smart, does not he?
With the travelers he does not
Missing list
I see you come a kilometer.
All right, listen to this.
Ray, what's wrong with you?
It was just a joke.
I love it too.
Let's stop joking.
- But, mam...
- I said no!
You will not go out alone at night
with a man.
Next to the Rhine is not a place
for decent girls.
You let Ray go.
Ray Schmidt is not my daughter,
but my stepdaughter.
So I do not have
authority over it.
They are very serious words.
So that's true.
If Ray Schmidt were my daughter...
I would not walk around
at night like a top.
Why not?
He works a lot in the store,
and at night...
At night it would be better
at home with your family...
and not tossed around
going out with some and with others.
But to the girls of today
They do not like being at home.
These young people are lost.
It is always said that
young people are lost.
But in the end,
they always manage to save themselves.
- Hello everyone.
- Hi, Kurt.
Is this Ray?
He has not returned yet.
He went to "Next to the Rhine".
- Are you still engaged in that madness?
- Oh, burn?
Kurt, I thought you were
an intelligent boy.
Autom viles!
Within five years
there will be no trace.
Do you believe?
There's a guy in Detroit
that makes them dozens.
- What's his name?
- Henry Ford.
Not the slightest idea.
- Well, he has almost won half a million.
- Half a million?
It's the funniest thing I've ever heard.
Cr ame, I would buy a
dealer of yours...
even if I had to sell my store.
Keep your store
and invest in horses.
Autom viles!
Dirty and smelly pots!
If that's why, the horses
They do not smell like flowers either.
"Kurt Schendler, do not be obscene!"
- Good evening, Bob.
- Adi s.
- Ah, Ray arrives.
- Good evening, daddy.
- Hello Darling.
- Good evening, Kurt.
- You went to "Along the Rhine"?
- Yes, I did not stop dancing.
You will be tired.
Ray, I was waiting for you.
- S? For what?
- I wanted to ask you...
You would mind coming tomorrow
to the store...
to help me with the books?
Of course not, I'll be delighted.
- They're done a mess.
- As usual.
I read that a girl of Indiana...
went to a bicycle shop...
and they found her dead
two weeks later...
with his head in a sack
of burlap.
You do not know,
but I'm going to bed.
Come on, Frida.
Mam, why do I have
to lie down so soon?
They say you can do that
a boy marry if...
Go to your room.
You are incorrigible.
It would be better if I left
to sleep.
There's nothing like a good night's sleep
to feel like new.
- Goodnight.
- Ray, will we see you tomorrow?
- Of course I do.
- Goodnight.
Simptic, right?
- Same as t.
- I, a great boy?
Of course.
Not anymore, honey.
I start going down.
Pap! Do not say that.
You are the most boy
young I know.
Ray, it does not seem bad to me that you
dream with something better than Kurt.
But maybe life
bring you something worse.
Kurt is a good boy.
Maybe it will never surprise you.
But it's almost better.
Most marriages
they end up giving many surprises.
Ray, come!
I want to teach you one thing!
Why is it beautiful?
- What's a wonder?
- It's fabulous!
I will finish it as soon as
receive a piece tomorrow.
- Will you accompany me to look for her?
- When I finish with the books.
You are charming, helping me
Sundays with books.
I do not even want to think
in how they would be if not!
- What happened?
- I've turned it off.
Ray...
Do you have confidence in me?
Of course I do.
You will be an important man.
I'm sure.
I'm glad to hear you say that,
why...
Ray, do you want to marry me?
Well, I...
I do not think it's
so funny. I...
I do not laugh at you, Kurt.
I just thought.
You are the first man
who asks me in marriage.
I'm the only one
that has had value.
Many have value.
They think they can have me
without marrying me.
What do they know?
Only because you're happy...
That they dare
to procrastinate with me!
Ray.
It's not like that, is it?
- What?
- That they can have you without...
I already knew!
Pap has gone up.
Ray, you have not answered
to my question.
- What question?
- Do you want to marry me?
- Kurt, you're great.
- But...
But you do not love me.
So, no.
It would be horrible to get married
with you...
and one day discover
who wanted another.
I know myself very well.
With me, it's all or nothing.
God assist man
I fell in love with.
Until you find it
will not accept a no.
I will continue asking for it.
It seems reasonable to me.
- Hello, Ray!
- Hello!
- How are you?
- Greatly.
- Do you know Kurt Shendler?
- Hello.
Do you mind waiting?
I'm going to the slogan.
- Sure, Kurt.
- See you soon.
- Are you going to take that train?
- Unfortunately.
- I have not seen you much this trip.
- And who is to blame?
What a way to treat me.
I learn to love you,
and then you leave me abandoned.
Do not start, do not start!
Ray, I'm going to take the train to
Detroit. Are you coming with me?
I would love it, but I can not.
- Why?
- I forgot the toothbrush.
You are always the same!
You baffle me.
I think you're a fraud.
But the next time it comes
You will not escape so easily.
We'll see.
- Hello, Walter.
- Bakeless, what's up?
- What are you doing here?
- As usual. Go and come.
- How is the bank going?
- All right.
- And the textiles?
- Fatal.
- Adi s, Ray.
- Adi s.
Oh, Walter. I introduce you to
a friend, Ray Schmidt.
Charmed.
- What do you think?
- I'm telling you?
I'll say it sooner or later.
I thought it is the day
more perfect than I've seen.
Are you crazy?
It makes embarrassment, and threatens
rain since this morning.
You are crazy The sky is
clear and the air is intoxicating.
God in heaven and you on earth.
It will make me red.
It is already
and it feels very good.
Come on?
- I have not heard his name.
- Does it matter?
Not especially.
- I'm taking her?
- I already have a car, thanks.
It seems to have everything.
Your car.
Not rush.
When are we ever seeing each other again?
Tonight at 10.
11th street corner with Adams.
- I have an appointment.
- An lela.
- Hello.
- What's up?
He does not seem surprised
of seeing me.
- I'm not.
- What do you think?
Are you very sure of himself.
Thus.
But if you want something very much,
It ends up becoming reality.
- Let's go a little?
- All right.
- What's his name?
- Ray.
- Oh, I'm glad.
- Are you happy? Why?
The names must be
appropriate for people.
Ray: Sunbeam, ray of joy...
ray of my heart.
Tell me, what do you do?
Work in the haberdashery
of my father.
How did he meet the guy
What did we introduce?
Bakeless?
He is a simple traveler trade.
- Now it's up to you.
- Breathe deeply.
Ahead.
- What's his name?
- Walter Saxel.
It is also beautiful.
Where do you live?
In Hamilton, I have come
to see the Tower.
- Do you know them?
- I know Corinne Tower.
Blonde, with blue eyes.
How did you meet her?
I've known her for a long time.
We are promised.
What luck is mine!
If I know a nice man
He is always promised.
Does he think of me?
It's raining.
It is completely right.
Let's go in there.
- Hello, Walter.
- What's up?
I'm glad to see you.
- When did you arrive?
- This morning.
- And your mother?
- All right. Come tomorrow.
- And Corinne?
- Very well thanks.
I'll be nervous about the wedding.
- It's in a week.
- Yes, that's it.
Are you waiting for Corinne?
In fact,
I was waiting for a taxi.
- Nice to see you.
- We'll call you.
- Say hello to Corinne.
- He will, good night.
- What are you doing, playing hide-and-seek?
- You're t!
I was grabbing to some friends.
- Who?
- You do not know them.
- Are you waiting a lot?
- What if I take a lot?
- I'm late?
- Half an hour.
I am sorry.
- Coach!
- Yes, sir.
- Where are we going?
- Wherever you want.
- A "Next to the Rhine"?
- Very good.
Next to the Rhine.
- What do you think?
- He should not have come.
Do you regret it?
Why do not you say
What you think?
- Will you marry here or in Hamilton?
- Let's not talk about that today.
I am sorry.
Do not misunderstand me.
Corinne is great.
We grew up together.
We promised each other two years ago.
My mother really wants that wedding.
Walter, I think we should not
come back to see us.
Actually, see us
It has been crazy.
You're adorable.
When I hold you in my arms
it does not matter anything else.
It's like a drug.
I feel like leaving everything.
Let's see here.
I have never met nobody like t.
Why did not I meet you?
Years ago, before?
If I knew you my mother!
Look, my mother will come tomorrow.
I have tickets for the park.
You appear casually
as if you did not know.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, Walter.
We will be at the kiosk
from the band at three.
We will sit right
in front of the kiosk.
You will come, will not you?
Yes, Walter. There will be.
- What a crowd!
- Yes, mother.
Let's feel here.
Cara, he will love me.
Cruz, he will not love me.
Hello, you've already returned
of the church?
Ray, I have to talk to you.
You tell me later.
I'm in a hurry.
Why do you close?
- I have to talk now.
- Of what?
Hugo leaves the city.
- And you worry?
- We have to stop him!
He has to stay and...
- Frida!
- No, Ray!
If mam found out!
Ray, you have to do something!
All right, talk to him tonight.
It will be too late!
I found it when I came back...
and leaves this afternoon
on the train at 3:20.
But Frida, I have
an important commitment.
A more appointment!
This is important.
Listen, Frida.
Nothing in the world is
so important
like today is in the park at 3.
Pray for me.
Give me luck!
Move away from the door.
If you do not come with me,
I swear I'll kill myself!
I will not be able to continue living if!
- I'll kill myself!
- Frida!
Boba!
Ray, do not leave me!
I have nobody but you.
No, I will not leave you.
You can count on Ray.
Come on. Come on.
Let's see him now.
Take, drop your eyes.
That your mother does not see you.
Wall Street NY
Walter!
You will not be long
without talking to me!
Walter Saxel!
The same, in flesh and blood,
Miss Schmidt.
- The usual Walter.
- I have not changed in five years?
5 years ago you planted me
in the park.
- He did not leave you.
- Of course I do.
- No!
Excuse me.
We obstruct the traffic.
Let's see, where were we?
Oh, yes.
The music kiosk.
I was there and you were not.
I arrived somewhat late.
We stay until
that the concert ended.
He arrived when he left people.
- I was furious.
- It looked in your note.
- Was it hard?
- Tremendous.
- I am sorry.
- Jur do not forgive you.
But you have forgiven me.
- Yes.
- The same Ray Schmidt as always.
Just as good,
More young than ever.
And you're still so smart
as usual.
Thank you.
What have you been doing?
Many things, I will be
partner of my firm.
That's great!
And I have given birth to two children.
- What smart!
- Y t, what have you done?
They are not going to make me
partner, but...
I am the best paid woman
of my company.
If we do not leave,
we will bury the snow.
Have dinner with me
- I have a commitment.
- R mpelo.
I will call my wife,
and will return at once.
- We'll have dinner together, what do you say?
- Very good.
Are we going?
- You're still beautiful.
- Thank you.
You know a lot of people
In New York?
Very much.
Is there anyone special?
Thank you.
I'm sorry I can not invite you.
No gentlemen are allowed
no dogs.
I understand.
My landlady has instincts
of bloodhound.
I guess we say goodbye here.
It has been great to see you again.
Really? I'm not sure.
It would have been better
not having seen us again.
But Walter!
I am sorry,
I did not want to say that.
Perd name.
Your memory has harassed me
day and night.
I tried to forget you.
And now, you come back to torture me.
Walter, honey!
What can I say? What can I do?
- Ray, you still care, do not you?
- You do not know?
When will I see you?
- When you want.
- I'll call you.
I'm going away two days.
I'll call you on Saturday.
You will find me in
Liberty 3270.
- Will you remember the number?
- I will never forget it.
- Adi s, honey.
- Adi s, Walter.
S bete the neck, do not get cold.
Be careful. Adi s.
Relax, I have loose.
How are you?
- I'm late?
- No heaven. Do we enter?
- Is for you.
- For me?
We could not continue
staying in the corners.
You do not care, do you?
No, Walter, I do not care.
Please, you want to call
to my number?
It seems to me that the phone
it does not work.
It does not work well.
Thank you very much.
After dinner,
nothing like my pipe.
In addition, I wanted to talk to you.
An excellent dinner
Corinne is perfect.
- And the house is beautiful.
- Thanks to you.
- How?
- You have paid for it.
Corinne has always been
my favorite niece.
And in addition, you earned it.
And that reminds me of something.
- You leave for Europe last morning.
- T o Felix!
The Dalmatia negotiations.
- You were going t.
- I have changed my mind.
We need a man more young
I'm counting on you, Walter.
It is wonderful.
A great opportunity.
I will be good a vacation.
I suggest you take to Corinne.
But Uncle Felix...
- Hello.
- Walter!
- Are you glad to see me?
- Sure! I did not expect it.
It should not be here,
but I could escape.
I had to see you.
- I'm glad.
- You've missed me?
You do not know how much.
It has been terrible!
- Only three days.
- Only three days!
For you it has not been much,
You have been very busy.
But, what happens to me?
Phone Slope,
to hear your key in the door,
waiting waiting...
- Walter, it's been terrible!
- I am so sorry. Really.
It does not matter anymore.
Come on, tell me!
- What?
- The great news!
If I did not say anything...
You did not say anything else
since you entered.
Do not lie to me ever, my life.
You tell me everything without speaking.
Your way of entering,
to cross the room...
that look of an excited child.
I am also excited. What is it?
It is exciting. Remember
the negotiations of Dalmatia?
T o Felix has decided not to go
and send me to me.
- We left after tomorrow.
- Passed tomorrow? To Europe?
- I can not believe it!
- What?
Europe! Not even
I dared to dream it.
Just going there would be wonderful.
But my first trip with you!
Walter!
Ray...
I'm afraid you do not understand.
I can not ask you to come with me.
Do not think I do not want to.
It hurts as much as it does you.
But Uncle Felix... It scared me.
It's like a sphinx,
you never know what he thinks.
He talks a lot about appearances
and he said he should take Corinne.
There is no one who understands!
Schedule scan it!
It is awful. Pass.
My husband told the landlord today
If we do not lower the rent, we move.
From all the houses
in which we have lived!
Although the hardest is you.
Remove a lot
of air and light, right?
It is a pity.
- Why do not you move?
- Right now I can not.
Of course, until your husband returns.
He's been away for a long time, right?
- Yes.
- Go back soon?
Your work is unpredictable.
It is hard to say.
Yes, I understand.
What is it, a tree?
No, it's a flower, is not it?
Is beautiful.
"Well, I almost forgot
why he had come!"
- Do you leave me a couple of lemons?
- Yes, of course.
My husband is arriving.
He loves lemonade.
And today I do not have...
Oh, is this your husband?
Well yes, it's him.
"Well, how handsome he is!
S that is brown!"
- Here's the lemons.
- Thank you very much.
- May I bring them to you.
- No hurry.
Let's see when they finish!
The floor is worse than mine.
It came well to Paris.
I wish you were with me.
I have to stay longer.
I miss you so much.
- Help!
- What was that?
Help! Help!
- What happened?
- An accident!
- The oven has exploded!
- My eyes!
- Call the firemen!
- A doctor, hurry!
Why do not you let me
Call your husband?
- No, do not call him!
- Well, he will not.
- I'm bothering you a lot.
- Do not worry.
You have been very kind.
Who are you? What is it called?
Ray Schmidt, your neighbor.
What has the doctor said?
Will it be disfigured?
Of course not.
I do not know what Jim will say.
- Let me call you.
- No, you must not!
He forbade me.
- In such a case...
- Do not understand.
I...
He is not really my husband.
He is married.
- Ray Schmidt!
- Kurt Shendler!
I knew that this was your house, but not
I expected to meet you at the door.
- How pretty you are!
- Wait until I recover!
- Where do you come from?
- Detroit.
Jam s would have recognized you!
How well you are!
And you're doing well!
What have you been doing?
- Is it that you do not know?
- Knowing what?
You do not know the Kurt Sussex?
- Sure, everyone knows them.
- Well, I'm that Kurt.
- T?
- Of course I am.
Kurt, I can not believe it!
- What are you doing here?
- Business trip.
It's my first trip to New York
and I want to see the city.
And you teach it to me?
Tact done?
You can be sure.
Let's go somewhere
where it makes less heat.
This is wonderful!
- For me, it's a party.
- What do you want to eat?
Do you know, Kurt?
I can not explain.
What have you done to yourself?
Remember that I had
the hair of end?
Well, I've crushed it.
I changed my glasses,
I wear a suit instead of a monkey.
But other than that,
I'm still the same as always.
How did you find me?
I wrote to Frida, she says that
you are still in the same bouquet.
- Now I'm on vacations.
- That's great.
Because I have a huge list
of places to go.
- Hello!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Come, come on.
- Very good.
Say? Hi, Kurt.
No, nothing.
I would love it.
Wait a minute, pass!
Now I'm going.
Yes, Kurt.
Why?
Very good.
About seven o'clock?
Yes, I'll be ready. Adi s.
Are you going out today?
Play the Detroit team.
Do not see how Kurt shouted.
- He's a great guy.
- It's great.
Have you been crying, True?
Ray, I'm going crazy
if I do not know something about Jim.
Francine, I hope you stop crying.
He does not deserve it.
Does anyone deserve it?
I know that now
It's very hard, but...
But is better.
Now you are free
to do what you want.
But Ray, I love him!
And he? Surely I
He loves you too, does not he?
Before, he loved me very much.
And I only asked him that.
I would have done any
thing for him.
He just wanted his love.
It's the only thing you have.
The only thing you will have.
And not for long.
What can it do for you
a man like him?
It can be seen with you,
introduce yourself to your friends?
You can only hide in a
alley where you wait
when the phone rings, to
arrive postcards without a signature.
If I could hate him!
If I could stop loving him!
Francine, esc chame. D jalo
before it is too late.
Find a good boy, c sate,
have children Only then will you be happy.
I know what I'm talking about.
There is not a woman in a million
who has found happiness
in an alley.
Hi, Ray.
Walter!
Cari o!
I present to a friend
Oh, Francine.
Francine, this is...
- It's Walter!
- Enchanted, Mr. Schmidt.
- Pleasure.
- I've heard a lot about you.
- Well, I'm leaving.
- See you soon.
- Goodnight.
- I'll pass by your house.
Walter!
Cari o!
When have you arrived?
I did not know that today
a boat arrived.
- When did you arrive?
- The day before yesterday.
Yesterday?
Walter, you've been two days
In New York!
I've been so busy...
You can not imagine it.
I know, Walter. But,
Could not you have called?
I wanted to call you many times,
but I could not.
- Perd name, please.
- Of course I do.
What's the summer?
You seems to be exhausted.
It will be better when cool.
It has been frightening.
T o Felix wrote me that
It has been the worst in 30 years.
In contrast, in Europe
He had to put on a coat.
And Switzerland!
Suiza? I did not know
that you were going to Switzerland.
Did not he write it to you?
I received three postcards
throughout the summer.
I know I wrote you more letters.
They must have been lost.
It's possible.
Finally, when finishing the
negotiations, thought:
Why not take advantage
and see Europe?
I spent four weeks watching
France, Switzerland, Italy...
It was wonderful!
And when you left you did not see
the time to return.
Four weeks!
Well, it was my first
trip to Europe.
You only told me
It has been very hot.
There is not much to tell.
You already know how time passes.
Making loners,
fixing some dress...
going to the market...
I have started painting porcelain.
So he had something to do.
In addition, he sold some pieces.
Why? I do not like
that you do those things.
There is no concrete reason,
Walter.
But sometimes, you want to have
money in your pocket.
Ray!
I forgot to leave you money
for those four weeks.
I'll fix it tomorrow.
I hope you did not have problems.
Absolutely. I managed it well.
- I'm sorry...
- I do not want you to feel it.
I was not looking for your compassion.
I do not feel worthy of compassion.
It would be a summer again
how is this if necessary?
But there is something
that we must solve.
There have been terrible moments.
I left my job to
be free when you came.
Very good. But, what do I have?
Loners, wait
to the phone ringing,
wait for you to come,
die when you do not show up...
I can not meet your friends,
nor make friends of their own.
You do not know what empties
that is my life.
Vac a, honey?
When do you have me?
That is just the question.
I do not always have you.
This summer I have not had you.
And every time you're more busy.
There will be more trips without Ray.
I can not continue like this, waiting,
dreaming, with empty hands.
Walter... give me a son.
Ray! Have you gone crazy?
I do not understand how
you can suggest it!
Have you thought about the consequences?
Unclear.
They would be terrible,
at least for me.
Think of the esc ndalo,
it would end with my future.
It's unthinkable!
After all, You are not my wife.
Ray!
I did not want to say that!
Do not worry.
You are tired.
Today you are not t,
or you would not have suggested
something like that.
You are right. I'm tired.
Ray... I have to go.
You know.
I'm so sorry, honey.
- Perd name.
- Of course I do.
Tomorrow everything will be different.
Adi s, Walter.
Ahead.
I'm sorry I'm late.
But when I was going to leave,
They gave me a call.
I have to return.
To Detroit?
- Tonight.
- I am sorry.
But it's a shame,
with the plans we had.
I had never had it as well.
But it is an important agreement.
I have to return.
Although I would like to leave it
and stay with you.
- What's wrong with you?
- Nothing.
Only today I am very strange.
It's been great to have you here.
I'm sorry you're leaving like that.
I will miss you.
I'm glad you told me that.
Leave like this, so suddenly
It gives me courage to ask you something.
Something that I have already asked for.
Something that will keep asking
if I keep my health.
I do not blame you
that you would reject me.
Then it was a simple
and poorer than rats.
- Not that...
- Let me finish.
Just when I collect value,
you interrupt me.
Have compassion.
Anyway, now I'm rich, or almost.
And I'm still crazy about you.
Do you accept me, Ray?
- You're a great guy.
- Yes, I already know that.
But that does not answer
to my question.
Do you accept?
Kurt, Do you know what I am?
Ray Schmidt, the girl
the world's greatest.
- Of course if you're not free...
- I am.
It was not, Kurt, but I already am.
So, this is the end
of ours, Walter.
I'm coming home to Cincinnati, and...
Again the door!
Excuse me, live here
Mrs. Hugo Hank?
Yes, but if you are a seller,
I warn you...
I do not sell anything,
I'm looking for Ray Schmidt.
I am so sorry.
Do not you want to pass?
I did not want to be so rude, but I
they interrupt ten times a day.
Almost always to sell something.
Back at any time.
He has gone to the shopping center.
- Mam, who is it?
- What manners are those, Hugo?
These are my children, sir...
I have not heard his name.
- Walter Saxel.
- Yes, Mr. Saxel.
This is Hugo, and little Ray.
- Hi, Ray.
- Hello.
- You're a beautiful girl.
- Yes.
- How is Ray?
- Divinely. Just arrived.
He will be married soon.
With Kurt Shendler, a great man.
Fig. They laugh at him
because he believed in the car.
I was one of the few people
who encouraged him.
- I think nothing is missing.
- See you later, Kurt.
Hi, Ray.
Hi.
I found your note on the floor.
It's not true that
this is the end.
- I've missed you.
- Me too to you.
If you wanted to make me suffer,
You've got it.
It has been frightening.
I did not think I could
need so much nobody.
I have no right
to ask you nothing.
Call me selfish.
I can not offer you anything
of what you could have:
A home, a name, some children.
I'm just one thing.
I need you. I love you.
Come back with me, Ray.
You try to run away from something.
Your site is with me.
But Walter!
If I go back now,
Where will it end?
I love you, Ray.
This trip makes me very excited.
I'm sorry you can not accompany me.
- You work too much.
- I'll find time.
- Hello, captain.
- Hello, Mr. Saxel.
Nice to have you here.
Do you remember Mrs. Saxel?
- My son...
- Charmed.
- And my daughter.
- It is a pleasure.
I hope we have a good trip.
If you need anything,
Do not hesitate to call me.
- Excuse me, Mr. Saxel.
- Where can I serve you?
What will you say to the commission?
Of Berlin?
I have no idea
Maybe you can help me.
Sr. Saxel!
Suppose I tell you.
Someone would take over
of my brilliant ideas.
- No thanks.
- Thank you.
A moment!
There is half of life there
by Walter Saxel.
- And there's the other half.
- Where?
That beautiful woman
of the silver fox.
It does not look like
of devourer of men.
Of course.
But go where Saxel goes,
his shadow will follow him.
- Will Corinne know?
- I doubt it.
For Corinne, a mistress
It is a novel character.
- Thank you very much.
- Come here, please.
I can make one here
with his family?
- Look, Dick!
- Where?
Beware of the step.
Could you tell me
My cabin, please?
How do you know?
Good girls we will be
blind, but not stupid.
- He has seen us.
- I'm not moving.
Through the second corridor
on the left.
I'm sick!
It has already humbled us enough.
We have to do something.
- Who is going to do it?
- I.
- Good evening, Miss Schmidt.
- Good evening, Mr. Saxel.
- Have you already had dinner?
- Yes, thank you.
I'm afraid I can not see you
In this travel.
Do not worry.
It seems that everyone
He knows me.
I understand.
We'll see each other in Paris.
In the usual place.
I want to consult you things
before the conference.
But hey, what's the matter with you?
You have taken it with that bitch.
As I caught you,
I will make you picadillo, bobo.
Let's go. S abete to your chair.
I've made you something hot.
I love this place.
It's a simple hotel,
but you give it something special.
"The magic touch
of a woman's hand
illuminates up
the darkest corner."
Thanks, honey.
Nothing like a chocolate
French made by you.
Thank you.
Do you want some cookies?
By the way, Where is my speech?
There. You already have it ready.
Here it is.
- Do you like it?
- It's the best you've written.
You did not say anything
of your contribution.
- My contribution?
- Your contribution.
I used to cheat myself thinking
that everything was more than mine.
A very bright guy.
But it is not true.
Walter, do not be absurd!
Now do not start arguing.
I'm not in the mood for nonsense.
- I would not hit a lady.
- Do not provoke me.
Par s always takes out
your animal facet.
Sit down and be nice.
This is not a way to rest.
You are getting more and more beautiful.
You will be divine with white hair.
You never drank it,
I hate artificiality.
Besides, it's not going for you.
You are too authentic.
I would like to take you to Berlin.
- Will you go back a lot?
- Four days. I'll go on a plane.
Check it well while I'm away.
Do not worry. Unseat the casino.
Player!
Remind me to leave you
money before leaving.
Ahead.
I think we do not need
presentation, Ms. Schmidt.
I've been around for years.
He has been following us
like an odious shadow.
Everyone knows less my mother.
And she will find out soon.
My sister is going to enter
in an aristocratic family.
If they inquire about you,
my mother will find out.
She does not imagine
that there are women like you.
I want you never to know.
"Leave us alone, Mrs. Schmidt!"
I would throw it out if I could.
You are all cold,
egoists, calculators.
They only have one purpose:
Secure your position.
I will not ask you to think
in my sister or in me.
What are the children
for someone like you?
I have not come to discuss,
but to warn her!
Leave my father alone!
For always!
You will receive a compensation.
After all, Money is what counts.
Ahead.
Hi, Dick.
- What are you doing here?
- I have the right.
I do not doubt it, son.
What are you doing here?
- I've asked your...
- Dick.
Sit down, son.
I want to talk to you.
Do not go.
Sit down, son.
Dick, a long time before
that you were born,
two months before I got married
With your mother.
I met Ray Schmidt.
For 25 years
we have loved each other.
You are too young
to know how much time that is.
I have not removed
to my family what I gave him.
You did not want it
and she was happy to receive it.
And she gave me what nobody
He had offered me.
This part of my life
It's just more.
You can not enter it.
Nor force me to abandon it.
That is all.
What do you want me to do,
who applauds?
I want you to understand
if you are mature enough.
And if I'm not?
Then, oc pate
of your affairs and leave.
I will go.
But it's my business.
You are despicable!
Outside!
Walter, you should not
to have spoken to him like that.
He is your son.
Naturally.
And I love him more
about you think.
But I would give gladly
everything I have, life itself,
for that little nose of yours.
I love you.
- I know, I...
- Do not ever leave me.
I will not leave you, Walter.
Tomorrow we will have
the day for us.
Are you happy?
It will come in the first hour
and we will have breakfast together.
- What did Richard say?
- Nothing important, Walter.
Breakfast is at 9.
You know I'm always punctual
when it comes to your breakfasts.
- Good evening, honey.
- Goodnight.
Ahead.
Good morning, ma'am.
- It's been a precious day.
- Thank you.
Bank manager Friedlander Kunz...
is suffering from a paralysis attack.
The millionaire Walter Saxel.
Walter!
Poor me!
The famous philanthropist and banker
I suffered a paralysis attack last night.
In a report issued
at five o'clock in the morning
your doctor, Dr. Durkin,
He announced a slight improvement.
Mr. Saxel's wife,
as well as your children,
do not leave their bed.
I'm going to talk to the doctor.
My son... My son...
Wants to talk to you.
Do you want to talk to me?
Alone.
Sorry, pap wants
talk to me for a moment.
What do you want?
Phone.
Do you want me to call?
Montparnasse...
six seven... five three...
Montparnasse, 6753, please.
- Montparnasse 6753?
- Yes, yes.
Wait a moment.
- Ray... Ray...
- Walter.
- I'm here. I hear you.
I can not hear you, honey.
What do you want to tell me?
Pap... Pap!
Nurse! Doctor!
Hurry, doctor!
Doctor, do not breathe.
Has died.
Walter! Walter, Walter!
Do not abandon me!
Cari o...
My life...
Today the funeral is celebrated
by Walter Saxel.
The funeral for Walter Saxel,
banker and philanthropist of New York,
will be held in privacy
at 11 at the Ritz-Carlton hotel.
After the funeral, his remains are
will take you to New York in the Baltic.
Ahead.
Can I pass?
My father would have loved
that came.
I guess he knows everything.
His last thought It was for you.
I called her and he tried
talk to him, but...
Mrs. Schmidt, my father would have
I wanted to leave you something.
I know for a reason
who said that night.
Naturally,
It does not appear in your will.
Did he take care of you?
My father how much?
I mean, what amount?
200 dollars.
- A week?
- A month.
- In total?
- Total.
Good heavens!
Do you want to stay here?
I would like to go home.
Yes, of course.
Every first of the month
I will receive the money.
If you need anything,
Do not hesitate to call me.
Walter!
Your son is going to take care of me.
He was so kind!
It could have been my son.
Our son.
Walter, I wonder...
what would have happened
if your mother I had known
that day...
in the park.
Mother, this is Ray Schmidt.
So you're Ray. You're lovely.
My daughter,
you have my blessing
and I hope you know very happy.
Are we going?
I'm coming, Walter.
I'm going.