Princeton University September 1947
Mathematicians won the war.
Mathematicians broke
the Japanese codes...
and built the A-bomb.
Mathematicians... like you.
The stated goal of the
Soviets is global communism.
In medicine or economics,
in technology or space,
battle lines are being drawn.
To triumph, we need results.
Publishable, applicable results.
Now who among you will be the
next Morse? The next Einstein?
Who among you will be the vanguard
of democracy, freedom, and discovery?
Today, we bequeath America's future
into your able hands.
Welcome to Princeton, gentlemen.
Man: It's not enough Hansen
won the Carnegie Scholarship.
Man #2: No, he has to
have it all for himself.
It's the first time the Carnegie prize
has been split. Hansen's all bent.
Man #2. Rumor is he's got
his sights set on Wheeler Lab,
the new military think tank at M.I.T.
They're only taking one this year.
Hansen's used to being picked first.
Oh, yeah, he's wasted on math.
He should be running for president.
There could be a
mathematical explanation
for how bad your tie is.
(Laughs)
Thank you.
Neilson, symbol cryptography.
Neils here broke a Jap code.
Helped rid the world of fascism.
At least that's what he
tells the girls, eh, Neils?
The name's Bender. Atomic physics.
- And you are?
- Am I late?
- Yes.
- Yes, Mr. Sol.
Oh, good. Uh, hi.
- Sol. Richard Sol.
- Neilson. The burden of genius.
- Bender: There he is.
- So many supplicants, and so little time.
- Mr. Sol.
- How are you, sir?
- Ah, Bender.
- Nice to see you.
- Congratulations, Mr. Hansen.
- Ah, thank you.
I'll take another.
Excuse me?
A thousand pardons. I simply
assumed you were the waiter.
- Play nice, Hansen.
- Nice is not Hansen's strong suit.
Hansen. Honest mistake.
Well, Martin Hansen.
It is Martin, isn't it?
Why, yes, John, it is.
I imagine you're getting
quite used to miscalculation.
I've read your pre-prints...
Both of them.
The one on Nazi ciphers,
and the other one on
non-linear equations,
and I am supremely confident
that there is not a single seminal
or innovative idea
in either one of them.
Enjoy your punch.
(Chuckles)
Gentlemen, meet John Nash,
the mysterious West Virginia genius.
The other winner of the
distinguished Carnegie Scholarship.
- Bender. Oh, okay.
- Sol. Oh, yeah?
Bender. Of course.
(Choral Record Playing)
(Coughs) Oh, Christ.
The prodigal roommate arrives.
Roommate?
Oh, God, no.
- Ugh.
- (Music Slows, Stops)
Did you know that
having a hangover is...
Is not having enough water in your body
to run your Krebs cycles?
Which is exactly what happens to you
when you're dying of thirst.
So, dying of thirst...
would probably feel
pretty much like the hangover
that finally bloody kills you.
(Chuckles)
John Nash?
Hello.
Charles Herman.
Pleased to meet you.
Player: All right, well done.
Charles. Well, it's official.
I'm almost human again.
Officer, I saw the driver who hit me.
His name was Johnny Walker.
(Mimics Rim shot)
Whew.
Well, I got in last night
in time for...
English department cocktails.
Cock was mine,
the tail belonged to a
particularly lovely young thing
with a passion for...
D.H. Lawrence. You're not
easily distracted, are you?
- I'm here to work.
- Hmmm, are you? Right.
I see. Crikey!
Is my roommate a dick?
Hmm?
Listen.
If we can't break the ice...
How about we drown it?
So what's your story?
You the poor kid that never
got to go to Exeter or Andover?
Despite my privileged upbringing,
I'm actually quite well-balanced.
I have a chip on both shoulders.
(Chuckles)
Maybe you're just better
with the old integers
than you are with people.
My first grade teacher, she told me
that I was born with
two helpings of brain,
but only half a helping of heart.
(Chuckles)
Wow! She sounds lovely!
The truth is that l...
I don't like people much.
And they don't much like me.
But why,
with all your obvious wit and charm?
(Laughs)
Seriously, John.
Mathematics...
Mathematics is never going
to lead you to a higher truth.
And you know why?
'Cause it's boring.
It's really boring. (Chuckles)
You know half these schoolboys
are already published?
I cannot waste time
with these classes...
and these books.
(Coughs)
Memorizing the weaker
assumptions of lesser mortals!
(Chuckles)
I need to look through...
to the governing dynamics.
Find a truly original idea.
That's the only way I'll
ever distinguish myself.
It's the only way that I'll ever...
Matter.
Yes.
Hansen: All right, who's next?
No, I've played enough
"go" for one day, thank you.
- Come on.
- l... I hate this game.
Cowards, all of you!
None of you rise to meet my challenge?
Come on, Bender. Whoever wins,
Sol does his laundry all semester.
- Does that seem unfair to anyone else?
- Not at all.
- Bender. Look at him.
- Nash!
Taking a reverse constitutional?
I'm hoping to extract an algorithm
to define their movement.
- Oh.
- Psycho.
Sol: Hey, Nash, I
thought you dropped out.
You ever going to go to class or...
Classes will dull your mind.
Destroy the potential
for authentic creativity.
Oh, oh, I didn't know that.
Nash is going to stun
us all with his genius.
Which is another way of saying
he doesn't have the nerve to compete.
You scared?
Terrified.
Mortified. Petrified.
Stupefied... by you.
No starch.
Pressed and folded.
Let me ask you something, John.
Be my guest, Martin.
Bender and Sol here correctly completed
Allen's proof of Peyrot's Conjecture.
Adequate work...
without innovation.
Oh. I'm flattered. You flattered?
Flattered.
And I've got two weapons briefs
under security review by the D.O.D.
Derivative drivel.
But Nash achievements:
zero.
I'm a patient man, Martin. Is
there an actual question coming?
What if you never come up
with your original idea?
Huh?
How will it feel when
I'm chosen for Wheeler...
and you're not?
What if you lose?
Bender. Ah, there it is.
(Chuckles)
You should not have won.
Hmmm.
I had the first move,
my... my play was perfect.
The hubris of the defeated.
The game is flawed.
Gentlemen, the great John Nash.
Charles. You've been
in here for two days.
You know Hansen's just
published another paper?
I can't even find a
topic for my doctorate.
Well, on the bright side,
you've invented window art.
This is a group playing touch football.
This is a cluster of pigeons
fighting over bread crumbs.
And this here is a woman who is
chasing a man who stole her purse.
John, you watched a mugging.
That's weird.
In competitive behavior
someone always loses.
Well, my niece knows that,
John, and she's about this high.
See, if I could derive an equilibrium
where prevalence is
a non-singular event,
where nobody loses,
can you imagine the
effect that would have
- on conflict scenarios, and arms negotiations...
- When did you last eat?
...Currency exchange?
You know, food.
You have no respect for
cognitive reverie, you know that?
Yes. But pizza...
Now, pizza I have enormous respect for.
And of course beer.
I have respect for beer.
I have respect for beer!
- Bender. Good evening, Neils.
- Hansen. Hey, Nash.
Who's winning? You or you?
- Bender. Evening, Nash.
- Sol. Hey, guys.
Hey, Nash.
Woman: He's looking at you for sure.
Neils is trying to get your attention.
- Bender. You're joking.
- Sol. Oh, no.
- Go with God.
- Come back a man.
- Fortune favors the brave.
- Bombs away.
Gentlemen, might I remind
you that my odds of success
dramatically improve with each attempt?
This is going to be classic.
Maybe you want to buy me a drink.
I don't exactly know
what I'm required to say
in order for you to
have intercourse with me,
but could we assume
that I said all that?
Essentially we're talking
about fluid exchange, right?
So, could we just go
straight to the sex?
Oh, that was sweet.
Have a nice night, asshole!
- (Man Laughs)
- Neilson. Ladies, wait!
Charles. l...
I especially liked the
bit about fluid exchange.
It was really charming.
Professor. Walk with me, John.
I've been meaning to talk with you.
The faculty is completing
mid-year reviews.
We're deciding which placement
applications to support.
Wheeler, sir. That
would be my first choice.
And actually, I don't really
have a second choice, sir.
John, your fellows
have attended classes.
They've written papers.
They've published.
I'm still searching, sir, for my...
- Your original idea, I know.
- Governing dynamics, sir.
It's very clever, John, but I'm afraid
it's just not nearly good enough.
- May I?
- Thank you.
I've been working on manifold embedding.
My bargaining stratagems are
starting to show some promise.
If you could just
arrange another meeting,
if you'd be kind enough,
with Professor Einstein...
- I've repeatedly asked you for that.
- Now, John.
I'd be able to show him
my revisions on his...
John.
Do you see what they're doing in there?
- Professor. Congratulations.
- Max. Thank you so much.
Congratulations, Professor Max.
- Max. Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
It's the pens.
Reserved for a member of the department
that makes the
achievement of a lifetime.
Now, what do you see, John?
Recognition.
Well done, Professor, well done.
Well, try seeing accomplishment.
Is there a difference?
John,
you haven't focused.
I'm sorry, but up to this point,
your record doesn't warrant
any placement at all.
Good day.
And my compliments to you, sir.
Thank you so much.
I can't see it.
(Whimpers)
- Aah!
- Jesus Christ, John.
I can't fail.
- This is all I am.
- Come on, let's go out.
- I got to get something done.
- John!
- I can't keep staring into space.
- John, enough!
Got to face the wall, follow
their rules, read their books...
you want to do some damage? Fine...
- But don't mess around.
...Do their classes.
Come on! Go on, bust your head!
Kill yourself.
John, do it. Don't mess around.
Bust your head! Go on,
bust that worthless head wide open.
Goddamn it, Charles! What
the hell is your problem?!
It's not my problem.
And it's not your problem.
It's their problem.
Your answer isn't face the wall.
It's out there...
where you've been working.
- (Panting)
- (Gasps)
That was heavy.
That Isaac Newton fellow was right.
- He was onto something.
- Clever boy.
(Giggles)
John. Don't worry, that's mine.
I'll come and get it in a minute.
- (Both laughing)
- Oh, God.
- Neilson. Incoming,
gentlemen. - Sol. Ay-yi-yi.
(Sighs) Deep breaths.
Sol. Nash, you might want to stop
shuffling your papers for five seconds.
I will not buy you gentlemen beer.
Bender. Oh, we're not
here for beer, my friend.
- John. Oh.
- (Sol Chuckles)
Does anyone else feel she
should be moving in slow motion?
Will she want a large wedding, ya think?
Shall we say swords, gentlemen?
- Pistols at dawn?
- Have you remembered nothing?
Recall the lessons of Adam Smith,
the father of modern economics.
"In competition...
Sol and Neilson: individual
ambition serves the common good."
- Exactly.
- Every man for himself, gentlemen.
Bender: And those who strike
out are stuck with her friends.
Hansen. I'm not gonna strike out.
Sol. You can lead a blonde to
water, but you can't make her drink.
- I don't think he said that.
- Sol: Nobody move...
She's looking over here.
She's looking at Nash.
Hansen. Oh, God. He may
have the upper hand now,
but wait until he opens his mouth.
- (Laughing)
- Remember the last time?
Bender. Oh, yes, that was
one for the history books.
Adam Smith needs revision.
What are you talking about?
If we all go for the blonde...
we block each other.
Not a single one of us is gonna get her.
So then we go for her friends,
but they will all give
us the cold shoulder
because nobody likes
to be second choice.
Well, what if no one
goes for the blonde?
We don't get in each other's way,
and we don't insult the other girls.
That's the only way we win.
That's the only way we all get laid.
(Laughs)
Adam Smith said
the best result comes
from everyone in the group doing
what's best for himself, right?
That's what he said, right?
- Right.
- Incomplete.
Incomplete, okay?
Because the best result will come...
from everyone in the group
doing what's best for himself...
and the group.
Nash, if this is some way for
you to get the blonde on your own,
- you can go to hell.
- Governing dynamics.
Governing dynamics. Adam Smith...
was wrong.
- Sol: Oh, here we go.
- Neilson: Careful, careful.
Thank you.
"C" of "S" equals "C" of "T."
(Muttering)
You do realize this flies in the face
- of a 1 50 years of economic theory?
- Yes, I do, sir.
That's rather presumptuous,
don't you think?
It is, sir. (Stifled Laugh)
Well, Mr. Nash,
with a breakthrough of this magnitude,
I'm confident you will
get any placement you like.
Wheeler Labs,
they'll ask you to
recommend two team members.
(Whispering) Yes!
Stills and Frank are excellent choices.
Sol and Bender, sir.
Sol and Bender are
extraordinary mathematicians.
Has it occurred to
you that Sol and Bender
might have plans of their own?
(Laughing)
- Baby!
- Wheeler, we made it!
- Cheers, cheers, cheers!
- To... oh! Oh!
Okay, awkward moment, gentlemen.
Umm...
hmm.
Governing dynamics.
- Congratulations, John.
- Thanks.
- Toast!
- To Wheeler Labs!
Neilson. To Wheeler!
The Pentagon 1 953 Five Years Later
Man. General, the analyst
from Wheeler Lab is here.
Dr. Nash, your coat?
Thank you, sir.
Doctor. General, this is Wheeler
team leader Dr. John Nash.
Glad you could come, Doctor.
Hello.
Right this way.
We've been intercepting radio
transmissions from Moscow.
The computer can't detect a pattern,
but I'm sure it's code.
John: Why is that, General?
Ever just know something, Dr. Nash?
Constantly.
General. We've developed
several ciphers.
If you'd like to review
our preliminary data...
Doctor?
Nash's voice.
6-7-3-7,
0-3-6...
(Mental Voice)
8-4-9-4.
(Continues Listing Numbers)
9-1-4-0-3-4.
I need a map.
46-1
3-08,
67-46-90.
Starkey Corners, Maine.
48-03-01,
Prairie Portage, Minnesota.
These are latitudes and longitudes.
There are a least 1 0 others.
They appear to be routing orders
across the border into the U.S.
Extraordinary.
Gentlemen, we need to move on this.
Who's big brother?
You've done your country
a great service, son.
- Captain!
- Yes, sir.
Accompany Dr. Nash.
What are the Russians moving, general?
Captain Rogers will escort you
to the unrestricted area, Doctor.
Thank you.
Captain. Dr. Nash, follow me, please.
Man On Radio. None of those who have
said they don't like the method
have told us any other
method they could use
that would be effective.
- And when you hear...
- Driver: It's Dr. Nash.
All right.
Wheeler Defense Labs MIT Campus
- Thank you, sir.
- Home run at the Pentagon?
Have they actually taken
the word "classified"
out of the dictionary?
Oh, hi. The air
conditioning broke again.
How am I supposed to be
in here saving the world
- if I'm melting?
- Our hearts go out to you.
You know, two trips to
the Pentagon in four years.
That's two more than we've had.
It gets better, John.
Just got our latest
scintillating assignment.
You know, the Russians have the H-bomb,
the Nazis are
repatriating South America,
the Chinese have a standing
army of 2.8 million,
and I am doing stress tests on a dam.
You made the cover of Fortune... again.
Please note the use of
the word "you," not "we."
That was supposed to be just me.
Oh. (Laughs)
So not only do they rob
me of the Fields medal,
now they put me on the
cover of Fortune magazine
with these hacks, these
scholars of trivia.
John, exactly what's the difference
between genius and most genius?
Quite a lot.
He's your son.
Anyway, you've got 1 0 minutes.
I've always got 1 0 minutes.
Sol. Before your new class?
Can I not get a note from
a doctor or something?
You are a doctor, John, and no.
Now, come on, you know the drill,
we get these beautiful facilities,
M.I.T. gets America's
great minds of today
teaching America's
great minds of tomorrow.
Poor bastards.
Now, have a nice day at school.
The bell's ringing.
(Door Opens)
The eager young minds of tomorrow.
(Loud Jackhammering)
Can we leave one open, Professor?
It's really hot, sir.
Your comfort comes second
to my ability to hear my own voice.
Personally,
I think this class will be a waste...
of your...
And what is infinitely worse...
my time.
However, here we are.
So you may attend or not.
You may complete your
assignments at your whim.
We have begun.
Miss.
Excuse me!
- Excuse me!
- Hey, hey!
Hi!
Um, we have a little problem.
It's extremely hot in here
with the windows closed
and extremely noisy with them open.
So, I was wondering if
there was any way you could,
I don't know, maybe work someplace
else for about 45 minutes?
- Worker: Not a problem.
- Thank you so much!
- At a break!
- Got it!
Worker. Let's go. Let's
clean it a little bit!
As you will find in multivariable
calculus, there is often...
a number of solutions
for any given problem.
As I was saying, this problem here
will take some of you
many months to solve.
For others among you,
it will take you the term
of your natural lives.
Man. Professor Nash.
William Parcher.
Big brother,
at your service.
What can I do for the
Department of Defense?
Are you going to give me a raise?
Let's take a walk.
- Impressive work at the Pentagon.
- Yes, it was.
Oppenheimer used to say,
"Genius sees the answer
before the question."
You knew Oppenheimer?
His project was under my supervision.
Which project?
That project.
It's not that simple, you know?
Well, you ended the war.
We incinerated 1 50,000
people in a heartbeat.
Great deeds come at
great cost, Mr. Parcher.
Well, conviction, it turns out,
is a luxury of those on
the sidelines, Mr. Nash.
I'll try and keep that in mind.
So, John, no family,
no close friends...
Why is that?
John: I like to think it's
because I'm a lone wolf.
But mainly it's because
people don't like me.
(Chuckles)
Well, there are certain endeavors
where your lack of personal connection
would be considered an advantage.
- This is a secure area.
- They know me.
Have you ever been here?
We were told during our initial briefing
that these warehouses were abandoned.
That's not precisely accurate.
(Low Radio Chatter)
(Tapes Screeching)
(Sirens, Man Speaking Russian)
By telling you what
I'm about to tell you,
I am increasing your security clearance
to top secret.
Disclosure of secure information
can result in imprisonment.
Get it?
What operation?
Those are a good idea.
This factory is in Berlin.
We seized it at the end of the war.
Nazi engineers were attempting
to build a portable atomic bomb.
The Soviets reached this facility before
we did, and we lost the damn thing.
The routing orders at the Pentagon,
they were about this, weren't they?
The Soviets aren't as
unified as people believe.
A faction of the Red Army
calling itself Novaya Svobga,
"the New Freedom,"
has control of the bomb
and intends to detonate it on U.S. soil.
Their plan is to incur
maximum civilian casualties.
Parcher. Man is capable
of as much atrocity
as he has imagination.
New Freedom has sleeper
agents here in the U.S.
McCarthy is an idiot,
but unfortunately that
doesn't make him wrong.
New Freedom communicates to its agents
through codes imbedded in
newspapers and magazines,
and that's where you come in.
You see, John,
what distinguishes you
is that you are,
quite simply,
the best natural
code-breaker I have ever seen.
What exactly is it that
you would like me to do?
Commit this list of
periodicals to memory.
Scan each new issue,
find any hidden codes,
decipher them.
Doctor: Place your
chin on the chin rest.
- Stare into the light.
- Man. Pulse 88, regular.
Okay, this may be a
little uncomfortable.
(Groans)
That's got a little
zap to it, doesn't it?
He just implanted a radium diode.
Don't worry, it's safe.
The isotope decays predictably.
As a result, these
numbers change over time.
They're the access
codes to your drop spot.
So what am I now, a spy?
- (Knocking)
- Come.
Boy, you must be really important.
It's all right, Mike.
What are you working on?
Classified.
Everyone waited half an hour.
For?
Class.
You missed class today.
Oh. I suspect that...
nobody missed me.
(Chuckles)
The problem that you
left on the board...
I solved it.
Oh, no you didn't.
You didn't even look.
I never said that the Vector
Fields were rational functions.
Your solution is elegant.
Though on this particular occasion,
ultimately incorrect.
You're still here.
I'm still here.
Why?
I'm wondering, Professor Nash,
if I can ask you to dinner.
You do eat, don't you?
Oh, on occasion, yeah. (Chuckles)
Table for one. Prometheus
alone chained to the rock
with the bird circling
overhead, you know how it is.
(Laughs)
No, I expect that you wouldn't...
You wouldn't know.
If you leave your
address with my office,
I'll pick you up Friday at 8:00
and we'll eat.
One more thing. Do you have a name,
or should I just keep
calling you "miss"?
Governor, may I present...
- Miss Alicia Larde.
- How do you do?
- Professor, please. You and the governor.
Wait, one second. I'm
sorry. I want a copy of this.
First big date and all, you know.
So, you boys need to look good.
Which is not a state you find
yourselves in altogether naturally.
There. Better.
- I'm surprising him.
- You just keep on surprising him.
Professor.
God must be a painter.
Why else would we have so many colors?
So you're a painter?
That's not actually what I said,
but, yes...
I am.
Here.
Me.
Your date?
Practice human interaction
and social comportment.
That's a plan.
Champagne would be lovely.
I'll be outside.
I will get the champagne.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you for that.
No, keep it.
I believe in deciding
things will be good luck.
Do you?
No.
I don't believe in luck.
But I do believe in
assigning value to things.
Oh.
I once tried to count them all.
I actually made it to 4,348.
You are exceptionally odd.
I bet you're very
popular with the girls.
A pair of odd ducks, then.
Mmm.
Pick a shape.
What?
Pick a shape. An animal... anything.
Okay.
An umbrella.
Do it again.
(Chuckles)
- Do it again.
- All right.
- What would you like?
- Do, uh...
an octopus.
(Dog Barking)
(Alicia Chuckles)
Alicia: You don't talk much, do you?
I can't talk to you
about my work, Alicia.
I don't mean work.
I find that polishing my interactions
in order to make them sociable
requires a tremendous effort.
I have a tendency to
expedite information flow...
by being direct.
I often don't get a pleasant result.
Try me.
All right.
I find you attractive.
Your aggressive moves towards me
indicate that you feel the same way.
But still, ritual requires that we
continue with a number
of platonic activities
before we have sex.
I am proceeding with those activities,
but in point of actual fact,
all I really want to do is have
intercourse with you as soon as possible.
Are you gonna slap me now?
How was that result?
Girl: What are you doing?
I'm attempting to isolate
patterned re-occurrences
within periodicals over time... and you?
You talk funny, Mr. Nash.
Do I know you?
My uncle says you're very
smart but not very nice,
so I shouldn't pay no
mind if you're mean to me.
And who might your uncle be?
The prodigal roommate...
returns.
(Chuckles)
- Come here.
- Charles, Charles, Charles.
My sister...
got herself killed in a car crash.
Not too far now, Marcee!
Her cowboy husband was too drunk
to know that he was too drunk to drive.
So, I took her in.
- She's so small.
- She's young, John. That's how they come.
I'm at Harvard...
doing the great author's workshop.
D.H. Bloody Lawrence.
I really do think you should
buy yourself a new book.
(Chuckles)
Well, I've been reading a lot about you.
How are you, John?
At first all my work here was trivial,
but a new assignment came up and...
I can't really tell you any details.
Top secret? Black bag? Black ops?
Something like that.
- And, uh...
- yes?
Well, l... I met a girl.
- No! A human girl?
- Homo sapiens.
- A biped?
- Yup. And contrary to all probabilities,
she finds me attractive on
a number of different levels.
(Laughs) Really?
God, that's wonderful.
There's no accounting
for taste, is there?
Should I marry her?
Oh, God. Right.
I mean, everything's going well.
The job is fine. I have enough money.
It all seems to add up.
But how do you know for sure?
Nothing's ever for sure, John.
That's the only sure thing I do know.
Waiter: Good evening.
Alicia, please don't be angry.
I just lost track of time at work...
- again.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry.
I didn't have time to wrap it.
Happy birthday.
The refractive faces
of the glass, you see,
they create a full wavelength dispersal,
so if you look inside it, you can see...
- Every possible color.
Yeah.
Remember you said that
time God must be a painter,
because of all the colors?
At the governor's house...
you said that.
I didn't think you were listening.
I'm always listening.
It's beautiful.
(Chuckles)
Alicia, does our relationship
warrant long-term commitment?
'Cause I need some kind of proof,
some kind of verifiable, empirical data.
(Laughs)
I'm sorry, just give me a moment...
to redefine my girlish
notions of romance.
A proof?
Verifiable data.
Um... okay.
Well, how big is the universe?
Infinite.
How do you know?
I know because all the data indicate it.
- But it hasn't been proven yet?
- No.
You haven't seen it.
How do you know for sure?
I don't, I just believe it.
Mmm.
It's the same with love, I guess.
Now,
the part that you don't know...
is if I want to marry you.
(Applause)
Smile for the camera!
Well done!
Oh, sweet pea.
- I love you.
- Congratulations.
Hey, Sol.
Woman. You look beautiful.
Sol: Hi, how are you?
Alicia: Hey, Sol.
- Woman: Bye-bye.
- Man: Bye, now.
- Bye!
Be safe!
(Gate Opens)
Cambridge, MA October 1 954
Get In. Hurry.
They're following us.
Who's... Who's following us?
The drop's been compromised.
- (Gunfire)
- Parcher. Get down!
- Stay down.
- (Horn Honks)
- (Pants)
- (Horn Honking)
(Gun Firing)
- Here, take this.
- I ain't shooting anybody.
- Take the goddamn gun!
- No!
Son of a...
(Screams)
You stay back. Don't move.
(Tires Screeching)
Alicia. John?
Hi.
Where were you?
- S-Sol... - Yeah,
I talked to Sol.
He said you left the office hours ago.
Why didn't you call me?
Are you all right?
Honey?
(Bolt Locking)
John...
Please, talk to me.
Tell me what happened.
John, open the door.
Come on, open the door! Let me in!
Talk to me!
John!
Open the door!
(Panting)
Woman: Watch for cars, kids.
(Door Opens, Closes)
John.
William.
This is not what I signed on for.
Every time a car backfires
or a door slams...
I understand... better than
you could possibly imagine.
You need to calm down, John.
Now listen to me. We're
closing in on the bomb,
in large part due to your work.
Now don't you think your
fear is a small price to pay?
William, my circumstance has changed.
Alicia's pregnant.
I told you attachments were dangerous.
You chose to marry the girl.
I did nothing to prevent it.
The best way to ensure
everybody's safety
is for you to continue your work.
Well, I'll just quit.
You won't.
Why would I not?
Because I keep the Russians
from knowing you work for us.
You quit working for me,
I quit working for you.
Parcher!
John, you all right?
John?
Turn it off! Turn off the light!
Why would you do that?
Why would you turn the light on?
What is wrong with you?
You have to go to your sister's.
I left the car out the
back. You take Commonwealth.
- No side streets, you stay where it's crowded.
- John, I'm not going anywhere!
When you get to your sister's,
you wait for me to call you.
- No, I'm not going.
- Just get your things.
- I'm not leaving...
- stop! Stop it!
Please, Alicia.
I'll explain when I can.
Harvard University National
Mathematics Conference
Marcee. Uncle John!
Uncle John!
(Growls)
- Hey, baby girl!
- (Marcee Laughing)
Wow, someone needed a hug!
I saw you on the slate
and I thought to myself,
"How can I miss seeing a guest lecture
by the inimitable John Nash"?
What's wrong?
I got myself into something.
I think I might need some help.
Well, now you tell me, what is it?
Woman. Professor Nash!
Welcome!
After?
John: So, we see that the... the zeroes,
of the Reimann zeta function,
correspond to singularities
in space-time,
singularities in space-time...
And conventional number theory...
it breaks down in the face
of relativistic exploration.
Sometimes our expectations
are betrayed by the numbers.
Variables are impossible
to assign any...
rational value.
Professor Nash!
- Hold it!
- Professor Nash?
Professor Nash,
let's avoid a scene, shall we?
What do you want?
My name is Rosen,
Dr. Rosen. I'm a psychiatrist.
Forgive me if I don't seem persuaded.
I'd like you to come with me, John.
Just for a chat.
It appears I have no choice.
Oh-hh!
Help me! Somebody!
(Screams) Somebody!
Help me! Get off me!
I know who you are! I know who you are!
No, no, no, no, don't.
Charles, they're Russians!
Call somebody! Call somebody, Charles!
- They're Russians!
- Steady the leg.
Get away from me.
Stay away from me!
Dr. Rosen. There, now.
All better.
- Everything's all right here.
- (Gasps)
Watch your head.
(Dr. Rosen, Faintly) John?
Can you hear me?
(Faint Whispering)
Go easy now.
Thorazine takes a
little while to wear off.
Sorry about the restraints.
You've got one hell of a right hook.
(Weakly) Where am I?
Ahem.
Macarthur Psychiatric Hospital.
I find that highly unlikely.
You made a mistake.
My work is non-military in application.
Which work is that, John?
I don't know anything.
(Laughs) There's no good in
keeping secrets, you know.
(Groans)
(Buzzer)
Charles?
I didn't mean to get
you involved in this.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Charles...?
The prodigal roommate revealed.
"Saw my name on the lecture slate"?
You lying son of a bitch!
Who are you talking
to? Tell me who you see.
How do you say, "Charles
Herman" in Russian?
How do you say it in Russian?
There's no one there,
John. There's no one there.
He's right there. He's right there.
Stop! I don't know anything!
Stop! l... I don't know anything!
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held against my will.
Somebody call the Department of Defense.
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held against my will!
Alicia. What's wrong with him?
John has schizophrenia.
People with this disorder
are often paranoid.
But... But his work.
He deals with conspiracies...
Yes, yes, I know.
In John's world, these
behaviors are... accepted,
encouraged.
As such, his illness
may have gone untreated
far longer than is typical.
What do you mean? How long?
Possibly since graduate school?
At least that's when his
hallucinations seem to have begun.
What are you talking
about? What hallucinations?
One, so far, that I am aware of.
An imaginary roommate
named Charles Herman.
Charles isn't imaginary.
He and John have been best
friends since Princeton.
Have you ever met Charles?
Has he ever come to dinner?
He's always in town for
so little time, lecturing.
- Was he at your wedding?
- He had to teach.
Have you ever seen a picture of him,
- talked to him on the telephone?
- This is ridiculous.
I phoned Princeton.
According to their housing records,
John lived alone.
Now, which is more
likely... that your husband,
a mathematician with
no military training,
is a government spy
fleeing the Russians...
You're making him sound crazy.
...Or, that he has lost
his grip on reality?
Now the only way I can help him
is to show him the difference
between what's real
and what is in his mind.
Come on.
What's he been working on?
His work is classified.
He mentioned a supervisor
by the name of William Parcher.
Maybe Mr. Parcher can
clarify things for us.
But I can't get to
him without clearances.
You want me to help you get
the details of my husband's work?
John thinks I'm a Russian spy.
Is that what you think?
- What did the doctor say?
- Is he sick?
I don't know.
I want to see what
Johns been working on.
- You know you can't go in his office.
- It's classified, Alicia.
Stop. Oh!
Oh, my God.
Why didn't you say something?
Alicia, John's always been
a little weird.
He said he was doing code-breaking,
that it was eyes-only.
- Top secret, part of the military effort.
- Was he?
Well, it was possible, you know?
Directives come down all the time
that some of us aren't cleared for.
- It was possible.
- Possible, but...
not likely.
Lately, he'd become
so much more agitated
and then when you called...
So, is this all he's
been doing every day?
Cutting out magazines?
Well, not all.
(Door Opens)
- Alicia: I'm so sorry.
- John: It's okay.
- I missed you.
I have to talk to you.
Okay.
Alicia, I've been thinking about it,
and I do realize that my behavior
and my inability to discuss
the situation with you
must have appeared insane.
I left you with no other choice.
I do understand...
- and I'm truly sorry.
- That's okay.
Everything's gonna be all right.
We just have to talk quietly.
They may be listening.
There may be microphones.
I'm gonna tell you everything now.
It's breaking with protocol
but you need to know,
because you have to
help me get out of here.
I've been doing top-secret
work for the government.
There's a threat that exists
of catastrophic proportions.
I think the Russians feel
my profile is too high.
That's why they simply
just don't do away with me.
They're keeping me
here to try to stop me
from doing my work. You
have to get to Wheeler.
- You have to find William Parcher.
- Stop.
- He can help us.
- Stop. Stop. Stop!
I went to Wheeler.
Good, good.
There is no William Parcher.
Of course there is.
- I've been working for him.
- Doing what?
Breaking codes?
Dropping packages in a secret mailbox
for the government to pick up?
How could you know that?
Sol followed you.
- He thought it was harmless.
- Sol followed me?
They've never been opened.
It isn't real.
There is no conspiracy, John.
There is no William Parcher.
It's in your mind.
Do you understand, baby?
You're sick.
You're sick, John.
John?!
John!
Code red.
(Over P.A.) Dr. Rosen, code
red. Observation room two.
Dr. Rosen, code red.
Observation room two.
(Keys Jingling)
John?
The implant's gone.
I can't find it.
It's gone.
Dr. Rosen. You see, the
nightmare of schizophrenia
is not knowing what's true.
Imagine...
if you had suddenly learned
that the people and the places
and the moments most important to you
were not gone, not dead,
but worse...
Had never been.
What kind of hell would that be?
Administering insulin.
Man. 8.42 am.
How often?
Five times a week for 1 0 weeks.
Princeton University 1 Year Later
Alicia. John always spoke so
fondly of being here at Princeton.
And Hansen is running
the department now.
So he keeps reminding
us, and reminding us.
(Laughs)
Yeah.
John won't come near the campus, though.
- I think he's ashamed.
- (Baby Cries)
Hey. Hey.
Want this?
So, Alicia, how...
how are you holding up?
Well, the delusions have passed.
They're saying with the medication
and low stress environment...
No, l... I mean, how are you?
I think often what I feel
is obligation.
Or guilt over wanting to leave.
Rage against John, against God and...
But...
then I look at him
and I force myself to see
the man that I married.
And he becomes that man.
He's transformed into
someone that I love.
And I'm transformed into
someone who loves him.
It's not all the time,
but...
it's enough.
I think John is a very lucky man...
Alicia.
So unlucky.
- Alicia: This is us.
- Sol: This is it?
- It's nice.
- It's near where I work.
Alicia. John? You've a visitor.
Hi.
I hope it's okay.
Hey ya, chief.
- Cigarette?
- Ah, no, thanks.
I quit, actually.
- Hello.
- Hey, John.
Have you met Harvey?
Umm, I...
(Laughs)
- John, there's no...
- Relax, it's okay.
There's no point in being nuts
if you can't have a little fun.
Jesus Christ, John. (Laughs)
I should have known.
Here you go.
I can take those later.
You're supposed to take them now.
- Can I bring you something?
- I'm okay.
Okay.
So, um... yeah. l... I was in town
giving a workshop.
I go back tonight.
You know, Bender, he really wanted
to stop by and you know,
see you. You know, say hi.
Squeamish?
Yeah.
I suppose I would be, too.
But alas, I'm stuck with me.
- I'm trying to solve the
Reimann Hypothesis. - Uh-huh.
Oh, yeah?
I figured if... if I dazzle them,
they will have to reinstate me.
But it's difficult with the medication,
because it's hard to...
see the solution.
You know, John, you should go easy.
There are other things besides...
Besides work.
What are they?
(Baby Crying)
Shh-hh.
Shh.
(Door Closes)
What are you thinking about?
What do people do?
It's life, John.
Activities available,
just add meaning.
You could try leaving the house.
You know, maybe...
talk to people.
You could try taking out the garbage.
(Muffled Voice)
John. And there's some
more... there's some more in...
(Muffled)
Who... Who were you talking to?
Garbage man.
Garbage men don't come at night.
I guess around here they do.
(Man Whistles)
(Truck Approaching)
(Giggles)
Sorry.
Alicia. Is it the medication?
(Door Closes)
(Screams)
(Sobs) I don't know what to do.
(Sobbing Continues)
(Car Door Opens)
My mother's going to keep the
baby a little longer tonight.
I can get three hours of overtime.
(Faint Music Playing)
I'm going to bed.
- Good night.
(Clattering)
(Gun Cocks)
Parcher. It's good to see you, John.
It's been a while.
Parcher?
Yes, sir.
You're not real!
Of course I am. Don't be ridiculous.
(Rifles Cocking)
I don't think that I
would go that way, John.
It's time for you to get back to work.
Parcher. The bomb is
in its final position
here in the U.S.
Knowing your situation
requires you keep a
low profile, "Mohammed,"
we've brought the mountain to you.
(Generator Whirrs)
(Radio Signals)
We've narrowed the bomb's location
to somewhere on the eastern seaboard.
But we haven't been able to
pinpoint its exact position.
Their codes have grown
increasingly complex.
Here, look at this, John.
What?
- Dr. Rosen said...
- Rosen! That quack!
"Schizophrenic break
from reality," right?
Psychological bullshit!
Look at me, John.
John, look at me.
Do I look like I'm imagined?
Wheeler has no record of you.
Do you think we list our personnel?
John, I'm sorry you had
to go through all this.
I've gone to a great deal
of trouble to get you back.
I can restore your status at Wheeler.
I can let the world know what you did.
But I need you now, soldier.
I was so scared you weren't real.
Princeton, New Jersey April 1 956
There's a storm coming.
I'm just going to
grab the laundry, okay?
I'll draw his bath.
It's okay.
Okay.
(Faint Radio Sounds)
(Muffled Radio Voice)
(Radio Static, Broken Voices)
(Whimpering)
(Crying)
(Thunder Rumbles)
John!
I've almost got it! Charles,
you just watch the baby.
- (Baby Crying)
- I've got one more to close!
- No!
- John: I'll be right there.
- Oh, God.
- (Crying)
I need a towel.
Shhh.
Charles was watching him. He was okay.
There is no one here.
- Charles was watching him.
- There is no one here!
He's been injected
with a cloaking serum.
I can see him because of a chemical
that was released into my bloodstream
when my implant dissolved.
I couldn't tell you, it
was for your own protection!
Alicia!
- No!
- Hello, I need Dr. Rosen's office, please.
You've got to stop her, John.
You leave her out of this.
- Who are you talking to?
- It's not her fault.
- John.
- She'll compromise us again.
- No, she won't.
- You'll go back to the hospital.
- John, answer me!
- Countless people will die.
Alicia, please, put the phone down.
- I can't let that happen.
- Yes, hello?
Hi, I need Dr. Rosen. Is he in?
I'm sorry, John.
John: No-oo!
- Alicia?
- Parcher. You know what you have to do, Nash.
- Get away from me.
- She's too great a risk.
- Get away!
- (Baby Crying)
I didn't mean to hurt you!
Finish her. She knows too much now.
Uncle John?
Parcher. Take care of her,
you pathetic piece of shit,
or I'll take care of you.
John,
Christ, John, please do what he says.
Move, soldier.
Now.
Marcee. Uncle John?
Charles. John, please!
Now!
(Mental Voices) Alicia and
Charles never co-exist in the same
interactive field. Alicia and Parcher...
(Voices Continue)
- Marcee: Let's play!
- (Voices Increase)
...Charles, and Marcee
cannot co-exist with Alicia.
I understand.
(Engine Starts)
(Screams)
She never gets old.
Marcee can't be real.
You see them now?
Yes.
Why did you stop your meds?
Because I couldn't do my work.
I couldn't help with the baby.
I couldn't...
I couldn't respond to my wife.
You think that's
better than being crazy?
We'll need to start you on a higher run
of insulin shocks and a new medication.
No.
There has to be another way.
Dr. Rosen. Schizophrenia
is degenerative.
Some days may be symptom-free,
but over time, you are getting worse.
It's a problem. That's all it is.
It's a problem with no solution.
And that's what I do, I solve problems.
- That's what I do best.
- This isn't math.
Dr. Rosen. You can't
come up with a formula
to change the way you
experience the world.
- All I have to do is apply my mind.
- There's no theorem, no proof.
- You can't reason your way out of this.
- Why not? Why can't I?
Because your mind is where the
problem is in the first place.
I can do this.
I can work it out. All I need is time.
Is that the baby?
The baby's at my mother's, John.
(Marcee Humming)
Dr. Rosen. Without treatment, John,
the fantasies may take over...
entirely.
Alicia. You almost ready?
Rosen's waiting outside.
I can't go back to that hospital.
I won't come home.
He said that if you said that,
he has commitment papers for me to sign.
Well, maybe you won't sign them.
Maybe you'll just give me some time.
I will try to figure this out.
Whatever you do,
Rosen is right about one thing.
You shouldn't be here.
I'm not safe anymore.
Would you have hurt me, John?
I don't know.
Maybe you should let Dr. Rosen
drive you to your mother's.
(Muffled Voices)
(Car Doors Close)
(Engine Starts)
(Car Departs)
(Footsteps On Stairs)
Rosen said to call if you
try and kill me or anything.
You want to know what's real?
This.
This is real.
Maybe the part...
that knows the waking from the dream,
maybe it isn't here.
Maybe it's here.
I need to believe
that something
extraordinary is possible.
(Sighs)
Princeton University Two Months Later
Hansen. Come.
Hello, Martin.
Jesus Christ.
No. l...
I don't have that one. My savior complex
takes on a completely different form.
(Nash Chuckles)
I heard what happened and well,
l... I wanted to write and
I tried you at Macarthur's
but you'd left, and I just...
this is Helinger's old office.
Yeah.
Yeah, I stole it from him.
Seems that you won after all, Martin.
They were wrong, John. No one wins.
Please, please have a seat.
God, it's so good to see you.
What brings you back to Princeton?
Charles. John?
John, I'm sorry, but
you have to tell him.
Tell him you're a genius.
You're a genius, John!
Tell him your work is critical.
John, please!
Is there any chance that you
could ignore what I just did?
Of course, what are old friends for?
Is that what we are, Martin? Friends?
John, of course.
Of course. We always have been.
Alicia and I think that...
That fitting in,
being part of a community,
might do me some good.
That a certain level of attachment,
familiar places, familiar people,
might help me...
elbow out these...
These certain delusions that I have.
It's a lot to ask,
and now that I'm here,
I'm quite certain that
you will just say no.
But I was wondering
if I could hang around.
(Sighs)
Huh.
Will you be needing an office?
No.
No, I could just work
out of the library.
Well, this guy tries to
wander into the library,
- but he doesn't have I.D.
- Why can't people read their memos, huh?
Then he goes totally nuts.
John: Not real! You're not real.
There's no mission.
Oh, shit. Shit.
Not real! You are not real!
Is this what you are, soldier?
Some useless ghoul?
The local madman?
- I'm not a soldier.
- You're gonna end up in a cell!
Old, worthless, discarded.
There's no mission.
And while you rock and drool,
the world will burn to ashes!
You are not real! You are not real!
You're still talking to me, soldier.
There's no mission! I'm not a soldier!
John? John?
John, John, John, John.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey, hey, hey.
John, John! It's okay.
I just heard what
happened, I'm sorry. John...
- I'm not a soldier.
- John. Hey, Nash.
Nash, hey.
Hey, you're all right.
Nash, Nash, hey, hey, hey.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the great John Nash!
Hansen: John?
John. You should've seen their faces.
Everybody was just staring at me.
John...
you know that stress
triggers the delusions.
I know.
But then, on the way home,
Charles was there.
Sometimes, I really miss talking to him.
Maybe Rosen's right.
Maybe I have to think about going
back into the hospital again.
No.
Come here.
Maybe try again tomorrow.
John, now, you can't ignore me forever.
Charles, you've been a
very good friend to me.
The best.
But I won't talk to you again.
I just can't.
Same goes for you, baby girl.
(Sniffs)
Good-bye.
I was wondering if I
might audit your course.
It's... It's an honor, Professor Nash.
Is something wrong?
This will be my first class.
(Laughs)
Good morning,
eager young minds.
(Muttering Numbers)
It's never gonna work, John.
You're just humiliating yourself.
It's pathetic!
You are being pathetic.
I'm ashamed of you.
(Laughing)
(Laughing Continues)
Oh, man!
Are you coming? You're gonna be late.
- Dad, you've got my book.
- What?
You've got my book.
Oh, right.
Thanks.
- Good-bye.
- Bye.
Alicia. See you tonight.
Bye, honey.
Princeton University October 1 97 8
Did you just solve Reimann?
Well, what do you think?
Huh.
That's an analog to Frobenius
for non-commutative extensions.
(Chuckles)
Yes, it is.
But it only appears to
work sporadically, so, no.
But...
I believe I'm making progress.
You're...
Youre John Nash, right?
- Toby Kelly.
- Hello.
I've been studying your equilibrium.
The one you wrote here, at Princeton.
To come up with something totally
original, the way you did...
You know, I was young. (Chuckles)
umm...
I've been developing a theory.
I believe I can prove
that Galois extensions
are covering spaces.
That everything,
everything is connected.
That it's all part of the same subject.
When was the last time you ate?
- Excuse me?
- You know, food.
Oh, uh...
My wife,
she loves mayonnaise.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Go on.
The function...
- is in the two
categories. - Um-hmm.
Hansen. Alicia!
Alicia!
John. ...coming together
at maximum speed of...
let us say 1 0 miles per hour.
So you have a fly on
the tire of bicycle B,
and the fly, who can
travel at 20 miles an hour,
leaves the tire of
bicycle B and it flies
to the tire of bicycle a
and backwards and forwards
and so on and so forth
until the two bikes collide
and the poor little fly is squashed.
- (Chuckling)
- This is the important thing
about actually focusing
in and comprehending
the area that you're dealing with.
Mathematics is very specific,
and it is an art form,
no matter what these people
around here will tell you,
especially the people from biology.
Don't listen to any of those people.
Let me go back to what
you were doing before.
I might want to steal this,
write a book and get famous.
I was thinking that I might teach.
A classroom with 50 students
can be daunting for anyone.
John, besides, you're
a terrible teacher.
I'm an acquired taste, Martin.
I was hoping there still might
be something I could contribute.
What about the...
Well, you know.
Are they gone?
No, they're not gone.
And maybe they never will be.
But I've gotten used to ignoring them
and I think as a result
they've kind of given up on me.
You think that's what it's like
with all our dreams and
our nightmares, Martin?
You've got to keep feeding
them for them to stay alive?
John, they... haunt you, though.
They're my past, Martin.
Everybody's haunted by their past.
Well, good-bye.
John, I'll talk to the department.
Maybe in the spring.
Hey, Nash?
You...
you scared?
Terrified.
Mortified. Petrified.
Stupefied by you.
Now you ought best ring Alicia,
- or you're gonna get me...
- I'll ring her.
...in an awful lot of trouble.
- Thanks, Professor.
- Good-bye.
- Have a nice
day. - Good-bye.
Papers in hand, Mr. Beyer.
"Princeton University March 1 994"
Professor Nash?
- Can you see him?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- Uh-huh.
Positive? He's within your vision?
- (Laughing)
- Okay. Good.
Forgive me, I'm just always
suspicious of new people.
- See you next week, Professor.
- See you next week.
So now that I know that you're real,
who are you, and what can I do for you?
Professor, my name is Thomas King...
- Thomas
King? - Mmm-hm.
...and I'm here to tell you
that you're being considered
for the Nobel prize.
John: Forgive me, but
I'm just a little stunned.
King: Over the past few
years your equilibrium
has become a cornerstone
of modern economics.
Suddenly everybody likes that one.
What about my work on other some
such projects... manifold embedding?
The application of
your bargaining problem
to F.C.C. bandwidth auctions
or to antitrust cases...
- Antitrust cases?
- Yes.
I never would have considered that.
- Well...
- Have I just reached
some level of honesty
that borders on stupidity?
(Laughs) No, no, you haven't.
'Cause, I wouldn't have thought of that.
Shall we have tea?
Oh, I don't go in there. I usually just
take my sandwich in the library.
Come on, John. Let's have
some tea. It's a big day.
M-Most...
Most commercially
available brands of tea
are not suitable to my palate.
I'm not...
There are some northern Indian
teas which are dense enough...
I enjoy the flavor that they have...
I have not been in this room
for some many years. I
wonder what tea they serve.
John. Why, thank you, young lady.
Things have certainly
changed around here.
I have a son that age.
- Harvard.
- (King Chuckles)
Hmm.
I would have thought the nominations
for the Nobel prize
would have been secret.
I would have thought you'd only
find out if you won or lost.
That is generally the case, yes.
But these are special circumstances.
The awards are substantial.
They require private funding. As such,
the image of the Nobel is...
I see. You came here to
find out if I was crazy?
Find out if I would
screw everything up if I actually won?
Dance around the podium, strip
naked and squawk like a chicken,
things of this nature?
Something like that, yes.
Would I embarrass you?
Yes, it is possible.
You see, l...
I am crazy.
I take the newer medications,
but I still see things
that are not here.
I just choose not to acknowledge them.
Like a diet of the mind,
I choose not to indulge
certain appetites.
Like my appetite for patterns.
Perhaps my appetite to
imagine and to dream.
Man. Professor Nash.
It's good to have you here, John.
Thank you.
- It's an honor, sir.
- Thank you very much.
A privilege, Professor.
Professor.
- Nicely done, John.
- Thank you, Tom.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ed.
That was certainly most unexpected.
(Applause)
Nobel Prize Ceremony Stockholm, Sweden
December 1 994
John. Thank you.
(Applause Fades)
I've always believed in numbers.
In the equations and logics
that lead to reason.
But after a lifetime of such pursuits,
I ask,
what truly is logic?
Who decides reason?
My quest has taken me
through the physical,
the metaphysical,
the delusional,
and back.
And I have made the most
important discovery of my career.
The most important discovery of my life.
It is only in the
mysterious equations of love
that any logical reasons can be found.
I'm only here tonight because of you.
You are the reason I am.
You are all my reasons.
Thank you.
John: So nice to have met you.
I'll call for the car, Dad.
Bye-bye.
Woman: Bye-bye.
- Are you ready to go now?
- Oh, yes, I am.
Yes, indeed, and yes, please.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
What is it? What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
- Come with me,
young lady. - Oh-hh...
I have a car outside.
Are you interested in a ride? "Nash's theories
have influenced global trade negotiations..."
Where's it going to? "national labor relations,
and even breakthroughs in evolutionary biology."
John and Alicia Nash live
in Princeton, New Jersey.
John keeps regular office hours
in the Mathematics Department.
He still walks to campus every day.
I will
Watch you
In the darkness
Show you
Love will
See you through
When the bad dreams
Wake you crying
I show you
All love can do
What love can do
I will watch through the night
Hold you in my arms
Give you dreams
Where none will be
I will watch through the dark
Till the morning comes
All the light
I'll take you through the night
To see
The light
Showing us all love
Can be
I will
Guide you
With my bright wings
Stay till your heart
Learns to see
All love
Can...
Be.
(Female Vocal)