Bad Guy
Episode 16
Enjoy:)
To tell you the truth,
the Haeshin Group mistook the young
Shim Gun Wook as Hong Tae Seong.
So when it was discovered that things
went wrong after he was adopted,
the Haeshin Group cast
him aside immediately.
Are you saying he was thrown out?
The scar on his back was
from that time, too.
Also, Choi Seon Young.
Even she died because of Hong Tae Seong.
Then that woman was...
He probably didn't want
that family living in peace.
Nothing has been confirmed for sure,
so let's not give up on him.
They, who treat others worse than insects
because of their worthless pride...
The ones who cover themselves
with a mask called Haeshin...
I'll crush them all.
Gun Wook...
I thought you said you trust me.
Then trust me until the very end.
Gun Wook...
No matter what happens.
Gun Wook!
Who exactly keeps sending me this?
Who?
You must've been upset that I'm alive,
even though you thought I was dead.
Why do you fear me so much?
You must be feeling uneasy...
thinking I might become a part
of your family again.
You're playing around with me
even after your death?
Evil bastard.
Do you think I'd fall for your tricks?
Me?
Shim Gun Wook...
There were a lot of patients
in the E.R. that day,
but I didn't treat any patients who
were involved in a car accident.
What do you mean by that, Dr. Kim?
You were doing the E.R. shift that night.
What are you talking about?
I told you to call me if there
were any patients in critical condition...
since I was going out to eat.
Oh, yeah. One of my colleagues
happened to visit me on that day,
so I definitely remember.
You came into the E.R. just in time,
so I thought you didn't go out to eat.
Nurse Baek, even though you
haven't worked here for that long,
can't you even recognize my face?
He wore glasses and had short hair...
I'm sure it was you.
Please show me the list of patients.
Here, I've had it prepared.
Is this not your signature?
This isn't my signature.
What happened?
Doctor's name: Kim Seong Jin
Yes, detective?
Have you found Gun Wook yet?
No. I haven't found him yet.
Aside from that,
was there anything...
weird about Shim Gun Wook lately?
Because I don't think
this was a simple car accident.
Maybe someone had intentions
to harm Shim Gun Wook, or...
Someone's trying to harm Gun Wook?
Have you heard anything
about Shim Gun Wook...
from Hong Tae Seong, or
Shin Myung Won from the gallery?
It seems like Shin Myung Won
knows who Shim Gun Wook is.
Then there's a chance that...
the people from Haeshin...
I'm not suspecting them of anything, but...
I'm just being open to all the possibilities
for the purpose of this investigation.
What's for sure is that...
someone intentionally erased all traces
of Shim Gun Wook.
I sent him on a vacation.
What brings you here?
Where did you...
send Gun Wook on vacation?
Why do I have to tell you that?
Did Gun Wook really go on vacation?
Maybe you don't know where he is.
What is it that you want to say to me?
It's been over a week since
Gun Wook disappeared,
but you lied to me about
sending him on vacation, and...
Tae Seong won't even try to look for him.
Did you conspire against Gun Wook?
To rid this planet of him?
Why do you concern yourself
about Gun Wook so much?
Because he's an important person to me.
An important person?
What is Tae Seong to you then?
We're not talking about
Tae Seong right now, though.
Let's stop this.
What...
did you do with Gun Wook?
Why do you think that I
did something to him?
If anyone's going to look for him, it's me.
When it comes to worrying about him,
I worry about him more.
You know...
who Gun Wook is, right?
What did you say?
The child that your family
threw out 20 years ago.
Isn't that right?
What do you mean, "the child
that my family threw out 20 years ago"?
This is the first time I've heard of that.
You're not pretending you don't know about
something even I know about, right?
It's our family affair.
I don't think you're in a position
to be involved in our family affairs yet.
Please leave my room.
You're making me feel uncomfortable.
They say Gun Wook...
died.
They don't even know where Gun Wook
is right now after he was in an accident.
Whether he was really
admitted to some hospital, or...
He couldn't have...
Gun Wook's ID was found with a dead body...
that was transported from a car accident.
I don't know what happened after that.
No way...
If...
it was Haeshin that did something...
knowing who he was...
Then I definitely won't stay
quiet about this.
Oh, you're here, ma'am?
The Director is in, right?
She's having a meeting inside
the room right now.
This is the second time,
Department Head Kim.
Why did something that was thrown
away appear in front of me a second time?
That is something I also do not know about.
Why wasn't I able to call you last night?
Are you sure you weren't meeting
with Shim Gun Wook or something?
I even put myself in the
face of danger to help you,
so are you trying to throw me out
using false accusations now?
Are you threatening me?
I'm sure you told me it
would be the last time, and...
that's why I took care of the
matter without leaving a single trace.
It was for Haeshin,
but also because things would be
troublesome for me if I made any mistakes.
It'll only make things difficult
for Haeshin if you suffer.
Do you think I would want that?
I have also protected this
company for 30 years.
Fine.
Was there anyone else who
saw him on the day of the accident?
Or was there anyone else who helped you?
I made sure not to leave any
traces behind as best I could.
I even took care of the car
from the accident.
He's dead.
Then I'll be leaving.
Department Head Kim. Where is Shim Gun Wook?
Tae Ra, you. Talk with me.
Department Head Kim, leave.
Please don't leave and answer my question.
Where is Shim Gun Wook?
Tae Ra, you. Why are you doing this at work?
Are you still looking for him?
Mom.
They say Shim Gun Wook died.
What?
You seem surprised.
That accident you were talking about.
You were talking about Gun Wook's accident,
weren't you?
What do you mean he died of an accident?
Don't pretend you don't know.
You were the one who told me.
That Gun Wook died.
Did I say that?
I can't even remember.
Tae Ra, are you going to find faults
in the things I said while I was angry?
Bastards like him could be
rid of using just a couple of cents.
Are you going to hurt my feelings like that?
Is that the kind of person
you thought of me as all this while?
Am I really wrong?
Do you really have nothing to do
with that matter?
One of the chairman's favorite employees
had a car accident not too long ago.
Since Chairman Hong was unconscious,
Madam Shin was trying to help him.
But where did you hear about his death?
Is he really dead?
Is that important right now?
He was punished by God.
He deserved to die.
Did he think he'd be safe
after ruining our family like this?
Mom.
How can you say that when someone has died?
It's not just anyone,
but someone who once called you Mother.
How could you...
I'm just saying that because
what he did was despicable.
Please stop.
How did she find out?
It seems like she sent her secretary
to the hospital to find out.
There is a record of his death, so it would
have been possible for her to find out.
Is that so?
It looks like it was taken care of well.
Take your leave, Department Head Kim.
Yes, ma'am.
~ I take a step back ~
Into the place seemingly close,
but unreachable
Even if your name that I couldn't call out
hits my chest and it bruises
I'm sorry for being someone like this
for not being able to get close to you
I love you
Shim Gun Wook...
you're really "that" Tae Seong?
Even though I still cry alone today
Jae In.
Miss Hong Mo Ne sent this
to you from the U.S.
Alright.
Ah, that's a lot.
- Make them order lots.
- Yes.
And spend less money on the vegetables.
Aside from that, Gun Wook
hasn't called at all...
What happened to him?
Hello?
This is Jang Seung from
the "Family Bulgogi" restaurant.
Who?
I'll send you a text if your hearing's bad.
- I'm kidding.
- Who the heck is this...
The reason I've called you is because...
I just can't seem to contact Gun Wook.
I told you to call me when
you find Gun Wook.
When did I tell you to call me
and ask where he is?
Well...
Hel-
I guess being a jackass is hereditary.
Do you know how to drive?
Do you want to drink coffee?
No. I'm fine.
Do I just keep going this way?
Turn left h-
I also hate it when others
touch me when I'm driving.
It's the same for me. I'm sorry.
I told you before, right?
That I had an officetel that I don't use.
How was that car from earlier?
Was it comfortable?
Have it.
The car and this officetel too.
What?
I was thinking, and I realized
I haven't done anything for you.
Mission complete...
or actually no.
There are a lot of things
I want to do for you.
Let's eat together with your
mother next time.
I want to give her something good, too.
To give me these things all of a sudden...
I don't want them.
I can't take gifts like these.
Why?
Why can't you take them?
You know you've been acting
a bit strange lately?
You look like you're out of it,
and you won't pick up my calls either.
Tae Seong.
Is it because of Shim Gun Wook?
Jae In.
Why do you care about him so much?
Do you know about Gun Wook?
You've had him by your side for a long time.
I do know something about him.
I know that he was trying to take
over Haeshin by manipulating Tae Ra.
Is that all you really think about Gun Wook?
Then how am I supposed to think about him?
It's not just Tae Ra, but Mo Ne and I
were manipulated by him, too.
Gun Wook is...
a person who used to be in your place.
He's the Hong Tae Seong who was
kicked out of your family 20 years ago.
A person who used to be in your place.
Just now...
What did you say?
I mean, Jae In...
What are you talking about right now?
It doesn't make any sense.
How can Shim Gun Wook be that child?
And, Jae In... how do you know about that?
I...
I don't understand a word you're saying.
The person who Choi Seon Young
fought with in front of the officetel,
perhaps it was the person who was
adopted and disowned before you...
were adopted into the Haeshin
household as a child.
So this is the place you've
come to while carrying her suicide note?
Because of you... a woman has died.
Are you afraid because I'm telling you to
kill me while standing in front of you?
Are you scared?
Shim Gun Wook.
You're like my brother sometimes.
Hey, Tae Seong.
Keep that up just until I finish this ice cream.
Try to act like you're my older brother.
I'm not raising any little brothers.
I have no intention of being an older brother,
and humans are supposed to live and die alone.
It's a butterfly.
Father, you remember, don't you?
The one who came before me...
I hear that he's Shim Gun Wook.
That guy...
after losing his place as your son to me,
he also lost his place next to Seon Young.
But he still took care of me.
He's funny, isn't he?
Why didn't he ask me for a fight?
Or just seriously kill me instead?
What are you playing at, Shim Gun Wook?
You're here.
Did you know about it?
What was it that he wanted?
Because he missed his family...
from the household that kicked him out...
Whatever it is, I'm not interested.
Why aren't you interested?
He even manipulated you.
What do you know?
It's not something you should
concern yourself with.
Aren't I your little brother?
Answer me.
Do you love him?
That's right.
I still love him.
Even if he approached me with
the intention of getting his revenge,
or tried to take over Haeshin,
I love him regardless.
But the one I love...
is gone without a trace,
and I don't know if he's dead or alive.
How do you think I feel right now?
If he's alive, at least...
I don't care about anything else.
Father!
- Father!
Father...
Even if your name that I couldn't call out
hits my chest and it bruises
I'm sorry for being someone like this
for not being able to get close to you
I love you
Because I wasn't able to
say that one phrase
Jae In.
I cry alone sometimes
I'm a truly pathetic person
After I reach the end of the world
without finding a single excuse for myself
I'll probably regret while looking back
I'm sorry for being someone like this
Gun Wook.
You should hurry home.
Where are you?
You're going to come back for sure, right?
I'll be waiting for you, so...
you have to come back for sure.
Alright?
Honey.
Please don't worry about anything,
since I'll take care of everything.
You can just stay relaxed.
Tae Ra is going to become
Chairman in your place...
and Tae Ra and I will protect our Haeshin.
I even removed him from our sight,
so who else would I support
in becoming the next Chairman?
Tae Seong?
Surely I'll be able to stop people like him?
How dare they set their eyes on our Haeshin.
Let's go to your room now.
It's time to sleep.
Mom.
He's dead! Dead!
Even Tae Ra said so. That he's dead!
Manager Eun!
He's dead! Dead!
Madam.
I've become too agitated.
Why am I like this?
Madam.
What happened to Shim Gun Wook?
What about the list of the deceased?
Yes.
I've looked through all the hospitals within
downtown Seoul and the city limits.
There weren't any patients
admitted with the name Shim Gun Wook.
And there were no deceased by that name, either.
Are you positive?
Yes.
Vice-chairman.
This is a delivery that was just
sent to your n-
Alright. You can leave now.
Shim Gun Wook...
Do you think I'll leave him
alone after what he's done to me?
It's something that has to be done,
no matter who does it.
Why? Are you scared?
I'm not a patient person.
Keep in mind...
that this is the last chance for you,
Department Head Kim.
Why? Are you scared?
I'm not a patient person.
Keep in mind...
Shim Gun Wook.
Shim Gun Wook. Shim Gun Wook.
Search all the hospitals that are out there.
He's not dead.
Shim Gun Wook.
No. He might've been admitted
under a different name.
Hong Tae Seong, Choi Tae Seong.
Whatever the name is.
Use all means possible to find him!
Director, Director Yoon has come to visit.
Oh my. Welcome, Director Yoon.
Have you been well, Madam?
Yes.
Everyone's talking about the upcoming election
for the new Chairman of the Board, right?
What are you doing right now?
Mom...
He was more resilient and
scarier than when he was young.
And yet you unknowingly protected him.
You killed him after all?
[Letter of Resignation]
Jae In, what's the matter all of a sudden?
Jae In.
Yes, detective.
Pardon?
You found Gun Wook?
Yes.
Oh. You're here, Tae Ra?
It's good that you're here.
I needed to talk to you about
the special meeting of Directors.
Shim Gun Wook...
Do you think I'll leave him
alone after what he's done to me?
It's something that has to be done,
no matter who does it.
Where exactly did you get this?
Mom, did you really...
kill Gun Wook or something?
I'm really tired of hearing
the name Shim Gun Wook.
Why would I kill someone like that? Why?
Then what is this recording?
What exactly have you done to Gun Wook?
I don't know.
The special meeting of Directors
is tomorrow.
That's when the new Chairman of the
Haeshin Group will be elected!
It seems like most of the directors
want Tae Seong as the new Chairman.
That's not what I'm asking you right now.
Did you order Department Head Kim to do it?
To kill him.
I'm right, aren't I?
You're not giving me an answer,
so that must mean I'm right.
Why on earth...
Why would you...
I told him to remove that bastard.
From my sight.
Are you satisfied now?
How could you kill someone who was once
Father's son and my little brother? How?
I didn't kill him.
Who says I killed him?
I just meant that he's a tenacious bastard
I wouldn't care for even if he died.
Do you still want to trust him even
after you've been tricked like that?
I am the one who feels the most anger,
hatred, and fury because of him!
I am the one who lost the most
because of him.
Two of my siblings, my father...
and my family was broken apart.
So please,
please let him go.
Tae Ra.
How could you still be so tender?
Don't concern yourself with
things like that.
What is most important for us?
It's Haeshin. Haeshin!
Set your eyes on nothing else. Nothing else!
I wanted to see you.
Where are you?
Stop playing around and quickly come out.
It's fine even if you manipulate me.
I don't even care if you despise
me enough to shiver in hatred.
Please show up in front of me right now.
Shim Gun Wook...
Please.
show up in front of me right now.
I was a bit late, checking security tapes to see
which direction the ambulance was headed.
Thank you.
Did they say Gun Wook was okay?
I think it's true that there
was an accident.
We'll have to meet him
to see how he's doing, but...
they say he was in a bad condition
when he was first wheeled in, so...
prepare yourself.
Tae Seong.
Tae Seong!
It's time to eat!
Oh, be careful. You're going to fall over.
The one in charge of the site
for the Incheon Theme Park...
[Letter of Resignation]
Get him to call me after five minutes.
[Hong Tae Seong]
What happened to Moon Jae In?
I'm not sure.
I think she left after she heard
that Shim Gun Wook was found.
Shim Gun Wook... was found?
Gun Wook...
Yeah?
You were hiding here.
You were alive.
Yeah.
Were you resting because you were tired?
Why didn't you tell me
you were having a hard time?
I could've lent you my shoulder...
Huh? It won't write.
Why are you doing this, Gun Wook?
The pen won't write.
It's a black pen, but it won't write.
Use this.
Stop it. You're hurting yourself.
Why are you crying, Mom?
Mom's not crying.
Oh my baby, Mom's not crying.
About that male patient in room 312...
Oh, the patient named Hong Tae Seong?
Hong Tae Seong?
Ah yes, he came in because
he was in a car accident.
He was bleeding quite a bit when he came in,
but he had no other problems.
He hurt his head, but his external
injuries weren't that bad.
But why is he like that?
I think he's mentally impaired because of
an unknown psychological trauma.
That patient's guardian told me he'd
go through a thorough check-up,
and get treated at a bigger facility,
so we're just taking care of him for now.
His guardian?
A young person sometimes comes to visit.
Could I get his or her contact information?
Contact information? Just a moment please.
You didn't have to go this far.
Take it.
Tae Seong.
I...
want to be by Gun Wook's side.
Don't be confused, Jae In.
People tend to want to see and
miss others more...
when they suddenly disappear
from their sight.
Is it because you sympathize with Gun Wook?
Gun Wook...
has hurt your feelings,
but I hurt Gun Wook's feelings.
Gun Wook probably needs me.
Did Shim Gun Wook tell you
that he needs you?
Why don't you know that it's all lies?
Do you want me to tell you why
Shim Gun Wook is doing this?
Because I cast Seon Young aside,
he wants to take you away from me.
I don't care how it is.
Then what about me?
Are you telling me to go like this,
without giving me a chance to
make you happy?
I...
want to...
support Gun Wook from his side.
I can't.
I can't give up on people anymore.
I'm sorry.
I...
I've done something horrible. I'm sorry.
I told you it's alright.
You've seen what I was like inside.
Tae Seong, don't love me.
Because she might...
suffer more...
and be hurt because of me...
I pushed her away. Seon Young, that is.
However, what Seon Young wanted
at that time was for me to hold onto her.
But I wasn't able to do so.
So if...
if I'm able meet someone I can love again...
I definitely won't lose her, and
I will do everything that she wants...
that is what I vowed to myself.
But you're telling me to let go
of you right now?
What I really want right now is...
for you...
to let me go.
I'm sorry.
Honey.
What's the matter?
Are you angry at me for something?
Is it because I didn't stay with you?
Bear with it.
I'm tired from taking care of
a lot of things these days.
I can just wrap up that problem
regarding Gun Wook now, and...
I think I'll have to kick
Tae Seong out of the family.
I just can't stand him.
Honey.
What's the matter?
Honey. Honey!
Honey!
Let me go.
Honey, what's the matter with you?
Manager Eun!
Chairman, please let go of her.
- Honey.
- Please let go of her.
Chairman!
Unni,
Aren't you going to put this watch on?
Give me your hand. I'll put it on for you.
Who did you meet?
Tae Seong ahjussi?
Or... Gun Wook ahjussi?
Both of them.
Are you cheating on both of them?
Are you?
Jeez. Just wait.
Was Tae Seong ahjussi's
blood type saved onto the phone?
The two of you are the very
essence of romance...
Jeez! What's up with this?
It shouldn't be like this! This thing!
Was Gun Wook ahjussi’s
blood type saved onto the phone?
Oh!
Have you come to a decision?
You've finally come to your senses! Eh?
Are you going to Gun Wook ahjussi’s side?
Going to Gun Wook's side...
It wouldn't be too late now, would it?
It's already late when you think it's late.
By a lot.
Then you can just start anew.
Cheer up.
Alright?
Hey, what's up with you?
Cheer up.
Jeez, what was his blood type?
Type AB.
Oh, type AB.
[27th Haeshin Group Chairman
Elections Special Meeting of Directors]
[August 3rd, 2010
Grand Meeting Hall within Haeshin Group]
Alright. Please have a seat. Have a seat.
I'll announce the results of the election
for the new Chairman of the Haeshin Group...
that the Directors have voted for.
Vice-chairman Hong Tae Ra, 15 votes.
Executive Director Hong
Tae Seong also has 15 votes.
Because of this, we'll have
a second vote to...
Just a second.
In place of Director Hong Mo Ne,
who could not make it here,
I would like to exercise her rights
to a shadow vote.
As you can see, it is a Power of Attorney
from Director Hong Mo Ne...
that states all her rights
as a Director and as a shareholder...
be given to Executive Director
Hong Tae Seong.
No way.
Mo Ne never made such a thing!
Why would Mo Ne give that
to him when she has her sister?
Alright.
This is definitely Director Hong Mo Ne's
Power of Attorney.
Then because of this,
with 15 votes against 16,
I announce that Executive Director
Hong Tae Seong...
has been elected as the Deputy
Chairman of the Haeshin Group.
No way!
What is this nonsense!
What's the matter again?
Executive Director Hong Tae Seong is a person
with no right to be here in the first place!
Please calm yourself and have a seat,
Mother.
I'm not interested in the position
of Chairman, or anything like that.
Tae Seong, you...
I don't know how you manipulated
Mo Ne, but...
things will not turn out as
you want them to.
They'll never turn out as you want!
Mom. Please stop it.
Madam Shin. Executive Director Hong
Tae Seong, as Chairman Hong's heir,
not only has the rights to Chairman
Hong's shares, but his position...
That's assuming he's an heir.
From the beginning, before everything else,
Executive Director Hong Tae Seong...
had neither the requirements
nor the rights to the inheritance.
- What is this?
- What is she saying?
Mother... I told you to stop it.
Mother?
You are not related to Chairman
Hong Jung Soo in any way whatsoever.
Huh, what?
I'm saying you're not Chairman
Hong Jung Soo's real son.
My...
Executive Director Hong Tae Seong shares not a
single drop of blood with Chairman Hong Jung Soo.
You can see this, right?
I prepared this in the event something
like this happened.
Mother, you're really too much.
I was never interested in the position
of Chairman since the beginning.
No matter what happened,
I was planning on giving it all to Tae Ra.
But...
you say I'm not my father's son?
Then did you think I was lying?
Mom, please stop it.
Tae Seong, you too.
I'm sorry. Let's finish the special meeting
of Directors at this point in time...
and I think it'd be a good idea
to discuss...
the issue of electing a Deputy Chairman in
our next special meeting of Directors.
Then I conclude this meeting.
[DNA Paternity Test July 29, 2010:
Hong Jung Soo/Hong Tae Seong]
[Results of Paternity DNA Test Analysis:
NOT A MATCH]
Then Mom...
if Tae Seong isn't Father's real son...
who's the real Tae Seong?
That child died.
When?
20 years ago.
What?
The real Tae Seong died?
Yeah, that's right.
After all the turmoil, your father looked
for the bastard child, but...
that was after he died.
I couldn't hurt your father twice.
You're saying it was one coincidence
after another?
This is all...
because your father made the
mistake of having an affair.
In the end, you end up receiving the
consequences for the mistakes you make.
Are you sure you're not the
one who gave him that consequence?
What?
Didn't you intentionally bring in Tae Seong,
who was completely unrelated?
Tae Ra, you...
What kind of a person do you think I am?
You're really selfish.
Don't you know how many people
are hurt and suffering because of you?
If you lied to Father,
you should have kept that secret
to your grave, why bring it up now?
Have you never considered
Tae Seong's feelings?
He doesn't share a drop of blood with me
and he's not my husband's child,
so why do I have to care for him?
I did everything I was supposed
to do already by raising him!
You've never truly loved
Tae Seong, though. Not once.
Everyone is born under different destinies.
His place is elsewhere.
Please stop it now.
Do you think he deserves to be
in our family?
He lives his life like that,
because we tried to put a misfit like him
into an unfitting lifestyle such as this.
Tae Ra.
You're someone who is soon to be
Chairman of the Haeshin Group.
Only think about how you
can move our Haeshin forward.
How far do you have to go
until you're satisfied?
You were the source that caused all
of this to happen to our family.
I'm tired of it now.
You... can have the position of Chairman.
You always told me, didn't you?
That the position is yours.
You are not related to Chairman
Hong Jung Soo in any way whatsoever.
The workplace is not like school.
Think about what you should be doing!
Try to understand what kind
of a place Haeshin is.
Father...
Tae Seong, let's go in.
I'm saying you're not Chairman
Hong Jung Soo's real son.
Who's the real Tae Seong?
He died.
Because my thorn, that grows
day by day, hurts you
I try my best to hide my tears, but
They're exposed when I stand before you
Even though I painfully push you away
You're always at the same
place in my heart
I'm in front of your apartment.
Come out for a minute.
Who...
My little sister.
Jae In.
Thanks. I'll enjoy eating it.
Because your scent still lingers in me
I cannot forget you yet
I can still feel your tears
I guess I'm still hurt that much
I'll make you lots of
tasty things when you're back.
I'll bring lots of tasty things, so...
make sure you come back.
I don't care about the condition
that you're in.
I don't care even if you laugh
like an idiot,
and I don't care even if you can't
recognize me, so...
come back quickly.
Let's eat together for sure this time.
I guess my never-ending love for you
would not let me send you away yet
What?
Shim Gun Wook is alive?
Where is he?
He was in a nursing home in Kangwon County.
He's been admitted under
the name Hong Tae Seong, too.
But Madam, I think he's mentally ill.
I don't think he's normal right now.
Should I just let him be?
No.
What happens if he regains his sanity?
The source of trouble should
be sliced away with a clean cut.
Father.
I can call you Father, right? Even still...
Why didn't she tell me a little bit later?
Anyway, Madam Shin and I catch
each other at the worst moments.
Can't I be with you a bit longer?
Father...
we grew close to each other
while you raised me?
I haven't done anything for you yet.
Do you still have something you want?
Uncle!
So Dam, where have you been?
A kiss?
Have you been listening to your mom?
I finally understand...
why you treated me so cruelly,
why you gave me the cold shoulder.
Mother, I...
Don't call me Mother.
You and I are completely unrelated.
Mother.
Do you know why I didn't
go to my biological mother?
I bet it was the money.
No.
Because the two of you at least
didn't throw me away.
So I thought there would
be a day I'd repay that favor.
I told myself I would, even if I
were to leave.
But...
it seems like I can't even do that now.
I have no reason to feel sorry for you.
We gave you the best lifestyle
you could have ever had.
I'm sorry, Mother.
I didn't even realize that you
raised me all this while, and...
I only got angry all time.
I should've been better to you much earlier.
I knew from the moment
I first came into this house.
That no one loved me.
That no one accepted me as a part
of the family.
I waited, thinking it was hard
for everyone...
to open up their hearts again
after the boy before me left, but...
if I'd known back then that everyone
couldn't love me...
it actually would've been easier for me.
Your father loved you.
Those words are...
the most kind, among all the things
you've ever said, Mother.
I'll be off.
A tadpole by the creek
Squiggle, squiggle
While he was swimming
Pop! the hind legs come out
Pop! the front legs come out
Hop! Hop! It's become a frog!
Squiggle, squiggle
While it was swimming
Pop! the hind legs come out
Pop! the front legs come out
Hop! Hop! It's become a frog!
Tae Seong.
Don't sympathize with me.
I really hate that.
It's nothing like that.
Eat before you go.
See?
You're sympathizing with me already.
I should cut my ties...
and go my own way now.
I'm going.
Tae Seong.
Where are you going?
Can't I go with you?
What?
You're going to meet Shim Gun Wook,
aren't you?
I also have a lot of things to
talk about with him.
Father.
I've left my seat empty for too long.
I'll get it back soon and give it
to Tae Ra or Mo Ne.
It would've been nice if Tae Gyun
were here too.
As you always used to say,
"If you can achieve something great, then
don't think about how the process may be. "
Shin Myung Won will keep this seat safe,
so please don't worry.
I've arrived, ma'am.
I'll take care of it without a trace.
Please make sure to take care
of it this time.
Call me when you're finished.
You're here, ma'am?
Hello?
What?
Shim Gun Wook has disappeared?
The only grief you feel
is for being tricked, right?
Then what about Gun Wook's tragic life?
I'm sorry, Tae Seong.
Why are you doing this to us?
Why are you doing this to me?
I won't come see you anymore.
I threw away the real one
and brought in a fake.
In the end, you lost your parents,
your brothers and everything.
Sometimes, even I don't know who I am.
Who will call me?
And which name will they call me with?
would not let me send you away yet
Because your scent still lingers in me
I cannot forget you yet
I can still feel your tears
I guess I'm still hurt that much
I always wander about your place
The alien ET...
he had supernatural powers,
but they were all friends.
Hoy hoy.
Why can't I have a Gumiho friend?
[My Girlfriend is a Gumiho]
The fox has disappeared!
Why are you doing this to me?
I liked you?
How can I pull that off?
You can't let me go.
You're mine.
Why me, why?!
You're looking for information, right?
The person you are desperately seeking,
is currently at Dongbo Charcoal Grill.
It's really not a big deal like I thought.
Will we be able to catch her alive?
- Dae Yong!
- Don't come any closer!
You stayed alive because of me,
but now you'll die.
[My Girlfriend is a Gumiho]