Read!
October 22nd, 2009, Thursday.
Year 1388 after the Rajah.
170th day after the beginning of spring.
295th day of the year.
Daytime gets three minutes shorter.
Defense of...
Kansan 1601.
"Facilitate things to people...
do not make it harder for them...
give them good tidings instead
of breeding hate."
Hadith.
Yusuf...
Take care of these,
your only pair.
OK.
Dad, I dreamed last night.
I was sitting under a tree.
The stars...
Dreams shouldn't be spread around,
whisper.
Don't tell your dreams to anybody.
Children, now close your notebooks.
Who wants to read?
Lpek, please read.
The Lion and the Mouse.
On top of a sleeping lion...
a little mouse...
was running around.
Its tiny steps...
woke the lion up.
He tossed the mouse...
to the ground.
And he grabbed it...
with his paw.
Fine, lpek. Well done.
Let's clap for lpek.
Come here lpek.
This is for you.
OK.
Be seated.
- Thank you!
Yes, Yusuf?
- May I read, teacher?
Let's try.
The Lion and the Mouse.
On top of a sleeping...
Not that one.
Turn to "The Eagle and the Turtle."
Read that one.
Turn the page.
You'll see it.
Go on, Yusuf.
Go on, Yusuf. Read.
The e-e-eagle...
a-a a-n-n-nd th-e-e...
T-t-tu-tu-rt-t-t-tle...
Quiet! Again, Yusuf.
Relax and speak louder.
The e-e-eagle...
a-a-an
Quiet!
A-a-an and
t-t-t-tu-tur...
r-r-t-tle.
Fine, Yusuf.
Let's try again later.
I don't know what to do with him.
Drink your milk, Yusuf.
Cut it.
What did you do today?
If you like, you can tell me
by whispering into my ear.
You know what? The tailless bear,
that bear had cubs,
the one that went after Idris' beehives.
Really?
- Really.
Have you seen the cubs?
Yes I have.
When can I see them?
On Saturday, when we go
to change the hives.
OK.
Yusuf...
what's this flower called?
Violet.
Both...
its honey and pollen
are of pinkish colour.
What about its taste?
- What?
Lts taste?
- Nice and sweet.
Yes, sweet.
What's this flower called?
Erikotu.
Its pollen can make honey.
Yusuf...
What about that flower?
But it doesn't have petals.
Not now, because it's off-season.
You tasted its honey last year
and it made you dizzy.
The crazy honey!
Havva come up to the blackboard
and read out page seventy five.
Everybody open up your books
and follow.
What are you doing, Yusuf?
Put it near the stove
and it will dry.
Go change your clothes.
Yusuf!
Yusuf?
I need rope from Hamdi's father.
Stay and do your homework.
Good afternoon, Huseyin.
- Hello, Yakup.
Is it done?
- The rope is done.
Come see me.
Here, for you.
Is that for me?
- Yes.
Do you like it?
- I like it.
Thank you, Uncle Yakup.
Have a nice day, Huseyin.
Thank you.
Dad, look at what Uncle Yakup gave me.
- Thats very nice, son.
Yusuf!
Yusuf, come here!
What's wrong, son?
Tell me, son!
Fa-fa-father...
Are you scared?
Come and help me!
The tea is ready.
Bring it to your father.
Me, me, me!
Open your notebooks.
I'll check your homework.
And your homework, Hamdi?
Didn't you do it?
How many times must I tell you?
Do your homework!
Tell your mother to come see me.
Be good like Yusuf.
Will you place those bees
in the hives?
Yes.
When will you be back?
In two days.
Is Camgoz going with you?
Yes.
May I go with you?
Who will take care of your mother?
There was a sailboat there.
It sailed out to sea.
Yakup?
Maybe we should take Yusuf
to lmam Niyazi.
Gokhan said that there is honey
around the Karaucurum.
I will place the new hives there.
Why?
There is no honey here.
The beehives across the valley
are also empty.
And the bees?
God knows where they are.
I must check the hives
around the junction.
I seek refuge
in the Lord of mankind.
The King of mankind,
the God of mankind.
Refuge from the evil of the whisperer
who whispers in the hearts
of mankind.
Be they of Djinn and mankind.
Good Morning.
Onder Saybas.
- Here.
Gulcan Kesici.
Yusuf Ozbek.
Yusuf Ozbek?
Hamdi Kaygin.
Hamdi is absent?
- He didn't come today.
Is he sick?
- I don't know.
Sevval Agun.
- Here.
Kemal Baylar.
Nazlican Kopuz.
Nermin Alinoglu.
Pricked by wheat,
on fine grass I'll tread:
Dreamer as I am,
my feet will feel its freshness.
I'll let the wind wet my bare head.
I'll not talk,
my mind will be a void:
But endless love will surge
within my soul,
And I'll go far, really far,
like a vagabond,
In the country,
happy as if I was with a girl.
On blue summer nights,
I'll go along pathways.
Pricked by wheat,
on fine grass I'll tread:
Dreamer as I am,
my feet will feel its freshness.
I'll let the wind wet my bare head.
Hamdi is inside.
Brother Zekeriya,
did you find honey?
A poor harvest this year.
Have you been to the Karaucurum?
- No.
I was wondering if you saw Yakup.
Faik met him the day before yesterday.
- Brother Faik saw him?
Faik, come here!
Hello!
- Hello Brother Faik, did you see Yakup?
Yes, he was trying to place his hives.
He'll be back soon.
- Around the Karaucurum?
Yes, he's looking for honey.
- Thank you, Brother.
Are you hungry, Yusuf?
On...
blue summer nights...
I'll go...
along pathways...
27th of October, 2009.
The tenth month.
31st day. 44th Week.
Daytime gets two minutes shorter.
Fish storm.
Yusuf!
Where are the eggs, son?
I'm baking cookies
for your father's return.
Bring me the eggs.
Drink your milk, Yusuf.
You didn't drink it.
What's wrong, son?
It's a pity to waste the good milk.
Come here.
Open it.
I had a very nice dream last night.
Your dad, you and me...
we were going to place
the hives together.
Down at the stream.
That spot where
we used to place the hives.
Then I saw a flower.
I bent down to take it.
I put it in my bag...
to plant it at home.
When we returned home,
those flowers were everywhere.
In the kitchen, in the bedroom...
Open your books.
You too, Yusuf.
Nutrition and its benefits.
All living organisms must be nourished...
to live.
Because nutrition...
provides the elements...
that organisms need to continue living.
Walking, running...
doing work of any kind,
all requires energy.
While our organs work,
the energy is...
Yusuf!
Yusuf, I can't see.
Stop it, son.
What's wrong with you?
Shall we do it that way?
Do you remember Gurol?
He was accepted into
the Istanbul Police Academy.
Your Uncle Bekir will visit us
this year for Bayram.
Would you also like to be a policeman?
What do you want to be, Yusuf?
Don't worry, dear.
He can't be in trouble.
He'll be back.
If you watch the boy,
I can go down to the gendarmerie.
Have a seat.
You have grown so much.
I knitted this sweater.
Try it.
It looks so nice, Yusuf.
Come with me to the highland?
Want to come?
I was asleep in Mecca when the ceiling
opened and Gabriel descended into my room.
He pulled out my heart
and washed it with holy water.
Then he brought a bowl filled
with wisdom and faith.
He filled my heart with those
and returned it in place.
He brought a fantastic white beast
called "Burak".
Smaller than a mule
but larger than a donkey.
The strides of this animal
are as long as the eye can see.
I was mounted on this animal.
Gabriel held my hand and took me
to the first level of heaven.
When we arrived, Gabriel said
to the guard: "Open the gate!"
The guard asked: "Who is it?"
Gabriel answered: "Gabriel!"
The guard asked: "Is anybody with you?"
"Yes, Mohammed is with me!"
Gabriel said.
The guard: "Was he dispatched?
Is it time for him to ascend to heaven?"
"Yes," said Gabriel.
And the guard replied:
"Then may he be welcome.
What a nice arrival this is!"
He opened the gate and we ascended
into the first level of heaven.
I saw a man. At his sides,
there were many people.
When he looked to his right,
he laughed.
When he looked to his left,
he cried.
He said to me,
"Welcome, mighty prophet."
I asked Gabriel: "Who is this?"
"Greet your ancestor Adam."
So I greeted him, as he did me.
Gabriel told me that Adam...
was surrounded by the souls
of his descendants.
Then Gabriel took me to
the second level of heaven.
He requested for the gate to be opened.
In this second level, I saw
the prophets Jesus and John.
Gabriel said: "Greet Jesus and John."
In the third level, I met Joseph.
In the fourth, the prophet Enoch.
In the fifth level, I met prophet Aaron.
I greeted them and they said to me:
"Welcome pious brother,
welcome mighty Prophet."
They brought me a bowl of wine,
a bowl of milk,
and a bowl of honey.
I took the bowl of milk.
How are you, Yusuf?
Send my regards to your dad.
Come on, Yusuf, put this on.
I'll let you know, mother.
Auntie Ayse, watch him a moment.
Brother Kemal, have you seen Yakup?
- No, but maybe he's over there.
Up there.
Yusuf, go on to school.
Read, Yusuf.
T-t-the L-l-l-l-io-o-o-n...
a-a-nd t-t-the M-m-mouse...
Fine, Yusuf. Well done.
Clap for your friend.
Come here, Yusuf.
He had an accident in the Karaucurum.
We're going to take his body soon.
May the Lord give you strength.
There is nothing we can do.