You don't have to decide now
so don't be nervous.
I won't be anxious about it.
Episode 39.
So please get your hands out of this.
Go to the cottage
where I and my mother used to live
or go to Soo.
It's a favor and an order.
Now I really go to the death of way!
Baekjae 4th Prince's way,
to Crown Prince's way!
To the way of King!
Please vanish in front of my eyes!
Yes, please vanish.
That's abandoning me.
If we have to be apart
because of danger,
if we have to farewell
because of agony,
if we have to be separated
because of considering each other,
I don't believe in those.
We must be together
because you have sickness,
we must be together
because you confront agony,
because you're in danger.
If we're not together for any reasons,
That's abandoning each other.
That's not protecting.
I don't do that.
If you have to use me,
I'll be used.
If I have to put my life on you,
I'll do that.
I won't ever vanish myself
for any circumstances.
This is the love I know!
Please use my vengeance.
How dare you!
I'll release soldiers and execute you.
Will you trust me
if I give the necklace to you?
I have a necklace 4 written on it.
If not, these don't mean
a thing to me.
So I will throw them away
into the ocean.
He gave up the necklace
which will prove himself?
He tried to be the throne by using me?
I didn't know this,
I didn't realize it!
Traditionally Baekjae gained strength
From diplomacy based on technology.
Isn't it why Prince Aja
used to concentrate on it.
It's true but in a way,
he had no choice.
He had no choice?
The Prince wouldn't dominate nobles,
it means he couldn't do national policy
under his leadership.
Do you mean there is
an important national policy?
Yes!
What could it be?
The King Onjo who found Baekjae,
The King Geunchogo
who strengthen Baekjae afterward,
the reason why he had to
conqeoror Mahan was because of salt!
To maintain lives of people at least,
Salt was essential thing.
That's why 3 nations were divided
in order to secure salt.
That's not all
but it's a significant reason.
Then what's the present era?
No, what's the next era?
- It's rice!
- Rice?
But rice isn't the main food.
Yes, but whoever had rice,
they want to have it again.
Yes, sure they do.
People want to have better food.
Yes, that makes the era.
What makes people better
naturally gets developed
its production and technology.
Finally rice will be the main food of 3 nations,
in this case,
Baekjae has geographic advantage,
And that's why we'll be attacked often.
In fact, during few centuries of 3 nations,
the production of rice rapidly increased.
What Mok tried to teach was
Jang's lmperial education!
I was only used!
Therefore, you make the naitonal plan
for the nation's future.
Notjust an individual engineer
can do to extend its prodcution
But what the nation can do!
What only nation can do!
Find those sorts.
If you succeed in it,
we'll attract nobles under Sir Sa.
How could it?
That's correct.
Nobles have open fields
they'll gain strength naturally
when agriculture is emphasized.
Princess will be satisfied
because it raises King's authority.
Satisfy, satisfy.
I'll be satisfied
when I'm used by you, 4th son.
I won't leave you alive!
What walked you here at this night?
What happened to this crack?
It's nothing serious.
Perhaps is it because of King's health?
Why didn't you tell me?
Are you afraid of me
just like Dalsol Giroo said?
If that's the case,
I'm little sad and disappointed.
Although I made
bad decisions along the way,
it was only for our father
to be enthroned.
Plus, even if we have different mothers,
I thought you'd understand me well.
I've never thought of you
as an enemy or not in the future.
I won't hurt you in any circumstances.
Please stop extending the power,
and straighten up the 4th son!
That's the only way to have peace
between you and me.
So please consider it carefully.
Brother!
It's nothing.
I'll consider what you just said.
How's the lord?
Those doctors are good,
the sudden fit is eased.
But nobody knows when it'll start again,
so I'm anxious.
My brother knows the Lord is
in critical condition.
What?
Then what happened to us?
He said that he won't hurt us.
Is it true?
Can we trust him?
So he wanted to me stop
extending my power,
and tell him about 4th son.
Right, it should be.
However, the lord's health
is getting worse.
Shouldn't we have to do that?
The man who brings this letter
is the 4th son.
This is the answer to you,
please take it.
We have to keep going.
But the situation is different
when I chose to come to the palace.
Yes, if I knew King was that severe,
I wouldn't have seen
Princess Wooyoung.
I would have gone to the general.
Pardon?
It was crucial to
come back to the palace.
I was desparate that
I had to prepare myself.
How much I could learn
in different circumstances,
what kind of danger would
come to people here...
And how fast the danger would come,
I'm not sure of.
But I just want to push it forward.
So instead me becoming the king,
please think first
What we need to do for Baekjae to improve.
I still don't have an answer to that.
I see.
What is it?
The King's health needs
special treatment.
I've written down
in detail how to treat him.
Please hand it over to Queen.
I know you'd be worried about
King's health,
but you should promote national affair
in situation like this.
Therefore I told Eunsol to provide
the important national policy.
- So, you need to...
- You people
fooled me like that,
and act like it never happened.
- Princess!
- Where is Jang?
This is it.
My lady asked me to organize
the regions of each nobles
its farm and special products
as well as minerals.
Yes, thank you.
May I take this and have a look?
Of course! She'd have made it for you.
By the way, where is she?
She went to palace.
To palace?
What brought you here?
I came to apologize.
Apologize?
Duke Seodong and I
unintentionally cheated you
and you must be disappointed.
Duke Seodong?
Who are you talking about?
I'm talking about Eunsol Jang.
Why do you call him duke Seodong?
He used to sell yam with his mother,
when he was young.
So?
I heard him saying it was his happiest days
when I was young,
so I've called him since then.
You met him when you were young?
- Yes.
- And?
Pardon?
How do you as a Silla woman end up here?
I met him when he was in Haneuljae...
Please forgive me!
Forgive you what?
You followed him here
and doing dangerous thing now
beucase of love.
You just surprise me.
Princess!
What is he that you risk your life?
Off you go.
Dismiss! Go and get Eunsol!
Creature like your love is just
the greed of becoming the Queen.
He's here?
She went to palace?
She went to see Princess?
Yes, but she didn't let go of her anger.
She won't let it go easily.
But I don't feel good.
She wanted to see you.
Go and see her.
Yes.
You need to go to Junghwajung.
The man who brings this letter
is the 4th son.
This is the answer to you,
please take it.
Internal Affair Eunsol is here.
Let him in.
How may I help you?
Have a seat!
Pick up the glass.
I don't drink but this Sogokju
is the best for Baekjae men?
Did you want to see me?
When my brother acquired
Giroo on his side,
I saw him started with
a glass of Sogokju.
I'm trying to do that.
If that's your intention,
I'll drink it with pleasure.
It is too early.
If I need to trust you intactly,
there must be no lie like the last time.
Whatever is it, I asked you to
give me your true heart.
In order to do that,
we must not have
any lies between us.
Yes.
Except the last incident,
truly, do you have any other lies?
You don't have any other lies?
No.
I'll ask you for the last time.
You really don't have any?
No, I don't.
Ok, I got it.
I'll trust you.
Now drink it.
Yes.
This is the first and
last drink I'll offer you.
Why you! Why you!
I'll serve you with my loyalty.
Yes, I got it!
It's time to see the lord.
You can deliver this to my brother.
This is the gift that Jin wanted to
give it to my brother.
Isn't it fragile gift inside?
It's not fragile material.
I don't want to give it to him
so you need to deliver it.
Yes.
Will he be killed?
He will be killed?
Jang!
He's not Jang, but the 4th son.
Jang,
Jang!
You don't have any other lies?
No.
I'll ask you for the last time.
You really don't have any?
I'll serve you with my loyalty.
I can't leave 4th son alive!
Tell him.
Eunsol is here.
Bring him in!
Please go in.
What do you want?
Princess wanted me to deliver it to you.
What is it?
This is the gift from merchant Jin Gakyung.
Really?
Open it.
Yes.
It's switched!
I sent the wrong one.
Mine is the small one
and yours is big one.
It's my mistake.
Then, I'll go out.
Whatever it is,
her mind was switched, not the thing.
What was it?
Princess! You just bestowed liquor to me.
You bestowed liquor as
its sign of your people.
To my brother,
I'll notice about your matter,
and hand over all of you!
I was afraid.
I was afraid that
King is getting severe...
I tried to give you and beg for my life!
But...
But?
But I can't watch you die.
I can't kill you!
Whether it was from method bribery
or messengers of Soo,
I do not know.
What I know now is
that I can't kill you!
Unpleasantly, undigracefully,
my heart started to be stolen.
What am I doing to save 4th son!
What am I doing!
Dalsol is here.
What is it?
I think the original chest
is the right one.
What are you talking about?
There were just accessories of woman.
Really? Then Jin must have
brought the wrong one.
Was it necklace?
What are you saying?
I heard that general asked you to confirm
To confirm just the 4th son.
4th son is dead!
Did you think
I wouldn't check and accept them?
Do you trust them?
They deceived their relatioships
and approached to you.
You've found out?
But you still trust them?
Do you trust them?
It's true that they hid it.
But when I investigated,
I could understand their situations.
I'm not like my brother.
I see what you're doing to me.
But I'm curious about you instead of them.
Their actions were all about their love.
You knew all about these,
and why didn't you tell him about this?
Plus why couldn't you understand
their feelings
and betrayed Dr. Mok and Jang?
How much do you know
and how much are you hiding
from my brother?
Did you love Jin Gakyung as well?
That must be it!
What did I want...
What did I want this from?
- Princess!
- According to Dr. Mok,
you're preparing the national policy
to open the reign of King.
What is it?
Sit down and explain it to me.
From doctor's vision,
it'll be the era of rice for the future.
Of course,
I prefer rice than any other crops.
But can it depend on the era?
If you like it,
people will like it for sure.
Anyhow isn't excellent reign
to feed people well?
Rice hasn't been great proportion
of agriculture,
but statistically among 3 nations,
only rice rapidly increased
its proportion.
It means that people favored rice.
So that Taehaksa investigated
to increase its production.
But the best way to cultivate
rice is not in field.
But in paddy field
where water can be supplied.
It's not the rainfall
but you can supply water on cropland?
Is it possible?
It looks impossible but if it's possible,
many people won't starve to death.
I'm trying to find a way.
So please allow me to focus on it
except I'm working here.
Although I lied to come back,
but my heart towards Baekjae is true.
I will dedicate this loyalty to you.
I understand.
Jang! Did you call me?
- Yes.
- Did you call them, too?
My father wasn't called up
but he followed me.
I just came to see Jang.
I told doctor about it
so you need to help me.
Open it now!
What, what's this?
Is it rice?
Isn't this the map of main land?
- Huh?
- Why this?
I wanted to make this as well.
You mean Baekjae?
It's good to make the whole thing
but that's too much.
Where mountains and open fields are.
Where rivers are and something like that.
That's foolish.
Mountains and rivers are
very large and tall and wide.
If there's a mountain,
woods have to be there.
As well as animals.
How can you draw all those
in a piece of paper?
Just like when we design things small,
we measure it and draw in reduced size.
Even if you reduce it,
think about it.
How can you do huge land
in this piece of a paper?
I see, I know people who can do this!
You're talking about Dolsye
from metallurgy, right?
Yes, and there's another person...
- Woosoo?
- Yes.
I stopped by on the way to here.
But she didn't want to talk.
After Juriyoung and Soji were killed,
she doesn't talk much.
I'll look after her.
I asked her something.
I'll investigate each regions with trainees.
I'll bring yummy foods when you're busy.
Please play with me!
- Deliver it.
- Yes!
Uncle!
Long time no see.
Now you're Sir Eunsol,
you must lower your honorific.
Please don't do that.
Still.
I came here to ask you a favor,
so please don't do that.
A favor?
Why the hell is she looking at
Jang like that?
He'll be drilled.
Hey!
- Hey!
- Why?
I was going to see you.
- I heard you don't eat much?
You gotta eat so you can fight with me.
When I fight with the weak,
what would people say to me?
It's the speical medicine
I asked from engineer Gomo.
This will stimulate your appeitite.
Don't worry.
Eat it! Damn it!
What's going on?
- I need to talk to you.
- Yeah? Let's go.
Just your land and
Sir Gook and Sir Baek,
try supplying water on it.
Then it's possible to use
a cow to cultivate
and it's notjust
strengthening your power,
you will grasp the era.
- Did you mine this mineral in that region?
- Yes.
- Have you found a mine?
It's a new mineral.
Here it is.
You came, Princess.
I'm raising 500 for martial soldiers
another 500 for weapon soldiers.
You must decide.
You must decide!
Lord!
Lord! What do I do! Lord!
This man is not the lord!
Master! Why did you scream?
Did I scream?
Yes, you shouted 'Ack.'
It's nothing, I just dreamt.
Go back to sleep.
Yes, master.
It's just a dream.
Doctor!
What is it?
I'm the servant of King's room.
King's room? So?
Lord, lord just suddenly had a fit.
What? Sudden fit?
Yes, so I was ordered to
bring the doctor and Gomo.
His health is...
I see. I will wake doctor up
And you can wake Gomo up.
Yes.
Doctor! Doctor!
Doctor!
What do you need?
I need to talk to you urgently!
I see!
What is it at late night?
A disaster happened to me suddenly.
A disaster?
I can't cope with it by myself,
so please wait for me
outside of palace, Songguemjung.
- Songgeumjung.
- Yes, I'll follow you soon.
I'm asking you sincerely!
Yes, I got it.
Lord!
What happened?
Lord! Lord!
He's not coming back after depleting blood.
Give me the musk!
Lord!
Yes, lord! This is Sun!
Can you see me?
Sun!
Yes, lord! I'm Sun.
Queen and Wooyoung,
- my Woochi...
- Yes, lord!
Lord!
Look after...
Lord! Lord!
You can't go like this!
What about us?
Lord!
Lord! Lord!
Lord! Don't leave us here!
Don't leave young Woochi here!
Lord!
Was I too cautious?
Lord! Lord!
How come Dr. Wooyoung is
no where to be seen?
She went to Nosaji with Eunsol Jang.
Isn't Nosaji the region of Sir Sa?
Yes, he went to examine the fields
and took Princess.
They will be back tomorrow.
What about Dr. Mok?
How come Dr. Mok isn't here?
Since Gomo is here,
isn't it why he wasn't called up?
Didn't you message Dr. Mok
when King started a fit?
Yes, I did.
Did you see him and say?
Someone delivered it for me.
I was in a hurry to
escort engineer Gomo.
Go through procedure
under Queen's order.
Yes!
I can't find Dr. Mok.
- Did he run away?
- I don't know about that.
Princess and Jang are on the way
to here from Nosaji.
Proceed all other things normally,
and arrest Mok and Jang quietly.
We have many things to ask them, right?
Yes!
Move, now!
Lord, lord passed away?
- Search it!
- Yes!
Do a complete search!
Did the King pass away again?
We didn't know much
but he had chronic disease.
He rumbled to get there and now he's.
Did you hear it and came out?
Where is Jang?
He went to Nosaji.
Why there?
He had business there with Princess.
Tomorrow will come soon.
You guys go to merchant Jin
and inform the death of King.
And dispose people
where Jang is coming.
Is general trying to harm him again?
- It looks like it.
- What about the doctor?
I put him in the safe place.
You guys go now
and don't let Jang to come here.
Stop now.
I stay a day in the Royal villa.
Yes!
But don't tell I'm staying here
but in Nosaji office,
to Dalsol of Internal Affair.
Princess!
You left the office for 3 days.
We have to go now
to work for tomorrow.
- Go and deliver it.
- Yes.
I'll do it.
If Princess and I don't go back...
I have an urgent matter
to discuss with you.
Let's go!
He's not there?
Yes, I searched the room
but it wasn't found.
Then did they notice first and escape?
Dr. Mok is in missing.
We're ordered to prepare
the funeral of the King.
Dr. Mok Rasoo is not around
at the moment,
so prepare it with caution.
Yes, sir!
They knew it already.
If it is so,
they will message Princess
and Jang coming here.
Release soldiers now.
Mind your own business!
Why are you so late?
I had to prepare for it.
What is it?
What's the disaster happened to you?
Please follow me.
You must help me.
- Isn't it a boat?
- Yes.
Why a boat?
I want you to meet
a man across the river
so I prepared it already.
A man across the river?
He needs your help desparately.
I can't do it with my power.
It won't be long.
So please get on it.
Isn't there other intention?
Doctor! Since when I had other intention
and lied to you?
I really do need your help!
Please get on the boat.
King really passed away?
Yes, the bell was rang already.
Ms Mojin said that soldiers were
looking for the doctor.
Where is he?
What happened to him?
Mother moved him to a safe place.
She told us not to worry about him.
So Jang!
Please don't let him come to the palace.
- I got it.
- He must have
and coming from residence of
Sa Dokwang to the palace.
Definitely, Abigi's men will be there.
Take Seochung and head
to shortcut behind the mountain.
- Yes.
- Stand in every path.
I got it!
Don't we have to go out?
I know.
Have you place men with Princess?
Yes,
It's right they visited
residence of Sa in Nosaji.
But why do you ask?
The King has passed away.
What?
Things are going easier than I thought.
Yes.
Did you find out?
Yes, Dr. Mok didn't come to Jin's house.
But trainee Bumro and
Eunjin just went by.
Isn't Dr. Mok in Taehaksa?
No!
I have to go to the palace,
please lookout whether Dr. Mok
goes to Jin's house.
Yes, I got it.
You message to people
who were dispatched with Princess,
and check where she is now.
If merchant Jin knows this,
certainly she will hide Jang.
Dispatch all soldiers on the way
to the palace!
- Understood?
- Yes!
Why now, why Wooyoung went to Nosaji,
and couldn't see the King passing away.
I've sent soldiers
so she will come back soon.
The will of the King is...
I'll keep his words.
Please don't worry.
Woochi,
Woochi!
How did you come here without alerting me?
I'll stay here one day and leave.
Yes.
I haven't eaten so prepare foods.
Who is it?
I'm Naesol of military police.
Aren't you guard of Princess Wooyoung?
- Correct!
- How come Princess is not here,
and you came here alone?
Why are you standing
on the way of Princess?
The King passed away.
- What?
- So we came to escort Princess urgently.
Did King really pass away?
Yes, where is she?
Where is she?
We're ordered to escort her.
I see, I will escort her now
- You people can go back.
- What are you saying?
We have to escort her right now!
She's in government office in Nosaji.
- Go and get horses now.
- Yes.
She wanted to the management
so she's taking a day there.
Go to Sir Dalsol and say
I'm going to Nosaji office.
Yes!
Let's go!
What are you doing?
Let's hurry!
Why? Why is he saying Nosaji office?
- Brother Goosan!
- What happened?
You've been standing like this
for whole day.
You said that you've
an urgent matter to discuss.
What? She went to
government office in Nosaji?
Yes, we met the guard of Princess,
and he said that Princess is there.
Alright. Get ready a horse!
I'm going myself!
- Royal villa?
- Yes, she went there
but the guard tricked them
that she went to Nosaji.
- Well done.
- Yes.
Where did Sir Heuk go?
He went to Nosaji office.
Damn it!
Get ready horses and 10 soldiers!
- Why?
- That's not it.
Princess!
Although I lied to you,
I know that you've looked after us.
So I gave you my sincere.
To open the reign of the King,
I will dedicate my loyalty with you,
Princess.
But,
the order that your heart
was stolen by me,
I cannot accept it.
That I cannot help myself.
Jin Gakyung, I truly truly...
You don't,
You don't have to love me.
The most important thing is
that I can't harm you.
So what I'm left with is...
to marry you.
Princess!