What will it be?
Fill it up.
Welcome aboard. I'm Jang Jin-pyo.
$50 please.
What's with the attitude?
Hey, you, come here!
He's really got an attitude!
Welcome!
Hello, pretty ladies. Fill it up?
You're so pretty.
What do you want for Christmas?
Nothing...I just want to see Joon-young.
You still haven't come to your senses.
I said no.
Can't I see just Joon-young alone?
No. My answer is no.
All done.
We're going to have a
party here this Christmas?
Then you have to let me hear your song.
Don't worry. Just knit the other mitten.
Promise.
Okay. Promise!
Oh Hyung... how's everything?
Have you heard from Hae-in yet?
No, but how are you doing?
When are you coming for a visit?
On Christmas Eve.
Really? Really?
eh, Mommy's here.
What are you doing?
There's something I want to say to you,
so I wrote it on the window.
Welcome.
Isn't Jin-pyo here?
No. How much?
Fill it up.
Okay.
Is there another one like you?
I told you, you can't
find another one like me.
$80 please.
Excuse me.
I forgot my wallet. Get it from Jin-pyo.
I can't do that.
Don't you know Jin-pyo? I'm his friend.
I'm sure the girls have money.
How can I ask a girl to pay?
Boss!
You sure are inflexible.
All right!
Sun-ah.
What?
Hey, Lee Gun-woo!
Hello.
You're already getting into trouble
now that school's out?
Who are they?
My older sisters.
Aigoo~ you like older sisters?
You'll be a high school senior soon.
Come to your senses, boy!
$20.
Okay.
A senior in high school?
You're a high school student??
Unbelievable!
I'm sorry, older sisters.
Hey noona, $80?
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Just study hard, kid!
Keep up the good work!
Come again!
Lee Gun-woo, what are you doing here?
You have such bad timing.
I brought some older girls,
but my cover was blown!
Those hot older girls?
Where are they?
They slapped me in the face
and then dumped me.
Those were some hot girls!
I was going to break up with her anyway.
What's with him?
I don't know. He never talks
about his personal life.
When do you get off work?
Let's go to the studio.
I'll be off soon.
Wait for me.
Please tell me. Where's the house?
I don't know.
But Lily told me she saw
you talking to Joon-young.
That's not true.
I'm going nto run away to
Seoul if you don't tell me.
Do whatever you want.
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve, and
I have something to give him.
Then just behave yourself.
He'll be here tomorrow.
Really? What time?
I don't know!
Thank you, Oppa!
That hopelessly idiotic girl!
Welcome!
Merry Christmas!
Thank you for the tree!
Isn't he cute?
He's not bad.
He's a big spender, and he's very popular.
Really?
Really.
Willie, this is Audrey.
Nice to meet you. I'm Willie.
Really? Thank you, thank you!
You're very handsome.
I'm blushing!
Shall we go to the Post Exchange with them
and get something to eat?
Shall we?
Hae-in, let's go grocery shopping.
I just want to stay home.
We'll go by car. Some fresh air
will do you good.
I'm tired.
You are? Well, I'll be back soon then.
Let's go.
Where to?
To Seoul Station.
All right.
TO HAE-IN
What's that?
He sure is cold!
Hi, friend.
Why are you eating when
there'll be food at the party?
Don't worry. I could still eat a horse.
Why did he have to come while I'm eating?
I want to dance with some
hot girls at the party!
Don't worry.
I convinced some flight attendants to come.
Really?
You're the best!
Hey! Give me the mitten.
I'm sorry. Was it yours?
Why wear this instead of your other ones?
What weird taste in fashion!
You don't have to look at me like that...
He said he was sorry.
Buy a new one, or have it cleaned.
Don't ruin such a nice day.
It's okay. Take it.
When do you get off work?
Are you nuts?
Don't ruin such a nice day.
Hey, stop!
I'm going to get fired if you fight!
Let go!
Hey!
Gun-woo!
You have to calm down! Gun-woo!
He can't control his temper!
There goes the party with the hot girls!
Welcome!
Show me your ticket.
I'll direct you to your seat.
You can't park here.
Hey!
This is your seat.
We have to finish what we started.
Satisfied?
We have to finish what we started!
You have to buy your ticket!
How much is it? There!
Why, you!
Let go of me!
Hey!
Joon-young!
What are you doing here?
I've been waiting for you since morning!
I've been out here in the
cold waiting for you!
You've been here since morning?
Have you seen Hae-in?
Hae-in? Why?
Have you heard any news about her?
What news could there possibly be?
Let's go eat something.
I have to go.
Let's go!
Isn't it pretty?
What is it?
I folded 1000 cranes wishing
I could see you again.
Put in on your desk and think
of me whenever you see it.
Thanks...
It looks yummy! Enjoy.
Joon-young.
Are you waiting for Hae-in?
Yes.
She didn't come.
I've been at the station since morning.
She still might come. Let's go.
I'm not finished eating.
Then finish eating. I have to go.
You're being so cruel.
I didn't even eat because
I was waiting for you,
and you want to leave now?
Sorry. See you later.
Suh Joon-young!
Shouldn't you call home?
My parents will be so upset
When they find out I was hurt.
I'm all right as long as you're here.
Cha Hwa-jung?
Yes?
Your injury's not serious.
But I'm in pain.
Don't worry. You just strained your muscles.
It really hurts.
Aren't you getting in?
Go ahead. I have to go somewhere.
You want me go to alone?
Sir, drive her to the beauty salon.
Sure.
Hey, Suh Joon-young!
Come again!
Hae-in!
Oppa!
Are you alone? Where's Joon-young?
Isn't he inside?
He said he was coming. Didn't you see him?
Come here for a second.
Joon-young doesn't live here anymore.
What?
He got into big trouble and ended up
at the police station after you left.
So Mommy sent him to live with his father.
Where does he live?
How dare you come back here!
Mommy!
How dare you show your face here!
Do you want to see your aunt behind bars?
Joon-young's not here. Leave.
Go back inside!
Mommy.
Hae-in, take care. I'm going inside.
Hae-in!
Hwa-jung.
Here's your ticket.
You really don't know where Joon-young is?
No, I don't. You'd better go
before you miss the last train.
This is my address.
Will you give it to Joon-young?
Okay. Go.
Thanks. See you again.
Sir, when did the train leave?
The last train left a while ago.
Joon-young.
Oh Hyung.
Did you see Hae-in?
No.
But she was here looking for you.
When? Where is she?
She left.
Mommy told her you weren't here,
and she left in tears.
I didn't have a chance to ask her
where she lives because
Mommy was so upset.
Willie!
Don't worry. She'll be back soon.
Go back inside. I ruined the party.
It's all right.
Look!
Hae-in!
What happened to you?
Where did you go?
I'm sorry, Aunt.
You went to see Joon-young, didn't you?
Are you crazy? How could you go there?
Audrey.
I can't see Joon-young anymore.
I don't think I can see him again.
What?
Move! You're splashing.
I was here first!
How long does it take you to wash your face?
You should go polish your head!
Polish my head? Unbelievable!
Why wash your face when it doesn't help you?
Why did you hit me?
Be quiet! Why are you fighting?
Can't you be more sensitive?
I heard Hae-in was here.
Go back to Seoul after you finish eating.
Why are you intent on sending me back?
Did you find a foreign boyfriend?
Yes, so go back to your father,
and don't get into trouble.
Don't interfere in my life anymore.
You don't have the right, Mom.
I don't want to see you anymore. Go.
Don't worry! I'll never set foot
in this miserable house again!
Joon-young! Joon-Young!
What happened?
Mommy!
Are you all right?
Joon-young!
Let him go. Don't call him back.
Mommy!
Joon-young!
Leave us alone.
Okay, Mommy.
I'm advising that you be hospitalized.
I know what I have.
I'm the doctor.
You told me rest won't get me well.
I don't need to live longer.
Take your medicine, and get
to a hospital right away
if you don't feel well.
And absolutely no smoking or drinking.
I'd rather die than live like a corpse.
Your English tutor will be here soon.
English, Japanese, French, horseback riding,
fencing and all the other lessons...
They're a waste of time.
You have it too good.
A lot of people with
they were in your shoes.
I hired a good tutor for you,
so pay attention.
Yes, come in.
He looks familiar.
He's quite handsome.
Give it to me.
Who is he?
Is he... someone you like?
Do you know he likes you too?
Sis, my English tutor...
Gun-woo.
Did manager Oh leave?
You must've been shocked.
I feel betrayed. How long has it been?
It's been a while.
Since he was my tutor when I
was in junior high.
So your crush on him developed into love?
Don't tease me.
Could Manager Oh make you happy?
His top priority is work, just like Dad.
Sang-jin is more thougthful than he appears.
You're already defending him?
You should go and study
with your English tutor.
You know that I'm on your side, don't you?
I trust you.
Joon-young.
Try it. Their soup's famous.
Do you want a drink?
No.
I thought you went back to your mother.
I lived without you for ten years.
But since you came back into my life,
I can't live without you.
I sleep, but feel like I haven't slept.
I eat, but feel like I haven't eaten.
I wanted you to come live with me
as soon as I could afford a place for us.
Yet here I am, middle-aged, and...
I still haven't accomplished that goal!
Drink slowly.
Now that you're here, I think I can do it.
I think I can play the saxophone again.
I haven't been able to play it
because I've choked every time I've tried.
I thought of how I left you with your mother...
But now I feel like I can do anything.
I can be a decent human being!
You two do look alike.
Really?
But your son's more handsome!
You sure have a good son!
Make yourself at home.
and let me know if there's
anything I can do for you.
I'm managing the money your mom gave us.
Get us some water.
Okay.
She can be ditzy, but she has a good heart.
Try to get along with her.
Okay.
I want you to quit your job at
the gas station.
You're a senior now, so I want you to study.
I'll give you an allowance.
Who is it?
Willie! What are you doing here?
Willie!
Do you want to go for a drive?
Get up. Willie wants to take us for a drive.
You go.
There you go again!
Let's get some fresh air.
Come on! Get up!
Change your clothes, and let's go out.
You're opening a gallery?
I'm sorry I can't attend the opening.
It's all right. Thanks for the thought.
Are you coming from the gym?
It's been a long time.
She's going abroad to study.
You're leaving before you graduate?
My dad opened a studio there,
so I'm going sooner than expected.
Congratulations.
Let's go out. My treat.
I have plans. You should take my sister.
Should I beat him up?
Go upstairs.
Can't you knock?
We skinny-dipped as kids!
What's the matter?
We skinny-dipped as kids.
You gave me my first kiss.
I'll date up a storm like you.
But I wanted my first kiss to be with you.
What should I do?
You weren't my first kiss.
I don't care because your last kiss
will be with me.
Did you get a new one? It's cool!
Is the jerk here?
But he's quitting.
I think he's running away
because he's scared of you.
I'm going to finish what I started!
Be careful! He might just knock you out.
What?
Welcome!
How much?
Card.
Card? You speak Korean well.
Aren't you glad we went out?
Aren't you hungry?
I'm hungry. Let's get something to eat.
Nice to see you.
We have to finish it once and for all.
Shall we do it here or somewhere else?
Hey!
Gun-woo's met his match!
Get off!
You're all right.
Let's be friends.
I'll give it some thought.
You must know by now, don't you?
I'm relentless. I always finish what I start.
Hae-in!
Come on! Let's sing
You sang so well!
Be careful.
I had so much fun!
The drive by the river was great,
and singing was so much fun!
Wasn't it fun?
Did you have fun?
Yes, so much fun!
Let's come again.
Really? Promise!
Is this Rosa?
Father!
It's been so long!
Is this little Juliana?
Yes, it is.
Hae-in, you remember Father John, don't you?
Hello, Father. How have you been?
Do you still play the piano?
Sure!
Do you live nearby?
My church is in the area.
That's great!
I'm really glad I ran into you.
Who's he?
I'm her boyfriend. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
He's handsome. You two make a nice couple.
Father, you're embarrassing me.
Then don't stand so close to him.
Oh, Father!
You grew into a fine young lady.
God must've created Eve with you in mind.
This is the marketing plan for Q-one's
launch in May.
We're accepting presentations from
local companies
as well as Japanese ones.
Good job.
I need your permisson on another matter.
What is it?
Su-ji and I like each other.
Give us your permission to date.
Here, let me pour you a drink.
I thought all you cared about was work.
You never cease to amaze me.
Su-ji had a crush on him since junior high.
It's been 10 secretive years!
So you've known my family for over 10 years.
Yes, sir.
It's only natural for two young people
to fall for each other over the years.
Thank you, sir!
Let's eat.
My pretty Hae-in. You're eating well.
You're so adorable!
Audrey.
It's so good!
It's yummy!
How long have you knowns Father John?
Since I was about this small.
You two seemed close. I'm jealous.
Nonsense! He's like a father to me.
Oh, my! Willie says he loves me.
Here are your noodles.
Thank you.
Enjoy.
Your favorite noodle
Egg.
You're weird.
I don't like the whites because they're slimy.
You're the werid one.
I don't like the yolks because they're dry.
This is good.
Why aren't you eating?
Go ahead. It's good.
English Subtitles by
KBFD - The Asia Network (TAN)
Transcriber: upikepik
Timer: ay_link