I thought I'd never see you again.
Episode 19.
Welcome.
You guys had enough.
So rest for a few days.
If you're a doctor...
Now I'm the master of Taehaksa.
I loved the man from Haneuljae.
Lock her up right now!
Lock her up in a single cell,
so I don't see her around!
Duke Seodong.
It's me, Jang.
Do you see me?
I came all the way to Taehaksa,
What? Rules of Taehaksa?
Prince's order?
Are you suspecting us?
Why don't you give my father a klin?
This isn't sleezy easy place
like Haneuljae.
Is it true that
you're not the master here?
Doctor is the only one
who can get it right.
Do not back off yourself, please!
What the hell are you doing?
You must not use
the same way to them.
Method bribery?
I confer you Naesol in foreign affair.
Psycho!
Well done!
You're my daughter!
I only followed
the rules of Taehaksa.
Now I understand your mean.
When we borrow Prince's power,
we have another authority.
Then nobody will study
the nature in Taehaksa,
Only general's power
and prince's power will remain.
Prince's power means
only people of Haneuljae.
So even if you become the master,
You'll be left with only Haneuljae.
Yes, they will isolate themselves.
So I'm trying to take longer way.
If I want to different destination with general,
I must go different way.
Does it has to be longer way?
Please tell me.
That's your choice.
You'll do it, right?
You'll clear my false charge.
You've merits
so they won't do anything.
Just do it!
Yes, we'll help you.
Do it.
We can'tjust undergo with it.
I never thought that Taehaksa is like this.
Same here.
This is not right.
You should step forward.
Jang doesn't know the situation and system.
It's dangerous.
Plus engineers are still young,
I'm worried
if their minds would change.
Please step forward and stop Jang.
I want to do this.
Right, do it.
Doctor!
Do it.
Yes.
You should stop him.
What in the world,
I want to see something.
See something?
Doctor!
This is Jang who is conferred as Naesol.
I'll go in and greet her.
I'm Jang who is conferred as Naesol.
You didn't refuse the order?
That's foolish!
Go out!
If this isn't precise,
we've a problem.
Precisely...
I'd like to know the number of people
in Taehaksa.
Who is in charge of each workshop
and how promote is done.
It's all there.
Can't you tell me while you go around?
I don't have the luxury now.
Why did you call us?
You guys can help me out.
What is it?
It's number of people
and their experience for all workhsops,
Ask people and find out precisely.
Alright.
Is this all?
Yes.
I will help anything like this.
Please get us back where we belong.
Yeah, engineer Gomo and Mojin
Can't go to their meeting yet.
And Young and Soji haven't been
arranged their workshop.
And we have no mission or position either.
Excuse...
The engineer who copied mine
She's the head engineer
of metallurgy's sister.
She became an engineer
not long she got here.
Same in the dye workshop.
I think he's general's people.
Dad said that people have good talent
and stayed too long.
There are too many people
staying as engineers.
That's the same as other workshop.
I get it. Find out in detail anyway.
Alright.
I feel like I'm a different person.
Is it because you said
you want to see her alive?
I got to see her again.
I don't wanna see her like the past
when I was powerless.
Forget her. You can't see her again.
She's mine now.
It's been over a year!
When will you develop it?
Get out if you don't have talent!
Didn't you use our papers?
It's all Soo's.
Then why didn't you develop it?
Because we have no talent. Why?
They don't support us.
I asked them to bring many types of wood,
they won't.
I asked them to make a machine,
Damn it! I should really quit this.
I've been hassled over a year, damn it.
What happened?
Yes, all papers are imported.
So we have to pay Soo with a lot of gold.
Prince Aja and general ordered us to
Develop it but it's not that easy.
May I have your name?
I'm Makhae.
You've been in metallurgy for 8 years?
And you're good at it.
How did you?
Your name is Jangbo?
You've been here for 7 years.
I'm Dolsye and 13 years, ok?
13 years?
Why are you still engineer?
Because I'm dumb, why?
Really dumb.
Bloody youngster comes in
and takes Naesol,
Bro, you've been here
more than 10 years and still engineer.
Why bother to live? Huh?
Why? It's good to see
younsters doing things.
Excuse me, Jang.
Dr. Wooyoung wants to see you.
Did you want to see me?
Doctors held a meeting what to do
with Haneuljae members.
All of you need to take promotion test.
That means you can't admit
the system of Dr. Mok.
Including you,
all are taking promotion test.
Yes, I will take it.
Instead, engineers who were here for 10 years
Let them take the test with us.
What's the reason?
There's no reason.
I checked the number of people
and many of them
Were over 10 years
and still engineers.
They have to be organized in any way.
You don't acknowledge my system.
Let's do that!
Whoever doesn't pass
this promotion test,
Leaves Taehaksa.
Whether they're Haneuljae
or experienced engineers.
Yes, but please make it open test.
- Open?
- Yes.
Alright, that would be clear.
Oh, my buddha.
Cut it out, dad.
I trusted him, I really did.
He could have sacked me quietly.
I'll be embarrassed
after test and get sacked.
Oh, my. How can he do this to me?
You can do it well.
Do it well? My eyes are blurry
and I'm too old for that.
I thought Jang was rectifying here,
why is he killing us?
That's what I'm saying...
Jang would have no choice.
So we have to help him with our talent.
- How?
- Is it?
- No.
- I think so.
That's why he asked for open test.
Open embarrassment.
But why are experience engineers
doing with us?
Maybe that's why he asked
us to do that.
Right, he'd have his idea.
Let's check it out.
Don't go.
Just warm your body here.
They will wield him.
Jang can't do this.
Doctor, this will scatter
Haneuljae people.
Jang, you can stop it now.
This will make things harder for doctor.
The situation will flow
as they wield,
I know you tried to raise our pride
So you asked for experienced engineers
to do it with us.
That gave our bad impression to people
Who is nothing to do
with authority and us.
I'm not saying I don't know
your will and provocation.
Let's just wait for doctor.
Jang!
Please help me.
What is it?
Don't you know?
I don't care you got
the trust from Prince.
Why you touch us to do the test!
What the hell do you think you are?
I only followed the rule.
You can't get promoted
for 10 years, I understand.
Invention is not anyone can do.
- What?
- Instead you have to be expert at it.
What the hell are you saying!
Anyway if you don't pass this test,
you all must leave here.
I'm letting you know.
Jang,
Why did you make those engineers
to take test together?
Is there any reason?
I want to know what I'm suspecting.
Anyway we can't avoid test.
Right, that would make us clean.
Yes, we just have to
show them our talent.
Nobody should be failed.
You heard Jang.
You get kicked out if you fail.
So what?
You always have stomache
before the big test.
And we get wrong
what you know.
If you do that, we have to say goodbye.
So practice now.
Try harder.
Make a loop until I count to 10.
That's...
- Start! 1, 2.
- Wait, wait.
3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
- 8, 9, 9 and half and half.
- Almost done.
10!
Here!
Little late. Again!
Don't worry about me.
Go to Sir Mack and do something.
Don't worry, he's determined.
Finally heaven has given me up.
He is determined.
I haven't seen him
working hard for long.
Engineer Mack Dosoo!
Be well, Haneuljae family.
Please don't forget me...
What, what is this?
It's just sad poem of regreting
the farewell.
Engineer Mack!
I'm trying to end everything now.
I don't want to cause
any trouble to Haneuljae,
I should...
I saw spirit in your pottery.
Put it in your pottery.
That's it.
It's related to our pride.
You must do it.
I trust you will do this.
I trust you, too.
It depends on Haneuljae's pride.
Trust.
The test will be in 15th at 9 o'clock.
Ok.
For Haneuljae's test,
engineer Gulchi will provide,
For Taehaksa, I'll provide it.
Alright.
For my test, I ask you to give it to me.
I see.
Start now!
The test will be held in court.
Let's go to court.
It's not practical.
Right.
Have a seat where your name is on.
It's about your specialty.
Draw what you're asked.
How many were there annually?
Never.
It'll start with the sound of bell.
Please ring it.
Why are you sitting at my seat?
- Look at your name, here.
- Mack Do...
It's here, here.
- This...
- Go.
Please do the open grading, too.
Impartiality doesn't guarantee
without open grading.
Please do the open grading, too.
I get it, but how?
The head engineers of
each workshop come front please.
Sit on the engineers seat,
And simply answer the question.
I made a question with
what was invented in workshop.
So simply draw your answer please.
Do that!
- Do it.
- Yes.
Proceed now.
Yes.
Grade the answers.
I have two drawings here.
One is the same as original
and another one is yours.
If two drawings match,
there's no problem.
If not, one is copied or stolen.
Please start.
Same.
Next.
Correct.
It's different.
Who is Eunjin?
Answer is wrong!
It is not.
I drew it right.
Really?
Bring the original draft!
It's the same.
How did it happen?
Engineer Soyoung copied it.
Confess.
I drew what I reflected.
- Mark it.
- Yes.
Next.
Same.
It's different.
How did it happen?
Mark it.
It's different.
Mine is correct!
This part and this part is different.
Engineer Dolsye drew it right.
This invention is very new,
And I know you got a lot
of points for this.
What are you saying?
Are you sure you made this?
What! Are you insulting me?
So you think a few engineers
Reported what they haven't made.
Yes.
Method bribery is in place?
That's not possible.
If it does, I'll abandon them!
Has anyone bribed your method?
Has anyone?
No.
Has anyone bribed your method?
I didn't intentionally do it.
My idea was reported
without knowing it.
You can tell me.
Has anyone done method bribery?
We've never done it.
Did head engineer steal your invention?
No.
This is wrong.
If you invented yourself,
it's your merit.
If everyone assisted,
it's everyone's merit.
It's not because name
and honor are important.
You have to do this
to put your heart into study.
We're meant to do that.
Has anyone done method bribery?
We've never done it.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
Anyone can tell me.
I'll get your merit back.
I'll get your name back.
You've done it more than 10 years.
You're still an engineer.
Come on, tell them!
What are you afraid of?
Tell them.
Taehaksa shouldn't be like this.
Only one person got stolen her method.
Only Haneuljae people are telling me
there was bribery.
You drove Taehaksa to currupted group.
Neverthless, I'll leave Haneuljae people
who passed the test.
You're responsible for me
and Taehaksa's disgrace.
From now on, you no longer
perform your position.
I'll deliver my mean to Prince Aja.
He's bright but still young.
That's right.
He thought expose will do the rest.
We're not that easy.
What about Mok?
Is he still in storage?
Yes.
What a fox.
Nobody admitted it
so Jang has to resign it.
For this, Taehaksa is very confused.
He wouldn't have done it
without an idea.
But no one comes out,
He wanted to change the Taehaksa.
But Wooyoung will gain more vigor.
What's Dr. Mok's intention?
They have maintained
the group without us for 10 years.
Did you think they will collapse
for your one exposure?
People don't change their mind easily.
Nor the group will.
So is this the end of what you tried?
Doctor!
There's nothing except Prince.
Doctor, why are you doing this?
What is it? Doctor.
What is that you're willing to see?
My power! I want to see my power.
I'm not weird person.
How are you gonna live
in Taehaksa now?
But we're acknowledge
because of Jang.
Acknowledgment is not important.
They ignore us
and treat us like insects.
It's scarier and shaking.
It's comfortable looking at their sign.
Right, I can't live like this.
We have to live together.
If we have to stay here,
that's better for us.
Now we can sleep in peace,
what's the matter?
You have no one else to lookout,
And with your audacity,
you can deal with it, Not us.
I'll be dead silent.
Let's not gather like this anymore.
- Right.
- Yes.
He saved you
when you were dying.
I saw your eyes last night.
What?
They were shaking.
What the hell.
I'm not telling you to do big thing.
Things that I made become mine,
and seeing people use it,
You may want to make better one.
Hey! Get rid of him.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Think about it.
Why are you doing this?
I'm trying to convince you.
You've gone insane.
I want to put a mask on.
Get your mind set, Jang!
Jang!
Have you given it pleasantly?
If so, I will go.
Stop it.
You put your heart into it
without any bad feeling?
Then I'll go.
Our identities aren't good
but I'm just happy to work here.
No, it shouldn't be like that at all.
Heaven has given your talent without identity,
Therefore Taehaksa has to be
equal for everyone.
I thought it was like that when I first came in.
Why are you blocking other people?
Why are you afraid of
getting acknowledged?
You're a coward.
You should be ashamed of yourself!
I will never give up.
You can't defeat me.
Young master!
Please have a seat here.
Are you alright?
I feel like tired.
Then why did you come out?
Until Goosan comes,
please take a rest.
Alright.
How the hell did you come to here?
Do you know something?
Frankly...
Frankly, Princess came to Haneuljae,
Ordered us not to chase Jang
who was carrying you.
What? Pricness did!
It shouldn't go for long.
What if it gets exposed,
what would you do?
Lord, please calm down.
She went out with Baekjae person,
Surely she was seeing Baekjae person?
Yes, he's the engineer of Haneuljae.
And Princess helped him to escape?
Yes, notjust escape.
They lived together for a while.
How did she know him?
He was the guy of Sedongyo,
And he used to be
her guard for a while.
And Kim Saheung knew all of these?
Yes, his second son tried to pacify it
So he ordered us to be silent.
Didn't you go to meet Giroo?
We have a problem.
What is it?
I didn't know our man is
close to Wie's man.
So? What happened?
I think he talked princess...
What?
Sir.
What is it?
All of asristocrats from Seorabul are
coming to palace.
What? They escaped and lived together?
I'm very sorry to alert,
But it is true.
Plus when soldiers pursued them,
She tried to kill herself to save him.
So what can we do it?
The rumor is spreaded all over the city.
It's ashamed if he's Silla person.
He is Baekjae person.
This is really shameful.
You got it all wrong.
Since she took a job in Naesung...
You knew everything about this!
You found it out through your son,
And you knew he is
the person of Seodongyo incident.
Why didn't you report it to the King?
Is that true?
You knew all about it?
When Princess and the man escaped,
It was his men
who pursued them.
What? Did you really
know about this?
The reason why the rumor is spreaded
is because of his men.
You despised not only king
but whole imperial!
Is that true?
Is Princess Chunmyung
telling the truth?
No question is needed.
Palace and market are so noisy,
as well as Hwarang.
You should lock him up.
The rumor is so disgraceful that
I can't believe it.
It must not be true, isn't it?
Please kill us.
They lived together,
is it true?
What drove you so reckless!
It's out of my hand now!
How can I do! How!
Have you been well?
Brother, your waist is bad
so I can...
He didn't come.
Didn't come?
He's been too hassled
so he won't come to work.
That's good.
His waist isn't well
so I can massage him.
Do you how many people absent
because of you?
They informed me that
they won't come to work for a while.
Here, I drew this.
I told you I won't look at your stuff.
If you don't look,
who will look at mine?
Report it to Dr. Wooyoung directly!
Is this because of the last time?
If so, I'm really sorry.
You guilty people are still digging up.
You're always asking the engineers.
That's not me.
I don't do that.
Aren't you guys
tenacious Haneuljae people?
I, I...
She won't accept it?
Since engineer does that,
other comrades won't talk to me.
Same here.
They won't reply back.
It makes me tired.
That's same as me, but
So please stop him.
Jang never gives up so they do to us.
But he's trying hard.
What hard? I got to live first.
Since we came here.
We can just live quietly.
Even doctor is quiet
and why is he doing it!
Calm donw,
I'll find him and talk with my dad.
Jang,
Stop it.
I was wrong
if they will change their mind easily.
But it already happened.
If I stop now,
their mind will shut down even more.
And they won't trust us.
You shouldn't do that.
I have to convince them
until they trust me and my heart.
At least one person.
What about Haneuljae family?
They can't even talk
and live in cold situation,
What about them?
Please help me.
That's what Dr. Mok kept for long.
Jang!
Mom! Did you talk to Jang?
He doesn't listen.
I can't take it anymore.
It's too hard.
Either I beat him
or I have to say I'm dying.
Bumro and his dad will
go and talk to him.
You have to come with me, mom.
Let's go.
It's so noisy because of Haneuljae.
I put more for this time.
Yes, thank you.
What are you doing here?
I said what are you doing here!
What is this?
Is this it?
You sold your name for this?
How much is it?
All the machines that you thought and drew,
How much does it cost to buy?
People get to smile with your machine,
And they thank you for it.
How much is it to replace that?
How much is it to replace your name
on Baekjae Singi?
I'll buy it all.
I'll tell Prince and buy it all!
Who are you threatening to name Prince?
Take care of him quietly.
Yes.
What are you doing?
- Hit him!
- No!
It's dangerous, Ms Mojin.
- If you ever touch him a bit
- I'll kill all of you!
You got the wrong people!
You can never win this fight!
Do you know why?
Jang does what he's got to do.
I scolded him for 10 years
but he never stopped what he wants!
Do you know the second reason?
We're next to him!
We know Jang is right
and we'll never leave him alone!
Right! We'll never leave him alone!
What the hell! You wanna die!
Let's go.
You four there!
Shh! Nothing but cowards,
Are you hurt...
There you are.
This is him, grandma.
Grandma wants to ask you something.
Go on.
You know...
Can little technique leave
my name on the book?
Of course, this man will do
whatever he needs to do.
Honestly I've been starched clothes
for 30 years here.
It can be nothing
but I have 10 years old riped starch.
I thought it'd be nice to make papers.
But Taehaksa seemed to have trouble
And it's not my specialty
so I didn't take it out.
But can you leave my name?
It can be great worth before I die.
What are you doing, Jang?
She's asking you.
She's asking you to leave her name.
Yes, I will.
I will leave your name no matter what.
Then I'll believe in you.
Can I believe in you?
Yes?
Leave my name on it?
Yes, I will leave it.
I do what I need to do
and I have Haneuljae people with me.
I designed the machine for making papers.
Really?
Then we have a job to do.
When I starched this,
no insect lay their eggs.
Take a look.
Do you press papers with it?
Yes, put moist paper and dried paper,
Before paper get dried, you press it.
Isn't it the same principle as ironing?
Yes, it makes the surface very smooth
And paper gets thin
and ink will spread evenly.
Gather up after work!
So how do you do starch?
If you ripe it, it spreads out well
in water and last long!
What do you do with paper mulberry?
Grind in millstone?
Tap it, grind it, and pound it.
Pound it? How?
Beat it like you wash the clothes.
If we need to make it smooth,
we need many materials.
Dr. Mok is in storage,
I'll find it out.
He'll steal it,
if it's for invention.
So who's making reed screen?
Isn't it tiresome?
Make Jang to do it.
Why me?
Because you're tiresome.
You do it.
Yes, tiresome and longer ones make him do it.
And creepy ones too.
He's so creepy.
Is it that serious?
Yes, lord.
If you listen to their demand,
our damage is severe.
Neverthless, progress has been very slow.
Make a plan!
We need to make it with our method.
Whoever invents it, reward them enough.
Yes, lord.
I told you to make it ages ago.
You still don't have good result?
Did you deliver its urgency?
We don't have skill yet.
Rushing it won't work.
What happened to Taehaksa's technology!
It depends on nation's benefit.
Why is it so slow?
We're doing our best.
Bu Yeosun came last time,
now it's Prince's turn?
Did someone burn something last night?
What is it?
There are a lot of ashes.
Frankly, there is mark of
using paper box.
Have we been robbed?
Nothing's missing but mark's of use.
You're harsh.
If your mean is this,
invent the papers.
Soon, Soo's messenger will be here.
They will ask for unreasonable demand
for their papers.
Yes, sir.
He's in Dr. Mok's room?
Yes.
How is Mok Rasoo?
He's stuck in storage.
How about Jang?
Jang and Haneuljae people are very quiet.
Please go in.
It looks like it'll rain.
- I'm sorry.
- You fool!
- Damn.
- We've a problem.
I'm inqurying my greet.
Who are they?
They're engineers of Haneuljae.
Isn't he Jang?
What are they doing.
Follow me!
Yes.
Hurry, hurry.
What the hell are you doing here!
Why are you gathered here and doing what!