They make cushions for the knees
but not for the ass?
I told you this wouldn't work.
Good drummers are
hard to find anywhere.
Two, three, four--
Just a minute!
Your necklace.
-What are you, deaf? The necklace!
-I'd like to keep it.
You'll get it back in a few days.
-You got a plane to catch?
-What do you mean?
You're playing like you're in a hurry
to get somewhere.
I agree.
-I'm not pushing it. You're too slow.
-I'm too slow?
I'm too slow?
-Luna!
-What?
If she's too fast
and you're too slow...
maybe you could both play
a medium tempo.
-A nun telling me how to rock.
-"Medium"?
Listen, baby.
There's no "medium"tempo.
There's only one tempo...
and it's mine
and this fucking isn't!
Go to hell!
The Minister for Internal Affairs
called an hour ago.
She wants you to play
at the Policeman's Ball.
A classy idea.
Right before the elections.
Provided, of course, I ensure that...
there will be no problems.
-Can I?
-You can trust my ladies.
There's a first time for everything.
Hey! Where are you going?
I don't need this shit from you!
Besides, I'm getting out in two days.
-Wrapping airline utensils-- so boring.
-What should I write on the napkin?
"Warning! Bomb on board!"
"You're eating this?
No wonder you're fat!"
"The pilot is screwing your wife."
"Your dog is dead in cargo."
"To Otto."
Oh, shit! Now I have to do them
all over again.
Where will you find the time?
Hello. I'm Angel.
That's Marie. She's a little--
She's been in here for a million years.
But she can fly.
Marie, what are you doing?
What are you staring at?
You got a problem?
No, I don't.
Nothing I'd discuss with you, anyway.
Oh, really?
And why not?
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
-That was an insult, right?
-Yep.
And that's Luna.
"Only you, you, you--"
"You have to cross seven bridges--"
-"Resi, I'm comin' for the tractor."
-I'm not singing that German shit.
Look, we wait for the cops
to get drunk...
then we can play anything we want.
Is that the sheet music?
No.
I can't read music anyway.
It's from Gold Records.
-A rejection.
-Big surprise.
They're not interested
in people like us.
We'll try again.
-What about the Policeman's Ball?
-Who gives a fuck?
One, two, three.
One, two--
Emma, you don't take part
in recreational activities.
You don't go to church.
You don't talk to the other women.
I have no leisure time.
I don't believe in God.
And I hate to talk.
Time passes slowly in prison.
- You can't just wait for years.
- Sure, I can.
For what?
For the sunset in Guyana.
It says on your record
that you were a musician.
The band is looking for someone
to play drums...
for the Policeman's Ball.
Would you be interested in that?
Well, then, what would you rather do?
You fucking pricks! Hurry up!
Damn it!
You're sure taking your time,
you stupid pigs. Come on!
Wake up!
I know you can hear me, goddamn it!
Hey! Wake up!
Damn it!
It's that stupid old bitch again!
Quiet!
You're letting her die,
you stupid fucks!
Alert the sick ward
before she bleeds to death!
-Can't you hurry it up?
-Just shut up!
What a mess!
Marie!
Appeal denied.
This decision is final, huh?
Yes.
So I'll be 42 then.
-Didn't they submit the photos?
-I'm sorry.
You'll probably be out
in only seven years.
That's comforting.
- Sorry.
- Wait a minute.
Yesterday you said three of a kind
was better than a straight.
That was before I had a straight.
What about a full house?
-That's cheating!
-No, it's "bluffing".
Hey... Hey, that was really--
I thought that was... wow!
I mean, that was through the roof!.
That was beautiful.
Wait, hold on five minutes!
One minute! A second!
Say something.
-Boy, you play pro ball, huh?
-Angel, get out of her way.
Tell her, Luna.
It was okay.
Okay? What do you mean, okay--
Aw, man!
Come on. Drummers always sit
in the back anyway.
What's the matter? You scared?
Everybody out! Now!
Everybody out!
Legs apart!
Just shut up
and get against the wall!
If we don't find the stuff,
you're all in trouble. Got it?
If I were a little birdie
Shut up!
And I had two little wings
- I'd fly to you--
- I said shut up!
But since that won't come true
I'll stay right here
If I were a little birdie
And had two little wings
I'd fly to you
But since that won't come true
I'll stay right here
Okay. "Pearls Before Swine,"
"Masturbation"...
"Crazy Motherfuckers"
or maybe just "Motherfuckers."
Or "Kill, Kill, Kill."
-Perfect.
-That's no name for a band.
Okay, I've got "Jailbirds,"
"Angel and the Banshees"...
or just "The Angels."
-"Jailbirds" isn't bad.
-"Bandits."
-"Band" and "tits"--
Why didn't I think of that?
-Luna?
-"Bandits." Fine. Fuck it.
Okay, then. Put down "Bandits."
Hold it!
Let's get one thing straight.
I do the counting.
Fine. If you can count that high.
- One, two--
- Three, four.
For that special occasion.
Bring some cute cops back
with you!
-I want one with a moustache!
-No problem!
I have to work this weekend
because of you stupid bitches.
Hey, Angel, you play trumpet, right?
Give me a blowjob, loosen those lips.
Do us both good.
Go play with your dick, Rick.
And so it's my pleasure to present...
this medal
to Inspector Robert Schwarz...
in honor of his outstanding work...
for the Criminal Investigation Division.
Nobody's here. They're probably
getting drunk already.
Go in and tell them we've arrived.
So... what are you going to play?
"A Good Man is Hard to Find"
and all that shit?
What was it you were singing
at rehearsal?
I'd do anything for you
'Cause I'm a filthy little bitch
So how does that feel, huh?
Luna! What are you doing?
They're gonna kill us for this!
I mean, really kill us!
You've got no clue, man! No clue!
Hey, Luna. The key!
Unlock 'em!
Unlock our handcuffs!
These women deserve a chance.
In fact, it is our duty
to integrate these women...
back into society.
Shit!
-Move it!
-Damn it! Where's reverse?
Watch out!
Sorry about that.
- Drive much?
- Pull over! I'm gonna throw up!
-Not now!
-Yes, now!
Oh, God.
I changed my mind.
Drive!
So I hope...
we all have a wonderful evening
listening to--
-What are they called again?
-Escape attempt!
A wonderful evening with...
"Escape Attempt"!
Get that car out of the way!
-Turn on the blues!
-Are you nuts?
Where's the goddamn switch?
Hello?
Leave it on!
-I don't see any police.
-I'm not complaining.
I can't believe we actually lost them!
With this piece-of-shit van!
Pull over.
Now I really gotta throw up.
Imagine their fat faces when
they realize the band didn't show up!
Hey, relax. Everything's cool.
Cool?
Excuse me,
but I don't think any of this is cool.
Luna, they're gonna put us away
in solitary for this stupid joyride!
They'll shave our heads!
And everything else.
And it's all her fault!
I was getting out soon.
Now I'll be as old as Marie!
There's a phone. Call the police.
Say it was a mistake. Go on.
- Maybe they'll forget it if we go back.
- What are you, nuts?
I'm out and I'm staying out.
I don't think I'll miss the nun.
But we have no money...
these clothes aren't exactly hip...
and that ugly van--
Know what your problem is, Angel?
You're a dope.
-Better a dope than dead.
-I'd like to go home.
-What are we gonna do?
-Don't ask me!
Think for yourself for once.
Shit!
Come on.
We're all in the same canoe.
Hey, Marie! Marie!
-"Boat."
-Huh?
-"Boat." We're all in an identical boat.
-You mean, the "same."
-What?
-The same boat.
Smart-ass!
-Cigarillo, madame?
-No, thank you.
-Yes, please.
-Any leads so far?
Afraid of not being re-elected?
Just out of curiosity...
why were four felons let out of jail?
Our latest concept for reintegrating
prisoners into society...
encourages them to develop
and put to use their unique abilities.
Sounds like that's exactly
what they're doing right now.
Let me put it this way:
If one person in that lovely band
of yours...
endangers one of my colleagues,
they're dead meat.
Got it, Dr. Roth?
-How long before you can catch them?
-I've never had a case that lasted...
longer than a pack of cigarillos.
Fast enough for you?
Marie, you can't get on board
without papers.
Sure. Nobody cares where you're from.
Just what kind of music you play.
- One word: "Harry."
- He's an old friend of mine.
Works for a shipping company.
Very discreet.
Five hundred marks
and he gets you on the ship.
Thanks, Marie.
I'll write you a postcard.
-Where shall I send it?
-I'm staying here.
All I want...
is to go see Otto.
Marie Irgang poisoned her husband
with arsenic.
Over two years' time. A little dose
every day. Schizophrenic tendencies.
Suicidal.
Ludmilla Nabiba. Armed robbery,
repeat offender.
Extremely violent.
Low threshold for frustration.
Angelika Kleinschmidt.
Several convictions, bigamy, fraud.
Quite an achievement for a 23-year-old.
Cooperative.
Emma Moor. Played in a jazz band
once. Even got offers from the U.S.
Guy in the band couldn't handle it.
Allegedly beat her.
-Until she shot him.
-Slight tendency to overreact, huh?
The court ruled out self-defense.
So where's the child now?
I want to know
who they called from prison...
when, what they discussed
and for how long.
Who came to see them?
Who were they hot for?
All of it! Get to work!
I'm going to Guyana.
South America.
- You're leaving? I mean, that far?
- With a ship's band.
-And you?
-Beats me.
But I won't be playing guitar
on the goddamn Love Boat.
Say, can I go with you?
That's up to you, Angel.
I gotta pee.
Hey, not so hard. Don't blame
the poor vending machine.
For what?
That you're too dumb to crack it.
You've got a problem with that?
I'm sorry! I'm really sorry!
They shot the little dog.
-Whose turn is it?
-I'm up next.
Go ahead. Let one of 'em loose.
I'd reconsider if I were you.
Yes?
You still haven't found the van?
Are we the police
or the Braille Institute?
Actually, 20% of female fugitives
return on their own.
It's 1 8 feet long,
9 feet high, and has 4 wheels.
And it's green. Got it? Green!
Hey, I'm in the mood
for some yogurt.
They did what?
Made 'em strip...
and rub dog shit all over themselves.
Okay, I get the picture.
License number?
HR HR 123. Thanks.
-At least they have a sense of humor.
-Harry?
No. No, I'm out.
Oh, I guess things could be worse.
I'm gonna visit Otto. Hello?
Harry? We're talking about
the MS Ikarus, right? Tell me:
Will this plan work, or am I insane?
When's it leave? And how much?
10,000 marks. Per person?
-Yell it a little louder.
-You need money? Hit a bank.
-Forget it.
-Why not? I've done it lots of times.
Piece of cake.
That's why you keep ending up
in the pen.
- There has to be a legal way.
- Legal?
Angel has 1 00,000 stashed away.
Are you crazy?
That was a secret.
Besides, it's for my future.
-Well, we have to respect that.
-No, we don't!
Turn down that fucking TV!
Is "fuck"the only word you know?
There are other ways
to express things.
Excuse me.
I didn't know you were a poet.
Pardon me, we'd really like to talk.
-Could you turn down the TV?
-No!
What is this?
"The Customer Is An Asshole"week?
We don't want people like you
in here anyway!
...successful escape.
The spectacular prison break
Saturday night--
They're gonna show our pictures.
André Roder and Herbert Rahn,
both serious repeat offenders...
convicted of murder
in the death of a banker...
escaped from Frankfurt Prison.
A large-scale manhunt is underway.
Now, the weather.
-Not a word about us.
-What the fuck is that all about?
Don't we count?
I mean, we broke out too.
This is the best thing
that could happen to us.
They only want them.
But I want them to want me.
I want someone to look for me,
for a change.
I don't believe this.
Hello? Listen, dick, how come
you put those jerks on TV but not us?
After all I went through.
I almost got a necklash.
"Whiplash," idiot.
-Don't call me an idiot!
-What? What?
Hello!
He wants to meet with us.
- Think he'll make us undress on camera?
- I told him you'd give him a blowjob.
Very funny. What'll we talk about?
-We'll think of something.
-Talk with whom?
We didn't even make the newspaper.
What does it take to get written up?
Just die. Then they'll put you
on the back page. Right, Marie?
Now you've totally lost it.
-Okay, so you broke out of prison.
-Good start.
Aren't you afraid of getting caught?
We're afraid of so many other things.
-For example?
-Super Glue.
If you get it in your eyes,
you can't open them. Right?
You'd just have to look
through your lids.
-All I can see is black.
-All you ever see is black.
That's not my fault.
So what are you gonna do next?
Disappear? Hide out?
I'd like to be carried away
like a queen. All the way to Gu--
Could you lend us some money?
Think we have a chance?
I wish I could fly.
Aw, erase that--
-We make music.
-We're a band.
-"Bandits."
-Rock and roll. You know?
Blitz TV with an exclusive interview.
Described by police
as extremely dangerous...
the fugitives call themselves
"Bandits. "
We don't know
where they're going...
but we can assure you--
Aren't you afraid of the police?
Police? What police?
I don't see any police around here.
You seriously don't know
where they are?
I told you. They called me.
-84% of all prisoners--
-Anyway, I met them there.
Next time, you take us with you,
is that clear?
You've heard of aiding and abetting
criminals, right?
Sure.
Welcome to the team.
Sentimental shit.
-Agreed.
-What's that mean? You don't like it?
As a matter of fact, I do.
Very much.
How deep did you bury this shit?
Damn it!
Maybe it was another tree.
You've been saying that for two hours!
You want to dig up the whole forest?
The man at the hardware store
told me aluminum doesn't rust.
- It's a real waste hazard.
- I found something.
-I found something!
-Really?
It sounds like metal.
-What's that?
-An unexploded bomb.
What?
A dud. From World War II.
-Can it explode?
-Not anymore.
Only if you keep pounding on it!
Shit!
Get out of here! Run!
Hurry up!
I told you nothing would happen.
So what do we do about money now?
I really did leave it here.
I swear.
Yeah, right.
Stop lying, Angel.
Where are you all going?
This next song will appeal
to your criminal instincts.
"Puppet on a String"
by your favorite fugitives, "Bandits."
That's our song.
That's my song.
-But they rejected it.
-I knew it. I knew it was good.
Don't they have to get
our permission?
What can we do? Sue 'em?
-What?
-Exactly.
Listen! My solo.
Be careful. That rug is Nepalese silk.
Very sensitive to stains.
- A little present from Phil.
- Phil who?
Collins.
Listen, buddy, if you want
to play our song on the radio--
I was just test-marketing it.
I'd like to help you, but I don't know
how best to do it.
Forty.
-Forty what?
-Thousand.
Forty thousand to test-market
your song?
But I haven't made a cent yet.
I get a funny feeling
you're trying to rip us off.
What do you need forty grand for?
- A quick getaway?
- Come on, you won't even miss it.
-You won't get far on 40,000.
-So give us more.
Who do you think you are?
The Rolling Stones?
You're just four losers from prison...
who make a lousy excuse for music.
The only reason you'd sell at all
is because the police are after you.
He who lives for money
gets nothing but money.
What?
He who lives for money--
Listen, there's a million musicians
out there.
And they're a thousand times better
than you!
But we're the only ones who make
big coffee stains.
What are you doing?
Oh, so sorry.
Are you all crazy? Stop it!
Forty thousand
or we start on the walls next.
- Okay, okay. Thirty thousand.
- Didn't I just say forty?
I'll give you thirty,
but on one condition:
You all sign this.
Our names are already on it.
It's just a formal agreement...
that I can keep testing the song.
-Fifty thousand.
-You got it!
- Oh, no.
- Fuck!
- Where?
- Oh, no!
- Oh, yes!
- Now what?
Sunglasses.
All I heard was an explosion,
and when I got here, they were gone.
They dug up the whole forest.
What did he say? His accent--
Something about digging up
the forest, sir.
-Big groundhogs around here.
-Wow!
I suppose they could have buried
money here once.
Think they found it?
- I have no idea.
-They have to get money somewhere.
-Maybe someone owes them a favor.
-Right. Go on.
Someone who can help them
get out of the country.
What makes you so sure
they'll leave the country?
Statistically, 68% stay inside
the federal borders--
Schneider, do you quote statistics
even when you fuck?
-Thank you.
-Don't mention it.
-Ludwig.
-Anytime I can help the police.
-God bless.
-My pleasure.
Thank you.
They found the Land Rover
near Frankfurt.
Sounds like they're heading north.
I swear, it's going to be a hit.
Even their worst song
is sure to be a hit.
And I have the rights for just fifty.
I hate to interrupt, but--
"Fuck you. Come fly with me.
Elvis. Fucking coffee."
What a lovely place. It's so red.
Hey, what's wrong?
I always wanted to be a clue
in the "Bravo" crossword puzzle.
So?
They don't run
the crossword puzzle anymore.
I need a mark-- now.
When you're dead,
you get eaten up by worms.
I don't want to be eaten up.
-I want to burn.
-Whatever you say, Marie.
Hey, bartender! Vodka!
We're gonna take little break.
-So, shall I come up for some coffee?
-Yes.
Yes?
Where?
What's more important to you:
sex with me or your career?
Sex with you.
I know a better way
to get an orgasm. We've got 'em!
Luna!
-What?
-Luna, the cops!
Ladies and gentlemen,
sorry to interrupt.
Inspector Schwarz, CI D.
I hate to disturb
your musical interlude...
but these ladies are under arrest.
Stay where you are.
You're surrounded.
-Keep calm.
-What do we do?
We should take a hostage.
Okay, who wants to come along?
-Everybody stay put!
-Nobody move!
-Drop the gun!
-Let's take the blond guy.
-No, that one.
-Make up your mind.
-Don't move!
-Him!
Come here!
You're Emma, right? Emma, calm down.
Everything's all right.
Drop it! You can't get away.
-Oh, yeah?
-Emma, let him go.
-Nice to meet you. I'm Emma.
-Hi. West.
Drop your guns! No guns!
Just let us through!
We'll let you go,
but let's talk first.
Don't buy it. Want us to blow
his pretty head off?
Let me help you.
-Then call your men back!
-I'll let you go if you let him go.
I give you my word.
-Drop your guns.
-Let's go!
-Emma, take me instead!
-Go fuck yourself!.
-Out of the way!
-Where's your car?
They're heading for the VW van.
Attach a transmitter to it.
-If I see one squad car, he's dead!
-You can peel him off the sidewalk!
We'll give 'em a head start,
then we'll follow 'em.
-Well?
-I didn't make it.
Shit!
How are you doing?
Shit.
- I can't believe I just did that.
- Very professional.
Now every cop in the free world
is after us.
We have to call Harry.
We need to go now.
Is there anything you wanted to do
but were afraid to?
Have a kid.
Not a thing.
You'd be afraid to kiss someone
if you wanted to.
Why would I want to?
Oh, yeah? Nice to meet you.
I'm Emma.
They've vanished into thin air.
This tape goes to every news staff...
at every dinky station in the country.
I want this shit on the 6:00 news.
Who's the weak link?
- Angelika Kleinschmidt.
- Right.
So that's the one we go for.
Will you fill it out, honey?
You rarely see couples
stay in Germany for their honeymoon.
We said to ourselves,
"There's no place like home."
Right.
-Here you are.
-Thanks. Let's go, dear.
Yeah, I know what it costs, Harry.
We already have the money.
When does the next ship leave?
Three weeks? Yeah, okay.
We'll be there. Call you later.
Born April 20. An Aries.
How cute!
Massachusetts. American.
My first time in Germany.
Just wanted to see the sights.
A tourist!
-I bet he's a good kisser.
-You think?
- You're right.
- Upper body needs some work.
Is it true that all Americans
wear boxer shorts?
-I'm sure. White?
-Red?
-Green?
-With smiley faces?
-I can't remember.
-Let's see for ourselves.
You must be getting awfully hot.
Our ship leaves in three weeks.
We just have to lie low until then.
You're missing a party.
Following a high-speed chase...
Herbert Rahn was killed
in an exchange of gunfire.
His accomplice, André Roder...
who received
multiple gunshot wounds...
died this morning
en route to the hospital.
We live with death our entire life.
Until the moment it actually occurs.
Luna's gone.
Oh, shit! Shit!
Luna.
Kiss my ass!
Damn it, Luna.
- Are you asking for them to catch us?
- You mean, to catch you?
That's not what I said.
This place really stinks!
-It stinks like piss!
-What do you want, anyway?
I mean, you don't give a shit
what happens to us.
You're just watching out
for yourself.
You wouldn't even notice
if the rest of us were gone.
Tell me what you want from me.
I just want--
Oh, get lost.
Like everybody else does.
You know what?
I'm really sick of your self-pity act.
You aren't the only one in the world
who's been hurt.
Oh, yeah? Tell me about it.
I don't want to talk about it.
Well, I want to talk about it.
For one thing, I'd like to talk about
why you don't want to talk about it.
I see. People don't talk
about those things in your circles.
Everything's so very discreet.
-Don't try to understand me.
-That guy you shot dead--
I bet he didn't understand you either.
-I don't want to talk about it.
-Exactly how did it happen?
You played together in a jazz band,
right?
And then one day he wasn't
good enough for you anymore.
I can just see it.
You wanted to ditch him,
and he got pissed off.
Then he grabbed on
to your middle-class ass.
Or was it your middle-class tits?
But nobody does that to you.
So you snapped, right?
And since Emma here is ruthless,
she shot him dead.
I knew someone
who was ruthless once.
You know what he did?
He beat me.
He beat--
He beat the life
right out of my body.
In fact, he tried to beat me to death,
but he didn't succeed.
Oh, God.
He only beat me till I passed out...
and then I woke up in the hospital.
When I was there--
When I was there,
I wished I was dead.
I wished that he had finished
the job.
That I was the one who was dead...
and not my baby.
The child that had grown inside me.
Understand?
I'm sorry.
Sometimes I say things--
I just don't know.
Yes?
I'm coming with you.
I know. I know.
"BANDITS
Now on CD, Cassette and LP"
Oh shit!
Fantastic. It almost looks real.
Wonderful.
It is real, you idiot.
I'm concerned about the hostage.
Perfect timing to have our faces
spread all over town.
Great. My mother will be so proud
to buy my record.
Our record.
What's going on here?
Rush hour.
You wouldn't understand, Angel,
You never had to rush.
Hey, aren't you the "Bandits"?
Yeah.
Wow! Can I have your autograph?
No problem.
Are you the hostage?
Don't push. One at a time.
-May I? Sorry.
-That's enough!
Get this shit out of here!
Recycle it.
-Or donate it to the poor.
-Boss, people keep calling in.
15 definite sightings, 20 cranks...
43 complaints, and get this:
1,427 support them.
Sure, they'll cheer on
a bunch of female convicts.
But let them steal their car
and they want a police state.
Great.
I'm finally a pop star
and nobody can recognize me.
Besides, I'm cold.
We can't even play anywhere.
Nine more days
and we got it made.
I want to go see Otto.
Didn't you say it was too far away?
Not really.
Hey, could I take a picture?
Nobody back home will believe this.
Sure.
I'm partial to this one here.
It's in a no-parking zone anyway.
Can you do it one more time?
I didn't get it.
-Sure. Because it's you.
-West!
I'd really prefer this one.
I bet you can't do it now.
What's taking Marie so long?
She said she'd be back in an hour.
It's been almost three.
She's probably got a lot to say
to Otto after thirteen years.
Where does Otto live, anyway?
That's Otto?
How long have you known this,
Marie?
A year after I went to prison...
he died.
I asked if there was any room
for me here.
If he'd move over a bit.
And what did he say?
Yes.
Opening night, my husband Paul
in the first row...
and Otto was playing
"Mack the Knife."
And suddenly he raced over...
yanked me
out of the orchestra pit...
and screamed in my ear...
"Sing, Marie.
Do you see the moon over Soho?"
And I said, "I see it, love.
Do you feel my heart pounding?"
And he said, "I feel it, darling."
And I said,
"I'll go wherever you go."
And he said...
"Wherever you may be...
I want to be there, too.
Love lasts, or it doesn't...
in this place or another."
Otto.
Hey, Marie! Move over!
Wait for me!
Shit! I think I lost my pants!
Luna! Come on in!
No, I--
I don't like swimming.
I'm going to buy us something to eat.
Want anything special?
West?
They didn't even pay the bill.
1,476 marks.
-This is every telephone call?
-Yes.
-Did we tap that guy?
-Harry?
The men are on it now.
This isn't too ironic.
We slave our butts off day and night...
and they have a party.
We've got 'em.
West Frazier.
F-r-a-z-i-e-r.
Thanks, Harry.
That's sweet of you. Bye.
-Hello?
-Hello, Angel.
Inspector Schwarz here.
I'd say you're in trouble.
You have beautiful eyes.
Yeah, right.
Just shut up.
My dream vacation:
sitting in cow shit in some barn.
You got a better idea?
You girls ought to do what I do.
You should use your heads.
Everybody is responsible
for their own actions.
So it's okay then if I smack you?
As long as you take responsibility.
-Is anything wrong?
-No. Should there be?
Just asking.
So now you know.
-Can I have the paper later?
-I'm not finished.
-I said "later".
-Yeah, I heard you.
-I just asked.
-Since when do you ask, anyway?
Just say what's bugging you.
For once.
-I always feel like I'm on a quiz show.
-You're the one who puts on a show.
At least I call things as they are.
No fairy tales
about buried treasures.
'Cause you've never had any to bury.
Shut up!
Are you okay? Should I drive?
What?
Should I drive?
Our ship sets sail in exactly
54 hours.
I can see it now.
There's a bar below deck.
Right. And a pool table.
And crew guys with their shirts off.
We have to get out of here.
Isn't that what we're talking about?
No, I mean now.
Keep playing, Marie.
That was so nice.
I need to tell you
something important.
But--
Marie?
She's not breathing.
Do they still have the hostage?
No, it doesn't look like it.
Block off the bridge behind them.
Elbe 1 3 to SEZ. Block off the bridge.
This is it.
No more life on the road for me.
Why is there nobody around?
Oh, my God--
What's going on, damn it?
Police. Everywhere.
Something's wrong.
We're moving in!
Luna, come on!
We have to get out of here!
No, I'm not going to leave her alone.
She's dead! You can't help her.
Let me go! I'm not leaving!
Listen.
Do you remember
what Marie always said about death?
Luna, what did Marie always say
about death?
"We live with death our entire life.
Until the moment it actually occurs."
Yeah.
I never understood
what she meant until now.
She's finally where
she always wanted to be.
They're getting closer.
You made her a promise.
What are they doing?
Don't shoot!
-Come on, damn it!
-I'm not jumping!
I'll hold on to you, okay?
See, it's really easy.
Hi. Get her out of here.
You think they survived?
Of course they did.
Marie! Marie!
Need a light?
I have a little theory.
Only the dumb criminals
end up in prison.
I consider you the exception.
Intelligent. Talented, no less.
I really like your music. Honestly.
I even bought a copy of your CD.
But you have one weakness, Emma.
You align yourself with people
who don't deserve it.
Do I have to sit here
and listen to this guy jack off?
Surely you must have considered that.
Because that's why
you're sitting here.
We weren't on that bridge
by coincidence, Emma.
You have two choices.
Tell me where your friends are
and I promise you'll get leniency.
If you don't help me, well...
your two friends might not
make it out of the country.
You wanted to leave the country,
right?
You have until tomorrow morning
to decide...
how important your friends are.
That's too bad.
Do I tell the prosecutor...
that these women
are harmless fugitives...
or do I say they pose a danger
to the public?
The difference is 15 years.
Would you like to get out of here
at 35 or wait until you're 50?
I'm sure she's in some dark cell.
High-security wing.
And it's full of cops.
-And they're armed, right?
-Of course. With machine guns.
One big security zone.
There's no way in without explosives.
And once you're in,
you'll never get out again.
"Pro - 1 , Con - 23"
She's not talking.
All we can do is hope
the others try to contact her.
-Feel like some coffee?
-At my place or yours?
Sorry, I won't be getting it up
till those women are behind bars.
Stop.
- Let her go!
- Drop the gun!
Careful!
Angel there is a lousy shot.
-See what I mean?
-Okay, drop your gun.
Yeah. And away to the side.
- Kick it away.
- Yeah, kick it!
-You're making a big mistake.
-Just one of many, mister.
One more won't make a difference.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Good evening.
Want to spend the rest of your life
in the high-security wing?
Angel, you're young.
You're good-looking.
A talented swindler.
-Don't you ever think of your future?
-Shut up!
That thing's pretty heavy, isn't it?
Come on, put it down.
You know I won't do anything...
until my partner returns unharmed.
You can trust me, Angel.
Quiet in there,
or we'll kick your ass!
"Freedom's just another word
for nothing left to lose. "
And you see how far Janis got
with that philosophy of life.
Better dead than a dope.
Where'd you get
the fancy suspenders?
From your wife?
-I'm divorced.
-Did she leave or did you?
My wife left me.
Abandoned men are dangerous.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
Hello, Inspector.
It's okay.
It's been quite a nice journey
up until now, hasn't it?
Actually, it was the best time
I've ever had in my entire life.
-Emma?
-Yeah.
I need to tell you something.
The police didn't show up
on that bridge just by coincidence.
Everything's set.
-Are you two okay?
-Sure.
Good.
In exactly 36 hours and 20 minutes,
we'll be on our way.
Just imagine:
A bar on a sandy beach...
a glass full of Caipirinha.
Sunshine.
Our only worry:
A coconut might fall on our heads.
In a year I'm sure we'll speak
fluent South American, right?
Right.
I wonder what Marie's doing now.
Probably playing piano for Otto.
I hope he likes our songs.
Sure.
Someday I'm going to do it
the same way.
Just decide when it's time to die.
With my luck, I'll be reborn as a rat
in a test lab.
No, you'll be a panther in the jungle.
I want to come back as you.
Honest. Or as you.
Or as me.
But with a little bit more up here.
Or as Marie.
At least then we can be reunited.
Play just like before.
"'Bandits' Outsmart Detectives"
"'Bandits' Disappear"
"'Bandits': Are They Dead?"
"'Bandits' Spotted In Asia"
They're gone. I'm 1 00% sure.
They're not gone.
"We were here."
I can't believe it.
We haven't heard from them in ages.
And we always did before.
We'll get them
if it's the last thing I do.
They're getting on my balls!
My neighbor asked me
if they ever give another concert...
would I go with her?
Surveillance on every club, bar
and concert hall in the city.
They're crazy.
They're out of their minds.
They just want to bug me.
Yes?
They're playing.
Boss, they just jumped
from the roof, and the people--