I am PhooIan Devi,
you sisterfuckers!
PhooIan! PhooIan!
She is onIy 1 1 .
TeII him to wait a whiIe.
But I've paid for her.
With this bike and cow...
there's no shortage of girIs for me.
It's rusting.
Agree, or I'm Ieaving.
Starved my cow, too.
Wait for how Iong?
What if she gets tampered with?
Another six months, pIease.
A daughter is aIways a burden,
and ours is no beauty.
I need a wife now.
My mother is oId and cannot work.
- Dad wants you, PhooIan.
- I've brought two buckets of water.
StiII, he wants you.
Your bridegroom is here.
I'II deaI with the bastard.
Not scared?
Of what?
AII men are motherfuckers.
Who says?
Women at the weII and in the fieIds.
Know what it means?
No. It must be something cute.
Get a move on.
Now, go quickIy.
What's the hurry?
Touch your husband's feet.
Take his bIessings.
What's this? Show me.
Hiding these earrings?
I gave them to her.
Not part of the deaI.
Now, just go.
This side is for high caste Thakurs.
Low castes use the other side.
OId man's wife!
Sons of bitches!
Motherfuckers!
May you marry witches!
It broke.
Why don't you get a brass pot,
Iike Thakur wives?
Who do you think you are?
These modern girIs!
ShaII I caII your husband?
PuttiIaI!
Think you're a queen, do you?
Being insoIent to my mother.
I'II teach you to show respect.
Be quiet now.
Sweet chiId.
Come here.
StiII not ripe.
Let me feeI you.
Grow up fast.
How does it feeI?
Don't be scared.
It's aII right.
Scared of your husband?
You have to do this after marriage.
You are pretty.
You're my wife.
You have to do this with me.
Come... come...
StiII suIking?
Who'II feed the goats? Me?
It hurts here.
It'II hurt more if you don't go.
Our daughter's taken her Iife
into her own hands.
Now she'II be bIown about
Iike a Ieaf.
She's a Iow caste bitch.
StiII, I'd have her.
She's run away from her husband.
She must be itching for a fuck.
HeIIo, PhooIan!
She'II spread her Iegs easiIy.
I'm getting the itch, too.
She's haughty.
Don't you hear me caIIing you?
I'm here for you.
I'II take your bundIe on my bike.
But you'II have to
do me a favor, eh?
Me do a favor for such a big man,
the headman's son?
You're not Iess than me.
No Iess than a Thakur?
That's a joke!
I Iike you, anyway.
- Let me heIp.
- No, I can manage.
I'm going to the fair tomorrow.
Want anything?
No.
What's this? Stop!
Grab the bitch!
Trying to trap me,
the Iow caste bitch!
Teach her a Iesson.
She's Iike a bitch in heat.
Break her bones!
Devideen, the viIIage eIders wiII
question your daughter. You agree?
- Yes, sir.
- Go!
Why were you aIone in the fieId?
I aIways go aIone.
Your daughter seems to have
no respect for Thakurs.
Why did you caII Ashok?
He came on his own.
On his own, did he?
Ashok, my son, I suppose
you offered to carry her bundIe?
- Yes, and he said he'd take me to--
- I know.
But what did you offer him in return?
Nothing.
- Suresh?
- Yes, UncIe.
You teII us.
Don't be shy.
WeII, she said...
that she's itching for it.
Don't Iaugh.
This girI's bad for our boys.
She'II have to Ieave the viIIage.
- You can't even ride a bike now.
- My brakes don't work.
You're a fat sIob.
Wait for me.
I don't wait for anyone.
These days, you move Iike a goat.
I said, ''These days,
there are Iots of goats here.''
What a view.
TotaIIy wonderfuI.
- Are you saying things about me?
- Yes. You can say things about me.
Such as?
KaiIash, how handsome you are,
just Iike a movie star!
You're a baIdy.
Don't Iaugh. Sit on my rod.
My wife's not here.
So? I'm your cousin.
I wish you weren't.
I'II pedaI, you sit on the rod.
I can do it, you'II see.
I can't sit there.
I'II sit behind.
AII right, fat sIob.
Be carefuI.
Mastana, he's here.
Don't! Stop teasing me!
- What's this?
- HeIIo, Brother Madho.
What took you so Iong?
Who is she?
Her? She's my driver.
Does she give a good ride?
Who's she?
Nobody.
Won't say a word.
She's dumb.
If you're taIking about me,
taIk to me.
So she's dumb?
Who is she?
Speak to me, I said.
- Does she know who we are?
- Bandits, what eIse?
I'm not stupid.
I was born in this Iand, too.
Why isn't she with her husband?
I Ieft him.
- Where's her father?
- I Ieft him, too.
- KaiIash, I'm speaking to you.
- I'm teIIing you.
She's our caste.
A Thakur tried to force himseIf on her.
Beat her and her father.
They threw her out of the viIIage.
She's Iiving in my house.
GirI!
The sisterfucker must have been
desperate to want you!
I didn't give you
permission to go.
Now, go.
- So you've seen Vikram again?
- Mind your own business.
You Iook Iike a bridegroom.
HeIIo, Sister-In-Law.
TeII her now.
What we decided.
I've changed my mind.
I'II teII her myseIf, then.
Be quiet.
You've been here Iong enough.
Aren't you pIanning to Ieave?
PhooIan! Where are you going?
Mind your own business!
Go and Iive under your wife's thumb!
SIave!
The Thakurs won't aIIow you back.
- Don't be stubborn.
- I'II see.
The train's coming!
You were expeIIed from the viIIage.
Why did you return?
Because I had nowhere eIse to go.
How many men have you had?
Why have you arrested me?
The headman's house
was burgIed Iast night.
I wasn't even here.
Do you think we're fooIs?
We know you met the bandits
with your fat cousin.
He soId you to them, didn't he?
Did they fuck you weII?
Why did you Ieave your husband?
CouIdn't he satisfy you?
You can't keep me here.
WiII you take us both?
One in the front
and one in the back?
She won't say.
She'II just do it.
Don't worry, we smeII better
than your bandits.
What are you doing
standing there Iike a statue?
Do something!
What about the briefcase?
Briefcase?
Okay.
Okay, okay. Let's go.
Put your thumbprint here.
Here's your girI, Devideen,
haIe and hearty.
Thank you, sir.
Touch the Thakur's feet.
They paid your baiI
of 25,000 rupees.
Look, what they've done to me.
Sergeant, what's this?
Thakur, sahib, she swears
Iike a fiIthy animaI.
Are your other girIs
Iike this one?
What happens to me?
These Thakurs paid your baiI.
Show your gratitude.
She can't go back to her viIIage.
Strict orders from above.
Come with us.
A girI chiId is a curse.
She knew she was banned,
yet she Ianded up here.
Where couId I go?
To the Thakurs?
Don't you know what they wanted?
They paid your baiI.
To bed me?
Are you my father or my pimp?
You are shameIess.
Not as shameIess as they are!
PhooIan! Come out!
This is Babu Gujjar's gang.
We have come for PhooIan Devi.
Everybody eIse remain indoors.
Send your Iow caste daughter out.
What is it? Who are you?
You come here.
Madho, get him.
Let him be.
You're PhooIan's brother?
- Where are you taking my son?
- Where have you hidden your girI?
She's at her aunt's.
She was at the weII an hour ago.
Vikram, go and check.
- Why hit him?
- Because he's a Iow caste MaIIah, too.
The headman's son has paid me
to do this job. Get her.
Remember, she's my catch,
you sisterfuckers, not yours.
It seems she's gone.
She can't be far.
PhooIan's brother?
PhooIan, I've got your brother.
I'II cut off...
his ears and nose.
I'm Babu Gujjar.
I keep my word.
I am here.
Let my brother go.
Long Iive Thakur.
Move! Move!
Tarika, come on.
Madho, get her.
- Where are you taking me?
- I'm not the Ieader.
WiII they kiII me?
What's going on?
She can't waIk.
Tarika, she can't waIk.
Cut off her nose and ears
and throw her into the river.
It's too much for her.
So she can't waIk.
- We shouId respect women.
- Now you're a preacher?
She's my catch, you sisterfuckers,
and I'II do as I Iike.
Is she your sister?
Come on, you whore!
Now, see what I do
with his sister.
They're here.
I don't trust that man.
So who'II get the ammunition?
MaIIah dog, your father?
If it's safe, why send two MaIIahs?
Why not send Tarika?
Because Tarika
couId fuck your mother.
ShaII I send her?
It's the motherfucking poIice!
Run, Tarika!
So, did you teII Nathu's mother?
I didn't need to.
She knew he'd die.
Like my mother knows
and your mother knows.
Like his fucking mother knows.
Take it easy. Who asked
the fuckers to become bandits?
- You're aIive to speak, bastard.
- On my own fucking strength!
The bastard's at it again!
Gujjar!
Nobody move!
Low caste bastards!
I said nobody move!
Say, ''Long Iive Vikram MaIIah!''
Long Iive Vikram MaIIah!
Victory to the Goddess!
She has taken Babu Gujjar.
Let's move.
This pIace is jinxed.
Madho, search the corpses,
and give everything to the poor.
It's bad Iuck to spend such money.
No one touches this girI.
Give her Tarika's cIothes.
ViIIagers of Astha...
I am Vikram MaIIah Mastana.
Greetings!
We are not poIice nor Thakurs.
Don't be scared.
We are MaIIahs Iike you.
We have come to make an offering.
O Lord Shiva...
and Goddess Bhavani...
we swear to protect this viIIage...
as Iong as it protects us.
Bharat, make the offering
for the prosperity of this viIIage.
May the Goddess protect you.
For the viIIage. Come.
This man's a woman.
No, a man with Iong hair.
PhooIan Devi. She's Goddess Durga,
sent to protect your viIIage.
HaiI, Goddess Durga!
Take this gift from the Goddess.
Women are forbidden in gangs, Vikram.
They bring bad Iuck.
Forgive me, Baba,
but bandits make their own Iuck.
I Iearned this from you.
Her father owes 25,000 rupees
to Thakur GuIab Singh for her baiI.
Then I have to return it
with interest.
Give him the cash.
The poor Thakur must be upset.
Such matters are not discussed
before women.
You go to sIeep.
Vikram, you are a MaIIah...
but Iike my son.
Don't do this.
Remember, the reaI boss of the gang is
Thakur SriRam, though he's in prison.
I know, Thakur Ghanshyam.
I can see hatred for Thakurs
in your eyes.
That is not good.
I wiII not be abIe to stand by you.
So you bought me for 25,000.
It's good to know your worth.
If you were paying, why kidnap me?
Babu Gujjar captured you, not me.
I don't buy peopIe.
I win their respect.
Even women.
Now sIeep.
Don't stare.
SIeep.
Shoot me.
What if I'd kiIIed you?
It takes a Iot to kiII a man.
You're not up to it.
Come on!
I can't!
Fuck!
Run!
The poIice! Run!
- Look under the seats.
- A radio, Vikram.
We're poIice. Come out.
I said poIice, motherfucker.
What's this, then?
You had nothing, eh?
PoIice dogs, don't bIame this
on some innocent man.
This raid is by the gang
of Vikram MaIIah and PhooIan Devi.
Vikram MaIIah and...
Write: Vikram MaIIah
and the beautifuI bandit.
Get out.
He's Iaughing.
Out with him!
LaIaRam, when wiII you be back?
I hope you've enjoyed your stay,
SriRam.
It's been Iike
a home away from home.
You brothers are our guests.
Make one move, and we'II invite you back.
Sign here.
SriRam.
Greetings, sir.
A good day for you.
Cup of tea?
With pIeasure, sir.
I hear there's a woman
in your gang now. Fun, eh?
But they say that a Vikram MaIIah
is now the Ieader.
So it's the ruIe of
the Iower castes now, is it?
The man hasn't been born
who can take over my gang.
He's my puppet.
I taught him everything he knows.
I hear he's dangerous.
Rubbish. He's a monkey.
He'II dance to my tune.
The Thakurs have come!
Greetings, Thakur sahib.
Here is your rifIe.
So, MaIIah, you've made
quite a name for yourseIf.
A big gang...
new guns, a woman, too.
By your grace.
A woman by my grace?
Bharat, tea.
Looks Iike you onIy get sugarIess tea here.
If there's a woman,
why a man to make tea?
You mean her?
Who eIse?
- She's just Iike us.
- Just Iike me?
Let's see her.
Come and sit here.
Don't be shy.
I used to dream of you in jaiI.
It's been a Iong time
since I touched a woman.
I saw a crow on a dead cow.
It's bad Iuck.
Why didn't you sIap SriRam?
If any bastard touches you,
take your gun and shoot him.
Even your boss?
So? Scared of Thakurs?
I don't trust
those sisterfucking Thakurs.
Where's your gun?
Don't trust anyone, PhooIan.
Stop them!
Stay where you are!
Who fired?
Don't worry,
the doctor wiII fix him.
Keep away!
Stay where you are.
- PhooIan, I'm finished.
- Don't say it.
I'II kiII you, sisterfucker!
Bharat, Madho,
coIIect money, aII of it.
He'II have to go to a city doctor.
The buIIet has grazed the bone,
but I couId fix it.
He knows who we are.
How did I fuck?
What did you do?
I did aII the work.
- That's how men do it in the city.
- ReaIIy? It's siIIy.
Let's see you naked.
Just once.
You're fiIthy.
- In the city, they do it naked.
- I'II cry for heIp.
I'm PhooIan Devi!
Vikram wants to fuck me!
- Who is it?
- The buIIet doctor sent me.
- What does he want?
- Cash.
- We paid.
- For the dressings.
Now he wants his fee.
His sister's getting married.
The bridegroom wants a scooter.
Six thousand.
- Tomorrow.
- Too Iate.
I'II have to fetch the cash.
I'II come with you.
I'II give the doctor his corn,
not show him the fieId.
I'II be back in an hour.
She's caused enough troubIe.
What's she back for?
She's our daughter.
Where eIse wouId she go?
To her husband.
That's where she beIongs.
That's worse than jaiI.
Do you know what--
PhooIan,
peopIe recognize you here.
We'd better Ieave,
or there'II be troubIe.
No offense to you, Vikram,
but a girI shouId Iive
with her husband.
The same fucking shit!
See how she speaks to her father?
Vikram, have I said
something wrong?
She shouId go to...
AII right, I'II go to my husband.
I'II do what you shouId have done
Iong ago.
Let's go, Vikram.
- Come out, PuttiIaI, you bastard!
- Don't beat me, pIease.
What do you want?
I'm a poor man.
I have nothing.
- Forgive me.
- Forgive you?
Write this to the poIice.
What?
Any man that marries
a IittIe girI...
I'II kiII him.
I've never seen that side of you.
Where did you get the strength?
I don't know. I ache aII over.
But I feeI at peace,
Iike after a piIgrimage.
That's good.
The gang wiII meet us here.
- I'II go on the mound.
- And me?
You rest.
You've avenged your honor.
Now you're a reaI bandit,
Iike the rest of us.
But remember...
if you kiII, kiII at Ieast 20.
- Why?
- KiII one, and they'II hang you.
KiII 20, and you're famous.
They'II beg you to surrender.
Even give you a pension.
Mastana.
Why did you become a bandit?
Not for the name.
I heard... you were married.
I heard you were, too.
Marriage is Iike
how my parents are.
What was I born of?
An act of Iove or of vioIence?
Show yourseIves, you motherfuckers!
- Don't hit me.
- What eIse are you fit for?
Vikram was a fooI to pamper you.
Draw water from the weII.
I'm thirsty.
Now, go Iike this.
Go, or I'II smash you.
Look, this is the queen
of the ravines!
PhooIan Devi,
they caII her a goddess!
This thing caIIed me
a motherfucker!
This is what we do
to Iow caste goddesses!
KaiIash.
PhooIan.
Vikram...
Shh. Someone's coming.
You can have me, too.
Have you gone mad?
You are PhooIan, PhooIan Devi.
Look at me.
I'm just a fat sIob.
Yet the viIIage saIutes me.
Why? Because I'm your cousin.
WiII he heIp me?
Nab Singh was Vikram's comrade.
- I don't trust any man.
- You trusted Vikram.
Baba, I've brought this woman
without your permission.
She wants a favor.
I know of her.
She caIIs herseIf Devi.
Greetings, Baba.
She was Vikram's woman.
I warned Vikram that SriRam and LaIaRam
were poIice informers,
but he wouIdn't beIieve me,
so he's dead.
Not just those brothers.
I have sworn to fight
the whoIe Thakur cIan.
Watch your tongue.
You're a woman, and of a Iow caste.
SiIence.
Bandits know no caste.
Those two caIIed themseIves
bandits, too.
They raped me...
stripped me and...
I know. I am sorry.
But now what?
Your men are mostIy MusIims.
They do not yet beIieve in caste.
But soon the caste thing wiII turn
the whoIe bandit kingdom upside-down.
This woman is troubIe, Baba.
What does she want?
She wants her own gang.
Let's see what support she has.
Who is with this woman?
I am.
And I.
I'm with Man Singh.
Man Singh, you've aIways wanted
your own gang.
You now have a partner.
Go ahead.
What can a woman do?
And a share for my other gun?
An extra gun aIways gets
an extra share.
PoIice uniforms. Twenty-five.
And 16 guns.
- How many don't work?
- Five.
Twenty-five men, sixteen guns,
five duds...
and you want to raid Jangamajpur.
There'II be at Ieast 50 poIicemen.
Even Mushtaquim wouIdn't try this.
Vikram wouId.
PeopIe of Jangamajpur,
Iisten carefuIIy!
This is the Man Singh
and PhooIan gang.
The poor have nothing to fear.
Anyone who tries to stop us
or cIose their shops wiII be shot.
Women and chiIdren, go in,
do not be scared.
Open up!
Out of here, motherfucker!
The poIice!
What?
Run, PhooIan!
The poIice are here!
You want me, bastards?
Here I am!
- What's your name?
- Damayanti.
- What does your father do?
- He drinks.
Want to come with me?
Keep this. For your wedding.
Long Iive PhooIan Devi!
Love Iive Baba Mushtaquim!
Your name echoes
throughout the Iand.
You are considered a terror.
With your bIessings, Baba.
I have news.
- There's onIy one thing I want to hear.
- I know.
SriRam and LaIaRam
wiII be attending a wedding.
- Where?
- Behmai.
Listen.
Don't do anything rash.
PeopIe of Behmai!
We've come for SriRam and LaIaRam.
We know they are here.
Surrender quietIy.
Any resistance
wiII be met with buIIets.
Women and chiIdren need not fear.
We've come for SriRam and LaIaRam.
Find them!
Smash the doors.
Bring every man out.
Don't touch women and chiIdren.
They watched the fun
whiIe I was raped.
Sisterfucking Thakurs!
You took my honor here.
Where is your Ieader?
I don't know.
Where's he hiding?
- Don't know.
- TeII me!
I swear I don't know!
Where's your Ieader, sisterfucker?
What prospect is there of catching
PhooIan Devi and her gang?
She's a woman, Iow caste.
We'II catch her sooner or Iater.
You journaIists are giving her
unnecessary pubIicity.
She didn't get SriRam and LaIaRam.
She kiIIed 24 innocent Thakurs.
I, too, have kiIIed,
but not for nothing.
The pIace is crawIing with cops...
Iike Iice in a beggar's bIanket.
Soon they'II set the army on us.
Each of those dead Thakurs wiII have
some fucking reIative in the government.
She'II die a horribIe death.
Worms wiII feed on her corpse.
BIoody bitch goddess.
We've surrendered. Don't shoot!
Where are the others?
PoIice attack... at river...
aII dead.
Speak cIearIy.
Run away. Don't go near water.
Look at this.
You brought buIIets?
He says it's aII over.
So he turns coward
at the first sign of danger.
- I've seen enough corpses.
- Look carefuIIy.
Bharat and Madho.
Shot them from this cIose.
Munna ran. Shot him in the Iegs.
Then a bayonet through his throat.
Girdhari had one buIIet.
Shot himseIf.
The poIice went to Ateek
and SuItan's viIIage.
They were stripped naked
and kiIIed in front of their famiIies.
The poIice say
they wiII kiII us aII...
unIess you surrender.
They've poisoned the water.
KaiIash, have you got guns?
I've got water.
KaiIash, you've come to heIp me,
haven't you?
KaiIash, wait.
My gang wiII come.
WiII you bring them?
Hey, my baIdy!
No one wiII come.
They're aII dead.
I'II form a new gang
or join another gang.
They wiII kiII you... and me, too.
Why, you, my oId baIdy?
I'm your cousin, that's why.
I am PhooIan Devi!
Queen of these ravines.
I wiII stay here.
The ravines wiII hide me
in their womb.
They cannot hide you now.
Come on out.
It's time to be reborn again.
Time to face the reaI worId.
- Dad wants you.
- I've brought two buckets of water.
Come out, you whore!
I can smeII you, fiIthy bitch!
You stink even worse.
I'II give you more pIeasure
than Vikram couId.
We know you are rotting,
you have no buIIets.
The press makes you out to be
some kind of a goddess.
But you're good
for onIy one thing now.
You know what, don't you?
Remember my rod?
You must be Ionging for it.
Lots of peopIe want you naked here,
even more than Behmai.
Motherfucker!
We kiIIed Vikram.
Now Man Singh wiII die because of you.
Let's move on.
Get away! Don't come near me!
Go and surrender!
I'II teII Vikram you're a coward!
He'II beat you!
The goddess is angry with me.
There were buIIets for everyone.
For Bharat, for Madho.
There are no buIIets for me.
I want my mother.
I want my father.
My terms of surrender:
Our famiIies must be protected...
and given Iand to Iive.
After reIease, we shouId be given
gun Iicenses for our security.
AII our chiIdren...
shouId be given free education.
The famous bandit PhooIan Devi....
and her gang wiII surrender...
before the Chief Minister.
The bandit PhooIan Devi...
We shouId be kept in open jaiIs
and reIeased after eight years.
Long Iive PhooIan Devi!
I am PhooIan Devi,
you sisterfuckers!
SubtitIes By
J.R. Media Services, Inc. - Burbank, CA