It's much too late.
I'm too old.
No, no.
With your serious money
I could fiX you up
with a plan as a starter.
You know,
I been meaning to ask you...
but a guy my age hates
to ask a punk like you
for tips on things.
What do you own?
What do I own?
I own
two catcher's mitts
and a baseball autographed
by each and every member
of the New York Mammoths.
Put it all together
you got a fin
in any hock shop in Chicago.
What I own is debts.
Well, that's simple.
We'll declare bankruptcy.
That's something for a fellow
to look forward to.
How?
I'll show you, but you got
to do me one favor.
What's that?
You got to lay off Pearson.
I just joke around.
It's something
to keep up my spirits
that's all.
He's dying.
You mean soon, any day now?
Could happen
any time.
Does Dutch know?
No. You mustn't
tell him, either.
He'd cut him loose in a minute.
Only me and you know.
Only you
and me know...
only you and me
will ever know.
Arthur?
Arthur? Arthur?
Who is that?
Arthur, Arthur,
something's happening.
Something's happening to me.
Yeah?
Yeah? What's happening?
Where's Goose? I need help.
What for?
You know.
Well, what do I do?
You can talk, Horse knows.
He told me.
You weren't supposed
to mention it.
Only my roomie.
You got to go get this doctor,
Dr. Charleston P. Chambers.
Check.
I'm really sorry
to have woke you.
I was hoping it wouldn't happen
at a bad hour.
I was hoping it
wouldn't happen this...
Make it back to me another time.
No, there's not going to be
another time.
Dutch'll probably bring
Piney Woods back up now
and he's going to be real happy.
Is the doctor going to come?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Goose went after him.
Goose? Why Goose?
Why Goose?
Well, he's right
down the hall.
Goose has got
a heart of gold.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I guess it never
really showed.
Probably you told him
or something.
I nev... I never told a soul.
Yeah...
Probably everybody'd be nice
to you
if they knew you were dying.
Everybody knows
everybody's dying.
That's why people are
as good as they are.
I'm scared. Hold onto me.
Who is
the sick baseball player?
Are you
a baseball player, too?
Yes, sir,
I'm Henry Wiggen, sir.
Thank you.
I've heard that name...
not that I follow the game.
I've detested it
since early childhood.
It's a dying game, I'm told.
Hmm...
Mmm.
Mmm. I think...
I think it's something else.
You mean something else besides
what they said in Minnesota?
Oh, I couldn't say about that.
I only mean that
I don't think
there's any danger
right at this minute.
Oh, boy.
'Cause this sure felt like it.
Now you can do me one favor.
Please send a bill
care of my wife
in Perkinsville, New York
and also not leak anything
to the papers.
I'm not in the habit
of leaking my, uh, house calls
to the papers.
Arthur, meet Mr. Rogers.
Mr. Rogers is a detective.
Sit down.
Mr. Rogers has been
down to Bainbridge
and is now on his way
up to Minnesota
filling in some facts for me.
However, you can save us
some time
by filling in the rest
of the story
which Mr. Rogers has begun.
I'll certainly try my darndest.
Tell him what you discovered.
In Bainbridge, Georgia,
the subject's domicile
I developed
the following information.
I interviewed a Mr. Jay Clark,
the mailman
and a colored woman named Janet.
Uh, never mind the facts.
Give me details.
The details are
that the subject, Pearson
told various people that he
wasn't feeling so good
and went to the
hospital in Atlanta.
The hospital in
Atlanta recommended
the hospital
in Minnesota...
If you'd actually spoken
to anybody worth the while
you'd learn that Pearson has
this old-time habit
of running back to Atlanta
maybe once
or twice a month.
No doubt you developed
that much.
No need telling you
where he went in Atlanta...
everybody knows that.
Naturally.
And you know
what you sometimes pick up
in such places...
which he did
and which he'd rather not
have them treat in Atlanta
so close to home,
for fear of it getting back
and embarrassing his mother.
So, up he goes to Minnesota
with his fishing gear
forgetting that the ice is nine-
feet thick that time of year
checks in with the Mayo Brothers
gets himself shot
with a couple of miracle drugs
flirts with the nurses,
checks out
meets me in Cannon Falls,
we hunted...
What? What?!
We hunted up some girls we know.
God... damn it.
God... damn it!
Hanson?
Hanson!
Loftus!
Randy, get me Doc Loftus!
What's the sudden
interruption?
I don't know.
You're the detective.
I seen the girls
he runs around with.
She'll give it
to the whole club.
She'll run
right around my infield!
Take down your pants.
Are you over the clap yet?
Oh, yes, sir; long ago.
How do we know?
Check him over, Doc.
All I need is the clap running
through my ball club now!
Hey, Arthur
what's going on around here?
Sometimes I don't know
what's going on, sometimes.
He looks just fine to me.
Never better.
Healthy young man
if ever I saw one.
Uh, should I head out
and develop this
information farther
in-in Rochester, Minnesota?
Rochester, Minnesota?
Where you got shot
for the clap.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Stay with it.
Some things have yet
to be eXplained.
In July, we dropped a couple
more games off the pace.
It was strange...
the team was going lousy
yet I led both leagues
in wins...
smelling 25, maybe more...
and for the first time
in his life
Bruce played regular.
He didn't bust down fences
left and right
but he hit steady... 265, 270.
That's not great,
but for Bruce, it's fantastic.
Wouldn't you say
that if the Arcturis
Company discovered
that you'd been
writing phony letters
to prevent Bruce from
changing his beneficiary...
Oh, that's not a phony letter;
that's a real letter.
- You wrote it.
- The company wrote it.
Or if you didn't write it
your wife wrote it...
that's my guess...
and several baseball players
tell me I'm probably right.
Maybe I'll go check this
with the company themself.
They'd take away your license.
Throw me in jail, hmm?
Ruin you as an
insurance agent.
Hmm...
Well, if you say anything
to the Arcturis Company
I'll stroll down to a certain
police station on 66th Street
and swear out
a complaint
against a certain
"answering service."
Well, I'm not really anXious
to complain
to the Arcturis Company.
I don't see any reason
why you and I can't...
arrange a settlement of this
between us.
A deal?
A compromise.
I can't compromise
with his money.
That's none of your business.
You're supposed
to do what he wants.
I'm deciding what he wants.
That's illegal.
I know.
First week in August,
his father hit town.
Safe!
Stee...
All right, Mammoths,
let's go, let's go!
Safe!
Get a job, Wiggen,
get a job!
All right, Arthur, it's
just one of those days.
It's the last
of the order, Dutch.
You've done a lot of pitching.
Let somebody else mop up.
Go ahead, take it easy.
Let's get Caselli in here.
Caselli!
Oh, Henry.
Hello, Mr. Pearson.
Please, move on, and don't
disturb the ball players.
That's okay, Jim.
I know I am intruding
on you, and I know...
No, you're not.
You've been
intruded on enough.
Aah...
It's a ball game, sir.
You win 'em; you lose 'em.
No, Henry, I mean,
regarding my son.
Sir?
You know about...
the condition of my son?
Yes, sir.
Well, so do I.
Yes, sir, I suspected you did.
How-How can he be so sick
and play so well?
I really don't even know, sir.
If I knew, I'd say.
And not play so well
but better than ever,
and that's a fact.
That's a fact, sir.
There's no mistake
about that.
So, I've been wondering
if they didn't make
some kind of a mistake
out there at that hospital
in Minnesota
because it-it's hard
to believe
that it can be true.
I-I, uh...
I don't think
I'd count on it, sir.
They got an awful famous
reputation up there.
I know it's been
a terrible strain on you.
It's a lot worse on him, sir
and on you.
So, I've been...
I've been thinking
and I don't generally swear...
You go ahead and you swear,
Mr. Pearson.
Plain old mother talk
ain't no words
near strong enough to describe
such a terrible miX-up
as life, Arthur...
but I'm swearing, my son's
been handed one shit deal!
Yes, sir.
What'd you do that for?
That's a really
juvenile thing to do.
Don't do that.
Now, they bombed
you out early.
Why didn't you use your
energy in the game?
What are you doing
it in here for?
Listen, don't mess around
with that stuff.
Everybody's going
to be very...
You're writing
a new book, Arthur?
No, Joe,
I'm being interrupted
by somebody
busting in my room.
About you and Pearson?
What makes
you think so?
I didn't understand
the situation.
What situation?
The situation you're probably
writing the book about.
Probably what situation?
The way I feel
about it is this:
I believe that Pearson's
a better tegwar player
than I ever realized
and should play with
us all the time.
I swear to God, Arthur
I'm shaking and my knees are
trembling, my heart is sick.
He told me on the airplane.
Who told you what?
Goose told me.
Why?
I've been calling Pearson
"Romeo and Juliet:
Which is which," see?
Now who'll you tell?
Nobody, Arthur!
Absolutely nobody!
I told the wife,
and that's the end of it.
Why "told the wife"?
Arthur,
I tell the wife everything.
Hello, Doc.
Sidney.
What's up?
Where is everybody?
Nobody knows.
I'll bet Tootsie knows.
Knows what, Arthur?
Now look,
I know something is up.
The long distance
been flying far and fast.
I could use two grandstands
any weekend or night.
Yeah, well, tickets are going
to be scarcer and scarcer
from here on in.
Why did I see Doc Loftus
just pass through?
Oh, Doc Loftus in the hotel?
Doc Loftus, telephone, please.
Who wants him?
Dutch wants him.
Who's sick?
I don't know,
somebody in Minnesota.
I'm not clear.
Look, I only catch
a little bit now and then
and, besides, who understands
this medical talk
they're talking?
But I believe he has a leak
in his blood somewhere.
Room service?
Just a moment, please.
Nothing serious,
but I don't know who.
I never heard of it.
But for two more grandstands
on the following day
I can tell you
something else.
Yeah? I'd hate to hear it.
You are in the doghouse.
Why you?
You've been playing
your heart out.
It's some of those other
so-called baseball players
been dragging their foot.
That's why
we haven't won it yet.
Why me?
Because of your contract,
Pearson...
Mr. Rogers
the detective, broke it open.
You see, very easy.
Joe Jaros and Goose Williams
spent the winter in Minnesota
with Pearson.
You know, I didn't even know
they were that friendly.
Well, takes all kinds.
The time is 8:06.
Third base side, Arthur,
lower deck, not too far back
and not behind no pillars
nor post.
I told you!
I told you I'd get
to the bottom of this!
Good morning to all.
Good morning.
Shouldn't have kept
it a secret, Henry.
I can't understand
why I'm not crying.
Keep your hankie handy,
dearie.
Makes you think it can happen
to your own son.
It upset Joe
something terrible.
Don't you think
we discussed it enough
as far as how horrible it is?
Tonight is another ball game
as usual.
Maybe we can get help
from the, uh, commissioner.
You can't get help there
and keep it in this room
at the same time.
Well, then let
the facts out.
It wouldn't be human.
Is it human to lose?
We're calling in Piney Woods
from Queens City
for eXtra catching.
Ready on your call
to Professor Traphagen.
Do we really need him?
He was the greatest
catcher I ever saw.
Arthur, you were his boy.
You talk him into coming back
to help us.
He's out of condition.
He teaches English
at a college.
He won't play.
He'll stick to catching.
He'll study us, help
us make it to the end.
How much can I offer him?
The sky's the limit,
and I'm sure the boys will go
to a full series share
if we win.
Red?
Oh, trouble, Red.
Lots of trouble!
Arthur wants to talk to you!
Yeah, it's Arthur who got us
in trouble in the first place.
Red, we got a crisis here,
and we need your help.
You get a full series share
if we win it.
Red, how do you like the sound
of a thousand dollars a week?
Can't find a substitute?
To do what?
Teach English?
What teach English?
People speak English already!
Red, Red, it's urgent.
I swear you won't have to play,
just instruct the catching!
Right!
Hop on the nearest plane.
Love and kisses, Red.
I hate him.
Have you thought up
anything yet, Doc?
I'm thinking.
You're a
slow thinker.
This thing, this...
What is it called?
The disease is named
for Hodgkin.
He's the man who identified it.
Find him.
Is he alive himself?
Maybe he thought up a cure
by now
that those jugheads up in
Minnesota didn't hear about yet.
What the hell kind of a place
is that anyway
to build a goddamn hospital
in the wilds of nowhere?
Does a man freeze his ass off
by the time they get him
down in bed?
You. You were there.
You sneaked out there
in the middle of winter
and all the rest
was horse feathers.
You and Mary "P" for palooka!
And hunting through the ice
and miracle drugs for the clap
and tricks on the telephone!
Whoo-hoo!
Howdy, partners!
Hey, Piney,
what's going on?
Tumblin' tumbleweeds!
Piney Woods!
Hey, Piney, Piney
did you come here
from Queens City
on horseback?
No, partner,
I flew.
Hey, it's Red Traphagan!
What's up, Arthur?
Damn if I know.
You know I'd tell
you if I knew.
It smells the same.
It stinks!
Human perspiration smells,
it doesn't stink.
Wouldn't have it
any other way, huh?
Arthur.
How are you?
Jesus, you've been
having a great year.
Best year of my life.
I've bet you got
no reception like this
in San Francisco.
No, they pray I
don't show for class.
What's up, Red?
Why are you here?
Let's get a statement.
Ponce!
Ponce, I want to talk
to my boys, huh?
Why is he here, Dutch?
What's happening?
- Is he going to play?
- Never.
He's here to coach
the catching
and Piney's here to
catch the catching
in case anything happens.
You'll get your story later.
- Why now?
- Mental lapse, that's why.
Beat it.
Look, there's lemonade,
there's cookies outside.
Why don't you get going,
stay outside.
If you want a story
I'll give it to you later on.
Where's your gun?
Well, right here, partner.
Hand it over.
I'm in no mood to
see anybody get killed
by a bullet wound.
Piney, I hear you had
bullets with it, too.
Well, yes, sir.
They're in the gun.
Why the hell didn't
you tell me?
Why, I didn't think
it'd go off.
I'm always very careful.
That's what everybody says.
That's why the hospitals
are full of babies.
- Jonah?
- Yeah.
You shot guns in the war.
No, sir, I played baseball.
Some hell of a war.
Canada.
Yes, sir.
- You shot guns in Vietnam.
- Right.
Here. Take and empty this gun.
Why am I here, Arthur?
Boys? Boys...
I want to welcome Red back
from the Coast
to bolster us
and steady up the instruction.
I want to welcome Piney Woods
back from the wild, wild west
to ride along with us
all the way now
is what I'm hoping.
You've all been doing
very good jobs.
Maybe now and then
some baseball player
or other type of person gets
the idea that I'm not human.
Well, for eXample, even...
Pearson here thought
that I sometimes
wasn't human.
No, sir.
I, uh, probably ate
you out now and then
but never
without a reason.
No, sir, you only ate me out
for doing dumb things.
No, no, no, no,
I ate you out
for the good of the club
and for your own pocketbook
never for
anything personal
because I know
that you know
that personally
I never had anything
but the greatest respect
for you as a human being.
Yes, sir,
that was how I always felt.
When I die...
...the papers will write
in the headlines
"Son of a Bitches of the World
Have Lost Their Leader."
Yet, many a boy
might shed a tear or two
that rode along with me
into the big bunny
and, uh, that's why
I maybe now and then
I ate Pearson out or
some other type of person.
It's time, Dutch.
Yeah.
I'll say it's time!
Let's go, boys!
Now that you're here
tell me what you see, okay?
'Cause I know I got faults.
I always did.
Throw the ball back
to the pitcher better.
Make it easy on him.
Right, I will.
I really will now.
I'll do that.
I told you that
a thousand times.
When he tells you,
you believe him.
Yeah, but he's a catcher.
You ain't no catcher.
We're of the tribe
of catchers.
Yeah, huh.
Oh, yeah, but when you hit
don't chew.
There's a system
to your chewing.
You give yourself away.
When he tenses up,
he stops chewing.
That's it.
Oh, one other little thing...
use a lighter bat.
I always thought you used
too heavy a bat.
Big, strong boy like you,
you just meet the ball.
Don't murder it.
Okay.
Is she familiar to you?
Oh, you bet.
I seen her on TV.
Plus, she was voted
Miss Industrial Progress
not so very long ago.
I believe I recall
the event.
Tell Mr. Wiggen your present
business address.
66th Street.
Where you've got
a golden lifetime pass to
just as soon as I lay my hands
on that Change
of Beneficiary form
to you-know-who's policy.
Miss Industrial Progress here
is a baseball fan
from way back,
aren't you, honey?
I sure am.
You won't play ball forever.
You got a short life.
Why not live it up a little bit?
I mean,
why worry so much about...
you-know-who and his family
and his little old policy.
Why?
I don't know why you don't
live it up all the time
when dying is
just around the corner
but you don't.
You'd think you would,
I don't know why.
All right, bring them in.
As I was walking the streets
of Laredo
As I walked out
in Laredo one day
I spied a young cowboy
all wrapped in white linen
Wrapped in white linen
as cold as the clay...
Then the cowboy speaks.
Try a different song!
Yeah, I don't like that song.
No, the cowboy speaks.
I don't want to hear
the cowboy speak.
I seen by his outfit
that he was a cowboy
And as I walked near him
these words he did sigh
"Come sit down beside me
and hear my sad story
Shot in the breast,
and I know I must die"...
You got another number, Piney?
That song stinks.
It's a cornball song.
Hey, I think it's letting up.
Let him sing.
Yeah, it sounds good.
Yeah, the cowboy tells
his sad story.
Yes, once in the saddle,
I used to go dashing
Once in the saddle,
I used to go gay
First down to Rosie's,
and then to the card house
Shot in the breast,
and I'm dying today
Get 16 gamblers
to carry my coffin
Get siX pretty maidens
to sing me a song
Take me to the valley
and lay the sod o'er me
I'm just a young cowboy,
and I know I done wrong.
Come on, boys.
Why don't you join in a little
like they do, you know?
Oh, bang the drum slowly
and play the fife lowly
Play the dead march
as they carry me along
Put bunches of roses
all over my coffin
Roses too deaden the clods
as they fall.
Hey!
Hey, it's Arthur!
Hey, Arthur, hat's off.
Come on in, Arthur.
Come on,
join the celebration.
I guess I will... I live here.
Celebrating what?
Uh...
celebrating!
Celebrating celebration.
Yeah, hats off!
Hey, gee, Piney,
he said "Hats off"
So take your hat off.
Well, whatever Bruce says,
I'll do, for in my opinion
there's no greater catcher
in baseball today.
Hats off.
Baltimore won.
Well, that's okay
'cause they ain't going
to beat us!
Best of five.
Hey, hey, why, hats off.
Oh, give me a home
where the buffalo roam
And the deer
and the antelope play
Where seldom is heard
a discouraging word...
I thought I might be dreaming.
I figured I'd wake up
and they'd be
ragging each other
and slinging horse shit
as usual.
But it was real.
They were there,
and Bruce amongst them.
It was a club.
...Where seldom is heard
a discouraging word
And the skies are not cloudy
all day...
No, there's no...
I don't want to be here
when he shoots.
He's gonna shoot goddamn...
Ah, my eyes.
Glass all over the floor.
Where's my shoes?
Arthur.
You all right?
Yeah.
Oh, they're a great bunch
of boys.
They always was.
Put a card there,
all right.
Joe, you up.
Yeah, I'm betting right now.
I want five dollars more.
I'm putting in five.
Five more.
What are you betting on?
Five. I'll tell you
after you put in the five.
And I'm going
to raise you two.
Okay, what are?
- Raise me two.
- I want to raise two.
- All right, he can raise.
- You owe.
Two and two better.
I'll raise you two.
Hey, you're not putting
in any money.
What are you holding, Joe?
- The siX dollars.
- What are you holding?
- I got it.
- I'll just raise you two.
Are you talking big,
or are you holding?
No, no, no.
I want to see his money here.
I just raised two, though.
I can't play.
Listen, put in the money!
I'll put it in,
but I don't understand...
Put in another
three dollars there.
That's it.
Three more.
- Here it is.
- No, but he didn't...
Jack and a three,
and it's all mine.
- Wait a...
- I've got the trump card here.
15, 15!
I haven't even played my hand...
No good, no good!
Wait a minute,
we got a split.
We got a run
right through the ten...
Can you beat
a Coney Island tady?
Yeah. Well, well...
Well, what about
this double ace deuces?
I wish you a lot
of luck with it.
It was a club
like it should've been all year
but never was
but all of a sudden become.
We'd begun to pull ahead.
Please welcome
for a return engagement
on this program
the Singing Mammoths
and their newest member,
Bruce Pearson.
Please eXcuse my tears
'Cause I've been
on the road to tribulation
And I find
no consolation here
What good is a love song
if the words are second-hand?
They don't belong
to anyone you can't get near
'Cause I live on the outside
of your joy and laughter
You gave me a good ride,
but I can't come after
All is said and done
I'm not the one
you really took me for
And so, you better look
before you leap
Yeah.
Come on there, Bruce.
Play it.
Whoo!
Yeah.
Yeah!
Whoo!
Yeah.
Ooh!
Uh-huh.
I live on the outside
of your joy and laughter
You gave me a good ride,
but I can't come after
All is said and done
I'm not the one
you really took me for
And so, you'd better look
before you leap
So you better look
before you weep.
Bruce, you
did it, man!
Get it over here!
Hey, get over here!
What, what?
Ah, nothing.
I'll call a
doctor, okay?
No.
Is it the real thing?
Well, yes and no.
I just feel a little dipsy.
Maybe if you open a window.
Hi, Katie.
I'm okay.
Well, I'm feeling
a little dipsy.
Uh, no, I don't think he did.
Oh, he's getting to it.
Mm-hmm.
No, he's getting to it.
Yeah.
Uh...
Katie? But I didn't...
Katie?
Well, okay, yeah,
and I love you, too.
Yeah.
I'll get Perry to warm you.
No, no, I'm okay.
Am I throwing
the ball back better?
Oh, yeah
and it's helping
me out a lot, too.
Everything had been
going our way
and when the Pirates came
to town
we had ourselves
a good cushion.
We were unstoppable.
It was only a matter of time.
Oh!
Keep it moving,
don't slow it down.
Are you all right?
You don't look all right.
Strike Three! You're out!
Hey, uh, are you all right?
Bruce?
He's all right.
We'll take care of him.
Stee!
Strike two!
Come on! Go!
Yes!
Heads up, Bruce, heads up!
He's not too clear
in his head, Dutch.
Then let's keep your sign
off the bench.
Ah, tell Horse to cover
pop flies around the plate.
Stee!
Ball two!
You can go in now.
It's sad; makes
you want to cry.
It is sad...
makes you want to laugh.
Hey.
Hi.
Hi, Joe.
Hope I brought
the right combination.
Yeah.
Did anyone bring my shoes?
Yeah, sure.
Thanks for everything, Arthur.
Thanks a lot.
And I'll be back in the spring.
I'm going to be in shape then;
you'll see.
Yeah, I'll see you then,
and, Bruce...
Yeah.
...see you in Aqua Clara,
all right?
Yeah.
Hey, Arthur, don't forget
to send me a scorecard
from the series, okay?
You bet I will.
Okay.
I'll see you.
We breezed through the playoffs
and wrapped up the series
on a Sunday.
My win.
I took the scorecard home
and threw it on the shelf
and left it lay there.
It would've been simple
to shove it in the mail.
How long would it have took?
Couldn't I afford the stamps?
In my Arcturis calendar
for December 10, it says:
Desoto visited Georgia, 15-40.
This hands me a laugh.
Bruce Pearson also visited
Georgia.
I was his pallbearer
me and some local boys.
There were flowers
from the club
but no person from the club.
They could've sent somebody.
He wasn't a bad fella...
no worse than most
and probably better than some...
and not a bad ballplayer
neither
when they give him
the chance...
when they laid off him
long enough.
From here on in, I rag nobody.