It's an impressive collection.
You have some very rare editions here.
Are you sure you want
to send them all?
They're of no use to father, not anymore.
Not since he's been this way.
His library was his whole world.
Now it's just...
...a painful memory.
Unbearably painful.
I understand.
Well,
at a rough preliminary estimate
you have a collection here
- worth around 600,000 dollars.
- 600,000?
Yes, worth that about.
I have picked up one or two volumes
that merit special attention.
This "Persiles", for example,
is important.
I'd hang on to that.
It'll never depreciate.
- It's a good investment.
- Valuable?
Very valuable.
As for this "Hypneratomachia di Poliphilo"
by Colonna, Venice, 1545,
I'm sure I can find you a buyer.
But I wouldn't let the rest go
for less than 500,000
under any circumstances.
It may take a month to sort of place them
so in the meantime
I advise you to be patient
A month?
Yes, a month or two, depends on
how much of a hurry you're in, and see,
more hurry, less money.
- Of course.
- Well, that's my advice anyway.
I'm sure you wouldn't
want to rush things
but please feel free
to consult another expert
aand if you have any questions
you know where to reach me.
Incidentally, this
four-volume edition
of "Don Quixote" is quite nice,
but not particularly valuable.
Now, I could
take it off your hands
right away.
How much were you thinking of?
Oh, I couldn't go more
than 4,000 - 4,200
Oh, fine.
- You here?
- Hello Witkin.
You didn't waste much time.
Listen, there's a small fortune
in there. Help yourself.
You're a vulture Corso!
A vulture!
- Who isn't in our business?
- You'd stuck to anything.
For a Quixote by Ybarra? You bet I would.
Unscrupulous!
Thoroughly unscrupulous!
Happy hunting.
I've just got on the phone
with Witkin. He's spitting blood.
Really? What's his problem?
He said you're a double-dealing
moneygrabbing bastard.
He thought he had that deal sold up.
He said you queered his pitch.
He should have been quicker
and offer them more.
- May I?
- Sure.
And he said your evaluation
was way over the top.
And those people coming out in a rash
now they're asking twice
what those books are worth.
Let's face it.
- You screw it off, that's what it's called.
- That's what it's called.
He also said that you snatched the "Don Qui-"
Ybarra, "Don Quixote", 1780.
All four volumes.
Son of a bitch.
Fantastic.
Fantastic, you are the best.
That client of yours, the Swiss, d'ya think
he'd still be interested in this edition?
I have Witkin on my ass, I really
told him I had no part in this operation.
Except 10%.
20%. The Swiss is my client.
No deal.
- 15, for my children's sake.
- You don't have any children.
I'm still young, give me time.
Ten.
...and earlier in 1580, in
"De la Dèmonomanie des sorciers"
by the French Jean Bodin.
Bodin was probably the first
to attempt to estabilish a system,
if the term "system" may be
applied to the Middle Ages,
for classifying the contemporary
perceptions of evil.
In Bodin we find one of the first
definitions of the word "witch".
I quote:
"A witch is a person
who, though cognizant in the laws of God,
endeavours to act thorugh the medium
of a pact with the Devil.
To assist them in their work,
many witches kept familiars,
that is to say creatures
such as cats or toads
in which supernatural spirits
or demons were thought to reside.
For those of you, ladies and
gentlemen who wish to dare more deeply
into the controvertial
subject of witchcraft,
a great deal of
relevant information
may be found
in the following works:
Nicolas Remis "Demonolatriae libri"
and "Compendium Maleficarum",
by Francesco Maria Guazo.
I see you were stimulated
by my little talk, Mr. Corso.
Did I snore?
Most nice of you to ask.
No, not that I noticed.
Shall we go?
- Don't you sleep nice?
- Like a baby.
Strange.
I'd have bet a brace
of Gutenberg Bibles
you spend half the night
with your eyes peeled
You're one of those lean,
hungry restless types
that put the wind up Julius Caesar.
Men who stab their
friends in the back.
Not that I suspect you have
many friends, do you Mr. Corso?
Your kind seldom does.
That makes two of us.
You're right, of course.
Your friendships don't
concern me in the least.
Our relations have always been strictly
commercial, and that's the way I like it.
The professional and the personal
should be mutually exclusive.
Listen, I came here to do some
business, not to shoot to breeze.
If you want to expound you personal
philosophies, write another book.
You don't like me, do you?
I don't have to like you.
You're a client and you pay well.
You're a priviledged, Mr. Corso.
Very few people
ever set foot in here.
This is my private collection.
Some bibliophiles specialise
in gothic novels,
others in Books of Hours.
All my own rare editions
have the same protagonist:
the Devil.
- May I take a look?
- Yes.
That's why I brought you here.
Beautiful, aren't they?
Their soft sheen,
their superb guilding,
not to mention the centuries
of wisdom they contain.
I know people who would kill
for a collection like this.
The "Ars Diavoli".
You'll never see as many books
on the subject anywhere else in the world.
They're the rarest, the choicest
editions in existence.
It's taken me a lifetime
to assemble them.
Only the supreme
masterpiece was missing.
Come.
"The Nine Gates of the
Kingdom of Shadows".
- You're familiar with it.
- Yes, Venice 1666.
The author and printer Aristide Torchia
was burned by the Holy Inquisition
together with all his works.
- Only three copies survived.
- One.
The Catalogue has three copies
surviving, of private ownership:
the Fargas, the Kessler
and the Telfer.
It's true, you know your business.
But you're mistaken nonetheless.
According to my own research,
only one is authentic.
Well, three are known.
That's the trouble.
- Where did you get it?
- I bought it from Telfer.
- Telfer?
- Yes, he fnally sold it to me.
The day before he killed himself.
That's good timing.
"Silentium est aureum".
- Silence is golden.
- Precisely.
Ever heard of the "Delomelanicon"?
I have heard of it, yes.
It's a myth, isn't it?
A book reputed to have been
written by Satan himself
No myth. That book existed.
Torchia actually acquired it.
The engravings you are now admiring were
adapted by Torchia from the "Delomelanicon".
They form a kind of satanic riddle.
Correctly interpreted with
the aid of the original text,
and sufficient inside information,
they're reputed to conjure up
the Prince of Darkness in person.
You don't say.
Are you a religious man, Mr. Corso?
I mean, do you believe in the supernatural?
I believe in my percentage.
Aren't you getting
dizzy standing there?
What is it that you
want from me, Balkan?
I want you to go
to Europe and investigate.
The other two copies
are in Portugal and France.
I want you to find some way
of comparing them with mine.
Every page, every engraving,
the binding, everything.
I'm convinced only one is authentic
I wanna know which.
That can be an expensive trip.
That's to get you started.
Spend what you need.
What if I find that
your copy's a forgery?
It's quite possible.
Really?
It doesn't appear to be.
Even the paper sounds couture.
Even so, something's wrong.
You mean the Devil won't show up.
If all three copies turn out to be bogus
or incomplete your work will be done.
If, on the other hand, one of them turns out
to be genuine, I'll finance you further.
I want you to get it for me.
At all costs. Nevermind how.
"Nevermind how" sounds illegal.
It wouldn't be the first time
you've done something illegal.
- Not that illegal.
- Hence the size of the check.
Do a good job.
I'll double it.
There's gotta be something wrong with it
if you're letting it out of your hands.
I have the outmost faith
in you, Mr. Corso.
There's nothing more reliable than a man
whose loyalty can be bought for hand cash.
Good morning. Dean Corso.
I'm terribly sorry to disturb you
at a time like this.
It would be very helpful ma'am
if you could tell me what you know about
this book.
- Isn't this one of my husband's books?
- Right.
It was in his collection until very
recently. He sold it to a client of mine.
I'm trying to authenticate it.
He sold it, you say?
How strange, this was one of his
most treasured possessions.
- He never mentioned this sale?
- No, it's news to me.
- Who bought it?
- A private collector.
May I know his name?
I'm afraid that's confidential.
- I suppose he has a bill of sale.
- No problem there.
Is this your job?
Authenticating rare books?
And tracking them down, yes.
- You're a book-detective.
- Kind of.
Do you recall when and where
your husband acquired this book?
In Spain.
We were vacationing at Toledo.
Andrew was very excited.
He paid a great deal of money for it.
He was a fanatical collector.
So I gather.
I'll show you.
It's impressive.
Andrew used to spend
many hours in here.
Too many.
Did he ever try it out?
I don't understand.
The book.
Did he ever use it to perform
some kind of ritual
intended to produce
a supernatural effect?
- Are you serious?
- Yes, absolutely.
Andrew was a trifle
eccentric, Mr. Corso,
But he wasn't insane.
It's true he'd been acting
strange in those last few days,
he shut himself up in here,
he seldom emerged, except for meals.
That morning I was awoken
by the screams of the maid.
He'd hanged himself.
Whatever he was up to,
I certainly can't see him chanting
mambo jambo or trying to raise the dead.
The Devil, Mrs. Telfer.
This book is designed to raise the Devil.
"Sic luceat lux".
"Thus might the light shine".
Son of a bitch.
Where did you get this?
Balkan.
He wants me to research it.
Balkan owns a "Nine Gates"?
Recently acquired by
the late lamented Andrew Telfer.
Trust Balkan...
What does he need you for?
I don't suppose he plans to sell it?
He wants me to compare it
with the other two survival copies
which are in Portugal and France.
So I'm off to Europe.
Compare it?
Yes. Only one of the three
is authentic, he says.
But this looks genuine enough.
Chrissake, it's gotta be worth
a million. Take care of it.
That's why I'm here.
I need you to stash it for me.
'Cause I'm starting to see things.
- Like what?
- Uninvited visitors, unfamiliar faces.
I don't trust anyone,
not even Balkan.
I come to think I'm not
even sure I trust you.
You know I wouldn't screw you
unless there was a good reason:
money, women, business...
Other than that you can relax.
- I'll take it up on my way to the airport.
- Sure.
These engravings are terrific.
Or horrific, whichever.
Sensational,
absolutely sensational.
May I come in?
Please, sit down.
I've come to talk business.
Yesterday, when you came
to see me about that book,
I was too surprised to react
as I should have done.
I mean it really was one
of Andrew's favourites.
So you said.
I'd like to get it back.
- That could be a problem.
- Not necessarily, it all depends.
- On what?
- On you.
I don't understand, Mrs. Terfel.
The book is not mine to dispose of.
You work for money, I take it?
What else?
- I have a great deal of money.
- I'm very happy for you.
You could stage a theft.
I imagine your client
is well insured.
- I'm a professional, ma'am.
- You're a professional mercenary.
Mercenaries work
for the highest bidder.
I could throw in a bonus.
- This has happened before in some place.
- I know, in the movies.
She had an automatic her stocking...
No automatic.
- Would you like a drink?
- Why not?
Okay. Where is it?
Where's what?
Don't fuck with me!
I thought I already did.
You have reached "Bernie's Rare Books".
Please leave your message after the beep.
Bernie, you there?
Pick up.
Give me a minute, I won't be long.
- Then you can take me on the "Kennedy"
- No problem sir.
Oh Jesus!
Jesus Christ...
None problem?
Stop.
Stop by that phone booth, pull over.
No problem sir.
He isn't available at the time.
May I know who's calling?
- You'd like to leave a message?
- No, I have to talk with him at once.
I'm afraid he is in transit.
If you can give me your number,
I'll have him return it
when he checks us.
No, I'm in a phone booth.
It's an emergency.
I have to speak with him right now.
Right now, do you hear me?
Right now.
One moment.
- Are you there, Mr. Corso?
- Yeah.
Ok, I'll put him through.
Mr. Corso, what have you got for me?
More than I'd bargained for.
- What do you mean?
- I mean I quit.
I wanna return you the
book. Where are you?
I'm disappointed in you, Mr. Corso.
You never let me down before.
Well, this is different.
Do you remember Bernie Orenstein?
The dealer?
I gave him your book
to stash it for me
and now he's dead, murdered.
- Because of the book?
- What else?
Look, I've never said it would be easy.
If it's a question of money...
It isn't the money, I want out.
This matter means a great
deal to me, Mr. Corso.
I'm not an ungenerous man,
you know that.
Proceed as arranged, and you can
tack another zero onto your fee.
What... Hey, where are you?
- Good evening.
- Good evening. Come in.
- You speak English?
- Yes, I do.
I would like to get your opinion on this.
What a habit for a book binder...
"The Nine Gates" - superb
edition. Very rare.
The Telfer copy.
Yes. You used to own it, right?
- We used to, yes.
- We sold it.
...when the opportunity
presented itself. It was too good to..
...too good to miss. An excellent sale.
An excellent buying!
Impeccable condition.
Impeccable.
Are you the present owner?
No, A client of mine.
I would never have believed
she would part with it. Never.
- She?
- Mrs. Telfer.
I understood that it was
Mr. Telfer that had bought it.
He'd pay for it.
It was Mrs. Telfer
who made him buy it.
- He didn't seem particularly...
- ...interested.
An exceptional specimen.
- Do you think it could be a forgery?
- Forgery? Hear that, Pablo?
I took you for a professional.
You speak too lightly of forgeries.
Far too lightly.
Forging a book is very expensive.
Paper of the period, right inks,
Too expensive to be profitable.
- Still it can be done.
- Of course.
It requires a great skill,
but yes it can be done.
Do you think that
could be the case here?
What makes you ask?
My client wishes to satisfy
himself on the book's authenticity.
His name's Balkan.
Boris Balkan of New York.
- All books have a destiny of their own.
- And a life of their own.
Mr. Balkan is a celebrated collector.
He's no fool, he must know
this book is authentic.
- We know it.
- So must he.
- We've had this book for years.
- Many years.
With ample opportunity
to study it thoroughly.
The printing, the binding,
are magnificent examples of
17th century Venetian craftsmanship.
Finest rag-paper.
Resistent to the passage of time.
None of your modern wood-pulp.
Watermarks, ink,
typefaces...
If this is a forgery,
or a copy with missing pages
restored, is the work of a master.
Have you studied the engravings? They
seem to have some underlying significance.
But of course.
Here, for example.
This one could be
interpreted as a warning:
"Venture too far" it seems to say,
"and danger will descend on you from above".
These types of books
often contain little puzzles.
Especially in the case of
such an illustruous collaborator.
Collaborator?
You could have not proceeded,
very far in your research, Señor.
Here. look close.
Don't you see? Only six of the nine
engravings were signed by Aristide Torchia.
Yes. And the other three?
This is one of them.
L, C, F.
Who's LCF?
Think.
Lucifer?
Very perceptive of you, Señor.
Torchia was burnt alive
because he wrote this book
in collaboration with someone else.
Come on. You can't honestly believe...
The man who wrote this book
did so in alliance with the Devil
and went to the stake for it.
Even hell has its heroes, Señor.
- I have seen you before.
- Have you?
Yes.
- Are you travelling in this car?
- The next one.
The sleeper... I travel on the cheap.
- Are you a student?
- Something like that.
I like trains.
- Trains I'm on?
- Just trains.
What's your name?
Guess.
- Green eyes?
- That'll do.
- What's yours?
- Corso.
Strange name.
Italian, it means "to run".
You don't look like a runner to me.
You're more the quiet type.
Well, give my regards to Balkan.
Tell him I'm doing my best.
- Balkan?
- Nevermind.
See you around.
Maybe.
I wouldn't be surprised.
Yes?
Yes... Dean Corso, Mr. Fargas.
- Corso? Oh yes, please come in.
- Thank you.
Please.
Home sweet home.
You won't say no
to a brandy I take it?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
What handsome glasses.
They're the only ones I have left.
- It has to have been a beautiful place.
- It was.
But old families are
like ancient civilisations,
they wither and die.
There they are, 834 of them.
What a pity you didn't
see them in better times.
I used to have 5,000.
But these are the survivors.
So this is the Fargas collection.
Not quite as I imagined it I must say.
C'est la vie, my friend.
But I keep them in perfect conditions,
safe from damp, light, heat, rats.
I dust and air them every day.
These are the occult.
- What do you think?
- Not bad.
Not bad indeed. At least
ten of them are extremely rare.
Here: Plancy, "Dictionnaire Infernal",
first edition, 1844.
Leonardo Fioravanti's
"Compendi dei Secreti", 1571.
And there it is,
in perfect condition.
It has travelled the world
for three and a half centuries,
yet it might have been
printed yesterday.
Is it in order? I mean you
haven't detected anything unusual?
Unusual? no.
The text is complete, the engravings too,
nine plus the title page's,
as the catalogue states, just like the
Kessler in Paris and the Telfer in New York.
Yes... It isn't the Telfer anymore.
Telfer killed himself.
But he sold his copy
to Boris Balkan first.
Oh, Balkan.
If he sets his eye on a book
no price is too high.
Not that I would ever sell this one.
Not at any price.
It's strange that he should
have sent you here if he...
...already had...
Do you have it here?
May I see it?
Oh, superb.
Beautiful. Identical.
Two of the only three
to escape the flames
reunited for the first time
in over three centuries.
Yes.
Look at this slight imperfection here,
the damaged "S"...
The same type,
the same impression.
Oh, incredible.
As you see if it wasn't for this slight
discoloration on the back of your copy
no one could tell them apart.
If you don't mind I would like to stay
for a while and examine them in detail.
What are you looking for, Mr. Corso?
I'm not quite sure.
Some books are dangerous,
not to be opened with impunity.
Very true.
I'll be damned!
Hello again.
- You didn't say you were bound for Sintra.
- Neither did you.
What are you doing here?
Reading.
I can see that.
And bumping into people unexpectedly.
Yes, unexpected is right.
Are you on a business trip? Is that
why you always carry that thing around?
- Just part of your course?
- My course?
"Winning friends and influencing
people". You said you're a student.
Did I?
So I am, in a way.
I like books. Do you?
- You been travelling long?
- A while.
I don't suppose you
ever travel by motorbike?
Sir? Excuse me sir.
Phone call for you, sir.
- For me? Are you sure?
- Yes sir. Please sir...
- Yes?
- Mr. Corso?
My God, how did you find me?
- Made any progress?
- Progress? Yeah, you can call it that.
Well?
Look, I can't talk here, I'm in the lobby.
Let me call you back, where are you?
Nevermind that. Get them
to transfer it to your room.
- I'll wait.
- Alright.
Señor, pardon me.
Could you send this up to my room?
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
- Still there?
- Yes.
Alright. I've examined
the Fargas copy.
It's authentic enough,
at least it looks that way.
It's like yours,
but there are discrepancies.
Discrepancies?
The engravings are not identical.
Just like keys
in different hands,
doorways open in one copy
and bricked up in the other...
- And there's another thing.
- Yes. Yes, go on.
The ones that differ aren't
signed Torchia. They're signed LCF.
- Still there?
- LCF.
Listen, where are you anyway?
I must have that
copy, Mr. Corso.
Get it for me.
The old man wouldn't sell it
to save his life. He said as much.
Did he?
Hello? Hello?
Just a minute!
- What time is it?
- Early, but you have to go.
- Go? Go where?
- To Fargas' place.
I've already seen Fargas.
I think you should see him again.
What is this, some kind of
practical joke? Who are you?
- What do you know about Fargas?
- Get dressed. I'll wait for you outside.
Don't bother. He isn't there.
- Oh really, then where is he?
- Over there.
God Almighty...
You want to get inside?
I had thought about it, yes.
You wait here.
Shit!
Well, did you find it?
You know, it's come to my attention
that you know too goddam much.
Why do you keep following me
around? Who are you working for?
You're wasting time asking all
these questions. We better get out of here.
There's a flight from Lisbon to Paris
at noon. We should just make it.
- What's with the "we"?
- There are two of us, aren't there?
What happened back there?
The old man caught
someone stealing, I guess.
- And what do you guess happened to him?
- He drowned.
- With a little help from who?
- He's dead, who cares?
I do.
I could easily end up the same way.
Not with me around to look after you.
- Oh I see, you're my guardian angel.
- If you say so...
- Someone is playing a game with me.
- Of course, you're part of it.
And you're getting to like it.
Keep the change.
Hello Gruber.
Hello Mr. Corso.
Delighted to see you again.
We don't have any vacancies, but...
I'm sure I'll be able
to organise something.
- Thank you very much. Please...
- Thank you, sir.
- Excuse me?
- Good morning madam.
The Kessler Foundation, please.
- Second floor.
- Thank you.
Good afternoon.
I'm Dean Corso, I have an appointment
with Baroness Kessler.
This way.
You have thirty minutes.
- Yes?
- Monsieur Corso.
Oh yes, Mr. Corso. Come in.
I've heard a great deal about you.
- Nothing good I hope.
- You hoped right.
Thanks, Simone.
Well, I'm reassured,
Baroness, because
in my trade
to be spoken well of
can be professionally disastrous.
My God.
Yes, there it is.
The Kessler Collection.
You know I know your
catalogue almost by heart?
Strange we
haven't met before.
Your name is a byword
among dealers and collectors.
But I imagine you know
your own reputation better than I do.
Yes, well it does keep the wolf
from the door, so to speak.
I'm sorry Baroness. Where you
in the middle of something?
Of my latest work:
"The Devil, History and Myth".
A kind of biography.
It will be published
early next year.
- Why the Devil?
- I saw him one day.
I was 15 years old and I saw him
as plain as I see you now.
It was love at first sight.
You know, 300 years ago
you'd have been burned at the
stake for saying something like that.
300 years ago
I wouldn't have said it.
Nor would I have made
a million by writing about it.
Yeah.
What is it you wish
to discuss, Mr. Corso?
There's a book in your collection
I'd like to examine if possible.
It's the book of "The Nine Gates
of the Kingdom of Shadows".
The "Nine Gates"?
An interesting work.
Everyone's been
asking me about it lately.
Is that so?
Follow me.
You truly believe
in the Devil, Baroness?
Enough to devote my life
and my library to him.
Not to mention
many years of work.
Don't you?
Almost.
This book demands
a certain amount of faith.
Well, I'm afraid my faith's
in short supply these days.
I know this work extremely well.
I studied it for years.
Do you have any doubts
about its authenticity?
Not wheresoever.
Are you sure?
My knowledge of
this book is profound.
I wrote a biography of its author.
Yes, I read it: "Aristide Torchia,
the Devil's Apprentice",
Excellent work.
A corageous man.
He died for the sake
of this very book in 1667.
While studying the
Black Arts in Prague,
he acquired a copy of
the dread "Delomelanicon".
This is Torchia's
adaptation of that work
which was written
by Lucifer himself.
After they burned him
at the stake, a secret society
was founded, to
perpetuate its memory,
and preserve its secrets.
"The Order of
the Silver Serpent".
What, a sect?
A kind of witches' coven.
For centuries they've met
to read from this book
and worship
the Prince of Darkness.
Today it's degenerated
into a social club
for bored millionaires
and celebrities,
who use its meetings
as an excuse
to indulge their
jaded sexual appetites.
I myself belonged to the Order,
years ago.
But time is too
precious at my age
besides my orgy
days are over.
I told them to go to the Devil.
You mean it's all about sex or...
Of course not.
They're under the illusion that
they owe their money and success
to membership in the Order.
- Do they still meet?
- Every year,
on the anniversary
of Torchia's death.
They'll be meeting
very soon now.
- And you said they read from this book.
- Not this one.
I took mine back when Liana Telfer
acquired the one in Toledo.
Victor Fargas is an unbeliever,
he's always refused to partecipate
so naturally they use the Telfer copy.
Not that it has ever worked.
Did Andrew Telfer ever take part?
Telfer? Oh, no, no...
That creature Liana,
married him for his money.
She comes from an old and
aristocratic French family,
The "De Saint-Martins",
but they were penniless.
So Liana used his dollars
to restore her castle
and buy the "Nine Gates".
If he ever finds out what his wife
gets up to at these gatherings
he'll probably kill himself.
Funny you should say that, Baroness.
He hung himself last week.
Who exactly are you
working for, Mr. Corso?
My client's name
is irrelevant, Baroness.
I'm simply trying to
authenticate his copy,
just the one that Telfer
sold him before he died.
How stupid of me!
I should have guessed.
You've out stage
of welcome, Mr. Corso.
I was hoping to examine
your copy in detail.
Certainly not.
Tell your client, who
can only be Boris Balkan,
to come and examinate
himself, if he dares.
Tell him not to send any
more wolves in sheep clothing.
Now kindly leave.
Well, I'm sorry
if I troubled you.
Thank you very much for your time.
You don't know what you're
getting yourself into, Mr. Corso.
Get out before it's too late.
I'm afraid it already is,
Baroness. Good day.
Thanks.
They're broken.
You should be more careful.
- I need a favour, Gruber.
- Certainly, Mr. Corso.
Liana Telfer,
Maiden name De Saint-Martin,
40ish, brunette, dishy,
probably accompanied by
a black gentleman with
closely cropped
platinum blonde hair,
and a moustache.
I wanna know if they're staying
in some hotel here in Paris.
It'll take a little time...
Yes, of course. Start with the
"Five Stars". That's your best bet.
- Very well sir.
- Alright.
Are you feeling alright?
I've felt better,
Gruber. Thanks.
Let me know if you locate.
Put this
against the back of your neck.
You were really great
on there by the river.
I haven't thanked you for that.
Alright. Look...
I think it's about time you
told me what's going on here.
- Someone's after your book.
- No kidding.
And you? what
do you feed into it?
Yeah?
Can I take it in
the reception please?
Alright. I'll be right down.
- Yes?
- Anything new?
Oh, His Master's voice again.
No, not much,
aside from the fact somene has tried
to take my life a couple of times
Oh yes. Fargas has been murdered.
Murdered? How do you know?
I saw him. And his copy.
Or what was left of it anyway.
Someone had snatched the engravings
and tried to burn the rest.
- What do you make of it?
- It's tragic, it's tragic...
What about Baroness Kessler?
How did you get on today?
- Where exactly are you?
- What about her copy?
No, why do I get the impression that you've
been breathing down my neck the entire time?
You're an investment of mine,
Mr. Corso. I'm really looking after it.
The old woman swears
her copy's authentic.
But I didn't get the chance
to examine it closely.
She threw me out as soon as she guessed
that you were behind my visit.
You're not exactly in her
good books, if you know what I mean.
You must see her again.
Are you kidding?
Have you seen her secretary?
Try the launch break.
Hello?
- Do you have a photocopy machine back there?
- Yes sir.
- Can I use it?
- Of course, sir.
Thank you.
Yes. Hello, Baroness. It's me,
the wolf in sheep's clothing.
I thought I made myself
bright clear, Mr. Corso.
Well...
I've got something for you, Baroness.
Kind of peace offering.
Will you allow me to give it to you?
Please?
First let me apologise.
I should have told you right away
that I work for Boris Balkan.
It was foolish of me to think that I could
deceive someone as astute as yourself, so
please forgive me.
Flattering will get you
nowhere, Mr. Corso.
Get on with it.
Right.
These
are for you.
What is this?
What is this supposed to be?
You said that your knowledge
of "The Nine Gates" was extensive, but
did you ever compare
your copy with the other two?
No.
Why?
Well, you should.
These are copies of the
engravings in Balkan's book.
- You'll find that some of them differ from yours.
- Differ?
So you question my book's
authenticity, do you?
It that's your peace offering
you can take it and go.
Mine "Nine Gates"
is absolutely genuine.
I don't dispute that, Baroness.
In my opinion all
three copies are genuine.
But the fact remains
they display variations.
Variations?
If that were true
it would be a revelation.
What makes you so sure?
I've already compared these
with the Fargas engravings.
In his book
th keys were in the other hand.
Here the doorway
wasn't bricked up.
And in this one the man
was hanging by the other leg.
- Well?
- Well what?
Look closely, Baroness.
The turrets.
Three in yours,
four in Balkan's.
Amazing.
I'm convinced there'll be
a third one in here somewhere.
Three variations
in three copies makes nine.
Coincidence or something more.
Maybe Torchia hid the secret of
"The Nine Gates" in three books, not one.
I must admit I'm impressed.
This puts an entirely different
complexion on the matter.
You have my permission
to investigate further, Mr. Corso.
Take as long as you need.
My permission did not
extend to that, Mr. Corso.
Nobody smokes in my library.
Baroness?
Idiot!
Excuse me. There's something
missing from my room.
- Has anyone been up there while I was out?
- Only your wife, sir.
My wife?
I don't have a wife!
Excuse me sir.
Yes? Yes, he's in front of me.
Alright.
For you sir. Booth nomber two.
Yes?
What news?
News?
Let me see... Well,
yes, the good news is that I got
to examine the old woman's book.
and three of her engravings
were signed LCF.
The bad news is that
someone strangled her
and made a bonfire of her collection.
Now that's tragic, wouldn't you say?
You put the words out of my mouth.
Yes. It's the Fargas story all over again.
I'm of the mind that they tore out the
engravings before they torched the place.
That makes two sets they've got.
And my copy?
Well, I learnt my lesson fortunately.
I don't carry it around
with me anymore
Otherwise it would
have gone up in smoke.
Excellent. Good thinking.
Well, with the two copies gone
that seems to conclude your assignment.
It only remains of you to return my book.
I'm staying at the Ritz.
You can pick up your check at the same time.
Shall we say in half an hour?
There is more bad news.
- I don't have it.
- You don't have it?
Someone lifted it from my room.
Listen to me very
carefully, Mr. Corso.
I think you may
already have some idea
of the length at which I'm prepared
to go when I want something.
Unless you recuperate
my property in double-quick time
you'll discover just
how far that can be.
Where is it?
- Where is what?
- The book. Where is it?
Would I be here if I took it?
You should know better by now.
I must apologise on my
young colleague, Mr. Corso
Was unpardonable.
Is that her?
No sir, she was tall, dark hair,
very chic, very elegant.
Which reminds me sir, I have
the information you wanted.
The lady and gentleman you mentioned
they're staying at the
Plaza Athené Hotel
suite 209-211.
Thank you very much Gruber, I owe
you one. I need a taxi, quick.
A taxi, quick.
Send this to Mr. Balkan
at the Ritz. it's B-A-L-K-A-N.
- Fax it immediately.
- Certainly, sir.
It was a pleasure
to be at your service.
Ain't coming?
What do you plan
to do if you see them?
Probably hide behind you.
Oh, that's them.
We should grab a taxi
before they take off.
Let's go.
They're going.
Coming?
Couldn't you have picked
something a little less conspicuous?
Don't be so picky.
Some people would give
their eyeteeth for driving this.
Listen we can't sit on their tail forever,
they'll bound and smell a rat.
How do I look?
Ridiculous.
Sit tight.
Take your pick.
No, you. You know everything.
If you say so...
We lost them.
No, not at that speed.
They must have gone the other way.
You mean I don't know
everything after all?
Turn around.
30ish, brunette, dishy?
- What was her name again?
- Telfer, Liana Telfer.
No, her maiden name.
- Saint-Martin.
- Look.
Excuse me?
We're looking for the house
of Madame De Saint-Martin.
The castle you mean?
The castle, I knew that.
Where's the castle?
Take the road behind
the Church there.
- Thanks.
- Not at all.
Keep going.
See them anywhere?
No.
Sorry to have to intrude
on you like this.
What are you doing here?
I jumped like to pick up the
book you stole from my room.
- That book is mine.
- We've been through all this before.
My husband gave it to me.
It wasn't his to sell.
He sold it to get back at you?
What happened? Did he
catch you with that albino?
How dare you?
Keep an eye on her.
Don't!
Be careful, she bites.
Hi.
Don't move!
Either one of you.
Get the book.
Don't kill them up here,
you'll make a mess.
Take them downstairs.
You'll go first.
Then you.
Down.
Open the door.
Watch out!
I didn't know you had it in you.
Eight Gates preceed the Serpent
who guards the Word.
We give loyalty to you, Lord.
We devoted our
bodies and souls to you.
The Serpent is a beast
that never sleeps.
A beast whose eyes can
see through the mirror of science.
We give loyalty to you, Lord. We...
Stay here and cover me.
I'm going down.
We won't be afraid of
the noose, or the blade, or the poison.
We give loyalty to you, Lord.
We devoted our
bodies and souls to you.
We'll walk intact through
the lepers and the plague.
We give loyalty to you, Lord.
We devoted our
bodies and souls to you.
The last hidden one
behind which is the Word
is the Ninth one.
Teth, Enneae, Oded.
We give loyalty to you, Lord.
We devoted our
bodies and souls to you.
- Glory to  Eloy, Agla, Zate...
- Mambo Jambo! Mambo Jambo!
Look around you, all of you.
What do you see?
A bunch of buffoons
in fancy dress.
Do you think the Prince
of Darkness would actually
deign to manifest himself
before the lights of you? He
never has and he never will. Never.
You read from his book,
but you have no conception
of its true power.
I alone have grasped its secret,
I alone have fathomed
the Master's grand design.
I alone am worthy to enjoy the fruits
of that discovery: absolute power
to determine my own destiny.
You're insane, Boris.
Give it back to me!
You, Liana de Saint-Martin,
you're even guiltier than
the rest of this pathetic rabble.
You have at least some idea of what
this book can do in the right hands.
Yet you grant yourself
to this farsical proceedings,
to these orgies of aging flesh
conducted in the Master's
name. You're a charlatan!
Don't Corso, don't!
Let it be.
What is it with you?
He just murdered someone
in public. You're off the hook
for the other killings.
You should be grateful.
I'm ecstatic!
You're out of the job, it's over.
- What more do you want?
- You know what.
Wait for me!
Not taking me for a ride?
You were working for him all along.
Funny, I thought you were.
Shit!
- Here you are sir. All's dry.
- Thanks madam.
- Excuse me?
- Yes?
Where is that?
Bernard I need you to
show something to...
Here it is.
Yes, that's it.
Exactly.
One,
four,
three,
six,
seven,
five,
eight, two, nine.
The enigma is solved at last.
"To travel in silence by
a long, unsecured road
to brave the arrows of misfortune
and fear neither noose or fire,
to play the greatest
of all games and win,
forgoing no expense
is to walk the vicissitudes of Fate
and gain at last the key
that will unlock the Ninth Gate ".
Corso?
What were you expecting?
An apparition?
You're not wanted here
Mr. Corso. Leave.
I'm the only apparition
you'll see tonight.
You'll find a check waiting
in my New York office,
payment in full.
You've killed for those.
They're worth more than money.
Infinitely more, but
they happen to be mine,
not yours.
Do you know something, Corso?
In spite of our differences
I have a sort of
bug for you.
- I'm touched.
- We have something in common, you and I.
We share the same passion. You've
developed the same obsession, haven't you?
Unfortunately for you only
one of us is destined to fulfil it.
You're out of your depth.
Kindly go.
- I'm not leaving here empty handed.
- Don't even think about it.
Stand aside.
I credited you with more finesse.
- You heard me? Stand back!
- Put that away, it's not your style.
Don't come near!
Seems you found
your proper niche at last.
I like that.
Now,
you can watch.
I'm entering an uncharted territory.
taking the road that
leads to equality with God.
You can't come with me.
I must travel alone.
But you may look
on me and marvel.
- That's very kind of you.
- Indeed it is.
There have been men
who have been burned alive
or disembowelled
for just a glimpse
of what you are about to witness.
I give you my allegiance, Master.
I pledge myself to you
body and soul.
Let me fear neither noose,
nor fire nor poison.
Erase me from the Book of Life,
inscribe me in the Black Book of Death.
Admit me to the Ninth Gate.
Let it be so.
Let it be so now!
I feel the power surge through me
like an electric current,
rendering me
capable of any feat
of mind or body.
I'm invulnerable, I'm invincible!
I can float on air,
I can walk on water.
I'm plunging my hands in fire,
I feel no heat!
This is great,
here's another one.
Sic dedo me.
Sic exeo me! Sic damno me!
It's miraculous!
I feel nothing, nothing at all!
Is that it?
Is the game over?
For Balkan yes.
Not for you.
Why didn't it work for Balkan?
The ninth engraving was a forgery.
Where is the real one?
I want it.
You're running low in gas.
- Hello. Ceniza brothers.
- Sorry?
- Ceniza brothers?
- Pepe Lopez. Ricardo Herrera.
Sure...
Do you speak English?