Some men do.
Just being so far from the armada,
the mind can start to fill
with strange thoughts, doubts.
Don't you ever have doubts, Vaako?
- Doubts?
- About the campaign.
About Lord Marshal.
First and always,
I am a Necromonger commander.
So if you're here to test my loyalty,
you succeed only in testing my patience.
Oh, no.
No, that's not why I'm here at all.
[ Dame Vaako ]
I'm so glad I could
steal you away for a moment.
Doesn't it strike you odd?
Here we have
the current Lord Marshal...
destroying entire societies,
and yet he can't bring himself...
to kill one
stranded Elemental.
Why is that?
You don't pray to our god.
You pray to no god, I hear.
Elementals-- we calculate.
Don't we all.
But now let's have first things first.
What of Riddick?
In truth, I don't know
where he went.
In truth, I'm more interested
in where he came from.
Watch your step.
I've always wondered,
does an air Elemental fly?
Now do me a favor.
Calculate the odds of you
getting off this planet alive...
and now cut them in half.
No, we can't fly.
But we glide very well.
Save your threats, Necromonger.
I would have told you about Riddick
for the asking.
It concerns a foretelling,
a prediction now more than 30 years old.
Ayoung warrior
once consulted a seer.
He was told a child would be born
on the planet Furya--a male child--
who would someday
cause the warrior's downfall.
[ Female Voice ]
Cause his untimed death.
Furya? Furya's a ruined world.
No life to speak of.
For good reason.
This young warrior
mounted an attack on Furya,
killing all young males
he could find,
even strangling some
with their birth cords.
An artful stroke,
wouldn't you say?
So this warrior, the one
who tried to outwit the prediction,
would later become--
That's why he worries.
The Lord Marshal.
Which would make
the man-child--
He worries he missed
killing that child in its crib.
Riddick.
[ Baby Crying ]
That's why it's so vital to him.
Wait.
- It's about a prophecy.
- Wait! Wait!
Are you there?
You do what your lord asks.
You cleanse Riddick for him,
and in doing so...
you prove your undying loyalty.
And perhaps then
he'll finally let down his guard.
[ Man ]
Still here, I see?
I've been here 1 8 years.
See this?
I remember how gorgeous she was.
Well, gorgeous in a certain light.
And now,
for the goddamn death of me,
I cannot remember her name.
[ Man ]
Feeding time!
[ Loud Snarling ]
We're here for the rest
of our unnatural lives.
[ Snarling Continues ]
Here they come!
Whatever you do,
don't make eye contact.
[ Clamoring ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Men Shouting ]
Aaah!
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Growls ]
[ Beasts Chomping ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Purring ]
[ Alarm Buzzing ]
It's an animal thing.
[ Footsteps ]
Check her for me.
She's always got a blade somewhere.
- Hyah!
- [ Groans ]
[ Grunting ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Yells ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Growls ]
I don't think
she likes being touched.
I'd take my wounded and go
while you still can.
[ Gasps ]
Is there a name for this
private little world of yours, huh?
What happens there
when we don't just run away?
You'll kill us... with a soup cup?
[ Laughing ]
Tea, actually.
What's that?
I'll kill you with my teacup.
You know the rule. They aren't dead
if they're still on the books.
Mmm.
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasps ]
Come on.
Death by teacup.
Damn. Why didn't I think of that?
I didn't come to play
"Who's the Better Killer?"
But it's my favorite game.
Haven't you heard?
I heard you came lookin' for me.
Is that all?
Then you missed the good part.
Hooked up with some mercs
outta Lupus Five.
Said they'd take me on,
teach me the trade, give me a good cut.
They slaved me out, Riddick.
Do you know what that could do to you
when you're that age?
When you're 1 2 years old?
I told you to stay in New Mecca.
[ Shouts ]
Did you not listen?
I had mercs on my neck.
I'll always have mercs on my neck.
I spent five years on a frozen heap
just to keep 'em away from you.
And you go and sign up
with the same fake badges...
that wanted to cut you up
and use you for bait.
What are you pitching, Riddick?
That you cuttin' out was a good thing?
That you had my ass covered
from halfway across the universe?
You signed with mercs.
There was nobody else around.
[ Door Slams ]
Let's pop the cork.
Get some fresh air.
[ Whirring ]
[ Hissing ]
So they do go topside...
to swap out air.
Interesting.
Who the hell are you?
When it happens, it'll happen fast.
Stay on my leg when I cut fence
or stay here...
for the rest of your natural life.
Nobody outs this place.
Nobody.
[ Kyra ]
He ain't "nobody."
Good news first.
Talked things over with my amigos here.
We'll cut you in for 77 5K.
Well, all right.
What's the bad news?
They close the local whorehouse?
[ Cackles ]
No. The bad news is worse than that.
Much worse.
Our pilot, he saw this.
It crossed a shipping lane.
Any idea what this might be?
Never saw nothin' like it.
This ship charts back
to Helion Prime.
You know, Anatoli's
got a nose for trouble,
and he thinks
trouble follows you here.
Look. We dusted our tracks
and got the hell outta there.
There is no way
we didn't lose them.
"Them"?
This is my prisoner. Mine.
Nobody else's.
And I want my money now.
So...
you stole a prisoner...
from "them"?
[ Yelling ]
[ Gunfire ]
[ Gunfire Continues ]
[ Gunfire Stops ]
[ Growls ]
No.
Riddick. No.!
[ Grunts ]
Shoulda taken the money, Toombs.
[ Electricity Crackling ]
- [ Throws Switch ]
-[ Gate Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Gasping ]
You gonna kill me?
[ Raspy Breathing ]
[ Whirs ]
[ Man Groans ]
Mercs.
Some guards here,
but this can't be all of them.
Check their slots in the back--
and be careful.
[ Riddick ]
Don't bother.
Guards ain't there.
They figured out the Necros
are comin'for me.
Plan was to clean the bank,
ghost the mercs,
break wide through the tunnel.
And then somebody got a lucky shot off
with this rocket launcher here...
and took out the sled.
Guards took off on foot
but rigged the door
so no one could follow.
They'll take the one ship in the hangar
and leave everyone else here to die.
How come you know all this shit?
You weren't even here.
'Cause it was my plan.
I shoulda taken the money.
[ Sighs ]
[ Snarling ]
Riddick!
[ Yelling Echoes ]
[ Whirring ]
[ Man ] What is this?
What is he thinking?
- [ Man #2 ] Once that sun comes up--
- We'll last five minutes.
Five minutes. We ain't gonna last
30 seconds out there.
It'll light you up like a match.
20-mile buffer zone
and 30 klicks to the hangar.
[ Murmuring ]
30 klicks over that terrain?
[ Murmuring Continues ]
It's moving in the right direction.
We could make it.
Stay behind the night,
ahead of the sun.
There's gonna be one speed--
mine.
If you can't keep up, don't step up.
You'll just die.
[ Kyra ]
Riddick?
[ Shouts ]
Go, go! Go on! Go! Climb here!
Climb! Go! Go, go, go!
Boss!
Up there.
- Take a look.
- Because Anatoli says so?
Because his nose says so.
[ Hisses ]
There's nothin' up here.
Oh, shit.
Riddick.
They're heading
right for the volcano fields.
They're going for our ship.!
No chance do they
get to the hangar first.
No chance!
Next one! Next hole!
We'll catch 'em there!
No more run for you.
Where did the big guy go?
- Ohh--
- [ Groans ]
[ Bullets Ricochet ]
Close it!
[ Trigger Clicking ]
[ Cries Out ]
What was that?
You don't care if you live or die?
If I kill them first, not really.
Maybe I do.
Keep moving!
[ Grunting ]
[ Riddick ]
Kyra?
- Kyra!
- What?
Get that ass moving!
- [ Rocks Sizzle ]
- [ Groans ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Shouts ]
Riddick?
Remember what I said
about not caring if I lived or died?
You knew I was kidding, right?
"One speed."
[ Rumbling ]
Temperature differential.
Your rope.
It's too late.
We're never gonna make it.
Your rope! Gimme your rope!
And your water. All of it!
Stay in the shadow of the mountain.
Don't wait for me. Run!
Riddick!
Aaah!
[ Flames Roaring ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Where the hell is that hangar?
[ Rocks Sizzling ]
There it is.
[ Grunts ]
- Listen.
- [ Wind Whistling ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Engines Thrumming ]
- [ Sniffs ]
- [ Amplified Breathing ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Let me guess. Necros.
And a whole lotta Necro firepower.
Shit.! I hate not being the bad guys.
[ Amplified Breathing ]
[ Electronic Clicking ]
[ Electronic Screeching ]
[ Rumbling In Distance ]
I figure we got three minutes
before the sun hits us again,
burns out this whole valley.
- Wait.
- We gonna do this or not?
Just wait.
Ellen.
Her name was Ellen.
I never really forgot.
[ Electronic Screeching ]
Aaah! Boss!
[ Gunfire Continues ]
- Remember that favorite game of yours?
- "Who's the Better Killer?"
[ Gunfire Continues ]
- Let's play.
- Come on!
[ Groans ]
On the right!
[ Yelling ]
Watch out!
Behind you!
Kyra.!
- [ Explosions ]
- [ Shouts ]
Sybar!
[ Screams, Grunts ]
[ Yells ]
[ Screams ]
[ Yells, Grunts ]
[ Growls ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Yells ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunts, Groans ]
[ Cries Out ]
- [ Shouts ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Kyra ]
No.!
- [ Yells ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
Aaah!
[ Gasping, Groaning ]
[ Yells ]
Get up. Get up.!
Please get up.
So,
you can kneel.
[ Woman's Voice, Distorted ]
I think you know now.
I think you know
who tore Furya apart.
This mark carries the anger
of an entire race.
[ Inhales ]
But it's going to hurt.
[ Groaning ]
[ Groans ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Engines Thrumming ]
[ Alarm Siren ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Soft Clatter ]
Kyra?
I was supposed to
deliver a message to you...
if Vaako failed to kill you.
A message from
the Lord Marshal himself.
He tells you to stay away from Helion,
stay away from him,
and in return,
you'll be hunted no more.
But Vaako will most likely
report you as dead.
So this is your chance.
Your chance to do
what no man has ever done.
The girl.
Where will they take her?
[ Gasping ]
We all began... as something else.
I've done... unbelievable things...
in the name of a faith
that was never my own.
And he'll do to her
what he did to me.
The Necromonger in me
warns you not to go back.
But the Furyan in me...
hopes you won't listen.
God knows... I've dreamed of it.
I have lost a Purifier...
but I have gained
a first among commanders.
It is overdue, isn't it--
that we acknowledge
your many accomplishments,
your steady faith,
and above all,
your unflinching loyalty.
Obedience without question.
Loyalty till UnderVerse come.
Well done, Vaako.
This is a day of days.
Look more pleased, Vaako.
You have killed his enemy...
and his suspicions.
- I should have brought back his head.
- You saw him unbreathing.
You saw him dead on the ground.
Riddick was no common breeder.
In a heartbeat he dropped 20 of my men.
All mysteries are not miracles,
not even in this religion.
And if you say it is certain,
then it is certain,
and we've already said it,
haven't we?
We have.
[ Door Opens ]
Now, tell me if it's true.
Tell me the Furyan is gone,
and I can close this campaign
without hearing his bootsteps.
If he is dead,
I sense I'm not far
from the same fate,
being of no further use here.
Shouldn't I tell you
that Riddick is still alive?
Don't try me, Aereon.
I could plow you under
with the rest of Helion Prime.
No one really knows the future.
Then tell me the odds
that Vaako met with success,
that I will now be the one...
who can carry his people across
the threshold into UnderVerse,
where they shall begin true life.
Tell me what I want to hear, Aereon,
and maybe
I'll save your home world... for last.
- The odds are good...
- That?
that you will reach the UnderVerse...
soon.
Ascension protocol!
We still have numbers
out there, Lord Marshal--
sweep teams, recon ships.
They would be hard-pressed
to make it back--
Get my armada off the ground!
[ Engines Thrumming ]
[ Large Machinery Noises ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Heavy Slam ]
- [ Chattering Continues ]
- [ Heavy Slam ]
- You mean on Helion?
- I mean here, on this very ship!
Could you be wrong?
Mind fabricates fear.
Not so wrong as you
when you left him alive!
It's twice a mistake.
Not only your failure,
but now the report of success.
How do we salvage this? How? How?
Lord Marshal's got to be warned.
You will never see the UnderVerse!
He will kill us both
before our due time.
I say give Riddick his chance.
If he is half of what you think,
he can at least wound the Lord Marshal--
and that is when you must act.
Just to take his place?
Just to keep what I kill?
- That is the Necromonger way.
- It is not enough!
Then you do it for the faith!
If he has fear, he has weakness.
If he has weakness, Vaako--
He is unworthy of lordship.
We do it for all Necromongers.
Protect the faith.
This can still be a day of days,
but the timing...
must be flawless.
Final protocol.
Execute on my order.
[ Panicked Chattering ]
[ Engines Thrumming ]
Go inside.
Are they leaving now?
Ziza! Go inside!
[ Gasps ]
We found this Lensor dead.
[ Lord Marshal ]
Show me his last sight.
Commander Toal.
He won't escape twice.
[ Chattering ]
[ Metallic Slicing Noise ]
[ Metallic Slicing ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Grunts ]
- Stay your weapons!
He came for me.
[ Lord Marshal ]
Consider this:;
If you fall here now,
you'll never rise.
But if you choose another way--
the Necromonger way--
you'll die in due time...
and rise again in the UnderVerse.
Go to him.
It hurts...
at first.
But after a while,
the pain goes away,
just as they promise.
- Are you with me, Kyra?
- There's a moment...
when you can almost
see the UnderVerse through his eyes.
It makes it sound perfect--
a place where anyone
can start over.
Are you with me, Kyra?
Convert now...
or fall forever.
You killed everything I know.
Vaako.
[ Grunts ]
Not yet.
Been a long time
since I've seen my own blood.
These are his last moments.
[ Grunting ]
Give me your soul.
- Fuck you!
- [ Groans ]
[ Growls ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Yells ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
You're not the one to bring me down.
[ Groans ]
[ Gasps ]
Now! Kill the beast
while he's wounded!
[ Exhales Deeply ]
[ Groaning ]
Help me, Vaako. Kill him.
Vaako?
Forgive me.
Flawless.
[ Gasps ]
No.
No-o-o!
[ Echoing ]
Now what would be
the odds of that?
I thought you were dead.
Are you with me, Kyra?
[ Sighs ]
I was always with you.
I was.
You keep what you kill.