Barefoot Friends
[Going on a retreat to
get close to each other!]
[Team Hyo Ri has W124,000.
Team Jong Shin has W7,000]
[Get to the lodging first!]
[And you can swap money
with the other team!]
[Team Jong Shin had a comeback!]
[Now Team Hyo Ri has W7,000.
Team Jong Shin has W124,000.]
[To be able to find food and lodging...]
[Team Hyo Ri decides to live off
of Team Jong Shin.]
[Except for one member!]
[Ho Dong is all alone with just W7,000.]
Bring the popcorn. That's ours!
[His stomach hurts
due to stress from Hyo Ri.]
[Will he be able to get
close to the others?]
[How will he survive alone
with just W7,000?]
[5:30pm: almost dinnertime.]
Were you sitting there the whole time?
What else could I do?
You should go find work or something.
Everyone, come on out.
Let's eat dinner.
- It's cold.
- Because we're in the mountains.
You didn't eat the popcorn
we left there.
- Where?
- Right there. A few pieces.
You have amazing self-control.
Do you want to get beaten?
Come and beat me if you can!
- Eunhyuk!
- Yes, Ho Dong?
- Let's go.
- Huh?
Let's go check out the village.
I think you're the only thing
that's worth checking out in this village.
Don't be stubborn.
Come join us.
- Come on...
- I should keep my words like a man.
He's going to butter up the ladies
and try to get food.
It's just one night and two days.
[Hyo Ri's nonstop attack!]
You need to stick to me or
to the other members...
In my opinion, the Hyo Ri
and Ho Dong duo is pretty cool.
I think the two of them make a great
duo for an entertainment show.
Don't you have too much
time on your hands?
No, I don't. I need to go
practice for my comeback show.
If I don't do well on my first live show,
it's all your fault.
- How come?
- I came on this show because of you.
Did I cast you?
I don't even know your phone number!
I came on the show because
I wanted to cheer you up.
I wanted to cheer you up! I mean it.
Everyone in the entertainment
business is trying to help him out.
[Explosion!]
Hyun Joong! Let's go.
- You said you'd go alone.
- He's on our team.
Come back safely.
Okay then. I'll be back.
You take care of them.
Okay? You should take care of them.
Look at your ugly feet.
Those toes are...
- Just go!
- Okay, I will go...
My stomach...
We will wait for you here.
My team, let's go look around!
It's just the two of us.
- I get only the two of you?
- Yes.
Are you sure the two of you
can capture my amazing gag?
Gosh!
You must be kidding!
I have so much to show on camera!
Amazing stories with the villagers...
But just two cameras to shoot all that?
That's too many!
[Whatever...]
[Anyway, how can I get dinner?]
Where should I go
to look around the village?
To look around?
- Go take the middle street.
- The middle street?
- Our house is that way too.
- Is it really?
Why don't we go together?
[Can you give me some of that?]
Kid, watch the road.
It's dangerous.
[Spotted the ice cream in his hand.]
[Cautious...]
- How old are you?
- Five years old.
Five years old?
What's your name? Huh?
- Ki...
- Ki?
Ki Yong Kwang?
You are a handsome boy!
Yong Kwang!
Can I have some of that?
What is that?
It's nothing...
Can you share it with me?
Yong Kwang! Please let me have some!
Please share with me, Yong Kwang!
That's food! Are you going
to eat all of that?
You'll get fat!
What grade are you in?
Introduce yourself to the camera.
I'm Kang Soo Won in the fourth grade.
- Is your last name Kang?
- Yes.
My last name is Kang too.
Let's shake hands.
[Still eating...]
You know what? You and I look alike.
- Like father...
- Like son...
At school...
What did your teacher say about sharing?
Did he say to share with your friends?
Or did he say you should be greedy?
- He said share.
- Did he say that?
- Really?
- Yes.
So this is...
Wow.
Are you going to share it?
Yes. So I'm taking it to my relative.
- You're taking it to your relative?
- Yes.
I guess it won't work then.
One more time. Like father...
Like son...
Okay. Go take it to your relatives.
[I'm hungry...]
[Where can I get food?]
What should we do about dinner?
- You guys haven't tried Hyo Ri's food.
- I really want to try her food!
- I heard it's good!
- It'd make you want to date me.
- Because of food?
- Yes.
Can I just eat your food?
We have potatoes... Potato pancakes?
- Potato pancakes?
- That sounds good for a rainy day.
That sounds good.
Let's make a simple meal with
potato pancakes and fried veggies.
My mouth is already watering!
- Let's go buy some rice.
- I will go.
- The market is right there.
- Yeah?
Let's go get rice.
To the market?
Should I go catch some snails
in the rice field?
Why don't you go with Si Yoon...
and get some side dishes like Kimchi
from the neighbors?
Okay.
[Just the two of us?]
[Awkward...]
[They look uncomfortable
for some reason...]
This is what Ho Dong
would do as a show host.
When was the last time
you had a girlfriend?
Why don't you answer?
I...
- In the last year? Or before that?
- Way before that.
I see.
What about you?
Do you still love her?
- What?
- That older woman?
That older woman?
No, it didn't end well.
- Was she really older than you?
- Yes.
Wow.
I guess we really don't
know about each other.
This is nice. Should we sit here and talk?
- Should we?
- Yeah.
So... do you still love her?
No... I just wish her happiness.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Is she the celebrity that I know?
- No, not at all.
- She's not the one?
- No, no.
You really had someone.
- You were caught off guard.
- No, I wasn’t.
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
She... was a good singer.
- And a good actress.
- No, I said she's not a celebrity.
She could be good at acting
without being a celebrity.
- She could also be good at singing.
- She's not a celebrity.
Please put a caption over here
she's not a celebrity.
How tall is she?
Over or below 160 centimeters?
I don't know but when I held her...
I held her like this...
[Reminiscing about her...]
I held her like this even
the day before we broke up.
And you guys still broke up?
Which is your type?
Hyo Ri or UEE?
UEE.
What about you?
Of course, it's Hyo Ri for me.
But Hyo Ri is totally different
from the time she was in Fin.K.L.
How so?
She was really pretty back then.
- And she's not now?
- Well...
She's cool now.
She's so cool. I just can't help
thinking that when I see her.
What about UEE?
UEE?
Well... with UEE...
We had conversations no more
than three times on the show.
When UEE sees me...
- You treat her like an older sister...
- She just greets me like this...
- You are too proper to her.
- I know.
I hope you can get closer to her today.
Should we go play a game
to bring you two closer?
Hey!
You should be a man,
act like a man of authority.
'Hey, come over here!'
'Cut the onions.'
- Can I do that?
- Be mean but desirable.
She'd think, 'Why is he doing this to me?'
But she'd be interested in you.
[30 minutes later]
- Like a mirage?
- Oh, hi!
Hello!
Do you want to trade Kimchi
for Si Yoon's autograph?
Do you know me? I got too tan.
It's Kim Hyun Joong!
- Did you eat dinner?
- Not yet.
Then dinner must be getting ready.
I'll take a photo of
you and Si Yoon together...
if you go ask your mom to
give us some side dishes?
- Our house is right up there.
- I see.
- It's right there.
- Really?
What a nice house!
Mom! Do you have some side dishes?
Hello! Hello!
May we come in for a moment?
Just whatever you have...
we need just a little.
- That's good.
- Do you want fish to grill?
No, thank you.
That's more than enough.
That's enough.
Wow, wow!
That's enough for us.
- You should save it for your family.
- That's enough.
Wow, thank you so much!
And the cabbage Kimchi too...
Wow...
This is the famous southern Jolla Kimchi.
Let me taste southern Jolla Kimchi.
This is delicious!
Thank you so much!
Kimchi and egg.
- Thank you for the food.
- We will enjoy the food!
Thank you for the food, Ma'am.
We will go back now.
Bye!
- Thank you!
- You are awesome!
Do you know where we came from?
Barefoot Friends!
Wow! Thank you!
Oh, the wrong slippers!
I'm sorry. Those looked better than mine.
- Bye-bye!
- Good bye!
Now that I look at myself...
I look funny wearing
socks with the slippers.
You're fine.
Forget about fashion on this show...
- Don't you agree?
- Yes, I do.
We bought two bags of
potatoes, which is a lot!
Let's do it quickly.
Go wash these, Jong Shin.
[He got used to listening to her.]
These don't need washing, right?
Wash after you peel them.
I'm doing her errands
for the first time in the long time.
- I swore not to do that again.
- Didn't you miss that?
I wonder where Ho Dong is.
I hope he's not having a feast somewhere.
He must be eating at someone's place.
He's super popular with the older ladies.
It's so much fun playing in the water!
It's so much fun!
[Did he eat dinner anyway?]
Feels so nice!
So cold...
[He's cold and hungry...]
I won't look pathetic to the guys.
If I ever failed to eat...
one's image is very important.
The vibe he gives is important.
So I would pretend to have eaten.
Like I could eat no more.
Pretend you ate too.
Pretend you ate with me.
You are my team.
Don't let me down.
They'll give me food
when I look indifferent.
Then I will eat just to be polite.
[Will Ho Dong's plan really work?]
- Sesame seeds? Green onion?
- There are sesame seeds in front of Bum Soo.
- The onion with leaves...
- I'm slicing them now.
- You mean these?
- Slice them.
- Slice them all.
- Sprinkle some pepper.
Smells so good.
- Smells good.
- It looks delicious.
- It's Ho Dong.
- Where?
- You are here!
- He's biting a toothpick.
I ate a lot.
- Where?
- Next to Surak Waterfall.
- Your tummy looks flat.
- No, it's full.
Did you really eat?
- I had mixed veggie rice.
- Really?
It was exactly W7,000.
And...
- Because I'm a celebrity...
- Okay, we won't give you any food then.
- I won't eat.
- Really?
Yes.
They gave me tofu on the house.
This much...
- After the filming was done...
- Aren't you going to eat?
- I said I already ate.
- Really?
Where did you eat mixed veggie rice
for just W7,000?
Oh, well...
There are lots of restaurants
by Surak Waterfall.
- Really?
- Yes, it was very good.
- That's great. We worried about you.
- Yeah?
It looks ugly, but should taste good.
- It looks ruined.
- Yes, it does.
[Aren't they offering to taste a little?]
[Don't touch!]
[You, heartless...]
You said you were full.
Why are you taking that?
Okay, my stomach is about to burst.
[Ho Dong's plan failed!]
You sound really hungry.
My stomach hurts now.
My stomach is so full it hurts now.
We're going to make ramen.
- You said you were full!
- You are full!
- We are going to make ramen.
- What?
Should I try that? Can I turn it over?
Good.
Just like that... oh, no!
You aren't going to eat that anyway.
- It looks...
- It doesn't look good... look here.
We're going to eat that.
Hold on. Hold on!
Not good...
What are you doing?
I am good at this.
- Don't let him eat.
- Don't give it to him.
I didn't know a toothpick could
be such a strong weapon.
Cook it a little longer.
- Let me try with this.
- Okay.
Wow, Mount Jiri is really nice...
[Not interested...]
I ate the mixed veggie rice
with my feet in the water.
And the free tofu.
- Did you really eat?
- Set the table just for eight.
Did you really eat, Ho Dong?
We have only eight spoons.
Ho Dong, we got this Kimchi from
the village and it's amazing.
This Kimchi is delicious.
Now I realize I'm in the Jolla Province.
- This table is perfect!
- It's nice!
- This table is...
- Are you having a food coma?
He's having a food coma
because he ate too much.
- The table needs cleaning...
- Like fathers after eating...
So busy...
- Here's the rice!
- Wow!
The rice is perfect.
Ho Dong, do you want to eat dessert?
- What do you have?
- Do you want fruit?
Do you want onion juice?
- It's good for health.
- Give him onion juice.
- It's good for blood circulation.
- That's right.
- Good for skin too.
- Yes, it is.
What a nice season it is. No mosquitoes...
It's a good season
to eat mixed veggie rice.
And free tofu...
There's lots of rice left,
since Ho Dong isn't eating.
- Should we make burnt rice?
- Yes.
- Make burnt rice?
- Let's serve it to the staff.
I will have two bowls of rice.
Thank you for the food!
- Don't you want to eat?
- I already ate.
I will go eat then.
[You should ask one more time!]
It looks so delicious!
I'm going to eat a  lot!
Steamy rice!
Everything's good.
You don't even have chopsticks.
Have some potato.
Pass me that.
Aren't you going to eat, Ho Dong?
Please have some.
He said he's full.
- He worked hard too...
- I'll go for a walk.
Oh, my stomach...
I'm having a food coma.
Just say you want to eat too.
You shouldn't be so prideful.
How can I eat when I am so full!
Or you could make me work!
You could ask nicely!
Go bring the ramen from the kitchen then.
- What?
- Go bring the ramen.
Do I have to make it?
We already made it, so just go bring it.
You trust me with that?
I could eat it all by myself.
- We know.
- I'm touched. Okay.
Since you guys trust me, I will go get it.
- Of course, we do.
- Yes, you do.
I guess he really ate.
He must really have eaten.
Did he say he spent W7,000 on the food?
- Hyo Ri!
- Yeah?
- It's right here.
- Come on over.
That looks unsafe...
Thank you.
Gosh!
- I almost fell in the ramen.
- Ho Dong turned around.
Ho Dong, leave the food alone.
Ho Dong, this is your last chance.
Just tell us honestly if you didn't eat.
Just tell us honestly.
- This is your last chance.
- Did you eat or not?
It's right here, Ho Dong.
Oh, my God. I could almost cry.
- You didn't eat?
- I can't eat any more.
Hyo Ri, you can't do that to me.
I was about to give you the money...
You said you spent the money on food.
The W7000 is right here.
- Is this some kind of magic?
- So you didn't eat at all?
This is a sad story...
Hyo Ri took away his last chance...
Ho Dong...
It hurts!
I'm sorry, Ho Dong.
I'm really sorry!
My stomach hurts again.
Come on up!
- Come on!
- I'm fine...
Come on up!
Please don't do that.
If I sit here, they can only see my back.
We're being considerate.
They can only see your back.
- You may be embarrassed.
- To save you from embarrassment.
- Do you want me to eat like this?
- This is all yours.
- I must look funny from behind.
- It's okay.
Let's eat.
Look how he's scooping the ramen.
He must have been hungry.
Ho Dong, come over here.
I was feeling dizzy.
- Ho Dong, come on over.
- Let's scoot.
Have some kimchi with the ramen.
It's really good.
[Mount Jiri's highlight]
[Become one with the waterfalls!]
[Come on! Let's cool off!]
[Why did they jump in the water?]
[The first night on the retreat.]
I've watched all of you and realized...
You are too polite and too proper
with each other.
That's true.
Be nice when you should be.
But you should be honest
to each other too.
[Huh?]
'Don't come on the show
if you're sick, Jong Shin.'
You could say that
on a trip like this.
You could even reveal your secrets.
Why don't we take a moment
to get to know each other?
We can get close that way.
I prepared something for that.
'Straight Ball, Up and Down!'
'Straight Ball, Up and Down?'
Your straight ball can lift
your friends up or bring them down.
- Just one shot?
- Lift them up or bring them down.
Before dinner, all of you wrote...
what words lift you up
or bring you down.
Now you should figure out
what the others wrote.
I answered the questions very honestly.
- You answered them honestly?
- I did too.
- Me too.
- Should we start?
Let's start with Ho Dong.
What words would lift Ho Dong's spirits?
- Don't show that.
- Let's start with something positive.
Eunhyuk!
'You are sentimental.'
No? No?
Incorrect!
I think I heard that before.
- Ho Dong likes this kind of thing...
- He's sentimental?
Eunhyuk!
'You are romantic.'
Nope...
That's not it. UEE!
UEE was faster.
'You are a kind man.'
Bum Soo!
'You are successful!'
Incorrect.
Hyun Joong!
'He's better than Yoo Jae Seok.'
That's not it.
You shouldn't say just
anything to be correct.
He's loving it.
- He's so happy.
- He's loving it.
He loves it.
He's thinking he should've written that.
That was the wrong answer.
That's not it?
Is there anything better than that?
I don't think he's heard this often.
Has anyone ever said it to you?
- He probably has...
- In a private meeting...
- I heard that from a female.
- From a woman?
'Your head is smaller than I thought.
Incorrect.
Jong Shin! 'You aren't as
ignorant as I thought.'
Incorrect.
'You aren't as fat as I thought.'
What did you think then?
[I thought you'd be fat...]
Eunhyuk!
'You are sexy!'
Really?
- 'You are sexy!'
- You got it!
I mean it. I thought that sometimes.
When women tell me...
I look sexy in person even
though I don't look it on TV
it makes me feel good.
Ho Dong told me that before.
Now...
Good times are over.
Let's just talk about positive things...
What would make Ho Dong feel down?
Don't be too nice. We don't
live in a nice world.
Eunhyuk!
You got the chance! You sexy brother!
'Go back to wrestling.'
Isn't that it?
'You better go back to wrestling.'
Incorrect!
- These days this would be...
- Don't give out.
I think he'd be hurt to hear that.
- These days?
- Hurt?
- What would that be?
- Jong Shin!
'I feel sorry for him.'
Incorrect.
I got it.
'He's bad.'
He's been hearing that a lot.
'Are you all right?'
That was a powerful ball.
Wait! Time out!
That doesn't just make me feel down.
It damages me.
That's mean.
Should we just bury you in the ground?
- I just feel...
- Just bury him?
Se Yoon!
'Be strong.'
I actually heard that a lot.
It doesn't make me feel down, but...
I should be the one
to cheer people up.
But...
others say that to me to cheer me up so...
I feel sorry more than
down, to be honest.
I didn't feel down, but felt bad.
I was really feeling sorry.
'These days you are...'
- 'These days you are...'
- UEE!
'You are not funny these days.'
Incorrect!
Don't do that!
Se Yoon!
'These days...  you're not it.'
'These days...'
'What's wrong with you?'
I'm totally fine.
He's funny.
Okay, you are funny!
Hyun Joong!
'You are no good these days.'
Hyun Joong...
That even makes me feel down.
Ho Dong! Ho Dong!
Se Yoon!
If I say this, it'll really bring him down.
'These days you are...'
'These days you are... in danger.'
Correct!
- I feel sad.
- But it's not true.
I know. I am just fine.
What kind of danger?
When I see that news headline...
There are such headlines...
'Kang Ho Dong is in crisis...
real crisis...'
You are tearing up.
Because they keep saying
I'm having a crisis...
It makes me really feel down.
In your opinion, what are
you really having now?
For me, it's not a crisis... but...
it all depends how you look at it.
I had to stop and think about it.
I had to reflect on myself.
It's not the outcome,
but the process that's important.
I realized it.
And I realized I'm really
happy to be working on TV.
I learned that working as an
entertainer is my true happiness.
- This is a new chance for you.
- Not a crisis.
It's a perfect new start.
I see.
Hearing I'm in crisis makes me feel down.
The headline tomorrow will be
'Kang Ho Dong in denial about his crisis.'
That's not it.
'Kang Ho Dong still in a day dream.'
'Kang Ho Dong doesn't even
know he's in crisis.'
Now, Si Yoon!
What words would make him feel good?
'You are a good actor.'
That's nice, but incorrect.
Eunhyuk!
'You saved the show, Kim Tak Gu.'
Wow... that's...
Incorrect!
I think Si Yoon was nervous
about being on a variety show.
Eunhyuk!
'You are funny.'
Close...
Jong Shin! 'You have good sense.'
Correct!
How did that feel?
That really touched my heart.
- Has anyone said that to you?
- Not yet.
I said it because I thought
I would never say that again.
- But really...
- This was my first and last time saying it.
Ho Dong is the god of variety shows.
What do you think of him?
In my opinion, Si Yoon is...
the most proactive and hard working
celebrity I have seen on a variety show.
How are his prospects?
He will get better.
I hope he will get better.
I wish he could get better...
He needs to get better.
Okay, next!
What makes him feel down?
Jong Shin!
Am I getting it too fast?
'He's done nothing after Kim Tak Gu.'
Incorrect.
It's similar.
Se Yoon!
'You are already in crisis.'
Don't say that to anyone!
- UEE!
- Time out!
Is crisis a popular word these days?
- Crisis...
- Crisis Kang.
I think celebrities don't
like hearing this.
And their families don't like it either.
Se Yoon!
'What are you doing these days?'
Correct!
I was doing something.
You were doing something.
After Kim Tak Gu, I did two
more dramas and a movie...
and even a variety show now.
But people still call you Kim Tak Gu.
People still remember him as Kim Tak Gu.
The show was a big hit.
- I feel bad to my family...
- Even though you might be okay.
Sometimes people worry about you
for no reason.
- I heard that even while I was on it.
- As if it was a fleeting popularity...
My family and I worked hard to get there,
but people say it wouldn't last...
Like 'It won't last long.'
This is...
That is something we should
embrace as part of our work.
You will hear that a lot.
But I'm happier now.
All the praise I received
because of Kim Tak Gu...
made me happy, but also
I felt I was in debt.
I was like that before.
I was not self-congratulatory.
Even when I won a grand award,
I didn't know how to enjoy it.
I felt I was still lacking.
But then I realized...
There's something that only I can do.
Something that other singers can't do.
From the moment I started praising myself,
I became more confident and better.
You succeeded because you did a good job.
Judging from what I've seen so far,
Si Yoon is very pure.
He's pure. He's innocent.
Next is Eunhyuk.
What words would make Eunhyuk feel good?
He must hear lots of praises!
'Super Junior is nothing without Eunhyuk!'
You're right.
'You are better than Gyu Hyun.'
That makes me feel bad.
Just don't compare.
You are a gummy handsome man.
He's a gummy man!
He's handsome.
That's my complex,
so I don't bring it up myself.
You shouldn't feel that way.
Just smile big.
Se Yoon!
'I thought you were like a sardine...'
'but actually you are not!'
What's that?
Se Yoon!
'It can't be!'
What are you talking about?
'It can't be that you are a sardine!'
Not a sardine!
I will give you a hint.
It starts with 'you'.
Hyun Joong! 'You are my love.'
It feels weird hearing that from a man.
'You are mine.'
Correct!
Eunhyuk, what's that about?
- I like being straightforward.
- 'You are mine!'
You like proactive girls!
I like when they are
straightforward in a cute way.
UEE should show us what it's like.
You are mine from now on.
I want to make you mine!
UEE was great.
That makes me feel good.
Your face is red.
I feel warm.
Such words make you feel flattered.
What makes him feel down?
- Be straightforward!
- Se Yoon!
'Gyu Hyun is better than you.'
UEE!
'You only dance when performing.'
Can't hear his voice!
That actually make me feel good.
I love dancing.
Hyun Joong! 'You are stingy.'
I got it!
'You are narrow-minded.'
Jong Shin! 'You look poor.'
Jong Shin!
'You are stale.'
Correct!
- Did you really hear that?
- You don't get that!
That's what musicians
hate hearing the most.
That's the worst.
- 'He lost it.'
- 'He's stale.'
UEE has a song with that title.
That would be the worst for
musicians to hear these days.
When did you hear that?
- I heard that expression about my looks.
- Really?
Since the other members on Super
Junior are all handsome...
People compare me to them a lot...
- 'Not fresh' is the worst.
- Like 'crisis'.
He hasn't overcome that yet.
Next is Jong Shin.
What makes him feel good
when he hears it?
UEE!
'You have a good wife!'
Nope!
'You don't look like a dad
with three daughters.'
Nice!
'You look young.'
Since I'm a man too...
- Have you ever heard that?
- I hear that a lot.
Incorrect! Si Yoon!
You are a true artist.
That's nonsense.
A true artist.
Eunhyuk!
'You last long.'
- What's that look?
- 'You last long?'
It's close. It's not just lasting.
'Last long and strong?'
- Long and strong?
- I've never heard that expression.
Last long and strong!
It's a hint.
What's opposite to thick and short?
Se Yoon!
'You will last thin and long.'
Correct!
That's what it was!
- Were you giving me a hint?
- But you didn't get it!
Does that make you feel good?
I like hearing that.
Because it can break easily
if it's too thick and straight.
I like the philosophy of being
soft and flexible.
I try to live that way.
What words make Jong Shin feel down?
It was too easy.
Don't have more to say? Say more!
Se Yoon!
You...
'Your music is...'
'outdated!'
Incorrect!
UEE! 'You are annoying!'
I like the sound of it.
Hyun Joong!
'You may not live long.'
How can you say that
with such a happy face?
I will live for a long time!
I think the answer you put down
is all wrong.
- Have you ever heard that?
- Yes.
- Really?
Three words after 'you.'
'You are not special.'
It's not nice to hear that from a woman.
Answer!
'You are too overactive.'
- There's a pattern here.
- Is that what I look like?
It's the perception of you.
In a large group, you tend to be this...
'Where were you?'
That's really close!
Eunhyuk!
'You were here?'
Correct!
That's not true!
You have an obvious presence.
I know you're here just
by hearing your voice.
In a much larger group than this...
I tend to be silent.
- That's not true.
- My friends...
can't even pinpoint my weaknesses
because I'm invisible.
There's something to learn from Jong Shin.
He may not be like a shower
on a summer day.
But he's like soft rain
that comes down all day...
Soft rain that comes down all day...
A sudden sneeze like that
would stop a conversation about me...
and it'd become about something else.
Next is Se Yoon.
Nothing can really make him
feel down or feel good.
But he's tender inside.
'You are... sophisticated.'
Incorrect!
'You are humane. You have a warm heart!'
That's similar!
Make a face to deserve such comments!
UEE!
'You are cute.'
- It's getting close.
- Close?
'You are friendly.'
Incorrect! Look at his face!
Got it! 'You are loveable.'
Correct!
That's not right, Se Yoon.
I feel good when I hear it!
'You are adorable from head to toe'.
That was unexpected!
I can respond to other praise.
- But I can't with this one.
- Who said that to you?
- Well...
- Friends?
My ex-girlfriends... and my wife...
And even... younger guys...
His lips looked like this
when he said that.
'My wife and younger guys...'
One, two... three...
[Adorable lips...]
He has a feminine side.
He's really adorable.
Then what words would make him feel down?
Jong Shin!
'You are distasteful.'
Incorrect!
'Watch your mouth.'
Se Yoon isn't that strong a character.
He doesn't make harsh comments.
'Are you a pervert?'
Yes, I am.
Incorrect!
'You are arrogant.'
I'm used to that.
He is a true professional.
Professional?
'You weren't funny this time.'
That was close.
- It's close?
- Close but far away.
It's really close.
'That wasn't good this time.'
Nope!
Actually, for variety show
amateurs like Si Yoon...
this would be a compliment.
But to pros like Ho Dong or Se Yoon
this would be an insult.
Se Yoon, this time you were...
'This time you were funny.'
Hyun Joong!
Correct!
'You were funny this time.'
When I hang out with my friends...
I would make a joke without
thinking too much.
And someone would say,
'You were funny this time.'
Like you weren't funny before?
That makes me think,
'Were you judging my jokes?'
I may be just chatting...
but people criticize my jokes
wherever I am.
He's sensitive.
He's really delicate.
You are pretty charming, Se Yoon.
And?
Adorable.
I don't know.
He sticks his tongue out.
Our female star, UEE!
What makes her feel good?
- Answer!
- Si Yoon!
'You are really a woman.'
Incorrect.
Jong Shin! 'UEE has the best body.'
- Why do you look at me?
- Is it not true?
Oh, well...
'Your legs are pretty.'
- Incorrect!
- Jong Shin!
'You are sexy.'
Incorrect.
- You are really pretty.
- Incorrect.
You look really pretty saying that.
You are pathetic.
I don't get to see handsome men these days.
I don't get to see them.
Don't think. Just say it.
'UEE, you are the most popular!'
It's very close.
'You are the best!'
Correct!
Do you really like that better
than you are pretty or sexy?
You should say it like,
'You are really the best!'
That's not it. They meant
you're the best athlete.
As an athlete...
Best athlete!
Just go do comedy with Gal Gal.
In everyone's eyes...
- It's obvious.
- So?
UEE, you are the best!
As an athlete!
As an athlete...
And there are words that
make even UEE feel down.
I've heard this so many times.
Got it!
'You are arrogant.'
He said it to UEE, but I feel the pain!
Hyun Joong!
'You don't look pretty in person.'
Incorrect!
Answer!
'You have broad shoulders.'
'UEE got the best shoulders!'
Incorrect!
Well...
Male idol stars may have said that to you.
'You must have lots of men!'
Incorrect.
Answer!
'You are not sexy.'
That really hurts my feeling.
Got it. 'You are a fox!'
He's shaking...
Jong Shin!
What is it now?
'Are you showing off?'
That must be close.
- Close but not exactly.
- Very close, Jong Shin.
Answer!
UEE is going to give you a hint.
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, just go away.
Get lost!
Got it!
- I will show you!
- Stop that.
'Don't overdo it!'
Correct!
But UEE doesn't do that.
That really hurts me when
I'm just doing my best.
I got the answer because...
I see pretty girls hearing that a lot
no matter what they do.
That's true. They are jealous.
Yes, it's jealousy.
People can't stand it.
I'm just trying to do my best.
But when people say that,
I feel discouraged.
When I hear that,
I don't feel discouraged.
[It's raining. Time to go to sleep!]
[Ho Dong, who has no money for lodging]
[sleeps here.]
This is a crisis. This is not right.
No, no.
- Sleep here, Ho Dong.
- Where?
How about on the floor here?
- You want me to sleep inside?
- Come on in.
Ho Dong, why don't you come
in over here at least?
[Should I?]
Come on in, it's raining!
[Hyo Ri suddenly appears.]
[Ho Dong lies down at the sight of Hyo Ri.]
[I'm scared of Hyo Ri.]
Ho Dong!
- Should I sleep next to you?
- No.
You scared me.
My stomach hurts again!
- No, no!
- Like this...
- Like this.
- Oh, no.
I can't breathe.
- Don't come near me.
- Are you going to be okay?
- I'm good.
- Come on in.
- This is good.
- The hard floor is about the same.
- Just come in.
- Ho Dong!
- What?
[Did you mean I should come here?]
- That spot is good.
- That looks good.
- That spot is nice.
- He looks sexy.
- Can you get out?
- No...
You are good at following the rules.
- Of course, I should.
- Come on.
Wow, he's sexy.
You're sexy, Ho Dong.
Tell UEE not to overdo it.
- Ho Dong?
- What?
Don't be prideful.
Come in if you want to.
If I want to?
Say that again?
You can come right up to here.
It's pouring too hard...
- Isn't it?
- Yes.
Should I keep watch here for you guys?
- Do something cute. I'll let you in.
- I can't do that.
- Try.
- Just let me in.
- Do something cute!
- I can't!
- Sleep there then.
- Don't do that.
Just sleep there then.
I'm closing the door.
Please!
Come on in!
Thank you!
[Luckily he can sleep on the hard floor.]
Hyo Ri, UEE! Good night!
Good night!
Good night! Have a good sleep!
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine!
- Good night, Jong Shin!
- Good night to you too!
[The first day to get to
know more about each other.]
[Everyone, good night!]
[The last day of the retreat.]
[Did they really become close?]
[I'm sexy.]
Did you really sleep here?
Yes, I did.
Ho Dong really slept there.
[Homeless Jong Shin?]
Come out and look at misty Mount Jiri.
Look at that, Hyo Ri.
Isn't that like a painting?
That's amazing.
Hyo Ri, when we go to the Surak Waterfall
since it's famous,
can I lead the group there?
Why don't you guys go then?
Aren't you going?
I'm good. No thanks.
Is something wrong?
Yes.
Let's go see it.
[Thanks, Hyo Ri.]
Gosh...
Jong Shin, with our cute Hyo Ri...
I know the way to the waterfall.
- After we all get dressed...
- Can we walk up there?
It takes about one hour and thirty minutes.
- Really?
- To get to the waterfall?
- It's a slope of 75 degrees.
- Don't lie!
Takes about 15 minutes.
Ho Dong, today is the last day.
- Today is the last day here.
- Yes.
- Aren't you sad?
- Time flies!
I know...
I will remember how I got kicked
in my ribs this morning.
Should I kick you one more time?
Kick you one last time before we leave?
Or I can teach UEE how to do it.
Yes, please.
She can do better with her long leg.
Look at that waterfall!
Are we really going in there?
[Mount Jiri's Surak Waterfall.]
[After the rain,
the water stream is even stronger.]
Let's go. But I already feel cold.
I took a picture here when I was little.
Look at that!
That looks fierce!
Scary!
It feels cool!
Look at the waterfall!
It's cold!
[Currently it's 15 degrees Celsius.]
The eight of us... and a guest!
A total of nine friends!
To deepen our friendship!
Let's go to the waterfall to pay our respect!
Pay respect like this?
Show us the true spirit of
Barefoot Friends first!
Should I show you the
spirit of Barefoot Friends?
- Our spirit?
- Yes!
- Your microphone...
- It's cold!
Ho Dong should show to us as the leader!
This is proper etiquette.
We never cut corners on a show.
We won't take a backseat.
We won't be cowardly.
Let's be all good friends!
[Bring it on, waterfall!]
[Ho Dong...]
[Welcome to Mount Jiri.]
[That looks strong...]
- Fighting!
- Hyun Joong, want to go first?
Want to go first?
Should I go first then?
- You are sexy, Ho Dong!
- You are sexy!
You're going to go?
Ho Dong, fighting!
Warm-up exercise is important.
You are sexy!
Are you really getting in there?
That looks really strong.
[Does anyone want to go first?]
He must be nervous.
Okay!
It won't be good if he falls down.
Ho Dong! You should go in there!
He must be scared.
Ho Dong!
He's going in!
I don't think he will go in.
- That's not a public bath!
- He's worried about his body.
You should do that before
you go in the water.
Fighting!
[I asked to come here!]
[They are all watching me.]
[Let's look cool for Hyo Ri.]
[I'm the tiger of variety shows!]
Not over yet!
Keep going!
- Don't stop!
- You are sexy!
You are sexy!
[Sexy tiger!]
Dive in!
Barefoot Friends! Let's go together!
You are cool!
Wow, that was...
Diving is the best.
The moment I dove in,
I felt new energy in me.
I found amazing new energy!
The energy of Mount Jiri!
Feel it!
Who's next?
Hyun Joong!
You will feel good!
What are you thinking?
Let's not catch a cold!
Fighting!
Microphone...
[The microphone is more
important than Hyun Joong.]
He's scared.
Don't you worry about me?
- I thought you were cheering for him!
- They said, 'Microphone!'
Save the microphone!
I thought they were cheering for me.
I think you should take off your hat.
Hyun Joong's t-shirt is all wet. How sexy!
He's sexy!
[Nice to see a handsome man!]
[The prince of Hallyu's wet t-shirt.]
Take a deep breath before you dive!
Barefoot Friends, fighting!
[I'm the prince of Hallyu.]
[Ouch!]
Think about your image!
That's not good!
That's not how it's supposed to be.
[Find out why they all
jumped in the water.]
Doesn't it feel nice?
It's not as cold as you'd think.
It's not cold at all.
Next! Next!
- Should I go?
- Bum Soo!
- Let's go!
- Go, Bum Soo!
35 years old, Bum Soo!
Barefoot Friends, fighting!
I think I can do it all over again.
- I feel so refreshed!
- Got energy?
I got the energy of Mount Jiri in me!
- Hyun Joong!
- Yes?
It's not cold, right?
- Was it cold?
- Bum Soo's going!
It wasn't cold at all.
Bum Soo went!
Fighting!
You should just jump in.
I will just dive in.
- Kim Bum Soo!
- Be careful!
You are handsome!
Nice!
[He's reborn as a variety show master.]
That's something to remember!
You look great!
[His stomach hit the bottom!]
That must have hurt.
My stomach hurts!
Bum Soo's pose was the most
memorable scene on a variety show.
- Like a monkey living in a waterfall.
- Bum Soo!
Look at his face.
I can't reach the bottom!
[Short legs...]
You are alive! Alive!
Who's next?
Barefoot Friends, fighting!
So cold!
Bum Soo had his cell phone in his pocket.
Bum Soo took his cell phone in the water.
Bum Soo's cell phone is all wet.
Go, Se Yoon!
[A monkey with a dog nose
showering in the waterfall.]
That was great.
He's a true entertainer.
He's cool.
Did it turn out good?
You were adorable.
Si Yoon, come over here!
What's your thoughts?
There's an Egyptian story...
You'll be asked two things
when you go to heaven.
Did you find joy in your life?
And did you give that joy to others?
I will give you that joy!
Be careful!
I think it's better to be barefoot.
Fighting!
Si Yoon, fighting!
[I found joy in Barefoot Friends.]
[Now it's my turn to give you that joy.]
[Let me give you joy and laughter!]
He's not good at jumping.
It's deep.
Next is Eunhyuk!
I made lots of good memories
on Barefoot Friends.
I hope you will make good memories too!
Fighting!
- It's cold.
- This is just beginning.
There he goes!
Eunhyuk, fighting!
In order to become a true sardine!
No, it can't be.
He cannot be a sardine!
Fighting!
[It's cold!]
Popping! Popping!
That's great!
[So cold...]
Sardine!
Let's go get him out!
Go, Eunhyuk!
Barefoot Friends, fighting!
- Should I go now?
- You might get sick.
Barefoot Friends will be a whole new show,
the moment I dive in the water.
Barefoot Friends, fighting!
Jong Shin, that's not it!
He can't even get there.
Oh, that old man...
Slowly...
Scary!
Hurry up and go in!
Fighting!
Poor old man...
I'm worried about him.
Is he dancing?
Fighting! Fighting!
Look at his face...
Just get it over with!
You did it!
Just come over here.
Don't do that.
- You can just come.
- You don't need to do that.
He just slipped in there.
- I'm going.
- She's good with water.
Wow, UEE!
[Former swimmer from the In Cheon
Athletic High School.]
My cell phone! Give me my cell phone!
Give me my cell phone!
My goodness!
Tell me what's on your mind.
[The paparazzi is ready.]
On next episodes...
I will be UEE who exceeds Hyo Ri!
Fighting!
Wave! Wave!
[Busy paparazzi...]
[Coming Soon]
What are you doing right now?
Gather the strength of the nation!
[Everyone becomes superheroes!]
[But!]
Hurry up and come here!
[Running Man Avengers!]
You are awesome!
[I got a scoop!]
Mount Jiri and UEE met today!
Show us a swimmer's dive!
[The little mermaid]
Awesome!
Show us more!
[A fish in the water.]
She looks amazing!
Now...
we got the spirit of Mount Jiri in us.
From now on, the friendship we
have on Barefoot Friends...
We will deliver that to
our viewers every week.
Let's keep that promise.
Hand in hand!
Barefoot Friends!
[Why did they dive in the water anyway?]
[The second project in the nation!]
[Barefoot Friends' diving challenge!]
[Just jump right in!]
[Overcome the fear of heights!]
[With your challenging spirit!]
[Dive beyond your limit!]