Because you know I'm all about that bass
Bout that bass, no treble
I'm all 'bout that bass
'Bout that bass, no treble
I'm all 'bout that bass, 'bout that bass
Yeah it's pretty clear, I ain't no size two
But I can shake it, shake it
Like I'm supposed to do
'Cause I got that boom boom
That all the boys chase
All the right junk in all the right places
I see the magazines
Working that Photoshop
We know that shit ain't real
Come on now, make it stop
If you got beauty beauty just raise 'em up
'Cause every inch of you is perfect
From the bottom to the top
Yeah, my momma she told me
Don't worry about your size
She says, boys they like a little
More booty to hold at night
You know I won't be no stick-figure
Silicone Barbie doll
So, if that's what's you're into
Then go ahead and move along
Because you know I'm all about that bass
'Bout that bass, no treble
I'm all 'bout that bass
I'm all 'bout that bass, 'bout that bass
I'm bringing booty back
Go ahead and tell them
Skinny bitches, Hey~
No, I'm just playing
I know you think you're fat
But I'm here to tell you that
Every inch of you is perfect
From the bottom to the top
Yeah, my momma she told me
Don't worry about your size
She says, boys they like a little
More booty to hold at night
You know I won't be no stick-figure
Silicone Barbie doll
So, if that's what's you're into
Then go ahead and move along
Because you know I'm all about that bass
'Bout that bass, no treble
I'm all 'bout that bass
I'm all 'bout that bass, 'bout that bass
Because you know I'm all about that bass
(I'm all 'bout that bass, 'bout that bass)
'Bout that bass, no treble
I'm all 'bout that bass
I'm all 'bout that bass, 'bout that bass
Because you know I'm all about that bass
'Bout that bass, no treble
I'm all 'bout that bass
I'm all 'bout that bass, 'bout that bass
**Meghan Trainor**
"All About That Bass"
Subtitle Created by
Jaryd's Music VideOke