[Episode 15]
Do you like it?
But... it looks expensive.
It was expensive.
I was surprised.
About our wedding...
Would you like to have it...
...when you get better
after the surgery?
I don't mind to skipping the wedding.
You should.
A wedding is also a way
to say thank you...
to your parents for raising you well.
Somewhere nice...
...with all our parents,
friends and relatives...
...I want to make you the prettiest
and happiest bride ever.
So if you want a fabulous wedding,
you should get better soon.
But then...
...our parents would have
to change their minds about us.
Take this as well.
She might get out of breath,
feel dizzy, collapse...
or in the worst case,
loose consciousness.
You should never be flustered.
It's important to keep her stable.
Is there any sort of program...
which I can learn
about her condition?
There's a seminar
about organ transplant patients.
I'll find out more and let
you know tomorrow.
Okay.
If you continue to stay here
at the hospital...
...I'll sleep over at
your place sometimes.
Thank you.
What is he doing that's taking so long?
It hasn't been that long.
Where did you go?
Oh.
I needed to look for some information.
Why don't you go home tonight
and get some rest?
Mom.
That's not what I meant.
I think you should take care...
of your children and work.
You haven't even had a chance to rest.
I'll stay here tonight.
Go home and get some rest.
Please don't go.
Grandmother came over for dinner?
Yes.
She even promised to visit often.
Ha!
What's going on with her?
I know.
I really liked her visiting, though.
Ba Da was unfamiliar
with her at first...
but they quickly became close
on the way to the hospital.
- Give this to *Unni.
- [Unni: Older sister or older female]
Ba Da and I made it...
because we can't take real flowers
to her because of the pollen.
I'll deliver it to her safely.
How is she sick?
It isn't a stomachache, right?
Does she have to stay in the hospital
for a long time?
I think so.
Dad wants to be with her to protect her
while she is.
What?
Of course you have to.
My dad is great.
You're the greatest in the world!
I want to marry a man like you.
I'm surprised you'd give me
such a compliment.
Protect her well, dad.
Keep my friend safe, okay?
Good morning.
My Bom, Bom, Bom, Bom!
Unni.
You didn't go to work?
Mr. CEO gave me the day off...
...because he's going
to look for something.
He asked me to spend time with you.
Ah, that's right.
He kept asking me
to take good care of you.
He's so sweet.
What is this?
Who made it?
It's so cute.
Look how adorable it is.
- Unni.
- Yeah?
I have a favor to ask you.
Yes, yes.
What is it?
- Tell me.
- Can you bring me the laptop over there?
Sure, sure, sure!
Where is it?
Here.
It's so small I thought it was a book.
I'll lift up your bed.
I'll lift you up.
What?
What do you want my help with?
You see...
I found something on the internet.
This.
Really?
How is your patient's
operation prognosis?
Her condition improved, so she's
been discharged from the hospital...
...and she has regular checkups.
Before the operation,
she could barely walk...
...but now she can have a normal life.
I heard that the patient is quite old.
Yes.
Her health was in such
critical condition...
it was difficult for her to undergo
the operation.
Abroad, there was a patient...
who lasted seven years
with the same mechanical heart.
I heard it was the longest success
of all these cases.
She's okay.
Hey, daughter.
I told you that your condition
hasn't worsened.
That means you're getting better.
Okay?
Bom, Bom, Bom, Bom Yi!
Hey!
Do you know how much work
I've done for you today?
I reserved...
an awesome place just for you...
What's wrong with you?
Hey.
You're back in the office
right after surgery.
Yes, I needed to review some materials.
How's Bom Yi?
She's just hanging in there.
I need to figure out something quickly.
- *Hyung keeps hurrying me.
- [Hyung: Older brother or older male]
Eat this first, then work.
What are you doing?
What?
Have a seat so we can share it.
You know that I hate eating alone.
Is this a joke or a favor?
It's a favor.
Then ask me politely.
Would you like to have a seat?
Let's enjoy it together.
The reminds me of old times.
Want me to spoon-feed you
like old times then?
I need to tell you something.
Huh?
Let's do it later.
A little later.
This is your favorite.
Open your mouth.
Don't do this.
Please?
Ah!
Oh...
I'll be back later.
Please come in.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
What is all that?
They're research and materials...
There's so much I can't understand
that I wanted to review it with you.
This is the critical moment.
Hey.
Why are you here?
What?
I don't have much to do after work...
so I'm on standby for you 24/7.
Have you gotten any sleep?
You look so tired...
...you look more lousy than before.
Hurry and go in.
Is Bom Yi in bad mood?
No.
She's just been waiting for you
for a while.
Is that right?
Bom Yi.
Don't do this now.
I want to give you a proper wedding.
When?
When you get better.
Then I'll just be a patient to you...
until then, Dong Ha.
I want to be your wife, not a patient...
...even if I only live
for another minute.
I'm sorry.
I know that you want to make me...
the happiest and
prettiest bride ever...
...but I'm so happy now...
...please forgive me even
if I'm not pretty.
You are pretty.
Even if...
I become your wife now...
...I won't be able
to do anything for you.
I can't make a delicious
meal for you...
find your missing socks...
...and I can't do anything...
for your children.
Only thing I can do now is...
...tell you how I feel about you.
I'm sorry.
I, Lee Bom Yi, take you, Kang Dong Ha...
the sweetest and nicest
man in the world...
to be my husband.
I promise to be true to you
in good times and in bad...
in sickness...
and in health.
Even though I can't
live for a long time...
whether...
...I live a day or eternity...
I'll love you and honor you...
all the days of my life.
It's your turn, my groom.
I promise too.
Then...
...you may kiss the bride.
How do you feel now?
Today must have been tiring.
But I was very happy.
I'm sorry.
Are you sorry for marrying me?
Do you want to cancel it?
I can't do that.
I hope that I get better soon.
I don't mind having a simple wedding...
but I'm looking forward
to the honeymoon.
Let's go then.
Is there somewhere you want to go?
The windy hills...
...of Udo Island.
What?
No way.
Never.
What are you talking about?
I think it'd be good
for her to visit there.
She's very depressed...
...because of the results
from her last checkup.
Still, it's too dangerous.
It is dangerous.
It could make things worse.
You heard him, right?
But I think I can find a way.
What kind of a way?
Don't talk so carelessly.
She's not your daughter.
What way?
I know a lot about the hospital
on the island.
One of my friends
is a thoracic surgeon there.
Fine, but...
she can't take a
flight in her condition.
It's on an island,
so there'd be a ferry ride.
She can't do that either.
What about a helicopter?
Here.
Hello!
Hold on.
What are you doing?
Don't move.
It makes it harder.
I didn't even have breakfast.
I'm embarrassed.
God.
My back hurts.
Hey, did you clean up the house?
Yes, I did.
Did you do it well?
Or did you just go around
and sweep the dirt under the rugs?
I said I did a good job.
I'll check under the rugs later.
Hello?
Did you clean up the house?
I did.
I told you I did!
Groceries!
Ask him if he did the grocery shopping.
That's right.
Did you get groceries too?
Did you buy everything we told you?
Yes.
Oh!
That's right.
The edges...
Did you cover the edges
of all the furniture?
Also, you need to boil...
the spoons, chopsticks
and dishcloths.
- Blankets!
- Of, the blankets!
The blankets and bedding...
You need to wash those too.
Yes.
Don't be mad at me.
We should have followed them.
It's their honeymoon.
We shouldn't have followed them.
That's right.
It's their honeymoon.
Do you want to have a wedding
and go on a honeymoon too?
They must be crazy.
They always talk to each other
when they call me.
What?
Huh?
Their honeymoon suite?
Don't worry about it.
I decorated the room...
..for a really sexy, hot mood.
Okay.
Oh, I'd like to call my parents.
That's right.
It's mine.
Hello?
Yes.
Did you get there safely?
Is Bom Yi okay?
Let me talk to her.
Wait a moment.
My wife wants to talk to Bom Yi.
Hello?
Bom Yi?
Was she on the phone?
Hello?
Mom.
Are you alright?
Yes, mom.
There's a doctor here too...
so don't worry, okay?
Okay.
Give me the phone.
Give me your hand.
I want to call your mother too.
Huh?
I can't just call my parents.
It's okay.
She doesn't even know we're married.
We didn't have a
proper wedding either.
She'll be mad at me.
I'll tell her about our wedding
when I get back...
...but I still want to call her now.
Hello?
Hi, Miss Lee Bom Yi.
Yes, it's me... mother.
How are you?
I'm fine.
I'm sorry to worry you.
Don't be sorry.
Mr. CEO is staying with me...
but it's making you
uncomfortable, isn't it?
He's doing it because he likes it.
Don't be sorry to me.
Use him as much as you need.
I have to tell you something...
...so I'll visit you soon.
No.
You're sick.
You shouldn't come out.
Once you get better, call me...
and I'll come visit you.
Yes, I will.
Being sick is just bad luck.
Don't trouble your mind
with your sickness.
Your body will heal itself naturally
if your mind is healthy.
So just eat good food...
and have good thoughts.
Okay?
Yes, thank you.
Yes, I'll call you later.
What did she tell you?
She told me to use you
as much as I need.
Of course.
There's no one on my side
in my whole family.
How do you feel?
If you're up to it,
why don't we tour the island now?
You told me that it takes
about five hours...
...to walk around the island.
I didn't say we'd walk.
[Udo Lover]
If...
...my heart...
...sent me here...
...I'd be much more
thankful than before.
I don't love you
because of my heart...
...but I do love you more because of it.
Can you see the windy hills over there?
I can see them...
...but they look even higher
than Halla Mountain to me.
Don't you think so?
Let's rest for today...
and go there tomorrow
if you're up to it.
I heard about Bom Yi.
You must be very worried about her.
Hyuk Soo.
You surprised me.
I didn't expect you to give up
the title of director so easily.
It isn't a big deal to me.
He isn't smart either.
He refused a good offer to stay here.
As my contract stipulates....
please begin work on reopening
the Organ Transplant Center quickly.
Hmm.
What?
Is there a problem with that?
No, I just think...
it will be difficult to reopen
the center after all.
What are you talking about?
We agreed on it when we renewed
Dr. Kang's contract.
What are you talking about?
Not one of you reviewed
the contract thoroughly?
It's your contract.
I inserted the clause regarding
the Organ Transplant Center.
Look.
- There's no clause.
- No way.
Where is Miss Bae now?
I'll find her.
Mr. Chairman Song, what are you doing?
He signed a contract without a clause
about the Organ Transplant Center.
Our counterparty has refused
this condition from the start.
So you've deceived us from the start?
Myeong Hee.
I'm a businessman.
I'm not a philanthropist.
We're friends...
...but I can't continue to invest
in this sinking hospital.
How many times did I tell you
not to believe him?
It's your fault, man.
What?
If you hadn't needed disciplining...
...the hospital wouldn't be
in this situation.
Fine.
[Hae Gil Hospital]
Ji Won.
Yes.
Did you have me sign a contract...
...without inserting the clause
about the Organ Transplant Center?
Did you deceive me?
No.
This is the contract you signed.
The contract Chairman
Song has is a fake.
I forged your signature on it...
so don't act too shocked.
If Chairman Song pulls out
of the hospital...
there will be financial
issues, but...
Why did you do it?
[Letter of resignation]
This is my letter of resignation.
Can you deliver it to Ms. Chairman?
I asked you why you did it, Ji Won.
When Chairman Song finds out
what you did...
and you're caught forging documents,
you could be in trouble too.
That didn't matter to me...
as long as I could help you.
I wished...
you would leave this hospital
with Chairman Song.
If you had...
my feelings for you...
would never have
been revealed to you.
Here's brown rice...
...and less salty soup.
They're all healthy dishes.
Now...
...is that everything?
Thank you.
I really like it when someone
fixes me a meal.
I know that.
Let's eat.
Did you wash your hands before cooking?
Yes, of course.
I even used a spoon to taste the soup...
and I didn't put it back
in the soup pot either.
Trust me.
The farmers, the fishermen,
sunshine and...
- What else?
- The rain.
Yes, the rain.
Thank you for the meal.
Mmm...
It tastes good.
I didn't think I'd really
be able to come here.
By the way, whose helicopter was that?
Was it Hyeong Woo's?
It's mine.
Ah, yes.
Good for you.
It was your first time, right?
Weren't you scared?
It wasn't my first time.
I don't remember it well...
but I rode in one...
to get to the hospital on Jeju Island
for my operation.
Speaking of...
...didn't you say that your father
cut in line to get your heart?
Yes, I believe so.
My memory's a little fuzzy...
about what I heard back then.
I'm not sure...
...but I think that he lied
about how critical my condition was.
He was disciplined for it...
and suspended as a surgeon.
It ruined the hospital's reputation...
so the hospital's been in trouble.
That's why your father is...
So free.
I think that he thought it would only
cause problems temporarily.
Hmm.
What should we do now?
Do you want to watch TV?
I'd like to get some rest.
Would you?
I need to get enough rest
to go to the windy hills tomorrow.
Yes, of course.
Wait a minute.
What was my friend
saying about the room?
Wow...
If you're sleeping beside me...
...I wouldn't be scared
even if I hear the wind.
Would you like me to
bring you some water?
Yes.
Bom Yi!
Hey.
Head up...
It's okay.
Bom Yi.
Come on, I'm here.
Don't be scared.
Slowly...
Breathe slowly.
That's right.
How are you?
You're okay, right?
You have such a nice husband.
He took very good care of you.
You should go back to Seoul
in the morning.
You can't take care
of her properly here.
What I did is only
a temporary expedient, so...
What about the windy hills?
No way.
Don't even think about it.
Okay?
Thank you.
I'm sorry...
for surprising you.
I wasn't surprised at all.
I don't think that we can go.
Right?
Can I get some fresh air?
It's stuffy in here.
Thank you for bringing me here.
If you want anything...
...tell me anytime.
I'm sorry.
Why do you keep apologizing?
I'm so happy right now.
Maybe...
we weren't allowed
to love each other...
...which is why we pushed
each other away...
and we tried to leave each other.
But now we're here...
as a married couple.
At first we sat here...
and talked about old stories.
Then we sat here...
and talked about the future...
so for now...
let's just talk about the present.
What if...
...by some chance...
...I don't wake up tomorrow?
That won't happen.
I didn't say it to hurt you...
and it's not because I'm
getting weak either.
I'm just worried that...
...I may not have a chance
to say goodbye to you.
Would you like to say goodbye
to me in advance?
Do it now.
I'll remember it.
Don't...
...come here again.
I won't...
become a star...
so don't come here...
to watch the night sky.
Don't come here and drink alone...
...cry alone...
...or sleep alone.
I don't want you to suffer alone...
...in a dream where I'm not there.
It makes you too attractive.
I'm worried you'll find
another woman that way.
Then don't leave.
Stay here with me like this...
...forever.
If there's a chance...
that I'll be reborn...
...I'll make sure I'm healthy
in the next life.
Then I'll love you much more...
and much longer than
I did in this life.
Then I'll be the one to protect you.
Now...
...the soup is ready and...
Here.
Are you ready to go to the windy hill?
I'm not really confident
I can do this.
It's not as high as you think.
You keep thinking you're sick,
so it looks father than it is.
That's why you're scared of it.
You just need to take one step forward
every ten minutes.
We have plenty of time.
I don't think that I can do it.
I don't think...
that I can do it.
I'll help you.
I'll help you...
...so don't give up.
- What are you doing over there?
- Oh my God!
You're not planning on falling
and drowning, right?
No, I'm not.
Why would I want to die?
I can't die young.
I have to live a long, healthy life...
- ...and live each day to the fullest.
- What is she talking about?
Soo Jeong!
Open your eyes, honey!
- Soo Jeong!
- Hey, wake up!
She isn't your wife.
I...
...prayed every day...
...for...
...someone else to die instead of me.
Then...
...it actually happened.
Are you alright?
That's right.
Soo Jeong's heart...
...is Bom Yi's now.
I thought...
...I liked her...
...because of your heart...
...but now...
...I don't think
that's true anymore.
I'm sorry that it isn't true.
I'm sorry, Poo Reum.
I'm sorry, Ba Da.
I'm sorry.
This heart...
...isn't hers anymore.
It's yours now, Bom Yi.
After I told you to leave me...
...I was so afraid...
...that you'd already left me.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Don't come here again.
I won't become a star...
so don't come here...
to watch the night sky.
Don't come here and drink alone...
...cry alone...
...or sleep alone.
I don't want you to suffer alone...
...in a dream where I'm not there.
Then don't leave.
Stay here with me like this...
...forever.
If there's a chance...
that I'll be reborn...
...I'll make sure I'm healthy
in the next life.
Then I'll love you much more...
and much longer than
I did in this life.
Then I'll be the one to protect you.
Are you okay?
Bom Yi.
Look.
You can do it.
You're almost there.
Just a few more steps.
Bom Yi.
Bom Yi!
Look at me.
Don't look anywhere else.
Bom Yi.
Now...
come to me.
Come on.
You can do it.
Good.
A little more.
You can do it.
You're almost there.
Good.
A little more.
Well done.
Good.
You did a good job.
Good job.
See?
You can do it.
Thank you.
Hey!
Look here.
Now...
One, two, three!