Faramarz Qaribian
Taraneh Alidousti
Babak Ansari, Ahoo Kheradmand
"THE BEAUTIFUL CITY"
Farhad Qa'emian, Houshang Hihavand
Editing:
Shahrzad Pouya
Script & Director
Asghar Farhadi
Who?
A'la?
- Just hurry up, Mr. Arab.
- What's wrong?
A'la cut his vein, search me.
It's okay, go.
A'la!
Hey, A'la!
Get up, what is it A'la?
A'la!
I'm talking to you.
What?
Here's to the honor of Akbar.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday to you.
Come and blow out the candles.
One two three.
Careful not to waste any of the cake.
Get back, pal.
Get away.
The cake got ruined.
Eat it with bread to get full.
Bread.
Akbar!
Hold on, what happened Akbar?
What's with you Akbar?
Hold on Akbar.
What's with you?
Go to the office.
Get out.
Come here.
What?
Nothing, sir.
Solitary.
Why are you hitting me?
Just so you invite me the next time
you throw a party.
I just wanted him to have some fun
before he's sent to the adult section.
So you're the one to give fun
to all those who are having fun.
Let it go.
- Two days in solitary.
- I won't go.
You won't? I'll beat you up.
- Piece of shit.
- Knock it off.
- Shut up.
- Be nice.
- Throw him in solitary.
- Okay.
- Throw him there.
- I will, you go.
Come.
You asked for it.
I'll beat the living shit out of him
the minute I step out of here.
- No, you won't.
- He is not logical.
You don't seem to
understand what you did today.
What did I do?
I had a festivity, is that a crime?
Who are you to remind that poor soul
it's his eighteenth birthday today?
- He's my friend.
- Is that how you show friendship?
I just wanted to make him happy.
- So why didn't he get happy?
- I don't know.
But I know.
He's eighteen years old fix today.
Meaning it's time for his execution.
Got it now?
Take him.
Jump up.
Don't you panic.
I have a feeling the guy
will finally give his consent.
Just be careful.
Adults' section is different than here.
You won't get close to anyone there.
And you'll leave everyone alone.
Just be yourself, got that?
Okay.
And if you're released and come
back here empty-handed. . .
I'll throw your ass in solitary for a week.
You're leaving early today.
I'm going to see the boy's complainant.
Aren't you tired yet?
It's the last time.
There might be hope yet.
You're only disrespecting yourself.
That fellow won't give an inch.
It won't hurt to go though.
Remember what I told you two years ago?
I said if we meet that
fellow ten years later. . .
If we beg him, and preach him. . .
He'll still want capital punishment.
Now you believe me?
I would have let go if it were
anyone else besides Akbar.
But that kid doesn't deserve to be executed.
Two and two is four.
You'll have to be executed
if you kill someone.
This is called justice
and the rest is bullshit.
Bring something on the way back.
A'la has cut himself and
is dying, Mr. Ghafourian.
Where is he now?
In the toilets.
They're coming.
Hit me.
Come on do an "X".
Hold it right.
Cut me, you idiot, before he comes.
Don't worry, do it.
Go on.
Goddamn, you piece of shit.
I got here a bit early, didn't I?
How did you kill your father coward?
He's killing everyone.
Cutie.
Get out of here.
Why did you want to cut yourself?
So we take you to the hospital
and you can escape from there.
How stupid do you think we are
not to know what goes on in your heads. . .
After four years of dealing with prisoners?
I want to get out of here.
What's going on out there?
Your wife and children are waiting for you?
Or your parents?
I have things to do.
Have you found new work?
Or the same shit and stealing?
I'll run away from here.
Go on.
Do it.
I want to do it for Akbar.
To do what?
To get his consent.
No way.
I'll do it.
I've done everything I wanted
to do in this world.
Thanks a lot.
You'll go and mess things up
worse than they already are.
What are they going to
do if things get worse?
Will they execute him twice?
This isn't your responsibility.
Whose is it then? You?
How come you haven't been able
to do it then?
I would have done it if it were
possible, you idiot.
I'll do it.
I'll stick to him in twenty four hours
and get his consent.
I'm a bastard if I don't get it.
Do it when your time is up.
He'll be executed by then.
I have to go now.
It's out of my hands.
Go in the ward.
And you do things like that once more
and you'll find yourself in solitary.
Now.
How much more is left of your jail time?
Twenty eight days.
I would have been able to help you
if you had good diciplinary things.
But you're always either
fighting or hitting yourself.
My record is black anyway.
But Akbar's is full of good things.
For him.
Get your hand off.
I swear if I get out of here
and get consent. . .
I'll be back by myself. . .
And I'll spend two months instead
of twenty eight days.
In order for the first good diciplinary
report to go in your record. . .
You'll bring my that cutter right now.
Sure thing, sir.
Get lost.
You've changed.
I even did my morning prayers.
How many times?
I said how many times?
I prayed for all the days I haven't.
Did you shower before it?
Did you see these photos?
Animals.
Can I go now? Is it done?
You'll bring the rest tomorrow.
I swear there is no more, sir.
You shouldn't lie when you pray.
There are more.
- Sure sir, I'll bring them.
- That's it.
Bring his file.
Let's see if there's anything we can do.
Put a couple of good behavoir
reports in there as well.
Never mind that.
He only has about a month left
of his time anyway.
If he were going to change. . .
He would have done so
during the past couple of years.
Besides the twenty some days left
of his time is for extra punishment.
You know his fines.
A'la Pour Salehi.
Get your belongings and come to the office.
Pour Salehi to the office.
Do you see that blue window?
That's Akbar's sister's house.
You'll talk to her.
And you'll go to the old man's house together.
You'll mess things up if you go alone.
Remember not to talk shit when you go there.
And don't get into a fight.
Be nice.
Get out.
Who do you want to see?
Who do you want to talk to?
What's it to you?
I said who are you here to see
in this house? Don't be smart.
With my friend's sister.
- Akbar?
- Is she here?
- No.
- When will she be back?
There's no telling.
Tell me, I'll give her the message.
I have to tell her.
She's out.
Give me a cold drink.
Do you want some?
Don't drink it, kid.
Give it to me.
You're a bit sick, aren't you?
Get out of here.
Don't cause trouble.
Why did you bring the kid here again?
What do you want keep knocking?
Get in the house.
You're stupid to bring the kid out
here in the dust and mud.
- Yeah, I'm stupid.
- You'll eventually kill the kid.
- Are you Akbar's sister?
- Get out of here.
What do you want?
I was with Akbar, in the rehab.
- Didn't I tell you. . .
- None of your business.
Do you have to bark at anyone
passing by here?
- You're the dog.
- Get in the house.
Shut your mouth.
- Is he your husband?
- Never mind.
What's new with Akbar?
Is he alright?
Yeah.
He's just scared.
Why?
It's time for his execution.
Easy baby, let me see what I can do.
When are they going to hang him?
Not much longer.
He begged for you to go and get
the complainant's consent somehow.
He won't.
I've tried it a thousand times during
the past two years.
I cried, I begged him.
I begged him.
The last time I bent down to kiss his hand.
He punched me in the head.
I've had a headache for a month now.
I'm embarrassed to go and visit Akbar.
How can I keep lying to him?
Doesn't Akbar have anyone else but you?
Like who?
We wouldn't be in this mess
if we had anyone watching over us.
As far as me too.
It's no difference if I go or not to go.
So you don't want to do anything for him?
Like what?
How much more can I drag the baby. . .
And go and keep getting
beat up and cursed out?
Maybe he wants money.
No, he doesn't.
Besides I don't have any
even if he wants money.
Get out of here, pal.
Don't come around here anymore.
Leave her alone.
Stop there.
What did you get from that addict?
Pardon?
Sorry ma'am, do you know him?
He's a relative.
Can you bring us some water?
Give him his bag and let him go.
- Is there something wrong sir?
- No, it's nothing
- How about a drink?
- Is it cold?
Come here, it's cold.
A stranger coming in this neighborhood
means he's here to buy drugs.
Come in and wash up.
No, just give me some water.
Where is Akbar now?
I'll find out for you.
No.
Just don't tell him you saw
me if you go to visit him.
I won't go to see him until
I get the consent for him.
- You want to go and meet his complainant?
- Yeah.
Do you have his address?
I'll get it from the rehab.
We'll go together then.
When should I come?
I'm home till noon everyday
then I go to work.
Stand over that line when you come.
- I'll see you from my room.
- Okay.
Does your husband sell envelops too?
- No.
- Bye.
Who is it?
Here's the key.
- You're leaving early.
- I have things to do.
Give me an envelop.
And pain killers the rest.
You still haven't gone to see a doctor yet.
Sorry, I'm late.
It's alright.
- I'll bring this.
- Thanks.
Watch the other way.
Take this.
And this too.
Walk him a bit if he starts to cry.
Give this to me too.
Don't you want me to come in?
Let me go in this time.
- Hello.
- Is your husband home?
- No, he's out.
For God's sake.
Do you know how far I've come
here in this heat with this kid?
You're gonna be ruded out again.
Haven't you had enough?
Let him do it if it makes him feel better.
Can't blame him.
Let me come in for God's sake.
Let me see what I can do.
Why are you upset?
Why did I come here then?
To babysit?
You don't know him yet.
He'll get pissed off if it's the two of us.
But I'm a woman and alone.
He'll take it under consideration.
I'll call you if he's in a good mood.
What can I do?
He doesn't want you in.
You let me come in,
tell him I forced my way.
You come and go but I have
to bear his bad attitude for two days.
Please, I won't come anymore.
He'll give consent today hopefully
and you won't ever see me.
- His got a patient in the room.
- Please, I'll wait till she leaves.
He's not in a good mood at all today.
He went to the cemetery.
I'm so sorry, let me come in.
Just two minutes.
I'll leave soon.
- Don't tell him I let you in then.
- Okay, don't worry.
Gather this up or I'll throw it out.
There is a Qur'an on it.
Will you throw that out too?
Let me talk to you for a moment.
I have to go out.
Mr. Abolqasem!
Pick this up and then talk.
Akbar turned eighteen.
They took him to the death row.
He's not the same boy you saw
two years ago in the court.
He's gotten old, he's a corpse.
He's a bag of bones.
He's gotten tortured as much
as ten executions during the past two years.
I would have brought him personally
if he had the nerve to do it.
You'd have given consent.
There's no time left, Mr. Abolqasem.
They'll hang him if you don't give consent.
Was that all?
I don't have anyone else besides him.
All my hope is for him to come
out in five or ten years. . .
And to take care of me.
Don't waste your breath.
I won't forget my girl's death.
I swear to God Maliheh wouldn't
be happy about Akbar's death neither.
Don't use my girl's name.
Who let you in here?
Do you belong to this house?
- Hello.
- Hi.
Give me your hand.
The baby is hungry.
Tell her mother to come out and feed her.
The milk she'll give the baby now
is more like poison to him.
What do I do then?
Give him to me.
Someone help me.
Shame on you, she's a woman.
Did he hit you?
Why are you lying?
I saw him throw you out.
What are you gonna do?
He's got no right to raise
his hand on a woman.
Come on out if you dare to.
Come on out you. . .
Quiet.
Get back.
I told you to get back.
Where is my baby?
Didn't they give him to you?
He notices all the animals in the forest. . .
To have a party for him.
The deer becomes happy.
I have to take him, dear.
That's the end of our story.
But not the end of all stories.
Come.
You wanted an envelope.
You want to write a letter
to your girlfriend?
Doesn't she have a phone?
She's worthless if she doesn't have a phone.
Specially for someone who's in prison.
If I told you not to come in. . .
It's because I knew that's
how it would turn out to be.
I'm willing to do anything for Akbar.
To belittle myself.
To be cursed, and to beg.
And to lie.
But I don't want anyone to see me that way.
Stop in front of the hospital, mister.
- Fare for two.
- No, just one.
No the two.
Pay attention.
Act like I don't know what you want here.
He'll put me through hell if he finds out.
Why isn't he coming then?
He's washing up.
- Who is it?
- I think it's a patient.
Hello Haji, how are you?
Hello son, sit down.
Sorry, it's a bad time.
Would you like to do your prayers first. . .
I'll bother you later then.
I'll pray at the mosque.
Sit down.
Come closer.
What's the matter?
What is your sickness son?
Nothing.
Why are you here then?
I have a letter for you.
Where from?
Someone who told me
to make sure you get it.
Who?
You'll know when you read it.
Should I read it to you?
Go on.
In the name of God.
Hello, Mr. Abolqasem Rahmati.
Now that I'm writing this letter to you. . .
I've turned eighteen and. . .
I'll be executed in a little while.
I know hearing this. . .
Is difficult for you.
But I didn't want to kill your loved one.
I meant to kill her and me both.
I was supposed to kill myself first.
But Maliheh said that if I killed myself. . .
She's kill herself too.
You loved her a lot.
Maliheh had told me about it a few times.
But I want you to know. . .
That no one loved her as much as I did.
And she didn't love anyone more
than me after you of course.
I don't mean to ask you.
To give consent so I won't be executed.
I wanted to be executed two years ago.
But I don't deserve to be executed.
It's not all my fault.
Remember how you beat her up
once in front of me.
The pleasure you find in venges. . .
I mean in forgiveness you won't
find in taking revenge.
May God accept it.
May God accept it, Haji.
Just give me an ear while you're praying.
I understand you.
You lost a dear one, and you're angry.
And you think you'll feel
better once he's executed.
But I swear to God you won't.
I swear to Qur'an if anything changes.
You'll be the first one to feel bad
once he's executed.
Do you believe in the very God
you're praying to now?
Refer him to God.
Doesn't he deserve to die?
God knows it better than you and me
what's right and what's wrong.
He'll do such a number on him
worse than a hundred executions.
For instance, once he steps out of jail. . .
He'll get run over by a car.
It's nothing for God.
He'll take care of it.
But if you don't believe me. . .
That means you have doubts in God.
Besides there is a difference.
Your girl didn't know she was going to die.
It was over in a moment.
But my friend knows he's supposed to die.
For two years.
Until he's hanged. . .
He'll die a hundred times a night.
Now is that the same?
You be the judge of that.
Hold on, Haji.
I want to talk to you.
Even if my own brother
had committed murder. . .
I wouldn't have left everything. . .
To go and get consent for him.
But Akbar doesn't deserve execution.
So I won't give up until I get your consent.
I'll be on you night and day.
Now it's up to you.
Okay, go on for now.
Until I think it over.
Thanks a lot, Haji.
Where did she go again?
My pretty baby.
Mother's baby.
- Hi.
Abolqasem isn't in.
I don't want to come in.
Here you are.
Why do you keep spending money, girl?
No matter how much I spent
it's not enough for you.
These are nothing.
Thank God, Mr. Abolqasem's gotten a bit soft.
Says who?
He told me last night.
He went to the court this morning.
To give consent?
Didn't he say anything to you?
Execution is his final word.
Last night he'd gotten a bit soft.
He didn't curse out nor did he beat me.
He listened to everything I told him.
How dare did he go to the court?
I'm not a kid to play me!
I'm tired anymore.
Do whatever you want to.
Come in and see him yourself.
Don't worry.
File a complaint and they'll take care of it.
For as long as they have hopes to
get my consent. . .
They won't let up on me.
So are you going to give consent?
How can I? He killed my girl.
Why are you here then?
I'm here to see if there's anything
I can do to speed things up.
And for them to stop hoping.
You waited for two years
and you can wait a bit longer.
They'll execute him.
But I'm fed up with them coming and going.
Well just as much as you loved your girl. . .
They love the boy too.
You can't blame them for trying.
To stop their boy to be executed.
What can I do for them to realize
I won't be giving my consent?
If you don't want the
execution to be postponed. . .
Go after coming up with the blood money.
I told you I don't have any money.
But you have to pay the difference
between a man and woman's blood money.
He killed my girl. . .
But I have to pay so he's executed?
The victim is a woman and
the murderer is a man.
The blood money of the victim
is half of the one of the murderer.
I'd told you this before.
So my girl's life is worth half
of that bastard's life?
According to the law the blood money
of a Muslim woman. . .
Is half of a Muslim man.
Are you a Muslim or not?
I sure am.
I believe in the same God
and prophet that you do.
This is the laws of Islam.
And the law says anyone
who's loved one is killed. . .
Has to pay a couple of millions
so you could execute the murderer?
Or is that what you say?
This money isn't going in my pocket. . .
Or to the government.
It goes to the murderer's family.
And I don't have time to explain
the logic behind it.
Is there any logic to this anyway?
The same religion you believe in. . .
It is hasty when it comes to someone
being killed. . .
And for another person to be
killed because of it.
So it's put barriers on your way. . .
So you would forgive.
I won't.
You will, God willingly.
It's more of a good deed.
One thing us poor people have a lot
in this world. . .
Is doing good deeds, sir.
So think about preparing the blood money.
- Bye.
- Take care.
Mister!
Are you his relative?
No, I'm his friend.
Akbar's friend.
Do they have anyone to pay money for them?
What money?
For consent.
I thought you said your husband
won't give consent.
What if I persuade him?
Do they have anyone with money?
How much?
Enough to cure my daughter.
From what I gathered from your husband
he won't give consent even with money.
He only listens to one person.
I'll go to him.
He'll make him give his consent
even if it's for the cure. . .
Of my daughter.
Who?
The praying leader of the mosque.
You have to stand up to him.
You're the one who has to forgive.
A mother is more righteous than a father.
I mean she was your child too.
And say you want to forgive.
Maliheh wasn't my daughter.
She was the only memory
of his late first wife.
You can't blame him for not forgiving.
Just don't let him find out I talked to you.
And if they gather enough money. . .
Let me know.
You haven't had lunch have you?
I had.
Okay eat this too.
It'll be your dinner.
How do you know?
Where do you stay at night?
In my mother's house in Niavaran.
Funny!
When will you be done work?
Why?
Let's go to get consent.
His wife said she'll force him to accept
it if we come up with money.
Tell your mother in Niavaran
to loan a couple of millions.
It's possible to come up with the money
if they don't want it all at once.
How?
We'll come up with it.
Why were you in the rehab?
For robbery.
When should I come to pick you up?
I'm here tonight.
So tomorrow.
- Are you full now?
- Not really.
Yes, Haji?
I looked the Qur'an for you.
You did?
Your wife told me to ask God
for advice for you.
What for?
For your problem.
Sit down.
My wife came to you without telling me.
I don't need advice.
Everyone needs advice
when you are in doubt.
And what better advice than God's?
But I'm not in doubt.
Sit down anyway.
Here.
[ reading the Quran ]
Anyone of you did something bad. . .
And if he repents and corrects himself. . .
And of course God is
merciful and compassionate.
This holy verse. . .
Doesn't precisely tell you what to do.
But it's talking about mercy and forgiveness.
I have a question, Haji.
Hasn't the Qur'an given me the right
to ask for revenge?
Doesn't it say murderers
should pay for their acts?
Haven't I been subjected to injustice?
So why does it keep putting
barriers in my way?
It's as if I've done something wrong.
And I'm the oppressor.
I swear to the prophet there is no one
else more oppressed than I am.
Don't say something you might regret later.
I won't forgive.
But God's happy if you do.
In that case God isn't just then.
Don't talk blasfemous.
I'm not.
But I'm upset with God too.
We the residents of Shams Abad. . .
The businessmen. . .
The people of the mosque area. . .
The workers of the textile factory. . .
Testify that. . .
Mr. Abolqasem Rahmati. . .
The son of Karim
The father of the victim. . .
And the fired worker. . .
Is ill. . .
And in poverty
And doesn't have the power. . .
To pay for the blood money. . .
Thus we are asking. . .
For him to reach justice. . .
For this amount. . .
To be paid by the government
And the verdict
And the execution of the murderer
To be carried out.
I took her to the doctor yesterday.
He went over the tests.
He said she can be operated on.
Scratch out the fired worker part.
But he said once she's older. . .
The operation will be harder.
It's too late already.
I want to do the surgery.
How much is it?
There are a couple of operations.
He said about four million tomans.
Or perhaps less.
Write small so there will be enough
room for a lot of signatures.
Listen to me.
If I had that kind of a money. . .
I'd pay the blood money to take
revenge for my daughter.
We won't pay anything.
Instead of executing the boy. . .
You can get the money from them.
Rewrite it.
Let me see you.
I would have thrown him under
the train if he weren't your husband.
Was I wrong for hitting him?
No, you were right!
Why did you take my side
if I did the wrong thing?
You're my brother's friend.
Well, he is your husband.
I'll take his side the next time.
Why did you take my side
if I did the wrong thing?
You're my brother's friend.
Well, he is your husband.
I'll take his side the next time.
All the injustice to the God's prophet.
All the problems caused for the
leader of the Muslims.
But he forgave.
What's the first verse of the Holy Qur'an?
It goes
In the name of God.
That's right.
Our religion is the right religion.
Why doesn't it say
In the name of the Angry God?
It says the Compassionate God.
Well that tells us something.
Read the Holy Qur'an.
Read it.
So many verses about mercifullness
and forgiveness.
Humans are the top of the creation.
And humans are valuable
since they're God's creations.
Any kindness we do to any other
human beings. . .
Means we've done so to God.
Peace be upon prophet Muhammad.
[ singing a song to the child ]
Hi.
What happened, Haji?
I told you, sister.
I can't do anything if you're in a hurry.
Sure, anything you say.
You can't blame him anyway.
He feels if he gives consent. . .
- He's made a deal over his girl's life.
- Hello, Haji.
- Hello.
- So he doesn't agree?
It's not something you do in a day or two.
It takes time.
But there is no time left, Haji.
They're going to hang my brother.
You get the blood money as soon as you can.
I'll persuade him.
Really?
I'll do it.
Goodbye.
What is your name?
Tell me your name.
A'la.
Tell me it doesn't suit me.
What?
Tell me what your mother. . .
In uptown, what does she call you?
They all call me A'la.
They call me Andy.
Tell him to be serious.
Ask him where his house is?
Shahr-e-Ziba.
Ask him how old he is.
I'm younger than you are.
A couple of years.
How old are you?
Tell him a year old.
I'm talking about you.
Does it matter?
No.
But you're older than me.
Do you what I thought the first
time I saw you?
I thought you were about twenty three.
What about now?
Now. . .
I think about thirty two.
I don't want to.
It's too much.
Eat it, don't be shy.
What is it?
Nothing.
Can I take a smoke?
- No.
- Why not?
I don't like the women who smoke.
But I like it.
How much, pal?
Be my guest.
Three thousand and three hundred.
Hold on.
I'll take you.
No, I'll go by myself.
Will you come tomorrow?
When should I come?
Sooner.
In the morning.
What?
At the hospital yesterday. . .
Why did you ask me the reason
I went to the rehab?
No reason.
You asked for Akbar's money.
I have to come up with that money.
I can do it.
You hate women who smoke. . .
And I hate men who are thieves.
And keep stealing.
They're constantly in and out of prison.
Why haven't you gone to work yet?
I'm tired.
Take this.
I quit.
There they come again.
Take these inside, Firouzeh.
I'm talking to you.
They'll arrest me.
- Hello, officer.
- Shut the place down.
I swear I'm working legal here.
Close it down.
Where are you taking me?
Let go of my hand.
I swear I've been here for three years.
The guy wants to move to Tehran.
His money is honest.
Is it cash?
It's enough cash to solve your problem.
I'll guarantee him.
He's a friend.
He'll pay the rest bit by bit.
I know him.
I've found a place for you too.
The rent is not much
and you can handle it.
Forget the building.
You have to price the land.
Should we write up the contract?
- Sure.
- Here you are.
Does it have city gas?
The plumbing is done.
It'll be connected anytime now.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
What's wrong ma'am?
Go to the clergy in the mosque. . .
Tell him Abolqasem is selling his house.
Bring him over.
Like I said before. . .
It's up to him.
He's not a kid.
You can't force him.
Legally he's got the right to anyway.
He can ask for execution.
What do you mean?
Is it right for him to ruin his family?
To pay the blood money to execute
his child's murderer?
Are you worried for his family
or thinking of your friend?
It's to his advantage too.
Instead of the execution he'll
get some money to cure that girl.
This is a better of a good deed.
Since when you can decide on what's good?
You aren't entitled to decide
what's good and what's not.
Why?
A five year old child can distinguish
between the two.
Yes, this way a life is saved.
But the society is not safe.
[ reading the Holy Quran ]
Do you know if an unwanted
person is executed. . .
How big of a good deed it is to others?
What unwanted?
My friend is a very nice boy.
How did he commit murder then?
He was young and stupid, only sixteen.
He was in love and blind.
He was going to kill himself too.
I have to pray first anyway.
You do the same for now.
He'll sell the house if we don't rush there.
He won't give consent if
he puts the blood money together.
- What do you suggest me do?
- Go now if possible.
- Hello.
The people are waiting for me.
- Is praying more important than saving a life?
- Yes, it is.
I'll send someone to bring him here.
Come to the agency and
take the cheques tomorrow.
Don't forget the documents too.
- The whole thing.
- God bless you.
Bye.
Is your cheque money?
It's cash.
It was meant to be.
You couldn't have found a better
house than that. . .
And he wouldn't have found a buying
customer in this neighborhood anytime soon.
I'll come to see you at the agency, thanks.
- Bye.
It's nothing personal.
I don't want your family to get tortured.
- Says who?
- Your wife's heart isn't in this.
And I don't want to have the curse
of your family on me all my life.
And take this from me. . .
Don't treat your family like this.
Don't break their hearts.
This is more urgent than anything else.
You'll excuse me, bye.
- It's alright.
- Bye.
It's over.
Thanks a lot.
What are you doing?
Someone help me.
Help me.
Somayeh!
You're crazy
and have driven us crazy too.
Two years.
You want me to live in rented houses
with this handicaped girl?
How could you be so vengeful?
Don't I own a part of this house?
I won't sell.
I would have done so years ago
to spend it on my daughter's treatment.
You're not worried about your kid.
You're only concerned with your share.
I would not have married you. . .
If that was the case.
Why are you embarrassed?
Just tell me you wanted a servant
and not a wife.
I've worked so hard for you.
Ever since the day I stepped in this house. . .
You've never treated me decently once.
Have you ever touched me
except for beating me up?
I came into this house with my girl. . .
So you'd be a father to her.
Didn't I do so much for your girl?
Why won't you let go?
Your wife died, and so did your girl.
You won't bring them back to life
by killing yourself.
Somayeh!
Let's go, dear.
Do you want me to take your hand?
Thanks.
Her uncle's house is here.
We'll manage from here.
I'm not here to get your consent.
I just want to say something and leave.
I went to see Akbar today.
I told him you won't change your mind.
He doesn't have hope to get
your consent anymore.
He knows he'll be executed in a little while.
But he wanted me to tell you something.
He said that he doesn't want the blood money.
And so don't sell your house
to come up with it.
He said he'd consent to be executed
without the blood money.
Just make sure he's executed
as soon as possible.
And he finally said. . .
To tell you. . .
To forgive him.
Tell them to bring the blood money.
I'll give my consent.
God bless you, Haji.
You're the best.
- What is it?
- He gave consent.
He gave consent not to execute Akbar.
- You're lying.
- I swear to God.
Akbar won't be executed.
Are you serious?
I swear to God.
Thank you God.
He gave consent.
He says Akbar won't be executed.
He'll be free.
He said it himself.
Oh God, he gave consent.
I ran all the way to here.
We have to tell Akbar.
Where are you going?
I came by to tell you this.
A'la!
Why didn't you come today?
I didn't go to work.
I thought you'd come for sure.
I kept waiting by the window.
I don't like it.
- Me?
- No, myself.
Why?
Akbar sent me here to get consent.
Not to back stab him.
What back stab?
You have a husband, it's not right.
I'm not the type.
Where do you sleep at night?
Anywhere possible.
In the park or the terminal.
Don't leave.
Stay.
Sleep in here.
What if your husband comes?
I don't have a husband.
Isn't he the father of your kid then?
That's all he is.
I divorced him a year and half ago.
But you are together.
But everything between us is separated.
What is this on your finger then?
How do you think I've been living
in this neighborhood?
Just like this.
A ring, and an addict
whom everyone thinks is my husband.
Here if you don't have a man...
You'll be faced with a hundred
men every night.
Why did you divorce him?
I didn't want to have to sell myself. . .
Everytime he got hard up to make
money for his fix.
Where is he now?
Don't worry, he won't be released
anytime sooner than a month.
Sleep.
I'm a lonely woman with a child.
I get paid fifty grand a month
and I have to pay rent with that too.
Even if I put everything I have together. . .
I may stretch it to be three hundred grand.
Let's say I get a loan too.
It'll be seven hundred grand.
What will I tell Abolqasem
with seven hundred grand?
Ask him to forgive his girl's murderer
with that money?
I swear I wouldn't have hesitated
if I had the money.
Why did you keep coming here then. . .
And forced me to work on the old
man to give consent?
Would you like me to talk to
the doctors at the hospital?
They might be less expensive.
Not every doctor can do this operation.
The expert doctors said she might
become paralyzed after the surgery.
Let alone those fake doctors.
You be in my shoe.
What would you have me do?
What can I do?
Can't you let me know soon
so the old man makes his decision. . .
To have the boy executed?
He hasn't been sleeping nor eating
ever since he's decided to give consent.
He's about to have a heart attack.
Take your fruits with you as well.
I'll come up with the money.
- How?
- Never mind how.
Don't even talk about it.
So you want him get executed
for a couple of millions?
I keep telling you I hate men like that.
So what?
Who are you anyway to be preaching me?
Don't I have the right to know?
- You don't know. . .
- I don't want you to go to prison.
I swear to God I won't.
I know my work.
I've done this many times.
Is that why you've spent seven
years of your life behind the bars?
I'll show you now.
A'la!
Don't go for God's sake.
Okay, stop.
For me.
Suppose I had the money to loan it to you. . .
It's just spending good money after bad.
Remember how you sold your life
to have her operated on?
Did it make a difference though?
What if she becomes paralyzed after
the surgery?
What will you do then?
She'll be a piece of meat for
the rest of her life.
That stupid Abolqasem doesn't
have a good head.
You have to be wise.
I've been wanting to tell you something
for a couple of days now.
- But I'm embarrassed.
- What is it?
There is a boy. . .
The one I told you who comes
and goes for the consent. . .
He's a simple kid.
I thought now that they
don't have the money. . .
Is he a clean kid?
He's got guts, that's obvious.
He went through hell and high water.
Until he forced Abolqasem
to give consent.
That's great.
Your girl is handicaped
but not in the brain.
Let him have her.
What if it's imposing the boy?
What? You've been imposed.
You have a stupid husband and
a handicaped girl.
But if he doesn't want your girl
he can come up witht he blood money then.
So the boy doesn't get executed.
Ten.
Why won't you tell him personally?
That's not right.
I don't want him to claim that my
girl was given to him by force later on.
You talk to him and send him over.
In fact tell him in your own words.
Tell him you've found a good girl for him.
Make him like her slowly.
You women know how to talk to each other.
Hopefully when they're wedded. . .
We'll take Abolqasem to the court.
To give consent so your brother is freed.
What did they want here?
The same thing.
Why did you cry then?
They want money.
We already knew that
they didn't need to come here for that.
They want the whole blood money
not just four million.
Bullshit.
That's what they said before.
What's the difference?
I don't have the money. . .
Whether it's four or ten million.
- Did you tell them you didn't have it?
- Yeah.
It's useless though.
They're looking for an excuse
to execute Akbar.
They're going over their words.
Take this.
Thanks a lot.
- Where are you going?
- They have to stand by their words.
Don't go.
I know how to convince them.
- You go in.
- Why are you scared of them?
A'la!
Is someone here?
A'la.
Give it to me, dear.
Go and get freshened up a bit.
Put on my colored scarf.
Come in quickly.
Hello.
Why don't you eat something?
- Do you want me to cut them up for you?
- No, I don't.
I'll eat.
- Did Firouzeh tell you to come here?
- Yeah.
She's a nice girl.
She wants the best for you.
She's talked to me about
you a couple of times.
I told her it's all up to fate.
Eat something.
Didn't you bring sugar cubes dear?
She panics everytime someone
comes to propose to her.
I'll get them.
Talk to the guest, dear.
Hello.
- What?
- We got a guest.
The boy who comes here for consent.
- What does he want here?
- It's a good thing.
I'll tell you.
Come here.
- Hey, mister!
- Firouzeh!
- Leave please.
- I'm talking to you, Firouzeh.
Please leave,
- Mister, please.
- Firouzeh!
Firouzeh!
Why are you running from me?
I'm late, what is it?
What should I do?
- What about?
- The condition they have.
What can I say?
I can't tell you to marry her
to save my brother.
I'm stupid, I'll do it if you want me to.
What should I do, Firouzeh?
She's a nice girl.
- So are you.
- Me?
I have a child.
I'm older than you.
I'm not good for you.
But you were good for me
till just a few days ago.
When did I ever tell you that?
You think I'm in love with you just
because I was good to you for a while?
I noticed you were busting your
bones for my brother Akbar. . .
So I was kind to you.
You're lying.
You want to force me to marry her
for your brother's sake.
Don't then, if you don't want to.
Why should you sacrifice yourself for Akbar?
I'm just telling you not to count on me.
- Hold on.
- I'm late.
Shahr-e-Ziba.
- Shahr-e-Ziba.
- Which part?
- The rehab.
- Where is that?
The Rehabilitation Center.
Amininan.
You have to make the decision.
I can't.
That's why I'm here.
Does his sister love you?
A lot.
Can you forget her?
- No.
- Marry her then.
What about Akbar then?
Do you know why Akbar killed that girl?
He loved her.
How can you kill someone you love?
He didn't want for someone else to have her.
What would you do
if you were in Akbar's shoe?
Would you have killed the girl as well?
I'd have forgotten her.
So you can forget someone you love.
Right?
You can forget Akbar's sister too
if that's possible.
No, it's not.
- Remember Shahin?
- Yeah.
Remember why he had committed murder?
They didn't have the money
to pay for her mother's debts. . .
So they had to kill the guy.
Yeah.
Shahin didn't have a father.
He loved his mother.
He didn't want her mother to go to
prison for her heavy debt.
He couldn't bear it.
He killed the man
in order not to lose his mother.
- Do you think he did the right thing?
- No.
What would you do?
Would you have killed the guy
or have forgotten your mother?
I'd have forgotten my mother.
So it is possible to forget someone you love.
No, it's not.
I can't.
It's easy to tell others to forget.
The judges who gave death sentences
to Akbar and Shahin and others. . .
They too thought the same.
What should I do, Mr. Ghafouri?
I would have forgotten about
Akbar's sister if I were you.
But I may fall in love some day
and won't be able to forget.
Even if it's at the price of someone's death.
Go and see the guys.
Think it over, I'll be right here.
If this boy marries your girl. . .
He'll destroy his and her life both.
I know this boy.
This condition is neither to yours
nor his advantage.
It's been two years.
Take off the black shirt.
- Don't unwrap it.
- Why not though?
I won't give consent.
I won't step out of this house
unless I get your consent.
Leave me alone for God's sake.
Why do you keep torturing me?
Move away from the door.
"THE END"
SUBTITLED & DVD AUTHORIHG BY:
PERSIAN ART PICTURE INSTITUTE - TEHRAN