Timing and Subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
♫ The first second I saw you, everything froze except for my heartbeat. ♫
♫ Oddly, I had to adjust my breathing and suppress my impulses. ♫
♫ Whenever you appear, warm thoughts of you ♫
♫  surrender me whole, and can never escape from your side. ♫
♫ The flaming knife slices into the silent night and ignites it. ♫
♫ My fiery eyes are locked onto my personal contact with yours. I smile. ♫
♫ The moment we clash allows no time for hesitation. ♫
♫  This is a world that does not give an option for failure.  ♫
♫ Even if I have to go against the world. SO. ♫
♫ Even if I stop breathing, I won't let go. SO.♫
♫ What chance? SO. What fate? SO. ♫
♫ Welcome to this crazy game of love. SO. ♫
♫ Don't worry about whether or not this is meaningful. SO. ♫
♫ Even without your approval, I must attack. SO. ♫
♫ What crisis? SO. What feelings? SO.  ♫
♫  Welcome to this game of master love guardians. SO. ♫
♫ Love is not a game. ♫
♫ I must do my best. ♫
♫ Even if people suffocate, ♫
♫ I can't waver. I can't give up. ♫
♫  For love, I'm an eagle. ♫
♫  No one can keep their distance.  ♫
♫  I'll wait for you closely. I'll protect you closely.  ♫
♫  While loving you, I forget how to love myself. ♫
♫ Even if I have to go against the world. SO. ♫
♫ Even if I stop breathing, I won't let go. SO.♫
♫ What chance? SO. What fate? SO. ♫
♫ Welcome to this crazy game of love. SO. ♫
♫ Don't worry about whether or not this is meaningful. SO. ♫
♫ Even without your approval, I must attack. SO. ♫
♫ What crisis? SO. What feelings? SO. ♫
♫  Welcome to this game of master love guardians. SO. ♫
Episode 23
Miraculous Doctor Lin, then is it that as long as I find a Heaven Level pure yang practitioner,
Xiao Xiao will not die?
Being able to sustain her life doesn't necessarily mean that she will not die.
Initially, it's true that a Heaven Level martial arts expert will be able to suppress it.
But as she grows older, this yin energy
will also grow stronger,
and it'll take more and more effort to suppress it.
Until it reaches a point where it'll be totally useless.
Miraculous Doctor Lin, is there any other way?
Actually there's still a way. It's just...
The medicine you're giving is becoming less and less effective.
Is it that there's some problem with this medicine that was newly developed?
Professor Mao said that this new medicine needs some time to get used to.
Time. Time.
Right now, I'm like a ticking time bomb. Even I almost can't control myself anymore. Don't you know?
I'm really almost running out of time!
Don't panic, don't panic. We're all aware of that.
At that time, you guys were the one who said, that as long as I cooperate with your research,
you guys will help restore my body.
But until now, there's no progress at all!
How long more must I wait before you'll be able to solve the problem with my body?!
Calm down and listen to me. Actually, recently, we found this thing called Holy Fire Spirit Fruit.
It's said that it can help control the chaotic energy in your body, and can even help sustain people's life.
Professor Mao said that, perhaps, this might be able to help you.
Holy Fire Spirit Fruit?
That's right.
In order to help you,
Master Bing has employed quite a number of people to find the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit.
Now is the transition period.
Hang on first. You need to have faith in Professor Mao.
[5 Years Ago]
Lad, you've woken up.
Are you still feeling unwell anywhere?
Where am I?
This is my territory.
Don't worry, no one will harm you here.
And you are...
You can call me Brother Hua.
How did I get here?
Lad,
a few days ago, you did something that created an uproar,
you -- Chi Feng High School.
You don't remember?
How can that be?
I... I actually...
This won't do. I need to go.
Xiao Hu (Little Tiger),
don't be in such a rush first. I guess that you've nowhere to go anyway.
You... How do you know my name?
I know the secret of your body.
Professor Mao wants me to tell you not to worry. Stay here
and cooperate with me. He will cure your illness.
Professor Mao... hasn't he died?
How could he...?
There's a lot of time ahead of us, you'll get to know about it in the future.
At that time, Master Bing and Professor Mao wanted me to rescue that rascal and bring him back here,
take him in, and even help him develop a cure.
After investing so much in him,
one day, I must get it all back from him, interest and all.
Actually, recently, we found this thing called Holy Fire Spirit Fruit.
It's said that it can help control the chaotic energy in your body, and can even help sustain people's life.
Holy Fire Spirit Fruit?
Can it really help restore me?
Strange. Why would that guy, Han Bin, be here?
Could it be that he's working here?
Is there something you need me to do?
Situ Ling, fifteen years old,
a girl who was in the prime of her life.
But because of a student's loss of control,
her young life was ended.
Her brother spent five years
and finally found the murderer.
The murderer...
is you.
I hope you can understand Situ Jiong's feelings.
It is very hard for him to forgive you.
I know. I never dreamed of anyone being able to forgive me.
But I think, I might be able to understand what you're feeling.
So from today onward,
Situ Jiong and I won't order you to do anything again.
Understand? What's going on?
Is she playing some kind of trick?
Situ Jiong, he's... actually a good person,
please give him some time. Maybe time, will be able to lessen his pain.
Could you?
Haven't I told you before? If there's nothing the matter, don't come here to find me.
If there's anything the matter, even more, you shouldn't come here to find me.
What if your identity gets exposed?
Brother Hua, please don't be angry. I've always been careful!
Besides, I purposely came out without putting on my disguise.
I look so different, no one will recognize me.
Hurry and tell me. How's the progress with the mission I assigned you the last time?
Err... to tell you the truth,
regarding the school... I might not be able to go back anymore.
What happened?
The mission failed. And Lin Yi's even got a voice recording as evidence.
What you mean to say is, not only were you unsuccessful in doing harm to him,
instead he got a hold on you. Can you put it that way?
That's right.
Good. Great! Then, you can sit in jail then.
Boss, please just do me a favor.
Boss, all these years I've worked, even if I didn't have any accomplishments, I still worked hard, didn't I?
Back then, when you sent me to the school undercover, we agreed that it would just be for three years.
But after three years, another three years, and after those three years, another three years...
Counting the years, I've been working undercover in the school for almost ten years already.
Boss, help me out. Give me a chance, will you?
Fine!
I will give you a chance, and help you.
If you want to show your loyalty for me,
it's best that you take responsibility for everything.
Rest assured, I won't treat you and your family too shabbily.
Remember, the cleaner you cut ties with me,
the better your family will live.
And as for you, the earlier you will be able to get out of jail as well. Understand?
Yes, Boss.
Is there anything else?
No.
Then why don't you hurry up and leave?
Yes, Boss.
Li Yao.
Yes, Brother Hua.
Arrange for a neat car accident to send him off.
Okay, let's try doing it now.
There is currently no one answering the number you've dialed. Please call again later.
Originally, I was thinking of asking Daddy out to eat.
Forget it.
But if I suddenly appeared in front of him,
he definitely will be very happy, wouldn't he?
[The ten things to do before I die]
Help you find Holy Fire Spirit Fruit?
Yes. Lin Yi, will you consider taking up this mission?
After all, this is my personal matter.
For public reasons, I can't use the country's secret agents, for personal reasons, in light of our previous good partnership,
I would feel more reassured if I entrust this to you.
Uncle Feng, but that old fart-
Legend has it that this is a very rare and mystical fruit,
called Holy Fire Spirit Fruit, which is a fruit that is purely yang.
It contains the most yang energy between Heaven and Earth.
If it is consumed, it can suppress the yin energy in the body,
for decades.
That's fantastic.
But this fruit hasn't undergone actual test verification.
The treatment effect differs for everyone.
It can be used for some. But for some, they might experience reverse effects.
Miraculous Doctor Lin, what does that Holy Fire Spirit Fruit look like? Where can we get it?
After all, it was from ancient medicine transcripts that I read of the existence of this type of fruit.
I only know that it's an excellent antidote for chilly yin poison.
As for where to look for it, and what it looks like, I don't know about that.
I know that the regarding the questions of where the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit, whether it exists or not,
or even whether it's just a fake myth, there are still no answers to them.
But Xiao Xiao only has a year left. As long as there's still any strand of hope,
I need to give my utmost to try.
Rest assured. In the finding process, I will provide you all the assistance you need.
Sorry, Uncle Feng. Because the current mission I'm on still hasn't ended,
if I withdrew to help you, it's not fair for my employer,
and it's also not my style.
Have you gotten it?
I got it from the black market.
This... is the map you wanted.
This is great.
I finally collected all the things necessary.
You've arrived just in time. I have some news to tell you.
There's a cure for your body.
Huh?
As long as I hand these two treasures to Master Bing,
I believe that Master Bing will quickly dispatch men and archaeologists to study it.
In this way, we'll be able to find the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit that you need.
These two things...
That's right.
This is the medical practice record log handwritten by the Godly Doctor, Zhang Li Ju.
In it, it clearly records the miraculous effects of the legendary Holy Fire Spirit Fruit
from the Fire Spirit Tree.
Brother Hua, but the words written on it is all in ancient script. How can we read it?
That's why we need to find archaeologists to explain it for us.
And the map that Li Yao found,
is the treasure map that has the location of the Fire Spirit Tree.
As long as we find the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit,
and follow the directions given on the medical practice record log,
we should be able to solve the problem with your body.
Han Bin,
your hardship days are almost over.
Brother Hua,
you're really going through so much trouble, just to save him?
Didn't you say that the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit was to be used to develop new medicines to make money?
Saving him is, of course, only one of the reasons.
As long as we find this magical Holy Fire Spirit Fruit,
Professor Mao will be able to stay put in the research laboratory to research.
Come that day, he'll be able to invent even more medicines which will be able to make money.
I will sell drugs in one hand, and antidotes in the other.
I'll definitely make shitloads of money.
Brother Hua's brilliant.
And finding the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit as soon as possible,
can help improve his problem of losing control.
Only then, will we be able to properly make use of his powerful strength.
That is what Master Bing, and us,
would really consider as helping.
This is what I was aiming for in taking him in.
Why? Why?
I'd already mentally prepared myself that I'd only have a year left to live.
But the moment I heard my dad say
that there was still hope for my body, as long as they find the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit-
Holy Fire Spirit Fruit?
I suddenly wanted so much to continue living!
Why did this happen?
What am I to do?
Someone like me,
am I really entitled to be saved?
The ten things to do before I die...
Holy Fire Spirit Fruit...
I've already searched all the databases and journals.
Even in the top research centers of the world, there's no information about the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit.
What to do? I can't find it.
Where in the world can it be found?
As expected, at this time, none of them are here.
If I didn't get it wrong, there shouldn't be any CCTV cameras in their office.
This-This really is the medical practicing record log left by a doctor from ancient times.
The Holy Fire Spirit Fruit's introduction and location are recorded in these two things.
But Han Bin, why do you have these things?
I can't tell you where they come from, but... there's also other people looking for the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit.
You must find it before them to save Feng Xiao Xiao.
Why are you telling me all these?
I want... to trouble you to help me take it to Situ Jiong.
Situ Jiong?
If I'm the one who hands it to him, he definitely won't want to see me,
maybe... even suspect what my true motives are.
But... why do you want to do this?
I want... to let Feng Xiao Xiao continue living.
Actually Han Bin doesn't want to let you know that he's the one who gave it to you.
Just take it that I'm a busybody.
Lin Yi, I hope that you can promise me something.
What's going on with you and Han Bin? You guys keep doing this to me.
Brother Hua, it really is that lad all right.
Who'd have thought that this lad would be so daring.
He actually dared to secretly sneak into my office.
I want to teach him what happens to those who betray me.
Go find him and bring him here.
Yes, Brother Hua.
How come I fell asleep here?
Where's Situ?
Has he gone to class?
Why didn't he tell me before he left?
Xiao Xiao, by the time you see this message,
I've already left to find the location of the Holy Fire Spirit Fruit.
I don't know how much time I will spend, but I promise you
that I'll definitely rush back before your 20th birthday.
Sorry,
I'd originally promised that I'd stay with you every day this year, and celebrate your birthday with you,
but please forgive my greediness.
I think that, if I sacrifice this period of time, very soon, I'll be able to accompany you every year.
Can you forgive me for breaking my promise?
You must wait for me. I'll definitely find this antidote.
Why is he still so silly?
Hi.
You- Who are you?
Good question.
Ah Huang. Ah Huang!
What do you want? If it's regarding money, it's easy to discuss.
Why did you betray Chu Peng Zhan?
Were you sent by someone?
Tell me the answer.
Because of my son.
Since I divorced with my wife, I placed all my focus on my son.
I wanted to train him to take over my career, so that he'd be able to carve out his own success.
But who'd have thought that he'd be addicted to video games, and even learned to abuse drugs,
and owed a whole bunch of money for drugs.
I only found out later.
I wasn't able to raise the ransom fund that they demanded in that short time span either.
And just at that time, I don't know where Jin Gu Bang got the news from,
he came to find me and said that if I was willing to do him a favor,
he'd provide the funds to help me ransom my son,
and help me keep it a secret, and not expose this scandal.
So I agreed.
I really let Chairman Chu down.
Sorry.
Seems like Uncle Chu was right.
This Xie Guang Bo really doesn't seem to be a bad person.
Ohh... So that's what happened. Old Xie's son was kidnapped by the triad gangs.
Jin Gu Bang lent him a helping hand, but used this to threaten him,
then Old Xie must be in agony.
But, if it were Meng Er who was kidnapped,
I would have made the same choice.
It's just if Old Xie didn't have enough money, he could have told me. I could have helped!
I think, lending money to Mr. Xie won't solve the root of the problem.
No matter how much money you give the other side, they won't be satisfied.
Xiao Yi, you're right.
But Chairman, there's something very suspicious.
How did Jin Gu Bang find out about Director Xie's son's matter?
Unless he has some links with the triad?
Given his actions at the Board of Director meeting, it's extremely possible.
I agree. What's more, he might even be connected to Li Bi Hua.
If it's as what you guys are saying, then is there any way
for us to seize back control of the company's management rights from Jin Gu Bang?
I think... that our only chance is to rescue Xie Jin Biao from the triad's clutches.
Also, I've already asked Mr. Xie to think of a way to delay it,
and do his best not to let Jin Gu Bang take over Peng Zhan Corporation so fast.
What's left is to wait for me to rescue his son.
But Xiao Yi, you don't even know where Xie Jin Biao is, how are you going to rescue him?
It's okay. I have a way.
Xiao Yi, I can't let you take the risk. What if you get injured? How can that do?
Don't worry, Uncle Chu.
Don't forget that I'm a bodyguard of international standard.
Sister 36 E, it's me, Lin Yi.
Stinky brat, what the hell are you doing?
I was having a meeting just now, and you kept calling. You called until my handphone was almost out of battery. What the hell do you want?
Is there news on the information I asked you to help me find the last time?
I've found it. But there's a lot of information.
It'll be better to meet up and discuss outside. Message me the time and location.
Let's make it tomorrow then. As long as you tell me Xie Jin Biao's location,
I'll give you evidence of Li Bi Hua and Jin Gu Bang doing harm to Peng Zhan Corporation.
Really? Then we're agreed. You're not to break your word, got it?
Just as I guessed.
- Is there a way?- Currently, our entire Special Forces Police...
Lin Yi? What's he up to?
Behaving so sneakily.
Deputy Song wants me to hand this to you.
- She also wants me to remind you that this matter of Xie Jin Biao being kidnapped--- Shh!
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
Don't touch her!
Are you okay?
You want to play hero, but still shiver to this extent?
Beat them both up!
What are you following me for?
Xie Jin Biao's my friend, I'm here to save him.
Long time no see. Why don't we hold a class reunion here?
What should I do? Usually, when Han Bin transforms, his power is already Earth Level.
Now, after the injection, he'll be even stronger.
Han Bin, don't!
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely, so lonely. I hate it. ♫
♫ I need a hug, as long as I'm not lonely. ♫
♫ I don't need a tall and handsome one. I'm not picky. ♫
♫ Hey boy across from me, I'm a good girl. ♫
♫ When I see you, my heart beats like thump, thump, thump. ♫
♫ A deer caught in headlights, I can't bear it anymore. ♫
♫ I never knew love was so magical. ♫
♫ I've already been burned by love's flames. ♫
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely, so lonely. I hate it. ♫
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely, hurry and kiss me. ♫
♫ I'm your love life. ♫
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely, hurry and pat me. ♫
♫ You are my love impulse. ♫
♫ I'm so lonely, so lonely, so lonely. I hate it. ♫