BEAUTIFUL BOY (2010)
- (wind howling)
- Man: Who's that?
Who's that jumping
on my camera?
- Who's that?
- (boy chattering)
- Peek a boo, I see you.
- Man: Hello.
- Man: Oh no, it was switched off.
- No. Really?
Man:
I don't know.
How can you see me through that?
- Man: How?
- Oh, can I see?
- Can you see him?
- Boy: Wait.
- Can you see us?
- Boy: Wait. No.
Boy's voice: "As the boy and girl
ran out from their station wagon,
the beach was happy.
It was happy to have
their small footprints upon it.
It was happy to have holes dug
with plastic shovels.
It was even happy
to have paper wrappers
blowing about after they'd gone.
But the beach knew
that there would no longer
be this to look forward to.
No more careless play,
only lonely snowfalls to mark
the beginnings of an endless winter."
Woman:
Whoa! Nice kick.
Boy's voice: "The beach
loved the boy and the girl,
though it had no way
of telling them.
And it knew that this was
their last time together.
Things would be different
from now on.
They didn't know if they
would be better or worse,
but for certain
things would change."
(bell rings)
(tapping)
Man:
Hey, chief. Bill.
We're doing the thing now...
Carl's baby shower.
Right. Right.
(over phone)
Hey, it's Sam.
Leave me a message
and I'll call you back.
- (beeps)
- Woman: Hi.
I haven't heard
from you for a while,
so I'm just calling
to see how things are.
I'm sure you're crammed
with exams.
Um, okay, call me
when you get a chance.
It's Mom, by the way.
- Oh, hi. Cooper?
- Kate, hi. Cooper Stearns.
Hi. Pleased to meet you.
How are you?
Good.
Can I get you anything?
- A coffee?
- No no, thanks. I'm good.
I can't do caffeine in the afternoon
or I won't be able to sleep all night.
Oh God, I live on the stuff.
It's how I got this thing finished.
Oh my goodness.
Congratulations!
Well, don't congratulate me
until you've read it.
Well, I'm just the spellchecker,
but I'm sure it's wonderful.
It's a big deal getting published.
It's not Simon & Schuster,
but my mom's real proud.
I bet she is.
Bill: So her dad put all the different
essential fluids in the trunk
in plastic soda bottles...
coolant in a Coke bottle,
oil in Mountain Dew
and wiper fluid in Sprite...
you know, like that.
- Don't tell me she drank it.
- No no, but one day she's...
she's driving around
and the car overheats.
So, you know,
she opens the hood,
and she looks at it
like a seasoned mechanic,
and she says, "I think
it's a little low on Dr. Pepper."
(laughter)
(over phone)
Hey, it's Sam.
Leave me a message
and I'll call you back.
- (beeps)
- Kate: Hi, hon. It's Mom again.
Let's go somewhere this summer...
a little family vacay.
It's been forever since we did it.
Anyway, love you.
Call me later. Bye.
- Hi, Bonnie.
- Hey.
- Let me help you with that.
- Thank you.
- How's Nikki doing?
- She's in a funk.
- Trying to lose her freshman 15.
- Oh no.
- How's Sammy?
- He's good.
- I just left him a message.
- Oh please.
I told Nikki if she doesn't
start taking my calls,
she's gonna have to pay
her own phone bill.
Thank you.
Ooh, the steaks are beautiful,
by the way.
On sale... $3.99 a pound.
Ah, it might rain tomorrow.
Kate:
What?
Bill:
It might rain.
Kate: Hey, how's your steak?
Is it too well done?
No, it's good.
- Did Carl like the baby blanket?
- Uh, yeah yeah.
Good.
So I think I found a place.
I'm gonna call about it tomorrow.
Wait, don't put that in there.
You need to rinse it cleaner.
Well, then what's the point?
We should just wash them all by hand.
It's the way things are done.
- I thought we decided to wait.
- Uh, I don't know.
I just thought maybe I should
put a deposit down.
That was the whole point
of the family vacation, right?
We're gonna spend
some time together
away from everything,
figure stuff out.
- I know, I know.
- Well, is that not the plan anymore?
- Let me know.
- No, I didn't say I was moving out.
I just... look, forget it.
It just looked like
a good place, that's all.
No no no, if you don't want to go
on this vacation, I understand.
- Just say so.
- No, I didn't say that.
- Honestly, I can just...
- I did not say that.
- Okay, what did you say?
- L... nothing.
I don't know.
I just think you're putting
a lot of pressure on one vacation.
Bill:
I'm going to bed.
Okay.
Thanks.
So what about Miami?
We're not really
the beach type, are we?
Yeah, anyway.
- Goodnight.
(phone rings)
Ah!
- Hi, stranger.
- Hey.
Where you been?
- You must be studying like crazy.
- Bill: Hello?
Kate: It's Sammy.
Hey, since I have you both
on the phone, can we please figure out
where we're going for vacation?
- I thought you said Miami.
- Kate: No.
I wanted us all to decide together.
Bill: Oh, I don't care.
You two pick.
- Whatever's fine.
- Kate: Fine.
Fine, I'll book Miami.
I'll book it tonight.
Bill: So how are you doing, Sam?
You got enough money?
Mm-hmm.
Car holding up?
Yeah. Car's good.
Good good.
Okay, well, I'm gonna
get some shut-eye.
Don't study too hard.
All right. Bye, Dad.
You sound a little tired.
Are you getting enough sleep?
No, not really,
but I'm gonna... I'm gonna
go to bed here in a minute.
I have an early class
in the morning, so...
Okay.
But listen, it'll get easier.
College is an adjustment.
At least you have
a lot of company.
All your friends are going through
the same thing, believe me.
Hey, guess what.
I ran into Nikki's mom.
She said she gained a lot of weight.
Have you seen her lately?
Hon?
Did you know that snowflakes
always have six sides?
Uh, I thought they were all different.
Isn't that what they always say?
Yeah, but they always
have six sides.
It's, um, something to do
with the... the positive
and the negative charges
in a water molecule.
I don't really understand it.
You know, even though
supposedly they're all different,
you know every single
one of them,
you can still count on all of them
having six sides.
Yeah.
You should think about studying
meteorology or chemistry
instead of English lit or something.
It sounds like you like
that sort of stuff.
Yeah, maybe.
Look, um, I gotta go.
Okay.
Study hard.
Bye, Mom.
Bye, honey.
(phone beeps)
Announcer on TV:
Today on "Inside and Out"...
Man on TV: I can teach you
how to eat all your favorite foods...
- all the foods...
- 'Night.
Man on TV: A new way to speed up
your metabolism really dramatically
and you can reduce your waistline
every single week.
Woman on TV:
I'm eating chocolate,
I'm eating pasta
with cream sauce,
I'm eating pancakes
and I lost 55 lbs.
(ballad playing)
(door opens, closes)
#Forget I need to breathe #
#And I wish you belonged to me,
but it's too late... #
(sighs)
(quiet chatter)
(music continues)
Bonnie:
Kate! Kate!
Kate!
(phone clicks)
Newscaster: We're waiting to get
more details on the victims
as there has been a conflicting number
of fatalities reported so far...
mostly students, but at least
three faculty members
are among the 17 people
known dead.
We're still trying
to get information on...
Newscaster #2: They are now saying
21 are confirmed dead.
Oh my God. Damn it, Nikki,
answer the phone.
Newscaster #2: And we hope
this number doesn't get any larger.
(over phone)
Hey, it's Sam.
Leave me a message
and I'll call you back.
- (beeps)
- Hi... hi, Sammy, it's Mom.
Call me back as soon as you can,
all right? Love you.
It's okay, it's fine.
They're fine.
Bonnie:
I'm just gonna go home.
- Maybe she'll call the home phone.
- (keypad beeping)
(over phone)
Hey, it's Sam.
Newscaster #2:in the wake
of what is now being called
one of the deadliest
campus shootings in history.
Newscaster #3:
...university dorm building
and later stepped
into morning classes
and opened fire
on students and faculty.
- It's still not known whether...
- (car turns off)
I can't get him on his cell,
but he never answers that thing, right?
Everyone's probably trying to call.
The towers are jammed.
We should just go
down there right now.
I got through to someone
in the dean's office.
The campus is completely
locked down.
- There's nothing we can do there.
- So we just wait?
- What do we...
- I'm sure it's fine.
Oh, God, he said he had
an early class this morning.
He's fine. He's fine.
I promise. Okay?
- (phone rings)
- Wait. Sammy?
No, hi.
Have you heard anything?
I know. Me neither.
Newscaster #2: None of the victims'
names are being released at this time
out of respect for the families.
However, students will be
holding a vigil
in honor of the deceased tonight.
Armed police are still
- arriving at the scene.
- (doorbell rings)
Students are being told
to stay in lockdown in the dorms...
- Are you Mrs. Carroll?
- (sobs) Yes.
I'm afraid we have some bad news.
No. He's dead.
- He's dead.
- Yes, ma'am.
No, he's not.
- Can we come in?
- I knew... I knew...
Ma'am, I'm afraid there's more.
At 7:15 this morning,
your son Sam walked
into a university building
- with two loaded weapons and...
- What?
...opened fire
on the students that...
- What?
- Ma'am, I know this is difficult,
but I have some questions
I need to ask you.
Liar!
No, Bill.
No.
Agent:
Did he say anything unusual?
No. He seemed... he seemed
completely normal.
We were planning a vacation.
(officer whispering)
When do we get to, uh,
see the body?
Lt'll be a couple of days.
But I have to warn you...
he died from a self-inflicted
gunshot wound to the head,
so he's pretty unrecognizable.
I'll give you two a moment.
They said he was
unrecognizable, right?
How can they be sure
it's Sammy?
It's not him.
I can't remember which books
go on which shelves.
I don't know.
He's gonna be so upset.
(crying)
Oh God.
(groaning)
(crying)
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Speaking.
Sorry, uh, we have no comment.
(phone ringing)
(chatter)
(phone continues ringing)
Why aren't you answering that?
There are all these
news vans outside.
What?
They must have released his name.
Kate: We just lost our son.
What do they want from us?
Bill:
We're news.
- (phone ringing)
- Ignore it.
We should go upstairs.
They'll start peeking in the windows.
Are they just gonna stay
out there all day waiting?
Come on. Come on.
Newscaster on TV: Is known
beyond the shooter's identity.
Students from his dorm only say
that he was quiet and kept to himself.
We go now to 7 News
reporter Michael Call live
outside the shooter's
childhood home.
Bill:
Turn that off.
Someone could see
the light from outside.
They'll just start
ringing the bell again
if they find out we're home.
Kate:
Are they still there?
The last one's finally leaving.
But they'll probably
be back in the morning.
- I'm so sorry.
- Thanks.
- You redid the kitchen, huh?
- Yeah, a couple months ago.
- Bill: It's nice.
- You don't have to wait on us really.
It's nothing.
Woman: I've put some
fresh towels in the bathroom.
Thanks.
This looks good.
- Is Dylan asleep?
- Yeah.
You'll see him tomorrow.
Delicious.
What'd you marinate this in?
Oh, it's just some bottled stuff
I got at the supermarket.
(sniffles)
(sighs)
I'm sorry.
I just can't believe it.
Was he okay?
I mean before, you know?
Bill:
We thought so.
We... we didn't see him much.
The first year of college
is always hard.
Being away from home
alone, I guess.
- Yeah, of course.
- Woman: Was he depressed?
Was he doing drugs?
- Trish.
- I'm sorry. Sorry.
Hey, did I tell you that Mom
bought a new car?
What kind?
He was a little quieter
than usual, that's all.
Which side do you want?
Uh, it doesn't matter.
You pick.
Your brother's doing
a nice job on the house.
This is probably worth twice
what they paid by now.
Did you call work and tell them
you won't be in for a while?
No.
They're gonna be staked out
at your office too.
(distant dog barking)
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
And uh...
(clears throat)
Thanks, I mean for...
Oh no. Hey, come on,
you're family.
If you need anything,
you know, just ask.
Morning.
(clears throat)
There she is.
How'd you sleep?
Uh, well, thank you.
Good morning there, Dylan.
How you doing?
Man: Trish taught him to read
the nutritional labels.
Trish:
And that backfired.
Now all he wants to eat are the ones
with 13g of sugar per serving.
Oh my goodness.
And you let him, huh?
Not always.
Can I make you any breakfast?
Oh no, thank you.
Just some coffee please.
I got it. I got it.
- That looks good.
- Yeah.
Here you go.
Come on, buddy.
You're done.
Only 15 minutes.
Then we get ready for school.
- (TV turns on)
- Mommy, Sammy's on TV!
This was completely
in your power to avoid today.
Except you only leave me
one option.
Oh my God.
And now you all have blood
on your hands.
You vandalized my heart.
Come on, sweetie.
Let's get ready for school.
- Dylan: But it's not 15 minutes yet.
- Man: Shh.
Sam:
Maybe now you'll listen to me.
- Okay, mister, time for bed.
- But I'm not done.
- Yes, you are.
- No!
- Trish: Dylan, let's go. Come on.
- Buddy.
He is stubborn.
Sammy was like that too
at his age.
We need to issue a statement.
What for?
It's the right thing to do.
You know, l... I just
mean something simple
just expressing our remorse
and sadness.
Kate:
Remorse?
If we don't give the victims'
families something,
they're gonna think we... we don't
feel bad about what Sammy did.
Kate?
(water running)
- Hey.
Do you use bleach in your whites?
Uh yeah, I think.
Katie, you know that he didn't mean
that you don't feel bad.
It's just that
you can't wait too long.
- I know.
- People aren't thinking straight
and you gotta give them something
so they know that you're on their side.
Eric, I know.
Okay.
(sighs)
We are deeply sorry
for the devastation
our son has caused.
Like all the victims' parents,
we are shocked
and utterly heartbroken.
Please allow us our privacy
as we mourn the loss
of our own son
and try to find
the strength to move on
from this horrible,
inexplicable tragedy.
Do you mind if I go?
Sure.
That's okay, I've got it.
(sighs)
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Thinking about taking a walk.
(distant children playing)
Kate: It's good to be
out of the house.
Bill: Yeah, Trish and your brother
are being great,
but after a while,
I just want them to...
I don't know... ignore me.
Kate: Mm.
(inhales)
Mm, do you smell the jasmine?
(sniffs)
- Smell it?
- (sniffs) No.
It's that sweet, flowery thing.
You don't smell that?
(chuckles)
I thought that was you...
your shampoo or your lotion
or something.
Kate:
Nah.
(door closes)
Bill: Trish gave us some Ambien
in case we need it.
Did we do something?
L... I mean, how could he do it?
- Did we not do something?
- No.
No. We gave him everything
he could want.
But he was...
he was such a quiet kid.
He was lonely.
He never played with
the neighbor kids.
We should have
known that there...
Why does it have to be
our fault? Huh?
We did the best we could.
- Come on, let's go to sleep.
- I don't want to go to sleep.
- I want to talk about this.
- What is there to talk about?
You were a terrific mother.
We... we didn't do anything wrong.
Okay?
Well, I'm tired.
I'm going to bed.
Okay, goodnight.
I was thinking maybe
I'd go back to work tomorrow.
Okay.
I might swing by the house,
get some mail,
make sure everything's okay.
Bonnie said the reporters
are still there.
Fine, I won't go.
I didn't say that.
You can do whatever you want.
You're not gonna be able to live there
after all this, you know.
Maybe we should start
talking to realtors.
(sizzling)
- Morning, Trish.
- Morning.
- Can I help?
- Oh no, I'm good.
Do you want me to get
Dylan up for school?
- Oh, he's up.
- Oh.
Maybe I can help him
get dressed then.
Eric's doing that right now.
- Please let me do something.
- Oh.
- You can make Dylan's lunch.
- Great.
Hey, did you ever notice
your fridge doors were uneven?
See, this one's a little lower
than the other.
I'll have Eric take a look at that.
- Bill: Hey, Harry. It's Bill.
- Harry over phone: Bill!
Jesus, buddy, how are you doing?
How's Kate?
Fine. Uh, fine.
She's tough.
So l... I was thinking
things must be piling up
- pretty high there without me, huh?
- Don't even worry about it.
I talked to HR and got you
four weeks of paid leave.
I figured you could use the time.
Oh well, you know,
I don't mind coming in,
making sure, you know,
nothing's falling through the cracks.
Don't you worry about us, Billy boy.
You just take care of yourself.
And if there's anything
I can do, you let me know.
Uh sure, okay.
Thanks. Bye.
I thought you were
going to work today.
Nope.
Good. You can go
to the cemetery with me.
Yeah, I'm just gonna
go out for a bit first.
You can stop right up here.
This is good.
Thank you.
Keep the change.
Eric: I want you to eat
just a little bit more, buddy.
Nice!
Eric:
Billy, is that you?
- Trish: You got a workout in.
- Sit down, man.
Your wife made a feast.
Kate: Maybe you should
take a shower first.
Yeah, I think I will.
Kate:
Oh, sit sit. I got it.
Dylan, would you like
some pie and ice cream, sir?
- Yes, please.
- I want you to eat one more.
One more, one more
before you get ice cream.
Okay.
- 'Night.
(sighs)
Woman on TV:
...in your bathroom.
It cuts through
the nasty ring around the...
- (channel changes)
- (laughter)
- And I know some of you
are back home thinking,
"Well, the parents are victims too."
No, they're not.
They raised this kid.
And I don't care
if he's a legal adult or not.
It's the parents who are
ultimately responsible.
And we should find them,
whatever rock they're hiding under,
so the grieving parents
can take a crack at 'em.
But here's the real question, folks:
Do they have any other kids
running around
that I need to worry about?
Because after their track record
with this little bugger,
I don't really want to meet
the rest of the family.
And I sure as hell
don't want the little psycho
going to school
with one of my kids.
- (Bill grunting)
- (racket striking ball)
Hey, I'm still using that.
Dude, we've been waiting
like a hour already.
- Man, come on.
- Dude, I'm still using it!
All right. Whatever.
Come on.
Hey.
Boy:
Oh! Oh!
You know I'm blocking it though.
- (ball thumps)
- Ooh! Ooh ho!
(sighs)
(ringing)
(over phone)
Hey, it's Sam.
Leave me a message
and I'll call you back.
(beeps)
Hi. It's Dad.
I know you're not gonna
get this, but I just...
I wish you could have told me
something was wrong.
You know,
that's what I'm here for.
Well, uh...
I just wanted to hear
your voice was all.
Bye.
Man:
Please be seated.
Our prayers today go out
to the family and friends
of the victims
of this terrible tragedy,
especially our own Patty Larson
who lost her youngest, Jillian.
There will be a memorial service
tomorrow at noon.
All are welcome to attend.
Today we look at Luke 6:37...
"Do not judge
and you will not be judged.
Do not condemn
and you will not be condemned.
Forgive and you will be forgiven."
Eric: You gotta stay on me
for eight seconds.
All right, are you ready?
(imitates bell)
(imitating horse)
Okay, you're choking Daddy.
You're choking Daddy.
Ding ding ding ding ding.
Yeehaw!
Then you gotta throw
your hat up in the air.
- You gotta throw your hat in the air.
- (laughing)
You gotta throw
your hat up in the air.
Kate:
Okay. There you go.
That's right.
- Bill: Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Kate:
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Is Sammy bad?
Uh, no.
He...
well, sometimes good people
do bad things by mistake.
- Why?
- Hey, partner.
Come on, it's time for bed.
Hmm?
One, two, three!
Get some sleep.
- You wanna?
- Yeah.
- Goodnight, buddy.
- Kate: Okay.
Do you want a song or a story?
- A song.
- Okay.
Um...
this is one that Sammy really liked
when he was your age.
#It's all right,
you can go to sleep #
#Finally still and laughing #
#So the world
won't make you weep #
#Dreaming until
the sun is calling #
#And the day will lift
the sorrow #
#And slow your mind
from thinking #
#While the man in the moon
is winking #
#"I love you..." #
(sighs)
#It's all right #
#You can close your eyes #
#I'm never gone #
#The night is falling #
#And the moon
will pull us through #
#Starlight is almost twinkling #
#While the sun is slowly sinking #
#Into you. #
So when does
this grace period end?
Yeah, I know
it's an unusual case, but...
no, don't transfer me ag... oh.
- Who is it?
- It's the bank.
I'm trying to figure out when we can
start paying off his loans.
That's what you're
worried about now?
Who cares when
his student loans are due?
I care. This stuff
needs to be cleaned up...
credit card bills, his Facebook account,
vacation deposit.
Tell me you're not trying to put our
finances in order before we split up.
No, of course not.
Yes yes.
- I'm trying to call about my son's...
- No, don't ignore me.
- Don't ignore me!
- I'm not!
It just took me 20 minutes to get
the right person on the phone.
I cannot believe
you are being so insensitive!
What am I being, Kate?
We have to try to start
moving forward.
I don't want to get
a surprise in the mail
a year from now and have
to relive this over again.
Right, so we're just going to erase
his memory, erase our son's memory.
- Is that it?
- Trish: We're back.
Yeah, that's what I want to do.
Can I have the phone?
- Hi there.
- Dylan: Look what I got!
Oh, my goodness.
Look at you.
Trish:
He got two gold stars.
Oh, you are such a smart guy.
Trish: All right, baby,
go wash your hands.
(cell phone chiming)
Automated voice:
You have one unheard message.
Hey, Kate, it's Coop.
Uh, Coop... Cooper Stearns.
I'm totally not calling to rush you
about the book, not remotely.
I was just, you know, wondering
how you were holding up.
Trying to convert me, huh?
The mission of addicts
and religious fanatics.
I haven't been
sleeping much anyway, so...
So, uh, sorry about
everything that's...
I mean, uh... God.
For a writer you have
quite a way with words.
It's a... it's a talent.
So did he ever give any reason?
Did you ever get a sense of why?
No.
I guess as much as we want one,
maybe sometimes
there just isn't an explanation.
Right.
Anyway, I know
you're eager to see this.
God, when I called, I totally
wasn't trying to rush you or...
No, please. I was grateful
for something to do, really.
Well, thanks for finishing so quickly.
- Wow.
- Oh, no no no.
- That bad?
- No, don't worry about it.
It's not as bad as it looks.
L... I like a red pen, I guess.
It was good, the story.
Not that my opinion matters much.
- I'm just the...
- The spellchecker.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I know.
- But thanks.
- Um...
- I should probably get going.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
Um, well, it was nice
working with you.
- You too.
- And if I ever write a second book...
- When you write a second book.
...you'll be the first to read it,
- you and your red pen.
- Take care.
I picked up some cute little carrots
for Dylan's lunch tomorrow.
Thanks. He doesn't...
he doesn't like raw carrots.
Well, you have to force kids
at that age to eat healthy stuff.
- I mean, Sammy...
- He just doesn't like them.
Okay.
Trish:
Is he asleep?
You know,
he's been telling everyone
his cousin's a TV star.
It's not, but it's almost
kind of funny.
No, it's a problem.
He was playing
shoot 'em up today.
All boys play shoot 'em up.
He's on a cowboy kick.
And your sister is all over him
like every minute.
Do you know she fixed
the fridge doors
because they were uneven?
Dylan sees Bill sleeping
on the couch.
She's playing supermom.
I mean she's everywhere,
doing everything
like this is her house.
For Christ's sakes,
they are not strangers.
He was part of our family too.
She's my only sister
and she lost her son.
Stop being so selfish.
Just cut her some goddamn slack.
(running footsteps)
Dylan:
No no no!
Hey. How was Sunday school?
- What happened?
- Some kids were picking on him.
They said he was going to hell,
just like his cousin.
- Excuse me. Here you go.
- Thank you.
This looks good, babe.
Hey, I just got off the phone
with Roger.
- Who's Roger?
- He's Bill's old college roommate.
He just got back from Europe
and we're gonna put him out for a while.
- What? No.
- Bill: Yeah, he's been bugging me.
- We owe him a visit.
- Trish: It's up to you.
I mean, you're more than welcome
to stay as long as you want.
Bill:
You want to try going home?
Kate:
No.
Bill:
So where do you want to go?
Kate:
I don't know.
(door opens)
- Girl: Daddy, customer.
- Okay.
Newscaster: A man
we still know very little about.
His motives are known
only by speculation...
He keeps watching
that scary boy on TV.
...no real explanation before he took
his own life and the lives...
Doesn't matter how many times
they show that kid going off,
he still freaks me out, you know?
He's like Charles Manson crazy.
- Can I, uh, get a room?
- Yeah.
Which bed do you want?
It doesn't matter.
Well, do you want to be
closer to the bathroom
or farther away from the AC?
It doesn't matter.
Please, pick one.
- You talk to Bonnie?
- No.
Bet the mail's piled up
pretty high by now.
TV's broken.
And I know it's far away,
but we can always go
and stay at my stepmom's.
Kate:
I just want to stay here.
(sighs)
- Should we grab some dinner?
- I just want to lie here.
Okay.
The seven of clubs is missing.
Come on, we should go
and eat something.
(groans)
Come on.
(chatter)
I'll get some menus.
(crying)
(sobbing)
(people murmuring)
Woman:
That lady's crying.
Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorr...
- Shh.
I'm so sorry.
We weren't the best parents
in the world,
but we weren't
the worst either, right?
Right.
I mean, there are
worse parents out there.
But their kids didn't...
Why did he...?
I don't know.
The very best the vending
world has to offer.
Dinner is served.
And dessert.
- Wow.
- (chuckles)
- Mm.
- Whoa whoa.
Come on, come on.
Let's eat.
And you know what?
For once I am gonna do
the cooking for you.
It's a very very old family recipe
handed down through
the generations
- from my old Grandma Winnie.
- (chuckles)
Have I told you about
Grandma Winnie?
- No.
- Oh, she was a very wise old woman.
And this was her favorite dish.
I hope you like.
- Ew.
- (laughs) Come on.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- Mm.
- Mm-mm.
No? No?
Grandma Winnie
couldn't cook for shit.
- Not so much.
- No.
Okay, well, for the second
course we have... ah.
- Ah, Funyuns.
- Funyuns.
- They're both fun and...
- And onions.
And onions, that's right.
Well, you know what?
You can have those.
I'm gonna go for the Lance
Fresh Toastchee crackers.
Not "cheese," "chee."
- (bag pops)
- Whoa!
Ooh, wrong end.
Mmm.
- Mmm.
- Not bad.
(laughing)
Mm, it's a little dry.
- You're so weird.
- Mm-hmm.
More.
Thank you.
- Bon apptit.
- Mm.
I don't know why I never
let Sammy eat junk food.
- It's really quite nutritious.
- Plus it's darned tasty.
Mm-hmm.
Cheers to that.
Ah!
Oh, and you know the best part?
- Hmm?
- (laughing)
No dishes to rinse.
No, but all the crumbs in the bed.
Oh God!
No crumbs in the bed!
- Stop it. Stop it.
- No crumbs in the bed.
Oh, that's so gross.
- (laughing)
- What time is it?
- Who cares?
- So what do you wanna do now?
- Let's play cards.
- I thought you said one was missing.
Five-card draw.
Nothing's wild.
Right. And what are we betting?
What are we, 16 again?
- (grunts)
- I fold.
Oh.
(giggles)
- You're stuck.
- Help! My head.
(indistinct conversation)
(Kate laughs)
Kate's voice:
What day is today?
Bill's voice:
I have no idea.
You know we can't go on
like this forever.
I know.
But we can do it for a little longer.
Yeah.
You want me to come with you?
I'm just gonna make sure
everything's okay,
grab some clothes and come back.
- The bills can wait, you know.
- I'll be quick.
I'll let Bonnie know, so she doesn't
accidentally call the cops on you.
Bye.
Yeah.
(loud thumps)
(objects clatter)
(clattering continues)
(rustling, clattering)
Dude, he's got an award
for perfect attendance.
(laughs)
Yeah.
Nice.
What are you doing in here?
Uh...
What are you doing
in my son's room?
I'm sorry. L...
I didn't know you'd be here.
What are you doing
in my son's room?!
I can't breathe.
- You fucking psycho!
- (glass breaks)
Ah!
Kate:
Bill?
Yeah. I'm back.
- Did you see Bonnie?
- No.
I feel overdressed.
Good. Look at you.
You changed your shirt.
The other one
was getting a little ripe.
Yeah.
- What happened to your hand?
- Oh, nothing.
I just... I cut it
on a piece of glass.
- It's fine.
- Are you sure? It looks bad.
Yeah, it's fine.
It's fine.
Oh good, you got me
some new clothes.
I'm sick of wearing the same thing.
Junk mail.
And what is this?
Would someone be looking
for a rematch?
What?
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah yeah.
I'm just tired, you know?
Yeah.
(DVD tray clicks)
Oh my God, Bill.
- Mom and Dad...
- Oh my God.
Oh my God.
...l'm sorry.
Please don't hate me.
Kate: Oh.
Bill: No, I don't... I don't
want to see it again.
No, but... but it's Sammy.
It's our Sammy.
- No, it's not. It's not him.
- Of course it is.
That's the real him,
not what those awful
television stations keep playing.
- This is him.
- No, it's not. It's not.
Well, it was him
until they changed him.
- They made him into that.
- No no no. It happened...
it happened way before
he got to college.
And l... I don't know how,
but we did it.
We messed him up.
We, uh...
maybe we didn't
give him any hope
or, you know, we didn't exactly
show him how to be happy.
- How can you say that?
- He wasn't well.
He was depressed and...
and irrational
and angry.
Well, everyone gets
depressed and angry,
but that's still no explanation.
We don't know why
he did what he did.
And I seem to be the only one
that cares about asking why.
You keep asking why because...
because you're looking
for someone to tell us
that we're not responsible.
And you keep avoiding it because
you assume we are responsible.
Because he... he did it, Kate.
He did it.
He walked into
those classrooms and...
and he actually shot
all those people...
- his teachers, his friends!
- No, I'm not listening to this.
- All right? He's a murderer!
- Shut up!
- He's a murderer and it's our fault!
You should be defending him.
You're his father.
Well, there is no defense
for what he did!
(sobbing)
I don't want to hear this anymore.
I don't even know who you are!
That's right,
you don't know who I am.
You never did.
You never even tried to.
You don't know me and you sure as hell
didn't know your own son!
Do you want to know
whose fault it is?
It's your fault!
If you weren't such
an emotionally absent
clich of a father,
this wouldn't have happened.
- He... he would be happy.
- So what, you're putting it all on me?
He wasn't happy
because you picked at every...
at every flaw he had,
every mistake.
No no.
At least he knew I cared.
- You and your red pen!
- I was there every time he was sick.
I was the one worried when he didn't
come home for dinner on time.
- And I didn't worry. I didn't worry.
- No! No!
I was the one who checked
his homework.
I was the one who planned
the birthday parties.
I was the one who picked
all of the Christmas gifts.
You... you picked at him.
You picked and picked until he...
till he exploded!
(sobbing)
L... I did the best I could,
but I was by myself.
And where were you?
You were at work.
You put a roof over his head.
But what... where were you?
Where were you?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Go ahead, leave.
You've been wanting to
for the last 10 years anyway.
Yeah, because I couldn't bear
to be with you!
I wanted to be anywhere else,
but I was... I was stuck.
No, you weren't.
You were not.
You're a big boy.
You could've left anytime.
I was stuck because of Sam!
I stayed because of...
because of him.
And look what...
look what he turned into! Huh?
- Look! Look!
- No! No!
I wish to God we hadn't had him!
- I wish we hadn't fucking had him!
- Don't say it.
Don't say it, please.
- I wish we hadn't had him.
- Oh my... (sobbing)
(crying)
Maybe that's the reason why.
- (ball thuds)
- Kate's voice: Whoa! Nice kick.
(young Sam giggling)
Bill:
Harry. Hey, it's Bill.
- Billy. How are you doing?
- Good.
Look, I was wondering
if you wanted to get a drink.
- Harry: Uh, sure.
- How about today?
Hey, Billy, sorry I'm late.
Traffic was terrible.
Have a seat.
Let me get you a cold one.
I can't stay long, but...
- So how are you doing?
- Great.
- And Kate?
- Great...
you know, considering.
- Here you are, sweetie.
- Thank you.
To be honest,
we're not together anymore.
- You're kidding.
- I'm getting my own place.
Don't you think you should just sleep
on a friend's couch for a while?
Try to straighten things out?
I don't have any friends.
Well, I sure hope
you two work it out.
So what can I do for you?
I'm ready to go back to work.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
What did you do to your wrist?
Oh uh, it's nothing.
So what do you...
what do you think?
- Bill...
- I need to do something.
I'm going crazy.
Harry, please.
Look, I gotta get going.
All right, come in next week.
I'll see you Monday?
Thanks.
(footsteps retreating)
(music playing over PA)
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Kate?
I thought that was you.
Hi. What are you doing here?
I was jonesing
for some Coco Pandas.
Goes with your
quadruple espresso, I guess.
Absolutely.
The sugar-caffeine diet.
Um, can I buy you a cup?
It's... it's not afternoon yet.
Let me give you a hand there.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Should I talk about it?
Should I avoid it completely?
Pretend it didn't happen?
I just... no one knew how to act.
Jeez, even your family?
L... I don't know,
I bet all that tiptoeing around
- would get to you after a while.
- No, it's not their fault.
I can't say I'd react
any differently if I was them.
- Can you hand me those, please?
- Was I a total idiot that time?
- Just like a complete, moronic...
- No.
- (laughs) I was.
- Yeah, a little bit.
But you were really sweet.
Thanks for that.
- You want to stay for dinner?
- Um...
Nothing fancy, but...
- Sure, I'd like that.
- Okay.
We haven't had a real dinner
in this house
where we actually
sat down and ate
since Sammy was like
a sophomore in high school, so...
Well, I'm happy
to bring back the tradition.
And it's really good.
I'm not sure I've ever had
mac and cheese
that didn't come out
of a little blue box.
It was his favorite.
Did he have a lot of friends?
Mm, mm-mm.
Now and again,
but he was a really shy kid.
Yeah.
Every year we'd go
to this annual Christmas party...
at Dr. Ko's house.
He was a friend of mine.
And he had this tradition where
before the kids got their gifts,
they had to sing a song
in front of everyone.
- Oh God.
- I know. It was awful.
And Sammy
would never do it, right?
He would rather
go without a present
than actually get up in front
of all those people, let alone sing.
Yeah.
Well, this one Christmas...
he was like nine...
and all the kids were getting up,
little kids.
They were getting up and singing
and getting applause
and getting their present and...
I don't know.
Bill said just to leave him alone.
But I don't know...
I guess I was embarrassed.
I just wanted him to,
you know, do it.
You know?
I wanted him to just get up and...
And?
Then he threw a tantrum
and I yelled at him.
And then I made him do it.
(whispers)
I made him do it.
So he started singing
"Jingle Bells"
and he cried
the whole way through.
And it was like a week
before he would talk to me again.
Well, I hope at least
the present was good.
No, a chemistry set.
He never even opened it.
- Um...
- (sighs)
- I'm sorry. God, I'm sorry.
- No, don't be.
- (groans)
- No.
(groans)
- So tell me about your book.
- (both laugh)
- What's your next book about?
- Oh, l... I don't know.
I just have an idea
I'm batting around in my head.
Can't you just tell me?
No, I can't.
It's... it's awful.
Come on, tell me.
It's just really
the beginning of an idea.
I don't have it
all worked out yet, so...
But the second I'm done,
you'll be the first to read it.
Finished, you mean.
Steaks are done,
people are finished.
That's why you'll be
the first to read it.
Right.
Restroom?
Down the hall, to the left.
Hey, do you want some
apple pie and ice cream?
Cooper: Yeah. You know
I can't turn down sugar.
(sighs)
What are you doing?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was just, um...
You didn't tell me
Sammy wrote stories.
You were doing research.
It... okay, I was...
I just wanted to see
who Sammy was a little bit better.
Stop. It's okay.
Just stop.
I want to show them
that he was human,
that he really wasn't any different
from anybody else.
It's okay. Please.
Everyone is capable of that kind
of rage, okay? Everyone.
It's... it's no one's fault
what happened...
not yours, not your husband's.
That's all I'm trying to say.
Can you please leave?
Okay.
(doorbell rings)
I'm sorry.
How's Nikki?
Eh, she's getting back to normal.
She lost 3 lbs.
We're selling the house, you know,
trying to make it presentable.
- I'll miss you.
- (chuckles)
- Bill's not here helping you?
- No.
That's too bad.
There just aren't a lot of people
out there who can really understand
what you're going through,
you know?
- Bill, hi.
- Hey, Bill.
(people whispering)
(soft chatter)
- Man: You killed it.
- Man #2: Thanks, buddy.
(people whispering)
(sighs)
What is it, huh?
What are you looking at?
Enjoying the show?
What, can't wait to get home,
tell everybody about the killer's dad?
Huh?
Tell them all he's crazy too?
"Must be where the kid got it from"?
- Hey hey hey, what's going on?
- No one can mind
their own fucking business,
that's what's going on.
- All right. Come on, folks, let's go.
- They keep staring at me.
They're just concerned.
They're your friends.
Bullshit. All I want to do is my job
and they won't leave me alone.
- Bill, maybe you came back too soon.
- No, it's them.
They're gawking at me
like I'm in a fishbowl.
How am I supposed...
Maybe you should take a few more
weeks off, see somebody.
I don't need to see anyone.
I'm... I'm fine.
- I just want to be left alone.
- Bill. Bill.
It's not a suggestion.
Well, then fuck you!
- Girl: Hurry up. Come on.
- Girl #2: I'm coming.
Yeah yeah yeah.
(girls laughing, chatting)
(soft chatter)
- Girl: Wow. Isn't that wild?
- (girl #2 laughs)
Oh my God.
I'm gonna settle up.
Your last night?
You going back home?
By the way, some reporters
came sniffing around.
L... I told 'em I'd never
seen you before.
Thanks.
I'm scared he got
all that rage from me.
You know, he...
he called us the night before.
And I keep... I keep replaying it
over and over again in my head,
trying to figure it out,
you know?
Why? Why did he call?
What did he want to say?
He must have been
asking for help, right?
He must have wanted us
to stop him.
What did he say?
I don't... I don't know.
I hung up and went to bed.
And then the next morning...
Wow.
What could you have
said anyway, you know?
Yeah.
(spits)
(breathing heavily)
(groans)
You really have left
a mess behind, haven't you?
But what do they say?
God doesn't give you
more than you can handle.
Not so true, is it?
(phone ringing)
Bill over phone:
Hi, we're not home right now,
but if you leave a message
with your number,
we'll get back to you
as soon as we can. Thanks.
(phone ringing)
He came in to check out,
but that was a couple of days ago.
He hasn't come out since
and he won't let housekeeping in.
I feel sorry for him, you know.
I just don't know what to do.
(knocking)
- You're his wife, right?
- Yeah.
I'm fine.
Just leave me alone.
- Bill, it's me.
- Katie?
Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you.
- (Bill crying)
- Oh, God, look at you.
Oh, angel.
It's okay. It's okay.
- I did love him.
- Oh, I know.
I know. I know.
Shh.
It's time to go home.
Okay?
It's time to go home, okay?
Come on, sweetie.
I know. I know.
I've got you. I've got you.
Come on.
(Bill sobbing)
Sam's voice:
"As the boy and the girl ran out
from their station wagon,
the beach was happy.
It was happy to have
their small footprints upon it...
happy to have holes dug
with plastic shovels.
It was even happy
to have paper wrappers
blowing about after they'd gone.
But the beach knew
that there would no longer
be this to look forward to.
There'd be
no more careless play...
only lonely snowfalls to mark
the beginning of an endless winter.
The beach loved the boy and the girl,
though it had no way of telling them
and it knew that this was
their last time together.
Things would be different
from now on."
Will you sleep with me, please?
Please, don't leave.
I won't. I won't.
Sam's voice: "And it didn't know
if they would be better or worse,
but for certain
things would change."
(folk music playing)
#This is love #
#Following the dream #
#Making things happen #
#It is hard #
#And not all it seems sometimes #
#When we both won't give in #
#Oh, I'm held by your anger #
#And I'm held
by your fisted hands #
#And so it goes,
and so it goes #
#And we begin again #
#Then we lie awake shaking #
#We lie awake breaking #
#And a little bit dies #
#In the end #
#Now we are still #
#And I want you near me #
#Even with words
we can never take back #
#We are always outspoken,
we're wiser when broken #
#And we're able to laugh #
#'Cause this is us
with cracks in the road #
#Lonely, causing
our journey to bend #
#We haven't lost #
#Something that we can't
find again #
#And we lie awake breaking #
#We lie awake aching #
#We lie awake making love #
#In the end #
#Yeah, we lie awake breaking #
#We lie awake aching #
#We lie awake
making love again #
#This is love #
#This is us. #
(piano music playing)
#It's all right,
you can go to sleep #
#Finally still and laughing #
#So the world
don't make you weep #
#Dreaming until #
#The sun is calling #
#The day will lift the sorrow #
#Slow your mind from thinking #
#While the man in the moon
is winking "I love you" #
#The night is falling #
#The moon will pull us through #
#So slow your mind
from thinking #
#While the man in the moon
is winking "I love you" #
#It's all right,
you can close your eyes #
#I'm never gone. #