The Beekeeper.
You're lucky, listen...
Doesn't it sound like a song?
What is it?
It's the virgins who would be queens
beating against their prison wall,
trying to break the wax doors down.
But the guards stand watch
and patch them up again.
Why don't they let them out?
Because only the queen bee
is allowed out.
Others are kept In case
something happens to the queen.
Soon the drones will go for water.
They got there before us.
See them?
What are they doing?
Waiting for the queen.
When she comes
they'll dance high up in the air
and she'll choose one of them...
Is that the queen's dance?
That's the queen's dance.
A film by Theo Angelopoulos.
The storm's ruined It for us,
hasn't it, teacher?
Still, spring is in the air.
Are you leaving tonight?
Yes.
Spring comes earlier in the south.
I'll see you later, Lina.
And the father of the bride?
Anna, where's Spyro?
- Come on, Spyro, old man!
- He's OK.
Smile please!
It's a wedding, you know!
And where did you say they'll go?
I told you, Aunt, our son-in-law
is stationed in Crete.
Do you need any help?
What was your son studying?
Put on another tape, Stefano.
- What do you want me to put on?
- Whatever you want.
A bird!
Don't frighten it.
Open a window.
I'm off, Spyro.
I'm going to get ready.
You look tired. Shall we put it off?
The others will have loaded up already.
No, it's all right.
I'll be there on time.
It's gone.
' Bye, Spyro.
- Bye.
What happened, Mum?
What's going on?
I don't understand.
She dropped the tray of glasses.
It's good luck...
What's this?
Why aren't you all dancing?
- Did you get wet?
- Just my feet.
- Is this the place?
- Yes. Can't you hear the music?
Hello. We've just finished.
- Are you the new teacher?
- Yes.
It was mayhem. They all fought over
who would congratulate their old teacher.
- Our best wishes.
Come on up.
- How are you, Niko?
- Fine, sir.
Do you still set your traps?
They're still upset
about your resignation.
Best wishes!
First I find you, then I lose you
I'd rather be alone...
You've had one too many again.
Spyro?
Where were you?
They were all asking about you.
I don't understand you, Father.
We're leaving.
I climbed up the pepper tree
to pick a peck of peppers.
But the pepper tree
came crashing down.
And cut my hand open.
Goodbye.
I'll go and get a cab.
Well, it's over.
What will you do?
I'll go down to Athens
with the boy for a while.
Now, with his exams,
he hasn't the time
to take care of himself properly.
After that...
I don't know.
I might sell the house.
Maybe I'll go back to work.
What did I do wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing...
Goodbye, Anna.
Take care.
From SA 3 diary.
March 21 st.
Spring heather...
orange trees, clover, thyme...
The trail of the ﬂowers
as Father used to say.
Let's go.
- I '1! be at the coffee shop, OK?
- Yeah.
Damn!
Congratulations.
Did everything go well?
- One more. Make It a double.
- Right a way.
I'm selling everything this year.
Packing it in.
- I'm tired of it.
- Last year there were ten of us, right?
All these years, chasing the flowers.
Departure - just like every spring.
It's been raining for two days now.
Condition of beehives - gocd.
Only numbers 3, 4, 9, 20
and 31 need changing.
Thinning out of the colonies.
Ageing queens.
Departures used to be
festive occasions.
We looked at each other.
Last year there were ten of us.
Now even George says he's tired.
Departure - just like every spring.
- Safe journey.
- Safe journey. Bye.
Drop me off anywhere.
Where are you going?
Anywhere,
as long as it's out of here.
I'll drop you off
at the first opportunity.
Don't worry. No one's looking for me.
Got a cigarette?
Still here?
Hungry?
Come on.
Don't worry. I told you,
no one's looking for me.
Do you want anything else?
Are you going far?
Will you take me with you?
I'm going to fill up.
Present arms!
- Are we there?
- We're there.
Are you sending me away?
No, but that's what we agreed.
Yes, we agreed
and if you change your mind
you won't live until Saturday.
What did you say?
Will you come back?
What do you want from me?
Look...
I have nowhere to go.
Shut the door.
Are you asleep?
Are you still here?
Can you open it for me?
I found a map of yours
and an itinerary.
Will you go to all those places?
It depends.
On what?
On the weather...
and other things.
When will you take off?
I don't know yet.
I like it.
What?
Just taking off...
taking off all the time.
May I?
You don't talk much, do you?
As you like.
All right, Dad.
I'm going for cigarettes.
Can I have 100 drachmas? I'm broke.
Were you asleep?
Talk about a coincidence...
Michalis and I grew up together.
I ran into him on the beach
by chance.
I almost didn't recognise him.
Can he stay here tonight?
He's just been discharged.
He's leaving in the morning.
OK?
Needless to say, I didn't find
anywhere selling cigarettes around here.
Go to sleep, we won't be long...
I'm dead tired.
Pack up your things.
Have you heard that one?
I climbed up the pepper tree.
To pick a peck of peppers
I climbed up the pepper tree...
1,200.
There were three of you last night,
Mr Spyro.
Normally I would have to charge you extra
for the third person.
The beehives...
it's getting windy...
It's 350 x 305 x 300 on the outside
and on the inside it's 260 x 185 x 110.
18 kg.
Tonight I drink with my friends!
I have to go.
The very best stuff!
I've been saving it
for this very occasion.
Shall I lock up?
He keeps returning to his past.
You know, his childhood in Normandy...
his coming to Greece in '48
and the years in prison.
I was expecting you.
I was looking at the tree
outside the window.
Spring is in the air.
And I said...
"They're bound to come at any moment
to have a drink with me."
How are you?
Fine.
And the wine?
Not now... We'll do it when
you get out of here...
- The wine.
- Let it go.
That's not what we came for.
The wine!
- Good?
- The best.
Yes, it is the best.
The best!
What's going on here?
That's not how we used to part.
How did you get in at this hour?
I'd like to see the sea once more.
We're not leaving. We'll be waiting
for you outside. Don't worry.
That first time
was a day bathed in sunshine.
We were dazed by the infinite light.
And none of our desires
could remain hidden.
In vain we searched
for some shade.
- Shall we go back?
- No.
I am what I am, can't you see?
Let's go and look at the sea.
I've been dreaming of seeing it
for two months now.
The sea!
And Anna, how is she?
What's come over you now?
Anna was adorable.
We were all in love with her
but he snatched her away.
I had a hard time getting over it, but...
I remember her...
at the first school dance.
She shone like a star!
I remember you too.
When you first came to the academy,
lost in the crowd.
You were the only one who graduated.
The only one who became...
a teacher.
Beekeeper...
A beekeeper's son,
a beekeepeﬂs grandson.
How many generations?
And he made money.
I wasted myself courting history.
- Do you regret it?
- No!
Here in this town...
we used to dream
of changing the world.
You down there!
You out there!
I'm cold.
Who'll join me first?
March 30th.
State of beehives -
1 to 30- good.
31 to 40- thinning out of the colonies.
41 to 45- beehives empty.
Small purchases -
medicine, sugar, wire netting.
I caught sight of Dimitris in Lamia.
He disappeared in the crowd.
3rd-6th April.
Loan', Istiaia, Atalanti.
Agitation in the beehives.
Constant movement.
It's toe late for the orange trees.
The past few days
I keep losing colonies.
April 17th.
I found an old photograph
taken at Maria's christening.
Anna used to smile and say,
"Don't worry, she's a Capricorn,
she'll make her own way. ".
When she left home, I realised it.
Maria, how did it all come apart?
Where did you disappear to?
Was it something I did?
Haven't you shaved?
Wait.
I looked for you afterwards.
You'd vanished,
but I knew I'd find you
somewhere along the way.
Loannina, Tsaritsani, Andritsena...
You remember the map?
I wandered from one place to the next.
Here and there.
Sometimes I'd like it,
others not.
You know...
You're the only one
who's been good to me.
No one else ever has.
I missed you.
I've got to go. I'm late.
I've come to fetch you.
I'm in the middle of cooking.
Sit down.
I came to fetch you, Anna.
The boy will be home any minute.
Wait a minute.
I want to look at you in the light.
Just a moment.
Goodbye.
Where are we going?
To the other end of the map.
Not like this!
Not like that.
Hello, Father!
- How come?
- I was just passing.
- Will you come in?
- I wouldn't want to impose.
Let him grumble.
I meant to come to the wedding.
I even had a dress made.
He didn't let me.
He's from Mani,
and they don't forget.
We're expanding -
a supermarket on this side.
We need permits, and all that.
- We've work to do!
- Leave me alone.
Won't you stay?
I wanted to tell you I'm sorry
for what happened when you left home.
I've forgotten about it.
I should have told you years ago.
Lowed it to you.
Did you pay that bank bill?
Will you be long? I'm frozen!
This calls for music!
What is it, Father?
What's wrong?
April 27th.
Someone will ask me,
a woman, perhaps...
"Who are you? What do you want?"
I'M answer...
"Nothing...
I was just passing by.
"I used to live here many years ago. ".
Is this the other end of the map?
I'm hungry.
You can get something at the canteen.
I'll be right back, take the suitcase.
I'll be right back.
I climbed up the pepper tree
to pick a peck of peppers.
But the pepper tree came crashing down
and cut my hand open.
Give me your
gold-embroidered handkerchief.
To bandage my bleeding hand
I'm drunk.
You left me and I got drunk.
Mr "I Remember", look at me!
I don't remember anything.
Cine PANTHEON.
Who is it?
- Spyro!
- Yes.
You're back, you old rascal!
Look at the state of the Pantheon!
My brothers want to sell it.
They say it's closed down anyway.
But I won't let them.
I come here every day
and service the old Debrie.
I'll be right down.
When was the last time?
Carnival time, wasn't it?
Let's go home.
May I stay here tonight?
- In here?
- May I?
Won't you come home with me?
My old lady will be heartbroken.
What happened? What's wrong?
May I?
All right, no questions asked.
Are we staying here?
It's better there.
There's wood flooring.
Only a skinny man like me
could fit into the projection room.
Just as if we'd robbed a bank.
We've hardly had time
to say anything.
Will I see you?
Look what I found.
My father's old mask.
So you visited the old place?
Did you see?
It's completely deserted.
Do you have a cigarette?
So I won't be seeing you?
Why are you so sad?
It's not because of me, I know.
Sing me a song.
I don't know many.
Just one.
What's that?
I forgot the words.
Sing me another.
I don't know any others.
DFESS me.
I'm very tired.
Let me go...
Let go of me.
Let me go.
Let me go!
What time is it?
Already dressed?
I'm ready.
Let me go.
Anééoun - Flpouupuovfi - nﬂléTﬂTCl
Movie World Ltd. Greece(Kriti). © 2012