>> Dear Vista,
I've been meaning to write
this note for a long time
but I'm not very good
at expressing myself.
So I'll just say this.
I miss your smile.
I'd say that I hope
this note finds you well
but as these things go..
...that won't be the case.
A few hours ago
I found this girl looking
a little too peaceful
in the last bathroom stall
of The Devoe.
I didn't know what to think of
it. I checked her pulse, but..
...she was gone
And the scary thing is she
reminded me a little bit of you
and just like you,
she left someone behind.
>> I'm sorry you had
to see this, Richie.
A beautiful young girl dead
on the toilet seat.
I mean, nobody needs
that kind of excitement
am I right?
What do you owe The Devoe?
Because that debt is gone.
It's gone, Richie. Okay?
You and me, we're even.
The money you owe everybody
else, I'm gonna look the other
way on that too.
You're like a son to me, Richie.
I feel like a father to you
all these years.
I know we don't
hang out together
but...that's how I feel.
I really feel that way.
I do.
Take this.
That's on me.
You don't owe me nothin'.
Take that and, uh..
just...just keep what you saw
here tonight between us
alright? Hey. Alright?
I appreciate that, Richie.
>> The world is a cold
and lonely place without
you in it, Vista.
I just miss you.
And since you've been gone
I've been accused
of being an observer
a user,
a loner,
a cleaner,
a failure and a fool...
but never a participant.
No.
No one's ever accused me
of that.
Anyway, I decided it's time
to call it quits.
The drugs no longer work.
I'm coming home to see you
and there ain't nothing
gonna stop me this time.
>> Hello.
>> Richie.
I need someone to pick up Sophia
from her school recital.
Can you do this?
I know, I know,
we haven't spoken in a while
but I'm not gonna be able
to pick her up from school
'cause something's come up.
I'm just so fucked right now.
I'm in a fucked-up situation
and I need a favor on this one.
Say something.
Jesus Christ, I know you're not
doing anything important!
You want me to beg you
over the phone?
This is me begging you, okay?
I'm begging.
Listen, when you get there,
there's a password, okay?
Only she and I know it.
The password is "Chestnut."
Are you hearing me? "Chestnut."
Okay? Can you be there
in 20 minutes?
Can you do this
one fucking thing?
What's it gonna be?
Please, Richie.
>> Okay.
>> I've had the privilege
of seeing these children
>> grow and move on
to pursue their dreams
and I must say, this class
has some of the smartest
and most talented children
I've ever seen.
So let's have another round
of applause
for the 5th grade choir.
>> My name is Sophia Holy Hill.
and for tonight's recital,
I have chosen
"Because I Could Not
Stop For Death"
by the 19th century
American poet, Emily Dickenson.
"Because I could not
stop for death
"He kindly stopped for me.
"The carriage held but just
ourselves in immortality.
"We slowly drove.
He knew no haste.
"And I had put away
my labor and my leisure too --
"Since then, 'tis centuries
and yet each seems
"shorter than the day.
I first surmised the horses'
heads were toward eternity."
>> Thank you, Sophia.
Let's give a hand --
>> I'm not done yet.
I will now recite the exact
same passage in Mandarin.
Password.
>> Chestnut.
>> Where's mother?
I have gymnastics rehearsal
in 27 minutes.
If I'm not there on time,
there'll be hell to pay.
After that,
you've to escort me home.
I have a test tomorrow,
I need to be home by 7
in order to study for it
properly.
If I'm not home by 7 p.m. on the
dot, there'll be hell to pay.
>> Well, now that
we cleared that up
I don't know
if you remember me
but...my name is Richard.
And I am..
...your uncle.
>> I don't care.
>> So, what, you, uh,
take school in the summer?
>> Yes.
>> What, did you flunk?
>> No, I'm skipping 6th grade.
>> You're skipping 6th grade.
Skipping 6th grade.
I loved 6th grade.
I loved it so much,
I took it twice.
>> You don't have to go
beyond this point.
>> Okay, yeah. Well, uh,
it's nice to meet you.
Tell your mom I say hello.
>> Goodbye.
>> Dear Vista
you're not gonna
believe this
but I now feel worse
than I did before.
I'm not even kidding.
Still, my plan remains the same
but I cannot bear to return
to the red water.
I'm gonna try a softer
approach this time.
Something that won't leave us
quite a mess.
Normally, as you know, I try
to stay away from the pills
because of the adverse
side effects
especially
the paranoid delusions.
They're usually
the first to surface.
I really hope
it doesn't happen now.
Particularly the one delusion
where I owe people money.
>> Richie!
>> Yeah?
>> You got our money?
>> Who is this?
>> You know who this is.
And you know the number.
It's $800.
>> $800?
Yeah, I thought it was $600.
>> No, that was yesterday.
Today it's $800.
>> Well, what if I
give it to you tomorrow?
What's it gonna be then?
>> You won't have it tomorrow,
Richie. That's the point.
You'll never have it.
>> I'll have it tomorrow.
>> Yeah? How you gonna do that?
>> Don't worry about it.
Okay? I'll have it
for you tomorrow.
I'm gonna have it for you
tomorrow at dinnertime.
>> Dinnertime.
So 5 o'clock?
>> Dinnertime
is 7 o'clock.
>> Dinnertime is 5 o'clock
where I come from.
Yeah? Well, I guess you
come from America.
I come from New York
where it's 7 o'clock.
>> You're full of shit.
You won't have our money
by tomorrow.
>> I ain't full of shit!
>> You're so full of shit.
>> You're so full of shit --
>> You know what I'm full of?
I'm full of 20 sleeping pills,
you pile of dung shit.
So I'm gonna be long gone
by tomorrow comes around.
>> What are you talking about?
>> Yeah, that's right.
I'll be facedown in
a puddle of my own puke
by the time you show up here,
okay? So meet me up whenever.
5 o'clock, 7 o'clock,
I don't care.
I'm gonna be long gone,
you understand?
>> You fuckin' psycho.
>> $600, $800, why don't
we just make it $1,000?
Go fuck yourself!
>> Richie.
Richie.
>> I'm coming to see you now.
>> No, that doesn't work for me.
>> We'll just see
about those sleeping pills.
>> You come tomorrow night,
dinnertime.
>> You just stay right there.
>> I'm gonna be long gone
by the time you come around.
>> I'm already in the building.
>> What?
>> I said I'm in
the building, Richie.
>> Bullshit!
>> There's a party
going on up there, right?
Yeah, Richie.
Party celebrating
the longest day of the year.
>> Nah, there ain't no party
going on up here.
>> Oh, yes, there is.
They're playing music up there.
I can hear it.
>> Yeah?
What song are they playing?
>> It's a good song, Richie.
It's David Bowie, I think.
Yeah, that's it.
It's "Five Years"
by David Bowie.
¶ The way that you talk ¶
¶ I kiss you you're beautiful ¶
¶ I want you to walk ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ Stuck on my eyes ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ What a surprise ¶
¶ We got five years ¶
¶ My brain hurts a lot ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ That's all we've got ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ What a surprise ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ Stuck on my eyes ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ My brain hurts a lot ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ That's all we've got ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ Stuck on my eyes ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ What a surprise ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ My brain hurts a lot ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ That's all we've got ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ What a surprise ¶
¶ Stuck on my eyes ¶
¶ We've got five years ¶
¶ My brain hurts a lot ¶
¶ Five years ¶
¶ That's all we've got ¶
¶ Five years ¶¶
>> I'm gonna shoot you in
the face with a bow and arrow.
>> She hasn't come home.
>> Huh?
>> Mother hasn't come home yet.
>> Are you sure?
>> Pretty sure.
>> Okay.
Well then, I -- I guess
I'll try to make it over there
in a couple minutes.
>> There's no smoking
in the lobby, sir.
There's no smoking
in the lobby, sir!
>> Would you give me
a fucking break?
It's my last day
on Earth, okay?
>> Hello?
>> Hey, hi, listen.
>> Jordan?
>> Yeah?
>> These -- these pills...they
don't, uh, they don't work.
>> Which ones?
How can you tell?
>> It says Opadin, you know.
That's supposed to put you
into a long sleep.
>> Oh, sleep. It's Opadin.
Nah, man, that's not
what you asked for.
>> What are you talking about?
>> I thought you asked
for Zolufen.
>> Zolufen What is that?
>> Yeah. I don't know.
>> Zolufen? What --
what is that?
>> You know, it's for, like,
menopause or something.
>> Menopause!
>> I don't know. Yeah.
>> Menopause? What --
>> Yeah.
>> Why would I want
a menopause medicine?
>> I don't know. I don't ask
any questions, Richie.
>> Menopause?! Ah!
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, you stupid, stupid --
>> You alright? What?
>> Stupid! Menopause?
Really? Fuckin' stupid!
>> Hey, are you
Margaret's husband?
>> No.
>> Well --
>> Well, I just wanted to make
sure she was okay.
>> Yeah, okay.
What's your, uh,
what's your name?
>> I'm just a friend.
She's my best friend.
>> And you think she's here?
Is that what you think?
You know, uh..
...if you're really
her best friend
you know that, um...
she doesn't have a husband.
Even when she was married,
she didn't have a husband.
Hey, who are you?
Who are you?
Hello?
Hello? Miss Best Friend!
Who are you,
Miss Best Friend Person
who are you?
There was a...blonde woman
over here.
>> I bet.
>> Alright, never mind.
Wow.
So she, uh, she hasn't
called yet or anything?
>> No.
>> Is she ever late like this?
>> Never.
>> Well, let's not get
worried, I guess.
Maybe -- maybe it's possible
that she, uh, I don't know
hung out with some
friends after work
or got a drink or something.
>> No. Never.
>> It's not possible?
>> No. It is not possible.
She never hangs out with
friends. She's never late.
She never allows me to be late.
She never drinks.
She never smokes, and she never
has left someone like you
looking after me. Ever.
>> Yeah, well, there's
a first for everything.
>> As soon as she gets home,
you can get back to your life.
>> Did you draw this?
>> Yes.
>> Huh.
Another artist in the family.
That's really good.
You know, it reminds me, uh --
I draw too. I used to draw these
flip-books when I was younger.
You know what flip-books are?
Anyway, I had this cartoon
character named Sophia.
Sophia and all
her little adventures.
Your mom used to love 'em.
She'd laugh at them,
she thought they were funny.
She thought they were real cool.
I don't know.
I don't remember us growing up
with anyone named Sophia.
Sometimes I wonder,
if maybe
she named you after..
...these flip-books
I used to make.
I don't know.
Maybe she mentioned something.
>> She doesn't talk about you.
Actually, she said
you were passive-aggressive.
>> Passive what?
>> Passive-aggressive?
Passive-aggressive?
What does that mean?
>> Look, I have
a test tomorrow morning.
So if you wouldn't mind --
>> You got a pencil over there?
>> Make sure you return it.
>> Dear Vista
this is the third draft
of a letter
that is supposed to only
be written once.
I'm writing to you from
a view of the beautiful city
that I know you loved.
I, unfortunately, need to stick
around a little while longer.
But I'm starting not
to feel so good
and I'm wondering how long
I can keep this thing up.
>> Mom?
Okay.
He's here.
I love you too.
She wants to talk to you.
You can use that phone.
>> Go into the other room.
I give you one thing to do.
>> What?
>> You dropped her off alone?
>> She told me to.
>> She told you to?
>> I don't know what to do.
>> Clearly.
Nothing changes with you.
It's incredible.
You're a marvel
of modern science.
>> You asked me to
pick the kid up and I did.
You didn't tell me
what to do afterwards.
>> What was the plan then?
You were gonna drop
her off alone
and disappear
for another 5 years?
>> Hey, I didn't disappear.
I didn't disappear
>> You disappeared.
>> Don't start with that.
You told me to fuck off,
I fucked off.
>> For 5 fucking years?
>> I don't see you calling me.
>> I called you today. Okay?
>> Yeah. And why is that?
>> I'm not getting
into this with you right now.
>> I made an error in judgment.
>> An error in judgment?
>> Like when you
punched my husband
in a restaurant?
>> Darren can go fuck himself,
that little bitch.
>> That's very apologetic.
Thank you. That's great.
>> That weasel. He's lucky
I didn't kick him in the nuts.
He's still reproducing,
can you believe it?
I should've kicked him
in the nuts.
>> You don't have the ability
to understand the consequences
of your actions.
>> You know what?
I'm all out of sorrys.
I ran out of those
in the 20th century.
>> Just leave the apartment.
I don't wanna fight.
>> What do you want?
I'm doing the best I can.
I've got a kid giving me
permanent stink-eye
old people are yelling,
I don't know where you are
I don't know where I am,
I don't know what's going on.
>> Just get out of my apartment
and have her lock the door.
>> Why don't you have your
blonde friend take care of her?
I'm just a little tired
of doing all the wrong things.
>> What friend?
>> Your friend
looking for you in the hallway.
Blondie McGee
or whatever her name is.
>> What are you talking about?
What friend?
>> Some cracked-out bird was
looking for you in the hallway
said she was your best friend.
I don't know.
>> What did she look like?
>> She was like, uh, blonde
and looked like she was trying
a key into your apartment
and then she sprinted down
the hallway like a crazy woman.
Hello?
>> Oh, my God!
>> Look, Maggie...I don't have
a lot of time left, you know?
I'd rather not
end things like this.
>> You need to get Sophia out
of that apartment right now.
It's not safe there.
>> Huh?
>> Get her out of the apartment.
Go down the stairwell,
exit through the street
not through 3rd Avenue.
>> Go down a stairwell?
>> Just do it!
>> From the 20th floor?
>> Get her out of the building.
>> Okay, so you want me to sneak
Sophia out of the side entrance?
>> Yes! That's exactly what
I want you to do!
>> What am I? James Bond?
>> You see that woman again,
you don't talk to her
you don't interact with her,
you don't do anything stupid.
You keep her far away
from my daughter.
>> So, you want me to
stay with Sophia now?
>> Just do one fucking
thing right!
Please, just do this one fucking
thing that I tell you to!
Can you do this? Can you get
her out of there, please?
>> Yes, fine, whatever.
Okay. Fine.
>> Are you listening
to me, Richie?
>> Yes, yes, steer her away from
Blondie, get her outta here.
>> Take her to your apartment.
I'll call you later.
>> Look, I'll do
whatever you want.
Maggie, but I don't think
she likes me very much.
You know, I think she'd like
to be with her mother.
>> Sophia, hang up the phone.
I don't want her
to see me like this, Richie.
>> Why don't you tell me
where you are
and we'll come over
there to you.
>> Can you just --
Can you just get her out
of the apartment, please?
>> What's -- what's going on?
Are you -- are you alright?
>> This is my one phone call.
>> Huh?
>> What do you mean
it's your one phone --
Maggie?
>> She said to take me
to your place.
>> She what?
Oh, no, no,
that's not gonna work.
>> That's what Mother said.
>> Yeah, well,
she's not my mother, okay?
My apartment isn't exactly
suitable for guests right now.
>> Well, that's what she said.
>> She told me to take you
out of the apartment.
There was no directive
as to any certain destination.
>> There certainly was.
I'm not budging until
we sort this out.
>> Are you gonna picket me?
>> I'll tell her you
find the terms unacceptable.
>> You do what you
gotta do, okay?
We are not going to my place.
That is an indisputable fact.
>> She's not picking up.
What are you looking for?
>> I don't know.
I got a headache.
Something with electrolytes.
>> Electrolytes?
>> Where's your bathroom?
>> What are you doing?
>> Nothing.
>> Why? Who does this?
You know who does this?
Animals do this.
Huh? I don't understand.
Why would you do that?
>> Alright, I'll check
the security footage
see who's responsible.
>> Here's some emergency money
for you to spend on me.
>> Let's go, come on.
>> Let's clear those out.
Hill. H-I-L-L. Margaret Hill.
>> One moment please.
Yes, we do have Margaret Hill
in our system.
>> You do? Okay, so, what,
uh, what is she doin' there?
>> I can't tell you what
she was brought in for, Sir.
I can tell you she was
transferred to central booking
about 2 hours ago.
>> Central booking, okay.
What -- what happens there?
>> She's placed
in a holding cell
and she's waiting
for her arraignment.
>> She's in a holding cell?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, what -- what --
Do you know what time
the arraignment is?
>> Let's see.
Her arraignment
is scheduled for 4 a.m.
>> 4 a.m.?
Are you fucking kidding me?
What am I gonna do
with the kid till then?
>> I don't know
how to respond --
>> Holy crow, I'm fucked.
I'm so fucking fucked.
Let's go.
>> What the hell is this?
>> It's called a bowling alley.
I work for the guy who runs the
place. We can bowl for free.
>> I don't bowl.
>> You don't bowl?
Well, this is all that I can do
for 10 o'clock at night, okay?
It's either this or the bar.
You know what I mean?
>> What are you doing?
>> What does it look
like I'm doing?
I'm doing homework.
>> Alright, so you don't bowl.
Okay, I get it.
There's other things
to do. There's food.
There's arcade games,
there's other activities.
>> What don't you understand
about homework?
>> Alright, fine, but you know..
...do you not ever have...fun?
I mean, don't you
ever let loose?
>> Gymnastics is fun.
>> Gymnastics. Okay.
So you did a triple-backflip
whatever you call it
but you did it with the face
of an assassin.
I mean, where are the smiles?
>> You don't smile.
>> What about your friends?
What do you do with them?
>> I don't have many friends.
Is that what you wanna hear?
Just me and Mother,
and that's just fine.
>> You and Mother, huh?
You ever heard of
the movie "Psycho"?
You know, there's always
a test, by the way.
Your whole life is gonna
be a test, alright?
I mean, sometimes I'd skip out,
I'd not do my homework.
>> Yeah and look
how you turned out.
>> Gideon wants to see you.
>> Gideon would like to see me?
>> Yeah.
>> What for?
>> I don't know.
>> Well --
I have -- I have my niece here,
you know? I mean, I'm gonna --
We need somebody to watch her.
>> It'll only be
a couple of minutes.
>> Get somebody to watch
my niece or I'm not moving.
>> I'll watch her.
>> Get somebody else.
>> Look, I, uh
I have to go for
a couple minutes
um, I'll be right back, okay?
You'll be alright?
>> Richie!
>> Gideon.
>> Who's the, uh,
who's the girl?
>> Oh, that's...that's my niece.
>> Oh, yeah?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, brother or sister?
>> Sister.
>> Yeah? How's she doing?
>> She's in jail.
>> Now that's cool.
>> Calls me tonight,
out of the blue.
To torture me, I guess.
>> I haven't spoken
to her in years.
>> You worked in
The Devoe last night?
>> Yeah.
>> I got this, uh..
...I got this problem, Richie.
I, uh...I met someone
recently, who changes
the way that I see things.
The way that I operate.
It's a, um...it's a girl.
It's not just any girl.
She's, you know, she's red-hot.
I wake up sweating thinking
she won't be lying next to me.
Maybe I'm thinking
I might get burned.
Whatever it is, it's the
worst-case scenario, you know?
I've dreamed up
all the bad scenarios.
I mean, this girl, Richie.
This girl has me under
a fucking spell, you know?
I just can't shake it.
It scares me sometimes,
the things I'd do for her.
>> I know the feeling.
>> I know you do, Richie.
That's why I can talk to you.
Because unlike these other
assholes, you have been in love.
Am I right? With that girl?
What's her name?
>> Vista.
>> Vista. Right. Vista.
>> You're probably gonna
be surprised by this
since you and I don't talk so
much, but when I met my girl..
...I kinda thought of you guys.
I thought of what you guys had.
>> Well, um, what's
your girl's name?
>> See, that's the thing, man.
She's, uh, she's gone,
you know?
She's been ignoring me
for the past 24 hours or so.
She completely disappeared,
you know?
Here. Take a look at her.
Beautiful, right?
Anyway, she doesn't
come home last night.
There's no call, no text,
no e-mail. There's nothing.
I ask around when was the
last people heard from her.
I don't like the responses,
you know?
Something about
the tone of a person's voice.
So, day keeps moving on
without her
and my imagination starts
running wild, Richie.
And I start thinking about other
guys I've seen her look at.
I started thinking about
her friends
that she doesn't know
I know about.
I started thinking
what I'd do to someone
if I found out he bedded her.
I would shackle the fucker up
for a year and I would slowly
and systematically
torture him every day
until he finally shuts down.
I would burn off all
his fucking skin
is what I would do.
These are the kinds of things
I'm thinking about, Richie.
I'm thinking
about bad things.
Right.
>> So, do you recognize her?
>> Richie.
>> Yeah?
>> You do?
>> Yeah, no, I mean,
I, uh, I --
I see her, I see her around
The Devoe sometimes.
I mean, I don't know her, but --
>> Hard to miss, right?
>> Right.
It's the arguments about
the little things that get you.
We got in some
little spat about something.
I don't even remember
about what, and then, poof
she's gone. She's out the door.
You know where
she goes, Richie?
She goes to The Devoe.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
She marches over
to that shithole club
she texts me that
she found her friend Flora
and that was it. That was
the last I heard from her.
I got friends over there.
I keep tabs on the competition.
The bouncers tell me that she
goes into the club around 1 a.m.
and then
she doesn't come out.
She goes in, but she
doesn't come out.
At least, not through
the front door.
You did the late shift
last night, right?
So I wanna know.
Did you see anything?
>> Did I see anything?
>> Yeah.
>> Mm-hmm.
>> My late shift
is later than most.
As you know, I don't...I don't
see much of anything ever.
You know, most days, nobody
even talks to me at all.
I mean, nobody sees
anything in me
and I don't see anything
in...in anybody else.
And that's, uh...that's my life.
>> You didn't answer
my question.
Forget it, Richie.
You're good people,
I just, uh --
I don't know. I thought maybe
you knew something.
You know, it's just..
...my head is just all fucked up
right now, you know?
>> I -- I'm sure that, you know
this will all...be sorted out.
I mean, these things happen.
These fights, right?
>> Yeah.
>> I mean --
Look.
Heroin does strange
things to people.
>> What was that?
>> I -- I was just saying
that I think
>> How'd you know
she does heroin?
How would you know that?
>> I must have misunderstood.
>> What's there
to misunderstand?
You said heroin, I didn't say
anything about that.
>> Didn't you?
>> No, no. I didn't tell you.
I haven't even told my best
friends. Why would I tell you?
>> You said that that she went
looking for her friend Flora.
Flora is slang for heroin.
>> You ever heard of that?
Ever heard of Flora?
No. Boy here knows everything
about that, he says no.
Would you fuckin' lie to me?
>> I had a very intimate
relationship with the lady.
I know all her secrets
and I know all her names.
I know who Flora is.
I know what she does.
I don't know much about
many things, but I do know that.
I have my niece with me.
Yesterday, I would've
told you to kill me
but today I have a niece.
Hey, listen, it's Richie.
Uh...about that girl
from last night
um...Gideon is asking
around about her
and he's...he's saying
that she was his girlfriend
and I'm just --
>> Hold on a second.
>> Hello?
>> Bill. Bill?
Um, what happened
with that girl last night?
Did she --
Did the police show up or --
>> What girl?
>> The girl from the bathroom.
From what bathroom?
Was there a girl in the
bathroom last night, Richie?
Is that what you're sayin'?
>> No.
>> You'd tell us
if you saw something
in the bathroom last night
wouldn't you, Richie?
>> I didn't see anything
in the bathroom last night.
>> Where are you, Richie?
Who are you with?
Let's just make this easy.
Why don't you come into your
shift early tonight?
Say, 1:30?
>> Yeah, sure.
¶ You've heard
all about your raggy melodies ¶
¶ Everything from
opera down to harmony ¶
¶ But I've a little song
that I will sing to you ¶
¶ It's going to win
you through and through ¶
¶ There ain't much to the words
but the music is grand ¶
¶ And you'll be singing
it to beat the band ¶
¶ Now you've heard
of your "Will O' The Wisp" ¶
¶ But give a little
listen to this ¶
¶ It goes Ja Da
Ja Da Ja Da Ja Da ¶
¶ Jing Jing Jing ¶
¶ Ja Da -- ¶
¶ Ja Da Ja Da -- ¶¶
>> Dear Vista, even Death
doesn't want me.
But he wanted that dead bird
who's flown back into
my night again to haunt me.
Meanwhile, my sister
normally Miss Perfect Pants
has gotten herself
into some sort of jam
and left me with her kid.
>> Richie.
>> Devin.
>> I wish I was on
my way to seeing you
but the night is really
starting to get away from me
and there doesn't seem
to be any end in sight.
>> Homework done?
>> This place is unacceptable.
Take me to your apartment.
>> Not gonna happen.
>> I have a test tomorrow
at 8:22 a.m. for second period
and so help me God,
if I bomb that test
I'm going to kill you.
>> Yeah, well, get in line.
We gotta go somewhere.
I gotta pick something up.
>> Is it at your apartment?
>> Is what at my apartment?
What I gotta pick up? No.
>> If it's not to your
apartment, I'm not going.
>> It's just around the corner,
okay? It's gonna take 2 minutes.
>> I'm not going.
>> Game over.
Pack your bag and let's go.
>> Hey, man.
Look, I'll be back
in a second, alright?
Just stay right here.
I'll just be
one second, okay? One second.
What's wrong?
What's the problem?
>> I wanna go home.
>> Look, I'm sorry, okay?
>> I'm sorry.
>> You spent the money.
>> I what?
Your money?
I didn't spend your money.
I got it right here. What does
your mother say about me?
>> She doesn't talk about you.
>> Would you
please stop walking?
Look, I went to
get these -- these flip-books
I was telling
you about, alright?
I didn't spend your money.
I wouldn't do that.
I didn't spend your money
and I don't lie, alright?
I don't lie.
I just --
I thought you'd
wanna see these, I don't know.
>> Why were they in there?
>> Because...because
I used to, I used to live there.
>> Look, I'm sorry, alright? I
shouldn't have taken you there.
I wasn't clear-headed,
I just was --
I thought you might
like to see these.
Would you like to see one?
>> She got shot by an arrow?
>> Yeah, yeah, see? It's like --
it's like Looney Tunes.
See? She dies, right? But then,
she comes back to life, see?
Sophia always
comes back to life.
>> How did you do all this?
>> Well, I was bored, you know?
I was a kid and your mother
and I, we didn't have
a lot of toys or video games
so we had to find ways
to entertain ourselves.
>> How many of them
did you make?
>> I got a box of these.
Like 60 of these.
>> 60?
>> Yeah, like 60 of them.
>> Yeah. Well, I was bored!
>> Yeah, but 60?
>> I know, it's ridiculous.
Can we please get into
the air conditioning? Please?
>> Favorite number?
>> 3.
>> Favorite color?
>> Blue.
>> Favorite book?
>> Don't read.
>> Who's the letter to?
>> What letter?
>> The girl you've been
writing a letter to.
>> Doesn't matter.
>> But I wanna know.
>> That doesn't matter.
>> You know you're not allowed
to smoke indoors?
>> Yes.
>> You know smoking is one
of the leading causes
of lung cancer?
>> Yes, I do.
>> Then why do you smoke?
>> Because it feels really good.
>> You don't look really
healthy. Do you take vitamins?
>> I take drugs.
>> Those aren't vitamins.
>> I know.
>> Do you have a girlfriend?
>> No.
>> Why not?
>> It doesn't matter.
>> Maybe it's 'cause
you don't look healthy.
>> Maybe. Can you please
finish up eating your fries?
>> Maybe it's because
of the bad breath.
>> I don't have the bad breath.
>> Smoking is one of the leading
causes of gingivitis.
>> You're really giving me
a headache right now --
>> You don't take
care of yourself.
>> You're giving me a huge
migraine headache.
>> You should get a girlfriend.
>> I can't --
>> You clearly can't
take care of yourself.
>> Totally believe you.
>> You have to do it.
>> Will you please
stop knocking?
There's a little girl in there,
can you please stop knocking?
Excuse me.
Can you stop...knocking?
Hello?
Will you...will you
please shut up?
Will you please shut up?
Shut up!
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
Shut up.
Would you shut the hell up?
Just shut the fuck up!
Please!
Shut your big, fat cow mouths!
Shut it the fuck up!
Just do it, man!
Shut it, please! God, shut up!
>> Seriously, alright.
Hold on.
>> Listen, uh,
get Bruce on the phone.
Ask him to find out what's
up with Richie's sister.
Have him help her out.
>> What's going on with my mom?
>> I'm not gonna screw
anything else up
by telling you something
I shouldn't.
>> It's from Gideon.
>> How come you guys
don't talk anymore?
>> Well, it's not
just one thing.
>> I wanna know.
>> It's a bunch of things.
We grew up in an unhealthy home,
your mother and I.
She had you when
she was really young.
she was a teenager.
And I guess, she didn't wanna
bring you up in that environment
and I was part
of that environment.
>> So what happened
was you grew apart?
>> What happened was..
...I became a bad person.
>> I -- I don't think
that at all.
I -- I think you're
a dumb person.
Oh, my God! I love this song!
¶ When I learned ¶
¶ Feeling alive ¶
¶ And you know ¶
¶ You were fine ¶
¶ Sharing knives ¶
¶ Cut and go ¶
¶ I just hoped ¶
¶ That you were home ¶
¶ It was the faintest cry
in a sorry place ¶
¶ In the faintest times
I will never forget why ¶
¶ I always liked ¶
¶ You and I ¶¶
>> Come dance with me.
>> I don't dance.
>> Come on!
>> Come on.
>> I don't dance.
A-ah!
>> What happened?
>> Nothing. Nothing.
It's just, uh --
It was an accident.
>> I think you need stitches.
>> You're the public defender?
>> No, I am not.
My name is Bruce Warham.
>> I work for Gideon Young.
>> Who?
>> Mr. Young has asked me
to represent you
as a favor to your brother.
>> My brother?
>> From what I understand,
the gentleman who assaulted you
has filed a cross complaint,
right?
>> My brother?
>> I want you to know
something. I, uh..
...I'm really glad
that I met you.
>> Richie, are you alright?
>> Yeah.
>> You okay?
>> I'm fine.
>> I'm sorry, Miss Hill,
I don't have a lot of time.
Are you aware of
the cross complaint?
>> Yes.
>> You should know that
even though you're the one with
the shiner, he also has grounds.
>> Grounds?
Grounds to what?
>> Oh, my God.
You're bleeding a lot.
>> There's a pharmacy there.
>> No, no, no.
>> I'm gonna go there.
I promise, I'll be right back.
>> Well, he could sue you,
for one.
He could press charges,
although I don't think
that's very likely, but..
...they could try and frame it
that way. You should know that.
>> Excuse me.
>> This man hit me,
he assaulted me.
>> I understand.
>> So why am I here?
>> How can he sue me
if I'm the victim?
>> This man punched a wall
and then he punched me.
>> But you were sleeping
with this man, right?
This man is married, right?
This man has children,
this man has a lawyer
who can frame this
any which way he wants.
>> But I didn't know
he was married.
>> I understand that, but
do you see where I'm going?
>> You're the mistress.
>> I'm what?
>> You're the other woman.
>> I'm the other woman.
>> It won't hold water.
I'll take care of it.
We'll get you out of here
in a few hours.
Miss Hill, it'll be fine.
>> Hey, Richie.
This might sting a little.
>> Ah! Jesus Christ!
>> I'm sorry.
It'll be over in
a second. Breathe.
Breathe, Richie.
>> I'm fine.
>> Then count to 3,
then breathe out.
This is a temporary fix. We need
to get you to a hospital.
>> No, no hospitals.
>> Go to a doctor.
>> I ain't goin' to a doctor.
>> If you won't do it for you,
do it for me.
>> Look, I just wanna get you
back home safe.
I just wanna do one
thing right, okay?
>> Then what?
I'll have to worry about you?
That I'll never see you again?
That you'll be gone forever?
Instead of thinking about
yourself, think about me.
How's Sophia supposed
to go on more adventures
if you're not around?
>> Sophia's gonna have a lot
of adventures, no matter what.
>> I know you're down
on yourself, Richard
but there are much worse people
out there, alright?
>> Look, your mother doesn't
want me around you for a reason
and they have good reasons.
>> You're better than
a lot of people.
At least you wouldn't say
that I shouldn't exist.
>> Huh? Who -- who says
you shouldn't exist?
>> Dad.
>> Dad? Darren?
>> Yeah, he's a jerk.
>> When does he say that?
>> All the time.
>> His life would've
been better.
I see him on the weekends.
>> Life would be better, huh?
What does your mom
say about this?
>> I don't bother mom with it.
It's just noise.
He called me a failed abortion
in front of his friends.
>> Failed abortion?
>> It's just his idea of humor.
It's just the way he is.
>> Just the way he is, huh?
Just the way he is.
Does he still work at that, uh
the store down the street?
That music store?
Does he work there
on Wednesdays?
>> We're closing
in a few minutes.
>> Darren working here?
Darren here?
>> He's in the workshop.
>> The workshop.
Give me one minute. One minute.
Stay there for one minute.
>> What the f --
Richie?
>> Failed abortion?
>> What the fuck are you --
>> A failed abortion?
>> I don't know what the fuck
you're talking about!
Richie, what the fuck?
>> Get the fuck off!
>> A-ah!
>> Fuck.
What the fuck, Richie!
What the --
>> I don't know what there is
to live for anymore, Darren
but I swear to God..
...I swear to God..
...if you say any more
fucked-up things to my sister
or her kid again
I will stay alive.
I will stay alive to make sure
your life is a living hell.
>> What the fuck, man?
¶ There is a house
in New Orleans ¶
¶ They call the Rising Sun ¶
¶ And it's been the ruin ¶
¶ Of many a poor boy ¶
¶ And God I know I'm one ¶
¶ My mother was a tailor ¶
¶ She sewed my new blue jeans ¶
¶ My father was a gamblin' man ¶
¶ Down in New Orleans ¶
¶ Now the only thing
a gambler needs ¶
¶ Is a suitcase and trunk ¶
¶ And the only time
he's satisfied ¶
¶ Is when he's all drunk -- ¶
>> Have a seat, Richie.
>> No, that's okay.
>> We're not stickin' around.
Gotta get her home.
>> I'm hungry.
>> No, you're not.
>> Sure I am.
Howdy, folks.
I'll have some
of those ribs, please.
>> With some vegetables.
>> I don't want vegetables.
>> Put some vegetables in there.
>> These are vegetables.
>> Those don't have vegetables.
Please put some green things
in there. Green vegetables.
>> Got it. Greenish vegetables.
>> Thank you.
>> Guys.
>> So who is this
fine young lady, Richie?
>> My niece, Sophia.
>> Hello, Miss Sophia.
Delightful to meet you.
Precious.
You never told me
you had family.
You never told me you were
friends with Gideon either.
>> I'm not friends with Gideon.
I work for him
the same as I work for you.
>> Is that all I am, Richie?
Just the boss man?
Did you make that date
with Flora last night?
>> No. That stuff will kill you.
¶ I got one foot
on the platform -- ¶¶
>> Is that what you think
I was trying to do?
Hmm?
Is that why you think
I gave it to you?
>> Gave what?
>> 8 years.
8 years you worked for me.
I never asked you for nothin'.
I treated you great
even when you went across
the street to work for that kid.
Never yelled at you,
never made you feel small
never asked
what was bothering you.
>> Never cared.
>> I cared enough
to leave you alone!
I respected that your business
was your own business!
Even when it cost me money!
Even when you couldn't afford
to live in the city no more
I lent you money!
Pretended like you had a home.
Like you had a life.
>> Like we were equals.
>> I guess we're not equals.
>> I was in a tough spot,
Richie!
They see what happened here,
they're gonna shut me down!
That's it! Over!
You'd be out of a job.
We all would.
The dream would be done.
That stupid...stupid girl.
The difference between 20 jobs
and a rock club
that's been lodged on Ludlow
since before Joey Ramone
was taking the 7 train!
It's either that
or the wrecking ball
wipes out this entire block
and replaces it
all with fucking condos!
Sorry.
I'm under a lot of stress.
This MSG will do it to you.
I'm not usually this direct.
I've never been in a situation
like this before.
I'm not the best at handlin'
situations like this.
I just wanted to let you know
where I'm coming from.
I like to talk about
other things.
Your niece.
World affairs.
These fuckin' ribs aren't
doing it for me today.
You're gonna have to eat
more than that, darlin'.
>> No I shouldn't.
>> You asked for it.
>> I just said that
to get back at someone.
I didn't mean it.
>> Come on. It's on me.
You can't quit all at once.
You gotta wean yourself slow.
Well, this will make you
feel real good.
Trust me.
>> I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
>> Alright, well
just make sure
you bring that cute little ass
back here, okay?
>> I have a man now.
>> You got a boy, darlin'.
You want a man?
You know where to find me.
>> You're a repulsive,
pathetic old man.
>> We're finished here.
Come on, finish that up.
We gotta go.
There's nothing good here.
Nothing good.
>> You alright, Richie?
>> Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
>> You gotta come
to work tonight.
>> No, not tonight.
>> You know the wonderful thing
about you, Richie?
It's that death isn't just
a destination for you.
It's a part of you.
It lives in you.
It's woven into the fabric
of your soul.
There's nothing you could do
but embrace the fact
that every day of your life
ought to be your last.
>> Let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
>> Did you brush your teeth
and everything?
>> Mm-hmm.
>> You brushed your teeth?
>> Okay, good.
>> You're not leaving me,
are you?
>> No, I'm gonna be
in the next room.
>> Promise?
>> I promise.
>> Oh, I -- I read your letter
when you weren't looking.
I was curious.
I hope you don't mind.
It's a love letter, right?
Right?
You forgot to tell her
you love her.
That's why it doesn't work.
Why you keep rewriting it.
That's the word that's missing.
>> We're gonna need you
to come with us, sir.
You wanna explain this to us
before we call the police?
>> I'd love to hear this one.
>> I don't remember this at all.
>> You don't remember this
happening a few hours ago?
>> No, I do not.
No, I do not, sir.
At the time that this
incident took place
I was under the influence
of a menopausal medication.
I don't remember much
of anything that happened.
>> Let's take a walk.
>> Until a couple --
>> Maybe you'll remember this.
>> Listen, my niece is up there,
okay? You gotta let me back up.
>> If we ever see you here
again, we'll call the police.
>> Please let me back up there.
>> You have 2 minutes
to get outta here.
>> Come on. Come on!
Dear Vista, I have stumbled
upon a part of me
that wants to see the sun
rise tomorrow.
A part of me that has been
buried deep inside
for so many years.
I wonder if it's better to go
through life thinking
that a loved one who's missing
could still be alive out there.
I'm guessing the answer
to that question is no.
But I've been asked to do
a favor that I don't feel
like delivering any longer.
It's a debt that I need
to settle before I go.
Hey, hey, have you
seen...Gideon around?
>> Yeah, man, he's fucked up.
>> Do you know where he is?
>> No, I haven't seen him
in like an hour.
>> Yeah, thanks.
¶ And it's not like Mr. Shock ¶
¶ To get shy when I'm asking
who is on top ¶
¶ There must be something deep
down in the middle down there ¶
¶ He's not too
easily scared -- ¶
>> Rich, Rich.
>> He invited me here.
>> He -- he invited me.
Devin, it's important.
It's important.
¶ Wouldn't care too much
if he just disappeared ¶
¶ Oh see there he is now
coming down the stairs ¶
¶ He pulled the mirrors
off his Cadillac ¶¶
>> Richie! Hey, come here!
It's good to see you, man.
Hey, I'm real sorry
about before. I fucked up.
I overreacted, okay?
>> You don't have to apologize.
>> No, no, no.
I fucked up. Okay?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
>> You don't have to be.
>> Come on,
let me get you a drink.
I've been thinking
about it, man.
about a lot of things.
And I -- I gotta stop losing
my temper, you know?
I gotta approach things in a
positive and constructive way.
Because when I think
about it, I was 18 years old
when I first got
into this business.
I didn't know what the fuck
I was doing, but I had
a positive attitude.
I took this
abandoned warehouse dumbo.
I turned it into
the hottest party in New York.
I was cleaning 60 Gs a night.
I was 18, on top of the world.
You know how I did that?
I seized the moment.
Anyway, enough of that shit.
Did you say your sister
was in jail earlier?
Or am I just
making that shit up?
>> It's not jail,
it's called Central Booking.
>> She's in Central Booking.
>> Yeah.
>> It's on Center Street, right?
>> She gets out in a few hours.
>> Good.
I was thinking
about maybe picking her up.
>> You should.
>> I don't know
what to say to her.
>> What do you mean?
>> I don't know what to say.
>> It's easy. You just tell
her you love her.
That's it.
>> Who else is gonna pick her
up? She got a husband?
>> She has an ex-douchebag.
>> A douchebag, huh?
>> Ex-douchebag. He knocked
her up when she was 17.
You gotta go there.
Here's what you gotta do.
You gotta go there
and be supportive.
>> Right.
>> She's your sister.
She's had a rough night.
I'm real glad you came by
to my little gathering
I didn't think
you were gonna come.
>> I'm not here
for the gathering.
I'm here to talk to you
about something.
>> I think I know what you wanna
talk to me about.
>> I don't think you do.
>> People come to my gatherings
not to see me
they come for other things.
>> No, that's not it.
I'm not here for other things.
Gideon, I'm not --
>> I got uppers, downers,
I got whatever you want.
You don't have to lie.
I don't give a fuck.
>> No, listen, I don't lie.
I don't lie. Okay?
>> Relax.
>> I don't lie. I want you
to know that about me.
>> Okay, okay. Okay.
>> No, it's not okay.
Because I was dishonest
with you before.
I was dishonest with you.
It's been eating me up all day.
And I try never to lie.
I hurt someone once
by lying and it just, it --
I wanted you to know
that about me. I don't lie.
Okay?
>> Okay.
>> It's important
that you know that about me.
>> Alright. It's duly noted.
>> Now that we've cleared that
up, I need you to do me a favor.
>> Alright?
>> Alright.
>> Ask me what I know
about your girlfriend.
>> You fuckin' with me?
>> No, I ain't fuckin'
with you.
I ain't fuckin' with nobody, but
I wasn't very truthful before.
So if you wanna redo that thing,
you wanna go ahead
and ask about her,
you go ahead and ask.
>> Okay.
>> Okay?
>> What do you know
about my girlfriend?
>> I know that she came into
The Devoe sometimes. I met her.
I met her a few times.
She was a real sweet girl.
>> Yeah.
>> But she's gone.
>> She's gone.
>> What do you mean she's gone?
>> I mean she's dead.
She's dead.
Do you hear what I'm sayin'?
Hold on. I don't know
what you're doing right now.
Why you saying this?
Let me tell you something.
You're talking
about the love of my life.
>> I know. I know.
>> If you are fucking with me --
>> I'm not.
>> The love of your life
died of a drug overdose
in the fourth bathroom stall
of the ladies restroom
in The Devoe last night.
I was there. I found her.
>> What? What?
>> She's beautiful.
She was beautiful to you,
and she was beautiful to me.
But to Bill
I guess she was bad
for business.
>> Where is she?
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know!
>> Why are you doing this to me?
>> I'm not doing it to you!
>> Why you telling me this?
>> I'm sorry I lied to you.
I'm sorry I lied. I didn't
know what to say.
I didn't know what to do.
Whatever you
do to me, I forgive you.
I forgive you.
>> Why are you doing this to me?
>> I'm sorry.
>> Why are you telling me this?
>> I forgive you.
I forgive you.
>> Pull over.
Get out.
Get the fuck out.
>> Your sister's
fucking my husband.
>> What was your plan?
>> I don't know.
Stab her in the eye
with a pen, maybe.
>> I'm so sorry.
I'm never gonna leave you
like that ever again, okay?
>> What happened to your eye?
>> Go back to bed for a couple
of hours before school, okay?
Be right back.
>> I love you.
>> I love you too.
>> Goodnight.
>> Night.
>> I can see it in her face.
She's changed since last night.
You got her liking you now.
10 hours and suddenly
you're Mr. Wonderful.
>> Don't pay me.
>> Take the money.
>> I don't need the money.
>> Take it.
>> I don't need the money
anymore, Maggie.
>>This is just between us.
This whole thing. Okay?
I'm gonna call out of work
for a couple of days.
Just do it from home.
It's work. It's fine.
>> You don't want anyone
seeing you like this.
You called me
because you don't want
your friends
seeing you like this?
>> I've a lot of people
depending on me. Unlike you.
There's a lot of money
on the line.
I walk into that office
with a black eye
with any scent of emotional
baggage, it's done.
Everything I worked for. Gone.
We come from different worlds.
>> I know exactly
where we come from.
And I know that we
used to be friends.
We used to be close.
>> Well, we were young.
And we could make mistakes.
>> Yeah, but I mean, don't you
miss anything, you know?
I miss what we had.
>> Yeah, 'cause you
got to be a teenager.
You got to do stuff
that other teenagers do.
I had a kid.
I didn't have the luxury
of hanging out
with friends
from the neighborhood.
I didn't have the privilege
of making bad choices.
Look, this is just a --
This is just
a onetime thing, Richie.
I don't want my daughter having
any more false idols.
Okay?
So, please..
...if you can just..
...leave.
>> 4th grade, PS 164.
Scottie Evans and Jimmy Knight,
they got to me.
Sometimes it was a black eye.
Sometimes they cut me.
Then one day, you come down
there. You remember?
You put your fist up
real high...and boom
you punched Scottie Evans
on his chin he goes down
like a ton of bricks. I never
seen anything like it.
They said, uh, "You embarrassed
that your little sister
fight your battles for you?"
I didn't think so.
Just seeing you standing
there, you know?
"You don't mess with Richie,
you don't mess with my brother."
I knew the truth.
I had the coolest sister
in the world.
And then we, uh..
...we grow up.
We change.
I changed.
And you go and you have this --
this beautiful girl, Maggie
I mean, she's a one in
a million. She's so smart.
I know you don't get
to be like that
unless your mother
is the best of the best.
And then I realized that, uh..
...some things never change.
You're still the coolest sister
in the world.
>> Look.
Why don't you come over
for dinner on Friday.
Around 7? We'll talk.
But if you're late
or you disappoint Sophia
I'm gonna kill you. Okay?
>> Okay.
¶ I'll be seeing you ¶
¶ In all the old ¶
¶ Familiar places ¶
¶ That this heart ¶
¶ Of mine embraces ¶
¶ All day and through ¶
¶ In that ¶
¶ Small cafe ¶
¶ The park ¶
¶ Across the way ¶
¶ The children's ¶
¶ Carousel ¶
¶ The chestnut tree ¶
¶ The wishing well ¶
¶ I'll be seeing you ¶
¶ In every ¶
¶ Lovely summer's day ¶
¶ In everything ¶
¶ That's bright and gay ¶
¶ I'll always ¶
¶ Think of you that way ¶
¶ I'll find you ¶
¶ In the morning sun ¶
¶ And when the night ¶
¶ Is new ¶
¶ I'll be looking
at the moon ¶
¶ But I'll ¶
¶ Be seeing you ¶¶
¶ When I learned ¶
¶ Feeling alive ¶
¶ And you know ¶
¶ You were fine ¶
¶ Sharing knives ¶
¶ Cut and go ¶
¶ I just hoped ¶
¶ That you were home ¶
¶ It was the faintest cry
in a sorry place ¶
¶ In the faintest times
I will never forget why ¶
¶ I always liked ¶
¶ You and I ¶
¶ It was a dead holiday ¶
¶ I just lost my head
I couldn't stay ¶
¶ When you find ¶
¶ You were lost in the fray ¶
¶ I will hold
my breath another day ¶
¶ It was the faintest cry
in a sorry place ¶
¶ In the faintest times
I will never forget why ¶
¶ I always liked ¶
¶ You and I ¶
¶ You and I ¶¶