50 Cent Before i self Destruct[2009]DvDrip-aXXo
People change
Do you never are together
Where am I
You can enrich you are
You can get high
Or sit and look are during such passes.
Need to be strong
That is, even when they are strong,
because of pressure can break.
All of us are a matter of change.
I love sport.
I used to play basketball.
Now I am a hunter.
I know it sounds funny,
that is a hunter in the middle of the city.
But I will hunt and I fly Do you head.
When it's time to go, go.
Hello!
Life has many twists.
There are many obstacles and people
who want to get beat.
It's been a year than I hurt the knee.
I love basketball.
It all know
Hey how you doing? Work? Yes.
Hey hey what are you doing?
I want to talk
Give me money. Watch your bascheii.
What are my bascheii?
I know man. Give me money, not joking.
Damn man. One day one to beat you.
What do you mean you do not want me doing?
I just want to play basketball.
You drive that car.
Shit! Grabe and you and you get it right
This shit is hard, man.
Give me the rest!
I thought you left me and one thousand
Do you not worry about my car.
Call me!
What do omuleule?
You want the ball?
Where's mother?
It's me, mom and my brother Shock.
Dad left the city
for a job
He probably found a good one,
because he never returned.
What are you doing mom?
Hi, Clarence.
What are you doing boy?
Read.
Why not play as a kid?
Why you always play basketball?
Because they are hard.
Only you seen the trophies.
What are those? These are false.
I have renounced to school, but
My brother is very intelligent.
Very expected.
Hello?
Hello, ma'am Jeckins?
Yes
Sun in connection with son you, shock.
I ve some good news and some bad.
The bad news is that Shock
not careful in class
and have become an obi and nuin.
The good news is that I can answer
absolutely all questions
put on it.
And this reason,
I want to recommend
Program for avansai
All you do is to pass an exam,
which to measure his level of intellectual.
And depends on how big is the note,
may have the opportunity to move
the following class
You complete and csuele down?
Yes, ma'am.
You can go to class.
Do you not to forget the books.
Hi Mom!
Hi honey, how was the test?
I think I've got.
Bravo!
I am very proud of you.
Single mother took care of us.
When things started to gather,
my mother said to me looking for a job.
And mother went to look
How long will the answer?
In 15 minutes.
Ready?
Yes, thank you
Have you ever been arrested?
No
Well
You experience?
There are a basketball player
Basketball?
So what do you think?
As you become a professional player?
It was a dream of mine.
Yes, you those 10 million by other children.
You never bothered to finish high school?
School was not my job.
You know you read?
If you make you read something
I want to know that you can do.
I know you read.
Do you mind wash floors or
if washing something?
Sure, why not?
Ok
Good Clarence, we will announce if yes or no
at the end of the week, ok?
Thank you.
Good to cunosc.Mulumesc you for coming
Shock you know that I love to eat
all trash those, but because
You worked hard today, you've got
those creamy chocolate cakes
that you like so much.
Yes?
Yes
Thanks Mom
A week later
It stops and you
Shock
Good morning love
It's time to wake up
You do not want to be late on your first day,
at your new school.
Come on, please wake up
Clarence
I want to take your brother
from school today
Further work, we need the money
Clarence, I hear?
Yes
How goes the work?
Expect response
Well
Are you gonna find something
See you later
Bye
You have emotions?
A little
This is your new school
Everything will be fine
What?
Look at them, are much better than me
It's good to have a wonderful one days
and everything will be fine.
Ok.
Well
You will be good?
well
Take it easy
See you later
Class, open the books on page 231
As you know,
we talk about nuclear war
Now who can tell
how to call cities
which were attacked
nuclear bombs in Japan?
Shok?
Hiroshima and Nakasaki
He and the E, good job on.
Kevin?
Yes?
How to call cities that were
attacked with nuclear bombs in Japan?
I do not know, right?
I'm not sure.
Normal, fool!
Calmai sure, everyone to stay quiet Tita
Kevin, you must be more careful
let pe d'These are things
It was very funny right?
Leave me alone!
I saw that laugh at me
Let me!
Jegosule!
What took you so long, Einstein?
Was to take a beating, but the teacher said that
not good, I'm upset.
He was lucky, believe me, I was pretty,
I almost beat him.
So what did you want to do?
I love you are with a book?
Why not? A book would be very good.
Yes? Let's go, tough guy.
And like in your new school?
Sounds very sexy
Look at this
I call you
What are you doing?
What do Shock?
Well
Stick head in those books?
Just kidding with you
What are you doing man?
May play?
A little
I saw you play,
should be professionals
I have not seen the others?
Could not pass you
You're crazy
You have much talent man
You were my first fish
No kidding with you
You're crazy man
It is good however
My mother made me take him from school
Ok
And at night the same shit.
Same shit all day.
I understand
Got to go
Let me see
What's the job of my shit?
It's crazy right?
That shit is for gangsters, nigga
What the hell Looking at you with that hand?
I am from Dominique Industries.
Where is Dominique Industries?
Yes, I know, I played with you
Bullshit man
What's with my crap?
Anyway this shit looks good
Looks good
It's like a flash for birds
I cover for him to not give me great
Okay, I understand
May play?
When I get a chance.
Ok, understand
Hell, Tiny and the blacks  knew.
What about them?
Tiny? Fucking went, man.
Really?
Yes
Black shows that I and muscles.
I mean if somebody puts Sean, bang!
Nobody put them
I'm going to go on this home omuleul
Go. Yells at me when you get
See you,
Well
Come Shock
You're okay?
yes
Your hair wants cutting?
What are you doing?
The same hairstyle
Yes
What about Tiny that?
It walks you make shit
I know are on Tiny?
I know only one thing,
when you see a burn to her ass
$ 2.
Let us see you
It is very easy to be trick.
knew not treat as if she did not know me
and how I fix things
Do know and tin with Tiny
Damn
I'll buy me a shame
But it does not say anything,
because I say no it does not
And I work in a supermarket
Yes, I heard this
What the hell are you laughing?
And you work in supermarkets.
You have to go home,
Do you wash you dinii,
You see the plane flying 747.
And I'm going to talk to her birds
It's the grubby job we had a
What the hell is that?
Shock where is mom?
I saw her when I came to school
What are you doing?
Learn
You think you're an artist?
Dream
May you remember when we were in the championship and i. ..
Words are always the same game
Yes
Score was 33 points, NVP
But what are you about this?
Who?
Police Department
Police Department?
Hi, Detective Sillivan
A know the Mrs. Diane Jenckins?
Yes, my mother
Mind if I come in?
Shock go to the Board
I'm afraid I ve are bad for you
Your mother was shot and killed cata
What?
in front of barber shops on Park Street Avenue
Leave a store and was surprised
of the shots in front of the barber shops
we believe that it is
a war between bands
That's my card
I want to call me when you feel able
We have counseling services for you
and for those affected by this loss
have found people who did it?
I'm afraid not so far
but investigations are ongoing
and yet something
I want to come to identify body
I'm sorry for your loss
You're sorry?
Yes
What happened to Mom?
He was shot and how much
After the mother died, I was lost
And I realized how much depended on it
He was everything to us
I was confused
I did not know what will I do
Shock, go
where are you going?
go to work
I have the keys mother
So if someone comes to the door
may not open
not to open
I know there's nothing to eat, but
one to bring when I go back
bring me cookies
d'those that I brought my mother
one to see what I can do, right?
Well, go back later
Clarence
Why do man?
your next restart of much later
Return to work
I washed the floor 5 times
May wash once
Clarence, come to my office
I am very disappointed in you
should call the police
steal?
Do you give me a break and you to me and rewards are?
are fired
Just go here
and to not see you ever
steal shit, what the hell is that?
what are you doing?
What do you do? are you?
are always rushed man
and just stay here in block
drawn from this one to see all slow motion
I just got fired, I gave out
from the supermarket.
You were fired?
Yes
Damn, why you were fired?
cookies taste like shit
yes, chocolate is good
my brother who wants cookies
mother brought him money but I did not so something
Do you put a question to one somewhere
are the Tiny That tells you that?
That in that day that I say?
yes
is the one who fired that day in the hairdresser
are not sure what it is?
d'These are positive things
everyone's talking, it was
I told you it's a bastard
that do not want to fuck
the best man
Do you tell me
take care of you, it's crazy
Well man, I left
Your black tre go home
Tell him I asked Shock
ok see you
I came home and I fired
found an evacuation order on the door
shit
hey, you get cookies?
No, I'm sorry Shock, I tried
never mind, I have some meal vouchers
are you?
I think I know who shot my mother
we need a gun
What are you talking?
do not talk so
I do not have money for rent
but I had enough money for it
knew many blacks are
$ 100 per night
blacks knew knew not why they are able
You played basketball, right?
yes
knew not know anything man
are Frico and, man
he shot a to c on tmpiii  knew
Why does it take so long?
I removed that from the car look so
Where the hell is going black man?
Fuck him
When we shot the Tiny
I believe that everything will come by itself
Clean the scenario
is that we lost free
but even then,
I did not know what to do next
still do not have money to rent
but this will not bring my mother back
Damn
not located what to do
I do not think we can sit together
What are you?
I can not take care of you
need to talk to your Sean
he has it on Tiny
not make any sense what you say
You Focus on school, right?
I think about the things adults
even if I told him to shut up
I knew that's right
and I went to see him Sean
ok, thank you, appreciate you
care of my business
Go directly to the hotel, okay?
See you later man
Clarence
Come on man, what are you doing with that gun?
Ms that you shot a mother was
Tiny of shot mother
Did you shot on Tiny?
Yes, I shot
ok
relax
to talk
come
Put the gun down
listen to me, I never told Tiny
You get one shot your mother
but as I know Tiny, no matter
to tells you something
with everybody we need
someone to love us
some black people fall in love with whores,
others fall in love with money,
others fall in love with action.
Tiny BC and put soul into what he did
That was his thing
black was an automatic gun
I put him on the streets to work
and some blacks deserve to Die
if a shot as a black mother
I would do the same thing you did
and is OK
come on, come on home
to talk about some business
Wait a second
I just bought this cigar
and thou wife does not like to smoke in the house
shit
take place
think are about what I Do you speak
you felt when you killed him Tiny?
I was sorry and a bit confusing
have you ever killed someone?
not so far
you think you have to kill over
If you need
can still think so,
nenorociilor to blow?
Let's think can do you do once?
yes
How goes the job?
you need money?
yes
I want to work for me
I like your style
Do you bring one to some money
Do you bring to 25 thousand in your pocket
What should I do?
to kill someone
with 25 thousand I could I get a home,
take care of Shock,
do I start a new life.
no, no, they are still here
one to do, give me an hour
ok?
ok bye
Sean baby, you got a phone
are Sean, what happened?
And lost his mind
And lost his mind, right?
I like that
I appreciate what you do
OK, stop talking
my man, Clarence, my man
Shok you finish your homework?
Yes
how goes school?
good
I received notes
where are they?
the refrigerator
Wow, the 10 addition to mate,
10 addition to science
and 10 plus plus in history
how do you get 10 with congrats?
I think we need to answer
all questions correctly
How do you take 10 plus to mate?
you they are all
I think we need to give them apples
That's why you get apples to school?
to wash the dishes, I have to go
I can stay up late tonight?
no
not?
OK, but just tonight, right?
ok
bye
He is hoes, you do not I have thought
that's all mine
You want to play with me?
Yes, I want to play with you,
I want to play pool
no, just kidding with you
bitch see there?
do not know what he searches for next
right?
not see what good are they?
I see that are good, but I talked pool
That black near there, she smiled and I get
smiled and you are
that over there?
yes
What do you think?
what the hell you talking about?
I believe that delirium
so what is your name?
Clarence
I am Miss Princess
delighted of knowledge
you see that?
you see?
bitch there not looked at
you since I came here
Who the hell Is that full of jewelry?
like something you've seen
are on here?
could 've seen
I thought are you playing?
I have a question, can you hypnotize
whores in the same room with me.
Yes?
I think you had a chance,
but the bitch still does not look at you
Fri immediately go to the bathroom
ok
let him pick up that fucking brother
why the hell are stops me?
let him pick up that black
you can not robbed you are here
why not occur
with all those jewels here
because we always come here
Why should I just robbed here?
ok
will I think about
because we
to make it on that wretched
on the street corner after
not stay there so often, right?
nigga, you are living up
s funny how things flowing
the money, beautiful things
and meets are all sorts of people
I'll give you look so
because I always stand in the way
this is mix
of 6 to 1
not to succeed and are
Look so is
Yeah, well
I told you not to succeed and are
Look, you Do you show me how to do
May not want to play.
what happened, you tired?
I did so to give Do you trust
what do bobby?
of that for me?
yes
look
I very much appreciate
what you do for me Shock
no problem
you write and wrong answers ite
in this test, not
because nobody will believe me
that we did everything correctly
relax, to get a 7, 85 at test
teacher
Do you will probably 7 plus the test
perfect, are the best Shock
Friend to life man
yes, no doubt, friends for life
OK, let's go
hi baby
what are you doing?
nothing
running
sure, ok, let me half an hour to finish
ok, bye
hi baby
hey
can make a shower?
Yeah, sure.
I sweat, baby
Mr Jenckins
Clarence
Please take a seat
So, like Shok home?
good
spoke of your mother?
a bit, sometimes
were apropiai
was exceptionally here
have discussed options
next semester?
no, not yet
We have 7 scholarships and school for him
Yale Harward, Colombia, Corrnell, NYU,
not to say that for another 14
is incredible
that is, what do you think we should do?
to continue work so,
we have every day a child 13 years
which to finish high school much earlier
wow
ok, thank you
is my pleasure
success
What do Clarence?
well
continue work
good, I'm glad
listen, I like this
be made without mistakes
understand
I want to give a statement
sure, sure
Hey Betty, get me some cheese please
ok,
are what I mean,
that is to be without mistakes
I can not leave them on the "knew what we do
hey baby
Clarence, she is my wife, Betty
Betty it is one of my associations
Very happy of knowledge Clarence
I heard many nice things about you
thank you, have a very beautiful house
Sean is right, insurance is a
great way to live
Hey Clarence, you hungry?
I see that are very warm,
but you smell good
stay for dinner
Yes, remain
baby, bring a plate
let's talk
Clarence's younger brother, SHOCK
is a genius
really?
is the wait
Come let me, it is the wait
is modest
listen, myV Shock was accepted,
Harward and Yale
and guess what,
less than 13 years and has tiul, do you?
yes it is true
I think you're very proud of him
yes, I
baby, Clarence and I need to talk
about some insurance, so I
to not bring us in the desert Ala and wonderful?
have to try it
Fri immediately
listen, I have an automatic gun
next mission
an automatic?
yes
not finish the job in seconds?
go to the dog, he will take care of you
ok
hey baby
Clarence, you must try this
My wife is a wonderful cook
not praise me
is good not you?
yes
my wife knows to cook
I do not want to boast...
How did you get insurance?
We know from high school, he played basketball
and broke his legs and knees.
Basketball?
yes
and I with some guys from my team,
He came to me, was very hard working
started from scratch
did a wonderful job,
is best of all
man they know
and he wanted to play basketball
baby does not begin with this
mia not say never
I was very good at running
hey mama
do me a favor
hiding knew for me
I only half ago
Check this out 5 thousand
take it easy, take time, everything will be fine
go
yes, go
is your bike?
no, not mine
yes, mine
go?
da go
let me go with her
Do you give $ 100
damn
sure are going
go brother
ok
everyone will eat
not much I like Sean
nobody likes
that is, if so be, so will be
I just know are B, are ready to go
know that you should not drink directly from the bottom
anyway not drink none but you and me
take, can use the cup, as ordinary people
know that not doing so while living mother
pray
give me ketchup?
You thought what you do when you grow up?
are too young to think about it
not think of anything serious
until you graduate
you choose whether you should choose now?
do not know
Wait I know, I want to have a big family
I want some 6 or 7 children
6 or 7?
and want a beautiful wife
to love me so as my mother loved me
6 or 7? You are a gracious
And you?
one to do what I do now
you can not do that always
why not?
How many husbands of 30 years and know you?
Who will take care of you?
Well you have P you to take care of me
one to take care of Uncle Clarence
to have a 6 or 7 children
to take care of me?
ok, I test results at
Mosse, you did a good job
but more than you work
excellent, keep it up so
Bobby's done a good job
I know you have much potential, keep it up so
thank you
I know that you said that you've seen?
I remember
Where?
in a supermarket
spent and are looking
and to not tell me anything?
because we work in a supermarket
you were one and APCA Gucci, Gucci pants
Gucci bag, you were wonderful
thanks
what do you like to live?
not working
Well and what do you do?
of family wealth?
yes
and why not have friends?
because people do not know me
so how do you
What made you ask me that?
I did not want to guess
sure you want this job? a little heavy
no one you know me think
why do not you have friends?
because I know you I choose
should one take as a compliment
Yes, should be
The food is very good
mine is better, want to try?
yes
is good right?
yours is good?
yes
and give me one thousand
in my food?
Yes, let me try
why do not you have ordered
if you wanted to try?
please?
This is how I ruin reputation, girl
Oh, shit
Clarence, who's your new friend?
Shok she is Princess, Princess he's Shock
delighted of knowledge
delighted
are very nice, what a gentleman
it will take care of you as the mother
will take care of me?
no, I'll take care of it
what you did my little brother?
You know you for 5 min
and already in love with you
Why look at me with that eye?
You finished your homework?
yes
Do you let show house
Hey Rafael
Hello Mrs. Ortiz
Tess is home?
No, I have some job
What you been Rafael?
not told?
mia not say no
I had some problems, but now it's all right
You want them to and a message?
maybe I could
to use the house phone
ok, go
Take it. You have not fought it?
no, do not be ridiculous, we love
ok, ya
hey mama
not your mother, your boy?
what are you doing?
Who is this?
What do you mean jokes are not?
I am, where are you?
are in the city
Why do the city?
visit my cousins and orului,
where did you get this number?
when you? you wearing as if
Do not have a right to know where you are.
I call you when I come baby, by the close to
What the hell?
hey baby?
Who to ask?
was the mother wanted to go to see her Friday
what the hell is wrong with you?
What took you so long?
I do not know who the hell do you think,
but you better call me back
OK, ma'am Ortiz, TRE to go
take care of you Rafael.
OK, see you later
I heard you're very iste Shock
can you say so
so it is right
behind your books
ok, who won presidential elections
in John Addams?
that's easy Princess.
Thomas Jefferson certainly
ok
I told you that boy is a genius
Who assassinated Abraham Lincoln?
John Books in shot
was president and when he shot him?
were both in theater
bleeding
what do then?
Part "I am the president of America
I thought you did
Who wrote Alla Goree
Plato
who can do so what?
is the most in shape in this stuff d'
look at sports?
no.
ok, well
Who won the cup in 1975?
The New York Dallas
Who was SuperBoll NVP to 5?
I did, I told you
I knew I did
Chuck Walley won
to SuperBoll. Next
I did so
So I pcleai not?
ready you won, you can not beat
omuleul This is like a computer, I told you
not know are Russian transferee
no one here
I would have to beat it
I could ask him
what uses it
let me ask you something
what baby?
trust me?
course that I trust you
what are you doing?
you up to something?
not have to do something
to make a motion
not put to something
OK, come, close your eyes.
come back and close your eyes
take your hands
thank you much baby.
love you
and I love you baby
why did you bring in the basement, man?
my turn to wash clothes
why not Do you get a housekeeper
to do this nonsense?
I do not need me a slut
to walk in my stuff
My chiloii and all these are private
listen, we have a problem
What?
Is that by fleeing,
now know all blacks.
They talked with the police?
so I
and have someone tell me everything
and my name is everywhere
and why not arrange it?
We can not arrange anything
we must take care of shit
you need money?
May I in that the last time
to tells you something about life
never get tired of this shit
I feel?
can take care of the rest of this
tre to go up, otherwise my wife
and i will realize that I do not insured
How not know why you do?
I question it every night
will you look, you can exit through the rear
I know not the best
in connection with school and stuff,
but I learned to talk more and
to be careful what I say
so not so good at conversation
I have little sympathy, but more money
at least I think so
that a fall
what do bobby?
Why do man?
Do you like basketball?
yes, who does not like basketball?
but video games?
course
look.
you here, man?
ooo, this is a new shit
where you got Shock?
tells you something, you can get
words are serious?
Yes, I take care of you, you for me
course
damn, where the hell are these bitches?
I love you are a baby
Do you buy one to heart
You are one so as not made you one
Who the hell is it?
just like your brother, you look like a gangster
are very nice
hey baby how are you?
surprise, come back
what the hell is this shit?
She did a
do not dress so, it's a good kid
does this stuff d'
exaggerate, was not even something serious
Yes it is, so there is something
was not my idea
come on, I asked to take care of him
not to do this shit d'
I'm sorry
is given hell
Shock you know are best
than this shit
I'm glad of knowledge
See you later
Is that for which it tells you
not a man so good
I appreciate what you did
and respect what you do
knew that I knew,
are very good business are
yes
are very satisfied
and I think are very stylish
I love how you take care of you
knew him see here?
I could not pick it up on Tiny
in a place like this
because it was not healthy
embarrassed me many times
Fuck him devil Ala
so, give it hell devil Ala
listen, that thing you made a
the bitch who spoke more
was their problem and they did all this
Do you like to show how much I appreciate
are the job, tell them thank you
if you leave the city,
May we never see asses together.
therefore celebrate
whoever said that money does not buy happiness,
was sure broke.
Money means freedom
freedom to do what you want
Do you need to fill
Why do baby?
but there is nothing which can not buy
Let's go
you miss me?
normal that I miss you baby
yes?
you know so it
come here
stay baby stay
slowly, slowly
damn baby
That's it?
What do you mean?
2 minutes?
I have not done this time
best 2 minutes of your life
I'm sure you fantasies with this 2 min?
you have not had fantasies as I was not home?
No, I had
yes you were
2 minute
that's all I have to say
Baby will you reward
where are my papers?
I need them
Why Why you, why not answer
where the hell are my papers?
what the hell is wrong with you?
Why the quiet tea that?
where are my papers?
Clarence
how the hell Clarence?
I have given my money to a black?
Who the hell is Clarence?
I'm sorry baby
Do you like that is sorry?
Who the hell is Clarence?
Who the hell is Clarence, slut?
I'm sorry
Do you like that is sorry?
Who the hell is Clarence?
take that phone and Call him here now
take that phone and Call Now That black
You do not know anything
well well
What?
Hey Clarence
I am Princess
I want you up here baby
nothing
are you?
yes, well
well baby
I want you up here, please
mother and took a couch and
not to a sole
We can introduce you to me?
ok
I can not bitch
I sold the car and I gave you everything
and you so are rewards me?
so are rewards me?
what the hell is wrong with you?
I can not believe
I'm sorry
Do you like that is sorry?
was Princess, wants to go to a help
her mother with a sofa
can I come and I,
I want to know her mother
no, wait and do your homework and go back
ok
why the hell are you crying?
what the hell is wrong with you?
and you were thinking about me when you fuck
with black Ala Clarence?
what the hell is wrong with you slut?
are bad bad
I'm sorry baby
how the hell Do you sorry?
all you have is because of me, my
I'm sorry baby, please
I can not believe
let me the hell alone
That there black?
with everybody we need someone
You love us,
Some blacks in love of whores,
some blacks of lovers of money,
Some blacks in love of action.
How about you? What do you have?
go fast, you do not stand much
where is my brother?
had to go a few days
Do you told me to say
would not do that, I would be called and
I would have said if leaves
Well it did not
what you did to my brother?
nothing
I'm not lying, what you did?
nothing, I did not do anything your brother
if something happens to my brother
I will find hooker
tre to go
can not do that always
why not?
I can not lose anything.
I have nothing to lose
Di Terjemahkan oleh
FadLyBronz a.k.a SkeeZy