*** FILME JÁ ***
http://www.filmeja.com/
DOWNLOAD DE FILMES E SÉRIES
[ Children Shouting ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Water Running ]
[ Bird Calling ]
[ Metal Banging ]
???? [ Classical On Piano ]
[ Girl Narrating ]
YOUR WHOLE LIFE CAN CHANGE
IN A SECOND,
AND YOU NEVER EVEN KNOW
WHEN IT'S COMING.
BEFORE, YOU THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT KIND OF WORLD THIS IS.
AND AFTER,
EVERYTHING IS DIFFERENT FOR YOU.
NOT BAD, MAYBE,
NOT ALWAYS...
BUT DIFFERENT... FOREVER.
???? [ Piano Continues ]
[ Girl ]
I DIDN'T USED TO KNOW THAT...
'TIL THE DAY IT HAPPENED
TO MY FAMILY.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THERE COULD BE
SUCH A THING AS "AFTER."
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT, FOR US,
"BEFORE" WAS ALREADY OVER.
[ Hits Wrong Note ]
???? [ "Chopsticks"
Drowns Out Classical ]
[ Both Laugh ]
[ Giggling ]
T.J., THIS WON'T HURT.
I PROMISE.
THIS IS MY SPECIAL
BOO-BOO LIGHT.
IN FACT, IT'S MAGIC.
DID YOU EVER SEE A MAGIC
BOO-BOO LIGHT BEFORE?
[ Woman ]
HE HAD NO BUSINESS
BEING ON HIS BROTHER'S SLED.
DARN THING'S
BIGGER THAN HE IS.
YOU'RE NEEDED DOWNSTAIRS.
[ People Murmuring ]
T.J.'S A LUCKY BOY,
MRS. FOLEY, BUT I'D
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
IF HE COMPLAINS
OF NAUSEA OR DIZZINESS,
OR EVEN IF HE JUST SEEMS
DROWSIER THAN NORMAL,
GIVE ME A CALL, OKAY?
THAT'S NOT MAGIC.
THAT'S JUST A FLASHLIGHT.
OH, YEAH?
HERE. BLOW.
SEE?
[ Giggles ]
SEE YOU LATER.
SHE'S GONE, TRYGVE.
NO, DAMN IT.
THERE'S STILL A CHANCE.
[ Trygve ]
GIVE ME THAT.
[ Doctor ]
TRYGVE, SHE'S GONE.
SHE WASN'T GONNA
MAKE IT ANYWAY.
[ Man ]
WE DID OUR BEST.
LET'S BREAK IT DOWN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
[ Doctor ]
SOME BASTARD CLOBBERED HER...
UP NEAR POOR FARM ROAD,
THEN LEFT HER THERE.
SHE WAS LYING IN THE SNOW
BY THAT POND.
DO WE KNOW WHO THIS IS?
[ Trygve ]
MARTHA TAVERNER.
MM-HMM.
OH. I'VE MET HER.
I EVEN TREATED HER ONCE,
I THINK, WHEN YOU WERE ON
VACATION, TRYGVE. REMEMBER?
YEAH.
[ Trygve ]
HE'S STILL OUT THERE,
WHOEVER DID THIS.
COULD BE ANYWHERE.
[ Girl ]
HEY, DAD. "THREE OUNCES
GROUND CUMIN SEED"?
MM-HMM.
YUCK!
WHAT'S CUMIN SEED?
OH-HO-HO-HO.
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY
THE MOST CRUCIAL,
FANTASTIC,
TOP-SECRET INGREDIENT
IN MY ENTIRE CHILI.
[ Door Slamming ]
[ Girl ]
HI, MOM!
HI. JACOB!
JAKE'S PARKING IS GETTING
SLOPPIER THAN EVER.
MAN! HIS CAR
IS ALL OVER THE PLACE.
BEN? I SWEAR I COULD HARDLY
EVEN GET MINE IN THE GARAGE.
PARKING IT RIGHT WOULD FEEL
TOO MUCH LIKE WORK.
MM.
[ Chuckles ]
HI.
LET ME HAVE SOME.
HEY, YOU'RE TREMBLING.
MM.
I'M JUST... COLD.
SIT DOWN.
[ Girl ]
DAD, THIS STUFF'S FREAKING OUT!
IN A MINUTE.
CAROLYN, WHAT--
[ Deep Sigh ]
WE HAD AN EVENT
AT THE HOSPITAL TODAY.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
"EVENT"?
DAD, COME QUICK!
[ Doorbell Rings ]
AHHH.
FRAN!
DR. RYAN.
[ Chuckling ]
YOU HAVEN'T CALLED ME "DOCTOR"
SINCE WE FIRST MOVED UP HERE.
HI, MOM.
BEN.
HEY THERE, CHIEF.
OUT OF UNIFORM TODAY.
WHAT'S UP?
UH, SORRY TO BARGE IN
ON YOU LIKE THIS,
RIGHT HERE AT SUPPERTIME.
- GET YOU SOMETHING, FRAN?
A BEER, IF YOU'RE NOT ON DUTY.
- NO, NO, BEN.
THAT'S OKAY.
THANKS. UM--
[ Sighs ]
IS JACOB AROUND?
HE'S UP IN HIS ROOM, I GUESS,
WITH THOSE DAMN HEADPHONES ON.
YOU KNOW JACOB.
YOU DIDN'T
SEE HIM COME IN?
I WAS IN THE STUDIO.
DO YOU NEED HIM FOR SOMETHING?
YOU WANT US TO GET HIM, FRAN?
I'LL GO.
YEAH, GO ON, HONEY.
IS THERE
SOMETHING WRONG?
[ Expelling Air ]
OKAY, UH--
SOMETHING HAPPENED
OUT ON POOR FARM ROAD TODAY.
SOMETHING PRETTY BAD.
A GIRL
GOT HERSELF KILLED.
- I KNOW. I SAW HER.
- WHAT?
WE HAD HER IN E.R.
BEYOND SAVING.
I MEAN, IT WAS--
IT WAS AWFUL.
GEEZ.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS GONNA
TELL YOU WHEN I CAME IN.
GOD, I'M SORRY.
WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO
WITH JACOB?
OH, GOD,
I DON'T--
I DON'T WANNA
HAVE TO TELL YOU THIS.
I REALLY DON'T.
JACOB WAS SEEN
WITH THE GIRL.
HE PICKED HER UP
FROM WORK.
SHE WORKS DOWN
AT JACEY'S AFTER SCHOOL,
MAKING ICE CREAM CONES.
HE CAME BY IN HIS CAR,
AND THEY WENT OFF TOGETHER,
LIKE THEY'D BEEN DOIN'.
AS FAR AS WE KNOW,
RIGHT NOW,
HE WAS THE LAST PERSON
WITH HER.
ARE YOU SAYING JACOB
WAS DATING THAT GIRL,
MARTHA TAVERNER?
NO, NO. WHAT HE'S--
WHAT HE'S SAYING IS HE'S--
[ Chuckles ]
HE'S STANDING HERE
IN OUR KITCHEN...
SAYING THAT HE THINKS
OUR SON WAS--
OH, FOR CRYING
OUT LOUD, FRAN.
BEN, HEY, HEY.
LET'S NOT JUMP THE GUN HERE.
I JUST NEED TO TALK TO HIM.
JACOB!
JESUS CHR--
HE'S NOT UP THERE.
I LOOKED ALL OVER.
WELL, THAT'S CRAZY.
I-I-- HIS CAR'S
IN THE GARAGE.
I JUST SAW IT.
YOU HAVE A SPARE
SET OF KEYS
FOR THE CAR?
YEAH, I THINK THAT I DO.
DADDY.
SOMETHING'S HAPPENED,
JUDITH, BUT THERE'S BEEN
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
WE'LL EXPLAIN LATER, OKAY?
MM-HMM.
OKAY, WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
DO WHAT?
YOU CAN'T GO SNOOPING AROUND
IN SOMEBODY ELSE'S CAR.
LEGALLY, THAT'S MY CAR.
YOU DO NOT HAVE
A SEARCH WARRANT.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
I'M SURE THERE'S SOME
VERY SIMPLE EXPLANATION
FOR ALL OF THIS.
JACOB AND THE TAVERNER GIRL
MUST HAVE SEPARATED SOMEHOW
BEFORE THIS EVEN HAPPENED.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE HE JUST
DROPPED HER OFF SOMEWHERE.
MAYBE SHE GOT OUT
OF THE CAR AND WALKED AWAY.
THERE'S A THOUSAND DIFFERENT--
FRAN, HOW DO WE KNOW
HE'S ALL RIGHT?
MAYBE SOME MADMAN DID SOMETHING
TO BOTH OF THEM, AND MAYBE
JACOB'S HURT, OR HE'S KIDNAPPED.
OH, MY GOD.
CAROLINE, FOR HIS OWN SAKE,
THAT CAR MIGHT GIVE US
SOME ANSWERS.
NO.
[ Gasps ]
[ Sighs ]
YOU'RE HIS PARENTS.
YOU WANNA PROTECT HIM.
I GOT KIDS TOO,
BUT--
BEN, IS THERE SOMETHING
THAT YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE
NOT TELLIN' ME?
HOW 'BOUT IT, JUDITH?
YOU KNOW ANYTHING--
HEY! HEY!
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
OFF LIMITS! LEAVE HER
OUT OF THIS, OKAY?
OKAY, PLEASE, PLEASE, BEN.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I KNOW.
IT'S JUST FRAN.
I KNOW
MY SON!
HE'S JUST TRYING TO HELP US
FIND HIM, DARLIN'.
I DON'T WANT IT TO BE LIKE THIS.
BUT IF I HAVE TO,
I WILL GO FIND JUDGE GRADY,
AND I WILL GET A SEARCH WARRANT.
YEAH, YEAH.
YOU DO THAT!
AND I WILL BE
RIGHT BACK HERE.
IT'S OKAY.
OKAY.
SWEETIE, YOU LOOKED UPSTAIRS?
YOU'RE SURE?
YOU LOOKED EVERYPLACE?
[ Car Engine Starts ]
WE SHOULD HAVE LET HIM
LOOK IN THE CAR, BEN.
THE HELL WE SHOULD HAVE.
NOT WITHOUT A LAWYER
TELLING ME I HAVE TO.
LOOK, WE'VE GOT
RIGHTS HERE.
AND WHEREVER HE IS,
WHATEVER THEY THINK HE DID,
JACOB HAS RIGHTS TOO.
WE'LL JUST HAVE TO TAKE THIS
ONE STEP AT A TIME, OKAY?
YOU AND I WILL LOOK
IN THE HOUSE.
TOP TO BOTTOM.
I'LL CHECK OUT
THE GARAGE AND STUDIO.
AND IF HE'S NOT THERE, WE'LL
JUST START CALLING HIS FRIENDS.
CAROLYN.
BETTER CALL
WENDELL TOO. HUH?
[ Squeaking ]
[ Chuckles, Grunts ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Panting ]
OH, NO.
OH, JAKE.
[ Panting ]
I KNOW THAT, WENDELL.
[ Judith ]
MOM?
WAIT, WAIT.
WHEN FRAN COMES BACK,
WE'LL BE PERFECTLY--
[ Carolyn ]
I KNOW IT'S A SMALL TOWN,
BUT IT'S OUR TOWN TOO.
HE WILL. I PROMISE.
I PROMISE.
JUST HURRY, OKAY?
LAWYERS.
MOM?
YEAH.
JACOB WAS REALLY MAD
THIS MORNING.
SAID HE MIGHT NOT
EVEN GO TO SCHOOL.
WHY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE AND DADDY, WELL--
YOU KNOW, THEY,
THEY HAD ANOTHER FIGHT.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW THAT JACOB
WANTS TO RENT A BIG CAR
FOR THE WINTER DANCE...
AND, LIKE, RIDE AROUND
ALL NIGHT?
SO DADDY GOES,
"HOW ARE YOU PLANNING
TO PAY FOR IT?
"WE'VE GOT RULES ABOUT
THIS SORT OF THING, MISTER.
IT'S TIME YOU LEARN TO PAY
YOUR OWN WAY, JACOB."
MOM, HE KNOWS JAKE
COULD NEVER SAVE UP
IN TIME. HE KNOWS THAT.
MM-HMM.
BUT, LIKE, JAKE'S
SUCH A BIG DOPE.
HE ALREADY PROMISED RIDES
TO ALL HIS CREEPY FRIENDS.
HE'S ALREADY BRAGGED
ABOUT IT TO MARTH--
MARTHA?
YOU KNEW ABOUT THIS GIRL?
JUDE, HOW LONG HAVE
THEY BEEN GOING OUT?
SINCE SEPTEMBER.
BUT HE MADE ME SWEAR
I WOULDN'T TELL.
JAKE SAID TO DADDY,
"YOU THINK 'CAUSE YOU'RE
THIS BIG ARTIST,
IT'S LIKE RULES DON'T APPLY
TO YOU, BUT THEY SHOULD
ALWAYS APPLY TO ME."
"YOU'RE A HYPOCRITE,"
JAKE SAID.
AND THEN DADDY--
DADDY JUST TOTALLY LOST IT.
BUT IT WAS
NEVER THAT BAD.
OH.
MOM, I'M SO SCARED.
HMM.
YOU DIDN'T SEE
THEIR FACES.
YOU WEREN'T THERE.
WELL, DADDY JUST-- HE WANTS
JACOB TO BE MORE RESPONSIBLE, SO
HE TRIES TO CHALLENGE HIS PRIDE.
MAYBE TOO HARD SOMETIMES,
BUT THAT'S LOVE, JUDE.
[ Sobbing ]
YOU KNOW?
THAT'S LOVE.
[ Sighs ]
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO!
OKAY.
[ Panting ]
[ Sirens Wailing ]
[ Fran ] I'LL GO ON
UP TO THE HOUSE!
[ Judith ] MOM!
[ Pounding
On The Door ]
OH.
WHAT ARE YA DOIN', BEN?
HAVING A LOOK
AT MY CAR.
DON'T I HAVE A RIGHT
TO BE IN MY OWN GARAGE?
HOW LONG YOU
BEEN OUT HERE?
COUPLE OF MINUTES.
ALL I DID WAS LOOK AROUND,
AND I SURE DIDN'T SEE
ANYTHING WRONG EITHER.
- KEYS, BEN.
- WHAT ABOUT THE WARRANT?
OH, BEN--
[ Sighs ]
YOU ARE ASKIN'
FOR TROUBLE ON THIS.
[ Sighs ]
YOU'RE NOT THINKIN' CLEAR.
NOW, HOW CAN I
HELP YOU IF YOU
DON'T EVEN TRUST ME?
IT'S ALL YOURS.
[ Trunk Lid Opening ]
[ Policemen Talking,
Indistinct ]
THIS ALWAYS SUCH A MESS?
[ Ben ]
I'VE GOT SUPPLIES
TO MOVE AROUND. ART STUFF.
I CAN'T USE CAROLYN'S CAR.
SHE HAS A FIT.
AND THE JEEP'S TOO SMALL.
[ Clattering ]
WHAT ABOUT THE FLOOR?
WHERE'D ALL THIS SAWDUST
COME FROM--
ALL THESE LITTLE PIECES
OF NEW WOOD?
[ Sighs ]
YOU THINK I'M STUPID, BEN?
YOU THINK I'M QUAINT?
OKAY. SO I LOOKED IN THERE.
MAYBE SOME SAWDUST
DRIFTED OUT. IS THAT A CRIME?
[ Sighs ]
THIS CAR IS
OFFICIALLY IMPOUNDED.
[ Sighs ]
AND I WANNA
TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
IF IT TURNS OUT
YOUR KID IS IN TROUBLE,
THEN YOU ARE
IN TROUBLE TOO.
NOW LET'S HAVE
A LOOK AT HIS ROOM.
YOU'RE SEARCHING JACOB'S
ROOM? [ Chuckles ]
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT I AM.
[ Fran ]
OHH.
[ Ben ] HEY, IF YOU
FIND HIS BED, LET US KNOW.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN IT
IN YEARS.
I DON'T LIKE
YOUR ATTITUDE.
IT'S NOT EXACTLY WHAT
I WOULD CALL DECENT,
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
WELL, WE HAVEN'T HAD
MUCH PRACTICE, FRAN,
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
ALL RIGHT, I WANNA LOOK
IN THAT CLOSET, BUT FIRST
I WANNA LOOK IN THIS TRUNK.
[ Fran ]
CHECK THE BOTTOM
OF THIS, INCLUDING HERE.
NOW LET'S GET THE BED.
[ Fran Talking,
Indistinct ]
[ Fran ] FINISH UP
IN HERE, WILL YOU?
[ Police Officer ] YEAH.
OH--
HEY. EXCUSE US.
"THE PREMISES,"
"THE OCCUPANT,"
"A SEARCH--"
NOW MAYBE YOU SEE WHY
I DIDN'T JUST FALL INTO LINE.
IT'S SO STUPID AND USELESS.
WHY AREN'T THEY OUT
LOOKING FOR HIM?
WELL, NOW.
HIDDEN IN
HIS TOP DRAWER.
[ Ben ]
SO?
SO...
THAT'S A LINK,
DON'T YOU THINK?
THIS PROVES THAT
THEY KNEW EACH OTHER.
FRAN, NOBODY'S PRETENDING
THEY DIDN'T.
SORRY I'M LATE.
I'M SO SORRY.
-IFTHAT'S EVEN HER.
- OH, IT'S HER, WENDELL.
IT IS MARTHA TAVERNER.
HERE'S
THE SEARCH WARRANT.
WELL, I WANT A COMPLETE
INVENTORY OF ALL THE ITEMS...
THAT YOU'RE REMOVING
FROM THIS HOUSE,
WITH A SIGNED RECEIPT.
COME ON UP!
OKAY!
OH, CAROLYN.
UH, ONE MORE THING.
WHEN DID YOU LOAN JACOB
YOUR TIRE JACK?
MY--
WELL, I'M JUST WONDERING
WHY A BEAT-UP OLD CHEVY...
HAS THE JACK
FROM A '94 PARK AVENUE.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
HOLD ON.
DON'T ANSWER THAT.
FRAN, FISHING SEASON STARTS
IN APRIL. LET'S YOU AND I
GO OUTSIDE AND TALK, HUH?
[ Fran ]
LOOK, JACOB, MAY NOT
EVEN HAVE BEEN THERE,
BUT THEY ARE PUTTING
THEMSELVES IN FRONT
OF THE LAW, WENDELL.
THAT DOES NOT HELP ANYBODY.
YOU SEEM TO BE CONDUCTING
A FULL INVESTIGATION.
[ Fran ]
I'M JUST SAYIN' THAT
AS A FRIEND.
[ Door Closes ]
CAROLYN.
PLEASE, COME HERE.
[ Fran, Wendell
CONTINUE CONVERSING,
Indistinct ]
WHAT-- WHAT DOES HE MEAN--
LISTEN, LISTEN,
LISTEN TO ME!
THERE WAS BLOOD
IN THE CAR.
BLOOD?
HER BLOOD ON HIS JACK.
BLOOD EVERYWHERE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
IT WAS HER BLOOD?
[ Inhaling Deeply ]
[ Carolyn ]
FOR GOD'S SAKE,
IT MIGHT BE HIS.
SHOW ME. I WANNA SEE IT.
NO, NO, NO.
YOU DON'T WANT TO.
BELIEVE ME. ANYWAY,
IT'S BEEN TAKEN CARE OF.
WH-- WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
"TAKEN CARE OF"?
WHATEVER WOULD BURN,
I BURNED.
THE JACK I TOOK APART.
I WASHED IT CLEAN.
OH, NO.
BUT THERE WAS NO TIME TO--
THEY MIGHT FIND SOMETHING
ANYWAY.
FIBERS OR SOME
LITTLE MICROSCOPIC--
GOD ONLY KNOWS WHAT SORT
OF TESTS THEY'VE GOT NOW.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
IF WE JUST HAD
MORE TIME.
YOU CAN'T JUST--
YOU CAN'T JUST DESTROY EVIDENCE
THAT MIGHT SAVE HIM.
YOU CAN'T JUST-- WHAT IF
YOU'VE DESTROYED EVIDENCE
THAT WOULD PROVE HE'S INNOCENT?
BEN, PLEASE,
JUST STOP ONE MINUTE.
PLEASE.
WE HAVE TO THINK.
WE HAVE TO DECIDE.
WHAT? WHAT HAVE WE
GOT TO DECIDE?
NOTHING'S GONNA BRING
THAT GIRL BACK.
I'M SORRY, BUT IT'S
TOO LATE. WE'VE GOT
TO THINK OF JACOB!
BUT JACOB'S INNOCENT.
JACOB'S NOT A KILLER.
IF ANYTHING,
HE'S IN DANGER HIMSELF.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT THEY
WERE ALONE IN THAT CAR?
SOMEONE ELSE MIGHT HAVE
BEEN THERE AND KILLED
THAT GIRL AND TAKEN JACOB.
AND NOW YOU'RE DOING
EVERYTHING YOU CAN TO KEEP
THE POLICE FROM FINDING HIM.
AND WHAT IF IT WAS
JUST AN ACCIDENT, AND JACOB'S
OFF RUNNING SCARED?
WE DON'T KNOW
THE FACTS, BEN.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
[ Tow Truck Pulling Away ]
OKAY, THEY'RE GONE.
YOU WANNA TELL ME
WHATEVER IT IS YOU KNOW?
[ Wendell ]
HEY, HEY, HEY. LOOK,
LOOK. I'M YOUR FRIEND.
AND I LOVE JACOB.
JESUS.
SAT THROUGH EVERY
DAMN CLASS PLAY OF HIS.
I GAVE HIM 50 BUCKS
LAST YEAR FOR THE BIKE-A-THON.
I'M ON YOUR SIDE.
- WENDELL, THERE IS
SOMETHING YOU SHOULD KNOW.
- HEY!
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT IS THAT, BEN RYAN?
ARE YOU GONNA PRESUME NOW
TO TELL ME WHEN I CAN SPEAK
AND WHEN I HAVE TO BE QUIET?
- YOU CAN KEEP YOUR OWN TONGUE
IF YOU WANT TO, BUT YOU--
- [ Phone Ringing ]
JACOB!
HELLO? YES.
WHO IS THIS?
[ Sighs ]
UH-- WELL, I HOPE YOU SLEEP
WELL TONIGHT. YOU'RE A PERSON
OF TRUE COMPASSION.
CAROLYN, IT'S BETTER
IF YOU JUST HANG UP.
YES, IT'S
OUR FIRST WELL-WISHER.
YES, YOU ARE.
AREN'T YOU PROUD?
OH. WELL, YOU HAVEN'T
GOT MUCH OF A BRAIN,
BUT YOU'VE GOT
MIGHTY Q-QUICK REFLEXES.
[ Panting, Sobbing ]
IT'S OKAY, HONEY.
IT'S OKAY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
[ Sobbing ]
IT'S OKAY.
[ Carolyn Sobbing ]
[ Panting ]
MA'AM?
[ Gasps ]
THE-- WE'VE BEEN
ALL OVER THIS AREA AND...
SOMEBODY JUST
BURIED THEIR DOG THERE.
OH.
WE DUG IT UP
AND PUT IT BACK.
[ Carolyn ]
I'M GOING BACK TO WORK.
WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS IS CRAZY.
WELL, I HAVE TO
LIVE MY LIFE.
AND THIS TOWN HAS ITS NEEDS TOO.
DOESN'T JUST REVOLVE AROUND US
AND OUR PROBLEMS.
I'LL EITHER BE BACK
IN 15 MINUTES
WITH A BLACK EYE...
OR I'LL BE THERE ALL DAY.
HEY.
HMM?
I LOVE YOU.
BYE.
GOOD-BYE.
[ Church Bell Tolling ]
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Children Chattering ]
[ Chattering Stops ]
[ Loud Sobbing ]
[ Woman ]
SLOW IT DOWN, OKAY?
[ Groans ]
[ Carolyn ]
JACOB!
WHAT IF WE NEVER
SEE HIM AGAIN?
OH, DARLING.
NO, DON'T LOSE FAITH.
WE JUST HAVE TO BELIEVE
THAT SOMEHOW HE'LL--
HE'LL FIND HIS WAY
BACK TO US. HE WILL.
AND THERE IS SOME OTHER
EXPLANATION FOR ALL THIS.
I KNOW THERE IS.
I KNOW IT.
"DEAR FOLKS, TOOK A LONG TIME
TO GET TO BOSTON...
"IN THE BIG STORM.
"WASN'T SURE WE'D MAKE IT.
I MIGHT MOVE ON.
"I MIGHT HANG OUT HERE
A WHILE.
WILL TRY TO WRITE.
I KNOW YOU DON'T PRAY,
BUT PRAY NOW."
POSTMARKED
THE DAY BEFORE YESTERDAY.
CAROLYN, HE'S ALIVE.
THIS IS CRAZY.
THIS ISN'T JACOB.
THAT'S HIS HANDWRITING.
NO, NO, NO.
SOMEBODY MADE HIM WRITE THIS.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
THE POINT IS, AT LEAST
RIGHT NOW, HE'S OKAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M CALLING FRAN.
I-I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT.
FRAN? CAROLYN,
LISTEN TO ME. WILL YOU
JUST LISTEN TO ME?
IF FRAN SEES THIS,
THE FIRST THING HE'LL DO
IS GET A COURT ORDER...
TO INTERCEPT OUR MAIL
AND TAP OUR PHONES.
THEN YOU CAN FORGET
ABOUT EVER HEARING
FROM JAKE AGAIN.
AND THAT'S JUST
FOR STARTERS.
THEY'LL SLAP A MANHUNT
ALL OVER BOSTON.
HE'LL RUN AGAIN.
GOD KNOWS WHERE.
THINK ABOUT IT.
DO WE REALLY
WANT HIM CAUGHT?
I-- I JUST WANT MY BOY BACK.
I JUST WANNA HOLD HIM AGAIN.
I JUST--
I JUST WANT MY BOY.
OH, SHH, SHH, SHH.
[ Weeping ]
[ Register Rings ]
THAT'S OUT OF 30.
TWENTY-SIX, TWENTY-SEVEN,
TWENTY-EIGHT...
IS THAT WHO I THINK IT IS?
TWENTY-NINE, THIRTY.
[ Whispering ]
BEN RYAN.
KEEP YOUR CHIN UP,
YOU HEAR?
SORRY, JOE.
ALL I NEED IS CHANGE.
OH.
GOOD NIGHT, KAREN.
SEE YOU FOR MY 8:00.
UM,
MRS. WEBBER CANCELED, DOCTOR.
SHE SAID
YOU'D UNDERSTAND.
OKAY.
GOOD NIGHT.
HI, DOCTOR.
T.J. HI.
I GOT A FEVER.
YOU GOT A FEVER?
OH, WHAT YOU--
COME ON, HONEY.
[ Awkward Laugh ]
I'M SORRY.
ST. LOUIS ON MARCH 11.
THAT'S THE THIRD CARD.
THEN HE WAS IN L.A.
JUST TWO DAYS LATER.
HI.
IT'S A NEW ONE.
CALIFORNIA.
WHAT'S THIS DOING OUT?
THIS SPOILS.
THAT'S IT? THAT'S
YOUR WHOLE REACTION?
LOOK, YOU WON'T SHOW THESE
TO FRAN. ALL RIGHT.
BUT YOU WON'T EVEN SHOW THEM
TO WENDELL, BENNY, AND HE'S
OUR LAWYER. HE'S OUR FRIEND.
IF THIS GETS OUT,
WE DON'T KNOW HOW IT
MIGHT BE USED AGAINST HIM.
MMM.
IN FACT, IT MIGHT
COME IN HANDY LATER
THAT WE KEPT QUIET.
HANDY?
[ Phone Ringing ]
WAIT, WAIT.
HELLO. WENDELL.
WHAT'S--
TURN ON THE TV.
CHANNEL 3. YEAH.
YEAH, WE GOT IT.
- ...CROSS AMERICA--
- ???? [ Theme Music ]
- JACOB RYAN,
THE 16-YEAR-OLD HIGHLAND
RESIDENT, WHO IS A SUSPECT IN
THE MURDER OF MARTHA TAVERNER,
WAS A FUGITIVE
FOR FIVE WEEKS.
THE TEENAGER, AS REPORTED
MOMENTS AGO, WAS ARRESTED
THIS AFTERNOON...
- [ Carolyn Gasps ]
-IN THE BUILDING
YOU SEE BEHIND ME.
APPARENTLY,
THE YOUNG FUGITIVE WAS HIDING
IN A FRIEND'S APARTMENT.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT HE IS NOW
BEING HELD IN THE JUVENILE
DETENTION CENTER,
AND IT IS EXPECTED
THAT HE WILL BE ARRAIGNED
SOMETIME TOMORROW.
[ Beeping ]
THIS WAY.
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
JAKE. JAKE!
HI, SON.
OH, THANK GOD
YOU'RE SAFE.
HOW ARE YOU, SON?
WHERE WERE YOU?
JAKE, FIRST OFF,
YOUR SISTER--
SHE WANTED US TO ASK YOU,
UM, IF THE POSTCARDS--
W-WERE YOU REALLY IN
ALL THOSE PLACES, JAKE?
OR WERE YOU HERE THE WHOLE TIME
IN YOUR FRIEND DARREN'S
APARTMENT, HUH?
YOUR DAD ASKED YOU
A QUESTION.
HONEY, ARE YOU
GONNA TALK TO US?
YOU DON'T THINK YOU'RE GONNA
BE ABLE TO HOLD OUT LIKE THIS
FOREVER, DO YOU, JAKE?
POLICEMEN CAN'T HEAR YOU.
AND WE HAVE TOLD THEM NOTHING.
ARE YOU STILL
MAD AT ME?
IS THAT IT?
YOU KNOW YOUR FATHER
HAS STOOD UP FOR YOU.
TELL ME, PLEASE.
DO YOU
REALIZE THAT?
JAKIE!
GODDAMN IT, MISTER.
HAVE YOU ANY IDEA WHAT
YOU'VE PUT US THROUGH?
MAYBE HE DOESN'T EVEN KNOW.
DO YOU EVEN KNOW
WHY YOU'RE HERE?
HAVE THEY TOLD YOU?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TO MARTHA TAVERNER?
THERE IS A WARRANT FOR YOU
BACK IN HIGHLAND.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
YOU MAY BE ABLE TO COME HOME.
FIRST, THEY JUST HAVE TO HAVE
A HEARING IN FRONT OF A JUDGE.
A-AND WENDELL BYE WILL BE
RIGHT THERE WITH YOU, AND
DADDY AND I WILL BE RIGHT THERE.
AND YOU BETTER SPEAK UP THEN,
JAKE, IN COURT.
JAKE.
CAN YOU LOOK AT US?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
DO SOME THINKING ABOUT WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA SAY TO WENDELL.
DON'T WASTE HIS TIME TOO.
LET'S GO.
[ Chattering ]
[ Demonstrators ]
NO BAIL! KILLERS IN JAIL!
NO BAIL!
KILLERS IN JAIL!
NO BAIL! KILLERS IN JAIL!
LOOK OUT, PLEASE.
GIVE US SOME ROOM.
LOOK OUT.
[ Chanting Continues ]
WHY DID YOU KILL HER?
JACOB RYAN, YOU'VE HEARD
THE CHARGE AGAINST YOU.
IN JUVENILE PROCEEDINGS,
WE ENTER A PLEA OF "TRUE"
OR "NOT TRUE."
HOW SAY YOU
TO THIS CHARGE?
NOT TRUE.
[ Demonstrators Chanting ]
JACOB RYAN
IS A LONGTIME RESIDENT.
HE'S A FINE STUDENT.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
OF FLAWLESS CHARACTER.
AND HE IS STILL,
AT THE MOMENT, A MINOR,
AND, THEREFORE,
WE RESPECTFULLY REQUEST
THAT HE BE RELEASED ON BOND.
JACOB RYAN
IS CHARGED...
WITH A TERRIBLE AND
ALMOST UNTHINKABLE CRIME.
MOREOVER, THE PEOPLE
WILL PROVE THAT HE
EXACERBATED THAT CRIME...
AFTER THE FACT...
BY HIS CUNNING, DELIBERATE
AND COLD-BLOODED DESTRUCTION
OF EVIDENCE.
NO PARENT
IN THIS TOWN...
AND SURELY NO DAUGHTER
COULD FEEL SAFE...
WITH JACOB RYAN
ON THE LOOSE AGAIN.
THE PEOPLE URGE
THAT BAIL BE DENIED.
MARION, I'M JUST
NOT PERSUADED...
THIS BOY IS A THREAT
TO THE GENERAL COMMUNITY.
YOUR HONOR,
I WAS ALSO THINKING
OF THEIR THREAT TO HIM.
DEFENDANT, PLEASE RISE.
PRETRIAL RELEASE GRANTED.
BOND SET AT $250,000.
?? YOU SAY YOU FEEL
SO DISTORTED ??
]
???? [ Continues, Indistinct
NOW LISTEN, MISTER. YOU CAN DO
WHATEVER THE HELL YOU WANT
WITH YOUR CATATONIC SELF,
BUT DON'T EVEN THINK
ABOUT OPENING THIS DOOR.
YOU HEAR ME?
[ Whispering ]
OH, BEN.
JUDE!
JACOB!
I MADE YOU SOME COOKIES!
- JACOB?
-[ Carolyn ]
MAYBE YOU--
MAYBE YOU WANNA HAVE
SOME SOUP FIRST OR S--
A SANDWICH OR SOMETHING.
MOM, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH HIM?
I THINK WE JUST HAVE TO
GIVE HIM A FEW DAYS, SWEETIE.
WHEN WE FOUGHT
THAT MORNING,
I RAISED MY FIST
TO HIM.
I WOULD'VE HIT HIM.
AND WE BOTH
KNEW IT, CAROLYN.
I SENT HIM OUT
INTO THE WORLD
IN THAT KIND OF RAGE.
BUT YOU DIDN'T, BENNY.
YOU DIDN'T HIT HIM.
AND PEOPLE DO FIGHT.
THEY ARGUE ALL THE TIME.
IF I'M TO BLAME
FOR THIS, HOW CAN I
EVER MAKE IT UP TO HIM?
NO.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED YET.
IF WE START BLAMING
OURSELVES, OR, OR EACH OTHER,
HOW ARE WE
GONNA GET THROUGH THIS?
WHEN HE'S READY
AND WHEN HE'S ABLE, HE'LL
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED. HE WILL.
RIGHT NOW...
THE ONLY IMPORTANT THING
IS THAT WE'RE ALL TOGETHER
AGAIN AND HE'S HOME.
HE'S HOME.
[ Whimpering ]
[ Weeping ]
[ Wendell ]
THEY GOT EYEWITNESSES.
THEY'RE NOT CLAIMING
TO HAVE SOMEONE WHO
ACTUALLY SAW THE MURDER.
AT LEAST NOT YET.
THEN WHAT, EXACTLY, DO THESE
PEOPLE CLAIM TO HAVE SEEN?
THE TWO OF THEM
IN HIS CAR, I WOULD GUESS.
HIS CAR STOPPED MAYBE
UP ON, UH, POOR FARM ROAD?
PROSECUTOR SAYS THEY HAVE PROOF
THAT JACOB DESTROYED EVIDENCE.
WELL, SHE
HAS TO SAY THAT,
DOESN'T SHE?
- THEY STILL HAVEN'T FOUND
THE MURDER WEAPON.
- BUT, BUT SURELY...
THAT HELPS OUR, OUR CASE.
- I MEAN, YOU'RE SAYING THAT
THEY'VE GOT A LOUSY CASE.
- CIRCUMSTANTIAL, YES.
I'M SAYIN' THAT'S POSSIBLE.
THEN I DON'T UNDERSTAND,
WENDELL. WHY ARE YOU
DROPPING OUT ON US?
[ Ironic Laugh ]
I WOULDN'T, UH--
IT'S NOT THAT.
LOOK, I-I--
I DO MORTGAGE CLOSINGS.
YOU NEED
AN EXPERT NOW.
CRIMINAL GUY.
AND BELIEVE ME, THIS GUY
I'M TELLIN' YOU ABOUT--
HE IS THE BEST.
UH, PANOS DEMERIS.
GREEK-AMERICAN.
LIVES OVER IN SPRINGFIELD.
HE'S LOST MAYBE ONE CASE
IN HIS WHOLE LIFE.
HE'LL HAVE JACOB'S JURY
VOTING FOR SAINTHOOD.
AND WHAT ABOUT THE TRUTH
OF WHAT HAPPENED?
DOESN'T THAT MATTER?
THE TRUTH, MRS. RYAN?
THE TRUTH ISN'T ALWAYS
SO SIMPLE.
I JUST MEANT DO YOU HAVE TO
BELIEVE SOMEONE IS INNOCENT
IN ORDER TO TAKE HIS CASE?
A LOT OF MY CLIENTS HAVEN'T BEEN
INNOCENT OF ANYTHING YOU'D CARE
TO LAY ON THEM...
SINCE THEY WERE FIVE YEARS OLD,
BUT THEY STILL DESERVE
A GOOD DEFENSE, RIGHT?
DO YOU MIND IF I EAT
WHILE WE TALK?
IS THIS LATE LUNCH,
MR. DEMERIS, OR
EARLY DINNER?
THIS IS BREAKFAST, I THINK.
I HAD A PRETRIAL MEETING
AND NEVER DID STOP.
OKAY, SO...
YOUR SON, JACOB.
NOW FROM WHAT
YOU'VE TOLD ME, HE SEEMS
LIKE A PRETTY REGULAR KID.
I MEAN EVEN THESE SILENCES,
YOU KNOW? HOPING IF HE
HANGS TOUGH LONG ENOUGH,
MAYBE THIS WHOLE THING
WILL JUST DISAPPEAR?
[ Chuckling ]
TEENAGERS, HUH?
GOD HELP US.
BUT, UH, LET ME--
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
NOW, PLEASE, TAKE THIS AS
A NEUTRAL QUESTION, OKAY?
IT'S NOT AN ACCUSATION
OF ANY KIND, BUT-- ANGER.
DOES JACOB HAVE ANY PARTICULAR
PROBLEM EXPRESSING HIS ANGER?
DOES HE TEND TO KEEP THINGS
BOTTLED UP?
DOES HE EVER JUST EXPLODE?
YOU SEE, I'M ASKING YOU BECAUSE
IF THERE'S ANY HISTORY HERE,
I MEAN EVEN JUST A WHIFF,
I HAVE TO HEAR IT FROM YOU.
NOT SOME PROSECUTOR.
NO, HE--
THERE'S NO HISTORY.
JACOB'S A VERY--
HE'S A VERY KIND PERSON.
DECENT. CARING.
YOU'D LIKE HIM.
SURE, SURE.
BUT YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND,
MR. AND MRS. RYAN-- I'M SORRY.
IS IT "MR." AND "DR."?
BEN AND CAROLYN.
OKAY. NOW YOU
HAVE TO UNDERSTAND:
JURIES, IN CASES
OF THIS NATURE, THEY TEND
TO BE VERY EMOTIONAL.
THEY TEND TO FEEL THAT
WHERE THERE'S SMOKE,
THERE'S FIRE.
HEY. I COULD BE UP THERE,
ARGUING THAT JACOB IS THE MOST
PERFECT KID IN THE WORLD.
THAT'S ONE STRATEGY.
BUT WHAT THEY'LL BE THINKING,
WHAT THEY'LL SEE
IN THEIR MIND'S EYE...
AND NEVER FORGET IS THIS.
YOU CAN'T--
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
NO, DR. RYAN, I'M--
YOU CANNOT JUST SIT HERE AND EAT
A SANDWICH AND DISPLAY SUCH--
- HOW DO YOU EXPECT US
TO SURVIVE THIS?
- DR. RYAN.
I'M NOT BEING UNSYMPATHETIC.
DON'T INFER THAT.
BUT THIS HAS GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH SYMPATHY. I THOUGHT YOU
TOLD ME YOU'D SEEN THIS CORPSE.
THIS IS NOT JUST ANY CORPSE.
THIS IS A GIRL THAT I KNEW,
THAT I ONCE TREATED.
JUST BECAUSE YOU SEE THIS KIND
OF THING EVERY DAY--
YOU SPEND ALL YOUR TIME
WITH VIOLENT, HORRIBLE PEOPLE,
BUT WE DON'T, MR. DEMERIS.
NO? WELL, THEN,
YOU'RE VERY LUCKY.
I'M A PHYSICIAN, AND THERE ISN'T
MUCH I HAVEN'T SEEN, BUT THIS IS
MY SON YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU MAY LIKE TO REMEMBER,
DR. RYAN, IT'S ALWAYS
SOMEBODY'S SON.
DON'T YOU PATRONIZE ME, SIR,
BECAUSE I CAN--
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
LET'S CALM DOWN.
ALL OF US. CAROLYN.
THIS ISN'T
GETTING US ANYWHERE.
COME ON, HONEY.
LOOK, I'M SORRY, FOLKS.
BUT IF YOU DON'T
LIKE ME NOW,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA SAY
WHEN I HAVE TO GET UP
IN FRONT OF THAT JURY...
AND ARGUE THAT YOUR SON
IS NOT GUILTY BY REASON OF
DIMINISHED MENTAL CAPACITY?
THAT HE WAS DRUNK.
STONED.
HEY, HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
YES, BOMBED OUT OF
HIS SKULL ON CRACK.
MY SON DOES NOT DO DRUGS.
HE MAY BE YOUR SON, MR. RYAN,
BUT HE WOULD BE MY CLIENT,
AND I WOULD NOT ASK
YOUR PERMISSION FOR HOW
I CHOOSE TO DEFEND HIM.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO DO
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
AND IF YOU DON'T LIKE
MY STYLE, WAIT 'TIL
YOU HEAR THE PROSECUTION.
LISTEN, DR. RYAN,
YOU WANNA JUMP IN
THE TRENCHES WITH ME?
WELL, YOU BETTER MUSCLE UP.
LOSE YOUR BEDSIDE MANNER
AND TRUST ME TO BE AS GOOD
AT MY JOB AS YOU ARE AT YOURS.
WILL YOU DO IT, MR. DEMERIS?
WILL YOU TAKE OUR CASE?
FOR YOUR SON, YEAH.
YEAH, I'LL DEFEND JACOB.
JAKE?
I KNOW YOU DON'T
WANNA TALK, BUT I
JUST NEED TO SEE YOU.
CAN I COME UP?
PLEASE?
CAN I JUST ASK YOU
ONE QUESTION?
DID YOU EVER REALLY
GO ANYWHERE, JAKE?
OKAY. THAT'S COOL.
I UNDERSTAND.
BUT JUST SO YOU KNOW,
WHEN YOU WERE
IN THAT JAIL,
I TRIED TO COME.
THEY WOULDN'T LET ME.
JAKE, I REALLY
WANTED TO SEE YOU.
THEY ACT LIKE THEY HAVE TO
PROTECT ME FROM ALL OF THIS.
SURE. THEY CAN'T EVEN
PROTECT THEMSELVES.
AND I HEAR PLENTY.
I KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
LIKE...
MOM'S HAD TO CLOSE
HER OFFICE.
SHE SAYS IT'S
JUST TEMPORARY.
SURE.
GIMME A BREAK.
WELL, ANYWAY,
THAT'S ALL.
I JUST WANTED TO ASK
ABOUT THE POSTCARDS.
NO BIG DEAL.
JUDE, WAIT. DON'T GO.
ONCE OR TWICE A WEEK,
I'D TAKE THE TRAIN
OUT TO LOGAN AIRPORT.
THEN I'D FIND A FLIGHT THAT WAS
GOIN' TO WHERE I WANTED TO GO.
AND THEN I'D FIND SOMEBODY
THAT WOULDN'T MIND MAILING A
CARD FOR ME WHEN THEY GOT THERE.
AND I SAID THAT
I'M HOME FROM VACATION,
AND I FORGOT TO SEND THIS...
AND I DON'T WANT MY PARENTS
TO THINK I DON'T MISS 'EM.
AND THEN, LIKE, I'D SIT
IN ONE OF THOSE CHAIRS,
YOU KNOW?
IN THE WAITING AREA
AT THE AIRPORT.
I'D SHUT MY EYES LIKE THIS...
AND SIT.
I WENT THERE WITH 'EM.
I WENT TO
ALL THOSE PLACES, JUDE.
YOU WON'T SAY ANYTHING,
WILL YOU?
NOBODY ELSE
WOULD UNDERSTAND.
[ Phone Rings ]
WAIT.
[ Rings ]
HELLO.
[ Laughs ]
YES, SIR, I SEE.
OH, THAT'S VERY BIBLICAL.
AND I TAKE IT
YOU WOULD LIKE TO CAST
THE FIRST ONE, HUH?
NOW, I WANT YOU TO
LISTEN VERY CAREFULLY--
NO, NO, YOU LISTEN.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW,
YOU GOOD CITIZEN,
THAT MY SON IS INNOCENT.
HE'S A FREE YOUNG MAN,
LEGALLY HERE ON BOND,
AGAINST WHOM NOTHING HAS BEEN--
NO, NO. YOU'RE WRONG.
UNLESS HE'S CONVICTED
IN A COURT OF LAW, HE IS
NO MORE GUILTY THAN YOU ARE.
SO SLEEP TIGHT, PAL,
AND HEY, HAVE A WONDERFUL
TIME IN CHURCH.
[ Hangs Up Receiver ]
YEAH, DAD.
YOU'RE SO COOL.
YOU REALLY
BELIEVE THAT?
WELL, OF--
OF COURSE I DO.
OUR WHOLE SYSTEM
OF JUSTICE--
I DON'T MEAN OUR SYSTEM.
I MEAN ABOUT ME.
DO YOU BELIEVE
THAT I'M NOT GUILTY?
JAKE,
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT--
WELL, NOW THAT
YOU'RE HERE, WE CAN--
WE CAN TALK ABOUT THAT.
BUT WHATEVER THE TRUTH IS,
WE'RE STANDING BY YOU.
ABSOLUTELY.
OH, THAT'S JUST A BUNCH
OF SENTIMENTAL BULLSHIT.
I MEAN ME.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
HEY. HEY, NOT SO FAST.
[ Carolyn ]
"SENTIMENTAL BULLSHIT"?
EVERYBODY'S PARENTS
SAY STUFF LIKE THAT.
DO THEY? DO THEY REALLY?
AND DO THEY HIDE THE WEAPON
AND DESTROY EVIDENCE...
CAROLYN.
AND LIE
TO THE POLICE?
DO THEY, INDEED?
YOU KNOW THIS
FOR A FACT?
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO JUST
SIT HERE AND TALK ABOUT
KILLING SOMEBODY?
JAKE, STOP RUNNING.
PLEASE.
YOU'RE HOME NOW.
STOP RUNNING.
IF I TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENED--
IT WASN'T ME.
[ Sighs ]
IT WASN'T ME, ALL RIGHT?
WE HUNG OUT A LOT
THIS YEAR.
I KEPT MEANING
TO TELL YOU GUYS.
I WANTED YOU TO KNOW,
BUT--
I TOLD MARTHA YOU GUYS
WERE COOL,
BUT THE IDEA OF HAVING TO
MEET YOU, CONVERSE WITH YOU,
IT JUST SPOOKED HER SOMEHOW.
THAT DAY WE HAD
A TERRIBLE ARGUMENT.
[ Sighs ] FROM THE MOMENT
I PICKED HER UP AT THE
ICE CREAM SHOP AT JACEY'S,
SHE WAS ON MY CASE ABOUT
NOT HAVING A RENTAL CAR
FOR THE WINTER DANCE.
SHE WAS SAYING IT'S YOUR WAY,
OURS,OF FINALLY SAYING
SHE'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
[ Jacob Sighs ]
[ Sighs ]
I-I TRIED TO EXPLAIN TO HER,
BUT SHE JUST--
SHE KEPT YELLING AT ME
AS I WAS TRYING TO DRIVE.
THEN SHE SAID,
"PULL OVER RIGHT HERE."
[ Jacob ]
AND IT TURNS OUT,
I'M NOT THE ONE
SHE'S MAD AT, REALLY.
SHE'S MAD AT EVERYONE
AND EVERYTHING.
GOD, ESPECIALLY,
FOR LETTING THIS HAPPEN TO HER,
'CAUSE IT TURNS OUT--
I'M PREGNANT.
[ Jacob ]
IT GETS EVEN MORE
COMPLICATED.
'CAUSE SHE DIDN'T THINK
IT WAS OURS.
SHE WOULDN'T SAY
WHOSE IT MIGHT BE, BUT...
OBVIOUSLY SHE'S BEEN,
YOU KNOW--
GETTING AROUND.
I NEVER EVEN
HAD A CLUE.
SHE FIGURED IT WASN'T
OURS BECAUSE WE WERE
ALWAYS SO CAREFUL.
SO SHE'S GETTING
ALL WOUND UP.
"I HATE YOU.
I NEVER WANT TO
SEE YOU AGAIN."
SHE WAS EVEN MOCKING ME
FOR TAKING CARE WITH HER,
FOR USING--
LIKE ONLY A WIMP
WOULD THINK AHEAD
LIKE THAT.
I SAID,
"THAT'S IT. LET'S GO.
"YOU CAN HAVE YOUR BABY
OR NOT; YOU CAN STAY WITH
YOUR CAVEMAN OR NOT.
I DON'T CARE."
SO THEN SHE GOT
ALL SORT OF--
[ Shifting Gears ]
JAKE, WAIT.
DON'T GO YET.
[ Horn Honking ]
NEED ANY HELP?
WE'RE ALL RIGHT!
LOOK--
[ Sniffles ]
[ Sighs ]
I DIDN'T MEAN
WHAT I SAID.
I'M SORRY.
I REALLY AM.
COME HERE,
I'LL SHOW YOU.
[ Jacob ]
WE STAYED FOR
A WHILE LONGER.
[ Sighs ]
WE SORT OF MADE UP AND...
IT WAS NICE, BUT...
BY NOW WE WERE BOTH
SO TIRED,
SO WIPED OUT.
IT WAS BEGINNING TO GET LATE,
SO I FINALLY STARTED UP THE CAR.
[ Engine Revving ]
AND THAT WAS THAT.
TRIED ROCKING IT,
PUSHING IT.
[ Door Closes ]
FIRST ME, THEN BOTH OF US.
WE EVEN TRIED PUTTING
FLOOR MATS UNDER THE WHEELS.
WE JUST ENDED UP
DIGGING OURSELVES IN DEEPER.
SO FINALLY SHE SAYS,
"GET THE JACK.
PACK SOME SNOW
UNDER THE RUTS
AND JACK IT UP."
- AND THAT DIDN'T EVEN WORK.
- THIS IS THE REASON
I CAN'T BE WITH YOU.
[ Jacob ] NOW WE'RE BOTH
REALLY PISSED OFF AGAIN.
YOU LET SHIT LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
JUST SHUT UP,
ALL RIGHT?
IF I WERE WITH KEVIN OR MATT,
I'D BE HOME BY NOW.
WHY ARE YOU SUCH A--
- I SAID, SHUT UP,
ALL RIGHT?
- [ Sighs ] RICH KID.
- FUCKIN' PUSSY.
PUSSY RICH--
- I SAID, SHUT UP!
I DID IT.
I SLAPPED HER.
I JUST LOST IT.
[ Sighs ]
DO I HAVE TO DO THIS?
PLEASE?
YES. YOU HAVE TO.
SHE STILL HAD
THE CROWBAR.
YOU--
[ Grunting ]
SHE JUST MISSED ME
BY ONE INCH, I SWEAR.
JUST ONE INCH.
[ Both Grunting ]
OHH!
[ Metal Clanks ]
[ Panting ]
JUST THAT ONE WORD--
MURDER.
THAT SOUNDS SO IMPOSSIBLE
TO IMAGINE.
IT WASN'T EVEN SOMETHING
I WAS TRYING TO DO.
IT--
IT WASN'T EVEN ME.
IF I HAD
JUST MISSED HER
BY ONE INCH--
ONE INCH,
JUST LIKE,
LIKE SHE DID ME--
[ Sighs ]
MY BIGGEST PROBLEM
WOULD BE,
DO I SAY HELLO TO HER
WHEN I SEE HER
IN THE SCHOOL HALL.
DARLING.
THANKS.
MMM.
NOW WE KNOW.
AT LEAST THAT'S
SOMETHING, BEN.
IF HE TELLS IT THAT WAY
IN COURT, THE SAME WAY
HE TOLD IT TO US--
HE WOULDN'T BE TELLING IT
TO PEOPLE WHO LOVE HIM.
NO, THEY'LL BELIEVE HIM.
THEY'LL SEE THAT IT WAS
JUST AN ACCIDENT.
ARE YOU PREPARED
TO BET HIS FREEDOM
ON THAT?
WHAT'S THE ANSWER, THEN?
OF COURSE HE HAS TO TELL THEM.
BEN, OF COURSE
HE HAS TO TELL THEM.
LET HIM TELL PANOS
FIRST, OKAY?
WE'RE NOT LAWYERS, CAROLYN.
THERE MIGHT BE A CERTAIN WAY
THIS SHOULD BE,
I DON'T KNOW,
PRESENTED.
I'LL TAKE HIM IN
TOMORROW MORNING.
OKAY?
- YOU'RE UP PRETTY EARLY.
- [ Gasps ]
I WASN'T GOING
ANYWHERE.
THEY KEPT THE CAR.
BUT IT'S CLEAN.
AT LEAST
I HOPE TO GOD.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
MOM SAID SOMETHING TOO,
LAST NIGHT.
OH, JAKE,
IT'S NOT IMPORTANT,
ALL THAT STUFF.
TRUST ME.
IT'S NOT A PROBLEM ANYMORE.
[ Sighs ]
DAD, YOU COULD
GO TO JAIL TOO.
IF THEY HAVE
TO TAKE ONE OF US,
IT'S BETTER IT'S ME.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
JACOB, LISTEN TO ME.
THAT NIGHT WHEN I CAME OUT HERE
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW WHAT
I WAS DOING-- PURE INSTINCT.
BUT MAYBE I BOUGHT US
A CHANCE.
THEY'VE GOT NO MURDER WEAPON,
NO PHYSICAL EVIDENCE,
NO WITNESSES.
AND WE NEVER HEARD
YOUR CONFESSION.
YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YOU NEVER SAID IT
AND WE NEVER HEARD IT.
JAKE, YOU'RE NOT
REQUIRED TO TESTIFY
AGAINST YOURSELF.
NOW, THAT'S FAIR.
THAT'S LEGAL.
THAT'S HOW
THE SYSTEM WORKS.
SO, IF WE ALL
JUST KEEP QUIET,
MAYBE THEY'VE GOT
NO CASE.
MAYBE--
MAYBE YOU'LL WALK AWAY
FROM THIS WITH SOME KIND OF
A LIFE STILL AHEAD OF YOU.
YEAH, BUT THERE ARE
WITNESSES.
PEOPLE SAW US PARKED THERE.
YOU'RE NOT DENYING
YOU WERE THERE.
YOU WERE STUCK
IN THE SNOW, RIGHT?
YOU HAD THAT ARGUMENT
AND YOU WALKED AWAY MAD,
LEFT HER WITH
THE CAR AND THE KEYS.
SO YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE HELL HAPPENED WHEN SHE
WAS ALONE, AND NEITHER DO WE.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
BUT THE CAR WAS HERE.
- YOU RECONSIDERED.
YOU CAME BACK
AND YOU FOUND HER.
YOU JUST PANICKED.
ISN'T THAT POSSIBLE?
BECAUSE YOU KNEW
YOU'D BE A SUSPECT.
DROVE BACK HERE,
STILL IN A STATE OF SHOCK,
AND TOOK OFF FOR BOSTON.
FOOLISH, YES.
BUT NOT MURDER.
I WISH THERE WAS
SOME OTHER WAY.
I STAYED UP ALL NIGHT
WRACKING MY BRAINS-- ANY
OTHER WAY THAT MIGHT BE SAFE.
IF I JUST TOLD THE TRUTH--
THE FACT THAT YOU RAN AWAY,
NEVER WENT FOR HELP,
NEVER CAME FORWARD AT ALL--
JAKE, HOW'S THAT
GONNA LOOK?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
CONVINCE A JURY.
THAT'S UP TO PANOS.
AND LET THE PROSECUTION
TAKE THEIR SHOTS.
ALL I'M SAYING IS,
LET'S JUST...
NOT MAKE THEIR CASE
FOR THEM.
SO I THOUGHT--
I FIGURED SINCE THE POLICE
WERE BOUND TO SUSPECT ME,
THEY'D ALSO BE LOOKING
FOR THE CAR, SO...
I THOUGHT
I'D BETTER HITCHHIKE.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Sighs ]
I-I KNOW THAT WAS REALLY
STUPID AND DUMB OF ME, BUT--
[ Sighs ]
YOU KNOW, ALL OF IT
IS JUST A BLUR,
MR. DEMERIS.
EVERYTHING
AFTER I WALKED BACK
AND FOUND HER THERE.
[ Tape Recorder
Clicks Off ]
WELL, JACOB, WHAT IF I SAID
IT SEEMED PRETTY CLEAR TO ME
THAT YOU DID IT?
YOU HIT HER ON THE HEAD
WITH SOMETHING,
THEN YOU JUST TOOK OFF.
- BUT I DIDN'T!
- NO, NO, NO.
NO, I'M THE PROSECUTION NOW,
AND YOU'RE THE GUY
WHO SMASHED HER UP.
HOW YOU GONNA PROVE TO ME
YOU DIDN'T DO IT?
WELL, I--
NO, NO, NO, NO.
YOU DON'T ANSWER THAT.
NOW, REMEMBER, JACOB,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
THEYHAVE TO ANSWER IT.
THEY HAVE TO PROVE
SOMETHING ONYOU.
YOU DO NOT HAVE TO PROVE
THE OPPOSITE.
SO?
HOW DOES IT LOOK?
WELL, THE GRAND JURY SITS
NEXT MONDAY, BUT WE'VE STILL
GOT A HELL OF A LOT TO PREPARE.
- YOU MEAN THE TRIAL
STARTS MONDAY?
- NO, NO, NO.
IT'S NOT A TRIAL.
NOT YET.
THE GRAND JURY WEIGHS THE FACTS,
THEN DECIDES WHETHER THERE'S
ENOUGH EVIDENCE TO INDICT YOU.
NOW, IF YOU'RE VERY,
VERY LUCKY, YOU MAY NOT
EVEN GO TO TRIAL.
BUT I'LL HAVE A BETTER IDEA
ONCE I SEE THE FINAL
WITNESS LIST AND FORENSICS.
THANKS.
OKAY.
SEE YA.
OH, JAKE. I'M SORRY.
I'M A LITTLE SLOW
SOMETIMES.
I'M JUST CURIOUS.
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT WERE THE TWO OF YOU
FIGHTING ABOUT?
I-I MEAN,
W-WHAT GOT YOU SO MAD?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I LET THIS GO.
SHE WAS PREGNANT,
FOR ONE THING.
- I THINK YOU'D BETTER
SIT DOWN AGAIN, KIDDO.
- COME ON, SON.
IT WAS SOMEBODY ELSE'S.
AT LEAST SHE SAID IT WAS.
WHAT?
THIS IS GOOD?
OH, THIS IS VERY GOOD,
MY FRIEND. THIS IS THE
BEST NEWS I'VE HEARD ALL DAY.
AND YOU'RE CONVINCED
THAT IT COULDN'T POSSIBLY
HAVE BEEN YOURS?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU MEAN--
YOU KNOW.
RIGHT. YOU KNOW.
WELL, YEAH, BUT
WE WERE AL--
WE WERE ALWAYS--
SAFE.
YOU CAN SAY IT, SON.
YEAH.
AND SHE SWORE THIS
WAS SOMEBODY ELSE'S.
GO TO THE MEDICAL EXAMINER,
GET A FULL D.N.A. REPORT.
I'M ALREADY ON IT.
PANOS, WH-- I DON'T--
WE STILL DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IT'S CALLED REASONABLE DOUBT,
MR. RYAN.
SUPPOSE JACOB AND MARTHA
WERE FOLLOWED BY SOMEONE WITH
GOOD REASON TO BE JEALOUS.
SUPPOSE THE WRONG BOYFRIEND
GOT ARRESTED.
SO?
SO WHAT?
HOW DO YOU THINK
IT WENT?
DID HE LIKE IT, YOU MEAN,
OR DIDILIKE IT?
LIKE WHAT?
YOUR STORY.
WELL, YES, MY STORY,
I GUESS.
OURSTORY.
JAKE,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[ Signal Blinker
Clicking ]
WHAT?
REMEMBER
THAT LAST MORNING?
THAT ARGUMENT WE HAD?
REMEMBER WHAT YOU SAID
TO ME?
YOU SAID THAT IT'S TIME
I LEARNED TO PAY MY OWN WAY.
AND YOU CALLED ME
A HYPOCRITE.
JAKE, IF YOU'RE NOT
OKAY WITH THIS,
WE CAN GO BACK THERE.
IT'S STILL
NOT TOO LATE.
[ Sighs ]
OH, MAN.
YOU SURE THIS IS
THE BEST THING TO DO?
I HAVEN'T BEEN SURE
OF ANYTHING IN MY LIFE
SINCE FEBRUARY 12,
BUT IT'S WHAT
WE'VE GOT, SON;
IT'S WHAT WE'RE DOWN TO.
ALL I'M PROPOSING IS
WE SAVE YOUR LIFE FIRST.
LATER ON WE CAN WORRY
ABOUT YOUR SOUL.
IS THAT BEING A HYPOCRITE?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT THE WORST THING
YOU CAN BE CALLED
IN THIS WORLD...
IS SOMEONE WHO DIDN'T
STAND UP FOR HIS FAMILY.
I--
[ Sighs ]
I REALLY AM GRATEFUL
FOR EVERYTHING YOU'RE
TRYING TO DO FOR ME.
I--
DAD, IAMGRATEFUL,
OKAY?
I REALLY MEAN IT.
COME ON.
WITHOUT A WORD, BEN?
NOT ONE WORD?
IT'S JACOB'S CHOICE,
JACOB'S LIFE.
AND YOU HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
WE DISCUSSED
HIS OPTIONS, YEAH.
"OPTIONS"?
BEN, HE'S YOUR BOY.
HE'S SCARED AND AFRAID
AND HE WOULD DO ANYTHING
RIGHT NOW,
HE WOULD SAY ANYTHING,
IF HE THOUGHT HE COULD
WIN BACK YOUR APPROVAL.
HE NEVER LOST IT.
AND IF YOU DON'T KNOW HE
DESERVES YOURS TOO, THEN YOU'VE
GOT A SERIOUS GODDAMN PROBLEM.
HOW DARE YOU?
- IT'S DONE, IT'S TAKEN CARE OF.
- JUST LIKE YOU TOOK CARE
OF THE EVIDENCE.
[ Ben ] THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU NEVER EVEN HAD TO
DIRTY YOUR PRECIOUS HANDS.
[ Carolyn ]
TRIM A LITTLE HERE,
ADD A LITTLE THERE.
HOW COULD I FORGET HOW CLEVER
YOU ARE AT MAKING THINGS?
ONE OF US HAD TO DO SOMETHING.
DO YOU THINK YOU'VE MADE IT
EASIER ON HIM NOW?
DO YOU NOT SEE THAT YOU
HAVE TIED HIS HANDS?
NOW HE HAS YOU TO DEFEND
AS WELL AS HIMSELF.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHAT?
THAT HE SHOULD PAY
WITH THE NEXT 20 YEARS,
30 YEARS OF HIS LIFE...
FOR ONE MISTAKE,
FOR ONE MOMENT?
THAT HE SHOULD COME OUT
OF PRISON A MIDDLE-AGED MAN?
WHO DOES THAT BENEFIT?
WHO?
OH, LOVE.
SOONER OR LATER SOMEBODY'S
GONNA HAVE TO BE FORGIVEN--
HIM FOR WHAT HE DID, OR US
BECAUSE WE DID NOTHING WHEN
WE HAD A CHANCE TO SAVE HIM.
WOULDN'T YOU RATHER
FORGIVE HIM?
[ Whispers ]
HEY... JUDE.
[ Door Closes ]
[ People Murmuring,
Chattering ]
GOOD NEWS.
OKAY, I STOPPED AT THE LAB
ON THE WAY UP HERE.
NOW, THEY HAD THE M.E.'S
FETAL TISSUE ANALYSIS...
AND THEY HAVE
THAT BLOOD SAMPLE THAT
WE SUBMITTED FROM JACOB.
OKAY, THIS GETS
PRETTY TECHNICAL, BUT--
JACOB WASN'T
THE FATHER.
BINGO.
OH, MAN, LISTEN TO ME,
TELLING A DOCTOR
WHAT'S TECHNICAL.
BUT THIS WORKS
BOTH WAYS, DOESN'T IT?
I MEAN, THEY COULD SAY
HE WAS JEALOUS.
THIS GIVES HIM A MOTIVE.
THIS LETS US
GO AFTER THE GIRL,
ATTACK HER CHARACTER.
MARTHA TAVERNER JUST BLEW
50 SYMPATHY POINTS.
LOOK AT IT THIS WAY:
THIS INTRODUCES DOUBT.
AND DOUBT, KIDDO,
IS OUR VERY BEST FRIEND.
- [ Door Opens ]
- MRS. RYAN?
[ Ben Shouting ]
GET AWAY FROM ME!
EXCUSE ME. MRS. RYAN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE'LL SEE YOU DAY AFTER
TOMORROW AT 10:00.
YES, THAT'S FINE.
[ Reporters Shouting ]
BENNY? BEN?
SCREW THEM! FORGET
THE WHOLE BUNCH OF THEM!
I DIDN'T TESTIFY
AND I WON'T TESTIFY!
SO YOU CAN PRINT
ANY DAMN THING YOU WANT TO!
HERE, GET THIS ONE!
YOU DIDN'T TESTIFY?
THERE'S GOTTA BE SOME
PROTECTION, SOME IMMUNITY,
SOME KIND OF PRIVILEGE SO THEY
CAN'T TRY TO MAKE YOU SNITCH
ON YOUR OWN FLESH AND BLOOD.
WHY DON'T YOU WRITE THAT?
THERE'S SUCH A THING AS
THE FIFTH AMENDMENT.
ASK MY LAWYER!
[ Reporter Shouting ]
WHAT ARE YOU HIDING?
WEREN'T YOU
LISTENING TO ME?
I TOLD YOU IF YOU HAD ANYTHING
TO ASK, COME OUT AND ASK ME!
I DIDN'T HAVE ANY QUESTIONS.
FIND ME SOME PRIVILEGE.
"FIND ME SOME PRIVILEGE."
WHAT, MAKE SOMETHING UP?
[ Reporters Murmuring ]
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS PARENT-CHILD IMMUNITY.
THERE OUGHTA BE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE ASKING FOR?
YOU'RE ASKING TO GO
TO JAIL FOR CONTEMPT,
FOR STARTERS.
YOU'RE ASKING ME TO GO
TO JAIL TOO, AND I'M NOT
DOING ANY SUCH THING FOR YOU.
WHAT DID HE MEAN
BY "PRIVILEGE"?
YOU'RE ACTING
AS IF WE'VE GOT SOMETHING
TO HIDE ABOUT JACOB.
THEY TWISTED EVERY WORD I SAID,
TRIED TO TRICK ME INTO SOME
KIND OF CONFLICTING EVIDENCE.
I WON'T PLAY THAT GAME.
I TOLD THEM SO. I GAVE THEM
A STATEMENT OF PRINCIPLE.
AND WHAT WAS THAT PRINCIPLE?
I THINK I MISSED THAT PART.
I DON'T BARGAIN FOR MY SON.
AND I WON'T HELP THEM
TO CONVICT HIM.
JESUS, BEN!
I WON'T TESTIFY, PANOS.
NOT TODAY, NOT EVER.
IF I HAVE TO GO TO JAIL,
SO BE IT.
AND IF THERE WAS ANY MORE
I COULD DO, YOU'D BETTER
BELIEVE I'D DO THAT TOO.
[ Reporters Shouting ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[ Knock On Door ]
OH. GIVE ME A MINUTE,
BEN, PLEASE.
MOM, CAN I
TALK TO YOU?
MM-HMM.
MOM, THEY'RE LYING.
THEY'RE COMPLETELY CHANGING
THE TRUTH OF WHAT HAPPENED.
HOW CAN YOU
LET THEM DO THAT?
WELL, PEOPLE DON'T GO
TO COURT NECESSARILY...
TO TELL THE TRUTH ABOUT
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED.
THEY, UM-- THEY GO
TO DEFEND THEMSELVES
THE BEST WAY THEY CAN.
BUT YOU HEARD JACOB
AND YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
ARE YOU JUST GONNA DO
WHAT DADDY SAYS?
[ Sighs ]
JUDE.
DIDN'T YOU EVER LEARN
SOMETHING ABOUT A FRIEND
OF YOURS, SOME SECRET,
BUT YOU KNEW IF YOU TOLD HER
IT WOULD JUST HURT HER FEELINGS,
SO YOU DIDN'T TELL?
I MEAN, THAT'S NOT--
THAT'S NOT LYING EXACTLY.
IT'S-- YOU JUST DIDN'T
VOLUNTEER SOMETHING.
JUST BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE DO,
JUST BECAUSE THEY MIGHT
GET AWAY WITH IT, DOES THAT
MEAN YOU HAVE TO LIE?
SOMETIMES-- YOU'RE JUST--
YOU'RE TOO YOUNG...
TO UNDERSTAND SOME THINGS,
THAT'S ALL.
I'M JUST BEGINNING TO LEARN
SOME OF THEM MYSELF.
SOMEDAY, DARLING,
YOU MIGHT...
DON'T TELL ME "SOMEDAY"!
UNDERSTAND WHAT DADDY--
I CAN'T STAND IT
WHEN YOU SAY "SOMEDAY"!
THIS IS HAPPENING
TO ME RIGHT NOW.
[ Judith ]
YOU LET DADDY CONVINCE YOU.
IT'S DISGUSTING.
NOBODY EVEN CARES
WHAT I THINK; I'M JUST
A STUPID LITTLE KID.
NOBODY EVEN THINKS THAT
I COULD GO AND TELL.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
"TELL"?
YOU FIGURE IT OUT!
JUDITH.
[ Door Slams ]
[ Footsteps
Descending Stairs ]
CAROLYN,
YOU ASLEEP?
MM-MMM.
ABRAHAM AND ISAAC.
REMEMBER THAT STORY?
GOD SAYS TO ABRAHAM,
"PROVE YOUR FAITH.
"TAKE ISAAC,
YOUR BELOVED SON,
AND SACRIFICE HIM.
"WHY?
BECAUSE I'M GOD.
BECAUSE I SAY SO."
AND ABRAHAM IS WILLING.
HE'S VERY SAD,
BUT HE'LL DO IT.
HE'LL CUT
HIS OWN SON'S THROAT...
IF THAT'S WHAT GOD
REQUIRES.
VERY OBEDIENT,
ABRAHAM.
AND VERY RIGHTEOUS.
BUT WHEN
THEY TELL THAT STORY
THEY ALWAYS MISS THE POINT.
WHO'D WANT HIM
FOR A FATHER?
[ People Chattering
Quietly ]
GOOD MORNING, CAROLYN.
HI.
FIRST TIME
YOU'VE DONATED BLOOD?
YES.
[ Sighs ]
[ Toilet Flushes ]
MRS. TAVERNER.
OH, PLEASE.
THIS HAS BEEN,
FOR ME, FOR ALL OF US--
IT'S THE HARDEST--
I'VE JUST-- I'VE SPENT
A THOUSAND HOURS NOT SLEEPING,
THINKING ABOUT... MARTHA.
AND I JUST WANT YOU
TO KNOW HOW SORRY I AM.
I AM SO SORRY.
I KNOW IT WON'T
CHANGE ANYTHING, BUT--
[ Sighs ]
OH, GOD, IF YOU COULD--
WHAT?
IF I COULD WHAT?
IF YOU COULD SOMEHOW...
LOOK AT US AS HUMAN--
AS A FAMILY, I MEAN.
JUST AS A FAMILY
THAT'S ALSO SO HELPLESS.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO BE HELPLESS ABOUT?
YOU TELL ME THAT.
SHE WAS ALIVE IN THE MORNING
WHEN I SAID GOOD-BYE TO HER.
YOU'RE A DOCTOR.
YOU THINK ABOUT THIS,
WHERE SHE IS NOW.
AND NOTHING YOU SAY
IS GONNA GET ANY PITY
OUT OF ME.
OH, I'M NOT ASKING
FOR YOUR PITY.
I'M-- I'M JUST--
YOU'RE TRYING
TO GET HIM OFF.
WITH YOUR BIG SHOT LAWYER
AND ALL YOUR MONEY.
HE'S FREE TO WALK THE STREETS
RIGHT NOW, AND YOU'RE TRYING
TO GET HIM OFF.
PEOPLE LIKE YOU THINK
THEY OWN THE WORLD.
[ People Chattering ]
[ Glass Breaking ]
JESUS.
- STAY INSIDE.
CALL THE POLICE.
- [ Carolyn ] NO, BEN!
- [ Jacob ] DAD, DON'T!
- [ Ben ] HEY!
- COME HERE, YOU BASTARD!
- [ Man ] I DID IT.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
- BEN!
- [ Man Grunts ]
HEY! HEY, YOU!
COME ON!
JAKE! JAKE!
PLEASE!
LET'S GO!
COME ON!
[ Men Yelling,
Whooping ]
MOM!
GOD!
GODDAMN IT!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
HERE!
THIS IS YOUR FAULT!
BOTH OF YOURS!
YOU'VE TURNED US ALL
INTO FREAKS!
SHUT UP, ALL RIGHT?
I WISH YOU'D NEVER COME BACK.
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST STAY AWAY?
I HATE YOU!
OHH!
[ Ben ]
IT'S OKAY, JAKE.
[ Yells ]
AAAH! GOD!
HELP!
[ Carolyn ]
JACOB!
[ Ben ]
GET DOWN!
[ Jacob Whimpering ]
[ Crying ]
IT'S OKAY.
LET'S GENTLY, GENTLY
GET HIM UP.
IT'S OKAY.
COME ON, SWEETHEART.
LET ME LOOK. LET ME SEE.
THAT'S IT, THAT'S IT,
THAT'S IT.
NO, NO. I CAN'T--
I CAN'T TREAT THIS HERE.
[ Whimpering ]
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
TAKE HIM TO THE OFFICE.
I'LL COME TOO.
NO, YOU STAY HERE
WITH JUDITH.
CAROLYN, I--
PLEASE, BEN.
THIS WON'T HURT,
I PROMISE.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M JUST GONNA
WRAP THIS UP...
SO WE DON'T HAVE TO
WORRY ABOUT INFECTION.
OKAY?
YOU MAY START TO FEEL
DROWSY NOW FROM THAT SHOT.
SO IF YOU DO, YOU JUST
PUT YOUR HEAD DOWN.
OKAY, LOVE?
OKAY.
MOM?
MM-HMM?
JUDE IS RIGHT.
YOU'D ALL BE BETTER OFF
IF I JUST DISAPPEARED.
MAYBE I STILL SHOULD.
DON'T EVEN SAY THAT.
I DON'T MEAN JUST YOU.
I MEAN--
I MEAN THE WHOLE TOWN.
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT
THEY WANT, ISN'T IT?
NO.
NO, JAKE, THOSE MEN--
THOSE MEN TONIGHT
WERE COWARDS.
IF YOU SAW THEM TOMORROW
IN THEIR SHOPS,
THEY'D SMILE AND NOD
WHILE THEY GAVE YOU CHANGE.
I'M THE COWARD.
I FEEL LIKE I'M BEING
TORN APART, YOU KNOW?
AND--
[ Sighs ]
IF I HOLD THIS IN,
I-IT'S LIKE...
A POISON, YOU KNOW?
IF I TELL THE TRUTH,
DAD'LL GO TO JAIL TOO.
HE'LL HATE ME.
EITHER WAY,
IT'S THE END OF US.
YOUR DAD'LL NEVER,
NEVER HATE YOU.
YOUR DAD LOVES YOU...
SO MUCH, JACOB.
AND RIGHT OR WRONG,
HE ALWAYS GIVES...
HIS WHOLE HEART.
IT CAN BE PRETTY
OVERWHELMING SOMETIMES...
BECAUSE HE JUST ALWAYS
SEEMS SO SURE.
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO
BE THAT WAY.
YOU KNOW?
IT IS POSSIBLE
TO DISAGREE WITH SOMEONE...
AND STILL LOVE THEM.
AT A CERTAIN POINT,
WE JUST--
WE HAVE TO MAKE
OUR OWN DECISIONS.
YEAH. YEAH, BUT HE
RISKED SO MUCH FOR ME.
MMM.
HE DIDN'T EVEN STOP
TO COUNT THE PRICE.
HE JUST DID IT.
MOM?
HMM?
HOW CAN I LET HIM DOWN?
HOW CAN I
DO THAT TO HIM?
YEAH.
HOW CAN YOU?
[ Whispering ]
MRS. RYAN?
DR. RYAN?
[ People Chattering ]
THERE SHE IS!
DR. RYAN!
DR. RYAN, DID YOU ALSO
REFUSE TO TESTIFY?
- HOW'D IT GO, TROUPER?
- I DID IT. I TOLD THEM.
SEE?
WHAT'D I TELL YOU?
NO SWEAT.
NO, I MEAN I TOLD THEM
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
WHAT?
BEN AND JACOB
HAVEN'T BEEN TELLING YOU
THE TRUTH, PANOS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU HAVEN'T KNOWN THAT.
WHOA, WHOA!
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA DO ABOUT THIS.
YOU COME WITH ME.
[ Reporter ]
MIGHT WE HAVE
A STATEMENT, PLEASE?
DR. RYAN!
EXCUSE ME!
TALK.
IT'S HARD TO SAY.
THEY'VE BEEN IN THERE
20 MINUTES.
THERE'S NO STORY HERE.
TWENTY MINUTES!
WHAT ARE THEY TALKING ABOUT?
OKAY. MY TURN.
JACOB DOESN'T KNOW,
DOES HE?
DID YOU AT LEAST
TELL BEN?
OH, JESUS CHRIST.
ALL I CAN SAY IS I HOPE HE
DOESN'T HAVE HIS SON'S TEMPER,
BECAUSE I WORRY ABOUT YOU.
HE DOESN'T HAVE
HIS SON'S TEMPER.
HIS SON HAS HIS.
THIS WEAPON.
THIS CAR JACK
THAT YOU SAY KILLED HER.
WHERE IS IT NOW?
IT'LL NEVER SURFACE,
I PROMISE YOU,
BUT I'M NEVER GOING TO SAY.
- DID YOU EVER SEE IT?
- MM-MMM.
WELL, THEN IT'S HEARSAY.
JUST LIKE THIS SO-CALLED
CONFESSION; IT'S YOUR WORD
AGAINST BEN AND JACOB'S.
THERE'S STILL NO PROOF.
PANOS, IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
WHY CAN'T JACOB
JUST TELL THE TRUTH?
JACOB IS MY CLIENT,
NOT YOU, NOT YOUR HUSBAND.
JACOB.
AND THERE'S NO WAY
I'M GOING TO PUT HIM
ON THAT WITNESS STAND...
FOR MARIAN RAYNOR
TO CUT TO PIECES.
I'M GONNA DEFEND YOUR SON
EVEN IF YOU DON'T.
EVEN IF IT MEANS
HANGING YOU OUT TO DRY.
ME?
COLD.
VINDICTIVE.
FULL OF CRAZY, PARANOID
FANTASIES ABOUT YOUR SON
AND HIS LOW-CLASS LOVER.
HONEY, BY THE TIME
I'M DONE WITH YOU,
YOU'LL LOOK LIKE MEDEA.
PANOS, IF YOU TRY
TO GO ON HIDING THIS--
IF WE DON'T,
AT SOME POINT, ACCEPT
WHAT ACTUALLY DID HAPPEN--
WHAT ACTUALLY HAPPENED?
CAROLYN, WHAT'S IT GONNA TAKE
FOR YOU TO GET THIS?
THEY TELL THEIR VERSION
OF THE STORY; WE TELL OURS.
- AND THESE 12 PEOPLE
DECIDE THE TRUTH.
- THAT'S NOT THE TRUTH.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT A CONTEST
BETWEEN AD CAMPAIGNS.
- I'M TALKING ABOUT
SAVING YOUR SON.
- SO AM I.
IT'S ABSOLUTE,
WHY I DID THIS, PANOS.
FINALLY, IT'S JUST
ONE TRUE THING.
ABSOLUTE.
I DIDN'T ASK YOUR PERMISSION
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT IT.
WE CAN'T AFFORD IT ANYMORE.
OH, MY DEAR DOCTOR.
YOU AND YOUR
GODDAMN ABSOLUTES.
YOU'LL SEE WHAT
A SHALLOW, LITTLE THING
YOUR PRINCIPLES ARE...
WHEN YOUR FAMILY'S
BLOWN TO HELL.
AND YOU WON'T
BE ABLE TO TAKE BACK
ONE SINGLE WORD.
JACOB. JACOB.
WHAT?
COME ON, WAKE UP.
COME AND HEAR WHAT
YOUR MOTHER'S DONE.
SHE'S DONE IT NOW, BOY.
SHE JUST COULDN'T KEEP
HER BIG MOUTH SHUT.
DAD, STOP.
YOU'RE HURTING ME.
WHAT IS IT? WHAT'S WRONG?
SHE'LL TELL YOU HERSELF.
TELL HIM.
TELL HIM!
WHAT KIND OF A LIFE
ARE WE GOING TO HAVE,
HMM?
WHAT KIND OF A LIFE,
ALL OF US?
I LOVE YOU AND I WANTED
TO SAVE YOU.
BUT SAVE YOU FOR WHAT?
AS WHAT?
EVERYTHING HE'S
BEEN FOR 16 YEARS,
EVERYTHING HE IS.
- THAT WASN'T ENOUGH
TO MAKE HIM VALUABLE?
- OHH.
YOU NEVER WANTED TO SAVE HIM.
YOU BROUGHT HIM
INTO THIS LIFE...
- BUT YOU'RE NOT
WILLING TO FORGIVE HIM.
- I FORGIVE US ALL, BEN.
JAKE, FOR GOD'S SAKE,
DON'T LISTEN TO HER.
WE CAN'T GIVE UP NOW.
OH, LEAVE HIM ALONE.
THERE'S STILL A CHANCE.
DON'T YOU HAVE ANY FAITH
IN HIM AT ALL?
WE CAN STILL FIGHT THIS,
YOU AND ME TOGETHER.
YOU BACK OFF.
BACK OFF MY SON.
IF HE'S YOUR SON,
THEN ACT LIKE IT.
JACOB. JAKIE,
I DID THIS FOR YOU,
FOR BOTH OF YOU.
I ONLY WAS TRYING TO HELP YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
OH, COME ON!
YOU'RE ASKING A HELL OF A LOT
IF YOU EXPECT YOUR OWN SON TO
UNDERSTAND WHY YOU BETRAYED HIM.
- I DIDN'T BE--
YOU CAN'T SAY THAT!
- GODDAMN IT, JUST STOP IT!
ALL RIGHT?
BOTH OF YOU.
HEY, MOM! MOM!
WAKE UP!
JACOB'S GONE.
HMM?
WHAT?
JACOB! HE'S GONE.
HE'S GONE.
CHECK THE KITCHEN
AND THE BACK OF THE HOUSE.
I ALREADY LOOKED.
LOOK AGAIN.
OH, NO.
OHH.
THE JEEP'S GONE.
HE'S RUNNING AGAIN,
AND THIS TIME HE'LL NEVER STOP.
NO, HE DIDN'T TAKE
ANY CLOTHES OR FOOD.
I'M ALMOST SURE, BEN.
MAYBE HE DOESN'T THINK
HE'LL NEED THEM.
MAYBE HE'S GONNA
DRIVE THAT THING
STRAIGHT INTO A TREE.
OH, MY GOD.
NO, THAT CAN'T BE TRUE.
BEN? CAROLYN?
I THINK YOU'D BETTER
COME WITH ME.
DO THEY KNOW?
UH-UH.
JACOB, WERE YOU RUNNING
TO SOME--
NO, I CAME DOWN HERE
TO TELL 'EM THE TRUTH.
EVERYTHING.
JUST LIKE I TOLD YOU.
BUT YOU WON'T BELIEVE THIS.
IT TURNS OUT
THAT IT'S NOT THAT EASY...
EVEN IF YOU REALLY WANT TO.
TURNS OUT THAT MY STATEMENT
ISN'T LEGAL UNLESS IT'S
SIGNED BY MY PARENTS.
DAD?
YOU WANT THIS NOW.
YOU THINK YOU WANT THIS,
BUT, JAKE,
YOU'RE STILL UPSET
FROM LAST NIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT
THINKING CLEARLY.
PLEASE, I AM. I AM.
I AM THINKING CLEARLY.
I'LL DO MY BEST TO LEAVE YOU
OUT OF THIS, BUT YOU MIGHT BE
IN SOME TROUBLE TOO.
AND I'M SORRY.
IS THAT WHAT YOU--
OH, GOD, JAKE.
IS THAT WHAT YOU THINK
THIS WAS EVER ABOUT?
FOR ONE MINUTE?
I DON'T CARE
WHAT HAPPENS TO ME.
WHY DO YOU THINK
I'VE BEEN DOING ALL THIS?
YOU THINK I'M SOME--
SOME KIND OF A SELFISH BULLY?
I'VE ALWAYS GOT TO HAVE
MY OWN WAY? JAKE.
NO. DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT YOU SAID TO ME?
YOU SAID THE WORST THING
YOU CAN BE CALLED...
IS SOMEONE WHO DIDN'T
STAND UP FOR HIS FAMILY.
THIS IS MY WAY.
THIS IS HOW I'VE
GOTTA STAND UP.
FOR US.
FOR OUR FAMILY.
THEY'LL PROBABLY TAKE IT
WITH JUST MOM'S SIGNATURE
ON IT.
BUT I NEED YOU TO DO THIS.
I NEED YOU
TO DO THIS, PLEASE.
I NEED THIS FOR ME,
PLEASE.
I HAD TO BE STRONG.
I HAD TO ACT CERTAIN
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT YOU
NEEDED FROM ME; ALL OF YOU.
BUT I CAN'T DO THIS.
[ Clipboard
Lands On Bench ]
I CAN NEVER PUT MY HAND
TO ANYTHING THAT WOULD
TAKE YOU AWAY FROM ME.
I LOVE YOU TOO MUCH, JAKE.
NOTHING CAN EVER
TAKE ME AWAY FROM YOU.
OH, SON. MY SON.
[ Jacob Sobs ]
I WISH WE COULD GO BACK.
YEAH.
I NEVER KNEW
HOW MUCH YOU LOVED ME.
I NEVER KNEW THAT.
[ Ben Sobs ]
[ Jacob ]
JUDITH?
JAKE.
[ Panos ]
LANGDALE'S A GOOD JUDGE.
HE'S SMART AND HE'S FAIR,
AND I THINK I MAY HAVE
CONVINCED HIM...
THAT PRISON TIME
IN THIS CASE WOULD BE
COMPLETELY INAPPROPRIATE.
I THINK WE GOT
A REAL SHOT.
BUT YOU SURE DIDN'T
LEAVE ME MUCH TO TRADE WITH.
I GUESS WE HAVEN'T BEEN
THE MOST HELPFUL CLIENTS
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
WHY DIDN'T YOU QUIT,
PANOS?
I TOLD YOU
I'D DEFEND JACOB.
OR MAYBE I JUST WANTED TO SEE
WHAT YOU TWO WOULD DO NEXT.
[ Bailiff ]
HEAR YE, HEAR YE.
THE THIRD DISTRICT COURT
IS NOW IN SESSION.
THE HONORABLE HENRY LANGDALE
PRESIDING. ALL RISE.
PLEASE BE SEATED.
HAVING REVIEWED ALL THE
EVIDENCE AND TESTIMONY...
IN THE CASE OF THE PEOPLE
VERSUS JACOB RYAN, JUVENILE,
THIS COURT IS NOW PREPARED
TO RENDER JUDGMENT.
MARTHA TAVERNER'S DEATH,
IN THE OPINION OF THIS COURT,
WAS NEITHER PREMEDITATED
NOR DELIBERATELY CAUSED
BY THE DEFENDANT.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
THERE WAS A HEATED ARGUMENT,
A MUTUALLY RECKLESS STRUGGLE,
BUT NO CRIMINAL INTENT.
[ Murmuring Continues ]
YOUNG MAN,
I'M ALSO MINDFUL THAT YOU'VE
EXPRESSED DEEP REMORSE;
THAT YOU'VE MADE A FULL
AND FREE CONFESSION...
AND DONE SO AT YOUR OWN
INSISTENCE WITHOUT STIPULATING
A PLEA BARGAIN.
NEVERTHELESS, YOU HAVE
A CLEAR CULPABILITY.
BY RUNNING AWAY,
BY COVERING UP
YOUR INVOLVEMENT...
IN THE DEATH
OF MARTHA TAVERNER,
YOU CAST GRAVE DOUBTS
ON YOUR OWN ACTIONS...
AND YOU SHORT-CIRCUITED
THE VERY PROTECTIONS
AFFORDED YOU UNDER THE LAW.
JACOB RYAN, PLEASE RISE.
- I FIND YOU GUILTY...
- [ Crowd Gasps, Murmurs ]
OF INVOLUNTARY MANSLAUGHTER
IN THE SECOND DEGREE.
I SENTENCE YOU TO BE TAKEN
FROM THIS PLACE AND CONFINED...
AT THE JUVENILE CORRECTION
FACILITY AT FRAMINGHAM...
FOR A PERIOD
NOT TO EXCEED FIVE YEARS.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
[ Gavel Bangs ]
STILL THINK
IT WAS WORTH IT?
[ Judith Narrating ]
MY FATHER HAD TO SERVE ALMOST
A YEAR FOR DESTROYING EVIDENCE.
JACOB WAS RELEASED ON PROBATION
AFTER TWO YEARS.
HE HAS TO GO TO COUNSELING,
THOUGH.
SO WE HAVE THEM BACK.
BUT NONE OF US IS FREE.
EACH OF US
IS MARKED FOREVER NOW.
BEFORE... AND AFTER.
I LOOK AT JACOB NOW...
AND I THINK ABOUT
HOW DIFFERENT OUR LIVES
MIGHT HAVE BEEN.
ALL OF US. AND THAT'S
THE SADDEST PART OF ALL.
[ Jacob ]
HEY, JUDE, LOOK!
[ Judith ]
BUT LATELY, SOMETIMES,
I CAN FEEL MYSELF STARTING
TO COME ALIVE AGAIN.
AND IT'S SCARY, KIND OF.
I DON'T KNOW
IF THAT'S EVEN ALLOWED.
MAYBE YOU CAN'T EXPECT
TO KEEP HAPPINESS OUT
OF YOUR LIFE FOREVER,
ANY MORE THAN TROUBLE.
YOUR WHOLE LIFE CAN CHANGE
IN A SECOND,
AND YOU NEVER EVEN KNOW
WHEN IT'S COMING.