Does it work?
To our friend, Hal Fields.
Hal, we love you!
Arthur,
you will come live with me, OK?
That's my car.
The dining room,
where people are sometimes dinner.
The living room.
The bathroom.
We are in 2003.
Looks like the sun,
the stars
nature.
The President.
And here is the sun in 1955,
the stars
nature
cars,
phones,
movies and the President.
Pets.
The fireworks.
Smoking, that was it.
Kissing, that was it.
Be happy.
Be sad.
My parents were married in 1955.
He ran a museum,
She restored the house.
They had a child
and stayed married 44 years
until she died in their beds,
after 4 months of cancer
to eat only french toast
before the Teletubbies,
by confusing
straws and cigarettes
and mixing times
in his head.
Six months later,
my father told me he was gay.
He had just turned 75.
I'm gay.
I remember him in purple sweater
but in reality he was wearing a bathrobe.
I loved your mother, but ...
Now I want to explore
that side.
I do not want to be gay
in my head.
I want to live.
He changed his wardrobe.
He found a boyfriend, Andy,
a sports coach
who spent his patent for fireworks.
After my coming out,
my father did me more about.
Since I am attracted
by older men.
It took a gay priest
as a spiritual guide.
He saw a psychiatrist for the 1st time.
He adhered to the Prime Timers,
to movie nights,
Pride in Los Angeles.
Four years after coming out,
he died in that room.
It's hard, loneliness ...
You should learn to talk to me.
I understand up to 150 words
but I do not know about.
I know.
Breathe calmly.
Oliver!
Remove me the ropes.
Daddy, stop!
You're going to hurt.
Mr. Fields, we will have
You attach the arms.
You two are married?
No, Dad.
Why not? It is great!
It's a great nurse
but does not know well.
T'assomment drugs.
Ah, you always had
good excuses.
Is not it?
No, I just do not become
as a mom and you.
Thank you!
Oliver?
Better than that!
That's good!
Throw yourself,
live your life with your fellow!
I will not stir from here.
I am a man, not a dog.
You are a Jack Russell,
a dog breed.
Your character was invented
by John Russell
a passion for hunting in the 19th century.
He raised your ancestors
for their endurance of hunters.
Do you think fox hunting
is your thing,
but you have been instilled
there for ages.
Today, bizarrely
humans find you cute.
They will raise
not for hunting
but to be cute
to show you on TV
in movies ...
You run after the ball
because you have more foxes!
MY PERSONALITY
WORK IS ANOTHER
And all he left behind,
IS THIS MORON T-SHIRT
Hi, Liz.
LOTS OF CHESS
I brought one of your books.
Okay.
Pass me the torch.
It's pretty ...
Andy has offered them to you.
It is that this picture?
I do not know.
It's just for decoration.
- And this?
- Photos, period.
What they do
in the exhibition?
These are personal photos,
not artistic.
That's the trick to fire.
- It's beautiful.
- What?
The Japanese garden up there.
It's beautiful.
Hal?
Andy!
I have something for you.
You've made a recording.
Even musicians
who want their portraits!
It pays the rent ...
You do something pretty
and they'll claim the same.
Hi, Liz.
Oliver?
The felt is not your friend.
The paper
is not your friend.
The party is your friend.
We are your friends.
Friends ...
are your friends.
I know how to
He knows how to move
I am moving
You know how it
Arthur, you're not invited to the party.
You're going to keep the house.
You remember Oliver
when he was funny?
When he spoke
in complete sentences?
"Funny" I do not know ...
"Fun" instead.
But if "dismal" is "fun"
it is pissing with laughter.
"Adorable", here!
You are absolutely adorable.
It is too cute!
He knows tricks?
Arthur does not turns.
Arthur sat!
The tab!
It is too cute, I do!
You zentai omnipotent
by giving zordres?
- Za gives you power?
- You are a psycho!
Freud!
Goodbye, Arthur!
I have not asked to be like that!
This color, nose,
the cheeks, chin ...
It's my life.
It is not in a fairy
nor a joke.
It feels good, Doctor.
To say what was on the heart.
Sorry, our session is over
for the week.
Thank you for coming.
I was just going to take a break.
We will kommencer by fotre mother.
I HAVE NOT UES
Fotre and father?
I do not understand, you're dumb?
Broblème pzykologique?
Crazy tread therapy?
I HAVE laryngitis
Z 'is a broblème of Zakynthos.
What are you doing at a party
If you are sad?
I managed to hide it so well ...
How did you guess?
Here I must drink a shot.
And you?
You stay there?
It's not a normal color
for a chicken.
You see what happens to you
when you leave your cage
- And you escape?
- You're more your color.
- Un .. Two ...
- Two glasses.
- What does that mean?
- They are two.
A girl and a guy?
Move!
Hello?
Oliver?
I am not sorry
to wake you up!
I went out to the Bar Act tonight.
Really?
They went to music
fantastically powerful ...
What is this music?
No doubt the house.
As "home." Okay ...
House ...
Music house.
- You made a match?
- Huh?
Young gays
do not want old gays.
For you, it's easy.
Would you like to dance?
Hello!
I can give you my number?
Thank you.
Tell him that the darkness
we swallow
If nothing radical
only comes on the spot.
I'm sorry I took Arthur,
I must go home.
I enjoyed our meeting.
"Goodbye!"
Is that you?
A beep for "yes".
I always wanted to talk
someone who is silent.
You want something done?
Now?
I parked a little higher.
You show leadership,
I drive.
By that?
It's pretty.
My mother?
My mother died there five years.
You have spoken!
It should not be.
My father died there two months.
Almost three.
He was gay.
He was gay throughout their marriage.
He's coming out
after the death of my mother,
at 75.
Forgiveness.
Are we may just sleep?
Of course.
WHO ARE YOU?
Oliver.
CASTING FOR NEW YORK.
RETURN Thursday.
After that, you stay here how long?
A year?
A month?
Okay ... Then what?
You play in a movie here.
What next?
Elsewhere ... Where?
I CAN see you again?
Hello, House!
"Hello, Oliver!"
Dad, you get so much mail!
Hal, progress has been remarkable
since you are on life support.
But ... ?
Bronchoscopy revealed a mass
the size of a coin
in the right lung.
The biopsy shows
it is cancerous.
I see.
It spread
to lymph nodes
of the chest and liver.
Given the weakness of the heart and lungs,
surgery
is impossible.
We can start by rays
and see if you support a chemo.
You can go home.
Have a question?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
No hurry to announce.
With Andy?
No need to panic.
You read me something?
"The Brazilian dancer
"Is a demonstrated ability to partner
"But also a soloist
inspiration multiple
"Which can be interpreted ..."
No hurry
TO ADVERTISE
Do not say anything
FIRST DECAPITATION
FIRST LUNG CANCER
- He sleeps on your bed.
- He eats?
Yes, he eats.
I am so worried ...
There you are!
- What is it?
- A slug.
Andy, you can not get it ...
If I can. Look!
Fuck you.
This is the time of the inspection.
Hello, Mr. Fields.
I'm Andy, the companion of Hal.
Me is Sophia.
I have as much right to be here
as anyone.
Go for a walk, calm down.
What was that?
It's not easy for Andy either.
Be nice to him.
Forgiveness.
Where did you pick up that?
In our own! Cheers!
Alcohol is prohibited in the rooms.
Really?
Excuse me ...
No, no!
This is an amazing nurse.
The health system!
What have you done to my father?
He was so nice!
I invited him,
but no longer answers me!
Two, four, six, eight.
That's all you talking about?
I'll see her at her hotel, OK?
Are you happy?
Yes, very happy.
And you're happy?
There are eight.
We have not had
of real conversation ...
You think about her all the time.
- You say that because ... ?
- Because you do not speak.
I know you!
It's true.
I am ashamed. At 38,
I fall in love with a girl.
As if I had lost the user manual
or that I had ever had.
Where is Dad?
The museum.
Is there something wrong
you?
- You're the FBI?
- No.
The CIA?
KGB?
SLA?
CIPF?
BMW?
Nothing wrong between Dad and me.
When you are sad,
you go to your room
you scream loudly
one or two minutes
and it goes away.
It's called catharsis.
I do not want to cry.
It will come.
What is this shit?
"L-E-IT" Elliot.
- But this is ridiculous!
- I know.
You are not encouraging.
You copy something that was done
there 30 years in the Bronx.
Yes, I continues a tradition
citizen of insubordination.
I leave my limits.
How does it work?
Must be shaken. Shake!
1985: BUSH discover Jesus
And that's what?
Awareness of history.
I leave my limits.
Is repeated.
OK but when you see her,
do not tell him you're taggueur
Awareness of history.
It is nice.
Your father is missing.
Perhaps it could be ...
talk a little bit.
Okay.
My name is Anna.
You're afraid to trust me,
you do not know me.
I understand.
It makes sense to me.
Oliver, stop!
It's old music!
It's black music.
This is the deepest:
it is they who have suffered most.
They and the Jews.
In my next life,
marry a Jew very passionate.
Someone emotionally.
I am a Jew, right?
You're the fourth.
Me in half.
Your father at all.
He's the least emotional.
You will be more emotional than he
but I'm the most emotional.
You make the driver
but way down the coast.
You become an excellent driver.
Excuse me, Mrs. Fields ...
What is prohibited
dialogue with the work?
Is that ...
And you love
to the citizen wise?
No.
You pass me my jacket?
No, my jacket.
"Caraco"?
You do not know what it is?
I was raised by animals.
They did not like questions.
They disapproved of it.
I had to just guess.
Ask me any questions
you want.
All?
What is out there?
A tree.
Of cars.
Another building.
With people in it, like us.
Half think
it will never work.
The other half
believes in miracles.
This is war between them.
How do you know people as well?
We must learn
to read their faces.
For example,
here is
anger.
Joy!
Sometimes there is nothing.
There is nothing there.
They know very well show
something
while they are something else.
You do not know me.
I like it.
- No, it's wrong.
- Really?
You have blond hair,
long before.
You smoke where prohibited.
Sometimes you bite ...
You, you drive on the sidewalk.
You were raised by animals.
Sometimes you seem very alone
as if you had just landed.
You see, you do not know me at all.
I have never seen a girl like that.
A spark into your life
and you fall into the trap.
When is the wedding?
It does not work like that.
There are other steps.
It's complicated.
I hope this feeling will last.
So do I.
Why it's over
Michelle?
I do not know ...
She seemed great.
It was great.
You should spend
a classified ad
to explain your situation.
My "situation"?
You want to be a couple
and you are not.
It's your father's advice?
The ads?
Lots of people do that.
Even me.
What?
Andy is not monogamous,
why should I be?
Name of God, Dad!
Name of God yourself!
Hello, House!
"Hello, Hal!"
What this time?
A green caterpillar.
- There is no green caterpillar.
- But if!
Damn, it's disgusting!
You go?
Yes. Michael is visiting.
Okay ...
I thought it was your boyfriend.
At least I'm his No. 1 ...
Dad!
My stomach ...
Come on.
- Imagine ...
- Arthur, come down!
Imagine that
since you were small,
you have always dreamed
to have a lion.
You wait, you wait ...
And the lion can not.
Then comes a giraffe.
Either you stay alone,
either you keep the giraffe.
Me, I'd wait lion.
That's what worries me.
THE HISTORY OF SADNESS
THE EARTH IS FORMED
(SADNESS not yet invented)
First married couple
For the wrong reasons
INVENTION OF ALCOHOL
(ANCIENT EGYPT)
GAY FIRST DIAGNOSED
MENTAL PATIENTS
PILGRIMS
PAST
THIS
You want me to be
with someone like me.
I love Andy
because it is not like me.
He's funny.
You found what?
Liv Ullmann ...
A professional!
And I dug
This book of crazy!
It's something very American.
Maybe we will find
very American things to do.
Page 75?
, Or from 75
to page 80.
"Louise Brooks, star of silent films,
"Was banished from Hollywood
in the thirties
"And finally as a sales
Saks 5th Avenue. "
I love it.
"Veronika Lake
"Model and was featured in the movies.
"After a series of broken marriages,
"She struggled against his mental illness
and alcoholism.
"She died of hepatitis
at 53. "
All these stories of players ...
I can tell you.
This is not good.
Well, I want
of real Mexican food.
And then try the page ...
46!
No!
- Yes
- Really?
It's really good.
So what?
It's too good.
I was not sure that you love.
You're an actress,
you live in a fancy hotel ...
I love this place.
Before, I loved the hotels.
Now
I change all the time flat
or hotel, anywhere.
How do you keep your friends
or your little friends?
It can quickly fall into loneliness.
Stay away from people.
Even without moving
you can get away from people.
You're like that, you?
That you?
Then
it is the same?
I feel.
I wake you?
Thank you, Maria.
Since you're here,
can you store it there?
I reorganized everything.
The Prednisone makes you crazy.
I did not sleep, that's all.
Dad, you should rest.
As soon as I finish these papers.
Okay, the papers?
"Okay, Hal.
"When you have finished,
you can rest. "
What?
No. You're pretty.
No.
If!
Jewish girls are not pretty.
They are "interesting"
"Cute" but not "pretty".
Are you kidding here?
My mother told me.
This is not true!
No, you're right.
It was a little girl to school.
At home, my mother told me:
"Anna, who told you that?"
Anna tells me is how
she is Jewish, in 2003.
How do I tell him
my mother was Jewish.
My father gave
his homosexuality
when my mother gave
his Jewishness.
They married in 1955.
My mother did not learn she was Jewish
than 13 years.
In 1938.
People, that was it.
Lions,
giraffes.
He was "The Man of the Year".
His father did not say
they were Jews.
The team sent the
when they learned she was Jewish.
That was "pretty" in 1938.
My father knew he was gay
at 13.
In 1938.
That was "pretty".
The high school where they met.
The war they made each.
This man was famous
when they found themselves.
This is the only place where my father
made love in the 50s.
He said: "If the vice squad
we took, we lost everything. "
"All", that was it.
My father lay on a couch
to talk about his problems
in 1955.
For the doctor, homosexuality
was a mental illness
we could treat.
Everyone would not heal.
My parents lived here in 1955.
And there, the first gay movement
met in secret.
During their wedding ceremony,
Allen Ginsberg wrote his famous
poem "Howl" a few blocks away.
"... Who is left
take the ass
"Angelic by bikers
screaming for joy
"Who sucked and were sucked
these human seraphim ... "
Just do their portrait.
This is an album cover, right?
That's all they want.
Okay.
Damn!
I know. Go.
It's about the Gay Pride.
Do not touch it.
Okay.
And that's the Gay Book Club.
Do not touch it either.
And the chair, she is gay?
The chair is not gay.
Is clear.
The hose is not long enough!
The beard, that thing!
What's that?
Now that you got out of hospital
we must exercise.
Good idea!
- We try. I'll show you.
- Later ...
I make tea.
Well, I'll clean it ...
The vase your mother needs flowers.
It must be said to Andy
you are not going well.
You leave the hospital.
You should take it easy.
Tell him, okay?
Me?
Please.
You know, I tried
to sleep with women.
I wanted you to know
I've tried. It did not work.
I have no problem
with gays.
Have you ever slept with a man?
It is said that a man
who has not slept with another man
always afraid of gays.
They represent a threat.
I do not know, Andy ...
I did not want you to feel threatened.
I do not want to sleep with you!
My practical
it's called even
sexuality.
I could not tell him.
It's good.
But no.
You can not hide from him,
he loves you.
You are very lavish
for someone so alone.
Take a look natural.
When he has his back turned,
it breaks.
No, no!
It was my father.
It is so bad?
I am my father
and you make me.
Sweetie?
You can never remember!
I'm busy.
I turn all the time.
You know, I keep thinking ...
You know that.
To do so.
To do what?
Kill myself.
You're the one to whom I can say.
You should talk
Mom, not me.
You are my daughter.
Now I have to kill you.
- Everything was going so well ...
- I know.
Sorry.
Really?
Hi, Anna.
Hi, Oliver.
That would tell you, vandalism?
I do not know.
Maybe so.
Oliver,
no text seriously, okay?
A funny thing.
Girls like fun.
Give me Arthur.
We will stay there
until it is done to stop.
You?
Yes. I will stay here
with my new friend.
Anna?
I try to impress you.
Is that true?
It works.
You make me laugh but it's not FUNNY
Arthur!
Sorry.
No problem.
What is it, this card?
I can?
Thank you.
It looked like your father?
At one point, he refused to admit
he was sick.
Oliver,
I want you to Blake.
A wonderful man.
I finally have a tattoo!
For that I find if I get lost.
Good for him.
We bought a lot.
Full of books.
Clothing.
He was obsessed by the paper mills.
We bought lots of plants.
Lots of parties.
- Glad you came.
- I was going to prepare us for dinner!
It's movie night, dummy!
Hal, you're beautiful.
I'm trying to turn the corner.
The parties 'political'
writing letters ...
There was a gay member of Congress
he argued.
He hired a secretary.
"One morning in May ..."
He began to announce
it was better.
Why did you tell them
you turn the corner?
You have a cancer in phase 4!
It's not that bad!
Dad,
Phase 5 does not exist.
That's not to say that!
So what does that mean?
That there had been three previous phases.
What do we look?
"The Times of Harvey Milk"
the first gay politician ...
- I know who Harvey Milk.
- Very good!
He wrote a religious test.
"One day
"Jesus became old.
"He could not walk long
nor preach his loud voice.
"He told his apostles
that he would leave soon.
"The three disciples prayed,
the washed and fed.
"After several days suffocated,
"One morning at dawn,
"Jesus died."
You have rewritten the death of Jesus?
It was too violent!
We need new stories.
For the 1st time
I saw love.
He was outstanding
but it must have been crazy for you.
I could not sleep
and I wanted to walk.
You have suffered a great loss.
If I was not able to compensate?
If it is too,
we have to stop there.
Wait.
I do not want to stop.
Ready?
Encore!
Yet?
Fuck!
Arthur!
You're awake!
Arthur says to get up.
He says it's his day off.
He will talk to you too.
- He says "Now!"
- You have trouble understanding English.
He said "10 minutes".
You?
Did you have unraveled.
And it was your first time.
You, you looked
all these people turn ...
Sorry, dogs are prohibited.
You have to get out of here.
If I leave him alone, he panics.
Dogs are not allowed
in the facility.
In the car, it's impossible.
Sorry, no.
It must come out.
I do not like
the tone it takes.
She said in French
it's a small dog.
You call security?
There's only biting the pads!
Come on, Arthur!
Excuse me.
I can not do it!
He never calls as often.
Sometimes he goes.
It should not do that to you.
Even if you do not answer,
it is still there.
I fly somewhere and ...
You leave the hotel soon.
You should come home,
move in with me.
You would
a strange girl like me?
Yes, many.
You're cooking?
I'd love that.
I must kill you now.
Why?
I'm falling in love.
Anna and I are together,
we are in 2003.
Here the sky
and stars.
When we eat.
When we tell
what comes to mind us.
I was born in 1965.
Anna was born in 1971.
The sun, that was it.
His animals.
His parents.
She left home at age 16.
She has lived here
and here
and here.
She lived three important relationships.
She left each time.
I lived four important relationships.
I left too.
Or I left them fail.
We have not experienced this war.
We did not hide
to make love.
This gave us a chance
melancholy foreign to our parents
and happiness
I've never seen at home.
We do not know where does
what comes to mind us.
But when it stops,
I can really see
Anna's eyes in 2003.
His ears.
His feet.
There she is when she says "I love you"
in 2003.
There she is when she cries.
When she told me
an empty room still waiting.
Before it was his freedom.
Today is the opposite.
- One more.
- Damn!
Go.
That's it.
This is for you.
It symbolizes gay pride.
- Everyone knows that.
- Oh no!
If everyone.
Do not be silly.
Everybody knows
the symbol of Gay Pride.
- Do you really think?
- Yes.
You, you know?
For me?
I thought you and Mom
were not in love.
We loved each other!
But you were gay.
- I struggled not to be.
- During 44 years?
I knew I was gay.
In the evenings
I watched the husbands, not women.
And sexually?
She has never seen
as a great lover.
But we got by.
I loved this life.
The museum, our house ...
This is what I wanted.
And mom?
You wanted it too?
Yes! Stop it.
It was she who asked me to marry him.
I replied:
"I love you, we're friends
but you know what I am. "
And she said:
"It does not matter.
"I will heal it."
I thought:
"My God ...
"I'm ready to try anything."
Sex.
Of life.
Healing.
The sun.
Nature.
The magic.
The serenity.
The mind.
The first gay flag was designed
by Gilbert Baker in 1978.
Each color meaning.
This man was president.
We invented it.
Movies, was it.
The animals.
November 27, 1978
Harvey Milk was assassinated.
The following week, my father opened
its Christmas exhibition.
He had collected
stuffed animals in the neighborhood.
My dad posted up
a quote from the "Velvet Rabbit".
The stuffed bunny asked:
"What is true?"
Then the rabbit said:
"It hurts?"
The horse answered:
"Sometimes."
"It happens all of a sudden?"
"It takes a long time.
"In general, when you become a true
your hair has been torn,
"You lost your eyes
and you're disconnected.
"It does not matter
"Because you have become true.
"You are ugly in the eyes of those
who do not understand. "
Andy moves.
This is reasonable?
Act as if you were happy.
THE SADS
FIRST COUPLE IN LOVE TOO
To be sad
The idea
The story of sadness.
It could make your ...
It will take a big case.
"There are 4 billion years
Earth was formed. "
The idea is that sadness
does not exist yet, but ...
Sorry.
Sorry too.
It went well.
When is the wedding?
Come on, Arthur.
The living room.
The dining room.
There are boxes everywhere.
Here are my parents.
My mother ...
Hal, Georgia, this is Anna.
Anna, Hal and Georgia.
- Stairs.
- Really?
They ride.
I made room for you.
I bring your suitcase.
You?
I was not sleeping,
I did not bother you.
I ...
I was nervous
and all excited.
I thought that perhaps
I'm not as clueless as that.
Why are you crying yesterday?
You?
You really seem unhappy.
And you're happy
here?
I'm not very good at that.
I do not know what I do.
But I want to be there.
I do not know, Anna.
I should not feel that way.
I then returned to New York.
Hal,
it is not worth
to come for treatment.
Something wrong?
Better to stay home.
Palliative care is most useful.
New treatments
lead ...
more pain.
I understand.
I wish I could do more.
You have been remarkable, Dr. Long.
And thank you
for coming to the party.
You would always hold my hand
when you were little.
I could not.
I was afraid it may seem odd.
I wanted to be affectionate.
Certainly my father
had never shown any affection.
As long as I was not like that ...
I barely remember you.
I was at work.
One can feel
the emotion of the artist
when it is gifted.
And his every move.
It's like an entity
independent ...
I mean ...
We go home.
... in the broadest sense.
And your father?
So what would he do without us?
Georgia, you're going?
Yes, Mary.
An emergency.
Oliver made a peritonitis.
My God!
He is a child not demonstrative.
You show leadership,
I drive.
On the left, or worse!
Then?
Left again.
You turn around, I like it.
We knew it would not work,
before the meeting.
It's me, leave a message.
Anna?
Where are you?
Well, that's it.
Arthur ...
You're going to watch Elliot.
I return in a few days.
Good luck!
He remembers me.
Hi!
Listen,
I am awfully sorry
I stand before your door,
in New York.
I am in Los Angeles.
You're in L.A.?
You had to go here!
I'm not.
Shit, I'm in your building!
Well, you see the window
near the radiator?
The key is hidden behind.
OK, I'm inside.
It's empty here.
No!
That's my kitchen.
This is where I eat.
My bathroom.
Very luxurious.
Through the window
we see the roof of the neighbors.
Basically, this is my room.
This is my closet.
My clothes.
My photos.
Why did you leave everyone?
Why you left me leave?
Perhaps because
I do not really
it will work.
So I do all
that it does not work.
Juan's hair is great.
Thank you.
I use a foam great.
- It's amazing.
- You want to try?
A little bit?
- I think not ...
- Come on, just a little!
To laugh.
How you doing?
I show you.
- That's it.
- That's it?
It suits me?
Super.
It suits you very well.
Oliver.
He died.
Less than one hour
after being called,
two men arrive
to place the body in a bag.
They charge $ 1,485 for a cremation
and make the ashes in a box
the size
a jar of peanut butter.
It will require a death certificate.
It will send
to cancel credit cards,
telephone, utilities,
subscription to the gym,
all insurance, loans,
and to inform taxes.
You will follow
all mail to your address.
You write the obituary.
The newspaper with a photo pass
$ 2 for the word.
You'll wonder
if it is just.
You throw a lot.
You will keep a lot of things.
The picture that my mother
had in his room.
Kid, I thought it was my arm
offering daisies.
Today I imagine
it is she who offers me the
saying:
"This is happiness and simplicity.
"That's what I wanted to give you."
Arthur!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Come!
That's because I'm gay.
Is that it?
What?
You're never happened to me.
No.
This is because my father
love you much.
Arthur!
Are you okay?
Between.
The lounge ...
The dining room.
Crazy picture!
I can read?
"I am looking for a sex plan
"Hoping that it evolves
"To a friendship or relationship.
I do not claim loyalty.
"I'm an old guy, 78,
but charming and warm.
"Art historian retired.
"I also like the house,
"Gardens, festivals
and walks with my Jack Russell.
"I am 1.80 m, 72 kg,
"I am thin, gray hair,
blue eyes, chest hair ... "
- Hairy.
- "Hairy".
"I love giving and ..."
And what?
"I love giving and receiving hugs
before sharing soft games. "
"In my beautiful home, there are
eating, drinking, friends and me.
"If you feel like an older man,
"Let us meet
and we'll see. "
He did not give up.
What is next?
I do not know.
How do we do?