PACU: My name is Pacu.
It's a brand new name,
so I'm not used to it yet,
I'm trying to remember a story,
Sometimes I can,
Sometimes I get mixed up,
Because there's another one
stuck in my head,
It's about me, my brother,
and a shirt in the wind,
The blood is starting
to turn yellow.
[Flapping]
[Wheel creaking]
[Father yelling at oxen]
[Oxen mooing]
[Father yelling]
FATHER: Yah! Yah! Yah!
Yah! Yah! Yah!
[Whips with leaves]
Yah! Yah!
PACU: It's Pa who drives
the oxen 'round the mill,
In Grandpa's time,
the slaves did all the work,
[Yelling at oxen]
Now we do it.
[Yelling]
[Liquid dripping]
PACU: Tonio, my brother,
crushes the sugarcane,
Ma gathers the scraps,
[Yelling at oxen]
Bring more cane, kid.
Hurry up!
[Flies buzzing]
FATHER: Let's go, Blocky!
Turn, turn!
PACU: Ma says
God never gives us...
heavier burdens
than we can bear,
But God keeps messing up,
He sometimes dumps such burdens
on us, we all collapse,
[Yelling at oxen]
We live in Stream-of-Souls,
It's in the middle of nothing,
All we know is it's above
the ground and below the sun,
It's so hot that it
sets our hearts boiling...
like a pot of molasses,
[Flies buzzing]
[Fire crackling]
[Steam hissing]
[Liquid sloshing]
[Bubbling]
[Hissing]
[Raspy breathing]
[Whimpering]
[Gunshot]
[Footsteps]
[Gasps]
[Crickets chirping]
PACU: Tonio, I dreamed
about Incio again,
[Tonio sighs]
Go back to sleep now.
Go on, kid.
[Speaking Portuguese]
[Bed creaking]
TONIO: And now, sleep.
[Flame crackling]
[Wind blowing]
[Footsteps]
[Metal squeaking]
[Mill grinding]
Go on, go on!
[Father yelling at oxen]
[Footsteps]
[Shirt flapping in the wind]
The blood has turned yellow.
Tonio...
you know what you have to do.
Don't go, Tonio.
Your brother's soul
isn't at rest.
He did what he had to do.
It's Tonio's turn now.
Don't go.
[Falls to ground]
FATHER: Listen to me, kid,
Your grandfather, your uncles,
your oldest brother...
all died for this land
and for our honor.
One day, it could be you.
You're a Breves,
I, too, did my duty.
But it wasn't God's will
that I die.
Tonio, you'll leave
at daybreak,
And remember...
you're only to seek out
your brother's killer.
Man to man, face to face.
[Crickets chirping]
[Footsteps]
[Birds screeching]
[Grass crunching]
[Ropes creaking]
[Insects buzzing]
[Birds chirping]
[Grass crunching underfoot]
PACU: Tonio will be walking
over land that used to be ours,
The Ferreiras took it from us
and we took it back,
Now it's theirs again,
That's how the feud began,
Pa says it's an eye for an eye,
One of theirs
for one of ours...
and so on, until everyone
ended up blind,
[Bird screeches]
In the land of the blind...
one-eyed people are
said to be mad,
[Crickets chirping]
[Footsteps]
[Cows mooing]
[Insects buzzing]
[Footsteps]
[Woman humming]
MOTHER: May God consent,
may it be God's will,
May the soul of Incio,
my first-born...
find peace alongside his own.
May each drop of his blood
cost the enemy two.
May you, my son...
find the peace you never found
among the living.
And watch over your brothers
when their turn comes,
[Humming]
[Cows mooing]
[Rooster crows]
-MAN: We're going for water.
-GU ARD: Yes, sir.
[Cows mooing]
MAN: Everything quiet?
GUARD: Yes, sir,
[Birds chirping]
[Cows mooing]
[Mooing]
[Milk hitting metal bucket]
Like this.
[Breathing quickly]
[Tapping]
Go outside, kid.
[Milking continues]
[Milking stops]
[Cow moos]
[Cocks rifle]
For my brother!
[Heavy breathing]
[Men grunting]
[Breathing heavily]
[Grunting]
[Gunshot]
[Thump]
[Panting]
[Gulps]
[Man gasping and groaning]
[Gasping]
[Gasping stops]
[Exhales]
[Liquid gurgles]
[Muffled scraping]
[Hoofbeats]
[People singing reverently]
[Sobbing and praying]
[Sobbing]
[Singing]
[Praying]
[Metal jingling]
[Crickets chirping]
[Praying and talking]
[Man praying]
I won't pray for your grandson's
soul, since he killed my son.
But I respect your suffering.
It's the same as mine.
Today, ours is greater.
My son asks permission
to attend the vigil...
to pray for the deceased's soul.
Afterwards, if you accept,
he'd like to talk to you.
-Where is he?
-Outside.
[Talking stops]
[Praying softly]
[Praying and talking resumes]
MR. FERREIRA: Thank you.
MAN: Good-bye, my friend.
[Clock ticking]
I prayed for the deceased.
I came to the wake
and the burial.
Now, I'd like to talk to you.
I request a truce.
[Cane tapping]
[Drawer slides]
Grandfather,
don't accord a truce.
[Cane tapping]
The truce is granted.
[Tonio exhales]
The same one your father
granted to my grandson.
Until the next moon.
From one death to the next.
This is your guarantee
until the full moon.
After that, when the blood
turns yellow, it will expire.
How old are you?
Twenty.
Your life is now split in two.
The twenty years you've
already lived...
and the short time
you have left.
Have you ever known love?
You never will.
[Clock ticking]
Do you hear that clock?
Each time it ticks--one more,
one more, one more...
it will be telling you...
one less, one less, one less.
[Clock ticking]
[Cows mooing]
[Footsteps]
[Wagon approaches]
Whoa.
Good morning.
Morning.
MAN: Do you know
of a little village...
near here
called Born Sossago?
It's over there.
But it's not little.
MAN: It's not?
What's this place called?
Stream-of-Souls.
So where's the stream?
Dried up.
Only the souls remain.
What is your name?
-Kid.
-WOMAN: What?
I don't have a name.
-What do they call you?
-They just call me kid.
They call the kid "kid."
Kid!
Here, this is for you.
[Harness jingles]
Can you read?
No.
But I can read pictures.
[Wagon leaving]
Hey, kid!
Stay away from those vagrants!
[Hoofbeats]
[Ropes creaking]
[Bird screeching]
[Mother humming]
PACU: Ma thinks the bloodstain
will come out,
[Humming]
But it won't come out,
[Water swishing]
[Humming]
FATHER: You did your duty,
my son,
Now you have much to do
before the next moon.
Crush the sugarcane
and fix the roof...
in case it rains this year.
It never rains.
Then the raw sugar
has to be sold in the village.
[Heavy breathing,
leaves rustling]
[Groaning softly]
[Inhales sharply]
[Sighs]
PACU: That sounded like
a bad dream, Tonio,
I tried to wake you up,
but you didn't want to,
What are you doing up, kid?
Reading.
Where'd you get that?
A present.
From who?
The girl gave it to me.
What girl?
My friend, of course.
-You went into town alone?
-PACU: No.
They were lost.
But not anymore.
I showed them the way.
Hmm.
So what's that book about?
It's about everything.
[Tonio chuckles]
Something's wrong, kid.
-What's wrong?
-It's upside down.
No, it's not.
Want to bet?
It's the same this way...
or that way.
No difference, see?
You don't know a thing
about books. Give it to me.
-PACU: It's her!
-TONIO: Her? Who?
The girl who gave me the book.
She lives in the sea with the
fish, the crabs, and the boats.
She'll take me with her.
She'll teach me
the alphabet and all.
You don't believe me?
When I grow up,
we'll get married.
-Has she been informed?
-No.
It's still a secret.
[Father speaking to oxen]
[Wheels clattering]
[Wheels squeaking]
PACU: One day...
the mermaid comes up
to the surface.
And she saw the tree, the cows,
the mountains, and grass.
When she looked at the top of
the raw-sugar house...
she saw the rooster with the
mangy neck crowing for her.
[Crows like a rooster]
Ahh.
Wow, she really liked that!
And she also saw
the sugarcane, the mill...
everything delighted her!
But the best part of all
was when she saw the kid.
Are you still reading that book?
Can't you see it will
hurt your eyes?
I'm trying to remember
the story.
Sometimes I can,
sometimes I forget.
Then just forget.
[Cows mooing]
MR. FERREIRA: Well?
It is beginning to change color.
It won't take long now.
No, it won't.
[Mr. Lourenco sighs]
[Rummaging in drawer]
[Clink]
You're the most important
merchant in town...
but with all due respect,
this isn't the right amount.
MR LOURENCO: No,
It is the right amount,
But I gave you
the usual quantity.
Steam power is bringing
the price down. It's progress.
I think you should follow
the example, Mr. Breves.
But Mr. Lourenco,
we had an agreement.
There is no shortage
of raw sugar!
[Singing and drumming]
[Children yelling]
[Man singing]
[Singing and drumming continue]
MAN: Come on up!
Come one, come all,
if you want to watch...
the snake and the toad dance!
[Children cheering]
Everyone will come.
Together we will go.
[Cheering]
Tomorrow night,
no one will sleep.
No man, no woman, no child.
[Children cheering]
Come one, come all!
CHILDREN: To the circus!
[Drumming continues]
[Wheels rumbling]
Mr. Lourenco wants to decide
other people's suffering.
[Leaves tearing]
[Chopping]
I saw her.
Who?
The mermaid.
Up on stilts.
On what?
She's in the circus.
Yeah?
They're bringing
the circus to town...
with a fire-eater, a clown...
and a snake that dances
with a toad.
-A snake with a what?
-A toad.
Yeah?
[Mill grinding]
[Speaking to oxen]
Hey, are you daydreaming, kid?
More cane!
Keep turning!
FATHER: Hurry up
with that cane!
[Yelling]
[Whip snaps]
[Ox eating]
Tonio.
I want to go to the circus
real bad.
You think Pa will let you?
We're like oxen here.
We go 'round and 'round
and never go anywhere.
[Door creaks]
[Sighs]
Let's go, kid.
You want to see the circus?
Hmm?
Then let's go.
[Fire roaring]
[Crowd cheering and clapping]
[Roar]
[Cheering]
See? I told you,
she's hot stuff.
[Laughs]
[Fire roars]
[R oars]
[Roars]
[Cheering]
[Crowd cheers]
[Crowd cheers louder]
[Shouting and cheering]
CROWD: Fire! Fire!
[Crowd yelling]
[Crowd laughing]
[Chuckles]
I'll be damned!
I'm toasted!
[Laughing]
[Crates thumping]
Salustiana, look who's here.
Hey! It's the kid
without a name.
Anything's better
than Salustiana.
[Equipment rattles]
My name's Clara.
What's yours?
That's Tonio, my brother.
Good evening.
Did you like the show?
I liked the fire best.
You're really hot!
Holy shit!
I brought the book so you can
remind me of the story.
It's late now.
SALUSTIANA: Hey, kid...
I'm going to give you a name.
A name all your own.
What's your favorite animal?
Do you like birds?
He only likes sea creatures.
Oh, yeah? Then I'll
name you Sardine!
Ha ha!
You bullshitting me?
We'll choose another name.
Pacu.
Pacu!
I've christened you,
You have a name now.
And I'm your godfather,
Hmm!
To celebrate your christening!
[Salustiana laughs]
[Crickets chirping]
[Hoofbeats]
-PACU: I don't like it,
-TONIO: What?
The name.
Pacu.
He's pulling my leg.
Pacu is a kind of river fish.
Tonio.
Do you think
they sleep together?
I don't know.
All I know is,
he's your godfather now.
Pacu.
Pacu!
TONIO: Pacu!
[Tonio laughs]
TONIO: Pacu! Ha ha!
Cut it out, will you?
[Crickets chirping]
Where'd you take the kid?
Where?
To the circus.
The circus.
Go to your room, kid.
Right now!
[Sighs]
FATHER: Having fun
at a time like this?
Have you no respect
for our dead?
You should follow
your older brother's example.
Don't worry.
I'll soon be like him.
Shut up.
Sorry, but I won't shut up.
[Breathes heavily]
-Shut your mouth.
-No!
-Shut up!
[Swings whip]
[Father grunts]
-FATHER: Shut up!
-TONIO: No!
[Swings whip]
-I won't!
-Shut up!
[Flame roars, then sputters]
[Breathing heavily]
[Crickets chirping]
PACU: Tonio,
You have to go away.
[Crickets chirping]
Did you see his black armband?
Yes.
He won't be around much longer.
-What are you talking about?
-It's true.
It's a family feud.
One side kills, then the other.
-How do you know?
-It goes way back.
They're fighting for the land.
They'd rather kill
than solve their problems.
Real fanatics.
It's like the two snakes
I saw fighting.
Each was biting the tail
of the other.
They ate each other up
until nothing was left.
Nothing but a pool of blood
on the ground.
They'll all be killed off.
Hmm.
I feel sorry for them.
I really do.
Yah!
Stay in line!
Keep it going, Slowpoke!
[Mill creaking]
FATHER: You're lagging!
Keep turning!
Come on, Blocky!
Keep it going!
Come on, Slowpoke!
[Yelling]
[Snorts]
[Yells]
[Yells and whips oxen
with leaves]
[Father yelling]
[Oxen snorting]
[Cogs creaking]
[Liquid dripping]
[Dripping slows, then stops]
[Oxen breathing heavily]
[Ox moos]
[Men grunting]
FATHER: Get up, Slowpoke!
[Ox moos loudly]
That's good, my ox.
[Hoofbeats]
Tonio!
The oxen are going 'round
on their own!
[Yoke clatters]
[Birds chirping]
[Liquid pouring]
[Dishes rattling]
[People chattering]
[Dog barking]
Need some help?
I can always use help.
Especially if it's free.
[Thump]
Where's my godson?
At home.
Come for the circus?
Heh!
You'll have to wait
till next year.
We're off to Ventura
for the festival.
Ever been to Ventura?
No. I haven't been anywhere.
[Hoofbeats]
[Whip cracks]
[Wheels rumbling]
SALUSTIANA: Were you born
dead or alive?
TONIO: What?
SALUSTIANA: Were you born
dead or alive?
TONIO: Alive.
Well, I was born dead.
True or false?
True, I'm afraid.
Ha ha!
Let me explain.
My mother almost died
giving birth.
I was born purple--so purple
they thought I was dead.
True or false?
They ignored me for two hours
while trying to save my mother.
Then they decided to wash me so
I'd look decent for the funeral.
As soon as I felt the cold
water, I started howling.
As a result, that was
my first and last bath.
No more baths!
And the second result:
Nothing bothers me.
Anyone born dead has
been through the worst.
After that, life's a breeze.
No kidding!
So when it comes to water...
I don't even use it
for drinking!
Ha ha ha!
Yuck! Let's go, Bootleg!
[Snaps reins]
[Harness jangles]
[Fire crackling]
[Bottle clanks]
[Fabric rustles]
[Salustiana sighs]
How long do you have?
Not long.
I'll go as far as Ventura,
then I have to go back,
SALUSTIANA: Clara...
where are you?
[Footsteps]
[Wind blowing, leaves rustling]
[Door creaks]
In this house, the dead
command the living.
MOTHER: Sometimes I wish Tonio
wouldn't come back.
FATHER:
Don't say that, woman.
MOTHER: Even the worst life
is better...
than being slaughtered
like an animal.
Look around you, woman.
What do we have left?
Nothing.
You see, we've already
lost everything.
And if Tonio doesn't come back,
we'll have lost our honor, too.
[Wheels rumbling]
SALUSTIANA:
Let's go, Bootleg!
Come on, Bootleg!
Sleep well, young man?
PACU: The mermaid
couldn't live on land...
because she had
a fish-tail...
where her legs should be.
The poor thing couldn't walk.
[Chopping]
Even so, one day she got furious
and jumped out of the sea!
She started fighting
with snakes and toads.
Then, because she missed
the kid so much...
she started puffing out
fire and smoke.
[Chopping]
So the kid got
on a tired old ox...
and galloped after the mermaid,
Do-dum, do-dum,
looking for the mermaid.
He went through the woods,
the cane fields...
and when he parted
the last row of sugarcane...
he came upon the sea.
[Rapid footsteps]
And he found the mermaid.
Following
in your brother's footsteps?
Think you can just
take it easy around here?
PACU: Give me my book!
Give it to me!
Give me my book!
GROUP: Die, you rabid dog!
Take that!
To hell with the traitor!
Hah!
[Children shouting]
MAN: Don't tell me this
shitty circus is still around,
What did you say?
MAN: You heard me,
-Shit what?
-MAN: Circus!
-SALUSTIANA: Get out of here!
-MAN: You lousy bum!
Ha ha ha!
Reginaldo. Come here!
Shitty things are impossible
to get rid of. Like you.
You mean like you.
[Men laughing]
REGINALDO: Is that Clara?
Your stepdaughter?
Spitting image of her mother.
REGINALDO: How she's grown!
[Liquid burbling]
Do it right, kid.
You're big enough now.
[People talking and clapping]
[Drum playing]
[Cheering and clapping]
Come, Tonio.
I'm going to show you
something, Tonio.
Help me. Pull on the rope.
CLARA: Start turning,
Turn it faster, Tonio.
[Breathing rapidly]
Faster!
Even more!
[Clara yelling
in Portuguese]
[Clara laughing]
[Clara laughing continues]
[Drums beating]
[People talking]
[Both breathing heavily]
TONIO: I'll never forget this...
or you.
CLARA: Neither will I, Tonio.
SALUSTIANA: Clara!
[Crowd chanting and clapping]
[Crickets chirping]
[Mill grinding]
[Father yelling at oxen,
whips with leaves]
FATHER: Yah! Yah!
Yah! Yah! Yah!
Whoa.
[Mill stops grinding]
Yah!
[Whips]
[Mill grinding]
[Father yelling at oxen]
The shirt is almost yellow now.
It always turns yellow.
With your permission...
I could get the men together...
and wipe those Breves
from the face of this earth,
MR. FERREIRA: I'll repeat this
one last time,
Blood has the same volume
for everyone.
You have no right to take more
than the blood taken from you.
Otherwise, you'll pay twice--
in this life and in the next.
That's what my father taught me
and his father taught him.
And that's how it'll be
until I die.
[Liquid boiling]
I taught you how to fly
with this, remember?
You were scared shitless.
[Both chuckle]
Tonio, today it's your turn.
Huh?
You take my place,
I'll take yours.
No, I don't want to.
PACU: Just once.
[Ropes creaking]
[Laughs]
[Pacu laughing]
[Rope creaking]
[Tearing]
[Snap]
[Thud]
TONIO: Ooh!
[Whimpers]
PACU: Tonio!
[Running footsteps]
Tonio. Tonio.
Huh!
[Both laughing]
You're too damn strong.
No, you just forgot how to fly.
[Both laughing]
[Mother laughing]
[Father laughing]
[Crowd cheering and clapping]
Let me, it's my turn!
Ooh, it's hot!
[Crowd cheers louder]
Ha ha!
[Crowd reacts]
SALUSTIANA: Hey!
[Crowd clapping]
This is my favorite part
of the show.
[Money rattling]
Ha ha!
Come on! Who's next!
Keep filling it!
Fill it up!
[Wind blowing]
[Fire crackling]
[People talking]
You can't do this.
Anyhow, he's already dead.
But I'm not.
[Jingling]
[Footsteps]
It's turned yellow.
MR. FERREIRA:
Is it really yellow now?
MAN: Yes, it's yellowed,
[Bird chirps]
You know what you
have to do, then.
Yes, I know.
Tonio, you know
the truce ends today.
From now on,
it depends on the shirt.
Don't go too far from the house.
Stay close to me,
And always carry the gun,
[Thunder]
[Bird chirps]
It's going to rain.
No, it's not the rainy season.
I know it's going to rain.
Tonio?
Pa took my book.
[Thunder]
I can't remember the story
or the mermaid's face anymore.
[Sighs]
[Wind blowing]
The mermaid...
[Hinges squeak and slam]
Had a fish tail...
while the boy had
toes, feet, and...
[Tonio sighs]
Aren't you going to sleep, Pacu?
I can't, Tonio. It's too windy.
[Sighs]
Then talk in silence.
OK.
[Wind whistling]
[Creaking]
Tonio.
[Wind blowing]
Clara...
I wanted to tell you
I've left everything.
I'm heading east, to the coast.
You have the right
to do it, too.
[Thunder]
[Rips]
[Water dripping]
[Whinnies]
[Thunder]
[Rain falling]
[Water dripping]
I'll be waiting.
[Footsteps]
[Thunder]
[Horse whinnies]
[Ragged breathing]
[Crickets chirping]
[Footsteps]
[Ragged breathing]
[Thunder]
[Footsteps]
PACU: Now you know my story,
But I still can't
remember the other one,
The mermaid, the shipsdamn!
The kid couldn't find
the mermaid...
no, it wasn't like that,
Damn,
It's the mermaid who came
looking--yeah, that's it,
I think I'm remembering it!
[Pacu sobbing]
One day, the mermaid came
and took him to live with her,
And he really liked that!
She turned the kid
into a fish...
and took him to live
in the east, at the sea,
In the sea, everyone wasn't
dying all the time,
There was a lot of room
for everyone,
In the sea, they lived
so happily...
so happily, they couldn't
stop laughing,
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha,
[Sobbing]
[Rustling footsteps]
[Thunder]
[Horse whinnies]
[Pacu laughing]
In the sea, they were so happy,
so happy together...
they couldn't help laughing.
[Pacu laughing]
[Breathing heavily]
[Gunshot]
[Gasping]
[Sobbing]
[Hinges squeak, door slams]
MOTHER: Tonio!
Oh, God, not my son!
Not my son!
[Yelling in Portuguese]
[Crickets chirping]
[Sniffs]
[Birds chirping]
[Sobbing]
[Mother gasping]
[Father sobbing]
FATHER: They've killed the kid.
[Footsteps]
Get the gun, Tonio! Right now!
There's no truce,
go avenge the blood!
Reclaim the blood of those pigs!
Go, my son! Reclaim the blood!
Immediately!
[Footsteps]
FATHER: What are you doing?
The gun!
Where's the gun, Tonio?
Tonio!
[Running footsteps]
Come back!
[Raspy breathing]
Come back or you'll die
for the honor of the family.
[Gunshot]
It's over! Don't you see?
It's all over!
[Speaking Portuguese
and sobbing]
[Gasping]
[Both crying]
FATHER: Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
[Grass crunching underfoot]
[Wind blowing]
[Waves crashing]
PACU: One day...
the mermaid took him to live
with her by the sea,
[Waves crashing]