~ Review ~Do you remember everything?
Am I even important now?
To me, you're extremely important.
I know all Capital wants is that lab journal.
You must have remembered where the lab journal is now, right?
17-year-old Ai Li Si is a dummy.
30-year-old Ai Li Si is still a dummy.
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
♫ What does it take to love you is a decision of my whole life. ♫
♫ If I lose, if I forget, I won't be searching numbly anymore. ♫
♫ It rains all night and I regret breaking your heart ♫
♫ I can’t have your tenderness. Quickly return to my bosom. ♫
♫ I want to approach you, but we are only friends now. ♫
♫ I can’t wake up from my beautiful memories. Why doubt? ♫
♫ Hug closer and closer, till we're unable to breathe the trace of our love. ♫
♫ The answer is you. ♫
♫ I miss you very much. I really miss you very much. ♫
♫ I can’t change myself in time. ♫
♫ I can’t resist. I can't resist anymore. ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end. Tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
♫ My only love... Yeah... ♫
♫ Yeah. My only love. ♫
What's up? Why didn't you call me?
He Hao Yi.
You really just called my name.
I'm going to brush my teeth.
He Hao Yi!
Go on a date with me.
I want to believe you, so go on a date with me.
Why do you suddenly want to ride the bus?
Thinking back to high school, if I wasn't with Lei Lei or with friends,
I would use the slowest form of transportation to get to the classroom.
I would take a look all around and worry that someone else might discover that I was searching all around.
What were you looking for?
You.
To see if you left the school already or if you were still playing basketball.
If you weren't at the basketball court, I had to run.
Run?
Hey... there are cars!
"Hi! What a coincidence!"
Then you would say...
"Come on, why would it be a coincidence? We go to the same school."
So I had to run faster in order to ride the same bus with you.
I didn't know this.
Hey, be careful!
You're really overreacting.
I'm not.
Emergency stop.
The driver completely understood what I was thinking.
Let's look for his name
and call his company to tattle on him.
Idiot.
Ai Li Si!
Did you get a little anxious because I'd disappeared?
I'm angry.
Not anxious?
I want to eat instant noodles.
Just because you want to eat instant noodles, you suddenly jumped off the bus?
- I told you to eat something more nutritious for breakfast.- I want to eat instant noodles!
Okay, let's eat.
Here!
For me?
Peel off the eggshell for me.
♫ What does it take to love you is a decision of my whole life. ♫
♫ If I lose, if I forget, I won't be searching numbly anymore. ♫
♫ It rains all night and I regret breaking your heart ♫
♫ I can’t have your tenderness. Quickly return to my bosom. ♫
♫ I want to approach you, but we are only friends now. ♫
He Hao Yi,
if I'm unreasonable to you today, don't take it to heart.
Just take it as a test for me to believe in you.
Here.
♫ I can’t change myself in time. ♫
The egg yolk's for you and the egg white's for me.
I'm glad you're at least conscientious.
♫ My only love. ♫
As long you believe me, I'm fine with everything else.
♫ My only love. Yeah. ♫
You said it!
I said it.
♫ Who is indeed not good enough? ♫
♫ I continue racing with time, ♫
♫ until I'll win your smile at the end. ♫
♫ I can’t resist. I can't resist anymore. ♫
Here, egg white.
Too small.
This one's bigger.
Aren't you going to buy another one?
It doesn't matter.
Go buy it.
The sun is so strong, why aren't you holding an umbrella?
You aren't holding an umbrella, either.
Also, I've used a sun protector.
The facial mask I gave you can whiten your skin, too.
That's why I use it every day.
Really?
See for yourself if you don't believe me.
Forget it. I'll speak first.
Liu Xiao Fen, why did you respond so strongly?
It wasn't the first time I didn't pick up your call because I was in love. Did you have to react in such a way?
It doesn't matter if anybody else doesn't understand me, but don't you even understand me?
- It was because Song Han Ming is...- I know!
You're right.
Song Han Ming doesn't like me at all.
He approached me, not for my beauty, nor my family status.
It was because he wanted to take revenge for Ai Li Si and himself.
Isn't it the little diary Ai Li Si buried in the time capsule?
Why is it here?
Just read it. Read it!
Today's Lei Lei's competition. Lei Lei's father...
Ai Li Si did a lot of things for us.
She didn't tell us anything, thinking we would know about everything because we were friends.
Also, she cared for our feelings.
That's enough.
During that time I misunderstood her, so I didn't go to our secret hideout to listen to her explanation.
I admit I was very capricious, okay?
Do you all have to remind me one by one?
- Lei Lei...- Also, why...
did Ai Li Si change school?
I was just angry at that time.
And she just disappeared at that time, so we didn't even have a chance to reconcile.
She was resolute, not me.
You better not speak of Ai Li Si like that; otherwise, you'll regret it.
Why will I regret it?
Is it because you guys know something I don't?
Actually, back in our high school days, Ai Li Si...
I never thought that Ai Li Si would be bullied.
I thought it was just because we ignored her,
she didn't come to the group activities and ate alone at lunch time.
Who knew it would be like this...
Who knew that some people would throw away her bento?
They even hid her sportswear during PE class.
Chen Qi Tai is such a bastard!
If I'd known this earlier, I wouldn't have let him off!
Even my brother just found out recently. Do you know how angry he was when he told me this?
I thought of someone...
Hey, Lei Lei! Where are you going?
Where's my shoe?
I told you I would bring it to the company. Save you the trip.
What are you doing!?
I should ask you that!
I just took it when you pulled my leg for your nonsense self-dignity.
But Ai Li Si's situation is different.
You gave me a hard time because of her, but you didn't mention the real reason behind all this.
What made you think you could hide the fact that Chen Qi Tai bullied Ai Li Si?
Tell me.
Why do I have to tell you?
How you treated Ai Li Si back then, I remember very clearly.
Bullying is not only limited to physical beatings.
Ignoring her is also a kind of bullying.
When she needed you the most, you turned a blind eye.
What are you talking about?
Do I need to refresh your memories?
When you initially ignored Ai Li Si, I could understand.
But that day she got watered down in the toilet, you both clearly saw it.
We did not.
Don't spout nonsense.
It can't be that day, can it?
Which day?
The day I lent you the 5566 band CD.
What kind of song is this? This is stupid, Liu Xiao Fen.
- Let me go. - It's very interesting. You didn't know that you'd end up like this.
- Lei Lei! Lei Lei!- Why did you offend him?
That's right. Are you having fun in there, Ai Li Si?
- See if you dare to do it again.- You deserve it.
Hey! What are you guys doing?
Hey, don't make matters worse.
If your dad knew, he'd get mad again.
So... the person in the restroom was Ai Li Si?
How can it be so coincidental?
It's all your fault.
I was about to go in and save her, but you stopped me.
My mom didn't pass on courage to me.
I was scared you would be scolded by your dad.
This stinks.
She definitely thought we ignored her,
and she also got bullied by Chen Qi Tai. That's why she transferred schools.
She must have been really disappointed in us.
That's right. We've been really bad to her.
Time check. It's 1:57 p.m. in the afternoon.
Meet me by the company entrance at 2 p.m.
She even gave me prior notice?
Hurry up. There's a hag who has been watching over us.
There is no hag here. The worst case, we'll just be getting a salary deduction.
I've always wanted to skip work at least once long ago.
Ever since I started as a researcher,
I've been afraid of having a failed experiment and uncontrollable variables.
Day and night, rain or shine, finally...
my first-phase research was a success!
If the research progress problem is resolved, are you going back to the US?
Yeah. Once I've finished the task, then I will go back.
But if someone misses me,
I will drop everything and come back as quickly as I can.
But... how can that person let you know she misses you?
Just say, "I miss you." That's enough.
What if she can't say it aloud?
Then just look at me like you are now.
If you are already in the US, how am I supposed to look at you?
Who knows. I might just pop up out of nowhere.
You will always be here, right?
Even if I make you angry, you will still accompany me. Right?
It's bubble tea!
Quickly! Time limit is five minutes.
Thank you, He Hao Yi.
I'm sorry.
Are you happy now?
You're not a child. Why do you like sweets so much?
Ai Li Si...
Whoa! Wait a minute.
- What are you doing?- You are too funny today.
No, I have to take a picture.
Why are you so worked up?
My goodness, come. Take a picture with me.
You need to do the expression from just now.
That anxious expression!
This is great.
Now that I've captured this moment,
whenever I'm feeling down, I can look at this and laugh to death.
Souvenir pictures.
They're...
real couple photos.
- Ai Li Si! Ai Li Si!- This picture has your eyes crossed.
I know you can't let your worries go and completely trust me.
But if you give me one more chance
and tell me where the lab journal is,
I can promise you I will be able to get Capital to keep supporting you
so you can complete your research.
He Hao Yi, what if I tell you that I trust you,
you probably wouldn't believe me. Right?
I will wait for you.
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
If the 30-year-old Ai Li Si
can open her heart to me once again, then that would be good.
He Hao Yi!
Are you outside?
Can I ask you a few questions?
Sure.
Why were you injured that day?
Did you get into a fight with Chen Qi Tai?
How did you know?
Because Chen Qi Tai also had wounds on his face.
Yes.
Was it because of me?
He Hao Yi, if I asked you to go bungee jumping with me again,
would you go?
Would You?
Would you jump with me?
Yes.
I would go.
You really treat me well.
It turns out that I have so many good memories to remove.
He Hao Yi,
after I lost my memory, if you weren't able to convince Liu Xiao Fen,
I wouldn't be able to stay at your place.
Whenever I lose the will to fight, you're the one to encourage me and cheer me on.
If I were to write down all your good deeds on a piece of paper,
can I fit everything on one A4-size paper?
Don't you have all kinds of notebooks?
That's true.
Ai Li Si,
I know I may not have the right to say these words,
but let's forget about the bad things from the past.
The reason that we reminisce about the past is to learn some lessons,
and to not make the same mistake again.
It wasn't easy for us to meet again.
It's not easy to meet for the second time.
Let's not miss out on each other this time, okay?
♫ I'm a little sad. Being around too many bright colors is very bitter. ♫
He Hao Yi,
you really are a good person, but I'm just not as positive as you are.
You've just forgotten that
I got all my good qualities from you.
♫ A transparent life is full of colors. ♫
♫ What's real? What's fake? Who cares that much? ♫
I will send a puzzle to you. If you can solve it, then we will meet there tomorrow.
Why do you have to go to so much trouble?
Didn't you say you want us to be like a couple
who meets in a special place?
Okay, send it over.
♫ I'm a little sad. ♫
♫ Being around too many bright colors ♫
♫ is very bitter. ♫
♫ A simple life ♫
♫ is always wishing for simplicity and pure. ♫
The hint is just too obvious. It's not hard to guess at all.
Okay then. See you tomorrow. Good night.
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, no. Did I guess wrong?
The lab journal.
He Hao Yi,
when you see this letter, I will have already left.
The lab journal is something that both you and Capital wanted the most.
Just think of it as the last present from me to you.
After going on a date with you, I realized that although 13 years had passed,
you could still live well without me.
Without you, I also lived well.
We don't need to pretend that we still care about each other.
From now on, I don't want to see you. Don't look for me.
After you take this, we are squared.
Thank you for letting me experience again the pure and happy feeling when I was 17.
He Hao Yi, goodbye.
Do you really want to do this?
I already gave the lab journal to He Hao Yi.
I don't want to do the research anymore.
Why?
You've worked so hard on this research ever since your college days.
Are you really an impetuous person?
I originally thought not.
In the past, I was the "garbage-truck girl."
I would take everything that nobody wanted.
If there was anything someone wanted, I would find a way to give it to them.
That was a long time ago, so I thought I had changed.
But when I met He Hao Yi, it was still the same.
Because he wanted the lab journal so much, so I gave it to him.
If you could give him that, then why can't you give him an opportunity?
These 13 years, I have watched over you.
You didn't cry or smile.
You were emotionless. You just suppressed yourself.
But after you met He Hao Yi, you started to smile.
He was the only one who could do this. And he is willing to do this for you now.
I really want to believe him,
but the one I can't believe is myself.
No matter what he does, I would be suspicious of him.
Whenever I see him, I worry about
if they would all leave me because of my little mistake.
So this time,
I want to be the first one to leave.
At the very least, he could get on the good side of me in my memories.
He Hao Yi is here.
You will help me, right?
You really...
Ai Li Si, are you really sure you want to do this?
I thought you really liked He Hao Yi.
I also originally thought this.
That's why I did a small experiment.
What experiment?
I went on a date with him.
Then I realized that...
I just wanted to fulfill the dream I had when I was 17.
That was to confess to him.
He really treats you well right now.
So what?
When I was 27, they didn't show up to retrieve the time capsule.
I was sad, and I cried.
Later, I pretended that nothing had happened.
Right now, getting into a relationship
is a burden to me.
Then you still gave the lab journal to him?
He wanted it, so I gave it to him. I can always start another research.
If I keep the lab journal with me,
he would just keep pestering me.
But I don't want him to get close to me.
It's annoying.
He is really annoying!
He is annoying me to death!
♫ Where did the love between us fall off? ♫
♫ Even if this happiness we possess is just vain joy? ♫
♫ That shoulder you have leaned on is still here. ♫
♫ I begrudge your breath.
♫ Where does this never vanished love fall off? ♫
♫ I keep searching without caring at all. ♫
♫ Some people will let a person forget himself, but also remember himself. ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
Are you back?
What's up?
Didn't you go to look for Ai Li Si? Why do you have such an expression?
There will be no Ai Li Si from now on.
What do you mean?
He Hao Yi! Go on a date with me.
If I'm unreasonable to you today,
just take it as a test for me to believe in you.
You'll always be here, right?
Even if I make you angry, you would still stay by my side. Am I right?
I just went on a date with him
to fulfill the dream I had when I was 17.
It's annoying.
He's really annoying!
He is annoying me to death!
Why did you call me?
To drink with me. It looks like you can't drink.
I can't drink. If there is nothing, then I will go.
Hey!
Sit down.
How could you know without trying? Come on, try it.
No need.
What's wrong? Now, I'm out of the game.
So even you just want to ignore me?
What do you mean?
I heard the conversation between you and Ai Li Si at her home.
You drank too much. Go home and rest.
Do I really look like I'm drunk, huh?!
Why should I keep my head clear?
Even if I'm not sober, I don't know what Ai Li Si is thinking anyway. So why can't I get sober?
So many years have passed.
I thought Ai Li Si and I would have a chance to be together.
But in the end, it's just a one-sided wish from me.
So are you giving up?
Am I giving up? Good question. Let me ask myself.
It's still pounding. Help me feel it.
Stop it, okay?
- Stop it!- Come on, just feel it.
It's still pounding.
But my brain is dead.
Do you know whose this is?
Whose is it?
- I don't know.- How can you not know?
You clearly know everything. You're the only one who knows everything! Huh?!
Oh!
Something dropped.
Oh, I picked up a heart. Is it yours?
Yeah, how did you know? Are you alone?
Do I look like two people?
How humorous.
My name is Alice. What's your name?
- Alice? Like the Alice in "Alice in Wonderland"? - Yes.
Could it be such a coincidence?
- Don't tell me you're called Alice, too?- Yes, my name is also Alice.
You're also called Alice?!
Give me two glasses of wine. I'll treat these two Alices.
How great! He's treating us to drinks!
- How many Alices are here? Raise your hands! - Here... !
I'll treat all Alices to drinks!
Why are you treating us to drinks?
- To Alice. - Yeah. To Alice.
Let me tell you. I also knew an Alice (Ai Li Si).
13 years ago.
13 years ago?
What did the Alice from 13 years ago look like?
That's right. What did she look like?
Hey, Song Han Ming is over there. Let me take care of Ah Di myself.
Wait a minute. Let's take care of Ah Di first.
- It's this person.- That's her.
Don't laugh anymore...
- I always missed my chance with her.- Missed your chance? How come?
Only until today did I realize that...
it's all my fault.
How come? What happened?
It's just one mistake after another.
Okay, let's not talk about it anymore.
None of you can leave.
- Okay, none of us will leave. Let's talk about her more.- She was on the track and field team.
I could never catch up with her.
- I kept chasing her, but now I have no more energy to chase. - Let's not talk about her. Let's drink.
I'm not going to chase her anymore...
- He Hao Yi, it's enough. Don't drink anymore!- Ah Di!
Let's go home... !
Hey! Why are you two here? Let me introduce to you...
Eh... Alice from Shilin, Alice from Tianmu, and Alice from Gaoxiong.
Okay. Stop it.
So many Alices.
You're drunk. How can there be so many Alices?
Of the many Alices,
which of them is my Ai Li Si?
Where is Ai Li Si?
Your Ai Li Si is at home. Let's go home, okay?
Let's go home...
Which one is my Ai Li Si?
She's not here. Let's go.
- He Hao Yi!- Hurry.
You're so heavy.
Why did this rotten Ah Di drink so much? He's trying to tire me to death.
Exactly!
I've never seen him drink so much.
He really never got drunk before. This is all because of her.
Seriously.
Ai Li Si...
Let's go.
Ah Di should be inside.
You go.
I don't want to.
You're his sister!
Just because I'm his sister, I can't say it.
Why can't you say it?
Then, what should we do?
It was all because of you. That's why Ai Li Si hasn't come home yet.
What are you talking about? It's because you lack persuasion skills, okay?
Who was the one that got upset and said, "Let's go. Let's go," and then left?
I haven't contacted Ai Li Si for 13 years. How would I know how to deal with her?
Have you guys had enough already?
Why do you guys have to be so loud?
Then think of a solution quickly.
I can't think of any.
Ai Li Si, I really thought you liked He Hao Yi.
He is really annoying!
He is annoying me to death!
Lei Lei and Xiao Fen,
you're really awesome!
Did he go crazy?
Anyway, we must have done something right.
♫ I can’t have your tenderness. ♫
He Hao Yi, you idiot!
Why would they speak so loudly?
It's because they wanted me to hear it.
I actually got fooled by this little trick.
I'm really an idiot.
He Hao Yi, you idiot!
Ai Li Si must have her own reason to go to this degree.
But I'm a risk management professional.
Ai Li Si, don't underestimate me.
CEO, the HR department has received Ai Li Si's resignation.
Ai Li Si resigned?
Why so suddenly?
Doesn't this mean we can have her hand over the lab journal?
If she says something to Capital, then it would be troublesome for us.
Then what should we do now?
For now, on one hand, we should see if she recovered her memory.
On the other hand, we must monitor the situation with Capital
to see whether they have the lab journal.
How should I find out if Ai Li Si recovered her memory?
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. Oh~ ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
Do you want some water?
Did you hand over the lab journal to Capital?
Not yet.
Why?
I will hand it over when I want to.
When will that be?
Wang Bo Jun's men are in Capital.
By then, he would know that you have the lab journal.
How did you know about Wang Bo Jun?
Because...
You don't need to know.
I wanted the lab journal because of Ai Li Si.
If Ai Li Si doesn't continue with the experiment,
having the lab journal is useless.
What happened?
It's none of your business.
I'm also involved in this matter.
If you don't tell me what happened, how am I going to settle this matter and protect myself?
You just need to pass them the lab journal.
It's okay if you don't want to tell me.
I know you went back home. I'll call your mom.
You have a registered mail. Thank you.
Your pen. Thank you.
Who sent this to you?
My ex-boss from my previous company.
Oh my goodness. Hey!
Why did your Boss send you a letter of attestation?
Did you have a falling out with him?
CEO sent a letter of attestation to me.
He said the lab journal belongs to JSUT.
He wants me to return it back to the company.
If you don't return it back, they're going to sue you?
What does this have to do with you?
What do you mean by that?
After you gave me the lab journal, I have the responsibility to protect you.
I don't need your protection.
I mean in legal terms. I can't let them sue you.
This is a matter of professional ethics.
Even if I'm getting sued,
it has nothing to do with you at all.
So please, hand over the lab journal.
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
Ah Di?
What are you doing?!
What's up with you? You look like you're going to murder someone.
What's wrong?
I'm thinking about how to solve this crisis.
What crisis do you have again?
Wang Bo Jun sent a letter of attestation to Ai Li Si.
Why did he do that?
Because he wants Ai Li Si's lab journal.
This is the one.
He wants to find another investor so he can reap his own benefits.
I kept standing in his way so he couldn't prevail.
However, Ai Li Si suddenly resigned.
I think he figured out Ai Li Si has recovered her memory.
- That's why he sent an attestation letter to test her.- What?!
What now then?
I need to devise a trap to lure Wang Bo Jun
so that he won't have the opportunity to threaten Ai Li Si anymore.
What trap? Have you thought of any?
It's like this...
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. Oh~ ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. My only love. ♫
I need to devise a trap to lure Wang Bo Jun
so that he won't have the opportunity to threaten Ai Li Si anymore.
What trap? Have you thought of any?
It's like this...
I'm proud of my Ah Di, who is indeed a crisis management expert.
He can even think of this strategy.
Now that we have a plan, we just need to find an investor.
An investor who can lure Wang Bo Jun to take the bait.
Once we have an investor like this in the fold,
Wang Bo Jun might just start to make his moves.
Investor...
This is simple.
I'll find my dad.
Oh, if your dad joins in, this plan will be even more complete.
However, Ai Li Si needs to willingly accept our help.
Oh!
That's right. With her current situation, she definitely won't accept our help.
One of them is the Queen.
The other one is an expert of persuasion.
How can they be so useless?
Hey! What did you say? I am very useful!
That's right!
Then show me the Queen's resolve and your persuasion skills.
If you don't take this opportunity to prove to Ai Li Si that you are trustworthy friends, then when will you?
What's difficult about this?
That's right. I'll keep persuading her 'til she raises both hands and surrenders.
I'll let Ai Li Si know that we are her closest friends!
Ai Li Si!
We want to borrow some of your time.
I'm not free.
How can that be? You already resigned.
Also, staying at home all day isn't good for your health. Come with us for a walk.
Let's go.
What are you up to?
Do you remember in high school, we always gave you our bags?
Thanks!
Liu Xiao Fen! Help bring my bookcase to the classroom.
I'm almost late for my morning swimming practice.
Give them to me. I'll help you bring them to the classroom.
Really? Thank you!
Love you!
Let's go. Hurry!
Isn't it tiring for you to carry two school bags?
I forgot.
I don't have time to play these immature games with you.
Ai Li Si!
I admit that before, the two of us were extremely immature,
so that's why we casually ended friendships.
What do you mean?
It's that... We... That is... I...
Before I... I...
At that time, their EQ was at the level of kindergarteners.
Whoever became friends with them would be unlucky.
However, we have grown up now.
- If we can start over...  - We would definitely recycle you.
Recycle us.
I don't have time to deal with you guys. I don't have time to enjoy your two-person comic show, either.
Are you done talking?
Ai Li Si!
I suddenly feel really dizzy. I might be having a heat stroke.
Hurry, take me to a cool place.
I feel so hot. I'm dying.
You guys think this tactic will work?
Ai Li Si, you sure are quick on the uptake. You know that we are reminiscing.
Even if you turned this cold, you're still just as smart.
- Sis, enough.  - What?
Well, we're just reminiscing and enjoying some shaved ice together, right?
It's no use.
This place doesn't sell pudding anymore.
You know this, too?
Obviously, you still remember stuff from the past.
It's here.
This is your order of "Disintegration of Snow Mountain."
This is mine.
Please enjoy.
Thank you.
How can this... ?
It's good!
Although the Queen has grown up, she still enjoys special privileges.
Boss lady, thank you!
You're welcome!
- You're awesome. - Of course.
Are you a vulture? Eating leftovers.
You don't eat pudding. It's a waste.
Next time, automatically put it on your big sister's plate.
- It's delicious!- Yes.
Eat!
Try it and see if the flavor is the same as before.
If you don't eat it, I will.
Liu Xiao Fen, you're so fat yet you're still eating?
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. Oh~ ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
How is it?
I ate it,
but I don't know if it tastes the same as what it did.
How can you not know?
Try one more bite.
Even if I eat one more bite, it's no use.
Because I forgot it.
I already gave you guys an answer. Can I leave?
Don't leave.
We should stop beating around the bush.
Actually, what I wanted to say is:
Ai Li Si, I'm sorry.
That year, because I didn't understand the situation well,
I shouldn't have misunderstood you, ignored you,
and let you go through so much hardship.
I really regret it.
I wasted thirteen years that I could've spent with you
going shopping, watching movies, enjoying afternoon tea,
and having heart-to-heart conversations.
Maybe you don't care anymore,
but I still want to say this.
Losing this friendship...
You're not the only one who feels upset.
I feel bad, too.
But just like you already know,
I'm pretty much a spoiled idiot.
I only know how to use anger to show my frustration.
I don't know how to tell you about my feelings.
But today, I have to tell you.
Ai Li Si, I'm really sorry.
Me, too. In the past, I only knew how to tease you,
and make fun of you.
I never tried to understand how you were feeling.
Now I know a true friend wouldn't treat someone like that.
Ai Li Si, I'm sorry.
Xiao Fen...
Lei Lei...
It's useless.
It's too late.
We said so much but Ai Li Si still won't accept us.
But I felt that
her reaction was a bit different from before.
Ah Di, hurry up and go take a look.
Ai Li Si?
Ai Li Si...
Have you had enough?
I have more important things to do.
If you're planning on going to negotiate with Wang Bo Jun,
don't even think about it unless you're bringing me with you.
Don't you find yourself annoying?
Didn't I tell you not to meddle with my business?
I have a way of stopping Wang Bo Jun from blackmailing you.
But first, you must cooperate with me.
I told you to leave me alone!
Ai Li Si!
Actually, you don't have to push me away like this.
When you were talking to Song Han Ming the other day at your house,
I just so happened to be outside. So I heard everything I should have heard.
I know the 17-year-old you already said goodbye to your first love.
The 30-year-old you has absolutely no interest in me.
I am a crisis management expert,
so when I'm supposed to work hard, I will work hard.
When I'm supposed to give up, I will definitely not hesitate.
I won't keep pestering a girl who is not into me,
so you don't have to worry at all.
Then...
why are you holding on to my hand?
♫ I have been embraced, so I desire to be more together, every day. ♫
I won't let my personal feelings interfere with my duty.
Since I've made you a promise, I'll keep my words.
Even if you don't want me to help you, I will continue.
After all, this experiment is your blood, sweat, and tears.
I won't let anyone else steal it from you.
♫ yearn for the vastness of the world. ♫
He Hao Yi,
thank you.
♫ I pick up some while dropping some. ♫
♫ Which one is worth more to be owned? ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a thief, ♫
I'm not just helping you. I'm helping all our colleagues in the R&D department and Auntie Yang.
Everyone is looking forward to the completion of your experiment.
Wang Bo Jun acquiring the lab journal is the largest variable for now.
As for what he wants to do, we don't have any say at all.
What if he disbands the entire R&D department of JSUT?
What if he sells the experiment results to a vicious company?
Then what should I do?
Continue to be my girlfriend.
Girlfriend?
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
~ Preview ~We just need to continue putting on this show for two more days.
This is all your fault, Ai Li Si.
If you feel scared, just hold my hand.
Then tell me why you left He Hao Yi.
Ai Li Si, is it caused by your brain injury?
I really want to start over with you.
No matter what happened to you,
I just want to start again with you.
♫ I have been embraced, so I desire to be more together, every day. ♫
♫ I matured, so I seek for the happiness of simplicity. ♫
♫ At that time, dreams were so astound. ♫
♫ I hide at a corner of the world and yearn for the vastness of the world. ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a thief, ♫
♫ city lights inundate the stars. ♫
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. ♫
♫ Oh~ Unwilling awakened dream. ♫
♫ Naivety exchanges with maturity. ♫
♫ A smile exchanges with a makeup face. ♫
♫ When I will really grow up, I will surprisingly lose my self. ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a spell, ♫
♫ I assume there will be more happiness for tomorrow. ♫
♫ I pick up some while dropping some. ♫
♫ Which one is worth more to be owned? ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a thief, ♫
♫ city lights inundate the stars. ♫
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. ♫
♫  Oh~ Unwilling awakened dream. ♫