[female voice]
This...is the story of a story.
Once upon a time,
there was this...
story,
and the story
said to itself,
"How shall I begin?"
[male voice]
Try the usual way.
What, in the dark?
With a man and a woman
and a story that's
still to tell itself?
Well, you've got
to start somewhere.
Say, "Long, long ago"
or "Far, far away"
or just "Once".
That's good.
"Far away"
so you know the place
is close
to your own heart.
"Once" is nice,
so we know
it always happens.
Hmm.
Once there was this...
hero.
Some hero.
Some man, then.
Any man.
Say, a man, a woman,
and some children.
Don't forget the children.
What's he doing now?
Still building the fire.
Hiding, you mean.
He's scared of us?
Some dad, huh?
Ha ha...
Well, it's been four years.
He's getting fat.
[giggling]
So what's in the story?
A man on a beach
all washed up.
A shipwreck.
A heartbreak.
Freedom?
Betrayal, regrets,
old shoes,
a crust of bread,
a bunch of roses.
Could be my story.
Anybody's story.
A journey.
A long, long journey.
Yeah. That's the story.
A long, long journey to...
where, exactly?
[giggling]
Go home!
Go on.
[female voice]
Once upon another time...
so long ago, nobody
had got around to caring
whether the world
was round or flat...
there lived--in a cave--
a man, a woman,
and some children.
Grr...
Grarr!
Dada, look.
Oww, ow!
[sniffling]
Inside the cave,
it was as safe as...
houses.
And every day, they awoke
into the only world
they would ever know.
[children laughing]
Stay home.
Dada's hunting.
Go.
Dada.
No.
Go home.
Go.
Maybe if the man knew
the whole story,
this very well
might have been different.
But this seemed
a morning...
like any other.
[distant voices]
[laughter]
[shouting]
[speaking barbarian language]
Go!
We go!
Move!
Arrows.
Up the hill.
Beach.
No. They're down there.
I saw them.
No. Other beach.
No. Up the hill.
Can't.
Up hill!
You're wrong.
Oh, you're wrong,
you're wrong.
Shut up!
[shouting]
Go!
Ma-mama!
Leave me!
Go on!
Don't lose the children!
Come, dada.
I get food.
Now, stay here.
No noise.
Don't move.
Dada...
Don't cry.
Shh.
Dada...
Dada, come.
Don't leave.
[voices]
[speaking barbarian language]
[laughter]
[voices]
Of course the man
had heard the stories
of the wandering men,
the ones who came
and took everything.
A story to frighten
his children with.
But up till now,
that's all it was to him--
a story.
[moaning softly]
Yaaa!
Mine!
Yaa!
Yaaa!
[laughter]
Mine!
Mi--
And they all turned--
at a loss--
to the priest for guidance.
He said,
"Look up there.
The stones.
We should surely pay tribute."
With these men,
suddenly everything
was out of kilter.
As they led their captive
by the rope,
even the priest was hoping...
when they got there,
he'd somehow know...
what to do.
[speaking barbarian language]
And the poet was already
making up the story
of this strange day.
Not mine.
Not my stones.
The leader stared hard
at these stones,
thinking
till his brain hurt.
Was it to make the sun work?
Was it supposed to be
one man over,
one stone on top, or what?
[shouting]
Huh?
Oss.
Oss?
Uh...
Oss!
Oss.
Schtorek...
garre.
Dada.
Dada?
[speaking barbarian language]
Dada...
Dada.
If the world is round...
you could still fall off the edge.
No. It's not round like that.
It's round like...
this.
You believe everything
that Greek tells you?
Where are we, then?
Rome must be in the middle...
here.
So we must be out here...
somewhere.
Right. Another time,
there's this man,
and he had a woman
and a child and a bed,
but it was not his bed...
not his child...
not his woman.
Everything he had,
even his smallest humiliation,
belonged to his master.
[man]
All must stop, Lucinnius.
No sign of the ships.
Bad omens, Hector.
Bad omens.
Everything's gone wrong
since the earthquake.
I knew that it was a sign.
The gods were trying
to tell me something.
I think the gods were
telling everybody something.
What could be worse
than to be a slave...
unless...
it's to be a slave
to a foolish master.
Bad omens, Hector.
Not an omen, an accident.
It's a bad omen.
An accident.
Get me something to eat.
Spoiled his day,
meeting your old man.
Been avoiding him all week.
The big bit.
Not the big bit.
His ships have gone as well, we heard.
What have you heard?
Last night. Nepos knew.
Pirates.
They're sunk, he reckoned.
That could finish him, eh?
This is the worst it's been.
He'll be up for sale before
you know it. Ha ha...
Will he lend you the money?
He was honest about it.
He said so plain, simple,
No.
That's a problem.
He didn't want any rope?
No.
And the ships have gone. I know.
I told you?
No.
But you knew?
Yes.
Who told you?
Julian's men.
Who told them?
Nepos.
Then Cyprian knows already.
He'll want his money back, too.
You get a chicken and
fetch Hermas the diviner.
Are my ships from Sicily still afloat?
No, no.
Offer the grain first.
Sprinkle some on the altar.
Making another sacrifice, father?
Shh.
Leave us alone.
And we can't ask the gods
specific questions.
It's a gentle, probing inquiry.
General questions.
Well, let's see.
General answer--
No.
What do you mean?
The liver says no.
Do it again.
I want you to do it again.
Is it the gods' will
that Cyprian...
be well-disposed towards me...
in the future?
Doing it again
means another chicken...
and another 15 sesterces.
I'll have my first 15 now, please.
And, uh, that's 2 for the chicken.
It was our chicken.
Oh, yes. Of course. Sorry.
It's all right.
Cyprian loaned me half a
million to fit out these ships.
I'm finished.
Just when things were going well.
I had plans for you, too, Hector.
In four or five years,
I was going to make you free.
You could've found your
family, brought them here,
everything.
Sounds good.
It does, doesn't it?
I shouldn't give up.
I can't.
I'll visit Cyprian...
first thing tomorrow
before the others get to him.
He's got to see reason.
I can pay him back...
sometime.
It's the only chance
we have, Hector.
Should I do it?
You must.
You're right.
I must.
Thalia,
I think I need one
of your massages.
Hector, you can finish the lamps.
Lower, Thalia.
Ahh...
lower.
[snoring]
[thunder]
Why does the thunder
always stay out at sea?
It thundered like that before
the earthquake, remember?
If he goes down, I'm
asking for my freedom.
He owes it to me.
And yours, too. We'd be free.
Then what?
What do you mean?
What we talk about.
We talk about going home.
Yours is that way...
mine is that way.
Your family's that way.
I made that up.
I don't know where they are.
We can't talk about families anymore.
It's been too long.
It's what you talk--
We talk about it
because it can never happen.
It's just you and me now.
Save your breath for
blowing in my ear.
I think you'll leave.
You are going to leave me here.
Shh.
And, every morning,
the man awoke into the only world
he would ever know.
I can't sleep.
Get me a chicken.
I want to make another sacrifice.
We'll do it ourselves.
[rooster crows]
We'll be first, Hector.
Definitely.
No one else will be there.
Not this early.
Were they friends?
Well, they were
as close to friends
as a master
and a slave can be.
I'm Cyprian--
I mean, Lucinnius.
I've come to see Cyprian.
Do you have a gift?
A gift? No.
Join the line on the left.
Thank you.
Leave the stool.
And as his master
went in to meet
the master of his fate,
the slave was free,
free to feel the sun
on his back
and squat in the dirt
amongst the litter carriers
and chicken imitators.
Cock-a-doodle-dooo...
Bawk bawk bawk bawk...
You seem much happier.
Relieved, anyway.
Relieved that it's over at last.
So...
He's going to help you?
I have to kill myself
by tomorrow morning.
He has my letters to Titanius.
None got through.
He says it's treason.
He says I should want to die.
I'm done for, Hector.
[man imitating chicken]
It's strange.
I--I feel kind of good now.
The struggle is over.
Ha ha ha...
Ah, we've seen it
through together, eh?
Let's get home.
We've a lot to do.
Tonight...
peace at last.
I don't feel so good
about it now.
You don't have to do it.
If I don't, they will.
He made that clear.
They need a sacrifice,
and I'm it.
[laughing]
Why is he always laughing?
What's he got to be happy about?
Why is everybody so happy?
'Cause they're not me,
that's why.
Let's go home.
No.
No, I can't.
[laughter]
We'll do it
with a knife, Hector,
when everyone has gone to bed.
The two of us...
to the end.
I don't understand.
What can I do?
I couldn't help you die.
We'll help each other.
We must.
We've been through
this whole mess together.
You don't understand, do you?
I'm asking you to die with me.
You're my closest,
my dearest slave.
What would they say about me
if you refuse to die with me?
You keep saying "we".
Why we?
Wh-what have I done?
I've done nothing.
I--I know nothing...
At Cyprian's this morning,
I had to sign certain papers,
tell a bit of a story.
What kind of story?
A confession.
That we were plotting against
Cyprian and the provincial senate
and were short of names.
Most of the people I know
were in the room,
people I thought were my friends.
So I mentioned you.
And what did I do?
You stole money from Cyprian
to bribe and corrupt
members of the senate.
You're a rebel against the state--
nasty piece of work.
Can I sit down?
Of course.
Do you think we go
anywhere else when we die?
I don't know.
They say so.
I hope not.
I just... want it to stop.
Just stop.
If I die a slave,
will I be a slave forever?
I would think so, wouldn't you?
I'm sorry, Hector.
But I would be honored...
if you would die with me.
Father, can I talk to you?
Not now.
I want to tell you
about the world.
You can tell me... later.
Thanks, Hector.
If he eats the grain,
it means yes.
He's eating.
He's saying yes.
Yes, we should die.
You asked if we had to die
or if there's another way.
It's saying,
"yes, there's another way".
No, it's saying,
"yes, we should die".
What?
Get the knife.
We'll do it the other way.
Solus, I'm eating chicken again.
I ate chicken yesterday
and the day before that.
Will I be eating chicken
again tomorrow?
Why am I always eating chicken?
That's what we have
in the kitchen.
The chickens have just
been turning up.
Two men have come to see you...
from Cyprian.
Good evening, Lucinnius.
Cyprian sent us to ask if we
could be of any assistance
in the business you have
to conduct tonight,
to make that business as
comfortable as you would wish.
Uh...
Thank you, gentlemen.
I will be capable
of taking care
of my affairs tonight
without your help.
Thank Cyprian
for his kind thought.
We're spending the night
at the house of Nepos
across the street.
Don't hesitate to
send your man for us.
We're anxious that things
go well for you.
Thank you.
Good night.
We'll call in the morning.
Thank you.
He looks like the kind
that's going to need some help.
You ever killed before?
Just a couple of chickens.
It's not much different.
Use a thin blade, but long.
Get it in deep, the heart.
Go between the ribs.
Or go in from the back,
any place he'll let you.
Getting it out's not
as easy as you'd think.
You have to twist to get
over the stickiness.
If it gets messy,
you come and get us.
If we're going to die,
can I die a free man?
I don't want to die a slave.
Very well, Hector, you're free.
I don't know the exact words.
I've never done it before.
Can you put that in writing
so when they find me
in the morning,
they'll know I died a free man?
Very well.
It's a nice thought.
You were right to ask.
Thank you.
Well, freed man, let's do it.
What do you want me to do?
Nothing.
Not--not to me.
I have to do it first.
You understand?
I understand.
And then you.
No. Oh. Oh. Oh.
If I don't succeed...
Stop it, Hector.
Then you...
You must help me.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
I can't do it!
I can't!
[crying]
Aah!
I did it.
On the stairs I did it.
It hurts.
It stings.
This is hopeless.
Help me.
You've done it.
Lie down.
Better?
Thank you.
Close your eyes.
You did it.
You do it now, Hector.
Be still.
Hurry!
Do it.
You promised.
I'll need the knife.
Take it.
Do it, Hector.
Oh!
Take it, Hector.
Take it, take it.
Do it.
And so...
wearing his master's cloak,
best foot forward
in a dead man's shoes,
the man walked out
into his own story...
Come on.
A free man.
The captain wants to see you.
Up there.
But that is another story.
[priest] We want to praise god
because we live
in this ultimate age
when all things are done.
O.K., this man...
he'd been through the wars,
and he'd been traveling a long time
through strange lands,
but he was on his way home.
[priest] All god's chosen
gathered in paradise.
I struggle against it.
I will not join myself
carnally with any woman.
I will carry my unspilt seed
from this world to the next,
as should every man.
I've written a small treatise
in favor of virginity, sister.
We could discuss it later,
if you like.
What are you talking about?
It's simple, brother.
If we cease carnal union entirely,
in 50 or so years,
we'll all be rid
of our earthly lives,
and god can proceed with his reign
over his heavenly kingdom,
that same paradise that
god gave to man before,
but which man was
so unfit to inhabit
that within seven hours,
Eve was already tempting
her master and mate,
and within nine hours,
the lord had to expel
the both of them.
[urinating]
[shouting]
[horse whinnies]
[sword fight]
Help me!
A bit cold for a walk.
[speaking Italian]
I don't know what you're saying.
A man, a woman,
neither speaks
the other's language.
They understand nothing.
"Well," said the story to itself,
"I suppose I must be a...
a love story."
Keep out of the way of temptation.
I saw the way you were
eyeing that widow.
If anyone's going to dally
with her, it will be me.
You couldn't handle her.
She'd bewitch you.
Why don't you get off
up the road tomorrow?
I'll catch up in a few days.
No.
Why do I talk so much?
You weren't even thinking of her
till I opened my mouth.
But I trust you, Hector.
You're not a sinner.
You wouldn't do anything
to anger your god or me.
Give me some bread.
No.
Why, you little squirrel?
What's wrong with you?
Nothing at all. I just said no.
I brought it because
I was near the table,
not because you ordered.
This woman's got to you.
It's not her.
I'm fed up being like your slave.
I want to go my own way.
In a month, we'll be at the channel,
then home.
The little ones that you talk about
when you're drunk, don't forget 'em.
I won't. I'm going home.
Give me some wine.
No.
May the lord forgive us
for our sins--
Those we have committed...
and those we as yet only dream of.
Ha ha.
And so it was,
as it ever was.
The country they traveled through
was troubled times.
The weather was wars,
as regular as rainstorms.
Love broke out like
epidemics of the plague.
[moaning]
You, priest, get to work on him.
He's not ready for heaven yet.
There's 100,000 on his head
if I get him to Paris alive.
Ha ha ha. Ha ha ha.
[speaking Italian]
Why do you speak so different
from everyone else?
[moaning]
You must be sore. Was it your dada?
If his head's small, he might be O.K.
Does your dada got a big head?
[moaning]
Are you a long way from home?
Home.
[speaking Italian]
No, I don't want your word for home.
I want you to say mine.
Casa.
Ha ha ha.
Pulce.
Un pulce.
A flea?
Pulce. Flea.
All right.
You itch?
[horse snorts]
My name is Peter--Peter.
Say it again.
Goodbye, Peter.
You're a busy man.
There's nothing wrong
with helping someone die in peace.
Nothing at all. You do it well.
You're leaving?
Aye. I feel lost, Ronald.
I'm far away from home.
I just want to be there.
What about the woman?
We're sharing a few days on the road.
I'm going home.
I told you she might be a witch.
Witch, my ass.
Wait for me.
I still have the money from Venice.
We can get home in a month.
You've got work to do here.
You'll make a good priest yet.
Do you think so?
You're a strange fellow.
I've been with you a year,
and I still don't know who you are.
You never will.
Are you a priest?
I don't know.
We're moving soon, father.
They need you in the valley.
I must be.
I can smell her off you.
Keep the sun on your back,
and you'll get home.
[Beatrice]
Hector.
[speaking Italian]
And so this man...
who so long did not know
which foot to put
in front of the other
unless he had
his friend to follow,
without a qualm, for once,
went his own way,
which was the way of a woman.
[speaking Italian]
Only when the woman slept
could the man catch his breath.
[speaking Italian in her sleep]
[wolf howls]
[birds tweet]
I bought that in Jerusalem.
It's one of the cups
from the last supper.
I don't know which apostle.
Might even be the cup
of Christ himself.
Christ?
Aye.
Jesus Christ?
Oh.
Hey, you!
Move on!
He's a dead man.
What was the story
of the dead boy?
A mystery--
Money? Revenge?
A jealous uncle?
A war is a good time
to settle old scores.
[speaking Italian]
[praying in Italian]
By the dead boy,
the living lovers loved.
You put magic
in that stuff, didn't you?
You're bewitching me.
I don't know what you're saying,
but I like it when you talk.
[singing in Italian]
Thank you.
Until one fine day,
they crossed a river,
and...
[speaking Italian]
everyone spoke like her.
Beatrice...
wait.
We're going the wrong way.
I've got to have
the sun on my back.
My back.
[speaking Italian]
No, the sun on my back.
Lower.
[singing in Italian]
Thank you.
Wash?
You want me to rest?
Man's dead?
His clothes.
You want me to stay, don't you?
I like that.
A bed.
Soft.
Better than a field, aye?
[boy calling in Italian]
Mama...
[speaking Italian]
Questo Hector.
Questo mio madre.
Huh?
And the dead boy's shoes
danced the live lad's feet.
What's that?
[speaking Italian]
Where were his own children?
Far away, right?
What were the wonders
they'd be showing
some sweet stranger
who wasn't their father?
Bread, you eat?
Blue.
Your mother wears blue.
Roses, oh.
Smell.
Oh, that's nice.
In there?
Mama.
[bird squawks]
Buon.
Hector.
[speaking Italian]
I have to leave here.
It would be wrong to stay here,
even for just a while.
I've got to go to home.
This was true.
He could not speak her language,
so he'd not needed to learn to lie.
Sorry I have to go.
I've got a family...
like you.
Like you.
Oh, you smell good.
I've got to keep the sun on my back.
Hector.
Mama.
You'd think the man
would have wanted
another helping
of chicken stew.
Second-day stew
is always better.
You'd think he'd have been content
with another man's coat,
for there was plenty
of wear in it
and precious few patches.
You'd think the man
would've wanted just one night
in the woman's bed,
for is not a feather bed
softer than a ditch?
But a man...
this man...
could not be happy
with such happiness.
He walked on his own two feet...
forever out
of this woman's story.
That's it.
Let's go.
Come on.
Tomorrow the boatman would be back,
and he could cross over.
Only this fine morning,
the man crossed the river,
but before night fell,
he'd left his lover.
[cough cough]
[singing in Spanish]
Andre.
Hmm?
I just had a wonderful dream.
I was lying beside a river.
I heard the water.
It was beautiful, clear water.
I drank some.
I think I ate some raspberries, too.
Hmm. I would like
to drink some water.
They've been doing that all night?
Mmm...
Ever since we came ashore.
You remember that.
What happened to Francisco and Ursula?
They're safe.
Where are they?
Over there.
Sometimes one day
changes everything.
Sometimes years change nothing.
I won't look.
Do you think I'll still see Europe?
I think there's more of a chance
of me eating you.
[father Diogo] God has seen fit
to preserve us
for six days on this raft
and bring us safely to shore.
I don't think
he'll abandon us now,
so let's get to work, my friends.
Come, come.
Africa must be full
of meat and drink.
See, there's this man,
and he wakes up
into the only world
he'll ever know--
shipwrecked,
washed up.
The worst of it is,
he's washed up once again
with the lover he had
so cruelly forsaken.
Where's the small box?
We had it on the raft.
Dona.
Dona Ursula.
Let me help.
I'll get it.
Allow me, please.
No.
Let me help.
Let me help you.
Leave me alone!
Don't be a martyr.
Let me have it.
Señor Hector.
Uhh!
[Andre] Come and help me.
Let me help.
Don't.
[Andre] Look. I found the box.
I'm sorry.
What was the story
between this man and this woman?
Shipwreck?
Heartbreak?
The usual.
Yeah, lots of different stories
washed up on this shore.
How many made it?
80 men,
10 women,
18 children,
and 45 slaves.
10 women?
We got you a big chair.
Where do you want it, in or out?
Out.
We got your table, sir.
Where do you want it?
Uh, right there, please.
Hurry up with that table!
I've lost a rather valuable ring,
and I'd like it to be found.
Please.
Francisco, I have
some cloth and carpet.
I thought if we worked together,
we could make a better shelter.
At least ask dona Ursula.
I don't have to ask her.
I know she'd agree with me.
Leave us alone.
Well, at least take the cloth.
The carpet, the cloth.
Keep it.
Build your own hovel somewhere else.
Leave her alone, Hector.
Francisco, I have some rope.
Thanks, Nuno.
I'll see you later.
All right.
Life is harder now.
Where's my hat?
It's in the bag.
Dear god.
Nothing.
Send 2 parties of 10 men each--
one to the north,
one to the south.
Bring back what you can--
Game, fruit, anything.
Are you serious?
Send someone back when
you find fresh water.
Any trouble, discharge three shots.
No, j-just one.
One shot, perhaps two.
[gunshot]
Ohh!
[bang]
They run off with the dried bread, sir,
And most of the fresh water.
There were eight of them.
We got these two.
Why were you running away?
Why were you leaving us?
You men are deserters,
and you will die tomorrow.
With all respect,
these sentences can't be lawful.
You don't think so?
Of course not.
They must hang.
They were stealing our bread.
I didn't steal any bread.
Gomes stole the bread.
He's away.
[Dom Paulo]
What do you think, father?
I'll comfort them
whether they live or die.
[Francisco]
There must be proper justice.
[deserter]
I didn't steal any bread.
[Salgado]
You must decide, sir.
Gomes told us to run.
[Dom Paulo] I'll decide!
No, I won't.
We'll all decide.
Most of the people
that matter are here.
We'll have a vote.
Who agrees
with Salgado and me
that they should die?
And those against death?
You can't vote!
This isn't working out, dom Paulo.
We need authority.
You must decide.
Very well.
Da Cunha.
Sir?
The cross the carpenter's
working on,
have him turn it
into a scaffold.
Have it erected
away from the women.
Executions will be
at sunrise tomorrow.
Tell father Diogo.
Take them to the raft.
Are we all in agreement
with hanging?
Should we shoot them or what?
Hanging is fine, sir.
Very well.
Who's going to conduct
the executions?
Shall we choose someone
Or have a volunteer?
Hector.
I'm not good with ropes.
I can barely tie my own shoes.
I'll do it.
At sunrise tomorrow.
Send the priest to them tonight.
He found your ring.
Me.
We found it.
Well...
thank you.
I found it.
Good work, Andre.
Thank you.
You go sleep by the big fire.
Oh...
Yes.
Good night.
Well, they were
as close to friends
as a master and a slave can be.
Keep warm.
I'll try!
And the woman...
Well, perhaps they were
as close to friends
as two old lovers can be.
Hector?
One moment.
Oh!
Nuno.
Here's what they found.
There are four for each of us.
They taste kind
of milky, but sour.
Thank you, Nuno.
My mother ate three
and she was sick,
so try two.
But she was sick before.
Maybe you can try three.
I'll start with two.
Hector,
Lopo, the boy they're going
to hang tomorrow,
he was my friend on the ship.
I was going to take him
something to eat.
I thought... maybe two of yours
and two of mine?
What about tomorrow, Nuno?
What am I going to eat tomorrow?
Dom Paulo would call it a waste.
[women singing]
You've got to keep yourself strong.
That's what he'd say.
God knows what's
going to happen to us.
We need you to be strong.
What if I take one to Lopo
and the other to dona Ursula
from you?
Thank you.
And if they don't
let you talk to Lopo,
give them both to the lady.
Thank you, Hector.
Thank you.
So, what was the priest to do
but bless the men?
There's water for one more day.
What do we do then?
Keep hanging people.
That'll solve the problem.
I wish they'd hurry up
with these two.
Hector!
What?
Hector, please!
Hector.
Yes?
Thanks for the fruit, Hector.
Promise me when we're dead
you won't let them eat us.
They said they would.
Who said that?
That was a joke.
You won't eat us, will you, Hector?
Oh, no. I won't eat you, Lopo.
Thank you.
You won't eat me, either?
Oh, god, no.
I'd never eat you.
No offense.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Come on.
I'm going to walk.
I want to walk!
Please let me walk, for god's sake!
Please let me walk!
Everyone kept their distance.
What now?
God knows.
Like any priest anywhere,
all he wanted was a sign.
We're being watched.
I bet some gunpowder
would scare them.
No. They might be friendly.
Then they'll have food.
That's right.
We mustn't be timid.
You.
Go and talk to them.
No.
Go on.
Get up there.
That's right.
Be friendly.
Smile.
Go on.
Don't you want a little
drink of water?
Go, go, go, go.
Oh...god.
What's this?
A bit of bread and raisins.
Thought everything had
been shared on the raft.
Well, that wasn't.
It's for her... and for you.
I must speak to her.
He could talk to them.
There's just the two.
Their leader arrives tomorrow.
Well, thank god we're safe.
Oh. And they said
not to sacrifice
any more men for them.
They don't like that.
Nuno!
It's stuff from the ship!
Did you give her the fruit?
Yes.
What did she say?
She said thank you.
Anything else?
Well, go on. Run!
Don't just stand there.
See if there's anything.
Run!
Look at it!
Ha! Just look.
[laughing]
Look at that!
Right up on the beach!
Turtle eggs.
Dr. Correa was shipping
them to the royal zoo.
I think he was hoping
they were going to hatch.
Eggs for supper tonight
for everyone!
Eggs!
Eggs! Eggs!
Why is she doing this to me?
Why won't she let me speak to her?
[women singing]
Oh!
You'd think in this awful situation--
death and pain all around her--
that she'd want to reconcile herself
to someone who cares for her.
Why can't I see her?
I just want to apologize.
Oh...
You have any eggs left?
The slaves only got three.
Yours were fine?
Yes.
I'm unlucky, Andre.
I'm unlucky with women,
I'm unlucky with eggs.
Have you eaten all of your eggs?
Yes.
At least one of us is well-fed, huh?
How are you doing, Andre?
I only have one small problem.
You still keep calling me Andre.
Oh, god. I'm sorry.
I did promise, didn't I?
I want to die...
at least with my real name.
Indro...
Indrabooti
Fadradakeeli.
Now I remember
why we call you Andre.
Indrapoo--
Indrapoop-
Indra--
Indraboot...
Indrabooti
Fadradakeeli.
Indrabooti Fadrabak--
Fadrabakeemi.
Indrabooti Fachabak...
Ohh.
Five deaths this morning.
We've stopped people
eating the fruit,
but some people just
ate too many eggs.
The nuns have gone.
How many eggs did you have?
Three.
I had them boiled.
I had four.
I don't feel very well.
Four's all right.
The really sick ones had 8, 10.
Let's not talk about it.
What do you have?
We'll have to trade for food.
They'll go for this--copper...
nails.
We're going to
meet a king today. Hup.
Dom Paulo,
they've arrived.
Excellent.
That's it?
[mules braying]
Where's the king?
He's not a real king,
But they are his camels.
[speaking native language]
He doesn't know if you're real.
He wants to see your navel
so he'll be sure you were
born like real people.
My navel?
You four also.
Now he wants to see you breathe.
Breathe.
And it shall be called
the way of holiness.
The unclean shall not pass...
and the thirsty land
springs of water.
Water.
And the mule.
So many stories--
crosses, eggs, nails,
shipwrecks, hanged men,
feasts, ropes,
corpses, bread,
wine, lovers.
Suck out the marrow.
That's the best bit.
But in the end,
isn't every story
all the one story?
Where's Francisco?
Dona Ursula's sick.
[Da Cunha] What about the sick?
How are they going to walk?
I'm staying here.
I'm going to work on that raft,
then I'm sailing home.
You can't.
They've taken all the nails!
What about them, dom Paulo?
I've been discussing it
with father Diogo.
I can't see how a hundred of us
can carry back 70 sick.
Going to take your big cross
into the desert, Diogo?
I thought we'd make a smaller one.
[laughing]
I'm going to search
the scriptures tonight
to find an answer.
An excuse, you mean.
Francisco.
Will you share a bottle
of wine with me?
I've had it since we left the ship,
and I want to drink it
tonight with you.
You should hang for this.
Some of the people
might have lived
with a glass of this
in their stomachs.
We'll save Ursula a glass.
Yeah, we will.
The natives are taking us to water.
We're leaving tomorrow.
She won't be traveling anywhere.
I'm staying with her.
I know.
That's why I had to see you tonight.
So you want to tidy things up
before you leave?
Put your conscience to rest?
Not just for me.
For all of us.
The pain and effort
she puts into despising me
must be tormenting her...
and you and I.
Am I selfish to want to stop that?
I'm your friend, Hector.
Your only mistake was getting
on the same ship home.
I never meant to get
on your damn ship.
If I hadn't gotten
on that ship,
I'd be home now, safe.
Understand me.
Tomorrow you're leaving.
Ursula and me, we're staying.
Believe me, many things
no longer matter to us,
Ursula and me.
Vanities, hurts from the past,
they're nothing.
They no longer have meaning.
This is my last bottle of wine.
I think tomorrow she'll talk to you.
You do?
I do. And what does it matter?
I'll never forget you or what
you're doing for these poor people.
Good luck to you.
It breaks my heart
to leave you like this.
What else can I do?
God protect you.
Well.
We're leaving the big cross with you.
Oh. Thank you.
And I'll comfort them
as best I can.
You're staying?
No. No. I'll comfort them
before we leave.
I think my place
is with you, don't you?
I think so.
I'll ask her.
In you go.
Thank you for seeing me.
I don't have much to say
except I'm sorry for all
the hurt I've caused you.
There are so many things
I could explain.
How we stupidly
misunderstand each other.
Later we can talk.
Later?
Yes. Later.
There's no later.
I'm leaving now.
You're leaving?
Yes.
You're not staying with us?
I'm living--
leaving with the others,
and I want to tell you
that I will pray
for your soul in Lisbon.
Oh, you'll pray
for my soul in Lisbon?
Yes.
I will.
At the cathedral?
At the cathedral.
Every day.
[laughs]
Oh...
Goodbye, Hector.
Have a pleasant journey.
I'll try.
What?
Ursula, don't turn away.
I have so much more to say to you.
We seem to be misunderstanding
each other again.
Idiot.
You've made your peace with her?
I think so. Yes.
Thank god.
Well...
Goodbye.
You want me to take
anything back for you?
A message, letter?
If you were carrying
something for me,
I'd have to worry about you.
If you go empty-handed,
I can put you out of my mind.
I want to ask you something.
There's no easy way to do it.
Go on, Hector.
Your boots.
What about them?
Can I have them?
You can have my shoes.
They're perfect for here.
I've got to walk 600 miles,
Francisco.
600 miles in these sandals.
Yes. You're right.
I daresay my boots
would take you 600 miles.
I look after them.
I'll look after them, too.
I'll walk all the way home,
and I'll remember you
in the cathedral in Lisbon.
In my boots?
Yes.
Oh...
Hector, you have surpassed yourself.
Sit down. Take my boots.
Really?
Yes. Go on.
[laughing]
Oh. These are fabulous.
Are they made by Da Fosco?
Ohh.
Best bootmaker in Goa.
Oh.
Hey. Pray for my soul
in Lisbon, Hector.
I will, Francisco.
Pray for your own.
Ha ha ha ha.
You really think you're going
to walk out of here,
don't you?
All the way home, Francisco.
Those are fine boots.
Aren't they?
They look a bit big for you.
Probably more my size.
No. They're fine.
Boots the wrong size are
worse than no boots at all.
Really?
Aah!
Oh.
[speaking foreign language]
Ya. Brooklyn.
I'm going to Queens.
Do you know the lady?
Think you'll go to jail again?
Will you release some
public comment to the press?
Will you talk to us?
Oh, Anna. Thank god.
Yeah. Listen, I'm at
that building in Queens.
Oh. I need your help.
Come get me.
Yeah. There's cops, dogs, everything.
I'm all right.
I need your car.
I don't have time
to get the rental car.
They won't let me out
of the building, Anna.
Building warrant, license...
I'm calm.
I'm all right.
Here's what you do.
It's not my building.
It's my partner's building.
I took the call.
I came to see if I could help.
Slow down, troup.
So, it's 3:15 on a Friday.
You are staying here
until mr. Santiago
gets the paperwork.
Get your partner over here.
This is serious.
It's 3:35.
I might have to close the place.
Why? What happened?
I danced with a prince
on my 18th birthday!
And now look at me!
I warn you Monday!
I told you the floor
was making noises.
It wasn't me, mrs...
Philippopilis.
Oh, castrate you...
Are you all right?
My son sees his mother
laying here...
he gonna sue you!
I'm not the landlord,
mrs. Philippopilis.
Yeah. I'm at the building.
She fell through the floor
on her toilet.
It's not funny. No.
You get down here.
Why'd you do this to me, Boris?
They want all sorts of documents.
The place is crawling with--
Oh, yeah.
[speaking Greek]
Mrs. Philippopilis,
this is my lawyer.
He wants to ask a question.
This place is a mess!
Mrs. P, you poor thing!
That doesn't sound good,
Leonard. I don't think...
Hey, troup...
You moving out, mrs. P?
Is the apartment
going to be available?
He's not going to the hospital.
I've got a family emergency.
Emergency?
What do you call this?
All right, listen.
O.K., um,
listen, how's Tuesday
for you, George?
I'm no good in the morning.
Maybe in the afternoon
I could meet you in the hospital.
I'll bring flowers.
Fuck flowers.
Who'll pay for this?
Who'll check her in the hospital?
Your building fell down.
It's not my building.
They won't let me leave.
They'll love this in court.
You didn't even ride
to the hospital?
You got a credit card
or something?
Yeah. Wait. The guy
you want is right there.
Can I get him?
That's my partner.
Can I bring him back?
Well, they were
as close to friends
as two mutual slaves
to money may be.
Boris, asshole,
it's never been this bad.
Did you bring all the papers?
Yes. We seem to be
covered for everything.
What do you mean "we"?
[siren]
Hey, it's your problem.
How is she?
She's a fucking voodoo witch.
She didn't break a single bone.
She's yelling at me,
"Jump through. Break both legs."
Why did you fuck me on this? Why?
I didn't-- Listen, I'm sorry.
I just put your name
on the lousy forms.
I didn't plan this.
I told you, don't
do that anymore, O.K.?
Just stop doing that.
It's my name, O.K.?
My name is mine.
Use your name on the forms.
Remember that?
Remember your name?
I got it.
Boris Borlanski!
Don't let it spoil your weekend.
You haven't seen these kids
for four years.
I'll take care of it.
Who's in charge up there?
Cobb.
I don't know him. Cobb...
All right. Go on.
I promise you'll
walk away from this.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I blew up at you.
You got to get out
of this business.
Here she is. Enjoy your weekend.
I'll straighten everything out.
Good luck. It's never
been this bad, Boris.
Everything can be fixed. Always.
What's up?
Am I glad to see you.
Hi. Uh...
You can drop me off
at the shop, right?
Yeah. You bring my bag?
Yep.
Where is it?
It's back there.
Your camera's in there, too.
Thanks.
Take some photographs of the kids.
I will.
That's nice. Thanks.
Don't worry. Come on, relax.
This is the beginning
of something, not the end.
Yeah.
I'm jealous. You're going
to start to be a father again.
Thanks for talking me into this.
You were totally ready.
You're right.
I am ready, aren't I?
It's been long enough.
I'm ready.
Oh. I'm going to fix
that shit with Boris.
Good.
I can't go on.
No. I want my freedom.
And the kids--
it's going to work out, isn't it?
When it does, they
can come over, right?
That was the plan.
When we get a bigger space.
That's all we need. We'll get
a big apartment together.
You just said a bigger
apartment together.
I said that, didn't I?
Yeah. What?
Hector.
What?
You're a man of decisions today.
I like this!
I am. Now get out of my car.
I don't want to drive
around the block.
Already it's your car.
What's the freedom part?
Freedom's from Boris, not you.
I'm your slave.
I'm your love slave.
You know? Come on.
Thanks for the car and everything.
Do the best you can with them.
I will. what are those?
Oh, my god!
You have to deliver them!
I don't have time.
It's two blocks before the bridge.
It's a five-minute detour.
Who died?
Nobody died. It's a golden wedding.
Yeah? Listen, please
don't ask me to do this, O.K.?
Honey...
Please.
What?
You have to.
You want my car?
You need my car?
This is how we help each other.
This is a relationship.
All right. All right.
Thanks.
Phone if there are any catastrophes.
Don't suffer alone, asshole.
[chuckles] Thanks.
Hector!
What?
No gas.
Great.
Hector, have a great time!
[horn honks]
And once again,
the man crossed the river.
Don't stop.
Hell.
[honk honk]
[siren]
Hello, Hector.
You made it.
The kids are just coming.
They're not crazy about going
to the beach house,
I should warn you.
I would have made other plans.
I thought this was
a good way to start,
but maybe it isn't.
You should be allowed
to make your own mistakes.
It's just for a couple of nights.
They can take it.
Check into a hotel
if it gets to be too bad.
They love room service.
Come on, guys. Let's go.
Your father's waiting.
Here's where we'll be
if anything crops up.
Thanks for the break.
Maybe this is a little sudden for them.
I should come by
a couple of nights
and get to know them that way.
By Monday, you'll know them.
You've grown.
Well, here he is--
the invisible dad.
That's what they call you.
Hi.
Well, you three have a good weekend.
If it gets too miserable
at the beach house,
your dad will take you to a hotel.
Good luck, Hector.
Thanks.
See you Monday, Hector.
Are these flowers for mom?
Oh, god!
Gee!
What have I done?
Ohh...
No.
What's wrong?
A lot.
I can't face her just now.
Let's go.
[car honks]
Have a nice time.
Portable phone.
You want to make any calls?
Tom?
No.
And it's Thomas.
But we called you Tom.
That's what's on
your birth certificate.
I changed it.
O.K...it's your name.
You can do what you want with it.
Hey, you guys,
you got to help me here.
We need supplies
before we get there.
Keep your eyes peeled
for a supermarket.
We also need gas.
Oh, god, we really need gas.
We're running on fumes here.
Steaks.
What? Let me keep a couple of steaks.
Give the chickens a break
this weekend, O.K.?
Want some hamburger, too?
O.K.
Obviously, we stay away
from the luncheon meats, huh?
What was wrong with that?
It's just kitchen towel.
It's paper.
It's bleached,
and it wasn't recycled.
This is better for the planet?
Mm-hmm.
You don't recycle?
No.
You just buy junk.
I don't eat steak. I eat chicken.
What's this?
Those are sweet rolls.
You like sweet rolls, Thomas?
No.
Why don't you ask us what we like?
It'll save you money.
You buy junk, we won't eat it.
Why don't you show me?
I'll just tag along.
You know what you like.
I do it every week anyway.
She does.
She tells us what to eat.
We let her.
O.K.
She seems to know.
Are you Anna?
Who?
The name on the car.
No, I'm not Anna.
She's my friend.
She loaned me the car.
Your girlfriend?
A good friend. Very close.
What about the flowers?
They look like they should
be delivered to somebody.
Is that your job?
Something like that.
I get it.
But you're not going to.
Well, I forgot.
I was slightly distracted.
You know, that happens.
Now we're on the
wrong side of town.
That's it?
Yeah, that's it...
I guess.
I see.
You're not seeing me
at my best today.
[tv]
O.K., so you're an aquarius
on the cusp of pisces.
What can I do for you today?
I'm thinking about moving.
You're thinking about moving.
You mean out of your house?
Is that what you mean?
Far away.
Be as specific as you can.
Hone in on the problem
that you have.
I'm thinking about moving
to California, Rob.
Let's see what the stones
say about that.
I can see a move to California.
The stones are
a little tentative,
and they're wanting to know
why you want to move
to California.
We passed the fun fair last night.
Why don't we take a walk there today?
We don't go to fun fairs.
Let's just take a walk.
I brought some books.
I want to stay home and read.
No. Let's take a walk.
All right?
Fine.
Good.
Don't tell me-- Donald.
Yep.
In a gale, it just about
powers the radio.
It seems to want to make
the house fly at the same time.
What are you doing?
This is a metal detector.
Donald give you that?
Yep.
He's a regular mr. Wizard-- Donald.
I guess you could say that.
Donald's shoes leak.
O.K., give me $10 worth.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Well, let's go.
Let's go have fun.
Both of Donald's shoes leak.
Hey, let's go on the ferris wheel.
It makes me sick.
How about the bumper cars?
Those are great.
No.
O.K. Hey, look, a roller coaster.
How about that?
Nah.
No.
I don't want to waste these tickets.
Let's go on this.
Three, please.
Here you go, bets.
The seats are wet.
Didn't count on a kitchen towel.
Unbleached, biodegradable,
and recyclable dry seats.
Huh? Ha ha ha.
Here you go, Thomas.
Thanks.
This is ridiculous.
Let's go someplace and talk, O.K.?
All right. If you want to.
How do you land these things?
Lots of people get divorced.
Doesn't mean they disappear.
You're right.
After that, I went kind of crazy...
for a long time.
I did come to see you a couple
of times. You remember?
No.
Not really.
It wasn't very easy.
She and Donald happened so quickly.
I missed you terribly.
I thought I should stay away
until your mother got settled.
That's not the truth.
I missed you, but I was still crazy.
We got married so young.
All that freedom went to my head.
Then you moved to New Jersey.
It's 40 minutes away on a slow bus.
You're right.
Not too many excuses
for the first year.
The second, it's easier.
I was in jail.
What for?
I was working for the government
doing big contracts.
There's a lot of money in that...
and a lot of temptations.
My boss asked me to juggle
a couple of papers.
I did, and I got caught,
and I had to testify against him.
It was like killing somebody.
Well, Thomas wanted
to visit you in jail,
but mom wouldn't let him.
You did?
We didn't even know
when you got out.
I wasn't in great shape,
and I didn't want you
to see me like that.
I went back to work in real estate
with this guy I met in jail.
He's a good guy.
He's a good man, really.
He's my partner,
but he's also my friend.
What about your girlfriend?
Anna...
Oh...
She's nice.
She can't wait to see you guys.
She likes flowers.
Well, you know that.
Monday she'll probably kill me.
So you haven't been
staying away because of us?
What do you mean?
Is that what you think,
I was avoiding you two?
You mustn't think that, all right?
That's terrible, uh...
I left you two, didn't I?
I left you all alone.
We weren't all alone.
The rain stopped. You want to go?
I didn't leave
because it was two days
before your swimming test.
It was just a day
your mother and I decided.
But you weren't there.
I'm sorry.
It doesn't matter.
It's all right.
How'd you do?
I passed.
I'm a lifesaver now.
Thomas, come on!
We're going to have a barbecue.
Betsy said I could have steak.
Hurry up, Tom.
Not supposed to call him Tom.
I'm allowed.
You are?
Always so far away.
How can I get to him?
It's easy.
All he wants is a hug.
No. That's not all.
He's been talking about it all week.
When he was little,
you'd squeeze him so hard
he couldn't breathe.
He said, "I bet dad'll do it
when he comes to pick us up...
on Friday."
When your mother and I split up,
She said,
"Don't lose the children."
Didn't mean much at the time.
She was right.
Who said I'd let you eat a steak?
I thought I could get that by you.
Hey, sport.
Look what I found.
This is pretty neat.
[together] What is it?
Keep it.
Yeah, thanks.
It was nice talking to you, finally.
Mmm, me, too.
She was sitting behind me.
This incredible perfume.
I'd been in jail nearly two years
with 400 sweating males.
She got off the train,
and I followed her.
That's how good she is.
She listened to a bum who
followed her off the train.
I guess I'm lucky with women.
[chuckles] I should say.
Mom, Anna...
You.
Well, I might not be such a pushover.
Yeah?
No, it's mostly roses.
The azaleas go all the
way around the outside.
$12 each? Make it 32.
Two dozen.
What are eight more roses going to do?
Biggest basket you have.
Must be delivered tonight.
It says, "A lifetime of love
from Stasia, Andros."
Dad, your credit card.
They need the credit card.
Just get it.
Hurry up.
"Melanie, little Melanie,
Alex, little Alex--"
I thought he was taller.
It's been a while. You're bigger.
I guess so.
He has gotten fat, though.
Think of all the junk he must eat.
Bet I could beat him
at the front crawl now.
So, with his family
and warmed by
the very thought of a fire
he'd built for himself,
the man seemed to feel
something in his heart ease.
What was it?
He looked out on the world,
the only one he would ever know,
and wondered.
Dad!
The boat's stuck!
It's filled with water!
I can't move!
Help! Help!
Come on in, Thomas! That's not safe.
I just found you.
I don't want to lose you.
Your mother would kill me.
Throw me the rope. Throw it!
That's one useless piece of rope.
[laughing]
Come on.
Oh...
Why does it always go so fast?
Just when I'm ready to
put the sun in, it's gone.
Hurry up, dad. I'm still wet.
Huh?
She even gets angry at the sun.
What chance do we have?
I used to know how to do this.
Oh, yeah?
I was really good at this.
Come on.
That's the smell of civilization--
scorched meat.
You can have a steak.
I'll have a piece of chicken.
Have some meat.
O.K.
I forgot that--how he eats,
how dedicated he is.
It's like his religion.
Things I like.
You used to hum while you ate,
like everything
was fine in the world.
I forgot about that.
It feels good.
[humming]
The weekend's turning out fine.
Relax.
I am.
I will.
Yeah.
Hey, Thomas, look.
There's old Mercury.
Remember?
We used to watch stars.
You could name all the planets.
You could recite them like in a poem.
You'd sit up in that little window.
You remember?
No.
And that's Saturn.
Sorry.
Glad you kept up with your astronomy.
That's real good.
I'm not into stargazing so much.
At school,
we're working on a computer
model of a biosphere
for deep space travel.
Everything's going to be O.K.
What do you mean, "going to be"?
This is it.
What?
This is as good as it gets.
This might be the best
moment of your life.
How much better do you want it?
Not much.
Enjoy it.
Thanks for the tip.
I will.
But they say the universe
might be like a piece of string
with the ends in a knot,
so infinity isn't really infinity.
When did he become Einstein?
Be quiet, Einstein.
Come up here. Your dad
wants to hug you to death.
That's been a while.
Wait till I finish my chicken.
I'm almost done.
You're amazing.
You'll get used to it.
Hey, Thomas,
don't worry about infinity.
Know what that is out there?
A big black sheet with holes
poked in it to let light through.
That's the latest.
That's what I heard.
The whole universe
is inside a speck of dust
in a ball of fluff
in the cuff of a pair of pants
hanging over the back of a chair.
That's not it.
You know what it is really?
The whole thing is
actually stars, planets.
Everything is on the skin
of a bubble of milk
that's about to pop.
It's in a bowl of cornflakes
that someone's about to eat.
Skim milk.
You don't get bubbles on skim milk.
Don't be so logical.
Don't be so unscientific.
I finished my chicken.
[Thomas giggling]
Whoa!
Don't squeeze him so hard
he can't breathe.
See? Come here. Sit down.
I've got a better one.
Well, we're all inside
a speck of pollen
stuck to the wing of a bee.
That's good.
The bee's sitting on a flower.
Don't mention flowers,
Betsy, please. O.k.?
Sorry.
It's all right.