[Script Info]
; Script generated by Aegisub 3.0.2
; http://www.aegisub.org/
Title: Default Aegisub file
Original Script: pyro
Update Details: 
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayDepth: 0
Timer: 100,0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,Arial,19,&H00FFFFFF,&H000000FF,&H00000000,&H00000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,2,2,2,10,20,20,0

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Name, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:00:31.80,0:00:56.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,
Dialogue: 0,0:01:01.80,0:01:06.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey brother,it's for you, score a goal
Dialogue: 0,0:01:09.40,0:01:13.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<font color="#808080">ZANA:</font> Hey brother,\NCome on, come on..
Dialogue: 0,0:01:15.47,0:01:17.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey,why did you do this to my brother?
Dialogue: 0,0:01:17.30,0:01:20.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, don't let them score
Dialogue: 0,0:01:20.14,0:01:21.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, don't let them..
Dialogue: 0,0:01:21.00,0:01:24.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother..don't worry ,\NI won't let them score..
Dialogue: 0,0:01:25.00,0:01:27.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, i don't let them score..
Dialogue: 0,0:01:27.00,0:01:29.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, i don't let them score..
Dialogue: 0,0:01:43.75,0:01:44.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, i didn't let them score..
Dialogue: 0,0:01:44.70,0:01:46.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I didn't, i didn't
Dialogue: 0,0:01:46.50,0:01:48.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Well done, my brother
Dialogue: 0,0:01:48.50,0:01:50.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother..i caught the ball,\Ni didn't let them score
Dialogue: 0,0:01:51.88,0:01:52.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What did you do?
Dialogue: 0,0:01:53.10,0:01:54.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<font color="#808080">KID:</font> I scored a goal
Dialogue: 0,0:01:59.50,0:02:00.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Idiot, why didn't you take the ball?
Dialogue: 0,0:02:00.80,0:02:02.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It was not my fault, they cheated..
Dialogue: 0,0:02:02.80,0:02:04.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<font color="#808080">ALL:</font> Superman is on...superman is on..
Dialogue: 0,0:02:04.80,0:02:06.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman is on...superman is on..
Dialogue: 0,0:02:06.80,0:02:08.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman is on...superman is on..
Dialogue: 0,0:02:10.40,0:02:12.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother..superman is here
Dialogue: 0,0:02:24.80,0:02:26.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}  <font color="#808080">HOMLESS:</font>
Dialogue: 0,0:02:26.80,0:02:28.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8} Translated by   <font color="#800000">> Shakir Abstract <</font>
Dialogue: 0,0:02:28.80,0:02:31.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8} Timing by   <font color="#0000FF">> [ PYRO ] <</font>
Dialogue: 0,0:02:32.40,0:02:33.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't move
Dialogue: 0,0:02:33.20,0:02:35.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080">ALL:</font> Superman..superman
Dialogue: 0,0:02:36.80,0:02:38.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Sit down idiot
Dialogue: 0,0:02:45.76,0:02:46.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mister, move the car
Dialogue: 0,0:02:46.90,0:02:48.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go away, go away..i have things to do
Dialogue: 0,0:02:48.30,0:02:50.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mister, Superman is displayed..move.
Dialogue: 0,0:02:50.10,0:02:52.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman and bullshit..go away
Dialogue: 0,0:02:53.45,0:02:54.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing?
Dialogue: 0,0:02:54.70,0:02:56.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> DRIVER :</font> Who the hell's sons are these?
Dialogue: 0,0:02:56.70,0:02:58.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Just wait for what I am\NGoing to do to you
Dialogue: 0,0:03:02.00,0:03:04.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ANNOUNCER:</font> Superman is on..the ticket is 1 dinar.
Dialogue: 0,0:03:04.70,0:03:06.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ANNOUNCER:</font> Come on..don't miss it
Dialogue: 0,0:03:07.70,0:03:09.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman superman
Dialogue: 0,0:03:13.40,0:03:15.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman superman
Dialogue: 0,0:03:16.50,0:03:18.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother...\NDo we have two dinars?
Dialogue: 0,0:03:18.40,0:03:20.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on,\NWhat are you talking about?
Dialogue: 0,0:03:20.40,0:03:22.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman is on..the ticket is 1 dinar.
Dialogue: 0,0:03:22.40,0:03:23.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on..
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.25,0:03:27.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, stop.
Dialogue: 0,0:03:28.70,0:03:29.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Climb up
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.70,0:03:34.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come back
Dialogue: 0,0:03:34.65,0:03:35.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come back, idiot
Dialogue: 0,0:03:36.72,0:03:37.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Did I tell you to get in there?
Dialogue: 0,0:03:38.39,0:03:39.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:03:39.60,0:03:40.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hahaha
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.00,0:04:28.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come here\NCome down .. come down
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.00,0:04:30.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing here?
Dialogue: 0,0:04:30.00,0:04:31.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing here?
Dialogue: 0,0:04:32.00,0:04:34.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey brother, please help me....
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.00,0:04:36.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, please help me.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:36.00,0:04:38.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Let me go.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:38.00,0:04:40.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Please don't beat him uncle.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.00,0:04:42.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Get away
Dialogue: 0,0:04:42.00,0:04:44.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Do you want to be thrown down there?
Dialogue: 0,0:04:44.00,0:04:46.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No please.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:46.00,0:04:47.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't come back again
Dialogue: 0,0:04:48.00,0:04:49.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother?
Dialogue: 0,0:04:49.40,0:04:49.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,GO
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.40,0:04:52.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't come back here, Bastards
Dialogue: 0,0:04:57.40,0:04:58.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Enough with you..be rational.
Dialogue: 0,0:04:58.40,0:05:00.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why should i?\N-And what do you want ?
Dialogue: 0,0:05:00.40,0:05:02.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I want to go back...and punch him in his mouth.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:02.70,0:05:04.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why didn't you punch him back there?
Dialogue: 0,0:05:04.70,0:05:05.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Because he terrified  me.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:11.40,0:05:14.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If our father was here,\NNo one could have hit us.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:26.28,0:05:29.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey brother..Superman was like this.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.64,0:05:45.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, what are you looking at?\NAmerica
Dialogue: 0,0:05:47.36,0:05:51.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Who's America? - America is a big city, \NSuperman lives there
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.76,0:05:55.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,There are lots of tall buildings..\NThey are tall enough to the moon.
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.84,0:06:01.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, how do you know these things?\NIdiot ..I have studied English..English
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.68,0:06:07.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,AH, brother..I also know America..\NSuperman lives there.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:07.48,0:06:12.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Well said my brother... Superman speaks American\NNow on, We both have to live there
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.00,0:06:25.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Where are you going?\NI'm going to bring bread and water
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.28,0:06:25.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why?
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.56,0:06:27.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Because America is far,
Dialogue: 0,0:06:27.56,0:06:31.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And you said we are going there\NIdiot.. We can't go like this.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:31.20,0:06:35.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why? nobody is there\NIdiot .. We don't have passports.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:40.68,0:06:44.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother. what is a passport?\NPassport is a small copybook
Dialogue: 0,0:06:44.68,0:06:47.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Containing your picture your name, \NYour father's name and your age .
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.96,0:06:52.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But We don't have a father.\NIn this case only your name would be written.
Dialogue: 0,0:06:52.24,0:06:54.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Let's go.
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.88,0:07:32.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hi\NHello,how are you?
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.26,0:07:35.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Is Baba Khalid here?\NNo, He went outside
Dialogue: 0,0:07:36.84,0:07:39.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Are you here for your stuffs?\NYes
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.08,0:07:47.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, damn it
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.92,0:08:06.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Goodbye, Mr. Ismael.\NGoodbye, Mr. Ismael.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.28,0:08:08.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Goodbye, boys.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:10.36,0:08:13.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey folks,come here! I'll shine your shoes!
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.96,0:08:16.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I shine your shoes!
Dialogue: 0,0:08:16.88,0:08:21.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I can shine shoes very good,\NI'll make your shoes shine like a mirror.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:21.28,0:08:24.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, Hey folks!\N Come here!
Dialogue: 0,0:08:29.12,0:08:32.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mister, aren't you ashamed that your shoes that dirty?
Dialogue: 0,0:08:32.16,0:08:34.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you were in America \NThe people would have made fun of you.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.92,0:08:37.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you talking about?\NWhy are you embarrassing me in front of these people?
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.70,0:08:40.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And do you have honor? \NYou can't mislead me.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:40.89,0:08:43.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on.. I'll make a man out of you for one Dinar.\N-What did you say?
Dialogue: 0,0:08:43.32,0:08:46.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I said for one dinar, \NI'll make your shoes look like a man's shoes.
Dialogue: 0,0:08:46.32,0:08:46.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I thought so
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.00,0:08:56.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Clean these for me.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.00,0:09:10.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, brother it's disgraceful..\NStop looking at her.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:15.18,0:09:20.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother, stop looking at her.\N-You just mind you own business.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:29.35,0:09:34.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey folks, come here! \NLet me clean your shoes folks!
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.18,0:09:37.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Shut up!  \NYou blew up my mind! Shut up!
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.20,0:09:43.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey folks, come here! \NLet me clean your shoes folks!
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.64,0:09:46.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey folks, come here! \NLet me clean your shoes folks!
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.32,0:09:48.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Here you go
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.72,0:09:56.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey professor, this is half a dinar! \NWe clean each shoe for a dinar.
Dialogue: 0,0:09:56.64,0:09:59.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> DANA:</font> Let it go.\N <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> Illiterate !
Dialogue: 0,0:10:10.00,0:10:14.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Nowadays, People buy passports.. \Nat very high costs in order to go abroad.
Dialogue: 0,0:10:14.29,0:10:18.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And the smugglers do it all in Baghdad.\N <font color="#808080"> DANA:</font>  Mister?
Dialogue: 0,0:10:18.36,0:10:21.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080">MAN:</font> Yes, son?\N <font color="#808080"> DANA:</font>  How much is a passport?
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.30,0:10:25.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080">MAN:</font>  What do you want a passport for, son?\N <font color="#808080">DANA:</font>  I and my brother want to go to America
Dialogue: 0,0:10:25.48,0:10:30.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\1c&H808080&\1a&H00&}MAN:{\1c&H000000&\1a&H00&} Son, a passport costs more than 7 or 8 thousand dinars, \NGo away, go away, stay away from here.
Dialogue: 0,0:10:34.66,0:10:38.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother what should we do now?\N{\1c&H808080&\1a&H00&}DANA:{\1c&H000000&\1a&H00&}  We'll work.
Dialogue: 0,0:10:38.48,0:10:42.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,7000 for me, and 7000 for you, how much is that?
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.16,0:10:44.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,14000
Dialogue: 0,0:10:45.10,0:10:47.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,14,000?!! 14..
Dialogue: 0,0:10:47.44,0:10:50.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And how much shoes is that equal to?
Dialogue: 0,0:10:50.34,0:10:55.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I don't know, 30,000 to 40,000 thousands.\N-30,000 to 40,000
Dialogue: 0,0:10:58.00,0:10:59.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-14,000
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.30,0:11:07.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Take out the gum, it's god's house.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:07.36,0:11:11.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,For each time you've slapped me, \NIf you were given a dinar, \NWe were millionaires by now.
Dialogue: 0,0:11:59.42,0:12:01.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> MULLAH:</font> Allahu Akbar!
Dialogue: 0,0:12:05.88,0:12:08.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> MULLAH:</font> Allahu Akbar!
Dialogue: 0,0:12:11.22,0:12:13.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> MULLAH:</font>  Allahu Akbar!
Dialogue: 0,0:12:46.50,0:12:50.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font>  Dear god, \NPlease help me and my brother.. \Nto go to America to see Superman.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:50.58,0:12:55.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And send all the dirty shoes.. \Nto us in order to get money.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:55.44,0:12:57.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And ask for one million dinar too.
Dialogue: 0,0:12:57.68,0:13:00.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Didn't Baba Khalid said \NWe shouldn't ask for money from god..
Dialogue: 0,0:13:00.40,0:13:03.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Otherwise he would take back everything we have?
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.10,0:13:05.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Idiot,what will you lose?  \NYou don't have anything.
Dialogue: 0,0:13:05.40,0:13:08.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ask for anything you want. \NAnd ask for some passports as well !
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.56,0:13:16.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dear god, forgive my brother, \NHe's a little confused today.
Dialogue: 0,0:13:22.22,0:13:26.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, let's do it quietly . \NSo that he wouldn't suspect us, OK
Dialogue: 0,0:13:39.28,0:13:41.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> BABA KHALID:</font>  Zana , Is that you?
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.56,0:13:43.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, Baba Khalid, it's not us\N-No, it's you.
Dialogue: 0,0:13:44.40,0:13:48.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come here Zana..give me a kiss my sweet son.
Dialogue: 0,0:13:48.00,0:13:51.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes, Baba Khalid, it's us.
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.46,0:13:56.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go ahead Baba Khalid ,sit down.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:04.20,0:14:06.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dana!\NYes, Baba Khalid
Dialogue: 0,0:14:06.26,0:14:10.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Your brother stinks\N-You have to help him to shower.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:11.16,0:14:14.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana. don't take off your clothes here, \NThe smell is gonna blind me.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.28,0:14:17.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid, don't you need anything?
Dialogue: 0,0:14:17.70,0:14:22.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, my heart. I just want you two to be happy.\NBaba Khalid, let me clean your shoes
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.00,0:14:28.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, I don't need cleaned shoes.\NAll the great men are wearing dirty old shoes.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.29,0:14:32.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid, I'm wearing dirty old shoes, too.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.00,0:14:36.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Son, you are my great hero, dear son.
Dialogue: 0,0:14:36.88,0:14:37.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> DANA:</font>  Zana
Dialogue: 0,0:14:38.30,0:14:41.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid, goodbye. \NI'll see you tomorrow
Dialogue: 0,0:14:41.50,0:14:44.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Goodbye, my dear sons, goodbye,\NWe'll see each other tomorrow.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:06.88,0:15:08.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come!
Dialogue: 0,0:15:11.50,0:15:13.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Take this, I'll come back now.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:15.34,0:15:19.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, come back, leave her alone, \NYou don't know anything about love!
Dialogue: 0,0:15:42.14,0:15:45.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> HELLIYA:</font>  Tell me how come you aren't tired.. \N of following me all this way?
Dialogue: 0,0:15:46.26,0:15:48.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If I were a singer, \NI'd sing you the best song ever.
Dialogue: 0,0:15:48.88,0:15:51.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What do you see \NWhen you look at me?
Dialogue: 0,0:15:51.22,0:15:57.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,A garden. a big garden. full of lions and elephants. \NAnd there's monkeys, too.I'm there too.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:04.20,0:16:06.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What did you call me before?
Dialogue: 0,0:16:07.10,0:16:08.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<b><font color="#6698FF">Butterfly</font>
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.14,0:16:12.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Close your eyes!
Dialogue: 0,0:16:19.52,0:16:21.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you tell anybody about it \NI will kill you... understand?
Dialogue: 0,0:16:21.50,0:16:23.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, no. God's promise.. I will not tell anybody
Dialogue: 0,0:16:26.48,0:16:29.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dear god.. I got married.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:35.26,0:16:38.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dear uncle, It's finished\N-Welldone.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:39.58,0:16:42.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Thank god\N-Welldone.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.74,0:16:47.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, you don't have work this hard.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:52.14,0:16:54.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You don't knock at the door, \NI'll do it and I'll talk.
Dialogue: 0,0:16:54.50,0:16:59.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why? are you the governor?\NYes, I am. now you keep your mouth shut.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.10,0:17:07.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hello, salamu alayk. \NAuntie Begard how are you?
Dialogue: 0,0:17:07.37,0:17:09.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hello as well, how are you boys?
Dialogue: 0,0:17:09.34,0:17:11.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Can we again take two pails of water?
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.00,0:17:14.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'm going to bring it to you, \Nbut bring the vessels back soon.\N-Wait here.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:15.58,0:17:19.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ARI:</font> What the hell!! \NYou don't have money for the water you beggars?
Dialogue: 0,0:17:19.46,0:17:22.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You always have to come here for water?!
Dialogue: 0,0:17:25.52,0:17:28.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Here they are Bring them back soon, Ok. \NThank you very much.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:28.26,0:17:32.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ari, \NAzad told uncle Ali \Nthat you have stolen apples from him again.
Dialogue: 0,0:17:32.40,0:17:35.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ari, is that true?\N-How many time did I tell you not to steal?
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.84,0:17:40.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,How many times should I  apologize to Mr. Ali ?\NJust wait, when your father comes home!
Dialogue: 0,0:18:11.10,0:18:13.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,How many times did i tell you not to... \N put your feet into the water at first?
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.40,0:18:15.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, 7 times\NAnd what did I tell you to do at first?
Dialogue: 0,0:18:15.76,0:18:17.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You said at first we should spray our bodies with the water
Dialogue: 0,0:18:17.10,0:18:20.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And we will not put our feet into the pail so that the water wouldn't be wasted.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:27.18,0:18:30.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, when will you think we get to Superman?
Dialogue: 0,0:18:31.26,0:18:35.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I don't know Zana\NKaka,can I buy a gift for Superman?
Dialogue: 0,0:18:35.00,0:18:39.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Idiot, what are you going to give him, \NHe has everything ,he's not like us.
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.26,0:18:43.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And Kaka, does he have a father?\NYes, his name is Superpapa.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:03.80,0:19:08.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I swear when i go back \NI will tell my father to smack his face.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.20,0:19:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go away, leave us alone, all  boys are evil\N-Why, what has happened?
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.72,0:19:16.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Azad took Helliya's golden necklace \NAnd threw it from the tree into the lake.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:16.38,0:19:17.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why did he do that?
Dialogue: 0,0:19:20.00,0:19:22.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go to Baba Khalid's shop.. I'll return now\NWhat !! where are you going?
Dialogue: 0,0:19:22.85,0:19:24.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You don't involve, I'll tell you later.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:24.06,0:19:27.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, if you don't come back safe, \NI'll break somebody's face.
Dialogue: 0,0:19:29.00,0:19:30.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You, come here !!
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.00,0:19:38.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ARI:</font> One day, I will catch you! \N <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> -In your dreams
Dialogue: 0,0:19:43.74,0:19:45.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Salamu alayk\N <font color="#808080"> OWNER:</font> Wa alayku salam
Dialogue: 0,0:19:46.00,0:19:51.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Do you have a copybook this size? \N <font color="#808080"> OWNER:</font> A small one? Yes
Dialogue: 0,0:19:57.04,0:20:01.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> COPYBOOK:</font> To Kaka Superman
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.42,0:20:08.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> WRITING:</font> Saddam Hussein.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:10.96,0:20:13.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> WRITING:</font> Ari.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:29.02,0:20:31.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why is that fierce face?
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.21,0:20:33.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dana just goes after this girl
Dialogue: 0,0:20:33.48,0:20:37.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Oh my son, \NSomeday you will go after a girl too.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.77,0:20:39.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Have you went after a girl too?
Dialogue: 0,0:20:39.00,0:20:44.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Son, the girl I went after.. \Nwas the most beautiful woman.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:46.10,0:20:49.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Daya xan? Daya xan has died !\NUnfortunately.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:49.88,0:20:53.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,When she gave birth to Karwan, she died.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.15,0:20:56.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Forgive me, but between you and me, I don't like him.
Dialogue: 0,0:20:56.90,0:21:00.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I know, he's my son. \NAnd he's an only child.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:00.67,0:21:02.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I love him.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:03.00,0:21:06.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid, you don't need him, \NYou have me and my brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:06.90,0:21:12.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ah, Zana. \NFirst you go outside and bring me 20 to 30 sticks
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.62,0:21:15.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Alright . I'm going to bring you the sticks.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:23.22,0:21:26.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid , \NIt really makes me happy when you call me son.
Dialogue: 0,0:21:26.56,0:21:30.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'm also happy to call you that, son!
Dialogue: 0,0:22:06.00,0:22:11.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> COUNTING:</font> 2,3,4.5,6
Dialogue: 0,0:22:11.18,0:22:14.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Help me!
Dialogue: 0,0:22:15.26,0:22:17.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Who is that?
Dialogue: 0,0:22:18.52,0:22:21.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on guys, this kid is drowning
Dialogue: 0,0:22:21.22,0:22:25.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Help\N-Is there anyone who can swim?
Dialogue: 0,0:22:25.10,0:22:27.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, I can't\N-What about you Hama?
Dialogue: 0,0:22:39.24,0:22:42.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,He's chocking Come on, pull it back
Dialogue: 0,0:22:48.90,0:22:52.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> MAN:</font> Is he alive?\N <font color="#808080"> ALL:</font>Yes He lives
Dialogue: 0,0:22:59.72,0:23:01.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Here it is, Bab Khalid.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:07.42,0:23:09.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana,\NYes?
Dialogue: 0,0:23:09.90,0:23:13.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Break this one into two pieces.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:13.00,0:23:14.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Alright.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:16.22,0:23:19.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid, I did it.\N-Very good
Dialogue: 0,0:23:20.18,0:23:26.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, this time break these altogether for me?
Dialogue: 0,0:23:26.90,0:23:28.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Alright
Dialogue: 0,0:23:34.86,0:23:36.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid, I can't.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:36.74,0:23:38.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ah, my son.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:40.00,0:23:47.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This is an example for family. \NIf a family is united, they will be strong.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:47.00,0:23:49.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,My son.
Dialogue: 0,0:23:49.44,0:23:54.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you and Dana are united, \NYou'll two be strong,
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.70,0:23:59.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If I and my son are united, we will be strong , too.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:22.56,0:24:24.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, my dear.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.44,0:24:27.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,One day a man came with a broken radio, I fixed it for him.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:27.80,0:24:32.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,He didn't have money \NHe left this watch instead.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:33.36,0:24:36.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And I'll give to you Zana. \N
Dialogue: 0,0:24:36.80,0:24:38.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Congratulations.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:38.80,0:24:43.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Thank you very much Baba Khalid\NCongratulation my dear son, It's for you.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:44.54,0:24:46.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Congratulations.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:48.28,0:24:53.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Thank you very much Baba Khalid\NBaba Khalid, I'm always your son
Dialogue: 0,0:24:53.18,0:24:57.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Of course darling, you are my son,\N Congratulations for the watch.
Dialogue: 0,0:24:57.99,0:25:01.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You are my son, Good bye
Dialogue: 0,0:25:08.44,0:25:12.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Laila, where's Helliya?\N <font color="#808080"> LAILA:</font> she's in the car, \NShe's going to America with her family
Dialogue: 0,0:25:17.16,0:25:21.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Helliya, please don't go.\NDon't go, please listen to me, don't go.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:21.76,0:25:23.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Please, do not go!
Dialogue: 0,0:25:24.10,0:25:26.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Helliya, do not go!
Dialogue: 0,0:25:26.12,0:25:30.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Wait, wait..look at this little devil..you broke the mirror.
Dialogue: 0,0:25:30.76,0:25:33.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why did you break the mirror of the car?
Dialogue: 0,0:25:33.44,0:25:35.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go,   Get out of here!
Dialogue: 0,0:25:35.58,0:25:38.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This belongs to Helliya
Dialogue: 0,0:25:38.80,0:25:41.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This belongs to Helliya, let me give it to her.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:54.40,0:26:59.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ahy ahy.. Mr. Ismael please put me down, please,\NMy whole body is in pain. put me down.
Dialogue: 0,0:26:59.88,0:27:03.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, you can not go there.\NIt's not good for you.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:03.44,0:27:05.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why? I'm just going to see Baba Khalid
Dialogue: 0,0:27:05.46,0:27:09.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana. you are still a kid. \Nyou don't understand these things.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:10.00,0:27:13.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Poor Zana, your Baba Khalid died too.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:20.56,0:27:23.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> SHOUTING:</font> Baba Khalid, please don't leave me.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:28.92,0:27:33.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid\NBaba Khalid ,please don't leave me.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:33.52,0:27:36.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid ,please don't leave me.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:36.99,0:27:40.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Baba Khalid ,please don't leave me.
Dialogue: 0,0:27:40.99,0:27:42.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> Baba Khalid
Dialogue: 0,0:27:43.09,0:27:45.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> Please don't leave me
Dialogue: 0,0:28:52.32,0:28:55.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, I'm sorry that I left you
Dialogue: 0,0:28:58.00,0:29:02.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I also loved Baba Khalid, \Nbut we have to continue...
Dialogue: 0,0:29:04.00,0:29:06.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,In order to go to America
Dialogue: 0,0:29:06.40,0:29:09.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What America!\Nwe can never go to America now
Dialogue: 0,0:29:09.56,0:29:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes, we can, \NI know everything about the road.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:13.82,0:29:16.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Look, I have the map too.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:24.82,0:29:25.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:26.54,0:29:31.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, we are here. \Nand America is...America
Dialogue: 0,0:29:32.80,0:29:36.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And this is America!
Dialogue: 0,0:29:37.00,0:29:40.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Trust me, it's not very far..
Dialogue: 0,0:29:40.40,0:29:43.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's only this far!
Dialogue: 0,0:29:48.24,0:29:51.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What the are you saying?!\N we don't have money or passports.
Dialogue: 0,0:29:51.59,0:29:53.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,How the hell we can go to America?
Dialogue: 0,0:29:53.44,0:29:56.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You are right, we don't have money
Dialogue: 0,0:29:57.58,0:29:59.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But we have this!
Dialogue: 0,0:30:00.78,0:30:04.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't bullshit me, \Nwhat is this piece of dirty cloth?!
Dialogue: 0,0:30:11.28,0:30:13.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ahh Kaka
Dialogue: 0,0:30:13.46,0:30:16.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We can buy superman with this.
Dialogue: 0,0:30:16.52,0:30:19.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,With the value of this  \Nwe will go to America.
Dialogue: 0,0:30:20.26,0:30:24.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And when we come back with Superman, \Nwe will everyone that superman is our friend
Dialogue: 0,0:30:25.00,0:30:28.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Sweet, hey people,
Dialogue: 0,0:30:28.19,0:30:33.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,One or two days from now, \Nwe will fly  in the sky of this place with Superman
Dialogue: 0,0:30:33.24,0:30:36.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey people, you hear me?
Dialogue: 0,0:30:40.20,0:30:44.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka , where did you get this necklace?\Nit doesn't matter Zana. i found it and that's all.
Dialogue: 0,0:30:44.99,0:30:48.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I wonder what a poor guy might have dropped it.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:09.14,0:31:10.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why did you do that?
Dialogue: 0,0:31:10.48,0:31:14.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I have always \Nwanted to have mother's picture in a pendant.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:22.20,0:31:23.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, I'm going inside, you stay here.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:23.98,0:31:25.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why am i not going inside too?
Dialogue: 0,0:31:25.30,0:31:29.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Because i said so. this is men's job. you are not a man.\N I am a small man!
Dialogue: 0,0:31:29.84,0:31:32.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Shut up! stay here and don't do anything.
Dialogue: 0,0:31:45.62,0:31:50.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle,...please..uncle\N  <font color="#808080"> MAN:</font> go away..i say go away
Dialogue: 0,0:31:52.92,0:32:00.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We will face lots of problems.. \Nat the border checkpoints tomorrow
Dialogue: 0,0:32:00.48,0:32:02.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's really a big problem
Dialogue: 0,0:32:12.54,0:32:14.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What do you want?
Dialogue: 0,0:32:17.42,0:32:20.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle...please!
Dialogue: 0,0:32:20.00,0:32:21.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I want to go to America with my brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:21.82,0:32:26.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> SMUGGLER:</font>America? great! \NI need moneydo you have money?
Dialogue: 0,0:32:28.84,0:32:31.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I have this
Dialogue: 0,0:32:45.34,0:32:48.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> KID:</font> You cheated !!\N  <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> I didn't cheat!\N <font color="#808080"> KID:</font>yes, you did
Dialogue: 0,0:32:48.46,0:32:52.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I swear if you don't give me back that marble, \NI'll call my older brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:32:55.16,0:32:57.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> KID:</font> I'll give  you this
Dialogue: 0,0:32:58.80,0:33:02.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This donkey?\N  <font color="#808080"> KID:</font> Yes it's a very good donkey
Dialogue: 0,0:33:14.52,0:33:17.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> KID</font> Trust me it's a good donkey,\N I know this very well
Dialogue: 0,0:33:17.52,0:33:19.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You shut up, I know everything
Dialogue: 0,0:33:36.24,0:33:38.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> KID:</font> Ok, deal\N  <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> deal
Dialogue: 0,0:33:40.12,0:33:42.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> SMUGGLER:</font> It's worth nothing. leave.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:48.10,0:33:51.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> Who's in the picture?\Nthis is my mother
Dialogue: 0,0:33:51.19,0:33:54.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> SMUGGLER:</font> Does she know about this?\N No, uncle..my mother has died.
Dialogue: 0,0:33:54.20,0:33:56.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's just me and my brother
Dialogue: 0,0:33:56.46,0:34:00.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> What was your mother's name?\N Khadijaja
Dialogue: 0,0:34:00.70,0:34:03.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> Was your father's name Khasraw?
Dialogue: 0,0:34:04.64,0:34:07.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> Are you Dana, their first son?
Dialogue: 0,0:34:07.90,0:34:10.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes, uncle..but how do you know this?
Dialogue: 0,0:34:11.60,0:34:14.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> Me and your father were.. \N with each other in the war
Dialogue: 0,0:34:14.05,0:34:17.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> He showed me your picture a lot.. \N when you were little
Dialogue: 0,0:34:17.47,0:34:21.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OSMAN:</font> Your father saved my life..\N take this, I'll take you to America.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:21.80,0:34:25.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> SMUGGLER:</font> Osaman ..I don't care about this. the road is dangerous..
Dialogue: 0,0:34:25.79,0:34:28.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,and i have a family with \N 3 to 4 other people with me.
Dialogue: 0,0:34:28.20,0:34:30.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I don't take two children with me, understand?
Dialogue: 0,0:34:30.86,0:34:34.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Here it is,, now get lost, go away, go
Dialogue: 0,0:34:36.26,0:34:36.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go
Dialogue: 0,0:34:41.88,0:34:45.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> KID 1:</font> Where are you going?\NAmerica
Dialogue: 0,0:34:45.10,0:34:48.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> KID 2:</font> Who's America?\N America is a very big city,
Dialogue: 0,0:34:48.36,0:34:52.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Superman lives there\N <font color="#808080"> KID 1:</font> Who's superman? is he a turk?
Dialogue: 0,0:34:52.08,0:34:56.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,The turks can't fly....\N Superman can fly and he's number one.
Dialogue: 0,0:35:00.16,0:35:04.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing over this donkey?\NIt is not a donkey, this is Michael Jackson, \NI I have named him.
Dialogue: 0,0:35:04.70,0:35:08.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Get down,,come here..come\N-Uncle..please don't hit my brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:35:08.92,0:35:12.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> What are you doing over my donkey?\N-I won it in marbling
Dialogue: 0,0:35:12.26,0:35:15.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Marbling and bullshit!!\N-Don't hit my brother, please
Dialogue: 0,0:35:15.26,0:35:18.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> My brother is a donkey, \N  <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Get off Now this is your donkey?\N <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> Yes
Dialogue: 0,0:35:18.76,0:35:21.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle..please
Dialogue: 0,0:35:28.10,0:35:32.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> If i see you here again, \NI'll break all the bones in your bodies.
Dialogue: 0,0:35:33.46,0:35:36.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, did you sell mother's necklace?\N-yes
Dialogue: 0,0:35:36.38,0:35:41.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Really,? how much did you get for it?\N-two tickets,,,\Nfor you and me to go to America
Dialogue: 0,0:35:41.66,0:35:44.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Only two tickets!..\NHe should have given you.. \Na thousand dinars as well
Dialogue: 0,0:35:44.48,0:35:47.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Would you shut up!..\NThat worthless necklace!,,,\NThey didn't even want it
Dialogue: 0,0:35:47.58,0:35:50.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We'll be stuck here forever...\NThese two eyes will never see America
Dialogue: 0,0:35:50.90,0:35:54.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Screw all of them,,,,\NWe'll go to America by ourselves
Dialogue: 0,0:35:54.45,0:35:56.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,How? have you ever thought about anyway?
Dialogue: 0,0:35:56.09,0:36:00.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Didn't you say America is only this far? \NWe'll go on foot then.
Dialogue: 0,0:36:01.46,0:36:05.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana,,,a good thing came to my my mind, \NWe will not go on foot..\N Come with me.
Dialogue: 0,0:36:15.28,0:36:19.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Michael, my heart.\N Zana wait here till I find the old man
Dialogue: 0,0:36:20.48,0:36:23.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#6698FF">\N[ FOR SALE ] </font>
Dialogue: 0,0:36:25.34,0:36:28.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dear Michael.
Dialogue: 0,0:36:30.28,0:36:35.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Little evil,, quick... come on.. \NGive my shoe back.
Dialogue: 0,0:36:35.24,0:36:38.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Please don't hit me uncle..\N-Didn't i tell you not to come here?
Dialogue: 0,0:36:38.16,0:36:44.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle, i swear it was not my idea..\NIt was my brother's ..\N I reminded him of something.
Dialogue: 0,0:36:44.68,0:36:48.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,So, you have come with your bigger brother  \NTo steal my donkey? isn't?
Dialogue: 0,0:36:48.76,0:36:52.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No..we don't steal it this time\N-We don't steal it by god!
Dialogue: 0,0:36:52.14,0:36:54.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Are you in love with  it?\N-Yes uncle
Dialogue: 0,0:36:54.90,0:36:58.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Idiot You fall in love with a donkey?\N-No..i have not.
Dialogue: 0,0:36:58.69,0:37:01.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle..please don't hit my brother, \NWe are here to buy the donkey
Dialogue: 0,0:37:01.48,0:37:04.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka! are we here to buy Michael?
Dialogue: 0,0:37:04.34,0:37:06.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You are here to buy my donkey?
Dialogue: 0,0:37:06.95,0:37:08.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes..it'll take us to America\N-America!
Dialogue: 0,0:37:08.90,0:37:10.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka we go to America with Michael?
Dialogue: 0,0:37:11.04,0:37:13.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes, uncle you sell it or not?
Dialogue: 0,0:37:14.26,0:37:15.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you are going buy it..\NYou must not call it a donkey!
Dialogue: 0,0:37:16.36,0:37:18.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Only stupid people call it a donkey...
Dialogue: 0,0:37:18.60,0:37:21.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This is a longed ear animal.. \N Calling it a donkey is offensive..
Dialogue: 0,0:37:21.45,0:37:24.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle..I've already changed his name to..\N  Michael Jackson
Dialogue: 0,0:37:24.40,0:37:27.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Nonsense ..Michael Jackson!
Dialogue: 0,0:37:27.30,0:37:30.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle..we are sorry..\NWe are here to buy your longed ears animal..
Dialogue: 0,0:37:30.55,0:37:33.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And forgive us for calling it a donkey before.\NBut please sell it to us.
Dialogue: 0,0:37:33.76,0:37:36.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We've been together for a long time..
Dialogue: 0,0:37:36.13,0:37:38.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We are friends. we love each other..
Dialogue: 0,0:37:38.79,0:37:43.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,He's intelligent, mute, obedient..
Dialogue: 0,0:37:43.30,0:37:46.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But i don't think you can afford buying him
Dialogue: 0,0:37:53.82,0:37:55.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Give me whatever you have with you.
Dialogue: 0,0:37:58.00,0:38:01.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle, I don't know how much that is but.. \N That is all we got..
Dialogue: 0,0:38:01.10,0:38:05.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We need him, \NIt's better you sell it to us.. \N rather than someone steal it from you
Dialogue: 0,0:38:17.28,0:38:20.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This is for you.\N- Thank you very much, Uncle!
Dialogue: 0,0:38:20.50,0:38:24.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I sell him to you, \NBut you must take care of him..
Dialogue: 0,0:38:24.57,0:38:27.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't hurt him, don't let him get hungry..\N Now good-bye to you.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:27.32,0:38:30.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Thank you, Uncle!\N- -ok ..ok.. let go of me..\N People are watching us.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:32.44,0:38:34.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Slow down Michael!
Dialogue: 0,0:38:35.92,0:38:37.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Goodbye.\NGoodbye.
Dialogue: 0,0:38:37.75,0:38:41.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Take care of him\N-Ok
Dialogue: 0,0:38:41.52,0:38:45.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dear God..take care of these kids, \NProtect them please..
Dialogue: 0,0:38:57.28,0:39:00.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka. which way is America?
Dialogue: 0,0:39:28.20,0:39:32.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana..from there..straight forward\N-Ok
Dialogue: 0,0:39:35.38,0:39:39.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, we can't go\N-What Zana! you want me to hit you again?
Dialogue: 0,0:39:39.39,0:39:43.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, what about our parents?!, \Nhow can we leave them all alone in the graveyard...
Dialogue: 0,0:39:43.04,0:39:45.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,for the sake of superman and America!!
Dialogue: 0,0:39:51.00,0:39:53.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Idiot, \NYou'll never understand! Superman is very brave..
Dialogue: 0,0:39:54.04,0:39:56.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,he can bring the dead back to life with a single touch !!
Dialogue: 0,0:39:56.56,0:39:58.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you want to live with our parents again, \N Get on..
Dialogue: 0,0:39:58.90,0:40:02.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, Superman is powerful enough..\N  to bring back our parents ?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:02.68,0:40:07.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Of course..that's why we bring him here..\Ni didn't want to tell you here..\N I wanted to keep it a surprise for you.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:07.45,0:40:10.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka you are very brave..you are number 1.
Dialogue: 0,0:40:11.88,0:40:16.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mom....DAD, \N I and Kaka are going to America to see Superman..
Dialogue: 0,0:40:16.76,0:40:18.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It takes one day only!
Dialogue: 0,0:40:18.57,0:40:21.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And then we will fly back with superman..
Dialogue: 0,0:40:21.15,0:40:25.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We will destroy Saddam .. \N and kick out all his soldiers..
Dialogue: 0,0:40:25.36,0:40:31.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka said Superman is brave enough \Nthat he can bring you two.. \N back to life with a single touch..
Dialogue: 0,0:40:44.00,0:40:48.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mom...Dad,\N  I swear I'll come back soon, Kaka said that..
Dialogue: 0,0:40:48.15,0:40:51.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Isn't Kaka?\N-yes, can we go now?
Dialogue: 0,0:40:55.46,0:40:58.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Thank you mister\N  <font color="#808080"> BAKER :</font>  You are very welcome
Dialogue: 0,0:41:04.14,0:41:07.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana..\N-yes\N <font color="#808080"> GROCER:</font>  This is for you
Dialogue: 0,0:41:07.68,0:41:10.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Thank you!!\N <font color="#808080"> GROCER:</font> No problem
Dialogue: 0,0:41:38.40,0:41:42.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ARI :</font> Zana..please take me with you too!
Dialogue: 0,0:41:42.64,0:41:46.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,When I came back with Superman, \N I'll take you all.
Dialogue: 0,0:42:38.69,0:42:40.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080">ZANA:</font> Kaka..will arrive America by tonight?
Dialogue: 0,0:42:40.82,0:42:46.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> DANA:</font> If we couldn't make it by tonight, \NWe'll make it by tomorrow, \NIf couldn't, \NWe certainly make it by the day after tomorrow.. \N OK Kaka.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:31.88,0:43:34.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka\N-yes
Dialogue: 0,0:43:34.98,0:43:40.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Is superman powerful enough to destroy all the bad people \Nand bring back all the good ones?
Dialogue: 0,0:43:40.03,0:43:43.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes.. he is.. \N And he's very brave and he can fly too.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:43.36,0:43:48.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, so why  doesn't he destroy Saddam? \Neveryone knows he's very bad with people \N And he has killed our parents too.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:48.70,0:43:51.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I don't know \Nmaybe he hasn't heard of Saddam
Dialogue: 0,0:43:51.80,0:43:55.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, i swear I'll tell Superman by myself.
Dialogue: 0,0:43:57.56,0:43:59.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, what is this notebook?
Dialogue: 0,0:43:59.42,0:44:00.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka i bought it...
Dialogue: 0,0:44:00.15,0:44:06.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I write the names of all those who treated me badly on it \NAnd I'll give it to superman.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:08.10,0:44:11.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, how did Superman become Superman?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:11.20,0:44:14.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,His father was superman\N-And does he speak Kurdish?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:14.28,0:44:17.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes, of course.. he's so brave..\NHe speaks in all the languages of the world!
Dialogue: 0,0:44:17.76,0:44:21.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kurdish , Chinese, Swedish  and Chinese.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:21.40,0:44:24.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, does Superman eat pork?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:24.79,0:44:28.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I don't know.. perhaps, \N  In America he does.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:28.00,0:44:32.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, if Superman has a child, \NDoes he become a Superman as well?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:32.25,0:44:34.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes, if it's a boy.\N-What if it's a girl?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:34.90,0:44:37.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Enough! you talked my ears off.
Dialogue: 0,0:44:48.70,0:44:52.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, look at all these Coca Cola, \Nthe whole world can live off of it !
Dialogue: 0,0:44:55.12,0:44:59.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, can we take some of it?\N-Zana, it's too dangerous, \N I'm afraid someone might catch us.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:03.72,0:45:09.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, Kaka. No one is around. \NOne for me, One for you, \N Tthat's all. OK?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:10.00,0:45:13.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But warn me if anyone came, Ok?\N-Ok, kaka. be careful
Dialogue: 0,0:45:20.40,0:45:22.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka?\N-What?
Dialogue: 0,0:45:22.40,0:45:25.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I can feel the taste.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:28.96,0:45:31.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana !\N-Kaka, Get off !
Dialogue: 0,0:45:34.32,0:45:36.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Michael, come on run
Dialogue: 0,0:45:36.76,0:45:39.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go after my brother, come on.
Dialogue: 0,0:45:40.04,0:45:42.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, Zana!
Dialogue: 0,0:45:42.92,0:45:46.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, come on!\NZana! I can't jump!
Dialogue: 0,0:45:49.36,0:45:51.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come here!
Dialogue: 0,0:45:53.60,0:45:57.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka\N-Zana
Dialogue: 0,0:46:11.60,0:46:12.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> HONKING:</font> Clear the street !
Dialogue: 0,0:46:14.00,0:46:17.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on Micheal..you gonna get hit, \Nstay off the street, come on
Dialogue: 0,0:46:19.62,0:46:23.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Didn't i tell to go after my brother?\N-why didn't you do it?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:23.64,0:46:27.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Now, we lost him. what should we do now?
Dialogue: 0,0:46:27.23,0:46:30.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You  brainless! you don't understand anything !
Dialogue: 0,0:46:35.20,0:46:40.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on, go after my brother.\N-come on, let's go after my brother, come on.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:21.66,0:47:23.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle, where are you headed to?
Dialogue: 0,0:47:23.90,0:47:26.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\1c&H808080&\1a&H00&}OLD MAN:{\1c&H000000&\1a&H00&} I'm headed to my brother's house in that village, \Nit's over there.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:26.34,0:47:28.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ok, let's tie up your wagon, \NI'm gonna get you there.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:31.34,0:47:34.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go  Michael.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:44.10,0:47:48.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> What about you son, where are you going?
Dialogue: 0,0:47:48.00,0:47:50.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Is the donkey your brother?\N-No, i've lost my brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:47:50.82,0:47:54.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Was he a key to be lost?\N-No, i haven't dropped him, i lost him, LOST !
Dialogue: 0,0:47:54.91,0:47:57.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>   Why did you lose him, \Nwere you gambling?
Dialogue: 0,0:47:57.90,0:48:02.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Oufffff. Uncle, \NHe got stuck in the back of a vehicle and he couldn't jump off.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:02.26,0:48:05.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> You said America, where's it?\N-it's over there.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:05.66,0:48:07.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,There?\N-yes.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:07.62,0:48:10.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> How do you know all these things ,son?\N-Because I've studied English.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:10.77,0:48:14.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> So, let's see you talking in English.\N-Hello mister, good...night...
Dialogue: 0,0:48:14.88,0:48:16.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,... Good sleep
Dialogue: 0,0:48:16.76,0:48:18.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- good... stop.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:18.40,0:48:21.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> You'll find your brother God willing.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:21.21,0:48:23.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,God willing?\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Yes, God willing.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:23.27,0:48:25.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle, \N So why did god take my brother away from me. \Nsince i don't have anybody..
Dialogue: 0,0:48:25.82,0:48:28.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,..I'm homeless and alone.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:28.00,0:48:32.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Son, you'll never be alone, \N God will always be with you..\N H has set a different path of life for any of us.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:32.34,0:48:34.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What path he has set for you?
Dialogue: 0,0:48:34.33,0:48:37.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> I'm advanced in years. \NHe has left me with a way to continue.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:37.40,0:48:39.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What's that way?
Dialogue: 0,0:48:47.58,0:48:53.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> It's end of the world !!. \NSatellite spreads immorality!.\NIt's all Saddam's fault.
Dialogue: 0,0:48:57.12,0:49:00.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And why are you watching it now?\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  I'm watching it from the back.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:00.43,0:49:04.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Does Saddam manufacture satellite?\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Yes, he manufactures it with the Chinese.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:04.07,0:49:06.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Wait , stop it . i have to pee.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:11.26,0:49:13.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  You have a beautiful donkey.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:13.82,0:49:17.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't call him a donkey again!..\Nthis is Michael Jackson.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:17.00,0:49:20.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Who the hell is Michael J..JJ..J Jackson.?
Dialogue: 0,0:49:21.72,0:49:23.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Who the hell is Michael Jackson?
Dialogue: 0,0:49:23.96,0:49:27.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,The one...the one who sings !
Dialogue: 0,0:49:29.42,0:49:31.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Is your donkey a singer?
Dialogue: 0,0:49:32.42,0:49:36.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Michael Jackson sings and dances on TV.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:36.72,0:49:39.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,He dances like that !
Dialogue: 0,0:49:39.80,0:49:43.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> What are you doing scamp?\N-I'm performing Michael Jackson's dance
Dialogue: 0,0:49:43.39,0:49:46.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Why do you have your hands on your balls.. ! \NGod sees everything.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:46.02,0:49:47.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Because he dances this way !
Dialogue: 0,0:49:47.70,0:49:51.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> You learnt this from satellite !...\Ni knew this satellite is evil.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:51.77,0:49:55.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Inshallah, God will help you to find your brother.
Dialogue: 0,0:49:56.58,0:49:59.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> But never buy this satellite! ok?
Dialogue: 0,0:50:00.10,0:50:04.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Look after your donkey, it's lovely.
Dialogue: 0,0:50:30.28,0:50:32.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-Uncle, this is my brother!\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Let's hope so.
Dialogue: 0,0:50:32.63,0:50:35.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I swear that's him, \Nwould you take this.
Dialogue: 0,0:50:36.18,0:50:40.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> YELLING :</font> Kaka....Kaka....Kaka\N-Kaka....Kaka....Kaka
Dialogue: 0,0:50:40.68,0:50:42.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana!
Dialogue: 0,0:50:42.40,0:50:46.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka....Kaka....Kaka
Dialogue: 0,0:50:46.92,0:50:50.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana! Zana! Zana!
Dialogue: 0,0:50:50.72,0:50:52.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka....Kaka....Kaka
Dialogue: 0,0:51:08.12,0:51:11.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Dear god, how mighty you are!\N-Dear god, how mighty you are!
Dialogue: 0,0:51:18.10,0:51:22.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You are international!\N -If you drink this, \N you will be international too.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:28.28,0:51:30.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What Zana?..don't you like it?
Dialogue: 0,0:51:30.88,0:51:33.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-I'm gonna keep half of it to that old man.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:33.90,0:51:36.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hello mister\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Hello to you and to mighty God.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:36.76,0:51:40.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-ok , let me sit over there.\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  OK
Dialogue: 0,0:51:41.50,0:51:44.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> what is it?\N  <font color="#808080"> ZANA:</font> Drink this.\N  <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> I don't
Dialogue: 0,0:51:44.56,0:51:47.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But you have to.\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  I don't\N-You drink it.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:47.26,0:51:51.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Let your brother drink it.\N-No, my brother has drank it already, \NYou drink it.it is yours.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:52.54,0:51:54.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on, Michael.
Dialogue: 0,0:51:56.94,0:51:58.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>  Hello mister
Dialogue: 0,0:51:58.60,0:52:01.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-Good morning.\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font>Good morning
Dialogue: 0,0:52:01.10,0:52:03.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,How are you?\N <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Thank yow
Dialogue: 0,0:52:04.10,0:52:06.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> ALL LAUGHING :</font>
Dialogue: 0,0:52:15.24,0:52:17.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Good bye.\N  <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Goodbye mister..
Dialogue: 0,0:52:17.76,0:52:21.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> God willing you'll make it to America.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:21.14,0:52:25.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> Say hello to America..\N I know what is he doing on satellite! ...
Dialogue: 0,0:52:25.00,0:52:27.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> OLD MAN:</font> God knows everything.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:38.54,0:52:41.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-Zana, wake up..i found a place.
Dialogue: 0,0:52:55.22,0:52:59.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Micheal, my sweet Michael, good night, \NWe will see each other again tomorrow.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:00.22,0:53:02.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come and sleep here...leave it alone
Dialogue: 0,0:53:02.48,0:53:06.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It would have been very nice..\N If Michael were able to speak.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:06.68,0:53:10.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It would have been very nice..\N If you were able to shut up for a minute.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:19.26,0:53:23.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What Michael ! what do you want?\N-Shut up, idiot!
Dialogue: 0,0:53:23.03,0:53:27.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You'll get us caught.\N-Michael made me to talk.
Dialogue: 0,0:53:27.03,0:53:30.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why! is your name  apshhhh au uuuuusha!?\N-yes kaka
Dialogue: 0,0:54:59.10,0:55:03.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle, would you clear the way for us..\N I and my brother are going to America.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:24.70,0:55:28.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> IN ARABIC:</font> Go away from here...\Nand never come back!
Dialogue: 0,0:55:29.60,0:55:32.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I swear I'll come back\N  <font color="#808080"> FIRST LIEUTENANT:</font> go away
Dialogue: 0,0:55:32.84,0:55:35.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> FIRST LIEUTENANT:</font> '' Going to America ''
Dialogue: 0,0:55:35.86,0:55:39.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> FIRST LIEUTENANT:</font> They are talking about America!!
Dialogue: 0,0:55:43.00,0:55:45.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle !\N <font color="#808080"> MAN:</font> what?
Dialogue: 0,0:55:45.72,0:55:48.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Is there any smugglers around here?
Dialogue: 0,0:55:51.28,0:55:53.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> MAN:</font>  Mr. Ali is inside, go talk to him.
Dialogue: 0,0:55:54.28,0:55:55.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#808080"> MAN:</font> Hurry up, what's this!
Dialogue: 0,0:56:14.00,0:56:16.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hello, Mr.Ali.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:18.24,0:56:21.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I and my brother want to go to America. \NCan you help us?
Dialogue: 0,0:56:26.26,0:56:28.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I will give you this.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:29.00,0:56:31.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It doesn't take you there.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:31.35,0:56:34.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Take us to where it can get us to...\N from there we'll make it to America.. \N by ourselves.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:34.22,0:56:37.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You will never make it by yourselves.\N-yes we can...
Dialogue: 0,0:56:37.19,0:56:40.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,...and we don't need you either.\N-good bye.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:40.57,0:56:43.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come...come here...come
Dialogue: 0,0:56:50.58,0:56:52.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You hit me too !
Dialogue: 0,0:56:52.48,0:56:54.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You want to go to America?
Dialogue: 0,0:56:54.46,0:56:55.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:55.79,0:56:58.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No matter how?\N-yes.
Dialogue: 0,0:56:58.25,0:57:03.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,There's only two ways\N-First one is, \N you have to hide yourself under one of the vehicles..
Dialogue: 0,0:57:03.00,0:57:06.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,.. that come out from the tobacco factory in the city..
Dialogue: 0,0:57:07.52,0:57:10.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But you have to be careful not to fall. \Notherwise you will die.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:10.63,0:57:14.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,because many people has died \N instantly as they fell, \Nand many get arrested at the borders.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:15.40,0:57:20.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Second one is..\NTomorrow morning I can take you with myself..  \N to the other side of the border..
Dialogue: 0,0:57:20.48,0:57:24.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And there I'll be done with you.\N-ok, take us.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:24.67,0:57:28.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ok..give me the necklace.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:28.50,0:57:31.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You will get it tomorrow morning, \Nand a long-ear will accompany us too.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:31.92,0:57:34.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,A long ear !?\N-a donkey.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:34.48,0:57:36.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Sell it off
Dialogue: 0,0:57:37.52,0:57:40.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Tomorrow morning at 7 \N be ready behind the tea house.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:40.52,0:57:44.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'll take you there with some other people.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:45.00,0:57:47.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Give me the necklace
Dialogue: 0,0:57:47.24,0:57:51.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, we have to sell Michael. \NI don't like it either. but we have to.
Dialogue: 0,0:57:53.00,0:57:58.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come over here..\NI have the best donkey ever...come on..
Dialogue: 0,0:57:58.04,0:58:01.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's international.\N-come folks!
Dialogue: 0,0:58:01.03,0:58:05.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come here for this young donkey, \Nit's very low-priced. come on..
Dialogue: 0,0:58:06.56,0:58:09.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I take it for 25 dinars.\N-are you an Arab?
Dialogue: 0,0:58:09.14,0:58:11.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What Arab!\N-it's like you are buying a sandal..
Dialogue: 0,0:58:11.64,0:58:14.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,..it's a donkey, if you want sandal, \Nit's there!.
Dialogue: 0,0:58:14.56,0:58:16.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I won't take it for more than 30 dinars.\N-you can go
Dialogue: 0,0:58:16.57,0:58:19.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's up to you.\N-Go buy your sandals
Dialogue: 0,0:58:21.36,0:58:24.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Boys, I will give you 40 dinars..
Dialogue: 0,0:58:24.33,0:58:27.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,..without any jokes and insult..\Notherwise I'll hit you
Dialogue: 0,0:58:28.00,0:58:32.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dear uncle, give me 50 dinars \N And i will kiss your both cheeks
Dialogue: 0,0:58:32.30,0:58:36.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I will give you 45 without \N kissing and stuff and come on, get off.
Dialogue: 0,0:58:36.24,0:58:39.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Here's your donkey \N and give the money to this boy
Dialogue: 0,0:58:39.52,0:58:42.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Here it's son. this is 30..
Dialogue: 0,0:58:42.32,0:58:46.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,..40 .. 44 .. 45. OK
Dialogue: 0,0:58:51.40,0:58:53.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I go now\N-God willing, \N it will be beneficial for you
Dialogue: 0,0:58:53.91,0:58:56.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Sweet Michael, Goodbye.
Dialogue: 0,0:59:23.52,0:59:26.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Helliya? Helliya?
Dialogue: 0,0:59:33.56,0:59:36.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing here?\N-I missed you so much Helliya
Dialogue: 0,0:59:36.67,0:59:41.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Didn't i tell you \N my father will kill you if he see you with me?\N-It's ok. but please let's talk for a minute. ok?
Dialogue: 0,0:59:41.68,0:59:45.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Helliya, where are you?\N-We stay at my auntie's house now..
Dialogue: 0,0:59:45.36,0:59:48.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's near the mosque, \N The number of the house is 13..
Dialogue: 0,0:59:48.78,0:59:52.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come there at around 6 and we can talk.\N-ok
Dialogue: 0,0:59:54.06,0:59:57.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka! where did you go?
Dialogue: 0,0:59:59.80,1:00:02.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, where were you?\N-i was upstairs
Dialogue: 0,1:00:02.45,1:00:05.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What were you doing there? \Nmy throat got ripped off shouting for you!\N  I turned into a donkey.
Dialogue: 0,1:00:06.00,1:00:09.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You sound like a girl\N-Whatever, \N because you are my brother.
Dialogue: 0,1:00:11.86,1:00:15.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ok Zana. \Nnow on  i will never go anywhere.. \N without letting you know.
Dialogue: 0,1:00:16.70,1:00:20.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Do you swear?\N-I swear !! \N why don't you come hit us a little too !?
Dialogue: 0,1:00:27.64,1:00:31.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't climb on people's walls...\N It's a shame!-get down
Dialogue: 0,1:00:32.18,1:00:35.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We will sleep on that roof?\N-That one?\N-Yes
Dialogue: 0,1:01:39.68,1:01:42.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka?\N-Kaka?
Dialogue: 0,1:01:51.20,1:01:53.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Where is your brother?\N-Isn't he here?
Dialogue: 0,1:01:53.20,1:01:56.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, i have not seen him, a\N And do you have the necklace with you?
Dialogue: 0,1:01:56.20,1:01:57.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, it's with my brother.
Dialogue: 0,1:01:57.91,1:02:01.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Without the necklace, \NI can't take any of you..understand?
Dialogue: 0,1:02:03.64,1:02:07.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Anyways...\N we will wait a little more until he shows up.
Dialogue: 0,1:02:14.24,1:02:18.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Helliya, \NI have never seen a beautiful girl like you before.
Dialogue: 0,1:02:22.40,1:02:25.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Helliya, close your eyes.
Dialogue: 0,1:02:37.14,1:02:39.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What time is it?\N-It's 7.
Dialogue: 0,1:02:39.39,1:02:42.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I have to go. if not so, \NI and my brother will not make it to America.
Dialogue: 0,1:02:42.89,1:02:45.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you talking about? \NWhat are you going to do in America?
Dialogue: 0,1:02:45.15,1:02:48.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Laila told me \NThat you go to America with your family too.
Dialogue: 0,1:02:51.68,1:02:54.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, i was just bragging about myself..
Dialogue: 0,1:02:54.92,1:02:58.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We moved to here.\N-My father teaches at a school around here
Dialogue: 0,1:02:58.96,1:03:01.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And neither of us will go to America...
Dialogue: 0,1:03:01.92,1:03:04.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We will see each other later.
Dialogue: 0,1:03:25.66,1:03:29.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It getting too late, \Ngive me the necklace \N and get on the car to go.
Dialogue: 0,1:03:29.20,1:03:32.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I don't have the necklace.\N-What?
Dialogue: 0,1:03:32.10,1:03:35.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Without the necklace, \NI will not take you...understand?
Dialogue: 0,1:03:35.45,1:03:39.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on... get on.. \N It's late.. let's go.
Dialogue: 0,1:03:42.00,1:03:45.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Would you tell me where's the necklace?\N-I gave it back to Helliya
Dialogue: 0,1:03:45.34,1:03:47.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What is Helliya doing here?
Dialogue: 0,1:03:47.56,1:03:51.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,She is living here with here family..\NI thought she went to America.
Dialogue: 0,1:03:51.67,1:03:57.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,So you wanted to live with.. \NHelliya in America not with our parents?
Dialogue: 0,1:03:57.24,1:04:01.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,That's why you want to go to America?!!\N-Listen, \N I want to stay and live with Helliya here
Dialogue: 0,1:04:01.25,1:04:04.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But didn't we promise.. \N that we will go to America to see Superman..
Dialogue: 0,1:04:04.12,1:04:06.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,in order to bring our parents back to life?
Dialogue: 0,1:04:06.24,1:04:08.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Try to understand, \NI want to live with Helliya here..\N understand it !
Dialogue: 0,1:04:10.60,1:04:12.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Do you understand?
Dialogue: 0,1:04:26.12,1:04:30.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Leave me alone..\Ndon't come to my sight again..\Nand don't follow me
Dialogue: 0,1:05:30.76,1:05:32.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#C11B17">\N[TOBACCO FACTORY ]</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:06:19.52,1:06:20.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, <font color="#C11B17">\N[TOBACCO FACTORY ]</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:06:25.72,1:06:29.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mister, where's the tobacco factory?\N-that way\N-thank you
Dialogue: 0,1:06:52.04,1:06:55.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother! Brother, help!
Dialogue: 0,1:06:55.76,1:07:01.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Brother! Brother, where are you?\NBrother, help me!
Dialogue: 0,1:07:45.46,1:07:49.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Hey uncle...what is that? \NWhat's leaking from your car?
Dialogue: 0,1:07:50.00,1:07:52.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's probably water from the ice-boxes
Dialogue: 0,1:07:52.52,1:07:56.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Are you sure it's nothing else?
Dialogue: 0,1:08:00.00,1:08:01.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Smell it.
Dialogue: 0,1:08:12.32,1:08:14.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,it tastes good...
Dialogue: 0,1:08:14.71,1:08:17.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,but fix it up uncle..fix it.
Dialogue: 0,1:08:19.00,1:08:21.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,come this way.
Dialogue: 0,1:08:41.20,1:08:43.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ahh uhhh
Dialogue: 0,1:09:31.56,1:09:34.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle !! Come!
Dialogue: 0,1:09:36.88,1:09:39.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What is that ?
Dialogue: 0,1:09:42.08,1:09:45.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-that's a metal plate.\N-it is a plate.\N-metal\N-ok..take it away
Dialogue: 0,1:09:47.16,1:09:50.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Done?\N-yes, it's done.\N-let's go.
Dialogue: 0,1:10:13.12,1:10:14.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana?
Dialogue: 0,1:10:14.92,1:10:17.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Are you here? Zana?
Dialogue: 0,1:10:27.32,1:10:29.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, are you here?
Dialogue: 0,1:10:30.04,1:10:32.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-I'm not gonna tell you
Dialogue: 0,1:10:32.80,1:10:34.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, is that you?
Dialogue: 0,1:10:37.28,1:10:41.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing here? \N I don't talk to you.. \Nand i don't go to America with you either.
Dialogue: 0,1:10:42.60,1:10:45.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, forgive me, \N  I know you are angry with  me.
Dialogue: 0,1:10:45.12,1:10:49.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But i regret everything \Nand i want to go to America with you.
Dialogue: 0,1:10:49.04,1:10:54.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you don't leave now, i will shout \Nand make every single soldier gather here.. \N  to take you and then kill you.
Dialogue: 0,1:10:54.57,1:10:56.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But they will kill you too!
Dialogue: 0,1:11:00.00,1:11:03.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, please forgive me,\N  I know you are angry
Dialogue: 0,1:11:03.32,1:11:08.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But if you forgive me, \N I will leave everything behind \Nand will never think about anything else
Dialogue: 0,1:11:10.52,1:11:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,But I want us to be together..  \N to go to America to see superman
Dialogue: 0,1:11:13.64,1:11:18.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you talking about? \Ni have written your name on the notebook. \Nand i'm gonna give it to superman.
Dialogue: 0,1:11:18.35,1:11:21.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And it's up to you if you want to come . \N your risk!.
Dialogue: 0,1:11:21.16,1:11:23.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,so what!  let's see him kill me.
Dialogue: 0,1:11:23.71,1:11:28.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,what are you talking about? \Nhe can make a hole in an iron with a single fist.
Dialogue: 0,1:11:34.24,1:11:36.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ok, let's get on it.\N-Ok
Dialogue: 0,1:11:37.28,1:11:39.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on, quick
Dialogue: 0,1:12:00.24,1:12:02.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, we are going to America.
Dialogue: 0,1:12:04.24,1:12:06.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We're going to America!
Dialogue: 0,1:12:08.64,1:12:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We are going to America.--\N we are going to America. to see superman
Dialogue: 0,1:12:15.08,1:12:18.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We're going to America!
Dialogue: 0,1:12:26.24,1:12:29.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, he's like that in the movie...\N-No, it wasn't like that...it was like this.
Dialogue: 0,1:12:51.44,1:12:54.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,-Zana..this is mr. Osman
Dialogue: 0,1:12:54.90,1:12:57.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Who is mr.Osman Kaka?\N-It's him, come on.
Dialogue: 0,1:13:01.04,1:13:03.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Dana? What are you doing here?
Dialogue: 0,1:13:03.40,1:13:07.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I and my brother have made it to here alone\N-you came here alone?
Dialogue: 0,1:13:07.68,1:13:11.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes\N-you have done a terrible thing.
Dialogue: 0,1:13:11.15,1:13:14.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What if something have had happened to you.\N-can you help us?
Dialogue: 0,1:13:14.28,1:13:18.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It's no that easy, you came here by yourselves \Nbut your lives is in danger.
Dialogue: 0,1:13:19.22,1:13:23.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We don't need any of you, \N As long as we have made it to here, \NWe can make it to America too.
Dialogue: 0,1:13:23.32,1:13:25.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What is it with you little dirty worm!
Dialogue: 0,1:13:25.86,1:13:27.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Yes
Dialogue: 0,1:13:27.17,1:13:31.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You can't go alone.\N-if they catch anyone crossing the border illegally, \N They will die.
Dialogue: 0,1:13:31.56,1:13:35.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,So, please help us and we promise you, \Nwe will not make any trouble for you...
Dialogue: 0,1:13:35.44,1:13:38.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Please help us...
Dialogue: 0,1:13:38.36,1:13:40.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I beg you.
Dialogue: 0,1:13:54.48,1:13:56.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Is it you filthy worm?\N-yes
Dialogue: 0,1:13:56.96,1:13:59.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Boys, come here.
Dialogue: 0,1:14:00.10,1:14:06.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We will drive off in two cars..\N you are going with \NMr. Jamal's car. he has a family with himself too.
Dialogue: 0,1:14:06.09,1:14:10.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You don't have any documents that's why \NI'm obliged to hide you in the car.
Dialogue: 0,1:14:10.12,1:14:11.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We will go to another city...
Dialogue: 0,1:14:11.14,1:14:14.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And there I'm gonna make some documents for you \Nand you will be recognized as the sons of this family
Dialogue: 0,1:14:14.89,1:14:18.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And then we will go to America. ok?
Dialogue: 0,1:14:18.56,1:14:22.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Now you have to go with Mr. Jamal.\N-Come on, hurry.
Dialogue: 0,1:14:24.54,1:14:27.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Boys, listen. \N we will get on the way in a minute..
Dialogue: 0,1:14:27.56,1:14:30.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And when we arrive at the checkpoint.  \N The officer will stop us..
Dialogue: 0,1:14:30.32,1:14:32.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,and i will get out to open the trunk..
Dialogue: 0,1:14:32.61,1:14:37.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,before i open it \N I'll hit it twice as a warning for you..
Dialogue: 0,1:14:37.15,1:14:40.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,You'll never talk, understand?
Dialogue: 0,1:14:41.96,1:14:46.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,And take this bottle to pee in it when you need to.\N-ok
Dialogue: 0,1:14:46.88,1:14:49.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't do it in the car, ok?\N-Ok, don't worry
Dialogue: 0,1:14:49.23,1:14:52.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'll take out your eyes if you do so.
Dialogue: 0,1:14:53.22,1:14:56.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Get in the bag, come on.
Dialogue: 0,1:14:57.88,1:15:00.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, i'm so scared.\N-It's nothing, don't be scared
Dialogue: 0,1:15:01.08,1:15:03.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Promise?\N-yes.
Dialogue: 0,1:15:25.08,1:15:26.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka?\N-What?
Dialogue: 0,1:15:26.68,1:15:30.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I have to pee\N-pee in the bottle.
Dialogue: 0,1:15:32.00,1:15:36.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I dropped the cap.\N-find it\N-i can't find it.
Dialogue: 0,1:15:36.00,1:15:38.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Shit..give it to me. \N You never do anything good.
Dialogue: 0,1:15:39.00,1:15:41.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka..i have a worm\N-shut up
Dialogue: 0,1:15:41.59,1:15:43.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Endure it. \N We may arrive in a bit\N-ok
Dialogue: 0,1:15:44.00,1:15:47.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't pee on my me\N-Ok
Dialogue: 0,1:16:32.68,1:16:35.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Where are you going?\N-That village ahead .
Dialogue: 0,1:16:40.08,1:16:42.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Your ID
Dialogue: 0,1:16:50.72,1:16:54.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Do you have ID?\N-yes\N-bring it.
Dialogue: 0,1:17:13.00,1:17:16.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Step out and open the trunk\N-ok
Dialogue: 0,1:17:18.92,1:17:21.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It always stuck.
Dialogue: 0,1:17:22.52,1:17:25.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Step back.
Dialogue: 0,1:17:25.42,1:17:27.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Farther.
Dialogue: 0,1:17:27.40,1:17:29.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Turn around.
Dialogue: 0,1:18:28.68,1:18:30.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come here.
Dialogue: 0,1:18:36.70,1:18:38.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go.
Dialogue: 0,1:18:49.04,1:18:52.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Mr. Jamal. don't you take out the boys?
Dialogue: 0,1:18:52.45,1:18:54.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't worry, they will be okay.
Dialogue: 0,1:18:54.90,1:18:57.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Have mercy Mr. Jamal. it's not fair.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:07.88,1:19:10.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Quick!
Dialogue: 0,1:19:14.12,1:19:18.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What are you doing filthy?\N-Shit.. you wetted me.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:18.15,1:19:21.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why are you hitting my brother?
Dialogue: 0,1:19:21.20,1:19:24.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kill you now? huh animal?\N-leave my brother alone
Dialogue: 0,1:19:24.20,1:19:27.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Now bugger off and go to America.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:27.30,1:19:29.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Bastards.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:29.57,1:19:32.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Don't leave us.\N-don't leave us.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:33.00,1:19:35.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Do not leave us!
Dialogue: 0,1:19:50.32,1:19:52.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, i would have smashed.. \N all his body if he didn't run away.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:52.70,1:19:55.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Stop it..\N now we have no chance to make it..\Nthe smuggler left us.
Dialogue: 0,1:19:55.41,1:19:58.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Why don't you understand anything, \Nyou are not my brother anymore.
Dialogue: 0,1:20:06.52,1:20:11.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka..kaka..kaka\N-what do you want?
Dialogue: 0,1:20:13.00,1:20:17.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,What is this?\N-this is a passport. \N I created it by myself for both of us.
Dialogue: 0,1:20:22.20,1:20:24.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<font color="#C11B17">\N[ ZANA ]</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:20:24.76,1:20:26.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<font color="#C11B17">\N[  AGE: 7 ]</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:20:33.60,1:20:35.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,<font color="#C11B17">\N[ KAKA DANA  ]</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:20:42.76,1:20:46.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana. I don't think it's too far to make. \Nand now after we have passports, \N We can make it by ourselves.
Dialogue: 0,1:20:46.84,1:20:50.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Let's go\N-Ok Kaka. let's go.
Dialogue: 0,1:21:13.48,1:21:18.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka..when I went to America, \NI will drink too much Coca-Cola \N until my urinate become Coca-Cola.
Dialogue: 0,1:21:18.50,1:21:20.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, in America....
Dialogue: 0,1:21:23.10,1:21:26.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,It almost ran over us.
Dialogue: 0,1:21:29.72,1:21:34.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, why have you written your age is 7 in the passport..\Nbut you are not 7, you are 6.
Dialogue: 0,1:21:34.00,1:21:38.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Nobody will figure it out if you don't tell anybody.\N-Ok. i will not tell anybody
Dialogue: 0,1:21:42.46,1:21:45.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, why aren't you coming?
Dialogue: 0,1:21:50.44,1:21:53.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on.
Dialogue: 0,1:21:53.03,1:21:55.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, come on
Dialogue: 0,1:21:55.16,1:21:58.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'm waiting for you , come on.
Dialogue: 0,1:21:58.00,1:22:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Let's make it to America before it is too late.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:00.00,1:22:03.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana, go away.  I stepped on an explosive.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:03.24,1:22:06.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, we don't have time for joking \N let's go before it is......
Dialogue: 0,1:22:06.40,1:22:09.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'm not joking, go away.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:16.00,1:22:18.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you don't come \N I will throw these stones at you.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:18.03,1:22:20.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I swear I am not joking, \Ngo away..
Dialogue: 0,1:22:21.88,1:22:25.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,This time I will throw them at you.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:49.64,1:22:52.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka. are you serious?
Dialogue: 0,1:22:52.04,1:22:54.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on. throw at me..\N come on.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:55.68,1:22:58.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on.
Dialogue: 0,1:22:58.22,1:23:00.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on. hit me
Dialogue: 0,1:23:01.78,1:23:04.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,If you don't go \N I will throw it at you.
Dialogue: 0,1:23:05.28,1:23:08.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, I will not leave here without you, \NNot without you. I will never go
Dialogue: 0,1:23:08.46,1:23:10.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I will throw more at you..\N go away
Dialogue: 0,1:23:10.57,1:23:12.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,We are men \Nhow can we leave each other?
Dialogue: 0,1:23:12.60,1:23:14.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I will throw it at you.\N-Do it
Dialogue: 0,1:23:14.80,1:23:18.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I will do it\N- I will not leave here without you.
Dialogue: 0,1:23:18.54,1:23:21.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Throw at me as much as you want \N but I will not leave you here.
Dialogue: 0,1:23:21.72,1:23:24.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I swear I'll throw it at you.. \N-Kaka I'll never leave you here
Dialogue: 0,1:23:24.96,1:23:28.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'll do it swear to God. \N-throw as much you want give it to me
Dialogue: 0,1:23:28.68,1:23:32.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'll do it, listen to me?\N- I'm not going, never
Dialogue: 0,1:23:36.80,1:23:43.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I will never leave you!\NI will not leave you!
Dialogue: 0,1:23:43.26,1:23:46.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Go away,
Dialogue: 0,1:23:47.48,1:23:49.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I'll throw it. go
Dialogue: 0,1:23:50.92,1:23:54.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I said go. \N- -screw America and Superman,\N  I don't want it
Dialogue: 0,1:23:54.52,1:23:56.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I do not want to go there!\Nenough with that,
Dialogue: 0,1:23:57.00,1:24:00.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,I just need you. only you.\N-Kaka I just want you. just you
Dialogue: 0,1:24:22.00,1:24:26.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ok Zana, \Ngo bring someone here to help me.
Dialogue: 0,1:24:26.00,1:24:30.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Ok don't move, \Ndon't do anything I will be back right away
Dialogue: 0,1:24:30.69,1:24:33.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka don't move. I will be back right away\N- Okay.
Dialogue: 0,1:24:53.00,1:24:57.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle..help me, help me
Dialogue: 0,1:24:57.32,1:25:01.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle, please help!
Dialogue: 0,1:25:04.32,1:25:07.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Help my brother!
Dialogue: 0,1:25:07.56,1:25:10.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,He has stepped on an explosive
Dialogue: 0,1:25:10.60,1:25:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Please help me!
Dialogue: 0,1:25:26.80,1:25:30.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Come on, please,\NMy brother, \N He has stepped on an explosive
Dialogue: 0,1:25:30.56,1:25:35.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,, Please!
Dialogue: 0,1:27:09.28,1:27:12.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Forgive me Brother.
Dialogue: 0,1:27:41.00,1:27:43.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle , haven't seen my brother?
Dialogue: 0,1:27:43.96,1:27:47.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle , haven't seen my brother?\NHe is wearing a dress with this color.
Dialogue: 0,1:27:47.96,1:27:51.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Uncle , haven't seen my brother?\N-he is wearing a dress with this color.
Dialogue: 0,1:27:53.04,1:27:55.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana!
Dialogue: 0,1:27:57.32,1:27:58.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Zana!
Dialogue: 0,1:28:09.24,1:28:11.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,Kaka, you are not dead?
Dialogue: 0,1:28:11.12,1:28:14.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,No, I'm not dead. \NI'm superman, \Nhow can superman die?!
Dialogue: 0,1:28:30.12,1:28:50.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,
Dialogue: 0,1:28:50.12,1:28:59.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8} Translated by    <font color="#800000">> Shakir Abstract <</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:29:00.12,1:29:10.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8} Timing by   <font color="#0000FF">> [ PYRO ] <</font>
Dialogue: 0,1:29:10.12,1:29:15.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,
