Avoid the occasions of sin.
For your penance,
say the rosary 5 times.
Now make an Act of Contrition.
Five rosaries?
Father, I have never in my life
had to say 3 rosaries,
let alone 5. 1, 2...
Belizaire!
The penance comes from God.
It's not something you negotiate.
Now make an Act of Contrition.
Belizaire! Belizaire!
The medicine you gave me
for my shoulder really helped.
Do you have any more?
Yes, I do, I have one bottle left.
That's promised to Madame Maraist.
I could make some more, but...
I'm gonna be on my knees all day
saying those 5 rosaries.
Belizaire. Belizaire.
The penance comes from God,
I only exercise...
a slight discretion
in determining what it is.
My power to heal
comes from God directly...
and I have a great deal of discretion.
If I had 1 rosary, I might have time
to make medicine for your shoulder.
Belizaire. Belizaire.
Think of the Bishop. He doesn't
understand these country parishes.
If he heard us negotiating,
you know what he'd do to me?
Ooh... Maybe you should talk
to the Bishop about your shoulder.
Belizaire!
(cough)
Bless you.
Mr. Belizaire!
My Mama's sick.
Sickness that foretells what's coming.
She said you'd know about it.
Hey, Dolsin.
Chew on that.
Well, you don't have the sunstroke.
And you don't have the moonstroke.
You're gonna have another boy, Alida.
Sometime between Christmas
and the New Year, I believe.
Morning sickness near sundown.
- But I always was a little contr...
- Contrary.
I'll leave citronelle and red raspberry.
That ought to make you fine.
Thank you.
Promise... Promise not to tell anybody.
Why?
Well, I can keep a secret...
Alida, Matthew's gotta act right by you.
No matter what his papa says.
It's good of you to care.
I do care.
I care much more
than you know, Alida.
Ah, Belizaire.
No wonder I hear such stories about you.
- What stories?
- What stories? You know...
the Widow Comeaux...
The Widow Comeaux?
She'd marry my mule if he'd have her.
Belizaire!
(horse whinnies)
That's Matthew.
- Meaux, get that for me, will ya?
- Try not to take too long in there.
HEY"
- How you doing, partner?
- Fine
- I'll give you this milk and stuff.
- I'll tend to your horse.
Take that for me, would you?
Here you go.
- Hey, baby.
- Hi, Daddy.
I brought you a little something.
Promise me.
Don't tell Matthew about the baby.
(Sigh)
Hey, darling.
How are you?
What's that? What? Matthew?
A little something special.
Something special for you.
Sounds like pecans.
It is pecans.
- That horse doctor here?
- I wasn't feeling well.
What you doing here?
As one with power to heal,
Matthew, I have the good fortune...
...to enter any home I please.
- I sensed a little stress in the belly...
- A little bellyache.
I suggested red raspberry and citronelle.
Herbs to calm my stomach.
People today barely respect
our Acadian ways,
but when one they love falls ill,
- they always come back to me.
- Thank you, Mr. Belizaire, we'll be just fine.
Alright.
Matthew, please.
Leave him be.
I didn't feel Well, that's all.
Matthew!
What the hell are you doing?
This is to knock the pain out
of your house, Matthew.
Thank you but I don't need the pain knocked
out of my house. Appreciate that.
You've got snakes.
Get away from here.
Don't you come around here again.
You aren't needed around here.
I don't wanna see you here again.
You hear me, Mr. Belizaire Breaux?
You castin' gris-gris spells?
Gris-gris is for evil, Mr. Willoughby.
A man like you might have use for that.
But my powers are to heal.
We had a Santo Domingo slave
who dealt magic. We sold her off.
Gris-gris...
Ooh... Don't put no curse on me, Belizaire!
Matthew!
Hurry up in there!
Hey, I have to go out again tonight.
Again, Matthew?
No more "again."
The meetings are finished.
Tonight we ride.
(horses galloping)
Hypolite Leger!
What's that?
What you men come here for?
Leger, you will undergo an infamous
punishment because...
you have taken part in crimes
that have desolated this country for years.
No longer having faith in our juries,
mauled by sheriffs who keep away
honest men from the jurors bench,
we have formed ourselves into juries.
You are found guilty of theft and barnburning.
You must leave this State in 2 weeks...
I didn't do it. I don't want trouble.
If you break this bond, you
will be hanged. Let's go!
Felix Nunez!
You must leave the State in 2 weeks.
Go elsewhere and seek a living
by work and morality.
If you break this bond,
you will be hanged.
Let's gm!
Hurry up, Belizaire!
Hurry up!
Hell, slow down, 'Polite.
Get down, get down, get down.
They coming for you too, Belizaire.
- They didn't come for you.
- I guess they come for me later.
We gotta warn Parrain.
Came to my house.
Nothing about the Sheriff.
Just said I have to go.
They said I did things I didn't do.
I didn't do it!
They gonna come and
get you too, Parrain.
They gonna come and get you.
- I didn't do nothing.
- You didn't mention the Sheriff?
They said I have to leave.
- Wake up in there!
- Wayne Plaisance!
Wayne Plaisance!
You will undergo
an infamous punishment...
- for taking part in crimes...
- Get out! Just get out!
Hey. get back. Hey!
Come on!
That's Belizaire Breaux.
We can get rid of him, too.
Right, Matthew?
That's enough. Just read.
Just read it!
No longer having faith in our juries,
...mauled by sheriffs
who keep away honest men...
...from the jurors bench,
we have formed ourselves into juries...
I found Dolsin trying to get into
your gun closet today, Matthew.
Well...
He can't get past the lock.
I know.
But he was trying.
He sees you practicing
and now he wants to shoot.
He needs more of you
than that, Matthew.
This vigilante business
won't take long.
Then the slave auctions in
New Orleans and the spring round-up.
That won't take long either?
My father needs me.
I know.
But your children, darling...
Your children need you, too.
I need you.
Don't forget, Matthew.
I'm scared.
My sweet...
My sweet Matthew.
We been here long before they was.
They can't make us go.
The dozen richest men in the Parish!
What can we do?
Know what I'm gonna do?
Smoke as much beef for the trail
as I can lay my hands on.
Maybe the Sheriff can do something.
Ha!
I'm not leaving.
I've lived here all my life.
I'm gonna stay here.
(horses galloping)
Here they come!
Be careful, Father.
Stay here with your wife.
This is no place for a woman.
- Meaux can stay with her.
- You stay with Rebecca.
When are you gonna talk about
giving us some protection?
Sosthene, you get the same kind
of protection you always have.
I might as well leave for Texas.
It's the big man with all his men behind him.
He wants to increase his land.
Sheriff, throw this one out.
We don't want your land.
I'm gonna stay right here, this is
my home. I ain't going to Texas.
I'm gonna say it again.
I belong right here!
I've called you men in here...
...to save you from getting into
serious trouble.
Twenty families you've exiled.
That's too many.
Pick five. Five of the worst.
And I'll personally
see to it that they leave.
No need for you gentlemen
to dirty your hands.
No, Sheriff, five is not enough.
Wait, I wasn't finished.
You pick five, I pick five...
From that list of 20
that you nominated last night.
For those who stay behind,
they will behave or I'll lock 'em up.
(humming)
Papa told you
never to come back here.
Dolsin? Oh my goodness!
Papa told you
never to come back here.
Dolsin! Stop!
Dolsin!
Dolsin! I don't ever want
to see you do that again.
Papa told him not to come
around here no more.
Go to your room.
Now!
Quick, Dolsin.
- I'm sorry, Belizaire.
- Ah, well.
I brought you more citronelle.
Thank you.
I want to thank you.
- For keeping my secret yesterday.
- Oh well.
I always know what to say, don't I.
Matthew, well...
...he gets mad when he's jealous.
But it doesn't hurt him to get
jealous every now and then, does it?
It's not jealousy that makes him
and his rich friends...
terrorize these common people,
is it?
He should make his committee realize,
that you by familial obligation...
...you're still beholden to your...
Let's talk about
something else, alright?
These people are given 2 weeks
to pack up and leave forever.
I've heard enough about the
vigilantes lately. That's enough.
Peep, peep, peep, peep.
Come eat.
Peep, peep, peep. Come eat.
Saturday I'll be playing my accordion
at that fais do-do dance.
If they still hold one.
Peep, peep, peep...
Oh, Madame Sosthene,
bring me Alida.
She's the one I have loved,
since I was 14 years old.
If she don't consent,
I will steal her away...
Oh, you used to come
to that fais do-do.
You used to be the best dancer
on this bayou.
- No, not the best.
- One of the best. - No.
All the boys would ask you to dance.
And we'd watch you
as we waited our turns.
That was before I met Matthew.
He changed you.
Everybody knows he didn't
even bother to marry you.
Belizaire Breaux!
- You are telling me this?
- I am.
Well at least me and Matthew,
we jumped the broomstick.
That was fine when
there was no church...
...with a priest now it's inexcusable.
If it's good enough for my mother,
it's good enough for me.
If I had a woman like you,
I'd marry her in a minute.
And I'd marry her
in the Holy Mother Church.
If you're gonna talk like that,
you're gonna have to leave.
But first, I'll pay you for yesterday.
And today, too.
There's no charge.
These were medical visits,
no matter what...
...nonsense you talk.
I'm talking nonsense today?
Pecans. They're sweet.
Here. Take them.
They come from
Matthew's papa's yard.
Maybe you should talk to Matthew.
Or his papa.
(whistling)
'Polite been by here?
Tell your cousin there's
no more credit around here.
Come join the game.
'Polite will be by in a while.
You can win enough to pay his bill.
I do have enough
to pay his bill today.
No more barter!
I have to be gone in 2 weeks!
Maybe then we can start
raising chickens again.
(laughing)
Since everything that's not nailed down
around here seems to be yours.
(laughing)
I have enough of being accused
for something that's not my fault!
Deal me in there.
(cows moo)
This is your plantation, Son.
What about Rebecca's portion?
Matthew will take care of his sister.
Go tend to the cattle, James.
If it wasn't for his vigilante committee,
I'd be done with the round-up by now.
If you'd take the opportunities...
James!
James! Later!
Want me to break
that funny looking nose of yours?
You're very brave
on the other side of a fence.
(cows moo)
You say you've run it for 10 years...
Your son wants to be an Indian or a Cajun.
That's his life.
He thinks he can make friends
with these people and that...
- James!
- They will at the same time respect him.
- James.
- But he's not one of them. Never will be.
Ever thought of shutting up
once in a while?
It'll take someone
as strong and as hard as you.
I know he's your son
but Matthew is as soft as Louisiana mud.
But my son will run this plantation.
I told you not to come
around my house Belizaire Breaux.
Well, Alida needed medicine, Matthew.
For what malady?
She doesn't seem sick.
I gave those pecans to Alida.
She paid me with them.
Tell me then. What is her illness?
Huh?
The female trouble.
Sounds like the male trouble to me.
- You should be ashamed, Matthew.
- Of what?
You come here and accuse Alida.
I'm not accusing her.
I'm accusing you!
What you gonna do to me?
Even your vigilantes aren't gonna do
nothing to a man as innocent as me.
I think I will have you
brought before the committee.
Don't bring your vigilantes into this.
He'll give you back the pecans.
No, Alida gave me these
as a payment.
Put the pecans in the sack.
I didn't know they was stolen.
Just a minute. Matthew, you can... ah!
You Wanna fight, huh?
No, wait!
Alida says you're a just man.
I believe her.
C'mon, c'mon.
Your committee had no right
to exile these people.
I think the committee
might have missed one.
C'mon.
What gives you the right?
- We studied each man's past.
- Whose? Whose?
'Polite Leger's?
Huh?
What you talking about, man?
- 'Polite Leger's?
- Huh?
What you talking about?
Fever took his family 2 years ago.
He ran wild for a time.
But he's better now.
I personally guarantee he's better.
- What's your guarantee worth to me?
- What is it with you man, huh?
Is it because
I keep my promise?
What promise?
Huh?
It's a secret.
You and your friend
can both go to hell.
You go ahead and ask her.
You ask Alida what the secret is.
Why would Alida
keep a secret from me?
Because like many people,
she's afraid of your father.
Yeah, you ask her.
Maybe you'll know
that I mean you no harm.
Just as these people here
do not deserve your exiles.
If what you say is true,
I'll do what I can for your friend.
Leger.
'Polite Leger.
You can have the pecans.
I'll take two.
If I lose these I'll quit
playing cards forever.
'Polite Leger.
(music)
(whip cracks)
(cows moo)
- Look how many men they have.
- Shhh.
Hey, Meaux, at least six head
we left in the woods back there.
Come on.
Let's go.
Where they going?
I sent 'em for the strays.
I'd have gotten to it.
Aah.
Let's get 'em.
They're stealing cattle!
I'm coming!
Heeya! Heeya!
No!
No shooting!
You three, get after him.
Let's all get back to the herd.
Matthew.
I said no!
Let's all get back to the herd.
That Leger boy, he don't give up.
Who?
Leger. 'Polite Leger.
Come on!
Who 'Polite?
- Yes, it was 'Polite!
- Couldn't have been 'Polite!
Now Matthew thinks you two are trying
to make a fool of him.
Maybe you think you can
make a fool of everybody, huh?
You promised not to tell.
- Alida, he couldn't beat it out of me.
- Matthew said you started the fight.
And you told him to ask me
about the baby.
I didn't tell!
An expectant father has
a right to know. But I did not tell.
Why did you come by, Belizaire?
Huh?
I have enough citronelle for a month.
The fais do-do is tonight.
Those days are gone.
You should see the neighbors
and relatives you don't see no more.
That's over with.
Why? Is he home tonight?
You need have no fear
for the child you carry.
- The baby is not the reason.
- The unborn, they love to dance!
If that child was mine,
we'd be dancing.
And we'd be dancing all the time.
Belizaire...
My goodness.
Go on home.
Well...
It's at Ozeme Guidry's house.
Go on.
Come with us, 'Polite.
I don't wanna go.
I'll be alright.
Here, take this gun.
You're gonna need it.
- What about you?
- I got a better one.
(noise inside)
I know I'm not to dig
in your armoire, Belizaire.
But I really needed a drink.
You rustling Perry's cattle?
No! Parrain needed some meat.
Matthew Perry was helping you.
- I didn't know that.
- I did this for you!
We was only after a head or two.
Where is your Parrain?
- They all left for Texas.
- So what are you doing here?
- I don't wanna go to Texas.
- Get on your horse!
- No, Belizaire!
- Right now! Get on your horse.
No, I don't wanna go to Texas.
(horse galloping)
Mr. Belizaire!
What?
Fais do-do at Ozeme Guidry's
house tonight.
I know that.
T-Paul, wait!
Why don't you, huh... go by
Alida Thibodeaux's house.
Sure thing.
You DEV-
(singing)
- Thank you. You dance real good.
- You're welcome.
I enjoyed it too.
Mama, my poor toes...
I think he broke some of my toes.
Take it easy, 'Polite.
You've had lots already,
and you're in trouble, boy.
Ah, there's Alida
with the 3 half-Americans.
You come to say bye to those
your husband is sending away?
'Polite, it makes me sad.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to dance.
I don't want no trouble with you.
Ever been to Texas, son?
Come dance.
I don't want to.
- Come dance with me again.
- I don't want to.
Come on.
I don't want to!
- He insulted my daughter.
- It's my house. I'll take care of it.
- 'Polite...
- Uh, oh.
- You need to leave.
- Leave? You're not a vigilante.
I know, but it's my house.
You know I let anybody come here.
I ain't got but 2 rules.
The drinks stay outside,
and the drunks stay outside.
Now go on with Belizaire.
I'm not gonna go.
- You're not a vigilante.
- Wait!
I ain't leaving.
- He insulted my daughter!
- Wait! Belizaire will take care of it.
I'm not going!
I ain't gonna go.
Let's dance.
(music starts)
I feel sick.
You always have something.
I feel bad.
Then go to my house
and you go to sleep right now.
I'm afraid of the Texas, Belizaire.
You think it's gonna be alright?
I don't know.
But you know everything.
No, I don't know everything.
You always said you did.
Yeah, well...
I guess I meant
almost everything.
C'mon. Go to my house
and go to sleep.
Goodnight, Belizaire.
Don't worry, Belizaire.
His horse will get him home.
Home? It'll get him all the way to Texas.
Pass me that wine, Sosthene.
Pass him this jug.
- You made that?
- Sure did.
There's much more
where that comes from.
You always made
the best wine.
Sure gonna miss that
when you're gone.
What you mean?
You're not gonna get rid of me.
There's no chance.
I'm gonna stay here.
I'm not leaving.
(singing)
Speedy, good boy.
I'm sorry!
Speedy!
(whistle)
(horses galloping)
Oh, no!
Get him!
Leave me alone, please.
Get a rope on him.
(shouting)
Take his shirt off!
Let go.
What's the matter,
did he hurt you?
This man is drunk, he doesn't
even know what's happening.
- No whipping needed here.
- You gonna let him go again?
No whipping needed I said.
Take him down from the tree.
Matthew shouldn't do it.
Let Meaux do it. Get the whip.
You gonna let him go again?
Huh? Why don't you let him do it?
You can kiss it and make it better.
You know what I wish?
I wish it was you that was tied to that tree.
(scream)
Matthew Perry, I'm gonna kill you!
Kill you!
(scream)
Let the good times roll!
Be still!
(scream)
We oughta stop 'em.
Then we'd all go to Texas together.
Make a wagon train.
I don't want any part of this.
We got our families to think about.
(chopping)
- It hurts.
- Shhh.
It hurts bad, Belizaire.
(groaning)
Matthew!
Come on out here.
Quiet! You're gonna wake the whole house.
- I wanna talk to Matthew.
- He's not home now.
Who is he whipping now?
I'll wait.
You come away with me, Alida.
Away from this place right now.
I can't. I'm a married woman.
Not in the eyes of my God.
You are not a married woman.
I am.
Even if there's no paper to say so I am.
I've got Matthew and my children.
There's no place left for you, Belizaire.
Matthew has his father and the vigilantes.
There's no room left for you.
It's too late!
It's too late.
Please, you must leave
before Matthew returns.
My God, I could love you if you
come away with me right now.
What about my children?
How you gonna feed my babies?
With pecans?
That you can't even keep.
What do you have
to offer us, Belizaire? What?
Dolsin wants a horse for his birthday.
Where would you ever get him a horse?
Where would we go?
Where would you take us?
(Creak)
- Come see.
- Look.
- Come here.
- Who is it?
Looks like a man's face.
Dolsin, stay!
(wailing)
Oh my God!
Matthew! Matthew!
They'll expect you to go west.
Instead go south to Cheniere au Tigre.
- No!
- You'll catch a schooner to Galveston.
- But Parrain!
- Your Parrain got you into this!
(sobbing)
No. No. No, Matthew!
No. No, Please. Please
I'll pray for you.
I'll miss you.
Heeya!
I will praise Thee with my whole heart.
Before the Gods will I sing praise unto Thee.
Whither shall I go from Thy spirit
or flee from Thy presence.
If I ascend up into heaven,
Thou art there.
If I make my bed in hell,
behold, Thou art there.
If I take the wings of the morning,
and dwell in the utmost parts of the sea,
even there shall Thy hand lead me,
and Thy right hand shall hold me.
Naked I came out of my mother's womb,
and naked shall I return.
The Lord gave,
the Lord hath taken away.
Blessed be the name of the Lord.
Therefore are they before the throne
of God and serve Him day and night.
And He who sits on the throne
shall dwell among them.
They shall hunger no more,
neither thirst in Him.
Neither shall the sun
light on them or any heat.
For the lamb in the midst of the throne
shall feed them and lead them...
unto living fountains of waters...
and God shall wipe away
all tears from their eyes.
Jesus said, "I am the
resurrection and the life...
He that believeth in Me
yet shall he live...
...and whomsoever believeth
in Me shall never die."
Believest thou this.
Amen.
(mournful music)
We're gonna ride.
If this keeps on there'll be
no stopping it.
Rebecca, we have to go.
Mister Perry.
I'm sorry.
I beg you to hear me.
How could a man do harm
or take the life of another man
if he could not walk?
Stay away from here!
After the whipping these men gave
'Polite Leger, he could not walk.
Show some respect!
Get 'em home.
Go! Go!
I tied his wounds!
Another matter.
Listen. Matthew's children,
you've got to provide for them now.
They're gonna need milk and rice.
They're just babies.
Mister Perry!
You better get these men
off these horses, they'll be criminals.
You men touch a hair on that boy's head,
I'll jail the lot of you.
You're putting yourselves above the law.
- We're gonna go by Cypress Island Road.
- Make sure you get him.
I know that Leger boy.
I'll have to lock up all of you.
You jail 'em now!
- You people ride out...
- Jail 'em now I said, you hear me?
You people ride out and hurt that boy,
you'll be criminals...
You, off your horse.
Careful, Belizaire.
After all, it was your cousin Leger's
choice to ride out of my town.
You don't need a posse.
Lend me Lightning.
He's the only fast horse in the Parish.
Lightning?
Lightning is Parish property.
Besides, he has a race Saturday.
Do you want them to hang 'Polite?
I'll not start a war.
No. You got it all wrong.
I got express permission
from the authorities to do What I'm doing.
Get your hands off!
(Punch)
Matthew and Alida
were never married.
You must have forgotten about it.
How large a bribe
are you asking?
Matthew's children would inherit
half the estate when Old Man Perry dies.
I know the law, Sheriff.
And to think people used to tell me
you didn't want to learn our customs.
What exactly do you want from me?
I want to end the vigilantes.
That's not under my control.
When they come back from hanging Leger,
I want them to find...
That I have caught
Matthew's real murderer.
But all of my best witnesses
are being chased out of town.
I need one of their own
to convince them.
I need you,
Mr. Willoughby, as my witness.
Who do you plan to arrest?
You knew Matthew's enemies
better than I did.
You choose.
(mosquitoes buzz)
Give him the milk.
- Careful.
- Hold on a minute!
What is he doing here?
We're not gonna let them go hungry.
- If you think we're gonna provide...
- No! James
- James, please!
- Grab him! Stop him!
- We're not going to let them starve.
- Bring him back here.
They are my brother's children.
- You hold still. Hold still.
- Let me go! Let me go!
Bring him over here.
I'm sorry did I scare you?
Come here. I want to talk to you.
- Are you alright, Dolsin?
- Come here. It's alright. I'm sorry.
Do you know who lam, huh?
I'm your uncle, right?
I didn't know you who you were.
Just give us a second here.
Your papa's dead.
Do you feel bad about that?
Does it make you feel just awful,
your Papa getting killed like that.
You know anybody
who was giving your Papa trouble?
If you know, then whisper it in my ear.
Belizaire Breaux.
Go grab the Sheriff.
Bring him back here.
Should I get the boy more milk?
We can't let the bastards think
they have any claim on this place.
Go grab the Sheriff.
No... James... stop... James!
What's the matter?
We are gonna care
for Matthew's children.
The hell we are.
You're not in charge here, James.
Then who is?
Matthew's dead.
So if I'm not in charge yet,
it won't be long.
And when I am, those bastard children
won't touch a head of our cattle.
You are not in Mississippi anymore, James.
The law in Louisiana
says I inherit the herd.
Not you. Not us. Me.
When it is mine,
I can do anything I like.
But the same Louisiana law
says I am the lord and master here.
Not you.
Not us. And not those bastard children.
I don't see what you're worried about.
We convicted men with half this evidence.
I don't doubt it. I just wish I had a guarantee
you'll keep your end of the bargain.
You got my word, don't you?
Ha.
- What?
- Dolsin...
He thinks you killed his Papa.
- Alida, I got to explain to him.
- No.
- The stories he's gonna be told.
- No. You don't understand.
He told James Willoughby.
But Willoughby would never believe
that I'm even capable of...
No, Willoughby is going to the Sheriff.
You must go no now, Belizaire.
You must leave. Please.
What?
Come here. They find you here,
they'll accuse you.
- Get in here. - Be careful.
- Just get in here.
That's him.
I did not kill Matthew Perry.
How'd he know we were coming?
And neither did 'Polite Leger.
I know what you're thinking, Belizaire.
You don't have a chance.
You have to come with us.
Oh...
Get him! Get up there, don't let him go.
(hatch slams)
Go around back.
Be careful now.
- Hurry.
- Come on, let's go! Get the ladder. C'mon.
Whoa. Whoa!!
That's too bad.
Alright in there?
Save yourself, Belizaire!
Where did he go?
There he is. Go around back.
Hurry! Go, go, get him!
Oh, the outhouse! I got to use that!
Yo!
Come on, get him. Get him.
Nobody shoot! We need him alive.
Call the vigilantes off 'Polite!
Too late for that, Belizaire.
What is it you want of me?
To say I killed Matthew Perry?
Would that end this violence?
Alright then, I killed Matthew Perry.
You hear me?
I killed Matthew Perry.
You call the vigilantes off 'Polite.
Your confession is written, Belizaire.
- I'll read it to you.
- I'll read it myself.
Didn't know you could read.
Theodule, see if the horses are ready.
Fathered...
Yes, that's right.
This says I fathered his children.
You read very well, but this is
a legal document that means...
No, Belizaire, it says you were
like a father to them.
No, it says that
I fathered his children.
This sentence means
that you are responsible. Otherwise...
There's no word about responsibility.
You don't understand
what you're reading!
No. What this means is that if I fathered his
children, they can't inherit his Wealth.
No, no. It doesn't mean that at all.
That's the only confession I'll agree to.
That you'll agree to?
Whose confession is it, his or mine?
What about Leger?
Sign and I'll send someone on Lightning to
save him.
(horse whinnies)
You promised Lightning.
That's a plug!
Get it!
You got it?
So what if you and your cousin hang?
I'll save nineteen families from exile!
We're going to get Leger.
What do you want, Belizaire?
I've been doing
a lot of thinking, and uh...
if I confess that I fathered
those children.
I should leave something
to provide for them.
Well...
Alright...
What exactly is it you want?
Just a cow.
A cow?
A milk cow...
a good producer.
Alida will need milk
for the children.
Alright.
I can let you have a cow.
A mule...
You're not gonna
leave her your mule?
My mule is enough to keep me in corn,
but with a family to support like that...
Give him a new mule.
Alright.
That's one cow and one mule.
Boy, I sure would love
to give her a horse.
No horse!
She got 2 mules.
She doesn't need a horse.
I know. I'm just saying,
I would love to give her a horse.
I'm not giving her a horse.
You're supposed to take care of her,
not me. I'm doing you a favor. No horse.
You're gonna give her the horse.
You give her the horse
or in my last words from the gallows, I'll just
tell how you and me killed Perry together.
Nobody'd believe you.
Oh, they'd believe me.
A man that's gonna hang
can afford to tell the truth.
I'm not gonna deprive a man of his
last words for the price of a horse.
The horse is not the issue here.
I will not be made a fool of.
Not by him.
I'm hanging the man.
What more do you want?
And not some little Creole pony, either.
I want a big, strong...
an American horse.
Oh, no.
You let that man speak from the gallows,
you lose me as a witness.
I must get rid of the vigilantes,
Belizaire.
I'm sorry... but I need him.
Well, if I can't speak from the gallows,
I got other ways.
What kind of spell you gonna cast...
in a ball and chain?
Get what you wanted, Belizaire?
He's a very rich man.
You could've gotten two
or three pigs real easy.
And on that curse,
make it a good one.
Get back, hurry up!
Hey, that's his horse.
- Now we got him. He's on foot.
- This way, come on!
Can't be far, we was
right behind him.
Leave the horses here, let's go.
Alright guys, let's go, huh?
Stop him. Stop him!
Come back with that horse.
Leger!
Watch out for hidden logs
now, huh?
Come on. Try that other side.
Give yourself up!
Give it up, 'Polite.
I left!
You told me to leave and I did.
You killed Matthew Perry
and you're gonna hang for it.
I didn't kill him.
You said you'd kill him.
When he whipped you.
He hurt me,
but I didn't kill nobody.
I stole a cow,
I didn't kill nobody.
Give yourself up, Leger!
I'll go to Texas.
I'll go further than Texas.
I'll go to Mexico.
Take him alive!
Give yourself up!
- Hold your fire!
Take him alive!
Please don't.
Please, huh...
Please, I'll go.
- Hold your fire!
This is not a firing squad,
it's a damn turkey shoot.
It's Belizaire! And he's on Lightning!
Get him, Theodule.
You got no right here, Sheriff.
You got no right.
You men throw those guns down.
Throw down those guns, I say!
Throw them down now.
It's not your affair, Sheriff.
What you been doing here?
Theodule, get those guns.
Theodule, pick up the guns.
Take that gun away
from that man.
Damn you, Willoughby.
(praying)
You men are murderers.
An execution is not a murder.
Killing an innocent man is murder,
and one of you'll have to hang for it.
Belizaire!
Which one of them you wanna
see hang with you?
Those.
(praying)
You got that pointed belly.
The boy grows well.
His name will be Belizaire.
Belizaire...
He'll be trouble.
(laughing)
I wish you could be
there to treat him.
Why a confession, Belizaire?
I could have proven you were innocent.
To save 'Polite.
But you didn't.
You didn't save 'Polite.
No, I didn't, did I?
And little 'Polite,
all alone out there.
Stopping the men that took the law
unto themselves.
Well, all a man's life is Worth
are his deeds.
And yet they come from 30 miles around to see
me hang for my prayers.
But I have no deeds.
I have no deeds.
The people will miss their healer.
(crowd talking)
Whoa.
Father...
Ohhh, Father.
It's funny, I just sent someone for the last
batch of the balm you need for your shoulder.
It should keep you
for quite some time.
Let me see that.
Thank you, Belizaire.
I've also given some thought
to your other problem.
My problem?
I'm here about your problem, Belizaire.
No, I mean the one
with the Bishop.
Yeah, huh...
A triple hanging will be terrible news
even in a place like New Orleans.
I'm sure he'll have heard
about that.
- The Diocese already wrote me about it.
- I knew!
Father, wouldn't the Bishop
be proud...
if that young American landowner who
was murdered, that... that Matthew Perry...
Let's just say that he was
the very Protestant...
that you had converted
to the Church.
A convert?
Married in the Church.
And you baptized his children.
Boo! Boo!
(cheers)
(applause)
Well, you want to talk to the Bishop?
No.
Please, please.
Of all this man's sins,
God knows I know most of them,
The greatest was to defame
the children of Matthew Perry.
No! No! Belizaire, no!
- Please, one moment, please...
- Trust me.
- Matthew Perry and Alida Thibodeaux...
- Well, then trust the Father.
Both of the Parish of Vermilion...
I trust him less, Belizaire.
Matthew and Alida
were married by me...
- ...when I first arrived years ago.
- That is a lie!
Don't believe that priest.
Get him off of there.
- Due to the circumstances...
- Hey...
...the Widow Perry is gonna need
help with her new estate.
How much did you pay him?
Get him off of there!
You know, Belizaire, I've always wanted
to get in the cattle business, on the side.
- The children are all his, all legitimate...
- How does he know this?
They're all legitimate,
all baptized in Holy Mother the Church.
This is a lie!
(applause and cheers)
You're betraying your Church
and you're betraying me.
Please, please...
I want to apologize to the family...
- Get him off of there!
- for not conducting the funeral services.
He lies to you from the pulpit,
he'll lie to you from the gallows.
How much did they pay you?
I hope this clears the whole matter up.
Liar!
- This town don't need you!
- Get outta here!
It brings me great sadness
to be leaving this earth now.
No! No!
You know, I haven't even apprenticed
my secrets of healing. But, uh.
Before I go, I wanted to pass out
to you a little inventory...
of some of my medicaments
and remedies.
There's nothing here
that's good without prayers.
But those of you if you could use it...
it's yours.
That's an elixir
for the breakbone fever.
Anybody could use that?
anybody?
Belizaire, me!
Good.
Pass that down to the man
in the straw hat, Theodule.
(applause)
Thank you, Belizaire.
There's a poultice for the snakebite.
That's good for
your afflictions of the gums.
Ozeme!
Yeah, for me?
Here you go.
You remember me to your daddy.
Maybe you have him cook up a nice
gumbo for everybody after I'm gone.
Two. Two gumbos.
Never say die.
Yeah, never say die.
Never say die!
That's the most potent and
popular elixir in the Parish.
One drop in a glass of water
to cure a cold, two for pneumonia.
Who wants it? Who gets it?
Sosthene.
Thank you.
Hey, that's a charm for the lonely.
If you put that under the pillow
of the one you love,
that'll bring a proposal
of marriage.
Ooohh...
It will.
Hey, where's Widow Comeaux?
(laughs)
Widow Comeaux.
Widow Comeaux!
That's for you.
Dolsin, will you come sit
in the buggy?
Yes, ma'am.
This was given to me by an old
Santo Dominguan slave woman.
- She called it the gris-gris of judgement.
- Ooohh...
But I warn you about that.
'Cause I've seen the effect
of that root.
Must not be touched,
nor played with...
by a little child.
Oh, no.
I've seen liars touch that and they was
stricken with the asthmatic fevers.
I've seen thieves touch it...
- They spit up their own blood.
- Ooohh.
You know, I've been told...
Belizaire!
Belizaire?
I've been told that a man who's had the
misfortune of taking another man's life...
should he be in the presence
of this root...
- ...he would be struck dead.
- Ooohh.
I guess that goes for me, too.
Ha, ha, ha!
You want to touch that, eh?
You wanna touch that?
How about you, Meaux?
How about you?
Oohohoh...
Oh no, the executioner, he don't
wanna touch that, does he?
Well...
Hey!
Whosoever wants that...
let him take it...
Mr. Willoughby!
I'm talking to you!
Here!
Why don't you touch that?
- I wouldn't dirty my hands.
- Touch it! - Touch it!
- You believe in it, you touch it.
- You touch it!
Don't you touch me, boy.
I'll tell you.
Here you touch that!
You can't fool me with black magic.
Nothing to do with me!
Now you touch that, unless you,
and not I, took the life of Matthew Perry!
Touch it. Touch it. Touch it...
Touch it.
Touch it. Touch it, Touch it...
Touch it! Touch it! Touch it...
Touch it! Touch it!
Touch it!
Touch it. Touch it. Touch it...
Touch it! Touch it!
Get off!
Get him!
(angry shouts)
(choking)
Belizaire!
Belizaire! Hold on!
Belizaire, hold on!
Hold on!
Breathe! Breathe, ooh, breathe.
Breathe, breathe...
Now you're a man of means,
Belizaire.
Dolsin, remember
what I told you to say.
Go on, it's alright.
Mr. Belizaire...
I'm sorry for all the trouble
I've gotten you into.
Oh, well.
No trouble.
Listen, uh...
I realize you were born in the fall
of the year, regardless of all that...
Happy birthday.
- For me?
- Yeah, that's for you.
Go on, get up there!
I guess a year and a day
you'll be in mourning for Matthew.
I've been thinking about that.
I mean, you'll need someone to provide for you,
now that I'm a man of means, as they say.
And, uh...
maybe you'll be fixing to marry me.
Ah!
Well, there's no harm in asking,
is there?
But, Belizaire,
you're not asking me.
Will you marry me?
We'll see, Belizaire.
We'll see.
Well...
Whew.
Come along, my children.
Come on.