Attention, please.
To all our dear and loyal listeners.
To mothers, fathers and relatives –
Stella Film announces a contest.
They're looking for a girl
between six and eight years of age.
A pretty Italian girl.
Take your daughters
to Stella Film offices...
in Cinecittà
Via Tuscolana, km 9.
It could be your and her lucky day.
Only girls between six
and eight years of age...
can enter the theatre
quietly and calmly...
to be seen by Blasetti, the director.
Keep quiet and stay calm!
Do you understand?
Hurry! Hurry!
- I've lost my daughter.
- She lost her daughter. Vito!
Where is she gone?
- What's her name?
- Maria Cecconi.
Little Maria Cecconi!
Quiet! Quiet, please.
There.
Politeness goes a long way.
In other words, we'll be able
to screen test your little girls...
if you keep calm and quiet.
Right? Good.
- Shall we start, Taparelli?
- Yes, we're ready.
- Glori, send the first child.
- The first child!
The first child, come on.
What can you do?
I can imitate Betty Gable.
That's great. Let's see.
Well done, you're really good.
- You're starting early. How old are you?
- 11.
Good. Give her a number.
Next one, please.
Quiet, over there.
Come on. Keep that child quiet.
- What can you do?
- "Arrivano i Nostri".
Good.
Start singing "Arrivano i Nostri".
Very good.
Yes, louder.
Chiari, give her a number.
- Next!
- Tell them to be quiet over there.
You have a Chinese hat, good.
Quiet!
I've spent hours looking for you.
How could I go home without you?
Look at the state of you.
Just look at that. Get up now.
You deserve to be smacked!
Why are you crying?
Look at the state of you.
Damn it! You drive me mad. They even
called you over the megaphone.
- Mummy!
- "Mummy" what?
What did she do wrong?
What did she do?
She nearly gave me a heart attack
I've been looking for her
all over Cinecittà.
- They won't let us in now.
- Are you here for the contest?
Yes, we are.
But look at the state of her now.
She looks worse for wear.
Come here.
If I were you, I'd leave her like that.
All dirty? Yeah, right.
They're much cuter like this,
all grubby and untidy.
Very funny.
She's got a pretty smile.
She's very photogenic.
And she's got beautiful eyes.
Let's see.
Really beautiful.
At least it's something.
Let's hope they'll pick you.
Gosh, I'm lost now.
- They're at number 5
- Number 5?
- Studio number 5
- And how do I get there?
- Calm down, I'll take you there.
- Will you?
How kind of you. Let's go.
I'll settle up with you when we get home.
This is the girl who got lost.
- Let the lady through here.
- If you say so
I've brought some photos of her.
Do you think it's a good idea?
Pretty. This child is really pretty.
- Well, at this age, they're all pretty.
- Yeah?
They're all pretty,
but I prefer their mothers.
May I give you a piece of advice?
The second audition will be harder
and these photos won't help you much.
- Are they ugly?
- A bit.
You need bigger and better ones.
Go to a professional photographer.
I can give you a name.
- That would be great.
- Tell him I sent you.
Alberto Annovazzi, that's my name.
The photographer is
in Via Quattro Fontane, number 14.
- Go and see him, he's great.
- I'll definitely go.
- Thanks a lot.
- Don't mention it
I don't know how to thank you.
- Can I go in?
- This way, it leads straight to the studio.
- I'm so lucky I met you.
- Best of luck.
- Say bye.
- Bye, and don't run off again.
- I'm holding her tight.
- Good.
- Good-bye.
- Good-bye, madam.
Painter, I need to talk to you
While you paint this altar
I am just a poor black man
And to pray God here I am
I know you'll be listening...
Excuse me.
I should have been up there long ago
I had lost my daughter.
Excuse me.
- Did you find her?
- She's found her!
Good evening, Mr. Blasetti.
Madam, stand back.
Good, well done.
But she's finished singing.
Mancinelli Silvana?
Mario! Give her a number.
Okay, now the next child.
Next child, come on.
Madam, who are you?
The incident's over!
Go back to your seats!
- Enough!
- That's it, the incident's over.
This is the child who got lost.
- Oh, yeah.
- I lost sight of her.
This place is like a town.
She was somewhere around there.
- Where did you find her?
- By the pool.
Ladies, quiet please.
Quiet, please.
- Where did you find her?
- By the pool, she was fishing!
- She got dirty.
- Yes, she ruined her dress.
Cute. What's your name?
- Maria.
- Say your name.
- Very good. Maria what?
- Maria...
- "Gecconi"
- "Giacconi"?
- No, she lisps slightly.
- So, what's her real surname?
- Cecconi.
Cecconi, good.
Repeat, "Maria Cecconi".
- Maria "Gecconi"
- Oh well, it must sound right to her.
When I made the announcement
you were outside looking for your child...
but I said that the child
has to be six or seven years old.
- Not younger.
- But she's seven.
Is she? She looks a bit... small.
Really? No, it must be the dress
that makes her look short.
In all truth,
she hasn't grown much this year.
She'll grow more next year,
it doesn't matter.
So, what can you do?
Do you dance? Sing? What can you do?
- Venice!
- You do Venice.
Mr. Blasetti won't understand
if you say that.
- She means a poem about Venice.
- Ah, okay.
Good. You can begin reciting the poem.
Go on.
"Venice, to thee comes at last
the last hour.
"Martyr illustrious, in thy foe's power.
"Bread lacks, the cholera deadlier grows.
"From the lagoon bridge
the white banner blows."
Did you teach her that?
She's a star.
Not even at Christmas
did she recite it so well.
Just for you.
You know what? We need to hurry.
It's two o'clock,
and if we get to the stadium late...
it will be full
and we'll have to stand up like idiots.
- Let's hurry.
- I don't feel like going anymore.
What do you mean?
You're not coming to the match?
Bruno, did you hear that?
You know that I'm worried.
She left early in the morning
and took the child with her.
I'm not in the mood, Franco. Don't insist.
She told you she was going to give an
injection in Monteverde, at her friend's.
Why would she go all the way
to Monteverde to give shots?
Exactly.
It's Sunday and the tram
costs 20 lire each way...
and the child pays full fare.
- I know.
- Your wife is mad. Tell her that.
Franco, drink your coffee.
See what you've done?
This moron's always laughing.
Whatever.
Drink your coffee and shut up.
Give me a chance, it's still boiling hot.
Mum, I won't even bother about her.
She always does as she likes anyway.
- She has to respect you.
- Yeah, exactly. She has to respect you.
You know what? I don't think
she's gone to Monteverde.
What are you talking about?
She's taken the child with her.
That's exactly why I think
she hasn't gone there.
Let's go, guys. It's three o'clock
and we're still here discussing.
- Let's go, it's late.
- Let's go Spartaco, come on.
- Come home early.
- Give her another kiss.
Mum, you never change.
Okay, I've made a mess of myself.
I'll clean you up. Bye.
Kiss my forehead.
Have fun, don't catch too much sun.
- Okay.
- When you see Maddalena tell her...
Yes, I'll tell her not to go away again
with the child.
It's two o'clock
and she still hasn't eaten.
- Bye.
- Good-bye.
- See you.
- Enjoy yourselves.
- It's late.
- Bye.
Hurry up.
Shut up.
Spartaco, there's your wife.
- And you were worried.
- There she is.
Where have you been all this time?
- Spartaco!
- Slow down. What's the rush now?
- I went there!
- Where?
To Cinecittà, for the contest.
- Are you mad?
- Maybe.
- In any case, they picked her.
- Who?
Our daughter, not me. I wish!
- Don't lie, you're always telling lies.
- I'm not lying.
Don't even bother,
she always does what she wants.
She's all talk. Let's hurry, guys,
the match will have started.
Mind your own business for once.
- Don't use that tone with him.
- Whatever.
I'll come to watch the match too.
- No, you go home and feed the child.
- Your mum can feed her.
- No, you feed her!
- Take me to the cinema tonight.
Forget it. We'll talk at home.
- Let's go, Franco.
- What?
- Keep yakking.
- Stop it, idiot.
We're going to the cinema tonight, right?
Don't act the fool.
Just go home and feed the child.
How nice. Let's go, darling.
Bye, darling.
One, two, three, four.
Mrs. Molteni!
What do you want?
Shout louder, I can't understand you.
It's all because of this damn noise.
They wake people up early in the
morning. What do you want then?
Is my mum up there?
No, she isn't here, Maria.
She's gone to Margherita's for the
injection. Let me call her for you.
Maddalena!
- Maddalena!
- What?
- Maria is looking for you.
- Who?
- Your daughter is looking for you.
- What do you want, Maria?
Mum, there's a lady
who wants a coffee.
I can't hear you!
There's a lady who wants a coffee!
Honey, don't hold me up,
I'm giving an injection. I'll be right down.
Be good. Thanks.
Mum said she's coming down.
She's busy giving a lady an injection.
You see this egg?
God helps those
who help themselves.
- Your daughter's been calling you.
- I know, my dear.
- Is she ill?
- Not at all. She's been picked.
We're going to the photographer.
When are you going to have this baby?
What are you doing here?
Don't you have a house? What a pain!
Those lovely images
The times that have gone by...
Gisella, can you please ask your
daughter to do Maria's homework?
We're going to the photographer.
She's been picked.
She's been picked! Bye.
Good for you.
What a fanatic, she's completely mad.
Don't choke, please.
Is this the lady
who wanted a coffee?
Sorry, but I had a cramp...
in my stomach.
I asked the child for some coffee.
I know. We don't have that,
but you found the eggs.
- They're better.
- Yeah, they're even better.
By the way, who are you?
- How silly of me. You don't know me.
- Exactly.
I'm Tilde Spernanzoni.
- The actress.
- What?
The actress.
I'm not working anymore... I'm tired.
When you get to a certain age,
you must rest.
Moreover, you have
to make way for the younger generation.
I do a bit of film work.
Mum, the lady drunk an egg.
It doesn't matter.
Little blabbermouth.
So, is this the child that has been
selected for the second audition?
Listen, who sent you here?
Cinecittà? Stella Film? Who?
Somebody must have sent you here.
You can't have fallen from the sky!
Somebody I know gave me the names
of the ones who were picked.
She's very pretty.
Give me your hand.
Let's go, good girl.
While mum prepares a nice
cup of coffee with plenty of sugar...
you are going to recite something
for me.
What a lovely garden!
Excellent. Let's go.
Yeah, this place is like a palace!
Thank goodness we're moving.
Where are you going? I know for a fact
that lessons aren't necessary.
They like her like this.
As long as she's bright and intelligent.
And my daughter is very intelligent.
- Plus, we can't afford it.
- I see.
Sacrifices need to be made
for our children.
Our children come before anything else.
Let's go.
Did you come here to teach me
how to be a good mother?
You're holding us up,
we need to go to the photographer.
How do I have to tell you?
- Go there later.
- What do you mean, later?
Where are you going?
Maria, recite her the poem, you know it
by heart, so we can get rid of her.
Yes, recite me the poem
in the garden.
Who sent her here?
Who on earth sent her here?
I really don't know.
You come home
and find a crazy person waiting there.
She tells you her whole life –
she's an actress, she's tired...
I've got my own problems already,
I didn't need her here.
She's wasting our time.
"Now I'm tired, I no longer teach..."
No, she's far from being crazy.
She may be tired,
but she drank three eggs.
She doesn't have any manners.
I'd better lock the meat up.
We're wasting half an hour
to let her hear a poem.
This is ridiculous.
We'll miss our appointment
with the photographer.
Doesn't she have anything better to do?
Wouldn't she rather be
at the park, where it's much cooler?
Instead of drinking other people's eggs!
I can't stand her.
This business about the eggs
is really bugging me.
- Madam, listen.
- Is the coffee ready?
It's coming.
Would you like it sweet?
The child is very good. But she'll get
to poetry later. Now, it's too soon.
It's tiring for her. I'm going to teach her
something new.
Let's find a quiet spot, let's see.
Here's perfect.
Give me your hand, follow me.
Come here, dear.
You'll see what I'm going teach you.
This is a lovely place.
Come here. Good girl.
Pretend that you are in a meadow.
A nice, large, green and cool meadow.
You have come here
to pick strawberries.
- Understand?
- Madam! Madam! She's deaf too.
The first exercise is role-playing.
Basically, you pretend to be
in a certain situation.
Do you like strawberries?
So you're happy
to be picking strawberries.
Look how many strawberries
there are under that oak.
She's mad,
where does she see an oak?
Quick, go and pick them.
Bend down. Good girl.
Pick them, there are so many.
Look how many.
And she's so silly to listen to her.
Madam, you're turning her brain to jelly.
Maria, what are you doing?
She's picking strawberries.
Can't you see?
Give it to me, dear.
What a nice strawberry.
Bend down and pick it. Good girl.
See? They don't understand anything.
If she doesn't leave...
Hurry! How long does it take you
to come here, darling?
We're running late.
She was driving us crazy.
Who is she?
You must only listen to mum.
Come on, we're late.
Wash your hands now.
Here's some water.
Get the soap, come on. Hurry up.
Look at the state of you.
Were you in the coal shed?
How slow are you?
Can you not be any quicker?
Rinse your hands, come on.
And also your face.
Look at the state of you.
In the meanwhile, I'll get ready.
What a strange person that woman.
"Go and pick the strawberries."
She was just joking, darling.
She was teaching you how to act.
Yes, to act...
After all, what is acting?
If I imagined to be someone else...
if I pretended to be someone else...
I'd be acting.
You're not interested, are you?
It's like when you say the nice poem
about the butterfly. How does it go?
"I'm a butterfly,
half white and half yellow."
The one where you move
your hands like this.
Say the poem.
"I'm a butterfly
half white and half yellow."
What about the hands?
Gosh! You see? You can act too.
You can act.
But make sure you don't stutter, honey.
Don't stutter, okay?
Let's go, we're late.
Listen to her
and you'll end up picking strawberries.
You listen to mummy. The other
mums here make me laugh.
"My daughter this, my daughter that."
They're just not made for this.
But you're my daughter
and you can become an actress.
You really can. I could have too,
if I had wanted to.
Let me fix your hair.
You look so messy.
Let's see how you look
with a centre parting.
No, you look ugly. Never mind.
All combed back, like mummy.
Let's see.
How pretty!
Let me undo your plaits.
Let's see. These plaits!
You're so pretty.
You look more simple and natural
in this way.
We'll have your photograph taken,
but it's all we can afford.
Do you understand, honey?
Mum, am I going back to school
tomorrow?
Dear Lord!
Now you're both stuttering and lisping.
- Say "school".
- School.
Are you doing this on purpose?
You never stuttered or lisped before.
Say "school".
- School.
- Great.
Pronounce it properly,
you can't speak Roman dialect...
if you want to be an actress.
- Come here. Say "house".
- House.
This is a real problem.
And now "soap".
- Soap.
- No, say it properly, without lisping.
You're making me lisp too, darling.
Get your shoes.
Go and get dressed over there.
Go and put your shoes on,
then put the dress on.
Careful not to mess up your hair.
Here we go again! Every time
I open the window, you're there.
Get out of the way, please!
He's got no shame. And he's so young.
This is crazy. They come
right into your own house!
Yes, in your own house.
Gosh, I'm lisping too now.
What's going on here?
Are you ready, Maria?
Don't mess up your hair when you put
the dress on, or I'll smack you!
That's too high.
Are you ready?
We're always rushing around.
Are you still there? How annoying.
What if that crazy woman was right?
Maybe you do need to study...
Maybe lisping runs in the family.
Maria, are you ready?
What does she look like?
Let me see her.
There you go. Excuse me.
How are you sitting her?
Like this.
That's not good.
Make her look more natural.
Mind your own business.
Excuse my wife. She's been invalid
so long, and this is her only distraction.
Let's be quick.
You can start choosing a pose.
- Sit up straight, petal.
- Do as I said.
I thought you knew each other.
After all, you're both auditioning...
and are acquaintances of Annovazzi.
Me? I hardly know him.
Maria, lift up your chin.
Come on.
Lift up your chin.
Keep your head straight.
I met him for the first time at Cinecittà
and he was interested in the child.
Look that way.
Don't cry, sweetheart.
We'll take a nice picture of you.
Aren't you happy?
He suggested I come to see you.
He liked her eyes the most.
Yes, her eyes.
Darling, why are you crying?
Poor thing, she's not used to this.
She's scared.
Smile, come on.
I see your child takes ballet classes.
- They have to dance in the film, right?
- No, they don't. Who said so?
I thought they had to, because one
of the other girls who came here...
- ...was at the Opera School.
- The Ruscaja School.
- No, the Opera School.
How annoying!
Excuse me, are you really sure
they have to dance?
In the novel the film is based on,
the child dances.
I've read it. The novel starts in that way.
I don't want to insist,
but I think you're wrong.
It doesn't start in that way, it starts
with her saying she has had enough.
It starts like that. And the child dances
around the table on her birthday.
No, she tells him that she's leaving him.
He wants to kill her, and the daughter,
who is so happy because of the party...
is dancing and fooling around
the table, where the cake is.
- In the book the child dances.
- Excuse me.
Anyway, the more they can do,
the better.
Dancing is not necessary.
- Are you ready, sweetheart?
- Wait, I'll fix her hair.
Madam, keep out of the way.
Smile to the man, look at the camera.
Done!
- You almost set me on fire.
- It was fine.
You scared her,
she probably closed her eyes.
No, she had her eyes wide open.
- Are you sure?
- Don't worry, madam.
- That's all I'm interested in.
- Madam, I'm very busy.
- I'm the photographer.
- Okay, no need to get upset.
- It's Isabella's turn.
- Darling, were your eyes open?
- Yes.
- You tell a lot of lies. Were you scared?
Or else we're wasting
time and money here.
Excuse me, when can I see
the negatives?
Come back tomorrow morning.
- Can I please come this evening?
- I can't have them ready tonight.
- Come back tomorrow morning.
- You're so kind.
Do you want to take it home?
I'll get you one like it.
We're late. Take the bag.
Dad must be starving.
- Good-bye and many thanks.
- Not at all.
These photos are very important.
I'm in your hands.
- Don't worry.
- Good-bye.
- Say bye to the gentleman.
- Say bye.
- Bye, sweetheart.
The needle's ready
Just keep steady...
- Are you ready, madam?
- Yes, I am.
Good, me too.
Choose a place
where you want to have the injection.
I've found it. It's on the right side.
But you've got so many bruises
on that side.
But it hurts on the other side.
Okay, then. Let's do it on the right side.
But if it hurts, don't complain.
- Is it Penicillin today?
- No, you are done with that.
- So what is it?
- We're starting the Balerofosforo again.
- I've had a whole box of that.
- But you need more. You're worn-out.
Just look at the white of your eyes.
You're big built, but very weak.
- I hope it works.
- What a chatterbox!
You're making me waste so much time,
when I'm so busy. Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
- Can I use your phone later, please?
Are you still lying there?
Come on, just find a place.
I have to call my daughter.
We've had the photographs taken.
They're really nice.
Come on, turn over.
You're going to set the bed on fire.
- Don't hurt me.
- Look at all this abundance.
- Who enjoys all of this?
- Who knows?
- Relax your leg.
- Don't hurt me
I'm in a rush. I have to go
to see the Commendatore afterwards.
- He's diabetic, poor thing.
- Poor him.
- You drink, eat and smoke too much.
- They're my vices.
- I can't help it.
- Come on, relax your leg.
Don't hurt me.
- You hurt me!
- You make me sweat when I come here.
You haven't even felt the needle.
I have such a light hand.
The Commendatore says that
he wants only me for his injections.
- He must be in love.
- I don't care, as long as he has them.
All done. You're as good as new now.
- Can I do this phone call now?
- Of course.
Thanks. If you don't mind,
I'll take the phone over there...
because I don't want to spill anything.
- Okay.
- Do you have guests today?
- No, it's my breakfast.
- No less!
- Do you eat four eggs?
- I need to get back on my feet.
Your liver must be bombproof!
- Madam, why is she complaining?
- No idea.
- Do you need an injection too?
- No, I don't need it, right, madam?
Of course you need it.
You have so much room in that body.
You're fat but I'll help you slim down.
Where did you find her?
Hello? Mrs. Gisella?
Hi. This is Mrs. Cecconi.
Yes. Can you do me a favour?
Thanks. My daughter is in the courtyard.
Could you tell her...
No, don't worry about going downstairs.
Just tell her from the balcony...
that I'm not coming back...
and she is to carry on with her lesson.
The acting lesson. She's in the courtyard
with her teacher.
And tell her that we'll collect
that stuff tomorrow.
A black cat crossed my path,
how unlucky.
What's he doing?
Has he died?
- Who is it?
- Finally.
It's me, Mrs. Cecconi. Good morning.
Oh, yes. Sorry.
- She's locked herself in.
- Come in.
Another black cat.
- Don't be afraid.
- No. How's the barrister?
- God! Another one.
- Let me tell you.
He's not well.
He's got high temperature again.
The doctor said to start again taking
the Streptomycin every 12 hours.
And not to stop,
even if his temperature goes down.
- Of course.
- You thought this was your last visit.
Instead, you'll have to come back
many more times.
- Luckily.
- What do you mean?
No, I meant, luckily for him
I can come back.
I'll be right there.
I'll take the syringe
and I'll be there in a minute.
I'll be very quiet.
He's not well, after all...
Good for me!
Five days, and the dress is paid. Thank
you, St. Joseph. You're so good to me.
I'll light a candle to you
when it's all finished.
- Eleonora, what are you doing?
- Wait, I'm coming.
Hurry, don't keep the lady waiting.
- This is all the tulle I've found.
- What are you talking about?
- The stockroom is full.
- That's all I've found.
- You're talking rubbish.
- Look, madam.
- Do you like it?
- Beautiful. It looks as soft as a cloud.
- Let me touch it.
- Sure.
- Isn't it a bit hard?
- Look at this other one.
It's a pre-war fabric.
I can give you a good price.
- This looks better. It's very soft.
- See?
This is the pattern –
a fluffy tulle skirt...
and the sleeveless satin leotard.
Have you seen "The Red Shoes"?
I'll make you something like that.
You'll be pleased with it.
You'll be beautiful, darling.
Do you like it?
- I'm a bit concerned about the price.
- Don't worry. I'll give you a good price.
I have had to spend a lot of money
recently for my little girl...
so I thought
I'd mention this just in case.
I'm a nurse,
so should you need any injections...
Are you joking? I hope I won't need them.
I am in very good health.
You don't need to have injections
only when you're ill.
You can also have them when you're
well, to keep in good shape.
Did you come here to jinx me?
No, but maybe you have a relative
who needs treatment.
I'm fine,
I don't need any injections.
The same goes for my family. Right,
girls? I don't buy into these sort of things.
Come here, darling, I'll measure you.
Up here, come on.
That one is so cute.
She must be my daughter's age.
- Yeah, she's young.
- Yes.
Goodness gracious!
Excuse me, madam. Why is she always
keeping her close to the wall?
She'll hurt herself.
Don't worry, she won't hurt herself.
It takes time.
We don't have time, we're in a hurry.
She should put her with the others.
Don't you agree, madam?
She's still keeping her by the wall.
Excuse me, but why is my daughter
always stuck by the wall?
Couldn't you put her
with the others?
They've been studying
for three years.
You came in here saying,
"Make her dance like a butterfly."
What do you expect?
And she's so small.
Why, how old does she need to be?
- Eight.
- We can't wait another three years.
Say what you want, my dear.
She's got tiny legs...
She's got two perfectly straight legs,
can't you see?
Having straight legs is not enough.
You need other things,
such as intelligence.
You dance with your head,
not your feet.
What?
You dance with your head,
not your feet.
My daughter has brains,
she was born healthy, my dear lady!
This is your opinion.
I'm starting to get annoyed.
We are the teachers. We say
if a child is intelligent or not.
I can say that because I'm her mother.
My daughter is not dumb.
Sweetheart.
Why are you crying, my darling?
They're not going to hurt you.
You'll become a good dancer.
Look how good that one over there is.
See? Don't you want
to become like her?
You'll become very good too.
Did you have to make her cry?
How rude.
Let's go home now.
Show me a nice smile.
Don't let Daddy see you cry.
I understand that the child
is a bit disheartened now...
but I'm telling you now that
in this place people study very hard.
I've been dancing for 40 years,
but if I didn't practice every day...
I wouldn't be able to
do arabesques and all the rest.
See?
- Very good.
- Placida, tell the lady.
Yes, madam. In here,
you have to study and sweat.
- Sweat and sweat.
- That's right.
- Hi, Spartaco.
- So, now you go out even after dinner?
And you take the child too.
What else could I do? You were not
here, I couldn't leave her at home alone.
- Where have you been?
- I went to give injections.
Say hi to Dad.
Hello, darling. Give Daddy a big kiss.
- Maddalena.
- Yes?
The instalments have gone up
from 60,000 lire to 65,000 lire.
- Why?
- Because of the lift.
We didn't count that. But everybody
paid for it, and so will we.
What did you get up to?
- Tell Daddy.
- I'm tired.
Little petal.
This is the new house that Daddy has
bought for you. Here we'll put your bed.
And Daddy will buy you a Pinocchio.
Do you know the story of Pinocchio?
The boy whose nose grew longer
because of all the lies he told.
He lied to his father,
an old man who...
Here there's only 60,000 lire.
I don't have any money left.
What am I going to do?
Spartaco, is the instalment definitely
due next Monday?
Yes, on Monday.
It's only an extra 5,000 lire and I have
a few people who owe me money.
You haven't fed the child.
As if I was starving her.
Anything else?
She had a big cup of coffee with milk
and two cookies.
Tell him.
Mum is going to undress you.
- Let me do it.
- Careful, you'll tear her dress.
Okay, do it yourself then.
- Give it to me.
- Dad will put you to bed.
Tomorrow I'll take you out
and buy you a nice ice cream.
Ice cream makes her tummy ache.
Maddalena, go next door.
Sure,
you know I do whatever you say.
Did you see how tired she looks?
Leave me alone.
How pretty. The baby of the house.
Do you love your dad?
Give me a big kiss and a pinch.
Listen, don't tell anything to Mum.
Tomorrow Dad
will buy you an ice cream.
Are you happy?
I have a lesson tomorrow.
A lesson? No, tomorrow
you go out with Dad, no lesson.
Give me a big kiss.
And now go to sleep.
If they're tired, they won't escape.
Don't drive them too hard
the whole time...
See? It's Montgomery Cliff.
He's nice, isn't he?
Maddalena, forget about cinema.
Spartaco, you don't understand me.
Look at those beautiful places.
And look where we live.
When I see these things...
Maddalena, it's a fantasy world.
It's not.
Look. They're taking the wagon across.
Unbelievable.
The horses are in the water.
Lucky them.
It's great, isn't it?
How beautiful.
I'm falling asleep.
- I can't keep my eyes open.
- Come on, let's go to bed.
- Listen, with this ticket you can't...
- No, I'm first!
- I'm in front of her.
- Madam, stop being so pushy.
- I'm not pushy.
- Calm down.
He's holding my ticket and you still
come here and say you are first.
- Where do I go?
- The room next door.
- What is the matter with you?
- So many injustices in this world.
- She just doesn't shut up.
- So pushy.
- Don't you ever get tired?
- I'm so tired I can hardly stand up.
It doesn't look like it.
Look, madam. I had my granddaughter's
photograph taken...
but I made her stand up
because I think she looks better.
- Definitely.
- We only took one, it was so expensive.
- They told me one is enough.
- Of course it's enough.
- Did you want to bring the whole film?
- True.
My child has only got one too.
The photographer wanted to take it while
she was dancing.
I told him that she'd show
what she can do at the audition.
This is if they choose her
for the audition.
I've heard that they've already
made their choice.
We're all wasting our time here.
I wouldn't be saying this
if I hadn't seen it with my own eyes.
- What have you seen?
- Tell us.
Well, yesterday I came here because
I got the days mixed up...
Mixed up! No, she did that on purpose
to get here before all of us.
No, madam, I genuinely made a mistake.
Basically, they were doing
their special auditions.
Yes, for those who were recommended.
I've seen it with my own eyes.
There was a lady with a child...
and she didn't ask for the director.
- She asked for the other one.
- Who?
The fat and ugly one. The one
that yells into the megaphone all the time.
The nasty one.
- Glori!
- So what?
As soon as he saw her, he said
that the girl was very pretty.
What's wrong with that?
My child's pretty too.
He was saying how pretty she was,
but he was looking at the mother.
- Ah, now I understand.
- That's how it goes nowadays.
It doesn't mean anything.
You're just making a big deal out of it.
Do they think we are all stupid here?
Probably, but I know exactly
what that lady is talking about.
But we'll go and speak to the producer,
the director...
and we'll tell them
that this is a disgrace.
It's clear that there are favourites,
while we should all be equal.
Yes, this isn't fair. We have
to do something about it.
Actually, I think my husband knows
someone who works here.
I'll call him and ask him to put
a good word for me with Stella Film.
My husband is a friend of one
of the phone company directors'.
What have the phone company directors
got to do with this?
Well, he's an important person,
that's all that matters.
Don't make us laugh. If we want, we can
all find someone to pull strings for us.
We can all find someone important.
I have a relative who knows
a waiter in Cinecittà.
He knows him very well.
He's got such a good job...
Excuse me, what are you doing?
Federico, I'm in a rush.
- Good morning.
- Bath or shower?
No, thanks.
We just need a trim and set.
That way, please.
Amerigo, a haircut!
- Don't we need the receipt?
- No, it's okay.
- Thanks.
- Can you add colour as well?
- Are you joking?
- She needs lighter hair.
Lighten it? If I take her home
blond, all hell will break loose.
It's just a slight...
She only needs a trim and some curls.
One moment, after this lady it's your turn.
What? Where are you?
They're making us waste time here.
- If it's only five minutes...
- Listen to me.
- We'll give you a good tip.
- That's not the point.
But it's going to take two minutes.
Come here, darling, let me show him.
It's just a trim...
and a couple of curls
over the shoulders.
Can't you see that I'm busy
with this lady?
- But she's almost finished.
- I haven't finished
I've paid, I have my rights.
Do you want to stay here
until tomorrow?
I have another client waiting.
You don't have an appointment.
But it will take you two minutes,
do me a favour.
- Leave her there, I'll serve her later.
- You're so moody.
- Do the balloons bother you?
- It's okay.
You're so kind.
See how kind this man is, darling?
Sit here. Give me the balloons
so I'll tie them here.
- Do they bother you here?
- No.
They'll keep you company.
Mum will be right back.
- Be good. Will we make it back in time?
- Yes, I think so.
If I don't come back, Mrs. Spernanzoni
will come and pick you up.
If I can't make it, a blond lady
will come on my behalf.
She's a middle-aged lady.
Her name is Tilde Spernanzoni.
She looks a bit odd.
She's her acting teacher.
- You'll recognize her immediately. Okay?
- I don't want to stay here!
What do you mean? You have to.
They'll make you so beautiful.
If you have to stay with her,
we can go another day.
No, it's not possible.
Okay. Remember to lighten her hair
to make it a softer shade.
- You want colour.
- No, she's not having it coloured.
Not a real dye.
Just highlights, natural streaks.
Just lighter streaks?
- And a light perm.
- No, don't ruin her hair.
Not a perm, just a set. Her hair's too fine
and won't stay in place otherwise.
- She took it from me.
- I could give you a nice hair-do too.
Don't even try,
no one has managed that.
- I could manage.
- You'd waste your time.
Anyway, how much is it?
- 1,250 lire.
- Shall I pay over there?
- Let's go.
- Be good.
Make sure you just trim her hair,
and curl it a little...
so that when I comb it, it's all fluffy.
- Be good, darling.
- Let's go.
Mum is coming back.
I don't want to stay here!
Hey, you're not alone,
the gentleman is here.
- Be good.
- Bye.
I don't want to stay here!
Don't start. If you behave,
I'll buy you some sweets afterwards.
Be good and I'll curl your hair nicely.
Amerigo, you have to set my hair.
It's still all wet.
Michele will take care of you.
Just a minute.
- I don't want Michele.
- Michele, come here.
Coming!
I want to go home!
I want my mum!
- Yes, Amerigo?
- Trim this child's hair.
How can I? I'm very busy.
- Call Guido.
- Okay, I'll call Guido.
- Hurry up!
- I went to get the shampoo.
- You're always complaining.
- Come on.
- I want to see my mum!
- Guido, give her a trim
I want to see my mum!
Just give the child a trim,
then maybe she'll pipe down.
- Amerigo, are you ready?
- Coming.
- Just a simple trim, okay?
- Yes.
- I'll take care of her.
- Amerigo, hurry up.
- I'm coming.
- Just a little trim?
- Yes, just a trim.
- Let's cut it here... And here.
I had an appointment
and now I am late because of a child.
- That's one done.
- This is ridiculous.
- Amerigo.
- I'm coming.
And that's the second one.
Are you happy?
Are you happy, Miss?
Is that okay?
I wonder what you must be thinking
of me since I asked you to meet me.
What can I think? When a beautiful lady
asks to meet me...
I think well, very well of her.
If you see it like this, even better.
I'm not used to long walks anymore.
Listen, be honest.
Do you think my daughter can make it?
I'm a little discouraged.
For no reason, you convince yourself
that something is very easy to get...
and then you don't think so anymore.
You start feeling worried.
I'm not sure if you know what I mean.
I wouldn't want to make
so many sacrifices...
and then see
someone who's been recommended win.
You do understand me, don't you?
Yes, but it depends on you.
What do you mean?
- A recommendation can help or hinder.
- No, no. It helps.
We're so used to recommendations,
both to making and receiving them.
If they were really worth something,
unemployment wouldn't exist.
In Italy we rely on recommendations,
"Please, don't forget."
"I assure you", "I promise you."
But we can't remember everyone.
Who are we supposed to remember
and why?
- There's only one foolproof method.
- What is it?
Putting the person who needs help...
in a position to ask for your help,
do you know what I mean?
- No.
- Do you already want to leave?
No, it's so lovely here.
I've never been here before.
Actually, I've been here on a Sunday,
but it was too crowded.
Today it's very pleasant.
Yes, it's very nice, but it's not a place
to come to alone.
You should come here
with someone nice.
- Am I nice?
- Very.
In that case, do me this favour, please.
- You're the nicest.
- Even better.
I want my daughter to have
the best recommendation ever.
When the audition is over,
I'll sleep better.
Look, it's as if she'd already auditioned,
the result is certain.
But it all depends on you, it's very simple.
Now I understand.
Do you know what we say in Rome?
"Nothing given, nothing received."
- You're not only funny but also clever.
- Everybody says so.
- And you're quick-witted.
- That's right.
To make a big profit,
one must take a big risk.
50,000 lire sounds fair to me.
You must be out of your mind.
50,000 is a lot of money.
It's not peanuts.
Nowadays, 50,000 is nothing.
Maybe to you,
but to me it means a lot of sacrifices.
In our case, it's the bare minimum
to achieve our goal.
I'll manage the 50,000 lire
and get you a contract.
You'll earn, at least, a million which is
20 times the amount you staked.
Do you think I'll be spending it?
The money's not for me but
for the favours we need to do in return.
Who will you do these favours to?
To everyone and no one.
A bunch of flowers to the producer's
wife, a bottle of perfume to his lover...
who is often the wife
of the leading actor.
Things like that happen.
It's not that they need it...
but it helps them to remember a name.
In this case, your name – Cecconi.
"Mrs. Cecconi, who sent that gift,
is very kind," and so on.
The word will spread quickly.
Have you ever thrown a pebble into a
pond? The pebble falls in just one spot...
but from that spot waves ripple out
until they reach the ocean.
- How shrewd you are.
- Shrewd?
It's a practical way
of getting through life.
Listen, do I have to take this risk
without any guarantees?
What risk would it be otherwise?
Do you want a guarantee?
I'll give it to you.
Your child will have a screen test.
All right?
I'm in.
It's a deal.
Because I do have that sum.
I even brought my savings book
with me, you see?
The problem is,
I need the money straight away.
It doesn't matter.
Let's hurry. Banks are closed now...
but a friend of mine will take my book
and give me the money.
And then she'll withdraw the money
tomorrow.
Listen, if it's a problem for you...
shall we just forget about it?
Moreover...
I wouldn't want to have
a business relation with you.
With you I'd prefer, maybe...
I don't know...
I prefer it this way. It's much better.
Let's hurry, it's late.
- Did you bring the money?
- Of course. Here it is.
One, two, three, four, 50,000.
- Where's the scooter?
- Out here.
Here it is. Do you like it?
You and your beautiful smile
You are easing my pain
You know
that you can't stay away from me
I see you, my beloved
You and your beautiful smile
Tell her that there's no one else
in my heart
Tell her that I love her
more than ever before...
- It's not my fault.
- Look at the state of that girl.
Where's her mother?
Who's complaining?
All I'm saying is, I've had enough!
The child has learned enough.
Do you expect me to thank you
after you've ruined her?
Of course. I'm used
to being thanked and respected.
I thank you and respect you. My wife
has paid you, this is the door. Out!
Your wife is the only one
who understands art.
Art, sure!
- Come on, I said get out.
- Watch your language.
Why are you shouting like this?
- Are you mad? What's happening?
- It happens that I've had enough.
I don't want any strangers in my house.
I won't leave my daughter with her.
In my life, I've never been lucky,
but I have been respected a lot.
Who should be interested
in your daughter anyway?
- Don't exaggerate.
- No, madam.
I've been patient,
but now I've had enough.
Do you understand me?
I've had enough!
Will you stop making a scene?
- Get out, that's the door.
- Spartaco, please.
Let me say something.
Darling. What happened?
Are you asking her? Where were you?
You left the child with this wretch.
- Are you calling me wretch?
- Yes, wretch!
- I'll report you to the police.
- Spartaco, don't make such a fuss.
It looks shorter because
she's got curly hair.
I'll wet it and straighten it out.
- Yeah, make her catch bronchitis.
- I won't make her catch anything.
Madam, why didn't you keep an eye
on her?
- Look at the state of her.
- I'm not paid to look after her.
I'm an actress.
Yes, but you also have eyes.
Or just because you're an actress...
if they cut her head off
you stand by and watch?
This is the door, get out.
- Excuse me.
- Who is she?
Is Mrs. Cecconi here?
- That's me.
- Fracassini the dressmakers.
Shall I leave it here?
Did I get here in time?
I have the invoice with me.
- I must collect the money.
- Thank you.
What did they do to you?
You have short hair.
Don't take me for a fool.
Pay up what you owe me.
That's 1,260 lire
1,000 for yesterday's
and today's lessons...
200 lire for
the child's haircut...
and 60 lire for the tram.
Don't forget it.
Don't get stressed.
We'll pay in full. I'll see to it.
You won't see to anything.
You've got to stop this nonsense.
- Hands off, Spartaco.
- How much do we owe you?
There, 1,260. Now, go.
- I'm 10 lire short.
- We'll give it to you.
- You can keep it.
- How generous. Now, go!
- Scoundrel!
- Out!
You did the right thing
by cutting her hair short.
It will make her feel cooler,
isn't that right?
Why don't you just leave?
- What's in there?
- Don't touch it. It's mine. Don't ruin it.
- I paid it with my money.
- It's not true.
I never asked you for any money.
Spartaco, I beg you,
let's not fight over it.
No, Spartaco! You only act like this
because I'm weaker.
Can't you see
you're scaring the child?
It's been a week from hell here.
You didn't take care of the house at all.
- Am I not in charge anymore?
- I've had enough of you.
I've done far too much for you.
I've done far too much for you!
Get out!
- Get out!
- I'm going to kill you!
- Go on, kill me, you lout!
- Am I a lout?
Concierge! Come down!
He's killing Mrs. Cecconi!
Concierge!
- What's going on?
- Go inside. They're killing each other.
- Concierge!
- I'm coming, just a minute!
- I can't risk breaking a leg.
- It's the Cecconis again.
They're always fighting, damn it!
Are you going to stop it or not?
Spartaco, today you've really
crossed the line.
Don't cry, darling.
I'm leaving this house. Let's go.
Spartaco, what are you doing?
If you take the child,
you won't see me again.
Take her away,
you think I'm not a good mother anyway.
He thinks he's the only one
who loves her and makes sacrifices.
I am the one who ruins her.
And do you know why?
Because I want her
to become somebody.
Yes, that's what I want for my daughter.
Am I entitled to feel this way or not?
She mustn't become a loser.
She mustn't depend on anyone
or get beaten like me.
You don't know
what sacrifices I made...
to find the money
to pay for these little things.
I've been running up and down Rome,
keeping it a secret from him...
not to have to touch his money.
And how does he thank me?
By beating me to a pulp.
Leave now!
Get out! I can't stand the sight of you.
You've ruined me. Look at me.
I'm full of bruises.
I'm full of bruises, look at me.
I'm all swollen.
Go away.
I can't stand the sight of you.
He ruined me.
- Maddalena, stop acting.
- I'm not acting.
Come on, Spartaco.
She's made so many sacrifices.
She went as far as Piazza Vittoriana
for a diabetic. What more do you want?
Give her the child.
I'll settle up with you later.
I don't want to see him again.
This man will be the death of me.
Give me the child.
We made it, honey.
If we didn't do that,
we wouldn't have got an audition.
My dear, do you think
I'm working for nothing?
Cheer up! You have to sing.
The children...
I've even lost my voice,
but you'll see how I sing tomorrow.
My darling.
My sweetheart.
FILMING IN PROCESS
Quiet, please!
What's he saying?
It's the voice of director Blasetti.
I'm going to faint.
Madam.
She's gone mad.
Good morning. My daughter is next.
We're trying to listen here.
Will you let us listen?
- What does she want?
- Madam, please.
If you say so...
Come over here a minute.
I have to tell you something.
- I'm going.
- Good.
I also have to tell you something else.
All the gifts, the presents...
All taken care of.
- Did you send the flowers?
- To Blasetti's wife, of course.
Because it's important, you see.
- What about the perfume?
- To the cameraman.
To the cameraman's wife, actually.
Cigarettes to the cameraman.
Right. And did you send
a big bunch of flowers?
Instead of a bunch of normal flowers,
I sent orchids.
They cost more but are more
impressive. You'll see that the gifts work.
I'm so nervous,
I don't care about anything.
My heart is in my mouth.
My hands are shaking.
- Don't faint like that lady.
- I won't. She was a fanatic.
Who is she? With that funny hairstyle.
That's Mimmetta.
- Hi.
- How are you?
What a rogue you are.
Did you get the scooter?
Yes, I did.
So, how are we inaugurating it?
With a proper launch,
a bottle of champagne.
And maybe even with a patroness.
I don't like ceremonies.
You know, Alberto, I may have a part
in Colamorucci's next film.
Glori promised me.
Well done. Congratulations.
So now you have to thank me, right?
Right.
Mum, I've finished.
- Yes? How did it go?
- Very well.
Mum!
Excuse me, Mr. Annovazzi.
Can I go in? It's my daughter's turn.
- Let me in.
- How rude.
There she is.
She's so pretty.
That dress really suits her.
She looks like a hen. See?
Mummy's sweetheart.
Make up, ready.
You come here.
- What's he telling her?
- Blasetti is explaining to her what to do.
Does she have to eat that cake?
They're lighting the candles. She has to
blow them out as if it was her birthday.
- She won't have to eat it?
- No.
She would have been good at that,
she loves sweets.
Why is he picking her up?
She's cute.
- He kissed her!
- Calm down.
He kissed my daughter! Did you see?
Well, that's how it is.
Everything's going to be fine, I'm sure.
Come to my mother-in-law's restaurant
on Sunday.
And bring along that lady...
what's her name?
- Mimmetta!
- Yes, the one wearing trousers.
Your fiancé, I mean.
You should have seen this child,
she was phenomenal.
All the spotlights were on her.
I felt as if I was in Piazza Navona.
And director Blasetti –
he overawed me.
I couldn't even look at him.
But she was calm and confident.
- So calm.
- She's a very calm child.
While you were so agitated,
as if it was your audition.
- Don't be silly.
- But you were shaking.
Maybe a little. After all, my daughter's
future is at stake here. Right, honey?
Your medicine! I forget everything
these days. My head is in a spin.
You have to take this medicine...
because soon
you have to start working so hard...
that if you don't get a boost...
What is it? Glycerophosphate...
- Sodium glycerophosphate.
- It will do you so much good.
- I don't want it! It tastes nasty!
- Come on.
If you don't take it, I will.
- See?
- You know what's going to happen?
The children who don't take
this medicine turn into geese.
Tomorrow morning,
you'll wake up doing this...
Come on. Take it.
It tastes like water. Quack quack!
- I'm taking it.
- You see?
Did you have to bring this chancer
home with you?
Don't make such a big deal out of it.
Why are you calling him chancer?
You're never happy if you're not
arguing with someone, are you?
Sweet like a cherry.
You know why I brought him here –
he helped me.
Don't pretend you don't understand.
- Here's the fruit.
- Thanks.
- Up with Rome!
Do you support Rome now?
Gosh! Get out of here.
What's the world coming to?
I want him to meet Spartaco
so he can tell you if it's true.
- Mrs. Maddalena!
- Yeah!
- You don't believe me, you'll believe him.
- Come down to the river!
- Are you mad?
- You'll see how cool it is here!
He really is mad.
I can't come because I'm in high heels.
Don't worry.
I'll give you a hand.
Listen to me, come up.
- Are you coming down?
- What a pain! I'm coming then.
- I'm in high heels, it will be a struggle.
- I'll give you a hand.
Careful not to hurt yourself.
I'm coming.
I nearly fell down.
Here you are.
You're mad to make me come here
in these heels.
See how fresh the air is here?
Fresh air? It's bloody hot here.
- It's cooler.
- Don't let me fall.
- Look what lovely greenery and water.
- Where?
This is nature.
But we're so used to it. It's no fun at all.
Then why do you stay indoors
all the time? You can walk down here.
It's shady and cool.
Shady and cool?
This is a refuse dump!
- We're hiding like quails.
- No, no.
Don't push me down. No tricks.
- What... Oh, Lord!
- Don't hit me, or you'll fall.
Let me take off my shoe
because it's full of sand.
Don't push me down there
or I'll take you with me.
- I'll drag you down with me.
- Fine.
Let me take off my shoe.
Heavens! It's full, I'm not lying.
Look.
- Nice soil.
- I must wash my feet. Hold me, please.
- I can't believe this.
- I'll hold you.
Oh, it's so cold.
Oh, Lord!
I am going to have a heart attack.
It's lovely here. Almost better
than the Naviglio canal.
This man is mad.
- I'm glad you came.
- This is madness.
- I really needed it.
- What?
- 10 minutes alone with you.
- Really? Why?
Did you want to thank me
for the gift I gave you?
- What are you talking about?
- What's it like? Does it run well?
How fast can it go?
- I don't understand what...
- Oh, you innocent!
May I give you a piece of advice?
Look after it.
You need to get a cover for it
so it won't get wet.
Because if you ruin it, you won't
find another fool like me ready to buy it.
I hope you don't think that I...
- No. I wouldn't dream of it.
- Seriously.
I don't care how you spent the money.
I knew it from the beginning.
I was interested in getting
what I wanted.
Fix your hair, you look dishevelled.
- You're fun to be with.
- I know, everyone says that.
I'm just too much fun!
So, don't be cruel.
I'm a sweet little angel.
And I'm also obedient.
It's so nice in here –
nice lunch, sunshine...
- All is missing...
- A girl, I know. But you didn't bring her.
- Mimmetta? She's not my girlfriend.
- Really?
We dated for a while and we may
get back together, but right now...
- Did you leave her?
- Me?
I never broke up with anyone.
- What if I told you it was your fault?
- Here we go.
- Where do I come into it?
- You do.
If you want to talk seriously,
we'll talk seriously, if you want to joke...
- I've seen her twice with you.
- Right.
- Is she jealous?
- Yes.
Of me?
Find a better one.
A pretty girl like her.
What am I compared to her?
- Come on.
- Well...
Do you think a girl
can't be jealous of you?
I'm not saying that, but...
- Has your husband ever told you...
- Of course he's told me, many times.
- Let's hope they win.
- Lazio?
- Rome! Let's not fight.
- No, Lazio.
- Woe betide Rome if they lose.
- Okay, then.
That's better.
Let me hear what they're saying.
I can't hear anything from here.
- That's nice.
- No, that's not nice at all.
Keep still. Stop it.
- Who, me?
- You have such a shrewd face!
- Let's be honest.
- Yes, let's.
I've helped your daughter.
I've lost my girlfriend.
You bought a scooter. What more
do you want? Come on!
Lord, how cunning he is.
- What a son of a bitch!
- Yeah.
- I got the scooter I wanted.
- Damn you...
- Life is great, isn't it?
- Sure. Life is great.
It could be great,
instead you only live once...
and life is short and not always good.
I know that you love your husband...
and are happy.
You're happy when
you're with him and the child...
but I also know that today...
right at this moment...
we are happy here together.
Why shouldn't I say so?
It's the truth.
We understood each other perfectly.
It's nice here. And I...
I'd love to hug you.
Is there anything wrong
in saying so? I don't think so.
For example, if my mother...
who's quite old now...
had let someone hug her
when she was young...
in the sunshine,
on the riverbank like this...
instead of tormenting herself
by thinking...
what my life would be like
as an adult...
today maybe she'd be less sad.
She spends her days mending my socks
and washing my shirts.
My mother.
Everything that she's given up...
she's turned it into hopes for me.
Bless her.
And now, like Mimmetta, she too
does nothing but say to me all day...
"Be a go-getter. Be a go-getter."
I am a go-getter.
You know that very well.
I never pass up any opportunities
that come my way.
I don't live in a dream world.
But I don't want to have any regrets.
Am I right, Maddalena?
Don't make me end my Sunday...
counting the ants on the sand.
Listen, Maddalena.
Have you ever tried
letting yourself go?
Doing one of those silly things
people do just like that...
once in a while,
without thinking much...
like rich people do
when they throw money away.
That's the best feeling.
It spices up our lives.
It's everything.
Do you know that in this light
your eyes are blue?
Or maybe green, like the water.
They change according to the light.
Now they're very light
and seem to be smiling.
Come on now, you're talking nonsense.
Look at this, I'm all dirty now.
- Why did you stand up?
- Because I have to go.
Do you want to stay
and count the ants?
Stay, if that pleases you.
I can send you my mother-in-law,
so that she can give you a hand.
Let's go.
Aren't you coming?
Or do you want to go in the water,
to cool yourself down?
Let's go. We need to see
the screen test. Hurry up, come on.
Poor dishevelled fellow.
It wasn't your lucky day.
Never mind.
You'll be luckier another time,
don't worry.
Let me get my jacket.
If you want to see the screen test,
come to the editing room in Cinecittà.
- Ask for Iris, okay?
- Yes, thanks a lot.
Good-bye.
Good-bye everybody.
Did you take your shoes off as well?
Can I come in?
Is Iris here?
That's me. Come in.
- Am I disturbing you?
- No, do come in.
Mr. Annovazzi told me
to come and see you.
He mentioned that.
I was expecting you.
- He said you have the screen tests.
- Yes.
Of all the girls?
- Then you have my daughter's too.
- Which one is she?
- This one here.
- Number 7. It's in the can.
- What do you mean, in the can?
- To be taken to the viewing room.
Ah, the film itself. I see.
- Can I see it then?
- This is a different screen test.
- Ah, it's another child.
- Right.
It's not very clear.
She sounds like a cat.
She gives me the shivers.
- Can you show me my daughter's now?
- You must be joking.
Blasetti is waiting for me downstairs.
Iris, hurry and bring the tests
down as Blasetti is waiting.
- I'm coming.
- He's angry.
- Room number 3.
- Okay, bye.
- Are they watching the screen tests?
- Yes.
- Including my daughter's?
- I'm begging you, let me see it.
- Sorry, it's not possible.
- I've come all this way.
- I am going to end up in trouble.
- But who'll see me?
- Nella, you tell her.
- Try to understand.
- It's just impossible.
Hey, do I know you?
Where have I seen you?
Help me to remember.
- Tell her. Are you ashamed?
- You saw me in a film.
That's right. At the outdoor cinema.
That really nice Roman film...
"Under the Sun of Rome."
- Yes.
- What a nice film.
You were the one who got slapped.
I've enjoyed it so much.
Do you remember her, honey?
You loved it too.
What do you do now?
Are you in this film?
No, I don't make films anymore.
- I work here. I do editing.
- So you don't make films anymore.
Why?
I'm not an actress.
They only hired me once or twice...
as I was the type they needed.
I even got my hopes up.
And I lost my job and my boyfriend.
All I can say is, either you are
a professional actor...
or give up your dreams
and stick to a real job.
I'm sorry to tell you this,
because you're full of hopes.
You might be right, but I doubt it.
So many people ended up badly
thinking they'd make it in cinema.
I convinced myself I was
so great and so beautiful...
and yet, I'm stuck here, doing editing.
Nobody called me, so I'm here.
Really?
Poor you. But I'm sure
it's not the same for everyone.
That would be terrible.
That would be really terrible.
Irreparable.
I risked everything for her.
I'd be disappointed..
Don't worry...
everything will be fine.
She's so pretty.
- Did you see the screen test?
- Yes, I did.
- Is she cute?
- Yes, very.
Please, let me see it.
- How can I?
- Let me see it.
How can I? Nella, what do you say?
Shall I send her up?
- Why not, give it a try.
- No one will see me.
I'll stand behind you.
You're so kind.
I'll take you there,
as long as you stay quiet.
I won't say a word.
I won't move.
Thank you.
It's my daughter's screen test.
Please let me stay.
You're very kind.
You see her?
That's the girl who was
at the photographer's. Remember?
- Do you see her?
- Yes.
Quiet, or they'll throw us out.
- What's her name?
- Maria Cecconi.
That's you.
Gosh, how small you look from afar.
What are you doing? Oh, yeah,
you're blowing out the candles.
Blow, blow!
Poor thing!
Couldn't you manage?
You have so much breath at home,
but not there?
My goodness,
you make me feel ill.
She really can't do this.
Stop it, guys!
I can't work like this.
Guys, please. Enough!
- Who brought her, Glori?
- Not me.
- Maybe him, Annovazzi.
- Did you bring her?
I only directed her here
because her mother asked me.
Now the poem.
You recite it so well.
"Venice, to thee comes at last
the last hour.
"Martyr illustrious, in thy foe's power.
"Bread lacks, the cholera deadlier grows.
"From the lagoon bridge
the white banner blows."
Did you cry?
Why did you start crying?
They're amused, see?
Perhaps you made them laugh.
"Venice,
to thee comes at last the last hour..."
What are they laughing at?
What are they saying?
Not good things.
Why are they laughing so much?
Why are they so amused?
She's a dwarf, look.
Bastard.
I can't take this. I can't take this.
What's all this? Isa, stop the film
and restart it from the beginning.
- What's so funny?
- She's so funny with that fringe.
She's not a kid, she's a dwarf –
she went to school with me in 1925!
- Are you saying you're 30 years old?
- Good.
- What do you think?
- It's a counter-productive test.
I see.
Excuse me, but if I may say
my opinion...
this last screen test is a waste of film.
I would have realized straight away
that the child was going to do that.
I have already told you...
Your name is Annovazzi, isn't it?
You were in the Army, right? Stand up.
Good. By the left.
By the left!
Quick march. Get out!
- Go away, because...
- Sorry, Blasetti.
If you carry on like this, you're out.
I won't be able to hire you anymore.
- You have no chance.
- At least let me apologize.
Do I have to lose my job
for such a silly thing?
- Let me apologize to him.
- I'll do that for you.
See, Blasetti, I was right.
We wasted time, money and film.
Time, money, film and health.
Our health, because we've been looking
non stop for two weeks for this girl.
And now you tell us that we've wasted
money. Stop it, Filippo!
You've been laughing until now. Go and
check what's happening over there.
- No, let me in.
- You can't come in.
Leave me alone, keep your hands off.
- Calm down.
- I want to talk to the director.
- What do you want to say to him?
- What?
What was so funny about this little girl?
Where is he? There he is.
Mr. Blasetti, listen...
Let me through. Let me through.
Excuse me, Mr. Blasetti...
but I was hiding up there in the booth.
I've heard you all laugh.
What was so funny?
Why does she make you laugh
so much? She's like any other child.
- One of you even called her a dwarf.
- No, no.
How rude! You've no respect
for other people's feelings.
You've no respect
for other people's sacrifices.
I made so many sacrifices
to buy her this dress...
- Calm down, madam.
- And the other guy, that Annovazzi...
- Where is he?
- We've thrown him out.
Well done. You're a person who
understands. You did the right thing.
- Let me speak.
- Well done to you.
How can we tell if someone
is hiding in the projection booth?
Mr. Blasetti, please,
don't send me away like this...
without a glimmer of hope.
You see, Antonelli?
This is cinema.
We're responsible for all this.
Glori, come here.
We can't deal
with the mothers too.
- Isa, put reel number 7 back on.
- The one with Maria Cecconi.
I want to see the test again.
Do you want to go?
- No, I'll watch it again too.
- I'm pleased.
The dwarf in the land of the giants.
Blasetti, remember that I'm a Northerner.
I come from Milan,
I never go to Donei's.
- You can get good deals there.
- Do you go to Motta's?
Quiet now, please.
"Today, tomorrow and never"
Seventh screen test.
Help!
Annovazzi! Alberto, wait for me.
Stop.
We need to find that child
who did the screen test.
The one that made us laugh.
What was her name?
- Cecconi.
- Yes, Cecconi.
Blasetti wants her.
Blasetti kicked me out,
it's no longer my business.
Don't be stupid.
- We must find her.
- You find her. I'll give you the address.
It's Via Alberto da Giussano, 4.
Bye.
If you find her, and if we sign
the contract this evening...
you'll work on this film, I promise you.
- Swear.
- I swear. I give you my word.
She lives in Prenestino,
via Alberto da Giussano, 4.
I'll go ahead, you take the car.
Da Giussano, 4? I'm off.
Orsini, hurry. You go. Orsini!
The contract is ready and signed by the
producer. All we need is your approval.
- We have the best actors, like...
- Amedeo Nazzari.
- And that American actress...
- Lana Turner. If not her, a better one.
Absolutely.
Maybe he's not interested in this
because he's worried about his wife.
Don't worry, your wife will be back.
She's not a child.
Are you worried? I'll take care of that.
The police and us are very close.
Orsini, go straight to Via Genova...
and talk to Superintendent Giusillo.
Tell him Glori sent you...
and that I need a favour.
- They even find people who drown.
- Forget about the police.
He's right.
My wife will be here soon. She always
wants to do things her own way.
I'd really like to know where she's gone.
I've asked somebody to let me know
when she arrives.
Take a seat.
- Orsini, you can go.
- We can discuss the contract.
Fine. So...
"With this private agreement,
we hire Maria Cecconi...
"as the leading young actress..."
Spartaco.
She's here, come up.
She's here.
After all you've done, you made it.
Stand back. Don't touch her.
- Don't touch her.
- Maddalena.
Hi, Spartaco. Don't wake her up.
Don't wake her up.
Let me through.
Don't touch her.
- Thank goodness she's here.
- Her husband was waiting for her.
- Her eyes are red.
- She's been crying.
What's going on, Maddalena?
You made it.
For once you're right,
and you start crying!
Let's sign this contract.
We don't have many options.
Either we sign that contract
or we end up in the street.
She's crying again.
Here she is, our Greta Garbo.
Don't you dare touch her.
Don't touch her.
Come on, let's sign the contract.
We just need one signature.
And I'll give you 250,000 lire
immediately.
A further 250,000 in a week,
and more in two weeks.
I'll give you the first instalment
straight away.
Where's the cheque book?
Do you have it, Alberto? No.
It must be at Cinecittà.
I'll be right back to pay you.
It's two million lire.
You're going to get two million.
Plus a thousand lire a day
that no one can take away.
Don't turn your back on this,
it only happens once.
Please, just sign it.
Very well.
Do you want her with curly hair
or straight hair?
Does she have to lisp or stutter?
Which one do you find funnier?
Haven't you had enough fun,
all of you?
I'm really sorry...
but my daughter is staying here.
I didn't bring her into this world
to amuse anyone.
To me and to her dad she's beautiful.
She's beautiful.
We're keeping her here.
Go now, or you will wake her up.
Go away.
Spartaco, what are you waiting for
to tell these gentlemen...
that your daughter
will never make films?
Kick them out.
Kick them out, Spartaco.
Maddalena!
Maddalena, can you hear me?
I don't think there's much we can do.
I know her very well.
Take the contract
and go back to Cinecittà. I'm sorry.
What are you doing?
You're always a nuisance.
Really? We're always a nuisance?
What about you,
with all the racket you make?
I'm the concierge. Don't I have the right
to tell these ladies...
what goes on in the building
where I work?
- Am I right or not?
- Be quiet. The child's sleeping.
- Be quiet.
- Let's go because the child's sleeping.
Do me a favour
and take these cows away.
Are we cows now?
Quiet. My daughter is asleep.
Go away.
What are you doing still here?
You'd better stop it,
or I'll send down my husband.
Send whoever – your grandfather,
your uncle... Just go away!
How rude!
How will I look in front
of the producer and everyone else?
And Orsini, who's got the car, has left.
How do we get back to Cinecittà?
I'll give you a lift on my scooter.
Let's go.
- Good night.
- Good night, or rather, good-bye.
Good-bye.
That damned outdoor cinema.
Always disturbing us.
My poor little house.
My poor little house,
what's going to happen now?
Give me my usual four slaps.
Give them to me
so that you'll feel better. Go on.
What are you waiting for, Spartaco?
This crazy wife of mine.
Don't worry about the house.
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
I'll pay for everything.
Even if I had to kill myself with work.
Even if I had to get everyone
in Rome to develop diabetes.
Don't worry, Spartaco.
Don't worry.
- Can you hear him?
- Who?
Burt Lancaster. He's so nice.
Maddalena,
now you really deserve a slap!
Am I not allowed a joke anymore?
Quiet, don't talk,
don't wake the child up.
Don't wake the child up.
Translated by Lorena Uras