Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
WARNING: these subs are google translated from Finnish!
The film is based on a true story
Germany 1936
Berlin is preparing to
Olympic Games.
U.S. threatens to boycott races if
Germany to ban Jewish athletes.
Bergmann Gretel one time
of the best high jumper -
and a Jew.
Officials are trying to prevent
he will be paid -
and looking for him for a better
athletes ...
Ketteler and Marie ...
is part of the plan.
BERLllNl IS VALMllNA
Joining me von Halti.
This is important. -Good morning.
Sports Ministry. Tschammer und
Von Osten wants to talk to Halti ...
Marie!
Marie?
Why did not you answer?
What does this have now again?
Take in the laundry!
Hurry up, Emma.
Have you seen this?
This.
Large demonstrations in New York.
U.S. Secretary of demanding
ambassadors to him.
They threaten to boycott,
josjuutalaisia ??are not included.
What is the height of the jumper's situation is?
-Everything is taken care of.
Ms. Bergmann is on its way to Germany.
Is he really that good?
He won the British championship.
-What about us our women?
Lilly Vogtja ...
-Thea Walden?
They can be improved upon.
There must now be found by someone,
which is that Jews were better!
Ladies and gentlemen naisetja -
may I present: the British
champion in high jump -
Gretel Bergmann, a German girl!
Drinks on me!
No, given the house to pay them.
They do not pay me
anyway enough.
Father!
How are you here?
Were you the stadium?
-Of course.
Congratulations, my dear.
Would you drink?
-No, thank you.
How can a mother?
-Well.
Very well.
-What about Walter?
He also.
Wait and see.
Rudolph took a picture of us.
ltselaukaisulla. It is for you.
Thank you. What has happened to your hand?
It was crushed.
Would you come out with me for a moment?
What's the matter? -Some people would like,
that you will return to Germany.
You will need to participate in
olympialaisvalmisteluihin.
I need to do what?
U.S. threatens to boycott the games.
I will not return.
-Hitler's racial politics.
I do not go back there!
Father, they have not given my
even to practice. -It's true -
but you are now the British champion.
Everything is different now.
Now this was your idea.
-I know.
You told me when I'm in London,
does not have to worry about.
Now we have to fear,
if you do not return.
Nothing is too much for them.
Not even the spirit of exploitation.
There is talk about this more tomorrow.
Good night, sweetheart. -Good night.
I ...
Hi ...
It's all right.
Welcome, Mr. Brundage.
-Thank you.
Mrs. Vogel.
Ritter von Halti know you.
-Karl.
Thank you for your warm welcome.
Mr. Brundage,
Ask questions.
Can Jews be
German sports association?
Do not. -Not at all my
Association in Chicago ...
If a Jewish athlete runs
100 meters in 10.3 seconds -
whether they participate in the Olympic Games?
How nice if he can not
to practice? -Of course you can.
As you may know, we invited
juutalaisurheilijat test matches.
A farce!
Every one of them
can cope with races.
So they get to participate?
Of course.
All right.
Hi, Mom.
-Darling.
Do you recognize me yet?
I am your brother, it is a genius.
Thank you, genius.
At least you could enjoy a little bit more.
Where is Walter?
-Oh yeah, you know not.
He is in the hospital.
It seems bad.
Hello, Walter.
Still have not grown up?
-Look at this.
Now I have them all.
Your daughter is right now a celebrity.
Oletjo 1 7-years old. Are not
not yet started your period?.
When were you last a doctor?
-I do not know.
It is estimated that?
I've never been sick.
Remove vaatteesija stand over there.
There are some good aspects of this, Gretel.
What could I do?
I would like to hear it.
Would we have been forfeited?
-After all, I came.
He's right.
Why did he bites one's food?
Without food I am weak and I can not
jump, the Nazis and do not choose me.
What a charming logic.
They can force me to return to,
but not the beat -
their father's land.
This is yours isanmaasi.
Do not miss it.
No more.
Your father fought in the war for this country
on behalf of, and almost lost his life.
Where are you, Emma?
You need to feed the chickens.
Where is he?
-Who?
What are you doing?.
What have I said?.
Is this a suitable book for girls?
I sanonutjo a thousand times!
This house is like a madhouse!
Gretel?
We were guests: Mr. Lowenstein
Jewish sports association.
I do not want to take your time in a long time.
May I?
I can imagine
how does this affect you.
First, you run the country
and then claimed back.
They can not dictate,
how high I jump.
He's going to embarrass the Nazis.
-I do not let them use me.
Do not you?
I think Gretel is right.
This field should not be disclosed to them
without a fight.
Probably because
you it should not be considered here.
Imagine that you win a medal.
The whole nonsense of the Aryan race
superiority of any meaning.
If you want to really embarrass the Nazis,
you will have to overcome them.
That's what I said.
You are the great hope of many, Gretel.
Perhaps you are considering this yet.
We can not in any way Berg's over.
All are waiting for the U.S.,
that he will participate in the preparation of -
and I say directly:
U.S. participation will depend on.
He participates in
In any event exercises.
Cognac?
-I'd love to.
Excuse me.
Two-brandy.
Well?
We might have
Gold medal candidate.
What do you mean "might"?
The matter is somewhat delicate.
Here is a doctor's statement.
Does somebody
In addition to doctors about this?
What is it?
If Lowenstein is right, they do not
can not let me in Berlin.
I believe that they do not have
other choice.
What if anything happens to me?
What could happen to you?
Keep in mind that the Americans
are on our side.
I wonder if my daughter
yet sometimes a smile for me?
Keep your head up.
Marie!
Marie, come here!
Gretel Bergmann.
Waldmann, Hans.
National coach.
-It was he.
Days.
-Days.
Come. I'll show room.
You do not appear to korkeushyppaajalta.
I've never seemed
But despite -
sivusin German records.
How long has it been?
Your tongue is sharp, at least.
Come on.
This is your room.
Who is sleeping in another bed?
No one.
So you can bring
your boyfriend here.
Is that allowed?
lltaruoka served at 19
Marie Ketteler?
Come.
You know who I am?
-I know.
lstuutukaa.
You kohdallanne
many things have gone wrong.
Normally I would get
sends you into a mental hospital.
I would not want
that this will need to go to it.
If it happens to you, I offer my help.
You would like the captain of the ship.
-So.
I can see to it
that you will get a decent education.
You would have to be
to do something about it.
What?
To serve your native country.
The task is not easy,
But you can do it.
Have you already esittaytyneet?.
Gretel, here are Lilly and Thea.
lstuutukaa.
A vain hope. The boys leave tomorrow.
-Too bad.
You've probably heard Gretel
success in England?
Let me make this clear:
elsewhere, you can rip each other's eyes
to get, but here you behave.
You can read the Bible or the Talmud.
Here, only the mean
suorituksetja success. Is that clear?
Well done.
Let's see what kind of endurance
is. Light warm-up run.
Posture, Lilly.
You need to keep your body
as long as possible straight.
A little more boldly.
Add to the dynamics of speed deployment.
Come on.
It remained at the optimum posture.
Completely error-free.
Perfect, Gretel.
Well done. This was not the first bad;
But remember -
leave your burdens to the ground. Every
jumping is like a flight to heaven.
You will become lighter than the birds.
Then there is jaahdyttelyjuoksu.
Go ahead.
155 centimeters?
How many times have you jumped in?
-Three times.
Three times?
A medical report is missing.
Why do you have my saippuani?
What do you need?
-It belongs to me.
So. It is Thean soap.
You know what?
Gave it to you.
Who are you?
Marie.
Did not you see,
bunk that is already taken?
I can not sleep at the top.
I am the way Gretel.
You do not have a particularly talkative.
What do you write?
In my diary.
-Interesting.
And who is H. W.?
Hans Waldmann.
What is it called?
"H. W. argues sivunneensa
German records in the past.
I asked, almost,
what type of sport. "
I'm glad you asked. Mr. Waldmann
is reportedly angry long.
The new roommate has jumped
This year, 155 centimeters.
Is that right?
I would not have believed it of him.
That is why I told you about it.
You now have four.
Only three can go to Berlin.
Out of bed.
He will do everything.
-Do not you then?
What is this?
Feet in front of another, come on!
Not to stay kuhnailemaan!
Not bad,
But that is not the height of the jump.
Technique, ladies!
Who's next?
Gretel.
Perfect, Gretel.
Would somebody is going to the ticket?
Well, do not ujostelko.
Excellent.
What about you, Thea?
Almost.
You're welcome.
Sport, seeking information about
women's abilities on a regular basis.
Of course.
How Marie Ketteler doing?
-Very well.
I have not seen a doctor for an opinion,
even though I asked for ...
Sport should be happy,
if Ketteler to reach Berlin.
I wonder what he thinks?
I coach a girl -
but he has to jump alone.
Or nostanko him enough self-confidence?
It is up to you how to do it.
Do not underestimate
her potential.
Heil Hitler!
"Perfect, Gretel."
Did you bring this time with its own saippuasi?
-I brought. It looks the same as yours.
You need to improve vauhdinottoasi.
You will be too much in front.
If you want, I can show you.
It does not matter, provided that the strip
remains at the top. -If you say so.
Do you think that I do not know,
that you are Jewish?
What does that mean?
We left, certainly the first.
"Fast as the greyhound,
tough as leather -
and hard as Krupp steel. "How
old are you? To 17-year-old. What do you mean?
Production of a disappointment to you.
I am not sure the source first.
What is it? What are you waiting for?.
Why do you call that?
Speak the manner in
which you try to exceed the bar.
Have you ever heard of saksauksesta?
Could you perhaps
show it off to us?
Or at least try?
What was that?
-I do not know.
The first Saksauksessa
the other foot, and then another!
Give her time now!
I beg your pardon?
-The technology is new to him.
Would you like to perhaps
results in practice?
What does that really was?
Take care of your own business.
I'm sorry.
Why do you tackle even the affairs of others?
-Why do not you have the other room?
I asked already.
-And?
Do not have any free.
Marie, we need to talk.
Then I travel to Berlin
magnificent white uniforms -
and I win the gold -
Fuhrer and then shaking hands with me.
Decathlete come!
Come on!
Days.
Hey.
Did you select the one already?
Very beautiful.
Is that him?
-Who?
He looks different in the picture.
That's true.
Somehow the better, is not it?
-So.
Are you here?
What do you want?
-It is he.
Can I get your signature?
It will kerailyalbumiini.
That's funny. -What is he?
I asked politely.
Great Britain's champion!
Is it a success, perhaps risen to the head?
Or do you like yourself better than others?
Be careful that it does not only end badly.
Do not want to raise them?
I interrupting something?
Who did this?
I want to know who did this!
I see. Women like one.
Well ... It's actually a good thing.
Too bad only the images with respect.
Enter them here.
Thea?
I wish I could see so much effort
in front of your training.
Thea is a stupid bitch.
Heil Hitler!
The Fuhrer asked me to convey to you
best wishes.
He puts hope in you, so
Please do not disappoint him.
If you could
to give up for a while ... trainers?
Hurry up then! You know what to do.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
We read the report.
Do you want to add something?
I think we can be
very pleased with the results.
I will be brief. It seems,
that you are not suitable for this position.
Fingertip feel when this is needed,
which you clearly is not.
If you are asking for,
I prefer that one of the girls ...
This is a sport, not politics!
-No.
This is a
merge them into one another.
That's why our roads that fork now.
I ask you to clear this
sty immediately.
Heil Hitler .
What actually happened over there?
Just like you do not know.
You were always his favorite.
"Perfect, Gretel. Good, Gretel."
You are unusually stupid detractor.
-I would be more prudent to assume your identity.
Is that your boyfriend?
-No, but my brother Rudolph.
You do not look alike.
-He comes from my mother. Look.
Will you get along well?
We will, and fighting repeatedly.
What about your parents?
My father is often traveling for work purposes.
He has a hiuslisaketehdas.
Your mother looks nice.
He is like all mothers.
He complains about all the time.
He brought the noise to London departing
due. When the father told him about it -
He locked themselves in their room
for two days in protest.
Then he blamed my father
week on how this release -
his daughter alone to London.
What is your mother doing?
I aitiniko?
Create manure in the barn. To milk the cows.
Hit their children.
What about your father?
-My mother drove him away from the farm.
Have you read this many times already?
-I am, very many.
Do you want it?
Thank you.
Mr. Waldmann left yesterday
due to a sudden family matter.
Derivative I now practice.
I Sigfrid Kulmbach.
Say as soon as
that things are changing here.
It is your own good.
There is talk of more in the field.
Enjoy your meal.
It's nice to see you, Ms. Bergmann.
Do you know him?.
You get to run more,
especially Gretel -
whose condition is room for improvement,
but we're working on it.
Gretel, five laps the field
round. Others come with me.
Now you can rest.
What about after that?
-Yet another five rounds.
Marie, Lilly, Thea.
Well done. Heal at all times.
How are you?
-Well.
Well done.
Marie, go sit in the other creates.
Do you work at all,
what the coach tells you?
I do not know. I ...
How long are you?
"Nobody could have predicted his heart
the amount of bitterness.
It was the perfect protective curtain
a deadly mission. "
What exactly is it done?
Captain Gundolf is a spy,
which attracts enemies into a trap -
and then ...
-Will he?
Do not want to read to the end?
I want to.
Gretel?
Would you show it to me yet?
What?
-The way in which the German.
Maybe.
So.
Curve of this back over the bar,
and ponnista ...
Is not transmitted to them.
A little further away.
That's it. Then ...
What are you doing?
-Is not it obvious?
I do not remember requesting your help.
Training will start after breakfast.
I have not jumped in your times
at all times. -In time.
Why do not you immediately dashed
my feet? -Continue in my office.
Close the door. Thank you.
I thought you realize this.
Access to Berlin
depends on their performance.
Why do not you let me jump in?
Of course, you jump.
It is your kohdallanne
Timing is important.
I have no you,
but I admire your gifts.
Let us not fool ourselves. Aryan
girls like to show rajanne.
I prepare you for it, if only
injury due.
You look exhausted.
Perhaps you would like to rest a couple of days.
It is not necessary.
You are an intelligent young woman.
I'm getting you certainly see things
my way.
What happened?
He wants you to give up.
"Perhaps you would like to rest
a couple of days, "he said.
The right pig!
Why should you donate blood?
You are the best.
Marie, a ten-fighters called the
us to join him.
One of them has a birthday.
What's the matter? -Nothing.
Today in the evening, at eight o'clock.
Am I really think is the best?
Well, maybe only second best.
Will you come with me?
I'll go only if you're going.
You look great.
-So are you.
Wait and see.
Sons of fingers do not
out of you.
lltaa.
Would you like to dance?
-Do not you know who I am?
Ask them if they say yes.
What is it?
Ernst, the decathlete.
Do you know what, he asked?
That I can help him improve
his high jump technique.
Have you had
never a boyfriend?
Is it even once?
What about you?
After all, they had a few.
What about now?
Now I only have my coach.
Good night, Marie.
-Good night.
Thank you.
Did you read the report already Kulmbachin?
-Of course.
What's in it Berg Mann? His
adequate performance in Berlin.
Do not worry about it.
We have full confidence in Kulmbach.
How can you be so sure?
-I know him.
He uses unusual,
but effective ways.
He does not have much time left.
I hope he understands it.
Then there are the Marie
and Ms. Bergmann.
All right. This is enough.
-What do you mean?
Are you afraid of the world record?
-Save it for later.
Hi, Open up!
Hello!
You can take this.
There is a gap in the laundry. I'm going to apply for
help. -You do not do anything.
Ow!
Where do you come from?
Yes?
Can I come in?
-You.
I wanted to tell you about it.
They forced me to ...
-Leave me alone.
Get out of here.
What happened?
Nothing.
Riitelitteko-?
We do not. Someone locked us into the shower.
Did you notice ... Marie How
its now saying ... Something weird?
I do not.
I hope your foot
did not make it worse.
We need to talk.
Who else knows?
-None.
I was examined by a doctor.
-Who else?
Tschammer und Osten. You represent a good-
friends, but you're one of them!
I do not.
Is this too organized thing?
This here, now? -No!
You realize everything wrong.
You need to replace me.
-No!
Why do they put the boy girl
clothes? -They do not put.
I have always used the
girls' clothes.
I do not understand.
My mother insisted on
to get the girl.
I had a sister,
who died a half year old.
How can anyone not noticed that you do not
not a girl? -She gave birth to me alone.
The coach wants to talk to you.
-Why?
He did not say.
All right.  Heil Hitler!  Check!
, Given your
You surely do not want to sit down.
Sometimes people think
strange things.
Especially if they happen to be
shock state.
In which state of shock?
If I get to hear rumors of -
sick rumor, which may
damage to the German sports ...
I assume that you do not know what I'm talking.
We do not.
So far so good.
Indeed, we would destroy
those rumors immediately.
One more thing. I was 10 minutes
Then a call from Berlin.
Based on their performance -
you have survived the races.
However, you are missing
competition experience.
He is a British champion.
That is why we decided to
with the Ministry of Sport -
send him
Wurttemberg championships.
When? -The day after tomorrow.
Or is producing problems with your feet?
No.
Much of your day.
Why did not you tell?
-Are you crazy?.
What do you think you have them do to me,
if they hear that I know?
Be glad then, that the
I was silent. -Not funny.
I'm serious.
We get this done in only one.
"We"?
Actually, it's a compliment.
What?
That they laittavat man to compete with
against me.
So.
It was a joke.
I realized, yes.
-Is that so?
Do you have the cream yet?
-It is, in the room.
You can sleep alasangylla, if you want.
-Thank you.
Is it any better?
What does not kill you, it strengthens.
They agreed that if a win gold,
I get to live as a man.
Think you can do it?
I'm supposed to give you wins.
Would you do that?
I do not.
Ladies first .
Do you like me a thumbs up?
How does the captain Gundolfin happen?
Which revealed the he in the end?
His people for his own shot him.
World Athletics Championships
Ms. Bergmann.
-Heinz!
Do you remember? We went to the same school.
Come. The competition has already begun.
Make haste.
How many people are still with me?
-None.
Yeah, but ... -You have the list.
Everything is agreed.
When is my speech?
-Now.
-I have not warmed.
-I can not help it.
We were just informed that Gretel
Bergmann comes a special reason  -
high jump competitions that
and height 142 start .
Gretel!
You're not going to be discouraged?
Do I have to tell you how
I know you? Look at me.
The more mud they at you
throw, the better you become.
1.42 is not a thing to you.
Show them!
News from Stuttgart.
-I am listening.
Bergmann took first place.
He was just overwhelming.
He almost broke the
the world record. -All right.
What time is it in New York?
-10 In the morning.
Try to get Mr. Brundage
closed as soon as possible.
Gretel!
-I am very happy. Congratulations!
Thank you.
-Congratulations, sister.
Thank you. I brought you something.
What a gorgeous!
It is even swastika!
I also have something for you.
-What?
Telegram from New York.
-Give me.
"Congratulations on your victory ...
and access to the Games. STOP.
See you in Berlin in an interview.
STOP. Pensionat Hardke. Jackson. "
Who is Jackson?
-New York Herald journalist.
Where is Walter?
-He is lying on the couch.
Is he sick?
-He threw up.
While removing it.
What am I going to hear at all?
Sorry. Where are you hurt?
What links here? Tanneko?
You've been in a fight.
Why?
Because of my nicotine?
-They talked bad about you.
Bergmann .
How many there were?
-Four.
Come to the phone.
Thank you.
Marie Ketteler.
I'm sorry for you.
-So, you won.
They could not stop me.
-What a nice to hear.
We'll see,
Do you find it nice to be in Berlin.
Thean hand broken.
Oh, poor abused.
-So.
Say hello to the other.
-I say.
See you soon.
I first thought that there was
a young man. -My God!
He has a very low voice.
Raise a toast.
Gretel prevail!
Well done. U.S. Olympic Team
was sent properly.
Continue according to plan.
Try to come up with
of a suitable press.
I have not seen for a long time
anything so beautiful.
Is it possible to talk about
Mr. Brundage with?
Perhaps the ship through the radio. It should
first to agree. -What are you waiting for?
I took it.
Right or left?
-Left.
Sports Ministry.
What does it say?
This can not be true.
What exactly is wrong?
Reading now.
"You will not believe in self-
recent performance
enough to gain entry to competitions. "
What is this?
Ticket to Ride for women
Olympic high jump to the rail.
Gretel!
Would you like something?
Have you heard of Mr. Lowensteinista?
It is as the earth would have swallowed him up.
Not even his wife does not know
where he is.
hereby declare the Berlin World Championships  -
and 11 modern Olympic Games
session opened!
We can start.
What about Gretel?
-He will come later in the stern.
What is he?
He was injured.
What is it?. The bus can not wait.
Please buy the Olympic News, 20 pennies!
U.S. and Canadian teams
have arrived.
Days.
Gretel! There you are.
I do an interview with the Olympic village.
See you tomorrow night.
-Where, Mr. Jackson?
Here, in my room. It is the number 7
-But ...
Karl!
-Welcome.
This way, please.
How are you?
Would you have a moment?
-Of course.
I understand that Ms. Berg's palsy
is worse than expected.
This is the case, unfortunately.
We do not give up hope.
We keep his place vacant.
That's right I said to the press.
Perfect.
Well done.
Marie!
-Gretel, what are you doing here?
Do you have a minute?
-I have to ...
What is your disability case? -Did
them that I hurt?.
This must be a mistake.
What are you doing now? -I will meet later
American journalists.
I have to go. Will there
later? Where do you live?
Pensionat Hardkessa
Mommsenstrassella.
See you.
-See you.
GERMANY OLYMPlAJOUKKUE
Late again. Hurry up!
-Where were you?
American Supplier wanted
interview. Sinultako-?
So. Who else?
-You do not speak English.
Mr. Jackson?
Ms. Bergmann?
-Yes?
A man is waiting for you downstairs.
Hello?
Underestimated you.
I was sure,
that failed you in Stuttgart.
What do you want?
A number of gentlemen
are not happy with me.
I assured them that
that I can get you to back off.
What do you retreat?
You did not want more cases?
A well-known Jewish
sports official was lost.
Amerikkalaistoimittaja had
a traffic accident.
This may happen around you:
your parents, your brothers -
Marielle ...
-Why is Marie?
Or maybe not. It depends on you.
It depends on the
what say you to the world.
Of course, this does not pass
so far. You see?
You do not talk to anyone, and do not in any
jumps in the name, which annoys me.
You can also choose the death of a hero.
However, we do not see each other anymore.
I wish you all the best.
What did he want?
So, give up.
What about an American journalist?
-Road.
Come.
What are you going to do now?
Nothing.
You can not just give up.
-Do you have a better proposal?
What if loukkaantuisin
in practice?
What does it benefit?
They voittivatjo.
Maybe not even then.
Coming up is
women's high jump final -
which are increasingly involved in the German
Lilly Vogtja Marie Ketteler.
Both have the opportunity to medal,
especially 17-year-old Mariella -
which is treated as drills
based on a favorite.
good jump. Lilly Vogt above
the first 154 cm of .
S  EXT is Marie Ketteler .
Another German crossed the bar,
and the medal hopes of voivatjatkua.
Mitalitjaetaan
these four young women between the .
S  Aksa will certainly get one medal,
but what?
Please silence Marie Ketteler
The last jump.
Tense your body until you have exceeded the
the bar. 160 is not a problem.
martial medal was solved .
Marie Ketteler will place four .
It is not only the Jews
were forced to concentration camps.
If he would have said something,
He ended up in there as soon as -
as it is claimed to be
a great lie.
It certainly was for him
bad time.
Perhaps the situation would have been different if the
he would have acted on a voluntary basis -
but he was forced to this, so
than me, too specific to your situation.
I was really sorry for him.
I wrote to him again -
but I never received an answer.
Marie Ketteler was forced to stay
The German women's national team -
and to participate in the
international competitions.
In 1938, he became
European champion -
a new world record
170 centimeters.
On the way home the tournament
He fanned the Gestapo -
beard, and to drive intoxicated,
and he was arrested.
In 1939, hanetjulistettiin
in a closed hearing -
Verden District Court of a man.
He survived the war and died in
complete isolation in 2008.
The number of times a dream -
I was in Berlin
preparing for the height of the jump.
It felt as if I had followed the
100 000 pairs of eyes -
and then kuulutettiin;
the high jump will start -
and I tried to walk, and could not.
I could not move the meat at all.
I was scared so much,
raajani that weighed as stones.
It was a recurring nightmare. "What do they
make me, if I win? "
Gretel Bergmann
moved to the U.S. in 1937 -
and won the U.S. Championship
the years 1937 and 1938.
Her fiance Bruno
was followed in 1938 -
and they were married
in September 1938.
The family managed to escape from the Gretel
ajoissaja survived the Holocaust.
Bruno and Gretel Bergmann-Lambert -
live now,
In 2009, New York.
Margaret Bergmann-Lambert for
and Bruno Lambert for
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org