Previously on ugly betty
Bradford thinks this wife
isn't really a monster.
Let's show him what she's capable of.
I can't believe she had this done to you.
That was just so horrible.
I'm divorcing Claire!
I heard you might be able
to help me with the problem.
I needed it eliminated.
I'm so sorry.
I love you.
He's my boyfriend.
You sleep with women to distract yourself
from what's going on in your life.
This is little something
i found overseas.
Where did you get that jacket?
A new up-and-coming designer--Tavares.
And when we're alone,
you're straight,and I'm naked.
My father is being sent back
to Mexico to wait for his visa.
Okay!Everybody!They just called.
The taxi is gonna be
here in five minutes.
I'm okay!
This trip cannot be
happening at a worse time.
Doesn't anyone care that i am
understudying the lead-in "west side story"?
God forbid Joey Colano takes ill and I
don't know my finger snaps for the rumble.
Justin we'll only be in mexico
long enough for grandpa to get his visa.
You hardly will miss anything.
Beside we'll gonna meet all our
familly members and practice our spanish.
Ola Comi atu Sorina.
You just said "i ate your niece".
Come on, Justin,help me please.
Hilda! Valmu mus!
Hey don't forget to ask your
cousin about the reception hall.
No! Santos we talked about
this,you are in charge of that.
Look,I gotta go, okay? I love you
Ok, bye.
Thank god, man! I gave him one
job,he just pull all that upon on me.
Hey! maybe we can find you
a wedding dressin mexico
The dress! Where am i
gonna find the dress?
When am I going to find the time
to do all of this stuff!
Oh maybe it's about the cake.
No more calls, Hilda,we are late.
Hi Betty.
- It's Henry.
- Henry.
It's me, Henry,i know you are kind of nervous
about the flying for the first time.
- So pick it up
- No
you have a far greater risk of dying driving to the airport
than actually being on the plane.
If you are hearing this then you
haven't droven to the airport yet.
So nevermind, adios, have a good trip.
That is so sweet.
And so gigi. Why don't you pick up?
Because, Hilda, I'm done with henry.
He has a girl friend I know what's meant
to be and it wouldn't really be this hard.
Whatever.
Message deleted.
OK. What's the one market we
are still not have been into yet?
Anyone? Sigle... young... man.
Well,we are a fashion magzine.
Exactly! Guys don't give a damn about our
clothes. What are they really care about? Huh?
Beer? Girls? Right? Guys want girls.
Girls that are accessible,girls
they think they can get.
We need to get those kind
of girls in this magzine.
And listen,they don't
have to be ugly,nor fat,
*** very good-looking,hot,and wear
really nice clothes,too,You know what I mean?
Uh,What you are saying is we should put thin pretty
women wearing nice outfits in this fashion magzine?
Exactly! You know,there
was something else.
OK,well, while Deniel is trying to remember
what the hell he is talking about,let's move on to...
Don't do that to me. You are
not the only one in charge.
But I'm the one with pupils that
are not the size of the quarters.
OK,girls,Tuck 'em back in,
you are both big.
Now,let's talk about the fearless women
feature. We've managed to secure... Jordan Dunn
Jordan Dunn? No. No,no,no,no.
That's not a very good idea.
That's a fabulous idea.
She hang-glides,she ice-climbs,
she swam the English channel in
a leather bikini,we've already have the title--
"the Dare Devil Wears Prada".
I said "NO"!
You know what? This meeting is done.
Thanks to Deniel,we've gone way over.
That was a... little bizzare?
That was amazing.
See,Jordan Don was Alex's girl friend before he became
a "she". I'm guessing they haven't seen each other since.
Your boyfreind faked as death
and come back as a very big girl.
That really isn't a coward for that.
Do not cancel that meeting.
It's gonna be awesome.
Yes! High five! Come on! Come on.
We did not just high five him.
Willie,you are smiling,laugh lines.
Oh,OK. Today is a good day,the brothers are fighting,
and Bradford sent the divorce papers in a mail.
And that much close to be
coming the next... Ms. Meade.
You,really can't see
those lines,can you?
No. You know, it's deadly on the outside
as you are on the inside.
Deniel,I'm on the plane.
Thank you so much for the tickets.
First class totally rocks.
I've tried lobsters and I watched wild
hogs,I think John Travolta looks better on a plane.
So how is Temp working out?
Fine,I guess Amber wasn't available huh?
Deniel, Amber couldn't type,or use a
pen. And she got lost on the elevator.
yeah,but she was hot.
Ellen was Miss Subway 1949.
So how are you? Is everything OK?
- Betty,I'm good.
- Are you sure?
You know this call?
Costs like, 10 bucks a minute?
Yes,yes,no,
burn it,burn it and bury it. oh,oh,Oh.
Is it good or bad?
I don't know,she is never
using the triple "oh".
It's bad.
Tavers,I'm sure you thought putting coconut
shell buttons on this jacket was adventurous,
But you've just murdered a blazer.
Murderer.
I was going for
something new,you know--
well,don'T. I don't want any
embarrassments at your debut.
- Fix it by tomorrow night.
- Coconut shell buttons?
You might as well havepunched
her in the stomach.
Okay,did that go
well,or does she hate me?
Are you kidding me?
She's bringingall the new york
buyers to your studiotomorrow night.
You're gonna be a wilhel
mina slater discovery,
and because I hooked you up,you have
to make out with me in the ladies' room.
shh!I'm supposed to be a big 'mo.
I tried being straight in
thisbusiness,and it doesn't work.
So unfair.
I finally got a hot boyfriend.
I can't even use it to make all the
other slutsfeel bad about themselves.
Guess I'll just make
that upto you later then.
Hey,hey,hey,girlie bag. That
top is love.Missoni or cavalli?
Yeah,I'm not doing thatwith you.
Keep the cham-plane coming.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Oh,papi. Papi.
Tell 'em that you didn't getyour complimentary travel kit,'cause
if I get another,then I can use them as bridesmaids' gifts.
- Here.You can have mine.
- Oh,no,you keep yours.
- You're my maid of honor.
- Oh,thank you.
Um,okay,so fernando,your
cousin,married natalia,
and their three kids
areluis,armando and teresa.
- That's right.
- Yes!Okay.
God,I just hate it that there's
no oneon mom's side of the chart.
I can't help you there,sweetheart.
I never really knew
aboutanybody except your mother.
Well,what year did grandma die?
I don't know,betty.Sometime
after hilda was born.
Mom never eventalked about her.
I mean,there mustbe
somebody who knows--
betty,concentrateon
the people we do know.
Okay. I-I
just w--
dad,are you okay?
I'm sorry,mija.
I guess I might be a
littlenervous about going home.
I didn't exactly leaveunder
the best circumstances.
So they don't know you
killed mom's husband?
- Ow!
- what,are you crazy?
Somebody's gonna hear you.
Nobody knows anything exceptyou
girls and my sister mirta.
Now can we please
stoptalking about this?
Betty,you're missing an earring.
What?
Oh,no!
My "dias" from my
"buenos dias" earrings.
I knew I shouldn't
havebrought my good jewelry.
You know,I know thisis the worst thing
to mix withyour cholesterol medication,
but I think a celebrationis in order.
Willie,I havea confession to make.
You didn't sign the papers?
Are you forgetting she
hired thugs to beat me?
- That she's a murderer?
- Wilhelmina.
oh,sorry.It's just this injury.
They say I'll have to
learnto live with it.
Willie,I have been marriedto
claire for so many years.
How do you juststart your life over?
Claire was a very,very toxic woman. I
could understandhow you feel a bit drained.
When I met claire,I
was... brad meade--
young,ambitious,felt
I could do anything.
Well,you still can. You just
have to get outin the world again.
I'm gonna take you to a
party tomorrow,downtown.
Party? Oh,I don't know.
You just needto shake things up a bit.
Buy a new car.Get a new look.
Oh,trust me,I can help
youfind "brad" again.
luis y natalia.
Y... um,armando.
No.
- E... ernesto.
- No.
Oh. Yo soy,uh,muy embarazada.
You just told them you're pregnant.
Fantastico!
No. Baby?No.
I know exactlywhat I want my dress to look
like in my head,but I can't find it anywhere.
And you feel likeyou're
running out of time.
Yeah,it's crazy,right? I
mean,there's plenty of time.
No,there isn'T.It's gonna go by like
that,and you're gonna end upwith nothing.
Oh! don't cry,mirta.
Why shouldn't I cry?
I haven't seenmy little
brother in 30 years.
I would like to saythat you look the
same,but you look like an old man.
Well,that meansI'm old,too.
- Is that why you're crying?
- Yeah.
oh,look at my son.Isn't he handsome?
Did you meet his wife?
Oh,yes.She cannot have a baby.
a cyst on one of her ovaries.
Now,mirta,go easy.
You know how you talk
too much when you drink.
Don't you worry. I've never
told anyone  your secrets.
My god. You are gray.
How gray am I?Don't tell me.
Look at you!You're so skinny!
You're the third
personwho's told me that.
oh,my god. I love it here.
okay,who is that old
womanthat keeps staring at us?
Oh. Isabella.
I forgot who she's related
to,but she's a curandera.
What's a curandera?
She's a healer. Very powerful.
That woman knows things,and
she can do things.
My husband miguelhad a wart on his hand.
She touched it.The next day,it was gone.
Wow. Well,maybe she couldhelp
you with your ovaries.
Ay,when that mirta drinks,she'll
tell anybody anything. Mirta!
Tenemos que hablar!
(We have to talk!)
Oops.
Um,hello.
T?ser*s infeliz por el resto de tu vida.
Did she just sayI'm gonna be unhappy?
Yeah,for the rest of your life.
Por qu?
(Why?)
Nunca conoceras felicidad
por que est*s estancada.
I-I'm--I'm
sorry.I-I...
- es muy triste,pero...
- m-m-m*s r*pido.
- You just told herto talk faster.
- no!
No mas rapido!
Hilda,what--what
is she saying?
Uh,she's sayingthat--that--that
you're stuck,
and that you can't move
forwarduntil you look back.
- De un arbol.
- Uh,oh,but there's hope.
She--she
sees a tree.
- Un arbol grande.
- A tree?
Yeah,a treewith missing branches.
La solucio es detras del arbol.
Debe buscar detr*s del arbol.
And the answeris behind the tree.
Uh... what does that mean?
it means the woman's nuts. A
minute ago,she was eating a candle.
okay. Thank you.
Gracias. Good-bye,mrs.Crazy.
Adios.
It's not on the plane.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
Sync:
YTET-gagegao -=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Ugly Betty
Season 1 Episode 22
hilda,I knowwhat the curandera meant.
The tree--it--it's the family
tree,and the empty branches--
that's--that's mom's sideof the
family. It's,like,so obvious.
She wants me... to fill
inmom's side of the tree.
Or you could climb
itwith those toenails.
Good morning,betty.
that's,uh,that's a lot of metal.
you want some coffee?
Aunt mirta,you knew my mother,right?
Oh,you lookso much like her.
She and I were very close.
She used to call mefrom new york
city,and we would talkabout everything.
Then--then you must
knowabout her family.
D-do you think that maybeyou could help
me fill out her side of the family tree?
Oh,no,no,no,no,no.I don't
know nothing about that.
No,she never talked about
them.I'll get you coffee.
nick,I'm busy.Whatever
it is,it can wait.
I've already waitedtwo years.
Hello,alex.
Jordan.
You look... different. New haircut?
Oh,hey,sugar booger.
So we'll go to my placeright after
work,and that'll give usplenty of time to--
don't tell me you forgotwe were gonna rent "300"
and enjoy the mildlyhomophobic/homoerotic content.
I'm sorry.It's tavares' party.
Of course. Tavares.
Clearly,you've replaced mewith that african
queen. Looks likeI'm yester-gay's news.
Okay,you're hurt.I am hearing that.
Anyway,you wanna goto the party?
- why would i want to do that?
- There'll be cute boys there.
Okay,I'm a littlemore
interested. Work harder.
You have to come,and
this is not just for me.
You are having,like,the
best hair day ever.
well-played,but just so you
know,I'll be bringing my own hag.
Or should I say haggis?
Polish off your best kilt,C.
We're going to a party.
Oh,sod off.
still finding our rhythm.
If you thinkthis is awkward,I
almost worethe same outfit.
Wow.
That reallyis you in there.
- Jordan,I know you must hate me.
- I did.
I'm a tough girl.
I got over it,
and I guess that this explains
a lotabout our relationship,
like why you neverleft
the toilet seat up.
- I wanted to tell you.
- I know,
but that would meanyou'd
have to say good-bye, and...
that was never one
of your talents, alex.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
This is whoyou're supposed to be.
And by the way...
- the boobs are amazing.
- Thanks.
They're yours. I took a
pictureof you to the surgeon.
The nose is kate winslet'S.
Oh,yeah.
Wow.
You really got marriedin this?
Oh,and I felt likea fairy princess.
But what color was
leftfor the bridesmaids?
Oh,there was no wayshe could wear white.
You're on thin ice,lady.
wow. That'S... fancy.
You know,I was thinkingthat maybe I would
just go a little bitmore traditional,you know,
like,um,one--one
or two colors.
Okay,but it's a wedding,not a funeral.
Ay,come on. I have two more.
Oh. Two more. Fabulous.
Let's havesome of your ponche.
Oh.Oh,no,no,no. Betty,I
had too much last night.
Oh,but it's so good,and--and
we'restill celebrating.
That's true. Salud.
Drink up.
Jordan!
- Hey,beautiful!
- Hi,daniel.
energy.
You look amazing.Wait
till alexis sees you.
Uh,he... she already has.
That's hard to get used to.
Oh,was it bad?How bad was it?
It was... weird,but I
think it's gonna be okay.
Good. Great.
God,I haven'tseen you in forever. I wish that we
could hang out,but I'm doing a shootfor you guys--
bungee jumping off the
brooklyn bridge--kid stuff.
Right.
- I want to see you later,okay?
- Okay.
Yeah. Hey.
I wanna come.I wanna jump with you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I thoughtyour sport was women.
I like to get my kicksin other ways,too.
- Okay.Come.
- Great.
But I know howyou and alex are. Do you
think that thisis gonna bother him--her?
Probably.
All right then,mr.Meade,time to sell it.
Are you sure he wouldn'trather just wear a
suit? I have a lovely charcoal--ted baker...
no suits,and remember,we
love anything the old fart--
ring-a-ding-ding.
Who is that hottie?
I didn't think I couldwear
leather,but maybe I can.
Of course you can.It's just,um,fun.
Can I just do one thing?
Perfect.
Good. Now I've gotta run,but
I willsee you tonight.
You look terrific,brad.
So,mr.Meade,are we
happy with the outfit?
Yes,very.
Maybe it couldbe a little more fun,hmm?
Your auntie teresa--a
widow for two weeks,
and she's already gota
boyfriend half her age.
Oh.Well,half her real age.
What else?Oh,your cousin
marisol-- her chi-chis--fake!
Really?
That's so surprising.
Um,aunt mirta,what aboutmy
mother's side of the family?
Well,I only knowrosa's mother yolanda,
and forgive me for saying
this,but that woman is a bitch.
Wait. Did you just say "is"?
Well,I haven't seen
herin years,but I hear--
so wait,you're sayingthat
my grandma's alive?
Crap.
- grandma's alive?
- Yes.
Dad,you lied to us.
Why would you keep the one
connection we haveto mom away from us?
It was your mother's idea,betty.
Your grandmother hated me.
- Why?
- I was a cook.
It was better her daughter staywith a
husband who beat her than to be with me.
The night we left,your grandmother
said if rosa walkedout the door with me,
she was dead to her.
So they--they just never
spoketo each other again?
Your mother tried.
She sent letters,pictures of you girls.
They'd alwayscome back unopened.
Tio,we're gonna be late
for your appointment.
Go.Go. It's about your visa.
We'll talk about this later,okay?
I wanna meet her.
I don'T. She sounds like a monster.
Hilda,she's our grandmother.
Why do you want to meet someonewho
doesn't want to meet you?
You were amazing.You
weren't even scared.
The first time I bungeed,I
threw up in my hair.
I know,I know. You know,I
wanna do something else.
Let's base jump off of the
topof this building,or skydive.
You are such a freak. I can't believe
how muchlike alex you've become.
Oh,I am much better than alex.
In fact,I have a confession to make.
The whole timeyou were dating
alex,I hada little crush on you.
You don't think I knew?
And the best part?You've
already met my parents.
Oh,tavares. uh,this is sebastian.
He's the buyer for barneys.
And this is his boyfriend,kenneth.
This is keith. Kenneth
and i broke up last spring.
I caught him making outwith a waiter
at the ready-to-wear showin paris.
Pret-a-poor
taste.
well,this is fun.
So far,I'm very impressed.
We're showing someof
tavares' best designs later.
They are,like,so good.
And the greasy pawsare on the prada.
Hey,you know what'd be
fun?Um,get me a drink.
- Oh,sure.
- Thank you.
you werejust dee-smissed.
Turns outhe's a mean gay.
So what?You're a mean gay,too.
Yes,but not to you.
Um,yesterday you told memy
head was too big for my neck.
That wasconstructive criticism.
- Well,what am I supposed to do about it?
- I don't know.
As a friend,my jobis
only to point things out.
oh,my god.
Oh,my god.
wow. Well,just wow.
It looks like"brad" is back.
any preference for how we
makeyour old man disappear?
I know your mother was
fondof cutting brake lines.
I don't want to knowany of the
details. I just want him gone.
Good,because once you get offthis
elevator,you never see me again.
I won't see youafter the lobby.
So how farto this outlet mall?
Clara saidit's about 2 miles north.
Well,I better finda wedding dress
there,because so farI have nothing.
Why is everythingwith this wedding so
hard? Sometimes I'm like,why even bother?
Hilda,come on.Everything's
gonna be okay.
Where did you geta quesadilla?
That guy in back.
Delicioso,ramon. Muy bueno.
(Delicious, Ramon, very good)
- I've had better.
- On a bus?
You got a point.
Henry?
Henry? Whatdo you mean "henry"?
It's nothing.I-I-I
was just seeing things.
Okay,I know that stuff with
momand her mother upset you.
I mean,honestly,that's why,when you
said,"let's goshopping," I said okay.
Oh,my god.
We're going tothat
woman's house,aren't we?
You know,you were a lot
smarterbefore you got engaged.
Amanda,baby,they love my stuff!
well,I'd hug you,but my greasy
pawsmight ruin your shirt.
Oh,I'm sorry about that.
It's just that it's sucha
big night for me,baby.
then lose this jacket.
What is thisstill doing here?
I like it.It's one of my best.
Coconut shell'sare the next big thing.
But wilhelmina hates
them.They make her eyes bleed.
Listen,if you wantto get ahead in
this business,you do not cross her.
What would I dowithout
you,huh? Come here.
really?
I think we're close.
Aunt mirta said she livedright outside
villanueva in a little blue house.
- I hope it's still blue.
- Well,I just want to go home.
And to be honest,that
quesadilla isn't sitting so well.
Oh,really? Because usually,when you buy
cheese cookedon a bus,it's pretty good.
Betty,what are you
hoping to get out of this?
Hilda,I don't know.
But afterwhat the curandera said
and--and us finding outabout grandma,
I just feel likeI'm
supposed to meet her.
Well,good luck,because I
don'tthink she wants to meet us.
- It is him.
- What?
Henry!
Betty--ow!
Wait!
Wait,henry! Henry,wait!
Betty!
What the hellis going on with you?
It was him,hilda. I saw it.It was henry.
Henry? Out here?
- Honey,you are hallucinating.
- Oh,no.
No,no!No,no,no,no,no!
Wait!
Wait up!Wait!
Ay,betty!
- What are we gonna do now?
- I don't know!
I think that there was a townback
that way,just a few miles.
- Miles?!
- Ow!
We may need this.
I wantmy bridesmaid's gift back.
And I hope you know that I am not
throwingmy bouquet anywhere near you.
You know what?I hope
gina gambarro gets it.
And if she gets marriedbefore
you,won't you be sad?
excuse us,mr.Gossett,jr.
I saw you kissing tavares.You're
in love with a gay man.
It's like you and meall over again.
I was never in love with you.
Oh... are you kidding?
When we first met,you
couldn'tkeep your eyes off of me.
Okay,that was beforeyou got your veneers.
You had that dark tooth.I couldn't look away.
- Big head!
- Dark tooth!
- Nicole bitchie.
- Nelly ripa.
It's sad and pathetic,mandy.He's gay.
No,he's not.
What?
He's just pretending to be to
get ahead in the fashion world.
He's straight,and we
aretotally seeing each other.
O.M.G.,He's pretending to be gay?
Well,that's a new twist
on an old standard.
Marc,you cannottell anyone.
mandy,you're with another guywho's keeping
you a secret. It's like danielall over again.
No,this is not daniel.
You are fabulous,amanda.
Why do you think you
don'tdeserve a real relationship?
Come outof the closet,sweetie.
I promise,it's better.
It's okay.I know what I'm doing.
Daniel,what the hellare
you doing with jordan?
Well,so far,just making out,but
by later tonight I hope--
stay away from her.
Oh,I love this. you're jealous.
Finally,I get the one
thingyou can't have.
You know I guess you probablyshould have thought
of that before you gave awaythe family jewels.
Daniel. Daniel!
What is going onwith you?
You've neverseen me win before.
Alex,this is me winning.
I can't believeyou made me walk
all this way in these shoes.
My feet hurt,betty.
- There's gotta be a bus soon.
- Well,let's just forget it.
Let's just live here,get
jobs,watch our asses grow.
I think we're still near villanueva.
Excusar me. Hablas inglés?
Yes.
Do you know ofa small
blue house around here?
A-a woman lives in
it--yolanda salazar.
I'm sorry.
Betty,just give it up.
you know,I'm gonna go askthat man
over there selling dirty fruit.
- You want some fruit?
- No.
Yes.
You look like you could
usea shot of tequila.
Or two.
Hola.Um...
Do you know if there is
a blue house near here?
excuse me.
- Henry!
- betty,where are you going?
Henry,wait!
Hey,handsome.
I'm giving you a ticket,'cause
you aresmokin' indoors.
Oh,my god. Mr.Meade.
I'm so sorry.I had no idea.
It's fine,marc.Thank you.
you owe me.
think of it as takinga
bullet for the team.
If he doesn't feel good abouthimself,he doesn't
move on. If he doesn't move on,I don't move up.
I'm sorry,I didn't mean to stare.
I think your earis oozing.
Oh... thank you.
henry!
missing branches...
the blue house.
hello?
Hi,um...
yolanda salazar?
Hola. Yo soy betty.
Rosa's daughter.
Your granddaugter.
you have no idea how
muchI've wanted to meet you.
Uh,mucho.
Uh,c-can you understand me?
Oh,uh... bueno.
She won't talk to you.
Her mind is...is no longer... I'm sorry.
He stepped out.
I was just going throughthe
proofs from the shoot--
I know what's going
onwith you and daniel.
Wow,that was fast. I don't
even knowwhat's going on yet.
You're gonnaget hurt,jordy.
Daniel's not in thisfor the right reasons.
He's angry and he's tryingto get back at me.
This is all about me.
Of course it's about you.
It has always beenabout you.
It's probably whyI'm
attracted to daniel.
He's the closestI'll ever
get to being with you.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to dowhat you
should have done two years ago--
have the gutsto say good-bye.
Good-bye,jordan.
hey,I,uh,thinkI'm gonna go.
What do you want me to do,walk you
to the door? Good night,girlina.
I think she's gota thing for you.
Yeah,she would sleep atthe
foot of my bed if I let her.
Sad little hags always
wantwhat they can't have.
Oh,really?
Well,apparently,that sad
little hag can have it and has,
in ways that are too
disgustingto even think about.
You could've had a realrelationship with
that woman,and you would havebeen lucky,
because she is one of the
nicest,easiest girls around.
- Marc...okay,maybe she's not nice.
- Shut up!
- What's the lesbiantalking about?
- I don't know.
Open your eyes,people.He's straight.
As straight as the
creaseon an old man's jeans.
well,this ismy very
first public "inning,"
and while it's interesting,I
don't see how it's relevant.
it isn'T. The one thing we are in
the fashion industryis tolerant.
If you look like that,you're in.
The only important thingis the design.
Well,then,should we startwith
some of his favorites?
I'm sorry to barge inlike this.
I didn't meanto disturb you.
Is it okayif I just...  s?
I just...I wanna say good-bye.
Rosa.
My daughter!You've come back.
no,no.
No,no,no,I'm not rosa.
Rosa...  perdóname...  ay,dios míO.
Forgive me for what I said last night.
You have always been in my heart.
You are my daughter and I love you.
Oh,thank God,for this second chance.
You left behind so many of your clothes.
What--what
is she doing?
She saysyou left some things behind.
Rosa,I was wrong.
Go with Ignacio.
If you love someone you must
find a way to be with him.
Even if you have to leave your family
mirta told meyou were here.
Did you understandwhat she said?
You are brave,my Rosa.
fight for the man you love.
I will.
you should have stayed a littlewhile longer at
the party.It did geta little more interesting.
I'm sorry,willie.I couldn't do it.
I was a fool to think I
could ever bebrad meade again.
You know,I remember brad.
He ran this placewhen I started.
Plenty of women in
the buildingwanted him.
However,there was one
womanwho wasn't interested.
Me.
I thought bradwas a fool,
but bradgrew
into bradford--
a strong,wise,sexy
man--
a man who's ruinedall other men for me.
Here's to starting over.
Mm,that feels good.
But you aregonna wash your
hands,right? I mean,you do touch food.
This is the specialtyof the house.
You seem so stressed.
Well,I don't knowwhy I wouldn't be.
I'm getting marriedin,like,a minute,
and everythingis so freaking hard.
I-I got no hall booked,I
can't find a wedding dress--
it seems like all the signs
aretelling you to not get married.
Well,I'm not really a
girlwho believes in signs.
Too bad,because there is a reason
why you cannot findthat dress.
There is a reason why
youwere brought here... to me.
I know what you're doing,antonio.
what?Who can blame me,eh?
But am I right?
Tell me,hilda,why is everything so hard?
Hilda!
- I found the house!
- You did?
Grandma gave me this.It was mom'S.
Oh,my god!
It's beautiful.It's the dress!
You see,antonio?I found my sign!
I'm getting married! Okay.
Oh,my god,tell me everything,but tell me in the
car. And grab my bag,cause I gotta get shoes.
gracias  for taking care of my daughter.
- Antonio barreiro.
- Ignacio suarez.
It is very good to
meet you,ignacio suarez.
Placer es mi?
(pleasure is mine)
You will never believe
who is back in Mexico.
Looks like you will
finally have your revenge.
hey,uh,I left my walletin
the bedroom. Just a second.
Hey,what
the--
- Okay,
- shut up.
- oh,sorry.
- Shh.We'll get caught.
Please,if anybody hears us,they'll just think it's christinastumbling
around blind drunk,crying and making out with a mannequin.
- Again.
- Okay,listen to me.
You havebeen through it tonight,woman,
and you deserve a treat.
- Mm,I do.
- And so do I.
The only action I got
tonightwas with old man meade.
And I'd say that's
worthsomething in a rare silk.
shoes. I wantthose peep-toe shoes.
peep-toe.
what?
oh,my god.
Fey sommers' secret room.
- The love dungeon?
- It's real.
I'm gonna fightfor henry.
If I don't,I'll regret
itfor the rest of my life.
I'm glad,mija.
I can't waitto get home.
Betty,I...
- I won't be going home with you.
- What?
Things didn't go so
wellat the consulate.
They denied my visa.
So what--what
does that mean?
It means I have to stay
here,for I don't know how long.
Okay,fine.Well,then,we'll all stay,
and we'll wait,and we'll figure it out.
Dad,I'm not going homewithout you.
No,no,you are going home,betty.
This is your future.
I leftmy family once,too.
Don't be afraid.
You're strong,mija,
just like your mother.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
Sync:
YTET-gagegao -=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Ugly Betty
Season 1 Episode 22