Episode 4
Subtitles brought to you by The Blue Sea @ Viki
Sir, last night in many villages along the west coast, they say there was a strange occurrence.
The clothes that were hung in the backyards, and shoes disappeared.
In their place, they say a rare quality pearl was left.
A pearl?
Oh My!
How can there be a burglar who takes only a few clothes and leave such a thing as a pearl behind?
If only the burglar also decided to stop by here...
Look here, Hong Nan half your dresser is pearls and precious treasures of gold and silver
I apologize that this concubine is overflowing with materialistic greed.
Since I am not able to completely have my spouse to myself, just think that I am compensating for that emptiness with material goods.
What I mean Hong Nan is
I'm saying that I will fill that other half of your dresser with jewels.
How long would that take...
Even though I'm busy as you can see, do you know why I'm on fire trying to catch a mermaid?
If I catch a mermaid, I can beat her and extract her tears again, and again
so that underneath each step you take can be adorned lavishly with pearls.
That's my plan.
And you have a way to catch one?
Method or not, that one will come back on her own.
Don't you think so Caretaker Jeon?
That's right. From the old times, the mermaid would come up to the village
and wear the clothes or eat food, they were sure to pay it back;
with rare pearls that can only be found outside the city.
So are you saying that the clothing thief was a mermaid?
Are you saying a mermaid came up to this village?
The mermaid who has fallen for the human must not go back.
That is part of their inherent nature.
For a mermaid that can only love once in her lifetime
She stakes her life on that one love.
For the mermaid, her one true love has appeared
and for me the lone opportunity has presented itself.
Let's do it like this, Caretaker Jeon.
Put out people to catch the mermaid before the village head does
Hong Nan you do your best to make sure a vicious rumor is circulated as swift as possible.
By vicious rumor you mean...?
The vicious rumor should be that recently a huge storm has caused the fishing boats to go missing
is all because of that bad omen, a mermaid.
When the mermaid was washed ashore and caught, since all of that happened
it really does seem to be true.
This kid's smart.
But that ominous mermaid
with malicious intent selfishly hid herself deep inside the village while taking human form.
But if we are unable to stop her, an even bigger calamity would unfold
many people will be injured and die.
In five days time
They'll be brimming with concern over the wind and waves
there's no better timing than this!
There's nothing better than fear to stop the people's thoughts.
The village head also cannot help but deal with the scared witless villagers.
Of course, sir.
If we're good, we can also force the village head into a deadly situation along with the mermaid.
Naive love is giving me great joy.
Aigoo the mermaid that was caught yesterday
has been seen again, have you heard?
They say that storm was caused by the mermaid!
Aigoo what can be done. With the strong winds, isn't my husband going to return as a sea monster if he rides out in his boat?(will be dead at sea, becoming a ghost haunting the ocean)
- Then we need to immediately capture and kill that witch! - Exactly!
What's the village head doing?!
Village Head! They say the mermaid has come up to the village!
Everyone is about to die!
I'm saying you can't come here and be like this!
I got the message so please go back!
Look, have you finally lost your mind?
Didn't you just receive report on what kind of strange rumors are circulating within the administrative district.
But what? Who're you going to find?
I think Se Hwa came to see me. I had requested it last time.
I asked her to come see me at the 20th solar division (lays between the first day of winter and the first big snow, around the 22nd of November)
and that I want to be able to see the first snow with her.
I mean...look here. For someone who's educated why are you being like this!
The subdivisions in the year are just that.
Just because it is November 22th it doesn't mean that the snow will be like falling--
Dam Ryeong! Dam Ryeong!
You can 't!
If that woman really won't be able to go back, that means she risked her life.
The same goes for me. What am I not able to stake at this point?
Think of your family! Think of your father's honor and position!
In Shin An (county)'s Docho Island, Yeosu's Geomoon Island, Incheon's Jeongmoon
the places where the mermaids frequent, tell the elders, there is but one answer:
The biggest weakness of the mermaid who can't go back
are her legs. After her legs are severely wounded
Legend of the Blue Sea
The whereabouts of Ma Dae Young who was jailed in the Seoul Correctional Facility for murder charges, is
unknown for the last three months. Unlike the initial prediction by the police that he'll soon be apprehended
there isn't any headway in the investigation elevating the fears of the citizens.
Police have not ruled out the chance that Mr. Ma might have an accomplice in his escape, and are continuing the investigation.
To find out the underlying motivation behind his jailbreak, police
are deeply investigating Mr. Ma's personal relations and those who are against him.  - That crazy bastard.
Yes, Ahjumma. You also packed the crabs in soy sauce, right?
Oh my. What happens if I bring this as is and the sauce would leak all over?
I already told you before, time and again.
If I ask to have food for take out, you should pay special attention to it.
Look here, you see the clasps? I locked them shut so
be sure to hold it upright properly.
I should have it stand like this?
Don't put it on the trunk
but place it on the floor in the car and be sure to secure it well.
On the car's floor? Securely?
You should be careful when you carry it.
Okay.
But who's whose superior?
Oh my! So funny. I'm speechless.
Yes, Madam. It's me, Jin Joo.
It's just that I have some side dishes that I think would match your taste and thought of you.
Yes, please taste it.
Wow, Mother. There's so many delicious things today.
Jin Joo gave it to us, saying it was made at her house.
Your sister's working real hard to make things work with our Chi Hyeon.
Is that so? If those who it concerns are fine then, well then that's that.
No, Father. I'm fine with everything if my parents like it.
Honey, our Chi Hyeon is like this. Others say he's a Papa's boy.
It's not good to be that too much.
Why?
-How is it?-Don't make me speak.
-It's too delicious.-Right?
Is it good, Heo Joon Jae?
Don't make me speak. It's too delicious.
Aigoo, we gave you the name 'Joon Jae' for you to become 'a brilliant man.'
But in order for our son to be a brilliant man, don't you have to be a conglomerate first, honey?
-When are you going to become a conglomerate?-Wait just a little bit. Just a little bit.
I'm going to make you a Madam and you'll be wearing luxury goods from head to toe.
See if you don't!
Here, eat the meaty part.
Why, honey? Does it not match your tastes?
No, it's really good. You try it too.
-Chi Hyeon.-Yes, Father?-You try it too.
Ah, no father. I have a shellfish allergy.
Honey, eat up! I heard Jin Joo had a new domestic help
they must have picked someone good now.
Honey...?
General Manager Nam
Yes?
Perhaps... do you keep in touch with Joon Jae these days?
Today, it's your son's birthday so must have thought about him.
I have came to conclude that until this summer he lived near Samsung-dong.
But it seems he has moved out again.
It's hard to find out his address.
Wonder what he's been doing... that pathetic punk.
Now, you should make up.
Make what up? Between a father and a son.
I'm saying it because it's you. But the only blood relative I have is Joon Jae.
Now I need to find him and have him beside me. I have a lot to teach him.
Can you get him?
It's me.
It's his birthday today.
He'll appear there.
Find out where he is. When you find out,
make him disappear.
Do you know me?
I'll ask again.
Hey, over there! Please hold onto her. Why is she so fast?
Aigoo. Thank you. She's someone who went into our facilities without our permission.
We need to investigate her.
- I know. - Pardon?
I am Detective Hong Dok Kyeong from the Myeongdong Violent Crimes Department. I received a report.
Already? Who reported her?
- I didn't.- Maybe the security team reported it.
- Are you the one in charge? - Oh yes I am
Breaking and entering tends to have a purpose and it seems like it would be very difficult without inside help.
Later, I might need to investigate witnesses. When that time comes I will call you.
Ah, yes. I understand.
We need to go together.
She's someone who's getting apprehended right?
I didn't get you out to save you.
There's something I need to know. So give me an answer.
This. Why were we together?
Why am I in here with Heo Joon Jae?
You know my name, too?
You know me, right?
You don't know?
You do know or you don't know?
You know me. You know my name too.
It's true that we were in Spain together.
But why do I not know you? Who are you?
Who are you?
Okay.
What's your name?
I don't have a name.
-You don't have a name?-Nope.
I don't have a name, but I was told I'm not a strange person.
-By who?-A good person.
I'm not sure what kind of person he/she was, but there's a high chance they're pretty strange too.
Your words and actions...everything is strange, you know?
Do you not speak Korean well? Are you an overseas Korean?
I'm going to ask you for the last time.
What happened between us in Spain?
I'm pretty sure I met you, but why don't I remember anything?
Was there an accident that happened that I don't know about?
You don't have anything to say to me, right?
There's a lot that curious about you, but you don't have anything to say to me...
So isn't it useless to keep being together?
Why? You have something to say to me?
Then don't follow me.
Subtitles brought to you by The Blue Sea @ Viki
Hangang Park
Your nose is really good right now!
Don't ever do surgery.
Ah, I'm not a strange person.
I'm not someone who's preaching the Tao or anything.
I'm just a Buddhist ascetic you know? Any Buddhist ascetic can see everything even when they try not to.(this is someone from the con-religion who claim to be Mireuk Buddhists)
What do you see?
Miss you don't have any luck with your ancestors
but your nose is blocking a lot of bad energy. But then...
It's ambiguous. No matter how nice your nose is, the lack of ancestoral blessings is stronger.
In the ground, your ancestors are crying.
What are ancestors?
What do you mean what are...?
The people who made you, the people who made them, the people who made them are those people.
Your roots! Your origin.
They wouldn't be in the ground.
If it's not in the ground, wh..wh..where?
Underwater?
Ah! They weren't buried.
So you spread their ashes over the river or sea, I see.
Well, wherever it is...
It's important that your ancestors are crying.
- Why are they crying?- What do you mean "why"?
It's because their descendants aren't doing their duty (gong)
Look at this.
Gong
This 'gong', okay? With this 'gong,'
if you read it backwards, what does it become?
You know how the word 'nim' (님, means loved one) turns into 'nam' (남, stranger) if you put a dot in it?
It's the same concept! Look.
If you read this 'gong' backwards...?
Woon
Ah, really. Come over here.
Here, here.
What does it say?
That's right! It's 'fortune!' That's right!
What does this mean? If you do your duty, then 'fortune' will also follow.
Wow! This truth is so scientific,
and proven, that's what I'm saying.
You have a strong energy.
You are strong and sassy too.(Cha Tae Hyun this actor and JJH played opposite each other in My Sassy Girl)
Excuse me, if you go to the parking lot
our minivan is there on standby. Why don't you go there.
Why? What? Who are you?
Me? Your ancestor.
I thought that if I continue to neglect my descendant, I thought the whole world will turn into a shitshow that
so I came here personally to get you. To take you away.
Wow, really. Who are yo—
Ah, this man. Oh?
Aish, this jerk! Are you a pick-pocket!
I'm going to report you immediately. I'm going to report you!
You're going to regret it! If I report you...
Please, give it to me, sir.
If you give it to me right now, I'l leave quietly.
It's because I can't have my identity leaked.
Ah, it's really cold.
I'm telling you this because it seems you don't really know what's going on.
You can't follow people like that man. They'll say you need to do memorial rites, and whatever. They will rip you off a lot.
Okay?
Dog Nam Doo
Yeah, why?
Ah, what are you going? What's wrong with you?
It's a gun!
A gun?
Ah, it's not a gun.
Stay still, Joon Jae. I'll protect you.
Ah, no, who's protecting who?
Sheesh.
Open your eyes. Believe in my words.
Look at the sky.
♬ Your gaze more than any words, is  ♬
skip
♬  meaningful ♬
Listen well. Protecting others... ♬  I can sense it ♬
comes after protecting yourself. The order is like that.
It's a stupid thing to switch the order.
It's not hot?
Are you listening to me?
That... it isn't hot if you touch it?
Is this really your first time seeing fireworks?
Fireworks?
There is a place called the Han River. In the fall, they have a fireworks display there.
Wow, that's incredibly beautiful.
I'll let you watch it with me.
Fireworks display?
That's right. Is this really your first time seeing it?
You can't touch it. Look, as soon as it explodes, it disappears.
♬ From the moment you came to me . ♬
♬ Come a step closer. ♬
♬ So I can even feel your breath ♬
♬ My heart is tilting towards you ♬
♬ Bit by bit, bit by bit. ♬
Why is everyone doing this?
They're taking pictures.
Taking pictures? What is that?
Ah, are you asking because you really don't know?
♬ Why is it like a miracle everyday. ♬
Here, like this.
"Ah," what even.
But why aren't you taking pictures? Everyone else is.
Because I can just remember it.
You're keeping it here, aren't you?
Usually, good and pretty things disappear quickly, Joon Jae.
Like this, with your eyes, you look at it well,
and then you keep it in your heart like this.
Then when you have a sad day, you think about it.
You go, "At that time, the fireworks in the sky were really pretty."
"Ah, that day was really good."
-Mom, we're going to come again next time, right?
-Of course.-And the next time too?
-Of course!-And the next time.
-Of course!-It's for real.
-Yeah!
But why do you keep speaking informally?
I'm going to speak informally now too then.
Should we watch golf?
Wait a minute...
No, Ahjumm...
...until 9:30 pm, vehicular traffic will be prohibited. Activities near the enclosed area will go into the late night
Nevermind. You can watch golf now.
Thank you.
What "thank you"?
This is our TV; this is our house.
Why are you following the Ahjumma's words exactly?
I don't know. Weirdly, every time she orders something, I do it.
Yeah.
I'm following him right now,
but he's with some girl.
But how did you know he would be here today?
He did that since he was young.
Even after growing up, he hasn't fixed his habit.
Joon Jae, where are you going?
My mom and I planned to meet each other on my birthday.
Mom will be waiting.
Let go. Let go!
Is that so? Then go.
Your mom won't be there.
Because your father gave her a lot of money.
But if she meets you, she has to return all of that money.
Why do you think your mother left you without a word?
It's because she likes the money way more than she likes you.
No! No, my mom isn't like that.
My mom isn't like that!
What's with him now?
He said he's meeting his mother.
This bast***.
Go into your room!
Why are you shouting at him when it's over something sad?!
No, no, my mom...
My mom will come to see me.
Joon Jae, don't cry. Your step-mother will be sad too.
Joon Jae, I'm sorry.
Do you know how much effort I've put into this hous
Now that it's time to clarify the inheritors, he looks for his son?
Be sure to find out where he lives today.
Okay?
I need to live for you to live.
Hang up. He's moving.
Why do you keep following me? I need to go.
What do you want me to do?
Can't I go with you?
Together? Where? My house?
No.
Why?
Of course you can't. How could a woman go to a man's house?
If your parents knew, what would they say?
I don't have any parents.
Then answer me. We know each other, right? Something happened, right?
See.
It's because you're like this, on what basis do I bring you home?
Give me your hand.
If you have something to say to me later, then contact me then.
I don't know.
I don't know her. What am I supposed to do?
I like it that I'm in Seoul.
You really don't know Seoul?
I'm sure.
It's cold. I'm closing the window.
I like it that I'm with you.
I love you.
Hey, I'm trying to compare something.
Say it to me.
Huh? What?
That. That "I lo..."
Nevermind. Do it later.
Ah, who's this guy now.
Are you still looking at that?
Oh right.
Have you seen a drawing such as this?
There's none.
How could a person from the Joseon Dynasty draw something like this?
The Professor said, it might have been that the painter rode a time machine and saw the future.
Somehow...
Feels very similar to someone I know.
Who?
There's someone. It's his birthday.
Come inside.
Hey! How can you bring her here? Are you crazy?
Did she hear?
Is there nothing to eat in here?
Why would something to eat be in there? Come over here.
Hey, miss, where is your house?
It's far.
Mine's far too. It's in Namyangju.
Mine's rea...
...lly far.
She doesn't match with me. Joon Jae, she doesn't match with me.
What would you do if she did match? Is someone giving a blind date for you?
But even so, we'll be living together.
"Living together" my butt.
You are also mooching of right now. You guys should leave now.
Oh my. This guy is so vicious.
If Tae Oh and I leave together, what are you guys going to do in one house together?
Ah, would I keep this girl with me?
I brought her because there's something I have to check.
What are you checking? Hey, don't take it out! Don't take it out!
You...know about this, right?
You know about it, right?
-Yeah. -Is it yours?
I gave it to you.
You gave this to me?
Yeah. Because you liked it.
Yeah, he probably did like it.
But it isn't an object that can be given just because he liked it.
Oh, you're really kind. It's sad to take it.
There's a lot of things like this in my house.
You have a lot?
Yeah, if you just search around, there's a lot.
Is that so? There's a lot if you search around.
Joon Jae. Lets let her stay at our house for a moment.
Look at you talking about her staying here.
Why? She said she doesn't know anyone in Seoul. But do you really have a lot of this stuff at home?
Yeah.
We...No, this oppa will help you with this harsh life in Seoul.
Instead, you can't forget that I helped you.
If you want to give thanks when you return home, you can do that too.
I know the bracelet but, you, who gave the bracelet to me; I do not know?
Do you think that makes sense?
See? She talks so well but when an important topic comes up she won't speak!
Hey, don't be too harsh. There must be a situation.
But what's your name?
She doesn't have one.
She...she doesn't have one?
-Why do people keep asking whether I have a name? -That's an interesting question.
People ask because they need to call you with a name.
They can't call me if I don't have a name?
It'll be hard. It's easier to call people with a name.
If I have a name, will you call for me?
-I guess I will if I have to. -Then make me a name.
-Make what? Do you think I would do that? -Give me a name!
A name comes from the feeling when you look at that person.
The image of that person. When I look at you, I think of Hepburn. Audrey Hepburn.
If you watch the movie, the princess would roam around not knowing anything.
Shall I say I could feel such vibe?
What about that name? Oh Deu Ree (sounds like Audrey.) Last name Oh. First name Deu Ree.
Just... Shim Cheong Yi.
She's extremely dumb. So Shim Cheong Yi is just right.
How could you be so insincere towards a person?
I like it.
What are you saying? He's teasing you that you're stupid!
I like that name. Shim Cheong Yi. I like it.
It fits her. You have a knack for naming.
What's your name?
I'm Tae Oh.
I'm Shim Cheong Yi.
But still, it's your birthday so I thought you should have a cake.
On my way home...
You had a guest! Who is she?
Ah...
Hello. I'm Shim Cheong Yi.
I see...
AH THAT SCARED ME!
Why are you like this? Get off of me!
Get off!
Hey, hey, hey!
You eat this after you blow out the candles.
Lets sing the happy birthday song!
Happy birthday to you-
Eat it after taking out the candles. Here.
Ah!
Oh my god.
Noone will steal it from you. Eat it slowly.
Joon Jae. Have some too.
It's fine. I'll do it myself.
Hey. Eat it from her. She must feel embarrassed.
Seriously.
Oh right. Joon Jae, you will go on Professor Jin's retirement party next week, right?
I will be meeting with him tomorrow separately. I also have something to talk to him about.
Professor Jin was so disappointed when ever he started a new project.
He's saying how it would have been nice if you were there to help.
So, she will be here for the mean time?
I stopped him too. I did.
But Joon Jae is weak against justice. She also seems mentally unstable and all.
Why are you being so bothered about that girl who doesn't even know her own name.
I don't know.
You should hold still and not leave this house.
No.
There's no room so where is she going to sleep?
Honestly, there is another room.
Come up.
Do I live here?
Get your senses together. What do you mean "live"?
I have something to find out that's why I'm letting you stay for a while.
It's only for a few days.
Aigoo.
Thank you, Heo Joon Jae.
Of course you should be thankful.
Let's now live quietly.
Hey! I can hear everything!
Subtitles brought to you by The Blue Sea @ Viki
Heo Joon Jae! It's morning. Let's eat breakfast!
Ahw!
The delicious meal is cooking.
Right, start. It would be better if you would hurry.
You're doing all sorts of things.
Wow! It's nice how this feels like a home.
Hey, where did all the milk go?
There's one person who drank it in one shot saying she's hungry while waiting for the food.
It's not like I can always say what is right.
Is anyone in there?
Is there anyone home?
I don't! Just because of this, you woke up a sleeping person?
Hey! What are you doing?
I saw you! What are you doing?
You are a thief, right? Don't you move.
This bastard.
What are you doing, you crazy bastard?
Thank you.
What is it?
Why did I go there?
We were apart and I hurt my head.
Certainly.
What is it, seriously?
Yes, Hyung?
Joon Jae, stop. Stop.
- What?- Look up front.
Hey.
What is it? What happened?
The one living next door, what on earth. There's a murder case.
- What?- I also called Tae Ho telling him not to come home.
Hurry and turn the car around. Detective Hong is out there.
Detective Hong, who is so bent on catching you. He also saw your face three years ago.
What are you doing? I said turn the car around.
Cheong Yi is alone at home.
What matters if she's alone for a while.
If you will keep on staying here then they will be suspicious.
What's wrong? It's not even on your district.
I heard the weapon used was a hammer. It's definitely Mah Dae Young.
Is it only Mah Dae Young who uses a hammer to murder? The victim was a loan shark so it's 100% obviously a revenge.
Where do you find a 100% on a case? First, let's look at the possibility. If it's not then I'll step out if it isn't.
Why isn't Heo Joon Jae coming?
Hey! You shouldn't have appeared in front of me!
You should have lived without knowing!
Let me tell you a secret.
Your father is...
What's wrong? Move.
Speak. Is she dead?
Is it Heo Joon Jae?
Listen carefully. Protecting someone else is after protecting yourself. That's how the order is.
Changing that order is being stupid. Do you understand?
Hyung, move.
Huh?
If you don't want to be stupid then move.
What did you say? Hey! Joon Jae! Heo Joon Jae!
Hey!
Subtitles brought to you by The Blue Sea @ Viki
Sa Wol. Sa Wol.
Yes, Madam.
Today is such a nice day. Open the jars.
That way it will get light and the taste will be better.
All of them?
Is it too difficult?
Well...
Should I do it?
No, Madam. I should do it.
Sa Wol.
Yes, Madam!
I have almost finished it.
Seeing the clouds, it seems like there will be a shower.
Close them.
What?
The jar's cover.
I just... opened them.
Should I do it?
Madam! I will close all the covers.
No. You have something else to do.
That punk, no matter how long I wait, there's no reply.
Go and hand my letter and personally get a reply.
Madam, I think she knows that's why she's doing it, to tear us apart.
If we were born again, let's meet as a couple.
And live 100 years.
We shouldn't have been born like this.
That's right. Next lifetime, I will be born rich.
What do you want to be reborn as?
Me?
I...
Sa Wol!
I want to be that b*tch master.
The Legend of the Blue Sea
If you don't say anything until tomorrow, then you must leave this place.
Don't stay here like a queen and leave.
Did you really let her leave in this cold weather?
You said you would not turn your back on someone who as nothing, what happened to you, Heo Joon Jae?
Next time at this time, let's do it on the first day of snow.
Let's meet there. I have something to tell you.
♬ So that I could feel your breath . ♬