Paulo's next.
He is also one of us! He downed his glass like everyone!
BEYOND THE WALLS
Fucking hell!
You have to help me here!
Bloody Hell!
Here...
I don't even know your name.
Ilir.
What does it mean? Where's it from?
Ilir, it's Albanian.
The Mafia?
OK, I see... you've got your head full of stereotypes.
Sugar?
Yes, thanks.
It means freedom in French.
- Can I bite mine too? - Sure, but have some water first.
Drink. You've got to dilute your hangover, trust me!
- Finish it! - No, I can't.
Trust me, you need to get rid of the toxins.
Or you'll feel like shit all day.
Good... drink, drink... swallow.
Don't choke yourself.
- I can't anymore - Thats fine.
- Go, if you have to - No, it's OK.
Was that your girlfriend?
No.
No, it wasn't... well yes, but not really.
Fine, say no more, I get it.
What do you mean?
You're still trying to figure it out, aren't you?
No.
Yes, I mean... you could say that.
- I can't remember last night - That's probably a good thing.
- Why? - Never mind...
No, go on, tell me...
We snogged, you wanted to suck my cock.
- Oh, no no... no - Oh yes... yes you did.
But it's OK, it's no big deal.
I'm really sorry.
Hey, I was joking.
Where were you?
Don't you have stuff to do?
I looked for yo.u everywhere, you could have called.
I was out of credit... my phone battery was dead.
Where did you sleep?
I don't know anymore.
I can't remember, I don't know...
Was it a guy?
- Have you got one size up, or not? - I'll be with you, madam.
You promised you'd stop.
Tell me the truth.
There, that's the truth.
Hi.
- Alright? - Yeah, you?
Yeah, good... good.
I've got your T-shirt.
Thanks.
Thanks, that's nice of you.
I washed it.
I hope so.
- Do you want something to drink? - Yes.
I'll have whatever... a beer... a beer.
- It's fine like that. - OK,thanks a lot.
- See you soon. - Bye.
- You're not having one? - No, I'm at work.
But if you feel like it, I'm doing a concert on the 30th...
If you have nothing else on, if you feel like it...
Well, do what you want.
Isn't it possible before that?
No, because...
it's not my decision.
I'm going out with some mates.
- Oh no, not tonight. - Why, what's up?
I just wanted you to stay here with me.
Me too... another time?
But you can't go out with that look.
Where should we go?
Sorry, sorry... I'm sorry.
Let me see... I really went for it, sorry.
Can I taste?
You want, too?
Don't resist. OK?
Just breath in, OK?
Do you love me?
Yes.
It doesn't feel like it.
You didn't even ask me how my meeting went.
- I did. - No.
OK, so I forgot.
How did it go?
It's too late now.
Sorry I forgot. I had other things on my mind...
You always have other things on your mind.
So what's up now? We're going to start this again?
This is no good.
You know it.
What? What's going on? What did I do?
We need to talk, you need to tell me the truth.
We need to talk!.
We do nothing but talk, bla bla bla all day.
Enough now, no?
Can I meet him?
I'm going to bed.
We should hook up again soon.
I miss you already.
I love you.
I want you to leave.
I've had enough.
I don't understand.
We're good together.
How can you say that?
It's been months since we've done anything.
Stop pressuring me all the time like that!
Get out! Get out!
- What, right now? - Yes.
Take your stuff and get out!
- No way! - Oh, yes.
Can you put me up?
We've seen each other twice. We hardly know each other.
We've seen each other three times.
Three times, if you prefer, but that changes nothing.
Where can I go?
- Your parents? - They live in the boonies.
Don't you know anyone who can put you up for one night?
I'd never beg you if I did.
Now is not a good time for me.
- Its burnt. - Give me two minutes.
Who is he?
Elina. This is Elina.
She's my sister!
Have you known each other long?
He's never mentioned you.
Leave him alone. He's a friend.
That's all.
- I'm only asking. - Mind your own business, OK!
What's wrong?
Nothing, don't worry.
I'll clean up.
- No wait I'll... - It's fine!
Leave that, I'll do it.
- What's the problem? - I want to be alone.
- He's here, isn't he? - Leave me alone!
As you wish.
Thanks.
No, I don't agree.
For tonight, just picture a line here, a frontier between us.
Are you punishing me?
Come on, move, get out of here...
There!
You're all I've got left.
What?
- Don't exaggerate... - No, it's true.
Listen, I'm happy to help you out, but...
I prefer things to be clear, for me this is just for fun.
What do you mean, just for fun?
What happened to me is your fault.
Come on, we had fun cuddling for a few minutes.
That doesn't mean I have to turn my flat into a YMCA.
Take care of me.
Blow jobby?
What?
No, no blow jobby now...
Blow jobby! Honestly what a word, blow jobby?
If you want, I'll swallow.
Where am I... I don't know anymore...
Right, I'm going to stop this, I've lost track...
Thanks... thanks a lot.
Come here.
No! Wait, just come here, like this.
Time to sleep,OK? - Yes.
Be a good boy.
Are there lessons on Saturday?
It's so the kids don't forget their origins.
One of my mom's great ideas.
Can you wait here, please. I won't be long.
What are you doing?
- Getting attached to you. - You prick.
We should play music together one of these days.
Yeah, if you like.
Bass and piano isn't great.
Can't you play another instrument?
I can play flute.
Idiot.
- No, honestly, it's true. - Yeah, right.
And singing? Can you sing?
I'm flying off to the sun, towards days full of fun,
I'm flying off to the sun, to give you advice second to none.
OK, so you can't sing.
No, stop, please... It tickles.
Let go.
Do you love me?
Not at all.
Go for it.
Don't forget, my eyes are closed.
I can't take it anymore, I'm on the edge, here.
- You've never taught anyone, have you? - For fucks sake.
- I'm not the worst. - I can't believe you!
I like you a lot, but you really exhaust me.
Wait...
- Look! - Fuck.
What now?
- I'll buy you one. - Well, hurry up.
Get a move on.
Shit, bollocks...
- Get up, for fuck's sake. - Sorry. I'm sorry.
Thank you. Thank you, madam.
Wait... are there any left?
Come on. Let's go. Don't touch me, not here.
Let me know when I'm allowed to touch you.
Don't make a scene. This is my neighbourhood.
everyone knows me, so get off my back!
I wasn't on your back, I just needed your arm to get up!
Don't they have any rubbers here?
Don't know.
- Do you know if they sell condoms? - What are you doing?
It's time we do some ass fucking, I'm sick of playing games.
- We'll see later. - What?
Oh, you're embarrassed. Look at me.
I thought you wanted everything out in the open.
- Miss, do you sell condoms? - She has no idea.
We'd like to spend a nice afternoon together.
Excuse me, could I have your attention please?
- Does anyone know where the rubbers are? - Stop!
Condoms, anywhere here?... No?
They're hard to find...
They didn't all hear me.
Please stop.
Don't touch that, you've made your point.
- One second, I've got to finish. - Put it back!
Relax, I'm just embracing my sexuality.
Excuse me, can everyone hear me, even over by the cheeses?
I'd like to introduce you to my princess...
who's a bit shy, she's called Mr. Paulo Moiro.
There, now you know him. We are looking for some condoms,
to spend a pleasant afternoon together.
Can anyone help? Because, you see, you can never be too gay.
- Hello - Hello
For the gel, do your prefer pineapple, watermelon.. or natural?
- Is there Kiwi? - Kiwi.
- Do you have Kiwi? - No, none left.
That's a pity.
No Kiwi left.
You decide.
I'll take pineapple, then.
How does it work?
You put your cock through it and then your balls round the back.
- Behind what? - Behind the cuffs and you lock it.
With a little key.
You lock it with a key? What for?
So whoever's wearing it can't open it without the key.
Fucking hell, they're crazy.
What?
You're actually into this stuff?
Just the thought makes my balls fizzle.
Fucking crazy... No way.
How can you put your...
We'll take this,
- and this too. - I'll give you a youth price.
Youth price? OK, I see, Here, keep the change.
Goodbye and have a nice day.
- Bye. - Come on.
Are you OK, whats up?
Nothing.
You know the rules, right? Ready...
Hands behind your back.
- Ready? - Yes.
I am, I'm ready.
two, three...
Oh fuck, breathe...
- Are you going for it? - Breathe... Yeah, totally.
No way, take your hand away.
You're cheating.
You cheated...
I lost.
No, do it for real now.
- Oh, you want to do it again? - Without cheating.
But I'd lost, you had your chance, young man.
Your hand.
Here you go.
The pineapple is overpowering.
I'm going to need three weeks to get over this.
Do you want to keep it as a souvenir?
No.
Shame.
- Are you sure? - Yes.
Here, catch.
Be careful! Behind you!
- I've been waiting ages. - I was getting you a present.
Little piglets.
Thanks.
You've missed your train now.
I'll just take the next one, no big deal.
Hold on to this, I'll show you.
Careful.
You'll be mine for the whole weekend.
- No no. - Yes yes.
Follow me.
Come on.
It's fine, you are allowed in here.
You're hurting me.
You're too hard.
It won't work if you're this hard.
I can't, I can't.
I don't know.
Think about your ex-girlfriend.
There.
Now you'll be happy, you're mine now.
You're mine.
Say it.
Stop, stop.
Say it: I'm yours.
I'm yours.
Come on, say it. I want to hear it.
Say. I'm yours.
Say I own you.
- Are you mine? - Yes.
- Only mine? - Yes.
Yes, only yours.
Only mine, only mine... Say it. Louder.
I'm only yours, only yours.
- Forever? - Yes.
Forever, I'm only yours forever.
Articulate.
I'm only yours forever.
Are you OK?
- No, no, no - give   ...
No way.
- two days is too long, give - Come on, only two days
There, speaking of keys.
I'll give you these.
Can I... can I help you?
I've...no...
Maybe you could help. It's complicated.
Yeah, seems s... what's up?
I've got this and I don't know what to do with it.
Thank you.
Where is he now?
Second door on the left.
It's for Ilir Loshi.
May I sit here?
You stole my sweater.
- Let me give it back. - No, it's OK. You're not allowed.
- I want to give it to you. - You can't.
It has to be in a package. Security measures.
Fuck!
Are you OK?
I guess.
You never even told me how long you were in for.
Eighteen months.
If things go well, I'll be out in a year they said.
A year? Congratulations!
Are you fucked up in here?
You think I did it on purpose?
300 of us on that train, and they went for me.
You've got hash smoker written all over your face.
You're a moron!
Crossing the border with hash on you, you fucking idiot!
Is that why you came, to lecture me?
There's more to it, so I want to know.
I fought back a little.
Thats good, there you go.
Assault and battery of a Police Officer.
Great!
What do we do now?
What are we going to do?
Wait, I mean you're OK aren't you?
I've got one bit of good news.
I've got a real six-pack.
You want to see? Look.
Three weeks intensive training.
Just imagine.
I must be dreaming,
What is it?
Is that all you can find to tell me?
Fuck, what do you want me to say?
Time.
Don't give up on me, OK?
How can I help you?
Maybe bring me some clothes.
Maybe you can lend me some money?
Why do you need money in prison?
Don't offer to help if you don't want to.
But I do.
I want to help, yes.
Everything costs s bomb in here, toothpaste, food,
The price of cigarettes is ridiculous.
Might help you to stop smoking.
I think they have a bank transfer system.
You could look into it, no?
Hello.
I've come to get some music sheets, I left up here.
I threw everything out.
Sorry.
Never mind.
What's the link...
between a bungee jumper and a faggot?
I don't know.
- Have a guess. - I don't know.
I give up.
If the elastic snaps. they're both up shit creek.
That's crap and disgusting!
Fuck, that's bad.
Wait, I've got a better one,
Two dogs on a walk in Berlin,
one of them lifts his leg
and goes like this,
and the other one also starts peeing...
The first looks straight ahead, not realizing they're both there...
and starts peeing in the other direction,
and the first dog...
is still peeing like that.
He turns round and says
wasn't there a wall here before?
In Berlin...
that's so bad.
I've got to tell you something too.
OK.
This isn't easy to say, so hear me out.
Go for it, I'm listening.
You've got to stop coming.
It's going to fuck us up.
It's a skewed picture of reality here.
But when we meet here it's good...
It hurts me more than anything.
Thirty minutes, for fuck's sake.
Thirty minutes in a week is...
What's the use?
It's still good, isn't it?
Listen, I know what I'm saying.
OK?
You've got to stop coming because... I've got my reasons,
everyone will be happier that way, especially you. Believe me.
How can you know that?
You make me weak.
As soon as I see you I go...
It weakens me.
I've got to protect myself.
Do it for me.
No.
Not for you, not for anyone, not for me.
I;m staying here, period!
I'm sorry.
I'm doing this for us.
- No - Stop... stop.
Stop, it's finished now.
You bastard!
- Stop it! - You have no right!
You fucking bastard!
Get him out of here!
Bastard! Bastard! Bastard!
- You want to start with that. - OK.
Your go.
Bring your knees together a bit.
Your back.
So...
Three, four, three...
again, three four...
Ilir!
Keep going.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Lets look after this.
- Answer. - No.
Come on.
No, its fine.
Hello?
Excuse me.
Wait, hello?
It's me, can you hear me?
Where are you?
I need your help.
Alright?
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, I...
a touch of flu, that's all.
Here, what have you got?
It's from a food tin,
with the lid.
Listen, I'm in a spot of bother...
If you could...
If you could bring me some stash.
Like what?
You know exactly what.
No...no.
Come on, please.
I'll send you money, that's no problem.
That's pointless.
It's real currency in here.
What do I do if I get caught?
Like you're going to get caught?
with your angel face.
No, no and no.
Forget it.
Thanks for coming then.
OK, it's all here.
- Do you want some help? - No.
Well, I hope he's worth it.
He's never asked me for anything,
so now I can help him, I'm doing it.
A 300 euro hash deal, love is beautiful.
- I thought you weren't jealous. - I'm not,
I'm worried, that's all.
It's alright, I know what I'm doing.
Well, if you get into trouble, don't come crying here.
- I hope that's clear. - Yes.
The 1:30 visit, ladies and gentlemen.
Hello.
Please close the door behind you.
Visiting rooms open.
- My side is fine. - Mine too.
Go for it.
They need to be smaller.
- Sorry. - Keep going, give me the rest.
Wait.
Wait, one second.
How's your family?
They're well, they're happy...
- What are they up to? - On holiday.
- That's nice. - To the country.
The country, that's good.
No, not yet.
They're well, really well.
- We could go to the country - That would be good.
We're clear.
Go for it.
Wait!
Sorry, Sorry...
Stop... stop, stop.
Spit it out.
Fuck!
Shit!
Thank Christ.
Where the fuck were you?
Where were you?
Tell me.
Tell me, for fuck's sake!
Answer me.
Let go of me.
This is still my home.
Stay there!
Explain it to me.
Did they catch you?
I fucked things up for him.
It's not your fault.
You can't save him.
You've got to stop suffering like this.
I'm useless, I'm useless, I'm useless!
Let me take care of you.
- Good luck. - Thank you.
I leave you alone for a bit, and look where you end up.
How are you?
And you?
I'm OK.
You could say hello to me.
Hello.
You know what they gave me when I was released?
Look.
It's too late now.
I hope so, for you.
I gave all your stuff to your sister.
Yeah, she told me.
Thanks.
Do you need some help?
Listen, I finish in two hours, we could meet up in a bar.
I don't want us to talk here.
OK.
- See you in a bit. - Yes.
Do you want some sugar?
Yeah, cheers.
You've become all grown up.
No, it's just that I made some choices.
Do you really find sexy boy better than me?
No, you are definitely better looking.
So?
So what?... so...
It's complicated.
Where are you crashing?
With my sister.
And are you sure you know where to sleep?
No, I'm not really sure.
I'm not sure about anything.
You know what, let's celebrate.
Forget about everything, celebrate and start from scratch, OK?
I don't know.
Oh come on, please, don't say no.
Should we go for a walk?
Cool.
Come on.
We'd like a room.
- For two? - Yes.
Twin beds?
- Does it look like we're together? - Oh yes, yes. I'm sorry.
We've got some luxury rooms at 340 euro.
- Nothing smaller? - No, that's fine.
I'll pay now.
- This is ridiculous, we'll share. - No, it's OK.
Hard to get it out. Here.
Do you want to come upstairs with us?
I don't even make you hard anymore, do I?
What's this?
- Nothing. - What?
It's nothing I said, too much playing.
Stop.
Stop, stop!
Stop it!
We're here all night, so...
Oh fuck.
It feels like I'm still in a cell.
And on top of it I picked up something nasty.
What?
Syphilis.
It's not the end of the world, just a pain.
But it's OK.
- But did you... - I didn't have a choice,
you had a choice.
What do you know? I did what I could, like you.
Like you.
If you say so.
Just like me.
In that case, bottoms up.
What are you doing?
- I'm leaving. Wait...
you can't leave like that, wait a couple of minutes.
I have to be somewhere.
I forgot, you're over-booked now you've become a winner.
If you say so.
Wait!
You know what, I...
I don't even have a photo of you.
It's not as if we're not going to see each other again.
One photo.
OK?
Are you ready?
No, wait wait.
This isn't us, is it?
We have to be happy.
OK?
Right!
- You've got to smile, OK? - Yes.
One... two...
and three.
subs by NERO2000