Subtitles by DramaFever
Why isn't anyone helping me get up?
Why?
Let's just end this here.
This is too hard.
It's just too hard.
No.
I have to live.
I want to live.
Someone...
Someone grab me.
I want someone to grab me!
How much do you think
this building costs?
Excuse me?
Do you think that there's
anyone out there
who'd want to exchange
their life for this?
By any chance...
Do you know of any
restrooms in the area
where a lot of homeless
people frequents?
What?
I'm sorry, but the patients in this
area needs absolute peace and quiet.
You cannot interview
anyone in this area.
Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk is
admitted here, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
Then I guess we can't do
anything else about it.
I'm sure he'll have
to come out sometime.
Let's just wait for him.
- Yes, Director.
- How's his condition now?
Okay.
Don't let him out of your sight
until I get there.
Okay.
Add him to the family registry quickly.
But all the reporters
are there already.
Reporters?
There's Kang Ji Hyuk right there.
Is it true that you're
Chairman Kang Sung Wook's hidden son?
What's the reason for keeping
that truth a secret all this time?
How do you think things will change as
you come on board as a new heir?
When did you find out that you're
Chairman Kang Sung Wook's son?
Is that fact related to
your recent accident?
What are you guys talking about?
- Aren't you Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk?
- Kang Ji Hyuk?
My name is Kim Ji Hyuk.
Ji Hyuk.
What a relief to see that you're okay.
I'm so glad to see you, Ji Hyuk.
Do you remember anything
from your childhood?
No.
I don't remember a thing.
Let's not rush anything.
Once we come to terms with our own
emotions, and get used to each other
I'm sure we'll be able to form a bond
as father and son, and as family then.
You understand what I'm
saying, don't you?
No, I have no idea what you're saying.
Okay, I understand.
I'm sure you must be flustered since
that's the way I'm feeling right now.
What I'm saying is that we both should
take some time to get used to the idea.
Get some rest for now.
What do you do for a living?
You'll find that out soon enough.
Do I have a mother?
Of course you do.
Really?
- Does she know?
- Of course.
You should've just let
the sleeping dogs lie.
We're just going to complicate
everything for one another.
I can't do that.
Because you're my son.
Because I'm your son?
What's the point of seeking me out now?
Why are they getting so curious about
our family registry all of a sudden?
I think they received a request
from the investigators.
I think they must've
discovered something
that may have been
done illegally.
Ugh, why now of all times?
Forget it. I don't
think we need to worry
about it since the
office will soon change.
Did you look into the foreign matters
that I told you to look into?
Yes, I think we'll get an
answer from them soon.
You think it'll work?
I think there's more than
a 90 percent chance that it will.
Is that right?
And one more thing.
That guy...
I want you to confuse him. Throw money,
women, and whatever else at him.
So that he doesn't have a chance
to think about anything else.
Yes, Sir.
That's the life history
of Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk
that we have of
him up to this point.
Don't you rather that you didn't know
any of that?
- Why do I have to know any of this?
- Because he's part of the family.
He's someone whom you need to serve.
I started searching for Kang Ji Hyuk's
whereabouts about a year ago
per Chairman Kang's orders.
I found out about Kang Ji
Hyuk's existence very recently
and I was able to find
his DNA records purely
by coincidence from
his recent accident.
That's the result of all my findings.
I just prepared some things that
I thought you may need for the moment.
Just let me know if there's
anything else that you need.
And one more thing.
This is the key to the car
that you'll be driving.
Let me know if the car
isn't to your liking
and I'll swap it out
for something else.
Are you trying to recruit me right now?
You know how those sports teams always
gets the players whatever they want
when trying to recruit them?
Getting them an amazing place to live
with a fancy car to boot.
There's no one in this world
who tries to recruit a son.
I'm sure you guys can do all this
since that guy has so much money.
Anyways, this is nice.
Getting a chance to live...
in an amazing place like this
for having met a nice set of parents.
Money sure is nice.
I want you to bring that scoundrel
back here and rip his heart out!
What floor are we even on?
Crap!
Thank you.
For some strange reason,
I keep having to receive help from you.
Um...
Call me anytime if there's
anything else that you need.
Yeah, sure.
But...
What is it that you do for them?
I'm an employee of Hyun Sung Group.
I take care of
Chairman Kang's family.
Really?
Then I guess you must get to see
those parents of mine pretty often?
- Yes, I do.
- Go give them a message for me.
Tell them that I'm
tearfully grateful for
buying me this grand
house and the fancy car.
The son that they just threw away
and abandoned for the past 30 years...
is speechless with utter gratefulness.
Please make sure to
relay that message.
Yes, Sir.
Now it's raining?
Well that's just depressing.
You told me to let you know if there's
anything else I might need, right?
Yes, tell me.
What is it that you need?
An extra umbrella so
that I may be able to
shield a lady from getting
soaked in the rain.
Dong Suk.
You're going to get up from that bed
as if nothing even happened, right?
I've been so afraid...
and because of that...
I've never even once got to
tell you that I love you.
So please just get up from that bed.
I can't live without you.
Oh my, look who it is!
Ji Hyuk's here.
Yes, it's me.
- Are you well?
- Of course!
Why are you still following me?
It's my job to do so.
Mom!
- Mom!
- What are you doing!
Get away from me!
You're grossing me out!
Mom, do you have any idea
how much I've missed you?
- You must've been so worried about me.
- Don't' talk crazy.
Why would I worry about you?
I'm busy enough as is with my own life.
Excuse me, but are you his mother?
His mother?
Mother, my butt.
He thinks that all the middle aged
women in this world are his mom.
Especially if there's something
that he can gain from the woman.
I bet he probably has
more than 30 women
in this market alone
whom he calls 'mom'.
No, Mom.
They're just regular moms.
But you're my mom.
Stop kissing my face.
Hey!
Where and what have you been
doing these past few days?
And... who is this young lady?
Did you cause another accident?
Accident?
Yeah, I did.
A huge accident.
You didn't.
- Before you're even married?
- Excuse me?
Come on, Mom!
What do you take me for?
You're painting a bad picture of me
in front of this lady.
Don't let her mislead you.
I'm much more virtuous than I may look.
Mrs. Hong!
Mrs. Hong, Ji Hyuk is...
Ji... Ji Hyuk!
Your Highness!
Please forgive me for
not having recognized
your status to have
served you properly.
I swear to pledge the rest of my life
in your servitude, Your Highness!
What's wrong with you now?
I told you that I caused
a slight accident.
- What is he talking about?
- Ji Hyuk is...
You know the company,
Hyun Sung Group, right?
Yeah.
He's that Chairman's son! It's all
over the internet and the newspapers!
- Is he serious?
- It's not a sure thing yet.
But that's what those
people are saying.
There's something that
I have to show you.
Is what I heard on the news... true?
What is it?
Is he mom's son too?
- Or is he just your son, Dad?
- Your mom gave birth to him.
Honey.
Madame Choi, he came from your womb.
You can't even remember that?
This is crazy.
Thanks, Dad.
You kept this a secret
for how many decades
just so that you could
surprise me like this?
I sincerely thank you. It was the
biggest surprise gift of my life.
Surprise!
What was the point of
lying to Jin Ah too?
Then you go tell
her the truth.
Tell her that we smacked a perfectly
healthy guy on his head
and lied about him
being our son just so
we could save
our own son's life.
Tell her that's how
evil her parents are.
Go tell her that.
Wow, this is like a scene
right out of a movie.
I feel like we're in a drama.
So they've
been watching you all this time?
Couldn't a document like this have
been forged if you guys had wanted to?
It's not like they were shot
in the head or something.
Why would they want to
claim you as their son?
What use could you be
to them when you've
got nothing to offer
them but your body?
Don't you agree?
If you have a hard time believing me,
I can get it authenticated for you.
Well... there's no need to go through
all that trouble.
Hey.
I think others are right about that.
You're being suspicious over nothing.
You should just be grateful that
they even sought out a son like you.
I told you that I'm too
busy to come tomorrow.
What?
Why do you have to put it like that?
Forget it.
I don't need your chump change.
You're the one who needs
to get it straight.
I'm hanging up.
- How unbelievable.
- Who was that?
That was Mr. Kim.
Mr. Kim from the butcher
shop at the market?
Yeah.
When I told him that I was going
to take the day off tomorrow
he threatened that he wasn't going
to pay me my wages that he owes me.
It's not like it's a lot of money.
It's just 100,000 won.
Maybe we should just
buy his butcher shop.
I bet 20-30 million won
is all we would need.
Ji Hyuk, since we're just
sitting around here,
should we call up those
girls for a date?
Don't you think that
they'd go out on a date
with us if we got them
a commercial deal?
- Dae Suk.
- Yeah?
Come over here.
We struggled through so much
all these years, haven't we?
I especially know how much
you struggled because of me.
Ji Hyuk.
Thank you so much for recognizing that.
There's no need to thank me.
Don't you know how well I know you?
You're...
What did you say, you jerk?
Buy the butcher shop?
Bite down.
Bite down real hard!
I'm sorry, Mr. Kim.
No, I had a few too much to drink,
and I must've been out of my mind.
I'm down on my knees right now.
Yes, I'll be there
first thing in the
morning, and get the
place sparkling clean.
Thank you, Mr. Kim.
Have a good night.
Satisfied?
Of course.
Don't you think that
you're being too harsh?
Let me enjoy some
of your spoils too.
And you should enjoy some of this too.
Doesn't this make you happy?
Your parents are filthy rich.
The parents that you've been wanting
to find all your life.
I didn't want to
find people like that.
Don't be a fool.
I'm sure you must've missed them.
They're your mom and dad.
I was curious to know who they were.
Curious to see how
they were living after
throwing their own child
out on the streets.
But...
they're living a high and mighty life.
Not only that, but they're chaebols.
I definitely didn't want to find
parents like that.
That's why I'm not as resentful.
I was about to get
really pissed about it.
Ji Hyuk.
It's time for you to get
down from there now.
Your mom and dad aren't coming today.
Just get down from there.
Mom...
Dad...
I received a call from China.
All the preparations are complete.
Really?
- When did they say is possible?
- They said it can be done at anytime.
We said we would prepare the
medical team on our end.
We just have to send the team
as soon they are ready.
Good job.
You did nice work.
And also... I've been giving some
thought to the issue with our guy.
What do you think of sending him to
our branch office in the Philippines?
- To the Philippines?
- Yes.
Kidnapping is a frequent
occurrence over there,
and the chances of
recovering the victim is...
Okay, you do what you think is best.
Yes, Sir.
I will take care of it.
Yeah, what is it?
What?
Who's there?
That bastard is going to drive me
out of my mind.
This is a house?
Ugh, what's wrong with my eyes?
You!
Are you by any chance...
Are you Jin Ah?
- It's great to meet you!
- It's you, isn't it?
You're that trash.
How can you call a person
you just met, 'trash'?
- You have a nasty habit with words.
- Hey!
Do you know how much suffering
you put me through?
I think that you must be
mistaken about something.
But I've never met you
before in my life.
Anyways, it's great to meet you!
Have you lost your mind?
Let go of my hand.
I'm going to report you
for sexual harassment.
What's going on out here?
- Who are you?
- Mom.
Wait... you're...
You're...
Hello.
Mom, you know this guy?
His name is Kang Ji Hyuk.
He's your older brother.
This trash is my brother?
Dear God!
Thank you so much!
I feel so much better now.
We're going to take our
own doctors too, so
the surgery shouldn't
be a problem at all.
Dear God... thank you!
And that scoundrel, Ji Hyuk, won't be
coming around you anymore after today.
- I'm thinking of sending him overseas.
- Overseas?
Okay.
So treat him like
a real mother would for the night
so that he doesn't become
suspicious of anything.
For one last time.
Okay.
I guess what they say about blood
being thicker than water must be true.
Seeing how you two have already met
by chance like that.
This makes no sense.
I cannot accept any of this.
This seriously can't be happening.
Why of all people...
I should've called to
invite you over sooner.
But everything just
happened so suddenly,
and I needed some time
to prepare myself.
So... are you liking the house...
that you're living in right now?
- Yes.
- That's a relief.
- Is there anything else you need?
- No, there isn't.
I see.
- Um...
You go ahead first, Honey.
I wasn't... oh, okay.
We really... would like to do something
really nice for you.
We know that you've had to suffer
quite a bit all these years.
We'd like to send you
on a trip overseas.
Why did you abandon me?
- Huh?
We didn't abandon you...
we lost you.
Then...
why seek me out now...
when you haven't sought me out
all these years?
Yeah, I've been curious about that too.
I've never once in my
life heard anything
about me having another
older sibling.
What's the reason for having
kept it a secret from me too?
That's because...
Why don't we do this?
Let's just...
Let's just live our lives
with some distance between us?
Instead of trying to force some
feelings that doesn't even exist.
I think that's the best thing to do.
Thanks for the tea.
I didn't want to tell anyone.
Because I wanted to
forget what had happened.
Whenever I would think of you...
I thought that my heart
would rip to shreds...
and I couldn't handle
the agonizing pain.
I've never once...
in all these years...
have ever stopped...
thinking about you.
I just hoped and prayed...
that you were still alive.
All I prayed for...
was that you were somehow still alive.
I prayed... every single night for you.
Thank you for still being alive.
Thank you... Thank you so
much for still being alive!
Thank you... thank you!
Thank you for still being alive.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you for still being alive.
What did you parents say?
The woman who calls herself my mom...
held my hand and cried.
Yeah... I can't even imagine
how much you mom must've missed you.
Didn't you feel something when you
held your mom's hand?
You felt the warmth of
your mom's hand, right?
I'm not sure.
Holding a mom's hand...
That's something
I never got to experience before.
There's no need for you to worry.
His health has deteriorated to a point
where the success rate is almost
at a hundred percent right now.
There's almost no chance
of any side effects either.
Being a parent is so hard.
I'll wait for you with
a smile on my face.
Dong Suk.
- Why are you being so loud?
- They want the Golden Boat!
- What's a 'Golden Boat'?
- I need everyone's attention!
In celebration of His Highness, Ji Hyuk,
having found his birth parents
he has offered to pay the drink tab
for everyone that's here tonight!
Hey!
I'm not paying for everyone's tab!
- Your parents are filthy rich!
- I'm not rich. Those people are rich.
That whole thing about the
Golden Boat is void, okay?
You have to pay for
your own drink tabs.
Don't be misled by what you have seen
or heard on the news, okay?
I'm not a rich family's son.
I'm just one of you guys
here at Guchangdo Market.
Don't feel awkward around me, and treat
me casually like you've always done.
- Let's cheers.
- Okay, fine.
If that's what you really
want, then go ahead.
But you have to pay for
our drink tabs, okay?
Okay, fine!
It'll be my treat!
But I'm not paying for the snacks too.
Just your drink tabs, okay?
- Okay, it's a deal!
- Wait! But no beers.
You can only get soju.
Who even drinks beer
anymore these days?
It's just expensive and filling.
Okay, then drink as
much as you'd like.
Okay, we'll take that.
A round of applause!
The guy who calls that a real treat,
and those that are satisfied with it...
You guys are all the same!
Why are you all so cheap!
Ms. Mi Ra!
The heir to the Hyun Sung
Group is going to
treat in celebration of
finding his parents.
But he only offered to pay for soju,
and we're not allowed to get any beer.
Don't you think that's an insult
to Hyun Sung Group's name?
I understand. I will pay for
everything with my company card.
Really?
Everything that these
people are having?
Yes, that won't be a problem.
You heard her, right?
Everything is on her!
Hurray for Ji Hyuk!
No, that's not the
right thing to say.
Ji Hyuk didn't pay for a thing.
We should hurray for Ms. Mi Ra.
- Everyone hurray for Ms. Mi Ra!
- Hurray for Ms. Mi Ra!
Here, let me pour you your first drink.
Hey, does she look like
the sort of person
who'd drink soju in a
filthy place like this?
You just don't get it.
I'm sorry.
I'll take you to a fancy place later
and buy you a glass of red wine.
No, I'll accept that drink.
Drink the whole thing.
Wow, she's a good drinker!
Let me pour you one too.
Wow, what a great drinker!
- Let me pour you a drink too.
- Stop feeding her drinks!
You scoundrel.
Just because she's your girlfriend...
- She's not my girlfriend.
- Let me see that.
Here.
If you're going to start
dating this rascal,
then you have to let
me pour you a drink.
If you don't,
then I can't give you my blessing.
- No, don't give her another drink!
- No.
I'll accept just one more drink
since you're already here.
I like your style.
Here, let me pour you one.
Take good care of our
Ji Hyuk for us, okay?
Sure!
I think you've had enough.
Let's get you up.
Are you okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- Let's go before you drink anymore.
Where do you think you're going?
She can't leave
until she sings us a song first.
Sing a song right now?
You think it's okay to just
let them go or not?
No, of course not!
What are you guys doing!
What do you think you're doing!
Ms. Mi Ra.
What a nice singer!
Ms. Mi Ra, wake up.
Is this the right place?
Thank you.
Thank you for still being alive.
Which one's your house?
I'll take you home.
Forget it.
Stop worrying about me,
and you just worry about yourself.
Me?
But I'm fine.
Look here, Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk.
Let me give you a piece of advice.
But don't get your pride all ruffled up
where it's not needed.
Take the money and
spend it all you like,
and do everything you've
ever wanted to do.
Buy everything you've
ever wanted to buy, and
eat everything you've
ever wanted to eat.
That's what you should do.
Why aren't you doing any of that?
Why?
Why aren't you spending any money
when they're telling you to?
Spend as much as you'd like!
I've never once...
thought of their money as mine.
That's why... that's why you're a fool.
- A fool.
- Excuse me?
Thank you for still being alive.
This is a nice neighborhood.
Can you come over here and
help me pick one out?
I've never been overseas before,
so I'm not sure which one to get.
Um... why didn't you ever join
a girl group or something?
Excuse me?
I don't think it's
too late for you yet.
You should start training or something.
You're a pretty good singer.
What are you talking about?
- You don't remember last night?
- No, not at all.
You must've been really
drunk last night.
I understand.
Because I myself confuse my dreams from
reality from time to time when I drink.
What do you think about this one?
Let me know if you need anything else.
No, I'm all set with this.
I forgot you told me to
go spend all my money.
I should just blow all my money here.
You called me a fool and
told me to spend all my money.
Let's go. I'm going to blow
some serious money on you today.
No. I didn't tell you to
spend it on someone else.
I told you to spend it on yourself...
So you do remember.
You should've told me
that you remember!
Why are you trying to lie to me?
Let's go. I'll show
you how I can spend...
No, please don't
be like this.
Everyone can make a mistake or two
when they're drunk. Let's go.
I told you to stop doing this!
- I was just...
- I'm sorry, but I'm working right now.
I hope that we don't make
things uncomfortable
for each other
while I'm working.
Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk?
I'm Reporter Bae from WVS News.
I met you at the hospital.
Can you give me an interview?
- What do you think?
- Huh?
- What interview?
- I'm sorry, but we must get going.
- I just need a few minutes.
- No, I'm sorry.
Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk!
Wait!
What did you and the
Chairman talk about?
I told you that you
can't interview him.
What did you two talk about?
Where does your shares
stand compared to
Director Kang Dong
Suk at the company?
I told you that you
can't interview him!
Reporter Bae!
Don't you think that it's time for you
to make a move in your career?
If a man like you came to
work for me at my company
I have a feeling that we could be
quite successful together.
Sir.
Why don't you just be frank with me?
What is it that you
want to hear from me?
I'll just be honest with you
since you're my junior.
Why do you keep digging
around my company?
You know a man by the name
of Jung Won Tae, don't' you?
He was the prosecutor for
Seoul's eastern district?
- Yes, I know him.
- You owe him a debt, don't you?
When he got transferred down to Busan?
Are you saying that I'm responsible
for his transfer?
It has been decided that he'll be
promoted to Chief Prosecutor.
Even though he's slightly starting to
dig around right now
he's going to get serious about it
once he's officially promoted.
I think it would be wise for you to
prepare yourself for a serious battle.
Ta da!
- Study hard, okay?
- Okay!
Okay, next!
- Thank you!
- You're so cute! How old are you?
- I'm five years old.
- You're five?
Study hard, okay?
I want something else.
- Just take what you're given.
- I want a robot too!
I don't have another robot.
Just take the pink pencil case.
I want a robot!
You little rascal.
Give it back if you don't want it,
and I'll give it to someone else.
Next.
What?
Did you just kick me?
Would you look at this kid. How dare
you glare at an adult like that?
Come over here, you rascal.
Hey!
Get over here right now!
You've met your match today.
Come here!
Come over here right now!
How dare you act like I used to
when I was a kid?
I'm going to drown
you with my kisses!
Let go of me!
My Sister Mom!
This is not a lie, but I'm really
going to come here often from now on.
No, it's okay. Don't worry about me,
and you just go live a happy life.
Okay, always be healthy,
and I'm going to get going now.
No need to see me out.
I'm going to get going.
Ji Hyuk, wait.
I've been holding onto something
that may have helped you
if you ever wanted to
search for your parents.
But now that you've found your parents
there's no reason for me to
hang onto this anymore.
I think this may have been in the bag
that you were carrying with you.
[I know that the
heavens will punish me
for abandoning my child
at this place...]
[But it's just too
difficult to raise
this child on my own
without his father.]
Have you known about it too?
Excuse me?
I'm sure you were just doing
what you were told.
I have an urgent matter to tend to,
so I'll see you later.
What is this about?
If you could just tell me
what this is about...
Oh my goodness!
- What are you doing here?
- Where's mother's room?
- Mom isn't here right now.
- Is it over there?
Hey... you! You seem to be
mistaken about something here.
But we don't think
of you as family yet.
No, you'll never be our family.
Do you know why?
It's because you're trash.
Take a good look.
Do you actually think that you and I
look like siblings?
No.
Not even close.
Right?
You don't think so either.
What the hell is his deal?
- Straighten that out.
- Yes, Sir.
Yes, Lady Jin Ah.
The caller you are trying
cannot be reached,
so please leave a
message at the tone.
- Yes, Director.
- What happened?
Why did Kang Ji Hyuk suddenly
cause a scene over at the house?
By any chance...
did he catch on to what's going on?
I think Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk discovered
something at the orphanage.
Really?
Do you remember the thing that I told
you to prepare in case of an emergency?
We need to get it ready in a hurry.
Send out a team over to the company.
Okay.
Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk.
What brings you by here?
Where's Chairman Kang right now?
I'm actually trying to locate
where Chairman Kang is myself.
I think he may be away
on a business trip.
Can you get in touch with him?
I'm not sure.
I tried to reach him,
but I wasn't able to get a hold of him.
He may be in the middle of
an important meeting right now.
What is it that you
need to see him about?
There's something
that I need to verify with him.
Why don't you tell me what it is?
- I can check for you when I see him...
- No.
I'd like to speak to him
directly in person.
I'll just wait for him.
Is there something...
that you're disappointed
with the Chairman about?
It's been quite a
while since I started
working for Chairman
Kang and his family.
There's something
that I've learned in
all the years that
I've worked for them.
All the members of that family...
are weary of other people.
Just think about what it would be like
if you had just walked out of a bank
with a huge bag of cash on you.
You begin to be suspicious of everyone
who walks by you.
Same goes for blood ties. No, blood
ties are even more suspicious.
Because closer a person is to you
higher the danger of that person
stabbing you in the back.
You cannot expect...
a normal family life
with people like that.
Is that right?
Then... why would people
like that falsely
forge up a family
registry document?
I have no idea what it is
that you're implying right now.
Looking at you right now...
I get the feeling that you know this
family better than anyone else.
Then I guess you must
know about it too.
What their true intentions are.
Mr. Kang Ji Hyuk.
You seem to be misunderstood
about something.
But you really are
the biological son of Chairman Kang.
There is only one reason why
anyone would show any kindness...
to a stray dog out on the streets.
It's so that they can devour the dog.
Then what do you think
the stray dog in
that situation must do
in order to survive?
The dog must rip them to shreds
as they try to attack.
That's the only way for
the dog to survive!
- What is it that you want from me?
- This is all a misunderstanding.
Do you know what kind of people
I hate the most in this world?
It's those who deceives
me about my parents!
No, that's not true.
You must believe me.
It seems as though
whatever you're hiding is
more important to you
than your own life.
Warn Chairman Kang for me.
Because I'm going to meet him
to get the truth out of him myself.
I'm not that generous of a person... so
you won't' get away easy the next time.
He's...
at the company's 48th
anniversary event right now.
Is Chairman Kang
in there right now?
No, he's not. But
Director Do is in there.
He's on his way there right now.
We don't need to explain
anything to him this time.
Just make it clean...
and get rid of him once and for all.
Don't go.
Please don't go.
I need to go and verify it for myself.
I need to find out who I really am.
Just who it is that I really am.
Hold on.
Yes, I understand.
Move!
Move out of the way!
- Dad.
- You're here.
What is it that you're
wearing right now?
That guy came by the house earlier
and caused a huge ruckus.
- Who did?
- Who do you think? Your firstborn son.
Let's talk about that later.
He's fake, isn't he?
- Chairman Cha... you came.
- Yes.
It's me.
We can't let that bastard go in there.
Stop him. Stop him even if
you have to ram him down.
What are you planning
to do in there?
I don't know what I'm
going to do either.
I believe that the
only reason Hyun Sung
has been able to endure
the past 48 years
was because of the efforts
put in by everyone at the company.
A leader with the correct set of
principles and experience...
and all the family
members at Hyun Sung who
followed that leadership
with loyalty.
I will do everything within my power
to grow the strength
further to last another
48 years, and longer
into the future.
My Hyun Sung family...
and everyone else who has
dedicated themselves
to the further future
growth of Hyun Sung...
I hope that we can all join our efforts
to grow Hyun Sung into a company
that could become a
leader of the future
for the people of
this country...
I will take the lead to pave the way
for a brighter future.
Chairman Kang Sung Wook.
Tell me the truth.
Am I...
truly your son?
I would like to introduce
you all to the
bright new future
of Hyun Sung Group.
He is the bright new leader who will be
the face of a new branch of Hyun Sung.
A man who will be leading
a whole new branch
of Hyun Sung into a
bright new future.
Allow me to introduce you all to
President Kang Ji Hyuk.
Under the orders of
Chairman Kang Sung Wook...
I promise to all of
you that I will lead
Hyun Sung Group to a
new age of the future.
[Next Episode Preview]
President Kang Ji Hyuk?
Where did they find a
character like that?
Fight is all about speed.
One swift blow to the face,
and all his teeth will be knocked out.
This is in response to
the complaints that
we've received in regards
to your leadership.
Are you trying to punish me?
Is that trash really my brother?
This is the final scene to the play.
Bringing Hyun Sung Group
down to the ground.
- A man is dead.
- Dead?
- Get rid of that jerk!
- This is my company!