* [ Record Scratches, Stops ]
* I was dancing
when I was 12 *
when I was out *
* I was dancing
* I danced myself
right out the womb *
* Is it strange
to dance so soon *
* I danced myself
right out the womb *
* I was dancing
when I was eight *
* Is it strange
to dance so late *
* How *
* How-ow-ow *
* I danced myself
into the tomb *
[ Bell Rings ]
* I danced myself
into the tomb *
* Is it strange to dance
so soon *
* I danced myself
into the tomb *
* Is it wrong
to understand *
* The fear that dwells
inside a man *
* What's it like
to be a loon *
Ah, no !
* I liken it
to a balloon *
* How *
* How-ow-ow *
* I danced myself
out of the womb *
Grandma.
[ Gasps ]
Your eggs.
It's Billy.
* I danced myself
into the tomb *
Come on.
* I danced myself
out of the womb *
* Is it strange
to dance so soon *
[ Record Scratches ]
Fuck !
You been playin' my records,
you little twat !
I never played naught.
Ow !
Knobhead !
If Dad knew you smoked
that stuff, he'd go mental.
Fuck off, will ya ?
Twat.
[ Softly ]
* I danced myself
out of the womb *
[ Older Boy ]
Here we go, Dad!
Come on, man.
[ Mumbles ]
Dad!
Hurry up, Dad.
We'll be late.
The whole friggin' world's
gonna be on that picket line
this mornin'.
Oi! You tidy our room.
Dad!
There's not much
of this coal left.
It's fine. We'll be digging
it up again next month.
Don't kid yourself.
I'm not waitin' for youse.
Tony. Tony !
see you down
the picket line, Dad.
[ Sighs ]
Leave it, Billy.
Mam would've let us.
* [ Humming ]
* [ Humming Continues ]
[ Dad ]
Your 50 pence
is on the fridge.
*
[ Men Chanting ]
Scab ! Scab ! Scab !
Are you sure
you're not going to come ?
Am I fuck.
It's a load of bollocks.
No, it's not.
It's a load of shite,
kickin'people in.
Anyway, I don't know
why you bother.
- I'm good at it.
-Are you shite ? Them gloves-
They went out with the ark.
- They're me dad's, these.
- Exactly.
Right, lads.
Listen up here.
Hold it !
Oi, oi ! Here !
Now, because
they're using downstairs...
as a soup kitchen
for the strikin'miners,
I'm going to let
Mrs. Wilkinson...
use the bottom end
of the boxin' hall
for her ballet lessons.
So no hanky-panky.
Understood ?
[ Boys Together ]
Yes.
Elliot, you're late.
Get changed
and get in here.
* [ Piano ]
All right then, lads.
Give it all you got!
Round one.
Well, don't just
stand there, Elliot!
Oh, no ! Not again !
This is man-to-man-combat,
not a bloody tea dance.
What're you doin', man ?
Hit him !
Greavesy, he's pissin'about.
Get stuck in and
give him a belt.
- He's like a fanny in a fit.
- Billy, hit him !
[ Trainer ]
Jesus Christ,
Billy Elliot!
You're a disgrace
to them gloves, your father...
and the traditions
of this boxin'hall.
You owe us 50 pence.
* [ Piano ]
Ho ! Liberace,
will you give it a rest ?
[ Piano stops ]
Billy, punch bag.
You're not goin'
until you do it properly.
Give these to Mrs. Wilkinson
and her dance class
when you've finished.
I'll see you next week.
[ Mrs. Wilkinson ]
Okay, girls.
Left hand on the barre.
Thank you,
Mr. Braithwaite.
And-
* [ Piano ]
Pretty arms.
Bottoms in.
Where are you lookin',
susan ?
Lift. Feel the music.
Feel it.
In time, Debbie, please.
And one, and two,
and three,
and four, and five,
six, seven, eight.
And one, and two,
and three,
and four, five-
And hold.
Hold it.
support yourselves!
Don't look at me. Look ahead!
Where's your confidence ?
Come on.
And down.
* [ Piano Continues ]
Lovely.
Oh, God.
And, Debbie, eyes front.
And five, and six,
and seven, and stop.
For God's sake.
Thank you, Mr. Braithwaite.
Right into the center,
girls, please.
Miss ?
Miss, the keys.
Not now.
Right, Mr. Braithwaite.
'The Sun Will Come Out
Tomorrow.'
Fat chance.
Ready, and-
* [ Piano ]
Port de bras forward.
And up.
Why don't you join in ?
Port de bras forward.
And up.
And up,
and hold.
And three, and four.
And, Debbie, straight leg.
seven and eight.
And one, and two, and three,
and four, and five.
Boots off.
Seven and eight.
What size are you ?
Miss, what about
the keys ?
Into the center.
Go on. I dare ya.
Prepare.
And one, and two,
and three,
and four, and five,
and six, and-
And eight, and hold.
Hold it.
Ooh, what have we got
here, then ?
Heel out.
Drop your hip.
Nice... straight leg.
Good arch.
Turn that leg out.
Right. Class dismissed.
Home time.
Debbie, get the 50 P's.
[ Car Horn Honks ]
You owe me 50 pence.
No, I don't !
- You do. Why don't you
bring it along next week ?
- Can't. I'm goin' to boxin'.
- But you're crap at boxin'.
- No, I'm not !
Shut up.
Thought you enjoyed it.
Please yourself, darlin'.
[ Voice Of Fred Astaire ]
* I'm stepping out, my dear *
* To breathe an atmosphere
that simply wreaks with class *
[ Feet Tap-dancing]
* And I trust that
you'll excuse my dust *
* When I step on the gas *
* For I'll be there
putting down my top hat *
* Mussing up my white tie *
* Dancing in my tails *
*
He was your mam's favorite,
was Fred Astaire.
We used to watch him
at the Palace Picture House...
and then dance round
the front room like lunatics.
Marvelous !
Mind, they used
to say...
I could've been
a professional.
Come on, Grandma.
Not now.
Ooh !
Grandma !
It's this one here !
It's over here !
Tony, do you ever
think about death ?
Fuck off !
Night-night, then.
Plenty of boys
do ballet, you know.
Do they now ?
What boys do ballet ?
Nobody around here,
but plenty of men do.
Poofs.
Not necessarily poofs.
Who, like ?
What about Wayne Sleep ?
He's not a poof.
He's as fit as an athlete.
Bet he couldn't beat
Daley Thompson.
Maybe not in a race,
but in stamina.
Why don't you come tomorrow ?
You can just watch.
I can't.
Gotta go to boxin',
haven't I ?
Please yourself, then.
See you around.
Aye. See ya.
Ta-ra.
[ Excited Chattering ]
[ Trainer ]
Right, lads. Look sharp.
Everybody, out!
[ Wilkinson ]
Turn, turn and stop.
One, two, three.
Arms are in fifth.
Turn, turn and stop.
One, two, three.
Where are those arms ?
I don't know what to do.
Follow the orders.
Shut up, Debbie !
One, two, three.
Nice pretty arms.
And stop.
See ?
I told you it takes
loads of practice.
Debbie.
What, Mam ?
What do you call me ?
Miss.
Shove off.
So, do we get the pleasure
of your company next week ?
It's just- I feel
like a right sissy.
Well, don't act like one.
Fifty 'P,' please.
If you're not comin' again,
give us your shoes.
Nah. You're all right.
Right.
What're you doin', goin' round
here like creeping Jesus ?
Naught.
We found your nana
in the Spar stores.
Where have you been ?
Boxin'.
Where do you think ?
What're you doin' ?
I forgot me gloves.
They were
my dad's gloves.
You better take
better care of them, okay ?
*
* Well, you're dirty and sweet
Clad in black *
* Don't look back
And I love you *
Copy that diagram.
We only have five minutes left.
* You're dirty sweet
and you're my girl *
Ow !
* Get it on
Bang a gong *
* Get it on *
* Get it on
Bang a gong *
* Get it on *
[ Coughing ]
* Well, you're built
like a car *
Hurry. This way.
* You got a hubcap
diamond star halo *
* You're built
like a car, oh yeah *
You go to ballet every week ?
Yeah, but don't
say aught.
Why do you take lessons ?
Why do you think ?
To get better, you diwy.
Do you get to wear
a tutu ?
Fuck off !
They're only meant
for lasses.
I wear me shorts.
You won't ask
for a tutu ?
What for ?
To dance in.
I'd look
a right dickhead.
I think you'd look wicked.
* Get it on
Bang a gong *
* Get it on *
Come on.
[ Laughs ]
* Well, you're windy
and wild *
* You got the blues
in your shoes
and your stockings *
* You're windy and wild
Oh yeah *
* Well, you're built
like a car *
* You got a hubcap
diamond star halo *
* You're dirty sweet
and you're my girl *
* Get it on
Bang a gong *
* Get it on *
[ Librarian ]
I don't know why
you're lookin'at that.
You can't take that out
on a junior ticket.
[ siren Wailing ]
Come on !
[ siren Continues ]
* Get it on *
* Bang a gong
Get it on *
* Get it on
Bang a gong *
* Get it on *
See you, then.
* Take me *
[ Laughing,
Excited Chattering ]
[ Wilkinson ]
Okay, Billy Elliot,
into the center.
I want you to watch
carefully, girls.
First, arabesque.
* [ Piano ]
Drop your shoulders.
Look forward,
beyond your fingertips.
There !
[ Groans ]
Spin it, Mr. Braithwaite.
Spin it !
Come on. Spin it !
Now, focus !
Look at yourselves !
Look in the mirror !
Ahh !
Christ Almighty,
what was that ?
[ Dad ] Oi!
What's goin'on ?
Uh, nothin'.
[ Wilkinson ]
Prepare, one and two.
strong position.
Weight on both legs.
And... pirouette.
-And down.
- [ Groans ]
[ Girls Giggling ]
Up you get.
[ Water sloshing ]
Find a place
on that bloody wall...
and focus on that spot.
Then whip your head round
and come back to that spot.
Prepare.
One, and two, and-
Fuck it.
Have you got
the spot ?
Prepare!
- Prepare.
- [ Whispers ] Prepare.
Go !
Go ! Go !
Go, Billy!
What have I told you
about that arm ?
Right.
Back to the barre.
You look like
a right wanker
to me, son.
[ Trainer ]
Listen, Jackie.
It was just 50 pence
a session, you know.
I can do without it.
I do not do it for the money.
What are you talkin' about ?
The boxin', man.
I haven't seen hide nor hair
of your Billy for months.
I was gonna say something,
but I thought
it might be embarrassin'.
First I knew about it.
He's never got his gloves off.
Send him round to my house,
and I'll sharp knock some sense
into him.
[ Shouting ]
[ Men Chanting ]
Scab ! Scab !
Step open and balance.
Balance, balance.
Scab ! Scab ! Scab !
Right.
Let's do it again.
[ Chanting ]
Open...
and lift your chest.
Let's do it again.
Thank you,
Mr. Braithwaite.
[ Wilkinson ] step open.
Open your arms. Do it.
[ Chanting ]
Pay attention.
Arms. Like this.
All right ?
Thank you, Mr. Braithwaite.
Step really open !
[ Shouting ]
[ Wilkinson ]
Powerful! Proud!
* [ Piano ]
You're not
concentratin'.
Yes, I am concentratin'.
You're not even tryin'.
- Can we have a go of it, Miss ?
- Let's do it again.
Have you noticed
anything weird about
our Billy lately ?
What, are you after
like a list ?
[ Dad ]
Aye, aye.
Got enough food there,
scab ?
What're you doin' ?
Eh ?
Scabs eat well, eh ?
You're me best mate.
First rule of a union, Gary.
You never cross a picket line.
Fucking hell.
We're all fucked
if you forget that !
We're fucked anyway!
[ Door slams shut ]
[ Radio Newscaster ]
In a speech to
Tory M.P. 's yesterday,
Prime Minister
Margaret Thatcher...
referred to members of
the striking National
Union of Mine Workers...
as 'the enemy within. '
The speech comes following
several months
of violent clashes...
between police officers
and striking miners-
See you, then.
[ Tony ]
Wait! Y-Your breakfast-
What the hell's he up to ?
One, two, three.
Pas de bourree.
And a one, two, three.
And a turn.
Pas de bourree.
And a one, two, three.
You, out! Now!
I beg your pardon ?
[ Girls Giggling ]
Please, Miss,
don't.
All right, which way
are we facing ?
Come on.
And a one, two, three.
Pas de bourree.
- Ballet.
- What's wrong with ballet ?
- 'What's wrong with ballet' ?
- It's perfectly normal.
[ Dad ]
Perfectly normal?
I used to go to ballet.
See ?
Aye, for your nana.
For girls.
Not for lads, Billy.
Lads do football or...
boxin' or...
wrestlin' !
Not friggin'ballet!
What lads do wrestlin' ?
Don't start, Billy.
I don't see
what's wrong with it.
You know perfectly well
No, I don't.
Yes, you do.
No, I don't !
Yes, you bloody well do !
Who do you think I am ?
You know quite nicely !
What ?
What are you tryin'
to say, Dad?
You're askin'
for a hidin', son.
No, I'm not. Honest.
You are, Billy.
Billy!
It's not just poofs, Dad.
some ballet dancers
are as fit as athletes.
What about that Wayne Sleep ?
He was a ballet dancer.
- Wayne Sleep ?
- Aye.
Listen, son,
from now on you can forget
about the fucking ballet.
You can forget about
the fuckin'boxin'as well.
I'm bustin' my ass for those
50 pences, and you're- No !
From now on you stay here
and look after your nana.
Got that ?
Good.
They used to say
I could have been
a professional dancer...
if I'd had the training.
Will you shut up ?
I hate you !
You're a bastard !
[ Shouts ]
Get off !
Billy ! Billy !
[ Dad ]
Billy!
* But you won't fool *
* The children
of the revolution *
* No, you won't fool *
* The children
of the revolution
No, no, no *
[ Grunting ]
* Yeah *
Aah !
[ Dog Barking ]
* You won't fool the children
of the revolution *
* No, you won't fool *
* The children
of the revolution *
* No, you won't fool *
* The children
of the revolution *
[ Doorbell Rings ]
* No, you won't fool *
* The children
of the revolution *
* No way *
Oh, hello.
[ Sighs ] My dad'll kill me
if he knows I'm here.
He stopped you
comin' to classes.
It's not his fault, Miss.
- That's all right
with you, is it ?
- I suppose so.
- You should stand up to him.
- You don't know what he's like.
Well, that blows it.
Blows what, Miss ?
Debbie ?
[ Mr. Wilkinson ]
I've heard a lot
about you.
Durham's little
Gene Kelly, eh ?
Your dad work
down the pit, then ?
Yeah.
Must be hard for the family
being out on strike.
He is out on strike,
isn't he ?
'Course.
I shouldn't worry.
It won't last long.
Tom, don't.
If they had a ballot,
they'd be back tomorrow.
It's just a few
bloody commies
stirrin' things up.
Let's face it.
They haven't got a leg
to stand on.
Who doesn't ?
The miners.
It stands to reason,
doesn't it ?
some pits arejust
uneconomical.
If it costs more money
to pay everybody...
to dig the coal out
than you get for the coal
when you sell it,
what does that
tell ya ?
Don't know.
You wanna think about that,
don't you, son ?
Tom.
If it was up to me, I'd shut
the lot of'em down tomorrow.
For God's sake.
What do you do,
Mr. Wilkinson ?
[ Debbie ]
He's been made redundant.
I thought he was gonna
hit me or somethin'.
Don't be silly.
He's just under
a lot of pressure.
That's what mam says.
I think it's because
he drinks too much.
Does he drink too much ?
He's always pissed.
Once he pissed himself.
Your dad ?
Because he's unhappy, because
they sleep in separate beds.
Why do they sleep
in separate beds ?
So they can't have sex.
Do they not have sex ?
Dad did it with
this woman from work,
but they don't think
I know.
Do you miss your mam,
then ?
Don't really miss her
as such.
It's more like
just feelin' sad.
Especially when I remember her
all of a sudden.
When I forgot that
she was dead and that.
What about your mam ?
Does she not have sex ?
No, she's unfulfilled.
That's why she does dancin'.
She does dancin'
instead of sex ?
Your family's weird.
No, they're not.
They are, though.
They're mental.
[ Laughing ]
Ow ! Get off !
[ Male singer ]
* Wow *
See ?
You're a nutter, you.
[ Mrs. Wilkinson ]
Debbie! It's time
for Billy to go home!
Come on, Billy.
I'll drop you off at the corner.
I'll see ya, Debbie.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
Okay, then.
Miss,
what have I blown ?
[ Engine stops ]
This'll sound strange, Billy,
but for some time now...
I've been thinkin' of
the Royal Ballet School.
Aren't you a bit old,
Miss ?
Ooh, not me. You !
I'm the bloody teacher !
They hold auditions
in Newcastle.
I'd never be good enough.
I hardly know aught.
They're not interested
in how much ballet you know.
They'll teach you that.
That's why they're a ballet school.
It's how you move and how you
express yourself that's important.
Express what ?
I think you're good enough
to go for it.
It would mean
an awful lot of hard work.
But I'm banned.
Then maybe I should have
a word with him.
No, Miss !
I could teach you
on your own, if you want.
We couldn't afford it.
I'm not doin' it
for the money, Billy.
But what about Dad ?
He doesn't need to know.
What about me boxin' ?
Oh, for fuck's sake, Billy !
If you want to piss about
with your little mates,
that's fine with me.
All right,
don't lose your blob.
'Blob' ?
So we could do it
private-like ?
Just you and me.
Miss, you don't fancy me,
do you ?
No, Billy, funnily enough,
I don't. Now, piss off.
Piss off, yourself.
see you Monday, then.
[ Dog Barks ]
- Are you comin' in or what ?
- What are you doin' ?
Nothin'.
Just dressin' up.
Whose dress is that ?
Come on.
It's me sister's.
Did she give you it ?
she doesn't know.
Do you wanna try ?
You can have one of me mam's.
Nah.
You're all right.
What're you doin'
that for?
I'm just tryin' it on.
Christ.
Come here.
Stay still.
There.
Won't we get
in trouble ?
Don't be stupid.
Me dad does it all the time.
He dresses up
in your mam's clothes ?
Only when he thinks
everybody's out.
Have you got
a tutu yet ?
Do you think being
a ballet dancer...
would be better
than being a miner ?
I don't know.
It's just, I've got
this audition in Newcastle
in a couple of weeks.
What for ?
For to go
to ballet school.
- Ballet school ?
Is that in Newcastle ?
- London.
You'd have to move,
with your Tony and everybody ?
No. By meself.
That's a bit steep.
- Can't you be
a ballet dancer here ?
- Don't be stupid !
So, when you goin'
there, then ?
I don't know.
I haven't even got in yet.
What does
your dad say ?
He doesn't know.
Fuckin'hell!
- Are you not going
to tell him ?
- Not yet, anyway.
He might be pleased about it.
He could rent your room out.
He couldn't.
What about our Tony ?
What do you reckon ?
I think
you shouldn't bother.
Why not ?
I'd miss you.
[ Sighs ]
Fuckin' hell.
Brought your things ?
I don't know
if they're right, Miss.
If they're special to you,
they're right.
What are they for ?
To give us some ideas
for a dance.
Come on, then.
Let's see 'em.
What's that ?
It's a letter.
I can see it's a letter.
It's me mam's.
she wrote it
for when I was 1 8,
but I opened it.
Here.
'To my son Billy.
'Dear Billy.
'I know I must seem
like a distant memory to you,
'which is probably
a good thing.
'It will have been
a long time,
'and I will have missed
seeing you grow.
'Missed you crying,
laughing,
'Laughing...
and shouting.'
'I will have missed
telling you off.
'But please know
I was always there...
'...with you
through everything.'
'with you
through everything,
'and I always will be.
'And I am proud
to have known you,
'and I am proud
that you were mine.
'Always be yourself.
I love you forever.'
'Mam.'
She must've been a very
special woman, your mother.
No, she was just me mam.
I brought tape and all.
What is it ?
'I Love to Boogie.'
It's one of our Tony's.
*
* We love to boogie *
* Jitterbug boogie *
* Bolan pretty boogie *
* We love to boogie
on a saturday night *
* Belinda Mae Fender's
got a Cadillac bone *
Spin it ! Go on !
* Jenny lost her cherry
walkin' all the way home *
* The passion of the earth
blasted its mind *
* Now it's neat sweet ready
for the moon based grind *
* We love to boogie
We love to boogie
on a saturday night *
* I said
we love to boogie *
* We love to boogie *
And tap. Go !
* High school boogie *
* Jitterbug boogie *
[ Gargling ]
* We love to boogie
on a saturday night *
* Oh yeah *
Whoo-whee !
Yee-haw !
*
* You rattlesnake out
with your tail feathers high *
* Jitterbug left
and smile to the sky *
* With your black velvet cape
and your stovepipe hat *
* Bebop baby
The dance is where it's at *
* I love to boogie *
* Yes, I love to boogie
on a saturday night *
* I said
I love to boogie *
* I love to boogie *
* Jitterbug boogie
I love to boogie *
Grandma, teatime.
Where are you goin' ?
Go back to sleep.
It's 4:00.
[ Cigarette Lighter
Clicks ]
You weren't thinkin'
of taking it with you ?
You just wanna stand around
getting the shit
kicked out you,
that's your funeral.
But some of us are ready
to fight back for once.
They're already after you.
- You're no good to us in jail.
- I don't plan
on getting caught.
- What's going on ?
- You, get back to bed !
- Both of you!
- Fuck you.
Put it down.
You gonna stop me ?
I'm warnin' you.
[ Tony ]
You haven't got it in you.
You're finished!
since mam died, you're nothing
but a useless twat! What the
fuck you gonna do about it ?
Stop it !
[ Sighs ]
What the fuck
are you lookin'at ?
You haven't been practicin'.
Prepare. One, two.
And one, and two-
Get up.
Miss, I can't do it.
That's because
you're not concentratin'.
I am concentratin'.
- You're not even tryin' !
- I am, Miss !
- Do it again.
- Can't.
You do it again.
No !
Shit !
I'm sorry.
It's all right
for you.
It's not you
who has to do it!
I know.
You don't know anything!
What do you know
in your posh house...
with your husband
that pisses hisself?
You're the same as
everybody else. All you want
is to tell me what to do !
Now wait a minute!
Look, I don't wanna do
your stupid, fucking audition !
- You only want me to do it
for your own benefit !
- Look, Billy-
Because you're a failure !
Don't you dare talk to me
like that!
You don't even have
a proper dancing school !
You're stuck in
some crummy boxing hall.
Don't pick on me 'cause you
fucked up your own life !
[ Crying ]
[ Billy ]
Can I put a tape on, Miss ?
All right,
if you must.
* [ Tape.: Swan Lake ]
*
[ seagulls squawking ]
* [ Swan Lake Continues ]
*
[ Billy ]
It's cush, isn't it ?
so, is there a story,
then, Miss ?
Of course.
It's about a woman
who's captured
by an evil magician.
Sounds crap.
And this woman-
this beautiful woman...
is forced to be a swan.
Except for a few hours
every night...
when she becomes alive.
She becomes real again.
And then one night...
she meets this young prince,
and he falls in love
with her.
And she realizes...
this is the one thing
that will allow her...
to become a real woman
once more.
So then what happens ?
He promises to marry her
and then goes off with
someone else, of course.
- So she has to be
a swan for good ?
- She dies.
Because the prince
didn't love her ?
Come on.
It's time to go.
It's only
a ghost story.
Come on !
[ Engine starting ]
* [ Swan Lake
Continues ]
*
No ! No, no.
It's me.
It's Billy.
Oh, little one.
Oi, little one.
What have I told you
about drinkin'
out of the bottle ?
Sorry, Mam.
Well, put it back.
[ Sighs ]
One.
Lift and reach.
Down, and one.
Breathe and stretch.
Stretch, and one.
Lift and stretch.
Back, and one.
Lift, and
lengthen that foot.
And it's one.
Extend.
Reach out.
Lift and breathe.
And one.
Lift out...
and close.
And one.
Lift.
When's the audition,
then ?
Tomorrow mornin'.
I'll miss you
if you go away.
Who do you think's better ?
Fred Astaire or Ginger Rogers ?
Billy, do you not
fancy us, like ?
Don't know.
Never really thought
about it.
If you want,
I'll show you me fanny.
No. You're all right.
* Oh oh oh oh *
* Oh oh oh *
* Now get this *
* London calling
to the faraway towns *
Get inside !
* Now war is declared
and battle come down *
The union leader ! Get him !
* London calling
to the underworld *
Get down !
* Come out of the cupboard
you boys and girls *
* London calling
Now don't look to us *
* Phony Beatlemania
has bitten the dust *
* London calling
see we ain't got no swing *
* Except for the ring
of the truncheon thing *
* The Ice Age is comin'
The sun's zooming in *
Thanks, pet.
* Meltdown expected
The wheat is growing thin *
* Engines stop running
but I have no fear *
* 'Cause London is drowning
and I live by the river *
* London calling
to the imitation zone *
* Forget it, brother
You could go it alone *
* London calling
to the zombies of death *
Shit !
* Quit holding out
and draw another breath *
* London calling
and I don't wanna shout *
* But while we were talking
I saw you nodding out *
* London calling
see, we ain't got no highs *
[ Policeman ] Here they come!
* London calling
see, we ain't got no swing *
* Except for the ring
of the truncheon thing *
* Except for that one
with the yellowy eyes *
* The Ice Age is comin'
The sun's zooming in *
* Engines stop running
The wheat is growing thin *
* A nuclear error
But I have no fear *
* 'Cause London is drowning
and I *
Tony !
* I live by the river *
Tony, go back !
* I never felt so much
a'like, a'like *
[ Tony shouting ]
Go on. Get in there !
Off you go, mate !
[ Ringing ]
[ Billy ]
Miss, I've got a problem
with the audition.
Hello ?
Hello !
Listings for court four.
Tony Elliot, George Brunton.
Gary Cummings.
What's the time ?
Colin Woodward.
Ten past 1 0:00.
Oh, Billy !
Hello.
Can I help you ?
I was lookin' for-
They're out.
Sorry.
Billy.
Please, Miss.
Don't.
What's goin' on,
Billy ?
Who the fuck are you ?
I think we better
go inside.
This might be
difficult for you,
but today Billy missed
a very important audition.
Audition ?
For the Royal Ballet School.
The Royal Ballet ?
School. It's where
they teach the ballet.
You've got to be jokin'.
No, I'm perfectly serious.
Have you any idea
of what we're goin' through ?
I've been in
a fuckin'cell
all night,
and you come around here
talkin' shite !
And you!
Fuckin'ballet !
What are you trying to do,
make him a fuckin'skirt
for the rest of his life ?
Look at him !
He's only 1 1 , for fuck's sake !
- You've gotta start trainin'
from when you're young.
- Shut it !
I'm not havin'any brother
of mine running around like
a twat for your gratification.
Excuse me.
This is not for my gratification.
What good's it gonna do him ?
You're not takin' him away.
He's only a bairn. What about
givin' him a childhood ?
I don't want a childhood.
I want to be a ballet dancer.
What do you know about it ?
What qualifications
have you got ?
I haven't come here
to defend meself.
For all we know,
you could be some fuckin'nutter.
Get the fuckin'social
on to you.
- You should calm
yourself down, son.
- You say he can dance.
Well, go on, then.
[ Billy Grunts ]
Let's see
this fuckin' dancin'.
- This is ridiculous.
- If you're a fuckin'
ballet dancer,
then let's be havin' you !
- Don't you dare !
- What sort of a teacher
are you, eh ?
He's got the chance to dance.
Now you're fuckin'
tellin' him not to.
Dance, you little twat !
No ?
So piss off.
He's not doin'anymore
fuckin'ballet,
and if you go near him again,
I'll smack you,
you middle-class cow !
You know nothing about me,
you sanctimonious little shit !
* stop dreaming
of the quiet life *
He won't grow up
to race whippets or grow leeks...
or piss his wages up the wall.
He's been with me-
* Well, stop apologizing
for the things
you've never done *
* Time is short
and life is cruel *
* But it's up to us to change
this town called Malice *
* Rows and rows
of disused milk floats stand
dying in the dairy yard *
* And a hundred
lonely housewives clutch empty
milk bottles to their hearts *
* Hanging out
their old love letters
on the line to dry *
* It's enough
to make you stop believing *
* When tears come
fast and furious
in a town called Malice *
* Yeah *
* Ba ba ba ba
ba da ba *
* Ba ba ba da ba
Oh *
* Ba ba ba ba ba da ba
Ba ba ba da ba *
* struggle after struggle
Year after year *
* The atmosphere's
a fine blend of ice *
* I'm almost stone-cold dead
in a town called Malice *
* Ooh yeah *
* A whole street's belief
in sunday's roast beef *
* Gets dashed
against the co-op *
* To either cut down the beer
or the kids'new gear *
* It's a big decision
in a town called Malice *
* Ooh yeah *
Ah !
* Ooh *
Billy ! Billy !
* The ghost of a steam train
echoes down my track *
* It's at the moment
bound for nowhere *
* Just going
round and round, oh *
* Playground kids
and creaking swings *
* Lost laughter
in the breeze *
* I could go for hours
and I probably will *
* But I'd sooner put
somejoy back in
this town called Malice *
* Yeah *
[ Groaning ]
* Ooh-ooh *
[ Grunting ]
* Town called Malice *
[ Angry Grunting ]
* Yeah, yeah *
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Boy ]
Billy!
Billy, come on !
Hurry up.
[ Trainer ]
Merry Christmas,
everybody!
[ Cheering ]
[ Crowd Chanting ]
* Here we go, here we go
here we go *
* Here we go
here we go
here we go *
* Here we go
here we go
here we go *
* Here we go
Here we go *
here we go
here we go *
[ Chanting Fades ]
* Here we go, here we go
here we go *
[ Man shrieking ]
Do you think she'll mind ?
Shut up, boy.
She's dead.
Well,
merry Christmas,
everybody.
Merry Christmas.
[ Tony ]
Merry
Christmas.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Crying ]
[ Billy ]
* Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way *
* Oh, what fun- *
Fuckin' great Christmas
this has been.
Go on.
Have some.
Where'd you get it ?
Me dad's got loads
in the kitchen.
Won't he notice ?
He never knows
how much is there.
[ Spits ]
Tastes like piss.
You get used to it.
Here.
Maybe you could
run away or something.
You know,
join a dancin' troupe.
Don't be
so stupid.
Well, maybe it's
all for the best.
What do you mean ?
You won't have to
go away or nothin'.
Me hands
are freezin'.
Give us 'em here.
What are you doin' ?
Nothin'.
Just warmin'
your hands up.
You're not a poof
or aught ?
What gave you
that impression ?
Aren't your hands cold ?
I quite like it.
Just 'cause
I like ballet...
doesn't mean
I'm a poof, you know.
You- You won't
tell anyone, will you ?
Come on.
It's fuckin' freezin'
in here.
Here.
What's this ?
Just put it on.
A tutu.
[ Chattering ]
...and as he's walking
through the bush there,
George. George,
there's somebody
in the club.
this kangaroo,
he's walkin' away
over it, right ?
And he's called Norman.
[ Laughing ]
And then round the corner
came this wallaby-
* [ Classical Piano ]
* [ Music Continues ]
Plie, first.
What's a plie ?
It's French.
Why's it French ?
I don't know.
Second.
Like a princess.
Second, and down.
And first.
Carry on. Fifth.
Shoulders down,
long neck.
How do I look ?
Fuck off.
Shut up, you poof.
[ Billy ]
second,
and down.
And first.
[ Billy ]
Fifth. second.
Down.
First.
Fifth.
Jackie.
Jackie, man.
Here.
Give us your hand.
[ Both Laughing ]
Dance!
* [ Orchestra Playing
Folk Arrangement On Tape ]
* [ Music Continues ]
[ stomping Feet ]
Dad !
Go home, son.
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
It is a friend
of yours, then.
How much
is it gonna cost ?
And a happy Christmas
to you too.
Not as much
as you might think.
Maybe two grand.
But there's a good chance
the council's-
Two grand?
I was talkin'
about the auditions.
Look, if it's just
a matter of the trip
to London,
I'll give you
the money
for the fare.
I didn't come here
to be patronized.
Oh, no one's tryin'
to patronize you.
You're bein' ridiculous.
Am I ?
Yes !
[ Sighs ]
Thanks for everything
you've done for Billy.
But he is my son,
isn't he ?
[Jackie's Voice ]
I'll handle this myself.
[ Footsteps,
Floorboards Creaking ]
[ Man ]
Hey, fellow.
Name. You.
[ Man #2 ] Paul.
[ Man #1 ]
surname.
Felton.
[ Man #1 ]
shorty. You.
What ? Thorpe.
Thorpe.
[ Man #1 speaking,
Indistinct ]
Smith.
smith.
Glenton.
[ Man #1 ]
Glenton. Kerner.
Kerner.
[ Man #1 ]
Is that the lot, then ?
Fuckin'hell.
Never thought
I'd see you down here.
Things change, eh ?
Right,
you, name.
Jackie Elliot.
Well, glad to see
you've come
to your senses.
Who's a big man now, eh ?
[ Man #1 ]
Right. Okay, you lot.
Over here.
All aboard the skylark.
Look lively.
Can't smoke on here, mate.
These are private buses.
Scab ! Scab ! Scab !
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Thudding ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Chanting ]
Scab ! Scab ! Scab !
Fuckin' prats ! Scab !
Scab ! Scab ! Scab ! Scab !
Scab ! Scab ! Scab !
Scab ! Scab-
Fuck off !
[ Chanting
Continues ]
Dad ! Dad !
Give us a hand.
[ Tony ]
Dad!
What the fuck
you doin' ?
Dad, you can't
go back ! Not now !
Look at the state of us.
What we got to offer
the poor sod ?
You can't do this !
Not now !
Not after all this time !
Not after everything
we've been through !
It's for wee Billy !
He may be a fuckin' genius
for all we know !
Fuck !
For fuck's sake, Dad !
You can't do this !
Dad ! Dad !
Tony !
[ Tony ] He's only 1 1 ,
for fuck's sake !
He's a kid. He's just
a fuckin' little kid !
I'm sorry.
Please.
[ Sobbing ]
We're finished, son.
[ Crying ]
What choice
have we got, eh ?
Let's give the boy
a fuckin' chance !
Please.
Please, don't do this.
Dad, we'll find him
some money.
We'll find it
for him.
[ Crying ]
What the fuck
is he doin', Tony ?
It's okay.
He's gonna be okay.
[ Man ]
Just get him
out of here, Tony.
[ Crying ]
Away. Leave it.
Go on.
Leave us.
Let's go home, Dad.
Dad's right,
you know.
Mam would've
let you.
[ George ]
All them 50 pences.
Here. It was a toss-up
between a new punch bag
or you.
It's not even enough
for the bed
and breakfast.
Forget about it.
You're dreamin'.
Look at youse.
Fuckin' scrabblin' round
for 50 pences.
[ Tony ]
You've got to do
better than that.
How ?
I'm gonna have
a raffle at the welfare.
And I'm gonna organize
a concert.
Thanks, George.
[ Billy speaking,
Indistinct ]
[ Tony ]
sheila's not got
that kind of money.
she can't even keep
her soup kitchen open.
[ Billy ]
George said we can have
another whip-round.
[ Tony ] Billy, there's
no money left. Get that
through your head, man !
[ George ] The lads
will always dip into
their buckets if we ask them.
[ Tony ]
George, you know
there's nothing left.
stop putting ideas
in his head, man !
[ Sobbing ]
[ Man ] Come on, lads.
Dig deep for the miners.
Is that
absolutely necessary ?
Walk normal,
will ya ?
So what's it like,
like ?
What's what like ?
London.
I don't know, son.
I never made it
past Durham.
Have you
never been, like ?
Why would I want
to go to London ?
It's the capital city.
Well, there's no mines
in London.
Christ.
Is that all
you think about ?
Can I help you ?
Billy Elliot.
We've come for an audition.
[ Woman ]
Oh, you mean
William Elliot.
[Jackie ]
Yeah, William.
Can you
go upstairs, please ?
This way ?
Thanks.
Yes.
[ Boy #1 ]
This your first time ?
[ Boy #2 ] Yeah.
I've been doing this
for two years now.
Hello.
Nerve-racking,
isn't it ?
Where are you from ?
Everington.
County Durham.
Durham ? Isn't there
an amazing cathedral ?
Don't know.
Never been.
[ Man ]
Up on the box,
please.
All right,
bend over.
Right down.
And come up.
Come up.
Head down.
Tiny curvature here.
Head down !
How tiny ?
Might not be
a problem.
Come on.
Keep coming.
Relax. All right.
Jump up, William.
It's Billy.
Billy Elliot.
* [ Piano ]
Two,
three and four.
Dad. Dad !
Dad,
for fuck's sake!
I changed me mind.
Get back in there !
Don't be so stupid !
And you are ?
Billy Elliot
from Everington.
[ Man ]
I beg your pardon ?
Billy Elliot.
Ah, yes,
of course.
Come to the barre,
please, Billy.
Left arm
on the barre.
Feet first.
Arms second.
Demi-plie
and... hold.
[ Whispering ]
Now, Billy,
we'd like to see you
move to some music.
Do you have
a piece prepared ?
[ Tape Player
Clicks On ]
* [ Orchestra Playing
Folk Arrangement ]
[ Grunts ]
* [ Music Continues ]
[ Music stops,
Tape Player Clicks Off ]
Thank you.
You all right ?
What's the matter ?
It was a waste
of fuckin' time !
Don't be upset.
It's only
a stupid audition.
It's all right.
Fuck off !
There's always
next year.
Look. Fuck off,
will ya !
Oh-
You bent bastard !
What on earth's
going on here ?
How did it go ?
Shit !
[ Man ]
Mr. Elliot, I'm afraid
that mutual respect...
and self-discipline
are absolute prerequisites
for any pupil in this school.
such displays of violence
cannot be tolerated
under any circumstances.
Do you understand?
I realize we shall
have to consider this
very seriously...
and it will be
bound to affect
our final decision.
Yes, well,
just a few questions, then.
Billy, can you tell us...
why you first
became interested
in ballet ?
Don't know.
-Just was.
- Well, was there any...
particular aspect
of the ballet which...
caught your imagination ?
The dancin'.
He dances all the time.
Every night after school.
Yes. Well, we have
a very enthusiastic letter...
from Mrs. Wilkinson,
and, uh,
she has told us...
of your personal
circumstances.
Mr. Elliot, are you
a fan of the ballet ?
I wouldn't exactly say
I was an expert.
You do realize
that all pupils...
must attain
the highest standards,
not just in ballet
but in their ordinary
academic work.
No child can succeed
without the 1 00% support
of the family.
You are completely
behind Billy ?
Are you not ?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
Do you want to ask us
some questions ?
[ Clears Throat ]
No, not-
Not really, no.
[ Man ]
Well, in that case,
we shall let you know
in due course.
[ Woman ]
Just one last question.
Can I ask you, Billy,
what does it feel like...
when you're dancing ?
Don't know.
Sort of feels good.
It's sort of stiff and that,
but once I get goin',
then I, like,
forget everythin'.
And...
sort of disappear.
Sort of disappear.
Like I feel a change
in me whole body.
Like there's fire
in me body.
I'm just there, flyin'...
like a bird.
Like electricity.
Yeah.
Have a safe
journey home.
Mr. Elliot,
good luck
with the strike.
[ Grandma ]
Toast!
I think you should
get yourself a trade, son.
Somethin' useful.
I could have been
a professional dancer.
What happened
to the dinosaurs, miss ?
[ Woman ]
They were crushed
as well,
and the pressure of all
of this caused the plants
and trees to change into coal.
Ow !
That's what must have
happened to her.
Michael Caffrey,
if you have got
something to say,
you can say it
to the class.
Sorry, miss.
[ Teacher ]
so, gradually,
over hundreds
of thousands of years-
Post !
This is it.
Have you heard
anything yet ?
Not yet.
You'll have
no problem, man.
Fingers crossed, eh ?
[ Door Closes ]
[ Sniffles ]
I got in.
He did it !
He fuckin' did it !
[ Man ] Jackie,
have you not heard, man ?
We're goin' back.
[ Man #2 ]
strike's over, Jackie.
The union caved in yesterday.
[ Billy ]
I think I'm scared, Dad.
[Jackie ]
That's okay, son.
We're all scared.
If I don't like it,
can I still come back ?
You kiddin' ?
We've let out
your room.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Laughing ]
Whoa !
Whoo !
[ Both Laughing ]
* [ Classical On Piano ]
[ Mrs. Wilkinson ]
...four, five, six,
seven, eight.
And one, two,
three, four,
five, six, seven-
Keep going,
girls!
Three, four, five-
[ Hinge squeaking ]
Miss, I just came
to tell you.
It's all right, Billy.
I heard it from Debbie.
Look, it was just-
Well, you know,
after everything.
I'll miss you, Miss.
No, you won't.
I will. Honest.
This is when you go out
and find life...
and all
those other things.
The best of luck, Billy.
[ Mrs. Wilkinson ]
Right. Back to
the barre, girls.
And again.
Thank you.
* [ Piano Resumes ]
One, two,
three, four-
Debbie, eyes front.
seven and eight.
And one, two,
three, four,
five, six, seven.
Was she there ?
Yeah.
You'll miss
the bus.
We're off.
I'll take it.
Give us the bag.
Okay, we're late.
We've no time for that.
[ Bickering ]
I'll take it.
Good-bye, Billy.
See ya.
Oi, dancin' boy !
We'll miss the bus, Billy.
Will you stop being
an old fuckin' woman ?
See you, then.
[ Engine starting ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
- I'll miss you.
- What ? Can't hear you.
[ Bell Ringing ]
Dad. Come on, man.
We're gonna be late.
Dad !
Come on !
[ Doorman ]
Show's just started.
Excuse me.
Can you tell Billy Elliot
that his family's here ?
* [ Orchestra Plays Music
from Swan Lake ]
Sorry, mate.
It's all right,
Tony.
It's me, Michael. Remember ?
It's Michael.
What the bloody hell
you doin' here ?
I wouldn't have
missed it for the world.
* [ Music Continues ]
[ Man ]
stand by, please.
Billy, your family
are here.
Thanks.
* [ Music swells ]
Subtitles by Angyalka 2003
* [ Rock And Roll ]
* Ride it on out
like a bird in the skyway *
like you were a bird *
* Fly it all out
like an eagle in a sunbeam *
* Ride it on out
like you were a bird *
* Wear a tall hat
like a Druid in the old days *
and a tattooed gown *
* Ride a white swan
like the people
of the Beltane *
* Wear your hair long
Babe, you can't go wrong *
* Da dee-dee da *
* If I believe
that I could do anything *
* Can I spread my wings
and say good-bye *
* so many people told me
I couldn't win *
* Look at me now
Here I am in heaven's sky *
* And sometimes
I say a prayer *
* Wishing that you could be
here with me *
* 'Cause I believe *
* I believe in love *
* It's the best
of everything *
* I believe in hope *
* And the changes
it can bring *
* If you believe that nothing
can stand in your way *
* Just say *
* It's a fact of life
that we're all in the game *
* But it's still your call *
* But we all play it *
* sometimes we win
sometimes we fall *
* But there's no reason
just to give it up *
* 'Cause after all *
* If you can't choose
what to be *
* You can choose
what to dream *
* And I believe *
* Oh, yeah, I believe *
* Oh *
* If you can't choose
what to be *
* You can choose
what to dream *
* And I believe *
* I believe in love *
* It's the best
of everything *
* I believe in hope *
* And the changes
it can bring *
* If you believe that nothing
can stand in your way *
* Just say *
* Oh, I believe *
* Do you believe *
* Would you believe me
if I said I'd never lie *
* Though it ain't easy
I can tell you I have tried *
* But I gotta say
that it comes those days *
* That I told
something untrue *
* Would you forgive me
if I said I'd lied to you *
* This is my fear
to tell you what I've done *
* As things come clear
I'm afraid that you'll be gone *
* But all I know
is if you go *
* At least
I've told what's true *
* Hope you'll forgive me
when I say I've lied to you *
* Yeah, I'm burning up *
* I'm burning for you *
* When the truth
has been spoken *
* There's nothing to do *
* Yes, I'm burning up *
* Burning up *
* I'm burning for you *
* When the truth
has been spoken *
* There's nothing to do
Oh, yeah *
* Yes, I'm burning up *
* I'm burning up *
* That's right
Yes, I am *
* Oh, I'm burning up *
* I'm burning up *
* Oh *