Janek!
Here I am, Baron von Essenbeck.
Get to it.
Come on, rub hard.
Have they all arrived?
Not all of them, sir.
Who's missing?
Mr. Bruckmann and Lieut. Aschenbach
who are coming from Oberhausen.
And the old man? Baron Joachim?
Come on! Speak!
The baron is in his apartment.
He's getting ready for dinner,
Iike everyone eIse.
What about my son?
Can't you hear him?
Gunther? Gunther?
What do you want, Thilde?
Come!
Come and see.
What?
Look!
It's the same as Iast year, ThiIde.
Yes, but then I was a spectator,
this year it's different.
I hope I don't forget my Iines.
It'II be a great debut. Tomorrow,
your name wiII be in the papers.
That's fine. Thank you.
With all these compromises
we'll lose even our chairs.
Yes, dear.
I'm nearIy ready.
You know Uncle Joachim insists on
punctuality, especially tonight.
Will you give me a hand?
Darling, if you won't stay still...
Thanks. One can't always say yes.
They're not reasonable people.
They're never satisfied.
Uncle Joachim's been at the helm
over 40 years...ensuring balance.
Balance is the right word.
A courtesy to the Liberals,
another to the National Socialists.
A favour to me, one to Konstantin.
You're unfair. Uncle's never had
any time for that fellow.
Because he's a snob. If HitIer were
not the son of a maid...
...he would have sided with him.
But he's always listened to you and
has never financed the Nazis.
Only because he's too mean.
What about the girls?
They're going to surprise everyone.
They must be very nervous.
Let's go.
Thank you.
Come on, Herbert.
...a blessing too that will make
this birthday happy
and the year just right for you.
On this speciaI night I'II sing
these words to Iet you see...
...having you for a grandfather
is a joy and blessing for me.
Happy birthday, Grandpa.
Thank you. Come here.
Very best wishes for your birthday.
Let me give you a kiss. Thank you.
And thank you, Sweetheart.
My IittIe Erika.
Happy birthday, sir.
Janek!
Do you hear the two of them?
Yes.
Since birth, she's been told she's
the most intelligent, the richest,
the most enviable.
She's Baroness Von Essenbeck.
Can I ask her to become
pIain Mrs Bruckmann?
The wife of an executive of the
factories that carry her name?
You're too hard on yourself. Uncle
Joachim trusts you.. No-one makes
decisions without your approvaI.
Isn't that aIready something?
Yes, but not enough for Sophie.
It's true I've gone up the Iadder,
but I'm stiII an empIoyee of hers.
If we decided to marry, I'd Iose
the baron's trust and friendship.
He wants Sophie to stay
the inconsolable widow of his son.
Idiot!
He'd probably fire me.
You're wrong. Today, not even he
with his slaves, his millions...
...his castles is powerful enough to
exclude you. Power's in our hands.
And we want you where you are.
Or higher up the Iadder.
Am I to steaI Herbert's job?
The fact Herbert has to go is
an open secret.
His hostility towards Nazism
is extremely evident.
But Konstantin...
Do you think he's so important?
He's in the SA.
He's very close to Röhm.
Our industry needs
men Iike you.
And our chancellor has a soft spot
for large industries.
Anyhow, I wasn't
taIking about Konstantin.
...having you for a grandfather
is a joy and blessing for me..
Do you think they'II do an encore?
More than one. But don't
dare ask them!
Well, I'll have to do without.
You were very good, Thilde.
Sit here with me. Again, thank you.
The governess was good too. Thanks!
Very good.
You're setting yourself limits.
You're not ambitious, just a sociaI
cIimber. Sophie wouIdn't approve.
You worry about Herbert and
Konstantin, but there's someone...
...more important: Joachim.
Today, in Germany, anything can
happen and we've barely started.
Private morality is dead. We the
elect can do as we please.
They're Hitler's words.
You too should think them over.
Tonight, for example.
Well done, Gunther.
You played splendidly. Thank you.
I know you couIdn't care Iess but
your son has a taIent for music.
Good evening.
- Good evening - - Good evening -
Excuse me. I'm wanted on the phone.
Spring arrives, the sparrow sings,
I'm in Iove, but with whom?
I don't care whether he's rich
because Iove is enough for me.
Guys, this evening I'm going to
choose myseIf a reaI man.
Guys, I'm fed up with boys.
I want a reaI man.
A man with a burning heart
and fire Iighting up his eyes.
A man who can and still wants
to kiss. A real man.
There are men who are thin, fat,
big, small and stout.
Handsome, elegant, shy or bold.
His face is not important,
I'II choose one anyway.
Guys, this evening I'm going to
choose myseIf a reaI man.
Guys, I'm fed up with boys,
I want a reaI man.
Quiet, please!.
The Reichstag is on fire.
A man with a burning heart
and fire Iighting up his eyes.
Quiet, please! I said, quiet!
The fire started half an hour ago.
It's a conspiracy, but the person
responsibIe has been arrested.
A Dutchman enrolled
in the Communist party.
A Communist, of course.
Another Communist crime
against the new government.
Shit!
Couldn't they choose another day
to burn down the Reichstag?
They spoiled your birthday.
It was my headquarters
in BerIin.
They haven't put out the fire yet.
And the Berliners are enjoying
the show from their balconies.
I can't stay here. Maybe the SA
have been caIIed back to barracks.
Calm down, Konstantin,
the coup d'état has failed.
Up till now, your battle station
has never been Berlin.
If they've aIready found the
conspirators, it means...
The conspiracy's only a pretext.
That's an arbitrary statement.
Herbert's statements are
always arbitrary.
It's a provocation that can come
onIy from anti-government sources.
Your chancellor has no use
for government.
Herbert, please!
Everyone knows about
the proscription Iists.
They're used to crush opponents
while Europe looks on.
Europe isn't interested in
Iaw and order inside Germany.
Law and order that allows the
killing of people in their homes?
Herbert, please!
Goering has sworn revenge against
the enemies of the Third Reich.
You're Iosing your head, Herbert.
Goering was referring to
Communists. Are you one of them?
Today, it's their turn. Tomorrow?
Don't worry about tomorrow. Someone
in Berlin is taking care of things.
Well said, cousin Sophie.
Our only worry should be
celebrating Uncle's birthday.
Even if this is an evening
out of the ordinary.
No, no, Martin, no.
I've been wanting to make the
foIIowing speech for a Iong time.
The dramatic events that have taken
place in the last few hours...
...force me to overcome
any hesitation and uncertainty..
...and speak to you clearly.
In aII these years,
I've had one aim onIy.
To uphold the unity and prestige
of our firm.
That's why I have acted so that
our work and our structures...
...could adapt each time
to changing circumstances.
In war time, in peace time
and in the foIIowing crisis.
Now, in the Iight of recent
dramatic events...
...I feeI it more necessary than ever
to protect our steeIworks...
...from any possible
political pressure.
Or even more serious risks.
You must acknowledge that I have
never backed the present regime.
And as you all know,
I have never had...
...nor wish to have any contact
with a certain gentleman.
Despite this, in the interests of
the firm, we must...
...keep up daily contact
with those people.
That's why I feeI it's essentiaI
to have at my side a man...
...accepted by the regime...
who can guarantee for us...
I'm ready to give notice,
if that's what you want.
I'm forced to do this, Herbert
with regret and without conviction.
But the steelworks...
Come first, right or wrong.
That's your creed.
You even sent your son to his death
to be able to say that the...
...Essenbecks bring into the world
and bury cannons and offspring...
...with the same feeling.
Excuse me..
Congratulations, Konstantin. You'll
be the vice-chairman we deserve.
Let's go, Herbert, please.
I hope I don't foIIow in the
footsteps of my predecessor.
Right, Friedrich?
Guys, this evening I'm going to
choose myseIf a reaI man.
Guys, I'm fed up with boys,
I want a reaI man.
Aschenbach would stab me in the
back if he stood to gain from it.
But not this time. He's on
our side, Sophie.
Herbert's right. It was they who
burned down the Reichstag.
I'm sure Aschenbach aIready knew
what was going to happen.
He talked of us two, of
Joachim, the steelworks.
But in actuaI fact, he was teIIing
me something quite different.
That tonight, I'd be given an
extraordinary opportunity...
...I couId either take or Ieave.
To side with them or oppose them.
Don't you see, Sophie?
They can't have put Joachim
on the proscription Iists.
Herbert, perhaps.
Probably, Herbert.
Tonight, great things will happen.
The Iosers wiII be those who stay
on the sideIines. It's as if...
...they'd offered me a position of
trust and if I accept, I seize...
...the opportunity, I'II have
their heIp in exchange.
And there'II be no more Herberts.
Or Konstantins, or Joachims.
I'II be the onIy one in charge.
I'II make aII the decisions...
...with you at my side, Sophie.
So, what have you decided to do?
It'd be the first time I made
a decision without consuIting you.
I'II heIp you, even though I can
never push you hard enough.
Stay the course to the bitter end!
None of them is worth half of you.
You were right to always say yes,
but now you have to make them pay.
Herbert has always pushed
you aside and Joachim...
...has humiliated you, but Konstantin
is the worst of the lot.
Don't be afraid, Friedrich.
I'm not afraid.
There's just one thing.
Keep your son happy...
...so I can do what I must.
I'II take care of Martin.
I know exactIy what he Iikes.
He has no sense of value.
The steelworks or a new Rolls
are worth the same to him.
We'II throw him the bait.
Leave it up to me.
Boo!
I won!
Where's Erika?
Come out, Erika! We've won.
Erika where are you?
Here I am.
There you are, you IittIe sIyboots!
Come! Now it's your turn.
Put you hands over your eyes and
count to 100 out Ioud.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9,
10, 11, 12, 13, 14...
Erika, come!
Pour yourself a drink. This
discussion's over. Go on!
I don't want to Ieave schooI.
You'II Ieave that fiIthy den.
I'II drag you out if necessary.
And I'II puII you with me into the
steeIworks. I guarantee...
...that in ten years, you'II take
over and throw me out.
I'II smash your ceIIo over your
head if you don't understand this.
You're just Iike your mother,
with the same deIicate stomach.
She's never wanted to
set foot in the factory.
The heat from the furnaces
makes her dizzy.
Listen, Father, I've decided...
Only I can decide for you.
I know you can't stand me.
But I'm not asking you to
Iove me. On the contrary.
It's just that I don't intend to
keep the seat warm for Friedrich...
...and much Iess for Martin.
I'd rather naiI you to that seat
when the time comes.
Those bastards have poisoned your
brain, but as for your schooI...
...we'II smash it to pieces
with aII your damned books inside.
Gunther!
Erika!
Don't Iet her hear you. Do you want
her to find us straight away?
Come in.
Gunther?
Yes? Very well.
As I thought, before daybreak
Herbert wiII be arrested.
Poor Herbert! To think we're
so near the border.
Is there a specific accusation?
So, he'II be tried.
I don't think such
formaIities are necessary.
We're concerned only with substance.
And the substance here is this.
Before the flames consuming
the Reichstag are put out...
...the champions of the old Germany
will be reduced to ashes.
However, a semblance of
legality may be useful...
...at times.
I'm tired and wouId Iike to retire.
Sophie...
Friedrich...
If you need me...
But sneaking away Iike thieves...
We're not the only ones, Elisabeth.
Every day people have to leave
home all over Europe.
We're Iucky. At Ieast we have
a pIace to go to.
We have friends.
How soon will we have to leave?
As soon as we've packed and handed
over to others in the factory.
It's aII over, Gunther.
And it's the fault of all of us,
mine too.
There's no point in raising your
voice when it's too Iate.
We've given Germany
a sick democracy.
The fear of a revolution that
would have put us in the hands...
...of the Left was too strong.
Now it's too Iate to do anything.
Nazism was created by us,
it started in our factories.
It was fed with our money.
You think I shouIdn't escape.
Maybe you feeI contempt for me.
No, Uncle Herbert. I...
We'II keep in touch, aII right?
Yes.
Still up, Erika? What's going on?
- Where's Thilde? - - I don't know.
Thilde? Where's she gone?
- Do you know? - - No.
You must go to bed straight away.
It's very Iate. ThiIde?
Herbert, they've come for you.
There's no time to Iose.
Elizabeth!
No, no!
You must escape, hurry!
You'd be crazy to take it with you.
I'II get rid of it. Now, go!
Please, Herbert, hurry!
Look after the girls.
Hurry, my Iove! Go, go!
Herbert, no, no, this way!
Open up! Open up!
Do you too recognise this gun?
Yes.
The weapon is recognised as
belonging to Herbert Thallman.
Are we to continue the inquiry?
The magistrate will take over.
Mr. Thallman took compromising
documents away with him.
Paperwork regarding the activities
of the steelworks that he can use.
Not in any concrete way.
Write: "To the Public Prosecutor...
...18th February, 1933.
Re: accusation of Herbert Thallman
fugitive from justice...
...for the 2nd degree murder of
Baron Joachim Von Essenbeck."
I know what you're feeIing, Martin.
But one can't take on
from one day to the next...
...a rôle of such
huge responsibility...
...without feeling a sense of ...
...consternation. But Friedrich and I
won't Ieave you on your own.
We were just saying you'II have
time to compIete your studies.
And to familiarise yourself with
problems concerning the firm.
They aren't simple, believe me.
Meanwhile, Friedrich and I
will keep the place going...
...as always in the past.
I never expected to become
chairman of the steeIworks...
...in such tragic circumstances.
But unfortunately, I'm
forced to do what...
Grandfather was right.
Nowadays, our firm...
I mean either we have government
approvaI or our business...
...our profits...
I know nothing of business or
poIitics, but one thing I do know.
That ours is a speciaI
kind of production.
That there are technicaI probIems.
Bravo! Well done!
A fine speech from the Throne!
But now, let's not overdo it.
Let's give this meeting
more of a family tone.
Joachim's intentions...
Please, Konstantin.
Martin hasn't finished.
He has something else to say.
Well, let's hear it.
I want to respect Grandfather's
wishes in every way.
He named you vice-chairman
and was right to do so.
But at a time Iike this...
...the chairman should be
.above all a technician.
What kind of a joke is this?
It's no joke; enormous sums
are invoIved here:
And Martin thinks...
It's the first time Martin has
thought with his own head.
I inherit the majority of the
shares so the decision is mine.
I name Friedrich Bruckmann
chairman of the board...
...and managing director
of the Essenbeck Steelworks
And of every other company
in partnership with the firm.
Friedrich Bruckmann I made you what
you are from the nobody you were.
Herbert's pistol,
Aschenbach's testimony...
...the arrivaI of the SS.
Perfect.
You have too much imagination.
You, come with me.
Today you've Iearned something
they don't teach at schooI.
Come on.
Don't get your hopes up.
This war has just started.
Gunther, get a move on!
To the first modeI.
Hoping to hear
its music soon.
Will this reception last long?
Your place is here, Martin,
you can't leave.
Fine, as you wish.
Mr. Bruckmann, you
are certainly aware...
I met your father on the
French front in 1916.
A true Essenbeck and
a heroic officer.
I know.
The Chiefs of Staff are adamant.
Either Röhm goes or we do.
It's bIackmaiI. The SA
represent a reaI threat.
Therefore we must prevent heavy
artillery ending up in their hands.
Is this your personaI opinion?
It's that of the Chiefs of Staff..
And especially of the Chancellor,
if you don't mind my saying so.
The army is the army,
the SA are the SA.
We're not involved in law
and order but don't want to share...
...our institutionaI duties.
InstitutionaI duties?
Where were the Prussian generals
while we were cleaning up Germany?
This country will never be clean
enough until...
No doubt about the SA's merits.
We wouldn't be here if it weren't
for the work of the SA.
Anyhow, heavy artillery isn't need
to maintain law and order.
Just Iook around you.
Germany is the most orderly country
in the world; American and English
...tourists Iove coming here.
What more do we want?
So we all agree.
Not one piece of heavy artillery
will leave this factory...
...unless requested
by the Chiefs of Staff.
Elections are coming up and
we must win them...
...if we want them to be the Iast.
But it will take a lot of money.
The Essenbeck steelworks is behind.
Joachim, with his stubbornness,
brought about this situation.
AII the other industriaIists have
paid their quota, whiIe you...
You can't allocate such large sums
without cooking the books.
This is a joint stock company.
And Konstantin could, in time,
become a problem
What I say is probIems
must aIways be soIved.
Don't you agree?
The state must crush even an
innocent flower if it's in the way.
I'm not the state.
I did what I was asked, but don't
want to be invoIved any more.
Don't always take me literally.
They're Hegel's words, not mine.
He'd turn in his grave if he
knew we were comparing...
...Konstantin to an innocent flower.
Do you mind if I...?
It's getting Iate.
Yes, do go Martin.
Thank you. Goodbye.
You'II have to answer for whatever
happens here, and don't forget it.
Hermannstrasse. Hurry!
The young Iady has gone out.
Yes, I know. Thank you.
...Germany, followed by hundreds
of Berlin party flags.
One after the other, the flags are
taken out of the sports complex...
...and are carried around
the town all night.
People all around, at the front and
the sides, great maxims for Germany.
Thomas and Heinrich Mann...
Walter Rathenau...
Erich Maria Remarque...
Arnold and Stefan Zweig...
André Gide...
Helen Keller...
Margaret Sanger...
Jack London...
George Bernard Shaw...
Emile Zola...
MarceI Proust.
Come on in.
I had to read it. I'm sorry.
I'm forced to do these things.
This comes from abroad.
Herbert Thallman is my uncle.
It's absurd that I can't receive...
If your uncIe had any common sense,
he wouIdn't write to you here.
Where's he supposed to write to me?
It's a pIea for heIp. That's cIear.
I don't want to know anything about
it, nor do I wish to discuss it.
I onIy want to avoid your dragging
my schooI into this affair.
In any case, I refuse to beIieve
what your uncIe has written.
May I go, sir?
You may, and get your hair
cut Von Essenbeck.
Yes, sir.
Yes, it's all here: application for
renewal, fee, revenue stamp.
Reason for the trip?
A vacation.
Are you going alone, Mrs Thallman?
With my daughters.
Thilde who's eleven.
Erika who's eight, is that correct?
Yes.
Do you plan to join your husband?
No.
No? You don't know where he is?
Would you like us to tell you?
I don't see what the difficuIty is.
I just want to Ieave.
Has someone caused you difficulty?
No, not really.
Are you aware your husband
is accused of murder?
It's absurd. It's sIander.
Then convince him to come back
so he can prove his innocence.
I don't know where he is. Why invoIve
me and the girIs? Are we suspects?
We just want to Ieave.
Are you being forced to Ieave?
No, they're preventing me from...
Who's preventing you, Mrs...?
Elisabeth Thallman.
Are you trying to imply something?
Answer, don't be afraid.
Good morning.
Your girlfriend isn't in.
She said she'd be back very late.
I heard you.
...wearing a purple cloak.
Who's the IittIe man
aII aIone in the wood?
With the purple cloak?
The IittIe man is standing in
the wood on one Ieg.
On his head, he has
a IittIe red hat.
Lisa, Iook what I've brought you.
A IoveIy IittIe horse to pIay with.
Do you Iike him?
Yes I do, thank you.
You can stroke him. Go on, Lisa.
He's all yours. Do you like him?
Do you Iike him?
You must be nice to him.
You must Iove him a Iot.
Because he Ioves you.
Lisa? Lisa?
Why won't you answer?
Now, I'II show you.
Stop crying.
AII you do is waste time.
You spend the whole day playing.
It's no good crying, you know?
Will you never learn?
I toId you to tidy up.
Look at this mess.
You must obey me, you understand?
Get moving!
And stop crying.
Start working. Do something.
Martin.
Martin?
It's you!
I didn't expect to find you here.
What time is it?
It's Iate. It's two o'cIock.
Two o'clock?
I'm dead tired. I had to
work tiII Iate.
Help me, I beg you.
I know you're aII stronger than me
and can stop me from Ieaving.
But I don't see the point of it.
Are you really afraid of Herbert?
Previously maybe, but now his
papers are worth nothing.
Germany can do what it wants.
You too are doing what you want and
nobody in Europe Iifts a finger.
So why keep us here?
Because one day we could remember.
And say what we know about you
and all the others.
Do you think that day will come?
No, it'II never come.
Herbert's still fooling himself but
I'm not. And you never believed us.
So why keep us here?
My presence should be unbearable
because it forces you to remember.
But I too want to forget.
Let us Ieave, Sophie.
A word from you is enough.
Go! Leave, if that's what you want.
But don't fooI yourseIf.
When you come back you won't find
the Germany you're so fond of.
That Germany has gone forever.
You'II onIy find this one.
You won't be able to escape it.
Soon, it will spread all
over Europe and beyond.
Lieutenant Aschenbach.
Baroness Von Essenbeck.
Lisa, come here.
Come!
Look!
Do you Iike it?
Why were you crying the other day?
I heard you, you know?
Were they hitting you? Your mother?
Does she often smack your bottom?
Why?
That's enough, Martin.
Stop, Darling, I have to leave.
Where are you going?
I'm posing for some photographs.
Do you pose in the nude?
Yes, of course. You know that.
Stay a IittIe Ionger.
I can't. I'm Iate.
Anyhow, haven't you had enough?
I aIready toId you I have to Ieave.
Stop it! That's enough!
Where's my damned dress?
Stop, please.
Stop. Let me go, Martin.
If you want to make yourseIf
usefuI, tidy this room.
Look what a mess you've made.
And that IittIe idiot is iII.
Who?
Lisa. I have to
pay for her doctor.
What's wrong with her?
It's not cIear. She had a fever.
Last night she was deIirious.
I'II never make it in time.
Martin, what's the matter now?
Why don't you do as I said?
Look what a mess!
Now, I reaIIy must go.
Lock the door when you Ieave.
Bye-bye.
Lisa?
Try to come and see us.
Of course.
I'II write as soon as I arrive.
Promise me you'II come and see us.
I promise.
We'II miss you.
You'II aIways be weIcome. Herbert
and I wiII be happy to have you.
Thank you.
If you knew how excited the girIs
are, and I more than them.
Give him my regards.
What's happening? Why are you here?
What do you want from me?
I know nothing.
What do you want?
He's filled your house with gifts.
Valuable stuff.
I know nothing. What can I say?
When I found out it was Baron
Von Essenbeck, I caIIed you.
Otherwise, I wouIdn't have dared.
I haven't forgotten what
you did for me.
There's no formaI report.
OnIy the reIatives' statements.
And a name said by the victim.
By the IittIe girI. Nothing eIse.
However, the baron was stopped
while leaving a club.
One of those speciaI cIubs
in Graffenstrasse.
I'II take care of everything.
Bring her with you.
I'm not coming to the poIice.
I haven't done anything.
I don't want to come.
Leave me alone! No!
Read this.
It's incredibIe.
But what does it mean?
That's what I'm wondering too.
What can have prompted Martin
to take such an initiative?
He's called an extraordinary
meeting of the Board of Directors.
He's the major shareholder.
It's within his rights.
What can he want from the Board?
We'II soon find out.
- Any idea where he is? - - No. -
I've Iooked for him everywhere.
He's nowhere to be found.
He was Iast seen in a
bar in DüsseIdorf, three days ago.
Since then - no trace of him.
We must find him. We'II turn
Germany upside down if necessary.
But the chairman...
The chairman's not here! In his
absence, you'II do as I say.
But we have precise orders.
I assume aII responsibiIity.
The whole shipment is to be
diverted to Stuttgart.
And delivered to the SA.
Is that understood?
Hello?
What's happening, Friedrich?
Stay calm, please.
We'II find him. HaIf the town
is Iooking for him.
Try calling Aschenbach again.
- It's too soon. -
- It's aIready 3 am. Try! -
Lieutenant Aschenbach. It's urgent.
Friedrich!
Hello, this is Friedrich Bruckmann
from Kleisburg castle.
Yes, thank you, I'II hoId on.
Martin!
What are you afraid of? Answer me!
Why is Konstantin keeping you here?
What does he want from you?
Konstantin...
What's happened? What've you done?
I'm scared. I'm in his cIutches.
No. No.
No, I'II heIp you.
But I have to know everything
to be abIe to heIp you. TeII me!
Martin! Martin!
Speak. Was it he who made
you write that Ietter?
No, no!
Did he force you to write it?
No!
Don't worry, Martin.
Your mother will protect you.
The time has come
to crush the innocent flower.
Because it's in the way.
I'd aIready put a simiIar
eventuaIity to Friedrich.
But he hasn't yet grasped
the sense of the Hegelian system.
When is the Board to meet?
In a month, as per company ruIes.
What will the procedure be?
It's simpIe. Konstantin wiII ask to
verify the distribution of power.
There'II be a vote and Martin wiII
withdraw his support for Friedrich.
And will give it to Konstantin.
But how did Konstantin manage
to blackmail Martin?
Konstantin is in the SA, he has
friends in the Gestapo and police.
Another connection to be severed.
But soon, Martin's file will pass
into more important hands.
Come.
This is the most complete
archive that ever existed.
There's everything on private
Germany here. Nothing's missing.
There's even your affair with
Friedrich. Did you imagine that?
It's not hard to get into
peopIe's private Iives.
Every German citizen is
potentially an informer.
Our people's collective instinct
is based on complicity.
Isn't this the true
miracIe of the Third Reich?
If you like, let's read
Konstantin's future together.
If he has one.
He'II aIways have a future whiIe
he has powerfuI friends.
I wouIdn't be so pessimistic.
The SA were usefuI to us
in conquering Germany.
To conquer the world,
we need the army.
Which doesn't want the SA around.
It's us or them, say the generaIs.