Rice has been grown in
northern Italy for centuries
like in China and India.
It grows in a vast plain
spanning the provinces
of Pavia, Novara and Vercelli.
An indelible mark has been
left in this land
by millions of women
whose hands have tended it
for 500 years.
Hard work
that never changes...
knee-deep in water, bent
double under the hot sun.
But only women can do it...
It needs quick, light hands.
The same hands...
that patiently thread
needles and nurse babies.
This is Radio Turin
bringing you a very special
show today. We're standing
near the trains that take the
workers to the rice plantation.
They leave for the plain
every year, in early May.
They come from all over
northern Italy.
It's a regular mobilization of
women of all ages and trades.
Farm hands, factory workers,
dressmakers, typists...
The planting and weeding
season lasts 40 gruelling days.
Let's hear one of the workers.
What's your name?
Severina Cerri
from Monselice.
Severina is now going to tell
us about the impressions
the needs and the ideals
of these workers.
Hope we don't miss him
in the crowd.
Boy, get a load of that!
Who's watching the entrance?
Donadio and Bonfiglio.
- That's 14, Father.
- Yes, correct.
- Come on, girls!
- I'm relying on you, Amelia.
Take care and stay together.
Be careful, with this crowd.
Don't worry, Father.
Police, let's see your I.D.
Platform 6!
Attention please!
Now leaving from platform 6
the first train to Vercelli
reserved for the rice-workers.
Candy and cookies,
not bad for the rice-workers!
There wasn't enough
se we passed the hat around
but we only have food
for them this year.
Who are you seeing off?
Are you taking a gift too?
I'm taking good luck wishes,
kisses... and cash.
I've got a gun.
Put your hands up!
You're coming with me.
Stop thief!
After him!
- What happened?
- A thief!
- Did they arrest him?
- No, he got away!
He was wearing
a light trench coat!
They'll soon get him then!
Walter! Where have you been?
I was just calling the hotel.
- Hold me!
- What's going on?
- What's wrong?
- Come on, it's not for long.
I'm not going to America!
Hold me, I said.
And don't look, you fool! They're
on to me, don't you understand?
The second rice-workers' train
is leaving from platform 4.
That's another one gone.
I got the tickets while I waited.
- What do we do?
- The train's no good.
They'll corner us. Come on!
There's two of them coming.
What do we do?
If anything happens,
go with the rice-workers.
Keep the thing on you,
it's worth millions.
Stop or I'll shoot!
- Out of the way, stupid woman!
- Go with the rice-workers!
What's going on, Father?
It's none of your concern!
Take care!
Big jewellery robbery
at the Grand Hotel!
Read all about it!
Jewellery worth 5 million!
- Wait a minute.
- What do you want?
I know about your friend.
- What friend?
- The guy that got away.
You can come clean with me,
I'm not the law.
- I saw what happened.
- So? I saw you too.
Yeah, but he put his arms
around you.
Put his arms around me?
He nearly got me killed.
He used me like
he danced with you.
I guess women are convenient
to him now and then.
Well, what do you know?
A guy like that...
Good dancer too.
You were better.
We dance every night
back home.
When anything new comes in,
I just have to see it once...
Hands off my phonograph!
Lisa, don't let them touch it.
Okay, Silvana.
So you decided to come
with us after that?
- After what?
- After he beat it.
You got that story
out of your magazine?
I need a job... I've been
out of work for six months.
You wouldn't believe
the things that happen.
It's all true what they
say in these magazines.
- You got a contract?
- No.
Don't worry, they take
everybody. We came through
the employment office, but
the bosses always hire more
even on the train.
Illegals, they call them.
Come on, I know a steward
who can fix you up.
Hi, how's business?
Find a seat, I'll take care of it.
There was a horse in here
before us. It left a memento.
Does your cousin know
we take a cut on her pay?
Everybody knows
you play dirty.
Listen, kid,
we do this for them.
They'd be at home and
out of work without us.
No, we got 40 down already
and that's more than we need.
But as a favour to you...
Hands off!
Okay, we'll put her down.
Hey, what... We put her down.
See how I fixed it?
You don't have to worry now.
Thanks, but don't stay.
What about your luggage?
The girls are minding it.
I like to move around.
Here...
Irene! How are you?
- Look at all the soldiers!
- They're at camp here.
The boss gave them the
farmstead for a few months
but they have to move out
now we're here.
- How do you know all that?
- A guy from back home is here.
- I'm seeing him tonight.
- You sure move fast!
I do what I can...
40 days is a long time!
We're in barracks too. You'll
see how the dorms smell!
Lucky I always liked soldiers!
How about you?
I've seen more soldiers
than a retired general.
I can tell the regiment
just by the smell.
- What's your name?
- Emilia Zarfaneti
but they call me Argentina.
I don't see your boyfriend.
I guess he couldn't make it.
He works at the farm
where I was last year.
We're going to be married
and I'll see him every day!
I'm scared I won't make it.
I'll work for both of us.
We need that rice back home.
We've got to make it!
Let's pick a bunk or
there won't be any left.
- This straw's damp!
- Never mind that.
- What are they doing?
- Stuffing their mattresses.
You can do yours later
no hurry.
I have my wool mattress,
I like to be comfortable.
Hi, baby! What are you
around the chest?
"I'm leaving a slow death
in the barracks"
"not in time of war...
in time of life"
It's better here,
a bit like a sleeping car.
- Top bunk or bottom bunk?
- Top.
I don't advise that.
My, what a hard head!
You want to move in here?
Yes, if you don't mind.
You take that one, Francesca.
The slats are missing here.
It's scented! What's in here?
Sugared almonds?
It's mine.
You take them with you to
remind you of your boyfriend?
Keep them, sugared almonds
don't go whith the army life.
A soldier's crazy to think
about getting married.
The pay won't feed two.
Come on, give me a hand.
It'll be all yours in a minute
including a couple
of hundred bedbugs.
- What?
- Bedbugs!
Bedbugs? Thanks a million.
Scared?
I like my sleep, don't you?
You get used to it.
I sure have, after 10 years
of barracks and the front!
You can forget sleep! But
it's the thinking that gets me.
I'm waiting for my discharge.
That keeps me awake nights.
- Are you from these parts?
- No.
- From Lombardy, and you?
- Ferrara.
- What's your name?
- Silvana.
- Why, you'll write me?
- "Lots of kisses from Marco"!
See you.
Don't read the trash
on the wall.
I already did.
"Love" can stay though.
Funny way to make up to me!
How do you know he was?
- Men always do.
- Hurry up with those pallets!
Do yours now.
Those without a regular
contract, come see me later!
- What's happening?
- Don't they want them?
It wouldn't be the first time.
It's their fault
for going under the counter.
That was Silvana's cot but
she changed over with me.
She likes to be
nearer the door.
What are you looking for?
It was here, I know it was.
What? Let me help you find it.
Do you mind me taking this cot?
It's to have the baby near me.
I'm Andreina. There was no one
I could leave him with, so...
What's going on?
Seems they want to send home
those without a union contract.
I always say it's not worth
coming if you're not regular.
No...
- they can't send us away now!
- It's not fair!
We're here to work, not steal!
Listen to me, will you?
If it was me, I'd hire you all,
but the boss gave orders.
You can't really blame him.
The union might send
an inspector.
We want to stay! We won't
let you send us away!
I'm only passing on orders:
No contract, no job.
We'll give you the money for
the trip home and a day's pay.
- A day's pay for each of you!
- We don't want your charity!
We want to stay here and work!
That's enough! Pack up!
Don't let me find you here
tomorrow!
What are you doing here?
Get into your heads...
you can't work here!
Where are you going? It's no
good trying the other fields.
It's too late to find work now.
Hold it! If we can mix in
with the regulars
we're home!
Let's see if you can get us in.
- You make it sound easy!
- Quiet you!
Do you think I want
to lose our cut?
Come on then!
What are we waiting for?
Yeah, let's go!
What are you staring at?
Look, the illegals came anyway.
They like working for free!
It's up to you now. You'll
have to brake your backs
and work twice as hard.
When they see what you can do
they won't think
of sending you away.
Off you go now!
Are you crazy? They have
to go, the boss said so!
Don't worry. Just wait,
you'll thank me later.
Our girls work a lot
harder and faster.
That's a good thing for you...
your girls will have to keep up.
You'll look good,
you'll save time and money.
Come on, back there!
Don't waste time!
Need a hand?
You'll work faster then.
Look where the illegals
are already!
I can't keep this pace up
much longer.
You've got to hold out or
you can forget the contract!
Look how far back they are,
they can't catch up with us now.
Hey, Silvana!
Going for a ride?
They don't let us talk. If you
have anything to say, sing it.
The illegals start off in a hurry
which is just what traitors do.
Better hurry when it's cool,
later on the sun beats down.
Poor illegal who is working
harder and harder.
In the cool or in the sun,
this is no way to work.
Wake up! Faster!
See where the others are?
Steward, you shout too much,
we know our job.
You look out for the blacklegs!
- Take no notice! Faster!
- Quiet!
Work faster!
Andreina is too old, she
can't take the rice-swamp!
- Get back to work!
- Blacklegs!
Traitors!
What are you after?
Cut it out! Stop that!
It's all her fault!
She's the blackleg!
She's the ringleader! She told
them to work faster than us!
What do you mean?
Nothing to say for yourself?
Got a guilty conscience?
Why did you set them all
against her?
Are you crazy? Do you
want to kill each other?
Get lost! She's a blackleg!
You can't lynch her!
It's her fault we nearly
had to work twice as hard.
Don't believe that idiot!
She was right! She started it!
Yelling won't help you
clear things up.
Nobody does something
for no reason.
Maybe she needs to work
more than you do.
Yes, they want
to send them away.
So they stood up
for themselves.
But they didn't think about
how that would hurt us.
Well, did you try to help us?
You know how we're fixed!
There, see, it's no good
fighting among yourselves.
Why not try to come
to an agreement?
Get it? It's up to us
to come to an agreement!
It's not fair
to treat them like that!
Let's go see the boss, all of us.
Everybody works or nobody does!
Go on then!
I'm with you! Let's go!
If you help us,
we won't let you down!
Go ahead, you guys,
I'll be right with you.
Where you mixed up
in that too?
Why did you blame me?
What have I done to you?
- Go away!
- What have I done to you?
Get out of here!
You've got to tell me.
Why do you want me to go?
You're a thief! A thief!
I didn't steal anything
from you.
- You're the thief!
- What's this then?
You stole it with
your boyfriend. Thief!
I saw you hide it. I knew what
you were right from the start!
We don't want thieves
here with us!
What's going on?
Turn her in! She stole this!
Why get so uptight?
Well? Are you going to turn
me in to the police?
I don't do things like that,
it's not for me to judge.
And you stay out of it.
Give her necklace back.
How much could it be worth?
I don't know. I never saw
stuff like that close to.
- It's not for us.
- What do you want me to do?
- I'm in your hands.
- I'm not a snitch.
It's up to you to decide.
Shouldn't she go to jail?
Jail was invented by someone
who never went there.
That's not the only answer
and jail doesn't save you.
You see, if Francesca
had a different face
maybe I'd turn her in
to the police.
Didn't you know
it's all in the face?
I've seen thousands of faces
in my life, in the army...
Here too... There's all kinds.
Each one has its own fate
and they can't help it.
Sergeant! You're wanted
at the camp!
After that I was a maid
for some very rich people.
The mistress was young,
beautiful...
- Was she very elegant?
- She had everything she wanted.
I used to dress her, undress
her, put her shoes on...
Why, couldn't she
bend down?
Why are they shouting
like that in the yard?
They're seeing the boss
about the illegals.
Let's hope for the best.
Go on.
Why do you want
to know about me?
What did you do
after that house?
They fired me because
I was expecting a baby.
I'd met him...
He was a real gentleman.
I fell for him like an idiot.
He gave me so many presents.
I knew he wasn't just anybody.
He said in a nice outfit
I was a real lady.
When he won at poker, he'd hire
a car and we'd take a vacation.
Did you go where they gambled?
No, it's dangerous.
They arrested him once.
Well, Francesca, how about
giving me my shot?
This is all they had...
I guess they're used
to horses here.
Still, the more the better.
- You made it up, you two?
- Mind your own business!
Keep your hair on!
Like him? He's a sailor.
He's been all over the world
even Shanghai!
- But I get around too.
- You split up?
I ditched him.
He's out of work now
and I got tired
of supporting him.
Where did we get to?
Oh yes, the baby!
He never got to be born.
I wanted him but he didn't.
- You know what men are like.
- Here, have a smoke.
He said kids tied you down,
they're just a headache.
After that, I did
everything he wanted.
He was wretching my life,
but he was all I had.
How I envy you, Silvana!
I wish I were you.
At least you've lived,
you weren't stuck...
in this squalor. You've
seen some nice things.
- Feel a bit better now?
- It's nothing.
Maybe it's that rice
they give us.
A lot of things
can make you sick...
Like these long faces!
How did you get
the necklace?
He came to see me one day.
I was working in a hotel then.
He said he had to pay off
a debt or go to jail.
He'd got it all planned...
the timing, where the key was.
He begged me on his knees...
- He was almost in tears.
- You hid it under the mattress?
Don't worry, I won't touch it.
I wish I'd never
touched it either.
You heard what
that Sergeant said?
I want to talk to him again...
I've thought a lot about that.
Will your boyfriend come?
- Who knows?
- He'll come
You'd have been in trouble
without the necklace.
Does he beat you?
- Don't you love him anymore?
- I don't know.
The boss said yes!
He'll hire them!
I guess you're not too keen
to let the cops see you.
- You sure trust me!
- Come on, mister!
I've only known you two
hours. Who are you anyway?
I talk and talk, I tell you
all about myself, and you?
You know the Arab proverb?
"Why talk if you can
be silent?"
Did you ask around?
Yeah, they're not there either.
Not your woman, nor mine.
But I'll find her, you bet I will!
And when I do...
We'll try that place later.
Maybe we'll be in luck.
"I've been thinking about you
for 12 months. Augusto."
Anybody here know
an Augusto?
"We danced together
last year. Antonio."
Who knows Antonio?
- Load up!
- Right, Sergeant!
Hold it! This is going to be
the best shot of the season!
Hey, Sarge,
you're spoiling the picture!
- That better?
- It was better before.
Army doesn't go with art!
Ready? Hold it right there...
Watch the birdie... Done!
- Two copies.
- They'll be ready in an hour.
Step right up, girls!
Come to Mascheroni!
I've got everything you need.
Nylons... how about this bra?
Why do you do that?
You spoil it all, I told you.
I have to want it. When
the time comes, I'll tell you.
- I can't work you out.
- You can talk!
You don't look all serious
like the other day
when you said those
things to Francesca.
Keep your hands to yourself.
Okay, but I don't feel like
being serious today.
That was some necklace!
I wonder what it's worth?
Like that, nothing. She can't
wear it or they'll arrest her.
- She got rich though.
- By stealing?
- But you let her off.
- I didn't let anybody off.
I see. You talked like that
just to look good with me.
It's easy... that girl's
future is marked.
I wonder what mine will be?
Read it in my palm.
Who can tell?
All I know is mine
won't be the army.
- I'll go abroad!
- Why do you want to go?
I'd stay in Italy if I had
a home and a job.
I waited 10 years to get out
of this uniform
and now I have to be afraid
of civilian life.
That's why it took me so long
to make up my mind.
I've spent so much time
in the trenches...
...I can hear the bullets
even when I go dancing.
I can do a lot of things,
I can handle all kinds of guns
but I don't have a trade. I can
do everything and nothing.
So if I have to start over,
somewhere far away is best.
- It might be easier.
- Where do you want to go?
South America maybe.
They say there's work there,
it's virgin territory.
Could be, but you never hear
about it. North America now...
- everything's electric there.
- Yeah, even the chair.
Want to come with me? It's hard
to go all that way on your own.
Soon as I get my discharge,
we'll go.
Who says that's my future?
I do. Try it and see.
No, don't start that again.
It's late.
The men are through
loading up.
- See you tonight?
- I don't know.
- Sergeant!
- Oh, it's you.
We didn't finish our talk...
It's a long story.
I'd like to explain.
Explain what?
- I feel I can trust you.
- Me? Why is that?
I don't know what it is,
but every time I meet you...
- it's like I was seeing a friend.
- I'm glad about that.
Don't worry, Francesca
I have to go now. Good luck.
I found a nice spot under the
trees, with grass this high.
Dad wants to sell the cow to
give me a dowry. What's best,
- the cow or the money?
- The cow!
I don't know why she's got
it on, but nobody else knows.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of it.
Stay where you are!
Sorry, I had to square
something with the girl.
Good for you, Sarge!
That showd him!
Are you crazy?
You've come out into
the open enough already!
Who is that?
Her boyfriend, I guess.
- Look, I've got the necklace.
- It's fake, you idiot!
Don't you read the papers!
Nice work you did!
- A fake?
- Yes, a fake! Stupid fool!
Okay, that's fine. Now Nanni
goes out first, then you.
We'll meet up
at the usual place.
We got about 15 kg, huh?
Yeah, maybe more.
Hand it over!
Take it easy!
You're not men, you're ants.
You're carrying away
one grain of rice at a time.
Who are you anyway?
A guy who's watched you
for threee days.
What are you doing here?
I live upstairs.
With the housing shortage,
they got no rooms for rent in jail.
There sure is some rice
in here...
How much would you say
counting the other barns?
- How much is there?
- I guess...
20 or 30 tons.
Go on like this and you'll
be through in 100 years!
You'd take it all in one go?
Why? You reckon
that's a bad idea?
We'd need all the trucks
on the farm.
You said it!
And what's it worth,
the rice in here?
Wholesale, around 7 million.
We just have to find
a buyer then.
No, we just have to get it out!
Right.
We could do the job together.
You can find me here.
Forget those bags now.
You could blow the whole
thing and wind up in jail.
Soggy rice again! Don't they
give you anything else here?
What were you talking about?
Business.
Let's get out of here,
what are we waiting for?
Where do we go without a cent?
Into the arms of the law?
We're both okay here. You
work and make a bit of money.
As for me, who's going
to look for me here?
Besides... maybe I've found
a way to make a pile of dough.
But that girl know everything!
She's hotheaded.
You can never tell
what she's thinking.
She's involved too now.
You didn't tell her it's a fake?
Don't worry then.
She'll feel guilty and
keep quiet about it.
I've got a good nose,
you know that.
She could be dangerous,
she's just a child.
I know a lot who'd like to play
with a child like that!
And what about her legs?
Yeah, okay, you've got
nice legs too.
Cut it out! I don't like
the things you get up to.
We're getting innocent
people involved.
They won't be innocent
much longer. I give the orders.
That's all you ever say...
Nobody else exists except you.
At the station you needed help,
and I was standing there
already... at your orders
ready to die even.
Give me a kiss...
Don't you like me anymore?
Stop it! I'm going...
The girls are all
in the dorm already.
Scared to get wet or something?
Aren't you going to jump in?
- What, in that dirty water?
Aren't you getting undressed?
- No, I'm going back to the farm.
- He's waiting for you?
- Who?
- Walter, your boyfriend.
He's not here any more.
I told you he'd gone.
- Don't you believe me?
- Lf you say so.
- Will he be back?
- Who knows?
He's unpredictable.
If he does come back,
that shows he's in love.
Yeah, right.
If he comes back...
I guess he likes someone.
Here come the rain!
Standing guard now
while I undress?
You talk like
it's all my fault!
Hands off! Turn around.
Who was that guy?
Search me!
But he sure can do
the boogie-woogie.
Boogie-woogie, corny
magazines! Is that all you see?
What else, when I'm knee-deep
in water from morning to night?
- What do you know about it?
- There's nothing to know.
Wearing that necklace
after what I told you!
What a fuss you're making
about a whim!
There wasn't any danger,
nobody noticed.
I guess they thought
it was junk.
Don't you understand? You
shouldn't have touched it.
It's stolen property!
Why didn't you report
Francesca then?
All you can do is preach.
Turn her in!
You know you're an accomplice
now in the eye of the law?
Who, me? What did I do?
Enough to wind you up in jail!
Why didn't you listen to me?
Your future is like
I said... with me.
I haven't changed my mind.
Go away! I don't want
to see you again!
Are you nuts or something?
What are you after?
I never came looking for you.
You're right...
How miserable
we'd be together!
I'm starting to think that too.
That's just how it would be.
It's lucky we realized in time.
I realized a while ago,
you know.
I'm not the right girl for you.
You'd better not come
to the farm any more.
Sure... I won't feel like
coming now anyway.
- It's better this way.
- Come on, it's cold!
They've nearly
finished it for me.
How do I look?
Make a nice mosquito net
if he ditches you.
Miss Rice and her Orchestra!
Come on!
Don't be so silly!
My, aren't we edgy!
You really like this wake?
You'll see when they say,
"Here's your pay and rice"
"but the rice is 5 kg less
because it rained"
and you sat on your hands
for five days."
Remember in 1942?
A week of rain
and 7 kg less rice.
Dresses! Perfumes!
Cigarettes!
Love letters written!
Come on, girls!
Summer rain is good!
Write a love letter
to your boyfriend back home.
Out of sight, out of mind,
you know.
Careful, you'll lose him!
Go on, send him a love letter.
A Mascheroni letter...
no spelling mistakes.
Well-written, original...
heartfelt... passionate...
Maybe you were hoping
for someone better?
- I thought you'd gone.
- Yeah, but I came back.
- What for?
- To dance with you.
I swore I wouldn't dance
again after what happened.
We could talk a little then.
- Yes, but not here.
- Why not?
It's raining outside
and it's better
if I'm not seen around.
Scared?
Come on!
We never talked much
but it's like I've known
you a long time.
- I feel the same.
- Aren't you sick...
of being with these people
all the time?
Who else is there?
It's only two more weeks.
You need a more refined
kind of occupation.
These are the hands of a lady.
If you take care of them...
You're the one
who's scared now.
Every time we meet,
something bad happens.
- At the station...
- Were you scared then?
No, but I was in trouble
the other night.
That's why it feels like I've
known you for a long time.
Without knowing it, we've done
a lot together already.
We're nearly on intimate terms.
Are you happy you met me?
- Who are you anyway?
- Don't give yourself airs.
It's not every girl gets
to go with a guy like me.
You think you're so special?
Well, I don't know... If you
prefer guys like that sergeant
who just rot in a barracks
all day long...
He's really gone on me, that
one. I can't stand leeches.
Good girl! It shows you're
the indipendent kind.
Punks like that don't deserve
a pretty girl like you anyway.
Leave it open, at least
we can breathe a bit.
Look at them!
You know what? That's
made me think straight.
We stand in water all day and
we're scared of a bit of rain?
This makes six days...
and 6 kg of rice we lose!
We'll be late getting back if
we don't make up for lost time
and a lot of us will lose the
harvest contracts back home.
If you agree,
we'll show the rain!
We'll go out and work anyway.
I'm with you.
It's not for us.
- They're all going.
- Come on then!
Let them be. What do we care
if they don't want to come!
Let them go. For us, the
longer we stay, the better.
They won't pay us, but at
least they'll have to feed us.
But they helped us when the
boss wanted to send us away.
- You'd better not come.
- Don't worry, I'm all right.
To work, girls! Every day
is one kilo of rice more!
What's a bit of rain? The damp
in here is killing us anyway!
- We'll get soaked!
- Rain makes your hair curl!
- Stay here, listen to me!
- No, I want to come too!
I'm going with them.
Come away from there,
they'll see you.
Can't you see
you're getting drenched?
- Let me go now.
- Don't I get a kiss?
Yes, but don't come
any closer.
Let me go!
- I don't see Silvana.
- We called her no end of times.
I guess she's busy.
You're supposed to pull up
the weeds, not the rice!
Can't you see?
The rice doesn't have
any white on the leaf.
Are you sick?
I said you shouldn't
have come!
Don't worry...
It's dangerous
in her condition.
We'd better do something.
Let's get her to the bank!
Sing!
Seems the authorities
are coming to the party too.
Lucky I brought
all the songs.
Come on, down there!
- Why the authorities?
- They'll say how good we were.
- What do they know about it?
- Those people know everything.
The band's good, they do
all the latest songs.
The accordionist is nice.
There's nothing like dancing!
- While you're young!
- I'll dance even when I'm old!
Tonight I want to dance so
much I'll be laid up for a week!
This is the first time our party
starts with a wedding.
Fancy getting married
on the last day!
- Come on, get that line up!
- Untangle the lantern first.
- Does it work on electricity?
- What do you think, matches?
I know who I'll dance with.
I'm taking my girl.
Mon and dad?
That's just great!
The best picture this season!
Hold it right there...
Watch the birdie...
Stand in line, I'm going to
hand out the sacks for the rice.
- These won't hold 40 kg of rice.
- They did the other years!
When do they give us the rice?
Tomorrow, before we go.
These trucks won't get all
the girls to the station.
- We'll do 3 or 4 trips.
- You guys got here early.
You wanted all the fun?
What about the trucks
if you go to the party?
Who's going to touch them?
Leave it, he'll do it.
Say, what can you do
with this baby...
on a full tank?
- 200 km?
- Are you nuts? 500 km...
- not counting the reserve.
- Say...
how about a drink tonight,
all of us together?
Sure. We might even get a steak
with all the meat around here.
Yeah, there's plenty
for everyone.
They lay on an end of season
feast for the rice-workers.
I don't need a sack,
I've got my rice already.
What about ours?
Take this to Gabriella from me.
Something to remember me by.
- But what about you?
- I'll get by
They'll be very happy back
home... Gabriella too.
- Why did she give hers away?
- I don't know.
She's screwy,
but she's not unkind.
We're home! The trucks
are going to be a walkover!
And we've got a heap
of rice all ready!
But how do we get past
the guy at the entrance?
Everybody'll be at the party.
If anybody catches on,
we've had it!
It's too bad you're
not mutes like him!
He says it's crawling
with cops...
the Police Chief came along!
What if we get
trapped in here?
Get those trucks ready to
leave as soon as it's dark.
That's enough talk! I'll take
care of everything now.
They'll wave goodbye
to us even.
Where have you been?
I missed you.
Everything's ready,
it's up to you now.
You want to help me, don't you?
- I'll do anything you say.
- You don't sound very keen.
I know, I don't like it either,
but it means everything to us.
What's beating you?
The girls were supposed
to get this rice tomorrow.
It's not a lot either.
I don't see why
you have to steal it
when you have a necklace
that's worth so much more.
The necklace...
you like it, huh?
I'm going to give it you.
It's my engagement present.
It's yours. You can do
what you like with it.
We'll be rich anyway,
won't we?
As soon as we sell the rice,
we'll move into a plush hotel.
Tell me the truth... I've been
wanting to ask you this...
Do you ever wear a mask?
- What?
- A black mask.
The other one's here...
Francesca!
Be right back.
Long time no see.
I have something
important to say.
We're not with rich people
that you can steal from here.
The girls broke their backs
for weeks on end.
You'll get medals for it
and citations.
No, we won't get anything
except what we earned:
The rice you want to steal.
I know what you're planning.
Congratulations! You used
to be slower on the uptake.
I can't put you back in the team.
Your place has been taken.
I don't care.
I'll never go back to you.
Now get out of here!
This is the only clean
place. I've ever known.
I guess I'll have
to disappoint you.
Go away... before
I turn you in.
Listen...
this is the biggest job
I ever tried to pull off.
Don't get in my way.
You're still tied to me.
Remember that...
all the way to jail.
And jail isn't the worst thing
that could happen to you.
Are you through?
Just clearing things up.
Yeah, everything's clear now.
Okay, that's enought then.
Yes, but you're coming
with me.
He'll wretch your life
- like he did with me.
- No, he'll marry me.
I'm sick of this squalor,
I told you.
But look at me...
It's different, he loves me.
- And you believe that?
- We just got engaged,
he gave me a present too.
Look what...
We've had enough of you,
beat it!
And remember what I said.
It feels so good to be in love.
Now show me you love me.
I need your help
to pull this off.
You won't attract attention
in the fields.
We need something
to distract them
if this is going to work.
Now listen carefully.
This is what you do...
- You came to say goodbye?
- You're going then?
Yes, I got my discharge.
I know you'd rather avoid me,
but please listen.
Something terrible
is happening.
I can't go to anybody else.
What's it all about?
I'll marry the winner!
She had to end up that
way... with a no-good!
We can't abandon her.
You can still save her!
I'm out of the army now.
I can go where I like.
There's plenty of people
at the farm, tell them.
It's hard for me. The girls
treat me like one of them.
I'd have to explain it all to
them, tell them what I did.
It's hard, but you have to
learn to get by on your own.
You're right, I'll do that.
There's plenty of people
at the farm...
the police too.
She's not here!
We can't find her!
- Where's Silvana?
- God knows what's keeping her.
Here she comes, the prettiest
of them all! She wins the prize.
The fields are flooded!
Quick! Hurry!
- What's going on?
- Don't worry.
I'll go take a look,
maybe they got Silvana.
All our work!
The diskes gave way!
We'll have to break the banks
to let the water out!
If we don't hurry, the rice
will get washed away!
Give me a shovel!
Come on, give us a hand!
Is this what
you were afraid of?
- They did it!
- Maybe it's too late.
- What can we do?
- Come with me!
We can't do anything here.
They did this to get
everybody out of the way.
Let's go to the farm, maybe
we can still stop them.
Francesca and the Sergeant
followed me!
- Hey, that was a shot!
- Lf he goofs, we scram.
Let's scram now,
before they catch us!
Yeah, let's go. It's his fault
for bringing a woman into it.
You'll drive that one,
I'll take this.
Don't worry about me,
watch out for him!
- Let's get out of here.
- No.
I'll see this through now.
We're trapped, we can't
get out of here.
You doublecrossed me!
I'll make you pay for this!
Where are you going?
Can't you see I'm hurt?
There's a first-aid box...
They'll shoot you, idiot!
Do something!
My wrist... my shoulder...
I can't defend myself now.
Get back!
Relax, I won't fire
if you keep still.
You have to lose
your poisonous blood.
This is where you have
to end your career.
Give my gun...
here, in my pocket.
You try... No, don't shake.
That's it, good girl.
Take the safety catch off.
Right, it's ready now.
Squeeze the trigger gently.
There's only 5 shots.
Don't waste them.
Aim carefully.
No, straighten your arm!
- Don't move!
- Shoot!
No, don't, you might
hit the wrong one.
Idiot! You wasted 3 shots.
There's only two left now.
It's all my fault
for dragging you into this.
I brought you bad luck
from the first day we met
but I so wanted it
to be different with you.
It's silly of me
to say that now.
It's not your fault.
I'd have met Silvana anyway.
I didn't realize... I guess I was
not meant to have a woman
after ten years in the army.
Or maybe...
that woman shouldn't
have been Silvana.
- Give me that!
- Don't shoot!
I can't make it.
You scared? I kew
you'd be scared!
- I can't do it!
- Do something, Silvana.
Say what you want to do,
we'll help you.
We can still save you.
Your courage has all gone.
They flooded the fields,
the harvest might be lost.
Why don't you say something?
I'm your friend, I know
you're not a bad girl.
Save your breath, idiot!
You really think a woman...
could fall in love
for a bum like you?
It's me she loves!
And she'll do only what I say.
For a poor slob like you
Francesca's more than enough!
You can have her
for all I care, she's yours!
Kill her!
Quick, kill her!
Don't come any closer!
Here's the necklace!
Take it!
Francesca, it's all we have.
Let us go!
The necklace...
is a fake.
It's worth nothing,
and he knows that.
That's why he gave it to you.
He used it to charm you.
It's phoney... like him!
You bastard!
Silvana!
Where are you going?
What's she going to do?
What are you doing?
Come down!
Where are you going?
Come on, it's time to go.
The trucks are waiting.
There's nothing more to see.
And so another season is over.
The time has come to go home.
Some will return
to their sewing machines.
Others to the fields
to cut the corn.
Others still to the factories.
Then, next year in May they'll
come to the rice plain again.
They may be the same ones
we met here
from Arceto, from Schio,
from Nonantola,
from Rio Saliceto,
from Casmara, from Cento,
from Emilia, from Veneto,
from Lombardy
from every village in the north.