BLACKBOARDS
a film by Samira MAKHMALBAF
- Said!
- Yes?
Thanks for your water.
- You've drunk it all!
- I was thirsty. I'm sorry.
Forget it.
Where did you go yesterday?
To Dezle.
Why?
Looking for pupils.
But no luck,
I couldn't find any.
I was there for three days.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
I don't smoke.
You couldn't find any pupils?
Not one.
My father warned me
but I didn't listen to him
and now,
I truly regret it.
- You studied for long?
- Two years.
You became a teacher in two years?
I worked hard.
- You like it?
- Not really.
Why?
I looked for three days and I found nothing.
I didn't listen to my father.
- What did he tell you to do?
- To be a shepherd.
I failed.
He's gone.
Get up.
Hurry UP!
And your wife?
When we got back from Tehran,
we had a fight about the doctor.
Her family insulted my family.
Mine responded in kind.
So her father took her.
Hurry up. We have to hide him.
It's been three months
since she went back with her father.
She left me with three kids,
one of them just a baby.
I tried to find him a wet nurse.
I went through a hundred families
to find one.
As a result
he's drunk the milk of many women,
even cows.
He looks like a hundred different women.
He's got the eyes of one,
the ears of another.
And he's sick.
Now I run from village to village
looking for a pupil I can make into a doctor.
That way, we'd never have to go into town.
If there was a doctor in the next village,
things would be easier.
- You're going to make a doctor?
- Yes.
- Which path are you taking?
- The one on the right.
It's dangerous.
- Which way are you going?
- This way.
But it's very dangerous.
Wait.
I'll tell you again, it's a death trap.
Yours is even worse.
No. Yours is more dangerous. Goodbye.
- Where are you going now?
- To the village.
- Can I come with you?
- If you like.
If we go together,
do you think we'll find any pupils?
- I'm not coming.
- Why?
I want to go to the top.
- How many pupils will you find?
- Two or three.
Fine. Keep them.
I'm going to climb to the very top.
The villages bring me bad luck.
My fortune lies up there.
Go on, you take the villages.
I'm going up there.
Take care.
Goodbye.
Hello!
Is there a school here?
I don't know.
And a teacher?
No idea.
Goodbye.
- And I'm sorry.
- The Lord go with you.
Excuse me!
Wait a minute.
What?
Please, read me this letter.
What is it?
What does he say?
Hold on.
Where does it come from?
This letter isn't in Persian.
For the love of God, read it to me.
It's from your son? It's not in Persian.
Maybe Arabic?
Where's it from?
From Iraq.
I don't know if it's in Arabic,
Turkish or Kurdish.
It's from my son.
But from where? I can't read it.
He writes that he's in good health.
He sends his regards to you.
I return them.
Next, he greets his mother,
his sister, his father and his brother
and no doubt his uncles and his aunts...
Wait.
He finishes by saying goodbye.
But how is he getting by?
Has he got money?
I'm getting to that.
I think he's saying that he's got a little.
Iraqi dinars.
How's he getting on in jail?
I'm sure he's fine...
He must have written that he misses you.
At the end, he says goodbye.
He doesn't say when he'll be released?
Goodbye.
I don't know.
But when will he be freed?
That's all?
If it's God's will, he will be released.
Don't worry.
Goodbye.
My God!
Young man!
- Are you okay?
- Yes, thank you.
Do you know where I can find
the shepherd boys?
Up there. This way or that way.
The goats go up this way?
Listen, I am a teacher.
- What?
- I am a teacher.
So what are you doing here?
- Looking for children.
- Good luck.
- Where are they?
- Up there.
Listen, young man, I'm talking to you.
I've already told you, they're up there.
- Which way should I go?
- The way I told you.
Straight ahead.
Do you know how to write?
What?
To read and write?
No.
Would you like to learn?
It's useless.
I'm talking to you!
Show me the way.
The way, young man!
Where are you going?
- Young man!
- What?
The way?
Here. There. Also here.
Not this way?
I'm talking to you!
- Young man!
- What?
Show me the way.
I want you to show me the way. Look at me!
Leave me alone.
Anybody here?
Is there anyone here?
Open the windows. Answer me!
Multiplication tables!
Come and learn how to multiply.
One times two is two.
Two times two is four.
Madam!
Do you need a teacher?
- What?
- I am a teacher.
Where are your children?
Leave me alone.
I have come to teach your children.
- Who are you?
- I am a teacher.
- Good for you.
- I'm looking for pupils.
- Where are the children?
- Go away.
Anybody here?
Is there anyone here?
I can hear voices.
I've come a long way
to teach your children
to read and write.
You won't need to pay me much.
I'll teach you to read and write letters.
Children, at last! Wonderful! Come here.
Stop. Tell me where you've come from.
Where are you going?
Where have you come from?
I've come from deep in the valley
to find you.
Let us through, mister.
Just a moment.
I'm not going to eat you.
I only want to talk to you.
- Do you have a school here?
- No.
- And a teacher?
- Would you like one?
- No.
Where are you going with those burdens?
- We're mules.
- What?
- Then I'll come with you, okay?
- No.
Let us get past, mister.
Let us get past!
Wait a minute, kid!
Allow me to finish and I'll let you go.
Just one question:
where are you going with those?
Let us get past!
It's heavy! You can't stay there like that.
Let us get past.
We're wiped out.
- You don't have a teacher?
- No.
There's no teachers here.
- Where are you going?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
Let us pass, we're wiped out.
Look.
You're holding us all up.
Let us pass.
I'm a teacher
and I've come
to teach you to read and write.
I've come a long way.
I've been looking for you for a long time!
I want to teach you to read and write,
to add up and multiply.
I don't want a lot of money.
If you don't have any,
you could just give me something to eat.
We carry contraband, stolen goods.
We take it
over the border
between Iran and Iraq.
We're always on the run.
Listen, my child.
With education,
you will be able to read a book
or, even better, a newspaper
when you're traveling.
Learn to read and write!
You'll know what's going on in the world.
You can learn to add up,
to subtract, to do your accounts
without being swindled.
What good is it, all that?
You can study or find work.
Doing the accounts,
that's great for the Boss.
Us, we're mules.
Always on the move.
How do you expect us to read?
To read a book,
you have to sit down.
Us, we never stop moving.
Listen, I want to talk to you.
Stop! Wait!
Wait!
Hello!
Do you know how to read and write?
- Do you?
- No.
- Do you want to learn?
- You don't?
- No.
Hello.
Do you know how to read and write?
- Do you?
- No.
Hello, sir!
- I'm talking to you.
- What?
You wouldn't have a scrap of bread?
It's freezing!
Where are you going?
I don't have a job, can I come with you?
We don't need you.
Hello. How's it going?
It's freezing!
Hello, sir.
Sir!
I'm talking to you.
Why won't you answer me?
Haven't you got any work for me?
No.
I'll do anything.
We don't have any work ourselves.
I could herd goats, sweep up.
Just give me something to eat.
We haven't got anything to eat either.
How do you survive?
We're nomads.
I'm hungry-
Give me a piece of bread.
Where are you going? Can I come with you?
We have strayed. We're old.
We are lost,
we don't know how to get back to Iraq.
Can you show us the way,
just as far as the border?
Fine, let's go.
I can show you, but it won't be easy.
Halaleh!
Bring your father something to drink.
Bring some water!
What do I get if I take you?
We have nothing to give you!
I have to guide you for nothing?
We have nothing to give you.
You must have something!
There is nothing.
Not even a piece of bread?
Not even bread.
It's a hard road.
You must give me something.
We don't have anything.
How can I lead you with no reward?
We have nothing.
Not even a scrap?
I can give you forty walnuts.
Only forty?
Forty isn't enough!
Give me fifty.
- The route is hard.
- You won't get more than forty.
It's a long hard road.
I accept.
- What's wrong with him?
- He's sick.
Give him some water!
Drink, drink.
Drink, drink. You won't drink?
Drink!
Dear lady,
give me a little water, too.
Madam, I'm thirsty.
I'm parched!
Give me something to drink.
I'm thirsty.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going on.
For five nuts, will you carry
the sick boy on your blackboard?
Five nuts?
God help us!
What's wrong with the old man?
He can't piss.
He's sick.
Sick?
Where are you taking him?
To the border.
To the border?
Who is that woman?
That's the old man's daughter.
He wants to marry her off.
Once it's done,
he'll go to his grave in peace.
- How much does he want for her dowry?
- Nothing.
What do you mean, nothing? She's poor?
If you want her hand,
give him a walnut tree.
I don't have one. I'm a teacher.
I only have this blackboard.
- Only this blackboard?
- Yes.
I must ask her father if he will allow it...
Sure you won't regret it?
No, I won't regret it. Get him down there.
What about me?
Let's go and ask for her hand right away.
Force yourself, my brother. Piss.
Hurry up. Don't be afraid.
Don't look at her!
You haven't been introduced.
Said!
You wish to marry Halaleh?
Yes.
- You agree?
- Yes.
Close your eyes and promise.
- I promise.
- You promise?
- Yes.
- You will shield her from hunger?
Yes.
Come on.
Come on... piss.
Halaleh!
- What?
- You wish to marry Said?
Are you sure?
Yes.
- You will shield her from hunger?
- Yes.
- And from thirst?
- I will shield her from hunger.
- You swear not to abandon her?
- I promise.
Halaleh?
Yes?
Do you accept Said as your husband
with this blackboard for a dowry?
Are you agreed?
You wish to marry him?
With the blackboard?
The blackboard? Yes.
Yes.
You are truly agreed?
Said, do you take her as your wife?
Halaleh!
And you, do you take him?
Yes.
You are now husband and wife.
Let's rest here.
You want to stop here?
You want to be stuck here forever?
Won't you get sick of it?
What's your name?
Have you got toothache?
Open your mouth.
Which tooth is it?
Do you know how to read and write?
Do you want to learn?
As you wish.
What's your name?
- Your name?
- Hayyaz.
Hayyaz?
You do this journey all the time?
Aren't you tired?
- You know how to read and write?
- No.
- You don't want to?
Do you know what it would allow you to do?
To read a book
or a newspaper,
to work, to listen, to speak...
When you can read a book,
you discover stories...
Stories? I've got a hundred.
It was spring.
I climbed to the peak with four friends,
to the top of the mountain.
The goats were grazing peacefully.
We chased a rabbit.
It ran out of breath. We caught it.
My friend tortured it.
He wanted to cut its head off.
I told him it was a sin.
But he continued to torment it,
he still wanted to cut its head off.
He tortured it
and tried to cut its head off.
I said that it was a sin.
I told him to stop
and I grabbed his hand, to try to stop him.
He insulted me
and cut the rabbit's head off.
They washed it and split it up
without giving me my share.
That upset me.
I went off and cried.
I led my goats away
and then we fought.
Then, as it was late,
we went our separate ways
to our homes.
Drop it! I don't need your stories.
I want to teach you.
Sir, Your Honor, please come here a minute.
- What's your name'?
- Reebok.
Reebok'? Me, mo.
No kidding?
Do you know what that says, Reeboir?
No idea.
That says "he who walks." The traveler.
- Do you know how to read and write?
- No.
- Do you want me to teach you?
- Yes!
- You really do?
- Yes.
- Shall we begin?
- Okay.
Take it, eat.
- No, thank you.
- Please, eat.
Thank you.
- What do you do?
- I'm a teacher.
You're joking? You're a teacher?
Can you teach me to write my name?
- Do you want to learn?
- Yes. Really.
Hello.
Where are you going with the kid?
Go and play.
Are you okay?
Go and play!
Don't cry, your mother's coming.
Come and play with the nuts.
Stay here, little one. Mommy's coming.
Sit down and play.
Don't move. Come on. Sit down.
Put the walnut on your hand.
That's right... like that.
That's it... just like that.
Lift your hand.
Flick it!
"I love you." Now, let's spell it.
Lift your hand, like that. Watch me.
"Love... you."
Look at me...
"I love you."
You won't answer?
Fine, I'll give you a zero
because you wouldn't answer me.
You cheated. You stretched out your arm.
You cheated!
We'll have a return game!
As you refuse to answer me,
I'll give you zero.
But because you're a good girl,
I'll give you eighteen.
"Eighteen."
Come.
Why do you refuse to learn?
I'm the best teacher around.
All my pupils get... twenty
out of twenty!
You deserve zero, but you're a good girl.
I'll give you eighteen.
I want to pee.
Help me, God...
Spare me, God...
Come here and try and relieve yourself.
If you don't squeeze it out, you'll die.
You've been suffering for three days now.
Hurry UP-
Piss... Piss... Piss.
Hurry up...
Relieve yourself. Quick.
If you don't, you're as good as dead.
Hurry UP-
Let's help him!
Couldn't manage it?
I love you
You, Blackboard! Move...
- You still couldn't piss?
- No.
God help me!
- You didn't piss?
- No.
I swear to you,
Satan himself could piss in that water.
I have pissed in that water,
but not him.
He must have committed
some terrible sin and now he can't piss!
You didn't piss?
No.
My God, have mercy on me!
Have mercy on me.
You didn't piss?
No.
That's it. Yes, R.
Well done.
B like Bread.
B like Bread...
O like Oil...
See how easy it is: Reeboir...
Run, quick.
Run!
Quick!
Repeat: R like Reeboir.
Reeboir.
He's fallen down!
Shakak!
- Who's fallen?
- Hayyaz.
Don't cry, Hayyaz.
Tell the story of the rabbit.
It was spring. Me and four friends
we climbed up high,
to the top of the mountain.
The sheep were feeding happily.
We saw a rabbit and we caught it.
- You can read and write, boy?
- Yes.
- You can?
But you told me you couldn't!
I don't trust strangers.
Why?
My mother warned me not to.
Your friends can read?
Most of them, yes.
But their mothers told them
never to trust strangers.
Children. Listen to me a minute.
Sit down.
Don't waste what time you have.
Let me teach you.
Look at my blackboard!
I want to teach you to read and write.
Watch me! Listen to me!
Don't listen to him.
Let's get out of here!
Children! Where are you going?
Let's go! Carry him.
Stop!
Listen to me!
Don't go!
It's your fault, all this!
Children!
- Repeat.
- Did I say it right?
Well done.
Very good.
Stretch out the R...
R like Reeboir.
Listen, friend.
The other story wasn't true.
What happened: we chased the rabbit,
we caught it
and we ate it.
It was tasty!
Delicious!
A like Apple...
Be quiet. They're behind us.
Reeboir and his group, this way.
Group Two, take the other path.
The rest of you, follow me.
Be careful. It's dangerous.
Not this way!
There are land mines everywhere!
Take the other path.
Look out!
Don't get yourselves killed.
Go round the other side!
Two times two?
Four.
Reply!
Reply swiftly, learn swiftly.
Two times three?
Six.
Four times two?
Come on, answer!
Two times five?
Come on: ten!
To learn quickly, you must answer quickly.
One times two?
Two.
Two times two? Four.
One times two? Two.
Mother, a rabbit!
Chuan!
What are you doing? The Devil take you!
Halaleh!
Where is she gone?
The Devil take you!
Halaleh!
Where are you?
Please, sir, have you seen my wife?
Where are you going?
Stop...
You want some walnuts?
One times two is two!
Why are you running away?
Have I done something wrong?
If math is too difficult,
I'll teach you to read.
Repeat after me...
"I love you."
See, it's easy.
Say it!
Come on, say it!
Say, "I love you."
Look at me.
What sort of student are you?
I'll give you eight.
No, not eight.
That would fail you.
I'll give you ten,
so you pass.
Say it!
Say, "I love you."
You don't want to?
What sort of student are you?
I'm giving you zero.
At least say that you don't love me.
What's wrong?
You won't say that either?
Here comes another zero.
Happy now?
Now a zero for your son.
Here's a zero for your son.
What?
You still won't answer?
I'll give you a zero for your father.
Here.
Still got nothing to say?
I'll give myself a zero.
For having been stupid enough
to follow you.
What kind of a life is this?
Goodbye.
How could I have loved you?
You're not listening to me!
Blackboard!
Stop!
Stop.
Listen!
My heart is like a train.
At every station, someone gets on or off.
But there is someone who never gets off.
My son.
Halaleh...
What's happening?
Escape! Hurry up!
What's going on?
The soldiers at the border have opened fire!
A like Apple.
Break the syllables up.
Excuse me, sir. I'm sorry.
We're in danger. I'll come back later.
Halt!
Who goes there?
What's your name?
- You don't want to tell me?
- Ghazal.
Do you know how to read and write?
- Do you?
- No.
- Where is your village?
- Down there.
- That's Dezle?
- Yes.
- Is there a school?
- No.
- Do you want a teacher?
- Will we have to wait long?
- Who knows.
Where are your friends?
We're meeting up by the river.
No, it was near the goats.
- They're not coming.
- They've been caught.
Thanks for the milk. Excellent.
Sir, I've written something.
- I wrote something.
- What?
- I wrote my name.
- Well done.
I wrote "Reeboir."
Run for your life!
Take him.
Come.
Quick.
It's just like at Halebtcheh...
I built a wall to protect us
from chemical weapons.
Father!
Chemical weapons...
Look after him.
What's happened?
I pissed.
Hide under the blackboard.
My daughter!
Your brother is dead. Let's go.
He isn't dead.
He wanted to die in his homeland.
Come on. He is dead.
Just like at Halebtcheh.
It's not chemical weapons. It's rifle fire.
Don't worry.
It's the soldiers from over the border
who were firing.
It's not chemical weapons.
Don't be afraid, my darling.
The women...
The children...
We're not going to die.
It's not chemical weapons.
It's the soldiers, over the border.
If they hear us, they'll fire.
I swear, it's not chemical weapons.
The women...
The men...
Hide under the blackboard.
I'll protect you.
Stop!
There. The border.
The land of your fathers,
of your ancestors.
Your homeland!
You're lying!
I swear I'm not.
It's the truth. Take a good look.
Don't you recognize Halebtcheh?
No. It's not the border.
He's tricked us, I know it.
He's lying. It's not the border.
We are lost.
I know our border very well. This isn't it.
I'm not lying.
I swear to you this is it.
This is your homeland.
This isn't the border! We are lost!
Can't you understand?
- Don't you believe me?
- You're lying.
You've tricked us, Blackboard!
I swear to you, I'm not lying.
It's been like this since the bombing.
It's not true!
I swear to you, this is the border.
You're looking at Halebtcheh.
It's because of the bombing...
God be praised!
We are grateful to you. Here are the nuts.
What will you do now?
Will you cross the border with us?
No, I can't.
But your wife wants to cross over.
She won't stay with you.
What's your decision?
If she doesn't want me, what can I do?
I don't know. You must decide.
A divorce?
Yes, if that's what she wants.
Let's find out.
Are you coming with us, Blackboard?
I can't. I belong here, in this land.
Your wife wants to return to her
own country. She doesn't want you.
Did she tell you that?
There's nothing I can do. I'll divorce her.
- You will divorce her?
- Yes.
Go and find her.
Put it down here.
Do you agree to a divorce?
And that you will take the blackboard?
The blackboard? Yes.
You may look at each other
one last time.
Lift your hand.
Take that stick.
Halaleh,
you are now divorced,
and the blackboard is yours.
May God keep you from hunger!
May God keep you from thirst!
May God keep you from solitude!
Take your blackboard.
And give me my stick.
Goodbye.
I love you
Chuan! What are you doing?
Hurry up. Come on.
Come, quickly.
Starring: Said Mohammadi
Behnaz Djafari
Bahman Ghobadi
Script: Mohsen and Samira Makhmalbaf
Camera: Ebrahim Ghafori
Music: M. R. Darvishi
Editor: Mohsen Makhmalbaf
Consultant: Babak Kari mi
Producers: Mohsen Makhmalbaf
Marco Muller for Fabrica Cinema
In association with:
RAI - Radiotelevisione ltaliana
In collaboration with: T-Mark
Thanks to: Paolo Landi
Federico Mariotto
Giancarlo Olgiati
Allessandro Favaron
Elisabetta Prando
Angela Quintavalle
Lucia Vellandi
Kitano Takeshi
Mori Masayoki
Takahashi Naoki
Director: Samira Makhmalbaf
Adaptation: Mamad Haghighat and Manaf