Sam!
Wait for me!
Come on.
"BLACK HEAVEN"
C'mon, Marion!
What's the time?
Shit, he'll be furious!
What's up?
My dad's due back,
and the place is a mess.
Can I come with you?
All right.
What are you doing?
What's up?
Marion?
Gaspard?
You'll be late.
That's your fault.
Sam?
Yes.
Sam, it's Dragon.
I wanted to hear your voice.
I was wrong to call.
- What are you doing?
- Looking.
We have to return it.
Or you keep it.
Shit, they're back.
I'll call you.
What did you do?
You ate her out.
Ignore him.
I Won't Waste my breath.
Did she blow you or not?
Lucio, you've got a dirty mouth!
Blowing isn't dirty.
It is.
Your language too.
Cut it out!
- I just want to...
- Enough!
I'm not answering.
What did you do, then?
You just kissed?
You're in love?
- Lucio...
-Yeah.
Shut the hell up.
See that, I got him!
You're in love!
That true?
It's why they didn't fuck.
Conversation over, thanks.
You're a sly one.
Coming to Memo's with us?
I can't.
I promised to repaint
the hallway.
Repaint it?
Need a hand?
Over my dead body!
You can ask Marion instead.
Gaspard...
Okay, We're going.
See you.
I Want the smutty details!
See you!
"Sorry I called.
I'll meet you as arranged.
From: Dragon"
Did you reply?
No.
Any old messages?
You want me to check?
Yes.
Hold on.
I'll read them.
"Insomnia I feel Weird.
I'd like to talk to you."
"No, I'm not scared."
"With you, yes.
I think I love you."
That's all?
I'll check what she sent.
"Meet me on Black Hole."
- What's Black Hole?
- No idea.
Another one...
"Saturday, 6:00 pm.,
at the chapel.
"We'll get what we need.
"We'll be together."
Signed Sam.
When was it sent?
This afternoon at 1:00.
Saturdays tomorrow.
I'm free.
You want to go?
What's the time?
6230.
Maybe it's too late.
Want to go back?
No.
I know what Black Hole is.
You do?
What is it?
Guess.
Tell me, what is it?
It's just an online game.
-You played?
- No, you have to buy the DVD.
That's Sam.
That's Dragon.
They've never met.
How can you be sure?
I don't know, but I'm sure.
I'll follow him.
You're sure?
You hear me?
I'm following him.
He's got rolls of tape.
What for?
No idea.
He's in the plumbing aisle now.
He's looking at pipes.
He's picked one.
It's a sort of plastic tube.
Hold on.
I can't see him.
- Okay?
- Come on.
We lost them.
Disappointed?
No, it was nice.
That's true.
It's so wonderful, Marion.
I love you.
Don't say it
if it's not true or it's...
it's what?
It's bad luck.
It's true, I swear.
I Wouldn't lie to you.
It's the truth.
What's that?
It's not locked!
He's dead!
She's breathing!
- What?
- Someone's there!
Anybody there?
Is anybody there?
That's my dad.
Good evening.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Need a ride?
I have to get the scooter back.
Marion says your parents
are away.
They're in Spain with my sister.
Don't worry.
it's a shock, but we'll be okay.
All right.
We'll fall asleep
and float in the clouds.
Give me plenty.
Here.
Tell me you love me.
I love you, Sam.
We're going far away.
To the Black Beach.
Yeah.
We're going away together.
Isn't working a drag
while we hang out?
No, I love being in a booth
as cars pass by!
It must be hell.
You learn a lot.
Yeah?
Such as?
Some people are nice;
others aren't.
Great discovery!
They're two different species.
Nice ones are always pleasant.
The others,
always nasty and dumb.
I'm a nice guy.
No way!
You're the kind
Who'd try to grab my hand.
Some do that?
Some even flash you their dick
at the tollgate
Are you nuts?
I'm not like that.
You are.
You think with your cock!
Here you go.
Bang on time.
Marion's great.
I mean it.
She's cute, friendly...
Smart too.
Yeah, dead smart.
She's a great girl.
I think so too.
I hope the four of us
stay friends.
How do you mean?
Well, now Marion and you
are together.
That changes nothing.
How do you run?
I'm looking for a girl.
This is the place.
But Watch out.
2,-'13 of the girls are guys.
Some are cute, though.
I know her already.
What's her username?
Sam, I think
There are loads of Sams.
Where does she hang out?
No idea.
You don't have a clue, huh?
Answer.
Don't be afraid.
Go on, answer.
Want to fuck her?
I understood.
What do I say?
Say yes. You'll see.
Too expensive.
She's nuts!
Shit...
Shit!
She killed you?
She sent me to Purgatory.
A real drag,
hours to get back.
Sorry.
Hey, that's life.
Do you like it?
What shall we do?
You choose.
Come see something at my place?
Yeah, okay.
You can even sleep over.
No.
My clad Won't let me.
I know him.
He freaks out.
What a drag!
He won't let me.
What did he say?
That I have to go home.
He's a pain.
He's totally anal!
Gaspard!
- Can I have a word?
- What for?
I just want a word.
Leave us, please.
She thinks I'm an old fart.
She never says that.
Whatever.
She asked to sleep
at your place.
I said no.
I don't think it's a good idea.
What do you think?
About...
Is it a good idea
for her to stay the night?
I don't know.
Yes.
I'm her father.
A father protects his daughter.
You must be reasonable.
- We are reasonable.
- Good.
You mustn't worry.
We're not kids.
We're careful.
Careful?
Careful of what?
Everything.
You think she's in danger?
You're talking
about contraception?
It's not just about
contraception.
Marion is a lot more fragile
than she seems.
She's very fond of you.
What about you?
Are you fond of her?
Yes, of course.
I have nothing against you.
I'm sure
you're a fine young man.
But I remember being young once.
I don't want Marion to suffer.
- You understand?
- I think so.
So think about it.
We're going far away.
To the Black Beach.
Yeah.
We're going away together.
Lucio, shit!
Okay if I take a break?
What for?
I need to pick something up.
Something?
Coming up with me?
- No.
- Thanks, Yann.
That's no surprise.
Gaspard?
You guys suck.
You're not letting me go
on my own?
- Okay, let's go.
- All right!
I know who my true friends are!
Hi.
Okay?
Good.
And you?
You said to stop by.
Want a beer?
Why not?
Not for you?
I don't see you much.
I'm kind of hard up right now.
Can I sit down?
Try this.
It's good.
Gimme a break.
it's the best shit ever!
Where's the toilet?
Second on the right.
Sorry!
I should have closed the door.
Stay, I don't mind.
What's your name?
Gaspard.
Are you a pal of Vincent's?
No, I came with a friend
to see Samoa
Samos is a jerk.
All Vincent's pals are jerks.
I know you.
What?
Where from?
I'm the one
who found you at the quarry.
Come with me.
Want to hear
the most beautiful song ever?
They'll wonder where I am.
Forget them.
Close your eyes.
It's better
with your eyes closed.
You saw it?
- What?
- My tattoo.
You were looking at it before,
right?
Yes.
Want to see it?
Know what it means?
Heaven.
Touch it if you want.
See, it makes a kind of bump.
Can you keep a secret?
You know Black Hole?
I thought you went for a piss!
Knock, asshole!
What's up, Audrey?
We can't listen to music now?
Watch your tone with me.
Who's he?
No one.
No one?
Come here, you.
She's my sister.
She's not well.
She just got
out of the hospital.
You understand?
What were you doing?
Nothing.
We were talking.
Just go.
Got that?
Get lost.
It's okay.
He's leaving.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
What were you doing?
Nothing, listening to music.
That's cool!
She's the girl from the quarry.
She is?
You never said
she was beautiful.
Did you get her number?
Did she give you
her number or not?
Fine, I'll ask Samos for it.
My name's Gordon.
Need help?
No, thanks. I'm okay.
Want to work for me?
I'll give you threads.
it's chilly here.
You can get rich with me.
Filthy rich.
Thanks, I don't need money.
Of course you do!
Everyone needs money!
You can't stay naked like that.
Do you know a girl called Sam?
Sam?
Noi don't know/ a Sam.
Work for me to meet people.
Sell these creatures.
How much?
Ordinary ones: 50 units.
Singing ones: 150.
We'll take one.
Thank you.
Excuse me!
Are you Sam?
No, I'm not Sam.
It's because of your tattoo:
Heaven.
It's a slave tattoo, honey.
Maybe your friend Sam
is a slave of Heaven too?
A slave of Heaven?
What's that?
Really?
You don't know Heaven, honey?
Good evening, sir.
May I come in?
Your card, please.
I'm looking for someone.
Are you a member?
No, I'm a friend of Sam's.
Piss off!
Yeah, Lucio.
Were you asleep?
Get over here, it's wild!
Wild!
Where?
What's that shouting?
Get your ass over here.
You'll freak!
You sound weird.
Are you blasted?
Yes!
Is Yann with you?
Yeah.
Audrey's here too.
Audrey's there?
- These guys are sick.
- What's going on?
Some crazy face-off.
About time.
Want to try?
Not particularly.
Samos has won, then!
What?
- Someone's cheating!
- Who's cheating?
I only had two goes.
I get a third.
What does the ref say?
He gets another go.
I'm warning you, I'm not moving!
You'll have to swerve!
- Want to get run down?
- Sure!
- Enough, you're blasted.
- Yeah, let's stop.
No one's stopping.
What's up?
Got no balls?
You're safe in the car.
Cut it out, Lucio.
Mind your own damn business,
Yann!
Go on, get going.
You'll swerve to miss me.
Maybe I won't.
You don't scare me.
I'll crush you like a hamster.
- Stop, this is totally dumb.
- Get in.
- What?
- Get in. I want a word.
Did Audrey thank you
for finding her?
You should thank him.
You're still here
because of him.
-Thank him.
- it's okay; there's no need.
There is.
Without you, she'd be dead.
Come on, Audrey.
Say thank you.
Thank you.
Fucking better than that!
He saved your life!
Thanks for saving my life.
There.
That's better.
Now kiss him.
Audrey had a camera in the car
that night.
A small DV camera.
Did you find it?
Are you sure?
Yeah, positive.
Maybe your friend took it?
Marion?
No, she'd have told me.
Yeah.
You're probably right.
- Are you okay?
- Fine, fine...
You're sure?
See?
You jumped.
You nearly killed him!
I knew he'd jump.
He said he wouldn't!
But he did.
Asshole!
What?
You're an asshole!
Okay, let's split!
The party's over!
Please, sir.
Yes?
Can I see your member card?
What?
I need to see your card, please.
What's wrong?
You from the club?
Yes.
No, you're not.
Good evening, sir.
Thank you.
Enjoy yourself, sir.
Wait!
Don't shoot!
You're Sam, right?
Yes.
What do you want?
To congratulate you.
A new member?
I never saw you.
I'm not a member.
How did you get in?
Sit down.
How do you know me?
Dragon told me about you.
You know Dragon?
I sold him a pet.
We hit it off.
That's what you do?
You sell pets?
Yes.
What did Dragon say about me?
Not a lot.
That you sang Well.
That's all?
He said he wanted
to die with you.
He told you that?
I never saw him again.
He's dead.
What's your name?
Gordon.
Nice to meet you, Gordon.
I have to get changed.
Gaspard?
You don't want
to see me anymore?
- What time is it?
- 5:30.
Sorry.
Need me to pick you up?
No, I took the bus.
Can I come over?
Yeah, sure.
Will I see you tonight?
Yes.
Gaspard?
Are you listening?
I'm listening.
Come at midnight.
The guy you killed
will block his card.
Use the emergency door.
The password is "butterfly"
- I'll come over, then.
- Butterfly.
What?
Yes, come over.
Okay, see you.
Take care.
Gordon?
Emergency door. Midnight.
Butterfly.
Get some fancier clothes.
I have a reputation to keep up.
- Yann and Ludo aren't helping?
- Not today.
What's up?
Hold on.
It's me.
No, I'm at lngrid's.
She asked me to sleep over.
You don't trust me?
Want to talk to her mum?
Okay, tomorrow at midday.
Sure you don't want
to talk to her mum?
Okay, see you tomorrow.
You'll get messed up.
Don't care.
- Gaspard...
-Yes?
I Want to make love with you.
That was beautiful.
I'd like to take you somewhere.
Know the Black Beach?
No.
It's where you go
when you die here.
- Purgatory?
- Yes. Already been there?
I thought people
stayed away from it.
It's my favorite place.
Want to go with me?
We'd need to die, then?
Yes.
Follow me.
I like it better here.
I'd like to disappear
and stay here for good.
Dragon liked this place too.
He wanted to disappear as well.
We'd decided to do it together.
I should have died with him,
but two kids found us,
and I'm still here.
Are you mad at them?
Who?
The kids who found you.
Yes.
We never asked them to.
I saw the boy again recently.
I intrigue him.
I think he's in love.
Why do you say that?
I can see it in his eyes.
Do you like him?
No.
He's too naive.
Next time, I'll die.
You'll try again?
Yes.
Gordon?
Ask me to do something for you.
What do you mean?
Put me to the test.
Tell me what to do in real life,
and I will.
In real life?
Yes, the first thing
you think of.
I'll do it.
For you.
Kiss that naive boy.
What?
Kiss him and sleep with him.
Sleep with him?
Yes.
That turns you on?
Okay, I'll do it.
I'll tell you about it.
Now what will you do for me?
Want me to do something?
Got a girlfriend?
Someone you're dating?
No.
I'm married.
Do you love her?
Why do you want to know?
- Can't you guess?
- No.
I'd like you to hurt her.
Does that shock you?
But you'll do it.
For me.
Coming for a swim?
Want to take your brother
to the pool?
Yes, he'd like that.
He keeps asking about you.
- He does?
-Yeah.
That's cold!
It's cold?
Hi.
Hello.
Want to come swimming with me?
Actually, I'm not alone.
Too bad.
Know Fallen Stone Bay?
I'll be there,
if you change your mind.
All right.
Who was it?
The woman next door.
What would you do
to hurt someone?
What do you mean?
If you had to,
what would you do?
I don't understand.
If you had to
hurt your brother,
what would you do?
I'd never hurt him.
What is this?
You never Wanted
to hurt someone you love?
No.
Never crossed your mind?
No, I don't think so.
That's your problem.
My problem?
You're naive.
It's naive
not to want to hurt others?
Funny how you
want to be perfect.
You think you're pure
and beyond reproach,
but you're just naive
Where's Gaspard going?
You're hurting me!
I'm sorry.
You came in the end.
You're not going in?
Where's Marion?
Looking after her brother.
Come on, no one's here.
What a bastard!
He's something else.
What the hell?
She looks so peaceful,
doesn't she?
Get out of here.
Did you hear me?
Get out.
So?
Did you sleep with her?
What?
You can tell me.
Audrey said she wanted to.
Was it good?
None of your business.
It is my business.
I don't want you to hurt her.
I won't
That's true.
You're a good kid.
The savior.
She needs help.
You want to help her?
To do what?
Two years ago, I realized
she was online more and more.
She'd chat to nutters
who wanted to waste themselves.
When I found out,
I chatted to them too.
One day,
I was online with a guy
and I told him he was right.
It didnt make sense
for him to go on.
He didn't deserve to live.
He should die.
I thought he'd tell me
to fuck off,
but instead, he started crying.
And he thanked me.
We chatted, and I told him
to jump under a train,
at a tunnel near his place.
I gave him the date and time.
You killed him.
He killed himself.
You've no idea
how many guys want to die.
Most can't manage it
but they're obsessed by it.
Know what they want?
Someone to help them.
Someone to give them
the little push they heed.
That's what they want.
A little push.
Not just losers or depressives.
Some of them seem to be fine.
- What?
- Someone's there.
Sam, we need to talk!
What's wrong?
- Your brother was at my place.
- My brother?
Yes, your brother.
Vincent.
How do you know him?
I'm Gaspard.
Silly me.
I should have known.
He was at the quarry
when you were with Dragon.
He was in the bushes watching.
Did you know?
Yes.
Tell me What's going on.
I can't.
Is he making you do it?
He made you use the camera?
No, it was my idea.
As a souvenir for him.
No, he said he makes people
commit suicide.
It turns him on seeing them die.
Go to the police, Audrey.
No, I can't.
You have to.
I can't!
Why not?
Because...
I'm his slave.
What are you saying?
Without him, I'm lost.
He loves me so much.
That's not true.
You don't need him.
He manipulates you. He's toxic.
He hurts you.
Go to the police, or I will.
It's true, he is mad.
He's driving me mad.
I'm ending all this.
I'll waste myself.
For good.
No, we can talk,
see each other.
- it's no use.
- It is.
I Want to see you,
see you face to face for real.
Okay?
Audrey, say you agree.
Okay.
Can you come into town?
Why not come here?
To your place?
I want to avoid him.
Vincent?
He isn't here.
Where is he?
In Nice with Samos and his gang.
What if he comes back?
He's spending the night there.
Are you afraid?
I understand.
Forget it.
No, wait. I'll come.
You will?
I'll be waiting.
Kiss me, Gordon.
Come on.
Make yourself beautiful.
Found someone?
Yeah.
What's his name?
Gordon.
Gordon?
You like him?
Yes.
Hi.
I saw Marion.
She's in a bad way.
She's worried for you.
She says you've changed.
You're not with Lucio?
No, Ludo's on a loop
about his sexual exploits.
Talk about young,
dumb, and full of cum.
He's a pain in the ass.
What's happening to us?
The four of us got on so well.
What went wrong?
I don't know.
You should see Marion.
Too late.
- Why?
- Audrey needs me.
Audrey?
That's bullshit.
You can't understand.
Marion's a thousand times
better!
I have to go.
Give me my scooter keys.
Now?
Yes. Now.
No!
Leave it on.
Hold me in your arms.
Hold me tight.
Tighten
Audrey...
You?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I don't want you to die...
I don't want you to die.
The savior wanted to screw her?
Why did you come?
It wasn't to save her.
That's bullshit.
Know why you're here?
I'll tell you.
You're like the others.
You want to die with her.
Get up.
Open the door.
Open the door!
Audrey!
Stop!
Vincent!
I'm going away, Vincent.
Get down.
Stay right there.
Don't be a fool.
Get down.
No.
I'm sick of it.
Come on.
No.
I'm going to the Black Beach.
For good.
Don't talk crap.
The Black Beach doesn't exist.
Yes, it does.
Marion...
You have to get up.
Your friend Gaspard
is in trouble.
I'll wait downstairs.
Where are you going?
Stay here.
Marion...
I wasn't lying at the quarry
when I said I loved you.
Maybe I ruined everything,
but I wasn't lying.
This is the place.
About...
We can't listen to music now?
Marion's a thousand times
better!