Wait downstairs,
Sean.
What's going on?
Mr. Randall,
we have a warrant
to search
your house.
A warrant?
What for?
Two upstairs,
two down.
Tommy,
what the fuck?
Ok, you guys cover the
bedrooms upstairs.
We got weapons
down here.
Call it in.
Call what in?
Ok, you just
stay right there.
You're about to be
front page news, Sean.
How do you
feel about that?
I told you,
I didn't do anything.
You planned to
do something.
No, I didn't.
I wish you'd
stop saying that.
Winchester 94.
Lever action.
Sleek, accurate,
no-nonsense.
Is that your
favourite?
We found it loaded,
ready to go.
Or the Remington 870?
Also loaded.
Were you going to
start with this one
and move to the Winchester,
or the other way around?
Those are my
dad's guns.
I don't know
anything about them.
I don't even
like guns.
Which gun is going to make me
feel like a man today?
So many options,
I feel giddy inside
just thinking about it.
Sean, put that
thing away.
They're close.
I'll take your
word for it.
How come you get the
pump action, Ricky?
I wish you'd stop
calling me that.
Well it is
your name.
Keep the
muzzle down.
Prop it up.
No!
Is that its heart?
Stop filming this.
You'll get
the next one.
The next what?
I'm just going
to run in --
you may as well
wait here.
Whatcha looking at,
you fucking weirdo?
They're cliches --
ignore them.
Dude, is that blood
on your hands?
Probably killed his
sister or ate his dog.
Goths are pacifists,
you guys don't know anything.
When did you become
the Goth expert?
I am a Goth.
Well goths don't listen
to Marilyn Manson.
I listen to
other stuff.
Check this out.
Oh, dude --
Stop filming this.
-- that is sick.
Oh, tell me that's
an animal!
It's a deer.
Fuck, Sean.
- That's gross!
- That is so fucking awesome.
Can you send
it to me?
Yeah, I'll just
post it.
What are you gonna do
take on the entire hockey team?
Yeah, sure...
why not?
Who threw it?
Deanna?
I didn't realize
you guys were friends?
We're on the
same bus.
Okay, then why don't you
tell him who did it then?
Yeah some friend.
Don't do it again.
Or what?
You gonna slit
your wrists?
How about I give you
your own website?
Dumb asshole jocks
dot com.
You serious?
Corey.
Here, give it to me.
This would make great
YouTube material, man.
All we need is a name.
How about "Freak gets
happy slapped."
No, that's too obvious,
isn't it?
Tell us about
this guy?
Cory?
Just a guy
at my school.
You must
hate him.
I know I would if
he did that to me.
I don't hate him.
But it's pretty clear
he hates me.
Maybe you should question him.
He's the dangerous one.
"Noon.
Felt like a good
time to start.
A clean, memorable,
turning point of a time.
The cafeteria,
with all its
pathetic symmetry
would be the place.
Two Colt 45s
would be the tools.
The captain of
the hockey team,
that vain,
preening peacock,
would be the
first target.
His bourgeois, groupie of a
girlfriend would be the next.
Followed soon after by the
rest of the hockey team.
It would be
methodical.
unemotional.
With his tools he
could fix them all."
It's interesting --
we found the same
story online.
Are you sure you don't
want that lawyer?
It's just
a story.
Ms. Dorey told me
to write down my --
Your feelings?
Who's Ms. Dorey?
I heard there was an
incident at the mall.
Do you want to
talk about it?
Not really.
Do you have anybody
you can talk to?
Like my dad?
You know,
you might not believe it,
but I dressed Goth
in high school.
I don't believe it.
I didn't live in Eastport. I
grew up in the city, like you.
Who did you
listen to?
Joy Division,
The Cult,
stuff like that.
Do you have
any tattoos?
Sure.
None that I
would show you.
This is the part when
I'm supposed to
open up and tell you
how much my life sucks?
Have you spoken
with your mother?
You know what I do
when I'm angry --
I write it down.
It helps.
Hey?
What are you
writing?
A story of
revenge.
Am I in it?
What, so you can
talk to me now that
we're all alone?
What was I
supposed to do?
Get up and walk
away with you?
They're my friends.
I burned you a CD.
Some stuff that I like.
It's mostly Industrial,
but there's this one band
on here called
Nemesiah that I love.
You probably already
know them.
There's this story how the
bass at their shows is like
so deep and constant
that people actually
shit their pants.
Anyway,
it's for you.
He's a fucking
heathen?
Cory?
He's not always
like that.
Yes he is.
What, you're
any different,
going around
cutting up animals?
What are you
talking about?
Your video!
It's gone viral.
You see what
you want to see.
Tell me what I'm
supposed to see.
What's going on?
I thought we were
getting along.
You won't even be
seen with me in public.
That's not true.
I mean sure, it'd be nice if you didn't
dress like every day was Halloween.
You could tone it down
is all I'm saying.
And be a bitch
like you,
Zamboni Man?
People don't like people
who stand out, Sean.
I belong in
the city.
Yeah, well, she's
not taking you back.
She made that clear.
She's not
even home.
They took Lily
to Florida.
Why don't you sit down
eat your dinner.
You killed it,
you eat it.
Can you see me?
Yeah, I can
see you.
Can you see me?
Yes, I can.
That's your room?
It's the room
I sleep in.
I wouldn't exactly
call it my room.
What is that?
This is Milton,
my lizard.
Oh my god!
Like the poet.
What?
Like the poet --
Milton.
Oh.
This is Snuggles.
Milton --
meet Snuggles.
Hello.
He comes with the
room by the way.
Well I just want
to come over there
with a spray can
and tag your walls.
I can see that.
So were you
born a goth?
You think
I'm a goth?
Aren't you?
Were you born
a princess?
Yes, I was.
No, this is
just who I am.
If people don't like
that's too bad.
You learn pretty quick
who your friends are.
And your enemies.
I just find it
interesting because
I'm like totally
the opposite.
I want everyone
to like me.
Everyone does
like you.
They like the
idea of me.
They don't
actually know me.
Sounds lonely.
I guess we're not
so different.
Sorry, I gotta
turn this down.
You didn't have
to do that.
It's not muzak.
I don't know
what that is.
A girl gave
it to me.
What was her name,
Elvira?
No, Deanna.
Not Deanna Roy?
Yeah, why?
Brian Roy's daughter?
The Puck Bunny?
I don't think they
use that term anymore.
She never misses a hockey
game is all I'm saying.
Well, sometimes
girls like guys
they can talk to.
Yeah, they call
them friends.
Hey, I was wondering what
you were doing at lunch?
I have a chemistry test
I have to study for.
I could help.
Did all that last
year in the city.
I study better
by myself.
Take a hint.
MacKenzie, you don't
have to be rude.
God, Deanna,
when did you become
such a freak magnet?
I should go.
Then go.
Wow, nice place.
Appearance
is everything.
I'm afraid to
touch anything.
Oh my god,
don't look at that.
Hard not to.
Shut up!
It's better than having
guns on your wall.
The thing that
bugs me about it
is the fakeness
of it,
like we're a happy
family or something.
So that's Big Bri, huh?
See that hand
on my shoulder?
Feels like it's
always there.
Tell him how
you feel.
Get your fucking hand
off me, you cocksucker.
Are you recording me?
Calm down,
I'll erase it.
Sean!
Wait -- let me
see it first.
Get your fucking hand off me,
you cocksucker.
Oh god, I look
so angry.
Who's this?
My sister, Lily.
I didn't know
you had a sister.
Half sister.
Sing the monkey
song again.
I did.
Do it again.
The monkey
was going.
I'm going to
do it faster.
The monkey was going ...
Sean, Jesus Christ,
she's not a toy you know.
You're really
sweet with her.
Tell that
to her dad.
He won't even
let me see her.
Thinks I'm gonna
kill her or something.
I heard it different.
Yeah, well my sister
knows his brother,
so I think that makes
me a much better source.
Wouldn't you
agree, Sean?
Yeah, Sean?
Sean, come on.
Sean, don't be
a retard.
What's going on?
Who is it?
It's my mom.
Can someone please
tell me what's going on?
You're like Homer Simpson hitting
his thumb with the hammer.
Oh my god,
is he texting you?
No.
Stop him!
So how did you
get her number,
Freak Show?
Why don't you
ask her?
No, I'm asking you.
She give it to you?
Fuck
If you go near my girlfriend
again I'll kill you
with my bare
fucking hands.
And I have the
means to do it.
He threatened me at school...
I was just responding.
Because his girlfriend
didn't want you?
What did she say?
Did you
talk to her?
This alleged threat of his,
were there witnesses?
Yeah, a few of his
friends Jason, Tyler,
a few others.
You mean the rest
of the hockey team?
We know about
your website.
Your videos. Your blog.
What we
don't know is --
why you're
so angry.
What did the
world do to you?
Can I see
my dad now?
Can you believe this?
Well, you dress
the part.
You wanted to stand out,
Sean, so now you do.
How's it feel?
I'm in jail,
how do you think
it feels?
I've been charged
too, Sean.
Improper storage
of firearms.
I've lived alone
for ten years.
They're saying I loaded them.
They're saying it's like Columbine.
I know!
Do you know how much
media is out there?
Does mom know?
I'm sure she
does now!
But they can't
give out my name,
right, because
I'm a minor?
They can give out mine,
so trust me she knows.
She's probably on a beach
somewhere breathing a huge
sigh of relief because you're
my problem now and not hers.
I should've been there
to raise you myself.
But you weren't.
Does he have
to wear those?
The whole town's
in there, Sean.
Take a seat.
Hi. You must be Sean?
Hi, I'm Andy Lewis,
with Legal Aid.
I've just been
assigned your case.
I just got your file.
Wow, it's nutso
in here.
Can you just tell them I'm
not who they think I am?
Lets take one
thing at a time.
We'll get you bail,
then I'll have a chance
to go over the file and
then we can talk, okay?
All rise.
The sitting of the Eastport
Provincial Court is now in session.
The honourable
Judge Campbell presiding.
Thank you,
you may sit.
Case number 6215,
in the matter of
the Crown versus
Sean Richard Randall.
Your honour,
Mr. Randall is accused
of making threats and
planning a violent attack
targeting specific students
and teachers at Eastport High.
Mr. Randall is clearly out of
control and a threat to himself
and the community at large.
Due to the uncertain nature
of the threats and the
instability of the accused
we request bail be denied
at this time and he be
remanded for the safety of
himself and
the community.
Proceed.
Uh, your honour.
I'd just like to say that I
find this a little bit extreme.
My client here has done nothing
but utter a few threats --
I'll have decorum in my court,
or I'll have the Sheriff
clear the room.
The point I'm trying
to make your honour,
is that my client's a minor.
It's my understanding that if
there is a parent or guardian
present and responsible,
bail should be granted.
Not if the parent is the one
providing illegal firearms.
Mr. Randall,
do you understand the
seriousness of
the charges?
Yes.
This is a tight-knit
community.
When you threaten our children,
you threaten us all.
I'm going to deny bail,
Mr. Randall,
pending further
investigation.
You're going
to Waterville.
For your sake and the
sake of the community.
Step through.
Step forward
to the line.
Turn around
and face me.
Take off
your shoes.
your socks.
Empty your
pockets.
Take off
your shirt.
your pants.
Rub your hands
through your hair.
Hold out your arms.
Open your mouth.
Wide as you
can please.
Stick out
your tongue.
Turn around.
Bend over.
BARKHOUSE!
Ce1l 2B.
Alright,
settle down.
Settle down.
In your cells in
twenty minutes.
I'll be watching.
It is about time
I got a new bitch ...
Eye down.
Fresh meat, huh?
Watch out
for Trevor.
I get the
headlines.
What's the
password?
Move.
Welcome to the
human fish tank.
You don't mind.
Can't whistle.
Birds whistle
and birds are free.
I didn't know.
Oh -- He didn't know.
Didn't know.
Speaking of birds fucking
parrot over here.
The question is --
just what kind of
bird are you?
Don't answer.
We have a tradition
here on West 7, ah.
Amherst teen arrested
for ATM bank fraud.
Ray, you're up.
Don't fucking
say a word.
I picked Hartford
youth gets
six months for
assault with
a deadly weapon.
Yarmouth teen sentenced for
eleven counts of joyridinq.
Could I see
bank fraud?
Maybe.
But assault with
a deadly weapon?
With his Aids
dick maybe.
And joyriding?
I swear Lucas you get
dumber by the minute.
Look at his face.
Joyriders are
friendly.
That's why they're
called joy riders.
This bird don't
like people.
He's got that
my-shit-don't-smell
look to him.
What's it say?
Eastport teen denied bail for
planning school massacre.
Trevor got it, I can
see it in his face.
Whoa whoa whoa,
he hasn't even one chosen yet.
Get them all in
front of him.
Come on, newbie,
who the fuck are you?
I knew it man.
I knew he was one of
them stinky-ass,
PIN stealing
muthafuckas.
Good count.
Okay.
Count up!
Hello?
Deanna?
Just a minute.
Who is this?
Friend of Deanna's.
What's your name?
Hello?
Okay boys,
in your cells.
Now.
No one lies to me!
No one!
Amherst teen my
fucking ass!
Teen dressed Goth and had a
large tattoo on his back
classmates described as
Satanic in nature.
The arrest follows a search
of the boy's home where an
arsenal of weapons were
found along with what is
believed to be a revenge
plan targeting the entire
hockey team.
Looks like I win
after all.
Let me see that.
Keep it,
Marcel.
Let it be a reminder to you
that you're still the same
dumb ass muthafucka
you always were.
Lying piece of shit.
BARKHOUSE!
Rollout!
Clean it up,
Columbine.
I ain't going to no
Discipline Unit
'cause of you.
You want
me to lie?
I want you home.
Your dad
wants you home.
That's why he
hired me, Sean.
To represent your
best interests.
How is saying
I did something
I didn't in my
best interests?
Please, Sean.
Mr. Johns is
here to help.
Look, I realize
those kids
at school were
the real threat.
But you got to
understand the system.
The parents,
the teachers,
the Crown,
they all want
blood on
this one.
Who do they
have, Harris?
It's a woman,
I think that's her name.
Dale Harris.
I remember because
Dale rhymes with bail.
They don't get any
tougher than her.
She wants fourteen year
olds tried as adults.
Fourteen.
How old are you?
He's fifteen.
Sixteen.
Point is you rattled
an entire community.
Accept this
and move on.
A couple years,
you'll be eighteen,
in college, nobody
will remember this.
I will.
Don't you think you'd
also remember a long,
drawn out trial?
Your dad's right.
I know you're
not guilty, Sean,
but the evidence against
you is very compelling.
If this goes
to trial...
I don't know.
What I do
know is this.
you put on
a nice suit,
you tell a nice story,
you'll get a slap
on the wrist
be released
for time served.
Lesson learned.
Make life easier
for yourself, Sean.
Doesn't anybody care
about the truth?
I'm due in court
in an hour.
Think about it.
Call me.
I'll talk
with him.
Do you have any
idea who that is?
It's only the best goddamn youth
lawyer this side of Montreal.
And he's here in this
room to help you.
Only you seem to know
more than he does.
What was wrong
with the other guy?
Andy the
Legal Aid guy?
He's a fucking idiot.
Barry Johns is
the real deal.
I mortgaged my fucking
house to bring him here!
Well I don't
like him.
You don't like
anyone, Sean.
Is it any wonder the
whole world's against you?
How do you live with
such an embarrassment
for a son?
Don't give me
that shit, Sean.
I'm here,
aren't I.
It's more than you can
say for your mother.
She's not coming?
I don't know.
We're playing
phone tag.
She's still
in Florida.
Says she's
coming though...
soon as she
gets back.
When will
that be?
I don't know.
But wouldn't it be
nice to get out of here
before she comes?
Get you cleaned up.
Put an end to all
this brutality.
Get your own
bitch, bitch.
Eat your peas,
Columbine.
You don't have
to call me that.
Why not,
Columbine?
Cause I'm nothing
like them.
That's not what
the newspaper says.
You know what you need,
Columbine?
You need to learn to
love yourself.
They teach that shit
here you know?
Yeah man,
they teach you how to
paint watercolours
and everything.
Express all that
pain you got,
so that when
you get out
you won't go blasting
up the school.
Why you in here?
Hey man,
this bitch is so new
he's still in
the wrapper.
You wanna know
what he did?
He killed
Santa Claus.
Some Christmas store
Santa up in Plate Cove
where he's from.
Some old retired guy,
everybody just fucking adored.
Turns out the guy's
a fucking pedophile.
One night,
takes Trevor out
to a dirt road,
starts to come on to him.
Tries to touch his
dick and everything.
Trevor goes ape shit.
Fucking kills the guy
with his bare hands.
When was that?
Five years ago.
Okay, wait,
he's here,
I gotta go.
Where they keeping you,
Australia?
You've been
waiting?
Yeah, I just got Gerry
breathing down my neck
every five seconds -
how much longer,
how much longer?
You know what
he's like.
He's in the car?
Lily's taking
a nap.
Lily's here?
Come here,
let me look at you.
Oh, Sean.
How did this happen?
Glad you're
here mom.
Yeah, well, I would
have been here sooner,
it's just Gerry's
family you know,
he hadn't seen
them in years,
and Lily was
so excited so...
Oh, I brought
some photos.
Most of these probably
wouldn't interest you, but...
Here's one of Lily.
Isn't that cute?
She looks older.
Her face.
I want to see her.
I wanted that for you,
I really did.
But - jail's no place
for a little girl.
So that's
why he came?
To keep away
the bad seed?
- No one sees you like that.
- Everyone sees me like that.
You're telling me he hasn't
been saying I told you so?
He hasn't.
Maybe he didn't
have to.
I told myself I wasn't
going to get upset so...
So, think that maybe when I
get out I can come and stay,
you know,
take Lily to the park...
I don't think that's
such a good idea, Sean.
I just think it's important
you spend some time
with your father,
at this point in your life.
It's hard
for everyone.
Yeah, I can
see that.
Yeah?
Columbine -- ball!
Come on, Columbine,
get the ball.
Oh wow.
I mean, they clowing
you for real man.
Where you going,
Columbine?
To my cell,
to read.
I ain't done
with you!
Come on back,
bitch!
Co-lum-bine.
Come on buddy you're letting
it get away from you.
Get the ball. Come on.
Attaboy.
Here you go, Kev.
Go get it.
Go ahead Lassie.
Oh what a
fucking cunt.
Now what am I supposed
to do with this?
Huh?
Rain cheque,
boys.
Big brother's
watching.
He ownes you G.
You got lucky,
Columbine.
Barry Johns.
Hi, it's
Sean Randall...
from Waterville.
Sean!
Good news.
Did your dad
tell you?
We got a
trial date.
Really, when?
Twenty first.
That's in
two weeks.
Well, it could've been a
hell of a lot longer, Sean.
They wanted to push it
until the new year.
It's just..
I just don't know if
I can last that long.
You know,
it's like you said:
kids like me aren't
safe here.
There's still the other
option we discussed.
So, if I can hold on
for two weeks,
you're saying
I can get out?
Well, first we view
the Crown's case.
We get to see the evidence
they've compiled against you.
It's called
disclosure.
If you still decide
you want to proceed,
you'll get moved to
the courthouse,
to a holding cell.
And then we
go to trial.
And I can't move now,
since I know that's what
I want to do?
That's not
how it works.
If you insist on
going to trial,
you're just going
to have to
find a way to
hang in there.
Let him eat.
Everyone deserves
a last supper.
We're short.
Missing a knife.
Seems like one
of you thought
you'd walk
out of here
with a little
souvenir.
You were wrong.
We have dedicated staff
who take their jobs
very seriously.
They know how serious
putting a weapon into
the hands of a violent
teenager can be.
Now, we can do this the
easy way or we can do it
the hard way.
This is no joke, boys.
We will search each and every
one of you if we have to --
Thanks for choosing
the easy way, Sean.
See you in two weeks.
A fresh face.
This way.
Might want to think twice
before jerking off in here.
What if I have to
go to the washroom?
Go up to the window.
That's how we know you're
about to piss yourself.
Like that guy?
Him?
No, he's just a
pain in the ass.
I can't sleep.
You know,
the lights --
they're brighter
or something.
The sound, the buzzing,
do you hear it?
It's driving me crazy.
Just go back to bed.
Try to relax.
Don't make me call
the Goon Squad.
Sean Randall?
Where are
we going?
Has it been
two weeks?
This way, son.
Thanks, Don.
Fuck!
Are you okay?
Is that the
evidence?
It's ninety percent
of their case.
Look I know it's hard,
it gets a lot worse
when it goes
to trial.
What do you
mean when?
Isn't that why
you're here?
To take me to court?
That's what we thought
too until this morning.
The trial's been
postponed, Sean.
The computer forensic
experts need more time.
How much time?
Could be a
couple months.
Procedure is long.
Life is short.
I've been trying to tell
you that from the start.
I know pleading guilty is
against your principles,
and I respect you for that,
but principles will not
end this vicious cycle
of abuse you're in.
What do
you say we
put  an end
to all this?
Your honour,
at this time my client
would like to enter
a plea of guilty.
Mr. Randall,
do you understand
that you are
pleading guilty
to planning an attack
on twenty-seven people
in this town?
Yes.
Please speak into the
microphone, Mr. Randall.
Yes.
Do you understand that you're
making this guilty plea
of your own free will,
and that no one in any way
is coercing you to make
this statement today.
Yes that's right.
Is there anything else
you wish to say?
No, sir. Just I'm
sorry, I guess.
Sorry I guess?
Mr. Randall,
sorry I guess doesn't
restore the damage you've
caused this community
or diminish the impact
on the lives of those
you've threatened.
Your honour, please,
my client may not be
particularly eloquent,
but he is deeply remorseful
and sorry for
what he's done.
Mr. Randall,
is that true?
Yes, sir,
that's true.
I'm granting an
order of release
with conditions.
Mr. Randall.
Due to the violent and
disturbing nature of your
intended crimes you are
prohibited from attending
any school within
district thirteen.
Not only can you not attend,
you cannot step foot
on school property.
You are also prohibited
from communicating,
directly or indirectly,
with any victim,
witness, or other person
identified in the
no contact order.
That's twenty-seven
people, Mr. Randall.
Twenty-seven people who
don't want to see your
face ever again.
So, I didn't know what
to do with your room.
I just closed the door...
left it.
I didn't know
how you'd feel.
It feels weird...
like someone else's room.
Maybe it is.
I mean,
maybe you changed.
I talked with Barry.
He said that you can have
your computer and all your
stuff back,
just a couple of
formalities to
go through.
What about
your guns?
I don't get
those back.
Part of
the deal.
what deal?
The deal to
get you out.
Sean, um, I was
thinking, you know,
with the school ban
in effect and everything,
that maybe you want to come
work with me at the rink,
help out some,
earn yourself a
bit of cash.
How's that
supposed to work?
The whole hockey team
is on that list.
I checked with Barry.
He said that as long as you're
upstairs when they're on the ice
it's no problem.
They have a schedule,
you have a schedule.
I don't know.
Can I think about it?
Yeah,
absolutely!
No hurry,
take your time.
I'll leave you
to settle in.
Can I get you a
sandwich or something?
I got some of that
thinly-shaved
turkey breast
you like.
Yeah, that sounds
great, thanks.
I'm glad you're
home, Sean.
Sandwich then.
Hey.
Pittsburgh's playing,
you want to watch?
I'm reading.
No pressure.
Thought I'd
mention it.
Two dollars each?
Thanks.
Look at you.
Dirt under your
fingernails.
That reminds me.
First pay cheque.
Aren't you going
to open it?
Right.
Probably know how much
is in there anyway.
Don't forget,
there's deductions.
I guess I should start
saving for plastic surgery.
What are you
talking about?
People think I'm
a psycho, dad.
No, they don't!
Everybody I talk to
knows it's bullshit.
You should've seen them
gawking at me at the mall.
You just like
thinking that way.
I saw Deanna.
Didn't go up to her,
just saw her.
I should
hope not.
I don't know.
I guess I wanted to.
Give her a chance
to explain herself.
When are you going to realize
she's not your friend, Sean.
Never was.
I heard Jimmy Cooke's
selling his wife's Dodge.
Probably let it go
for fifteen hundred.
Consider going in on it
with you if you want.
Oh, come on,
Talbot!
How do you
miss that?
When did my
stuff get here?
I don't know,
earlier sometime.
My car got
vandalized.
The net was
wide open!
What did you say?
My car got
vandalized.
What?
What happened?
What did you do?
Nothing -- except plan
a school massacre.
"Get your fucking hand off me,
you cocksucker..."
"Are you recording me?"
"Sean!"
Hi.
You look different.
That's kind of
the general idea.
How are you?
Alright.
Just working now,
just got my own car.
Yeah,
that's cool.
How about you?
How long have you
been working here?
Just like
a month.
It was my
dad's idea.
He knows the owner,
so that's how he
keeps tabs on me.
Anyway, I just -
wanted to say
I was sorry.
I didn't mean
to scare you.
I feel sick to my stomach
about what happened.
I don't talk to
Cory anymore.
Not at all.
You know the cops came
to my house and told me
that you had a plan?
I didn't
have a plan.
It was just
a story.
A story of revenge?
Where do you
want to go?
Mexico.
I should have
said something.
My parents are
impossible to talk to.
But I should have
said something.
I don't blame you for
not trusting me.
When did you get
the nose ring?
It's a nose stud.
Nose stud.
I like it.
So I was going
to head to Johnny's,
half price burgers.
You want to come?
Actually there was
something else I was
thinking about doing,
but thanks.
Okay.
Next week then.
Hi.
Your dad gave
you his Lexus?
Told him I
needed tampons.
Works every time.
No, you can leave
your boots on.
Unless you don't want
them to get dirty.
Um, the bathroom --
up and around the corner,
if you want to use it.
Okay.
Do you want to hang out
here or in my room?
Sure.
Which one?
We can go to
your room.
Okay, it's just here.
Wow, the walls
are so bare.
Yeah, it's part of
my new look.
Or non-look.
Are those
live maggots?
Yes.
I like the way
you look.
I feel like I
can see you.
You can
actually read?
Yes, well, it's not
exactly Dostoevsky.
Did you get
that in jail?
Yeah.
I feel really bad.
Don't.
I kind of like it.
It adds character.
Is that
your dad?
Yeah, just wait here.
There's a Lexus
in the driveway.
Yeah, that's...
Deanna's here.
Oh no, no,
she's not!
She's leaving!
It's not
a big deal.
You'll be arrested.
I won't be...
I won't be arrested.
Is that true?
You could
be arrested?
She doesn't know?
Know what?
You going to
tell her?
There's a restraining
order and you're on it.
Hey!
Time to head up!
Hey, look
who it is.
Careful,
he's got a weapon.
So like I'm
confused man
did you want
to fuck her
or did you want
to kill her?
Fuck her then
kill her?
Kill her then
fuck her?
What did you
want to do?
Sean!
What did you
want to do man?
- What are you doing?
- I'm working!
- Hey, hey.
- Sorry.
Sean -- you got to go.
We got to go.
Get your fucking
hands off me!
Go!
Sean!
What's going on?
I just wanted
to see you.
You know, I was
thinking about you.
You can't
be here.
Someone sees you and
they'll call the police.
I got into a fight
with my dad.
I think
I hit him.
I'm pretty sure
Are you okay?
No.
We can't talk here.
Try me later on Skype,
but wait until after eleven,
just give my parents a
chance to fall asleep, okay?
SEAN! SEAN!
OPEN THE FUCKING
DOOR, SEAN!
Get out of my way.
What, you gonna
hit me again?
That was an
accident.
What the fuck?
You knew the rules.
Why can't you
just lay low?
I can't be you.
So you want to go
back to jail?
I AM IN JAIL!
DON'T YOU
FUCKING SEE IT?
Fine, get the
fuck out.
Fuck!
How was I
supposed to know
it was her dad
on the phone?
Mr. Johns.
Thanks for coming on
such short notice.
So, here's
the deal.
The parents are filing
harassment charges.
They can
do that?
They basically
entrapped him.
It's still a breach
of probation, Ricky,
and for that reason
they see Sean as a threat.
You were
reckless, Sean.
You knew the conditions
of your release -
stay away from the
people on that list.
How hard is that?
Look, he likes
this girl,
and this girl
likes him.
It's the parents
that are threatened.
Sure, it's not like he bought
their daughter flowers
and took her
to the prom.
He had her in
his revenge plan.
He didn't have
a revenge plan.
Sure, well,
they think he did.
So what do
we do now?
Same as
before, Ricky.
He goes in,
says he's sorry,
it won't happen again,
lesson learned.
At most he's going
to get house arrest,
three months.
I didn't harass her.
Then take it to trial,
put her on the stand.
I'm sure she'll really
swoon over you then.
They want to
send you back.
Okay.
You look good.
Hey, don't worry,
we're going to
get you out
of this.
Don't look at
them, Sean.
All rise.
The Eastport Provincial
court is now in session.
The honorable Judge Campbell
presiding.
Thank you,
you may sit.
Mr. Johns?
Your honour,
at this point my client
would like to enter a plea
of guilty to the one count.
And does this satisfy the Crown,
Miss Harris?
The Crown
is satisfied.
Mr. Randall,
please step forward.
State your full name
for the record.
Sean Richard Randall.
Sean Richard Randall,
do you understand that
you're pleading guilty to the
charge of harassment,
and that this guilty
plea is being entered of
your own free will?
Yes, I understand
what you're saying.
Listen -- this isn't
about what I say.
We want to hear how you
feel about your actions.
You mean going
up to Deanna?
Going up to her,
emailing her,
following her home from school,
harassing her at work...
Mr. Randall?
We're waiting.
Well, um...
it started
when I saw her
working at
the mall,
and I just wanted
to apologize
for everything.
Look at me,
Mr. Randall.
So you wanted to
make things right?
By apologizing?
Yes, that's
right.
You wanted to apologize
for planning to kill her
and her friends?
Tell me,
Mr. Randall,
how does one go about
apologizing for such a thing?
That's not why I
was apologizing.
Then why were
you apologizing?
Because I didn't want
her to think she
had to be
afraid of me.
I wasn't planning
to kill her.
anything.
Mr. Johns,
I think you should
take a moment with
your client.
He seems to be confused as to
exactly why we're here.
What are
you doing?
Telling the truth.
Do you want to
go back inside
with those animals?
He's embarrassing
himself, Ricky.
Let him speak,
Barry.
Your honour, I tried
to make it clear,
but my client wishes
to speak on his own behalf.
Fine.
Sit down.
Mr. Randall,
you realize you are
speaking against
your lawyer's advice?
Yes.
Are you his
guardian?
Yeah, that's right,
I'm his dad.
Do you want him to proceed
against counsel's advice?
Yes I do.
He's a good kid,
he didn't mean to do--
It's okay,
It's okay.
You can sit.
Mr. Randall,
do you understand
exactly why you're
here today?
Yes, I'm being charged
with harassment.
Yes, you're charged
with harassing a person
you we're ordered to
stay away from.
What we are asking
here today is:
do you plead guilty to
this charge -- yes or no?
No, I do not.
Not guilty.
I was angry.
I wrote things down.
Stupid, but
not dangerous.
So what suited you yesterday
doesn't suit you today?
We have a name for
that here, Mr. Randall.
It's called perjury.
Is that what
you're saying?
That you
perjured yourself?
I'm saying I lied.
If that's perjury
then yes.
You leave me no choice,
Mr. Randall.
This court is all about the
consequences of your actions
and the implications
to this community.
So I'm going to remove you from
this community for three months.
The next time I see you --
make sure you have a lawyer.
Got you boys
a present.
Holy fuck!
Whoa, Columbine!
Did you miss us?
Check out the hairdo.
Hey, Trevor?
Where's Trevor.
Trevor don't do
Christmas, man.
What do you mean
he don't do Christmas?
Where is he?
Yo Trevor, get your
ass out here man,
you gotta see this.
Well I can't believe
he came back though.
He know's he's gonna
get killed right?
I wonder what's going on
in the world today.
Looks like the dollar's
still gaining...
Sidney Crosby's out
with concussion...
Oh, here's something:
"Eastport teen
jailed for perjury."
Do you know about this?
Purge-re?
What the fuck
is that?
It means I lied
in court.
It means Columbine
don't want to be
Columbine no more.
Only he is Columbine
so they won't let him
not be Columbine.
Ain't that right,
Columbine?
Why's it matter?
You're in jail,
I'm in jail.
We've all
done stuff.
Not me,
I'm innocent.
You can call me Columbine
all you want.
I know who I am.
You know
you're dead?
Fuck this.
What the fuck, man?
Put it back.
Game's shit, bro.
It's a fuckin'
blowout.
Oh, shit yo --
I know this.
Yeah, I used to watch this
at my grandma's every year.
Man, does this look
like your grandma's?
Yeah man,
this is a classic
It's about this fella,
he claims to be the real
Santa Claus and shit.
Fuck, Marcel man,
no one wants to watch
a fuckin' black and white
movie from the depression -
Who's fucking go?
Shut up, Tyrell,
I'm trying to listen.
"She's a little confused."
"Would you tell her that you're
not really Santa Claus?"
"That there's actually
no such person?"
"I'm sorry to disagree with you,
Mrs. Walker,
but not only
is there such a person,
but here I am
to prove it."
Whose fucking go?
Go Ray!
- Slow ass motherfucker.
- "I want you to tell her the truth."
- "What is your name?"
- "Kris Kringle."
"I'll bet you're in
the first grade."
"Second."
"I mean your
real name."
"That is my
real name --"
"Second grade,
good gracious."
"It's a progressive school."
"Ohhh, progressive school"
Fuck -- can somebody
go already?
Chill out.
"Where did you get
such a lovely outfit?"
Get up!
Open the door.
Lucas, open up,
it's me!
Get the fuck
out of my way!
Whoa, shit yo!
Hey you look out
for my name man.
You know
what it is.
"To Seen."
What the fuck?
Man, that's
Columbine.
Okay.
Yo, Seen --
Merry Christmas.
My name's Sean.
Yeah alright.
Now tell me why I got
a wallet in a prison.
What money do I got?
Muthafuck!
I mean damn.
Columbine got
an iPhone 4.
Check this out --
it's still in its
plastic and everything.
Holy Shit.
What I would do
with an iPhone4.
I hear they got like a
camera... Internet...
Alright man,
what you get?
A jumpsuit,
but I didn't find it funny.
Hey yo you guys,
check this out right here.
What do you get if you cross
Santa Claus with a duck?
Your momma?
A Christmas Quacker.
Yo, Trev,
you ain't gonna pull at
your cracker?
Hey yo,
put on your hat.
Fuck that.
Come on Trev,
we all got ours on.
Trade hats with me,
Columbine.
I got your color.
You think you're
all tough now?
Cause you got
by my bitch?
Should have killed him,
weak punk ass faggot.
I guess killing's
not my thing.
Not here, Trev.
There, can we
fucking eat now?
What are you
so afraid of?
It's just a hat.
You're gonna kill me
because of a hat?
I want to kill you
because you're a faggot.
Is that why you
killed the old man?
Because he was
a faggot?
Or was it because he
thought you were?
FUCK YOU!
I'LL FUCKING KILL YOU!
I SWEAR TO GOD!
I'LL FUCKING
KILL YOU!
Let me go!
Fucking let me go!
Get your fucking
hands off me!
What the fuck, man!
Get your fucking
hands off me!
OPEN THE DOOR!
Stand down!
D.U. code 11.
Sit down!
Back away and
stand down!
Back down.
Code 11.
D.U. Code 11.
Code 21.
D.U. Code 21.
Hey, I just want to
go to sleep, huh.
Hey!
HEY!
AHHH!
AHHHHH!
The fuck!
Ah!
Is he okay?
Fuck!
Stop it! It was just
a glass of water.
Sit the fuck down.
What the fuck's
wrong with you?
You didn't have
to do that.
I'll kill you, man.
I'll fucking
kill you!
I just want to
fucking eat.
D.U. Code 21.
I just want to
fucking eat!
HEY!
Oh my god!
Fuck!
Keep moving.
Weirdly the food tastes
better in here,
don't you think?
Randall.
Fly away little bird.
What about Trevor?
We came in at
the same time.
He ain't ready.
If he's not ready,
I'm not ready.
It was self defense.
He had this way of
locking the doors.
Like a cop.
I just wanted out.
You can have it.
I don't want it.
How was my dad
in the car?
I learned a lot about
Sidney Crosby.
He's a nice guy --
Sidney Crosby?
Your dad.
You're lucky
to have him.
What about
your dad?
He know
you're here?
No.
I couldn't
breathe anymore.
It was either move out
or slit my wrists.
Well, I'm glad you
chose to move out.
Do you have a
marker or a pen?
Yeah, I have a
ball point?
Yeah thanks.
I hate seeing you
like this.
Your whole
face is just --
It's okay.
It's only two
more months.
You know --
he's not going to want
us to be together.
He's not going
to make it easy.
Oh, that's okay.
Easy's not really
my thing.