Look like you're enjoying it!
What's the matter with you?
Look more excited,
That's good,
Zoom in on her face,
I ll try from under the table,
Good,
Face the camera,
Looking good,
Good,
What's the matter?
This position is wearing me out,
- Wait a second,
- Hurry it up!
My legs are numb.
Change to another position,
- Try it from behind.
- You come closer,
I can t do This anymore,
What the hell?
What are you doing?
What s the matter with you today?
I feel like I m going to...
get morning sickness again.
Let Meiko take a break,
If you don't feel good, we
can replace you.
Just hang on for a bit longer,
I can t do it anymore,
Get off of me!
I really can t do it any more today,
You give up too easily,
Let s take a break,
Right,
Everyone take 5.
I want to go, I just want to leave,
Where to?
Anywhere, anywhere but here,
I am sick of This,
Don't say that.
You can't say that,
We re almost done shooting,
We still have hours till we re finished.
We re almost done,
My family doesn't want
me to do This any more.
Why do they care?
I m like a whore. They're upset
about What I ve done with my life,
What are you talking about?
It's your life, not theirs.
Don t listen to them,
I m not, This is my choice,
Quit your nagging,
Then quit?
Who s stopping you?
You always think things are so simple,
It s annoying,
So What do you want?
I've given you anything you've wanted.
And now you give me This?
There's many girls who d kill
to be in your shoes,
You have to
treasure What you have,
You just have to push yourself,
You are already famous in Japan,
You ll be even more famous
if you give it some time.
And You ll earn so much money,
you won t know What to do with it,
But I've been doing
these movies for so long,
Women get tired too,
I'm afraid I ll Hurt the
baby if I keep working.
You think fucking will Hurt the little guy
in there?
Thanks for getting Her knocked her up.
THANKS FOR WATCHING OUT!
How can a woman live
if she has a miscarriage?
You don't get it,
Meiko,,,
There's no use,
You don't know anything!
Just let me do the talking, alright?
Here s What it is, 100,000 yen to stay,
If you don't want to do it, How
much money would change your mind,
No more movies,
I just want to have my baby,
God kill me now,
Today was my Last scene,
FUCKKKKKKKKKKK!!!!
Gimme that, you're pregnant!
- Is that everything?
- What the fuck do you think?
You know,,,
Life is easy for a woman,,,
you have a kid, and you take it
easy at home for all your days,
What are you talking about?
Is that all you think we do?
When are you going to marry
your co-star?
Don't give Her any ideas,
I've already lost one actor,
You guys are something else,
This shit is heavy,
There we go.
Please wait in the lobby for your bill,
Okay,
Thanks,
Hello,
Bye,
It s so hot,
Very hot,
Seeing your beautiful face,
You just made my day
100 /% better,
I hope l see you soon,
DENTAL CLINIC
I'm a genius.
Good day,
I think I left something.
Go ahead,
You re so nice.
Excuse me, I forgot to get something,
Sorry,
Ready,
Action,
Again,
Okay,
Where to next?
The Zoo,
Just do one more movie,,.
Did you hear me?
Yes,
This will be the Last one, I promise.
One more, that s it,
I ll Let you go afterwards.
Totally off the hook,
I'm serious,
No,
There s no time to waste,
Don't hesitate,
You can go out with a bang,
You are one of the best stars
I ve ever seen,
You can't change my,.,
Just listen!
You've got to help me
out This time,
Watch it.
I Helped you out When you were
nothing,
You had nowhere to even live,
Say something,
Don t you have any loyalty?
Just Help me out with one more movie.
And that's it,
I don't want to do one more,
You won't change my mind,
You bitch,
Stop it,
I am serious,
Don't you trust me?
Trust me,
Have I ever lied to you,
as long as I ve known you?
This film will be the best you've
ever made,
Share your beauty with the others out there.
Show yourself.
Let everyone feel the sweetness of sex.
You got it?
What're you thinking?
It sounds like a good idea, but.,,
l don't want to do it,
What are you talking about?
Listen here,
Will you at least think about it?
For me?
Do it again.
Stop recording.
Good,
Done!
Again,
Bastard,
That's pretty amazing
stuff they do over there,
What s there to see?
It's so boring,
We are so pathetic,,,
working like a couple of dogs,
How does it sound?
Good,
Here.
Let me try This,
Take This,
Working in here is busier than in an office,
No,
Hold still.
Don't move,
That girl sounds good doesn't she?
Here,
This here is What l recorded of that girl,
I ve never met anyone like her,
I left my recorder in there,
and This is What I got,
This recording is pure gold,
I ll sell it at 6,000 yen a piece.
We ll be rich,
Filthy rich,
What?
It hurts, It hurts.
What does that sound like to you?
You think she d complain about Having
a kid?
She sounds perfect,
Maybe I ll ask Her to work
for us,
Listen to This,
It hurts so much.
What do you want me to do?
That's as wide as it gets.
You are despicable.
I can't believe you're doing This,
This is good,
Too good,
I got to go find her.
There's no time,
I got work to do.
I LL see you,
You're leaving so soon?
Please, do It slower.
You're hurting me,
Please be more gentle,
Here, take This,
Try harder next time,
Sorry,
Excuse me,
It s so hot,
Yes,
You come here often?
Back for some more fun?
No, not at all,
You have tooth ache?
Well, have you?
Of course - why else would I be here?
Everyone here does,
You know,,, I m a movie director,
A Movie director!
What kind of films
have you made?
I ve done quite a few, they re,.,
Sex films,
Really?
I only give girls that I think are
special a shot at it,
Did you come back in here,
to recruit me?
You re a smart one.
That s exactly why I came back in here today,
I'd like to give you a job working
on screen.
I think you Have a lot of potential,
and can make a lot of money,
And from What I Heard the other day,
I think you're exactly What we want,
You could be filthy rich,
Okay,
Come meet me at the bridge When
you're done,
I can explain all the details
to you about the job,
I LL see you,
Excuse me,
Finally l found another girl,
I have nothing to worry about anymore.
I Haven't played around
for such a long time.
It s been almost 30 years by now,
I ve been very healthy despite it,
You have to exercise everyday,
You can't play by yourself,
Madam.
I almost thought you wouldn't
show up,
I won't take up too much of your time,
You look upset, Are you okay?
I m just a bit worried, that's all,
I've never done anything
like This,
I m sorry, but This is all new to me,
Being filmed while having sex,,.
I can t even imagine What it s like,,,
It seems almost like being
a prostitute, I'm not into things like that,
Honey, you ve got nothing to worry about,
No way,
It s not like being a prostitute,
You re going to love this job,
No way,
Come on, come with me,
Go find somebody else,
I changed my mind,
It s really not that big of a deal,
You'll enjoy it, Madam.
I promise you, it ll be great,
I am serious,
I wouldn't lie to you, I promise,
Just listen to This, okay?
Listen,
Nothing that big has ever
been in my mouth.
That s my voice,
I recorded This at the dentist's office,
You ve gone too far!
Oh yes!
Yes!
Don't be so loud.
I have to get out of here!
Look, just calm down.
Get back in here,
Madam, Madam!
Let me go, I want out,
Don't be like that!
I m not going to Let you fall,
Don't be so emotional,
Hey, stop that!
You ll get Hurt!
Your head will splat all over the place,
It s just a tape,
Why did you have to play that here?
Jesus Christ!
Please, get rid of the tape.
I ll do anything,
Okay,
I will,
But, only if you promise
to talk with,,,
our cameraman,
Okay,
No, no.
No! It hurts!
So here we are, I m sorry
about the tape.
Shooting a film.,,
is like shooting a photo,
Don't be shy,
Anything you need, I ll get it for you, Madam.
Here,
Whatever you need, to make
you comfortable, I can Help,
Hello,
Do you know who he is?
Does he look like an honest man?
He's the cameraman I talked about,
Does he look like a weirdo?
He's one of the best in the business.
And the nicest man You ll ever meet,
He's serious,
He s an excellent cameraman,
This way Please,
We shot one of our movies here,
You shouldn't worry
about What other people think of you.
This is funny,
What are you thinking about?
Could you do me a favor?
Can you leave for a second?
l need to talk privately,
Okay,
I know What you re thinking now,
What should l do?
I'm so confused,
I can give you a lot of money,
Yes, but it's still not worth it to me.
Do you think that's all I'm worth?
I understand.,,
you re worth a lot more,
Madam we all Have
to make sacrifices,
Please, let s work together,
I have to talk to my boss.
Do you have anything to say?
Please tell me What you think,
A beauty like you is really rare
It'd be a shame to say no,
but I can't force you,
I ll go tell them you said no, okay?
I can't do This.
I m sorry, but I just can't,
You'll have to shoot
your movie without me.
Where are you going?
Home,
Madam.
What s going on?
Nothing, You going back home?
You lose another one?
What do you know?
She's new.
She s timid, so What?
You have to be careful,
You want to get that girl
for your movie?
Don t you think I know that?
She was my only hope,
I see,
What happened?
She looked very shy anyway,
It gets me excited just talking about her.
She s like no other,
She makes me crazy,
She s just so wonderful,
Wait a minute, What the hell am I doing?,,,
I got to go get her, I need her,
I couldn't go on not knowing
What Could ve been.
Careful,
Faster man, go get her!
I can't Let her get away!
I Will see you later
and I LL have her,
No, Please,
What's going on In there?
I m trying not to hurt the baby,
I'm almost done,
Bastard!
The both of you will fuck alone,
but not on camera, huh?!
- Don't hit him.
- Get off of me!
No!
What is This?
Why would you want to kill yourself?
Here you are,
Madam, you've been riding in Here
for more then an hour,
I know.
Is everything alright?
I just really like it,
- I see,
- Madam,
Come on in,
Why are you here?
Are you the one who,,,
saved me?
The money you offered me was so
awfully low,
It made me feel worthless, I wanted to die,
How much do you want?
Tell me What you want?
Whatever you want, you got it,
I m not going to lose you,
Okay, no more messing around,
Let me tell you a story,
My wife passed away a few years ago.
I ve been living alone all by myself,
Really?
Do you know How Hard it's been,
losing someone that you love?
I couldn t imagine,
Killing yourself hurts other people,
It was one of the most terrible things
that s happened to me,
It s so awful,
I m sorry,
Take This,
It must be awful to lose someone
you loved so much,
Did you consider remarrying?
I didn't want to hurt my daughter,
So I never tried to find another woman,
But seeing you,,,
makes me want to remarry,
I've never met someone else
so beautiful to me,
I Hope you understand where
I'm going with This,
I understand What you mean,
Thank you,
I'm sorry but we just met.
How Could we get married?
How?
I ll give you a good life,,,
Don't you worry,
Please believe What I say,
Will you be with me?
What about your daughter?
I think she'll like you,
You really think so?
I ll think it over; you did save
my life after all,
Go straight ahead,
Madam, Madam!
I don't Have any money
for the taxi,
Don't worry, I got it,
Still going straight?
Yes, Please,
We are the same kind of people,
We're both stubborn,
Is that What you think?
Do they know What you do?
Of course they do, they've seen
my films before,
Are you ready to watch one?
You can see if you still want to do it,
You're already a grown woman.
Why are you so shy?
I want to watch it so you
think differently of me,
Alright,
just give me a sec, okay?
Everything in the film is staged.
It s not real,
It's all fake,
Don't take it seriously.
They're acting, remember,
I hope you enjoy it.
Okay, let s begin,
Were those girls kissing?
That sure looks real to me,
This kind of thing shouldn't be shown,
I am not watching it,
I can t watch This,
Turn it off,
I m leaving,
It s okay, don t worry,
Take a look,
No,
Please, for me.
It's very natural.
2 people giving in to desire,
Is it?
Yes, it is,
It s no big deal,
Don t be like that,
Other women don't think it's a big deal.
Why should you?
Really?
You don t have to be shy.
You gotta knock that off, and
grow up a little,
It s like having a delicious meal,
That can't be described in words,
It s like a great meal,
Really?
It s nothing, no big deal,
Just express What you feel inside.
That s all I ask of you.
You want me to?
You have to keep your
interest for such great things,
This is a part of life,
Something that has to be experienced,
Really?
It's so good. Why do you
want to avoid it?
Really?
Please don't be so shy,
This is interesting.
And educational,
What?
Please, help me,
I saved your life, Please
do This for me,
No,
You can t run away from,,.
What you have to experience,
No,
Come on,
Keep rubbing it, keep it up,
Please,
Come on,
You'll love This,
Don't be shy,
Just give in already,
I really like you,
No,
Please,
Come on,
Wait,
Give me a minute,
You re so beautiful.
So beautiful,
You ll get used to making
love every night, right?
A beautiful body,,,
A soft and tender body,
You are so charming,
I've never seen a body like yours,
This is wonderful,
Attractive breasts,
Nice stomach,
Let me see that pussy of yours,
Just beautiful,
Finally I have my chance,
I ve been dreaming about
What This would feel like,
Do you like it?
Wonderful,
Marvelous.
Everything is just perfect.
All of it is mine,
Get off of me!
Stop it!
No!
Let me go!
No, Let me go!
Quit trying to resist,
Listen to me,,,
I love you!
Please, Help me!
What now?
Don't you feel better?
I ll make you feel better,
Only I can do that,
Only I can give you,,.
What you need,
I ll take you higher today,
Get a close-up,
Zoom out.
This woman is overcome with ecstasy,
You can stop shooting,
It feels so good,
You bastard!
I hate you!
Calm down,
What position do you want to try next?
What are you talking about?
Are you going to sell This?
Yes,
For retail,
No, no!
Stop it!
How can you earn money,,.
without making a little sacrifice?
Women always think like This,
Let me go!
It's too late for you to go now.
We already filmed it,
Is that so?
You are so naive,
You can't be serious?
What do you want?
Get the fuck up,
lf you want to get married, you
have to do This,
Do you understand, bitch?
Understand?
I see,
It feels so good,
You see,,,
It s good isn't it,
Are we getting married now?
Of course.
Will you marry me?
I do.
ALL This walking is making me tired,
What?
We're almost there,
So if I shoot This scene with
This other man, we can get married?
I m kinda worried abo,,,
Oh my god!
Are you alright?
I got you, I got you,
Are you okay?
He's a nice guy; he won t hurt you,
After you sleep with him we'll be rich,
and we'll live happy ever after,
Okay?
Alright,
I still feel so nervous about
sleeping with him,
I don't know if I can do it,
Don't worry,
This is the only time You ll have to do it,
No,
Do it again,
Action,
Take it off slower,
Let s take a break,
Alright, are you ready?
Let's get started,
Do I really have to do This?
Don't worry, it'll be over soon.
And We ll  be rich,
But, I don t want to do it,
Come on, Let's go,
Let s start with you eating her out.
Get the lights ready,
I want you to show some
expression as he s pleasuring you,
Right,
Honey, don't look over at me,
Close your eyes, and tilt your head,
Act like you re enjoying This,
Get into it,
That s right.
It feels so good,
Get a table shot,
Good,
Looks like she likes it.
Make them stop,
Just relax,
That s my fianc !
Don't shoot anymore,
Move over that way, away from me.
Here.
Show the camera how I make you feel,
Why don t you join in with them?
You bastard,
Shut up, You ll ruin the shot!
Keep your mouth shut,
Stop it, make them stop!
Just keep it down.
Why are you doing This?
Make them stop, goddamn it!
Keep it up,
Your face looks good,
Please - Please make them stop,
Keep going! Harder,
Good, very good,
Keep going,
I m going to cum inside you,
Alright, that s enough!
Get the fuck off of her!
You fucking bastard!
What are you doing?
You fucked up the scene,
Sorry, it was feeling so good,
How could you do This to me?
Did you forget about me?
Honey, I'm sorry,
Sorry,
I ll never forgive you for This,
Get lost!
Hey, watch out!
Watch out!
Get the hell out of here!
You bastard, she s just a whore.
What are you doing?
I love her,
I don't know What to say,
Honey,,,
can we get married now?