Blame it on Fidel
Why isn't she doing anything?
She doesn't speak French.
Her name is Pilar.
She is Spanish.
What's going on here?
Yes?
I'm teaching them
to cut fruit properly,
but they're not very gifted.
You're such a lady!
Children, you may leave the table.
Isabelle, forget about them.
Hurry up and make me
some grandchildren!
- There's no rush.
- Of course.
You should go kiss your grandpa.
He'd love that.
Isabelle, you look lovely!
You'll see.
You will have your own room.
Would you like to go swimming?
You could learn how to play music.
We'll go see clowns at the circus.
Do you like the circus?
What else do you like?
You'll see that in no time
you'll be speaking French.
That comes easy to you.
Cat!
François, don't!
You'll get me dirty!
Leave me alone!
Stop following me around!
Anna, be careful,
or you'll tear that veil!
Give it back to Isabelle.
Why is Dad always
with Pilar and her mom?
Don't bother them.
Life is tough
for your aunt and your cousin.
Give me a hand.
Was your bridal veil as long?
I had none.
We got married at City Hall.
You said there was a party there!
Just my parents, Mathieu,
and some cousins.
That's all?
It didn't matter to us.
Mathieu and Isabelle love festivities.
And it pleases your grandparents.
This is their place now.
They'll live with Granny and Grandpa?
Lucky them!
Mom, doesn't Isabelle
look like a princess?
You're not playing
with the other kids?
No. All they do is run.
If you stay here, I'll tickle you.
Tickle, tickle!
Stop!
Will Pilar and her mom
go back to Spain?
Not right now.
They're never going home?
There are laws in Spain
against people like Marga or Quino.
I'll explain some other time.
But you're a lawyer!
You can help them go home!
It's too complicated now.
In Spain, you can't do as you please.
Where will they go?
To our place in Paris.
In our home?
Until they find a place, yes.
Will that take long?
What is it, my princess?
They should just go home.
Anna.
Your uncle Quino died.
I had to smuggle them out.
I can't send them back there.
We have to take care of them.
If François was in danger,
wouldn't you help him?
Anna.
Don't pretend you don't understand!
She's my sister,
and in these past 10 years,
I never helped her.
I did nothing!
So we must all take care
of her and Pilar!
You may open your notebooks.
What did you get?
- And you?
- 9 out of 10!
Good morning,
Sister Anne-Marie!
See you later,
Sister Genevieve!
Take your Bible study notebook, girls.
Anna, homework time!
Why leave?
You can live here!
There's room for everyone!
I don't know if I can.
I don't know
what I am going to do.
I fought for 15 years.
15 years of my life.
Always with Quino.
Now I have nothing.
You could fight from here.
And what about your daughter?
You must think
of your daughter now.
This life isn't for me.
A family, a house, a job.
That's your choice.
I can't live that way.
But thanks, anyway.
- Thank you for...
- What are you doing?
Do your homework!
It will be time for your bath soon!
François, stop splashing me!
- Hi, kids.
- Hi, Mom.
Mom, I got 9 out of 10 on my essay!
In Bible study,
we did Genesis, my favorite!
Your favorite what?
Story. How the world began.
You only like stories
about princesses.
Get up, François!
Mom, why has Dad quit his job?
I hope you didn't bother him.
I said to leave him alone.
He needs to think.
So, are you going to ask me?
It's the 25th of the month.
Your magazine!
I can't find Mom's article!
Anna, this is not the time!
Put it away!
Tell us about your essay.
It was about our vacation
in Bordeaux.
I wrote about Isabelle
and Mathieu's wedding.
But I didn't write about Uncle Quino.
I didn't know what to say.
You did well.
Some things are secret.
Why?
Like having Communists in the family.
- What?
- Communists!
The barbudos!
I had to leave Cuba because of Fidel
and the Communists.
They took everything!
My house, my land, everything!
Damn them!
They almost caused a nuclear war!
A nuclear war?
Listen, Anna!
I hope your aunt leaves!
She'll warp their mind,
like all those dirty reds!
Third! You can do better than that!
How do you say patata?
Potato.
- Potato.
- Very good.
If your aunt is Spanish,
then your dad must be Spanish too?
Not really.
He never goes there.
His parents died when I was little.
- But he has an accent.
- Really?
Judias verdes is green beans.
I'd never seen someone
whose dad was dead.
But she seems normal.
Why can't they go home?
- They're Communists!
- What's that?
Filomena says
they're red and bearded.
But I think they don't fear the Lord,
and they move all the time.
- Really?
- Yes!
Pilar doesn't take Bible study
at school.
In Spain, they had to move
all the time!
Soon they're going to move again.
They're moving to an apartment.
Don't stay there, girls.
Take this to your parents.
Why did you invite them?
You're here all day.
We never go out.
Why them?
He's unbearable!
I thought it was a good idea.
Anna and Cecile get along well,
and her mother is nice.
No, she's not nice!
She's dumb!
They're just like the people
we are friends with.
You can't stand anything anymore,
locked up in your office all day!
Why won't you go to Spain?
Or do something about Spain?
- It's useless.
- Be a lawyer for refugees!
Even here, things are blocked.
Then, leave!
Go to Latin America!
Things are happening there.
What about you?
I'll come along!
You'd come?
Yes.
And the kids?
They'll be fine.
They've spent two weeks alone
with Filomena before.
Children!
Your parents are on the phone!
Hurry!
- What time is it there?
- Almost noon.
What presents will you bring back?
Let it be a surprise.
I can't talk for long.
On the calendar I left you,
change the last date to November 20.
- Big kiss, my love!
- Me too.
Is everything okay, Anna?
Dad, why did you change
your return date again?
Things are happening here.
We'll tell you when we're back.
How was it at Marga and Pilar's?
I don't know. We didn't go.
You didn't go?
Let me talk to Filomena.
- Give it to me!
- Okay.
Dad, why so long?
When will you be back?
1... 2... 3...
They have changed
their return date three times!
They left so that Dad could think.
When they're back,
it will be just like before.
Dad says a lot is happening there.
That must mean it's good.
So, what else do you do on Sundays
with your parents?
We do tickle, tickle!
Then we all take a bath together!
All four of you?
Naked?
Sure!
Well! We've already missed Church.
You'll have your bath alone today.
All alone!
People of France,
France is widowed.
In 1940, he saved our honor.
General De Gaulle has died.
In 1944, he led us
to liberation and victory.
It's all over.
Chile is a rich land,
but it has too many poor people.
The wealth must be shared.
We must intervene in every sector:
Education, healthcare
and land reform.
We'll give free milk to every child
under the age of 4 every day.
We'll build 100,000 new houses,
so every family owns one.
Here, this is also for you.
It's a momio. A mummy.
In Chile, that's how they call those
who are against Allende.
We arrived in Chile
as elections were happening,
important presidential elections.
We were in Santiago.
It was a strange
and exciting moment.
Allende got elected,
but there were threats of a putsch.
What's a "poontch"?
It's when the army
overthrows the President.
They tried, but it didn't work.
Allende is now officially President.
Are you going to work with him, Dad?
I'll help him
establish ties with France.
Are we going to live in Chile?
No, but we must make changes.
We must all be united and support
your dad's important work.
How will you get by?
- Marie, what will you do?
- Keep writing for Marie Claire.
I can pitch them many articles now!
What do we have to change?
You said there would be changes.
Don't worry.
If we all do our share,
we'll get by.
- Hands up! It's a "poontch"!
- Not funny.
François, go finish your breakfast!
Go on!
You don't want to eat?
Come.
There. That's the first time
I measured your height.
This will be my first Christmas
without you.
It won't be a real Christmas.
Grandpa and Granny
won't be here either.
There will just be Marga and Pilar.
It's all because of them.
Your parents say
they can't pay me anymore.
But I know why I was fired.
They've become Communists!
Is that why we're moving?
You are like me!
I fled Cuba, driven from my home!
Now you, too,
must abandon your house!
- It's Fidel, he drives them nuts!
- Then...
Fidel is to blame.
Mom!
Anna! What is it?
I dreamt we were in our old house.
What's that noise?
It's a meeting for my work.
Again!
We always have people over!
Come say hello for once.
This is Emilio.
And Pierre.
They work with me
for Allende's government in Chile.
My daughter Anna.
My little mummy.
You mean... like those mummies?
Your daughter is reactionary?
She insisted on staying
in Catholic school.
She made a real scene!
You put her in Catholic school?
It was a long time ago.
Marie wanted her to go.
Why do you say that?
My school is fine!
You liked it, too!
Your brother sleeps well.
He breathes so loud,
it keeps me awake.
Don't exaggerate.
What's that?
I told you not to read this anymore!
Mickey Mouse is a fascist!
Don't sulk.
I am leaving tomorrow.
For as long as last time?
No.
And Mom is staying here.
And the lady
who picks you up from school.
- Panayota!
- Yes, Panayota.
She's nice, right?
Okay, she's not much fun,
but she's very unhappy.
Her husband is in jail.
She fled from Greece.
You know where that is?
Tomorrow look in your atlas.
Now go to sleep.
Filomena had to leave Cuba too,
to escape the barbudos.
That's different.
Go to sleep.
Hello, Sister Anne-Marie!
Miss Anna de la Mesa?
Your parents want you
out of Bible study.
This has been granted exceptionally
to Miss de la Mesa.
There will be no others.
Come, Anna.
I don't like the skin.
We can't eat yet.
We haven't had our bath.
Tomato skin is good for your health.
Eat!
Is Marie Claire for me?
- It's late. I must leave.
- Thanks.
You can leave the table, François.
It's very good.
You should taste it.
Why can't I go to Bible study?
Didn't Dad explain?
He just said religious stories
were nonsense.
Anna, you insisted to stay
in that school,
and I promised you would.
But to convince your dad,
I had to make some concessions.
Now I'll heat your plate,
and you'll finish it!
Don't waste food!
Some people have nothing to eat!
Your brother isn't so fussy!
All these changes
are hard for him, too!
It's tough for me, too.
So help me. And eat.
- I want to go to Bible study!
- Stop it!
I want Bible study,
our big house and Filomena back!
You're not the only one
who wants things!
I want your dad here!
I'm sick of unpacking!
I want to write on politics,
not cooking!
With Filomena, life was better!
We ate normal food,
we had a garden,
we bathed before dinner!
You want a bath? Fine!
It will calm you down!
I'll calm down! I promise!
I'll calm down!
Are you done?
I hate you! I hate you!
I hate you!
Have you and Dad
become Communists?
Why do you ask?
Are we poor now?
Poor?
We eat weird things
in this tiny apartment.
Those people come all the time.
We have less money,
but we're not poor.
If you ask Grandpa and Granny
for money,
can we have our old house
and Filomena back?
Anna, please.
Do you want to sleep with me?
If we find money,
can life be as before?
You don't find money.
You earn it or save it.
I won't ask my parents
to pay for my heating and light.
That's enough.
Let's sleep.
What are you doing?
Tell me, what are you doing there?
You talk of right and wrong,
and now you steal!
It's to pay our bills!
Next Thursday, you'll apologize.
Mom, my snack!
I forgot. This isn't the time!
You also forgot to comb me.
Your snack is a "blacklava."
It's very good.
What are you doing?
We must not turn this light on!
- Why?
- Because.
François, turn it off!
What are you doing now?
Leave me alone!
I don't mind
that you quit Bible study.
Can I come for tea on Candlemas
and play in your garden?
Can I sleep over?
Quiet, girls!
There's enough daylight!
But...
Aren't you in the park?
Isabelle!
Why are you crying?
Is it because of the General?
- What's wrong with her?
- I'll explain later, not now.
We have to talk.
Don't worry.
- I can't stay with you?
- Take them outside.
- My sister-in-law needs me.
- All right.
You're not eating it?
Don't you want to go play?
You and I could play a game,
or I can tell you a story.
I can tell you a story of mythology.
Any princesses in it?
Even better.
There are goddesses.
To understand, you must know
that in the beginning...
The beginning?
When the world started,
if you prefer.
Shall I go on?
In the beginning,
there was only Raos.
Raos?
Like the word "chaos".
Everything was born out of Chaos.
First came the Day and the Night.
Then Gaia, the Earth.
She's the oldest Greek goddess.
The Mother of all living beings.
She gave birth to Uranos, the Sky.
She made it just big enough
so the Sky and the Earth
fit perfectly together.
This isn't the zoological gardens!
I didn't say we would go there.
I said it was a surprise.
- Hello.
Hello.
Free abortion and contraception
We're fighting the 1920 law.
- Hello.
Here are your pills.
It's very simple.
Take one a day.
Is Suzanne here?
Yes. I'll get her.
You could say hello.
Are they gypsies?
What are you saying?
Did you see how they're dressed?
Filomena said gypsies kidnap kids
and sell them to circuses!
I tried to call you.
Isabelle left.
Was Isabelle the surprise?
- What? I talked to her yesterday!
- I know, everything was fine.
But she spoke to your brother
and decided to leave.
Couldn't you stop her?
Marie, we help women
who want abortion and peace.
This is not jail.
Stay for a while!
You wanted Anna to see the house.
- Would you like that?
- No, we'll go.
Don't take it that way.
You didn't force her.
An abortion is tough
on a young woman like her.
I want you to write that book.
So women like Isabelle
know they can choose.
Okay. I'll call you.
Let's go.
Mom, what's an abortion?
What's an abortion?
Don't shout!
I'll explain later.
Come along.
Don't be sad. It's normal
that she went to Bordeaux.
Her house and her husband are there.
Stop talking nonsense.
Mom!
Mom! I want to go to Bordeaux
for my vacation!
Tickle, tickle!
That's enough.
Calm down, kids.
See you later.
- See you later.
Time for your bath.
Will you tell us a story with gods
in the bath?
Yes.
It's cold! It's cold!
What's wrong with the heater?
When Isabelle came,
I was happy to be helpful,
but I failed.
You did the right thing.
I called Mom to tell her Anna
would like to go on vacation there.
She had the nerve to tell me Isabelle
was back, and things were fine!
I didn't even react to that!
I said nothing, like an idiot!
How can I write a book
against all this hypocrisy?
Marie, you confuse things.
Writing that book is a great idea.
You'll learn a lot.
You'll see.
Anna, wake up!
We're "Sundaying"
with Mom and Dad!
Hello, kids.
Did you sleep well?
No "Sundaying" today?
Don't look so sad.
Today we'll show you
something important.
What?
Group solidarity.
In Spain, some people
are facing death penalty.
So, we go out in the streets with
other people to show we disagree.
A family must stay together
on Sunday.
See, it's not a good idea
to take the kids to a demonstration.
No, it's fine.
They must learn.
Come sit down.
Learn what?
For 15 years,
Quino and I fought together.
He died for nothing.
That's what I learned.
Marga, stop it!
Dad, what's group solidarity?
Franco is a murderer!
Franco is a Fascist!
Stop the Franquists!
Are you all right?
Did I hurt you?
No death penalty!
You have to run!
Are you okay?
I want to pee.
You're not hurt?
I'm hungry.
I want to go home.
Me, me, me!
That was group solidarity!
We're here for your future!
My future?
When you're older,
you'll see that we were right.
In Spain, they kill men like Quino
because of their ideas.
In Latin America,
the poor live in shacks!
I know we have to help the poor
and be polite to them,
but why do all that?
Let's do what Granny does!
Where does Granny fit in?
Stop talking nonsense!
- Are you both okay?
- Fine.
My love.
Come in, Anna.
Then stay there!
Think about what I told you!
I won't!
I'm glad I'm going
to Granny and Grandpa's!
They don't bother me
with group solidarity!
Anna, calm down!
I took the skin off.
Go on, eat!
You must be hungry.
Are things okay at school?
Yes, but it's hard to do homework
while sharing a room with François.
Oh, my dear,
that makes you even worthier.
Granny, I'm not allowed
to take Bible study.
Your parents did that?
Hi, Anna.
What is it?
Mom sewed it on for me.
Look.
I'm Anna de la Mesa.
I'm going to
Chateau de la Caussade.
They made her travel all alone.
Is she sick? What's wrong?
The Greek god of wine
was Dionysius.
You know what the Romans
called him?
No.
Bacchus.
They told the same stories.
They just changed the names.
- Who came first?
- The Greeks.
Then the Romans took their stories.
So that's why Panayota
says the Greeks did it all.
Even the beginning of the World.
In what way?
The Bible says
God made everything in six days.
But Gaia and Uranos
were here before that.
In Ancient times, people
believed all kinds of nonsense.
It was just stories
for ignorant people.
Look.
A fox got caught in this trap.
To be free, it gnawed off its paw.
We're taking all this
to the presbytery?
First we'll ask our help
if they want any of it.
The presbytery gives it
to orphans and the poor?
Why do you ask?
We've done this before.
Granny, do you think farmers
should share fields
among those who have lots
and those who have less?
Those are the ideas of your parents.
You think they're Communists?
Who are the Communists, Granny?
Students, workers,
people like everyone else.
But most of them are poor.
- What do they want?
- Everything!
Our houses, our vines,
our clothes, our money,
and your toys.
Why?
I guess they don't like us.
They don't like us?
We give them milk, clothes,
we're polite to them,
and they don't like us?
What do you do next?
I leave it off,
until it gets really dark.
Sometimes, I turn the heater off.
Do you really think
it will change anything?
You should find a spot for yourself.
We're home.
Marie?
Don't move!
Come, Anna.
Come here.
Anna, what are you doing?
This is a nice little spot.
Not really.
So when can I come sleep over?
You promised,
and my mom said yes.
Well, okay.
Great, see you tomorrow!
Well...
- Are you alone?
- No.
Hi, Anna!
Mom, who is the Chinese lady?
Anna, what did I tell you
this morning?
If the doors are closed,
I can't come in
because you're working!
They come to tell me their lives.
It's hard for them.
Where is Panayota?
I forgot. I'm sorry.
Panayota went home to Greece.
Her husband got out of jail.
Mai Lahn will be taking her place.
What's her name?
Mai Lahn is from Vietnam.
We talked about that country.
I know! It's where kids
are burnt with napalm.
I should have warned you.
I'm sorry.
But don't burst in on me!
You said never to follow strangers!
You should have asked François.
He knows her.
Anna, you're disqualified.
It's a relay race.
You must pass the baton.
I can't believe it.
You have to comb her hair
before we leave.
Tell me the rest of the story.
What story?
About the frog whose pool dried up.
It didn't want to die
and went to see
the Emperor of the Sky
to scold the Rain Genie.
- What's a Genie?
- He's like a God.
Are there other genies,
like the genie of wine?
Not of wine, but of the Sea,
of the Moon.
Is there a story
about how the world began?
Yes.
Not that one! I know it!
I heard it while you were on vacation.
I want the end of the frog story!
The frog doesn't want to die.
So it decides to go see
the Emperor of the Sky.
What?
The Emperor of the Sky,
the boss of the Rain Genie.
On the way...
- As it's going there?
- Yes.
It meets other animals.
A crab, a fox, a bear,
and last a little bee.
The frog tells them
that if they'll come with it,
they'll have a better chance
of being heard.
So the animals decide
to go with the frog.
And they all leave together.
It worked because
they went as a group?
Yes, it worked
because they were numerous.
Who came first,
the Greeks or the Romans?
Well, girls?
Who thinks the Romans came first?
Who else is for the Romans?
Are you done?
You're all wrong.
I tried to be like the frog.
They all said the Romans.
So like the bear and the bee,
I went along.
Grandpa had told me.
I won't trust group solidarity again!
I'm not sure I understand.
She confused group solidarity
with sheep behavior.
Am I right?
How can you tell sheep
from group solidarity?
You're never mistaken?
Hello.
It's that way.
Another "whatness"!
You mean witness.
Your dad and I are proud
that you tried group solidarity.
And I'm glad
you're inviting friends again.
Cecile is sleeping over.
I spoke to her mom.
Cecile is coming here?
- Hello.
I'll be right back.
- Thanks a lot.
- Good-bye.
Good-bye.
Where are you going, Mom?
To Marga's.
Mai Lahn is staying
until Dad is back.
See you later.
That's a lot of people
in such a tiny place.
- It's not tiny!
- It is compared to your old house.
Here, we don't have to be careful.
We do what we want!
But you have to share a room.
It's nicer with Anna.
I'm less scared.
Someone is always leaving
in our family.
And you don't have
a garden anymore!
We go to the little park.
It's nice.
What's wrong with Cecile?
She saw Dad naked.
She'd never seen a dickie.
Sure, yours have been cut off.
No, they haven't.
We have duckies.
And what are duckies?
Dickies that have been cut off!
Shut up! I want to sleep!
We need engineers.
They're important.
All the Americans will leave.
To hell with them.
The Americans, sure,
but not the engineers.
Stronger towards them.
- That's the important thing.
- I can't believe it.
- Benito.
- Thank you.
Anna?
Are you okay?
Where are Mom and Dad?
Fernando went to get Marie
at your aunt's.
Go back to bed.
Once you've nationalized,
the imperialist pigs will leave
and destroy everything.
Right! That's why
we're looking for people here.
I am afraid I will forget
what I need to ask them.
Stay here if you want.
You can't stop production.
You need that money.
Anna!
Are you sure
you don't want to go to bed?
You want something?
Some food?
Done.
Are you barbudos?
What do you know about them?
They're Communists
who want nuclear war!
Granny says they want
to take our money and our house.
I see why Fernando
calls her a little mummy.
Look, I'll show you something.
Imagine that all the wealth
of the world is an orange.
Some want to keep the orange
all to themselves,
once they've really peeled it.
And others want to divide it
in equal parts
to share it.
Your father, your mother and us,
we're for sharing.
So are the barbudos.
Taste it.
This is the game.
You buy a plate from me
for five francs.
What for?
To resell it for 10 francs!
It's bad to make profits
and sell things for so much.
Then some people
can't buy anything.
That's good.
That way you'll have money.
Please buy something from me.
Why can't it be free?
We could swap things,
instead of always buying.
Look, I take this.
In exchange, I do you a favor.
I could help with your homework.
Hey, we're playing shop!
I've already done my homework!
Mom!
Why aren't you in bed?
It's late.
We tried to explain
how to redistribute
wealth equitably, but...
She wouldn't buy it.
Go to bed!
I think she wanted to talk to you.
Really?
She'd never seen a boy's dickie!
Without a little brother, you would
have been like your friend Cecile.
Didn't Granny tell you about it?
Not even about the little seed?
Not a chance!
Some parents don't tell their kids.
Why?
Because some things can't be said?
Who told you that?
Filomena and Granny.
Is it better to say or not to say?
It's always better to talk.
But that's not your problem.
You're a talker.
Go to bed!
And be nice to your friend Cecile!
But she's not nice!
She didn't like Mai Lahn's rice,
she says we have a tiny home,
and there's no garden!
I know someone
who complains about everything,
who says that the park is dirty,
and who turns the heating off
in mid-winter.
Do you know her?
No.
Come along.
Miss de la Mesa.
Please.
Go wait in the study room.
- Are you okay?
- Leave me alone.
Starting today, girls,
we'll study the life
of Our Lord Jesus Christ.
I was born in France in 1949.
I'm the third of a family
of seven children.
My father was a factory worker.
My mother was a housewife.
At the age of 16 and a half,
I worked in the factory.
I met a boy there,
and I got pregnant. That's it.
Don't try to tell your story
in chronological order,
or any kind of order.
Just say what comes to mind.
If we want more details,
we will ask you a question.
Go on.
I didn't make enough money
to raise my baby alone.
He cried all the time.
I was exhausted.
Then he was put in a foster home.
I only saw him on Saturdays.
I had a nervous breakdown,
and I was in a mental hospital
for 10 months.
When I got out,
I wanted my son back,
but they said I had to show
three months of salary.
So I got a job as a typist.
But I can't spell at all.
And I am a single mother.
- So no "Sundaying"?
- Hush, let me listen.
I would have done anything to keep
my baby, even go back to the factory.
Then May '68 came.
Anyone could go to college.
I managed to work and study
at the same time.
And I read books.
Are you hungry?
Dad, what's May '68?
During the month of May, in 1968,
people demonstrated
to change things.
- To change what?
- Lots of things.
A bit like what we're doing in Chile.
Were you there, in May '68?
I would have liked to,
but I had a job.
You saw nothing to change?
That's not it.
Sometimes you miss out.
Then it's too late.
There. It won't take long.
Are there things to change now?
Sure.
There was Quino's death,
then Marga.
We went to Chile,
Marie decided to write her book.
So you were wrong, before?
Not entirely.
I have a beautiful family
with two beautiful kids.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
How can you be sure
you're not wrong now?
I'm not wrong.
I try to help others.
Look, I need 10 minutes,
then my work's done.
Is 10 minutes long?
Depends.
If you're busy, it goes fast.
Quick, hide!
There's a policeman!
Move over!
Move your foot!
If he comes close,
will he throw napalm on us?
No, napalm is only used in wars!
They torture with napalm
during "poontches"!
But not kids!
Will he start a nuclear war?
You're confusing everything.
The barbudos start nuclear wars!
Like Filomena said,
they're red and bearded.
You got it all wrong!
Santa Claus is red and bearded!
Let's play Allende and Franco.
I'll be Allende.
He's the good guy.
So is Franco.
Dad's dad knew him.
He's bad in Pilar's song!
What song?
Jesus was crucified
on Mount Golgotha,
in Jerusalem.
- What do you do during Bible study?
- Nothing.
- Don't you miss it?
- No.
What do you do with God,
Jesus and the Virgin Mary?
Nothing.
I know why she skips Bible study.
Her parents
have become "beatnik-hippy".
They don't have
a big house anymore.
They live in a tiny crowded place,
and they eat weird food.
It's not weird!
Her parents go around naked.
I won't invite you again!
You're an idiot!
So stupid you've never seen
a boy's dickie!
What's a boy's dickie like?
She doesn't even know
how kids are made!
Yes, I know!
Oh yeah? How?
- I won't tell you!
- See, you don't know.
Yes, I do!
No, you don't!
Yes!
No!
What's a "beatnik-hippy"?
I don't know.
So how are babies made?
Your parents never told you?
When I ask,
they pretend not to hear me.
My parents do that too.
Especially my grandmother.
Why is that?
I don't know.
My mom acts like a hen,
with her neck.
So how are kids made?
- What happened?
- Please, ladies.
- This is a scandal!
- What are you talking about?
- You know what I mean!
- Not at all!
I can't even discuss it!
I'm leaving!
Come along.
I want no sign of you for a while!
Scram!
How is your married life now?
My life now?
In four years of marriage,
my husband has always
seen me pregnant.
The kids are sick all the time.
We're always short of money.
I'm often irritated and tired.
I didn't want a fourth child.
So every time he touched me,
I turned him down.
It's no life for him.
I asked my doctor for advice,
but he said I had marital duties.
So every month I panicked.
I checked endlessly for my period,
but got pregnant again.
I wanted to get rid of it,
but I was afraid.
I was told that they sewed
the fetus back on in the hospital,
or that they did
a painful curettage to punish you.
And I'm a Catholic.
Faster! Faster!
First! Great, Anna!
We're done for today.
Don't forget, there will be no class
during the Easter break.
Hi, little mummy!
- Well? You sold everything?
- Yeah.
You're rich now.
You can help the poor.
Hello.
How are you?
Mom?
Are you okay?
Hello.
How are you?
- Hello.
Hello, Miss.
Hello, Emilio.
Hi, little mummy.
How are you?
Will you help us win the elections?
I don't know.
Dad?
Dad, I thought Allende
had already won.
Yes, that's right.
Excuse me.
But if the people aren't happy,
they can change things.
So, there are various elections.
These are municipal.
If he loses, will Franco win?
Of course not!
But he'll win, don't worry.
Hello.
How are you?
Fine, thanks. And you?
Fine.
You speak French well.
You never talk to me when we meet.
That's true.
Is your school nice?
It's okay, but Mom wants me
to be the best.
Cat!
François gets it wrong!
He says "Ay Camellia, Ay Camellia"!
It's not Camellia.
It's "Ay, Carmela! Ay, Carmela"!
I knew it.
Bedtime!
Come! Tomorrow you have school.
And the election results?
We'll know tomorrow morning.
Five minutes more.
We're leaving.
Mom.
- How much did he say?
- I don't know.
Don't you speak Spanish?
You're our good luck charm,
our mascot.
See? Things always end well.
From the deep crucible
Of our homeland
The people's voices rise up
We sense a new day is dawning
All Chile is starting to sing
We shall prevail
Though a thousand chains
We must break
We shall prevail
Poverty will be overcome
Though a thousand chains
We must break
We shall prevail
Poverty will be overcome
Explain this!
How could you do this to me?
On a day like this!
I signed a petition.
343 French women
dare admit they had an abortion.
Everyone will talk about this.
That bothers you?
Everything's fine!
We won the elections!
It's illegal!
You know the 1920 law?
Over 300 signed.
They can't touch us!
You said I'd learn things
writing this book.
You never had an abortion!
We needed to be
as numerous as possible.
That's it!
It's group solidarity.
Precisely! That's what it is.
Abortion.
That's what Isabelle did?
Abortion is when a woman
decides not to stay pregnant,
because she can't or doesn't want
to have a child at that moment.
It's her choice, you see?
What's this macho act?
Don't you start, like Marga!
Leave Marga out of it.
At least she fought!
Your pro-Franco family
is your burden.
What burden?
How about yours?
You preach woman's liberation,
and you let nuns and Granny
raise your daughter!
As for Isabelle...
Deal with your own guilt,
but let me do my thing!
- As usual, you confuse everything.
- No, you do!
You fight for a country that is
miles away, that isn't yours!
- Odd way to make amends.
- For what?
For doing nothing
when Quino and Marga
risked their life in your country!
For fleeing here rather than choosing
between your sister and your parents!
You sneaked back once to see Marga,
and once to introduce Anna
to her grandparents.
I worked for my family.
And for you!
You thought it was exotic
to marry a Spaniard,
as long as it didn't upset your world!
My family backed Franco,
but you didn't mind
until Marga came!
The counter attack is raging
We must resist
Ay, Carmela
Who taught you that?
You're both out to get me!
Let go of her!
What's gotten into you?
What is it?
You scared her!
You should have told me you were
going to sign that manifesto.
Can we stop now?
Chile
Are you okay?
What are you doing?
Watching the clock.
Ten minutes is long here.
"The king was pleased.
Thinking it over,
he approved of men
being responsible for what they ate.
After punishing him,
he said to the fisherman:
'Give a man a fish,
you feed him for a day.
Teach a man to fish and
you feed him for a lifetime.
Then the King disappeared."
Can we go home now?
I'm hungry!
Here.
Are you sure?
It won't be a fun trip.
Where did you get this?
In the library.
Where's your house?
You lived in the countryside,
like Mom?
It was more like a desert.
Long ago, my ancestors
tortured people on tables.
That's how we got our name.
"Mesa" is Spanish for "table."
They tortured them
in the house where you went?
No.
I don't know, maybe.
It's so sad.
Miss de la Mesa.
Repeat what I said.
"The goat was eaten
by the wolf for disobeying."
Sit down.
Getting eaten by the wolf
was its punishment.
So the text is about
the need for obedience.
Sister, I don't get it.
My grandpa showed me
the paw of a fox caught in a trap.
It gnawed off its paw to get free.
That's quite different.
The goat wasn't trapped.
Mr. Seguin fed it, loved it.
But he kept it tied up.
It's in the book.
Are you saying
the goat wanted to die?
That would be a sin.
Sit down.
Animals aren't Catholic, Sister.
What do you think it says?
The goat has two options:
To stay at Mr. Seguin's
or escape to the mountains.
It leaves,
thinking the wolf won't eat it.
Stand up to speak!
It goes up to the mountains,
hoping to become free.
Well, it was mistaken.
And so are you.
Sit down.
I'll get a bad grade
and lose my bonus points.
We think you were right.
Trust us.
You also say Snow White
and Mickey Mouse are fascists.
And the Americans, and napalm!
You make mistakes, like Dad did.
He said he did.
Yes, sometimes we're wrong.
So is your teacher.
So, no one's really sure
about anything?
What do you think?
Were you wrong about the goat?
Are you sure?
Yes.
You see.
I'm hungry.
Can we eat?
Yes, come help me.
Is that why you want
to change schools?
You won't see
your friend Cecile anymore.
It doesn't matter.
It's like changing nannies.
How?
It's sad when they leave,
but if the next one is nice,
it's okay.
Thanks.
Here we are!
It's like "Sundaying" on Wednesday!
Exactly!
Pasta!
Yes!
Wait, put this here.
The Right To Live Differently
You're hearing the last speech
of President Salvador Allende,
who died during the coup in Chile,
last September 11.
I'll pay with my life
my loyalty to the people.
History is ours
and is made by the people.
Long live Chile!
Long live the people!
Long live the workers!
For Elias