Fucker!
Bleak Night
Charge!
Becky, come join us.
- Just leave him.
- What sup?
That's a fall!
Is not, not, not!
Yo, Becky. Come here.
What's with him?
Just let him be.
- What do you mean?
- You know what.
Know what?
What's with you two?
It's nothing.
Talk to me.
Really.
Stop worrying.
Why can't you talk?
Seriously. It's nothing.
Closed till Feb 8th due to
personal reasons
Wanted to meet you in person
and ask about...
No, there's no problem.
I just stopped by the school.
The admin office gave me
your number.
Sure. I'm alright.
Yes, I'll just...
Right.
Thank you.
- Why are you blowing me off?
- What now?
Give it back.
Come get it.
Come pick it up later.
- Just pick it up and shove it.
- Under here.
- Over here.
- Just give it to me.
Guys, Becky's here.
Warm yourself by the fire.
You're late!
Don't keep me waiting.
Sorry.
I missed you buddy.
Don't be late again, alright?
Your backpack's been smoked.
It's a joke.
You think I'd do
that to a friend?
Where's my backpack?
It's at Lego's.
This fucker wanted to burn it,
but Lego stopped.
- It is smokin'
- Right under here.
- There's history book.
- Where? Where?
You good, Becky?
What is?
Are you having fun?
Nah...
I got witnesses say you are.
Eyeball one, two, three, four
Glasses count for four,
so eight, nine, ten...
You're laughing again.
I'm not.
Do I look funny to you?
Like a fucking comedian?
- Bitch, just stop.
- Give it back.
Stop fucking laughing.
Is this funny?
Sir, please come in.
Please, have some.
You came to the funeral?
Yes, to the funeral cortege.
Frankly, I can't remember
who all came.
You look a bit familiar.
It's OK.
Many kids came that day.
So, how did you get my number?
Your teacher gave me
some phone numbers.
Kids said you were
good friends with Ki-tae.
I'm not here to intimidate you.
Just wanted to chat.
Sure...
I'm sorry to bother you.
It's alright.
It's your senior year.
You must be busy studying.
I'm alright.
When do you start school?
Next week.
I found many pictures of
you and Ki-tae together.
I see.
There was another boy,
but I'm not sure who it is.
It's probably Dong-yoon.
Dong-yoon.
Yes.
- Awesome.
- Fucking change.
Homerun!
Last one!
Hurry up.
If it's out, we have to change.
I'm tired.
Last one.
Rock, scissors...
Bitch!
Hurry up. Run.
- Shit, that hurts.
- Watch out.
Let's just buy another ball.
No way, you retard,
Ki-tae loves that ball.
What's in that ball?
- It's expensive?
- I don't know.
Did you look here?
Guys! I found it.
Yeah?
Let's go chill.
You like Bo-kyung that much?
What? No, I don't.
Dumbass, you like her.
- No, I don't.
- It's written on your face.
How about Wolmi Island this weekend?
With Bo-kyung and other girls.
3-on-3?
With Se-jung too?
It's definitely a GO!
How about it, Becky?
Yeah, whatever.
You suck.
What?
- He thinks he's so cool.
- Dumbass.
Do I look it?
Yes, you fucking do.
Okay, I'll go.
Dude, my head hurts.
You little shit.
That hurts.
I said I'll go.
You sure Se-jung's coming?
How many times did I say yes?
If not, I'm not going.
You're acting weird.
I can ask.
You're only going
for your own sake.
No way, bitch.
I'm trying to hook up
Becky and Bo-kyung.
What did I do?
He's going because of Se-jung.
So what?
You're the one always complaining.
Now, you're coming out.
No, I'm not.
Besides, why can't I get
with Se-jung?
Huh? Bo-kyung, Se-jung...
Fucking dumbass
Be more aggressive.
You're gonna blow your chance.
Fine.
Look at Dong-yoon.
He's just going at it.
You think I don't wanna?
Shut up and listen.
Picture her here. Gaze at her.
- Then once she sees you, look away.
- That's aggressive?
- That's aggressive!
- How's that aggressive?
- Just ask Dong-yoon.
- You suck.
If you did half the shit he did,
- You could have had her already.
- You suck.
Hurry up.
Okay.
Yo, hurry up.
I told you so.
He's acting strange.
Just like that.
- Said look into her eyes.
- Move your ass.
Go take care of his dumbass.
What did he say?
I don't know.
He said to look into her eyes.
Don't you get it?
I'm describing exactly
what he does.
What do you want-la?
Hurry up-leh.
- Feels like we flew here.
- We're really in China.
I bet everyone speaks Chinese here.
- How about lunch?
- I can speak a little Chinese.
- Wo ai ni. Zai Zien.
- Wo ai ni, my ass.
- Zai Zien
- Ni hao ma.
Here's another.
Ni chi fan le ma.
You cussed. You're bad.
- No I didn't. It's Chinese.
- You cussed. You're bad.
It's not cursing.
Where we going?
I'm hungry.
Let's go here.
Oh! I know who it is.
I saw him carrying bunch of flowers.
- Wearing this apron.
- That faggot.
Why?
It was a super cute apron.
- This is spicy.
- Drink this.
What did he eat?
- You two look cute.
- Asshole.
No we don't.
I would've done the same for you.
- You two lovebirds.
- Shut the hell up.
Ki-tae, have some of this.
- Is it good?
- Yeah.
Isn't this far too?
Have some of this too.
- What are you doing?
- What?
What are you doing?
You were far from the dumplings.
You said you didn't
want your noodles.
Are you trying to make
Hee-june jealous?
What?
You are, aren't you?
Stop with your bitching.
The food's pretty good.
- It is great.
- Have some.
What do you know about dumplings?
Pretty good.
- I hate when you joke around.
- The food still sucks.
She's into you.
Good luck. She's pretty.
Dude, stop.
Let's all go to your place.
- And do what?
- Just hang.
Are you two dating?
Are ya? Are ya?
I've never been.
I think he was uncomfortable
bringing friends home.
He came to my house
and Dong-yoon's a lot.
My mom knows Ki-tae too.
- Really?
- Yes.
It's not only Ki-tae.
All kids act differently
when they're around parents.
He wasn't in any trouble at school?
No, at least not before I moved.
Frankly, I don't know why
Jae-ho gave you my number.
I moved weeks before
what happened to Ki-tae.
So, I don't know anything.
So you haven't seen him
since you moved?
He came by once to see me.
Couple of days after I moved.
We said our hellos and
I haven't seen him since.
You didn't notice
anything strange?
I guess he came to say goodbye.
He seemed alright.
What about the other boy
in the picture?
- You mean Dong-yoon?
- Yes, him.
Did he come to the funeral?
No, he didn't.
I thought they were close.
Well, he didn't come.
I haven't talked to him in a while.
Can you tell me
a little about him?
About Dong-yoon?
They were good friends
since junior high.
I met Ki-tae in high school.
Was Dong-yoon in the same classes?
No, he was in different classes.
Ki-tae and Dong-yoon were special.
What do you mean special?
I'm a high school friend.
They were best friends
since junior high.
I could never be as close...
Not like those two.
- As long as you don't pick me.
- Ki-tae's so good.
No, don't get that.
Dumbass keeps taking it.
Why? I think he's it.
You better choose well.
This is boring.
Why don't you go play?
You want some?
When are your parents coming home?
Maybe tomorrow.
Then I'm gonna crash at your place.
Alright?
Fine.
You want me to go?
No, it's fine.
Go talk to Bo-kyung or something.
Why are you so quite?
What's wrong, yo?
What were you two talking about?
What do you mean?
Earlier in the room,
I saw you and Bo-kyung talking.
You saw?
Why else would I ask?
It wasn't anything.
You don't think something happened.
Nah...
You got it all wrong.
Stop that.
Alright.
That's strange...
A guilty conscience
needs no accuser.
- What do you mean?
- What?
What do you mean by that?
It's nothing.
- You need to stop.
- Don't touch my head.
Becky, you've grown up so fast.
Don't talk to me like that.
I'm not your bitch.
Dude, I was joking.
Jae-ho, come out this way.
He's caught again.
Get him.
- Jae-ho does flower arrangement?
- Yeah, At his mom's flower shop.
I'm trying to be a good son
Assholes!
That's better than
your mom telling you to study.
I fucking work every weekend.
- You don't have private tutoring.
- I'd rather do that.
How much do you get paid?
- Two bucks.
- Two bucks?
Damn.
Ask for a 50 cent raise.
You're like those
underpaid foreign workers.
It's about being a good son.
I'd rather get paid two bucks
and hang out with my mom.
You and your flowers.
So cute!
Shut the hell up.
I do look hot carrying flowers.
Guess what fucking happened
yesterday.
What?
- That underpass place.
- The underpass?
What's with the junior high asses
smoking cigarettes?
With bitches on the side.
For real?
You left them alone?
I was glaring at them.
Then these fuckers gave me looks.
They gave you dirty looks?
They're begging to die.
There were about seven,
not counting the girls.
I was gonna go,
but it was a big group.
So I turned away,
but then I got pissed.
- Let's get them.
- Go?
- Where?
- So what happened?
You should've called us.
- You should've called me.
- So what happened?
- You didn't lose, right?
- Junior ass is my specialty.
Yo, talk.
I need to go shit.
Finish the story.
What up?
- Maybe he got his ass kicked.
- He's full of shit.
Where you going?
Come stand here.
What's up?
Why did you do that?
What?
You two were doing that thing.
What do you mean?
Giving funny looks to each other.
You think I'm a retard?
You better tell now
or I'm gonna kick your ass.
Hurry up, fucker!
We were talking earlier.
About?
How you always get quiet
when we talk about parents.
You suddenly stop talking
then you switch subjects.
You did it again today,
and it reminded us.
That's why you two were laughing?
At me?
I'd never laugh at you.
That's why you two gave
funny looks?
Look at me.
I'm sorry.
Start talking.
- We weren't laughing at you.
- Fucking tell me.
We looked at each other,
but we weren't laughing at you.
Why would I do that?
Are you gonna see Se-jung later?
No.
The CD, Lego gave you.
Are you gonna watch it with her?
Dumbass.
I didn't get anything.
- I saw you.
- I was pretending.
You're so into her.
- Sure am.
- I'm jealous now.
Wanna go play baseball?
Go play it with Se-jung.
Go to hell.
Ki-tae, let's go play baseball.
Let's go play baseball.
Go. Go!
Let go.
What?
I'm just gonna say one thing.
- Me?
- Becky.
Me?
When you go home, your mom makes dinner
and tells you to study. Right?
What's up?
When I go home,
I cook my own dinner.
Sometimes, if I get lucky,
I get to see my old man and say hello.
I'm always late to school.
I get pissed that no one woke me up.
But you see, my mom's gone.
OK. I get it.
There's no one.
That's about
all I can say about my parents.
Are you satisfied?
Are you?
I'm gonna split.
Ki-tae.
OK.
- I was just asking to play baseball.
- Don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
I don't.
You're still here.
You came out earlier than I thought.
I couldn't concentrate
so I'm going home.
Is it because of me?
No. Is something wrong?
The number you gave me.
Dong-yoon's cell is turned off.
I haven't talked to him lately, either.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but could you help me?
I'm not sure who to call.
Maybe, you have some friends,
who still talk to Dong-yoon.
Please?
I was wondering
if you still talked to him.
I have his home phone too.
OK, let me just ask for a favor.
If Dong-yoon calls, give me a call.
- Give me your left hand.
- Light me up.
Give me your left hand.
Now, my hand smells.
- I dropped my cigarette.
- They're gonna check me too.
Light me up.
Becky, keep a lookout.
Are you deaf?
I said, go keep a lookout.
What?
You don't even smoke.
Dude, it's just a joke.
Fine.
Don't get pissed.
I get it.
- Relax. I'm sorry.
- I said, I got it.
- OK. I'm really sorry.
- Fine.
I'm gonna go in now.
Fuck!
I told you I'm sorry.
Like I said, I got it.
I said I'm sorry.
Stop looking at me like that.
I said stop frowning.
Just stop.
Becky. Look at me, shitface.
Let go of me.
You're gonna be like that?
Look at me, bitch.
He's not picking up.
Yeah?
Maybe, Becky's in trouble.
Nah, he's fine.
Think you're smarter than me?
- Growing up so fast.
- Fucking fast.
Yo, Becky!
This is a type of
traditional Korean poem.
Characteristics of poem are?
From the end of Goryeo dynasty.
It's a good test question.
Highlight.
Why are you napping all day?
Yo, Becky.
Raise your fucking head.