That day you would have gone for a long journey.
That night, someone would come to you.
That person will make a plea from you.
Do not decline that person's plea.
I beg you.
On that day, you must return.
You must, in order for that person to live.
And also, on the morning of that day,
that child will break a medicine bowl.
And also, what else happened that day?
Right.  By the windowsill, in their full bloom,
I remember those chrysanthemums.
On that day, you must not send that person.
What awaited that person on that day was a trap.
Hence, Eun Soo, please hold onto that person.
Episode 17.
Go and relate this.
Go and relate to that Prince Deokheung His Highness of yours.
That the High Doctor from Heaven wants to see him.
Right this very minute!
Why, what's so urgent?
Are you intending to kill that man Choi Young today?
Is it true?  Were you really?
How did you know?
It was real.
I told you!  Don't touch that person!
You agreed!
As I know it, I did.
The offender chased by the entire world came into the palace and tried to poison me, the king's proxy.
A person of such, you said to send him out of the palace without so much as a hair harmed.
Hence, did I not do that for you?
Today's trap.  What is it?  Where is it?
You know it's a trap?
I said, where is it?
Where do you intend to kill that person?
How did you know?
That he would be driven into a trap today.
The one who is fretting isn't me though.
Since that trap will soon be invoked.
My notebook.  It was written in the last part.
Save that person.
What is that thing called notebook?
It couldn't be that today's trap is written in the few sheets left in that notebook.
To say such nonsensical thing...
I'll do everything.
I'll do everything you ask.  So please.
This house and today's movement.  Who else knows?
Other than us, no one should be aware.
That royal seal.  Is that really that important?
Look here.  This is for our citizenry to receive His Majesty the King's will.
To receive that will, isn't this something that can be produced again many times?
Whether those punks outside came with that royal seal as their aim,
or for some other reason, is what I must find out.
What outside punks?
Teacher, where did Scholar Moon go?
Who is that?
The owner of this house.  Lately we've been using this house to hold our secret meetings.
However, that person...
Stay there without a stir.
Choi Young is difficult to kill by sword, I heard.
Hence Prince of the Court taught me.
That person's weakness is justification.
Even if the petty folks betray him, as long as they bring him a justification, he can't shoot them out.
So with that justification, I set down the snare waiting for the trap prepared.
So you're saying you will kill him?
That person is no longer the captain of Woodalchi and he's someone trying to flee.
He's someone who would never force his way unless he's being attacked first.
Why must you kill him?
Because he's a hindrance.
In making you a person of mine.
What in the world are you saying?
I must have you,
in order for me to have Prince of the Court from Deokseong as well.
Under where that person is at, cords of explosive powder have been laid.
One ember and even if he's a master of internal power, it will be unbearable.
What do I need to do for you?
You and me... I am thinking we should start with a marriage first.
What?
A marriage to a royalty like me.
And soon, you could become Her Royal Highness the Queen as well.
This letter is a command to halt all operations.
We don't have a lot of time.
Is that it?
I just need to marry you?  Then let's do it.
What in the world are you doing right now?
Move aside.
The captain left safely, I'm told.
And people from Suribang joined him.
She's asking if there's more you'd like to know.
That's enough.  As long as that person is safe, it's enough.
What is this matter?
These are sent to High Doctor by Prince Deokheung.
There will be a small feast in the evening. He said he'd like you to attend.
What is that?
We'll come to escort you at the hour.
What exactly is happening?
I said I would marry that human being Prince Deokheung.
What?
Does any dog or cow come and go here?
It's His Majesty's order.
To keep the door open day and night.
Then, the spies and the assassins?
Watch well
and find them out by sense?
His Majesty awaits.
I'll go first.
Look here.
Yes.
Thank you.
For guarding us safely.
I'll be going.
Your Majesty.
You have toiled much to come here.
Please sit.
How would we dare to, at the same table as the King?
See?  Didn't I say those who are much learned would be much startled?
This is a seat that old and young, women and men of this neighborhood,
even those of slave class have sat.
Hence, do not decline.
Or how about helping me a little while you're here?
By help?
I am in the process of sorting out the slave roster made in the past decade.
Slaves, you said?
First, those who were demoted from Yangmin to slave status, I will dispose of their slave papers.
You could start looking through those papers first.
We came to bring the Goryeo national seal.
I have heard.
I don't like this.  Something's strange.
They were intending to lock you guys up and blast the explosive powder?
Just at the boiling point.
But suddenly, they all disappeared.
Leaving the explosive powder as is.
What could this be?
Could it be Prince of the Court's doing?
Prince of the Court, just to kill a few old men,
he used such a complex measure?
Then it's Prince Deokheung.
Just to crush a royal seal?
Or he wanted to kill you, you brat.
Is that it?
Those old men were the bait and you were the quarry.
Why me?
That's what I'm saying.
And what's with the guard situation here?
I'm really not liking it.
His Majesty, in going out to the streets, has to check.
Go out where?
Together with Her Highness the Queen, there isn't anywhere they don't go.
Taking the Woodalchi kids and our maid warriors, giving us the taste of death.
Yesterday, they wanted to pick chestnuts and wandered around the back mountain, and ack!
Not liking it.
But anyways, where's High Doctor?
Why didn't she come with you?
I thought you were together.
What's with you?
Huh?
Well that... so...
what I'm supposed to do next.  I don't know it.
The Goryeo national seal produced upon gathering the will of the statesmen.
With relating this national seal as your pretext, you must have come to scope me out.
Indeed, is the King who's left the palace not in his right mind as the rumors have it?
Is he so feeble-minded that he himself delegated the King's power to rule to his uncle?
What else would there be?
Soon a petition is due to be sent to the Yuan emperor.
They probably need to judge which king to support.
Scared that they'd be caught on in their hovering in the middle, in trying to grasp the situation,
they even summoned the man they themselves cast away to guard them.
And that one that guarded has no pride.
That's what I'm saying.
Goryeo monarch's new seal.  Good.
Do Chi.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I now have a new royal seal.  With that new seal, I will write my first royal order.
I will reinstate Choi Young and the reason is as follows:
Choi Young saved the queen's life during the revolt by Jo Il Shin...
and he contributed a great merit in safeguarding the King and the Royal escort.
For any faults prior, I give my pardon and I reinstate him.
Seoyong [서용] = appoint one who's committed an offense to officiary post again.
You are scoping things out well, right?
You come alone? What about your bodyguard?
I said I would come alone.
Have a seat.
Your Majesty can't be protected in this manner.
You let anyone in and out, and come and go.
And send your bodyguards away whenever you want.
Then, shall I slowly return to the palace?
Not before Prince Deokheung is sent out.
Two thousand palace soldiers are still in his grasp and moreover, he is one who uses poison.
Do you know how difficult it is to safeguard someone from someone who uses poison?
Is this amusing?
Whether as a Woodalchi or as an offender chased out,
whether as someone I trust or don't trust, how is that you are so without change?
I wonder too.
Is your dream to become a fisherman still?
That... I have forgotten that for quite some time.
Just earlier, with the royal seal you escorted here safely, I pardoned and reinstated you, Captain.
And I promoted you from 4B ranking to 4A.
And now your ranking is Hogun (General).
I don't think the statesmen would be pleased.
I may dismiss you from office again or even send you to exile at a given time.
Because... I am King.
Yes.
Still, I wish you would be with me.
I'm sorry, for giving you an officiary post again.
A letter from Royal Doctor Jang, did you say?
Hurry and read it.
What does it say?
Give it to me.
High Doctor accepts Prince Deokheung's marriage proposal.
What is this saying?  How could this...
Would it do to not tell him?
What?
To Captain.  Shouldn't we let him know?
What is it?
What is what?
What happened?
The matter that must be hidden from me.
High Doctor...
is getting married.
Marrying Prince Deokheung.
I don't know the details yet, but according to the letter from Royal Doctor Jang, High Doctor has agreed.
Don't be joking.
Royal Doctor Jang is worried as well.
Saying he's not sure what High Doctor's thinking.
That person is getting married, you said?
With that punk?
It seems to be the case.
Aunt.
Yup.
I just received an appointment to office so I need procedure to vacate my position.  Do that for me.
I'll go.
Those punks were aiming for your life.
So if you go, it could be dangerous...
I'm going.
Will you be alright alone?
I'll be back.
Like rain
falling endlessly,
you are falling deep into my heart.
Like sand
that cannot be counted,
my heart is brimming with you.
Days that were lonely,
tears that twisted and turned,
I'm sending them away planted in a smile.
Because my steps linger,
because my heart lingers,
it has taken so long to return.
Because of it, it aches, and I yearn,
that which tears even in laughter is my love.
Even if time halts,
even if my heart halts,
like a lie it will live in my embrace again.
I love you.
My heart jumps
for you only.
I've been waiting.
That royal throne.
This king's seat.  Would you like to sit in it?
Let's do this.
From now on, I will show proper decorum to you as the one from heaven who is to become the queen.
So you treat me as someone who is to become your husband and the king as well.
Here.
How do I look from there?
Imagine... I'm draped in Yongpo (king's garment)
and look clearly.
Here, tell me.
From what I see, you have a narcissistic personality disorder.
Greed for success.
Do whatever it takes for that success and lacking in empathy towards others.
Among patients who suffer from that, many think they themselves are geniuses.
Then let's do this.
Erase all moments prior to this moment.
Start anew as though we just met, you and me.
You poisoning me, I can forget it.
Since I am no longer in pain.
However.
You trying to kill that person.  I can't forgive.
I will think of it everytime I see you.
"This person tried to kill that person."
It's better to keep a feeling of such hidden.
Since it will be a great weakness of yours.
Let's go.
Where is she?
In there?
She went out.
To where?
To Prince Deokheung.
Prince Deokheung is being guarded by palace soldiers day and night.
Hence, let's sit and talk first.
Please sit.
That...
I can't.
I am unable to sit.
Were you always such a cheap ass?
Cheap ass?
An antidote that needed to be taken every three days for seven times total.
I knew from then.  The rest of my notebook.
You should just give all of it to me, but you go and save half of it?
So it was that.  The rest of the notebook.
Yea, that!
When are you going to give me the rest of what's mine?
Tell me the truth.
What's written in there?
That Prince Deokheung could never become king.
Hence you shouldn't dream in vain, and leave Goryeo.
How will you tell me properly?
If you give all the rest to me, I could let you know.
How about this?
The night we marry,
I will give it to you as a token.
It's dangerous.
Have them stop.  People are getting hurt!
That hand!
Move it.
Leave him be.
This man is a general.
I will ask you.
Did you say you would marry this person?
That's right.
Why?
That...
No matter how big your liver is,
this is the palace and I am the King's proxy.
Look at the eyes watching.
Be quiet.
I am talking to this person right now.
The moment you draw that sword,
it is treason for you.
For today, just go back.
I have my reason.
That so-called reason...
was it the price of my life?
Three days ago, in the morning,
I nearly died but lived.
Was that the condition this man put on you?
Or else, Imja...
would have no reason to do this.
Is that it?
If it is?
So that you can never menace this person...
Don't.
Don't do that.
Let's go.
Let's go... together.
The wedding will take place in over a month anyway.
And the gate to heaven will open before that so I can leave and that's the end.  I have thoughts too!
You called that thoughts?
Because there's some matter I need to accomplish here.
Tell me so we can do it together.
You wanted to flee from the start,
I'm aware of it.
From the very moment we met until now, Imja,
nearly died many times and not one day have you slept in ease.
You cried many times and that's all because of me.  I know that well, but...
still...
I can't leave you by the side of a punk like him.
Imja.
There's only a few days left before you will return.
Those days that are left,
I can't leave you by a punk like him, I'm saying.
Hence...
couldn't you be by my side?
Answering...
you won't?
I...
You know I came from heaven, right?
So even if I talk strangely,
you can roughly believe me, right?
Go ahead and speak.
The latter part of the notebook I so wanted to see.
In there, some person would fall into
a danger of death.  It was written in it.
And then?
Upon seeing that a few days ago,
I was able to save you.
That certain someone.
It was you, you see.
What are you talking about?  Why would I...
But I told you.
You are
very famous in heaven.
What I saw was only half.
But that rotten Prince Deokheung...
he's not giving me the remaining half.
But in there,
I think there might be another day recorded about you being in danger.
So I need that.
So then?
That's why you're saying you will remain here?
Just when I might die.  Because you want to know it?
In order for me to block it.
So then?
When does he say he will give you the latter?
Wedding day at night.
So you're going to wait until that night?
Before that, somehow...
How?
He is a punk that fed poison to Imja.
To a punk like him, so fearlessly...
marriage?
To save me?
Then do I feign ignorance when I can save you?
Just leave you be?
Think about it with our perspectives switched.
Right before I am to die, you can save me...
This hopeless person...
what am I to do with you.
Subtitles brought to you by 'The Faith' team@Viki.com
High Doctor is getting married to my Uncle...?
Did you know about this?
I heard it yesterday.
I couldn't believe it at all, so...
Since Your Majesty is staying out of the palace,
the engagement was done simply.
And he wished Your Majesty
to be the officiant for this marriage,
and hoped you would accept this request.
We came to escort you to the palace.
Why to the palace...?
Ah, I'm fine to be here, but why...?
Hey, I said I'm fine here.
Wait, wait!
Ah, I'm fine to be here, but why...?
Hey, I said I'm fine here.
Wait, wait!
We will move your belongings
you used here.
Returning to the palace?
If I say I want to return,
can I go?
If it's only returning to the palace, or...
Since my uncle, Prince Deokheung is sitting
on my throne with my permission,
I want to drag him out of there.
I understand.
Still, most of the Court subjects
would think of me
as a feeble-minded king who ran away.
You would need to filter out
those Court subjects one more time.
I heard that 2,000 of Royal Palace Guards
are supporting Prince Deokheung.
Those Royal Palace Guards,
I will try to bring them back to you.
Prince of the Court is still at Prince Deokheung's side, so his private soldiers are still threatening.
I will find a way.
Then, are you saying,
with 50 of Woodalchis,
you would fight against 2,000 of Royal Palace Guards and even the private soldiers of Prince of the Court?
I guess I need to find a way to not require us
to fight against them.
And these.
These are a few official positions.
I thought you would need them
when you make some move, General.
I heard about High Doctor.
What I'm saying is that I'm very anxious
if you would run away again with High Doctor.
Just for your information.
Oh, Lady Choi.
What on earth did you do?
I know...
I'm not even sure what I did...
Please take a seat.
Is the date set?
Well, the date or what-not,
I have no intention to get married.
For now, getting engaged,
but seeking the right timing to be disengaged.
Then, after that....
This is an engagement with Prince Deokheung, the only left Royal family except for His Majesty.
Disengagement?
Can't I?
Last night, did General Choi Young stop by?
Don't even talk about it.   Once he saw me,
he threw a fit,
and he said to come with him no matter what...
Come where?
So, I mean... run away...
If he runs away with a fiancee of the Royal family,
he will get a death sentence to have his limbs cut away..
I was sent by the Queen Her Highness,
to make you come to your senses.
Ah, wait!
So, I mean, I just said I would do that by words.
It's not like we had
some separate engagement ceremony,
and...
You've received the official letter
of marriage request.
I'm not good at Chinese characters,
so I didn't even think about reading it...
And you've already received
the wedding presents.
They just brought them without saying any...
Should I return them
although it's a bit late?
By the way, that guy, was he originally fearless,
ever since he was a little kid?
Do you mean Young?
When he was surrounded by soldiers,
how could he be like that,
seeing anything else?
If he ran away with me like that,
he would've become a criminal
committing a high treason.
That's right.
Ah, this guy, he's not listening to my plea,
nor my tears.
It's always just words that he would be careful!
Here I'm presenting the Royal Order
of His Majesty.
What are they talking about?
Wasn't Prince Deokheung here
the proxy for His Majesty?
We will receive His Majesty's Royal Order.
The King, His Majesty gave the order ;
From now on, all the Royal Orders would be proven by the new Royal Seal, "Goryeo Dynasty's New Seal".
As there should be only one Royal Seal
of one country,
he instructed to make sure there should
be no confusion in this subject.
The King, His Majesty, also gave this order;
From now on, His Majesty will resume
his governmental affairs,
and he has appreciated
Prince Deokheung's effort so far.
The Court subjects can attend
the morning meeting
in the separate palace
where His Majesty is staying now.
And the King, His Majesty, gave a new mission
to General Choi Young.
Choi Young will also have the position
in charge of Military Mobilization,
so he will stay in the palace
until the day when His Majesty returns to the palace,
and control the peace and order in the palace.
I will receive the Royal Order.
And I will execute the first step of that mission.
Prince Deokheung,
the seat you're sitting on now
is the throne that only His Majesty can sit on.
Please come down from it now.
As you know well,
I'm a very busy man.
As the knowledge of Heaven, which our High Doctor is giving me, is really huge, literally,
just writing it down itself is....
The King has changed his method.
Instead of coming back to the palace, he's thinking to pick things out of the palace, one by one.
Do you know whom he sent to command that?
Did that bastard appear again?
The first one that bastard would pick out
would be your High Doctor.
What should I do?
We have no other way.
I will strike the King.
However, I would need a justification to do so.
At least, he's a King of one country.
If the justification is too weak,
it will put me in a difficult position.
I will make that justification.
Ah, by the way,
did you say you set the wedding date
one and half month later from now?
Yes, so?
High Doctor said that the day that Heaven's gate opens is 2 months from now.
But somehow, I think she lied to us.
She's letting me know too many things
without any hesitance.
Then, the time when the Heaven's gate opens would be...
It can be...  soon.
Investigate the Royal Palace Guards and all Generals
who are at Prince Deokheung's side.
Yes.
There must be some groups which are resisting the order, so investigate that side, too.
I understand.
Dae Man, you should check thoroughly
where Prince Deokheung goes.
He is hiding something,
so I have to know where he's hiding that.
Yes, General!
Jeong Woo, you should take care of the private soldiers of Prince of the Court from Deokseong.
Yes.
My, you're working hard!
Evil one.
This is not someplace where you are welcome.
There's no such place!
They say the king who resides here doesn't block anyone.
Not even a slave, a butcher or a beggar.
The king is not blocking you.
But I'm going to have to block you a bit.
If someone trifles with me,
a lot of people will be hurt here.
Subtitles brought to you by Faith Team @ viki.com
What do you think?
In the interior and in the exterior each
there are 20 Woodalchi kids.
They are doing their reconnaissance separately.
Is that all of it?
That's as of right now.
What the... ?
It just requires the two of us.
That's what I'm saying.
Hey!
What are they doing here, huh?
It seems they came to spy.
What is it?
We thought we'd greet the king and came.
That's impossible.
Why?
Because I said no.
But I really want to have a real go at it today.
These days, my mood's been so-so too.
Let's go.
It's an explosive!
What are you looking for?
What are you doing here?
The book that you are looking for is not in here.
Really?
Then...
then in that room...
That rotten punk plays baduk in there by himself a lot.
He might have hidden it there.
Is there anything else in that book, that doesn't relate to me?
The days that tell when the Heaven's door will open for this world and the Heaven's world.
Anything that relates to you?
Is there anything that is written about you being in danger?
There is nothing like that!
If that is so...
then give up, that book.
But...
I am aware that Imja can see the future but never once have I coveted it.
Therefore...
give this up too.
This... is related to you.
I don't want to know.
It doesn't matter
about my death.
Then, what I can do for you,
would be nothing.
Soon, we have to part for real.
This isn't like others who fight and part,
but we can't go to each other again after drinking some alcohol either.
Nor is it possible to run to each other by coincidence.
It's to simply part for real.
But still...
on the other side of the brushwood,
that you are living,
and living well.
I have to be able to think that so how can I give up?
What is it!  In this night?
Eleven with rankings higher than general are assembled together.
Each and all of them have recently become abundant in family fortune.
Though they participated in Jo Il Shin's revolt, they were not reprimanded afterwards.
It seems they are the core that joined hands with Prince Deokheung.
The fireling and the pipeling went to Hyeongo Village.
And then?
They came and counted how many we were and left.
It's prepared.
It's been a long time,
Ahn Jae.
Choi Young, you're the one full of ups and downs.
So then?  What is it that you wanted to meet this secretly?
Oh, these are my comrades cum friends.
Then we'll get straight to the point.
You guys,
you traitors who pointed your swords at His Majesty the King to drive him out of the palace.
Right?
That's right.
To handle you guys, nine of my subordinates died.
And we, just under thirty.
I don't know just how much money your superiors stuffed themselves with.
A bit much.
Want to come back?
His Majesty the King is waiting.
Just because a few of us want to go,
he'll have us?
What if I make it so you can come?  Will you come?
About when is the day of the revolt?
As quickly as possible, even by a day only.
The roster of newly subsumed royal armymen.
Two in the ranking of Joongrangjang (level 5) and five in ranking of Rangjang (level 6).
Create the promotion roster in advance.
So we can use them in proper time.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Oh right.
The royal army will move, you say?
If I were Choi Young, I would carry out that matter.
To mobilize the royal army.
Then, attack the Hyeongo Village before the royal army moves to the King's side will do?
Is that possible?
And the justification?
On that day he will attend my wedding ceremony.
A simple ceremony held at Bojae Temple.
Upon completion of the wedding ceremony, my wife and I will return to the palace, however...
about then, the King would be...
He would die in the hands of the band of robbers.
Since our kids are now getting ready to be dressed as a band of robbers.
Upon completion of the state funeral, my queen would leave for a short trip.
You can take her then, to the heaven door.
I understand.
Then the wedding date...
Day after tomorrow.
Aren't you rushing too much?
As quickly as possible, even if only by a day.
There are many days left until the wedding day.
Isn't it okay to bring High Doctor back
until then?
There's no time.
You'd better be careful.
I am.  How can I be more careful?
Even if we are in the same palace,
I'm not even visiting her.
Don't lose your temper either, you punk!
Make sure to drag that Deokheung bastard out as a traitor, then bring her back.
If you succeed before the next full moon day, then...
The next full moon day....
is the day when that person
would return (to Heaven).
Is that so?
Have you asked...
if she has thought about staying here....?
She doesn't have any.
Not even a piece of heart
thinking to stay here...
I guess so...
considering what she had to go through here....
Please just find out where those generals
of the Royal Army might gather.
If we capture them one by one, their subordinates would get involved, so it will become bothersome.
When those heads gather in one place,
I will take care of them at once.
By the way, when I think about
what High Doctor said...
Translations brought to you by The Great Doctor Team at viki.com
Let's end it here.
What is the matter?
You never intended to have a marriage in the first place.
You just needed me to make a deal
with that Ajussi, Prince of the Court.
Don't you want to be the queen?
Didn't I tell you that you can never be the king?
Does that mean you don't need the book anymore?
Yes!
This is a problem.
I give up.
Would you teach me what that book means?
You never know, I might give it away to you for free
if you convince me well.
That's my homework.
Homework?
Someone left me homework.
That person must have thought
that I would solve that homework no matter what.
Then, you are going to give it up?
For the remaining time,
I'm thinking to stick to his side.
I don't know what the question on that homework was, but I might be able to solve its answer anyway.
So you are going to break this engagement?
Sorry, then...
It will become like this.
If you break this engagement, the reason will be because of your affair with the Woodalchi General.
In that case, for its punishment, you two would be demoted to the local provincial office's slave, if lightly,
or exiled.
But before that, Tae Hyeong. (Flogging)
Prince of the Court from Deokseong
wouldn't like that idea.
I can send you as a slave to that Prince of the Court from Deokseong.    Both of you.
As if that guy would get captured obediently
as a slave.
The King, His Majesty in Hyeongo Villiage.  The soldiers who are guarding there are just 50 people.
The Royal Army I have is 2,000 people.
If it becomes a matter of the life of the King,
he would kneel down.
That person Choi Young, like the last time,
he seemed to put the King ahead of you.
What is it?
They were the clothings of bandits.
More than hundreds.
- Dae Man.
- Yes.
I want you to run in the fastest speed
of your entire life.
- Go to His Majesty and tell him to start.
- Yes.
Dol Bae, go to Dan Ji and tell them that all operations would be moved up....
Lady Choi told me to relay this message.
Wait, what did you say?
There will be a wedding ceremony at Bojae Temple today.  Hence...
Now, what's going on right now?
I will escort High Doctor.
Where do you want me to bring her?
At Pyeonjeon, His Highness Prince Deokheung and the statesmen are waiting.
They will head to Bojae Temple together.
However...
she can't go like this.  It is still a wedding to His Highness the Prince, so she can't go dressed as this.
Hence...
All preparations have been finished at Bojae Temple.
First to move then at at that place...
What should I do?
400 of our troops have crossed Doeunggye.
As soon as they reach Balgye, they will change their attire and begin immediate attack.
What are you doing here?
They should be waiting outside.
About now, Hyeongo Village that the King resides in, will be besieged by my troops.
I told them to escort the King here alive.
Today is the wedding and a good day.
Without the wedding, there wouldn't be the good.
Just go and get it done.
You were startled, right?
It isn't too far to reach Bojae Temple.
Together with out statesmen, let's feel the autumn wind and walk.
What are you doing there?
On a joyous day like this, you intend to cause mayhem.
Hyeongo Village will suffer an attack.
I know.
That is why there is no time.
You should go.
There is no other way!
Thank you for watching with us.