Do you have pain-killers in the house?
- I don't think so.
Codeine?
Sorry.
What the hell happened?
- I have no idea.
Is this your place or mine?
Mine.
So that would make you...
- Jane.
So, then I am... of course...
Rick.
- Rick and Jane, right.
I remember it.
From last night, right?
Last night...
Yeah...
What happened?
That's what I just said, what happened?
Oh my God, my head...
Let me ask you a question.
- Ok.
We didn't...
Last night, I mean... we... didn't we...?
No.
Good.
Why good?
- Because I like to think that I will remember.
Who the hell is that?
-What time is it?
It's 4:37, Jesus Christ...
Don't move.
Sara? Is that you?
Honey, what's goimg on?
What happened to your face?
- Got wet.
Honey, how did you get here?
- Jane?
I screwed up.
- How did you screw up, honey?
He attacked me.
- Who attacked you?
The football player.
Penorisi?
Wait, what do you mean attacked?
- Let me here.
Is she alright? What Jesus, what
happened? What did he do, Sara? Tell me.
Just tell me.
What the hell are you doing?
- Bitch! Did you become crazy?
He fucking raped me.
What?!
You are fucking wasted here, I hate you!
Honey, you are scaring me.
Just try to calm down, ok?
This girl is psychotic.
- Rick, stop it!
Relax!
- He threw me on the ground.
What do you say? Did he forced you to fuck him?
- Rick, stop it! Just let her go. Stay out of here!
- What did she say?
Just leave us alone! You are making
her worse. Just get out of here.
Alright.
Take the jacket.
Alright, I'm going. But look at her face,
you need to get her to hospital.
Go, get out of here!
What happened?
- I don't know, Jane.
Ok, so let's go to my place
and we can see the boys later.
Yes, we're gonna have a great time tonight.
Come here at my desk, Gary!
- Have a nice weekend, counsellor.
If I'm a little bit late,
just let yourselves in, ok?
Ok. Bye.
And later, we'll go to the pool room.
I'm working there tonight.
No. Jane's with me at her house.
Yeah. Eight, nine...
Ok, then we'll just go from there.
People don't date anymore.
You know, I mean a sort of... go out with friends.
You meet in a restaurant
or a club.
Whatever, and then... everybody just... a sort of...
checks everybody else out and then things happen.
You know... people sort of... connect.
Or they don't.
So... you go out with your friends, right?
You hang out...
You're trying not to have that look on your face.
When you haven't been laid for six months,
you get a very desperate look.
Men see it and run.
I have seen women at a bar with
that look on them.
And you think:
she's waiting.
She's either, fucked up
or she is an actress.
Dating spells relationship.
But, if you're just hanging out with someone
and you know... you kind a fall to bed with him
But it's not like you're really involved. It's safer,
you know. It's just sex.
Ok, I got you. Nine o'clock.
Hey sweatheart, you know me. If there's pussy on
the menu, I am there. Out.
For me, it's not the question to date or not to date.
For me, it's a question of to hose or not to hose.
And I hate missing the opportunity.
I think important is a certain number of hosings
and each time you pass it up, it's gone forever.
It's like in porn, with a certain number of hard ons.
Maybe it's measured in courts... or in my case gallons... whatever.
As long as there's pussy on the menu?
- That's what he said.
Are you ready to go?
- Five minutes.
Hey, Rick, we're going to have Trent with me tonight.
- Yeah, well... maybe no one will notice him.
Hello. Mr. Thorpe, how are you doing?
What situation?
Right, Malaysia, yeah. I'm all over there,
I've been watching that, we come in right now.
You know... I work hard, I play hard.
When I go out with a bunch of guys,
I know where I want to end up. And it's not a bunch of guys.
I don't want to end up engaged and married, either.
I like to come.
That's my favorite part.
Shoot me.
I believe in courtship. I like dating... I mean,
I coudn't just jump in the bed with somebody.
Even if all you're after is just the sex.
I need that time. I need that... process... ritual.
It's not about getting close to someone, because you're not.
It's easy to think you're getting close to someone...cause
you're having sex with him. But see, that's the illusion.
Cause if you really get close to
everyone that you fucked...
...you wouldn't be this lonely, would you?
Lonely as this lonely does!
- Here is Friday evening.
KRCK k - Wreck radio, babe. Ok, we're talking shit,
what are you doing this weekend?
It's sunny and clear today, 70 degrees,
sunny and clear tomorrow, 70 degrees.
Sunny and clear Sunday, 70 degrees.
Absolutely man, look. If a woman gets you exited. And you
get an errection. If she doesn't have sex with you.
Your penis is going to fall off.
- That's true. That's a fact, it will fall off.
It has happened to a couple of friends of mine.
- I've had my blue balls so I know what you guys are talking about.
No, blue ball's nothing. We are talking about the penis
We are talking about the constant graining and the grouch
when the jeans' on, for now...
then the dirty girl dares look you in the eye and tell you she's not
gonna go down. - Oh, I hate life had to kill that one...
Break!
Can we please get back to your story?
Anyway, we're outside. And two of the friends come up.
So, just tell me exactly,
how drunk were you at this point?
Drunk? Rick, no no, see, Rick's not drunk at all.
Rick is a fucking shit can at this point.
With pure funk in me. Done. The only thing I'm thinking right now
is heil Mary up to God, I'm thinking, please...
...God, just, I want my dick dock before I pass out.
No, I mean, I like blow jobs, I do.
I mean, when you think about how all your senses are just
concentrated in your face and...
...put a front row seeded on a guy... I mean... what's not to like?
Some women don't want to.
Some women just won't.
Well personally, I mean, I like that power of it
that I am being in control.
Yap.
Yeah, you teeth are right there...
The problem is, once you get down there,
it's kind a awkward to stop, you know.
You have locked jaw,
your saliva is like coming out everywhere...
...you know, your eyes are watering... I mean, I've always
been thinking, am I doing this right?
Well, you learn.
Practice makes perfect.
I mean, the blow jobs I give today are a lot
different than the once I gave five years ago..
You know, there is this class now in L.A.,
it's a blow job class.
No way!
- It's true.
I have a friend, her boyfriend gave her
courses of that.
It just simply not all going to fit.
Now the other thing is that from a technique standpoint,
your hands and your mouth...
... are so much more versatile than your vagina.
Gotta be hands on. You gotta be using your hands.
There's a technique. Most women are just not aware of this.
Now what you are doing with this technique is
mimicing those sensations.
I think if you really analyze it, it's
a combination of technique and context.
It's what's being done, and actually where it's being done.
In a car. In a bathroom,
at a party.
Outdoors is good.
You know, you got people nearby.
The danger of being caught is very good.
I like that.
It's a combination of three things: one is the heat,
the second is the moisture and the third is the pressure.
Tongue, of course. Oh, and lips, oh yeah,
big, collagen, sucking lips.
Make the appointment,
pay the plastic surgeon. Just get it done.
Lips, tongue, hands.
No teeth.
What are you talking about? Teeth are the best.
First that had my nob showing...
she had braces.
Alright? My dick looked like a fucking chew toy,
but, you know, it was a... you know that sweet kind of pain.
The whole apparatus should come with a blue print.
Pictures and instructions... I mean... in English and Espanol.
And just some things that you gotta learn.
So really what you are doing, when you do these manual and
oral techniques, is you are mimicing those sensations.
And in essence, creating an imposter vagina.
Now, going forward with that, you've chosen your lubricans,
great. You have your dildo dejoured, great.
Now ladies, if you can put that all together. Ok?
So, like this... and come down.
You can actually... is that comfortable?
They were squealing there, "what's going on".
I'm like, hey, come on in, wanna have a look.
Hello, barkeep, let me get four J&Ds for me
and my boys here!
Hey, Penorisi!
Can I get a vodka soda, please, my love?
And Tenny, when you get the chance, can we get a Marlot,
a vodka wodka-tonic and a club soda for me.
Drink!
Yes, salut!
Cheers!
A need another Jim Beam here.
- You know... I'm sorry... I do not actually work here.
Well, make it for mine, for Christ sake.
Fucking aloman.
What?
- What?
This venom!
Haven't any food in my stomach.
I am Mikey, by the way.
Ricky being a raw peace of shit that he is.
Shit, I'm sorry. Mike, Shawn Denigan, works in my office.
Shawn, this is Mike Penorisi.
Alright, that's it. I just wanna get so fucked up.
I wanna sing and scream and dance all night long...
and pee in the bushes on the way home.
Do you know what do you need? - What?
- You need a new man.
See, that's exactly what I don't need.
Because you can't do shit with the man. Nothing.
I can remember you from Arizona State. This guy was
number one that came down from Georgia
This kid is everywhere. Tackles, picks...
- Football sucks.
Who is he play for?
- Raiders.
And he just signed a five million dollar
contract. And he is gorgeous.
Well, his wallet sounds... gorgeous.
- Yes, he sounds like just your type, Sara.
Shawn desperately wants to be a Raiders fan,
but he's canned.
Why's that?
- He hasn't kill anyone yet.
You peace of shit, come here!
Hey, guys, no, no... come on now!
Yeah well, that's the joke, right?
Two guys, that they are so in each other, that they wish
one of them had a vagina.
And when they both go to Sweden, they both
get it done to surprise the other one.
That's the joke.
Ricky ever tell you he was always the last one picked
for kick ball during recess.
The exchange students were making
fun of him.
Sorry about that, folks.
Just get this lovely couple around.
Yei, my favorite!
How many football players are coming tonight?
- Oh, the whole team's been working to do all of them.
Oh, yeah!
- How many is that?
So how many are gonna be there?
- Three, maybe four.
Good looking in this shit?
- What do you think?
How about that Shawn?
- Uhm, I don't think so.
He... he's the one that actually is Rick with.
They work together.
What's the name of this lawyer? This one you're after.
- Jane. Her name's Jane.
She's a... pretty special as a girl.
You'll see... you'll see when you meet her.
She clerks at the DEA's office, actually Shawn introduced us.
He's dating a friend of her, Sara.
Two lawyers in bed together.
Anyway Shawn is like the perfect gentleman.
He takes me to the most amazing places
What do you think? Pretty nice, a?
This is so beautiful.
He orders for both of us, he opens doors...
- You just like him because he orders appetizers.
Hey, I always said I would never marry a guy
unless he orders appetizers.
It is a true reflection of his lifestyle.
We should start with some appetizers, a?
- I love appetizers.
We are like twins together already, ok?
And the guy not even tried to kiss me.
Honey, he hasn't kissed you yet
because he respects you.
Can you understand my concept?
No!
I can't, you know, this whole 'nice guy' thing is just...
it's too much for me, you know... it's just... too personal.
Ain't a thing that you should worry about it.
I mean let's just go out tonight and have fun.
I like Shawn, I do, but... I don't know, I mean...
He doesn't even drink.
You know what? I mean... I haven't been to a club
since me and Keith broke up.
But that was three months ago.
Keith is nothing but a teenie memory now.
Very teenie.
You got to go?
- Yeah. Grab a bite to eat?
Alright, there's three guys, right?
Rick, Shawn and Mike.
Is there more?
- There is and there isn't.
Is he hot?
- Oh no, it's Trent.
No, no, please tell me it's not Trent.
What's up, nigger?
Holy fucking West Hollywood!
- Jesus Christ Trent what the hell you're thinking?
Dude, I ain't fucking eighteen, what do you
want me to do, go home and change?
Why would you even wear this for golf?
- Ah, excuse me, silence, alright?
Want another burrito, fat boy? - Fuck off steriod!
- Better be far than near me.
Hey, how is it going, pal?
I just made ten grand of this mexican conglomerate.
Fucking merger, I called it, dude. Stock has five percent
gabbled up and it's time to celebrate.
A little golf to bring with a country club, little blues, little pussy.
- Ehm, Mikey, boost boy.
Can I? - Go ahead.
- Thank you.
That's Trent, I like it.
- It's gonna get you GL wild.
Who I'm gonna fucking tonight? Whitney?
- Want to snap?
No she's all over my fucking shit last week.
She's grabbin' my hag and everything.
Oh yeah, Trent you gotta nice way with women there.
- It is a combo thing, sexy clothes, charming personality.
Fuck, you know what, I'm gonna see that pussy tonight and
I'm gonna fuck and swing my dick and you guys can eat baked hackoes.
I'll take a piss.
- I hope we don't beat the shit out of that guy.
What is so wrong with Trent?
- Oh my God! He's a fricandeau, Jane.
He was so drunk at this place when Eddie
was gazing at this woman...
...and smiled at us... like you must have been jealous or something.
Is that the guy we saw that night?
- Yeah, when we ended up at Cue's.
Oh, you had to see the girl... she was... uh...
That was so no girl, whatever it was.
I bet it was 60.
She had a vigorous bunch red fuzzy hair and the biggest...
like... her boobs, no joke, are like this big.
And his face was stuck in her cops.
- It was horrible!
Ok, you take your 20 year old, right?
- Yeah, great body... no contest.
You want skills, you gotta go at least 30, 35.
Now you gonna have to give a little bit of tongue for that, ok... because...
...you know... 30, 35, I don't care,
you go to jam her twice a day, three times a day doesn't matter.
Twenty year old body is going by by, alright?
But if you get over that visual thing and I tell you something, alright...
You have never had, what you have with a 40 year old woman...
if it's the right 40 year old woman.
And if you are ever fortunate enough to run into the right
50 year old woman...
...oh my God, you have no idea.
You got no fucking idea.
He was sucking her boobs in a bar?
- Yeah!
Then he passed out on them.
And then the bouncer kicked them both out.
Speaking of boobs... my here lay calm.
- Don't worry, they are still new.
I know, but they haven't loosened up at all. They are like
chunks of granit sticking out of my chest.
I still can't believe you make 3:40 at night working at this place.
- Then might she works hard.
No, I work hard.
She helds up the fucking teller.
Agip! How are you sweetie?
- Hey, how are you doing?
Looking good, looking good!
I didn't know you're working tonight. - Yap!
How many in your party?
- Four, ok?
Come on in ladies.
- Thank you.
We have no Trent, man? Didn't he get in?
- I don't know. He's right behind us, wasn't he?
Excuse me!
What do you guys make, make like what, ten bucks an hour?
- Hey no, it's a night job, buddy.
Oh, yeah, what are you doing on fucking days? Selling Groscard cookies?
Bake sails?
Provide newspapers? - Ey, you know what, I won't let you in,
even if I wanted you in. You're dressed like a fucking morron.
Fuck you, man!
Hey, don't forget your golf clubs next time!
- Posers!
Is Sara the one in the miniskirt?
She is fucking terrific, man!
Mikey! Three please... thank you.
Hey man, I want that Sara chick.
You'll know what I'm saying if you look at that shit.
She's taken bro', alright?
- By who? The charlatan next to you? Please.
Barkeep, shot please.
Shot of what?
- Tequila.
Aright. Let's go to work.
I think I will try. - Thank you.
- Thank you Whitney!
Shots comming aroung. Shots, boys.
I forgot, so what is it you got... an inspiring actress or...?
- Yeah. - That's great.
And you're the director?
- Right, right.
Well, I am available for sex.
- That would be wonderful, you know actually, you're perfect.
The guy over there has a number of different identities he can afford.
I'll be right back sweetie. - Ok.
There's something really basic and biological, I think,
about letting someone into your body.
You know, there is a... certain...
Loss of control.
Comes with that.
Sometimes you don't want to be in control.
Sometimes you just want to loose control
I don't want to get hurt by a woman.
So if I want to break down the wall, let her into the psyche, into the heart...
it's got to be the right person.
It... it's not a big deal to figure out who you wanna fuck.
But who you want to love either.
How do you figure that out?
Two for the road. Thank you.
Let's get out of here.
Miss Roboto.
Penorisi. Have another cocktail, why don't you?
Jesus Christ!
Men have sex, right?
Women have sex. Sure.
People fuck... it's absolutely correct.
But here is the thing...
Here is the thing in a nutshell...
Sex without love
equals violence.
There is no way around it.
Sex without love equals violence.
good sex,
bad sex
This isn't funny.
I have issues.
Well, at least you realize that you need to get youself some treatment.
- Dude, this clothes smell like fucking garbage.
I can smell it from here.
You clothes spent a night on the corner
of Florence and Normandy.
Wilshire and 6th.
What the hell is on Wilshire and 6th?
- Trust me. Absolutely nothing.
Where the hell have you been all night?
- Oh dude, you have no idea.
You've seen my Vicodin?
- No.
Thanks Trent, that's nice, now I know what to think of
before I try to come.
Who's that dude at the club last night...
that had all the bodyguards?
Some moviestar, I think.
Who's he freaking out about?
- Penorisi.
Penorisi got into a fight with one of the bodyguards.
Wait here, I'm going to sign out.
- Sara!
Here, I will make you feel better.
Baby you don't look so good. - I'm okay.
I left the jacket there with that guy.
Take it easy, a?
- You look cute.
Hey, here's the jacket. What's up Shawn, where've you been
all night big guy? I've been looking all over for you.
We're out of here!
The lead bodyguard, he's a... comes crashing to the dancefloor...
cut a little swaft through the crowd.
Penorisi, Jesus, have another cocktail, why don't you?
I've see the whole thing developing, so of course my puty ass makes away.
Here's your Vicodin.
These guys were beasts.
- Yeah, no they weren't small... make yourself useful there will you?
No, they weren't small.
That bodyguard couldn't get through, he came right to Mike
and pushed him... while Sara was still up on his shoulders
Penorisi, Jesus, have another cocktail, why don't you?
You man, get the fuck off the way.
So what happened?
- She fell right over the bar. Did you hear about that?
Give it to me.
You're alright?
Excuse me...
Come on!
- Let's go!
Outside. Right now!
Gonna make me your bitch?
Try to make me do it?
Enough!
What happened to you?
- Nothing.
Nothing.
You're okay?
Sure.
You want some?
- No, I don't drink.
Me either.
We better go back inside.
Sometimes there's just this need to come...
that just... something that takes over.
It really doesn't matter who, when, where or how... actualy.
It's actually not even about that. It's just...
...about coming.
The thing about it is this:
If a guy wants to come, he comes.
With a woman it takes a little bit of effort.
So, that's the least you can do,
it's... make the effort.
It's what women don't get, alright?
Guys like eating pussy. I speak for myself.
I like to take the paper bag down there and just huff. Ok?
I can do fucking spreadsheets down there.
Some women won't let you.
It can be a real issue with them.
But I tell you, I got to have that in my arsenal,
otherwise I'm... I'm out of there.
Just enjoy it too much.
I watch that. I hear them thinking, oh shit,
he's doing me, I got to do him.
They think that's something we don't like. But I ask you this:
is this something you would if you did not like it?
I have this ongoing discussion with my girlfriends,
about whether oral sex is sex or...
whether it's just a part of making up.
There's a wholeness of sexual acts that just
don't count as far as I'm concerned..
One is a blowjob... especially with someone you don't suit with.
Another would be... having sex in a foreign country
while on vacation. That doesn't count either.
But kissing someone you really like... that counts.
When woman has an orgasm, it's like a...
it's like a fucking earthquake, right?
I was doing this one Bertha, I swear to God
it was like a 7.5.
It's like I'm looking at my dick and...
Jesus why can't you do that?
I know some guys who... hide it when they come.
They literally... don't make a sound.
I mean, some women pretend that they're
coming when they are not.
But some men pretend they are not coming
when they are.
You're...
What?
You're alright?
Yeah... that was...
- Yeah...
I better run...
- Yeah.
Oh, Em, hey...
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I just get too drunk.
You ordered like... three bottles of red last night,
didn't you?
It wasn't all for me.
- Yeah I know but I...
I think maybe you should have just a glass
from now on and I mean...
You know it's not real... attractive... when you walk all night
with a bottle in your hand.
Come down to the gym with me.
We gotta get that poison out of you.
When are you gonna figure me out?
I need grease.
I need fries... and a big gope.
Please go with me. I hate going by myself.
At least you slept in a bed last night.
Where did you sleep?
- Fucking ghetto.
Which one?
- Dude, I past on it, alright... no money.
Must have been like a car accident or something, I don't exactly know
what happened cause... then I wake up.
Next thing I know I'm on a strech on my way
to the emergency room.
They tought you're one of the guys in the car accident?
- That thought I flew out of the window.
What did you do?
I went with them. Cause they... you know...
well they were going north, but...
I got out and... I made a couple of blocks but...
dude I had lied on it, I just couldn't walk.
Jesus Trent...
Why do you drink to troubling yourself into...
never seen anything like it.
Last night was like nothing I've ever seen.
How did you get home?
- I don't know.
I walked outside and I ran into Trent.
Oh please... no... tell me you didn't.
What? I mean... he was there and he said he was stranded.
She took you home?
- Dude I pound that, didn't I tell you that?
Shut up!
- I did.
I thought you slept in the ghetto?
- No no, before that.
You made love to Whitney?
- Yeah.
Intercourse?
Your penis penetrated her vagina?
- Yeah what... dude we had sex, so... yeah.
Hey, blondgirl.
Blondgirl!
Blondgirl.
So then what did you do?
- I searched her proper for a fucking rubber, that's what I do.
Dude I don't have one in my wallet, I didn't see one laying around.
- What do you expect... a drawer full?
No. You know what I thought?
Chicks have to start getting prepared, man.
I can't be responsible for everything.
But I'm ready to put a fucking sandwich bag on my dick,
that's how horney I am.
You're not getting.
- Dude, come on, you never did that before?
No, I see no concept of what you're talking about.
You take a sandwich bag, you slap in on your cock
as fast you have ever been.
That's the worst thing I've ever heard.
- I didn't do that every time I had a condom.
She can't figure out what's on my penis, alright.
And I wanna get laid, right? I am going to get laid.
So I check a medicine cabin... though
I had to do it first but...
...what I find is even better than baggies.
Better than baggies? - Yeah.
Alka Seltzer.
- What the hell are you talking about?
This is good alright. You take a pack of Alka Seltzer... right in front of her,
so she can see it.
You tear it open, and then you
pretend to put it on as it were a condom.
Wind up and get to go. She thinks she's protected...
it's dark and he can't tell shit from shine over.
And this works?
- Dude I don't know, I didn't even had the chance to try it.
Hey, blondgirl.
What the hell is that?
Keep the watch.
Oh my God look at you!
Ok, where we're going?
Oh that's good. Little lower'd be good too.
Yeah right there.
Ok, that's low enough.
I don't mind being tied up.
It is dangerous. It's about control.
I like that, I need that.
Locked up very big like that.
No, I haven't been lucky enough to be tied up yet.
But I am still young.
What's your name anyway?
You dirty little whore.
Oh, that's good.
Bondage is ok. I can get me do that. But I don't know about spankink...
I just... I would feel ridiculous.
I'm gonna make you pay for that.
Hot wax is good.
Feathers are good. Ice can be good.
Fuck what was that movie?
More and more guys are into this. I mean, I didn't have any idea
it was such a turn on.
Oh that's good. Yeah. Little lower.
Oh you wouldn't...
Oh you would!
I mean I didn't even know that this had a name.
Around the world... rimming, butt sucking...
whatever you want to call it.
How do you do?
Shakespeare said of this:
Her tongue in your tail.
I'm sorry, I'm not... I'm not sure what we're talking about here?
I think that penetration is interesting for everybody.
I mean even for men.
Because... the prostata is like a g-spot.
And when a man comes close to orgasm
it is the same thing.
I mean the pressure is applied.
Yes officer! ID's in the glove compartment.
A little finger action of the but at the right moment?
Fuck yeah!
The best thing is... that I still get the Alka Seltzer...
you know that's good right now.
Thank's dude.
Where have you been?
I've been callling you all morning.
How's your hang over?
Mine, too.
I've been at hospital all night.
- Why?
I don't know how to say this, but
something happened to Sara last night.
What did he do Sara? Tell me.
Just leave us alone, God, don't you see you're
making her worse. Just get out of here.
Here honey, go. Sit down for a second.
It's okay.
She went to the police. She's charging him.
For the rape.
Oh my God!
I knew something was wrong.
Where is he now?
- He's in jail.
The cops picked him up at some burger join afterwards.
Grabed him for a fucking burger.
The police coming...
Hurry, hurry.
Does he have a weapon?
Don't move or got damage!
Give me a couple of seconds, fellows.
My fries are almost up.
Do you want it?
Jesus Christ, don't tell me you believe
this fucking bullshit?
Why shouldn't we, big boy?
- Stop calling me big boy, you fat fuck!
Mike, be polite.
Pondered her face against the head port? Jesus!
She must have given you two quite an incredible performance.
At least she talked to us. She didn't need a God damn lawyer.
- Not being accused of anything asshole!
Mike stop it, please!
Excuse me.
If he wants to talk, let him talk.
Hey, she told she's an actress, right?
Studies in Beverly Hills, did she tell you that?
We know all about her.
- We want to know about you... besides what we hear on ESPN.
I think you could be nominated for a freacken Academy Award.
- Mike, would you please shut the fuck up!
Look, an attorney will be here
within moments for my fellow, if you just...
No no no! I got my rights.
I did not rape Sara... what's her face? Ok?
While feminist bitches might say otherwise,
they don't know shit, they think holding hands is a freaking rape.
Mike, look, I'm sorry, but you're a fucking idiot!
Listen to yourself!
Ok, here's the tale. This is the way it happened.
Sara, what's her face, and I go down by the water.
Down by her place.
We're kissing, we're hooking up, we're making out...
This girl is all over me, all over me.
Then what happened?
- It starts to rain. She wants to go inside, so we did.
Come on, let's get out of here!
I'm leaving.
- Oh no.
Going home, good night, thank you very much, good night.
- Good night.
Me so tired.
Harder, harder.
And you didn't make any moves before you went to the bedroom?
- Yeah, I kissed her probably, normal stuff.
Hickeys all over her neck. - Only because this psycho begged me to.
She wanted that marks on her neck, to show her stupid boyfriend.
Look. She takes off my clothes. I take off hers.
One thing leads to another. And we fuck.
Not all this whore shit that I forced myself on her,
come on man, I play for the Raiders.
Here we go, you can get a piece of ass anytime you like, right?
She never said no, alright?
She said a lot of things, but none of them sounded like no.
Mike, stick to the specifics, please.
- Fuck specifics, Rick! Fuck them!
I want to say this.
On behalf of all the guys who have to deal with this shit
and these two cops know what I'm talking about, they've been there.
Shit, we all have.
You go out with some chick, right? And she says
nothing's gonna happen, right? Wrong.
What do you do... you warm her up with a little forplay. You show her that
no way this is gonna be a one night stand, and before you know, you're fucking caved.
They are doing the horizontal shuffle on their lovin'
every 30 seconds of it. And it's always the same old story.
Oh my God! Nothing is gonna happen, ok. I can't do this. Oh my God!
Oh my God, go get a condom.
Good yes. We don't have one? That's ok we don't need one.
I can't believe I'm doing this. I'm such a good girl. Oh God, I never do this.
Look, can we stop this now?
- Let him talk for Christ sake!
Mike... I can't believe you're in your fucking grave here Mike.
What did I do wrong Rick?
You tell me what did I do wrong.
Sara asked me if I had protection.
I said I didn't.
So I'm expecting she's gonna say, no glove no love.
She hasn't say a thing.
Have you a condoom?
- No, no, I'm sorry.
She wanted me, I wanted her.
Ok? What happened? You hit your head? -Yeah.
- You're alright? - Yes, let us stop.
Alright. That's it. Pull down.
Hey, cowboy!
- We're done.
We're not done untill we say it's done.
She was crazy, man.
She looks normal but deep down she is... God!
Yapping about her old boyfriend the whole time... begging me to
suck her neck. The whole time I'm thinking...
...this chick is a fucking psycho.
She wanted to get back at this Keith for dumping her.
There is another reason why did she get so upset.
And this is sick in the head.
Sure you don't wanna come? How would you not be starving?
- I'm positive.
Right before I left her place to get a fucking cheeseburger...
Good night, Whitney.
I called her own name.
Just get the fuck out. Whitney. Get the fuck out!
I called her Whitney.
Get the fuck out of here! God damn it!
And that's why we are here.
Because I mistook her for one of her dope friends.
Oh, shit!
What do we know about Sara?
- Just what she said when I took her to the hospital.
Is she okay?
- She has a... like a bump here with a cut...
And here she has some cuts...
some hickies on the neck
Sara, I am dr. Cook. -Quietly.
- It's ok.
It's alright.
It's just the doctor, she's just gonna help you.
It is a safe place. Come sit. Sara you're on a safe place.
- Just stop!
Come sit, alright?
Now the three of us are gonna take off
your jacket together, ok?
Excuse me, nurse. Can her father give us a statement, please?
Can wespeak to Mr. Olswang? - Stand back, please!
I thought I could trust him, you know.
I thought that he would never do something like this,
he'd never want to screw up his carrier like this.
Alright, that's... that's enough.
- I'm sorry, but we have...
No, don't tell me you're sorry! You're not sorry, you don't know what sorry is!
Sorry is when the son of the bitch is in jail for the rest of his life.
Sir...
Would you like to wait outside, sir?
It's okay.
- Yeah.
You're sure?
- You're alright?
I'm okay.
I wish just... really scared.
We got back to my apartment...
...around 3... 3:15.
We walked down, by the ocean road.
He was very aggressive.
Then it started to rain.
Come on! We go to your place.
So, just to get out of there we went back to my appartment.
Look, you should go, it's late...
No, wait, please... one second, one second please,
I'm showered to the bone, come here!
We got together a little bit.
It was okay. Except his breath made me kind a noxious.
A lot of boosts?
He tried to deal my bra.
But... he was so wasted that I had to do it myself.
Get this thing off, get this thing off!
- Yeah yeah, I'll take it off, ok, i'll take it off.
I didn't mind that, cause I knew I wasn't
gonna let him go any further.
I just wanted to do to sleep.
- Where were you at this time?
My apartment.
Where in your appartment?
- The living room.
Ok.
He started getting out of control.
He shrugged his hand off my skirt.
He kept saying that he was really horney though.
And that he was gonna get off with or without me.
Leave!
- Please, I'm gonna get off with or without you.
I told him that it would definitely be without me.
So then he took me...
and grabbed me... and dragged me into my room.
And threw me on the bed...
like I was some kind of fucking football doll.
He pulled my panties aside.
He stabbed it between my legs and he...
I couldn't stop him,
I tried it.
A few minutes went by...
...and he had that orgasm...
and then he left.
Have we got evidence of penetration?
- Yes we do, officer.
Semen?
- Yes.
Can we have a minute?
Please, Mr. Olswang.
This is not gonna be easy.
- This guy, Penorisi, he's got a high profile.
I don't care if he's God damn Joe Montana.
What's up bro?
Dude, what's happening?
That Mike guy... supposedly... raped Sara last night.
Oh, holy fuck.
Dude, I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ!
I should have done something, I mean...
I should have stopped her from getting in the car with him.
Oh, yeah... oh, dude, I can see that happen.
I can totally see that guy doing something like that.
Fuck!
Fuck, what happens now?
I meet a woman in a bar.
She says to me: I'm not wearing any underwear.
What am I supposed to think?
I'm gonna think she's gonna come across.
Women head on me all the time.
And they are not interested in my mind.
There's something about having sex forced on you.
That does cut the chase.
You're having taken your responsability for him.
I'm talking about fantasies now.
This is not an invitation to rape.
I'm just saying... that's why the rape fantasy's so appealing.
When you're a kid it's a game.
First base, second base, third base.
And if a guy hits a homerun with a girl
then he's a winner.
And she's a slut.
It really ain't different now.
Just came right from the station.
- Yeah, thanks bud.
Here's the grand.
- No, no, it's alright, thanks.
Where is she?
And I don't give a shit,
I want his fucking neck broken.
Hey, look me in the eye. - Ok.
- And just tell the truth. - Ok.
With all these lawyers you have to be strait. - Yeah.
- You have to have your stories strait.
Yeah, I hear you.
I tell you boys, don't tell me how tough it is,
I want to know what makes his dick hard.
It's okay.
Hi sweetheart. - Hi.
- We need to talk for a second, ok? Come here.
We're charged with one kind of sexual assault
and one kind of rape.
That's twenty years per count in State of California.
That's just what you're up against.
Everything that you've ever done in your life
will be dug up and used against you.
But you have to know your side of the story,
then you have to let them go after her.
What do you think they're gonna dig up on me Jane?
- Dear, what would they ask?
What does it matter what they fucking ask?
The guy is a son of the bitch who should be executed.
Yeah, we know that, Emma, but if you knew anything
about how a legal system works, you'd know that's not the issue.
The issue is if she was raped. How do you prove that
in a court of law, that is the issue.
If? If I was raped?
Yeah, Jane. Ask me.
Ask me what you think that they would ask.
How did you get home?
- We took a cab to her place.
Who paid for it?
- I did.
It's a long ride to Santa Monica. How much was it?
- 25 dollars, with the tip.
Pre-eve of your paying for the cab right on, what exactly did you think was gona happen?
So what happened when you got there?
- We went down to the beach. - And...?
And... we got together... I guess.
No no, Mike, how did you get together? Did you kissed?
Did you balled her? Did you fuck her in the sand?
What? You got to tell me.
- We kissed and...
He kissed you where? Standind up? Sitting down?
- Down. We were down in the sand.
And?
- And... we dry-humped.
What is that mean?
- We had sex with our clothes on.
Okay.
And it started to rain,
and she wanted to go inside.
And then you went back to the appartment?
- And he came inside.
Ok, so you were inside the appartment?
What happened next?
I was little drunk, Jane.
- Have you ever been really drunk?
What do you mean?
Well, have you ever had a black-out? - Jane!
A lapse in your memory. Do you know what a black-out is, don't you?
Jane don't.
- Why not?
Alright, look, you started making love. Then what happened?
I don't know. - What do you mean?
- I don't know what happened.
I don't understand you.
- Passed on hard, Ricky, and then I can't remember.
You know what a black-out is, don't you?
- I don't get like that.
What do you say? You don't know?
Okay.
I don't.
Gina Perry's birthday party.
Don't you remember you sort of blacked-out... in the noon party?
What are you doing?
- He writes something on my face.
Hey, fuck of!
Hey honey, why don't we go to the bathroom...
And then the night that you broke up with Keith.
You had alcohol poisoning. We took you to the hospital
and they pumped your stomach.
Don't you remember how mad you were... the next day?
Honey, the court will have records of all that stuff.
- I don't remember.
I didn't rape her, Rick.
I know I didn't rape her.
Did you blacked-out with Mike Penorisi?
Look at me. Look at me.
Sara, look at me.
You didn't blacked-out, did you?
Honey, just look at me. What you told me
in the hospital. That's what really happened, right?
I don't remember, ok?
I'm telling you, I don't remember.
You want the truth? There it is.
Look at me.
Shut your fucking mouth and you listen to me!
I understand your plaintive sympathise.
But I'm telling you right now brother, as your friend...
The judge in the jury are gonna throw the book at 'I don't remember'!
My mind's blank, man.
- Yeah, you were really eloquent with the cops last night!
I can't remember.
Look at me and answer the question!
God damn it Michael!
You're accusing somebody of a felony!
I swear to God, you will do prison-time,
unless you remember exactly what happened!
Did you hear this stop!
Jane, are you trying to tell me that
I should just let him walk?
You're a stupid son of a bitch, you know that?
What do you want me to say, Ricky?
Just tell me what you want me to say and I'll say it.
Alright.
Alright look... let us go through the basics, right?
Now, what happened in the bedroom?
We had sex.
- Ok.
What kind of sex did you have?
- Missionary.
No Mike. Not what position.
Was the sex consented?
Yeah.
So, what kind of sex did you have?
- Consensual sex.
We had consensual sex.
- That's perfect. That's exactly how you say it.
You didn't say yes or indicated any kind of consent, is that right?
- Right.
And that's what you say. Ok?
You told him no. You resisted.
And he forced himself on you.
Yes.
Yeah, that's good. That's really good,
that's exactly what I'll say.
No, Mike. You'll say it because it's true.
- It is. Sure, it's true. Rick, it is.
Mike look at me.
It is true isn't it?
Jane...
You still don't believe me, do you?
You don't believe that it really happened.
- Did it Sara?
Cause if you say it did, then I believe you.
Sara...
Hey. Hi.
God, I'm so sorry about last night.
- Yeah, me too.
Hey, blondgirl.
- Hey. How is it going?
I should have been looking out for you.
It's okay.
Gonna be alright?
- Yeah, I'll be fine.
Who made the first move? She...
Hi, it's Jane. Please leave your name and number and I'll call you back.
- Hi. It's Rick.
I'm just calling to say...
I don't know what to say actually...
Cause everything what I want to say will take more time
than I have on this machine.
I just... thought we were close to something.
You and me, you know I...
I just thought we had a chance.
I just... hate to loose that.
So call me, will you?
I Don't want this thing come between us. Please.
Ok. Bye.
It'll be Mike Penorisi date rape case.
Lack of evidence and confuted he-said, she-said testimony
led yesterday to a hung jury in a much publicised trial.
I don't understand people who are afraid of sex.
Because sex is not dangerous.
It's not bad for your.
Here is AIDS, right AIDS... accepted that.
So fine, alright. Let's don't have sex. Why have sex?
Whatever you wanna do, it's not that a big deal.
And you say people that they say what they really want is...
they wanna... they wanna be in love.
I think if you wanna be scared of something
you'd be scared of that shit cause that's... hi-tech.
Yeah, love is dangerous.
But people survive.
There is a... pain...
You have a... compromise and sacrifice and... and hardship.
But it's all just... speed bumps.
I have this nightmare... I have sex with some guy and...
...the next day he won't leave.
He's in... my bedroom and he's in my bathroom and
he's in my serial...
...and I just... I can't get rid of him and he just
keeps getting bigger and bigger and bigger...
...until I can't breathe.
Yeah... I can separate sex and love.
But I still want to love... you know,
cause it's the love that makes you vulnerable.
It's love that makes you hurt.
And it's the hurt that a... that makes you know...
that you're still alive.
There is always a door
you do not want to open.
Or place you don't wanna go.
A question you don't
wanna answer or...
...one word that you just don't wanna hear.
Because if you do... you know you'll never be the same.