You Who Came From the Stars
Please look over here!
Excuse me!
Are you saying she eventually went
aboard that boat wearing those shoes?
Yes.
And, you're still here?!
Will you be okay not going?
Lawyer Jang.
Yes?
I've lived in this place for 400 years.
There's been many, many occurrences.
Some too awful even to be imagined.
Mother, Father! I've come home!
I've come home! Mother!
My Lady!
My Lord! The lady has returned!
The Lady, who was said to have
died, has returned!
My Lord! Please come out!
My Lord!
Mother!
What has happened, my daughter?
With only knowing that you had died, I prayed so
much that you did not die a painful death.
Let me look at your face.
I did almost die, Mother.
The in-laws tried to kill me.
To get what they want for 'A Virtuous Woman'.
Oh, my goodness.
Is there not anywhere you've been hurt?
Yes. I'm fine, Father.
The man over there saved me
and helped me return here.
That man is my life's savior.
I shoulder a great gratitude towards you
for saving my daughter.
I don't know what I should do to repay you.
I hope that you'll think of this place as your own home
while you're here. Please eat and rest comfortably.
Why...?
Living in a dirty manner,
is not better than dying cleanly.
This is what I've taught you.
You've defiled your body
and soiled this household's honor with embarrassment.
Knowing this, how could you have
stepped foot back into this house?
Mother...
Die!
You are already a dead daughter to the nation, so just die!
Please!
Please save me! Save me!
Hurry and run away.
Go, hurry!
If your father comes, you and I will
both die in his hands.
I argued with him that if we were to
kill our child, I would do it myself.
Go already!
Go anywhere
and live in secrecy as if you were dead.
Mother.
Why did you bring an unknown stranger with you?
To your father, the family's honor is
more important than his child's life.
Did you really not know that?
That person...is someone who saved my life...
Mother! What about that person?
What happened to that person?
Is he not dead yet?
What is going on?
He ate the rice porridge with the poison.
He should have died by now.
So, I'm not sure why he isn't dead.
The pharmacists don't have any idea why, either.
The pain that I thought I would never forget
passed away over time.
I don't really understand since
I haven't lived such a long time.
But I do get these thoughts as I live.
People...
live really diligently even though
they know they're going to die.
Even though they know they will break up at some point,
when they love, they love like
there's no tomorrow.
These childish beings are exactly what people are.
Things will get better as time passes.
It could even become as if it never happened.
But...although the future is important,
isn't the present just as important?
Are you confident that you will be okay
if something bad really does happen to that person?
The child star, Cheon Song Yi, who became famous with her popular chocolate CF, made her first drama appearance
in a historical drama that would have been
difficult even for an adult actress.
Aside from the fact that she was the main character's child actress, despite her young age,
she became a high class star
with her mature and graceful image.
All the dramas and movies she has
acted in have been hits.
Even now, she is continuing to show
herself as the nation's very own 'goddess'.
First love?
Ah, the question is so tacky!
Ah, first love...
Well, I have gone on a couple of dates,
but there's no one who I would
call my 'first love' yet.
Although, when I was young, there was a time
when I could have gotten into a big accident.
But, there was a man who saved me.
I can't really think of his face, but he was
rather tall, and he was the warm, gentle type.
It was the best.
Though it was just a short moment,
it was very mysterious,
and warm at the same time.
I still remember it.
I don't know if that man will remember me though.
But you know, if I see that person, I
think I would recognize him immediately.
Just like 'Fate'.
60 hours later
With the bizarre case that top actress'
been missing during cruise party
The whole country's been restless for 3 days.
When searching around the Han River at 4pm today
to the south of Seo Gang University,
a body was found
The body is being identified.
A lot of reporters are waiting at the scene
and trying to get a hold of what happened.
My Love From the Star
Episode 4
Did you check the identification?
We're investigating. We're investigating.
Why are you being like this? I'm going to die.
I won't do it.
From my experience this is a suicide for sure.
She was taking antidepressants,
and she even left a twitter message a few days before she died saying
"what should I do when it's so hard to live".
I listened to all the people at the site.
They said she was really drunk. Really drunk.
The answer comes out immediately.
A top actress could not overcome depression,
and suicided because of alcohol. This is it.
Our prosecutor is new
so he's over-passionate.
He wants to know as much as he can for now.
Why does a case like this have to happen in our area?
I can't work because of the reporters.
We have to end the case soon.
What are you doing?
Here.
You're Officer Park, right?
- Nice to meet you. I am...
- Yeah I know. Thank you.
Could you please finish this case soon?
Bereaved families don't want to carry out autopsy.
According to forensics, there was no sign of resistance.
She was not hit by any object either.
- It's like that.
- Oh is that so?
It's so obvious.
- From my experience, this is definitely...
- Should we start from checking the CCTV?
I already kind of
checked all of it.
- You can't kind of checked it.
You have to check it carefully.
There were 7 people invited in total on that day.
After checking all their identification
They entered.
It was a place where no one could go in
except guests and workers.
The bride and the groom were stars and they were related to conglomerates so
If you see the guest's faces
you recognize them. Most of the people there were like that.
This is a red carpet.
The day of the incident
Oh so cold.
Look at the goosebumps on my arm.
I'm so cold.
Who told you to wear something so revealing?
Wear the ones with long sleeves. Like turtle necks that come up to here.
I'm so cold.
Why can't the managers come in?
They're worried that pictures leak out.
- Why are they making such a big fuss?
- That's right.
Let's not make a big fuss and get through this quietly.
Like at a Catholic church. So the right mood would resonate.
Please do that. I'll elegantly bring lots of money
And go for sure.
- I'll be sad if you're just saying empty words.
- I don't say things like empty words.
- Oh Oppa.
- Hyung.
- Hello Oppa.
- It's been such a long time.
- You're doing well, right?
- Yes. Good to see you.
By the way, I'm curious about something.
Do you have someone you're dating?
- Why?
- It's just that Han Yoo Ra
said she was going to marry a guy from SC Group.
There's only two sons in that household. You and
Hui Kyeong.
It's not me. I don't even know Han Yoo Ra.
If you're talking about Han Yoo Ra, then she's our department store's model,
but I just know her face.
I know, right? Han Yoo Ra. I knew it.
How can she lie so sincerely?
Try acting like that.
Hey. People are watching.
There're rumors that you're not friendly with Han Yoo Ra already.
It's true that we don't get along.
Where's the waiting room for a bride?
Omo Unni.
You're probably busy preparing for the wedding.
When did you go and come back from the hospital?
Your that assiduous part is
Something I should emulate.
I changed a bit. Does it look okay?
You look so young that Suzy will come
and try to be friends with you.
Hey, it's not that good.
Congratulations Seo Young.
Thank you.
Oh right.
I'm going to get your bouquet.
Na Rae Mi said she was catching my bouquet.
She said she broke up with her boyfriend.
Then what about you? Do you have someone?
Are you going to get married?
You're doing fireworks at midnight?
Yes.
Keep your expectations up.
There will be a surprise announcement at that time.
You're holding an event at other people's weddings?
You're copying other people's shoes too now?
I didn't copy anybody.
- I am the first one in our nation to...
- Why do you guys fight whenever you meet?
Just stand at the side. We're going to take pictures.
- Please take a picture of us.
- Yes.
Please gather closely around the bride.
What are you guys doing?
Please take it. Now.
I closed my eyes. Take one more please.
So pretty.
We're taking a picture. Look here please. 1, 2, 3.
Where's Han Yoo Ra?
I haven't seen her. Why?
I met her in the restroom a while ago. She left this.
Did you guys fight again?
Am I somebody that fights every day?
I'm hungry. Is this all?
You want something else?
They have foie gras and caviar.
You eat those things.
Excuse me.
Do you have spoon worms here?
Excuse me?
Hey. Why are you looking for things like that here?
We are next to the water. Shouldn't I eat that at least?
Soju and spoon warms. Perfect fit.
Why?
Are you embarrassed of me?
No.
Director Park?
How have you been?
You're making a new movie, right?
I saw the scenario. It was really good.
Why was that sent to you?
We were thoroughly on the security.
What?
You gave it to Song Yi.
I saw a bit of it while Song Yi was reading it.
If you have a good role, call me too please.
Yes. We'll see.
Sometime
you should come over and have a drink.
Pardon?
You told me to call you over.
I'll call you sometime, so just come.
Is that movie even going to be crank in?
You can make it only if someone invests.
Director Park Yoo Kon, your movie can be made only if S&amp;C Entertainment invests in it.
If they don't invest, then you can't make it.
Who are you?
I'm S&amp;C Lee Hwi Kyeong's younger brother Lee Hui Kyeong.
My brother decided to invest in something like this,
but that guy has no artistic sense so he doesn't know much about art.
He always asks me to tell him if its interesting or not.
I saw the scenario.
It was boring.
So I told him to not invest.
I did that.
Hey.
- Why did you do that?
- Why else?
Have you not heard the rumors about him?
He's like a gangster.
Don't come into contact with guys like that. Got it?
I got it. Let go of this.
And also, apart from me, all men are wolves.
If you ever get a boyfriend, tell me.
After I get to see him and say he's fine,
you can date him only then.
Who do you think you are?
Me?
I'm...
your BFF's soon to be husband.
By the way, where did your BFF go?
She went to get a drink.
Again?
Ah, Cheon Song Yi.
Is she a goddess of alcohol or something?
How come she must see the end whenever she drinks?
Song Yi, it's dangerous over ther-
Hey, be careful.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Where did Song Yi go?
You said she went to drink.
She was there just a moment ago.
Did something happen?
There's still an hour left until it's over.
It seems like someone's disappeared.
A person? Who?
Hey, Se Mi. Did something happen?
Song Yi has disappeared.
We can't find no matter how hard we look.
What? My Nuna?
And...Yu Ra has disappeared too.
People are looking for them inside, right now.
What?
Cheon Song Yi!
This way.
How much did you drink?
At the moment, it was 1:42 AM.
Ms. Cheon Song Yi was the last person to get off the cruise.
Prosecutor Yoo Seok
We investigated later but couldn't find Han Yoo Ra.
What is the estimated time of the death?
Ah, this.
The last time she was seen...
Ah,
she was last in the women's toilets with Cheon Song Yi.
I heard they fought a little then.
And that was around 11:30PM, they said.
Since people found out that Han Yu Ra disappeared around 12:30,
then during that one hour this incident occurred.
Aigoo. Prosecutor, reporters keep calling me.
They're asking if it's because of Cheon Song Yi that Han Yu Ra became like that.
How is Han Yu Ra dying because of Cheon Song Yi?
I don't know. Their relationship wasn't very good or something. Anyway, that's what the rumours say.
The worse rumors the stronger.
A long time ago, at the well in town,
all rumours started.
Nowadays, instead of at the well,
around coffee vending machines, cafes, pubs,
rest area, internet blogs, and so on.
Anywhere people hang around and rest,
rumours start.
To the extent that they could kill a person,
those deadly rumors.
Did you hear that?
After Han Yoo Ra was fed up with Cheon Song Yi,
she committed suicide because her depression got worse.
I heard she (Cheon Song Yi) harassed (Han Yoo Ra) a lot.
Really?
Cheon Song Yi didn't come to school today, right?
After doing such thing, wouldn't it be even more weird if she wanders about?
Have you seen the video uploaded on YouTube?
Cheon Song Yi is really no joke.
What is it, what is it?
Look.
How is it that when people get together, they talk about me and my dramas?
It seems they have nothing better to talk about.
Fine.
Oh my, she's no joke.
With doing rating 4% drama, who doesn't even know who started and ended
More than no-one knowing it.
Ah, that's right.
Your drama just finished at 4% ratings, right?
Oh my.
I really don't get women. Seriously.
I'm speechless.
Aigoo, it's a big problem.
Oppa, I brought this juice for you.
This afternoon, at the Han River, the corpse found
was revealed to be top talent Han Yoo Ra.
Ms. Han attended actress Noh So Young's
wedding on the 23rd
And went missing. So the police started their investigation after her manager reported.
Many people are in a shock by the death of an actress who remained in the top for a long time.
There's been an assumption that Han Yoo Ra's death is caused by a troubles between her and an actress Ms. C.
Yoo Ra had depression.
But it's true that it got worse because of Cheon Song Yi.
[Park Il Woo, Han Yoo Ra's manager]
Honestly, being humiliated and talked down at in front of everyone, by someone younger than yourself,
who wouldn't be angry?
Because our Yu Ra was kind hearted,
she tried so hard to endure, but
even the day before she died, she said that because of OOO,
she was having a really hard time.
Eish!
It's shocking that the dead body found in the river was the top actress, Han Yoo Ra.
Don't exchange the mangas secretly.
Please don't do that!
You, who play billiards with Tiger Woods and get your computer fixed by Steve Jobs, shouldn't do that.
That's only 80 cents.
You know, those who owns a lot (wealthy) are supposed to be worse.
Do you know money is earned from nothing?
But, what happened?
So they are saying that Han Yoo Ra committed suicide
because Cheon Song Yi harassed her, right?
Cheon Song Yi is really evil.
I was planning to marry her, I guess I have to
remove her from my "womens list".
Hey! It's true that Cheon Song Yi has a bad personality,
but she's not that sort of a person!
She's one of my friends, so I know her well.
Why are you laughing?
You told us not to lie, but you're saying she's your friend?
You've gone too far, too far. Why?
You should just say Chun Song Yi comes here often.
What a lie, really.
The articles aren't very good.
The public is also deteriorating.
Reporter Choi, you won't answer your phone?
You only call me Hyungnim when I buy you drinks and play golf with you?
Bomi, hurry. Go to Song Yi's house and protect her.
If reporters bulge in, it'll be out of control.
Yes!
Nuna.
What?
Come to the back parking lot, hurry!
Why? Did filming get scheduled?
Have you not seen the news?
She died?
Yes.
How? Was it an accident?
What happened?
We don't know that much yet.
Why?
Firstly, come out.
The reporters are going up so hurry!
Quickly take the elevator! Quickly!
I'm going you bastard!
No! Not the elevator!
No? Why not?
The reporters have taken the elevator.
The emergency exit!
The emergency exit?
No!
No? No? What is it now?
A few have gone up that way too.
Just go back inside for now.
Go back in?
Hey! Why do I have to run away?
Can we not talk about that now?
We don't have time!
Is that so?
Hey,
what's the password to my house?
I don't know. You changed it.
So what number did I change it to?!!
Eish!
Wait a moment! Wait!
Cheon Song Yi!
Are you sure she's at home?
Yes. I overheard her manger on the phone.
Then, she'll come out soon.
What is th-
Cheon Song Yi is home, but she's not coming out.
Please just let it go.
If I go out now,
I will be bitten to death by those people.
I'm very sorry for saying these words in this situation,
but do you have any ramen or cold rice?
I didn't eat well last night, so I'm a little hungry.
Get out.
I said, get out.
Yes, Vice President.
Then you can just give it to me as a whole.
In searching all over for Cheon Song Yi,
we are, now, in front of the home of
actress, Cheon Song Yi's home.
We came to hear her opinion on the death of Han Yu Ra.
First of all, I'll try ringing the bell.
There is no response.
Ah, we'll ask her neighbor over here.
Excuse me, did you see Cheon Song Yi earlier?
Move the camera.
Yes.
What's with him?
Hey, does that make any sense?
Why would Han Yu Ra die because of me?
Are people seriously believing that?
Yes, the atmosphere right now isn't good. So,
I think it's best that you don't leave your house.
You got home safely last night, right?
Please don't go out for a couple of days
and just stay home, alright?
That...
Aish, the battery.
What is this?
He doesn't even have a cell phone
and he uses a beeper.
Does he not even have a home phone?
Aish, this person. Does he live his life alone?
Am I locked in here right now?
What? I'm tired.
Where's Song Yi?
Even at home, am I also just Cheon Song Yi's friend?
I'm not your daughter?
What?
I received so many calls asking how
is Cheon Song Yi, so I turned it off.
I can't contact Song Yi, either.
Is that so? That's worrisome.
What about oppa?
Your oppa is busy these days.
But it's really strange.
What is?
I went somewhere to look at something last time,
and they said that there,
that Cheon Song Yi's fame was just up until last year.
That she will face something terrible this year
and the rest is dark, as if she can't see anything.
But for you, they said it's the exact opposite.
After Cheon Song Yi's luck fades, your luck blooms.
Mom.
Are you trying to make me disappointed in you?
I'm her friend.
There are many times I've disliked her,
but we've been friends for more than 10 years.
Did you think I would like it if I heard something like that?
And also, is Song Yi your daughter?
Why would you look at Song Yi's?
So...
until when are you going to live as the second priority?
Do you like being the second priority in your life?
I don't like it.
Since my daughter is the second priority, so am I.
-Mom.
--You
Do you know why life is interesting?
It's interesting because you don't know what's ahead of you.
It's something you don't know,
how everything may turn around.
The Hui Kyeong that you've liked for so long,
you can make him yours,
and you can receive the spotlight that was made just for you.
I want my daughter
to live that kind of life for once.
What kind of mess is this? You said
it was still under investigation!
And, they've said they don't even know if it's a suicide
or an accident. So, what's with everyone?
Don't worry too much.
I will try to steer this in the right direction.
Representative.
I'm in the middle of a conversation.
Right now, there's mayhem happening from advertisers.
That we violated the contract about model's quality.
They're saying they will back away from the offer.
The people from the drama want to see you, too.
Why?
They say the viewer ratings are coiling up right now.
Well, mother, we will try to guide this
well, so please go back home for now.
I'll get up now since I have something to finish.
Oh, right, Representative Ahn.
What I told you last time, about Song Yi's renewal issue.
You said that we should drag it
out for a month. We'll do that, then.
Pardon?
I said, let's do it like that.
There are times that we've spent together,
I can't just fall over for someone else just
because they try and persuade me otherwise.
I'm not a woman who's that disloyal.
When should I stamp it?
Should I stamp it now while I'm here?
Ah, mother, there's no contract that was made for today,
so let's talk about it slowly another time.
I will leave first.
This phone is turned off...
What is this girl doing?
Agh, that awful bastard.
I begged like that saying I was hungry.
I crawled over to him once and
he acted as if I wasn't even there.
This bastard who doesn't acknowledge anything.
They said the tiger comes on its own feet, too.
It probably comes after being begged to.
Do you not want to eat ramen together?
Then just sit in front of me, at least.
Why should I?
Because I don't want to eat alone.
Because if I eat alone, I lose my appetite.
That bastard who has no taste for people.
That alien-like bastard.
A person is asking you earnestly like
that, but you just completely ignore them?
What is this? When did I eat all of this?
I was going to stop eating after 3 bites.
Ah, I'm ruined!
Where exactly is the bathroom?
It seems like he knows his paintings.
It's a complete fake, but it looks real.
Aigoo, what is all this?
"Records of my last 3 months on Earth?"
What are you doing?
Oh, my god, you surprised me.
What are you?
Without any warning!
When did you come in?
That's what I want to ask.
When and why did you come in here?
I was looking for the bathroom,
but...
what is this place?
And what's all this?
Are you running two jobs?
Like buying books and paintings from a long time ago?
Like saving up to pay a debt? Something like that?
Come out.
Get out.
I am sorry about going into your room.
How can I get out now?
Like I care.
Everyone's thinking how to kill me.
"Should I rip her to death?"
"Should I dry her to death?"
Everyone's like this...
But if they see me coming out of a man's house.
I will really be dust and die.
That's none of my business.
I think it this way.
It's a duty for a teacher to take care of his student.
Even if our society has become heartless,
the relation between a teacher and a student is...
should not be like this.
When the student is in trouble, the teacher could help a bit.
Who's your teacher?
You?
I've never thought of you as my student, ever.
Get out now if you don't want to be dragged out.
HEY!
(Informal)
Hey?
Let go of this.
(Informal)
What?
You said you are not my teacher.
I've been using honorifics for nothing.
I should've just talked informally.
Look here, Ms. Cheon Song Yi.
What's up, Mr. Do Min Joon?
Come to think of it, why don't you show me your ID?
How old are you?
You're younger than me, right?
If I step out of this house, I'm not the one who's going to die.
Mr. Do Min Joon is going to die, too.
Why? Because news articles saying that you're my secret lover will be out.
Everyone will know your face.
Do you want to live a noisy life?
While every little movement of yours
being watched by people...
That's more terrible than you think.
Please let me stay for a while.
I beg you.
First, don't touch anything
in this house.
I won't touch anything. I won't.
Second, don't ask me any questions.
I won't ask any. I won't.
Then in meaning of thanks,
shake hands?
Third,
keep your distance from me, 1 meter at least.
Ah, what's this?
Keep your distance from me, you.
Do you know whom I make movies with?
Jung Woo Sung, Kang Dong Won, Won Bin.
With such amazing people-
It's so unusual.
It's impossible for a man to not like me.
Does he have a different taste?
(Is he gay?)
The bereaved families don't want to carry out an autopsy.
Police assumes that it was a suicide.
The media are also seeing it that way
It's likely that they would close the case like this.
But...
In Ms. Han Yoo Ra's laptop, some video clips of you and some phone conversation recordings were found.
I took care of the laptop but there was an evidence that she kept copies of those files somewhere.
Where are the copies, then?
When I checked the black box in the car, I saw that she put a USB in her clutch bag.
It's the clutch bag that she brought to the wedding.
Did you find it?
No. It wasn't in the cruise.
Get the CCTV data.
Find out
who took it.
Yes, sir.
Hyung!
You can go now.
What?
You saw the news, right? Why is it my Cheon Song Yi's fault that Han Yoo Ra died?
I think I'm going to lose my mind.
Gather some reporters you know.
It might not be a suicide.
It could be an accidental death.
Bluntly saying, it could be a homicide.
There are a lot of similar cases abroad, too.
On a boat or a cruise they fabricated homicide
as suicide
It's being investigated now, so the truth will come out.
How can I believe that?
Let's eat first, eat.
Hey, here!
That's why...
What's with these people?
Excuse me.
Which reporter are you?
I'm reporter Kim Hyuk Soo from the Dae Han Daily News.
I'm Na Jae Ho from the Yu Il Newspaper.
She's not coming out.
We've already rung the door.
It will be a real big news,
if Cheon Song Yi's boyfriend or someone
comes in at a time like now.
Excuse me.
Don't just stand there. Come eat these fried dumplings
Aiyoo, it's fine. Come on.
No, it's fine...
She won't come out now.
Here.
Are you sure that she's inside?
We're sure. Her manager tried to bring her out but failed.
Then, she's-
Ms. Cheon Song Yi.
Wouldn't she be starving right now?
By the way,
is it true that Han Yoo Ra died because of you?
You saw at the hair salon.
Is she a type of person who would jump into the Han River because she doesn't want to do anything with me.
She would never do that.
When I saw her for the last time,
how much she bragged about
saying that she's getting married soon..
She was only 30 years old.
How in the earth did this happen?
I did nothing wrong, but
why does it bother me? Why do I feel sorry?
When did you last see her?
Last time when I saw her...
[ Day of the incident at 11:30pm ]
Why can't I say anything?
What was that?
Bluntly saying, are we having an affair?
Han Yoo Ra.
Let's go in.
I think everyone who knows me
and knows you is here.
Count on me.
What would I say to those people.
I'm going to make a surprising announcement later.
If you hear that, you'd probably
be surprised, too.
Yoo Ra.
What?
How's your depression these days?
My depression is up to you, Oppa.
I stopped taking medicine a while ago.
You know I like you, right?
Take a good care of your health.
What is this? They are going out.
Jae Kyeong oppa's being so coy.
Oh my.
What are you doing?
By chance, were you eavesdropping?
A little?
I'm going to make announcement of our wedding.
But does it have to be Jae Kyeong Oppa?
What do you mean?
No, I mean...
Even though you're not my style, Unni,
I think men could think you quite attractive.
Why?
Do you think I'm clinging onto Mr. Jae Kyeong, when he doesn't like me?
It kind of looked like that.
Don't be flip with me.
There's something you don't know.
The inside story why Oppa can't actively ask me
to marry him.
What is that?
Do you think I'd tell you?
I mean, I'm not that curious either.
When I get married, I will immediately retire.
If I'm gone, you do all you want.
Don't worry.
Even now, I'm doing well enough.
Rude girl.
You won't let me win, not once.
Look who's talking.
Ah, why did she leave this behind?
That was the last I saw of her.
I looked everywhere for her to to return her pouch,
but couldn't find her.
After that, I got too drunk, so my memory is a bit...
Why?
Truthfully, something was really strange that day.
I'm pretty sure you watched enough.
Let's just call it a day
Everything's been answered and accounted for.
Huh?
Come on, give it a rest.
Who is this?
This person isn't on the list.
Who?
Right here.
That's Cheon Song Yi.
No.
Next to that.
That night I fell asleep on the boat,
I had a dream.
In my dream, you appeared.
It was so clear that
I wondered whether it was really a dream.
It's true.
I checked and this person isn't on the list.
He's not on the worker's list either...
But, what is this?
What the heck?
Where did that person go?
Exactly.
Ah, I'm getting goosebumps.
A ghost, isn't that a ghost?
Right. It must have been a ghost.
This video hasn't been tampered with, right?
Is it something like those water ghosts
who were drowned to death?
This is freaky...
Aish...
But,
they both disappeared.
Now what?
When this man disappeared,
Ms. Cheon Song Yi also disappeared.
This thing...
What could it be?
Because it was so vivid, I couldn't help
but think it was real.
Perhaps,
did you come that day?
That couldn't have happened.
That's right, you couldn't have been there.
But I feel like
I definitely saw you there?
Then, what were you doing that day?
What the heck?
♫ In the past memories. ♫
♫ In that pain, I call you. ♫
♫ You are are my destiny. ♫
♫ You ♫
♫ You are my destiny. ♫
Kiss?
It's not like I didn't have a chance, but
I've never done it before.
Honestly, because I look like this,
there were a lot of temptations.
What is it that you need to talk with me?
Mr. Scholar,
This , , ,
You've heard of Dan Won?
Dan Won Kim Heung Do.
He's the one who even drew a portrait
of the eldest grandson of the king.
He's a painter,
who's most popular in Han Yang these days.
Since it's my heart,
please accept it.
Also,
this too...
The request of the most beautiful woman in Han Yang,
I can't reject that.
However, I have a confession to make before that.
Do you know where I'm from?
What?
I came from the star.
Therefore, will you be okay?
You won't, right?
Since we are people from different planets.
If you don't like me, you should've just said so.
How could you make up a nonsense like that?
Such an absurd lie...
You're too much.
Good morning!
You're dead!
Hey!
Oh, Father
If it's really a suicide, then Han Yura...
She died because of our Song Yi?
Then, what's going to happen to my Song Yi?
Look, it's her will.
It's game over.
Should I teach you how not to be hurt by people?
Don't give or accept anything.
Also, don't expect anything.
Jae Kyeong Oppa?
But, how do you know where I live?
Mr. Do Min Joon!
Mr. Do Min Joon, are you not there?