Timing and Subtitles brought by Love On The Air Team @ Viki
I'm curious about you.
PD, why do you keep bothering me?
Just show me Lee Kang's que sheet.
Let's share some information. I'll look at it quickly and give it right back.
You said to hand over the plans earlier.
Ah, it doesn't matter. Whichever one works.
Hand over everything. Hurry.
-Why are we doing this Ji Soo Ho? Why don't we just say hi?
-Sh.
But look here, you look better since you've been working with Lee Kang.
Are you happy? I asked if you're happy?
Who's happy? I just want to kill him. I pulled an all-nighter yesterday too.
PD, you should've recruited me onto your team earlier.
I was so happy when I was on your team because I got to do nothing.
What are you saying you jerk?
I said to hurry and bring me the que sheet! Ah, really.
Hold on, it's in the booth. Wait here.
Okay, so is this the portion where we move onto the bridge?
Ah, yes. I underlined it with a highlighter.
What are you two doing here?
We're preparing for the broadcast.
From the crack of dawn?
Since I was helping Ji Soo Ho with this and that. And besides, they say that the writer and DJ are one.
Are one?
Also, could you write down the reactions I should be having on the script?
Huh?
What? They worked all night?
Our Ji Soo Ho was working so hard.
From the crack of dawn, he was looking over the script with Song Geu Rim.
-Does that mean that the two slept together?
-Hey!
What kind of nonsense are you speaking?
Song Geu Rim that girl. She's real provocative, that one.
But you guys know what they say right? Whenever you stay up all night in the booth, something always happens. Right?
Why are you trying to curse us with your superstition?
Hold on here, Song Geu Rim vs. Ra Ra Hui. Who do you think won when it came to viewership ratings?
It would be easier on us if Writer Ra Hui won.
Exactly.
I think Song Geu Rim won.
Of course we won, we have Mr. "Namaste" on our side.
Namaste.
Alright everyone, this was a special survey commissioned by KBC.
And the viewership ratings for the two programs are finally in.
But this graph line going upwards.
It this really our radio viewership ratings?
Alright then, is it 'Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance',
or 'Let's Meet Jay at 6'? Who could it be?
-Ji. Soo. Ho!
-Yeah!
The team that lost in viewership ratings has to broadcast on Sundays too. Do you remember?
On this red day, you'll be stuck in a heated room and will have to work really hard.
Our team is going to go out to play.
Go ahead, go ahead.
Ah, and also we're going to start using Teacher Sung Woo's booth from our next live broadcast and onwards.
-What?
-Really?
Did you get permission?
-Namaste.
-Hey!
It's all good. Let's not do this again and just record one segment.
What recording?
Hey, hey, hey, hey you!
That jerk, I can't hate him.
But, where did Song Geu Rim go?
Who knows?
I hope it looks like this everyday.
Ji Soo Ho, what was it that you were saying?
You said you were curious? About what?
You said that to me earlier. "I'm curious about you."
Ah, that. That's--
Ah, really! Why do you always steal my food everyday?
Ah, really? Are you going to act that stingy maknae?
Here. You can eat all of this.
Thank you.
-But Ji Soo Ho, we placed first in viewership ratings.
-Oh really.
So today, we're not going to be broadcasting and have somewhere to go.
Everyone gather!
Are you really not going to come with us?
Ah, yes. Because I have a full schedule tomorrow and have to prepare for the broadcast--
But you have to be there Ji Soo Ho.
Why?
We're on our way to receive a PPL (produce placement), so we need your face.
I told you no.
Why can't we?
What kind of broadcast are you going to do in there?
Acting all sly. Did you think I'd let you borrow it if you brought Ji Soo Ho?
How great would it be if Ji Soo Ho broadcasted from your booth?
I'm telling you, our viewership ratings were through the roof.
That's right. And if Ji Soo Ho broadcasts in your booth, he can receive special training from you.
That's right. And if Ji Soo Ho broadcasts from your booth that'll mean he'll have to play all the records himself and I'll have less to do.
I'm sorry.
Ah, really. It was always my dream to broadcast from your booth, teacher.
If you lend us your booth, that means I've totally succeeded. Right?
You should give it to us as a "welcoming Ji Soo Ho to the radio" gift.
The booth of a living legend.
Why don't you say something Ji Soo Ho? Why do you want to DJ from my booth?
I don't really have any thoughts of wanting to do it there.
It doesn't matter to me, whether or not it's your booth.
All booths are the same.
I'll let you borrow it then.
What?
I'll let you borrow it if you go mountain climbing with me every week.
What are you saying?
Since you said all booths are the same, I have to let you know how different each climb is.
Starting with your next live broadcast, use the booth.
Teacher, you promised us.
Yes!
Teacher, I'm rolling in betrayal right now.
What are you saying?
I mean, climbing a mountain together is something you do when you're on the third level of a best friendship.
Why are you already inviting Ji Soo Ho to the mountain?
He's cute.
He's a novice that doesn't even know how important the setting is to the radio. I've got to teach him a thing or two.
Ah, really!
Can't you teach me like that, huh?
The Ji Soo Ho effect is killer. Everything works 100% with you.
I'm good.
Well then, since we've received our setting placement, should we move on to receive our next PPL (product placement)?
Actually, I'll be heading out.
Then, let's do this.
We'll go by whoever throws it into the goal.
That's fine. What is this?
What do you mean "that's fine" in a world full of competition. Are you not confident in your athletic skills?
Yes!
This, this, this, this this, make sure you place it in the trash properly.
Where are you headed?
Shouldn't we give our listeners armfuls of gifts too?
I feel like I'm freezing to death. What gifts?
Excuse us.
-Hello.
You're the president of the Cheong Yoon Research Facility right? The one that sent his story to our radio?
I'm PD Lee Kang.
You were researching on how to restore youthfulness and glow into both men and women's skin, but you were rejected by both men and women.
You were the one that couldn't even eat ramen because of debt.
The hardships you go through during youth persist even when you're standing, are words I hate the most.
Even if I spend all night working, the only thing that adds up is debt.
The reality of my situation is that I can forget about looking for my own home  when I can't even figure out how to pay the next month's rent.
Let's break up...
The reality is that if you dream you become foolish.
There were a lot of foolish people like me sending in their stories to the radio.
But, I don't think I can live as a foolish dreamer anymore, since I'm all out of funding for my research.
I'm going to buy it. Your cosmetics.
Our program is going to.
Hey, you have the progression fee right?
Since we have Ji Soo Ho we could have so many sponsorships sticking to us at no cost, but why are we paying--
Ji Soo Ho and our program want to cheer on the youth.
We cheer you on!
We'll also be trying our best to promote your products to our listeners, through Ji Soo Ho.
And I heard this yesterday, but mistakes can become hits.
So don't give up. We support you.
-We support you.
-The individual that I'm currently in charge of,
is still refusing counseling and is struggling with chronic insomnia.
This individual since childhood, has never established real relationships with another.
And only created fake relationships in order to maintain a facade that is required in the viewable world.
He is both afraid of and rejects the idea of revealing his true self.
However, it has come to my attention that recently it was not a situation, but rather through a person,
that this individual has been making choices different to those he made in the past.
I will continue to monitor and observe these decisions and changes.
I guess you can't reach Ji Soo Ho at all now.
I'm aware of him being with the radio team.
Exactly. Soo Ho isn't one to fit in with others. But he's fitting in.
Isn't that strange?
However, I feel like this time around Soo Ho has opened up a little bit more--
Exactly! I'm saying that that's strange.
You understand what I'm saying right?
You may leave.
Yes director, I've sent Jin Tae Ri over.
Have you met with her?
Yes. Of course, I'm doing well.
But Jin Tae Ri, I never see you on TV ever.
Well president, it's not to the point that you'll "never see" me on the TV.
Do you think you're good enough to be in a commercial promoting our company's refrigerator?
If you ask me if I'm "good enough" to my face. Can I reply with of course,
I'm "good enough"?
Director, you should know better.
Am I "good enough" for your company's refrigerator commercial?
Of course, the rumors were true.
"Of course, the rumors were true," is being said by a bald-headed ahjussi (older man).
But what rumors are you referring to?
You really, aren't afraid of a single thing.
Since you're at the bottom of your career you're being called out to places like this.
At least I'm better than the scum that call out people like me to "places like this".
-What?
-It's true.
You dumbasses can't even seduce me, who's at the "bottom of her career".
This girl, really.
-Hey, do you think you're at our level?
-Hey, let go!
You're acting like you're a top star when you're the lowest of the lows!
Department head Kim? Why are you here?
Oh, this kid's under your management.
Am I your kid? Why are you throwing around that word?!
Can't you be quiet.
Come out.
Timing and Subtitles brought by Love On The Air Team @ Viki
I'm sorry. If my kid made a mistake, please forgive her, and if she went overboard please show her mercy.
That cheap thing acting like she's all that!
Department head Kim, make sure you look after her well!
Kids like that always stab you in the back.
Yes, I'll offer you a drink.
But, director. Are you going to use our kid in your refrigerator commercial?
Are you crazy Department head Kim? Who would use something like that?
Exactly. If you're not even going to use her,
why did you hit her and pull at a girl's hair?!
I'll pay for your room. Then.
Ahjussi, so hurry up and give it to me.
I'm going to use Ji Soo Ho in whatever way I can.
I know about Ji Soo Ho's past and you have the evidence to back it up. Hm?
So, where are you going now Writer Song Geu Rim?
We have to head to the broadcasting station and probably stay up all night again.
And, this is the rewritten script.
I feel like this is the only thing I can do right now.
Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance
Maknae, let's go.
Then Ji Soo Ho, we'll be leaving.
But, why do you keep calling Writer Song Geu Rim maknae again?
Isn't Writer Song Geu Rim the main writer?
There's another maknae writer now, so it gets confusing.
There's no reason to be confused, I only call Writer Song Geu Rim maknae.
And the maknae writer we have probably quit. I can't contact her.
But I would still prefer if you didn't call her maknae. She has a title as the main writer--
But you treat Song Geu Rim like the maknae too. Of course in a different way than I do.
What are you talking about?
You ignore all the scripts that she writes and send her on errands.
You treat our main writer like the maknae.
Then Ji Soo Ho, we'll head out and see you tomorrow. And until then, we'll be cohabitating.
Writer Song Geu Rim!
Could I talk to you for a moment?
I have a photoshoot located out of the city tomorrow.
Yes, I  heard that it ends at 2.
What if I'm late to the live broadcast?
What?
Since I can't be late. I'd like to use Article 4 of the Song Geu Rim contract.
4. Song Geu Rim cannot say no to whatever Ji Soo Ho says
So I think you'll need to drive me tomorrow.
Am I your personal driver?
So instead of cohabitating, you'll probably have to go home and head to bed.
So you can drive safely tomorrow.
I'll do what I need to do.
What if we lose in terms of viewership ratings again, even if we give out gifts like they're candy?
But isn't it weird?
How come JH is supporting us instead of her son?
Stop thinking of useless things and raise the viewership ratings. Viewership ratings!
You worked hard on today's broadcast too.
Are you making fun of me?
That's not it.
But what even if your role on that team?
Ji Soo Ho's planning team is writing all the scripts for you right?
Then are you a useless writer or a lackey writer?
Winning in terms of viewership ratings makes you think you did well right?
Making anyone the main writer is really humiliating me, really.
Ji Soo Ho's planning team is writing all the scripts for you right?
Then are you a useless writer or a lackey writer?
A failed project can become the hit.
[ Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance ]
Mom
Yes, Mother.
Hello? Ji Soo Ho?
This is Song Geu Rim.
I know.
The script...
What did you think?
Well...
I couldn't do my homework to air it tomorrow.
It's okay. You still read it.
Yes.
- All right then.
- C'mon!
You're going to hang up already?
Well, what do we do then?
Ji Soo Ho, I really want to write a great script.
If I write well, you'll do the show with my script someday, right?
Right.
So, the DJ has to talk to the writer the most.
I'm the one who writes down what you want to say in front of the mic.
Well, not yet, but still...
But... aren't you offended?
Pardon?
Me not using your script for the show.
Well, I am a bit angry about it, but what can I do?
For you to use it, I have to write an amazing script for you.
But my circumstance is that I'm not able to write a script like that.
And now that I think about it...
I'm not angry with you, Ji Soo Ho. I'm angry at Song Geu Rim who can't write well.
Ah, I'm curious about something.
This is a personal question.
Why don't you carry a cell phone?
Why do I have to carry a cell phone around?
There's no reason for me to call anyone.
What?
Who would I call? I have no one to call.
There's no one to answer my call either.
Wow... you're so selfish.
Why don't you have anyone to call?
You have to call me, PD Lee Kang, and your manager.
And why aren't there anyone who'd answer your call?
When I have a writer's block while writing...
When I want to ask you what you like and how you want to say it...
You can answer my call.
Ah, Ji Soo Ho. Can't you buy a cell phone?
And if I buy one?
If I buy one...
Will you call me every day?
What?
Are you home?
Yes, I'm home.
Go to bed early.
You have to be my chauffeur tomorrow.
Whoa...
Nice, nice...
♫ Woke up on the right side of the bed ♫
What a nice shot. It's great.
♫ What's up with this Prince song inside my head? ♫
♬  Hands up if you are down to get down tonight. ♬
♬ Cause it's always a good time♬
♫ Slept in all my clothes like I didn't care ♫
♫ Hopped into a cab, take me anywhere ♫
♫ I'm in if you're down to get down tonight ♫
Okay!
We'll resume after we eat.
♫  Good morning and good night. I wake up at twilight  ♫
Yes, I'm in the area somehow.
Then can I come by and meet the idols quickly?
Ah, okay. I got it. Okay.
Ji Soo Ho, how many hours do you have left for you to finish shooting?
I have to go somewhere...
I'll take this car and will be right back.
You want me to get off the car?
Ready, start.
♫ Hello, my cute friend ♫
♫  When the faraway ship horn blows,  ♫
♫ Cry without anyone else knowing. ♫
Then is Sang Goo the only one graduating?
Those kids...
They'll be integrated to local schools.
There were two sixth graders, but Sang Goo alone got to graduate.
Where is Sang Goo?
Are you a reporter?
Stop coming around bugging me. Go away.
What did you say?
Are you here to write an article or something?
The reporters came by yesterday, too.
Hey, Sang Goo. I heard you're throwing a tantrum because you don't want to graduate.
Why are you doing that?
Why do you want to know?
Go. Go away!
Why do you keep trying get cozy with me?
Why should I tell you that?
If you don't want to do it, don't do it and leave.
I said to go away. Please.
Hey, you really resemble someone I know.
This is Gyo Min.
He's supposed to graduate with Sang Goo this time.
But Gyo Min will never be able to graduate now.
I couldn't tell the kids. So, I told them he went to Seoul to receive treatment.
I think they'd be extremely shocked.
But I had no idea he'd be waiting for him every day.
So, Sang Goo is insisting that he won't graduate until his friend comes back.
Director, you received a call from the CEO, right?
What the heck?
Director, what's going on?
What do you think?
Get out.
Da Jin, I'm sorry.
The JH CEO asked us to change the content all of a sudden.
Are you kidding me?
Does this make sense? We're on a different level.
I guess you want to die, huh?
Hey, you! Why are you doing this with every little thing?
Why do you keep picking fights with me?
I don't like you.
You're not prettier than me and your acting sucks.
But I'm totally offended that you're so successful.
What do you want me to do?
If you're not doing well, there must be a reason.
Hoobaenim, I'm being extremely patient right now as you can see on my face.
I'm warning you. Shut up.
Are you kidding me?
Yes, CEO, the mood here is a bit...
Why are you doing whatever you want?
You're the one who's doing whatever you want.
You do the radio show the way want to... you cause the live broadcasting accident the way you want to...
So, I had no choice.
I'm in the middle of something urgent.
I'm hanging up.
Will it be okay?
You're already talked to Ji Soo Ho, right?
He's doing the radio show daily.
It's okay.
It's possible to do according to your schedule.
Over here, look.
Hold the beer up high, so we can see it well.
So sexy.
Soo Ho, look at the bottle.
Ah, nice...
Look over here. Look at the camera.
Okay. Good job.
Hey, Ji Soo Ho.
Why do you keep ignoring me?
Just think I must have a reason for ignoring you.
Couldn't you just ignore me, too?
Finally, Ji Soo Ho is speaking with me.
I guess my appearance today was quite shocking.
What are you going to do? Why are you like this?
Soo Ho, we have to be close from now on.
Don't be like that with me.
Acting all friendly towards you isn't even a hard job for me to do.
That's right. You received the grand prize for acting.
- Is that all you want?
- Huh?
This is the CEO's line.
"Is that really all you want?"
You two really seem like mother and son.
Right, Ahjussi?
Yes, of course.
I followed Ji Soo Ho to the shooting location. Don't worry.
Aigoo, aigoo, look at you talking.
You... stick by him and come together, okay?
I'm going to get Ji Soo Ho and get us back to Seoul. Don't worry, Director.
But, what about that rude, crazy PD?
- Is this your present for today's live broadcast?
- Yeah.
And, today, you're still only going to have Ji Soo Ho for two hours without a guest?
Mr. peer, don't try to win with idols or gifts.
Why don't you find the value of the radio instead?
Do you think you're the only one who's right about the value of the radio?
Then what about everyone else's thoughts? Are they all incorrect?
Why am I using idols? Why do I keep spending money? Huh?
Yeah.
How could it be that simple, the road to messing up the radio?
"Mess up?"
Hey. We have to bring in the teens and those in their twenties somehow. The world has changed.
Focusing on catering to those who like to listen to the radio now, what are you going to do about the future?
I'll borrow your words that you like to use frequently.
"In order for the radio to survive as long as the earth lives and breathes,
we need to bring in people in their teens and twenties, and make them admire the radio."
"This is all the content that you want." We have to do that.
- That's true.
- What?
I'm saying that you're right. I'm contemplate on that. Thank you, Mr. Peer.
Also, don't touch how that was set up, you punk.
We have to get going right now.
You can go first. I'm going to go with Writer Song.
Jin Tae Ri, you can go first.
Just ignore me instead.
Ji Soo Ho, get in.
In Gangwon, Yeongseo, and surrounding regions there has been a notice issued for heavy snow fall, with many accidents due to this reason.
Gosh, I'm going crazy.
According to the weather station in Gangwon, snow clouds that developed in Seoul are moving towards other areas.
And in three hours, the snowfall will increasingly get heavier.
The snow will fall until the night.
Here is the next news.
Heavy Snowfall Alert
Seoul-Gangwon Route: Halted
Seoul, 125 KM
Be cautious of car accidents ahead
Wow.
PD Lee Kang, what should I do?
I don't know if there's been an accident ahead or anything, but we can't cross the bridge or move an inch in this traffic.
So, you can't come?
What's it like, just let me know.
I can't guarantee it, but probably.
Hey, you guys have a recording set aside right?
You probably have at least one spare pre-recorded segment, right?
Hey Song Geu Rim, you told me not to worry about a single thing. You told me you'd bring him here no problem!
Yes sunbae, you can send us a truck from Choongcheon right?
Hey Song Geu Rim, do you really want to get fired?
Where did you say you were again? We're broadcasting today no matter what.
Do whatever you can to get to the nearest place that has transmission. We've done a lot of broadcasts on the move, right?
Come to your senses starting now. We're broadcasting with a truck today.
What about you?
I'll be in Seoul. You'll have to rewrite the script but you can do it, right?
The opening and segment written about the Dongchon Branch school graduation.
PD, I have a good idea.
Yes, PD-nim.
Alright maknae, like you said you'll be broadcasting from the school.
But you're fully responsible for everything there. Do you understand?
Yes, PD-nim.
Set everything up within an hour. The story you chose today was good, so trust in yourself.
And put Ji Soo Ho on the phone.
Ji Soo Ho, you told me not to call Song Geu Rim maknae, right?
You said you were a pro, right?
So, what are you trying to say?
Please treat Geu Rim as the main writer today.
We have to broadcast in the situation we're in right now, no matter what. There's no room for mistakes.
There'll be no mistakes on my end, so you should just look after yourself.
He's bothersome right?
Don't be nervous.
I'm not shaking because I'm cold.
Let me know what I can do right now. I'll do it.
Today, we have to do a live broadcast here, right?
Yes.
And us two, we'll have to do it on our own somehow.
Then let's wake up, calm our nerves, and do what we need to do.
Alright, what should be start doing?
Then...
Ji Soo, I need your help.
The 12th Dongchon Branch School Graduation Ceremony
I have to write a script within the hour.
The segment is going to be about this school's graduation.
I ask you to please interview the last graduate, Sang Goo.
He's similar to you, so I think you guys will connect.
Aren't you going to stop me?
-Are you going to stop if I tell you to?
-No.
Then go ahead.
What are you? Why do you keep lingering around and following me.
You're on the same side as the woman with the poodle hair right?
You really are like someone I know.
What? I asked you to go.
You. Did you say stuff like that to your friend too?
What?
Did you tell him to go and push him farther away, because you wanted him to stay?
Go!
Just go to Seoul all by yourself.
How do you know?
I know what that's like too.
But, he won't come.
Some people are just meant to never return.
KBC Radio
On Air
Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance
The 12th Graduation Ceremony of Dongchon Elementary School.
You're here. Where's Sang Go?
He said he'd go first and wait. He must've gone to his teacher.
I couldn't do this well.
It's fine.
Can I look at the script, too?
Here, make sure you organize the song selection accurately.
Yes, I've done it.
Come support us.
There's no technical difficulties right?
Sang Go has disappeared.
Sang Go came and found me, then asked for Gyo Min's address.
He was crying and asking where in Seoul it was. Then, he just left.
I thought he'd come quickly, but.
What should we do? We finished all of the script.
I don't think we'll be able to do the show. I'll let PD Lee Kang know.
Hold on. Let's look for him a little more.
Did you tell Sang Go about Gyo Min?
He left to Seoul to receive treatment, but he won't ever be able to return.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have said that earlier.
But, "People who will not come won't come." That's right.
But, there are people who can't come even if they want to.
Someone told me this long ago.
"Not crying doesn't mean you're not sad."
"Like how laughing doesn't mean you're happy."
You are still small, weak, and young.
If you keep holding back your tears and living like that, you'll turn into me.
He said he'd go to Seoul.
He said he'd come before my graduation.
He told me that he'd be back if I waited a little bit.
I told him to go. I said I wouldn't wait.
I told him that.
I thought he couldn't come because I told him to go.
That.. That really hurts my heart.
Do I have to keep waiting and not graduate?
Or, is it okay for me to graduate? I have to hear that from him.
Should I tell you how?
Ask him directly yourself.
How can I do that?
Through the radio. He'll be listening from wherever.
How many minutes until the live broadcast?
Ten minutes.
PD Lee Kang.
Hey, Hoon Jeong. Get ready to go on air.
What? Okay.
Mic Test. 1, 2, 3.
Hello, this is Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance. 1, 2, 3, 2, 2, 3.
We're on air.
On Air.
I was sending him a signal with the flashlight.
For how long?
Until now, probably ten thousand times.
Come back quickly.
Come back, and hold hands with me.
The plant we've been taking care of together,
the soccer we played together every day, and graduation - let's do that together.
I want to say I'm sorry for telling you to go.
To be honest, I wanted to tell you not to go.
Yes, this is Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance.
Yes, we're accepting stories right now. You can upload them to the message board.
We're accepting stories right now, so you can upload them to the message board.
Thank you.
Yes, this is Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance.
Any final things you'd like to say?
Please don't let our school be closed down.
I'm not going to graduate,
so if I'm not there and the school isn't there,
then, my friend has nothing to come back to.
We said we'd graduate together.
I can't graduate by myself.
The last song is special. All the students at the Dongchon Branch School will be singing Sanulrim's 'Goodbye'.
Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance. This last song is a special one.
Singing Sanulrim's 'Goodbye', are all the students of the Dongchon Branch School.
♫  Hello, my cute friend. ♫
♫  When the faraway ship horn blows,  ♫
♫ Cry without anyone else knowing. ♫
♫  Alone in a room where everyone has fallen asleep. ♫
Ugh, geez!
This is sad.
♫ Tell them, without anyone knowing ♫
♫ crying and gone far, far away. ♫
♫ Hello, my cute friend.  ♫
Ji Soo Ho. For the closing, instead of going along with the script, you should say whatever you'd like.
Pardon?
The script today wasn't written by only me today. This is a broadcast you and I made together.
I think it'd be nice if you said something you really want to say.
♫ Crying without any knowing, gone far, far away.  ♫
I've heard this once on the radio.
"Not crying doesn't mean you're not sad."
"Like how laughing doesn't mean you're happy."
"Like how laughing doesn't mean your happy."
A friend once told me this.
This has been Ji Soo Ho's Radio Romance. With these words, I'll say my goodbye.
PD Kang?
Yeah?
The message board.
Ji Soo Ho is a murderer!
Ji Soo Ho killed someone.
This has been coming in for a few days.
Ji So Ho Mur. Der. Er.
Ji Soo Ho killed someone.
Ji Soo Ho is a murderer.
The murderer that I'm working with...
It looks like he'd fall into a relationship he's never experienced before... What kind of reaction would he have?
I'm so curious, myself.
You're curious, right?
Where did that ahjussi go?
I wonder where he went. Maybe the bathroom?
But, when did you get so close to him? What's the secret?
He said he's the same as me. He wanted someone to not go.
He told them to go, too. Do you know who that'd be?
He said that people who will not come will never come.
He said all of that. It seems like he's waiting for someone.
Oh, and–!
You can go now.
I told you my number. When you get to Seoul, contact me.
Let's get going. You, too.
Are you telling me to go or not?
This time, I'm telling you to really go.
Congratulations on your graduation.
But, where should I hang this?
Where did you hang your graduation certificate?
I don't have one.
Woo Ji Woo.
This is to certify that the person listed above has been awarded this diploma for successful completion of 3 years of Middle School
Graduation Certificate
Name: Ji Soo Ho
I'm so happy.
I had a dream of leaving a trace, step by step, like this.
♫ A hazy barely visible ♫
Because you read my script today, I left all the traces of my dreams in it.
To those who listen to the radio, it was a stamp for the first time.
Thank you, Ji Soo Ho.
There's something I'm really curious about.
What is it?
The thing you said earlier.
"Not crying doesn't mean you're not sad."
"Like how laughing doesn't mean you're happy."
I really like that saying. Where did you hear it from, Ji Soo Ho?
♫ I can't find it.
♫
♫ My dear be my strength
If you look that, it doesn't seem like we don't connect.
Right?
♫ So that I can find my way
♫
♫ My love open the path for me
♫ My hidden path
♫
♫ Shall we go here or there?
♫ Even though it's far
♫
♫ I who left as though I were being led
When I was really young, I had a high fever for three days.
♫  I have found my way.
♫
But, my dad and my mom didn't know.
♫ Waving my hand and letting you go
♫
Funny, right?
♫  When loneliness  ♫
It's not funny at all.
It's not funny. Why are you laughing?
♫ My love, help me.
♫
♫  Made for me,  ♫
When I'm hurting and my mom pats me like this, it melts my heart.
It's as if I'm not hurting.
I heard this on the radio.
"Not crying doesn't mean you're not sad."
"Like how laughing doesn't mean you're happy."
Song Geu Rim.
You really don't remember me?
Timing and Subtitles brought by Love On The Air Team @ Viki
♫ Do you have a time, this time is for you.
♫
♫ Have you ever listened? ♫