Boris Godunov
It was the year 1598.
No lawful heir remained
after the death of Tsar Feodor, son of Ivan the Terrible.
The road to power lay open to Boris Godunov,
the late Tsar's brother-in-law.
Yet, Godunov was slow in accepting the crown.
The people were made to plead with Boris
to accept the throne.
You loafers - have you turned to wooden statues?
Down there - on your knees!
Faster! Go down!
You're the devil's sons and daughters!
Lord in Heaven, do not reject us, oh Father.
Lord, we beseech You that You protect us, o Father.
We are all orphans without You - help Your children. Lord!
And with tears we ask You, Lord in Heaven:
hear our wailing—hear our bitter cries.
Help, Father—Lord in the skies above.
Oh Father, Benefactor, don't leave us - Help, Father!
Mityukh—say, Mityukh: why do we cry?
Brother—I can't tell you.
We must find a Tsar to govern Russia.
To hell with it! I'm hoarse from shouting.
I ask you, my darling dove—have you a drop of water?
Wait—I'll serve you in a moment.
Just do not shout so much, so you won't be so thirsty.
- Women, stop your silly chatter. Quiet!
- And who are you to tell us?
Don't think that you can bully us!
Oh, you witches, keep your mouths shut!
Listen to that little devil.
He's a fool—he's only boasting.
He's a heathen—he'll be roasting.
God have mercy on this sinner.
Let us run and look for shelter.
What's this? so silent? you spare your voices -
I'll show you!
- Don't be mad, Nikitich; don't be mad, beloved.
- Let us do some breathing—then we'll do some praying.
He won't let us breathe, the bastard.
Shut up—use your voices as you're told.
- All right.
- Well?
Lord in Heaven, do not reject us, o Father.
Lord, we beseech You that You protect us, o Father.
We are lost without You.
Lord in Heaven:
hear our wailing—hear our bitter cries.
Help, Father!—Lord in the skies above:
o Father, o father in Heaven, o Father. . .ah. .
Quiet—and listen.
Hear what the Duma councillor has to say.
Hear me, citizens of Moscow.
The Boyar has not relented.
He pays no heed to the Boyars of the Duma or the Patriarchs.
He does not want to hear of his accession.
Woe to Russia, woe to us, the Russian people.
Our land groans, in lawlessness.
Let us pray to the Lord in His mercy
that He may comfort our troubled Russia by His divine consolation,
and grant His guidance to Boris' weary soul.
Long may he live.
Tsar Boris Feodorovich.
Long life and glory- Our Tsar and Father.
Praise him!
As the sun is to Heaven, its highest glory,
glory to this country, to Russia.
Tsar Boris is glory, glory.
Long life and glory
Long life and glory. . . .
Hail to Tsar Boris.
Long live Tsar Boris.
Long life and glory. Be happy, friends.
Jubilate, and be happy, friends.
Let us praise our Tsar, Boris Godunov.
Long life to him! Tsar Boris Feodorovich.
Long may he live.
To the mightiest of Tsars, Boris,
be glory—glory—glory—glory!
glory—glory—glory—glory!
My soul is sad -
a strange and fearful omen
invades all my being with its dark foreboding.
My Lord and God — You, my Eternal Father,
from Heaven's throne in mercy look on us,
and send to me, and to the power of my reign, Your holy blessing.
Let me be kind and merciful like You,
let me bring glory to the Throne.
And now we bend our knees
before the mighty Tsars who governed Russia.
And then I'll invite all the people to a feast!
All - from Boyar down to the lowly poor,
all be my guests, all will be dearly welcome.
Glory—glory—glory. Long life and glory
Our Tsar and Father—long may he reign, the mighty ruler!
As to Heaven the sun is its glory, glory.
so to Russia her great Tsar Boris is glory.
Glory—and long may he reign.
GLORY GLORY!
Just one more page, the last of all my stories,
and this will end the chronicle I wrote.
The work is done, entrusted to this sinner by God, the Lord.
And not in vain have I been called for many years to be a witness:
there'll come a day, a monk will read these papers,
and he will reap the fruits of all my toiling.
Then he will light, like me, his lamp at midnight,
and shake the dust of all too many years
to tell again the legends of the fathers.
And thus the true believers will remember
all that befell our homeland in long forgotten times.
The dawn of day is near -
my lamp is but a flicker -
Just one more page, the last of all my stories. . .
Lord in Heaven, Father, have mercy on Your slaves!
Merciful God.
From the flock of true believers
turn away all evil thoughts, merciful God!
That dream again!
The third time I dreamt that dream!
How it haunts me, that cursed dream.
Awake so soon, brother?
I beg you: give me your blessing, worthy father.
May God the Lord protect you, son -
today, and always, and forever!
All through the night you never ceased your writing.
I was asleep—and yet I am not rested:
an evil dream has stirred my tortured heart.
I mounted on a mighty stairway
that led me to a tower
and I saw all Moscow from on high.
Like in an ant-heap the crowds below were running to and fro.
At me they laughed, and pointed with their fingers.
It frightened me, and I began to tremble . . .
I tumbled down the stairs,
and I awakened.
But now, I want to ask a question that is on my mind:
Who killed young Dimitri, our Tsarevich?
You, I am told, were present that frightful day in Uglich?
Yes, I was. Our Lord and God had destined me
to see and witness
the heinous crime.
I came at night.
Next morning dawn awoke me.
there was a noise, the sound of tolling bells,
- screams - shouts,
we all ran to the palace -
What a sight we saw!
A sea of blood, and in it the Tsarevich . . .
this mother the Tsaritsa unconscious by his side.
His faithful nurse was crazed with fear,
and sobbed in desperation.
And then, quite suddenly,
the crowd cried out in wrath
and dragged in the servant who betrayed her helpless master.
"Confess the deed," the crowd shouted.
The murderers, in fear of death,
admitted they killed the boy by order of Boris.
He would be as old as you are—and Tsar today!
But God did not allow it,
and thus the crime that Tsar Boris committed
will conclude the chronicle I write.
Brother Grigori, by learning you have formed an eager mind:
to you I want to leave my work;
This is the matin bell.
Do give your blessing, Lord, to all Your slaves.
I need my stick, Grigori.
Lord, have mercy on us, have mercy, God, on us all!
Heavenly, mighty Father—ever just, eternal, have mercy. Lord!
Boris, Boris, you make the country tremble,
and no one ever dares remember
the fate you meted out to the Tsarevich.
Yet in this quiet cell
a monk recorded all that he knew
of this most heinous murder.
You will be called before your earthly judges,
nor can you flee the judgment of the Lord.
In a pond quite near lives a gander here,
oh—you my gander, dear! my beloved gander, dear!
Now you must stay here, lovely gander, dear.
Likes to swim in every pond, of the willows he is fond.
Fold your little wings, darling gander mine!
Don't fly away from me, stay and keep me company.
You will be my love like a turtle dove,
and this love will have no end ...
Brothers and Christians, friends and honest people,
for the church we're building we ask you for a modest gift.
Bread on the waters—you'll be rewarded!
Wandering monks they are—two worthy pilgrims.
The Lord may bless this house of yours!
Would you like to eat something, reverend fathers?
We take whatever God may send, mistress.
No wine today?
Why, of course, father!
I'll bring you some,
have a seat.
What are you so glum about, companion?
Here we are close to the border now: Lithuania!
And that's where you asked us to take you.
I'll never really be safe till I'm over the border!
And what's so good about Lithuania?
Take us—: my friend Missail, and I, wicked sinner:
since we escaped from the cloister walls,
we don't care a single rap what country we're in -
Lithuania, Russia - what do we care?
It's all the same to us
if there's some wine!
Ah, there is some now.
Near Kazan—near the famous olden fortress
sat Tsar Ivan—making merry at a banquet.
Tartars got from him no pity
they were told to leave the city,
and not to come again to Russia!
But one day the Tsar had enough, and in the dark of the night
asked his men to put a lot of mines all over the town.
But the Tartars kept on acting like the owners of the place,
when they saw Ivan, they simply laughed right in his face.
That's the way the Tartars are!
And the Terrible Tsar was sad by day and night,
hung his head to the left, but later also to the right.
Then he called for all his cannoneers,
and he ordered them to be prepared —
every one of them.
As the fuses began to smolder merrily,
one young man threw a light into a powder keg,
they exploded every single mine that could be found. Hey!
One could hear the blast for miles around - what a noise it was!
That's how it went in Kazan, the famous city!
Tell me: don't you drink anything?
And it seems you don't even sing?
I don't drink.
Each to his own taste!
. . . and mine is for wine! Come on, Missail,
let us drink a toast to our charming host. . .
Now listen, brother:
I do not care for those that don't like wine!
Drinking may be piggish.
soberness is priggish!
Phew!
There was a man,
a darling man,
spurred his horse so it ran.
He wore a cap ...
Please tell me: this road out there,
where does it lead to?
... he did not care a rap
Into Lithuania.
... he was filthy, that chap!
- Is the border very far?
No, it isn't.
if you hurry you can still get there tonight
- if they do not stop you
Me? Why should they?
Somebody must have escaped from Moscow,
police have been ordered everywhere to look out for him!
Eh! this does not seem to be my lucky day!
Do they always get them?
No—they don't!
It might be desperate, if there were no other road
than just the high road, but let me tell you:
If you cross the main street, you'll find a foot-path
— keep on walking—you'll come to a chapel, near by a brook. . . .
and from there to Khlopino—and then to Zaitsero
—From there on you cannot miss it: you are almost at the border.
Police are everywhere—: therefore be careful!
They are out to fleece us, and rob us of our last copeck!
Came to a door - he made: knock—knock
and then he knocked again: knock- knock—knock.
Who is it now?
Them again! Oh, darn it all!
There was a man ... a darling man . . .
spurred his horse so it ...
Who are these two men?
We are two lay brothers—
we are poor and honest,
wandering through the villages,
begging for a copeck, or two!
And you—who are you?
Our companion.
A peace-loving friend of the law!
I have come with these worthy old men,
I'm on my way home now.
Try to get milk from a stone!
That case is hopeless.
Let's try the old ones.
Lord above—have mercy on us sinners!
How is everything? tell me:
how are they treating you?
I'll tell you.
Alyokha: have you got that sheet?
Let's have a look. Listen—
From his cell in Moscow escaped some unworthy monk:
Grishka Otrepyev
Have you heard about it?
No—never.
Well, the Tsar has ordered us to find that heretic,
to arrest him and hang him!
I'm sure you have heard that?
I have not!
Are you a reader?
No—sorry. I was not meant to be.
Come, have a look at this.
Yes—I can read.
Take this. Hurry up. Read aloud!
"Be it known to every one:
that a heretic, named Grigori Otrepyev,
has run away from a Moscow monastery.
After he listened to the Evil One, he set out
to tempt his brethren with visions of sin.
Now that Grishka may be trying to reach Lithuania.
The Tsar orders you to arrest this man . .
"... and to hang him!"
It says nothing here of hanging.
Fool! You ought to learn to read between the lines. . . .
Again: ". . . to arrest and to hang him."
". . . and to hang him."
As for his age
. . . Grishka is . . .
He's about fifty two. , . .
. . . has a rather red nose . . .
is of medium height, but heavy. .
That's him all right: let's catch him,
children!
Hands off! I warn you—don't lay hands,
you picked the wrong man. . . .
Who says I am Grishka?
No, friends—: I don't care for such jokes!
My reading may be halting—I don't say it is fluent ...
but I can try—let me try
it seems my life may hang on my reading.
. . . his age . . . age ... his age is twen. . . twenty!"
Who says "fifty-two"? Liar!
"Of medium height ... he has reddish hair . . .
and on his nose there is . . .
on his nose there is one little wart. . . .
Furthermore—one of his arms . . .
his arms ... is shorter ... one of his arms is ..."
I think it might be. . . .
It's him. Don't let him get away!
- Get hold of him!
Where are you, love of mine?
You, for whom I'm longing.
Resting under the green-sward,
far from all who love you,
you must be so lonely,
there under your tomb-stone.
You don't see my sorrow.
You don't hear my crying.
Why did you leave me?
Like you I am lonely.
Good Heavens!
What's this? What wolf has stirred
the hen amidst her brood?
Mightiest Tsar, forgive me:
but I am old, and everything upsets me.
My Xenia,
my much beloved daughter!
You shed a widow's tears before your wedding,—
for he who was betrothed to you is dead.
Father and Tsar,
please do not heed
the tears that I am shedding,
for all my grief must seem so unimportant
compared to your afflictions.
And you, my son, my Fyodor
What is this?
This is a map of Russia, of our country
from East to West.
All this is beautiful, my son.
As from the clouds you see our country,
this great and mighty realm before you:
the borders, rivers—cities.
Go on, and study, Fyodor!
The time will come, perhaps it will be soon,
when you will be the Tsar of this holy land.
Good-by—my son.
Mine is the highest power!
In its sixth year my reign is calm and peaceful.
And yet my heart
has never known a moment's peace.
How often have I heard it prophesied:
my power and my glory would be endless!
But life, and fame, the heady wine of power,
the people's applause,
all that has lost its lure.
How heavy lies on me the hand of the Lord!
And every sinful soul must fear His verdict.
There is darkness all around,
in vain I strive to flee from it.
Oh, for a ray of hope to guide me!
My weary heart is aching with longing,
it cries to God for mercy.
At times I hear around me a secret whisper ...
I am betrayed, the Boyars hate me,
open revolt is rife in Lithuania,
hungry crowds and plague and devastation!
Like an angry beast on the prowl
are the people, in hunger and poverty,
Russia moans.
For all the sorrows that Heaven has sent us,
to punish the sins we committed, they blame the Tsar!
For all their misfortunes they curse my very name,
curse and despise Boris!
I cannot sleep at night, and yet I have night-mares!
The child appears to me, its bloody head,
eyes red with crying, begging and pleading,
pleading for mercy.
But there was no mercy.
Gaping the wound in its body,
piercing the shriek, it cried in dying.
Oh—Lord above!
God!
Ah, shush!
What has happened?
Ah—shush—shush! Quiet!
Find out what's going on there!
- Shush—shush—shush
- Well—what now?
Ah— how they yell!
Well—speak up!
Speak!
Almighty Lord and Tsar,
Prince Vassily Shuiski is asking to be received.
Shuiski? He's here?
Tell him We shall be glad to see him,
to listen to his message!
Last night one of Pushkin's servants came to tell us
that Shuiski and Mstislavski, and some others,
and even Pushkin, held a meeting in the middle of the night:
a man, it seems, arrived from Cracow, to report. . .
Arrest that man!
Aha, Prince Shuiski.
Almighty Tsar and Lord,
I greet you!
Oh! it's you, my worthy Prince!
the man who's proud to lead the brainless masses,
a master in the noble art of treason
You—the evil spirit of the throne.
Every oath that you swore you've broken threefold
cunning hypocrite—wheedling flatterer,
a traitor disguised as a Boyar.
Deceiver! Snake!
When Ivan ruled Russia,
Shuiski was a name
that used to be received with honors!
Is this perhaps the news that you and Pushkin heard
when you received a message from all your Boyar friends
that I have banished.
Yes, Sire.
The rumor speaks of a usurper;
the Poles—the Pope, they all are on his side!
But—who is the man?
Whose name has he usurped, the scoundrel ?
Yes—first I want to know his name! You know it?
Believe me, Tsar: your power is tremendous.
Your charity, your kindness, and your bounty
have won the love of every humble slave,
and they have vowed their faith to you and to your throne.
Yet, I must warn the Tsar, my master and my Lord,
although with sorrow and with grief my heart is bleeding,
you must be told that this may happen:
if he should drive so far his criminal intentions
to enter Russia and to march on us,
and if he tries to captivate the crowds,
- Dimitri's name may be a mighty weapon!
- Dimitri? Tsarevich, leave us!
Please Sire, me stay and let me hear ...
No—no, you must not stay! You heard me
Tsarevich, leave us!
Take measures, don't delay:
have soldiers guard all Lithuanian frontiers at once,
that not a single soul can enter Russia any more!
That's all.
No! stay here, stay here, Shuiski.
I ask you: have you ever heard
that children who are dead, return from where they slumber,
to prosecute the Tsar, the Tsar,
the ruler, elected by the people,
and crowned in solemn ritual by the Patriarch?
What?
You laugh?
Why don't you laugh, then?
Forgive me.
Almighty Tsar and Lord.
Tell me, Prince:
That day in Uglich, where the murder was committed,
and when Dimitri, the Tsarevich, was killed,
are you quite sure the victim was Dimitri?
- Quite.
- Vasili Ivanich!
By all that you hold holy,
I beseech you, be frank with me.
Truth is all I want!
I shall be magnanimous: the past is past,
and even your betrayal I can forget.
But if you cheat me now, and lie to me,
I shall devise a punishment so devilish
that Tsar Ivan himself would tremble in his grave with horror.
Now answer me!
You speak of punishment to scare me,
no death I fear, I only fear your displeasure!
Everyone in Uglich had seen the body:
five days and nights it lay outside the old cathedral,
and with the child another thirteen corpses,
disfigured terribly, in rags, and blood-bespattered.
One could see how all of them
had slowly started rotting.
But then I saw Dimitri's face
was peaceful, pure, and radiant.
But bloody red, frightfully, his wound was gaping,
yet on his lips, so chaste and so guileless,
a child's contented smile was playing.
He looked as if he were asleep and dreaming a happy dream,
and in his right hand he clutched a little toy,
as though defending it.
Enough!
Ah!—for some air!
I'm suffocating here.
I feel how all my blood is rushing to my head,
it's raging in my temples.
Oh guilty conscience,
how cruelly you punish!
If you did but once in life an evil deed,
and though it was your fate that made you do it,
your soul is doomed, your heart is drowned in poison,
it'll be hard, hard, one becomes oppressed,
like hammer blows pounding in your ears,
the thunder of damnation.
Something smothers and chokes you ...
My head is spinning.
before my eyes . . . the child ...
I see it lying there in its blood . .
There ... there ...
what is it?
there in the corner
It threatens me . . .
it grows . . . closes in
it moans and trembles . .
Away! Away!
not I ... I did not ... murder you
away ... away, my child
it was not I,
it was the people! away, my child
away!
Oh Lord!
You wouldn't want the death of a sinner.
Have mercy on the soul of a criminal, Tsar Boris.
Do not speak to me of love and passion,
all your solemn oaths, I fear, will not convince me.
Yes, my friend, your case is hopeless.
Moscow's haughty power will yet yield to Poland.
And her mighty soldiers, they will rot in prison.
And Boris, their ruler, we will beat forever!
Yes, it sounds enchanting, but why don't you do it?
Show the Russians: you're the stronger.
And Boris is Tsar no longer!
For Poland's greater glory first we must destroy
the might of Moscow!
Marina cannot help us: her beauty is too cold
she's haughty—proud . . .
And now—let's drink, my friends!
To the health of the Mnishneks.
And here's to you, Marina!
Drink with us to fame and beauty!
A glass of wine to toast Marina!
The crown of Tsars will yet adorn Marina!
Vivat! vivat!
Dimitri! Tsarevich! Dimitri!
It's you—Marina!
You have come, beloved,
most beautiful of all.
How the days are long, and lonely, dearest,
when I must be without you.
Doubting, my heart is suffering tortures,
all that I cherish,
all that my longing heart ever has hoped for,
the dream of love and passion that I dreamed now is shattered.
I know:—you suffer.
No sleep at night and yet you dream;
for day and night you always dream about Marina!
Yet there's no sacrifice, however great,
that you won't bring for me,
if love demands it so!
But when will you set out for Moscow as the Tsar?
The Tsar?
How cruel you can be, Marina,
in all your words I feel the chilly wind of winter.
See me lying at your feet,
a humble slave, I beg of you:
do not deny me, and my ardent passion!
Serve your Polish masters, you impostor!
Marina-hear me first!
Go away, Polish slave!
No, Marina!
I will not have you throw into my face the bitter lot
of times that are behind me.
Lies! and you know you're lying.
I am the Tsarevich!
And one day soon from Russia's farthest regions
a host of valiant men will heed the call of duty -
I will lead them all! We will march on Moscow
and conquer the throne that fate has willed to me!
Yes, and then, as Tsar and master, enthroned in lonely splendor,
I shall sit above you, laughing and jeering at you!
I shall be happy seeing you humbled at last,
and you, in abject obedience,
bewailing the glory that could have been yours,
will be crawling up to the throne on which I sit.
Everyone will point a mocking finger at the foolish Polish lady,
and deride you!
Deride me?
My Tsarevich! I beseech you,
do forgive me for the evil words that I spoke.
If I blamed you, if I scorned you,
believe me, Dimitri: love inspired all my words
love for your glory,
a deep, abiding love for you my master.
My Lord and Tsar!
You may put all your trust in your Marina,
forget, yes, forget your Marina!
Let fame be your only love,
and conquer the throne of the Tsar!
Marina! Oh, how I wish
that your words were true -
do not betray a love that is holy!
I love you, Tsar!
Yes, I love you. You are my hero!
Oh—let me hear it again, Marina.
Yes, this deep delight that you promise me
will bring peace to my tortured heart,
for ever and ever you are mine!
My Tsar!
- You, Tsarina, you will be forever mine!
- You have conquered my heart, and I love you.
- Come, and embrace the man you love.
- I'm forever yours. Oh, my Dimitri, the Tsar you will be!
vivat! vivat!
Say—is the service over?
Yes, and once again he was cursed!
What do you mean?
Once more they cursed Grishka Otrepyev's name.
Grishka?
Listen, brothers, let me tell you
how the deacon, the fat one,
started yelling:
"Grishka Otrepyev — Anathema!"
This is very funny - why should Dimitri care
if they are cursing Grishka?
That's certain.
He is not Grishka!
The Tsarevich is not Grishka.
He's not Grishka
For the Tsarevich they sang a requiem.
For a man that's alive?
Well, just wait.
Our Tsarevich's alive,
he'll show Boris!
Some have seen him in the Kromy woods.
They say his troops can't be very far from Moscow.
And soon he will destroy Boris and all his might.
Triumphant, he will mount the golden steps
to the throne that rules over Russia.
He'll save us all.
Through him Boris and all his henchmen will be doomed.
Will you shut up? Stupid devils,
or are you longing for the torture-chamber?
Trr, trr, trr, tr . . .
his hat is of tin - it makes such a din!
In the sky the moon is shining,
on earth, a kitten whining
get up, you simpleton,
pray to God above you,
ask that He should love you,
praise Lord Jesus!
Lovely weather . . . lovely moon-light
lovely weather
moon-light
Greetings! Greetings,
dear simpleton Ivanich,
get up and greet us!
Bow to show us your respect
and take off your cap —such a heavy cap .
I have a kopeck, I'm hiding it here!
Liar!
Do not try to fool us, fool!
- Here
Ah—ah—
Why did you take my kopeck away?
Come and give it back to me!
ah ... ah ... ah
Please, in the name of Christ,
do save us from hunger! Tsar—Father,
in the name of the Saviour!
Look, there's the Tsar.
Tsar — in the name of Jesus, our Saviour
you are our father.
have mercy on us,
for we all are your children!
In the name of Lord Jesus, our Saviour.
Your people cry — we're hungry
Tsar, give us bread to eat!
We are hungry Tsar—give us bread to eat!
In the name of Lord Jesus.
ah - ah - ah
Boris, hear, Boris!
Those wicked boys are nasty to me.
ah - ah - ah
Why does he cry so?
Those boys,
they took my only kopeck away.
Why don't you have them murdered?
The way you murdered long ago our little Tsarevich!
Be silent, fool!
Arrest the stupid fool!
Don't touch him!
Go, pray for me,
holy fool.
No, Boris -
I cannot pray for you, Boris.
I cannot pray for King Herod.
The Holy Virgin forbids it.
Let's set him down - right here,
let's make him comfortable.
Sit down!
And so that he won't yell,
and that his noble throat won't suffer damage,
let's stop his mouth! That's it!
But, listen: here sits a Boyar,
and you do not pay him homage.
- What? No one greets him?
- That's a scandal!
Friends of Boris deserve more honor!
Boris, the robber Tsar, he stole the throne of Russia,
but then this robber robbed the thief!
So—let's honor him for that, like any decent thief.
Hey! Fomka—Epiklan, be his body-guard.
That's it.
Dim in the sky are sun and moon —
and all the stars will have vanished soon—
the day of final reckoning has begun
for all the evil deeds Boris has done.
Deep is the grief of this holy land,
and heavy is the hand of him who scorned the Lord,
that threefold cursed hand of him who killed a Tsar
for his sins he will pay in all eternity!
Everywhere Boris has his henchmen,
who torture innocent people!
Torture most frightful, hanging and beating,
the true believers must suffer
- Death!
Death!
Death for Boris!
Death for the killer Tsar!
Kill Boris, the killer Tsar!
He who has killed must die!
Well Boyars, let's take a vote on it.
First, tell us
what you think about him?
Well—our opinion is,
and always has been:
- take notes, Andrei Mikhailich -
The scoundrel, whoever he may be,
once he's caught, he shall be tortured
and then we'll kill him,
and we'll hang his body
Let him be food for the hungry crows!
No! the flames shall burn his body,
and all the people shall be present to witness his death
and curse his ashes three times.
And, falling on our knees, we'll pray and ask the Lord
to have mercy on our Russia,
the long-suffering.
But . . . Shuiski is not with us?
though he's a traitor,
when he is not with us
we miss him in our council.
Boyars! I ask your pardon!
Why, speaking of the devil!
If I am late, forgive me,
and do believe me that I have my reasons!
Last week I saw the Tsar, and when I left him,
my heart was heavy with pity for his soul's affliction . . .
A secret door was open . . . and I saw ...
Oh what a sight I witnessed, Boyars!
His body shaking and mumbling to himself,
some strange and incoherent phrases,
a secret pain distorting his features.
Thus I saw the Tsar of all the Russias!
Then he began to stare into a corner,
he started to moan and to shiver.
Lies! Lies!
and, crying out, he called the dead Dimitri,
Seeing his ghost, he raised his hands to chase it
"Away! away" he begged.
- Away, away!
- Away, my child!
Heaven! It's he!
Help us. Lord
Almighty God: have mercy and protect us!
Away - away!
Who says that I have killed him?
It is not true:
The child lives!
And Shuiski -
I will have him drawn and quartered for all his lies!
May the Heaven's blessing be with you!
What?
I called for you, Boyars,
because I always trust your wisdom.
In times of danger and bitter trials
you are the guardians of my power, Boyars!
Almighty Lord and Tsar!
You know I am your humble slave,
yet duty bids me speak:
here's what happened, Tsar:
a man came to your door,
he's very old and humbly hopes he might be allowed
to stand before his sovereign.
A man of truth and wisdom,
his life was pure and blameless,
he says he knows a secret that he must tell you.
Very well, Prince,
admit the man!
One evening, close on the night, a shepherd came to me.
His face was old with wrinkles.
he sat with me and this is what he told me:
"From early childhood" he started
"I was blind, I'd never seen the dark of night nor daylight,
my eyes were dead!"
Once ... I heard a voice in dreaming,
soft and childish, it called my name,
I still hear that voice . . .
"Come! get up at once, find out where Uglich is,
go there and enter the cathedral.
And then you kneel and pray where my grave lies.
"Know this, old man.
I am Dimitri, your Tsarevich!
But I am now among the Angels of the Lord
and am endowed with all the blessed gifts of healing!"
I'm choking—choking!
Help me!
I want to see the Tsarevich.
I , . . cannot breathe . . .
cannot . . .
Leave us alone,
all of you!
Farewell, my son,
I am dying ...
from now on
you will be the Tsar!
Don't ever ask
how I ascended to this throne,
my son,
you need not know. . . .
Tsar you shall be,
and rightful ruler
as my successor,
my son, my first-begotten.
Hear me! My dear child!
Do not trust the slanders of the seditious boyars,
Never forget
that some are traitors in league with Lithuania.
Punish treachery without pity,
without mercy!
Yet, to be just in your judgment,
listen to your people.
Like a warrior, defend the true belief,
and revere the Saints,
and ask them to bless you.
Oh Lord! Lord!
Look down upon a sinful father's tears.
Not for myself I pray,
not for myself I beg You! Father!
See my children,
send to them the light of Your unending love,—
Protect them both, forever. They are guiltless.
Angels of God the Lord:
You who guard the eternal throne
unfold your shining wings to give him shelter,
to save my son, my Fyodor, from every ill,
and from temptation.
Hear those sepulchral sounds!
Mortal brothers, weep and cry:
for his end is near...
The funeral dirge ...
give me . . . the cloister's vestments
the Tsar
withdraws to God!
... his lips will close in eternal silence
Mercy! Hallelujah!
Mighty Tsar, have courage,
the Lord will help you.
No, no, my son,
this is the end.
Dying, a child appears before our eyes,
we lament it, poor child ...
Oh Lord, I am sorely afflicted.
Will my sins never be forgiven?
... it struggles, it moans and sobs
and cries and begs for mercy,
Oh fearful Death,
how cruel is your torture!
... and cries and begs for mercy,
but death will show no mercy!
Wait!
I still am Tsar!
Heaven! Death!
forgive me, all ...
the Tsar is now ...
Tsar ...
forgive me ...
forgive ...
Ever rising, ever spreading grows the people's might.
Like an ever-swelling tide.
Bid him welcome, dearest friends,
the one and only Tsar!
Bid him welcome,
him whom the Lord has saved
from the evil hands of his vilest foe!
Bid him welcome, dearest friends,
and greet Dimitri, noble son of Ivan!
Domine, Domine, salvum fac ...
Nasty ravens, both of them.
It seems they also are defending the rightful Tsar.
We won't have it, father Missail!
We won't have it!
Domine, Domine, salvum fac Regem,
Regem Demetrium Moscoviae ...
Let's kill the cursed ravens!
A tree! A tree! A rope!
Yes! we will hang you three-fold cursed enemies!
Yes, dearest friends,
we will hang them on the highest tree!
There they can pray for the universe in eternity!
We, Dimitri Ivanovich,
by the grace of God, the Lord,
Tsarevich of all the Russias,
Prince of the blood of noble forebears,
We assure you victims of Godunov of our kindness.
To those whom Godunov made suffer
we will grant protection!
Mighty Lord, our Tsar Dimitri,
glory to you!
Rise, Boyars!
I lead you fight with me
to free the land of our fathers!
With me march on to Moscow!
Deo gloria! Deo gloria!
Gush forth, gush forth,
bitter tears!
weep, weep, faithful heart,
weep in deep anguish:
soon the foe will come
and darkness will fall
night will blind us all
and no hope of dawn.
Russia's sorrow is great.
Weep, weep, Russian people,
starving people ...
Thus ends Mussogsky's musical drama
"BORIS GODUNOV"
Engl. translation: John Gutman
slight corrections and timings: serdar202