Steven Spurrier.
I own the winery Madeleine...
and founder of the Academy of Wine.
Sorry, sir,
but your name is not on the list.
The Englishman is not in the list.
The receipt.
I bought a ticket two weeks ago.
Follow me sir.
The Bicentanial of the United States.
Cross the Atlantic
¿Mr Tari?
Hello.
We met at dinner
of the New Federation...
the other night.
Sorry, I don't remember you.
Look.
The poor and reviled...
St. Estèphe Cos D'Estournel del 59...
neglected by negligible acidity...
and low fiber.
I hear you.
I predict that aging...
will prove his critics
were wrong.
So, ¿I am accused of having open it...
15 years too early?
20 would be better.
Do you like vintage.
I prefer them young.
¿I can sit with you for a moment?
¡We're here!
Hi. I'm fine.
¡Mr. Kahn, delited!
Agreed. Allons-y! ¡Lets go, Lets go!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
my name is Steven Spurrier. Welcome.
I conceived this wine tasting
Franco-American...
to educate my palate...
and others in this new forum...
about winemaking in the United States.
1976, the year of the Bicentennial of the United States.
I thought an event like this...
we remember the importance of France...
in American history
200 years ago.
I was surprised at the quality...
of California wines.
And their originality.
There is some interest in the Napa Valley...
to experiment in winemaking...
with novel methods.
that said...
I've selected the best wines of California...
made in the French style...
together with some
from my favorite French wines.
And in order to be objective...
tasting will...
blind.
I now...
I present to you...
the Judges.
Mr Christian Vannequé...
the sommelier of La Tour d'Argent...
Mr Jean-Claude Vrinat...
owner of the famous restaurant Taillevent...
Mr Pierre Bréjoux...
Inspector general of the A.O. C...
Mrs Odette Kahn...
chief writer...
of The magazine of French Wines...
Mr Pierre Tari...
secretary general of the Association
of "Grands Crus Classés"...
Mr Raymond Oliver...
owner and chef del Grand Vefour...
Mr Claude Dubois-Millot...
director of marketing of Gault Millau...
and Mr Aubert de Villaine...
part-owner
of Domaine de la Romanée-Conti.
Thank You everyone.
¡Lets start!
My dear Bréjoux, ¿what do you think?
It is solid.
This is not a French wine.
We are here to judge the quality,
not the country of origin.
¿Kidding?
This is surely a French wine.
Clear.
leathery...
and a little dominant and its mellow.
Has an acceptable taste.
For once you're right.
without a doubt from California.
No, Bréjoux youre right.
This one is French.
Its acceptable.
Of course.
Unpleasant, with no taste.
Ladies and Gentlemen...
let's take a little break...
before moving on to the reds.
Take this opportunity...
to do a vote recount for the
white wines.
¿Who won?
One second...
Please.
Sir, I would like to see
the results.
Please.
We are all waiting impatiently.
Yes, yes.
Here we go.
In First Place...
with a total of 132 points...
is for...
Château Montelena...
of Napa Valley...
in California.
Representing Montelena...
Mr Bo Barrett.
In Second Place, with 126...