I知 goin' to California
and I値l be sleepin' out every night
but I値l be sleepin' out every night
cos' them Oklahoma women
Well, they just ain't a-treatin' me right
Well, I would rather drink muddy water
Whoa, and sleep in a hollow log
Than be down here in Texas
Treated like a low-down dog
Well, them California waters
They taste like cherry wine
Them California waters
Taste just like cherry wine
Yeah.
Cherry wine
Cherry wine. Goddammit, Woody!
I致e got half a notion to pull up stakes
and hit the road for California.
I been thinking about heading down the
Gulf of Mexico or the Rio Grande valley.
Just somewhere's where
I could grow some fruit. Peaches.
Them Indian blood peaches,
with that red meat.
Shit fire, Carl! Why down there?
In California, you just plop a seed in the
ground and it sprouts the very next day.
Seems I sure gotta do somethin'.
I just don't know what's gonna happen
to everybody around here.
You folks sure are depressin'.
Well, I got one.
- Put a buck's worth in.
- Yes, sir!
A buck's worth
of the finest gasoline in Texas.
You boys got any news?
Ain't nothin' interestin' to tell, except
people are movin' out of these parts.
My name's Collister, and I been runnin' all
over this here state to them fortune-tellers.
Ain't a one of 'em's told me a damn thing.
Someone tell me somethin' worth
listenin' to, and I値l pay 'em a dollar.
It's been pretty dusty around here.
Hell, Woody,
that ain't worth nothin', for sure!
Well, I ain't much for fortune-tellin'.
You're a inside man.
Got a big job with the oil refinery?
- How'd you know that?
- Well...
Ain't nobody else got money to waste
on fortune-tellers and soda pop.
Keep goin'.
Well, them creases
in between your eyebrows,
You're probably a man
takes his work serious.
Always lookin' for a way
to do things better.
You get 50 cents
Keep talkin'.
Well, you probably got some kind of idea.
An invention of some kind.
A big company wants to buy you out.
You get a paper dollar
if you tell me when to do it.
Hell, I ain't no mind-reader.
You're the only one I ever met that didn't
claim to know everything in the world.
- What's your name?
- Woody.
Woody Guthrie.
Well, Guthrie, I値l spread the word.
You're worth every penny.
Thank you kindly.
There's a nickel for the coke,
a dollar for the gas.
The momma bear says:
"Ain't nobody gonna eat none of my
porridge and get away with it."
So she takes up a pair of sheep shears
And she cuts every hair
off the top of that little kid's head.
- Good one, daddy.
- Yeah, ain't that somethin'?
Then old Goldilocks,
she just heads on back into the forest
and she goes to sleep for about 20 years.
When she wakes up
all her hair is growed back.
Well, looks pretty good, don't it?
It looks darn good.
But... there ain't nobody round here
gonna pay you to talk to 'em.
Oh, now, that fella down at the gas station
said I was the best fortune-teller
he had ever seen.
That weren't nothin' but happenstance,
and you know it.
You could be makin' regular money with
your sign paintin', Woody, if you tried.
Just ain't no sense in harpin' on it, Mary.
It'll do no good.
You could do it. You could do 'em so
special, somebody'd be sure to want 'em.
Come on in and...
...talk it over
Lay your head upon my shoulder
she's my curly-headed baby
come from sunny Tennessee
Iain't really a doctor.
Well, she ain't sick exactly.
Her oldest girl died of the dust pneumonia
almost a week ago.
She ain't drunk a drop since.
She can't swallow.
- I don't see how i...
- some fortune-tellers have got the gift.
Healin', layin' on of hands,
discernin' of spirits.
I ain't really a fortune-teller.
Poor little thing. We can't just
let her waste away. Go on.
Ma'am?
Do you have faith that you'll be cured?
Well, look.
Your daughter.
Don't you believe she's up in heaven?
Well...
that means you believe in god.
And if there's a god,
then it was him gave you your mind.
Well, everybody knows the mind's
the boss of the whole body.
It just tells all the nerves
and muscles what to do.
Your arms and hands and back.
Throat.
You don't wanna die, do you? Leave
your husband and your kids all alone?
Your husband wants you to talk to him,
don't he? Your kids to boot.
There ain't no two ways about that!
Could I have some water here?
Away all that monkey business.
Just send a message straight down there
to your throat, mouth, and...
tell 'em to just swig down this here water.
Thank you.
Just try.
Just do it.
Afterwards, you tell me how dandy it was.
Now...
now you swallow it. Swallow it.
That was easy.
You did it! You can do it some more.
Next couple of days, I want you two ladies
to pour water down this lady's throat.
Why, you can have a water-drinkin'
contest every now and then.
You just talk to her now about everything.
Talk to her.
You'll be ok.
All right.
See, you don't... you don't owe me nothin'.
Bless you, Mr. Guthrie.
Phew-ee!
I did it!
I think.
- Afternoon, Donna Jo.
- Good afternoon, Woody.
Woody? Do you and Mary
have any use for a bedroom set?
It's real nice. It's called
the waterfall design or somethin'.
I just hate to leave it, sat there.
Howdy, Jesse.
Uh, sure.
Sure, I guess we can do somethin' with it.
Good. There's an old chair in there too.
We just ain't got room for everything.
- Where are you folks goin'?
- California.
I don't know, it just seems like
everything ran out around here...
when Jesse got laid off.
Y'all are welcome to anything you find
in there that you wanna use.
Ok. Thank you kindly, Donna Jo.
You folks take care.
They might have jobs in that
new department store in Amarillo.
Hell, pa, I ain't gonna be
no shoe salesman.
- There might be somethin' else.
- It's too damn far out there anyhow.
You tell her that when she's beggin'
for milk in the mornin'.
- Tell her it's too far to travel.
- Mary, it's 62 miles.
Well, maybe you could sing one of your
songs to her or tell her fortune instead.
- Just don't start in on me, ok?
- It don't do no good to be carryin' on.
Times and the weather are bad enough.
It just don't do no good.
I don't mean to be startin' in.
I don't mean to always be at you, Woody.
But it just don't seem fair.
Even your brother's been out lookin'
for somethin', and he's just a boy.
How about some new signs
on your truck?
No, not today, Woody.
What in the hell are you doin'?
I told you I wanted white on black.
I thought you'd like red better.
Shows up from a mile away.
I asked for white on black
and you give me this red bitch thing?
Was you plannin' on gettin' paid for this?
- I was plannin' on it.
- Well, just plan away, Guthrie.
What am I supposed to do
with this red bitch anyways?
Why don't you fold it five ways
and stick it where the sun don't shine?
I値l tell you what else I don't need.
I don't need none of your lip neither!
Ain't you kids got nothin' better to do
than lollygag around here?
She's my curly-headed baby
used to sit on daddy's knee
she's my curly-headed baby
come from sunny Tennessee
and I知 gonna tell you
'bout these women
I知 gonna tell you what they do
lay their head upon your shoulder
flirt around...
did you really write that song about me?
Sure. Sure it's about you. Damn right.
Curly-headed lady...
remember what you asked me?
It hasn't been outta my mind for a second.
- I don't care.
- Don't care about what?
If we do.
- Do what?
- You know.
Come on.
Guess this town ain't entirely dead yet.
I don't know if you knew it or not,
but you lookin' at an insane man.
Well...
why don't you take off
a couple of sweaters and sit down?
I really am insane.
Well, hell...
hell, so am i. Off and on.
I heard tell about you in the next town
and thought I壇 better come.
I been in the insane asylum twice.
You have?
Maybe I better watch out,
havin' you around the place.
I wasn't crazy when they sent me there,
but then I beat up them two guards and...
now I知 a-here,
and even if they get me pretty quick,
Iwanted to tell you
Igot newsreels in my head.
- Newsreels?
- Yeah.
Since I was a kid. And my momma
always told me I was crazy.
They just never stop.
What kind of newsreels?
That the boom is over,
and the weeds are blowin' out,
and the dust storms are gettin' darker,
and there's people fightin' and killin'
and there's kids sick.
Ain't nothin' wrong with your head.
I see these shapes and designs,
and I see how to build roads better, and...
them your brushes?
Sure. Yeah.
I知... kind of a painter.
I sure wish I could sit down
and paint all them pictures I see.
Sometimes I think I could spend for ever
just paintin' and paintin' all them pictures.
Well... why don't you just take these?
Take 'em? I ain't got no money.
You don't need no money.
Just take 'em. I got plenty more.
Take some of this paint here.
Take those ideas and...
then find yourself someplace where...
where nobody'll bother you.
And just put those things down.
Just put those things down on paper.
You know?
Now bow to the person.
Now bow to the corner.
Join hands to the left.
Do-si-do!
Whoo-hoo!
- Dust storm!
- Dust storm's comin'!
Better get on home, Woody.
- You better get inside, Woody.
- Ok.
Looks like things ain't gonna be
too pleasurable around here.
- It's gonna be a real big 'un.
- Can I help you?
I got it.
Let's move the couch, pa.
Y'all's gonna ruin them things in this dust.
A little dirt won't hurt.
If this train rides me right
I値l be home Saturday night
cos I知 900 miles from my home
and I hate to hear
that lonesome whistle blow
it's that long lonesome train
whistlin' down
pawn you my gold diamond ring
mornin', jimmy.
Mornin', Woody.
Well...
got any more dances lined up?
Ain't heard of none.
What about that place over at Cartersville?
They was givin' a dance a month.
Yeah. Used to.
Yeah... well...
take her easy, jimmy.
- Let me give you a push.
- All right there, Woody.
- What do you think it is, Joe?
- I don't know, Woody.
- It's just dust.
- Thanks a lot, though.
It's dust, that's what it is.
Bye, Woody.
Seems like things just ain't
goin' so good around here.
Not the way they's goin'.
Hi, honey.
See you later, Woody.
- Mornin'.
- Get down! Get down, boy!
Get down!
- This train goin' to California?
- It's goin' in that direction.
Can't ask for more than that.
- You boys are gonna catch this train?
- Yeah.
Mind if I ride along?
No.
How come we're sittin' here so long?
Oh.
Welcome aboard, boys.
Welcome, cowboy.
Mind movin' over a little bit there, friend?
Much obliged.
- My name's Guthrie.
- Slim Snedeger.
- Slim.
- That there's "po" Steve.
- Howdy, Steve.
- I知 crippled whitey.
- Whitey.
- Crippled whitey, huh?
Crippled whitey is a fight-spotter.
- A fight-spotter?
- Yeah.
I can spot a fist fight on the street
three blocks before I come to it.
I can spot a gang fight
an hour before it happens.
That way, I tip off the boys
and they know how to lay their bets.
You got a fight spotted now, whitey?
I got a whopper.
When's it gonna happen?
- Not more than ten minutes.
- Ah, bullshit!
You watch your tongue, you young
jackass, or I値l tear you apart.
Hey, whitey, one doesn't start up by itself,
you're gonna whip up one of your own?
When it starts, I値l be sure to bust
a box over your head, fella.
Cantankerous, ain't he?
Yeah.
But it be he's like that sometimes.
Ridin' these boxcars and things can make
you meaner than 52 rattlesnakes.
Beats walkin', though.
Don't it?
Hey!
Don't push me out!
Whitey! Let me go!
Hey, whitey!
Whitey...
hey, we're slowin' down.
Let's jump off this son of a bitch.
- Jump?
- Jump!
- Go ahead, jump!
- Wait a minute.
And when you hit the ground, be on your
feet. That way, you won't break your ass.
Come on.
Come on up here.
What's wrong?
My brushes. Damn, I lost my brushes.
You gonna lose your ass. You're hangin'
halfway between heaven and hell.
Come on up here.
Let's move on down the car there.
- Damn!
- Let's move on down.
Them was about the best brushes
money could buy.
You a artist?
I was hopin' to pick up some money
paintin' signs on the way.
I知 pretty good at sign paintin'.
Sign painter, huh?
I expect you gonna do all right
in California.
Know why?
Cos they puttin' up signs and buildings
and everything out there.
- You been?
- Who, me? Nah.
But I heard a heap of talk about it.
They tell me, California's the place
for some real nice livin'.
That's what I hear.
What are you gonna do
when you get there?
Well...
Whoo!
Well, first thing I知 gonna do is take me
a long look at that pacific ocean,
cos I been wantin' to see
that booger all my life.
Then I expect I値l ease on down
to one of them fruit orchards
and get me a job, pickin' fruit.
They tell me fruit is just beggin'
to be picked out there.
You know what I mean?
You drop a seed in the ground,
and you blink your eye,
and you got yourself
a tree bustin' with fruit.
Yeah?
Everything a man needs,
right out there in California.
- Know what I mean?
- Everything a man needs?
Yep.
Let's check 'em, boys.
Shit! We comin' into Acomita.
Come on outta there, you yahoos.
Come on outta there now, dammit!
- Let's go!
- Get outta there, woman.
- No!
- Pull her out.
Hey, you son of a bitch!
Ok, boys.
Poor bastard. Ice didn't help this one.
Smells like he's been in there for a week.
You haven't been takin'
full advantage of the railroad facilities.
We want you to ride in full comfort,
so we're gonna put you inside,
where you can stretch out your legs
and rest your heads back on doilies.
Wouldn't that be nice?
- How much money you got?
- A dollar, fifty. I don't know.
He can ride all the way to Holden on that.
Write him up a ticket.
How much you got?
Don't hear nothin' jinglin',
don't feel nothin' foldin'.
Boy, you appear to be a vagrant.
We have a curfew on vagrants.
Or didn't you know that?
I don't believe I did. When is it?
Every hour, on the hour.
Get on your hands and knees, sonny.
I could shoot you in the hand if I wanted.
Or in the thigh, in the soft part.
Or I could take you out in them weeds
after everybody's gone.
Agh!
Your mother'd wait a long time
for those letters you promised to write.
Come on, move on.
Let's get aboard. Come on.
Keep it movin'.
The rest of you,
get your ass down the road.
Come this way again, gentlemen,
and it'll be 30 days. 30 big 'uns.
Move it out!
So long, Guthrie!
See you in California!
Take it easy, slim!
But take it!
Howdy, pastor.
My name is Guthrie.
I...
well, have you got any work I could do
for just a small meal of some kind?
Well, sir, I would do anything to earn it.
Son, I致e been in the service all my life.
I致e seen thousands of men like you,
who go to work for a meal.
However, at this moment
there isn't any work to be done.
Therefore, if I were to feed you,
it would be an act of charity.
Which may be all right for the moment,
but could cause harm in the long run.
You seem to have retained
your pride and your dignity,
since you didn't ask outright
for a free meal.
And that's to your credit.
But to answer your question,
there's no work to be done.
And, therefore, you can't earn a meal.
Good luck, son.
We been all over. Niagara falls,
Washington DC, New Orleans, Chicago.
Spent a couple of weeks this past winter
in Miami Beach.
- Must have been real interestin'.
- You bet it was.
Meetin' different people, seein' all the
sights, goin' to the unusual restaurants.
I found out somethin'
about eatin' on my trip.
- Really? What was that?
- The more you eat, the more you shit.
A hard-workin' man and brave
he said to the rich
"give your goods to the poor"
and they laid Jesus Christ in his grave
Jesus was a man, a carpenter by hand,
his followers, true and brave
one dirty little coward
named Judas Iscariot
laid Jesus Christ in his grave
put your money away, Guthrie.
It's on the house. You really sing great.
You know the one I like the best? The one
you sing about that dead cowboy guy.
I like it. It's good.
I wrote that song especially. Just for you.
In a pig's ass you did, Guthrie.
Just as he's walkin', a man is talkin'.
To who's he talkin'?
The man who's walkin'.
Why is he talkin'?
To keep on walkin'.
Keep on walkin'.
Walkin' and talkin'.
Talkin' and walkin'.
Whoo-ee! California!
Hey, take a look at that. California!
Everything a man needs, out there.
- Yee-ha!
- Yes, sir, the California state line.
- What's goin' on?
- Looks like some kind of hold-up.
Maybe a accident or somethin'.
Accident, hell!
They're turnin' people back.
What's goin' on?
They're checkin' us out,
to see if we got any money.
Gotta have $50 to get across the border.
- $50?!
- Yeah, in cash.
That's right. Los Angeles police
came out here and set up this blockade.
- We that close to Los Angeles?
- Yeah, about 300 miles.
Jesus!
What are you gonna do?
Ain't no sense in waitin' in line,
just to get shoved back.
I might as well turn back right now.
You comin'?
No. I reckon there's more than one way
to get across the border,
if you don't have a family taggin' along.
Look... why don't you take this?
It ain't no $50,
but you got them kids an' all.
Thanks. I appreciate that, friend.
Maybe we'll both be millionaire's sons
next time we meet each other.
- Maybe so.
- I hope so anyway.
- Take care.
- Thank you kindly for the ride.
Howdy.
Hey.
Hey, why don't you come over
and share my bed?
Come on.
Sure.
- Thanks, mister.
- I can't stand chatterin' teeth.
Better watch yourself,
cos when she gets here,
she's gonna be movin'
like a turpentined cat.
You sure as you know what you're doin'?
Them guys won't do nothin'
once she's movin'.
Get us into la 'fore you know it.
Ain't this a son of a bitch?
I never seen a train take off...
you got him.
That is about as clean
as this wall is gonna get.
Did you get right on top there?
- I did. Where's my chilli?
- It was very greasy over there.
- What's your name?
- Woody.
Yah, Woody!
Yes, sir! Best chilli in the city.
Goodbye, fellas.
Best in the world...
as far as I知 concerned.
- Damn!
- Here, have some onion and crackers.
Put lots of onion in it.
Tastes good that way.
Look at this mess, huh?
Just one bowl of chilli and a lot of mess.
You know where a fella
can get a job hereabouts?
- You just come in town?
- Mm-hm. This mornin'.
You better go home.
A chilli and crackers!
- Deadhead.
- Push it down.
- You mean let it down?
- You know what I mean.
That's as far as it'll go down.
If I let it down, it won't...
- I can't even lift the thing.
- It won't go on the hub.
It won't go. You gotta have it up.
Would you like to just do this yourself?
Looks like a mighty stubborn tyre.
Just like everything else.
- Be glad to help.
- We'd sure appreciate it.
Yeah.
- This wheel's bent.
- Bent?
Seems like everything in California's bent.
I hope we find somethin' in this place.
Yeah.
She just needs milk real soon.
We'll be ok.
What the hell's goin' on here?
How come all these people
are livin' like this?
It ain't no different.
It's the goddamn same as all the rest.
Growers, they need
three or four hundred workers.
They put out leaflets and posters
and advertise for a thousand,
and 1200 showed up.
They got the first ones that get here
crammed inside them shacks over there.
They're workin' pretty steady.
All the rest of us are sittin' on our asses,
hopin' they're gonna need extra workers.
Hell, I worked three days
in the last two weeks.
The wages, they doesn't buy...
the wages...
I don't know,
makes me sick just talkin' about it.
What are we gonna do, then?
We got nothin' left.
Ain't got no choice.
You're welcome to spend the night
in the truck, if you want.
Seems to me somethin'
ought to be done about this.
There's nothin'.
There's always somethin'.
There's been some talk about
formin' a union, goin' on strike.
But... hell, Woody, not many people
can afford to miss a day's work.
No.
By the time they call on us to pick,
we're more than happy to work
for four cents a bushel.
What'd you say if I took
this little old guitar into town?
Maybe I can pick up a dime or two?
You comin' back?
Got no place to sleep,
'cept in your truck.
Hell, yeah, go ahead and take it.
I ain't in too much of a mood
to use it anyway.
Thanks.
See you later.
Tell you what, I値l paint you a new sign
out there for a bowl of that soup.
Well, I tell you what, it's not necessary.
The food is free.
Well, suppose I said
I don't want no free food?
we don't have any other kind?
Well, I guess... I guess I壇 have to say
"please pass the soup."
Do you play?
Yep.
I studied piano.
Years ago. I never had the patience.
- That so?
- Yes.
Would you really paint us a sign?
- For food?
- For a favour.
I壇 have to think about that.
Uh... we don't have
any paint here right now.
Then how would I paint a sign?
I could bring some tomorrow.
Yeah, well, I値l see if I can come back.
Thanks for the soup.
Red and white paint is pretty nice.
Red and white.
Well, I was down in the henhouse
on my knees
I thought I heard a chicken sneeze
it was only a rooster
sayin' his prayers
thankin' his gods for the hens upstairs
just takin' it easy
lady, what'd you say?!
Hit him, bill!
Quiet down!
Now, we need 30 more pickers for today.
Quiet! Quiet down!
We're payin' four cents a bushel.
Four cents.
Line up over here by the gate
in single file.
Stop pushin' over there!
Keep on shovin',
and we won't take anybody.
Cheapskate!
Bastards.
Goddamn bastards!
- That's all they're takin', them 30 people?
- That's all they ever take.
Well, hell, why do you stay here? One
of them other camps may be hirin' more.
It don't make no difference.
I mean, they all work the same.
It's the fourth one we've been to, and...
they's all alike.
All of 'em is bastards.
That's beautiful!
- I had a terrible time with the one I did.
- Yeah, it looked like you did.
I really appreciate it.
Can I get you something to eat?
Not here.
What do you mean, not here?
Well,
you could fix me dinner at your place.
No, I couldn't do that.
Why not? You got a man?
No. My husband died.
- Well, what's your name?
- Pauline.
Mine's Woody.
- How about next Sunday?
- Woody, I知 not gonna fix you dinner.
Why not?
Because I just can't.
Yeah, course you can't.
- I can't say as I blame you.
- That's not the reason.
Well, it's a pretty good reason.
Listen,
give it a couple of hours
before you handle it, ok?
Way down in Columbus, Georgia
wanna be back in Tennessee
go and leave me if you want to
never let me cross your mind
if in your heart you love another
leave, little darlin', I don't mind
thinkin' about my blue-eyed sally
pretty little gal that I left behind
way down in Columbus stockade
wanna go back to Tennessee
way down in Columbus, Georgia
wanna be back in Tennessee
- it's Ozark!
- Who's Ozark?
- Ozark blue sings on the radio.
- Sometimes he comes to entertain us.
- Hey, Ozark.
- Hi, how are ya, sis?
I swear, you get prettier every day.
Hey, Jed, look over there and see what
I brought for you guys. Open that door.
You get to eat it
without pickin' it for a change.
I can see that you haven't been doin'
like I said and organisin'.
You're still lettin' those bosses
pay you nothin'
for bustin' your behinds
in those fields all day.
Now, the only way I値l do any singin' today
is if we all get together and shout "union".
Now, one, two, three...
union!
That was pitiful.
Now, we're gonna try it once more, and if
more of you don't join in, I知 leavin'.
Ah!
We're gonna try it again,
and I wanna hear more of you joinin' in.
- Now, one, two, three...
- union!
All right.
Now, it wasn't perfect...
but I reckon it's a start.
Let's have a little pickin' and singin'.
Yeah!
Long-haired preachers
come out every night
try to tell us what's wrong
and what's right
but when asked about somethin' to eat
they will answerin' voices so sweet:
You're gonna eat by and by
when you learn how to cook and to fry
chop some wood, it'll do you good
there'll be pie in the sky when you die
that's a lie!
There'll be starvation...
hi, neighbours! Come on over!
Come on over.
Now, I want you to listen to this verse.
It makes sense.
Workin' men of all countries, unite
side by side for freedom we will fight
when this world and its wealth
we have gained
to the grafters we'll sing this refrain
everybody!
You will eat by and by
in that glorious land above the sky
work and pray, live on hay
there'll be pie in the sky when you die
that's a dirty lie!
- One more!
- I値l tell you somethin' that's even better.
I want everybody here
that plays an instrument
to get that instrument
and come back here.
We're gonna have the damnedest
hoedown you've ever seen!
Round, round, old Joe Clark
round, round, I say
I知 gonna walk ten thousand miles
to hear them fiddles play
round, round, old Joe Clark
round, round, I say
I知 gonna walk ten thousand miles
to hear them fiddles play
round, round, old Joe Clark
round, round, I say
I知 gonna walk ten thousand miles
to hear them fiddles play
down in the valley
valley so low
late in the evenin'
hear the wind blow
roses love sunshine
violets love dew
angels in heaven
know I love you
write me a letter
send it by mail
let's move these people
back in their shacks.
Send it in care of
Birmingham jail
send it in care of
so, though it's been good to know you
this dusty old dust storm
is gettin' my goat
and I got to be driftin' along
driftin' along
- real good. Real good.
- Yeah. Too many strings on it.
Here.
- It might help.
- It might at that.
This train's bound for glory, this train
this train is bound for glory, this train
whoo-whoo!
This train don't carry no gamblers,
this train
this train is bound for glory, this train
this train is bound for glory, no one
aboard but the righteous and the holy
this train is bound for glory, this train
this train don't carry no liars, this train
this train don't carry no liars
oh, none of those midnight flyers
this train's bound for glory, this train
this train don't carry no con men,
this train
don't you know that, this train
don't carry no con men? This train
hey, this train don't carry no con men
none of those wheeler dealers,
here and gone men
this train is bound for glory, this train
this train's bound for glory, no one
aboard but the righteous and the holy
this train is bound for glory...
what the goddamn hell
do you think you're doin'?
This train...
what the hell does it look like we're doin'?
I warned you to stay
away from here, Blue.
Yeah, well, I forgot.
Let's get outta here.
- Ok, that's it!
- Hey!
Let's move outta here.
Get in the car!
Let him get through, everybody!
- Get him off!
- Get him off that car.
Get him off the car!
Union! Union!
- Union!
- Union! Union! Union!
This sort of thing happen every time
you come out to entertain folks?
Sure seems like it. As long as I知 gettin'
those goons riled up, I知 doin' my job.
I値l tell you, those boys
don't seem to like you too much.
Yeah? Well, they didn't seem
to like you too much either.
I wasn't even tryin'.
Maybe you ought to start.
- Start what?
- Tryin'.
Tryin' what?
You sure as hell don't look like much.
How do you sound?
- Makes me happy.
- Wait till you hear him, Mr. Locke.
Ok, Guthrie, let's hear something.
I壇 like to sing a song about the place...
Guthrie, let's just get on with it, please.
...place where I grew up. It's called "in
those Oklahoma hills where I was born".
Many a month has come and gone
since I wandered from my home
in those Oklahoma hills
where I was born
many a page of life has turned
many a lesson I have learned
and I feel like in those hills I still belong
way down yonder on the Indian nation
Ridin' my pony on the reservation
in those Oklahoma hills
where I was born
way down yonder on the Indian nation
the cowboy's life is my occupation
in those Oklahoma hills
where I was born
well, as I stand here in la
many a mile...
ok, Guthrie. We'll give you a try.
- ...my pony through the draw
- uh, Guthrie!
Where the oak and blackjack trees
kiss the playful prairie breeze
and I feel...
Guthrie! You have the job.
Way down yonder on the Indian nation
Ridin' my pony on the reservation
in those Oklahoma hills
where I was born
way down yonder on the Indian nation
the cowboy's life is my occupation
in those Oklahoma hills
where I was born
here's an advance, Guthrie.
I... I want you to go out
and get a set of decent clothes.
And...
and show up here next Thursday!
At 20 bucks a week.
Yahoo!
Since I知 almost respectable now, maybe
you can ask me to your house for dinner.
- That's not why I didn't ask you.
- Well, what is why?
I don't know you.
Well...
I think I壇 like chicken, with dressin'.
So go to sleep, my weary hobo
let the ton drift slowly by
and can't you hear
the steel rails hummin'?
That's the hobo's lullaby
folks, we got a real treat for you tonight.
We got an old boy from Oklahoma
who not only sings songs, he writes 'em.
And his name is Woodrow Wilson Guthrie,
but we just call him Woody.
And his song is called
"I ain't got no home".
Well, I ain't got no home
I知 just ramblin' around
I知 a hard-workin' ramblin' man
and I go from town to town
police make it hard,
hard everywhere I go
and I ain't got no home
in this world any more
I used to work for shares
seems like I was always poor
I laid my crops right at the banker's door
my wife took up and died
on the cabin floor
I ain't got no home any more
- howdy, Ozark.
- Hi, neighbours!
- Can I talk to you for just a minute?
- You sure can.
If I had to drag my tail home with 80 cents
in my pocket after workin' all day like this,
I壇 begin to wonder
if somethin' wasn't wrong.
It'd be nice if you had enough money to
put food on the table at the end of the day.
Did you ever stop to wonder if you could
do something about the way you live?
Because you can, friends
Woody!
I知 gonna get you!
Get outta the valley!
You sons of bitches,
stay out of this valley!
You people, get back to work!
Union! Union! Union!
I been ridin' in fast rattlers
I thought you knowed
I been ridin' in flat wheelers
way down the road
I been ridin' in blind passengers,
dead enders, kickin' up cinders
I been havin' some hard travellin', Lord
I been walkin' that Lincoln Highway
I thought you knowed
I been kickin' that 66
way down the road
I got a heavy load and a worryin' mind
I知 lookin' for a woman
that's hard to find
I been havin' some hard travellin', Lord
- Whoo!
- All right! Let's hear it here.
Now, the farm workers need your help.
I was expectin' the mayor! I thought
this was city hall there for a second.
Come on in, Woody.
How much you get paid
for workin' at that place anyhow?
I don't get paid.
I知 a volunteer.
Excuse me,
but could I ask you a question?
Sure. What?
Well, don't you get embarrassed ever?
"Embarrassed ever" about what?
Well, don't you get just a little bit
embarrassed about havin' so much,
when so many people got nothin'?
Well, I don't think "embarrassed".
I am very sorry that there are
so many people who have nothing.
Sure.
Course you are.
Sorry don't get the hay in.
So you ladle 'em up the soup
and dish out a little charity?
Well, we're not all as gifted as you are.
Some of us just do the best we can.
Pauline, let me tell you somethin'.
When i...
well, when I was on the road,
I met a lot of different kinds of people.
There was bums and freeloaders.
There was families that was torn apart.
And poor people that just was achin'
for some kind of work.
And men that are just tryin'
to get somewhere. Anywhere.
They all got somethin' in common,
that every one of them
had somethin' to give me.
Then you meet some man
that's got some money,
and he'll be... tied up and anxious.
The human thing is just gone.
It's just gone, cos he's afraid.
Afraid that he's gonna lose somethin'.
He's afraid to smile, cos somebody's
gonna swipe his teeth out his mouth.
You don't believe that
just because a person has money
that he completely loses touch?
Because that's wrong.
I feel as alive and human as anyone else.
That don't give me nothin'.
What the hell am I supposed
to give you, Woody?
Just why did you come here?
I just liked the way you looked, and...
I thought you had possibilities.
Possibilities.
Well, what must you think now?
I think I知 lookin' at a... rich person.
So?
So, you're the only one
that's ever looked back.
You know, Samson went out walkin'...
and slew a lion with his bare hands.
But it took
a pretty woman
to show Samson he was just a lamb
come on, we haven't got all day.
I have a reputation to uphold.
If anybody catches us here,
they're gonna be a little bit angry at us.
Doesn't have to look like
Rembrandt, did it?
- Next time I知 paintin' the sign.
- It ain't bad.
There ain't no sense in doin' it
if somebody can't read it.
- Might as well paint signs white.
- You never been caught.
I wouldn't wanna be caught by them guys
with a sign that looked as awful as that.
B- e-l-l-l-e.
There we go. S.
Ok.
"Come on..." you can read that.
Come on, let's go.
Good evenin', y'all. This is Woody, talkin'
to you while Ozark痴 catchin' his breath.
I壇 like to dedicate a song tonight
to all you folks sittin' out there
in them fruit-pickin' camps.
I know you're squattin' there, hungry,
either too darn hot or too darn cold,
and wonderin' if you
should have ever left home.
This here's for y'all.
If we don't organise,
if we don't unite in our struggle,
those growers will have us
on our knees for ever!
- Let's strike.
- We gotta work.
- We gotta strike!
- But our families? How are we gonna eat?
There are donations of food and clothing
coming from all over the state.
- We don't want charity, we want jobs.
- Listen. Listen to me!
There ain't nobody gonna get any
damn jobs until you start to listen to us.
- You're nothin' but commies!
- Sit down!
- You sit down!
- No.
Now's not the time to sit down,
but to stand up for your rights.
Sit down and shut up.
Please listen to us.
We're telling you the truth.
Hold it! Please, hold it.
Just a tune of "free red range".
There once was a union maid
who never was afraid
of the goons and the ginks
and the company finks
and the deputy sheriffs
who made the raids
she went to the union hall
when a meetinn' it was called
and when the company boys
came round she always stood her ground
oh, you can't scare me
I知 stickin' to the union
till the day I die
well, the union maid was wise
to the tricks of the company spies
she was never gonna be fooled
by the company stools
she'd always organised the guys
she always got her way
when she struck for higher pay
she'd show her card
to the national guard
and this is what she'd say:
Oh, you can't scare me
I知 stickin' to the union
oh, you can't scare me
till the day I die
everybody!
Oh, you can't scare me
I知 stickin' to the union
oh, you can't scare me
till the day I die
- outside!
- Get off me.
- I said, outside!
- Get...
...I知 sti...
excuse me.
Do you ever think of becoming a painter?
I reckon I壇 get busted up doin' that
just as easy as anythin' else.
I "reckon" you would.
Woody?
- Woody!
- Uh-huh?
I知 happy.
I知 really happy that I know you.
Yeah.
Yeah, what?
Yeah... I知 married.
I got a wife and I got kids.
I guess I could have lied to you before,
but I can't lie to you
now you're startin' to care.
I was carin' too, Pauline.
Just... bein' around you...
knowin' you.
Most of this mail is favourable, Woody.
Yes, very favourable indeed.
I didn't have no idea
that many people was listenin'.
Well, apparently they are.
Woody, I知 gonna give you and Memphis
sue your own half-hour show, every night.
- How does that sound?
- Whoo-ee!
Now!
And, of course,
that means more money too.
Say, 35 a week?
No.
- However...
- however, what?
However, you now have
new sponsors, Woody.
They've insisted there be no controversial
material on their programme.
So just stick to the songs
that have been out and around for a while,
and everything'll be fine.
Does that mean I can't do
my own songs on the show?
Of course you can sing your own songs.
As long as it doesn't get anybody riled up.
That sure sounds ok with me, Mr. Locke.
Um...
sure.
Guess it sounds pretty ok to me too.
Fine. And we'll start on Monday, let's say?
Operator?
I壇 like to talk to Mary Guthrie
in pampas, Texas.
You'll have to get a hold of Mr. Jenkins,
and he'll go and get her.
It's just so good to hear your voice.
I知 gonna send you the money,
and you just come on out here.
And I値l find you a little house
we can live in.
Oh, sure, honey.
Just like you always talked about.
I love you.
Hey, Woody. Look at that.
- What is that?
- A field school.
- What do you think?
- Sure.
About music, the wonderful thing is
you don't have to know how to play.
To make music you just sing.
You just go ahead and sing
any song you wanna sing.
You can make up a song
and just sing it to yourself.
You can just go ahead
and sing it out screamin' loud.
You can sing about your troubles,
or you can sing about your happiness.
You can sing about your teacher,
or you can sing about the crop duster.
There's singin' in all of us.
You just gotta learn to let it come on out.
Well, you stick out your little hand
to every woman, kid and man
and you wave it up and down
and howdy-do
I feel glad when you feel good
you brighten up my neighbourhood
with a do-de-di-de-de-de
howdy-do, howdy-do
with a howdy, ho-di, howdy, howdy-do
he has every right to set down limits.
He's not gonna allow
preachin' on your show.
I suppose you're right.
But they got a Sunday mornin' gospel
hour every night, and he sure preaches.
That's what Locke痴 payin' him to do.
He's payin' you to entertain.
What would you do?
- I壇 do just like he said.
- You would?
Because that's how I make my livin'.
That's how I eat.
It don't have nothin' to do with comin' out
to the fields, doin' the benefits or nothin'.
You can separate it, just like that?
I can separate it, just like that.
Drop whatever you are doin'
stop your work and worry too
sit right down and take it easy
here comes Woody and Memphis Sue
you just drop a card or letter
we will sing a song for you
easy-goin' country people
plain old Woody and Memphis Sue
good evening to you all. Tonight Woody
and I have 30 minutes of your favourites.
We're gonna start off
with "Cimarron spoonin"'.
One, two...
I just decided to sing somethin' else.
Well, lots of folks back east they say
they're leaving town most every day
and they're tryin' to beat their dusty way
to the California line
well, across the desert sands they roll
tryin' to get out of that old dust bowl
and they think they're headin' for
a sugar bowl, but here is what they find
cos the police at port of entry say:
You're number 14,000 for today
and if you ain't got do re mi, boy
if you ain't got the do re mi
you better go back home
to beautiful Texas
Oklahoma, Georgia, Kansas,
Tennessee, South Dakota
California is the garden of Eden
a paradise to live in or to see
but, believe it or not,
you won't find it so hot
if you ain't got...
Locke talked to me, and he is ticked off.
I expected that.
Yeah, well, he said that from now on
you have to make a list each week of
all the songs you're plannin' on singin'.
He might as well fire me, then,
cos I ain't makin' no list.
Dammit, Woody,
don't mess up this job.
God knows what'll happen to you
if you get...
will you stop splashin'
when I知 tryin' to talk to you?
You stop it too! Now, dammit,
that ain't funny! Stop it!
- Ain't it somethin'?
- The whole city is somethin'.
- You've only seen a bit of it, Mary.
- You know what we ought to do?
Get a picnic together
and take the girls down to the beach.
That'd be sometime else
me and Mary ain't seen each other
for a few months. Understand?
Oh, yeah, right.
You need some help with those?
No, I can handle it ok.
- Thanks for the ride, Ozark.
- You bet.
Ok, honey, let me show you the inside.
Huh?
Come here, let me show you this.
- Oh!
- Electric.
A refrigerator!
- Let me show you the bedroom.
- I ain't finished lookin' at the kitchen.
Oh, my god.
Our own bedroom.
Oh!
Momma's pin.
Whoo-ee!
Oh, you!
It's so pretty, Woody. It's so perfect.
To celebrate, say "whoo-ee".
No! I don't want to.
- Go ahead and do it.
- No.
Go ahead. Or I値l tickle you.
Tickle you here.
All right. Whoo-ee.
Ain't you ticklish no more?
Really do it. Come on. Come on.
Ok!
Whoo-ee!
- Hey, we have wet shoes!
- Yeah!
- I think I sounded awful.
- You were great, Sue.
- I wasn't great.
- You were.
Mr. Guthrie, excuse me.
My name's baker. I知 an agent.
I know you're working without a contract.
If you would be willing to travel a bit,
I think I could double,
maybe triple, what you're earning.
- How would you do that?
- Better shows, for one thing.
I think that I could wangle you
a coast-to-coast broadcast.
I mean, I know a lot of important people
that I would like to talk to about you.
Well, I値l think it over.
Well, ok. I mean,
I don't wanna press you.
Why don't I come back when I致e got
something in the works for you?
Sure.
Mr. Guthrie, you're gonna be on your way
before you know it.
Hello, baker. Woody, just a minute,
please. I wanna talk to you.
Um...
I haven't seen any list yet.
- List?
- Yes.
The list of songs that
you're scheduled to do next week.
Oh, yeah. I ain't... wrote it yet.
Well, I need the list, Woody,
because the sponsors are insist...
what the hell is that?
It's an artichoke.
An artichoke?
What do you do with it?
You eat it.
Damnedest thing I ever seen.
Don't look too appetisin', do it?
- I gets paid to pick 'em, not to eat 'em.
- I guess you are.
Bet they don't pay you much for pickin'
them ugly old things either, do they?
- I don't get much.
- Do you ever think about all that stoopin'?
For just pennies?
You one of those union men? You one
of these fellas talkin' about a strike?
I talk about whatever it is that works.
I got no time to talk to you, mister!
We died 'neath your trees
and we died in your bushes
both sides of the river
we died just the same
is this the best way
we can grow big orchards?
Is this the best way
we can grow our good fruit?
To fall dry leaves
that rot on my topsoil
and to be called by no name
except deportees
goodbye, my Juan
goodbye, Rosalita
adios, mis amigos Jess y Maria
you won't have your names
when you ride the big airplane
all they will call you will be deportees
Oklahoma and Texas ain't nothin'
compared to California.
That don't seem right somehow,
it bein' so pretty out here.
No.
It ain't right.
It ain't right at all.
It does seem like it was easier to put up
with nature and dust storms an' all
than it is to put up with greed.
Yeah, I guess so.
Did you... did you ever make
that list for Mr. Locke?
No, I didn't. Not yet.
- Don't he want it right away?
- I suppose he does.
It just ain't that easy for me to do.
Make up a list!
No, I guess not.
I was cleanin' yesterday, Woody.
This old man - he must have been
70 years old - he didn't have no teeth,
and he wasn't wearin' no shoes.
He came to the door, beggin' for food.
I gave him some fried chicken.
His wrinkled...
wrinkled old face just lit right up.
Then I started in worryin' about us.
I got real worried, Woody, askin' myself:
"My god, are we gonna be like that
again two weeks from now?"
I can't help thinkin' about those bad times.
I don't want 'em to happen again.
Woody? It's me. Johnson.
Hey! It sure is!
What the hell happened to you?
Oh, we had some trouble out there.
Them owners, they sent their men
chargin' into a picket line we had set up.
And they're swingin' their clubs
in every direction just... they just got me.
- They did that to you?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
- There were some others, I知 afraid.
What about your family? They ok?
Yeah. Yeah, they're fine.
Fact is, I been learnin'
an awful lot from that baby of mine.
- You been learnin', have you?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I been learnin'.
When that baby wants somethin',
she's gonna cry
and carry on somethin' awful
till she gets what she's after.
Then I started thinkin' about
all those thousands of people,
workin' out there in the fields,
never gettin' nothin' they want.
Just givin' up, never sayin' nothin'.
I don't wind up like that, Woody.
I don't wanna end up just sittin' around.
So I made up my mind that I知 just gonna
speak out, just like that baby of mine.
I知 gonna let folks know what I want.
What's Liz think about all this?
She's plenty scared.
You know how women are.
She says she's proud of me.
I bet she is.
Yeah.
Anyway, Woody, what I come to tell you...
is keep up your music,
cos everybody's listenin'.
Well, Luther...
keep on doin' the work, huh?
Woody. I want the list,
and I want it right now.
That wasn't so...
just a minute, please.
That wasn't so painful, was it?
"Bury me beneath the willow",
"sweet pearl"...
"long green valley"? What is that?
That's not about the San Fernando valley,
or pickers, orchards or anything like that?
It's about a man that kills his sweetheart
cos she's sleepin' around.
- Oh, good.
- At least, he thinks she was.
Well, that's good.
Yeah, these are fine, Woody.
Fine. Thank you.
It's a mighty hard row
that these poor hands have hoed
my poor feet have travelled
a hot, dusty road
from out of the old dust bowl
and westward we rolled
and your deserts were hot
and your mountains were cold
green pastures of plenty
from high desert ground
from the grand coulee dam,
where the water runs down
this land I値l defend
with my life if need be
cos these pastures of plenty
must always
be free
look on them deserts
all around me
you and me
this land...
there's a better world a-comin'
tell you why
by and by
there's a better world a-comin'
can't you see? Can't you see?
There's a better world a-comin'
can't you see?
When we'll all be union
and we'll all be free
there's a better world a-comin'
can't you see?
I知 a union man in a union war
it's a union world I知 fightin' for
now, there's a better world a-comin'
tell you why, tell you why
there's a better world a-comin'
tell you why
through the marchin' and the battlin'
you can see the chains a-rattlin'
- what are you doin'?
- Get outta here.
I値l get out when I知 good and ready,
and I ain't ready yet.
Yes, you are!
Joe, hold him!
I just been on the bum
for the last few months.
Figure now I値l go to la and stay there.
Where are you from?
Shit, I think I was born in an orange grove
somewhere's. I don't know.
Do your folks know where you are?
Unless they counted heads,
they wouldn't even know I was missin'.
Daddy!
- Hey, Sue.
- Hi, dad.
Hey! Give me a kiss.
Daddy!
What you doin' here anyway?
And the boy scolded us,
and their mothers and fathers...
- we'll eat 'em for dinner.
- Sure.
Guess who's home!
Hi, honey.
- Where've you been?
- Oh, I just had to...
touch the people for a little bit, honey.
Well, darn it, Woody.
While you been out fightin' again,
you may have just lost that job.
Mr. Locke痴 been callin' every day,
and he's upset.
And that agent fella's been callin',
and he's mad.
- To hell with them.
- You can't say that. You can't say that!
Mr. Locke is paying you better than ever
before. You can't say to hell with all that.
That don't mean nothin'.
Well, if it don't, what does?
I know it ain't me and the kids.
You don't think nothin' about runnin' off
whenever you get the urge.
Oh, Mary... don't even talk like that.
Now, I truly care about you
and the kids. I truly care.
That sure ain't the way it seems.
You're spendin' your whole life
tryin' to fix the world.
- You don't do nothin' to help our family.
- Hell!
I brought you out here to California!
And then you left!
Hell, Mary, it's just that i... can't seem to...
just can't stand to sit still.
I always feel like I ought to be
somewhere's else. Anywhere's else!
Well, what about me?
What am I supposed to do?
Sit, and wait, while you are off
gallivantin' around the country?!
Am i?!
Am I supposed to just sit, and worry
if the kids are gonna have a daddy,
cos maybe you got your head bashed in?
Am i? Am i?!
Supposed to sit home and pray you ain't
wanderin' around, bleedin' to death?
You keep goin' like this and our family's
gonna be beggin' them growers for work.
- Dammit...
- we'll be beggin'!
- Stop your talkin'.
- It won't make anything better!
- I said, stop talkin'!
- I ain't through!
Just one more word, now,
just one more word...
are you sure you haven't got somethin'
else on your mind? You positive?!
Oh, now...
ah...
- Mary...
- no.
So help me, if anyone else had walked out
on me, they'd be out on the street.
I知 gonna give you one more chance.
Just one. But I want you to be responsible.
No, I won't take off my buckskin gloves
they're made of Spanish leather
I値l go my way
from day to day
and sing with the Gypsy Davy
and sing it with the Gypsy Davy
that song with the Gypsy Davy
and lovin'
that Gypsy Davy
I壇 like to dedicate this next song
to all you pickers out there,
with your hearts achin'
and bellies growlin'.
And I壇 like you to remember that
if you feel like singin' along with me,
and you don't know all the words,
just go ahead and make up
some of your own.
I知 sure you all got plenty to say
about the way things are.
You continually force me
to treat you like a child.
What do I say to get through to you?
You could tell me
you don't like my singin'.
That is not up to me, Woody.
There are sponsors.
- Now, if it were up to me...
- then you do like my singin'?
That isn't the point! I知 trying to tell you
something. There are sponsors.
They pay for the right to hear
what they wanna hear.
Maybe you like
some of my singin' but not all?
Woody, please! Just listen to me.
They feel that that kind of material...
I like my singin' too much
to take orders from some fat little squirt
doesn't even know his own mind!
Well, then there's not much
to discuss, is there?
You want the job,
or do you not want the job?
Do you think I can't replace you?
In ten minutes? In five?
I don't need this place.
I can sing on the street.
Well, get the hell outta my office!
I don't need you.
I can sing while I知 walkin'.
Woody!
- What the hell are you up to?
- I ain't in no mood for talkin'.
- You got your butt fired, didn't you?
- Damn right, I did.
- What did he tell you?
- Nothin'.
- He didn't say anything about baker?
- Who?
- That agent.
- Hell, no.
No, he wouldn't. You see, baker's
been callin' you about 20 times a day.
He is startin' to get things
rollin' for you, Woody.
Rollin' how? What do you mean?
He's got you all signed up
to do a spot for CBS, coast to coast!
- Coast to coast?
- That's right.
- Damn! Coast to coast.
- And that ain't all.
He's got an audition lined up,
some big hotel downtown.
A show like that could bring you in
another 100 a week.
Damn!
Shoot, Woody, you're gonna wind up
singin' to this whole damn country.
We got us some celebratin' to do.
Damn! Coast to coast?!
Whoo-hoo!
Come on, Woody.
Jesus!
Here comes Santa Claus!
Where is everybody?
Whoo-hoo! It's everybody's birthday!
And there ain't nobody gettin' any older!
Mary's gone.
She took the kids.
Gone back to pampa.
Oh, hell!
You don't think she left cos you got fired?
She left before that.
She always leaves the time on a note.
4:30.
4:30, yesterday afternoon.
Damn woman, anyhow.
Who the hell cares
what time you write a note?
Huh?
I知 in the mood for love
simply because you're near me
funny, but when you're near me
I知 in the mood for love
heaven was...
there's steady money here at the grove.
I知 gonna book you here for six weeks.
Then I知 gonna book you in every
top hotel and club in the country.
You gotta watch your step,
though, at CBS.
You gotta be careful
about the material you select.
Thank you. Thank you.
We already have a ballad singer.
- I think we should see him.
- Who? Guthrie?
I heard good reports about Guthrie.
Mr. Guthrie.
It's a mighty hard row
that these poor hands have hoed
my poor feet have travelled
a hot, dusty road
on the edge of your city
you'll see us there and then
I come with the dust
and I知 gone...
Mr. Guthrie. That's enough.
...with the wind
that's enough, Mr. Guthrie.
Thank you!
- You have a really nice quality
- he's wonderful.
- I told you I heard good reports.
- What kind of angle could we use?
Western?
What about
a simple hillbilly presentation?
Big overalls, maybe a straw hat.
Stick him in front of a haystack.
That might work. We could get
the Benton brothers to back him up.
I think so.
Let's use him as a lead into...
excuse me.
While you folks are talkin' to each other,
which way is the bathroom?
Oh. Out the door, turn right,
first door on the right.
Woody!
This is a big chance for you.
Can you afford to throw it away?
- Where are you goin'?!
- Out of this damn hotel.
I got no desire to sing to folks
that's drinkin' martinis
and stuffin' themselves full of lamb chops.
But the CBS broadcast?
You gonna throw that away too?
Standin' in a radio station, doin' what they
tell me to do, ain't my idea of havin' fun.
Woody, stop a minute and let's talk it out.
This is important.
It ain't nothin', Ozark.
I値l tell you what's important.
The worst thing that can happen
is to cut yourself loose from the folks.
Where the hell are you goin'?!
- Just tell me where you're goin'!
- Hell, I don't know.
Europe, New York, China...
New York.
- Maybe I値l come. When are you leavin'?
- Now!
Why do you have to go at everything
like you're killin' snakes with a hoe?
- And why New York?
- Why the hell not?
It's got people, don't it? It's got unions.
Besides, I can sing while I知 walkin' there.
This land is your land
this land is my land
- so long, Woody!
- From California to the New York island
from the Redwood forest
to the Gulf stream waters
I hate a song that
makes you think you're not any good.
I hate a song that makes you think
you're just born to lose. Bound to lose.
No good to nobody.
No good for nothin'.
Because you're either too old
or too young or too fat or too thin
or too ugly or too this or too that.
Songs that run you down
or songs that poke fun at you,
on account of your bad luck
or your hard travellin'.
I am out to fight those kind of songs
to my very last breath of air
and my last drop of blood.
I知 out to sing songs and to prove to you
that this is your world,
even if it's kicked you pretty hard
and knocked you down for a dozen loops.
No matter how hard it's run you down
or rolled over you,
no matter what colour,
what size you are, how you're built,
I am out to sing the songs
that'll make you take pride in yourself.
Nobody livin'
can ever stop me
as I go walkin'
down the freedom highway
nobody livin'
can make me turn back
this land was made for you and me
I roamed and rambled
and I followed my footsteps
to the sparkling sands
of her diamond deserts
and all around me
a voice was sounding:
This land was made for you and me
When the sun came shining
and I was strolling
and the wheat fields waving
and the dust clouds rolling
as the fog was lifting
a voice was chanting:
This land was made for you and me
nobody living can ever stop me
as I go walking
down the freedom highway
nobody living can make me turn back
this land was made for you and me
I致e sung this song
but I値l sing it again
all the people I致e met,
the places I致e been
some of the troubles
that bothered my mind
and a lot of good people
that I致e left behind
singin'so long,
it's been good to know you
so long, it's been good to know you
What a long time since I致e been home
and I gotta be driftin' along
Tom Joad got out of
that old McCallister pen
it was there that he got his parole
after four long years
on a man-killin' charge
Tom Joad came walkin' down the road
poor boy
tell me, what were their names?
Tell me, what were their names?
Did you have a friend
on the good Reuben James?
What were their names?
Tell me, what were their names?
Did you have a friend
on the good Reuben James?
I知 blowin' down this old dusty road
and I ain't gonna be treated this way
roll on, Columbia, roll on
your power is turnin'
our darkness to dawn
so roll on, Columbia, roll on
I been havin' some hard travellin'
I thought you knowed
way down the road
I been havin' some hard travellin',
hard ramblin', hard gamblin'
I been havin' some hard travellin', Lord
as I went walkin'
down the ribbon of highway
I saw above me that endless skyway
and all around me
a voice keeps sayin'
this land was made for you and me
as I went walkin'
I saw a sign there
and on the sign
it says "no trespassing"
but on the other side
it didn't say nothin'
that side was made for you and me
this land is your land
this land is my land
from California to the New York island
from the Redwood forest...
--== ripped from PAL DVD ==--