Here...
we are...
still...
alone.
It is all...
so slow...
so heavy...
so sad...
Soon...
I...
will be...
old...
and...
it will...
at last...
be over...
I came to say I'm leaving you
Your tears won't change my mind
You remember happy days gone by
Hello, Henri.
Don't say that.
You told me to clear out,
so I did.
I have Pimpernel with me.
We're driving to the mountains.
Don't say that.
Don't!
Hello, Henri.
It's Maité.
You told me to clear out,
so I did.
I took Pimpernel and the car.
We're going to the mountains.
One more thing:
I've got all your poems
and crappy paintings.
You know where
I'm going to dump them all?
In the water, Henri.
In the river.
Don't hang up.
Listen to this.
Look, Pimpernel!
All the lights went out.
What's the date?
May 24, 1983.
It's 10:20.
Thomas!
Hi.
Terrible heat.
I like it here.
The river, the highway...
Right.
She's a great girl.
Yes.
Of course,
you know how it happened.
You know the story.
She's deaf in one ear...
the left one.
She was sleeping
on her good ear.
I said to her, "You're a love."
Startled, she turned to me...
and asked me how I knew.
I played along...
That's how I found out.
I would have anyway.
Florence is a lousy liar.
She thought I'd said...
"You've got a lover."
I figured it out fast.
I was relieved that I knew him.
Even if he was my best
and only friend.
And now she's gone.
Shit, I never thought
it'd get to that.
It's not like me at all.
That's crazy.
Florence's favorite colors.
She took everything, the bitch.
Where are you going?
Out.
Why won't you talk to me?
Mireille...
Sorry, but I can't talk
about it here and now.
So go talk about it elsewhere.
I forgot my keys. Leave them
in the box if you go out.
I'm not going out.
You don't love me anymore.
What did you say?
You heard me, Bernard.
Yes.
But don't say that, Mireille.
Why do you say that?
I know it's not easy.
I'm indifferent to you, but
that's not indifferent to me.
I love loving you,
but my head's a mess.
It took us a while
to love each other equally.
I watched your love catch up
with mine. And when it did...
a tune started going round
in my head.
You know I love it when we kiss.
But then the tune went...
"What's she doing here?
Who's that monster?
"How dare she touch me
with her mouth?
"She must think I like it!
"Her breath stinks."
I know you smell good...
but I've convinced myself
that you stink.
When I look at you,
it's not your beauty I see...
but the space you take up:
standing, sitting, lying down.
As I watch you, the tune goes...
"I don't want
this girl anymore."
I don't want anyone else
to have you...
yet I don't want to be loved.
The few times we talk now,
I don't take you seriously.
I talk and listen,
but I'm watching you.
I see your shell and insult you
silently, to hurt myself.
Then I feel pity for you...
and myself.
So I hate us.
Lonelier together than apart,
who could ever love us?
We're gluey together.
I want it to be like before...
To stop all the spying...
to stop all the sabotage...
Bye, angel.
I won't be home late.
My name is Bouriana.
The problem with loners
is that they're never alone.
What'll it be?
A small lemonade.
No small drinks after 10 p.m.
How about a large?
Well?
A glass of milk.
Bouriana...Yes, I'll hold on.
Give me a beer.
How much?
That'll be seven francs.
I'm holding on.
Excuse me.
Can I buy you a coffee?
Thank you.
That's right. I'm Bouriana.
This gentleman's paying
for my coffee.
Bouriana.
"B" as in Bouriana...
"O" as in Ouriana,
"U" as in Uriana...
"R" as in Riana,
"l" as in lana...
"A" as in Ana, "N" as in Na...
and "A" as in Alfred.
Alfred Bouriana!
We're having a real heat wave...
Your emotional blackmail...
it's like making love
in the shit house...
You can't fool me!
It's too late for your love!
I won't fall for that!
1970-1976: High school.
F cheats on me. 3/26/83.
1st shoplifting: 1968.
1st lie to F: 3/13/81.
My bank.
Luxembourg Park - Readings:
1977-1979.
Born: Cochin Hospital - 1960.
1st night with F:
7, rue Pascal, 1/2/81.
Hospital - April '80 - Hernia.
1st kiss F - 12/22/80.
I meet F: 6/2/80.
1st murder attempt: 5/25/83.
The air is so still.
Let's put on a fresh shirt!
Now you're mad!
How can you want to make love...
when the world's such a mess?!
Are you blind?
You act so cute...
but you're just an animal!
You feed on rotten meat...
laced with tenderness.
You like it?
Not me.
Can't you smell it?
You must have a cold!
Or else you'd puke!
You ask me
what's come between us?
Life, that's what!
Isn't that enough for you?
I'm gonna hit!
Watch out! Here it comes!
You gotta hit! Hit!
I'm gonna hit!
I'm hitting!
You can't leave, Anna.
We live together.
One, two, three, and four.
Alex? It's your father.
Hi. How are you?
Fine.
What time is it?
6:39.
The telephone startled me...
It was a sort of déjà vu...
like a memory of the present...
That's why...l'm in a daze.
-Tomorrow, I'm...
-I know. That's why...
-Let's drop it.
-All right.
-You heard about Aunt V.?
-No.
She didn't die.
Why should she?
They're keeping her alive
on a drip-feeder.
A plumber's nightmare!
It's dreadful!
That's not new.
I'm counting on you.
If I get senile - Bang!
Who wants to be
a bedridden vegetable?!
Remember our contract:
You put a bullet in my brain!
Promise!
I'm not kidding, Alex!
Swear it!
I already did.
Unless I die first, of course.
Cut that out, you asshole! Shit!
Bernard dear...
I'm giving a party
at my place Friday...
to celebrate the tenth
anniversary of Stan's death.
Bring Mireille with you.
Faster!
Your turn now.
Your turn.
Play with me a little.
Then we'll turn over and begin.
Then what?
What is it?
I'm lost.
Wasn't it good?
Not really. Something's wrong...
What?
I don't know.
What's wrong?
I don't like it so wet.
You salivate too much.
I feel like...
You're like Alex. You like it
dry so it almost hurts.
It doesn't hurt.
I prefer touching
when it's not so wet.
It's nicer with saliva.
For you.
Don't disappoint me yet...
So soon...
I thought you liked it that way.
But I was wrong.
Tell me when you don't like what
I do so I don't waste my time.
What don't I like?
When I take you in my mouth
and salivate.
I meant when I do it to you.
But I like it when it's wet.
I assumed you'd like
what I like. I was wrong.
No...
Like putting a finger in...
I didn't like that
with Alex at first...
Now I do. But you clench up
before I can get it in.
So we get nowhere.
You know why.
I know. You only let me put
my finger in when I suck you.
But I come too fast that way.
Then you complain.
No. When I want
to give you pleasure...
I don't mind that.
So you say.
I love to hear you moan...
even softly.
And if you weren't so passive...
like Alex...
I'd do it more often.
Be right back.
Cheater!
Me, I'm a sneaky opportunist,
the child of sacrifices...
Me and my shitty asshole, my
blisters, my insatiable shoes...
They judge us by our shoes.
His feet were often sore...
he'd put ice cubes in his shoes.
I tried it once.
It helped at first,
but then it hurt even more.
My feet were growing...
So was my soul...I was becoming
sublime in every way!
I'm Bernard's friend.
He just left.
The poor boy had a stomachache.
Mireille is still here. Come in.
You know Mireille,
his girlfriend?
Do you work nights
at the post office with Bernard?
No. I'm an...oceanographer.
We've got some very special
people here tonight.
That little boy...
has the highest IQ for his age
in all of Europe.
That little man there
is the human time-signal.
It's his voice you hear
when you dial 463.84.00.
But it's been downhill
for him ever since.
That's Henri Bestouches,
artist and poet.
He's very ill. He has a bullet
lodged in his brain.
There's Mireille over there
with Elizabeth.
The lady in the white sweater,
Josette Lemercier...
was Miss Universe
in the late '50s.
The handsome guy
near the window...
is Jerry Bridgeman.
A U.S. astronaut
who walked on the moon.
Who are you?
I'll be off, Alex.
First came words.
No, emotions...
Sorry. I don't understand.
He says,
"Young people are too silent."
"You've forgotten how to talk."
"Maybe you think
people aren't worth talking to."
That's not it.
"You're wrong.
Maybe you're afraid."
He wants to know
if you like movies.
"I was a grip when movies
were as silent as I am."
"I pushed the first dollies."
"I remember that matinee idol,
Jonas."
"He made the whole crew laugh.
"Whenever they shot
a love scene...
"the director
told the actors..."
"to say tender words
to each other before kissing.
"Anything, so one could see
their lips moving.
"So in the middle
of a love scene, Jonas...
"would make daring comments
on his partner's breasts...
"or proposition her
during a take."
"Jonas,
who was a gentle person...
"and shy with women
in real life...
"became a lion
in front of the camera."
He says...
"When the films were shown..."
"during the love scenes...
"one or two people
in the theater would laugh.
"They were deaf people...
"who could lip-read
Jonas' obscenities.
"Silent films were better
because...because..."
Slow down, Sylvain.
Excuse me.
Miss, I watched you all night.
I composed this for you.
I'll play it for you.
We're too old to change
our habits.
Shit!
They say that broken glass...
We should pick it up.
What did he say?
He said, "C'est la vie."
That's what life's about.
I was nine when you walked
your first steps.
For years,
I lived only for outer space.
But don't you think
it's hopelessly screwed up now?
How old are you, Jenny?
18. And you?
I turned 53...recently.
I'll be 28 on August 22nd.
You know what distresses me?
That I've accomplished
so little in my life.
It's my 37th birthday today.
37 goddamn years!
Makes you stop and think.
When Mozart was my age,
he had been dead for two years!
How depressing!
But there's a way out:
blowing my brains out!
-May I make a call?
-Come with me.
Axel.
Thomas? It's me.
Recovered from your swim?
Is that Florence I hear?
There's a letter for both of you
under the door.
The records in the bag
are for Florence.
That's all. Ciao.
Good night, Nicolas.
Good night, Pimpernel.
You know our names, Mr. Bear?
Of course.
Will you come play
with us tomorrow, Mr. Bear?
Only if you go to bed right now!
Good night,
Nicolas and Pimpernel.
Good night
to all our little friends.
Time for beddy-bye.
Kiss your parents good night...
and we'll be back
tomorrow night.
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
You're just like Bernard
at a party:
always in the kitchen, alone.
I'll get you a glass.
All the glasses
are in the living room.
This cup is all that's left.
My private cup.
I'm the only one
who's ever drunk from it.
Even my brother Stan
would never have used it.
He bought it for me in ltaly.
Stan traveled everywhere.
Whenever we were apart,
even as children...
we would meet through
telepathy at night.
At exactly 10 p.m...
I'd think very hard of Stan...
and he'd think very hard of me.
Three years ago, I forgot
my telepathic date with him.
He was in Germany,
on a business trip.
I never saw him again.
He died on a German freeway...
In his car...
Totally dead!
Be very careful with my cup...
Alexander.
Mireille?
Your hair...
Next time you do something
like that...
please don't do it in my home.
You did it behind
Bernard's back.
He'll be furious.
Bernard won't mind,
I assure you.
Don't worry.
You, too!
Isn't it nice
to drink through the chink?
I'm going to wind up a loser.
Yet I stood a chance.
I wanted to be someone
outstanding:
flyer, traveler, musician...
Can't I be reborn?
I'm going to wind up a loser.
Yet I stood a chance.
I wanted to be
someone outstanding:
flyer, traveler, musician...
Can't I be reborn?
It's our first meeting.
Only first times matter to me.
Then you won't last long.
If I had a kid,
I'd ignore him once he talked.
For years,
I longed to make love.
Then I actually did it.
I mean...
No, it's the opposite.
I never tried to fulfill my best
dreams. Only to re-dream them.
Want some tea?
Sure.
There's only one cup.
The label's been cut off.
It could be anything.
I saw you in the bathroom
earlier.
Quite a scene.
So you're the spy.
I've tried it more often
since I came to Paris.
Haven't you ever?
I'm too happy for that.
Too happy?
Yes. I mean, too scared.
Where are you from?
Blois. In the Loire Valley.
I came here a year ago to live
with my friend, a Parisian.
I wanted to act in commercials,
but I got nowhere.
I almost got hired
by a chocolate firm...
but then they saw my tooth...
Next, it was a cosmetics firm...
but with my wrinkles...
What wrinkles?
On my forehead.
I see.
Five of them.
I've had them since childhood.
I make films.
Films or video?
For now,
what I do is dream up titles...
for the films I plan to make.
If I were you...
I have to go into the army
tomorrow.
If I were you, I wouldn't go!
Right. Why go,
when we're already veterans?
It's menopause time.
And I'm in a rush.
Yet I'm all for conquerors.
I had a great line worked out
for the army psychiatrists.
I told them
I was unfit for service...
because I couldn't sleep
in a room with other guys.
It didn't work.
They said the army wasn't for
sleeping. So I'm off tomorrow.
Do you fall...
Do you fall in love often?
Yes, easily.
I thought so.
But a real lover sticks around.
I feel closer
to people once I've left.
Love is as old as the hills...
Lovers are worn out.
Desire isn't easy to come by...
and it doesn't come cheap
nowadays.
There's plenty of passion,
but it gets wasted on details.
And it doesn't travel.
Me, neither.
Mireille...
I'm going now.
OK.
Who are you in love with
these days?
I'm on to a new heartbreak.
I don't want to lose it.
My heart's proud of its pain.
Her name is Florence.
I met her two years ago, but I
toyed with her before that.
Now she's left me
for my best friend, Thomas.
Same old story.
I've never cheated on anyone.
Never got the chance.
She's gone.
She left me a note
in our toothglass:
"I'm leaving to forget you."
In her deadly prose.
We lived in my room.
We slept in my single bed.
And lived on her unemployment.
Yet she still loved me
on Sunday...
Even Monday...and Tuesday...
She told me all about her youth.
She had lots of love affairs.
One when she was very young
with a boy who died.
His death nearly destroyed her.
I never got along with her...
Last summer,
we were on an Aeolian island.
I gave her my first slap.
I could've held back,
but I decided not to.
I don't try to change.
She didn't get it...
that I kept tabs on my
cowardice, on my weaknesses.
I like to spy on myself
as if I were a foreigner...
a foreign body,
as scientists say.
If I changed,
I'd distort the experiment.
I can see the kind of movies
you'll make.
It's easy to get self-obsessed
when you're alone.
I've got lots of projects,
enough for two lives.
I like to view my life
as a biography.
Born in Paris 1960. Died
in Paris 2040. I won't leave.
Last week I had a dream.
In my dream, I was asleep,
then I was awake...
and found a book between
the sheet and the blanket...
a book I'd never seen before.
I leafed through it.
It was my autobiography.
But it was unfinished.
I'd died while writing it.
-Want some?
-I don't drink.
Florence was madly
in love with me.
More than I with her.
So now she's down, and I'm out!
When she left three days ago,
we had a...
She took all her things.
She wanted to take the letters
I wrote her.
I said they were mine.
I wrote them. They're mine.
In the end, I gave in.
She doesn't know
I've Xeroxed them.
This scarf
is all I have left of her.
But...it's her all over.
You really think so, Mireille?
You know my name?
In the army, they should
assign you to espionage.
-Want one?
-I don't smoke.
I'm going out for a walk.
I'll come with you.
I like walking alone.
So do I.
Then we can go together.
In fact, I don't go out much.
I'm scared of getting
pushed under the subway...
or being blown up
or finding out I've got cancer.
At 15, I wasn't scared.
Now I'm old enough
to be tortured in a war.
I had a nightmare.
Midnight?
Know this one?
"Here's how many nights
and a day
"Here's how long
you've been away
"It was to be
our last time apart
"The last strain
on my shipwrecked heart
"You said you'd be back
in spring
"A time for sweetness
and whispering
"You said we'd meet
in a budding grove
"And through Paris streets
we'd rove"
"I love you and love you still,
I love you alone and always will
"But if you choose
to go your way
"I'll remember our love
as a happy day
"I'll hit the road,
a smile on my face
"I'll go bask in the sun
some other place
"Sorrows won't make me
give up my life
"I'm not as patient
as a sailor's wife"
He got home very late.
I was asleep.
For a long time,
he sat on the bed, in the dark.
The sound of the key
had woken me...
but I pretended to be asleep.
I felt his eyes on me.
It was a drag.
It wasn't the first time.
Then...
he got into bed...
and made love to me trying to be
gentle so as not to wake me.
He likes to do it that way.
Sometimes he says to me...
"Let go. Play dead."
When I met him...
at first, right after
my father's death...
he felt at ease with me.
Now he criticizes me for things.
Things I don't understand.
For him, it all matters:
my past, my future,
my present, and my death...
I often wonder what my father
would've thought of him...
and of me today.
I am...l'm what I am.
It's very late.
It's today I'm leaving.
Everyone's going.
We're the last.
I'm leaving.
It's like a dream for me,
being with you.
Like an unusually deep dream.
Only deep sleep
makes you dream like that.
Sitting beside you this way...
is like eternity.
The moment I saw you...
I knew I was destined
to love you.
I'll say it once and for all:
I love you, Mireille,
more than anything.
We must fall in love!
Unaware of it, wordlessly...
It's too late!
Pretend you didn't hear that...
Time to shut up. I will.
After 20 years of battling,
silence.
To think that your body
will age...
Shriveled breasts
and more wrinkles, Mireille...
On your belly, under your ass.
It's all my fault...
You see, Mireille, love...
Iove without regrets...
Iove without
nasty afterthoughts...
Say come, I'll come,
say smile, I'll smile...
We'll sleep together
for as long as you want...
I want to work with you,
form an unbeatable team...
Whatever our signs,
Libra or Leo, I'll sign up!
Maybe Florence, seeing
our strength, will join us...
You and Florence and me...
I'll be the go-between lover...
It should be so moving.
Back and forth I go!
Alone, you couldn't jolt me out
of my shell...
Together,
we'll change our habits...
We'll leave Paris,
maybe even France.
And out of love for me, Alex...
you'll stop
destroying yourself...
You'll respect the warmth
of your blood...
your serene presence...
your clear perception,
your gentle feelings...
Under your impulse,
our melancholy will fade away.
If I could only escape
monologues, Mireille.
Mental diarrhea!
Not set my sufferings to music!
Not bury my lover with words!
But if I shut up,
she'll kill herself!
Kisses won't seal our lips...
Help me take wing, Mireille...
I weigh a ton!
Don't look, I'm a truck!
I'll never live again,
Mireille. Never!
Sorry, I'm going to the can.
Hold it, young man.
You can't relieve yourself
until we're moving.
Taken!
Got any change?
I'll have one last game.
It's not two francs.
It's three.
The cost of living goes up.
Life doesn't.
Try again, Earthling!
How about this for an answer!
I've had it, never again!
They'll never screw me again!
It's over.
He's not even tired.
But he's going home
to his mistress.
He played badly.
He lost everything.
But he'll play tomorrow.
He's going to sleep
in her bed...in her arms.
Good night.
Try again...
Earthling!
Mireille...
It's Alex, I missed my train.
Can I speak to Mireille?
I'm not here, Bernard.
I'm not here at all.
Mireille, it's Alex.
Alex, help me...
to get out of this...
Bernard!
Bernard...
I turn my back to you.