Boys Before Flowers
Enjoy:)
Episode 24
Something happened to you, didn't it?
You weren't asleep?
Don't even think about lying to me.
What could happen?
I...
I'm going to live here with you,
Dad and Kang San.
What?
Why?
And what about Young Master Jun Pyo,
school and everything?
I already told you.
There's nothing between Jun Pyo and me.
Also...
Mom, after everything, you still think
that there's any future left?
You...
So in this small room, selling fish,
crabs and webfoot octopus,
smelling like fish,
that's how you want to live?
You want to live like that?
And what's wrong with that?
We're ruined.
We're finished.
Now, with what hope can we live on?
Mom...
Oh, that's enough!
Yi Jung sunbae.
Still no news about Jan Di?
No. I really don't what to think.
She turned off her phone and only
said that she was going somewhere.
Whether it was east or west,
she wouldn't even say.
She's probably fine.
It's Geum Jan Di, after all.
It seems like you know my
friend better than I.
I told you, I know a little bit about women.
How is Jun Pyo sunbae doing?
He's a mess, what else.
Ga Eul.
Now, shouldn't we have a talk about us?
Ga Eul, I...
I'll go first.
You don't need to feel
any obligation towards me.
I know everything... how you feel.
That's why as of now,
I'm not going to seek you out.
Ga Eul.
My teacher...
No.
Eun Jae said that she did everything
she wanted to do so she had
no regrets or lingering feelings.
Thank you.
For giving me the opportunity to do my best.
When I hear from Jan Di,
I'll let you know immediately.
Well, then...
What would be good?
Ahjussi, our Jun Pyo...
If he continues like this,
he really might break down.
I'm so afraid.
Miss, you too can't be like this.
That's not it.
This time, I really don't
have a good feeling.
Miss.
Dad...
Dad!
How could you do something like that?
Can't you see that even without you causing
a fuss, things are difficult enough as is?
Mom...
No, I'm beginning to hate calling you "Mom".
How...
How could someone...
do something as extreme as that?!
Exactly what are you talking about?
How could you tell me that
the father I love was dead?!
You...
How did I find out?
At this moment,
that's what you're curious about?
I'm asking you.
Leaving Dad buried like that,
did you intend to deceive me forever?!
Why did you do it? Why?!
Your father would have wanted it as well.
Wh-what did you say?
I planned to take responsibility
for everything.
But then, your father suddenly collapsed.
Into a condition no different
than the living dead.
The lineage of the great Shinhwa Group
ending in such manner.
I couldn't let that happen.
My pride wouldn't allow it.
Your pride?
You're saying that telling us
that the father we love died,
telling the whole world,
and also deceiving your children.
That absurd situation was
all because of your pride?!
It was for your father.
What are you talking about?
Jun Pyo.
I will carefully explain everything.
I...
I asked you what you were talking about!
What does Dad's son have
to do when Dad's not around?
I have to protect my sister,
Mom and Shinhwa Group.
Gu Jun Pyo!
As one man to another, can you promise?
Yes, Sir!
For the sake of this group, which
you might toss away in an instant,
your father did his best until the very end.
Are you thinking of throwing him away too?
I'm sorry, Young Master.
I'm truly sorry.
This time, I realized it.
That you and I are from
two very different worlds.
No matter how much you fight it,
you're Shinhwa Group's Gu Jun Pyo.
There's not a moment
that I ever forgot that.
I am at the fish market.
Everyone, look over here. Right now,
it is overflowing with fresh seafood.
"Spring News:
Crowded early morning fish market"
Oh, it's a webfoot octopus,
a webfoot octopus! Wow!
These days, webfoot octopuses
must be the best.
No! It's so good that if two
people eat it together,
one wouldn't notice if the other died!
I'll give it you for cheap. Buy some!
Everyone, you heard, right?
For tonight's dinner, how about cooking
some webfoot octopus soup as a Spring dish?
Reporting from Isangsaewodo,
I'm Cho Bo Ram reporter.
Mister! Mister!
I'm going to see Dad.
You're gonna come with me, right?
I'm not going.
Jun Pyo!
Jun Pyo.
Come and talk with your mom.
"Mom"?
Was there even one moment when
you were like a real mother?
You should now stop the mother act
because such charity doesn't suit you...
President Kang.
I'm not interested.
What?
If you're going, then go by yourself.
Gu Jun Pyo.
Jun Pyo, are you serious?
Don't be like that and just go.
I said that I wasn't interested!
Let me ask you one more time.
Are you serious?
If you want to see her so badly, then leave.
I'm heading out first.
Come or not; do what you want.
Weren't times like these when
you needed Geum Jan Di more?
And after I bring her back,
what am I supposed to do?
Now, I can't promise her anything.
That I'll always make her laugh,
"I'll make you happy so believe only in me."
My confidence to say such
things has disappeared.
Jun Pyo.
Being the child of that kind of person.
Being a member of that kind of family.
If even I hate it this much,
then how do you think she'll feel?
During that time, given what she went
through, she probably detested it.
It's Geum Jan Di so it could be different.
That's even more reason why I can't.
Because it's the woman I love.
That's why I can't even more now.
It would've been nice if we
could've sold the rest of it.
Mom, I'm hungry!
Oh, Kang San, sorry, sorry!
I'll prepare dinner at once.
Let's go.
Wh... what's the matter with everyone?
"What's the matter?"
But that's what we want to ask you!
Even if you look down on us because
we're simple country people,
you should be discrete about it.
How could you try to con us?
Con?
You said that you're Shinhwa Group's
future daughter-in-law?
My daughter says that Shinhwa
Group has a different fiancée!
Look at this!
This young lady is the daughter of a wealthy
family even bigger than Shinhwa Group!
Those two getting married
was even on the news!
But that's already an old matter.
Eh? Then what? Are you really Shinhwa
Group's future daughter-in-law or what?!
That's not it.
Oh, whatever! Hurry up and immediately
pay back the money you borrowed!
Eh? Pay it back immediately?
That's right! Who knows if tonight,
you'll flee in the middle of the night?
Think about how you sat there and
ate the food that you got from us.
How is that any different from conning us?
Even if it's only the interest,
hurry and pay up!
Wait, how can you suddenly...
No, pay up now!
Hurry and pay up, huh?
I will give it to you.
Su... Sunbae!
That Yo...Young Mast...
That money... For now, I will repay it.
He's handsome.
And tall...
He must be the son of a rich family.
Oh, what should we do?
See! See!
So she was telling the truth about
having a chaebol* for a future son-in-law.
*Son of a wealthy family.
So he's the young master of Shinhwa Group?
Just look at his face!
He just radiates refinement...
Oh my, it's the first time I saw such
a handsome young master!
Must be nice.
I'm not dying by myself.
I'm not going to die by myself.
How did you know that I was here?
I heard it.
The emergency bell.
I couldn't sleep at night because
I was scared I wouldn't hear it.
How could you do it?
How can someone be like this?
Sunbae, I've received too much from you.
You've done more for me.
Does it seem like I'd be fine without you?
Are you fine without me?
A world without you is so hard,
I resent myself for breathing.
What should I do? Even now,
I live each day broken by your single word.
If being like this is wrong,
tell me. You and me.
How's your grandfather?
Like before, going to work at the clinic.
Perhaps, he'll keep going
until he collapses again?
That's like your grandfather.
Grandfather gave this to me.
He said that my grandmother
gave it to my mother.
Sunbae.
I don't know when it started either.
But... now, I can't live without you.
I can't accept this.
Jan Di.
I thought that I could forget him.
I thought that I'd forgotten him.
And yet...
This is the only thing I can't throw away.
It won't let go.
I can't sever my connection to Gu Jun Pyo.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Sunbae.
It's OK.
Jan Di...
I don't think that I can let go of her.
Instead of me who only makes
things difficult for her,
I even once thought that it'd
be better to send her to you.
No, that's not it.
If I had to give up Jan Di to another guy...
I hated to even imagine
it but if I had to do that,
then that other guy
absolutely has to be you.
Ji Hoo, it couldn't be anyone else but you.
That's what I thought.
I'm not dying by myself.
I have to see the end of Shinhwa Group!
I won't be the only one who's ruined.
No!
Jun Pyo!
Jun Pyo.
Hey, Gu Jun Pyo.
Quickly, wake up.
Gu Jun Pyo!
He had it coming.
You reap what you sow.
It's not your fault.
Hey, Gu Jun Pyo!
Wake up!
Hello?
My friend is dying.
I said that my friend is dying!
Jun Pyo.
Jun Pyo!
Wake up.
Hey!
Wake up!
This is breaking news.
Tonight around 8pm, in a local coastal town,
the successor to Shinhwa Group,
Managing Director Gu Jun Pyo,
was a victim of an assault.
This news comes as a shock.
Caught at the scene, the defendant Kim
was a representative of a company
that was bought out by Shinhwa Group.
It was revealed that
he did it for revenge.
Now are you satisfied?
Is this what you wanted?
Miss, please calm down.
You said that in the end,
it was all for Jun Pyo's sake.
You always said that it was because
of the Shinhwa Group assets
that were to be handed down to Jun Pyo.
So look.
Look at what's happened to your son,
your overwhelmingly happy son
if we go by your words.
Mom...
Do you have any idea what
your son likes to eat,
what he likes or what he wanted to do?
They say that the surgery went well.
It appears that he's
past the critical stage.
That's a relief.
Then, we should go.
What did you say?
There is an urgent meeting in Hong Kong.
Was Dad not enough?
Answer me.
Which is more important to you,
Shinhwa Group or Jun Pyo?
Just once, tell me!
Madam President.
Jun Pyo...
really likes egg rollups and ramen.
He especially likes to eat the fish
sticks from street vendors.
In one sitting, he probably
would eat about 20 of them.
He also likes to pack a lunchbox
and go on a picnic.
Using the telescope that
his parents bought him,
he likes to look at the stars.
Don't worry.
Gu Jun Pyo
He'll get better.
Jun Pyo.
- Jun Pyo.
- Are you okay?
Jun Pyo, it's your sister.
Jun Pyo.
Jun Pyo was moved to a room.
You should go.
If he knows you're by his side,
he'll wake up sooner.
Stop here for a second.
Do you have any idea...
What your son...
Likes to eat?
What he likes or...
what he wanted to do?
Jun Pyo...
really likes egg rollups and ramen.
He especially likes to eat the fish
sticks from street vendors.
In one sitting, he probably
would eat about 20 of them.
Let's go.
I don't know when it started either.
But...
Now, I can't live without you.
Jun Pyo!
I told you before.
It can't be anyone but you.
Grandpa.
Ji Hoo.
Yes, yes.
Tell me.
Setting Shinhwa and me
being a plutocrat aside,
have you ever considered me as just one man?
No.
No matter how much you try,
you're still Shinhwa Group's Gu Jun Pyo.
I have never forgotten that
for not even a single second.
Gu Jun Pyo.
Can you hear me?
I lied to you again.
To me, you're...
Always just Gu Jun Pyo.
You're the dummy Gu Jun Pyo who
likes the ugly, poor, nameless Jan Di.
So wake up.
Wake up.
Wake up, Gu Jun Pyo. Wake up.
Oh!
Honey!
Is everything okay?
You're healthy right?
We... We moved back to our house.
This is all because of you.
Because you suffered a lot on the boat.
Yeah!
The building owner felt bad about last time,
so we're renting it out for a cheaper price.
Dad! When I become a pro-gamer,
you won't have to ride a boat.
So come back soon! Soon! Soon!
Dad! Dad! Dad!
Don't worry about us and be safe!
Yes, Honey.
Come back soon!
Sunbae.
Jun Pyo woke up.
Jan Di, welcome.
You look so normal for just waking up.
That's the miracle of human recovery.
Yo my bro. Welcome back.
Thanks.
For what?
For living.
Did you think the almighty Gu Jun Pyo
would live* an unnatural death?
*He said 'Bi MONG Hoing Sa',
which should be 'Bi MYUNG Hoing Sa')
You really are Gu Jun Pyo.
He said it 'Bi MONG Hoing Sa'.
Jan Di, why are you just standing there?
Come here.
You worried a lot right?
All the test results came out fine.
That's great, Gu Jun Pyo.
But who's this rustic girl?
Jun Pyo, don't you know Geum Jan Di?
Stop playing around.
Geum Jan Di? What's that?
Gu Jun Pyo...
Jun Pyo...
Do you remember everyone else?
Are you kidding?
Tell me my name.
So Yi Jung.
Then me? Do you remember me?
Are you crazy? You're Song Woo Bin.
But...
You don't know who Geum Jan Di is?
Am I supposed to?
Is she your girl, Ji Hoo?
It's selective memory loss.
For this particular patient,
It's Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder due to
the accident which was almost like a terror.
But how come he can't remember
just one person?
It's perhaps because the memories
of that person were too painful
or too important that the strain
made him forget those memories.
Then, when do you think they'll come back?
I'm not sure.
Usually it takes about six months,
but sometimes there are cases
when they never come back.
Hi, Gu Jun Pyo.
The weather's really nice, right?
Do you want to go take a walk?
You.
Who do you think you are
to come barging into my room?
Are you interested in me?
Don't you think you're being
ridiculous as Ji Hoo's girl?
Hey!
I'm not anyone's girl!
If I have to say it,
more than being Ji Hoo's girl...
I'm your...
Get out.
Are you deaf?
I said get out. I hate girls like you.
Gu Jun Pyo.
Can you leave? I'm going to sleep.
Why aren't you coming out?
Come out!
I said to come out!
Hey!
Unni, here.
So don't cry anymore. Okay?
The vending machines here
have to be hit to do their job.
Thanks.
It sounds like you been
in the hospital for a long time.
- What's your name?
- Yumi. I'm Jang Yumi.
I'm a junior at Korea Arts School.
I'm Geum Jan Di.
A senior at Shinhwa High.
You go to Shinhwa High?
I'm so jealous.
Anyways, who did you come to see?
A friend.
I see.
I broke my leg while skiing so I'm a long
stay guest here for the whole vacation.
Do you want to sit here?
Be careful.
Yumi, your personality seems really bright.
It's just because.
In the hospital,
everyone gets very depressed and annoyed,
And I hate that.
What can you to do
for that type of people?
For people who've been in the
hospital and have gotten really annoyed.
You just have to act naturally.
Naturally?
Hey, are you okay?
Oppa, it looks like you're
not fully healed yet.
If you just walk around like that,
it's dangerous.
Oppa?
Do you want ride a wheelchair?
Don't worry about it.
Then do you want my crutches?
Oppa, do you know how to use crutches?
Hey peanut,
don't pretend like you know me and get away.
Your personality's nasty huh?
I'm not a peanut but Yumi. Jang Yumi.
What?
You're the one in the VIP room, right?
I don't know what kind of great person
you are, but all patients are the same!
No wait.
In this hospital, I'm your senior!
If you don't want to break your other leg,
here lean on me.
No. No, Yumi.
Since your leg is not healed yet,
here, lean on me.
You... didn't leave yet?
Unni, I'll see you later!
So we should do something
to give him some shock.
Or how about reenacting something
to trigger his memory back?
Like?
What events with big impact,
relating to Geum Jan Di, are there?
Gu Jun Pyo.
What's with her now?
What are you doing?
When you get your memory back, call me.
What?
What kind of crazy girl is this?
What kind of girl are you?
Jun Pyo, did you remember anything?
Remember what?
How I am so unlucky,
that a trash girl is teasing me.
Was the memory too old?
No... I think it was too weak.
We should try something harder next time.
Harder?
I told you this is the
last time I'm going to let it go.
Hey.
Who are you to keep playing jokes on me?
I'm not going to hold back
any longer even if you are Ji Hoo's girl.
Gu Jun Pyo.
I told you I wasn't going to let it slide!
I told you!
Hey Yoon Ji Hoo.
Make sure this girl never
crosses my sight again!
Understand?!
Don't worry about it.
You're not a person who's easily forgotten.
He could've been having such a
hard time that he wanted to forget me.
Even if he did,
if it was a connection to be forgotten,
do you think you would
feel more comfortable?
That makes no sense!
Where in the world is there a person
that gets special crutches?
I'm being serious.
Do you think the almighty Gu Jun
Pyo would use any kind of crutches?
Here, hold it once.
You're serious! Why is this so light!
It doesn't feel like I'm holding it.
It's called titanium.
This is so funny, Oppa.
Jun Pyo.
Ji Hoo. You were here?
Oh, it's Jan Di unni!
Hey!
Unni, did you see Jun Pyo's crutches?
He says it's titanium.
Isn't it funny?
It's not like he's Iron Man or anything.
Wow. Your boyfriend's really handsome.
Hello, my name's Jang Yumi.
It's nice to meet you.
It's cold, let's go in.
Who is it?
Late night delivery.
It'll be really nice to look
at the stars through a telescope.
Do you like stars?
Stars?
The star that shines the
brightest on a winter night.
I guess I can say it's a
star like the almighty Gu Jun Pyo.
What?
Then I'll be that one.
Oppa, what's wrong? Does something hurt?
I feel like I forgot something important...
but I can't remember.
I feel like my chest is going to explode.
Don't try so hard.
If it's important, you'll remember.
If you can't remember,
then it probably wasn't important.
It's not good for your body
either if you stress out about it.
Yo, What's up?
How are you feeling?
Hello!
We're seeing you a lot more.
We're HC.
HC?
Hospital Couple.
All the patients and the nurses
in the hospital said that we were.
What do you think?
Do we look good together?
Jun Pyo, do you still not
remember everything?
What am I supposed to remember?
Geum Jan Di.
Do you not remember?
You keep saying something about Jan Di.
Why do I have to remember your girlfriend?
Just forget all that...
And of all girls, where did you
find such a forceful girl like her?
Does she think she's a
gangster or something?
Make sure she doesn't
come into my room ever again.
Gu Jun Pyo!
Just stop.
What's wrong with him?
Sunbae.
I'll get some tea.
I'm sorry.
What are you sorry about?
I should the one that's sorry.
I got angry without thinking.
I didn't stop you because
Jun Pyo would had gotten hurt.
I thought that you would had
been more hurt if you had hit him.
So I stopped you.
How long did you wait outside.
Why is your hand so cold?
Give me.
The thing that's cold right
now is your heart.
You don't have to act so
strong in front of me.
It's not acting strong.
But because you are here...
Because you are here for me,
I am can become strong.
I'll go get the tea.
Abracadabra~
Gu Jun Pyo will remember Geum Jan Di.
I remember now.
The person I forgot is you.
It's all over now.
I'm not going to allow this
ridiculous situation break you two up.
That girl's expression
won't disappear from my head.
In the end...
Geum Jan Di and Gu Jun Pyo
was only... was only just this.
Today, we have something to tell everyone
here, which is why we arranged this party.
Gu Jun Pyo, Jang Yumi...
We will be studying abroad together
in America starting next month.