♫ It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
Charge!
Stop right there!
Attack!
Opening Track: "Beautiful Day" by Mister Mouth
♫ It's a rainy day when I got out, but I left my umbrella at home. ♫
♫ I forgot to recharge my phone and didn't bring enough money to fill up the gas tank. ♫
♫ You don't need too much luck. You don't need to take everything you want. ♫
♫ Life is actually very long. ♫
♫ One beautiful thing is more than enough. ♫
♫ Maybe it won't end. ♫
♫ Tragedy might repeat itself. ♫
♫ It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
♫ Beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
♫ Maybe in a place not too far away, ♫
♫ I’ll leave behind my footprints ♫
♫ It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
♫ Beautiful, oh, it’s beautiful. ♫
Breathe in!
I Am Sorry, I Love YouEpisode 2
Timing and Subtitles Brought To You By The Regretful Lovers Team @ Viki
♫ I don’t think I will hold anything back from you, ♫
♫ even though your smile is no longer because of me. ♫
♫ I really wish that you were still mine, ♫
♫ but I don’t have the rights to give you more. ♫
♫ I still live in my memories from the past, the prime time with you. ♫
♫ Have you ever thought about me ♫
♫ in your new life? ♫
♫ “I'm sorry and I love you.” That’s something I really want to tell you. ♫
♫ But no matter what I say, nothing will be changed. ♫
♫ I just want you to be happy. Your happiness is my happiness. ♫
♫ I just want you to be happy, no matter whose embrace you are in. ♫
♫ Our love and my care for you ♫
Doesn't this feel like we're exchanging rings?♫ Our love and my care for you ♫
After we graduate from college,♫ As long as you can be happy, ♫
let's get married.♫ I’ll be okay with being the only one lonely. ♫
♫ I just want you to be happy. That’s my only request. ♫
♫ I just want you to be happy. I will be a good audience member. ♫
♫ Your present and future will no longer have me. ♫
♫ I want to give you so much more, ♫
♫ but all that’s left to give are my blessings. ♫
Hong Pei,
do you want me to help you?
With what?
I'll help you get fire and burn down the house.
What? Burn what? You can't!
You came here in hopes of seeing somebody, didn't you?
But the result was only disappointment.
How did you know?
I suggest that you stop having hope in people other than yourself. Nothing good will ever come out of it.
This is so boring. Let's go. I have to hurry home to watch my cartoons.
Hey! We're almost late!
It's normal to have hope,
hope that she still remembers me,
just like what I believe. One day, we'll meet again.
Jian Hao, why are you here?
You ask me that every time we see each other. I don't even know how to answer anymore.
I'm sorry. I just didn't expect that someone--
That someone will come here, right?
I suddenly missed him a lot today.
It felt like he came here,
so I came here without even thinking about it.
Don't you find it very magical?
We both came here at the same time without any planning.
I was thinking, maybe Hong Pei was telepathically thinking about us.
I heard others say that only people whom he loves can sense it.
Sometimes, I wonder whether or not I should believe this type of superstition. I clearly know that it's not very scientific,
but I can't help but believe it.
I believe it
because you and Hong Pei were good friends.
It's very natural for you to be able to sense it.
I was thinking, in this world, only us two can get together
to miss him together. Why?
Because you are his girlfriend, and I'm his good friend.
Since both of us are already here, where is he?
Hong Pei! Ling Hong Pei!
Could he have left already?
He won't ditch us.
- Ling Hong Pei! - Hong Pei!
Ling Hong Pei! Hey, Ling Hong Pei!
Hey, why are you in such a rush? Are you being chased?
Didn't I already tell you that I have to hurry home to watch my cartoons? Of course I have to rush.
Cartoons don't have legs, so it's not like they'll run away. What's the rush?
Of course I have to rush. In just an hour and forty-three minutes,
I would have already gone a whole week without seeing my Xiao Qian (Character from the cartoon). You ask me why I'm in a rush?
My feet are in more of a rush than I am. Look at how fast they're moving.
Wow, your geek-level is completely maxed out. Can't you just watch it online?
To be honest, I've noticed that there's almost nothing that you can't do online.
Of course.
Hey, stop doing that. What do you want now? I've already done everything I could.
- It's nothing. Don't you think the weather is really nice today? Doesn't it feel good? - It's alright.
Can I ask you for another favor?
- No! - Big Brother Shu Hai!
Hey, aren't you too shameless? We were born in the same year, but you were born in an earlier month.
You call me Big Brother Shu Hai?
It's true we were born in the same year, but I've been dead for six years. If I'm 22 years old,
- then you're already 28 years old!- You--
I don't have much time left. After you return the watch...
You're so annoying.
I know.
What do you want?
Why did I agree to this?
I haven't been in a basketball court in so long. It feels great.
Let's go play a round!
Hey, watch your words. I didn't say that I would play with you.
What's wrong? You don't want to play? Not interested?
What do you think?
Whatever.
♫ One beautiful thing is more than enough. ♫
♫ Maybe it won't end. Tragedy might repeat itself. ♫
Good one!
♫ It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. Beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
♫ Maybe in a place not too far away, I’ll leave behind my footprints. ♫
♫ I’ll leave behind my footprints. ♫
♫ It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight ♫
♫ Beautiful, oh, it’s beautiful ♫
♫ The choice isn’t just a few days when it comes to your own adventure. ♫
♫ When you’re on the edge of expectations, ♫
Wang Shu Hai, you should play.♫ a lot of helplessness are inevitable. ♫
♫ You don't need too much luck. You don't need to take everything you want. ♫
Hurry.♫ You don't need too much luck. You don't need to take everything you want. ♫
♫ One beautiful thing is more than enough. ♫
♫ Maybe it won't end. Tragedy might repeat itself. ♫
- Try it again!- Catch the ball! ♫ Maybe it won't end. Tragedy might repeat itself. ♫
♫ It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
♫ Beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
Shu Hai, why are you so bad?♫ Maybe in a place not too far away, ♫
♫ I’ll leave behind my footprints. It’s a beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
Why is your face so pale? Are you okay? Let's just go home.
Who said that? I can do it.
I don't believe that I can't score.
Hey, look!
W-Wang Shu Hai! Wang Shu Hai, I touched the ball!
Wang Shu Hai...
Wang Shu Hai!
It's so magical. This is a shocking new discovery! I was able to touch something.
I clearly couldn't touch things, but at that moment, how did I touch it?
That's weird.
It was your willpower. It shows how badly you want to hurt me.
It was a basketball player's reflexes. Don't take it to heart.
I didn't take it to heart. I took it to my face.
How have I ever wronged you?
I'm sorry. You know that it was an accident.
Why do I feel like you're still laughing at my sufferings?
Laugh. You laugh. You'll be crying in a little bit.
I'm not laughing. I naturally look like this.
[I think I saw you on the basketball court today!][That's right. I did, too!]You're happy, aren't you? See, not only am I an ugly geek, I'm now tan, too.
What "ugly geek"? Stop making up words.
- Shh... I don't want to hear the details. - His nearsightedness must have gotten worse.
- He must have met a ghost. - I saw him, too.
That's right! I went to play basketball today with a ghost!
- Really? - How would you play? - It must have been hard to play defense. - Who won?
I'm still happy, though.
I originally thought that I have nothing to do with this world anymore.
I was already mentally prepared for it, but the moment I touched the ball... Wow.
- Stop being so stupid. No matter how handsome he is, he's still a ghost! - Oh, please. Meeting a beautiful female ghost is called real luck.
I don't know.
- What did he wear while playing basketball? A ghost wearing clothes doesn't sound very logical. - How would a ghost change clothes after he sweats?
[My god! How's his body? Does he have chocolate abs?] I'm suddenly not hopeless anymore.
I feel like I haven't left the human world yet.
I suddenly feel so real!
Get him to take off his clothes!
Take off his clothes!
Hey, you're so dirty. You're so sweaty from playing basketball.
You're laying on my bed without even showering.
Was your room very clean to begin with?
I think being comfortable is being clean. Uncomfortable is unclean.
At least take a shower and change your clothes.
How would I change?
Use your willpower.
Why are you suddenly asking me to change clothes?
Oh! What are you looking at?
It's not that. A ghost only needs a soul. Why do you need to wear clothes?
If you put it like that, you're naked right now, right?
Naked? Would it be like that?
Why did you take off your clothes?
It was all your fault! You were talking about being naked!
Don't be worried. Wait a second.
What are you doing?
Burning clothes for you to wear.
What's wrong with you? Why are you burning a sailor suit for me?
Don't come over here.
Abudaladalah. I'm going to kill you with my Hexagram Curse.
I'm going to use my electromagnetic waves and the power of science to blow you up!
Beep-beep. You dare to chop me? I'm going to beep your beep!
Wang Shu Hai isn't coming today, either.
It feels super weird to be missing one person.
It's so beep-beep. Dorae-Supermon is late again.
It's strange. I don't think he's late.
Haven't you realized that we haven't see Dorae-Supermon in a long time? This isn't logical.
H-He completely disappeared.
It's so beep-beep. Dorae-Supermon has always been great.
We don't have to worry about him.
From what I can tell, your spirit is affected by hidden cues.
These hidden cues are like commands.
As long as your spirit thinks about what you should wear,
it will be able to wear the clothes it wants.
This is different from willpower, though.
Your willpower makes up a part of the command.
To put it simply, as long as you want it, you can have it.
It's true!
Wow!
What are you doing?
Turns out your legs are really floating in midair.
This is the same as when you hit me and your change of clothes.
Because you thought that you could touch these things, it appeared as you were really touching them.
It really only lasts for one second.
That's right. It's only one second.
So that means that I might have other abilities that I don't know of?
How about it? Do you want to try some more things?
Okay.
But I suddenly feel so tired. I suddenly want to sleep.
I thought you didn't need to sleep.
Hey.
He fell asleep.
Touching too many things
uses up a lot of energy.
Timing and Subtitles Brought To You By The Regretful Lovers Team @ Viki
Hey, aren't you cold standing here?
Why are you still here at this time?
There's a meeting tomorrow, so the design department is working overtime.
Assistant Director, aren't you too strict? I don't think there's a need for this.
In the previous years, the seasonal packaging design change usually happens--
In order to decrease my guilt, I was going to go out to buy midnight snacks for them.
Let's go.
We're not going together?
Aren't you just trying to get me to go into the company?
No one can force you to take over a position that you don't want. Isn't that right?
We don't have to follow our parents' arrangements.
If we don't go down that road, no one can force us to.
What should I do?
I'm already on this road.
More importantly, no one forced me to.
Wang Shu Hai isn't here?
It's so late. Where would he have gone?
We should have it.
It's in the second cabinet's third or fourth row.
I will have to return this watch to its owner sooner or later.
Wouldn't that mean Ling Hong Pei will completely disappear?
No, I have to think of a way to help him.
♫ How I wish I could undertake all the pain you’ve suffered before. ♫
♫ I’m willing to give you all that I have ♫
♫ in exchange for you to receive the life that you want. ♫
♫ I’ll help you achieve everything that you desire. ♫
♫ Every possibility of happiness ♫
♫ will be exchanged for the life that you want. ♫
Hello?
Hello, Dorae-Supermon.
What? What do you need?
I wanted to ask you how your progress on the watch is.
Oh. I haven't fixed the watch yet.
Could it be so hard that it's even unfixable for you?
How is that possible? The word "unfixable" isn't even in my vocabulary.
It's fixed, then?
Of course. It's been fixed for a long time.
That's great. Hey, will you come to work tomorrow?
Bring the watch with you.
- Hey, Zheng Nan. Wait.- Bye bye! See you tomorrow.
Hello? Hello?
- You... - I... - You first. - You say it first.
You're the dead one, so go ahead.
Aren't you pursuing your goddess colleague?
You're going to work today, right?
I'll come with you.
To repay you, I can help you...
Stalk her.
You're the one who gets to stalk her, not me.
What do you think?
I will think of a way to get her to like you.
Stop dreaming. She's a goddess.
How could she like me?
How will we know without trying? We'll have to try it to find out. I can promise you that
there won't be a problem!
Your promise has no evidence.
Am I the naive one or are you?
Wang Shu Hai, getting her to like you is my responsibility.
- So... - Stop. Please don't be like this.
What do you really want? Say it.
Say it!
I'll help your pursue the goddess,
- and you help me with yesterday's...- No.
I already said that I will return the watch today.
So soon? Can't you postpone it?
No. I have to return it back to her.
Just help me one more time. Maybe I'll find a way to break away from this watch.
Aren't you very interested in this experiment, too?
That's true, but we can't.
Didn't you already see it last night? You don't need to sleep at all,
but after our experiments,
your situation worsened.
I don't want to take that risk.
But I'm fine.
I find it regretful, too.
After I slept, I'm all energized again.
This corn is so good. What brand is it?
I'm being serious. If you return the watch, I won't even have the chance to take the risk anymore.
If I disappear, I won't have another chance. Please help me one more time.
Are you just hoping to see your girlfriend
or family members again?
Why can't I have hope? I'm not you.
If it's something I can do, I would do it and try it.
I won't avoid something without even trying.
Maybe you once got hurt because you had hope, but I won't, okay?
Okay. As long as you don't get hurt, then it's fine.
Then there's no point in me feeling sorry for you.
What do you mean?
Because I won't do anything that satisfies what you are hoping for.
What was he trying to lecture me for? Who is he trying to piss off when he's dead already?
Dorae-Supermon, you're so great.
It's just like new! Wow.
Wait.
Could you have bought a new one for me because you couldn't fix it?
Good thing I, Dorae-Supermon, have a great foresight,
so I purposefully didn't fix the scratch on the watch.
I'm sorry. It's not that I didn't want to fix it, but as long as hate still exists in this world,
I will have to have hundreds of ways to justify myself in order to handle others' ridicule.
I'm not afraid of your hate. I'm only afraid that you have no hate. So? Scared, right?
Are you done talking? Was that supposed to be a riddle? Aren't you a hateful person yourself?
None of your business, but no one can hate on me.
Fine. How much was it? I'll pay you.
Are you mental? You don't have to give me money.
Don't worry. I won't pay you for fixing the watch. I was asking about the material fee.
Finding these materials must have costed you a lot of cash, right?
What cash? Hey,
with our friendship, this amount of money is nothing.
What an idiot. Unless you want to give me 15,000 NTD.
In your dreams!
All in all, you brought this watch back to life.
My friend will be super happy! Good job!
It's nothing.
Okay, I'm leaving now.
Zheng Nan.
What do you want?
Who's that friend of yours?
The person who wanted me to fix the watch was a girl?
Do I know her?
She's my best friend from college.
Wait a second. When have you ever been so interested in my friends before?
How could possibly want me to introduce her to you?
I was just thinking, it's not like the watch is a person.
How could she be so happy after it being fixed? Can't I be curious?
You can't. I already told you that she's my best friend college.
If she's happy, then I'm happy
Then... Is she living well?
Don't tell me that she already has a boyfriend or she's even married?
Don't worry. Even if you, Wang Shu Hai, were to reincarnate 5380 times, the answer to this question
is still none of your business.
So that means she does? For how many months?
You're so weird. When did you turn from a geek into a pervert?
I'm not.
I'm going to stop bickering with you.
I have to go to a meeting.
Hurry, then. If there are any problems with the watch,
you can bring it back to me.
Don't worry. Your Dorae products have amazing qualities.
High five!
Wait for me!
I'm sorry! Are you okay?
You seem to be bleeding.
Aren't you Zheng Nan's friend?
♫ I don’t know when you started telling me all sorts of things. ♫
It's okay. Don't worry about it. I can do it myself.
♫ But after chatting for a while, I realized that I was head over heels in love with you. ♫
♫ I’ll keep you company along with the night sky. You talking about your honey completely breaks my heart. ♫
Si Yi, the meeting is about to start. What are you doing?
Why are you here?
Don't always ask me that. I'll definitely appear.
You have to remember to put on medicine.
♫ But you don’t see the truth. ♫
♫ Oh, baby. If you’re crying in pain, I’ll stay with you the whole night. ♫
Look at Shu Hai. He's acting so weird.
♫ I’m still willing to wait, wait until you slowly realize it one day. ♫
Everyone.
2D interactions
can no longer satisfy me!
Could you have reached 3D interactions?
Interactions:
A term used in anime.
2D Interactions:
Interactions from a virtual world of video games.
3D Interactions:
Interactions in the real world.
Shu Hai, you have to explain everything clearly to us. You can't miss a second.
♫ You know I love you. ♫
I'm too embarrassed to.
Hey!
It's really fixed?
- Wow.- Didn't I tell you that he's very amazing?
Then how much is the repair fee? Does he have a repair store?
He only repairs as a hobby.
No, I have to pay or else I'll feel bad.
Just ask him for a price.
He won't want your money.
Really? But... Hey!
What about this, I'll treat him dinner?
Let me tell you. Whenever he's face-to-face with a girl,
he can't make eye contact for longer than three seconds.
You are Zheng Nan's neighbor and friend, right?
Wait for me.
I'm sorry! I think you're bleeding.
He seems like he's shy.
He is not shy.
He has an illness. I suggest that you don't personally experience it, okay?
Zheng Nan, I really want to treat him for dinner.
I want to personally thank him.
If you treat him for dinner, I think he will be super excited!
Okay, leave it to me.
Thanks.
Oh, yeah. Don't tell him that the owner of the watch is treating him to dinner.
Why not?
I'm scared that he won't come.
He won't be like that--
He will. Just listen to me.
Let's go.
- It scared me today.  - What's wrong?
Xiang Jian Hao! Why did he suddenly appear in the meeting?
Wasn't his chuunibyou acting up before, saying that he won't take over the company, no matter what?
Just start eating. Your dad and Director Xu are in the guesthouse.
They have things to discuss. Let's just eat.
Thank you.
I heard that at the board meeting today, you officially accepted the CEO position?
I did not accept the position to inherit the company.
That's okay. You can enter the company and learn the work first
Oh, yeah. Why aren't you entering the company to work?
Oh. I haven't graduated from college yet.
That doesn't matter. Your dad opened the company. Or are you scared of others' gossip?
He's not like you. He doesn't have the capabilities.
Let's eat.
Oh, right. You and Li Mei--
I don't want to talk about this.
This problem has already been delayed for a long time, and also--
I'll say it again.
You don't have the right to interfere with my marriage.
Older Brother, don't talk to Mom that way.
I'm sorry,
but she is your mom, not mine. Also, I am not your brother.
- Older Brother... - I don't have family members like you two.
Let's eat.
Is your brother's chuunibyou acting up again?
Chuunibyou: A Japanese internet slang, making fun of teenagers who are arrogantly conceited, thinks that they're misunderstood, and thinks that their lives are horrible. It's an immature act of escaping reality or self-assurance.
There's not one day that he doesn't act up.
What will you do?
This was all because of me.
I have to find a way to help him.
Why should you help him? It wasn't your fault.
It was my mom's fault.
I was a mistress's child.
My whole existence is a mistake.
Xiang Jian Ren, why are you so pessimistic?
I'm not being pessimistic.
I'm just stating the truth.
Because I understand this truth,
no matter how angry my brother gets at me,
I have to find a way to forgive him.
Hey, I'm sorry.
You're the only one I can complain to about my chaotic family.
It's not like we're strangers. I'll listen to whatever you have to say.
Thank you.
Traditional Massage
No matter who it's with, I must receive 3D interaction!
Hey, is this really the right place?
Of course. Don't you feel like the magnetic field here
is very different? It's unscientific.
This doesn't feel like a place we can get 3D interactions from, though.
Are you sure you've been here before? It has "pure" written on there!
I've never been here, but don't you think that this "pure"
looks very much like a disguise?
Also, look at how mysterious the design here is.
Most importantly, this place is in such a small village.
Why would ordinary people come in here? It's unscientific.
Only people who are familiar with this place would come. Isn't that right?
Judging by what you said, it seems to be true.
I think your analysis is very logical!
What do we do now? Should we go in?
Oh! I don't dare to! You guys go first!
Hey, since you recommended this place, you go first.
From a scientific point of view, if I wasn't afraid to go in, I would have gone in a long time ago.
Hey! Why did it turn into me?
You guys are such scardy cats. How would you get 3D interactions this way?
How about I count to three, and we go in at the same time?
I'm going to start now: One...
Hey! Wait for me! Who's calling me? Oh, Zheng Nan.
Hello? What do you need?
Wang Shu Hai, you're so dirty.
Uh... I'm done.
Come out and let me see.
Let's just forget it. I'll find someone else.
- Don't be like this, Zheng Nan! - That scared me.
I'm begging you, don't leave.
I still have a lot of clothes left. I won't disappoint you.
Fine, get up. Get up! It itches.
Are you free on Saturday?
Saturday? Yes, I'm free.
What was with that twirl?
I'm embarrassed.
Are you mental? Why would you be embarrassed?
Because this is the first time you've ever introduced a girl to me.
My little brother Shu Hai has been behaving very well these days.
Is this how you repay me for fixing the watch?
You could say that.
Then, what other things do you have for me to fix?
I don't have that many broken things.
All in all, it's on Saturday. Don't forget.
Time to go to sleep.
I'm going to remind you again: The other person is an unsurpassable beauty.
She has a good figure and good skin. You need to remember three things.
- Number one, don't be too messy. - Okay.
Number two, don't be late.
- Okay. - Number three, you're not allowed to embarass me.
Okay. I'll try my best to be embarrassing.
What are you talking about?
I mean, I'll try my best not to embarrass you.
Good boy. Get to sleep early.
Bye bye.
Everyone, how do you turn a geek into someone handsome?
I'm done for.
How do I turn handsome?
As long as you want it, you can have it.
I'll help you get your goddess. I'll think of a way to get her to like you.
Ling Hong Pei!
Get up. Hurry and get up.
What?
Didn't you say that you'll help me get the girl?
You have no integrity. I don't want to help you get your goddess.
It's not the goddess. I'm trying to get the fairy this time. They're different.
Can we renegotiate the conditions?
Oh, whatever. I'll agree to whatever requests you have.
You have no moral principles. I don't want to help you.
A handsome guy like you doesn't understand what it's like to be a geek.
To be honest, you're hopeless.
- How about you possess me?- Huh?
Can't ghosts possess people? You can possess me
and then meet with the fairy in place of me. What do you think?
Wow, Wang Shu Hai. I really don't know what to say to you anymore.
In order to get a girl, do you really have to come to this extent of asking to be possessed by a ghost?
I heard from the others that the first impression is the most important.
What can I do? I don't know how to possess people. How do I possess?
This is the only time you're willing to test things out with me?
Just get on. Stop saying so much useless things.
Is it like this?
Hey, you're a ghost. You should know more than I do.
How would I know? It's my first time, okay?
It's my first time, too.
Okay, so be gentle with your actions. Don't get too rough.
I'm coming.
How about this, I'll turn around. It might be easier for you that way.
Is it more comfortable for you like this?
It doesn't matter whether or not I'm comfortable.
As long as you can come into my body, it'll be okay.
- Are you sure? - Yes.
Just do it.
Okay.
Then I'm really going to do it, okay?
- Are you in? - Am I? I don't know. Do you feel anything?
I feel like I'm having trouble breathing,
my mouth is dry,
and my four limbs are stuff.
That's because you're nervous. You're too tight.
Really?
Front and back both don't work.
How about you be on bottom this time?
I just knew that you would be here.
Hey, you should stop trying to get ghost-possessed.
Okay. It was my mistake just now.
Why don't you just get a makeover?
We still have sometime left until the weekend, anyway.
Let's come up with a solution together.
I'll leave it to you then, Pei Pei.
Hey, what's wrong?
It's nothing. I was just dizzy for a moment and I was very tired.
I think you should just get some good rest tonight.
I don't sleep this early, though.
A makeover starts with readjusting your sleeping schedule.
Hey, the owner of that watch was your girlfriend, right?
Do you still want to see her a lot right now?
I already asked my friend. She said that the owner of that watch
is living very well right now.
Even though I'm not sure, I don't think she's lacking handsome guys like you around her.
When I first started fixing the watch, I guessed that
if the watch is already so destroyed,
the owner of the watch must be no longer of this world,
but I would have never thought that when you died,
you were wearing the watch.
Actually, I really want to tell you
to not worry and just let her go.
But since your girlfriend still kept the watch on her
and even wanted to fix it,
it means that she still hasn't forgotten about you.
At least meet with your girlfriend one more time.
I'll help you with that.
♫ Inexplicable sadness ♫
♫ floods the eyes. ♫
♫ A firework of memories flashed by of the past. ♫
♫ Unreachable places ♫
♫ and unoccupiable hope. ♫- Long Hong Pei! - Mrs. Ling, please get a hold of yourself!
♫ There is nothing left worthy of waiting for the change of fate. ♫
♫ The red spider lilies form two trails of tears, ♫
♫ with pain that can’t be erased. ♫
This is what Hong Pei wanted to give you.
I want you to forever remember this moment.
♫ will the ending still be the same? ♫
You should wear this watch for the rest of your life.
♫ of the unbearable weight of life. ♫
Remember
that Hong Pei died because of you.
♫ At least I’ve once passed by this sweet aroma. ♫
Timing and Subtitles Brought To You By The Regretful Lovers Team @ Viki
Remember
that Hong Pei died because of you.♫ Inexplicable sadness floods the eyes. ♫
♫ Inexplicable sadness floods the eyes. ♫
I want you to forever remember this moment.
You should wear this watch for the rest of your life.
♫ Unreachable places ♫
♫ and unoccupiable hope. ♫
Get up.
It's so cold.
Didn't you want to transform yourself for the fairy?
I was meaning to ask you this before, but why do you set your alarm at such a weird time? It's not 10, nor 11.
10:11.
That's the goddess's time.
My goddess coworker will always eat bread alone on the stairs at 10:11.
♫ I don’t know when you started telling me all sorts of things. ♫
How did you know?
In the beginning, I didn't really pay attention to it,
since I was able to be in the same area as my goddess,
but later, I realized that she always came at the same time.
Every time she came, she would be alone, sitting and eating,
but she never eats that much.
How did you know that she doesn't eat a lot?
Wang Shu Hai!
You still won't admit that you're a pervert?
Hey, have I ever denied it?
I really don't know what to say to you anymore.
The first time we met was at the stairs,
but I don't think she remembers.
All in all, I'm the only one who knows about this:
the goddess's secret.
If you put it that way, you're so strange. You clearly like the goddess so much, but why would you meet the fairy?
Because the goddess will never like me.
You're doing it again.
That's how I am.
Like what?
Like what I'm like right now.
After my alarm rings, I'll know that she'll be at the stairs. In the next fifteen minutes,
she'll be on the stairs, nicely and quietly,
without any disruptions, eating cakes, breads, and cookies.
I'm the only one who knows about this, even if I'm not with her.
Oh, yeah. I should say that this has nothing to do with whether or not I'm with her.
That's how perverted I am.
This is how a pervert loves someone.
Uh- Then... Pervert In Love, hurry and get ready to leave.
Okay.
Hi, Xiao Bai.
Xiao Bai? Who's that?
Are you blind?
I've rode him and met him before. I didn't know that he has a name.
Whatever. Today, I'll formally introduce you two to each other.
Xiao Bai, his name is Ling Hong Pei.
Ling Hong Pei, this is Xiao Bai.
Xiao Bai, ghost. Ghost, Xiao Bai. Xiao Bai, ghost--
- Hey!- Huh?
Well... Xiao Bai, he's my... ghost friend.
I'm telling you, after I modified Xiao Bai,
going 60 kilometers only takes five seconds.
Oh? How fast is that?
Very fast.
Very fast?
Hey, didn't you say that you only need five seconds to go 60 kilometers? How could I can walk faster than you?
That's because I haven't turned on turbo mode. If I ride too fast, I'll get afraid.
What's so hard about buying clothes?
It's not hard. How about you try to match a pair of clothes?
Okay.
It looks like Halloween.
Timing and Subtitles Brought To You By The Regretful Lovers Team @ Viki
Hey, make sure you don't fall in love with me.
Buying clothes is way too hard.
Actually, half of the difficulty is because you're not used to the society.
What's the other half, then?
You have horrible fashion sense.
Whatever.
You're going to give up?
You've decided already?
I'm going to invent a tool that you can find suitable clothes with without shopping.
What do you mean?
I have a 3D scanner. I'm going to scan my image into the computer
and then I'll pair it with the clothing online and put them on my body.
That way, I can tell whether or not these clothes are suitable for me.
- You know how to invent things?- It's not a big deal.
If you apply for patent, you can sell it for money, right?
I currently have 128 rights to apply for patent. I would only sell them if I need money.
Don't you know that your nonchalant self-confidence is really annoying?
Thank you for your compliment.
Is the store we're about to go to very fancy?
If a person like me goes in there, it seems kind of weird.
What about you? You're a genius! What are you afraid of?
Did she see a ghost or something?
Hey, h-have some respect.
Okay, I'm sorry. I was the one who saw a ghost.
Save me! Robbery!
Save me! Robbery! Someone stole my purse!
- What do we do? - Chase after him!
I'll go get my Xiao Bai and you find a way to call the police.
Save me! Robbery!
Shu Shu!
He went that way. Hurry.
Don't run! Stop!
♫ It was a rainy day when I got out, but I left my umbrella at home. ♫Xiao Bai, hurry.
♫ I forgot to recharge my phone and didn't bring enough money to fill up the gas tank. ♫
Thief, stop! Don't run!♫ You don't need too much luck. ♫
♫ You don't need to take everything you want. ♫
Don't run!♫ Life is actually very long. ♫
♫ One beautiful thing is more than enough. ♫
♫ Maybe it won't end. Tragedy might repeat itself. ♫
It's not this way. Turn right!
- Shu Shu!- Where is he? - This way!
♫ Beautiful day, beautiful day tonight. ♫
♫ Beautiful, oh, it’s beautiful. ♫
Stop!
Don't run! Stop right there!
♫ The choice isn’t just a few days when it comes to your own adventure. ♫
♫ When you’re on the edge of expectations, a lot of helplessness are inevitable. ♫
♫ You don't need too much luck. You don't need to take everything you want. ♫ Why did you have to run? Why can't you behave?
♫ Life is actually very long. One beautiful thing is more than enough. ♫
- Shu Shu!- I'm sorry!♫ Life is actually very long. One beautiful thing is more than enough. ♫
Hey, Ling Hong Pei, what's with you?
I don't know, either. Really, I don't know.
You were teleporting and moving so fast!
- Isn't it so magical?- Is that you ability, too?
- I think so. - This... Other than stalking in broad daylight,
this is an ability that living humans all wish to have. If you put it that way, being a ghost isn't so bad.
- That's right. Let's go together?- To die?
We're here.
- Shu Hai. - Huh?
Where are you going? We're here.
Wang Shu Hai!
Fine.
Hello. Welcome. Please come this way.
Shu Hai, act normal.
How would you like your hair to be done?
Y-You can take care of it.
Leave it to me.
- Woah! Shu Hai!- What?
If we fix you up a bit more, you might actually turn handsome.
Isn't that right? I just knew that I had it in me.
You can pursue the fairy now.
Of course I can.
[Date with the Fairy]So handsome.
I know.
Let's go.
Hey,
shouldn't you change into something as handsome as I'm wearing?
We'll talk about it later.
Don't be nervous.
It'll be okay. Let's take a deep breath together.
Fairy, I'm coming!
Why isn't Wang Shu Hai here yet? I told him not to be late. I called him but he wouldn't answer.
Would he not come?
That's impossible. Do you know how happy he was when I first told him? He was--
I won't destroy his image yet. He'll come. Trust me.
He's here.
Wang Shu Hai!
I told you not to be late, but you're late again!
I'm sorry! I was outside--
- You're late again. What's up with you?- I'm sorry. Just now, I was outside--
Timing and Subtitles Brought To You By The Regretful Lovers Team @ Viki
♫ My love for you is still in the same place. It has never left, ♫
♫ but you deserve the freedom to love. ♫
♫ I really want you back. I really want to hold your hand. ♫
♫ It’s all my fault for not continuing to protect you. ♫
♫ I still live in my memories from the past, the prime time with you. ♫
♫ Have you ever thought about me in your new life? ♫
♫ “I'm sorry and I love you”. That’s something I really want to tell you, ♫
♫ but no matter what I say, nothing will be changed ♫
♫ I just want you to be happy. Your happiness is my happiness. ♫
♫ I just want you to be happy. I will be a good audience member. ♫
♫ Your present and future will no longer have me. ♫
♫ I want to give you so much more, but all that’s left to give ♫
♫ are my blessings ♫