(birds chirping)
(man over radio) Ten-four. I'll notify PD
with a description of the vehicle.
(I "She's Not There" by The Cruel Sea)
J' Well, no one told me about her
J' The way she lied
J' How many people cried
J' Well, it's too late to say you're sorry
J' How would I know, why should I care?
J' Please don't bother trying to find her
J' She's not there
J' Well, let me tell you 'bout
the way she looks
J' The way she acts, the colour of her hair
J' Her voice is soft and cool
J' Her eyes are clear and bright
J' But she's not there
J' Well, no one told me about her
J‘ What could! do?
J' And they all knew
J' Well, it's too late to say you're sorry
J' How would I know, why should I care?
J' Please don't bother tryin' to find her
J' She's not there
J' Well, let me tell you 'bout
the way she looks
J' The way she acts, the colour of her hair
J' Her voice is soft and cool
J' Her eyes are clear and bright
J' But she's not there
Mrs Patty Va re?
Sorry to bother you, but we're trying to
speak with everyone who was at a party
at a William Ryan's house last night.
- You were at a party at the Ryan house?
- ls something wrong?
Well, to start with, somebody stole a car
belonging to Mr and Mrs Rune Carter
from the parking lot
of the Landmark Tavern.
- Were you at the Landmark Tavern?
- I was at Billy Ryan's.
That's only 100 yards
from the Landmark.
I didn't see the Carters.
How did you get home last night, ma'am?
I got a ride with some girls from Blakely.
Look, if that's all, I got toast in the toaster.
(cop) ls anyone here with you?
In the house?
Like who?
Like anyone.
Not right now.
OK.
That's legal.
I'm just wondering now
if you think you'll be here later.
- What for?
- In case we need to come back.
Well, I won't be. I'm going out for a ride
and I'm not gonna be here. I'm sorry.
A ride in that Porsche?
I'm going for a ride on a horse.
- Gotta warn you, it's supposed to rain.
- Thank you.
OK.
J' Well, it's too late to say you're sorry
J' How would I know, why should I care?
J' Please don't bother trying to find her
J' She's not there
J' Well, let me tell you 'bout
the way she looks
J' The way she acts, the colour of her hair
J' Her voice is soft and cool
J' Her eyes are clear and bright
J' But she's not there
(horse whinnies)
"| sat at the table then with bloody hands."
"| sat waiting for the sun to rise with
my wife - at least, the biggest part of her -
still sitting beside me."
"Her head was chopped off
and, having rolled to wedge beneath
the dishwasher, no longer fazed me."
"All I could see was that plastic barrette
clipped onto the back of her hair
and the trail of her blood leading to me."
That's it.
You're messed up, man.
- (teacher) You call that writing?
- Pardon me?
You call that writing?
- What d'you mean? What's wrong with it?
- It's not writing.
That's chocolate syrup
on chocolate ice cream. Now get rid of it.
- You asked for a scene of domestic...
- Rancour. In the style of John Cheever.
- That's what it is.
- I don't think so.
Well, I do.
What you have written
is not in the style of John Cheever.
Therefore you will rewrite it
before we see each other again.
All right, sir.
That's what you should
have said in the first place.
In the meantime, I've also
given you a zero for being late.
- I'm cutting that class tomorrow.
- Why? Because he didn't like your story?
No.
Because he gave me another zero
for being, like, three minutes late.
He gives the same zero
for being late as for being out.
Better off just cutting.
He starts off five minutes early
and acts "Where were you?"
Yeah, I know it, dude.
He leaves me no choice.
It's designed to make you cut.
It's fine with me. I'm glad to do it.
(I "l Knew That" by The Devlins)
J' They said the sky
would be burning bright
J' And all the angels would begin to fight
over the reason why there's no seasons
J' And there 'II be no day and night
J' But, oh, you see, I knew that
J' Yeah, I knew that
J' Don't you see, I knew that
J' Yes, I did
J' I heard the words you were telling me
J' I heard your lies, your stupidity
J' All these things you say to me
J' You just don't understand
Hey, Heinz. Fucked again, huh?
- I'm going to go get something to eat.
- Have fun in class?
- Frances. Hey.
- Don't bother me.
Gimme some potato chips, all right?
- 2.50.
- What?
That's for five of ‘em, doll.
50 cents apiece. Four on credit's the limit.
- Frances.
- That's my name.
- I don't have it on me.
- Oh, please.
Please what? I'm on a scholarship.
The Elks lodge in Elliston pays my way.
I see. Well, maybe you'd better tell your
Grand Pooh-Bah to set up a snack fund.
- Milkshake or egg cream?
- Baker, I gotta talk to you.
- Fucking bitch'd let me starve.
- I heard that.
Frances.
- Watch it.
- (boy) Baker.
- Yeah, what?
- I gotta talk to you privately.
- Privately? You got dirt on your face.
- You gotta get the car.
- What?
- I left a lady out there with Murphy.
- What do you mean, "a lady"?
- What do I mean? A lady!
What lady?
Well, I don't know what lady, Baker, but
we need to go get her. We have to drive.
- Baker, gimme some money, I'm hungry.
- Hey, guys, want a chip?
- Hey, where'd you get those?
- Found them.
Baker, please.
- All right, let's go.
- You'll go with me?
Yeah, I just said "let's go".
Where you going? Gimme those.
- What's with them?
- I don't know.
- Cooke, try to take it easy. We'll find her.
- I know.
What were you guys doing out here?
We were cutting IFS.
We were coming across the field and saw
a horse. All saddled up but no one around.
Murphy wanted to take off.
I thought maybe the horse was lost or...
All right, there's Murphy.
(faintly) Over here!
Come on!
(Murphy) Hurry up!
(Cooke) Let's go.
Look at her.
Look at this.
(Cooke) I told you.
She moved while you were gone.
What do you mean? What did you do?
I didn't do anything. I didn't touch her.
What happened to her?
(moans)
He") me!
- Whoa.
- See?
Man, I say we get the hell outta here.
- That's brilliant, Murphy.
- (Murphy) Well, what do you suggest?
I don't know. I'm thinking.
Miss?
Ma'am, are you in there?
HEY-
Where's my horse?
- We're taking you to a doctor.
- No. No.
- Why not?
- I'm fine.
- I don't think you're fine.
- I don't want to go to a... a doctor.
(Cooke) What if something's broken?
- Do you want us to drive you home?
- Where do you live?
(Baker) Do you live around here?
- Ma'am?
- (Cooke) Uh-oh.
Oh, fuck this.
- Murphy, shut up.
- Well, now what? Now what?
We'll take her with us.
We're not gonna take her to school.
Why not? She said not to take her home.
So take her to a gas station, Baker.
Call the freaking cops!
- Murphy, did you hear what she just said?
-Yes, I heard her!
What if she's on the run?
I can't just turn her in.
Tum her in for what, Baker?
For falling off a horse?
Well... I don't know for what.
(I "Colored Water" by Orbit)
J' Paper bag
J' Picture postcard
J' Wasted time
J' I know nothing 'bout you
J' Do you care?
J' Strip you bare
Hey!
What?
What are you doing?
Nothing.
(clock chimes)
(I "Bellylaugh" by Compulsion)
Hey, dude.
- What are you guys doing here? It's 6.30.
- We needed a lighter.
-You don't have a lighter?
- They're all in here, thief. Ready?
Ready.
- (Baker) Aren't you guys going to dinner?
- Oops.
All right. There we go.
- If you don't leave now you won't make it.
- Oh, dude, your dad called again.
You want to know something? I think
he likes talking to me more than you.
I'm really glad, but it's, like, 6.30.
I think he said you forgot
your mom's birthday again.
- (puts on deep voice) Sonny, goddammit!
- Don't call me that.
Maybe if you ran a humorous anecdote
by him now and again, he'd like you more.
Hey, it's Jimmy Cooke.
- John.
- What?
- My name isn't Jimmy. It's John.
- Oh.
John. Johnny. Jimbo.
How's it going, Bill?
- Get the hell out of here. All of you.
- What'd you say?
Hey, man, that was my shit.
This is my room.
- What's wrong with you, dude?
- Nothing. I just want some privacy.
Do you guys understand that?
(Heinz) OK.
- What are you doing that's so secret?
- Nothing.
-You building a tunnel or...
- No, asshole.
I got a girl knocked out in the back and
I can't bring her up until I get rid of you.
Yeah, in your dreams.
Thanks, guys!
We're coming.
- Jeez. What did you do, stop for a Coke?
- ls she all right?
How do I know?
I can't tell if she's dead or alive.
What do you want with her?
She's an accident victim.
(Baker) I know that.
- Come on. Let's get her inside.
- (Murphy) Not me.
Forget it. I'm going to dinner. You can do
whatever you're trying to do without me.
I'm trying to help her.
Come on.
(moans)
What is it?
It's a 20.
- "Patty S Vare".
- Can I see?
"Eyes ha..."
- Hazel.
- Right.
- "Birth date: two, nine..."
- She's 25.
- She's saying something again.
- ls she up?
She might be. I don't know.
(Baker) Hey-
You're up.
(Cooke) Hi.
How are you feeling?
(Baker) Nothing's broken, is it?
- (Cooke) We took your boots off.
- So you could sleep.
Are you all right?
- (Cooke) Want us to call the infirmary?
- No.
She speaks.
We should take her to the infirmary.
- She just said no.
- Where am I?
You're in my room. It's my room.
- I'll call the infirmary.
- Cooke, Jesus, she just said no.
- I think I'd like to sit down.
- Sure.
Where's my horse?
We're not sure.
Cooke, why don't you go get her
something to eat? Get her a sandwich.
(Cooke) Now?
ls that what you want? Are you hungry?
Not really.
- Get her some soup.
- Why don't we flip to see who goes?
All right, I'm going. If they don't
have soup, are doughnuts OK?
Doughnuts are fine. Go.
So.
- What'd you do?
- I fell off my horse.
Why didn't you want to go to a doctor?
ls that what I said? I don't remember that.
- I'm not surprised.
- Why? What else did I say?
(knocking)
You said... you didn't want to go home.
Did I?
Yeah. You know, it sounded like
you must have done something.
Mrs Patty Va re?
- Did you steal something?
- What?
Did you kill someone?
What are you talking about?
The perfect crime.
But then it started to heat up
so you had to get out.
What are you saying?
I don't know.
It was just an idea.
I guess I was just hoping... Someone like
you in the middle of a field, all alone.
I get to rescue a fugitive or something.
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint you.
Don't apologise.
You're not a disappointment.
What's your name?
Louise.
Louise?
(knock at door)
Can you hang on a minute?
- Who is it?
- Murphy. Open up!
- I can't right now.
- What the hell is that supposed to mean?
- It means you can't come in.
- Baker, open the door or I'm getting Hunt.
Whoa. She's up.
- (Baker) What do you want?
- ls she all right?
- She's fine.
- It's a good thing she woke up.
Murphy-
She could've died on you, bud.
What's your name?
- Louise.
- (Baker) Get the hell outta here.
- Are you hungry?
- She's not hungry.
- Do you live around here?
- Leave her alone!
You leave her alone, dude.
How about a cigarette?
Hey! Ow! Stop it!
(Baker) Excuse us for just a second.
(Murphy) Let go of me!
- Visiting hours are over. You hear me?
- Look like yours are just getting started.
You have a very big mouth
for an eighth grader, Murphy.
My mouth is nothing
compared to that boner in your pants.
- What did you say?
-You heard me.
(Baker) You'd better hope
I misunderstood you.
Hi.
- What do you want, Marco?
- Nothing.
- Marco, go get Mr Hunt for me. Now!
- Marco, don't you dare.
Marco, go!
You're gonna get so booted for this.
- You think so?
- I know it, man. You're outta here.
Murphy, you're gonna make somebody
a great cop someday. You know that?
(horse whinnies)
Still not back?
Still not back.
Figure she went somewhere
with the ballplayer?
Hard not to think it. I don't know.
I don't like feeling like I'm being avoided.
Well, it's not like this one
hasn't gone on binges before.
- You know her?
-Yeah, I know her.
So, where'd she be goin‘ in such a hurry
that she'd leave her horse on Route 9?
No idea. She could be anywhere. Horse
could've walked down there himself.
One time she left him tied to
Fenton's back porch. You know Fenton?
-Yeah, I know him.
- She left that horse for three days.
Well, where was she?
I don't know. She and Fenton
went somewhere or other.
One thing lead to another, I guess.
I don't know. Fenton won't say.
- She's kind of a firecracker.
- Yeah? That's what I hear about Bud.
He may have met his match with this one.
Right.
- Come out with your hands up!
- Jeez! You nearly made me drop this.
-You spilled some, dude.
- Shit.
-You working room service now?
- No, asshole.
-You treat him like he's Elvis.
- I do not. This is for me.
- I don't think so.
- What do you know?
- We know he's trying to hide it.
- Hide what?
You're gonna get nailed
just for knowing about it.
- So illegal, dude.
- No, he's just making sure she's all right.
- She?
- I mean...
- Oh, man.
- I don't believe it.
- It's a girl.
- I knew it. I knew it.
- That snake!
- Wait. What are you talking about?
- Come on.
- What girl? I didn't say anything.
We'll catch you later, mouth.
Thanks.
I'll keep an eye on the door,
if you need me.
Good.
(man) Who is that?
That's Fatty Vare.
(I "Vlﬂldwood" by Paul Weller)
You know her?
Yeah, I know her.
Do me a favour.
Oh, what?
Hey. Patty.
- What?
- Come here. Meet someone.
who?
Come on.
Bud, this is Patty. Patty, Bud Valentine.
Bud Valentine?
You know, there's a pitcher named
Bud Valentine. He pitches for Pittsburgh.
That's him.
It's him.
- That's you?
- Yes, ma'am.
How nice for you.
I'm dating a guy who's a big baseball fan.
That's how I know your name.
If he's dating you, he's a lucky guy.
Aren't you sweet?
ls he here?
No, he isn't.
Sorry.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
(I "Domestique" by Compulsion)
- (approaching voices) Ow!
- Watch it!
Marco. Get over here.
Keep your hand here and don't move it.
Don't let anyone touch this door.
- How come?
-You're playing a role, dude. Enjoy it.
Wait! Baker! What do you mean?
What if somebody has to go in?
Where is she?
Where's who?
Where's who? I love that.
She left.
- You're lying.
- Maybe she's in the bathroom.
Yeah, right.
Go look.
Let's look outside.
She's not outside.
- We're looking outside.
- Fine. I don't care.
(I "Begging You" by The Stone Roses)
J' I'm begging YOU"-
- What happened?
- I grabbed the shelf.
- Are you all right?
- I don't think so.
(breathes heavily)
Cooke, she needs a blanket.
(heavy breathing)
Your shirt is soaked.
We should get something dry on you.
Baker.
What should I do?
Go get me a shirt from my room.
Hello?
What?
- Did you hear me?
- Huh?
Go get me a shirt.
- Cooke, is there anyone out there?
- I don't think so.
(I "Honeysimple" by Scarce)
- Are you OK?
-Yeah. I'm OK.
- Are you still cold?
- No, I'm hot.
- What are you doing?
- I feel too hot now.
What the hell's goin‘ on in here?
- (Baker) Shit, Cooke!
- (Cooke) Uh-oh! Sorry.
- Baker! Open the door!
- Let us in!
(Baker) Will you shut up out there?
- (Baker) What?!
- Candygram.
Hey, guys, the bathroom's trashed.
How come the bathroom's trashed?
Hey, Baker, the bathroom's trashed.
I hate it here. I hate it here.
I hate it here so much.
- What? You want me? Looking for me?
- Who is she, asshole?
Who is who? Wait!
What are you guys talking about?
- Where'd she come from?
- You gotta tell us.
- Baker, you don't have a choice.
- Are you threatening me?
Don't threaten me.
- Well, don't try and hide things from us.
- Why not? Who are you?
I'm your best friend.
I deserve to know who she is.
You're my best friend?
Baker.
Dude, listen.
Dude, I'm telling you, it's too much for
you to handle. So just back off, all right?
Ow! Oh, man!
- (Baker) Jesus, what did you do?
- What the hell happened?
I think I just broke my hand.
- Oh, God. Look at it.
- Baker, take me to the hospital.
- Me? I can't right now.
- What?
What? Van Slieder can take you.
I've gotta stay here.
- What?!
- I just told you, I've gotta stay here.
Jeez, Phillips. It's not my fault you broke
your hand. Just go to the infirmary.
You're staying here with your girlfriend
and I'm getting hauled to the hospital?
- That's it.
- Phillips, shut up, OK? I'll take you.
God. Come on, let's go.
- I'll punch your face in.
- Know something?
- What?
- Thank you!
Hi.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
I brought you a soda.
Are you all right?
Yeah. I borrowed
some pants and sneakers.
That's fine.
- Did you call anybody?
- You mean about you?
Well, yeah.
No.
I'll be right back.
OK.
(Bud) Whoa!
Oh, shit.
I owe you, Cooke.
No, you don't.
(banging)
- (Murphy) What was that?
- Sorry.
- Let me in, guys.
- Just wait a minute, Murphy.
- Hurry up.
- Let him in.
Hurry UP-
- I don't believe you.
- Why's that?
-You've still got her in your room.
- Yeah? How do you know?
The whole school knows, Baker.
Even Marco saw her.
- Marco didn't see her.
- How long is she staying here?
Why do you ask? It's not your problem.
- I'll tell you something my mom said.
- What?
Give a stray kitten too much milk, you'll
have a permanent cat on your hands.
- She sounds like a genius.
- Shut up.
Murphy, you don't get it.
It's not what you think at all.
I don't get it?
(thunder)
- What are you reading?
-Your homework, I guess.
It's pretty gory-.
It's just a story.
I like the part with
the three prostitutes in the tub.
- Can I have that back?
- What class is this for? Creative writing?
- Yeah.
- There's no grade on it.
- It's an elective.
- A what?
It's pass-fail.
Oh.
So, how you doin‘ so far?
Are you passing or failing?
50-50.
Can I have that back?
It's not bad. A little flowery.
Yeah, that's what my teacher says.
- Really?
- Sort of.
- ls your head all right?
- Oh.
I have a cut.
How'd you get a cut there
if you fell on your back?
Look, my name's not really Louise.
I know.
It's Patty.
Patty.
Yeah.
I knew this would happen.
What would happen?
- That I'd get thrown out.
- You got thrown outta school?
Not yet, but I look at you
and I know that I will be.
Would it help if we left?
If you left? Yeah, it'd probably help.
You wanna come with me?
I'm in high school.
You could help me find my horse.
If you want.
What's wrong? What are we doing?
We're not gonna find
your horse out here, Patty.
Maybe someone found him
and took him back to your house.
Maybe we should check at your house.
You don't look like you like that idea.
I don't. I guess.
- What are you lookin‘ at?
- Those lights up there.
It's the fair.
You wanna go?
- Now?
- Yeah.
Are you kidding?
I have to get back to school.
- It's a really good fair.
- I'm sure it is, but...
- Patty.
- What?
I feel like I woke up with the dial
on the wrong channel or something.
I feel like that every day.
So what do they have?
Like, rides and stuff?
(I "If I Didn't Love You" by Squeeze)
J' If! didn't love you, I'd hate you
J' Watching you play in the bath
J' A soapsuds stickleback navy
J' A scrubbing brush landing crafi'
J' Your skin gets sofier and Wanner
J' I pat you down with a towel...
Patty.
There you are.
(slurring) I got another
one for you, all right?
There's these two women.
- What? What are you looking at?
- You told me this one.
- How do you know?
- You told me this one five minutes ago.
There's these two women
and they're sittin' on their front porch
and one of them sees their husband...
Boyfriend, with a bunch of roses.
- You told me this one.
- Did I?
- Yes.
- Oh.
What? What's the matter?
- I have to tell you something.
- Me too.
Let me tell you first.
I never tell anyone anything.
(man) Hey!
Patty Va re.
- Hey, Fenton.
- Where you been at?
I've been here tonight.
Where've you been?
- Having a couple of brewskis, huh?
- Yeah.
-You met Jilly?
- We met, I think.
Who's this?
Oh, this is my brother... Lars.
Well, his name's Lars,
but he goes by Larry.
Hey. She talks about you all the time, kid.
Fenton Ray. This is Jilly.
- Hi there.
- Hey.
You ride as good as your sister?
- What?
- He means horses, Larry.
- No, I don't like horses.
- Larry's into cars.
No kidding?
There's that fathead cop again.
He was down at the Landmark today.
What did he want there, Fenton?
How do I know?
I told you.
You're supposed to use your sight.
(mimics cop)
"Fenton, we're looking for a stolen car."
"What can you tell us?" They always think
of me first. What do I know about it?
- There's somethin‘ up that guy's butt.
- Will you excuse me? Be right back.
- (Jilly) ls she all right?
- I'm sure she's fine. I'll just...
I just miss something?
She's got a real protective brother.
(Patty) Larry!
(I "Sad and Beautiful World"
by Sparklehorse)
- Patty-
- Hey-
Come on.
- I thought you were leaving.
- I wasn't leaving. I was just getting in line.
But you disappeared.
There's people around here, Larry.
Be careful.
What do you mean?
- What are you doing?
-You started it.
I didn't start it.
Don't you start it.
Larry.
- Will you marry me?
- What?
I know that sounds ridiculous to you,
but I would do it. I'd do anything for you.
(boy) Ma! Jesus!
Got a little more...
Why don't you take him
over to the fountain?
All right. Come on, let's go.
We'll be right back.
- What's that?
- Where's Kellogg?
Oh. He says he's doing it by himself.
- Who's that guy? I've seen this guy.
- Bud Valentine. Plays for Pittsburgh.
- Right. He's the pitcher.
- Right.
- Do you like him?
-Yeah. He's good.
Been in a slump lately.
Missed a start in Atlanta today.
ls he wanted for something?
- What do you mean?
- He's just missing?
What?
What are you looking at?
What is it, KC?
(grunts in exasperation)
(1109 growls)
- What is it?
- Hold still.
(both laugh)
(I "The Secret" by Monster Magnet)
(Baker) Wanna know what my dad does?
What?
He owns seven Piggly Wigglys
and nine Sir Steaks.
No, ten Sir Steaks.
He bought a new one from RadioShack.
It used to be a RadioShack.
Know what I'm saying?
You don't wanna do that.
I don't wanna do that.
You know what he wants me to do?
He wants me, someday, to take the whole
chain to the New York Stock Exchange.
Me, the captain of industry.
He's the one that's been telling me
since I was two I'm a time-waster.
"Sonny, goddammit,
get your ass down here."
My mom would go
"For Christ's sake, he's only eight."
- He sent me away when I was 12.
- Threw you out?
He sent me to school.
I said "Fine with me,
at least I get some privacy."
Get me outta there, Patty.
I'm begging you.
Let me be your butler or something.
I don't need a butler.
Well, could I just come live with you?
-You wouldn't like it.
- Yes, I would.
Not for long.
You make everything look
so different to me, Patty.
- Oh, yeah, like what?
- Like everything.
Everything else just seems pointless
compared to being with you.
Like, what am I doing in school?
I don't know.
I'm afraid I might never see you again.
Will I?
Well, yeah.
You'll see me. I'm right here.
You want, like, a beer?
Yeah, OK.
(Bud) What was your name again?
Patty.
You're drunk, Bud.
Get in the car.
- Whose car is this, anyway?
- It's a rental.
I would think a guy like you
would have his own car, Bud.
Yeah, I do.
So why are we taking this one?
I like it. It'll always remind me of you.
(engine starts)
Bud Valentine, car thief.
Whaddaya know?
Am I gonna need lipstick for this?
(Feﬂlbn) Farney!
(Patty) Shit.
Well, hi-de-ho, Patty.
What are you doin‘ here?
(Jilly) Farney!
Fucking Grand Central Station.
I found your dog, Jilly.
Well, God, where the hell was he?
Farney!
- Come here!
- Where was Dennis the Menace off to?
Just shut up, all right?
What you looking at me like that for? He
only got three days to live or something?
Jeez, Patty. ls this serious or what?
I don't know. No, no. I don't know.
Look, Fenton, I'm in some trouble.
- With that kid?
- No.
- Will you do me a favour?
- Yeah.
Will you get me outta here
before that cop comes back?
And makes a scene
in front of your brother?
Yeah.
The last thing he needs is...
(Fenton) ls you?
Yeah, is me.
(phone rings)
- Hello?
- Yeah, who's this?
- Jonathan Marco. Who's this?
- It's Baker. Go get Cooke. Hurry up.
- Hello?
- Cooke, it's me.
- Baker, where are you?
- I'm at the county fair.
What? You're in big trouble.
- No, I'm not.
-Yes, you are.
Everybody knows you're gone.
You're missing. You disappeared!
- I know what I did.
- They called your parents.
- Who did?
- Hunt. Murphy must've told him about...
Cooke. Hey, Cooke, are you there?
Yes, Dad?
Oh, Jesus. Did someone come in?
Yes, Dad.
- Not Hunt again?
- Yes, Dad.
Oh, man.
- I'll call you back.
- That's not all.
Can I talk to Mom?
- What are you talking about?
- To both of you.
Dad... yours.
What?
To see you.
Oh, shit. My parents are there.
Way to go, Dad. I knew you could do it.
- Put my father on.
- That's so funny.
- I mean it, Cooke. Put him on.
- Dad, come on.
Put him on. Tell him it's me.
You won't get in trouble.
Uh, Mr Baker?
It's for you.
- Hello?
- Hey, Dad. It's...
Sonny, goddammit.
Where the hell are you?
Your mother's a goddamn nervous wreck.
It's him.
Dad, listen. I'm living my life.
- Boy, I don't believe this.
- What?
You don't wanna know.
Dad, it's nothing bad. It's a good thing.
Where the hell are you callin’ from?
I'm with a friend,
but that's not what I had to tell you.
I'm out in the world
and I'm doing fine. I'm great.
Sonny, that's got to be the dumbest thing
I ever heard outta you.
Now, you listen to me.
I'm here at your dorm with Steve Hunt.
And we worked it all out. You hear me?
Now you can go back to class
in the morning with a clean slate.
Steve's a good friend of mine
and he's willing to forget...
But I'm not. I don't wanna go back.
Sonny, goddammit! Look.
- We know you got mixed up with a girl.
- Dad.
- We don't know how...
- And we don't want to know.
- We don't want to know.
- Well, why not? I can tell you.
An angel fell in my lap and brought me
up to heaven and that's where I am.
You hear the music? That's where I am.
Sonny... please.
What? I'm throwing oﬁ’ the shackles, Dad.
I'm not coming back.
Congratulate me.
- He's hung up.
- (sighs)
(phone rings)
- Hello.
- I forgot to tell Mom happy birthday.
Tell her I said happy birthday.
He called to say happy birthday.
State police, son.
Who were you just on the phone with?
Just a friend, sir. Why?
I'm sorry, am I doing something wrong?
Where's your girlfriend?
What do you mean?
All right.
- You know this man?
- No.
I mean, it looks like Bud Valentine.
He's a pitcher for the...
- Yeah, that's who it is.
- Why are you showing me this?
Why does she disappear
whenever I show up?
- Who?
- Ms Fatty Vare.
- What do you mean, disappear?
- How do you know her?
Well...
I just... know her.
- How long have you known her?
- Just today, really.
So you don't know anything
about a stolen vehicle?
Black Jetta. Licence plate RB567K.
- Wait a minute. I don't know...
- That car's missing.
And so is Mr Francis "Bud" Valentine.
I believe your friend
knows the whereabouts of both.
For some reason she's being very evasive
today. And I'm hoping you'll tell me why.
- Look, I was just having a couple beers.
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, I see that.
You got some ID?
I got... school ID.
Drinking underage, I guess?
Yes, sir.
"John Baker Junior."
"Sherwood School for Boys."
Graduating soon?
June. I mean, if I graduate.
If?
Hate hearing that.
Yes, sir.
I tell you what I'm gonna do,
John Baker Junior.
I want you to call this number
when she contacts you again.
What do you mean, when she contacts...?
Don't tempt me not to trust you.
John.
Patty?
(I "Tell Her This" by Del Amitri)
J' Tell her not to go
J' I ain't holding on no more
J' Tell her something in my mind
J' Freezes up from time to time
J' Tell her not to cry
J' I just got scared, that's all
J' Tell her I'll be by her side
J' All she has to do is call
J' Tell her something in my mind
J' Freezes up from time to time
- Hi, Mom.
- Sonny.
- You OK?
- Oh, yeah.
Come in.
- I'm sorry to wake you up.
- Oh, no, it's fine. It's... uh... We're up.
What the hell's going on?
- I've got class at eight. I just wanted to...
- What do you mean, you got a class?
I have a quiz in Spanish.
- So you're going to class?
-Yeah, I guess I have to.
- How'd you get here?
- Here?
Well, I hitched a ride.
You stole a car from the school.
I just returned it.
Jesus, Dad, gimme a break.
- What kinda break did you have in mind?
- Parole at 35?
-You're not in jail. It's the opportunity...
- I'm not wearing stripes, you mean?
All right.
- We'll call Steve Hunt.
- I don't want to wake him up too.
Sonny, could you just sit down?
"Cuando el tiempo empieza a ponerse
més célido después del inviemo frio..."
(Hunt) Dr Paz? Hola. I'm sorry to interrupt.
John was with me this morning.
I hope you'll excuse his being late.
Oh, esta’ bien.
Como Ies iba diciendo,
Pedro tiene una casita en Ias montaﬁas,
donde él pasa sus veranos.
Y tiene una huerta
donde Ie gusta trabajar.
iOué cultiva en su huerta?
Seﬁor Phillips.
Uh...
E I cultiva zanahorias.
Zanahorias. gQué més? Seﬁor Heinz.
- En ella, él cultiva Ios hongos.
- (Van Slieder laughs)
Uh, uh, uh. Los hongos crecen
silvestres en el bosque, seﬁor Heinz.
Seﬁor Baker.
iOué més cultiva en su huerta?
En su huerta, uh, gzanahorias?
gEstamos hablando
de un enamorado de Ias zanahorias?
El seﬁor Phillips
ya mencioné zanahorias.
4- Que' rnés ?
Perdén, seﬁor. Uh...
E I cultiva manzanas.
gManzanas?
Uno tiene que distinguir
entre huerta y huerto, seﬁor Baker.
Perdén, seﬁor.
Too rough for you, huh?
Don't worry, I'll take over tonight.
- Your dad have to resuscitate you?
- (laughter)
(Paz) Seﬁores...
Si estan hablando de algo
que no tiene nada que ver con Pedro,
hablen ma's alto
para que todos podamos participar.
- Seﬁor Heinz.
- Si, seﬁor.
iOué puede ser tan interesante
para no prestar atencién a Ia clase?
Nada, seﬁor. Perdéneme.
Estén discutiendo
e interrumpiendo Ia clase sobre nada?
No, seﬁor.
Seﬁor Baker.
Lo siento, perdéneme.
No me siento yo hoy.
(sniggefs)
What is so funny?
(Paz) Seﬁor Baker, péngase de pie.
Péngase de pie, seﬁor Baker.
gLeyé o no Ieyé Ios capitulos
para hoy de "Pedro en Ios Pirineos"?
No Io lei.
g Y tiene alguna explicacién
para no venir preparado a Ia clase?
- Tengo problemas personales.
- (sniggering)
(coughs)
iOuiere explicar
sus problemas en inglés?
Well, sir, not really.
It involves my father.
He's had a long battle with alcohol.
And my mother can't help
because she's unstable as well.
(sniggeriﬂg)
Shut up, Heinz.
(Phillips) It involves a piece of ass.
Cost him his entire allowance
in one night.
Hey!
I will not allow physical disturbance.
I know, Dr Paz. I'm sorry.
- I think I've got the flu.
- (Paz) The flu?
Yes, sir. I think I'm not well.
You are asking me to excuse you
from the quiz that I scheduled for today?
-Yes, sir. I'd prefer to take it later.
- Save your strength for your girlfriend.
Watch my hand!
(I "Wait For The Sun" by Supergrass)
J‘ White budding sun
J' It's gonna come again
J' Wait for the one...
Oh, God. Speak of the devil.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It means I've just been talking about you!
- What's the matter? Where you going?
- Nowhere.
- Why aren't you in your class?
- I'm finished, Frances. I quit.
I see. Before you give your books to the
poor, someone's in there looking for you.
- In where?
- The snack bar. She says she's your aunt.
She doesn't look like your aunt.
She looks like Barbara Stanwyck.
She's having a cup of tea
with your number on the bag, Baker!
Watch yourself!
(Baker) Hey-
You looking for me?
Hey, lady, say something, will ya?
I'm sorry about last night.
Where did you go?
I waited for you. What happened?
(Fifty sighs)
Got a ride with Fenton.
What?
He... he gave me a ride out to his house.
You went to his house? You went home
with the convict, or whoever that was?
He's a carpenter, Larry.
My name's not Larry. It's John.
John.
He helped you get rid of me?
No. No, he didn't.
(sighs)
Look, I don't wanna keep you
from your schoolwork.
I dropped out of school, Patty!
Or at least I tried to.
God, are you always like this?
Yeah.
I'm always like this.
Do you know anything about
a pitcher named Bud Valentine?
(squealing tyres)
(I "Begging You" by The Stone Roses)
- What's that?
- It's a picture.
Melanie Carter.
You took the Carters' car.
(Bud) Whoa.
This is... uh... Rune and Mary Carter's car.
This is their daughter.
She killed herself last year.
- I don't feel so good.
- Car's haunted.
- Don't say that.
- I'm just kidding.
- Think I'd better go home.
- No, I'm taking you someplace.
I know, but I don't think
I wanna go anywhere right now.
- Too late.
- Come on, you can take me tomorrow.
- I won't be here tomorrow. I got a game.
- Bud, this isn't our car.
Bud!
- Bud! Stop!
' (TYPES squeal)
- Bud, why won't you stop?
- What?
(gasps)
I couldn't breathe.
I had to get out. I...
I was just too scared and...
I left him.
In the car.
I don't know why I got out and not him.
Larry?
Yeah?
Where the hell are they already?
They'll be here.
Miss Vare?
Ma'am, I would like to take you
into Wayland. If you don't mind.
- Officer Cane here can bring Mr Baker.
- He's not involved in this.
Well, it's routine.
It won't take very long. Don't worry.
You don't have to grab me.
Wayland.
Wayland. W-a-y-l-a-n-d.
OK. Thanks.
- Mr Baker?
- Yes, sir.
- All right, I think we're about done here.
- Good.
If we need to get in touch
with your son again, we'll contact you.
I appreciate your help, Lieutenant.
Sonny.
Hey, Patty. How are you?
I'm good.
Larry, this is my sister Ellen
and my brother Tom.
All right, Sonny. Let's get going.
I got fingerprinted.
Why?
Contributing
to the delinquency of a minor.
. Hey, Patty.
. Hey, Billy.
Let's go.
- What have you been saying, Fatty?
- Nothing.
- Sonny, goddammit!
- Goddammit what?
- Don't use that tone with me.
- John, he's just trying to help the girl.
That girl has plenty of people
to sort this out for her, all right?
- We said we'd keep this short.
- You'd better get outta here.
Don't push your dad any further, Sonny.
Please.
Better be a big elevator.
We'll just wait for the next one.
(I Gotta Know Right Now"
by Smoking Popes)
J' If I told you that I really
really liked you a lot
Dammit!
J' But I never had the guts
J' I wonder what you would say
J' I just can't go on this way...
- Hi, officer.
-You can't leave a car here, son.
My therapist told me to wait right here.
She'll kill me if I move.
I don't know who your therapist is,
but she can't leave her car here.
J' I wanna do something half insane
J' To prove to you that I'm alive
J' I wonder what you would say
- This your car, sir?
- Yeah.
- This is an illegal parking place.
- Sorry.
(engine starts)
Sonny, goddammit!
J' As I walk by your house
for the third time tonight
J' And I stand in your driveway
hypnotised by your bedroom light
J' I wonder what you would say
J' I just can't go on this way
J' I gotta know right now today
J' I gotta know
J' Right now
(I "Sweet Life" by Lucid)