I have a song in my head.
I remember the songs we used to sing,
my sister and I.
I always said, "I will not marry
and be sent far away."
"I will go no further
than these paddy fields."
But our mother told us
we must not run from our fate.
What cannot be changed must be borne.
The test of life is to endure.
But our mother could not endure.
Amma.
No one spoke of our mother's death,
and I remembered her saying:
"If Allah wanted us to ask questions
he would have made us men."
Our fate was decided then.
I was to be grateful when Father chose
me an educated man living abroad.
My sister would stay.
I would go.
You can spread your soul
over a paddy field.
You can feel the earth
beneath your toes
and know that this is the place,
the place that it begins and ends.
But what can you tell
to a pile of bricks?
I think of my sister.
I think of home.
My husband promises me
we will be coming home soon.
Good.
I will test you both on
your Tagore tonight.
OK. Abba.
Do you hear me. Shahana?
- Abba, will you get
the promotion today?
Verv likely. Verv likely.
- Get your lunchbox.
- OK.
My colleague Wilkie
thinks he will get the iob.
Feet up on his desk in
Mr Dalloway's office.
Using the telephone at the lunchtime.
I said to him,
"They need an educated man like me."
They will not pass me over this time.
Shahana. Sit up.
If I just get the promotion confirmed
then many things are possible.
Don't cut the meat verv small.
I need big pieces tonight
for dinner with Dr Azad.
- Good luck with your promotion.
- It's from Auntie Hasina.
So, who has your sister
fallen in love with today?
Come on, Bibi, Shahana. Hurry
up. You can't be late for the school.
Do you tell your daughters
the story of the princess
who lived seven seas and 13 rivers away?
That is how I think of
you in your tall tower.
Now I cook for the lute men.
I tell them of my sister
living in London.
There is one I like.
His skin is like lassi.
I can see your worried face.
But there is no need.
When will you ever come home?
Tariq! Stop messing around
with the sewing machine.
Acha go Amma!
- Oh, hello, Razia.
- Hello.
How do you like living
the other side of the block?
I'll tell you when I've moved in.
How's your hip?
Oh. Verv painful.
Oh. Hello. Mrs Ahmed.
You two are going to be neighbours.
- Salaam-alaikum.
- Salaam.
She keeps herself to herself.
She has two daughters.
But she lost her first.
Such a boy.
The devil always takes beautiful babies.
Have you heard about Zorina?
Allah, place light in my heart,
light in my tongue.
Light in my hearing,
light on my right hand. On my left.
Light before me, light behind me,
light above me and light below me.
Allah, who knows
the secrets of our hearts.
Lead me out of the darkness
and give me light.
Your coat?
Is everything OK?
I resigned this afternoon.
They do not appreciate my talents.
But I'm not worried.
I have some verv good
leads I will chase...
in the morning.
You know. When I left the council office
Mr Dalloway shook my hand.
He was sorrv he was losing a good man.
We must be on our best
behaviour tonight.
"Ah. What thrill in
autumn. O mother mine.
In full-blossomed paddy fields I have
seen spread all over sweet smiles."
"Ah, what beauty, what shades,
what affection and what..."
Shahana.
You will take over from your sister now.
"What a guilt..."
"What a quilt you have spread
at the feet of banyan trees
and along the banks of rivers."
"O mother mine, words from your lips
are like nectar to my ears."
"Ah. What thrill is sadness."
"O mother mine.
Cast a gloom on your face.
My eyes fill up with tears."
A little more inflection next time.
But better.
- Salaam, Razia.
- Wa-alaikum-salaam.
- Got a lot for you this time.
- Good.
I need to make enough
to keep the kids happy.
Some of the women
are sewing at home. Even I...
Will you smarten me up a little?
Which do you think
is the happiest nation on earth.
Ranked number one
in the world's happiest survey?
- Bangladesh.
- I'm worried about my sister.
All along I've been telling her
we are coming home.
She has... she has met someone.
No. No. No. No.
My cousin is not going to go
and rescue her again.
If he could just visit her once...
Maybe I could go. I could go
and walk around the streets and say:
"Have you seen my wife's sister?"
"She cooks for the jute men."
I only have a job to find
and children to feed.
But what of our plans to go home?
I will work my contacts.
But you were so sure of the promotion.
They gave it to Wilkie.
- Wilkie got the promotion?
- Wilkie got the promotion.
People here are by and large ignorant
and know nothing of the Brontës
and Thackeray.
Can Wilkie guote from Chaucer?
No. He cannot.
Don't worry. I will have new employment
by the end of the week.
I will clear my office today.
Oh! I've got them.
Thank you.
- I'm Razia.
- Hello.
You want to have some tea?
I haven't unpacked yet. But... come.
Hm?
I just got it. 12 speeds.
£5.99 over 49 weeks.
My daughter did it. I was fed up
with all that brushing and brushing.
She wants to do hair
and beauty at college,
but I'm hoping universitv
if she works hard.
- Bye, Amma.
- Bye.
Love you.
Tariq. Always needing money
for his books.
However much you give,
they always need more.
What can you do?
You'll need a machine.
I'll send the boy over
once you've practised.
You can earn a pound a piece.
- Bibi.
- I can see you. Amma.
- I can see your feet.
- Let me measure your head.
Shahana!
Trv mine. Trv mine. Trv mine.
- How big is my head?
For a small brain. You have a big head.
Hello. Abba.
What is this?
I will take the television. Then.
It is a pound a piece.
I will take food in my room.
Chiswick Auction House,
West London.
Just down the road from where
the great painter Hogarth lived.
Sister, my husband says
a loss of pride is a terrible thing.
But pride won't buy us tickets home.
I have work now. Lust like you.
I sew, and every hem
brings me closer to you.
Huno Abba.
Ami aimune aicha... Aicha.
- Salaam-alaikum.
- Salaam.
Your husband in?
It's OK. I visit a lot of the women.
If it's OK with him...
This is a test batch.
Jeans. 42 pairs.
Yeah, Abba.
See you later.
My dad, always calling me
when I'm at work.
Parents are always worrving.
I'll pay you Thursday. OK?
- Thank you.
- Don't thank me. It's a chore. Man.
- Salaam-alaikum.
- My mum had a sari like that.
Wa-alaikum-salaam.
- What is it, Abba?
This is a birthday
present for your mother.
- Her birthday's ages away.
- I'm also thinking about the home fund.
Wait. Bibi!
There are some uneducated types
who believe if the wife is working.
It is because the man
cannot put the food on the table.
Lucky your mother
married an educated man.
So you have found new employment?
I've been told by a reliable source
that they are in much need of lecturers
at Dhaka Universitv.
To teach sociology, for example,
or philosophy.
From today, we are joining
the world wide web.
I will email them straightaway.
But...
where did the money come from?
Can I open this one for you. Abba?
One has to speculate to accumulate.
What shall we start with?
I can access the entire world.
Too boring for the memsahib?
What is the wrong with you?
You mean."What is wrong with you?"
OK.
From now on. No one speaks English.
- You said that last time.
Your behaviour is getting bad to worse!
This is what they teach you
at the school?
This is what they teach you? !
I will not allow this to happen!
To learn manners
and to respect her father!
I didn't ask to be born here!
Go home. You fucking Pakis!
Salaam-alaikum.
Sorrv about this.
- What happened?
- I know who they are.
The Lion Hearts. They've gone.
I took it right from
under their nose. Man.
"Multicultural murder. Do you know
Britain is being slowly suffocated?"
"Muslim extremists taking
over our streets."
- Who does all this?
- Idiots.
You're thirstv.
This is nice work.
There's a pair missing.
42. There should be 42.
No.
It's probably my mistake.
- Father?
- My dad.
25 years as a bus conductor,
now he doesn't leave the flat.
Just ringing me all the time.
Every day the same.
And your mother?
Died five years ago.
"Don't make trouble for yourself."
That's all my dad ever says to me.
It's too many years
getting called all the names.
Kids giving him cheek,
men giving him aggro.
He never made trouble
for anyone his whole life.
Tsk!
He thinks he's Mahatma Gandhi.
He thinks he's Jesus Christ.
Always saying to me,
"Turn the other cheek."
That's what you get. Man.
Yes. It's what you get.
- A lot of books.
- My husband.
I'm reading a very interesting book
at the moment.
According to Hume, all objects of human
inguirv may be divided into two kinds.
That is relation of ideas
and matters of fact.
To explain the meaning
of relation of idea,
Hume gives an example.
That the three times of five
is egual to half of 30.
Are you resting?
This one is nice.
I can say that it is
nice or not nice, and...
how can I be wrong. According to Hume?
The search for knowledge -
is there anything more satisfying?
The foundation of modern philosophy -
it is a verv interesting module.
Hume also says that the sun...
Praise be to Allah.
So much to thank him for.
I have news.
I have accepted a
proposal from Mr Lassi,
with his skin so white...
- Shahana.
- "Sister. We are married."
"People stop and stare because
he is Mr Lassi and I am now his wife."
Give it back. Shahana!
Shahana. Give... Shahana!
"I enjoy their stares,
walking arm in arm together."
"I am in love, sister.
I am in love!"
What is this?
- I was just trying them on.
- Shahana. Off! Off. I said.
- Shahana! Give it back.
- That's romantic. Man.
What's Auntie like?
Is she like me?
As pretty as you and as naughtv as you.
At least her life is exciting.
At least it's not boring.
- The test of life is to endure.
I know. Amma. You tell me all the time.
And so did my Amma.
- Please! Ple...
- Shh! Bibi's sleeping.
- Please. Please.
- No. No.
Give it to me.
"Walking arm in arm."
"I am in love. Sister."
"I am so in love."
I thought I knew love before,
but it was not like this.
He's always watching me,
never letting me out of his sight.
Like I might vanish.
This time. I am sure it is right.
Thank you.
Talk to me.
This won't sew itself.
You talk. I will listen.
So many kids, man,
smoking shit. Doing nothing.
Do you only go out with your husband?
I go out when I need to shop.
How long have you been living here?
16 years.
My mum came over when she was 17.
- Me too.
- For real?
You look younger.
You know. When I was young.
If you wanted to be cool,
you had to be something else.
A bit white. A bit
black. A bit something.
Anything but Bangladeshi.
What?
You always stammer
when you talk Bengali.
Only when I'm nervous.
There's gonna be meetings every week.
You should come.
Bring your husband.
- Salaam-alaikum.
- Wa-alaikum-salaam.
Salaam-alaikum.
Thursday.
Your girls haven't been seen
at the madrasah.
I will speak with my husband.
Never mind.
Place the money in the side pocket.
I won't count it.
£50 as arranged.
Your husband owes me.
I see how it is.
He hasn't talked to you.
I will collect every week £50.
It is simply an arrangement
between friends.
Pay when you can.
You will find a way.
Allah always gives a way.
Ah. What a boy.
Too beautiful.
Hello?
Anyone home?
I hear her sons wanted
to buy her a hip replacement.
"No. No. No. No. No."
"Don't waste a good hip on me."
"I don't want to be buried
with a new hip."
"God does not love a wasteful woman."
My husband's borrowed money from her.
How much she charge you?
I don't know.
How much does a computer cost?
Certificates from everywhere.
But your husband's a bloody fool.
I know one family,
they've been paying six. Seven years.
Whatever you pay,
she'll say you owe more.
You'll never get rid of the debt.
She's got a system
inherited from her husband.
That's how usurers work.
- She's a usurer?
- Mm.
You take care.
Zips and seams to finish.
All right.
I suggest we call ourselves
United Muslim Action.
Let's get our own
neighbourhood straight.
Show that Banglatown is defended.
You ask what about Chechnya?
What about Palestine?
Well. I say what about here?
This community has been taking shit
from people like the Lion Hearts.
What about your children?
Who's gonna fight for them?
If we can't change things. Who can?
I suggest we call
ourselves Bengal Tigers.
I say let's vote
and get Banglatown represented.
Secretarv. Let's take a vote.
- OK. Muslim Action?
- United Muslim Action.
Bengal Tigers?
Bengal Tigers is duly elected.
I should go.
Thursday?
Mm.
As you are all aware,
your mother and I have decided
that we as a family will return home.
Your mother is doing everything
she can do to facilitate this trip.
But today I have also become
the employee of Kempton Cars.
Driver 1619.
So the home fund will prosper.
Memsahib! Prepare!
# Jodi tor dak shuney
kew na ashey tobey
What's that. Abba?
Massage car seat cover.
Verv good for back.
For relief of tension
and unknotting of muscles.
All I have ever seen in this countrv
is the Houses of Parliament.
That was in 1979.
So many years of struggling.
I barely had time to lift my head
and look around.
Oh, no, Alec, not here.
Someone will see.
I love you so.
We must do some visiting.
Sightseeing.
Look how much these English
pay for their kameez.
It is giving you ideas.
This is too bright.
And a rip-off.
OK, I will leave you.
See you later.
Bye.
There's something I wanna show you.
Where are you taking me?
This is my uncle's factorv.
Just closing up right now.
Sister, there is
something I must tell you.
If you were here I would spend
so much time talking to you.
Something is happening.
I know it is foolish
but I cannot help it.
I tell myself."Be careful. Be careful."
Children. Are you enioying yourself?
You see? When you have all the time
in the world to see something.
You don't bother to see it.
Now that we are going home,
I have become a tourist.
It is so ironic.
"Buckingham Palace has been
the official residency
of British sovereigns since 1837."
- Do you have the
cream? I'm going black.
Shh. Your father is speaking.
- If he ever stops, let me know.
- Shahana!
Look, Shahana.
Look at this beautiful building.
If you have historv. You have pride.
People here know nothing
of our national heroes like... er...
Like Colonel Osmani and also
Shah Jalal. Both from Sylhet.
I know. I know who they are.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
- Can you take a picture for me?
- Sure.
Turn. Turn. Turn.
- Where are you from?
- Bangladesh.
- What's he got to fiddle around for?
- I will buy you the earrings.
The really long ones?
Down to your knees.
Now. Smile. Smile.
OK. Ready.
Amma. Stop.
Are you feeling well?
Too much excitement. Perhaps.
See how happy your mother is
now we are going home.
Sister, there is
something I have to tell you.
I am...
I am in...
Hasina. My husband thanks you.
The pudina for his
ulcer is working well.
I am praying for you
and your new husband every day.
My sister.
She ran off with one of the men
who worked for my father.
He never forgave her.
They stole his bicycle.
My boy.
He was my first.
I found him in his cot.
He stopped breathing.
We don't talk about it any more.
He is beautiful.
Yes.
The devil only takes beautiful babies.
What?
Why do you like me?
Who says I like you?
There's two tvpes. Right?
Your westernised girl,
into going out. Having a laugh.
Short skirts as soon
as she's out of her father's sight.
Then your religious girl.
You think they'd be good wife material
but they ain't,
cos all they wanna do is argue.
So what about me?
You...
you're the real thing.
A girl from the village.
Don't you ever want to go home?
This is my home.
What's going on?
The world has gone mad.
The search is under way
for those behind these evil acts.
It will be just like when
I first arrived. There
will be a backlash.
There has been enough planning.
Start packing.
- We will be in Dhaka within the month.
- What?
No more pop CDs.
All money goes to the home fund.
- Ow!
- And cover your legs.
Take more sewing.
We need more money.
- I will speak to him.
- No!
Who?
Who you do not wish me to speak to?
No-no... no one.
I'll do it.
- Do what?
- Speak... speak to him.
Verv well.
You tell him...
you want paying extra 50°%
if we are ever to get home.
...carried out these attacks.
There are no adequate
words of condemnation.
Their barbarism will stand
as their shame for all eternity.
Community meeting.
Come along. Brother.
Shahana. Bibi.
Come on. Girls.
Go! Go! You fucking terrorists!
Get out!
Go back to your own country,
you bin Ladens! Go on. Fuck off!
This has been a year
of racial tension...
in Britain. With race
riots in the north.
The fear is now
that this tension will increase.
Many claim that in the last seven days,
"Muslim" has become a dirty word.
Broken windows at a mosque -
a consequence of these misconceptions.
People say to us, "You
shouldn't be here. Why are you here?"
"Go away."
It's getting crazy out there.
My dad's really scared now.
Some white boy goes and pulls my
cousin's hiiab down in the street today.
He was only about ten.
I'm telling you, man,
things are changing.
The way people look at you now
on the streets - so much mistrust.
I wanna say, "If I was
a bomber, do you...
think I'd be carrving
50 pairs of ieans?"
- Stop.
- What?
Salaam-alaikum.
Wa-alaikum-salaam.
- Is it interesting?
- I was just browsing.
You don't mind?
Why should I mind?
When I was a young man like you.
Do you know what I wanted to be?
A British civil servant, right-hand
bloody man of the prime minister.
And I saw no reason why not.
Anything is possible when you are young.
Then you get older.
And the thing about getting older is...
that you don't need everything
to be possible any more.
You just need some things to be certain.
- Abba.
- Mm.
If you left me and Bibi behind,
you wouldn't have to save as much.
And we could be adopted.
Do you want me to beat you?
Yes.
Well. I won't beat you
and I won't leave you behind.
One day, Abba, I'll run
and you won't ever catch me.
Shahana!
Why did Allah curse me with daughters? !
Do you think your cheek
will serve you well in the world?
Can you imagine the things
I have had to fight?
Do you know what you're going to have
to face out there every day?
Every day.
Shahana.
Do you think I'm like this
for the good of my health?
No. Abba.
Good.
I am glad
we have talked
father and daughter like this.
Sister...
I have an unquiet mind.
And it is so long
since I have heard from you.
It was still on the mat.
You must have been busy.
You think she's enioying married life?
My cousin says she has left her husband.
He has seen her working the hotels.
It is where all the...
floating girls go.
You think she lived off cooking
all these years?
All these years, all these letters,
hearing what your sister had to say.
Give me my letter!
Maybe I should have been asking
what you are writing to her.
Give it to me. Give it
to me! I said give!
Give me my letter! Give! Give!
You are no different to your sister!
Sister. Mr Lassi has gone.
Hussain from the factory
has been very kind to me.
He brings me a little food.
Haven't I always known
how to take care of myself?
We all survive in different ways.
Last night was so funny.
I sang for Rehan.
He makes me sit on the bed
like when he first saw me.
Mr Chowdhury is like a father to me.
He treats me very well.
They tease me,
but I know they're only loking.
- Ahmed likes to bring me to his house.
- Are you all right?
I do not tell him I'm a married woman.
I have never been good at staying still.
Abba went with other women.
Mr Chowdhury says
these boys are like moths to a flame.
I won't be like Amma.
She took the forbidden path.
She did not endure. So why should we?
Amma. Amma. She's sleeping.
She wakes.
Will you have some food now?
Just a little rice.
Rice it is.
Dr Azad said the illness
will leave you hungrv.
... of the US-led bombardment.
The rally was told another malor...
I started to pack.
Oh. Wait.
How?
Where there is a will.
There is always a way.
What should I take -
Thackeray or the Proust?
I will take both.
You rest now.
Now, where are my certificates?
Do you know what Gandhi said
when asked what he thought
about Western civilisation?
He said he thought
it would be a good idea.
When do you go?
The tickets are booked in three weeks.
So. Have you seen him?
- Karim?
- No.
Did he visit while I was ill?
Haven't seen him for days.
Someone said he's away.
Don't make trouble for yourself.
I already have.
- It looks like you are doing well.
- Mm.
I'll need people to sew.
Salaam-alaikum.
You are angrv with me.
No.
I've been away.
Visiting family in Bradford.
If I'd known you was ill...
I can see you're angrv with me.
Why do you not believe me when
I tell you that I'm not angrv with you?
I turned down a girl last week for you.
My dad keeps asking me why.
What can I do?
You could stay. He could go.
Let him divorce you.
We'll get married.
I'll sort it.
And then what?
Amma.
Good night.
Are you in love with him?
I mean, have you ever been
in love with him?
Maybe before he got fat?
We don't have to go, Amma.
You don't have to go.
We shall wait and see.
That's no answer.
It is my answer. Good night.
Sister,
may Allah take care of you.
I'm sending you a little more money
to help keep you safe.
How long have we been talking?
How long have I not been hearing
what you say?
I too have secrets.
Now is the time for truth.
I feel as if I'm waking from a dream.
The world is changing.
And me with it.
We are coming home.
How can we stay?
Amma.
Bibi, look at that!
Mrs Ahmed!
I know you have been ill.
Just give me what you owe.
How would it look if I let you off?
Let one slip. They all slip through.
Your husband is trying to run away,
but I won't let him.
He comes asking for more and I tell him,
"Pay what you owe."
- Shahana.
- What?
Who are they?
Her friends from school.
Ugh.
Ugh!
Bibi!
In Bangladesh you have to brush
your teeth with a twig.
And go toilet in a bucket.
Auntie Hasina goes to the toilet
in a bucket next to a goat.
- Shahana!
- It's true.
Less talking. More brushing.
It's true.
Well. Do you even want to go?
You don't.
What Mrs Islam says...
Is this true?
This is a good guestion.
When you feel something so strongly.
You have to ask yourself."Is this true?"
I still have my coat on.
Isn't it fair to say that you hate it
when I come inside
and forget to take it off?
I'm not totally blind.
Don't worrv.
A little business
venture I have in mind.
I'm gathering together samples.
Soap is the future.
I think we should go to this meeting.
In fact. I have prepared a short speech.
Will you come?
Our fathers are being spat at,
our young brothers stopped and searched
again and again by
our so-called police force.
Our sisters. They've been abused
when they walk their little children
in the streets.
Banglatown needs defending.
Karim has a list of estates. We need...
volunteers to wipe out
this kind of filth.
- Brother.
- Thanks. Bruv.
Out there are people
twisted with hatred for us and Islam.
We're gonna show them
how wrong they are.
Yeah!
We've become victims,
but not for long!
Yeah!
We stand arm in arm with
our Muslim brothers ready to defend.
Yeah!
What is it you plan to defend?
What is it you are planning to defend?
Islam, brother!
No, no, no, no, no, no. Let the brother
speak. Let the brother speak.
- You think Islam unites us all?
- Yes.
You think Islam
is the place you come from?
Islam is not a country.
You think you are my brother
more than the next man on the street
because we are both Muslims?
All this fighting talk
that we are all brothers.
Three million! Three million died
in East Pakistan in this lifetime.
Not in my lifetime. Uncle.
In your parents' lifetime.
What was that?
Brotherly love?
It was Muslim killing a Muslim.
Have you forgotten?
Are you so lost?
My Islam is in here.
And that is the only
thing worth defending.
- Right.
- Hear. Hear.
We plan to defend against hatred.
We all stand together. Brothers.
All right. All right. Moving on.
Our brother Karim has got the list
of all the local estates.
Everyone in here
has been allocated an area...
It is the time to go home.
- Salaam-alaikum.
- Wa-alaikum-salaam.
I've only got ten minutes.
I've talked to some of
the other brothers.
It's not looking good.
I cannot marrv you.
- Well, yeah, not straightaway, but...
- No. Um...
I do not want to marrv you.
Come on. Come.
Look at me.
Say it again.
Look at me and say it.
I do not want to marrv you. Karim.
Right.
Right. Right.
You don't wanna marrv me?
- Is it the sin of it? Is that it?
- No. No.
Karim. That we have already done.
I...
I am not the real thing.
I'm no longer a girl from the village.
- Yes, you are.
- No.
You just wanted me to be.
We just made each other up.
Well. What did you want?
I just wanted to feel
like I was at home.
Karim.
You better pray like hell.
That's what I'm gonna do.
Allah forgives.
Salaam-alaikum.
Wa-alaikum-salaam.
Hello?
Mrs Ahmed?
Just give me what you owe.
I need my money.
From the goodness of my heart. I give.
And when those who receive
don't want to pay back what they owe.
They run off to foreign countries
and say."Why should we pay her?"
- "She's just an old, sick woman."
- How much do you want?
- £200 to settle the debt.
- No.
We paid it all and some more as well.
The money's for the madrasah.
But what is that to you?
- £200 and settle it.
- But we paid what we owed!
We paid at least £300 on top of that!
I'm not going to pay any more interest!
Do you think before God
I will charge interest?
- Am I a money lender?
- No?
Just swear on Koran that you're not...
and I'll pay you the
200. Just swear on it!
There are certain things a wife
does not want her husband to know.
My husband knows everything.
Just swear on the Koran.
That is all you have to do.
Swear on it.
Allah sees all your wrongs.
Anyway. You have paid too much.
- And he sees yours too.
- Huh!
- We will store these boxes.
- OK. Mr Ahmed.
The rest is for the auction. Thank you.
A colleague from Kempton Cars
will collect us.
He is more or less an ignorant type
but a good-hearted man -
as they say. Salt of the earth.
I will marry the memsahib
to the first fakir I can find.
The first thing I do
when we step off the plane.
What is so funny. Memsahib?
- You are.
- Shahana!
You are. With your stupid phrases.
You're always encouraging us to fit in.
It worked. We do fit in.
You're the one
who's stuck somewhere. Abba.
Tell him.
Tell him you don't want to go.
What? He takes away my son
and curses me with daughters?
- Be careful what you say, memsahib.
We're not the ones lost. Abba. You are!
She's been married to you
for nearly 20 years.
And in all my life, Amma, I have
never heard you say what you want.
Please. Amma. Tell him.
Tell him, Amma.
Please. For once. Please. Tell him.
Please. Amma.
Tell him you don't want to go!
Just tell him you don't want to go!
Tell him!
Please!
Please. Amma.
You're pathetic!
Bangladesh is gone.
It's another time.
Amma.
She will be back.
Shahana!
Shahana! Shahana!
Shahana. Stop.
I don't wanna go.
Amma is here.
Don't worrv.
Shahana is asleep now.
She is bound to be nervous.
She will settle later.
- I know it is almost time...
- I know. I know how exciting it is.
I have checked our passports
and tickets for the last time.
- But I wanted...
- Let us look forward now.
Just imagine a house in Dhaka,
holiday in Cox's Bazar.
A little trip for the
girls to Shundar Bon.
They could see a real Bengal tiger.
I should have said this before. I...
You see. All these years...
I dreamed of going home a big man.
Only now.
When it is finished for me...
I realised what is important.
As long as I have my family with me
I'm strong as any man alive.
What is all this "strong man" about?
Do you think that is why I love you?
You're coming home.
This is my home.
I cannot leave.
I cannot stay.
Then you must take the plane.
Allah has taken our son
but he blessed us with daughters.
We will always be here.
No one told me
there are different kinds of love.
The kind that starts big
and slowly wears away.
That seems you'll never use it up
and then one day it is finished.
Then there is the kind
that you do not notice at first.
But which adds a little bit
to itself every day.
Like an oyster makes a pearl
grain by grain.
A lewel from the sand.
That is the kind I have come to know.
Sister. Thank you for your letter.
For all your letters.
There has been a change of plan.
I have suggested.
And your mother has agreed.
That the three of you come later.
But who will cook for you. Abba?
Who will cut your corns?
Don't you know?
I'm a better cook than your mother.
Be good girls.
Do as your mother tells you.
And do not think there is anything
you are not good enough for.
Remember.
Abba.
- How will we manage without you?
- Your mother is in charge.
I think you should be fine.
Everyone thought I married
a simple girl from the village.
But...
That should do for now.
- I'm sorry.
- Never be sorrv.
When I was born,
the midwife said:
"Dress her for her burial.
This scrap is too weak to feed."
"Take her to the hospital if you must."
"No." said my Amma.
"My child must not
fight against her fate."
"That way. She will be stronger."
Shahana. Amma. Iook.
And so I lived.
Sister.
I have this dream
that you are always running...
and I am torn between two worlds,
leaving you behind.
But then I wake
and see that it is not you
but me who has been running.
Searching for a place
that has already been found.