You guys? Sorry.
Um, I just want to
take a second
to thank everybody for
coming out tonight
to help us celebrate
our fifth wedding
anniversary.
It's not often that,
um, you meet the girl
of your dreams,
much less get a chance
to marry her.
Guests: Aw.
Marriage these days,
um, is-is-
as most of you know,
is not any easy thing
to get right.
It takes love and humor
and attraction
and a real willingness
to really, really
let yourself
be seen by someone.
I know people who have
searched their
whole lives
for what we have,
and I'm just glad
to have it with you.
I love you, Audrey.
Guests: oh. aw.
Happy anniversary.
Oh, and wait. Sorry.
I want to also thank
our good friend
Nora Wilder,
who introduced us,
and without her there
wouldn't be an 'us. '
May there be many years
of celebration.
Cheers, everybody.
Guests: cheers.
When are you gonna give
us some grandchildren?
Hi.
Oh, hi, baby.
Hi, mom.
You look lovely.
Oh, thank you.
So do you.
Give me a hug.
Hi, Irving.
- Hi.
How are you?
I'm gonna get you a drink.
You want one?
Uh, champagne.
3 coming up.
Thank you.
Oh, I didn't mean
to embarrass you.
Mom: I wish you would have
married Mark.
Oh, mom.
He was always so
crazy about you.
You know that.
It would have been perfect.
Good family and friends.
He's so handsome,
and he's successful
he has a terrific trust fund.
Audrey's never gonna have
to work again in her life
if she doesn't feel like it.
You know, I don't know
why they haven't
started a family yet, though.
It's really odd.
You should never have
introduced them.
Audrey's my best friend.
Mark's my friend.
They're really happy together.
You know I love Audrey.
She's practically part
of the family.
I'm only saying that, you know,
she knew a good thing
when she saw it.
The good ones get snapped
up so quickly
at your age.
Good afternoon.
Guest relations.
This is Nora.
Oh, hi, Mr. Harris.
How are you?
I'm good, thanks.
How can I help you?
6 people at 8:00
tonight at Nouveau
might be a little tricky.
Is there a backup you'd like?
No? Well, let me try to work
some of my magic,
and I'll call you back
with an answer.
You're welcome. Bye.
Your job is so weird.
No kidding.
Knock, knock, knock.
Hey, Glen. What's up?
You weren't answering
your phone,
and Mr. Gable is checking in,
and he's not happy
with his room,
and he's being really
high-maintenance
about it,
and I don't know what
to do with him.
I'll take care of it.
Oh, hey, Audrey.
Sorry. I could try another name.
Try Kurt Vonnegut.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing.
Well, what other name could
I have checked in under?
Try Walt Whitman.
It's not in here.
Mr. Gable?
I'm Nora Wilder,
manager of guest relations and
special services.
Is there a problem?
Yeah, there is a problem.
I usually get a room on
the fifth floor.
My assistant or my manager
or someone screwed up,
and now it's apparently not there,
and it's got, like,
arched windows,
wood floors.
Do you know what
I'm talking about?
Yeah. I thought there
might have been
some mix-up.
The room you usually stay
in is occupied
right now,
but I can show you something on
the seventh floor
that's very similar.
All right.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
Great.
I don't want to seem like
a pain in the ass
or anything, but...
No. It's not a big deal.
Yeah, well, he's making
me feel like a nazi.
Yeah. We'll take care
of it right now.
Anyway...
I hope this is good for you.
Yeah. Ok. This is good.
It's cool.
It's better light.
This one I can have?
Yeah.
- Good.
Great. Life is so much better.
I'll just get someone to
bring up your bags.
Oh, that'd be Rad.
Hey, thank you for
being so sweet.
No problem.
What do you do here?
You just deal with professional
complainers like me?
I deal with V.I.P.s
and their needs
and wants.
So I'm a V.I.P.
Of course you are.
So if I need anything,
I can just ask you?
You can ask at the front desk
or the concierge,
but I'm in charge of
all that stuff.
How come I've never seen
you here before?
I've taken care of
things for you
in the past.
You just didn't know because
there's never
been a problem.
Oh. Thanks.
Sure.
Oh, shit.
What?
Can I ask you for
one little favor?
Sure.
Will you go to dinner with me?
Uh...
Or do they not let you
do that here?
Sure. I guess so.
Great.
How about tomorrow night?
Yeah.
Sweet.
I'll just call down
and get someone
to bring up your bags.
Ok.
Good afternoon.
Front desk.
This is Glen.
Hey, Glen.
Could you bring up Mr.
Gable's bags, please?
Woman on tv: Take
a big breath in
and exhale a big sigh.
Women on tv: Ahh.
Did you have a good
time the other night?
I guess. Mark did.
The whole Andrews family did.
I'm so stupid.
I think I'm having
a personal crisis.
Woman on tv:... as you exhale,
begin to bend the knees.
A little bit of space
between your hands and thumb.
I haven't slept without a drink
or sleeping pill
since I can remember.
Join the club.
No, really.
I think my marriage
is falling apart.
You don't think it's just p. m.s.?
No. He's driving me nuts.
All he cares about is recognition
and going to parties
and winning awards,
instead of just doing it because
it makes him happy.
I mean, we used to laugh
about that stuff.
I'm sorry.
It's just so depressing.
What's going on with you?
I got asked out on a date.
You did? By who?
This guy-Nick Gable,
that actor.
He's the hitman.
He's in the hitman.
That Mr. Gable?
You're going out with
a hotel guest.
Are you allowed to
date hotel guests?
I don't know.
Do you think that's creepy?
Just don't sleep with him
on the first date.
Oh, no.
That would be so available.
I don't think it's like that.
Arigato.
Do you live in L.A.?
Yeah. I hate it.
Oh.
It's awful.
I mean, it's cool once you find
your little coffee spots,
Blah blah blah.
Anyway, I'm gonna be
here for, like,
forever.
What are you working on?
I am working on a movie called
Rain Dancer,
where I play a medicine man,
Anwahatu,
who's a member of the choctaw
tribe.
There's actually a whole tribe of
medicine men
that used to basically
travel around
sort of poisoning
the European settlers.
Oh, my god.
Yeah, I know.
He's kind of a villain, I guess.
Do you like playing bad guys?
Yeah. You know,
it would be nice
to take a shot for leading man
every now and again.
Mm-hmm.
Don't want to get pigeonholed.
I mean, I'm grateful for working.
That's so cool.
Thanks.
How about you?
Are you interested
in the hotel biz?
Yeah. Uh, I've been
working at the hotel
for about 6 years,
since it opened.
Oh, my god. 6 years.
That's, like,
forever.
It's awesome.
So is there, like,
a hotel school
for that
or something?
No. um, I went to Sarah Lawrence.
Oh. Sarah Lawrence.
I got a liberal arts degree,
and I was an arts major there.
I thought I'd do something
in the art world.
So now you do just hotel stuff,
which is cool.
Yeah.
- Yeah.
I mean, you can't just say you're
gonna be an actor.
You know, you've got to, like,
really dedicate yourself to it.
You've got to, like,
go to school for it.
You can't just walk in and do it.
You got to study,
you know?
I studied for...
6 months.
I did, like,
this intensive thing
on 'Melrose Place'
where you just,
from 10:00 to 3:00
every day,
you're in there just
doing monologues
and doing scenes from tv shows,
and it's unbelievable.
It's hard work.
Yeah. Of course,
I think I'm gonna
just walk
into some casting
director's office
when I graduate
and, you know,
just get some big
huge role
and become a big star.
Oh, definitely.
I know what you mean.
Hey, when I was much younger,
I thought that I would be married,
I'd have kids, you know,
by the time I was 30
and I'd have the exact
career that I wanted.
I still don't know what
I want to be
when I grow up.
I'm so glad I met you.
Me, too.
No, I'm serious.
I think you're
totally refreshing.
Yeah.
What do you say,
we get out of here?
You know what...
says about...?
that 3 are too many and
one is not enough.
Who says that?
Hefner. Hugh Hefner.
The guy should talk.
He's only got 19 girlfriends.
Do you know how pretty you are?
Thank you. I think that
you're really cute
and that you're a really good actor
and that you're gonna
be really successful.
I think so, too,
about you.
I'm sorry.
Why? Why?
I should have asked you if I
should kiss you.
Oh, don't worry
about it.
I'm the special services director,
and I want you to know
that I don't just
go around kissing guests.
Do you know you are a V.I.P.?
Thank you.
Mmm.
Fuck.
Look who's here-Nora.
Oh, my goodness.
Hey, darling.
Come on in.
You remember Eleanor, don't you?
Nora.
Of course.
How are you?
Sit down, Nora.
I'll get you
a drink.
We've just been bragging
about your glamorous life.
You remember Bill,
don't you?
Hello, Nora.
It's good to see you.
You, too. You, too.
So is it just exciting,
running that little
chic hotel of yours?
Well, I don't actually run it, but-
Mom: Oh, sure, she does.
She does everything over there.
She plans all their parties,
all of the special events.
They're a pretty spoiled group.
That's my job.
Nora.
Do you have someone special?
Well, uh, actually,
I have started
to see someone.
He's, um-he's an actor.
Anyone we know?
His name is Nick Gable.
He's in The Hitman.
Oh, we just saw that last week.
It was terrific.
I loved that movie.
Really? - Yeah.
He's the hitman.
Well, that's wonderful.
Well, why don't you
invite him over?
We would just love to meet him.
You know, we could
have maybe a little
dinner party.
That would be great.
Let's have a toast to celebrate
Nora having a new boyfriend.
Hey-Nick and Nora.
Oh, you're dating yourself.
A little bit.
Who's that?
I don't know.
Lisa someone.
Some tv actress.
She scares me.
She's so tacky.
Look at those lips.
It's the only part of her face
that can move.
What an idiot.
You two are the most
judgmental people
in the world.
Who watches these stupid
entertainment shows?
It's better than watching the news.
Propaganda nightmare.
Oh, look. Turn it up.
Oh.
People wonder what's inside the mind
of a hitman.
You know,
these guys are sick,
sick guys.
You know, as a result, they spend
a lot of time alone,
so most of my scenes were shot virtually
by myself, you know.
I think I'm gonna be ok, though.
Ooh.
Woman on tv: Don't feel too sorry
for this guy.
He's been dating his sexyhitmancostar
Serena Hill.
Serena. Oh, god.
Oh, Serena-she's a great woman.
She's totally refreshing,
and, uh, I'm crazy about her.
What else can I say?
That's probably all I should say,
you know what I'm saying?
What is wrong with me?
Why can't I meet someone nice?
There's nothing wrong with you,
Nora.
You just go out with the wrong
people.
Stop dating actors.
They're crazy.
No, that's actresses.
I shouldn't go out with anyone anymore.
I'm going home.
Hey, don't feel bad.
That guy's a jerk.
I love you.
Me, too.
Ok, I'll call you.
Ok.
Oh, god.
Poor Nora.
She has the worst
time with men.
You know,
I love Nora,
but she has no insight when it
comes to men.
She doesn't understand the hunt.
Men like a challenge.
Like a bitch,
like me?
Kinda.
You think I'm a bitch?
Come on, baby.
Don't fight me
all the time.
I think you're great.
I worship you.
I put you on a pedestal.
Like an object.
Shut up.
Honey, do you feel all right?
You look pale.
I'm ok.
You don't think you should see
the doctor?
No. No. I'm fine.
Really.
Thank you, though.
I've just been working too hard
and just drinking too much, smoking
too much.
You know what I heard about your liver?
You should not have anything to drink
two days a week.
They don't have to be consecutive.
and of course you know smoking is suicide.
Mm-hmm.
How are things with your boyfriend?
Oh, it's over.
Oh, is that why you're depressed?
No, that's not it.
I just feel like I have the worst
luck in the world
when it comes to men.
I think I must be doing something
horribly wrong,
but I don't know what it is.
What happened?
Oh, he has a girlfriend.
Oh.
You know, I can't quit thinking about
how hard it must be for young women nowadays.
I mean, on the one hand,
the world is wide open
to you.
All the choices you want.
I think there are too many choices, really.
It just must be very confusing
to try to find a path through all of that,
especially with men,
though you have had some very nice boyfriends.
I know...
but that was college.
I don't know what happened.
I feel so closed off,
so desperate to find someone to love.
Oh, honey.
Even I can't stand the sight of
my own desperation.
Honey, hey,
you know what?
You're in a funk,
that's all,
and there's only one way to get
out of a funk,
and that is to engage.
Even if you don't feel like it,
just fake it.
Just go out and get the highest heels in town
and some new lipstick and go everyplace.
Smile. Act like you're having the time
of your life.
But don't always go with married couples.
You're never gonna meet anyone that way.
Sure. I'll give it a try, you know.
You know...
I could fix you up.
No.
Now, just listen to me for a minute.
You know Megan Ross,
my friend.
She has a son.
I don't think you've
ever met him.
Nice-looking,
successful,
and I know he's not seeing anyone
right now.
Are you Nora?
Yes.
I'm Charlie Ross.
Hi.
- Hi.
Nice to meet you.
- You, too.
It's pretty funny that our moms
set us up.
You don't know the irony behind it.
I'm glad.
Me, too.
I haven't seen this movie in a really
long time.
It's one of my favorite films.
Yeah? No, I love this film, too.
I've never seen it in a theater, though.
Really?
- Yeah.
Uh, should we go in and get seats?
Yeah.
Yesterday,
about 3 p. m.
I wanted you to think about it twice, too.
I've been looking for someone for
a long time.
I love that movie.
It really holds up.
Bogart reminds me of my dad.
I met your dad once.
He seemed like a great guy.
I'm sorry about him.
Yeah, me, too.
I really miss him.
I feel lucky to have had him at all, really.
Now my mom has Irving,
so she's not alone.
Yeah. My mom doesn't really date anyone
anymore.
She went through a string of them
after my parents divorced,
but she always drives them away,
on purpose, I think.
I wonder if we always turn into our parents.
I like to think of it as where my
parents left off.
That's a great way of putting it.
Oh, shit.
What?
Uh, nothing.
It's just my ex,
Jennifer.
She's totally crazy.
Is it gonna be ok?
Hi, Jennifer.
Hello, Charlie.
How are you?
This is Nora.
'How are you?' How am I?
I'm fucking great, Charlie.
How are you?
And Nora?
We're good.
We just went to the movies.
He took you to see an old romantic movie.
It's his signature move, you know.
My mom was-
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Will you excuse me for one second?
I'm sorry.
Charlie: Why are you doing this?
Jennifer: What are you doing here?
What do you mean-
I just talked to you this morning.
You said you weren't dating anybody.
Charlie: I'm not dating anybody.
She's the daughter of my mom's friend.
I think I brought her here because I...
I was missing you,
and this reminded me
of our first date.
Don't touch me.
Hey, we're leaving.
Are you ok?
Look, I'm so sorry you had to see that.
What happened?
We haven't been broken up that long.
It's-it's been really hard.
You're actually the first person I've
dated since Jennifer.
I think I'm still in love with her.
I'm-I'm so sorry.
This was-it was
too soon.
Um, you know, I think I'm just gonna go.
I'm just so, you know,
out of it.
Is it ok if I just put you in a cab?
Yeah.
I'm really sorry.
You're so nice.
Men hate me.
You hate yourself.
No, I don't.
Why do you say that?
You've got to stop punishing yourself
all the time
for not having a boyfriend.
Everyone else is in a relationship.
Why can't I be in one?
You'll meet someone.
Just don't go nuts
next time.
It's like the only thing that matters
is finding this guy.
It doesn't even matter who it is.
Not every guy you meet has to be your
future husband.
Believe me.
Do something else.
Go to yoga or something.
You're right.
I'm being a total
freak.
I have to calm down.
I love you.
I don't like to
see you like this.
Oh, god. One minute.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Ok.
It's Mark. He'll be here in two minutes.
Where was he?
Mmm. Having a meeting with
that actress Caitlin Fox.
Oh, no.
Yeah. She wants him to direct her
in a movie about fairies.
Barf.
I know.
I don't want to sound like a broken record.
I just feel like we're not best friends
anymore.
Do you talk about it?
Yeah, we have been.
He thinks everything is fine and that I'm
just freaking out.
I swear, if he blames it on my hormones
one more time,
I'm gonna lose it.
He's the one who's hesitant about having kids.
Really?
I didn't know that.
Yeah, whatever.
I don't want to
talk about it.
Let's just drop it.
But I can't believe you're not coming
to Miami with us.
Please come.
Mark will pay.
I just don't feel like it.
I just want to stay here.
Ladies. I'm doing the fairy movie.
Woman on tv: I'm Jill Scott.
Hamburgers and hot dogs are a standard for
july fourth weekend,
but if you're looking to
spice up your holiday...
Joining me now with some new ideas of things
you can cook on the grill
is Anita Lowe from Anita's
restaurant.
Hi, Anita. How are you?
Answering machine:
Hi, it's Nora. Leave a message
Hey, Nora, it's Glen from work,
and I got my party saturday night,
and I want to make sure you know about it.
I left a flier in your mailbox
and also stuck one in your purse.
It's gonna be great,
so hope to see you.
Bye!
Anita on tv: This is a Japanese version of
buffalo chicken wings.
They're marinated with a good...
which is a Japanese...
Glen on voicemail: Hey, Nora. It's Glen.
I think I called you already.
I'm not sure.
I'm just taking a head count-
Nora.
Hi.
Oh, my god.
What a surprise.
Wow. You look great.
Thank you.
Wow. Jeez.
I was beginning to feel like the last
person on earth,
so I thought I'd come by.
Well, this is the place.
It's a nice place,
Glen.
Oh, thanks.
I just can't believe
that you're not out of town.
I just didn't feel like it this year.
Oh. Well, I'm glad that you're here.
Hey, uh, I'll get you a drink,
and I'll introduce you to some people.
This is, um, uh...
Carl.
Hi.
You're kind of pretty.
Do you, uh-do you work with Glen?
Yeah.
Hotel business?
Mm-hmm. I have to get my drink.
Hot.
It's a fine day
to escape from a bad dream...
Hi. There you are.
Are you having
a good time?
Yeah. I'm exhausted.
Really?
I'm gonna go.
Yeah.
Oh, come on. Stay.
Have one drink.
I'm so tired.
Please? With me.
You know, we never get a chance
to do this.
I know. Thank you so much for inviting me.
I'm so glad that you came.
Are you sure you
don't want to stay?
Come on.
It'll be fun.
Please? Just one little drink.
Hey.
Julian!
Common ça va? Salut!
Hey, Nora, Nora.
Julian, I want you to meet someone.
Nora, this is Julian.
Hello, Nora.
Hi.
Is this your fiancee?
No. We work together.
Oh. cool. Would you have another drink with me?
Nora has got to leave.
No! Why? Why are you leaving?
I'm tired.
I'm exhausted.
It was nice meeting you,
though.
What are you doing?
Convincing you to stay.
Come on,
for just one drink.
Please.
Ok.
Glen: Ha ha ha!
Mon ami.
How do you know this guy?
Well, I lived for a year
with his family in France.
It's a long story.
So, um, can I get you guys a drink?
Yeah. I'll have a vodka straight up
with a twist.
Ooh. Et Julian?
Yeah, I'll have the same.
Ok.
Common ça va?
Yeah, say va.
You know,
I saw you before.
Really? Where?
In a hotel.
You were with a man who had a pillow.
Oh, yeah.
Hi.
You don't speak French?
No.
A little in high school,
but no, not really.
Tu es très jolie,
Nora.
Thanks.
You don't believe me?
No, I believe you.
I just don't think you're probably
that picky.
I don't understand.
Forget it.
I'm glad you are here.
One more minute,
and we would have
missed each other.
It's fate to see you again, don't you think?
Why do you laugh?
You are afraid?
You know, your approach is just
really intense.
Do you want another drink?
Yeah.
Oh.
So, what are you doing in New York?
I came here to meet you.
No. Really.
No, really,
I came here to do
some work
on a project,
on a film.
You're not an actor, are you?
No.
Good.
You know, once you're calm,
you're not that bad.
Why?
Why what?
Why was I bad?
No, I'm saying that you're not bad.
Oh. Cool.
Let's go somewhere.
I don't think so.
Why not?
I'm not looking for anything.
Like what?
Trouble.
Trouble?
I'm no trouble.
I'm not looking for trouble.
Where do you want to go?
Show me something.
Like what?
I don't know.
Something...
very New York.
No.
What?
I don't want you to kiss me.
I told you no.
Why?
Oh.
But I just want to kiss you.
No.
Come on.
No. I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
Ok, you don't like me.
It's more like I don't want
you to kiss me.
Why not?
I don't know.
Because.
We were having
some fun,
and you are so beautiful.
I just wanted to kiss you.
Well...
listen, I had a great night
with you tonight,
but I just want to go home.
Oh, no.
Come on, Nora.
I'm excited to be with you.
It's late.
There's nothing to do.
I wouldn't know what to do.
But we'll find something.
Come on.
It's a beautiful night.
I promise.
What do you want to do?
Where do you want to go?
We'll go in here.
Here?
Nora, dance with me.
Oh, no, no.
Break. Break.
Uh, two shots of tequila.
Is that ok with you?
Yeah.
Ok.
All I need is something to drink.
Bobby.
Nora.
Hey, baby.
What are you doing here?
I was on tour in Philly.
I had the night off.
I came back.
I had to do a few things.
What are you doing?
Actually, I have him with me.
Very nice.
So you want to be alone, no?
No. You know what?
This is perfect.
Oh, my god.
It's so crazy.
Ay, ay, ay.
And you, Julian.
What are you doing here?
Are you on vacation?
He's working on a movie.
He's not an actor, though.
Bobby: No?
I came here for a woman.
Ay, dios mio.
No, please. Ok.
Tell me. Let's go.
She was my girlfriend,
she's an actress,
and she came here to do a movie,
so I take a job on the movie so I can
be close to her.
But then she leaves me for the actor
in the movie.
That's terrible.
So you're no good at love, too, huh?
No. Très mauvais.
Ok. Kiddies,
I got to go.
It's getting late.
It's so late,
it's almost early.
It was a pleasure meeting you.
I hope to see you around more.
Ok, and thank you for the smoke.
Ah.
Ciao.
Bobby: Oh.
She's a very good girl, ok?
Yes. I know.
Ok. Ciao bello.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
I'm making you coffee?
I thought you left.
No. I'm here.
You have plans for today?
Uh, no. No.
I guess not.
It's ok, then?
Yeah. Yeah.
God.
So, what do you want to do?
I'm angry.
Yeah? About what?
I don't know.
Anything.
What?
I'm angry.
Oh, you're hungry. Oh.
I thought you said you were angry.
Oh, no. Never.
Never.
So where do you want to eat?
Food. Manja.
Come on.
I had a nice time with you last night.
Really?
Yeah, sure.
Even though we didn't have sex?
Of course.
Why not?
Do you think if you don't have
sex with a man,
he does not like you?
No.
I don't know. Maybe.
I think it just depends on the guy.
You don't have any hang-ups, do you?
What is hang-ups?
Problems, fears,
things that scare you.
Like what things?
I don't know.
Uh, heart attacks,
terrorism,
random acts of violence,
worrying about what other people think,
not succeeding in life.
Wow. That's a lot.
No. When I was 8 years old,
my mother died,
and my father
told me
that life was something short
and to always make some value in it.
When my father died,
I think I did the opposite.
Is he still alive,
your dad?
Yes. He lives in the south of France.
Marseilles.
Marseilles?
Come on, Nora.
You've got to go somewhere.
I know. You're right.
We've been walking a lot.
Are you tired of walking?
No. It's perfect.
Yeah?
I know what we can do.
I love these penguins.
Sometimes when I'm sad,
I come here
and just watch them.
They make me feel better.
Come here.
I want to kiss you.
La pirouette.
Bien. Pirouette.
pwe wet.
pwe wet?
What would you say to a French girl
if you were having sex with her?
I would say, 'Oh! oh!
C'est très bon!'
Ah! Ha ha ha!
Are you starting to love me?
Ha ha! I'm not ready
to give out that information at this time.
Nora, you are the exact
girl that's on my mind.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
What are you thinking?
Hey.
Nothing.
I was just thinking about how I was telling
my friend Audrey
that I wasn't gonna see anyone.
and I changed your mind?
Are you seeing anyone right now?
No, not now.
Just you.
But you do see other women.
If I meet someone I like, yes.
Why? What?
Nothing.
Of course you do.
But you don't?
What is this?
What are we
doing here?
We take a bath.
Why do you talk about love?
When?
Before.
I'm just trying to figure out
if this is supposed to mean something.
I don't know, Nora.
We have no contract.
We are just meeting each other.
You're right.
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
You still didn't tell me what you do.
I start to record sound on movies.
Ah. Mystery solved.
Do you like it?
Is it fun?
Yes, I like it.
I like to listen to people,
to hear their voice,
how they feel,
and I get to travel.
But there's not only work.
I also play some music.
Ugh. I'm so glad I don't have
an acoustic guitar.
Nora?
Guy, hi.
How are you?
I'm great.
Good. How are you?
I just got back
from a wedding in Rome last night.
You know Jim, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. It was his wedding.
It was totally insane.
That sounds great.
Yeah. Hey.
Uh, I'm Guy.
Sorry.
Hi. I'm Julian.
You, uh, you around this summer?
Yeah. Yeah.
I have no plans.
I'm just working,
you know?
Ok. Well, cool.
Um, I'm here and at the beach,
so I'll give you a call.
Great.
Nice to meet you,
man.
Nice to meet you.
See you.
Bye.
I'll have, um,
half a dozen
of the white cookies with the sprinkles
and, um-they're famous for their
cannolis.
I'll have a half a dozen of those
and, um...
I'm so sorry.
I was so rude.
I don't know what happened.
I'm just so stupid sometimes.
I just got caught off guard.
I'm just not used to being with someone.
I mean, not that we're together or anything,
but I'm just not that experienced
in how to act with a guy.
It's just so weird you come into my life,
and-I don't know- you've...
I have to go to the bathroom.
What are you doing here?
I'm such a freak.
I've turned into such a bitch.
Are you ok?
Yeah.
I'm not mad at you.
Oh, good.
I'm relieved.
Something wrong?
I just want to go home.
Hey. I don't think you're ok.
I'm ok. I just want to go home.
Do you run from me?
No.
Do you feel sick?
Yes, I feel sick.
I feel like I'm going to die.
What are you doing?
Oh, come on, no.
No, no!
Give it to me!
I'm not gonna kill myself!
I'm just gonna take one!
Are you ok?
I will be.
Is there something wrong with you?
Yeah. I'm a freak.
I had an anxiety attack.
Do you want me to stay with you,
or do you want to be alone?
You can stay.
I'm not good for a NY action, though.
That hasn't happened in a really
long time.
It's really scary.
Julian?
Hi.
Hey. You came back.
I'm-I'm very sorry for what I did.
No. I'm sorry.
I'm just an idiot.
You didn't do anything.
I just blew things out of proportion.
We were having so much fun.
I'm fine now.
You know, Nora,
I'm leaving tomorrow,
and I thought maybe we could spend this night
together if you want.
Tomorrow?
Yes. Very early.
I had the best time with you, Nora.
Me, too.
Come with me.
Come to see paris.
Come on the plane tomorrow
and run away with me.
No. I can't.
I can't.
Why not?
A million reasons.
Like, I couldn't possibly be ready
to do that in time.
I- I have to work.
I have obligations.
Those are only some excuses, all right?
I want you to come.
What are you gonna do?
Stay all your life,
do the same thing?
No. I'm-I'm just being realistic.
We've only known each other
for a couple of days.
I can't just pretend that everything
would just magically work itself out.
I know better.
You shouldn't make promises that you
can't keep.
Why not?
I don't know.
Uh...
It's just not what I imagined for myself.
I'm not like that.
Why? Because I'm French,
because I'm younger than you?
What is it?
Yeah. You live in another country.
we've had a really nice weekend.
You shouldn't feel bad about it.
I don't want to fight about this now.
I'll come to Paris with you
and we'll just see how it goes sometime
in the future.
You promise?
Yeah.
Ok, Nora.
I have to go.
I had a great time with you.
Don't cry.
I left my cell phone number next
to your bed.
Come here.
Kiss me.
What?
You need to go on a date.
Ugh. No.
Mm-hmm.
Duty dating.
What's that?
There's a theory that you should
go out
with guys who ask you out,
even if you know you don't like
them in that way.
For practice.
That is the saddest thing I think I've
ever heard.
No, it's not.
You need to get out there again.
Otherwise, you're just gonna retreat.
I know you, Nora.
Nobody's asking me out.
Uh-uh
Steve, you tell Nora you were an architect?
Yeah. I was doing private homes
and office buildings.
I mostly build boutique hotels now.
I have to say,
it's really
challenging, you know...
Mm-hmm.
Making each one
different.
Mm.
Nora works in a hotel,
Sullivan House.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Do you like it?
No.
Not really.
Hi, Nora.
You got a minute?
Yeah.
I just wanted to talk to you seriously
just for a bit.
Ok.
I was wondering, um,
how it's going,
how you're doing with the planning
of the company picnic.
Oh. That.
Um, I, uh, haven't really gotten
around to it yet.
We've been kind of swamped.
Haven't got around to it yet?
Uh, Nora, there's only 5 weeks left.
I mean, there's a lot more to it
than-than just locations alone.
I mean, you've got food and invites, buses,
games, employee of the month.
Have you even voted for the employee
of the month yet?
Not yet.
Well, when were you planning on doing
all of this?
I don't know.
I'm sorry. I forgot.
Look. You know what?
I don't understand
what's wrong
with you lately, Nora.
You were always so reliable,
and now you don't even come around anymore.
Nobody's seen you.
What's wrong with you?
Is everything ok?
Because you cannot go on like this.
You know what, Perry?
You're right.
I can't go on like this.
I've been awful.
I can't do this anymore.
Do what?
This! I can't do this anymore!
I see something in you.
Huh?
I can tell you things about your life.
Your father misses you.
You were his favorite person in the world.
He knows how lonely you are,
and he wants me to help you.
Come inside.
So wait a minute.
You went to a psychic to have
a curse put on you.
Please. I'm humiliated enough as it is.
She didn't put a curse on me.
She removed a curse.
Did you pay her?
I don't want to talk about it.
No. Please.
I have to know
so I can understand your insanity.
I don't know.
I'm going totally crazy.
You'll be fine.
No, I won't.
I quit my job,
and I went to a witchdoctor.
I can't believe you quit your job.
I know.
Do you think that was the right thing
to do?
Maybe it was.
Maybe I should have gone with Julian.
Why didn't you?
I'm a coward.
So... what are you gonna do about it?
Is this safe?
It's fine. relax.
we don't even know what's in here.
What if it's drugs?
It is not drugs.
My parents know the guy.
I can't believe we're doing this.
Listen. It was the only cheap ticket. I swear.
Oh! I hate Mark.
He's mad that we're doing this courier shit,
riding coach. Oy.
Uh, hi.
We're not sure
where to go.
Um, we need a small,
little hotel
in the middle of town that's not
very expensive.
I don't think he understands you.
Oh, no.
I think he does.
They just pretend not to understand.
Watch this.
Excusez-moi.
Vous comprendre?
Oui, oui.
I understand.
Hmm?
Merci beaucoup.
Thank you very much.
I hope you find happiness.
A penis?
Yes.
Oh...
Skanky.
Well, at least it has a bathroom.
This really sucks.
I'm sorry, Audrey.
Don't be ridiculous.
We're in Paris.
We're gonna find Julian.
Let's deliver these packages first,
get it out of the way.
We're so crazy for doing this.
I know.
It's totally crazy.
You know, we could probably get a map
downstairs.
Oh, you're so on it.
Well, it's probably just easier for me
to be objective right now.
When should we meet back here?
I don't know.
Like an hour,
an hour and a half?
But if we get held up,
let's just call the hotel
and touch base, ok?
Ok.
Ok. Now which way is the Seine?
Because I am going the opposite
direction.
Excusez-moi.
Oui?
Do you speak English?
A little.
Could you tell me where the Hotel Meurice is?
Uh, it's just over there.
Ok. Great.
Madame Grenelle?
Qui est lá?
Uh, I'm sorry.
Je ne parlez français.
Do you speak English?
Of course I speak English.
What do you want?
My name is Nora.
I have a package for you.
The door was open.
Well, bring it to me.
I hope I'm not bothering you.
It's been a long time.
Excuse me?
Mr. Larson?
Hi. I'm Audrey.
Come in.
Please sit down.
Thank you very much.
I wouldn't entrust this to the regular mail.
But I have to say I didn't imagine
someone like you
delivering it to me.
Are you surprised?
Yes.
Are you hungry?
Um, actually,
yeah, I am.
Let's go.
You turned out very pretty.
Thank you.
You know, your mother never let me see you much.
I think she was ashamed of me,
and she moved to America.
She was always taking these wild chances,
and your father was quite handsome.
Where do you live?
New York City.
Are you married?
No.
But you want to be.
Yeah. I guess so.
Why?
I don't know.
I, um...
I guess then I would really know that
someone loved me.
Marriage is a contract,
but to feel love is something else entirely.
I don't think I've ever really been
in love.
You have probably been in love
lots of times.
Besides, you are young.
You have time.
But I'm getting older.
You will be fine.
You are from good stock.
Don't let anyone tell you otherwise.
You will get nowhere in this world
by feeling sorry for yourself.
So what will happen to you when your friend
finds this man?
Depending on how happy he is
to see her,
either I'll leave on my own,
or I'll take Nora with me.
I love being in Paris.
My wife loves it here.
Sometimes comes with our children.
and she doesn't mind you taking another
woman to lunch?
Not at all.
Does your fiancé mind you going to lunch
with me?
Yeah. I don't think he'd be too crazy
about me having lunch
with a handsome stranger in Paris.
No.
And he's my husband.
I just forgot to wear my ring.
Is that terrible?
You know, I think in relationships
there are things you are honest about
and things you choose to keep to yourself.
Are you good at keeping secrets, Audrey?
I have to call my friend.
Can I borrow your cell phone, please?
Sorry I'm late.
What's going on here?
What happened?
Nora, what happened?
Did we get robbed or something?
I lost the piece of paper
with Julian's number on it.
What?
I looked everywhere.
Look at this place.
It's gone.
Ok. We'll find it.
You don't understand.
I looked everywhere 20 times.
Well, I'll look again with fresh eyes, ok?
What about the phone book
or information?
His last name is Durand.
It's like the Smith of France.
Then I talked to the concierge
for, like, an hour.
I've tried everything.
I even called Glen.
He wasn't there.
Are you ok?
Well, I want to feel that way, too.
All right.
This.
I'm gonna go take a shower.
I'll be back.
Ok.
I'm sorry about today.
You called.
Tomorrow will be fun.
Thanks for coming with me.
I love you, Nora.
I love you, too.
Good night.
Good morning.
Whoa. You're pretty chipper today.
Yeah. This is ridiculous.
I came here to surprise some guy
I hardly know
that I can't find,
but so what?
We're in Paris.
Yeah. We've always wanted to do this.
Yeah. So let's just enjoy it.
It's time I got my sense of humor back.
Good for you.
I think we should still look around town
for your mystery man.
You never know.
We may run into him.
Yeah. What do I have to lose
at this point?
Nothing.
Plus we can go shopping.
Right.
Ohh.
I can't believe
it's raining in Paris.
I can't believe I thought I'd find
Julian in these places
unless he's into women's clothes.
Do you want to get a tea or something?
A tea?
That's funny.
Ha ha ha!
Thank you.
Merci.
Did you see what was in the package?
Just some business papers.
What about you?
No. Nothing too exciting.
The old lady was really cool.
She thought I was her granddaughter.
God. That kind of thing
only happens to you, Nora.
Ha ha!
Ahh.
Mark called this morning.
He said he missed me.
Wanted to know if I wanted to work
on our relationship.
Do you?
I suppose.
I mean, I guess I just shouldn't throw
my marriage away
without trying.
I mean, I do really love him.
Maybe I just shouldn't be so critical
just because things aren't
in the greatest place,
you know?
I think that's great, Audrey.
Ok.
Let's do it.
Audrey...
I know I'm crazy,
but I think I'm gonna stay.
Nora, I am your friend,
and I love you,
but this just isn't working out.
You got to give this up.
I can't.
You go.
I know Mark is waiting for you.
Nora, you have no sense
of direction,
and you are way too shy.
Do you want me to stay with you?
Because I will.
No. I have to do this for myself.
I have to stop relying on other people
to make decisions for me.
You're gonna come home, aren't you?
Yeah. I have no job and no money.
I have to come back to reality soon.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Something I feel like doing, I guess.
Well, I'm really proud of you.
I got to go.
I know.
Ok.
I'll call you.
You weirdo.
I don't speak French.
Ah. I said,
'it makes me
want to cry. '
You are American?
What are you doing in Paris?
Just looking.
Just looking?
You like art.
Ah. I go with my friends.
We go have a coffee.
You want to come with us?
No, thank you.
Ok. Well, if you change your mind,
we'll be just across the street, ok?
Ok.
I'll see you there.
Ah, si, si.
Eh, come, come.
Hi.
Sit down,
sit down.
What's your name?
Nora.
Nora, hi.
I'm Guillaume.
- Guillaume.
This is Sébastien.
Nice to meet you.
And that's Karim.
- Enchanté.
Would you like a glass of wine?
Yes?
Let's toast.
No, no, no.
No crossing.
Go first.
And then the others.
Voilá!
Is that crossing if I do that?
No.
No, no. That's fine.
It's direct line.
We drink now.
Ha ha ha!
So what are you doing in Paris, Nora?
I'm looking for someone.
And did you find him?
No. No.
Well, you're not so bad right now.
Not bad.
Are all French guys like this?
Like what?
Um, passionate,
interested, uh...
Mm-hmm.
Attentive
but kind of like dogs, too?
No, no.
Dogs?
The women-the women are the ones, you know?
The last time I had a girlfriend,
all the time we had some fight.
She tried to jump out of the window
all the time.
Yeah. Ha ha!
No.
That was super-scary.
It wasn't funny, you know,
especially for me.
Sorry.
There's one, she tried to stop me.
Yeah, but that was crazy, you know.
It's true.
Did you ever think that maybe you were
the ones
driving them crazy?
No, no, no, no.
I don't think so, no.
Not like this.
Because I've heard differently.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
Because of the French mothers.
What, uh-what about the French
mothers?
They, um, they're in love with their sons.
And the American mothers are not?
Not as much.
I think because of the food.
Here you go.
Merci.
Bartender: Bonsoir, monsieur.
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
Bonsoir.
Are you American?
Yes. Why?
Because you look a very beautiful
American woman
sitting alone in this bar.
Maybe I'm waiting for someone.
Well, but you look alone.
No?
My name is Jean Paul Claremont.
What's yours?
Nora Wilder.
Nice to meet you,
Nora.
Nice to meet you.
May I offer you another drink?
Sure. Well,
after this one.
Cheers.
I mean, what were the chances that
I would find him?
But, you know,
the funny thing is
after a while I wasn't even
looking for Julian.
I was just doing my own thing,
and it felt good.
It's not wrong to want someone
to love you.
Most people are together
just so they are not alone,
but some people want magic.
I think you are one of those people.
Nothing wrong with that?
Nothing,
but it doesn't
happen all the time.
Does it ever happen?
First, Nora,
you must find love
and happiness in yourself.
Do you understand?
I think so.
Oh. We are both drunk.
I will put you in a taxi to your hotel.
It's time to go.
Jean Paul: Tomorrow,
you will start
your life again.
I don't know why,
but I will never
forget you.
I'll never forget you either.
Never.
Hello?
Hey, Nora.
It's me.
Audrey, hi.
How's it going?
Everything's ok.
I'm just leaving for the airport
in a couple of minutes.
Well, did you find him?
No, I didn't,
but I'm all right.
Really?
Yeah, I really am.
Ok. Good.
Listen. I got to go,
but I'll call you
on the way to the airport, ok?
Ok. I miss you.
Oh, I miss you, too.
Fly safe, ok?
- Ok.
All right. Bye.
Bye.
Hi.
Nora.
I can't believe it.
What are you doing here?
Well, I'm-I'm going to a sound expo
at Le Bourget,
but what are you doing here?
I- I'm going to the airport.
What time is your flight?
In 3 hours.
They make you get to the airport
so early now.
Merci.
Ok. I just want to ask what you are doing here.
Did you come to see me?
Because I don't understand.
I like you so much,
and I never hear anything from you,
and then you are just here
in front of me now.
Why?
It's really complicated.
Ok, but try to explain.
I came here to find you.
Then I lost your number.
You came here to see me?
And you never find me?
But then you find me?
And now you leave?
So you like me?
Yes.
Would you stay with me for another drink?
But you know you're gonna miss your flight?
I know.
...could have come through?
Anytime
Cold, lonely
puritan.
What are you
fighting for?
It's not my
security.
It's just an old war
not even a cold war
Don't say it in Russian.
Don't say it in German
say it in broken English
lose your father
your husband
your mother
your children
what are you
dying for?
It's not my
reality.
It's just an old war
not even a cold war
don't say it in Russian
don't say it in German
say it in broken English
what are you fighting for?
could have come through?
anytime
cold, lonely
puritan
what are you
fighting for?
It's not my
security
It's just an old war
not even a cold war
don't say it in Russian
don't say it in German
say it in broken English
what are you fighting for?