Every day there's more to tell
Dreaming, I'm little now
Fading away every passing day
And I just have
one thing to tell you
You're further
and further away...
I need more vocals,
I can't hear myself.
Guys, I have 8 more bands
to balance,
the competition starts in 3 hours.
Clear the stage.
Welcome to the Young Bands
Competition, here's the first band.
I can't leave now,
we haven't even performed yet.
So I'll do the song
and I'll come home,
I won't even wait for the results.
So take them with you!
But it's not my fault
they called you in.
Mom, I'm not coming.
You heard me.
Let them fire you.
You heard me, I'm not coming.
Maya.
-Yoram, let me go.
There'll be other gigs.
Come on, Bahr,
come out already.
You know I have to go,
right?
But you'll take me
to kindergarten tomorrow?
I promised, didn't I?
Promise-promise?
Promise-promise-promise-promise.
Maya, I'm sorry.
I begged them
to find someone else.
Do you want me
to get fired? Maya!
I hate you.
Serves you right.
I love these
mother-daughter talks,
we should do it more often.
-Maya, I'm sorry.
Go to work, Mom,
lots of kids need you there.
Bahri, what's the matter?
You couldn't fall asleep?
Come on, let's go to sleep.
Good evening, everybody.
This song was written by a girl
who's kind of strange,
she couldn't come to sing it tonight,
so I'll sing it instead of her.
Her name is Maya and the song
is called "Animated Movies".
She wrote it for her father.
Still have so much to say to you
Every day there's more to tell
Dreaming, I'm little now
Fading away every passing day...
Hey, Skeleton.
-Don't call me Skeleton, dummy.
Yair, you promised
you'd go back to schooI today.
Maya, don't touch the blinds.
Murderer. You just destroyed
millions of planets,
there must be life
on one of them.
You destroyed
entire civilizations.
Take your bones and get lost.
Life is here, Darwin,
on this planet.
Yair, get up!
Leave me alone, Maya,
stop it! Fuck!
Get your frozen feet away
from me, I want to sleep.
Answer one little question
and I'm out of here.
There is no God,
there is no truth,
and there is no meaning to
your bony existence. -Great.
You little shit, why do I
always have to do everything?
Cause you're older.
I had a gig last night,
my first gig.
WonderfuI.
How was it?
I don't know,
I wasn't there.
Mom was called to work,
you disappeared, as usual.
Remember we used
to read each other's thoughts?
You know what I'm
thinking right now?
I'm fuckin sick of you,
Yair, totally.
How could I have wet my bed
if I pee like an elephant?
You're the peeing champion,
you should be in the "Olympees".
Could be worse, right?
-Yes, it could be worse, really.
I'm not washing my hair.
-OK.
And I'm not getting dressed till
Mommy comes.
You are too!
But I'm not going to kindergarten
till Mommy gets back, period.
Lie on your side.
Don't breathe in,
exhale slowly.
Breathe slowly.
Good, good.
I'm not going till she gets back,
I'm not going till she gets back...
Get lost.
I'm not going
till she gets back...
You're such a pain.
Sisi, hi, it's Maya.
Fine, hanging in there.
Did Mom leave?
Yours is with mayo and avocado.
I have to talk to her.
Sisi, Mom didn't come
to take me!
Hello, Maya?
-Where are you?
I'm late. What's going on?
-Nothing.
Bahr won't go till you get back,
Darwin went back to sleep,
Ido switched sheets with Bahr again,
and I'm late for school,
but it could be worse, right?
Right. Make sure they dress
warmly and make them sandwiches.
I already did.
Pick her up at four and fix dinner,
I'm on the night shift.
She won't go without you. -Let me
talk to her. Wait, Maya. -What?
Are you OK?
Do you hate me for yesterday?
You know I had no choice.
So you're OK?
-Everything's OK, Mom.
Did you eat something?
-Bahr...
Where's Bahr?
-In my pocket.
Bahr!
Bahr, open up!
-No!
Bahr, Mom wants to talk to you.
-Then she should come home.
Bahr! Open up right now!
Mom, she locked herself in.
She won't come out.
Mom, I'm late for schooI,
when can you come?
Maya, why are you yelling?
Maya, what happened?
-Why are you doing this?
Doing what?
-Idiot.
What do you want?
-Don't sound like Dad.
Make Bahr come out
and wait for me outside...
You won't make it. -I will,
and then I'm taking you to schooI.
I'm going to work.
But Yair, you promised me.
I tried, it didn't work.
-What do you mean, you tried?
School only starts today.
Yair, I don't have time
to argue with you.
Let me talk to Ido.
Ido! -Dafna, why isn't anyone
in number five? -Five?
I'll go to five, she's mine.
-Thanks.
What do you want?
Are you OK, sweetie?
-I have a tummy ache.
You're just nervous,
it'll go away.
I told you
he wouldn't go back.
Ido, I promise
he'll go back to school today.
"Bahl", sweetheart,
is that you out there?
I'm locked inside
and can't get out.
I need help "despelately".
I love you. Bye
Do you know why I call you "Bahl"?
Because I can't say "R".
I'm locked inside
and I'm "leally despelate".
I'm so afraid.
So "vely, vely aflaid".
You said "afraid", with an R.
-Did not, did not.
Having fun out there?
Doesn't basketball
practice start today?
You said it, you said it!
Hey, Ido!
Gimme my hat!
Leave him alone!
Ouch, he bit me!
Ido, you little fucker,
we're gonna kill you.
Today?
I forgot all about it.
But we made an appointment,
didn't we?
How can I go like this?
Look at me, Sisi.
Sorry.
-Watch where you're going.
Sorry, I got off
at the wrong station.
Station? You mean floor.
What floor is this?
-The third!
Mom said she'd come,
didn't she?
Yes, but we're
not talking to her.
Could be worse
than wetting my bed, right?
What do you mean?
It's great.
I try to wet my bed every night
but I can't do it. -Nonsense.
Bahr, don't you think I should
start getting serious?
I'm almost five and a half
and I don't have a degree.
You're totally screwed up.
I have drawings.
Abstract.
We'll have three tests,
two quizzes...
Good morning, Maya Ulman!
-Good morning.
If you know that it's morning,
then everything's fine.
Come on in,
summer vacation is over.
What a great way
to start the year.
Tell me about it.
What's up? -Gaga,
it's too early for questions.
Come on...
Shit!
What happened? Are you OK?
Are you hurt?
Show me where it hurts.
-I'm OK, I'm OK.
Why do you drive like that?
Can't you see it's dangerous?
Dangerous...
Aren't you a bit old for a scooter?
-It's not a scooter, it's a moped!
It's you again...
You're trying to kill me today.
-I'm sorry.
What? Don't worry, I'm OK.
It's my daughter's
first day at kindergarten,
I have to be there in 10 minutes
and I'll never make it.
Do you have another helmet?
This scooter is nice, after all.
Are you new at the hospital?
-What?
How long have you been working
at the hospital?
I got back from California
a couple months ago.
Why did you leave there?
Did you murder somebody?
What?
Never mind.
Make a right.
Did we make it on time?
-Perfect.
Thank you very much.
Bye.
Excuse me...
Dafna.
-The coat.
Oh, your coat. Sorry.
Good night.
You're so smart,
you can learn so much.
Mom, I'm working.
Want to get me fired?
Look at yourself
in that stupid outfit.
Do you want to grow up
to be a mouse?
What's wrong with being a mouse?
I'm sick of your mice philosophy.
What's wrong with being
an ordinary person?
You're meeting the school counselor
in 20 minutes.
Dafna, relax.
Don't call me Dafna,
I'm your mother!
Be nice to the counselor,
don't scare her.
Is that new lipstick?
Yair, I told you,
he just gave me a ride.
Mom, I know you,
you're going somewhere.
I'm not going anywhere.
Don't be such a wise guy, OK?
I just wanted you to know that
it's totally OK if you are,
as far as I'm concerned.
Give me a kiss.
-Cool it, Mom.
Bye.
I won't ever do it again,
I promise, OK?
Iris...
What are you doing here?
I'm not talking to you.
Yair Ulman?
Come on in.
Have a seat.
OK, I'm Flora, the new counselor.
I understand that
you were allowed
just to take exams last year
and now Pnina wants you to come back
to school on a regular basis, right?
I understand that you stopped
studying on a regular basis
nine months ago
following a crisis.
Do you want to talk
about it?
Pnina also told me that you're
a great basketball player
and that you left
the school team as well.
Want some coffee?
You probably know that she thinks
you're not using your full potential.
What do you think about that?
-I don't.
But if you passed the exams
without going to school,
she must be right.
But if I get Bs without
going to school,
I must be using
my potential, right?
How can one not use
their full potential?
Look, why don't you tell
Pnina that everything's fine
and that my potential is being used.
-It won't work, Yair.
It creates a precedent.
They took into consideration
what happened...
But in any case, it's over.
Let's play a game, OK?
I'll throw the ball to you
and say a word,
you throw it back and tell me
the first word that comes to mind.
In this room there are no parents,
no teachers, no school,
just you and me, OK?
As you guys say: Give and throw.
-Give and go.
Give and go, what did I say?
Good.
Morning.
I.
-Mouse.
Boy.
Glasses.
Mom.
Sister.
Dad.
Fear.
Anger.
Dad.
Are you mad at me?
How can I be mad at you?
You don't even exist.
Excuse me?
Do you know what your Nemesis is?
What? -It's waiting
outside your room,
where there are no parents,
no teachers and no counselor.
We can play ball forever
but your words are meaningless.
You're a particle of dust
floating in the universe,
you and your socks.
This conversation doesn't exist
and you don't exist,
so how can I be mad at you?
You're dead.
Why did you come here? -So my
mom will be able to get some sleep.
However, those who disapprove
of the ecomomic system
see purple children floating
in the sky, picking balloons.
Maya and Gaga, good morning.
I see you're
still on vacation,
or perhaps you're having
deep thoughts on the subject.
Stand up and share
your thoughts with us.
Stand up.
Do you have to use the bathroom?
-My foot fell asleep.
What do you have to say?
The free economy?
Fantastic. Anything else?
If after 20 years on the job
my mom can't afford a babysitter,
free economy isn't
really working, is it?
Quiet.
That's an excellent example.
Listen carefully to what
Maya is saying.
Her mother has been in the
same line of work for many years
and still hasn't
made it financially.
Maya, what sector does
your mom work in? -Sector?
My mom practices the
oldest profession in the world.
Maya... -She's a midwife.
What did you think I meant?
Maya.
Wait up.
What's with you? Do you want
to get expelled? -Yes.
Hold on, Maya.
-What?
Did you get a call
from Helicon Records?
No, Gaga.
Why should I?
Cause one of them
was there yesterday
and said we have
an awesome song,
that we should have won.
He even asked for your number.
So he didn't call...
-No.
Good dog, Alex.
Yoram! Call Alex!
Quiet.
Hi.
OK, bye.
I just came to apologize
for yesterday,
I'm really sorry, it won't
happen again, I promise.
Maya.
It's over.
I'm leaving,
I'm moving to Tel Aviv.
But it won't happen again.
-It's not just the gig.
I don't want to be stuck
here all my life.
We have a gig in two weeks.
-At a school.
Lots of bands perform at
schools, you said so yourself.
Yeah, but they get paid.
Have you been thinking
about this long?
Maya, you're a kid,
you're still in high school.
I'm 24 years old,
I should be dead from an overdose
or something. Maya!
Dafna Ulman?
Get up, come on.
Smile.
You're going to pay for this.
Maybe this isn't
such a good idea.
I just finished a night shift.
It'll be fine, don't worry,
we'll have a little rehearsal,
then we'll shoot it.
Tell me something about yourself.
My name is Dafna,
Im 43,
I have four kids.
-Say that youre 39, not 43.
But I wrote 43 on the form.
It doesn't matter.
It's the video that counts.
Try again.
My name is Dafna, I work
at Rothschild Hospital,
I'm a midwife,
I have 39 kids.
Sorry, sorry,
I got mixed up.
That smile, that's it.
OK, let's start.
Hello, Dafna.
How are you? -Fine.
Dafna, without knowing you,
I'd say you're a very friendly
and curious person, am I right?
If I were to give you a ticket
to go anywhere,
where would you go?
How does Europe grab you?
Yes, but I'd feeI strange
moving to a new place...
No, just for vacation.
-Oh, vacation.
Of course. I've never been
to America either. -Great.
If I were to send you to America
with the man of your dreams,
what would he look like?
What would he do?
What would you do together?
We'd go for walks together.
I think we'd go to
the movies sometimes...
Go to the beach
on Saturdays...
Look, this wasn't
such a good idea after all.
I'll come some other time.
No, I'm sleeping!
Close the door.
You scared me. Lock it.
This stuff is amazing.
Want some?
What's up?
-Nothing.
Are you OK?
Do you love me?
-What?
You know I do.
Since when?
What's with you?
When did you start loving me?
In third or fourth grade.
What would you do for me?
I don't know,
I haven't thought about it.
So why do you love me?
Dunno.
Idiot.
Close your eyes.
-What?
-Why?
Cause I said so.
What's going on?
I want to see.
Maya, what are you doing?
What's wrong?
-I can't do it.
Why not?
I don't know,
I just can't.
What? -Ido, Maya didn't
come to pick me up.
Then spend the night there.
-Come on, Ido.
Then you're coming
to the pool to film me.
But Maya doesn't
let us go there.
Then walk home alone.
I'll come with you.
-I'm on my way.
It's OK, my brother's coming
to get me. -Are you sure?
Bye, sweetie.
-Bye.
Cut it out, you're not a baby,
you don't have to hold my hand,
otherwise you'll never
learn to walk home alone.
But Maya always let's me.
But Maya isn't here and today
you're learning to walk home alone.
Look left and right,
left again and then cross.
If you're not coming,
I'm leaving.
But Maya always let's me.
Bye, I'm leaving.
-Then I'm not coming to the pool
and I won't film you
jumping in.
Can you see me?
-Yes.
Press the red button.
Hello? -Hello,
may I speak to Dafna?
Speaking. -Hello, it's Flora,
the counselor at Yair's school.
Did I wake you? -It's OK,
I was on the night shift.
I met with Yair today
and we're having trouble accepting
him back at schooI. -Why?
The boy can't come back to school
without getting psychological treatment.
Why do you always
make things difficult?
If it's a financiaI problem,
there are ways we can help.
That's not it.
He finally wants to go back to
schooI, why can't you help him?
Flora, I have another call,
can you hold on?
Hello, this is Ehud from Helicon,
I'm looking for Maya.
Hello? Hello?
This is Ehud.
Excuse me, do you know
what time it is? -What?
The time.
Do you have a watch?
Where to?
I screwed up, I was supposed
to pick up my kid sister.
My mom's gonna kill me.
What time is it?
I'm such a screw-up.
Ido, please.
Ido, please!
Get up, please, Ido, get up.
"Hello, you've reached
the Ulman family.
If it's not the wrong number,
leave a message."
Where were you?
Bahr!
Are you OK, sweetie?
Ido fell.
-Where?
I couldn't wake him.
-Bahr, where's Ido?
He jumped into the pool,
I think he's dead.
Help me with this damn door.
Ido, wake up, this is Mommy
talking to you. Ido, wake up.
Yair, it's Maya.
Something happened to Ido, call
Mom when you hear this message.
Mom.
-Maya, leave me alone.
An 11 year-old, unconscious,
head injury,
following a three-meter fall.
-Ido wake up.
Ido, open your eyes.
Ido, wake up.
Widening of the pupils,
slow reaction,
no reaction to pain...
Take her home,
I don't want her to be here.
I want to stay.
For once, do as you're told.
The CT looks OK,
no swelling,
it'll take time for
the boy to recover.
Dafna, do you need anything?
What are you doing here?
Is this private property?
I thought you weren't
talking to me.
I'm not, I came to practice
my hook-shot.
Do you sleep here?
I like your pajamas.
When did you get back?
Two months ago.
Why?
-We missed you.
Just kidding, my mom had
an affair with Clinton.
She had an affair
with all of Baltimore,
Max eventually dumped her.
I'll never make this shot.
-Of course not, you're a girl.
Is that so?
Watch this,
with my eyes closed.
You retard.
You could have split
your head open. -But I didn't.
What are you doing here anyway?
-What are you doing here?
OK, let's go.
-Where to?
Inside, I forgot my keys.
I'm not allowed in
without psychologicaI treatment.
She said that to you too?
Come on, I'll treat you.
I'll do your homework for you.
Fishbaum!
It's so weird here at night.
-It's much weirder in the morning.
Why?
Isn't it weird coming to this
lousy place for 12 years
to get a piece of paper
with grades?
Is handing out flyers
any better?
Flyers, diplomas,
it's all paper.
Nothing you do
really has any meaning.
Why not?
-Think about it.
You're a speck of dust in a
expanding crazy universe.
Your life is such a tiny dot
in time that it doesn't even exist.
It's like a three-pointer.
The ball leaves your hand,
it's in the air,
and that's it, you're dead.
Iris?
Iris, come on!
Iris!
Sorry for calling so late,
it's Ehud from Helicon.
I've been looking for Maya all day.
Please tell her to call me about
the recording session tomorrow.
What recording session?
Just tell her to come to Helicon
with her band, she'll know. OK?
She won't be able to make it.
-Why not?
I'm sorry, she won't
be able to make it.
"Hi, you've reached Yoram. Leave a
message and I'll call you back, or not"
Yair?
-It's me.
Yair didn't get back?
No. Is there any change?
No, nothing.
Mom... -Tell Yair to call me
when he gets back.
Ido, don't you want
to talk to me?
You know...
I promise you...
I'll try to find a job
without shifts,
maybe we can move
to another city.
Iris, for fucks sake,
I've got to work tomorrow!
Iris!
Iris, what are you doing?
Do you think I can shoot myself
into the basket?
What are you waiting for?
Let's dive into your
never-ending universe,
we're specks of dust,
aren't we?
Let's shoot a three-pointer,
let's get it over with.
I didn't mean that you're
a speck of dust.
I am.
So you're a speck of dust.
I actually like specks of dust.
My best friends are
specks of dust, I swear.
Then why didn't you write to me?
You know,
mice don't write very well.
Stop it, Yair,
say something real.
Dafna and David Ulman
and Maya, Yair, Ido and Bahr
Hi.
-What are you doing here?
Did they call you?
-Yes, sorry, Yoram,
I can't come.
Something happened.
I just knew you'd
fuck this up, Maya.
Something happened with my brother.
-You always have some excuse.
You don't understand.
-What's there to understand?
Then leave. -No, I want
an explanation, Maya.
But you don't want to listen.
Why do you always have
to be such a martyr?
That's what you think of me?
-What else can I think?
Look at the way you're behaving.
What do you want to hear?
That she was 3 months in bed?
That I had to drag her
into the shower?
That she didn't change sheets
for 3 months,
because she thought
his smell was still there.
Is that what you want to hear?
All I want is to hear you sing.
Dr. Goldman.
-Valentin.
Sorry to disturb you.
It's just that I saw you
walk by the window earlier
and I remembered...
I wanted to offer you
a cup of coffee.
No, no, it's OK.
You just got back
from California, right? -Yes.
Do you know Abby?
-Who? -Abby.
She works here.
-I told you, I'm new.
But she came back from California
and she's a nurse,
a registered nurse.
-She worked there?
You know, it seems
so complicated,
moving to a new place,
starting all over again.
Never mind, I...
Maybe I should
talk to Abby about that.
My father died,
that's why I stopped writing.
I know. You were
in the middle of a game,
and he and Maya were at the beach.
On their way back
Maya had to pee.
How do you know?
-Maya told me.
What's this?
Nothing.
Is that why you went
to see Flora?
Let's get down.
From which side?
Your side.
What's wrong?
You're shaking.
Yeah, it's weird.
-What's weird?
That I'm scared.
Why are you scared?
-Because I'm happy.
Give me your glasses.
Wow, that's why you didn't
recognize me on the subway,
you've turned into a mole.
Wanna hear something
amazing about moles?
No.
OK, bye.
-Bye.
Hey, Iris, you took my thingy.
Bye. -Bye.
Where's Bahr?
Outside.
Did she get any sleep?
-A little.
Did Yair call?
I want to go to sleep
for a couple hours.
I want you to take over for me.
Mom.
Go on, say it.
Maya, I have nothing
to say to you.
You have nothing
to say to me?
OK, go to sleep,
we'll talk on the phone.
Maya, I'm sorry, I don't have
the strength to fight with you.
Just once, I said I'd pick her up
and I didn't,
and you don't ask yourself
what happened? -What happened?
This is what happened.
Don't you get it?
Too bad you didn't die instead
of him. -What?
What? what was that?
Too bad you didn't die
instead of Dad.
Mom, I'm sorry,
I didn't mean it.
Mom.
I want you to take your things
and get out.
Ever since Dad died...
-Maya, be quiet.
All you want to do is sleep.
How do you expect
anything to be all right?
What happened to your hair,
Skeleton?
What are you doing, sis?
-I don't know you anymore.
Maya, where are you going?
-Away from all of you.
Hold on, Maya.
Go to the hospital, try talking
to your brother like Dad,
maybe it'll work on him.
Hospital? What are you talking about?
-Leave me alone, OK?
Hello, this is Maya,
Dafna Ulmans daughter.
Maya, sweetie, how are you?
Do you want to talk to your mom?
No, that's OK,
I just wanted to know
if there was any change
in my brother's condition.
No, no change.
Don't you want me to go get your mom?
-No, that's OK. Thanks.
You started smoking again?
Don't worry, Mom,
she'll calm down and come back.
You think so?
-She's a big girl.
She's not a big girl,
she's a baby.
Why don't you go to sleep?
-You think I can sleep now?
Go home, you'll feeI better.
You also think that all
I want to do is sleep?
I'm worried about you.
I'll take over for you,
we'll do it in shifts.
Come on, Yair,
I want you to take Bahr home
and fix her something to eat.
It'll be OK.
I'll talk to you later.
He seems so calm.
Usually he's angry.
Angry with whom?
I don't know.
Me, everybody.
He doesn't really talk to me.
I understand.
-What do you understand?
You don't understand anything.
Do you have kids?
-One daughter.
Where is she?
In California.
And your wife?
She's there too.
Why are you here
and they're there?
It's OK, what's the problem?
They're both married.
Happily.
You're staying
with him tonight, yes?
I'm on duty, so...
If you need me, I'm...
Thanks.
-Bye.
Excuse me, sorry.
-It's OK. -Good night.
Excuse me?
-Yes.
Is Ehud here?
-He's in a recording session.
When can I see him?
-Do you have an appointment?
Kind of.
He told me to come today.
He's in a session,
come back in two hours.
Call before, just in case.
Hello. Take bus no. 18...
Can't you ask him?
I came all the way from Haifa.
Sorry, he's in a session.
Is there somewhere I can wait?
Then come by bus...
-If you see him, tell him
that I'm waiting for him
over there, OK? Thanks.
Sima, one with avocado.
-Excuse me, darling.
Put it on "The Widows" tab.
One beer.
-One mint tea.
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
Did you do this yourself?
Looks nice.
You've got talent.
Did anyone ever tell you
you've got talent?
Yes, you.
What else can you do?
Nothing.
Then what are you doing here?
You wanted to hear me sing.
Come here.
Would you have recorded
the song without me?
Maya, how much longer
can I wait for you?
As long as it takes.
Dr. Goldman? -Are you
going to sleep for awhile?
No, I have to go look
for my daughter.
Would you mind
taking over for me,
I'll be back in a few hours?
-Sure.
I'll give you my number, call me
if something's wrong.
No problem.
Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Mikush, it's the middle of the
night, why aren't you asleep?
I can't finish work if you keep
calling me every five minutes.
For Gods sake, Mikush, put on
your pajamas, a CD and go to sleep.
I love you.
Really?
Then I love you millions.
Then I love you billions,
all the stars and the sky
and the moon and
all eternity too.
OK, darling.
OK, bye.
These nights do me in. Want some?
-No thanks.
The lyrics are yours,
aren't they?
And the music?
-Both of ours.
He's good.
Is he your boyfriend?
Kind of.
Did you write it about him?
-No, I wrote it about my dad.
Really? Lucky him.
He's dead.
-What?
He was stung by a bee and died.
Funny, isn't it?
No. Didn't he know he was allergic?
He knew.
Then what happened?
On our way back from the beach
I had to pee, so we stopped
on the way.
That's when he got stung.
Didn't he have an injection
with him? -He did.
Then how?
I went really far
because I was afraid people
could see me from the road and...
when I came back...
Did this happen
a long time ago?
I don't know.
Is nine months a long time?
Still have so much to say to you
Every day there's more to tell
Dreaming, I'm little now
Fading away every passing day
And I just have
one thing to tell you
That you are further
and further away
Further and further away
Now that you are
A blurred memory
Everything here
Looks like an animated film
Still have so much to say to you
There's another crisis every day
I have no strength left in me
But you can't hear anymore
Can't hear anymore...
I know you don't do anything
for the first 24 hours,
but she's 17.
Do you know what can happen to
a 17 year-old girl in 24 hours?
Can't you announce her name
on your walkie-talkie,
that she's missing?
Fine, don't do anything, OK?
Ido.
Ido, I'm asking you to wake up.
Ido, I'm talking to you,
I'm asking you to wake up,
I know you can hear me.
Ido, I'm asking you to wake up!
Dafna, what are you doing?
-I have to wake him up.
He's not asleep, he's in a coma.
It's dangerous, stop it.
Don't tell me what's dangerous,
he's my son.
Do you have something
that could wake him up?
Maybe some...
Trick you learned
in California?
Dr. Goldman?
Valentin?
Do you see me?
Press the red button.
You are going to get
a dunk on your face.
Who taught Jordan
everything he knows?
Who taught Jordan basketball?
Dad! Let me!
There you go!
Give it, Dad.
-Here.
Hello?
-Hey, Skeleton, where are you?
Don't call me Skeleton, dummy.
Are you OK?
No.
Did something happen to you?
Then what's wrong?
-Nothing.
If nothing is wrong
then something must be right.
Don't be so smart, Yair.
I don't know you anymore.
Where are you?
Alone.
Tell me where you are
and I'll come, OK? -No.
Why?
Because Mom doesn't
want to see me.
Mom's here waiting,
she looked all over for you.
Maya, tell me where you are
and I'll come, OK?
But Yair,
it could be worse, right?
What could be worse?
This shitty life,
it could be worse?
It could be worse.
And about Dad too,
it could be worse, right?
Yes, it could be worse.
It really could be worse.
Right?
Where are you, sis?
Tell me where you are
and I'll come.
I want Mom.
You want to talk to Mom?
Not to talk,
I want her to come.
Bahri.
Bhari.
What?
-Come on, get up.
Come on, get up.
What happened?
-Lets go wake up Ido.
I didn't wet my bed. -It's OK,
you'll wet it tomorrow.
My foot fell asleep.
Sleep, baby.
The fans are going wild!
Yair Ulman has the ball,
he passes, it's in!
Yes!
Twelve seconds to go,
Ulman has the ball.
He turns around, yes!
40,000 spectators
are going wild!
He goes in. Yes!
Who was that?
-Valentin.
What happened?
-Ido woke up.
Everything's OK.
I'm a terrible mother, Maya.
-No, you're not.
I'm a terrible mother.
I turned the engine off.
I'm sick of this crappy car,
I'm so sick of it.
Let's call a tow truck.
-It costs as much as the car.
Come on, push.
-I'm pushing.
Gimme five.
High-five.
Not a chance...
I'm fed up with this car.