Zentropa Entertainments 14
presents...
A film by
Susanne Bier
I will always love you.
That is the only truth
that remains.
Life is neither right nor wrong,
good or bad.
But I love you.
That's all I know.
BROTHERS
We leave in 14 hours.
This is the last thing
I'll be saying to you on Danish soil.
I know that some of you
are going for the first time.
You won't encounter anything
you haven't been trained for.
If any of you doubt that we're doing
the right thing, wait til we get there.
Then you'll know we're doing
the right thing. Okay?
See you tonight.
Hi there.
Don't do that.
Stop it.
You are such a pain, man!
New wheels.
Looks pretty nice.
- Can I drive?
- No.
- Can I smoke in the car?
- Smoke... Smoke away, man.
Smoke, smoke.
- So there's dinner tonight?
- Mum and dad are coming at five.
She hesitated between roast duck
for you and meat loaf for me.
Go figure. Where did she get
the idea that duck is my favourite?
Or that meat loaf is mine?
I hate it.
- So we agreed on duck for you.
- Why doesn't she just make spaghetti?
There's something I think you should
consider when you have the time.
What?
- What the hell is this?
- It's the woman you assaulted.
- I know. Why do I need her card?
- She's back at her branch now.
I don't give a shit.
Where the hell did you get her card?
I spoke with her a couple of times.
I apologized on your behalf.
Who the fuck do you think you are?
It's none of your business.
She couldn't work for six months.
You've completely ruined her life.
Jannik, stay here. Jannik!
Jannik, what the hell
are you doing? Jannik!
- You can't park there.
- Sorry! My mistake.
Jannik!
Sorry.
Idiot.
- Is dad here?
- Yes.
- They're really beautiful.
- Wanker.
Hello, mum.
- You're so thin.
- I've put on weight.
Nonsense. It's a good thing
I've roasted two huge ducks.
- Oh... We're having roast duck?
- Of course. It's your favourite.
- Are we ready here?
- Will you get the duck?
- Hi.
- Thanks.
- They're from the service station.
- Hi, dad.
- Hi.
"How can you care for someone
so ugly and stupid?"
- Do I have to have potatoes?
- Take two. Give her two, dad.
Here you go.
Two small ones.
I want to get a picture of this.
It's so seldom we're all together.
Smile for your Gran.
You too, Jannik.
- What time are you leaving?
- At twelve.
We wanted to take
you out to lunch.
- We would have more time together.
- We're here now, aren't we?
Your mum still finds it strange that
she never sees her two sons together.
- It's not my fault Michael's leaving.
- Leaving? He's going to work.
There's a difference between
rebuilding a country and jail.
What are you talking about?
They shoot at anything that moves.
- A group of women again, right?
- They all look alike.
- It's those dresses they wear.
- Burkhas.
Alright, alright.
More...?
That's why Sarah wears jeans.
Michael shoots anything in a dress.
- They only shoot the bad guys.
- Do you know the difference, Natalia?
They only shoot the bad
guys, right, Jannik? Relax.
- That kitchen still bothers me.
- We'll survive.
I wanted to finish it before I left.
It's a mess.
You can't cook
properly in that kitchen.
- We'll just order pizza.
- Live on pizza for three months?!
Of course we can.
Shut up about that kitchen!
Cheers.
Have a good trip, son.
- Oh, right, have a good trip.
- Cheers, darling.
It's a good one.
Really good.
- Oh, there they are.
- I really hate that you're leaving.
You'll have the house to yourself.
You can make all the mess you like.
Can't you just stay home?
I love you.
Dad's leaving now.
Don't.
Is it cold or hot in Afghanistan?
- It's a little bit cold.
- Last time it was hot.
Warm here means it's warm there.
Cold here means it's cold there.
Won't you be home for my birthday?
That's not until February.
Give me a kiss.
- Don't!
- Natalia...!
Just leave.
I don't care.
- Give me a hug.
- No.
- A kiss on the cheek?
- I want to watch the film.
- Two kisses on the cheek?
- Just go.
- Three kisses? A hundred?
- Stop it.
That's two against one!
Not there. That's not fair.
What's going on?
Kanstrup and his men were
fired upon while scouting.
Their radar operator was left behind.
Niels Peter Johansen.
He can barely wipe his own ass
without help.
Settle in first. I'll send you out
tonight to look for him.
It's good to see you.
- Hi, Sarah.
- Hi there. Hello?
- Hi. I've arrived.
- Did you call before?
No connection.
I'll make it fast.
Just say that you love me.
That you miss me.
With all the new nurses here?
Are you crazy?
Give the children
a hug from me. Hello
Sarah, are you there?
I just mean that it's
pretty shitty, isn't it?
- Copy, Féborg. Change the record.
- There must be some hookers here.
I can't NOT fuck for 6 months
just because they're Muslims.
Stop that redneck crap, or hookers
will be the least of your problems.
Féborg is actually a big town.
- I decide that. Understood?
- All I'm saying is
- Hi. ls your mother home?
- She's in the bath.
- Mum!
- May we come in?
- Some people want to talk to you.
- Coming.
Come on, girls.
Go watch the film.
Okay, relax.
Sorry, sorry.
I know, I know.
I completely forgot.
I had a flat
or I thought I had a flat.
Are you drunk? Are you driving
around drunk in our car?
Relax.
It's not that serious, is it?
Why are you still up?
Did you talk to Henning and Else?
No, not since I left school,
but that was a really good chat.
Hold on.
Michael lent me the car.
You don't need to stand there
looking so pissed off.
Or look like
You know what I mean.
- I have a taxi coming in a minute
- Michael is dead.
- What?
- They crashed.
What ...?
What are you ...?
What are you telling me?
He's dead, Jannik.
Won't you come in?
No, I don't want to come in.
Sorry, but
What is this...?
I come here to drop off
Why the hell didn't you call me?
We've been trying
to reach you all day.
I'm going home to my mum.
Jannik.
- What are you doing?
- I'm organizing these records.
I found the Beatles record
in the Mozart piano concerto cover.
No wonder I can't find anything.
Michael is dead.
Yes.
Natalia, are you ready?
- Where's your dress?
- It's ugly.
Put it on, Natalia.
We have to go.
I don't want to.
Then I don't want to wear
mine either. It's itchy.
Come here.
Is dad really dead
like your mum and dad?
Yes.
I don't want to wear
this crappy dress.
Sarah.
I just want you to know
that if there's anything I can do...
I knew it could happen.
I've known that all along.
We've even talked about it
many times -
- but I don't believe
that he's dead.
I can't feel it.
Don't you think I'd sense it somehow?
Come on, girls. Come on.
- Dad, shouldn't I drive?
- Get in, girls.
- Why should you?
- You've been drinking.
Who do you think you are, brat?!
Come on, girls.
- Let me.
- When did you become so responsible?
Let Jannik drive.
When you manage to get a job,
then you'll have money to buy a car.
Then you can drive all you like.
Until then, I drive.
Could you try not to be so such
a fucking asshole just for today?
That in there
that was my boy.
He is gone now.
lam left with nothing.
Do you understand that?
Do you?
Jannik...
- Are you a complete idiot?
- He's just acting out as always.
- Let's go.
- Give me the keys, and I'll drive.
Give me the keys!
I don't know what the hell's
got into everybody.
Right, move over
and make room for Grandad.
Niels Peter?
lam Michael Lundberg,
and I'm a major.
Are you okay? Are you well?
Did they mistreat you?
- Hello.
- Hi, it's Jannik.
Hi I'm sorry to call you
at two in the morning.
It's four o'clock.
Okay.
I'm in this bar with no money.
I happened to buy
some beers and
Sweetie...
I have to go somewhere.
You're just insecure because
your nose is the size of Funen.
Hey, Sarah! Say hello to The Nose.
The Nose has closed the bar.
- How much does he owe you?
- 435. And two broken glasses.
- Keep the change.
- Get him out, or I'll call the police.
Relax! You're just grumpy
because you have a big nose.
- That's enough of that.
- Are you going to sneeze now?
Let's cover the bar with a tarp.
Sneeze coming on! It could get ugly.
If you show your face here again,
you'll get your ass kicked.
- Let me touch it.
- Piss off!
You're such an idiot.
Didn't he have a huge nose?
Wasn't it big?
You have to admit that.
It was huge.
When we were kids, Michael
always beat up the ones I pissed off.
Did you call because of the bar tab,
or because you missed Michael?
I never fucking
missed anyone before.
I really miss him.
I really do.
So much
that my stomach hurts.
What a pile of shit.
Sony
The light is green.
Oh no, I dropped it.
I'll make another one...
- Try again.
- You have to do it like this.
We'll throw it to mum.
Oops! It almost went
into the bedroom.
- Hi. Why are you sleeping here?
- It's hard to catch them.
We're making pancakes for mum
so she won't be so sad.
- It's because our dad is dead.
- He knows. He's his brother.
- It hit the ceiling.
- Just spread the jam on the ceiling.
No drinking from the carton!
- Shut up and make your pancakes.
- Want one?
- I don't like pancakes.
- You don't know that.
- Eat your own crap.
- Good-morning.
- Up already?
- We're making pancakes.
One of the pancakes landed
on the shelf up there.
Grandpa's here!
Grandad!
There's pancakes, Grandad!
- Hi, Henning.
- Good-morning, Sarah.
Come on, girls.
Grandpa's waiting.
- Hi.
- Are you having pancakes?
- No. You want one?
No thanks. Listen
I was a little stupid the other day,
but I was okay to drive.
We were both a bit
Okay. It was good to talk things
through properly, anyway.
Is there any coffee?
Dad
I know Michael was always better
at the things men should be good at.
- Football and things like that.
- Yes, he was good at that.
It's because you always give up.
Michael never gave up.
No, I know that.
I've always looked up to Michael -
- but he's gone and it isn't my fault.
I'm really sorry about it.
Yes, but that's the way it is.
Isn't there any coffee?
- Jesus, dad
- Don't you start like your mother!
You can't change the past. You can't
whine about something that's over.
I just want peace and quiet!
Understand?
I don't want to listen
to any more bullshit!
If you want to do
something worthwhile -
- then start by fixing up this
goddamned kitchen. It looks awful!
- Kitchen time!
- Boring colours!
Check that one out.
- That's a big one, Preben.
- You don't see that around often.
I bet the owner
did a spot of DIY.
Hi.
This is Preben One...
Preben Two.
This is Slobodan.
- I'm changing to Preben.
- Coffee?
- No thanks. Maybe a beer.
- Let's start with some beers.
Take your jackets off, girls.
- Can I help?
- What?
- Why don't you just watch TV?
- Please!
- Alright. You can paint up here.
Get up there.
Shit!
What the hell are you doing?!
- Sorry.
- You ruined my trousers.
You little bandit.
- What happened?
- I dropped the paint.
- Where's the toilet?
- Stay there a second, please.
What are you laughing at?
You've ruined my clothes.
- You hardly notice it. I can't see it.
- Of course you do.
- What the hell are you staring at?
- You have a lovely body, Preben.
Shut your mouth.
Do you work out?
Your socks are pretty cool, too.
- You're so fucking funny.
- Here you go. I think they'll fit you.
A t-shirt and trousers are fine.
Take it all.
- I don't need all that.
- There's more.
You don't have to do that.
She doesn't have to give me all that.
Why don't you take it all?
Please take it.
- I don't have to bring it back?
- No, just take it.
- Why don't we call it a day?
- Yes, of course.
You know the bank, right ...?
You know about the robbery?
Michael wanted me to go
and see the lady and apologize.
Of course he did.
Well, the day after that
memorial service for him -
- I went down there
and said I was sorry.
At first she was scared
and they wanted to throw me out.
Then they let me talk to her.
- What did she say?
- She didn't say much.
She'd had counseling and hadn't
slept properly in three years.
She dreamt that I would
come back and shoot her.
When I said that she shouldn't
be afraid of me anymore -
- and that I wouldn't harm her,
she started to cry.
She was so happy
that she hugged me.
I opened an account with her.
It's true.
I know he's gone.
I know he's never coming back.
Happy birthday to mum
- Thank you.
- Now blow out the candles.
- I couldn't.
- Four boyfriends!
It's very impressive.
Did you make it yourselves?
- Gran helped us.
- No, I didn't.
- Don't lie to them, Else.
- Will you be working full time?
- Oh, yes! Jannik's got a job.
- A job?
I'm helping Preben Two
fix things...
You got a job?
That won't last long.
Preben Two? ls that
a company name? Preben Two?
- Whispers tell lies...
- Don't you want some cake first?
- Mum, come on.
- We broke something.
I was playing with it,
and then I stepped on it.
- Well, well
- I'll eat that ugly cake, then.
Gran will make sure he doesn't
touch it before you're back.
- Happy birthday!
- A bicycle!
It was the girls' idea.
- Isn't it nice?
- It's lovely.
It has a giraffe on it
that Camilla chose.
- Aren't you lovely, girls!
- Can we have cake now?
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
- Hi.
I just wanted to put the last
of the fillets on.
Okay.
- Where are the girls?
- They're sleeping.
You know what... I'm sorry...
I shouldn't have kissed you.
- No, it was me
- It was stupid.
Don't worry
Alright then
I'll just put these in place.
We just miss Michael so much.
The others miss him too.
Of course they miss him, but...
Right
I always thought you were
a stupid bastard.
And I thought you were
a boring, middle-class bitch.
I don't want to ruin anything.
I just want to keep coming here.
You can come here all you want.
Hell, you can have a key.
I'd rather have one for the car, then.
- What's going on?
- Quiet.
Show us how to arm this.
- I said show us how to arm this.
- I don't know anything about this.
Are you sure you don't know how?
I know how to do this.
I can show you.
Let him go
and I'll show you.
Show us again,
slowly this time.
Let him go.
And give him water.
He needs water.
We both do.
And perhaps he would like some
Coca-Cola and air-conditioning too?
He needs water.
We both need water.
Take the battery
Take off protection cap
open the sight-
- release the safety catch.
Release the gyro.
You hear a high-pitched tone -
- and when it get's constant,
you elevate -
- and you pull the trigger.
- Will they come and get us?
- They'll come and get us.
Why don't they come, then?
Stop crying-
All you do is lose body fluid.
Alright?
They're going to kill us.
If they wanted to kill us,
they would have done it by now.
Why are they keeping us here?
I keep thinking about Ditte.
And little Gustav.
I just want to
I just want to hold him again soon.
- I don't want to die.
- You won't.
- Why don't they find us, then?
- They will.
- You have to keep a level head.
- I'm not like you guys.
I haven't trained for any of this.
I'm just a radar technician.
I can't do all this stuff.
We'll get out of here.
I promise you.
You don't think we're going to die?
Yes, I do.
But not here.
Look at me.
We'll make it.
We'll make it alright.
To live, you must be of use.
He's of no use.
Kill him.
You're a brave man.
- Kill him or you both die.
- Michael...!
Do you want to live?
Yes.
I want to live.
Do it!
Do it now!
Come on!
Now!
Do it!
Again!
Do it now!
Do it!
Again!
Don't move!
Get down!
Hello.
Can you hear me?
Captain David Ward,
British Army.
- What's your name?
- Michael Lundberg.
- And where are you from?
- Denmark.
- What's your rank?
- Major.
- I want to speak to my wife.
- Yes. Yes, of course.
How were you treated
in the camp?
- Well... I'm alive.
- Yes, sir. You were lucky.
Did you have any contact
with the other captives?
- What do you mean?
- You must have seen them.
I'm sorry we have to do this but I have
some photos of men missing in action -
- I'd like you to look at.
These photo also contain
non-British nationals.
We just need to know
if you've seen any of these men.
No. I'm sorry.
You're certain you've never
seen these faces?
No. I'm sorry.
Well, thank you, sir.
Now get some rest.
- You've earned it.
- Thank you.
Michael!
Jesus, it's good to see you!
Likewise.
I want to talk to my wife.
Why can't I talk to her?
Has something happened to her?
We thought you were all dead.
You've been declared dead.
Have I?
All we knew was that you crashed.
What does my epitaph say?
I hope Jannik didn't write it.
- Up you go. Are you drunk?
- No, you're drunk!
You look plastered to me.
How much did you drink?
Sarah speaking. Yes?
- I want it!
- Don't do that.
- I want to throw it
- Throw it! Go on!
- Natalia, what happened?
- What did you do to my sister?
You're too easy!
What's wrong?
Hi, dad.
- Don't cry now.
- I'm not crying.
- Who will get there first?
- I will.
You have to see the kitchen, dad.
Come on, quickly.
- Look what we made for you.
- Jesus Who did this?
Jannik and the three little pigs.
- Did Jannik do this?
- Yes, and some carpenters.
- Are you hungry?
- No, thanks.
What are you doing?
What's he doing?
What's going on?
Can't we just lie here on the bed
for a while? All of us.
Come on.
- How long do we have to lie here?
- Just a little while longer.
Can I go watch TV?
- Just stay a little longer.
- Okay.
Is dad dead again already?
- He's just sleeping.
- You can't die more than once.
- Yes, you can.
- No, you bloody well can't.
- Hi, Michael.
- Can I talk to you in private?
Of course.
We'll go down to the office.
- Are you managing alright?
- Sure.
I wasn't alone at the camp.
I saw Niels Peter.
We were in the same camp.
I didn't think you had
any contact with others.
But it's good
you remembered it.
Yes.
He were in the same camp.
I---
It can be difficult to remember
what happened.
- What?
- Sit down, Michael.
Michael, when we find out what took
place, I'll pass on the information.
Just take it easy.
Give yourself some time...
Then your memory
will come back to you.
I'm better than I thought.
Thank you for taking care of Sarah
and the girls. I didn't expect that.
- But of course.
- I mean it. I'm proud of you.
Yes, of course.
It suddenly made sense, right?
I want to ask you something.
I know it sounds far out.
I don't mind if you have.
Did you sleep with her?
- What?
- With Sarah.
I can forgive you.
I just want to know.
- I mean, you thought I was dead.
- But we didn't.
What the ...?
Of course we haven't. Michael
- I can forgive you.
- We haven't.
- What makes you think that?
- You look like teenagers in love.
Come on! You used to be pissed off
because I couldn't stand her.
Now that I've found out how nice
and lovely she is, is that wrong, too?
- No, no.
- Then don't say things like that.
She's way too old for me anyway.
Shall we ...?
Tobias is stupid, but Arnold is nice.
He never hits people.
- He never hits people?
- No, just the small boys. Not girls.
He's the best at maths,
and he's got a dog with big ears.
- I can't remember its name.
- Elephant?
It's not a dog, is it?
An elephant is not a dog.
- It was only a joke.
- But it's not funny. ls it?
Sitting there talking nonsense!
Michael, relax.
It's alright.
Don't be afraid.
And don't be sad.
The girls have taken a fancy
to Jannik, haven't they?
- He said he's slept here.
- Yes, a few times.
- Did he sleep in here?
- Of course he didn't.
You could have fallen
for each other.
- You thought I was dead.
- No, we couldn't have.
- You look so cute together.
- Stop it.
- Did you sleep with him?
- Michael, stop it.
- You slept with him.
- Michael, nothing happened.
We kissed.
We were just confused.
- What else?
- That's it.
Let go.
Let me go!
Let me go! Let me go
What the hell is wrong with you?!
What the hell are you doing?!
You're crazy!
All of you! Crazy!
Don't be afraid of me.
Your hair looks nice.
Did mum do this?
- Natalia did.
- Did you?
Yes.
Don't be afraid of me.
Alright?
I'm sorry that I shouted
and did all those silly things.
But I love you.
Very much.
Both of you.
Don't be sad. Don't cry.
I want you to be happy.
I want us all to be happy.
Promise me
that you'll both be happy.
Do you know this one? What is white
in the air and yellow on the ground?
An egg.
- Have I told you that one?
- A hundred times.
Is that right?
A hundred times?
- Shall I push you?
- Yes, please.
Michael
We have to talk about this.
Can't you tell me what happened?
- Nothing happened.
- Oh, come on.
Can't you tell me just a little bit?
- Tell me just a little bit.
- There is nothing to tell.
I sat in a dark room, thinking.
I thought about you all-
- and the time we broke up.
I drove over to your flat
to apologise -
- but you wouldn't let me in.
Come in!
- Ditte.
- Michael.
I'm glad you people call all the time,
even if there is no news.
As long as we don't hear anything,
there's still hope.
- Would you like some coffee?
- Yes, please.
Thank you.
I saw Niels Peter down there.
He was down there.
- Did you see him?
- We were in the same camp.
Why didn't he
come home with you?
He was moved to another camp.
That means he's still alive!
Yes
When he
He was moved to another camp,
but he was fine when I saw him.
He'll make it.
Would you like some cake?
We were together for a long time
and he told me about Gustav
and about you, of course.
He told me all sons of things.
- You're taking your driving test.
- I didn't pass.
No, he said you wouldn't
- He was very proud of Gustav.
- He really wanted a girl.
But when Gustav came along,
he was so pleased.
I'm sorry.
- Hi.
- Hello. This is Solvej. Sorry.
Solvej, my brother's wife Sarah.
Come on in.
- There you go.
- Do I look okay?
You look fantastic.
Come on in.
Sorry.
Hi.
This is Solvej and this is my dad
and my mum.
- This is my brother, Michael.
- Natalia is watching TV.
- This is Camilla, the birthday girl.
- Thank you so much.
We just met.
It happened so fast.
It's very nice to meet you.
Great!
- Where's the bathroom?
- Upstairs. I'll show you.
Taking a piss again?
Why don't you open it?
Where did you meet her?
At the Royal Library.
What do you think? In a bar.
- She certainly looks
- She seems quite nice.
Lovely, lovely.
Rationally ...! What are you
talking about? It's war.
Today people need therapy
when they fall off their bikes.
- They're soldiers and trained for it.
- Stop messing with that doll!
Maybe they're not trained
to see people get shot.
- What do you think they trained for?
- Yes, but...
- That doesn't make it nice, does it?
- Now Solvej has a point here.
- If it was nice everyone would do it.
- Stop it, Natalia!
Stop it, Natalia!
Eat up. You hardly touched it.
- I'm not hungry. I want to watch TV.
- Eat your dinner.
Camilla ate her dinner.
But then Camilla got the best doll.
I didn't get my bag.
- You'll eat your dinner.
- You don't decide shit around here!
- Couldn't you just stay dead?
- Natalia!
Why are you taking it out on me?
You're just pissed off because
mum would rather shag Jannik.
- What are you saying?
- You and Jannik shag all the time.
- That's enough!
- Disgusting!
Oh, stop it. She has no idea
what she's saying.
- Give me your plate.
- It's not true.
This is insane.
She's just upset.
How long were you
in India, Solvej?
- Four months.
- Did you ride elephants?
- That is so far out.
- Were you up north? It's beautiful.
- No, we didn't have time.
- Little bastard.
Who the hell do you think you are?
I forgot I have to meet
some friends, so
Sit down, all of you.
It's Camilla's birthday.
- Nobody is leaving.
- I don't think we need that tone
Oh, be quiet. You don't know
what Natalia has seen.
What does that matter?
It's difficult for all of us.
The important thing here
is Camilla's birthday.
- Yes, that's right!
- And we're celebrating that.
Mum ...!
_ Mum!
_ Shut up!
Mum.
- Why aren't you asleep?
- I can't sleep.
That was the worst birthday
in my entire life.
We'll have a new one.
I promise.
What are you playing at?
I'm sorry about what I said.
Why did you say it?
I don't like dad. I'd rather have
Jannik around instead of dad.
Me too.
Dad will be himself again soon.
Michael.
Get out of my way!
- Mum!
- Go up to your room. Now!
- Please stop.
- Do you realise what I did?
Do you realise what I did
to be with you?
You don't understand anything!
I'm going to fucking kill you!
Should I kill you?!
I'm going to kill you!
I'm going to kill all of you!
Jannik.
Michael's gone berserk. Hurry!
Come on down, girls.
Come on down.
The police, please.
I'm bloody well going to kill you!
I'm going to kill you all!
Sony
Don't cry.
I'm going to kill you!
Sarah. Sarah
- My little brother.
- Jannik.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Let's all sit down and talk about it.
- Sarah, go to the car.
- Go to your room!
- Stop it!
- Michael!
- Go upstairs again! Sarah!
Take the car keys!
What did you do?
You call that a punch?
Michael, Michael
Did you call the cops?!
- Did you call the cops?!
- Michael
Did you call the cops?!
Of course I didn't call the cops!
You idiot!
- Nothing happened.
- Stop there. Stop right there.
We got into a fight.
Nothing happened.
Stay down!
- Fuck, man! He took my gun.
- Drop the gun.
Drop it.
- Drop the gun, Michael.
- Then shoot me.
- Drop the gun!
- Come on!
- Shoot me, then.
- Shut up!
Come on!
You'll get a promotion.
Michael, drop the gun.
- Drop the gun.
- Who the hell are you?
Who the hell are you?
- Michael, for my sake.
- Shoot me.
Come on!
Shoot me!
- Put the gun down.
- Drop it!
- On the ground, both of you.
- On the ground.
- Get down!
- Michael, get down.
- Get down on your belly.
- Lie down on you belly, okay?
Michael...
Do it!
Arms stretched out!
Handcuff both of them.
Don't move.
- Hi.
Fuck...
He'll get off lightly.
He's never been in trouble before
and has a bag full of medals.
This is incredible. Oh, I should be
careful not to drop ashes in here.
- Let's clean this up.
- Yes.
I'll throw this out.
I will always love you.
That is the only truth that remains.
Life is neither right nor wrong,
good or bad.
But I love you.
That's all I know.
PRISON
Michael Lundberg, visitor for you.
She's waiting outside.
- Hi.
Visit number 00412.
- Do you want to walk or sit?
- Okay.
- Take a walk?
- Yes.
- Did you have your hair cut?
- No.
I'm wearing mascara.
That's right.
- You look good.
- Thanks.
This is from the girls.
- How are they?
- They're fine.
And mum and dad?
Michael
- I want to know what happened.
- No, you don't.
It doesn't concern you or anyone
else. It's my problem, alright?
If you don't tell me,
you'll never see me again.
Ever.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
He had a little boy.
Subtitles: Amalie Foss
Dansk Video Tekst