Delicious Vegan Sausages, Cheese
and Burgers - Vegusto.co.uk
Raquel, sensually yours.
I'm not telling
this story to apologize
or to explain the reason I left.
Especially because the only
people I wanted forgiveness from...
I left behind that night.
When my parents
woke up the next day,
I wasn't there any more.
Come in.
Sit down, kiddo.
What's up?
I called yesterday.
Raquel.
Oh, what a surprise!
You came to see the place?
Yeah, I figured I could stay,
lulu.
See how things work.
Let me look at you
Any experience?
Sit here, kiddo.
You're a pretty thing, huh...
It's all right, sweetie,
I'll let you stay.
We'll see how the month goes,
and then we'll get
your paperwork in order
Are you going to
sign work papers?
Sure, so you can
receive your benefits,
pension, Christmas bonus,
retirement fund...
Just kidding', silly.
The deal is simple: each
trick lasts one hour for R$100.
40 is yours and
60 goes to the house
If you change your sheets
too much, you'll pay for laundry.
- OK?
- OK.
Let's go meet the girls.
Did you choose that name, Raquel?
It's kind of lame, get another.
Let's go, sweetie.
Look at this woman's fake boobs
They don't even move.
- Let me see.
- Ila
Look at that!
We work the whole day.
We're open from 10 am to 10 pm. -mun
Rush hour is during the day.
Girls, she's going to replace Joyce.
Here you can wash your clothes,
get dressed, wait for a client...
The lockers are over
there, one for each girl.
Not much space,
but it's enough.
Thanks, honey.
You should all go to sleep,
tomorrow is the 10th,
our busiest day.
It always scared me spending
the night away from my home.
I'd want to leave in
the middle of the night.
Suddenly, I was somewhere
I didn't know very well,
sharing a room
with three call girls...
that I'd never seen before.
Which class do you have today?
Several, mom.
It's not just one.
Hey folks!
Good morning, son.
Let's go to the game on Sunday?
Yeah, sure.
Be careful, you're going to
get your clothes dirty.
Don't worry, mom,
she's already kind of dirty
Rodrigo!
Writing is a way of saying
what can't be said.
Revealing what we don't
like about ourselves.
Giving this to the reader
as an ugly gift,
that we give away
expecting nothing in return
Hey, class.
Gabriela and Lucian
are up next week.
Hey, did you get my text?
Yeah.
So, let's study at
my place today?
I don't know. I won't
be able to stay long.
It won't take long.
It'll be quick.
Hi.
Hi, I managed to show up.
I'm glad you're here
Let's go inside.
My room, Raquel. Raquel, my room.
Make yourself comfortable.
Should we study
the whole book or...
only the last two chapters?
I forgot my book at school.
No problem, we can
study with mine.
NI-m.
I want to kiss you.
We better study.
I can't stay for long.
I should be home.
Just a little kiss.
Come here.
Go.
- Do something for me.
- WI.
Come on.
Hm.
This is what you came for.
Enough! Get off!
You can't stop now.
You gonna leave me hanging?
Jerk!
Why don't you do
what you did to Felipe?
Blow me till I'm done.
You fucking nerd.
Honey, did you decide
on your school trip?
It's this weekend.
Have you talked to your father?
Everyone's going.
I still need to pay.
Let's change
the subject, Celeste?
- - As usual...
Have you thought about
studying, going to college?
Trying to become someone.
And now you're complaining,
"I'm not going on the school trip..."
- Rodrigo, please.
- Mom, I have to...
Let's change
the subject, Celeste
HI, RAQUEL, CHECK MY PROFILE,
I HAVE A LITTLE SURPRISE FOR YOU.
Yesterday, I HAD A GREAT TIME
STUDYING!
IF YOU WANT A STUDY PARTNER,
I RECOMMEND HER! LO
Asshole, son of a bitch.
- Raquel, have you...
- Can't you knock?
Have you seen the jewelry
your father gave me?
The ones from the wedding?
Yes, from our anniversary.
It must be in the closet.
That's where you keep them.
Raquel, are you sure
you don't know where it is?
No.
RAQUEL'S A COCKSUCKER
Ms. Larissa! Client!
No need to yell,
I see who comes in.
Remember, sweetie, my monitor?
Look who's still alive.
It's been a while.
Honey, get up there.
Now look what
a coincidence, Hudson
A pretty little thing just arrived,
that you'll really like.
Tell us, how did you
end up in this joint?
'Cause you sure don't
look like a call girl.
If you tell me you're a virgin.
I'll believe you.
Ms. Larissa said
she is coming up.
Client or complaint?
It's that nice guy that
hasn't shown up in a while.
Girls.
These stairs kill me.
You, client.
Hurry up, honey.
I don't have all day.
Girls, fix yourselves up,
you're looking worn out.
Come, sweetie, get down there.
Hi.
I'm Hudson.
Hi, Hudson.
What's your name?
Brunei.
What?
How old are you, Brunei?
I'm 18.
It's your first trick, isn't it?
It is, here.
Calm down. Relax.
Come here, sit down.
Stand up.
Lay down
I didn't cry.
I didn't ask to stop.
I didn't run back
to my parents' house.
At that moment, Raquel,
the Raquel I once was,
was dead.
Can I leave this here to wash?
Leave it with the others.
Oh, My God!
Barbie, when you open
the tap, the shower goes cold.
Go wash your
undies somewhere else
Hurry up in there, Janine.
Want a fix, cutie?
Let's get dressed,
we got clients.
Just like any other job,
the secret was knowing
how to sell yourself.
I'm Mel, I suck real good.
Hi, Mel.
I'm Janine, how you doing?
Better now.
Hi, I'm Brunei and I'll do
whatever you want.
At first, I didn't know
how to be sexy,
how to be desired.
I never imagined someone
would pay to be with me.
On the first week,
I had about 30 guys.
That's more than most
women fuck in their entire lives.
Earn 5000 Raise a month
giving massage.
This is what the ad said.
It sounded like the
easiest job in the world,
but it wasn't.
But what I made
working there...
was more than double
my brother's income.
It was more than those
preppy school girls...
would earn with a diploma.
Girls, introductions in room 3
Mel and Janine, go.
Brunei, you can rest
Come on, girls.
Larissa, if you want
I can go again.
If I keep this up,
how much can I earn a month?
Sweetie, a lot more than a
saleswoman behind the counter.
Now, please buy
some sexier outfits.
Those rags you wear
I like this one.
Those are granny panties.
There are some
great blouses over here
Let me see.
It looks great.
I don't know...
We beat you 3 nil, bro.
That's Brunei.
Fuck, man, she's hot.
For real!
"I"
No, we can chat upstairs.
I can call the other
girls for your friend.
No, I want you
Let's go upstairs?
OK.
- Wait here.
- What else can I do?
The girls said that in the beginning
every newcomer did well.
But while they talked about me,
I was making a name for myself.
I have to confess,
I loved being the
most popular girl in school.
Oh, .fuck.
Yum.
That feels good.
Hi.
I'm Brunei
Gustavo.
"- Let's go upstairs?- pl
- Come in.
- Excuse me.
Please come back.
I will.
When you go downstairs to pay,
tell them this one is on me.
- Lily'?
- This one is the house.
I'm fed up with this shit.
Barbie is hogging all the clients.
Let the girl earn her money
Are you jealous?
I'm not jealous!
I have a son to raise.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
There's something
we don't know about her.
There sure is.
Hi, I'm Brunei.
I'm Rodrigo.
Remember?
Remember me, Brunei?
I'm Celeste and Mr. Otto's son,
that great naive couple,
who adopted that ugly little girl,
believing she could be someone.
And look at what she turned into,
a whore.
- You are a whore.
- What are you doing here?
I should ask you.
What are you doing here?
You whore.
My mother loves you.
Their life turned into a living hell
They keep blaming
each other and here you are
spreading your legs
for a hundred raise!
I'm going to scream!...
Is it money you want?
Take it!
Now stay away from my family.
I'll tear you apart,
so help me God.
Slut. You piece of shit.
Stay away.
Alright?
Brunei...
Whore.
I don't know why,
but for some reason,
I thought! was doing that
because I loved my parents.
It was never something
I did to hurt them,
I just wanted them to
feel something for me.
Longing, shame,
Of even anger.
Hello?
Raquel!
Is that you, Raquel?
Raquel?
Hi.
You are not well today.
What's the matter?
Everything's OK, Hudson
Hudson.
I'm a working girl.
If things are fine
with you, then I feel great
No, I don't want
to have sex today.
Today I want you to smoke.
Go over by the window.
I want to look at you.
Don't look at me.
Can I tell you a secret?
Is it what I'm thinking?
You were my very first client.
Is that what you were thinking?
No. I thought you were
going to tell me your name.
You know my name
It's Brunei.
Tell me your name, come on
My name is Brunei.
Pour me some coffee, hon.
The next client is all yours.
It's time for
you to haul a man.
Let's go to my office,
you'll put on some perfume
and go to the reception.
Let's go. -
Grab my cigarettes.
What about the diary?
Have you been writing?
Yeah.
Want a cigarette?
No, thanks.
Fuck! I can't believe it!
Someone stole my stuff!
Who was it?!
Are you nuts?
- It was you, wasn't it?
- What are you talking about?
- Maybe you misplaced it?
- Someone broke into my locker.
They took
my jewelry, my money- W
Maybe you deserve it...
What do you mean,
you jealous bitch?
Everyone knows
who you really are.
I don't steal from anybody.
I'm gonna kick your ass
I'm not stupid.
- What's going on?
- Brunei’s locker was broken into.
Everything I had was stolen.
- I'm going to call the cops
- Are you insane?
What's going on?
I.-1" SHI’ITE-I.
Larissa, look at me.
I swear on my son.
I didn't steal anything.
She says she didn't
take it. Enough.
The show's over. Scatter.
- - Who does she think she is?
- Be quiet.
What do you want me
to do? Let it slide?
I told you, Janine
has a short fuse.
She'll do anything for
a client, but she's not a thief.
Who else would want
to screw me?
Don't run away,
I'm talking to you.
'Wig?
Where's my money?
What money?
I didn't take anything.
Are you insane?
You're fucked if
you don't tell me.
Say it! Say it!
I didn't take anything.
I'll have to hurt you.
Where is my money?
Say it. bitch!
I don't want to hurt you.
I'm not a preppy
idiot. Tell me.
I'm sorry
I spent it all on coke.
I'm pathetic. Sorry.
You'll pay me back.
I'm not an idiot.
You will pay me.
You hear me?
Fucking junkie!
Piss off, you wanna-be slut.
What are you writing?
A letter to my son
What do you want with me?
I want to apologize.
I'm sorry for accusing you.
I know it wasn't you.
Listen up,
I've starved,
couldn't send money home,
but I've never stolen anything.
I'm apologizing.
You girls think I'm a stupid
prom queen on vacation.
But for me it's hard
as hell to be here too.
I respect all of you.
I want to be respected as well.
Alright.
People think call girls
work at night,
But the truth is we're
busier during the day.
I never stopped.
When I closed the door, I didn't
want to be just another fuck.
I wanted to be the
highlight of that guy's day.
I didn't discriminate.
Call girls don't choose.
I treated everyone well,
I guess that was my secret.
Sometimes, knowing that
a client wanted me,
was worth more than the money.
It was weird thinking
that while they were there,
their wives were at work
or cooking at home.
But even this became
a subject in bed.
Each of them was a trip,
another story for me to tell.
There was a guy who liked
to show me how big he was.
Biggest one you
ever seen, right?
Another one paid to
move furniture around.
Now... the bed goes over there!
It was all he could do, poor guy.
- Is it good over here?
- I want to look out that way
Put the stool on that side.
It will look great!
But the funniest
client, was Mr. Powder.
Go on up, dear.
He almost poisoned us
with all that baby powder.
Hey, Janine, Powder digs you.
There were many strange guys,
but for some reason,
I pleased them all.
Seven out often guys
wanted Brunei.
Brunei,
now that you're experienced,
tell us, what do men like?
Every man likes something different.
Men like to make women cum.
If you moan just right,
even if you fake it, they go crazy
If the guy realizes you're
doing it for money,
he's not coming back.
- Right, Janine?
- Moan for us.
Moan so that we
can hear Barbie moaning
Let's find out how
you get so many clients
Moan! I want to see
if you're a professional.
- Moan, goddammit.
- Moan, come on. It's easy
Sometimes you take in
a breath, like this...
Stop it.
Moan, girl!
Could you tone it down a bit,
the customers are complaining.
The customers?
And what are we?
I'm asking with all due
respect for you to keep it down
I'm not keeping it down.
I'm a customer and
I'll talk the way I want.
I think you're losing
your temper for nothing.
Be honest, you don't
serve prostitutes here.
Madam, if you keep
screaming I'll call security.
Take your hands off me.
Let's go, girls, we're leaving.
You got a problem?
- How much do I owe you?
- You don't have to pay.
I'm going to pay.
Listen up, ladies,
while you complain
about other people's lives,
we have an appointment
with your husbands.
If you want to learn something,
here's my business card.
This is bullshit.
Go fuck yourselves.
What was that?
Screw your customers!
Leave it over there.
My nails look terrible.
Why did you pay?
Why did you waste
all that money?
Shit.
It didn't smear that much.
I was watching you
on the dance floor...
You rocked, girl.
What's your name?
Brunei.
Pleasure. I'm Carol.
I'm with friends in the VIP area
that would love to meet you.
VIP area?
Guys, this is Brunei.
Nice to meet you, Brunei.
How are you?
Never seen you here
before, Brunei. First time?
What do you work with, Brunei?
Sex.
I want to talk with my friend.
We're waiting for
you outside. Let's go?
Hey, Brunei
Give me a call,
I'd love to see you again.
Here's something for
you to remember me by.
We're leaving.
Bye. You better go
cause she's stressed out.
Oh, fuck. Turn it off.
Shit, the cops.
My registration's expired,
everything is fucked.
- Good evening.
License, please.
Just a second.
Damn it. I left it at home.
Everything is in my other purse.
At least give me the
vehicle's registration.
I left it all there, man.
I'll have to seize your
vehicle and your license.
Let it slide, man.
There are only women here.
"Let it slide?"
Officer, can I have
a quick word with you?
A quick word?
What's she going to do?
I can't believe it.
Look!
I'm shocked.
He fell for it.
Barbie scored the cop.
Our princess had a quickie.
We're good to go.
Me and my girlfriend,
Were holding each other tight,
She turns to me and says,
Would some wine be alright?
Next thing I know,
She has lost her mind,
Now everyone is looking'
At my princess' behind!
She's a goner, dancing' crazy,
Morin' across the? oor,
I'm standing' here like a fool,
Trying' hard to ignore,
But she keeps getting' down and dirty,
Shaking' it from bottom to top,
She goes up, she gets down,
My princess just can't stop!
She goes up, she gets down...
Oh, God... My head
Jesus, major hangover...
I think I'm still drunk.
What's gotten into you?
Are you deaf?
I'm ringing the damn bell
and no one showed up.
And what about this dirty table?
Kelly!
Got wasted last night, huh?
Whoever not ready in
five minutes is getting fined.
What about sleeping beauty?
Where is she?
Jesus Christ.
There are no clean sheets.
There's nothing I can do.
The laundry isn't back yet.
You expect me to
work on cum-stained sheets?
Turn them over.
You've slept more than worked,
so they can't be that stained.
Alright then.
When the next client arrives,
I'll fuck him on the floor.
You're starting to
piss me off, you little bitch
Punk.
How much longer, Carol?
At least another 45 minutes.
- 46!?
- Dmlnnl
I have to be careful
not to get ugly again.
Don't get paranoid, sugar.
You look great.
By the way, Miguel called me.
He spoke highly of you.
I'm going to introduce
you to some high rollers.
Just like your sugar daddy,
with an allowance every month?
Soon you'll score a man who'll
pay for your vacation, benefits...
III
Don't even say it.
I ran away so that I
wouldn't depend on anyone
Now, honestly,
that friend of yours Gabi...
just won't do. She's cheap
She's too ghetto.
You're at another level.
- I'm playing for keeps.
- You're picking up all my cards
I'm playing for real.
I want to win this cash.
Listen up, girls.
I want everyone's attention.
If you want to fuck up
your nose snorting, go ahead
But not in my place.
I want to know whose this is.
Who owns this crap?
There's a bunch of girls
out there looking for work.
Plenty of hot,
beautiful college-girls!
Spill it, Kelly.
If you don't, you'll be the
first one out on the street.
Leave her out of this.
I admit it. It's all mine.
I don't care.
It's all mine, Larissa.
News flash.
Both of you, pack
your things and get out.
Do you hear me?
Now! 1, 2, 3, out!
Fucking bitch.
For what the building offers,
the price is excellent.
- Yes, it really is.
- It's pricey, though.
Services like parking and
rec area are included.
Everything's included
I don't think
we need a place this big.
A flat like this doesn't cost as
much as a hellhole in the ghetto.
These stairs lead to the suite.
Lavatory, kitchen, terrace.
Carol was my ticket to
the world of VIP clients.
Gobi, my partner, was with me.
They were my only friends,
but back then I was more
concerned with money than friendship.
I'm afraid we're
risking too much.
Gobi, some call girls earn more
than doctors or lawyers.
If all else fails, the worst
that can happen to you
is going back
to turning tricks.
You now that
I'm looking for another gig.
I wanna work in fashion
and never turn tricks again.
Did you manage to get my things?
At least now I have clothes.
Guess what happened?
Larissa is pissed.
Clients keep asking for Brunei,
who looks like a surfer girl.
Now she understands
who kept that place going.
That's it, Gobi, of course.
What?
Brunei Surfer Girl
BLOG TITLE
ABOUT.' BRUNT SURFER GIRL
IS YOUNG, BLONDE AND HOT.
Disservice MEN, WOMEN, COUPLES.
I'LL DO WHATEVER YOU WANT.
YOUR BLOG IS READY!
TODAY'S THE FIRST DAY OF MY BLOG,
A PEEP INTO THE DIARY
OF BRUNT SURFER GIRL.
Every day we'll post
a different picture.
I TOOK SOME HOT NEW PHOTOS,
I'LL POST A NEW ONE EVERYDAY.
Brunei Surfer Girl.
Hold on. Let me
check my schedule.
Gobi, I'll do anything, OK?
Let me see...
Tomorrow at noon
is great. Fine then.
It's scheduled.
Come in.
Hudson.
Hi.
Welcome to Surfer Girl's place.
Wow, very nice.
- LEl?
- Look at this...
You made a huge investment,
Brunei Surfer Girl.
And you thought that
I wouldn't make it there.
Make it where exactly?
I set up the
computer you gave me.
I noticed.
- Li p all liq main.
- Yeah.
Master suite.
You'll love it.
User name: Brunei
Password: *****
New Comments:
Brunei, I love reading about
your routine, tell me more...
Brunei, you're incredibly hot.
I enjoyed our chat. LO
Are you a real call girl?
I love you S2 H!
Right away, I realized that
the biog would set me apart.
I didn't make up
anything, that was my life.
And everyone was
curious about a call girl's life.
YESTERDAY WAS A BUSY DAY,
A LOT HAPPENED...
THE 1ST ONE ALMOST DIDN'T GET
THERE, BUT I WARMED HIM UP.
I realized that besides
fooling around,
guys loved to talk
about their problems.
And I liked to listen.
- Where do you work?
- In a bank.
A bank! What do you do?
- I'm an business man.
- Dbl'?
My darling.
She's so cute!
She is so smart!
- You're so proud, aren't you?
- She's going places.
To this day I don't know
what my profession is.
I took a public service exam.
I start at 8am, leave at 6pm.
No one talks to each other.
I stare at the computer...
I was the perfect woman.
I was there to fuck,
listen and never complain.
My wife doesn't help either.
She only worries about the dogs.
Cooker Spaniel this, Poodle that.
YOUR BLOG IS VERY NICE.
I WANT TO SEE YOUR FLAT.
I CAN'T WAIT TO BANG YOU AGAIN.
YOU'RE AWESOME! SO HOT!
WHERE IS YOUR FLAT?
LET'S GO TO A
SWING CLUB ON FRIDAY?
Whoever had Brunei Surfer Girl
always wanted more.
What I didn't expect
was to become the most
famous call girl in Brazil.
Not bad for someone
who had low self-esteem.
You're really hot.
I'm not the same Bruna you
met at the club
Now I'm a different Brunei...
Brunei Surfer Girl.
It's the money.
So, Brunei, if you had
to give me a score,
what score would it be?
What do you mean a score?
A score from 0 to 10?
It doesn't need to be
a standard score.
It could be some kind of rating:
Good, hot, excellent,
incredible, loser, limp dick.
Let me think...
Excellent!
NEWS FLASH! FROM NOW ON
SURFER GIRL WILL RATE HER CLIENTS.
3rd ROUND: BUSINESS MAN,
40 YEARS OLD. SOPHISTICATED.
TOOK A WHILE TO WARM UP...
The ranking idea made
the biog even more popular.
I'd do 25 to 30 dates a week,
an average of 5, 6 dates a day,
which meant'
a lot of money. In cash.
I thought you weren't coming.
SINGLE MAN.
KINKY BALD GUY.
HE WAS VERY HORNY.
HE TOOK FOREVER TO CUM.
NICE TIP.
It took me 6 months to get
enough money to bang you.
6 months?
MARRIED MAN. VERY KIND.
***
I never thought
that job was wrong
or dirty.
Men don't consider being
with a call girl, cheating,
and they go home
much more excited.
Rate: ****
NEW COMMENTS
- Want a cigarette?
- No, thanks.
My Wife!
Tell her you're at the airport.
Hi, babe, miss you.
Just a couple more
Hold your breath
and it'll work better.
That's it, cutie.
Give this baby
some tea, cause I like it
Drink it all.
I don't think of myself as
home-wrecker,
Brunei Surfer Girl
saved a lot of marriages
Living the high life, girl.
Turn the volume down.
Brunei Surfer Girl.
It's your boyfriend.
Hi, handsome.
I read your biog.
I saw what you posted
about your fabulous clients.
They think the world of you.
I'm pissed off.
I can't believe
you'd be jealous, -Huldson.
I want compensation
for all this debauchery.
You and me.
Dinner. At a restaurant
There's a place
I want to take you.
- I charge for out calls.
- You can charge me.
Out calls are twice the price.
Think about it.
Your professionalism and
the vulgarity of your biog...
You can't imagine
how horny that makes me
Follow me, please.
Make yourselves comfortable
and have a nice dinner.
- Thank you.
- Excuse me.
So, do you like it?
This place is amazing.
And to think no client
had ever asked me to dinner.
That's because you don't
accept the good things.
Yet you keep finding me special?
L- Listen, Bruna...
or whatever your name is.
I know that somewhere inside
you lives an amazing person
that you killed off
for some reason.
And I want to find out why.
I brought you something.
Stop playing a role.
I don't deserve this.
It's yours.
Hi, Gobi.
I'm on a date,
tell them to wait.
It's gorgeous
Fine.
But later, when you're
fucking those guys,
remember very well
the life you chose.
I hope you have a lot of fun
OK. It's scheduled.
Do you have any
fetishes in particular
a fantasy, something?
Sure. That's what we're here for.
Hold on a sec.
Hello? Who?
Fucking hell!
Wake up.
Client!
- Wake up, Brunei
- I'm sleeping.
Get up
I'm sleeping, god dammit.
Let's go, let's go.
I had a dinner yesterday,
a bachelor party with 8 guys...
It's our fourth
cancellation this week!
Soon we won't
have any clients left.
Who gets fucked
to support this shit?
Want to trade?
Now she is rating the guys.
- Look at this picture.
- She looks gorgeous.
I started blogging about my clients,
but after awhile I became
the main subject.
- Brunei, I want to interview you
- You are so hot!
- How much for the whole night?
- Write some tips on your biog.
- Show me your boobs.
An
- I love you, marry me!
- I want to go to your party.
Do you really surf?
My web page had more than
10 thousand views a day.
I became a hit on the web
And I finally understood why
people want to become celebrities.
It's not for the fame,
but to be loved.
Great. Everything is perfect.
There's only one
Brunei Surfer girl.
She's lucky, honey.
You're jealous.
You gotta pay
to have a piece of this.
Don't forget to thank them.
Thanking is classy. OK?
I'm starting to get anxious.
Our company is called
Kelly & Mel, get it?
Mollycoddle. com. BR
Girls, you look gorgeous.
How is Brunei doing?
She is great. Very excited,
a lot of positive energy.
Shouldn't she make a more
discreet entrance, greet people...
No way, sugar.
You're narrow minded
We still have a surprise
at the end. I'll handle it.
Goddess!
You are so hot!
Brunei, I love you
Good evening.
What a beautiful, sexy,
and horny crowd.
I'm very happy to be here,
at this parti that
It's a dream I was
able to accomplish,
because I never stopped
believing in what I wanted.
That's why you have to
fight for what you believe in.
You can be someone as well.
That's it.
That's always it.
Now I'm going to
call a friend of mine,
my friend Carol,
who put this party together
We have a little surprise for you.
Happy birthday, girl.
I have one thing to say.
Here at my best friend's Birthday,
You're the ones
who get the presents!
Brunei Surfer Girl is
yours tonight for free.
Listen, everyone, get in line.
Calm down, people.
Here is your number.
Do you have a number?
Quit it, Gobi.
Ghetto insecurity.
Wake up, don't you get it?
I'm Brunei. Brunei Surfer Girl.
Plexiglas.
Everyone wants to fuck me.
Go on.
Do you doubt me? Choose one...
Cut the bullshit.
You're spending too much
snorting like crazy.
If you want to keep this up,
I'd rather you call your girlfriend,
whose only concern
is her own line of coke.
Carol, your problem is Carol.
What is it?
Are you jealous of Carol?
Or maybe you envy her?
Envy?!
Envious of a bloodsucker
who depends on a geezer?
I prefer to open my legs
for 20 bucks.
So that's it.
Carol does her job, you do
yours and stop bothering me
If you don't want it,
quit, it won't matter to me
That's what I'll do.
I'm leaving.
This way, both of you can
fuck up the rest of your life.
Don't overdo it. Come on.
You're the one overdoing it
and you don't even realize it.
By the way,
don't forget to pay these bills
for that fancy party
Carol threw for you.
Hey, I need a break, alright?
Let me go! Let me go!
Your time is over, let me go!
Your time is over,
It's only one hour.
Are you out of your mind, fuck!
What?
Be cool, I'm going to write good
thing about you on my Blog.
I thought you were professional.
Surfer girl!
Take it!
Your services are really bad.
Brunei?
I'm going to drink some
water and then we'll start.
Today I'm talking
to Brunei Surfer girl.
Brunei, how did it
feel to be awarded
for the top blog of the year.
Did you imagine that
your biog was this popular?
I don't know if this much.
Did success change your routine?
What are you going
to do after this interview?
I'll wait for my clients
as I always do.
I want to thank
everyone who nailed me.
My fee is the same and I haven't
stopped because I'm famous.
If you want to fuck me, visit
my blog at Brunelleschi. com.
What else?
Brunei.
Come in.
Excuse me.
I scheduled with Gobi
Gobi doesn't work here any more.
I booked a time with her.
I looked for you
everywhere, babe.
I went to where you worked,
but they didn't know about you.
There are a few new girls
over there, nothing interesting.
Haven't you heard
about the internet?
Blog, Brunei Surfer Girl's blog?
Nice place. You have
a pool, you can sunbathe.
30?
Are we fucking or do you
intend to keep up this little chat?
300 Raise.
This is entertainment.
I don't work with charity.
I see.
Sorry, my bad?
I think I got it all wrong
This isn't what I expected...
TODAY I TOOK THE DAY OFF. AFTER ALL,
SURFER GIRL NEEDS TO REST.
COME BY TOMORROW.
SHOW UP, I'M WAITING FOR YOU.
LET ME KNOW WHEN YOU CUT
THE PRICE. I'LL BRING SOME FRIENDS.
Cut me a line.
- Sorry?
- Cut me a line.
Didn't you sleep last night?
- Half and half, right?
- This is mine.
This doesn't even cover
half of what you owe me.
So take more then half.
Leave some for me.
Take care. Call me.
- I'm going to take these.
- Just a second, please.
I'm going to grab
some beer inside.
Where is the beer?
What is your code?
- - I'll pay for these with the gas.
- G.
I'm taking these.
Carol.
Carol, open the door.
I know you're in there.
Open this fucking door.
I swear I'll pay you.
- L.- Lady, .which number is up?
- Number 23.
They told me this girl is hot.
Line up, boys
It's gonna be a long day.
Come on.
Next!
Someone help me,
she passed out.
Someone help.
Emergency room 2.
You'll be fine.
What are you doing here?
I brought you some clothes.
What happened?
I'm tired.
I'm spending
New Year's at the beach
Do you want to come?
I really want you
to change your life.
I want to be with you.
I've got everything.
You don't have to worry
You can go back to your studies,
graduate high school,
study psychology...
- Stop the car
- What?
Please, stop the car.
You are very sweet
you know that?
I just wish you
could understand me.
I left my parents' house,
so I wouldn't depend on anyone
So I could have my own life.
Raquel.
My name
My name is Raquel.
Sometimes I miss my old life,
my dad, my mom,
I even miss my house.
I think I miss the
family! wanted to have
more than the family I had.
I'm proud of myself,
I met all kinds of people.
I allowed myself
to be another person.
I also made bad choices.
But if it wasn't this way,
I'd never learn to love
myself for who I am.
That's why y I'm telling this story,
so I'll never forget it.
It was as a call girl that
I truly found myself.
I learned a lot of things.
Maybe if I never
left my parents' house,
my relationship with them
would have gone back to normal.
Brunei wouldn't
have existed, only Raquel.
Only Brunei could reach
this conclusion, not Raquel.
I'll stop turning tricks.
I want to marry and
have children like everybody else
Before I do that, I need to save
enough money to live comfortably.
I'll work for another 6 months,
it'll be about 700, 800 dates.
If I ever leave this life,
I want to leave it
the same way I started,
accepting that it was my choice.
Come in.
AFTER 6 MONTHS,
RAQUEL STOPPED TURNING TRICKS
SHE WROTE THE BOOK
"THE SCORPION'S SWEET VENON",
THAT SOLD MORE THAN
250 THOUSAND COPIES IN BRAZIL...
AND WAS TRANSLATED
INTO 15 LANGUAGES.
TODAY RAQUEL LIVES
WITH AN EX-CLIENT.
SHE NEVER TALKED
TO HER PARENTS AGAIN.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org