And I'll be right here
till the day I die
Lister.
- Here.
- Collins.
- Coy.
- Here.
Rain every day now for a week.
I used to like the rain when I was a kid...
even when it rained hard like now.
My last fight outdoors, it rained.
Slowed me up a lot.
One of the most beautiful ladies I ever knew,
I met in the rain.
High heels on wet pavement.
Here's your last look at Frank.
They don't waste much time, do they?
Today they're gonna bury Frankie McLain
No more aches and no more pain
The good Lord
he treated Frankie very fine
He let him out
before he finished his time
Well, gentlemen,
that's one way of getting sprung.
Maybe he's better off.
I didn't think that even Captain Munsey...
would put a 62-year-old man
to work in the drainpipe.
Yeah, another dead guy,
compliments of Captain Munsey.
Always on tap.
There he is now.
Joe. It's Joe with him.
Too bad about McLain.
You and he were good friends,
weren't you, Collins?
Frankie only had about eight months left to do,
didn't he, Captain?
Knowing McLain,
out in eight months, back in nine.
Right, Collins?
Still carrying a grudge, eh?
Lay off, Munsey.
No, not Munsey. Sir.
You won't even meet me halfway,
will you, Collins?
Ten days in solitary
haven't taught you a thing.
I bet it taught him
not to carry a shiv anymore.
Or do you still claim that knife
was planted on ya?
Never mind that.
The episode's closed.
Collins.
Why keep on fighting?
After all, I've got a job to do.
Very well. Have it your way.
Joe, I meant to come down
and visit you, but l...
Dr. Walters.
There's a meeting this morning.
You'd better get straightened out.
And the same to you.
Me ol' friend Joe
was in the hole
And it was worse than
where they're diggin' coal
He comes out holding
very high his head
And the man to blame
soon be very dea
- Good to see ya, Joe.
- I'm glad you're back.
Heard from the wife?
Joe, you know Kid Coy.
Seen him around.
They moved him
into Frankie McLain's place.
Frankie was tops,
a hard guy to follow.
Whatever you say, Joe.
About the stool pigeon, Joe...
We made arrangements.
Everything's okay?
What's okay?
Nothing's okay.
It never was, and it never will be.
Not till we're out.
You get that?
Out.
Joe. After solitary,
even this will taste good.
- Thanks.
- Had a long talk with my mouthpiece yesterday.
Your lawyer came all the way from New York
just to give you advice?
Nah, ain't you heard?
He's right here in stir too.
Roberts, I need a little help.
- Get away from me.
- But you're in with Gallagher.
Roberts, you know Gallagher
can fx anything.
There are some things
that just can't be fxed.
Roberts, if you could put in a word for me...
- Gallagher, I gotta talk to you.
- What's he want, Louie?
- Blow.
- You gotta listen to me.
- I said blow.
- They'll kill me.
- Who is he?
- Wilson. He's here on a 529.
Also a stool pigeon.
He planted the shiv on Collins.
Munsey made me do it. Honest.
You can fx anything, Gallagher.
If you can call off Collins, I'd pay. I'd...
You'll pay.
Hello, Roberts.
How's that cold coming along?
Fine...
Strella, they tell me you're pressuring
some of the inmates in your area.
Am I?
Captain Munsey, sir,
I've gotta talk to you.
Please, sir. Please.
I understand you're responsible for
settling that little feud over in cell block "J."
We appreciate your assistance
of course, but...
The boys and I were only trying to help.
You and your boys.
There's a very old bylaw in this institution
about gangs or cliques.
We don't like them.
We don't want them.
Why don't you break them up, Captain?
Gallagher, when are you gonna remember
that you're not back home...
running a gang of hoodlums?
Let me be the policeman, eh?
You just serve your time.
And that way, we'll both get paid off.
That's right, Captain.
Like the Book says, we always get
what's coming to us.
All of us.
- Oh, excuse me, sir.
- What's the matter with you?
Wasn't his fault.
Sorry, Lister.
Ah, the warden's breakfast
ready and made
With the ham and eggs and the marmalade.
Sounds like a very important meeting
you're going to this morning, Doc.
Is Captain Munsey
gonna be there?
Brandy's the very best
drink in the world
If you drink enough
your toes get curled
Calypso, statistics show...
that if the level of alcohol in the blood
exceeds one half of one percent...
the blood pressure is affected,
a cerebral condition occurs...
and then... you're cockeyed.
And maybe that's the way it should be.
You don't like this place, Doc.
What for you stay here?
You haven't got much choice, Calypso.
Neither have I.
But it's not as easy as all that,
Mr. McCallum. This prison...
This prison has almost twice as many men
as it was built to accommodate.
There's not enough work
to keep the inmates occupied.
Why not?
The world we live in.
Yes, we can give them real work,
teach them trades, produce things.
But the civilian manufacturer
says we're competing with him.
Trade unions say we're putting
their people out of work.
Nobody wants to help.
Not us.
Manufacturers, unions.
You might as well blame the weather.
What you're really saying is
you can't handle the situation.
Excuse me, sir.
I don't think you quite understood
what the warden meant.
It's not only a matter of controlling the men.
He wants to help them.
Munsey, what this prison needs
is absolute discipline...
not charity.
Your loyalty to the warden
doesn't change the fact...
that he may be getting
too old for his job.
Age, Mr. McCallum,
is a matter of arteries, not years.
It's a pity, Walters, you're a better philosopher
than you are a doctor.
But I'm getting tired of you in both roles.
I was sent here today for one reason...
to tell you that if there's any more trouble...
if this prison isn't brought under
the strictest control...
- Mr. McCallum...
- There will be an immediate change
in practically all personnel.
We don't want to be bothered anymore.
Is that clear, Warden?
- Clear to you, Doctor?
- Oh, absolutely.
You can't be bothered.
Well, that simplifes everything.
The great public and its servants.
You put up prisons, thick walls...
and then your job is over, finished.
But is it over?
You and your patent medicine remedies.
Change the warden.
New personnel.
Absolute discipline.
Do you know what this prison is,
Mr. McCallum?
One big human bomb.
And you say, kick it and it'll be quiet.
Smash it and it won't explode.
Munsey, what do you think
of the doctor's viewpoint?
I think, sir, that on occasion,
the doctor becomes unduly alarmed.
Warden?
I do. Like so many dreamers
and drunkards...
the doctor's emotional words are empty.
What's your solution?
All I know is that when people are sick...
you don't cure them
by making them sicker.
By your methods,
we send the man back to society...
a worse criminal than he was
when they sent him to us.
Platitudes, Doctor.
I'm waiting for your solution.
For men like you, Mr. McCallum,
there will never be any solution.
- Wait a minute, Walters!
- Not while you wanna destroy instead of build.
What we need here is a little more patience
and much more understanding.
We've been patient too long.
And as for understanding...
I'm positive the purpose of my visit
cannot be misunderstood.
You'll remain here, Warden,
only as long as there's no further trouble.
Doctor.
I'll see you to the gate, sir.
I've been warden here
for such a long time.
I wouldn't know where to go...
what to do.
- The place looks so nice now.
- Oh, that's swell.
- I got fiower drapes and big chairs...
- The boy doesn't know anything about it.
- Fine, fine.
- And if he did...
- She loves to come to see you.
- It's good she's so young.
She thinks it's such fun, like a holiday.
Over there. Your attorney.
- Ruth?
- She won't go through with it.
- But she's got to.
- I've had three different doctors to see her.
They've all tried to explain how
important an operation is, right away.
But she keeps saying no,
not unless you're there.
Nothing matters to Ruth without you, Joe.
Not even her life.
How long has she got?
I don't know.
Let me tell her you're here.
- No.
- She loves you, Joe.
- She'll understand.
- No.
Okay. I guess you know
what you're doing.
Go back and talk to her. Try to make her
go through with it. Keep tryin'.
- All right, Joe.
- Wait.
- Get some cash. Keep it in your offce.
- What are you going to do?
There's not much I can do, is there?
I'm not trying to interfere.
I'm just saying that if you send Roberts
back to the drainpipe, I won't...
All right, Munsey, have it your way.
They letting you run around loose?
I'm waitin' to be reclassifed.
Munsey'll find another job for me.
He always has.
Well, sit down.
Be with you in a second.
Glad you dropped in.
A patient of mine, old Pat Regan,
wants to see you.
There's a pass to the infrmary
right there on the table.
How quick will cancer kill somebody?
Well, that's the wrong way
to put the question.
These days, cancer doesn't
have to mean death at all. Why?
Well, how about
if they have to operate?
Even so, it depends entirely on the case.
The important thing, of course,
is the time element.
Somebody close?
By the way, what time is it?
- About 10:30.
- Are you sure?
To be exact, it's 10:27.
Why?
Wilson, 10:30.
Did I ever tell you about
that last limousine of mine?
Beautiful... and roomy.
Listen, that car was so long, when I picked up
the phone to talk to the chauffeur...
I had to call long-distance.
Strangely enough,
had this same number on it.
Keep movin'.
Wilson, 10:30.
- Where are you goin'?
- Just to get a drink, Wilson.
He made me do it!
No, don't! Stay away from me!
Captain Munsey made me do it!
You guys would have
done the same thing!
Dr. Walters.
Yes, Warden.
What?
Yes, yes. I'll be right over.
Warden, when did it happen?
- A prisoner just killed.
- Yeah?
Well, this is one rap they can't
hang on you, Collins.
I'm your witness.
Important thing, witnesses.
Lucky you asked me before
exactly what time it was.
Yeah, wasn't it?
A fella named Wilson.
Tough break.
Accident?
Positively.
Witnesses.
A human interest story.
Remember that terrifc third baseman,
got paroled a couple of years ago?
- Dougherty?
- He'll be back for the book.
just knocked off his old lady.
You don't say.
just shows you a guy don't think.
If he'd done it last year, we might have beat
the Patrolmen's Benevolent Association.
If you'd asked my advice about Wilson,
I'd have said, "Don't do it."
Maybe that's why nobody asked you.
It'll only make things tougher
for everybody else.
- I don't care about everybody else.
- That's cemetery talk.
Why not? We're buried, ain't we?
Only thing is, we ain't dead.
What's on your mind?
You and me... out.
They told me you had the fever ever since
the day you got here.
- I thought you had more sense.
- No lectures. Just yes or no.
Look, Collins, cons respect me.
So does the warden.
I've had a good setup here
because I've tried to help both sides.
- And I never crossed either.
- So what?
So, in spite of Munsey,
I'm still number one.
I've been here six years.
Know how many propositions I've had
to crack the wall?
Six thousand.
They're on tap all the time.
- Look, Gallagher...
- Wait a minute.
See this fella at the Linotype machine?
He's a lifer. Done 12.
- You know Collins. He's okay.
- Sure.
How's the plan?
If there's no hitch, we go Tuesday.
- You in, boss?
- No. Good luck.
It's all set this time.
It's been all set every Tuesday for 12 years.
And 12 years from now,
it'll still be next Tuesday.
Look, Gallagher,
I know this drum's full of crackpots.
One con's gonna buy his way out.
Another knows the governor's cousin.
A third guy's even gonna fioat out
in a homemade balloon.
But I'm not buyin' any pipe dreams.
It can be done. It's been done before,
and it'll be done again.
It can be done here... by us.
By you and me.
Collins, if I ever put in with anybody,
it'll be with you.
There's no need for that now.
You I can tell why.
Promised me my parole.
Very soon now,
I'll be walking out of here.
- Next Tuesday?
- Could be next...
So long, Gallagher.
White tie and tails
for the movie tonight
The boy gets the girl
and that's all right
It is too.
Check... mate.
Clip you again, soldier?
Yeah, chess, dominoes,
whatever we play.
- Don't you ever lose?
- Very seldom, friend.
I was born with what
you might call the golden touch.
I almost won the Golden Gloves once.
They gave me a watch
and a robe with my name on the back.
My girl was there... Henrietta.
I'll be in the infrmary.
I gotta see a guy.
- Still figurin'?
- Still.
Save me a seat at the movie.
Take it easy, lady.
Hey, what goes between you guys
and this dame?
Watch your language, my unromantic friend.
You're speaking of a lady.
It's enough to give somebody the creeps.
You fellas smilin' at a picture, throwin' kisses
at her. You might think she was real.
She is.
After a while, you'll get to know it too.
It's true.
To me, she looks exactly like...
- Like my wife.
- Yeah.
That's no ordinary pinup girl.
To each one of us, she's somebody special.
You mean if I keep lookin' at her
long enough like you fellas...
she'll begin to remind me of Henrietta?
But Henrietta's a blonde.
She don't look nothin' like her.
She doesn't have to.
Our calendar girl is just an inspiration,
Brother Coy.
She starts you thinking
about the one you really wanna see.
For example,
the last couple of days now...
she's had me thinking about Flossie.
I never told you gentlemen
about Flossie, did I?
To me, she's all the women I ever knew...
and a few I hope I haven't met yet.
I ran into Flossie one night
in Eddie's Place in Miami.
I had just sold a trusting gentleman
a few shares in a radium mine...
and I was trying to parlay my luck.
I had only met Flossie that afternoon...
but we were already very good friends.
The dice were hot,
and she kept them that way.
I was heading for a fortune.
Suddenly, just when everything
was sunshine and roses...
I heard the old familiar noises.
Leave it to the police
to break up a wonderful evening.
It looked as though everybody
was caught with their chips down.
The raid didn't worry me, but the gun
I was carrying was a problem.
So Flossie had me slip the gun
into her purse.
She was not only beautiful,
she knew the score as well.
Furthermore, she knew precisely
how to guide me through a back exit.
Obviously, the girl was no tourist.
My car was waiting there
just as pretty as you please.
And with my money and my gun still safe,
off we drove.
Driving along with such
a dream doll beside me...
I figured myself a pretty lucky guy.
Flossie had looks, brains
and all the accessories.
She was better than a deck with six aces.
But I regret to report that she also
knew how to handle a gun...
my gun.
Before, I had only suspected
that she was talented.
Now I was positive.
I didn't do much talking because,
for once in my life...
I couldn't find the right words.
She wanted all the money I had won,
and I never refuse a lady...
especially when she's armed.
Accordingly, I stepped out
of the automobile...
without any arguments whatsoever.
And that, gentlemen...
was the last I ever saw
of my car, my cash...
or my Flossie.
I wonder who Flossie's fieecing now.
I don't get it.
Why would a guy want to hang on
to a memory like that?
Who knows?
I guess when you're on the inside...
even the phony things on the outside
seem wonderful.
just so they happened on the outside.
All right. Go ahead.
Joe, how's the boy?
Where have you been?
All day long I've been askin' for you.
Frankie McLain...
he died in the next bed.
He gave me a message for you.
Drainpipe got Frankie.
Same as me.
But in that same drainpipe...
there's a way out of this place.
Go ahead.
He said...
"Ask Soldier how, in the war,
they took Hill...
Hill ..."
633?
Joe...
you... just gotta get in that drainpipe.
Oh, wait till Mr. Henty sees these.
I'll bet you he'll give us the biggest
egg contract in the county.
Do we have to name them all?
Well, they're not pets, you know.
They're our stock-in-trade.
If they don't get jammed
under the brooder and smother...
or drown in the drinking fountain
or get coccidiosis...
or peck each other to death, we...
we may be in the chicken business yet.
After you've fed
and watered them every three hours...
which you have to do until they can
take care of themselves...
you won't feel so sentimental
about 'em.
- Where's Tom?
- Stayed in the cell.
Another letter to his wife.
- Be with you in a minute.
- No, take your time.
Anything new?
Around here?
I ran into Harry Thomas
and his wife today.
Thought it'd be a good idea to get together,
maybe sometime soon.
You mean we might be
going out for a change?
Honey, make a wish.
What are you talking about?
Oh, Tom, darling.
Here, put it on.
It's beautiful.
It's the most beautiful thing
in the whole world.
It belongs on you.
It makes me feel so...
I don't know.
Like I was somebody.
Where'd you get it?
Where'd the money come from?
Cora, I stole the money.
I juggled the books and took $3,000.
You? You stole?
- Why?
- Darling, the way we were going...
you wanting things,
things you oughta have...
and me strapped all the time...
we were heading for a split-up.
Don't you see?
I just had to do it.
All my life, the one thing I really wanted
was a fur coat.
- I can't give it up. I won't, Tom.
- No, darling.
- But what if something should happen?
- Nothing that happens could matter...
unless I lost you.
Sorry about that little incident
this morning.
Those things happen, you know.
- Yes, sir.
- Cigarette?
Tom, you're no hoodlum
like the others in this cell.
Why protect them?
We've been over that before, Captain.
Before, you didn't need my help
as much as you do now.
I'm in a position
to make things easier for you.
Like you did for Wilson?
Wilson was careless.
Careless people have accidents.
I get quite a kick out of censoring the mail.
All these letters you write home,
for example...
and the answers you never get.
Please, Captain,
let me alone.
She's the most important thing
in the world to you, isn't she?
Well, you'll come up for parole soon...
if your conduct's good.
I'm the one that decides that.
I'm the only one who can help you.
No one else.
Captain, I'm a cheap thief.
I know I'm a failure...
but I'm not an informer.
That's what I like to see in a man...
stability, fdelity.
You're right, Lister.
We're both wasting our time.
Me by talking to you
and you by writing to your wife.
- Captain, you've heard from her.
- By mail this morning.
Please. Please, Captain, tell me.
In a way, Tom, you're a free man.
She's divorcing you.
just a minute.
just a minute. Sit down.
The warden's going to talk to you.
All ready, Warden.
Men, I'm going to try to talk
some sense to you.
I'm gonna lay it right on the line.
There has been, in recent weeks,
a mounting unrest in this prison.
Don't think for one minute
that I don't know about it.
Up to now, you've enjoyed
the regulation privileges.
However, if you persist
in fighting among yourselves...
antagonizing the guards
and making way for accidents...
like the one that happened
in the machine shop this morning...
Then all your privileges will be revoked at once.
Be careful of your associates.
Always remember that one bad prisoner
can spoil things for the rest of you.
So watch your step.
It's up to you to protect
your own interests...
as I am compelled to protect mine.
If there's one more infraction of the rules...
if you cannot conduct yourselves
without creating a disturbance...
without further accidents...
then I shall have to use every means
to keep you under control.
So that's it, men. Meet me halfway
and you can depend on me...
to see that every prisoner is treated fairly.
Cell R17.
Convict McLain of cell R17 buried.
Collins comes back from solitary
to cell R17.
A prisoner is killed in the presence
of three convicts...
all from cell R17.
And now a suicide.
Same cell, same gang, same trouble.
just a minute. You're not tryin' to say
that we had anything to do with that.
- You said yourself, it was suicide.
- Only because I can't prove otherwise.
- Tom was one of us. The way we felt about him...
- I know. I know. You loved him.
You can't throw the hook into us.
We didn't touch Tom.
- You know we were at the movies.
- So you were.
And Collins was at the doctor's offce
this morning when Wilson was killed.
I'm a realist.
I don't believe in coincidence.
Especially when it happens
more than once.
You fought the warden,
the guards and me.
You're not ft for civil life,
and you won't accept prison life.
So tomorrow you'll begin a new life.
You'll all report for work in the drainpipe.
Hill 633, what is it?
What does it mean to you?
Well, it's a hill in Italy,
not far from Rome. Why?
- Tell me about it.
- There's not much to tell.
The krauts had the hill,
and we were ordered to take it.
How?
What'd you do, charge 'em?
Did you ever try it uphill with a few
kraut 88s puttin' the blast on ya?
Spencer, let me have those chessmen,
will ya?
Give me some light.
Here was the hill.
Here was us.
Mountains here,
the ocean here.
- Stalemate.
- But you took it.
Yeah. We took it, all right.
Give me some more light.
We sent some men out in a boat.
They landed up here.
We covered 'em
with a heavy bombardment.
At "H" hour, we attacked uphill.
The krauts turned all their guns to stop us.
That was exactly when the other gang
attacked from behind.
And it worked.
We got through, all right.
Most of us anyway.
The rest are still there.
They couldn't cover both sides, huh?
Thanks, Soldier.
How's that tie in with us, Joe?
What are you gettin' at?
We'll see tomorrow.
You know, I was just thinking.
An insurance company
could go flat broke in this prison.
I know how you feel, Gallagher,
and I'm sorry, but that's it.
But it doesn't add up, Warden.
You're punishing all of us
because Lister took his life. Why?
Things are out of hand. That's why.
It's the only decision we could make.
- We? You mean Munsey.
- No.
- I'm the warden here. This is my order.
- It's his work.
I've heard complaints about Munsey for years,
and I'm sick of'em.
Munsey knows his job, and he does his job.
Gallagher, I've tried my best to do
the right thing by the men, but it's just no use.
I'm convinced now that what's needed here
is not more charity, but more discipline.
Yes? No, no. Absolutely. No interviews!
I don't care what newspaper he's with.
Did you get McCallum yet?
Well, keep on trying.
Well, thanks for seeing me, Warden.
Just a minute.
There's one more thing, Gallagher.
I was going to send for you.
- This letter concerns you.
- Yeah?
Gallagher, you and I have always
been able to work together.
- You've been a great help to me with the men.
- What is it?
The Department of Corrections...
They've canceled
all parole hearings indefinitely.
What's this mean?
Another year?
Two? Five?
Not necessarily.
I'm sorry.
It's not my fault.
It is your fault!
You've given in to Munsey all along the line.
A couple of weeks ago I stood here, and you
told me the gates were going to open for me.
In just a few more days I was going home.
Home.
I should have known better.
Those gates only open three times...
when you come in,
when you've served your time...
or when you're dead!
Gallagher.
Can I still count on your cooperation?
Look at me, fellas. Hi.
I just got a pip of an assignment.
I gotta write a story provin' how good
the chow is around here.
You prove that and Time magazine
will make you man of the year.
Ah, there's somethin' interestin'.
Now what have you got here?
Message. Collins. Drainpipe.
- We're hot.
- Gotta be done.
Smell that.
Now you know
what happened to Rin Tin Tin.
- Western Union.
- Who?
- Collins.
- What's all the gab about?
Every day, I have to take chow
to them guys down in the drainpipe.
I don't like the job.
The air down there is very unsanitary.
Don't breathe in.
Just breathe out.
I've seen many a guy go to work
in the drainpipe.
There's more goes in as comes out.
They keep buildin' it long enough,
they'll run out of guys.
Besides, they're buildin' it backwards.
Nobody knows where that drainpipe
is goin' or where it'll come out...
or if it'll ever be used.
You know, the way I got it figured out...
Make sense.
What are you tryin' to say?
I got a favor to pose you.
Don't ask me no favors.
I can't be bribed, see?
Besides, you ain't got enough dough
to bribe me.
I was once married
to a dame like that bridge.
- What are you talking about?
- Wonderful structure...
but up in the air most of the time.
Becker, leave him alone.
Get back to work.
- He's sick. He needs help.
- Back!
I said get back.
- No. None for me.
- Better take it.
- Don't mind us, Father. We're just looking around.
- Shopping or buying?
New orders. We're supposed to
watch the men no matter where they are.
In here,
someone else watches after them.
- However, if you wish to stay.
- Thanks.
This'll be it then.
The main tower.
We need it to open the gates.
When the gates open,
the bridge comes down.
We all know there's no way out
except over that bridge.
So frst we've got to take the tower.
Now, you'll be here on the inside.
When we come out of the drainpipe,
we'll be here...
on the outside.
We hit the tower from both sides.
Lot of rifies and ammunition
in that tower...
but only one machine gun.
Only one. Which means
they can't cover both sides.
- Once we take the tower...
- Yeah.
- How many men have you got?
- Five, countin' me. All set.
I have six.
My men won't know about you. I'm gonna
tell them only what they have to know.
Mine won't know any more.
When are you figuring?
- 12:15 tomorrow.
- You're crazy!
- That's just why we've got a chance.
- This takes timing, planning.
No. The longer you wait,
the longer the odds.
Somebody cools off,
another guy stalls...
a third guy can't keep his mouth shut.
No. For us it's now. We hit 'em hard,
fast, sudden, and we make it...
All right, Collins.
Tomorrow it is.
You will take care of everything?
The stuff to blow the tower?
- That's gonna be tough.
- We gotta have it.
All right. I'll try and get it to you.
Tomorrow then.
You hit the yard at 12:15.
I'll need two minutes.
At exactly 12:17 I'll be in the tower
opening the gates.
12:17.
The yard'll be full then.
When those gates open,
the whole population'll break out.
I know you got it all worked out, Joe,
but don't we need a getaway car?
How about money?
Can't get far without a little cash.
And clothes.
In these things we'd be spotted right away.
That's all I can tell you for now.
But we've been talking out
for a long time, and this is it.
Joe, I don't want you to get sore, but, well,
I've only got a short stretch left to do, and...
There's no such thing as a short stretch.
But you haven't told us much. We don't know
how it'll work or what's supposed to happen.
You're moving so fast that I...
Say it.
You want to pull out?
He can't.
We don't know any more than you do.
- You declared yourself in. You can't quit now.
- Shut up.
Don't misunderstand me, Joe.
- How many?
- Two.
- I'll play these.
- Three here.
In or out?
No guarantees go with this break.
It's all or nothing.
But you've gotta make up your mind now. Now.
Either way, no hard feelings.
With you, Joe.
I'll play along.
I never thought different.
- Neither did I.
- Joe.
I wonder what I'm gonna do.
Manage a couple of heavyweights maybe.
Who knows? I might even
wind up owning a piece of a champ.
All you guys'll sit ringside... free.
You're kidding yourself, Coy.
Odds are, once we're on the outside,
we'll never see each other again.
The big city for me.
When you got millions of neighbors,
nobody cares who lives next door.
I'll find a right dame.
That'll be that.
Say, won't Henrietta be surprised?
I think me and her'll go away
on a long trip.
Sure. Most cons get married
as soon as they get out.
Married? Gee, I never thought of that.
Hope you make it, Coy.
You going back in the stock racket, Spencer?
I think not.
Printing costs are so high these days.
I don't exactly know what I'll do.
Not yet.
What about you, Soldier?
I got a long way to go.
Ever since the war, I've been trying to
get back to a little town in Italy.
But you know how the breaks go.
With me, one rap led to another.
Anyway, I was never able to make it.
Maybe this time.
Robert, you must go away.
The military police... they were here.
When were they here?
How long ago? What did they say?
I talked to them.
It was nothing.
- There are more important things.
- He has brought no food. He is leaving.
- So?
- Food's out there in the truck.
- Thank you.
- No. We will take nothing.
You will stand in line with the others.
When there is food, you will eat.
- And when there is no food?
- Then you will starve with the others.
We're not all
so fortunate as you, my daughter.
We have no great love
to quiet our appetites.
Robert does not object.
Why do you?
He does not know you so well as I.
Ah. Is it so great a crime to accept food
from those who deprived you of it?
Nothing personal, of course, but...
since you do not spare the bombs,
we do not expect you to spare the food.
- You Americans are such a generous...
- Never mind the speeches.
- The food's out there. Go get it.
- No!
He hates you, Robert. He hates your uniform.
He fought you in Sicily. He still fights you.
My position does not permit me
to hate anyone.
I'm foolish, so I cry.
It's nothing.
In a war, people cry easy.
Promise me you won't come here again.
Bringing us food this way
is against the law.
The law is second.
My wife comes frst.
Your military... they are back!
This food... say nothing about it.
You understand?
Robert is a stranger.
We never saw him before.
He stopped here for water.
Water for the truck.
And if they discovered I was lying,
what then?
- Why should I risk my neck for you?
- Because I stuck mine out for you.
For me? No, signor.
You came to see her.
I will not lie for you.
You and your police can destroy each other.
Sit down!
Gina, keep him here.
I'll get the water.
If they believe me, I've got a chance.
- You had nothing to do with this. Remember that.
- No. Robert...
Nothing. Nothing. Nothing.
Hey, Soldier. Snap out of it.
You're missin'a swell yarn.
- Go ahead, Spencer.
- Well, gentlemen, as I was saying...
there I was,
besieged on all sides...
the citizens to the front,
the howling investors behind me...
the sheriff's men closing in.
But I remained undaunted.
Smiling, secure in my rights.
- What happened?
- Here I am.
- Okay. Break it up. Let's try to get some sleep.
- Why?
- I like to hear Spencer talk.
- We've talked too much already.
There are ears all over this drum,
and they all belong to one guy.
What's the answer to it? Are we going to
have to keep every prisoner in ritual solitary?
Other prisons must have
these same problems...
but they clear them up,
keep things running smoothly.
We've been through
diffcult times before, Warden.
Oh, never like this.
And McCallum is coming tomorrow. Why?
Why can't he let me alone?
Everything's gone wrong.
I don't know who's to blame, but...
I do know that every prisoner hates us.
Not us. Me.
- It's me they hate.
- I wonder why.
You put on a guard's uniform
and see how much they love you.
You talk to the prisoners over a loudspeaker.
I talk to them with a club.
- You only make the rules. I have to enforce them.
- Maybe it's the way you enforce them.
Maybe it is.
I'm not criticizing, Munsey.
It's just that...
But you are.
And perhaps you're right.
All I know is that I've tried
to do my job as I saw it.
But if I'm the cause of this trouble...
if I'm wrong and those convicts are right...
then you can have
my resignation immediately.
No, Munsey. That's just what the inmates
would like. No, no. That's not the answer.
As you said, we've been through
some diffcult times together here. Well...
we're still here,
and we're still together.
Let's leave it that way?
Well, the situation
seems to call for a drink.
I'm going to turn in.
Good night.
Don't be discouraged, Warden.
It's a rule in all the best stories.
Everybody always lives happily ever after.
You don't believe I meant
what I said about resigning, do you, Doctor?
In a million words...
You're wrong.
I really want to help the warden.
It's just that he's confused.
He doesn't know that kindness
is actually weakness.
And weakness is an infection that
makes a man a follower instead of a leader.
Seems too me a very great leader
once said the meek shall inherit the earth.
Science contradicts that, Doctor.
Nature proves that the weak must die...
so that the strong may live.
Authority...
cleverness...
imagination.
Those are the real differences between men.
I walk amongst these convicts...
these thieves and murderers...
alone, unarmed.
But they respect me.
They obey me.
Fits you, doesn't it?
The warden's chair.
- It fits you.
- You're drunk.
Why not? I'm a very ordinary man.
I get drunk on whiskey.
What makes you drunk?
- Power?
- You flatter me, Doctor.
I'm just a policeman.
I carry out the warden's orders.
Did he ever order you
to crucify the prisoners?
Were you ordered
to make convict Lister hang himself?
- What are you talking about?
- You were seen going into Lister's cell...
and you were seen coming out.
What happened in between?
Did you censor his mail?
Wouldn't he give you
any information?
Or did you tell him a few lies
about his wife?
You better stop drinking, Doctor.
Your imagination's working overtime.
Visiting cells is part of my job,
helps me keep tabs on the men.
- In that way, I can control them.
- Control them?
You mean torture them, don't you?
The more pain you infict,
the more pleasure you get.
That's why you'd never resign
from this prison.
Where else would you find
so many helpless fies to stick pins into?
You talk to me like that?
If I didn't keep you here,
you'd be starving.
You surgical butcher.
For me, it's the last stop anyway.
But for you it's just a beginning, isn't it?
Why, you're Genghis Khan...
Alexander the Great...
Caesar.
Look at you in the warden's chair.
Caesar trying out his throne.
- That's enough.
- Caesar cries "Enough"?
You're obvious, Munsey.
Your every move is obvious.
You've cheated.
You've lied.
You've murdered.
You're worse than the worst inmates
of this prison.
You're the psychopath here,
not they!
That's it, Munsey.
Not cleverness.
Not imagination.
just force.
Brute force.
Congratulations.
Force does make leaders.
But you forget one thing.
It also destroys them.
Couple of hundred yards ahead
there's a side road. Turn right.
We got over a hundred miles to go.
We shouldn't be stoppin' now.
- Shut up.
- Take it easy, Joe. Take it easy.
Why don't you see her after the job?
Because I said we're stopping now.
I'll only be a few minutes.
- Sadie.
- Good evening, Mr. Collins.
- Is she all right?
- She don't complain none, but she's about the same.
See that she doesn't need anything.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Collins, I'm glad you're here.
Ruth.
- I was dreaming about you.
- Something nice?
I dreamed I was running up a hill.
I was chasing you.
- Catch me?
- Almost.
I must be slowin' down.
I guess I can make it come out
any way I want. It's my dream.
Pretty soon now you're gonna be
getting out of that chair.
And it won't be a dream either.
The frst thing we'll do
is go for a long walk.
- No cars for us. No trains.
- Just walking.
- We'll walk around the world.
- I'm tired already.
I'll have Sadie fx you some supper.
And then we'll talk.
Oh, I've got a million things to tell you,
and this time I won't forget them. I made a list.
Ruth, I can't stay.
Next time, when I come back, I'll...
- Another next time?
- This is the last of them.
When I come back, it'll be for good.
Why? I'm sick, Joe.
Why do you love me?
When you're sick, people don't really love you.
They only feel sorry for you.
I'm not people.
I'm Joe Collins. One guy.
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm selfsh.
Every time you walk out that door
I'm afraid you're never coming back.
If I only knew where you came from,
where you go, what you do.
Ruth, let's leave things
the way they started.
I'm a guy who ran out of gas who saw
an ordinary little farmhouse by the side of the road...
who found the frst important thing
in his life waiting for him in a wheelchair.
Let's keep it that way
for just a little while longer.
Another day, maybe two, and...
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
I know what I want to know.
The rest doesn't matter.
If I weren't so sick, I could help you.
There are all kinds of sick people, Ruth.
Maybe we can help each other.
- I love you, Joe.
- Go on back and finish that dream.
I'll slow down,
and you won't have to run so fast.
And when you catch me,
hold on tight.
Only a couple of more hours.
Work close together.
Load's ready.
Take it easy, Roberts.
You got the whole day ahead of you.
- Sure. This is my racket.
- Thanks.
Soldier. To the right.
That switch.
When we break, you'll handle that switch.
Puts us on the other track...
the one that leads to the tower.
- Got that?
- Check.
- What's all the chatter?
- Just wondering what time it was.
Why? You workin' by the hour?
- Morning, fellas.
- Hi, Louie.
- Morning, Chappie.
- Another story?
- Yeah, but this is a good one. Hiya, fellas.
- Hello, Louie.
Finally gonna make you grease monkeys famous.
Gonna put you all on the front page.
That's what got us here.
Tell me, Charlie. What has prison life
taught you about being a mechanic?
It's taught me that when I get out
I shouldn't be a mechanic.
What about it, Andy?
Got anything to say to the press?
There ain't much to say.
I do as I'm told.
Everything?
Where do you keep your tools?
Eight frebombs flled with juice.
The best.
Eight fuses.
Light two as you drive into the yard.
Like I say, I always do as I'm told.
We go to press at 12:15, sharp.
I'll be there.
Spell his name right, Louie.
His wife keeps a scrapbook.
- Is this all right, Gallagher?
- Yeah, fine.
- News. Some good, some bad.
- Good?
Eight frebombs in the toolbox,
truck ready to go.
- Bad?
- No dynamite.
- Gotta have it.
- Not a chance. Just came from the dye plant...
- Gotta have it!
- Not enough time.
Look, Louie.
I've got an important assignment for ya.
- Get down to the drainpipe. See Collins.
- Collins?
He's with us.
Tell him there's no dynamite.
- Do we go anyway?
- We'll have to go without it.
And, Louie, you got 45 minutes.
Think I'd be late for my
own coming-out party?
I've already...
But I've tried to explain, madam.
No. No, I'm sorry. All visiting days
have been canceled, even for families.
- Take off your hat.
- I'm here to get a pass, Miss Lawrence.
- Where to this time?
- To the drainpipe.
We're doin' a special layout, and...
- Wait a minute. What's wrong?
- Nothing.
You want to do a story.
We want to help you.
Captain Munsey's offce.
Whose car?
Mr. McCallum's?
Okay. Pass it through.
- What's the matter with him?
- Munsey left orders.
You wanted to
go to the drainpipe, huh?
- Yeah. Anything wrong with that?
- Munsey in?
- In and waiting.
- Come on.
A customer for the drainpipe.
7033. Convict Miller.
Gallagher's man?
He was looking for a pass
in the warden's offce.
Gallagher?
- You want to see him now?
- Yeah. Yeah. Bring him in.
I understand you're interested
in the drainpipe.
I don't get this, Captain.
We're planning a big spread on the different
kinds of work the cons are doing, and I...
Oh, that's right.
You are a reporter, aren't you, Louie?
Sit down.
No, not there. Here.
What's the point, Captain?
I've been to the drainpipe before.
I've been there a hundred times.
- What's the idea of all this?
- Tell me, Louie.
How does an illiterate like you
become a reporter?
Even a star reporter?
- I don't know, sir.
- I do.
What business did you have
in the drainpipe?
- I told ya.
- Tell me again.
To write a story.
I don't like that answer.
Gallagher sent you to the drainpipe
to see somebody.
- Who was it?
- Nobody. Just to write...
- Wrong answer.
- Leave me alone, Captain. Please.
I don't have the answers you want.
Now, we'll begin again.
Who was it Gallagher sent you to see?
I told ya. Nobody.
He gave you a message.
What was it?
There was no message.
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
- You don't know much about anything, do ya?
- No.
I suppose you don't even know...
that Collins plans to break out
of the drainpipe at 12:15 today, do ya?
Do you?
You have been lying to me, haven't you?
Gallagher does know something
about the break, doesn't he?
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
You can hit me.
You can keep on hitting me.
But I don't know what you want.
Take him to the isolation ward.
Spread the word that he had an accident
coming back from the drainpipe.
Is there any connection
between Gallagher and Collins?
No.
If there was, he would have told me.
Okay. Get your man out of here.
Hey, you. Muggsy.
Comin' up!
- Bring anything for me?
- No.
- You sure?
- Sure, Joe.
- Anything wrong?
- No.
Back to work.
Collins.
The cardiogram just came back
from the lab, Collins.
- Yeah?
- Have to check you again.
Make it snappy, Doc.
Okay, okay. Keep it moving.
Louie was beaten up.
Munsey.
Louie might die.
He sent a message.
Whatever your plan is,
don't go through with it.
Munsey knows.
Believe me, Joe.
He knows you're going at 12:15.
He's ready for you, Joe.
He wants you to go.
A prison break finishes Warden Barnes.
Munsey'll be the hero.
He's using your life to make
himself warden.
Gallagher been picked up?
Gallagher? No.
Why?
Joe, you haven't got a chance.
How did Munsey find out?
The Munsey way. An informer.
One of your own men, I suppose.
Don't go through with it, Joe. Don't.
Thanks for tryin', Doc.
We got about 10 minutes.
There's fve of us. We'll have to go one at a time.
- What position do you want?
- You're the boss.
Whatever you say.
Take your pick for the break.
What position?
I said I'd play along with you, Joe.
You name it.
- You.
- Same goes for me.
We've only got a few minutes, Freshman.
When we break,
what position do you want?
I want to give all the help I can, Joe.
- What position?
- Last.
That'd be the toughest,
wouldn't it, Joe? Last.
Louie got hurt.
Got banged up, they say,
comin' back from the drainpipe.
- Coming back?
- Yeah.
- Munsey.
- Keep circulating.
Clay pigeons would have
a better chance.
Sorry, Captain.
I didn't see you there.
That's all right, Hopkins.
But just remember. There's no reward
for bringing them back alive.
- Not in this jungle.
- Yes, sir.
- Now, is there anything else you want done, sir?
- No.
Bradley, join the guard
along that section of the wall.
Ready to go?
Look out!
Drop the club. Drop it.
Coy, you and Spencer dump this dirt.
Dump it back there.
Give me a break, Collins.
I didn't do anything.
- I didn't have a gun. Give me a break.
- Shut up.
- Now you men listen to me.
- Collins, count me out.
- I don't want any part of this.
- Take me with you, Joe. I'll do anything you say.
- Just take me with ya.
- Me and my boys are gettin' out of here.
The action starts in the yard.
That's when we go.
After that, you can suit yourselves. Right now
do as I say. Get back in the hole... all of you.
Spencer, you and Coy
strip some of that electric wire.
Soldier, get that hack over there.
Joe, what about me?
It'll be no discredit to you.
You'll go away for a short while.
When you get back,
we'll try to ft you in someplace else.
I can't resign.
- This is my whole life.
- Sign it.
Get on that loudspeaker.
Tell them you've resigned.
Attention.
This is Warden Barnes.
I have just resigned.
Tell them the prison's now
in charge of Captain Munsey.
- Munsey?
- Go on. Tell them.
With Warden Barnes's resignation
now in effect...
this institution
is in charge of Captain Munsey.
I repeat. Captain Munsey is your warden.
You will obey him.
You will take all orders from Warden Munsey.
- Quick!
- You got me wrong! Munsey made me do it, Joe!
Please! I'll tell you everything! Joe!
Don't! Not this way! Joe!
Joe, will you listen to me?
You'll never make it!
It's a setup! They're waiting for us!
You and Tom get down there.
Here. I'll take this.
Get the gun and come on.
Come on, Collins. Come on.
What's the plan now?
The plan's a flop. You're on your own.
It's a million-to-one.
He's trying to ram the gates!
It's Collins!
That hurt plenty.
This place is full of pain, Calypso.
You're hurt.
Collins and Munsey are dead.
And the others.
All those others.
Why do they do it?
They never get away with it.
Alcatraz. Atlanta. Leavenworth.
It's been tried in a hundred ways
from as many places.
Always failed.
But they keep trying.
Why do they do it?
I don't know, Doc.
But whenever you got men in prison,
they're gonna want to get out.
But they learn.
They must!
Nobody escapes.
Nobody ever really escapes.