Birdie Buddy
Episode 23
Previously...
Didn't you say that it is an occassion worth congratulating?
The person that said that it is worth congratulating to even be nominated..
sure doesn't look like he's having fun.
Really?
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm not the partying type.
Are you sure you are really sick?
I need to eat to get stronger!
I cannot really taste the food...
but I need to eat to get better
But still, shouldn't you have gone to the awards?
You should go to those award ceremonies.
Wearing a dress, and taking pictures, how great that would be.
I also thought about it but...
but if I went like this and get no awards... and get even more sick...
it's embarassing.
Let us now begin the
2010 KLPGA
Awards Ceremony.
First we will announce the rookie award to the player that stood out from all the other rookies.
This year the nominees for rookie of the year are Min Hae Ryung and Sung Mi Soo.
I believe they're both nervous seeing it's an award you can only receive once in your life.
I believe they're both nervous seeing it's an award you can only recieve once in your life.
Then let's see who the winner is...
This year's rookie of the year goes to...
Sung Mi Soo!
Congratulations!
Due to personal obligations, Sung Mi Soo wasn't able to attend.
Therefore her coach, John Lee, will be accepting the award on her behalf.
Please give a round of applause.
Rewards and trophy, also flower is being given.
Once again, please give him a big round of applause.
Yes, thank you very much.
Sung Mi Soo even prepared a dress for this day
because of her bad cold, she couldn't attend today's ceremony.
Personally, rather than the fact that she herself couldn't get this award
but the fact that we couldn't see her in a dress
makes me really sad.
I think she would really like this.
I will make sure she gets this safely. Thank you.
Yes, thank you very much.
Please give him a round of applause.
Should I call Gong Sook and Jun Gi
for some beer?
Oh, I'm freaking bored!
What do I do?
Yes..?
I'm okay
If I rest a bit, i'll get better
You want me to make you get well right away?
Pardon?
The rookie award.
They say that you got it.
Sung mi...
Sung mi soo...
Me?!
See?
I told you you would feel better right away.
I got it for you. We should have a conveying ceremony.
You owe me a meal!
Sure!
Let's look at the news.
Just look at the midnight news.
Did you buy TV to watch drama?
Mom!
Yes, why?
Dad!
I... got the Rookie Awards!!
Wh..wha...Mi Soo!!
That's great!
So we should have gone no matter what!
You got the award?
Of course!! Who am I?
You were in LA?
This is a very famous place for sports agency!
I am in the golf department.
I go around all the games around the world to look for a great player.
I came in to take a look at Korean players... but all the games seems to be over by now.
There are a lot of good players in LPGA.
I'm looking for new players.
All the good players are already in a long term contract, so I can't do anything.
I see...
Oh, I can take YOU with me!
I don't know if you can pay that much...
You now even make a joke!
Are you the old Min Hae Ryung?
You changed a lot.
Let's have a meal together before I go in.
Call me!
Where were you?
I just gave a call to Mi Soo.
I am tired... let's just go home.
You look happy.
Really?
Of course you are happy since your player who went through a lot just got the award.
You don't have to read me.
Are you okay?
I feel a little bit...unsatisfied...
Probably its because of the intentional putting miss on the Il Rose game.
It would have been hard for them to just ignore that.
Right...
Should I rather be thankful?
for making a player like me a nominee ..
I will give you your own rookie award.
You can count on it.
Really?
Really.
Change it into something into high class even if that means a lot of money.
Just changing some of this and that wouldn't do anything.
We will make a draft and give it to you.
Okay.
You seem to be in a good mood.
Not good... not bad...
I guess the weather is just okay.
I thought you would be all down...
It feels good to see you smiling.
Thank you.
Do you have an appointment tonight?
John seemed to be making reservations for tonight at the restaurant.
Stop hanging around with just the two of you but invite your old mom once in a while.
I will give you your own rookie awards.
You can count on it.
It will all get off in a day... no need for all this...
I also made a food in the kitchen with you.  Well that was because you asked me to help you.
I can't even cook since I'm afraid the nails will get dirty...
Then just take care of your hands.
Come once in a while.
Your hand is very rough.
It is, right?
That hand is not just a hand.
It's the hand that made the rookie of the golf industry, Sung Mi Soo.
Oh, are you Sung Mi Soo's mother?
Wow...
Then we are taking care of Min Hae Ryung and Sung Mi Soo's mothers!!
Come often!
Yes...
You two seem close.
We are friends.
I see.
Sung Mi Soo likes it, right?
The rookie awards? Yes of course.
It would have been better if both of them could get it...
Why aren't there any double prize winners.
How can two people get rookie awards.
My Hae Ryung can get the Best Player of the Year award next year.
Yes...
Subtitles brought to you by Birdy Buddy Team @ viki.com
Should we give a toast?
To congratulate Sung Mi Soo's winning of the Rookie Prize.
Cheers!
Oh, what's up Hae Ryung?
What are you doing right now?
I'm...
Eating dinner with Mi Soo
Also to give her her trophy.
Did you eat yet?
Of course I ate already.
look at what time it is
Enjoy your meal
Give Mi Soo my congratulations
I wanted to see some Korean players.
But all the games seems to be over.
There are a lot of good players in LPGA.
I'm looking for new players.
All the good players are already in a long term contract, so I can't do anything.
Do you still sleep with your 8 iron?
I just did that that time!
It looked very natural to me!
Now you will hold onto that trophy when you sleep...right?
You are jealous.
What?
I also got a present to give you!
I should just return it.
Why return it!
It was just a joke...
Wow!
It's pretty
Do you like it?
It's ok, it's ok
Compared to that guy, I'm not that great but...
but still..
I still don't understand why you won't accept me
That's your problem
You start of by saying that you are worse off than others.
The guy Gong Sook met
how do you know that he is a good guy or a bad guy?
He might have a good job or a good family background.
You were mad that I messed up her set up date...
You know that!
and pork is all you give me?
You should have at least ordered korean beef!
Should I order korean beef?
Aigoo..
How can I communicate with you..
You...
do you want to marry Gong Sook?
Yes.
If you allow me too
Gong Sook...
Can you keep her happy?
She...
I can't promise that I will make her live like a princess.
I can't lie that she won't ever have to wash the dishes.
But,
I will not make her cry because we have no money to feed on.
I won't make her cry because I am sick.
I won't make her cry
because of myself.
Let's eat
America?
Your talent is too good
just to be used in Korea.
Thank you for the compliment.
But I am not experienced with real games that much.
and also that...
I want to stay with my friends and family
How long do you think you can survive in Won Resort?
As long as you stay here,
how much you try, you will always feel like a adopted child here.
Don't misunderstand my intentions.
Who ever was in that position would feel the same.
Why did you...
Come to be particularily?
Sung Mi Soo?
Isn't she in your company?
All the contracts are not completed until it ends.
Penalty and everything...
I don't want anything complicated.
It won't be complicated.
I am going to plea not to the president of the Won Resort
but my mother.
This is what I do.
I am doing this so that I can live
but making good players play in much better condition
makes me feel good.
When I was in the worst situation
when the world was against me
the only company that held out their hand was Won Resort.
What if the Resort would just let you go easily?
Then would you go to the States?
It might be a little bit uncomfortable
it can be a little bit slow
I won't leave Won Resort.
There is no game for a while since its season off
So I was thinking of going to Australia or New Zealand.
You going to come with me, right?
I should also ask Mi Soo.
Why Mi Soo?
You are both Won Resort players
I don't think I can just send one player for training abroad.
What I meant by going abroad was not for the training.
Hae Ryung.
If you don't get ready right now, games next year will get hard.
You know that better than me.
Then I can just try harder next year and get ready for the next next year's game.
If you are in a bad state, we should consider that.
But Mi Soo can't just rest
because you are taking a rest.
Did you not hear?
Mi Soo will soon get a new coach.
You don't have to care for her anymore.
What?!
New coach?
Mom said that she will tell you in person.
I guess I went ahead...
Does Mi Soo know?
Mi Soo, Mi Soo, Mi Soo...
Now I'm really getting sick of it.
Is your head just full of Mi Soo?
New coach...
then I can just find a new coach...
Subeam @ viki.comtitles brought to you by Birdy Buddy T
What exactly are you trying to do?
I know I did wrong
I want to be alone
If you're going to be like this, it will be difficult
What will be difficult?
Difficult for you and Sung Mi Soo?
Stop it right now!
Untill when are you going to be like this?
I...
am not stupid.
I know what's right and wrong.
I know really well that I shouldn't do this to her.
I know that she is a great person.
But it's not going well.
I just can't control myself when I see you two together.
Then are you still...
going to make such a energy consuming fight?
That's why
we should leave.
America or anywhere!
I really didn't know you would be this selfish.
Min Hae Ryung.
John.
John!
Hae Ryung!
Mom..
Did something happen?
Sung Mi Soo will go to the States.
Just let her go without saying anything.
What happened?
Nothing happened, she will just go. So you just
let her go when she says she wants to go.
Okay?
Calm down and talk to me.
I cannot undersatnd what you are trying to say.
All you have to do is
just letting her go with no conditions.
Just do that.
There is no reason why I should stop her from leaving to a big company in America.
I have no reason to keep the pride of the current company.
But,
If this is not her own choice
I cannot agree.
I will hold on to it.
Min Hae Ryung!
Why is that so hard?
It's a good chance for her as well.
I will look for a new coach right away.
New coach?
It won't matter.
As long as she is in Won Resort, John won't let her go!
Why do they have to be seperated?
The things they went through together, the relationship they have...
those things exist but how can they act like they don't know each other?
Mom..
You know what?
I know that all.
So every morning I tell myself in the mirror
that I shouldn't be like this today.
That Mi Soo is a good co worker.
That John loves me only.
But it's so hard.
If I see John smiling at Mi Soo
it drives me crazy!
It kills me to see them looking at each other!
Subtitles brougt to you by Birdy Buddy Team @ viki.com
If... Won Resort just sends you off easily
would you go to America?
You are my player, right?
Sung Mi Soo!
Yes, coach.
This is Sung Mi Soo.
I...
want to go.
But there are some conditions.
I want to...
move as fast as I can.
Really?
Of course!
All of a sudden?
The manager
was in the awards ceremony by chance.
She saw me getting the rookie award
and she had interest in me even before that.
The world is so small you know. The president and they know each other somehow.
What did the president say?
She obviously said okay.
She said that it would be a good opportunity.
But still... you didn't play much game after you became a Won Resort player.
Is it possible to change companies like this?
Others are suffering because they can't go.
Why does she have to read other people's minds.
The president
also likes it better if she goes.
What is he saying?
Hey Sung Tae Gap!
He is making no sense at all.
I don't know.
You can't even speak English!
Are you fearless
or
is it that you have no other choice!
He is...
he sometimes thinks that he is older than me.
Aren't you hungry?
Let's go out for some noodles!
I need to go on a diet!
Where do you need to loose weight?
I'm worried the plane won't fly.
Are you really going to go?
Can I not go?
That's not true...but
why do I feel...
so bad?
They say that chances come without notice.
I need to hold onto that chance when its here.
What did the coach say?
Oh..
I didn't tell him yet...
Did Min Hae Ryung ill-treat you?
Mom!
If not,
did coach not care of you much since he met his old lover?
Mom!
It's either one of them!
I am your mother! You think I won't know?
You are my mom, but why don't you know?
They are both not true...
Mom,
I want to just concentrate on golf.
If I'm here, it reminds me of master
bad memories of Jay Park...
mom, dad, and Tae Gap...
all of them.
I just want to forget them
I want to concentrate on golf where noone is there.
Really?
You...
just...
not running away because you are hurt?
Of course!
And mom...
to coach,
don't tell him that the president knows this company.
He might misunderstand the situation.
Okay...
Okay so just go on and tell him for sure. He might be disappointed to know later.
Okay.
I will tell him tomorrow.
I wanted to discuss with you about being a coach.
Rather than finding one all of a sudden
I want to make a training program abroad
for both Mi Soo and Hae Ryung each.
While the winter passes as they are in the training
when a good coach comes out
then it would be better to bring him in.
That sounds good.
And the coach...
please look for two of them.
I want to...
take a rest.
We will take a look at bring in the new coach.
Something might happen.
Something?
Sung Mi Soo wants to move to a company in America.
What?
Did you think over it?
Yes.
I have the tendency to think quickly.
Is there anything that I can do?
I was in America for quite long
I might be able to help you.
I will call you when I get there.
I can just call you when something comes up.
You can pay for the phone calls.
It's coach!
I didn't tell him yet...
Yes coach.
You surprised me!
Right now?
Where are you?
Okay.
I need your
support.
Both coach and you
have a lot of experience abroad
so you might say that it's really nothing...
I really want to go.
Please say good things about all this.
I should go.
Bye.
I think love is
love is important.
To me it is.
I heard it in the radio
It is hard for a person
to find someone to love
when capable of loving someone..
Really hard...
How good is it to you then?
I will support you.
How can you decide so easily without talking to me?
So I was going to tell you now...
It is hard for you to go right now.
If you really want to go
I will find a place for you.
What's the difference...
The one that you look for
and the one that agency finds for me...
It will be hard for you if you go out like this without any preperation.
Did you go out with preperation?
In the old days...
Did Hae Ryung go out with preperation?
All the golf players
They were not fully armed
when they went out.
What makes you think that it will be impossible for me?
Really...
is it really your won choice?
I want to play in a bigger stage.
Honestly...
I really don't want to care for all the little emotional troubles...
I have nothing with me
and there is a very long way to go.
Ther is no time to wait...
The surrounding is
stopping me.
Then let's go together.
Until you get settled.
The three of us?
You want all of us to go?
Cheers!
Wow you are the best among us, you are even going to America!
I know. With talent now you even get scouted.
You are awsome.
Why are you doing this?
You know what I dream of these days?
I dream of going to a supermarket being very hungry but not being able to speak a word
being lost and not being able to speak a word and sweating myself...
Wow... it really sucks.
Hey, we have our own bodies!
Body language!
Don't try too hard to learn English
just work on your looks!
Looks?
Pretty women are international language itself.
The beauty itself...
You are crazy!
Come back as soon as you think something's wrong.
Don't try too hard on your own.
Take care of parents well.
Don't just date around, okay?
I will take care of them. Don't worry.
If it's his parents
they are my parents as well.
Hey!
One day you would have to call Mi Soo 'Hyung Nim (a term used to call one's husbands older sister in Korea)'.
Oh really? Should I call her that now?
Hyung Nim!
Wow!! Don't do that!
Hyung Nim! Nice shot in America as well!
Let's eat now.
Wow!
I'm just going to go now.
I saw you yesterday.
I will call you when I get there.
Take care of what you eat.
They will take a good care after you.
Don't worry.
Okay.
Good bye.
Then...
Please take a good care of Sung Mi Soo.
Of course. I'll see you again.
Sung Mi Soo is leaving today...
Did you get to see her?
I saw her yesterday.
I hear that the manager will take her to the airport.
The person who was just with me is the manager of Sung Mi Soo's agency.
Oh...
I see.
Don't worry too much.
Sung Mi Soo is much stronger than us.
Yes.
Subtitles brought to you by Birdy Buddy Team @ viki.com
When will you give my Rookie Awards? - Hae Ryung
This is a famous place for a sports agency.
I take care of golf industry.
I am around all the games around the world to find a great player.
The person who was just with me
Is the manager of Sung Mi Soo's agency.
Mi Soo Mi Soo Mi Soo!!
Now I am really sick of it...
Is she all that is in your head?
I don't want to get bothered by little emotions here.
I have a very long way to go.
There is no time to wait..
the surrounding is...
stopping me.
Shall we go now?
They are now getting on board.
Of course.
Coach!
What are you doing?
There is something I need to check.
This isn't right.
Please call Hae Ryung.
That things got a little bit wrong.
Coach why are you doing this?
Why are you doing this?
Let's go.
Things got more complicated.
I will go on a evening plane.
You can't.
Why are you doing this to me?
What is the reason for you going to America all of a sudden?
Did someone ask you to move out?
Your hometown, your family...
Why are you leaving by leaving all this behind?
Why?!
I am going because I want to.
Because you want to go?
You knew that Hae Ryung was behind that manager.
You knew that but why did you go?
If you smile, that's enough for me.
Do you know that?
Rather than me smiling, when you feel good
and when you can smile, that is enough for me.
Why?
What am I to you?
What am I that makes you sacrifice all this?
'Cause I love you..
Two years later.
Sung Mi Soo.
Yes.
If you win this Shanghai Open
then you are winning nice games in a row.
I want to hear your honest thought about this record.
I never held on to the result.
I just tried my best for the best shot.
You are doing great and even was casted to be the cover page of the New York Times.
What's the motive that made you get over the great slump last year and
get the great triumph this year?
The motive?
That motive...
longing...
Subtitles brought to you by Birdy Buddy @ viki.com
Why did you say that you would go?
You knew that I was behind it, but why did you go?
My love...
is not for you to be happy...
Why did the coach...
disappear like that?
I didn't call you because I couldn't get home.
When I am suffering with clear mind
You need to drink...
Where did you get this?
I got it as a present!