The film was awarded
the Jury Prize
at the 47th International Film
Festival in Cannes (France),
Grand Prix “Amber Panther”
at the 1st International Film Festival
of Baltic States
in Kaliningrad (Russia)
Studio TRITE (Russia)
Camera One (France)
NIKITA MIKHALKOV
MICHEL SEYDOUX
present
Just like a boy.
- Switch off the light.
- What light? Oh, the light.
Hold it.
Philippe, I asked you
to speak Russian.
Your father put me in service in 1901.
Took you in service, Philippe.
Took me…
Philippe, turn on the radio.
The radio.
This is the radio…
He asked me
to speak only French with you.
Here, I found it.
It’s something absolutely amazing,
as your maman used to say.
Uninvited guests.
In the last two weeks there have been
recorded in regions around Moscow
severale cases…
Several.
Several
cases
of a sudden appearance
of fireballs.
The uninvited guests disappear as
unexpectedly as they appearing…
Appear.
Appear, doing a lot of damage
to the people’s economy, to the health,
and even life, of work people.
Working people.
The direction of the fireballs’
movement
directly depends
on the activity of their position
neary objets.
- Near.
- Objects.
Some believe that
this phenomenon is nothing less
than a partie of well…
- Part.
…well thought-out
and prepared sabotage.
BURNT BY THE SUN
It’s me.
I agree.
Original idea by
Nikita MIKHALKOV
Screenplay by Nikita MIKHALKOV
Rustam IBRAGIMBEKOV
Dialogue by Rustam IBRAGIMBEKOV
Nikita MIKHALKOV
Starring
Oleg MENSHIKOV
Nikita MIKHALKOV
Ingeborga DAPKUNAITE
Nadya MIKHALKOVA
Also starring
Vyacheslav TIKHONOV
Svetlana KRYUCHKOVA
Vladimir ILYIN
Alla KAZANSKAYA
Nina ARKHIPOVA
Avangard LEONTYEV
Andre UMANSKY
Inna ULYANOVA
Lyubov RUDNEVA
Original music by
Eduard ARTEMYEV
Cinematography by
Vilen KALYUTA
Production Designers – Vladimir ARONIN
Alexander SAMULEKIN
English subtitles by
Tatiana Kameneva
Producers – Nikita MIKHALKOV
Michel SEYDOUX
BURNT BY THE SUN
Directed by
Nikita MIKHALKOV
Mama! Grandma!
The tanks!
Tanks are coming, mama!
Mama! Grandma!
There! Get it!
- Come on!
- There you go!
Come on!
Marusya.
That’s all. A blissful break.
Give me the duckbill.
The duckbill? Here.
Marusya.
What?
The tanks! The tanks, Ilyushka!
Turn back!
You’ll ruin the crops!
Are you crazy, Lieutenant?
- Get out of here!
- Oh, you!..
Gee up, Boy!
Wait! Where’s
Zgoryanka or Zagoryanka?
- I’ve got lost.
- There’s no such village here.
- What?
- There’s no such place. Go back.
- What do you mean, back?
- I’m busy.
It’s only 7, and he’s too busy already.
I’ll soak it. I’ll soak it.
What do you think it is?
This is a shirt. A man may
have anything in his shirt.
I’ll soak it. I’ll soak it.
Maybe he has 3 rubles in his shirt.
Or whatever,
some documents.
- Who is there?
- I need to see Kotov.
- The tanks are going.
- You know what time it is?
- I need to take my medicine.
- I need Kotov. It’s an emergency!
What happened?
Who are you?
- Comrade Kotov.
- What do you want?
You must help us.
The tanks are going over the field.
What tanks?
Our tanks. They’re ours.
- No one can stop them but you.
- How do you like that!
- Only me!
- No one else.
Thank you very much, my dear.
It’s my day off!
To stop the tanks…
Found yourself a scapegoat.
They’re begging you to come.
What do you have your chairman for?
- The chairman’s on a dirigible.
- On a dirigible!
The NKVD has arrived,
he oh’s and ah’s.
- Oh’s and ah’s.
- Crying.
Crying…
- Everything depends on you.
- I got only one day off!
- Where shall I run?
- Here’s the horse.
- What?
- Can you ride without a saddle?
Please.
Here we go!
My day off!
Hi.
- What’s the horse’s name?
- Boy.
Stand, boy. Stand.
All right, keep up with me.
Dad! Where are you going, dad?
Just one day off!
No, they have to rouse Kotov!
They have to find Kotov in a bathhouse!
What are you doing?
This is the people’s bread grain!
I’ll send you to the tribunal!
What are you doing?!
What are you staring at?
Get out of here!
Why?
I’ve got an order!
What order?
Don’t you yell!
I’ve got my own commander.
What?
Hold him. Not afraid of the tanks,
but shit yourself before a horse?
Are you nuts or what?!
You goat!
Get lost before I shot you!
I’m going to wipe my ass with you,
Comrade Senior Lieutenant!
- What?!
- Attention!
- I’ll show you!..
- Who are you?
Don’t you know me?
Perhaps you didn’t recognize me?
And now?
You recognize me now?
Comrade Kotov…
Stand still.
Who is your commander?
I…
Brigade Commander Lapin.
Lapin? Oh God!
All right, where’s your liaison?
What liaison?
Sexual, my ass!
Where’s the wireless?
The aviation is coming, Comrade Division
Commander. What do we do?
The aviation is coming!
They’re flying in the sky!
Comrade Kotov!
Why are you standing?
I’ll tell you why we’re standing.
Who is that?
A fish in the net.
It’s Sergey Kotov.
Hi, Misha.
- Kotov?
- That’s right.
Comrade Division Commander?
What are you doing there?
Scattering sticks and
picking them up to form bricks.
- What?
- Yes, yes.
Misha, perhaps you’ll be taking
prisoners and bombing cities too?
The lieutenant here agrees with me.
Yes, he agrees. He agrees.
Look here, Misha.
Do you remember me well?
Yes, Comrade Division Commander.
- You remember me very well?
- Very well, Comrade Commander.
Then turn your machines back
and devise another stratagem.
- Yes, Comrade Division Commander.
- Repeat it, please.
Yes, Comrade Division Commander.
There you go.
And what’s your name?
I say, what’s your name?
Misha. Oh, sorry, Kolia.
I was a bit rude to you, Kolia.
Please, excuse me.
Why this stupid smile, Kolia?
And you make your ears grow,
to see the road better.
You see?
I recognized him right away.
Turn the machines around!
Why didn’t you go home?
- You were swearing!
- Who?
My God, you swore like hell!
Me?
Me? When?
Did I swear, Nadya?
as for me, I didn’t hear anything.
Why are you saying it then?
I got only one day in a week.
Can I spend it with my family?
To say a thing like that!
- No one forced you to say it.
- What wrong did I say?
He got so excited. He was shouting:
bread grain, field, collective farm!
What do I have to do with it?
I’m not a Michurin, am I?
It’s just amazing!
Orders, my dear, must be carried out.
I’ll stick up a watermelon to them!
But they obeyed me, didn’t they?
Though they may stick up
a watermelon to me, too,
and they’ll be just right.
Seryozha, there’re no watermelons now,
they’ll come later.
What?
At dinnertime.
Some family!
Even your uncle, Marusya,
is crazy, though he’s a professor.
I don’t understand why one should
go to this dirty village bathhouse
when he has a wonderful, clean bathroom.
I know. I know.
Suvorov, Kutuzov and Pushkin, -
they all washed in a bathhouse.
But a child has no business
in a bathhouse.
Vsevolod, why do you always keep
silent?
You are… like Switzerland,
you’re well-fed and aloof.
On the contrary. I’m hungry
and passionate like a Gypsy.
You always sit in the way,
with those legs of yours…
Oh, damn it!
Our commander is right,
this is a madhouse.
The tired-out tender sun
To the sea bade its farewell,
When you came to me to tell
That there was no love.
Masha, Goshka, hi!
Hi! Hands off! Hurray!
Grannies, what are you doing there?
Why did you start all this?
- Why? I don’t understand.
- What do you mean, why?
Borya had brought these medicines
before the Revolution.
Why are you throwing them away?
It’s the only way.
Look how many of them.
And she stuffed in some grass, too.
You know that
she’s crazy about medicines.
The doctor prescribed
for her to take iron,
so she boiled nails
and drank the broth.
Girl!
Yes?
Excuse me, girl, is this Zagoryanka?
Why Zagoryanka?
What Zagoryanka?
Maybe Zgoryanka?
Oh, my God…
Excuse me, young man,
is this WAMP?
Yes, it’s some swamp.
What do you mean, swamp?
A community of writers, actors
musicians and painters.
The acronym is WAMP, my friend.
She’s coming.
Right, like salted dough.
What is this?
Confession is the mother of justice.
The young pioneers brought it
for Comrade Kotov.
For breakfast.
No, can you imagine it?
Confession is the mother of justice.
Seva, please, no comments.
Your tongue is your worst enemy.
I’ve always believed and still believe
that presumption of innocence
is the foundation of any law,
including the Roman law
which I have the honor to teach.
Stop it. Stop it.
It’s just some buffoonery.
- Olia, when will you give me a haircut?
- You think you need it?
Don’t you see how overgrown I am?
Borya just loved it
when I cut his hair.
Bring me the mail.
My brother had
an awful hair style.
But it was so…
We had another purge.
Half the faculty body
was fired for poor knowledge
of the original works
of Marxism-Leninism.
They haven’t touched me.
Uncle Seva, play it.
- What?
- Play something.
Wait, it’s my dental plate…
I’m sorry.
Nadya, this instrument is yours.
I’ll show you
how to blow it!
Look!
- Bravo!
- Very good.
Where was I…
I wanted to say something very
important… Oh, yes!
Here I am!
Lyolya, what are you doing?
It’s like a greatcoat,
will never wear out.
It’s not ready yet.
Everything is great.
Don’t be angry, please.
It will look beautiful.
I’m upset.
I wanted to demonstrate a really good
thing.
You can already see it’s good.
It becomes you.
- It does?
- Very much.
There it goes again.
An infuriated virgin
is more fearsome than a tiger.
She sucks nails.
One day we’re going
to discover her poisoned corpse.
Good morning to everybody!
Happy holiday, ladies and gentlemen!
Pardon, comrades.
Mokhova!
- Don’t touch Katya.
- These are some biscuits.
They’re preparing something great!
The celebration of Stalin’s dirigible!
What? Right.
What’s going on?
It’s the dance of a bird that flew
in a dirigible, our dear enchantress.
An interesting word – entrance,
enchantress, sorceress.
How rich is the Russian language!
What do you think, Sergey Petrovich?
- Happy holiday!
- Yes…
Why is he picking on me?
Really,
you shouldn’t, Sergey Petrovich.
He never takes
alcohol.
Never.
No, don’t say anything. After all,
today is holiday. It’s hot.
You know what I just remembered?
You know what I remembered?
I remembered how Grand Duke
Dmitri Pavlovich
rocked him as a child.
Yes.
He rocked him, rocked, and got him
over rocks…
…early in the morning.
You’re like Petya Trofimov.
Chekhov had one, remember?
- “The Cherry Orchard”.
- Yes, the perennial student.
And you’re a perennial docent. All
your friends are academicians already.
Oh no! They’re not my friends.
My friends… Some have been
gone, the others far away.
- Where’s the debt?
- What debt?
That I’ve given for the sodas woman.
- Mother, why are you in a coat?
- I tried it on.
- It’s so hot, and you’re in a coat.
- I had to demonstrate it.
I’ll return it tomorrow. Honest.
Where’s the hot dish?
Kirill, do you always drink chacha
in the morning after port wine?
You know, Sergey Petrovich,
drinking shouldn’t be looked upon
as a vice, so to speak…
How did you put it?
As a vice of the will.
It should be regarded as
a movement of a distressed soul.
Enchantress!
And you borrowed 5 rubles from Marusya.
Why don’t you return it?
It’s not nice, is it?
The tea is cold too, by the way.
Come on. What’s the matter with you?
See, he got hurt.
Lyuba Grusheva.
Lyuba, why didn’t you say
you were coming here?
I would’ve given you a lift on my
bike. It’s so romantic.
Especially when it’s a ladies’ bike
without a crossbar.
So what?
I don’t know. I never rode
a bicycle without a crossbar.
Are we going swimming?
- Yes!
- Greetings!
- Greetings.
- Are you going swimming?
It’s not me. Of course I am.
When will you learn not
to throw things about?
Well, Lyuba dear,
your thesis is not bad.
Oh, great! Comrade Kotov!
We have his portrait at our faculty.
- On a horse?
- No.
Without a horse. On foot.
Do you have my portrait too?
And who are you?
Me?
I’m that horse in a dress.
You’re joking.
I’ll tell you later.
Yes, Mokhova, that’s the end of your
medicines.
Boris Konstantinovich brought a French
one. I forgot against what.
Don’t cry, Mokhova, please.
I’ll tell dad
to bring you more pills.
Oh, the pioneers, Mokhova!
Don’t cry.
The pioneers never cry.
The pioneers are coming.
It’s some holiday today.
You know which one?
You know, I don’t understand
their holidays.
But I know it’s some big day,
something big and Soviet.
- I think I’ll lie down, too.
- Sure.
I feel somewhat…
somewhat giddy.
I’d better lie down.
And Nadya…
Nadya knows all the holidays, every one.
My God!
Whose smell am I sniffing?
Can it be the future pioneer
and exemplary girl Nadya?
How do you know me?
Well!
How would I not know
the future most exemplary student?
Perhaps you’re a summer Santa Claus?
Yes!
Nadya, I’m a magician from Maghreb.
What’s Maghreb?
Well. Maghreb is the country
of summer Santa Clauses.
A Soviet country?
Of course.
All summer Santa Clauses
live only in a Soviet country.
- What about winter Santas?
- Winter ones, too.
- Maybe you’re a doctor?
- Quite.
Mokhova needs a doctor.
- Is she still alive?
- Yes, alive.
My great-grandmother Lyolya
has drowned all her medicines.
She alive, too?
Very much alive!
Mokhova!
He’s to see you, Mokhova.
Out of the way, virgin!
Who invited you here?
What?!
Attendez!
Go wash Marusya’s peepees!
We’ve got a lot of our own nutcases
here.
What do you want here?
Silence, polygamist!
What do you mean?
Happy holiday,
valorous great-grandmothers!
Why great-grandmothers?
I’m not even a grandmother yet.
Katya! Katya!
Anybody!
Why do you have to stamp your feet?
You’re here too, the lover of sweet
wines and capricious women.
34-15, extension 19.
What did he say?
That’s the office telephone number.
Hello!
Mitya!
I didn’t recognize you!
My God, Mitya, my dear!
That’s what Borya used to say
when Marusya was a baby.
Go wash Marusya’s peepees.
Dmitri, I must tell you…
Uncle Seva!
Welcome back, Mitya.
At last, Mitya.
Quiet, please.
Please meet my husband, Sergey.
And this is that very Mitya,
a friend of the house, my father’s pet.
His best student.
- Kotov.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Me, too.
- We’ve met before, you know.
Of course, I remember.
You have?
It was long ago, fleetingly,
and in the past life.
- And who is this?
- Our daughter, Nadya.
Nadya, you can call me Uncle Mityai.
Uncle Mityai!
Close your mouth.
Mokhova!
You’re my undrilled pearl.
Are you still undrilled?
Mokhova never dusts, does she?
Who?
I never dust?!
Never dusts, as usual.
Wait!
Wait. The New Year eve. From 1927
to 1928, before I left.
We were hiding presents.
I hid a chocolate right here.
Mokhova, I hid a chocolate.
Nothing!
Everyone has a holiday,
but they have to spoil it for me.
Lydia Stepanovna, he does it
on purpose!
Marusya, please, give me some
water. I’m dying of thirst.
Is Philippe with you?
Philippe is with me. I’ll tell you
everything after I wash up.
Has he grown old?
I’ve never seen him young.
Mitya!
Are you married?
Yes, I’m married.
- Do you have children?
- I do.
- How many?
- Three!
Good boy!
- You haven’t given up music, have you?
- No.
Mitya, I must ask you,
in all these years…
Yes? Yes?
Never mind. Later.
- Uncle Mityai!
- Yes, Aunt Nadya?
What would you have,
tea with jam or coffee with milk?
I’ll have coffee with jam.
Isn’t it something!
Grandma!
Uncle Mitya said
he’d have coffee with jam.
No, he couldn’t!
Nadya!
- Nadya, how old are you?
- Six!
Olga Nikolayevna, remember when
Marusya was 6 and I was 16?
We went to the Bolshoi Theatre.
Boris Konstantinovich was conducting.
Mitya, I’m very sorry.
Just until the evening…
Tonight I’ll…
Mitya.
I’ve brought him a towel.
The overture started, and she
nudges me: “I want to pee.”
Thanks, Mitya.
I say: “We’ve just arrived. Hold it.”
And she: “I want to pee.”
I say: “Hold on.”
And she says: “I want to pee.
I want to pee.”
Everybody begins to “sh” at us.
But she says she wants to pee,
and that’s it.
And where can I take her?
She says: “I won’t go alone.”
I can’t take her to a men’s room,
and I can’t go to a ladies’ room.
What do I do?
I’m dragging her to the men’s room.
And we run into Rakhmaninov coming
out of there.
Rakhmaninov… and he says:
“Whose is this…
…lovely child?”
I say:
“It’s Boris Konstantinovich’s child.”
He says:
“Such a good boy.
Tell Borya
to buy him trousers.”
Coffee or tea?
I just wanted some water.
Nothing for me, thank you.
Thank you, I had a late breakfast.
Bon appetite.
This is dad’s chair.
Nadya, aren’t you ashamed of yourself?
Dad, you did drive Kirik away.
Kirik deserves it.
- Dmitri.
- Yes.
I didn’t mean that.
Dmitri, in yesterday’s Pravda…
- Serge, I asked you, didn’t I?
- Mother.
Marusya, you want to drink something?
Me? No.
And why this…
This?
This is a glass.
Yes…
Well, how about it?
Are we going swimming?
We’ve already wasted half a day.
- Let’s go swimming!
- With pleasure!
- Where’re your things?..
- Hanging over there.
Kirik, come on!
Everything as before.
You haven’t changed a bit.
Only a different hairstyle.
As for you, you’re not
changing either.
- Really?
- Come on…
Too late for us to change…
- The sugar.
- I’ll get it, mother.
Today at 17 o’clock,
on an open stage of the Park of
the Taking of Bastille,
a gala concert will take place
playing the works of
composer Dvinyayev,
dedicated to the 6th anniversary
of the national holiday
of Stalinist dirigible construction
and aeronautics.
The admission is free.
Happy holiday, dear comrades!
I won’t give it!
Comrade. Comrade.
What time is it?
Halt! Attention!
At ease, guys.
Happy holiday!
Mokhova, don’t thrust dolls at me,
I’m not little anymore.
What else shall I thrust at you?
You’re supposed to play with dolls.
Stop being naughty.
Not little anymore…
I want to be a pioneer so much.
I just can’t wait.
Why?
What do you mean “why”? To get up
to a bugle, to go swim to a whistle.
Yeah, and lie in a coffin to an orchestra.
Why?
Don’t you understand?
To get up by a bugle.
To a whistle…
…go swimming.
To a drum…
…go marching.
Dining to an accordion.
If you do it all well,
you’ll be lying in a coffin
to an orchestra.
Why?
Marusya, I’ll go to the platform.
Listen, Uncle Mityai.
- Why are you saying thar?
- What am I saying?
Stop pestering him.
Am I pestering him?
Yes, you are.
I like that!
All right, you may sit here. I’m off.
Here, play with it.
Nadya!
What?
Nothing. Go run.
Attention! Whoever found a white
poodle named Filimon,
please come to Dacha No.17
and ask for the guard of
the order-holding professor Kalyuta.
Happy holiday, dear comrades!
Why are we pouting?
What happened to you?
Mom drove me away.
Mom drove you away?
Oh-oh-oh, mom drove us away.
Oh, what a bad mom.
You must have been pestering them?
With your questions?
Honest?
They want to talk.
They’re old friends.
They haven’t seen each other
for so long.
And here some kid nags them with her
questions.
We’d better go and take
a boat ride.
Sergey!
Don’t! You know I don’t like it.
Let her swim here.
Marusya.
We’ll decide it ourselves, all right?
We’ll be all right.
And you sunbathe and rest.
Strong bronzed shoulders.
Of course, I understand.
A white-teethed smile,
portraits in every office.
But it can all be destroyed!
With a flick of the fingers.
Olga Nikolayevna, remember when
Marusya was that little?
Of course, I remember.
She was about 2 months old, I think.
And, respectively, I was 10.
You took me to her crib,
and said: “Here, Mityul,
meet little Musya.”
I reached with my finger
for her hand,
and she suddenly grabbed my finger!
And she opened her eyes.
Then she farted and said:
“Come closer.”
What nonsense you’re talking!
How could I say anything
being only 2 months old?
You said it, you did.
If you didn’t say it, you thought it.
And what is this?
- You didn’t have it before.
- What?
It’s nothing, I brushed it against a cover.
What cover?
A coffin’s cover.
I wonder, if we ask them,
can they turn it on louder?
Marusya.
Why don’t you
ask me about anything?
You keep silent.
Why do you keep silent?
I’m reading.
Why don’t you ask?
I don’t want to know anything more.
What do you mean “more”?
More than I already know.
It’s interesting.
What do you know?
What is this?
When did you do this?
- Back then.
- And?
They had saved me. I didn’t know
I was supposed to do it in the water.
So the blood doesn’t coagulate.
Marusya.
Musya, Mityul.
DEAD.
- DEAD!
- Quiet!
Defense exercises and drill.
Civil defense exercises again.
A chemical attack.
Go away.
Go away, or they’ll take you.
- They’re still far away.
- They’ll take you again!
They’ll put on you those hoses again!
I’m scared.
They’ll put gas masks on us again,
grab us by our breasts.
We can still get away.
They caught us then,
those perverts.
- Porters, Katya.
- What porters?
Perverts. They grabbed me
by my breasts, my knees.
Any girl would be only happy.
Stop talking nonsense.
- What are you saying?
- A big deal.
I’m a virgin, and they grab me.
Everyone in the neighborhood
knows you’re a virgin.
Look at your little heels.
So round, so soft, so beautiful.
And take mine.
Just look at them.
See?
Like soles of a boot.
Hard and worn.
You can put out cigarettes with them.
Have you run a lot?
Yes, I have run and I have walked.
Where did you run?
Now after them, then from them.
And you’ll have those heels of yours
till your old age.
- Why?
You’ll always have them
that round.
Because there’ll be many
airplanes and automobiles,
streetcars, trolleybuses, the metro.
The roads will be very smooth.
The shoes will be very comfortable,
the socks will be very soft.
Why?
What do you mean “why”?
Because that’s what we’re building
the Soviet power for, Nadya.
So that everyone has their heels as
round as yours till their old age.
And so they don’t need
to run from anybody.
You’ll just walk quietly, honey.
Only study well.
Respect your parents.
And love your Soviet motherland.
How hot you are.
Why are you so hot?
You’re not sick, are you?
- Honest?
- Honest.
Oh, Dad, I feel
so good with you.
Really?
And I feel good with you.
I feel peaceful with you.
I feel so easy with you.
I just adore you, Daddy.
We’ll be always sailing
with you like this, right?
And with mom.
Of course, with mom. By all means.
How can we do without mom?
I’ll go and swim.
Comrade, what time is it?
Are you all right?
Will you help this poor invalid up?
Yes, yes, of course.
- Half past one.
- Thanks.
What a fool.
Mitya.
Mityul.
Mitya!
- You got scared?
- You stupid!
- Got scared, didn’t you?
- Let your wife get scared for you!
Remember this spot?
A month after
Boris Konstantinovich’s death,
you caught
Olga Nikolayevna with Kirik.
It was awful.
You got so upset,
and ran away from home.
I found you here.
Right here.
It was cold.
It was raining.
I tried to persuade you to come back,
but you wouldn’t.
And I stayed with you.
Don’t you remember?
You don’t remember it either?
We spent the night
in a buoy-keeper’s shed.
Our first night.
And what was next?
I had a book by Shakespeare
with me, “Hamlet”.
I read it.
She cried. You…
…cried.
Ere yet the salt of most unrighteous tears
Had left the flushing in her galled eyes…
You know what I remember
especially clearly?
The print on your belly.
From an elastic.
It was so pinkish.
- Like a baby’s.
- Why are you telling me this?
I don’t know why.
Marusya.
I thought that
since I had no life here,
it meant no one else had.
And no one was left from the former
life.
And now I find out that you’re all here.
And everything is as before with you.
Only without me.
Have you crossed me out?
Erased me…
…with a rubber?
A gas attack!
It’s a matter of state importance.
Put on the gas mask.
It’s the duty of every Soviet man and
woman
to strengthen civil defense
against the hydra of world
imperialism and fascism.
Forward!
I got your umbrella.
Let’s go. Don’t worry,
everything will be all right.
Hey, comrade!
Don’t you need wounded
people, comrade?
- We do.
- I’m wounded.
- Seriously wounded.
- Seriously?
- A gas mask.
- Yes!
- Lie down.
Forward.
Just a second!
Comrade! Comrade with a trunk!
And what about me? What about me?
- What’s the matter with you?
- I’ve been killed.
- We don’t take the killed.
- What do you mean you don’t?
A stretcher!
- A gas mask.
- Now you’re wounded.
And forward.
Oh, it hurts so much!
Forward!
Let me go, now!
Do you hear?
The girl on the front stretcher,
what’s your name?
I was ahead of you in line.
The Red Civil Defense is
the Soviet land’s strong shield against
the aggression of world imperialism!
Happy holiday, dear comrades!
I am on a cherry tree,
Cherries are so yummy.
Uncle Stalin’s telling us
To obey our mommy.
How’s that?
Where’re our folks?
Yes, it’s interesting.
Look, they’ve left the shoes,
and the ball,
and the book.
- And they left without us.
- Yes.
Daddy, why are you running?
Nadya.
Am I running?
I’m just walking.
You’re not catching up with me?
Let me carry you.
Like on a horse.
Here we go.
Let’s go and look.
Where can they be?
Daddy, can you imagine
if I forgot my book on the beach?
- What would mom have done to me?
- What would she have done…
- Daddy, it hurts.
- Where does it hurt? Where?
You’ve got some character. Mom is right,
you’ve got a hell of a character.
Daddy, you’re crushing my tummy.
Look, daddy, uncle Mityai’s pants
are hanging, and his shirt.
See how interesting? Uncle
Mityai has already hung his pants.
Come on, hang it.
- How can I hang it?
- Try to do it somehow.
Take aim and hang it.
Well, enough.
That’s it. That’s it.
Enough, that’s it.
Enough, I’m afraid, enough, enough!
I just recalled how Borya decided
to let the poor student Mitya
earn some money
by giving Musya
music lessons.
As long as I was in the room,
everything was very serious.
Legato, staccato,
pedaling, fingering.
Once I left them,
and it took me a while to stay out.
And suddenly I hear…
What did you play, Mitya?
Cancan!
Mother comes in, and I…
I was as little as Nadya,
and I was doing like this.
Dances!
Oh, no, come on.
Sergey Petrovich.
Why are you dining alone?
Why didn’t you wait for everybody?
I wanted to call them, Mokhova.
But I don’t speak French.
Yet.
Give me a napkin.
And you, Mokhova…
…do you speak French?
Then you, too, go to…
Shall I help you?
Dinner?
Let’s go and eat!
And where’s Sergey Petrovich?
Sergey Petrovich is already eating.
Mitya, your clothes must have dried
already. I’ll bring them.
Marusya, why are you
clutching my clothes so?
Hey, men, the address here,
it has washed off.
Help me. A village of
Zagoryanka, or Zagorka.
I’ve been circling the neighborhood
since morning.
How did you get here?
Get out of here, quick!
It’s a secret object here!
Get out of here!
How beautiful! How wonderful!
Just like when Borya was alive.
Oh, my God…
I remember Lyolya
singing this from the stage.
Oh, what a time it was!
What a time!
The time isn’t so bad now either,
but…
The general aroma…
The taste of life.
It has disappeared.
For good.
To listen to you, your life
used to be so good.
Yes, good.
Why didn’t you defend it then?
- I beg your pardon?
- Why haven’t you defended it?
We were defending ourselves.
How were you defending yourselves?
Why did you run?
- Who ran?
- You. Why did you run?
You, all armed,
supported by the Allies’ Intervention.
All strong and with shoulder straps.
Why were you running
from poor, illiterate people?
I, for one, had never had
any military training.
But I was driving you on and on,
from the Urals all through Siberia.
I was driving you all right.
It’s a philosophical question.
Right.
It’s a philosophical question,
my dear academician.
You always say that,
because you had nothing to offer.
You wanted everything to remain
as it was before.
Why? Because you hoped
everything would resolve by itself.
It would just resolve.
But it didn’t.
And now we’re reminiscing – oh-oh-oh,
what a life we had,
how good we felt,
how beautiful it was.
Sure, some of you
did the right thing
and began to serve the Revolution.
Efficiently, honestly,
with total dedication.
By the way, Sergey Petrovich,
though I’ve been pronounced
unfit for army service…
Because of your flatfoot.
Because of my flatfoot.
But I was…
…wounded.
In a poolroom with a ball.
Why do you keep arguing,
my dear comrades?
Oh, Nadya.
You know how they would call you
if you lived in France?
Nadine.
No. Nadia.
You know what, Nadia?
Come here.
Come, I’ll tell you a fairy tale.
A fairy tale.
In a certain realm
in a far-off land,
there lived once a boy
whose name was Aytim.
He could sing beautifully,
played many different
instruments and loved poetry.
And his parents were friends
with a very kind wizard
named…
…Sirob.
- Without a tail.
And the kind Sirob liked little
Aytim very much.
And he took him into
his house to raise him
and teach him magic music.
And they came to love each other, like
father loves son and son loves father.
That’s how the story goes, Nadine.
Soon Sirob had a daughter.
And they named her…
…Aysum.
A funny name.
Sirob had a big house,
filled with light and noise,
full of merriment,
and, of course, a happy house.
- Like ours.
Like yours.
Bit one day it all ended.
The coffee on a verandah
from white cups like those.
The charades,
and the croquet after dinner.
And the reading aloud
to the cricket’s singing.
And the debates and laughter,
everything had ended.
It had ended
because a war broke out.
A war with whom? With the bourgeois?
It doesn’t matter with whom, Nadine.
What’s important…
…is that Aytim went to fight.
And all that time,
in the trenches and in a hospital,
and in different countries,
every day,
yes, Nadine, every day
he was thinking of the big house,
and of the garden,
and of all the faces, and even
of the old cricket
whom everybody had cursed
when he interrupted the reading.
We have a cricket, too,
over there.
That’s a different cricket.
He sings cheerful songs.
And the other one sang sad songs.
Let’s have a drink, Nadya?
- Are you crazy?
- Let’s have a drink.
Let’s have it.
So, for 10 years he was wandering…
Oh, here we are!…
He was wandering over different lands.
He did all kinds of things:
drove a taxi cab,
played the piano in restaurants,
sang in the streets,
danced in a cabaret.
He even sewed slippers.
Thanks.
And all that time
he was terribly homesick
for that house.
The house he had lived in before.
And in 10 years he came back.
His parents were dead.
They were killed
in that war with the bourgeois.
He had nowhere to go anymore,
and right from his train
he ran to his teacher.
It was wintertime.
And, but the snow, he didn’t
recognize a thing in his country.
So much it had changed.
Only the house was as before.
His heart skipping a beat, he rang…
…the bell.
The door was opened by a girl
of such a beauty
that Aytim had never
seen anywhere,
though he traveled over many countries.
“Who are you?”
asked the dumbfounded Aytim.
“I’m Aysum,” answered the beauty.
“Oh, my God,
are you the Aysum
who peed under the columns
and fell asleep on your father’s knees
when he taught music to me?”
“Yes, I’m that Aysum. Come on in,
we’ve been waiting for you.
But our father is very sick.”
And the dumbfounded Aytim was standing
and looking at the beautiful Aysum.
And he couldn’t utter a word.
I know what was next.
What was next?
They got married and…
No, they didn’t.
They didn’t get married.
- Why not?
- Because they didn’t have time.
Because Aytim was summoned by
an all-powerful and important man.
Who?
- Who?
- Kashchei the Immortal?
- Not as important as Kashchei.
- Wood goblin?
No, not the wood goblin.
I don’t remember his name.
He summoned him to his
big house and said:
“Look, my dear
Comrade Aytim,
go I don’t know where
and do…”
I don’t know what.
Right.
Aytim answered him: “How come,
my all-powerful master,
I mean, comrade. I’ve traveled
a lot, I’ve fought a lot.
I want to live peacefully with my family.”
And that man says: “You’re talking
like a philistine, dear Aytim.
Like a philistine.”
What is “philistine”?
Not right.
“You’re talking bad, Aytim. Very bad.
You’ve been let
into the country
not to build your bourgeois,
bad nest.
So pack your things
and write an application of your own
will.
You got a week
to think it over, otherwise…”
Your head will roll.
Right.
And so, Aytim went home,
very sad and unhappy.
He walked about, dark and gloomy,
he thought hard,
then he packed his things and left,
not saying a word to anyone.
Why?
Because he had
nothing to say, Nadine.
He’d seen too much blood and woe.
And he didn’t want that blood and
woe to come to his dear house.
And because, Nadine,
he was only 27.
Like your mother is now.
And he wanted to live so much.
And what about the princess?
The princess?
The princess cried and cried,
cried and cried,
and got married.
To whom?
To Kashchei?
To the man
I don’t remember the name of.
Marusya, wait.
Wait.
Wait, Marusya.
Don’t… don’t come near me,
or I’ll jump out of the window.
Marusya, it’s embarrassing.
Listen, there’re people there.
Marusya, there’re people there.
It’s embarrassing.
Come here.
Please, don’t come near me.
Marusya.
Come here.
Come to me, my darling.
You know, after sleeping
we’ll play soccer.
- Where?
- On the croquet court.
Play soccer?
Why not croquet, like before?
Because daddy says that croquet
and tennis are bourgeois games,
and soccer is not a bourgeois game.
Good boy.
Who’s a good boy?
Your daddy is a good boy.
Yes.
Daddy is always a good boy.
You know, tomorrow
daddy and I are going to the zoo.
I’ve been to the zoo one
hundred times already in winter.
And never in summer,
because we’re at the dacha.
They even carried the grannies out
once in Moscow, they swooned.
I can show you.
I am there too.
Where?
Right here.
And what is Aydan?
Aydan is…
Think.
So it’s you who smell of wine.
- It’s not true.
- It is.
Nadya, the granny isn’t sleeping.
Oh, here’s the one who smells of wine!
The one who drinks must eat.
You’re at it, too! You’d better
learn good things from your daddy.
Go and play
with kids of your age.
Want to get it on your buns?
Mitya, you get what I mean?
Will you?
No.
Are you really married?
No, not married.
So you lied.
- I lied.
- I see.
- You lied.
- I lied.
Everybody is sleeping.
The land of Nod.
Want a candy?
You remember?
You smoke now.
You disappeared, and not a line
from you.
Where do you work?
In the NKVD.
Kidding as usual.
- I’m serious.
- Where do I work…
I played in a restaurant near Paris,
now I play near Moscow, in Podolsk.
You should’ve said so.
I remember it. I remember.
And where do you work?
Me?
There’s a rest home not far from
here, I show movies there.
You smoke,
and still you have good hair.
And I’ve got a problem.
When did you come back?
Six months ago.
Why didn’t you come?
There was no occasion.
Are you kidding?
You know what was going on with her?
Did you see her arms?
She cut up her veins.
She’d been waiting for you over a year.
It’s only later…
that this commander appeared, with
flowers, Conservatory, restaurants.
What could she do?
A hero!
Did you come back for good?
For good.
What about her?
Though the commander would
look great with horns.
What are you doing? It hurts.
Sorry, I miscalculated.
I have to work in the evening.
Wait, wait, wait…
You’re my joy…
- Can you do it?
- I’ll try.
Come on!
Was it you who helped him?
Yes, me.
Marusya.
He left himself,
of his own will.
He had a choice.
There were many like him.
But…
He would’ve been arrested.
He had no choice.
Man always
has a choice, Marusya.
He may say something or he may not.
He may go or he may stay.
There’s always a choice.
Why didn’t I know?
I don’t know,
so many years have passed.
You remember that many
people were sent abroad then,
to embassies, missions,
journalists.
Besides, he…
He had an experience of living
abroad, he knew languages.
Marusya, let’s move
to a state-owned dacha.
Come on.
You know how good it is there?
Everything’s in order, everything’s
clean,
with a fence,
white chair-covers, billiards,
a volleyball ground, guards.
They frown on me in the Kremlin.
I’m a division commander, Marusya.
Just look, Marusya, what’s this?
Look, we live like paupers.
If you want, we can take
your grannies with us.
Tell me…
If you had to do it,
would you go, leaving Nadya and me?
Of course I would.
I’m a military man.
Marusya, dear.
I would have gone because I…
…love my homeland.
And he went because of fear,
to stay alive.
See the difference?
My darling.
Because of duty or because of fear?
You see the difference?
Good work.
And let me, my dear friend
Nadine, ask you
if you can do tap dance?
- Let’s go, I’ll teach you.
- Let’s go.
Mara, do a flick, will you?
Flick it.
Please,
do it for me, Marusya.
I’m begging you.
You’re my joy!
Once again.
Mitya.
What?
I wanted…
I got it, Marusya. I know.
I’ll leave soon. Ask Sergey
to come down for a couple of words.
Are you leaving?
Frankly, Nadine, I am not.
I can’t lie to you.
A car will come for me in the evening,
then I’ll leave.
Hurray! A car!
But it should be our little secret. Not
a word to anyone. A military secret.
Well, Nadya.
Go out and play for a while.
All right, do you know this game?
Who can sustain a note longer.
You breathe the air in, you exhale -
I count, I exhale…
- I count.
- Yes.
Let’s try it.
Inhale deep.
Did you call me?
What is it?
All right, listen.
Not a word to anyone.
You’re our guest.
So behave like a guest.
The car will arrive, we’ll go together.
We have soccer today.
Do you play soccer?
- I played once.
- So we’ll play.
We always play soccer on Sundays.
Perhaps you didn’t understand?
Everything’s clear.
We got 2 hours before the car.
Why waste time? It’ll be soccer.
Soccer! Where’s that bird
flying away in a dirigible?
Daddy, wait.
- What?
- Look.
Good for you!
Great, Nadya, good girl!
Daddy!
You know what
uncle Mityai can do?
Uncle Mityai can do nothing.
Stop it, Nadya, don’t embarrass me.
Well, go ahead.
- Come on, show us.
- Don’t be shy.
All right, stop.
Look, Nadya. Look here.
Can your uncle Mityai do like this?
What?
This is the dance of a bird flying
away in a dirigible. Soccer!
- Hey, man!
- What?
- Is this the way to Zagorenka?
Is this the way to Zagorenka,
or Zagoryanka?
There’s no such village here.
What do you mean, no?
I’ve been shown this way.
Who showed you? This way is
Grebnevo, my brother lives there.
Zagorenka, Zagoryanka…
There’re no such villages here.
- What?
- They said go that way!
Motherfuckers,
they said go that way!
Look, you sucker in an Asian cap,
come here.
Listen carefully,
I’m saying it in plain Russian.
If you go this way,
there’ll be Petryayevo, then Kuzemlya,
then Petrovo, and then Goryayevo.
But no Zagorenka.
Get out of here!
- Fuck you!…
- What?!
For this collective-farm
hay, shit,
I’ll make you eat
your cap, you parasite!
Idiot!
Get out of here!
You don’t know a shit!
You asshole, you don’t know a shit!
You live here, idiot,
and don’t know nothing!
Sergey Petrovich!
You found it?
- The ball?
- No. But I’ll find it.
It must be somewhere here.
Sergey Petrovich, it looks strange.
Perhaps you haven’t understood.
You’ve got only an hour.
What are you wasting it on?
You thought I’d be burning papers
or decide to shoot myself?
I’m interested in something else.
Did you come here yourself,
or did they made you, Andersen?
What?
Fucking storyteller.
Why didn’t you…
Why didn’t you mention
in your fairy tale
that since 1923
you’ve been recruited by the OGPU
and, as a secret agent
nicknamed either Pianist,
or Musician,
turned in to us 8 high-ranking
officers of the White movement?
With your help they were kidnapped,
brought here and shot
as counterrevolutionaries
and enemies of the people.
- You believe they are not?
- Me?
They are.
Only I fought against them for 4 years.
And you fought for them, on their side.
And then you turned them all in.
Eight men: General Kornev,
General Weiler, Mashkov, all of them.
Sergey Petrovich, you know well
that they forced me to do it.
Who?
Who forced you, my dear angel?
I didn’t know you back in ’23,
I never heard of you.
They bought you.
Bought you in a most vulgar fashion,
for francs.
Don’t dare talking to me
like this!
I was dying to get back here,
to this house.
They’d promised me and I was foolish
enough to believe them.
You friends told me:
do this
and we’ll let you come back.
And they cheated on me, and deprived
me of everything.
Everything!
My life, profession,
love, Marusya, faith,
homeland – you took it all!
Oh, that’s why you came here.
To savor it.
To savor your hurt.
Drop by drop, gulp by gulp…
…to drink it in.
And then…
Bang!
You’re under arrest, citizen Kotov.
By the way, I’ve done
a malfeasance
by warning you.
You’re lying!
You’re lying again.
You’re again acting
like a lousy whore.
Working both sides of the street.
So that I remember it.
You know how it’s going to end.
Who will dare touch me?
Who will dare touch me?!
Kotov, the Revolution’s hero, legendary
commander. Who will dare touch him?!
Oh, I’ll make you remember all this.
Oh, I’d love to look at you
in some five days,
when you,
crawling in your own shit,
will sign voluntarily
a confession
that since ’20 you’ve been
a German spy,
and a Japanese one since ’23.
And that you’re a saboteur and organizer
of an attempt on Comrade Stalin’s life.
And if you don’t sign it, bastard,
we’ll remind you
that you have a wife and a daughter!
Daddy!
The pioneers are coming to you!
Your pioneers are coming!
What pioneers? Why?
And where’s uncle Mityai?
Uncle Mityai has found the ball.
Nadya, do you know why they
keep hurting me in this house?
Daddy, your pioneers are coming!
Hurry!
- Mitya, come on. Uncle Mityai!
- Let’s go. That’s all. Come on.
Come on! Come on!
There’re pioneers with flags there!
- Did I hit you hard?
- No, it’s all right.
Why did they send you ahead?
So that you didn’t do any foolish things.
- Will there be a search?
- Yes. Tomorrow.
- Why tomorrow?
- So it’s not in my presence.
I see.
Look, not a word to anyone. The car
arrives, we go together. That’s it.
- All right.
- You promised me.
The detachment, named after the hero
of the Revolution and the Civil War,
the order-holding Bolshevik
and the legendary Division Commander,
Comrade Kotov,
has lined up to give a solemn oath
personally to Comrade Kotov.
One, two!
We, young Leninist pioneers
of the detachment named after
the hero of the Civil War,
a loyal follower and comrade-in-arms
of Comrade Stalin,
the order-holding Bolshevik,
the legendary commander Kotov,
in front of our comrades
and in presence of Comrade Kotov
personally,
give a solemn oath
that we shall be faithful successors
to the cause of Lenin and Stalin,
the first heroes of
the Great October Revolution…
Hey, girl, is this Dacha No.9?
9!
Don’t you see it’s 9?
I’ve been waiting for you for a long
time!
You came for uncle Mityai.
I’m going to call him.
Uncle Mityai!
There we go.
Uncle Mityai, where are you?
A car has come for you.
So it’s time to go.
Where’s your dad?
- I don’t know.
- I need him now.
Uncle Mityai,
may I sit in your car?
You may.
Thanks.
I’ll be driving. Hurray!
You hear, granny? I’ll be driving!
Mitya.
Why did you make up that fairy tale?
You know, once I sat
by your father’s bedside.
He was already very sick then.
He was unconscious.
Suddenly he opened his eyes,
took my hand and said:
“What a pity.
I’ve lived such a long,
interesting and beautiful life.
And what am I seeing before dying?
Some trains with geese.
What a pity.
How silly it is.”
Later we found out
those were his last words.
Why have you never
told me about it?
There’re many things I haven’t
told you about, Marusya.
Me, too.
Is that his daughter?
Who knows? Perhaps she is.
It looks like she’s his daughter.
- Hello.
Bon appetite.
I’ll go as far as the turn with you.
I’ll drive in the field.
At the wheel.
What are you munching?
Food.
Shall I bring you some
of my granny’s pie?
No, thanks.
Nadya! Nadya!
Don’t tell them
I was outside the gate.
Coming, grandma!
A smart girlie.
I told you she’s his daughter.
Ever seen him?
I have.
On those…
On portraits.
I see.
- Did you call me, Grandma Lisa?
- No. Your daddy called you.
Where?
Where’s he?
Why are you scaring me?
Jumping like a boy.
He’s upstairs.
Lyolya.
How long do I have to wait?
I’m sorry.
- It’s cold.
- No, it’s all right.
Daddy!
There you are!
Why is your cup here?
Did you drink?
You did?
I did.
And didn’t eat?
I didn’t.
Where are you going?
You leaving today?
The car is here.
I’m going to Moscow.
- And where’s your car?
- It’ll come tomorrow.
At 9. I’ve got some business…
- 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, at 8.
- At 8, right.
Hurry up, uncle Mityai told me
that I can drive
the car, too.
Drive as far as the turn.
Come on, hurry, daddy.
Dad, remember Mitya was
telling me a fairy tale?
Remember what funny
names there were in it?
So it turns out…
If I had been in it, you know
what name I would have? Aydan.
- What does it mean?
- It’s Nadya backwards.
Come on, hurry.
Dad…
You know, we can’t
go to the zoo tomorrow.
I’ll be busy.
- Don’t get angry, all right?
- We’ll go some other time.
Duckbill.
Oh, what a duckbill we got.
- Dad, can you play this game?
- What game?
Look, you cover your ears and hum.
- How is it?
- Like this.
What?
You stop up your ears and hum.
- What kind of a game is that?
- Who can hum longer.
- Who can hum longer?
- Yes.
Three, four.
I’m little, I may to do it two times.
And I may do it three times!
I may do it three times,
because I’m little.
It’s awesome!
Hurry up, daddy, they’re waiting for us.
Let’s go.
Let’s go, Nadya.
I’m Vsevolod Konstantinovich.
Did you come for
Dmitri Andreyevich?
How nice.
May I ask you
what organization
is sending such an auto?
Regional philharmonic society.
Yes, yes, yes…
Philharmonic society…
Where are you going?
Here we are!
The car is here, so I can go with them.
Why are you in full regalia?
Smoking is bad for you.
Marusya, you must just know everything.
Remember, better on your breast
than on a pillow on your hearse.
Let’s go, storyteller.
Sergey Petrovich, please
bring me a rose facial cream.
And where’s your bird
that flies away in a dirigible?
We’ll see you off.
Mokhova!
First-rate semaphore!
Come on, say it: “Grusheva, Lyuba”.
Grusheva, Lyuba!
Good! Now say:
“Grusheva, Lyuba!”
Good! Say: “Commander…”
- Commander stupid!
- Quiet!
Some nightmare!
Nadya, is this the car?
- Whose car is it? Yours?
- Yes, mine.
What a beauty!
Meet my comrades.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
Let’s go and have tea on our terrace.
We’ve got a pie!
A delicious pie!
Excuse me.
What tea?
We’ve drunk up the samovar empty.
What’s your name and patronymic?
- Just call me Vassily.
-No, it’s not polite.
Again! You want to ride me again!
Somebody, sit beside her.
Daddy, come sit by me, you’ll see
how I’m driving.
No, Nadya!
Your dad will seat in the back,
he’ll see better from there.
All right.
Dmitri Andreyevich, the guitar.
Mokhova!
Well, Mitya.
We haven’t sung today.
Yeah, we haven’t.
Well, start singing.
Nadya, only as far as the turn, and
come right back home!
Good for you, Nadya.
Well, Nadya, thanks for giving us
a ride. Step on the brake.
Run back home.
Your mom is waiting for you.
All right, dad. Bye.
Bye.
Excuse me, please.
Have you been in the zoo?
What?
- Have you been in the zoo?
- Sure I have.
Why did you run away?
Did they feed you badly?
Nadya!
You can’t talk
like this to grownups.
- It’s not nice.
- Sorry.
Get rolling.
Nadya, go home, your mom’s waiting.
All right, bye.
Shall we have a drink?
Shall we? I’ve got something.
Here it is.
Let him.
You think I’ll take poison?
No, I won’t.
Will you?
As you like.
- Mityul?
- No, thanks.
How about some cognac, soldier?
Neither drink, nor smoke.
I’m not offering it to the driver.
Guys, congratulations on the holiday
of Stalinist aeronautics
and dirigible construction.
You got any arms?
Yes?
I’m asking, you got any arms?
Are you nuts or what? I’m a division
commander. Of course I got arms.
Give it up, please.
I see.
Be careful, it’s loaded.
Oh, boys…
Look at the sunset.
Tomorrow will be a fine day.
Shall we sing?
Let’s sing, Mityul.
Remember this?
The morning welcomes us with cool air,
The river welcomes us with the wind.
My darling, why are you in despair…
My darling is in despair.
Where are we going?
Maybe we’ll go to “Aragvi” restaurant,
guys?
You’ll be my guests.
Mityul, do you know
this phone number – 24-37?
No.
You don’t.
And you can’t know it.
Because it’s a direct line
to Comrade Stalin.
And tomorrow…
No, today.
I’ll call him, and there’ll be
a turmoil in your department…
Trains with geese.
Oh, boys…
You’ll get everything: geese with
apples and chickens with giblets.
What is that jerk doing all sprawled
out there?
- Pass him on the right.
- Yes.
Only no stupidities.
Of course not.
They’ve all been done already.
Burned up all gasoline!
Driving since early morning.
Hi!
My wife washed my shirt,
with the address in its pocket,
and I don’t remember whether it’s
Zagoryanka or Zagorenka.
I can’t find it…
Nobody knows a shit!
Some assholes live here!
I ask everybody, they send me places!
I’ve been driving about all day!
Nobody knows a fuck!
Look, man…
Give me a bit of gasoline,
and I’ll move off.
What are you looking for?
Comrade Kotov! Is that you?
Wait.
Perhaps you need Nagorye?
I don’t remember.
Nagorye is the other way.
I’ll show you.
- Are you crazy?
- Sit, bastard!
You’re strong, son of a bitch!
Stop!
Come back.
Comrade. Comrade, I just…
I got the address washed off.
I’m just moonlighting,
I got the papers.
- I have the documents…
- Freeze!
Hands behind your head.
Handcuff him.
Comrade, you know…
I just…
I got the address washed off.
Comrade, comrade…
I’ve got all the papers,
they’re in the truck.
It’s just… I’m only…
They’re waiting for me there.
The customer is waiting.
I just need… He waits since morning.
My papers are all in order.
Comrade… Comrade, I am…
I am…
Comrade Stalin.
Comrade, comrade…
Comrade, is it really
Commander Kotov in the car there?
Over there, in the car,
is it really Commander Kotov?
No, just his look-alike.
- Documents.
- What?
- Your documents.
- Here. They’re in order, comrade.
My wife…
Comrade, what about my driver’s
license…
Comrade…
- What are you doing…
- Hurry, and let’s roll.
- Alexei.
- Yes.
Take him.
The tarpaulin.
Let’s go.
You’re only good at working
as a ticket collector.
Just think what they’ve schemed up.
He could’ve run away.
- Look how he put his truck.
- Bullshit artist.
Blocking the road.
He’s torn my jacket.
Hit me right on the nose.
What was it he was saying?
Washed his shirt.
Some note…
And it looked so natural!
A real artist.
Damn, my nose’s always been my weak
spot.
Since I was a kid.
Good for you, Andreyevich.
I’d never have figured it out.
Real smart!
That’s education for you.
Enemy’s seed!
We could be riding like him now.
He’s torn my jacket…
I hate writing those explanatory notes.
Moscow time is 7 a.m.
Good morning, dear comrades!
We start our morning exercises.
The tired-out tender sun
To the sea bade its farewell…
Kotov, Sergey Petrovich,
Red Army Division Commander.
Shot August 12, 1936.
Rehabilitated posthumously
November 27, 1956.
Kotova, Maria Borisovna.
Sentenced to a 10-year imprisonment.
Died in the GULAG in 1940.
Rehabilitated posthumously
November 17, 1956.
Kotova, Nadya.
Arrested along with her mother
June 12, 1936.
Fully rehabilitated
November 27, 1956
Lives in Kazakhstan.
Works at a musical school.
Cast:
Dmitri – Oleg MENSHIKOV
Sergey – Nikita MIKHALKOV
Marusya – Ingeborga DAPKUNAITE
Nadya – Nadya MIKHALKOVA
Vsevolod Konstantinovich -
Vyacheslav TIKHONOV
Mokhova – Svetlana KRYUCHKOVA
Kirik – Vladimir ILYIN
Lydia Stepanovna -
Alla KAZANSKAYA
Yelena Mikhailovna -
Nina ARKHIPOVA
Driver – Avangard LEONTYEV
Philippe – Andre UMANSKY
Olga Nikolayevna -
Inna ULYANOVA
Lyuba – Lyubov RUDNEVA
NKVD officer – Vladimir RYABOV
NKVD man -
Vladimir BELOUSOV
2nd NKVD man -
Alexei POKATILOV