Subtitles By Phaeton
How are you doing, Keaton?
I can't feel my legs...
...Keyser.
Ready?
What time is it?
Twelve thirty.
It all started in New York
six weeks ago.
A truck loaded with stripped gun
parts got jacked outside of Queens.
The driver didn't see anybody
but somebody fucked up.
He heard a voice.
Sometimes, that's all you need.
Mr. McManus?
Christ! Don't you fucking
guys ever sleep?
We have a warrant for your arrest.
Fuck you!
Todd Hockney?
Who wants to know?
New York Police Department.
Shit.
Freeze!
Sure you brought enough guys?
It's quite simple, really. A restaurant
that changes with the taste...
without losing the overall aesthetic.
In other words, the atmosphere
will not be painted on the walls.
Well, let me give you an example...
This I had to see for myself.
David.
- I'm in a meeting.
- Time for another one.
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
Special Agent Kujan. U.S. Customs.
These gentlemen are from the
New York Police Department.
You look good, Keaton.
Better that I would have thought.
You have a problem, Mr. Keaton?
Small matter of a stolen
truck loaded with guns.
Mr. Keaton?
Would you excuse us for a moment?
We have some questions
to ask you downtown.
No, no, please... sit down.
This is...
This is a small problem.
Enjoy the meal.
It didn't make sense that I'd be there.
I mean, these guys were hardcore hijackers...
...but there I was.
At that point I wasn't scared.
I knew I hadn't done anything
they could do me for.
Besides, it was fun.
I got to make like I was notorious.
Allright, you all know the drill.
When your number is called,
step forward and repeat the phrase...
...you've been given.
Understand?
Number 1...
...step forward.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
Number 2, step forward.
Gimme the fucking keys, you
fucking cocksucker motherfucker--!
Knock it off! Get back!
Number 3, step forward.
Hand me the keys,
you cocksucker.
In english, please.
Excuse me?
In english.
Hand me the fucking keys,
you cocksucker, what the fuck...
Number 4, step forward.
It was bullshit.
The whole wrap was a set-up.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
It was all the cops' fault.
You don't put guys like that
into a room together.
Who knows what can happen.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
This has really got to be...
...embarrassing for you guys.
They drilled us all night.
Somebody was pissed about that truck
getting hijacked, and the cops had nothing.
They were hoping somebody would
slip up and give them something to go on.
They knew we wouldn't fight it
because they knew how to lean on us.
They'd been doing it forever.
I mean, our rights went out the window.
It was a violation. I mean, disgraceful.
They went after McManus first.
Top-notch entry man.
What truck?
The truck with the guns, fucko.
Fucko? Brrr...
He was a good guy.
Crazy, though.
Wanna know what your
buddy Fenster told us?
Who?
McManus. He told us
another story altogether.
Oh, that one about the
hooker with dysentery.
Fenster always worked
with McManus.
He was a real tight-ass...
...but when it came to the job,
he was right on. A smart man.
What are you saying?
I say he'll flip you.
- He what?
- Flip you.
- Flip you for real.
- Yeah, I'm shaking. C'mon.
Answer my question.
Can you hear me
in the back?
Hello? I want...
...my lawyer.
I'm gonna have your
fucking badge, cocksucker.
Todd Hockney.
Good with explosives.
Without a doubt, a one guy who
didn't give a fuck about anybody.
You guys don't have a
fucking leg to stand on.
You think so,
tough guy?
I could put you in Queens
on the night of the hijacking.
Really?
I live in Queens.
Did you... put that together
yourself, Einstein?
What've you got, a team of monkeys
working around the clock on this?
You know what happens if you
do another turn in the joint?
Fuck your father in the shower
and then have a snack.
You gonna charge me,
dickhead?
I'll charge you
when I'm ready.
With what?
You know damn well,
dead-man.
But Keaton... Keaton was the real
prize for them, for obvious reasons.
It was your mistake,
not mine.
Did you ever stop to ask me?
I mean, I've been working around
with the same face, the same name.
I'm a businessman.
Yeah, what's that?
The restaurant business?
No, from now on, you're in the
"getting-fucked-by-us" business.
I'm gonna make you
famous, cocksucker.
Like I said...
...it was your mistake.
Not mine.
Now you charge me
with this shit...
...and I'll beat it.
Ok?
Let's get back to that
truck, asshole.
So I did a little time...
...does that mean I get
railed every time...
...a truck finds its way
off the planet?
Fuck them!
Fenster, will you relax?
These guys don't have
any probable cause.
You're fucking A-right. No P.C. ...
No goddamn right.
You do some time,
they never let you go.
You know, treat me
like a criminal...
...I'll end up a criminal.
You are a criminal!
Hey, why you gotta
go and do that?
I'm trying to make a point.
Oh, why don't you
make your point.
You're making me
tired all over.
Oh, fuck it then.
- I heard you were dead.
- Oh yeah?
Well, you heard right.
The word I got is you
hung up your spurs, man.
What's that all about?
What's this?
Rumor has it,
Keaton's gone straight.
I hear he's tapping
Edie Finneran.
Who is that?
She's a heavy-weight
criminal lawyer from uptown.
I hear she's Keaton's
meal ticket.
How 'bout it, Keaton?
You a lawyer's wife?
What kind of "retainer"
you giving her?
Hey, Fenster.
Do your friend a favor...
Tell him to keep quiet.
Dean Keaton...
...gone clean, huh?
Say it ain't so.
Was it you that
hit that truck?
Forget him.
You got to talk
to your lawyer?
This whole thing
was a shakedown.
What makes you say that?
How many times have
you been to a line-up?
It's always you
and four dummies.
P.D. are paying homeless guys
ten bucks a head half the time.
And there's no way they'd line
five felons in the same row. No way!
And what's a
voice line-up?
A Public Defender could
get you out of that one.
So why the hell was I
strip-searched?
It was the Feds.
A truckload of guns
gets snagged...
...Customs comes down to N.Y.P.D. looking
for answers - they come up with us.
They are clutching
at straws.
Ah, the guys fingered
my asshole tonight.
Is it Friday already?
Yeah, lover-boy.
You want a piece?
Something, I love you.
So who in the goddamn place...
...stole the fucking truck?
What did you say?
Who stole the fucking truck!
I don't want to know.
Who asked you,
working man?
Fuck who did it.
What I want to know is who's the gimp.
He's ok.
Says you. How do I know that? What
about it, Pretzel-man? What's your story?
His name is Verbal.
Verbal Kint.
Verbal?
Roger, really.
People say I talk too much.
Yeah, I was just going
to tell you to shut up.
We've met before
once or twice.
In county. I was in for fraud.
You were in the line-up
then, too. What happened?
I walked.
Ninety days,
suspended.
So you did it!
All right, now look...
We've all been put out by
this whole thing, right?
So I figure we owe it to
ourselves to salvage a little dignity
Now...
...me and Fenster heard
about a little job.
Why don't you just
calm down?
Why do you care
what he has to say?
I'm just talking here.
And it seems to me like Mr. Hockney
wants to hear what I got to say...
...and I know Fenster's down.
What about you guy?
I'm interested, sure.
There, see?
So now I'd like to exercise
my right to free assembly.
Why don't you just shut up?
You're missing the point.
No...
YOU're missing the point.
I don't want to hear
anything from you.
I don't care about your job.
And... I want nothing
to do with any of you.
I beg your pardon...
...but you can all
go to hell.
Dean Keaton...
...gone the high road.
What is the world coming to?
Fuck him.
And that was how it started.
The five of us being brought in on a trumped-up
charge to be leaned on by half-wits.
Ok, now I really can't talk
about it much here...
What the cops never figured out,
and what I know now...
...was that these men would
never break, never lie down...
...never bend over for anybody...
...anybody.
Who are you?
Agent Jack Baer, FBI.
How many dead?
15 so far. They're still pulling some
bodies out of the water, though.
Any survivors?
Yeah, there's two.
One guy is in county hospital, but he's
in a coma. The D.A. has the second guy...
...a cripple from New York, I think.
Listen, the chief wants
this place sealed off.
If you have any questions,
give him a call--
This is Dave Kujan. I'll be in
Los Angeles until tuesday.
If you need to reach me, contact...
...Jeff Rabin at the
San Pedro P.D., at extension 112.
Have a nice day.
- Why can't I see him?
- Dave, I told you...
...the D.A. came down here last night...
...ready to arraign even before
they moved him to county. Ok?
Kint's lawer shows up five minutes later...
...D.A. comes out of the office looking like
the boogey man smacked him around.
Allright? They take the statement
and they cut him a deal.
What? Did they charge
him with anything?
Yeah, weapons.
Misdemeanor two.
What is that?
Listen, I give the D.A. credit for
getting that much, you understand?
Excuse me.
This whole thing
has turned political.
The Major was here last night. The chief.
This morning...
...the Governor called, ok?
I'm telling you this guy is protected from
up on high by the prince of darkness.
Take my word for it.
When does he post bail?
Maybe two hours, tops.
I want to see him.
- No, Dave.
- I gotta see him, Jeffrey.
Dave, no!
I can not do this for you.
I came a long way for this.
Dave, please.
Even if I let you talk to him,
he won't talk to you.
He's paranoid about
being recorded.
He knows the interrogation
rooms are wired.
This won't be an interrogation...
...just a friendly chat
to kill some time.
He will not go into
the interrogation room.
- Just someplace else, then.
- Where?
If this was a dope deal,
where's the dope?
If it was a hit,
who called it in?
I'm sure you have a host of wild
theories to answer all these questions.
- You know damn well what I think.
- That's crazy.
And besides, it doesn't even matter...
...the guy's got total immunity.
His story checks out.
He doesn't know what
you want to know.
I don't think he does.
Not exactly.
But there's a lot more
to his story, believe me.
Jeffrey, look... I want to know why
27 men died on that pier...
...for what looks to be 91 million dollars
worth of dope that wasn't there.
And above all...
...I want to be sure
Dean Keaton is dead.
He's dead.
C'mon, two hours.
Just 'till he makes bail.
They're all dead.
I don't care how tough a guy
you say this Keaton was...
...nobody on that boat
could have come out alive.
Is he talking?
He regained consciousness
less than an hour ago...
...he spoke, not english...
then he lapsed.
- Hungarian?
- I don't know. I think that may have been what it was.
Yeah, most of them
were hungarians.
You've got to put on these.
Burn victims are very
succeptible to infections.
And, of course,
there is no smoking.
Keep your mask up.
Please don't touch him.
Is he gonna die?
He has burns over 60% of his body,
a number of his ribs are broken--
Call Hospital Security.
Get a man. Put him on the door
until the police get here.
Is he dangerous?
Yes!
Do it!
Do it now!
Joel?
Yeah, Baer, down
at L.A. County.
Look, the guy they pulled out
of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
Yes!  Yes, I'm sure.
No, no, he's all fucked-up.
What?
I can't hear you.
Shut up! I'm on the phone!
Yes.
Well, no. Not--
Just send me someone
who can speak Hungarian.
Yeah! He's awake and
talking like a Thai hooker.
No, just somebody who--
What?
No shit!
Joel. Yeah, call Dan Metzheiser over at Justice...
...and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
Verbal, this is Agent
Kujan, from Customs.
Nice to meet you.
He wants to ask you a few
questions before you go.
What about?
About Dean Keaton mostly.
But I'd like to start at the
line-up back in New York.
Can I get some coffee?
I a while.
Let's talk about the line-up.
I'm really thirsty.
I used to dehydrate
as a kid.
One time I got so bad,
my piss came out like snot...
...I'm not kidding--
I'll get your fucking coffee.
Get me one too
while you're at it.
That guy is tense.
Tension is a killer.
I used to be in a barber shop
quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
...the bariton was this guy named Kip Diskin.
Big, fat guy.
I mean, like orca-fat.
He was so stressed
in the morning--
Verbal, you know we're
trying to help you.
Sure. And I appreciate that.
And I want to help
you, Agent Kujan.
I like cops.
I would have liked to be a
Fed myself, but my C.P. always--
Verbal, you're not
telling us everything.
I know you
know something.
I told the D.A.
everything I know.
Verbal...
...I know you like Keaton.
I know you think he's a good man.
I know he was good.
He was a corrupt cop.
Sure, 15 years ago.
But he was a good thief.
Anyway, the cops wouldn't
let him go legit.
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
Are you trying to get a rise
out of me, Agent Kujan?
I just want to hear
your story.
It's all there.
May I have a cigarette?
- According to your statement--
- I need a light.
According to your statement,
you're a short-con operator.
Run of the mill scams.
That's been suppressed.
Anything in there is inadmissible.
Oh, I know.
Sweet deal you have here.
Total immunity.
Well, I do have the
weapons charge.
I'm looking at six whole
months hard time.
You know a dealer named
Ruby Deemer, Verbal?
You know a religious
guy named John Paul?
You know Ruby is in Attica?
He didn't have my lawyer.
I know Ruby.
He's big on respect.
He's good friend of mine.
Likes me very much.
Now, I know your
testimony is sealed.
Ruby's well connected.
He's got a lot of friends inside...
...do a lot of favors for him.
What do you think he would say if he found
out you dropped his name to the D.A.?
There's nothing in
there about Ruby.
I'll be sure to mention
that to him.
First thing on the job, you know what I learned?
How to spot a murderer.
Let's say you arrest 3 guys...
...for the same killing.
You put them all in jail overnight. The next
morning, whoever is sleeping is your man.
You see, if you're guilty and you know
you're caught, you get some rest...
...you let your guard down.
You follow me?
No.
Let me get right to the point.
I'm smarter than you.
And I'm gonna find out
what I wanna know.
And I'm gonna get it from
you wether you like it or not.
I'm not a rat.
Thanks.
Back when I was picking beans in Guatemala,
we used to make fresh coffee.
Right off the trees,
I mean.
That was good.
This is shit.
But, hey,
I'm in a police station--
Can we get started again?
Now, what happened
after the line-up?
...the Desk Sergeant is actually trying to tell
me that they he couldn't release you.
Can you believe that?
You weren't even charged!
New York Police!
You know, I want to have
pictures taken of your face...
...take them to the D.A.'s office
first thing tomorrow morning.
Just forget about it.
Absolutely not! I'm gonna have this thing
in front of the grand jury by Monday.
Look, I don't want to
talk about it, Edie. Ok?
So what did Fortier
and Renault say?
They asked for some more time
to think about the restaurant.
They just want more time! It's ok...
More time for what, Edie?
No matter how you cover my tracks,
they're still going to find out about me.
Give me some credit.
I got you this far.
Let's go to the grand jury.
You know, this isn't going to stop if we--
It's never going to stop. Period.
By next week, every investor in this city
is going to be walking away from us.
It's finished.
I'm finished.
Don't give up on me now, Dean.
It's never going to stop.
I love you.
They ruined me in there tonight.
Do you hear me?
What?
All right.
Let's just go to my place.
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
Fenster and McManus had a cagey proposition.
A fast jump. High risk.
Long money.
We all knew it could be done.
The way I figured,
to do it wrong meant killing.
To do it right took five men.
Five men meant Keaton.
Keaton took convincing.
New York finest taxi service.
Bullshit!
They don't operate anymore.
McManus has a friend in the 14th Precinct.
They're coming out for one job - Thursday.
They are picking up a guy smuggling
emeralds out of South America.
McManus already has a fence
set to take the stuff.
A fence? Who?
Some guy in California.
His name is Redfoot.
I never heard of him.
You have to come.
What's it to you
wether I do it not?
They--
They don't know me. You do.
They won't take me
unless you go.
Look at me.
I need this.
Oh, are you telling me
you don't need this?
Is this your place?
I'm not knocking you, you look like you've got
a good little scam going on with this lawyer--
Sorry.
It's ok.
You say it's the real thing?
That's cool.
You're ok?
I was out of line.
But they're never going to stop
with us, you know that.
As clean as you could ever get,
they'll never let you go now.
This way we hit the cops where it
hurts and we get well in the mean time.
You sure you're ok?
I'll be all right.
Look, I...
- ...sometimes get--
- Forget it.
I probably shit blood tonight.
So, how do they want to do it?
McManus wants to go in shooting.
I say no.
Fenster?
Hockney?
They're pretty pissed off.
They'll do anything.
Now, I've got a way of doing
it without killing anyone.
But, as I said, they won't
let me in without you.
Three million?
Maybe more.
No killing.
Not if we do it my way.
New York's finest taxi service was
not your normal taxi service.
It was a ring of corrupt cops in the
N.Y.P.D. that ran a high-profit racket...
...driving smugglers and drug
dealers all over the city.
For a few hundred dollars a mile,
you got your own blue and white...
...and a police escort.
They even had their
own business cards.
After a while, somebody
started asking...
...questions and the
taxi service shut down.
Ever since then, Internal Affairs had been
waiting to catch them in the act.
And that's where we came in.
So, how was the flight?
Fucking great.
Will this get me to Staten Island?
Kidding me? This will
get you to Cape Cod.
McManus came to us with the job,
Fenster got the vans...
...Hockney supplied the hardware.
I came through with how
to do it so no-one got killed.
But Keaton...
Keaton put on
the finishing touch.
A little "fuck you" from the
five of us to the N.Y.P.D. .
All right, watch this.
Careful!
Asshole!
Don't move, you fucker!
- Who the--
- Drop it! Now, motherfucker!
Drop the fucking gun!
Don't you fucking touch
those fucking things!
What the fuck d'you guys want?
Stupid asshole!
Watch it!
You want a buckshot shampoo, Chubby?
Afternoon, my little pork-chops.
Now gimme the shit.
Give him the fucking shit!
Hurry up!
C'mon!
Now the money!
- There's no money!
- Gimme the money! Right now!
- There's no fucking money!
Give him the money!
The money!
Give me the fucking money!
Do it!
- Give him the money!
- Hurry up!
Do you peolpe know
who the fuck I am?
We do now, jerk-off.
What's that?
What the fuck--?
Holy shit!
Keaton made an
anonymous phone call...
...the press was on the scene
before the police were.
Strausz and Rizzi were
indicted three days later.
Within a few weeks, 50 more
cops went down with them.
Everybody got it right in the ass,
from the chief on down.
It was beautiful.
I owe you $2.50 .
There's more here than I thought.
When does the fence come?
Redfoot never comes to see me,
I always go to see him.
In California?
Yes, Verbal, in California.
Fenster and I will--
Wait, wait...
Hold the fucking phone...
...you and Fenster?
No, no, no...
You fuckin' kiddin' me?
Ok. So...
...who's gonna go?
We all go!
What's your fucking
problem, man?
My fucking problem, man, is that you and
Fenster are off honeymooning in California...
...while the rest of us are
sitting here holding our dicks.
Hey! The job's over.
Cool it.
L.A. is a good place
to lay low for a while.
Wanna dance?
Ladies...
I would like to propose a toast...
There you go.
...to Mr. Verbal...
...the man with the plan.
We're gonna miss the flight.
Don't do this.
Send her a note - something.
I said we'll make it.
We're gonna miss the plane.
She'll understand.
That's heartwarming.
Really.
I'm weepy.
Jeff, you wanna wait outside?
You guys wanted to know what happened
after the line-up. I'm telling you.
Come on, Verbal.
Who do you think
you're talking to?
You expect me to believe
that he retired?
For a woman?
Bullshit!
Keaton was using her.
He loved her.
Sure.
I'm supposed to believe that hitting the
taxi service wasn't his idea either?
It was all Fenster and McManus.
C'mon, Keaton was
a cop for 4 years!
Who else would know the taxi service better?
That job had his name written all over it.
But Edie had him
all turned around.
Let me tell you something.
I know Dean Keaton.
I've been investigating him
for the past 3 years.
The guy I know was a
cold-blooded bastard.
I.A.D. indicted him on three counts of murder
before he was kicked off the force.
So don't sell me the hooker
with the heart of gold.
You got him all wrong.
Do I?
Dean Keaton was under indictment a total
of 7 times while he was on the force.
In every case the witnesses either
reversed their testimony to the grand jury...
...or died before they could testify.
When they finally nailed him for fraud
he spent five years in Sing Sing.
He killed three
prisioners inside.
Of course
I can't prove this.
But I can't prove
the best part either:
Dean Keaton was dead.
Did you know that?
He died in a fire
two years ago...
...during an investigation into
the murder of a witness...
...who was going to
testify against him.
Two people saw Dean Keaton
walk into a warehouse he owned...
...just before it blew up.
They said he went in to
check a leaking gas main.
It blew up, and took all
of Dean Keaton with it.
Within three months
of the explosion...
...the two witnesses,
they were dead.
One killed himself in his car...
...the other fell down an
open elevator shaft.
Agent Baer.
This is not what we discussed.
There are far too many people in this room--
Look, doctor, I promise we'll be out of
here before he blows his porcelain. Ok?
I have a noon meeting, Baer.
- Agent Baer, five minutes.
- Look, everyone just calm down. All right?
I want you to ask this man about the shoot-out in the harbor.
He says they were buying--
Dope, we know.
He doesn't know what they
were buying, but not dope... people.
What?
He needs guarantees...
What is he talking about?
He says his life's in danger.
He saw the devil.
Looked him in the eye.
- I'm on my way.
- No, no. Wait a minute.
Ask him to tell him what he told me.
About the devil.
Who's the devil.
Keyser Soze.
He was in the harbor...
...killing many men.
He saw Keyser Soze?
He saw his face.
Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
Describe him.
Six weeks ago I get an anonymous
phone call telling me...
...I could find Keaton eating at Mondino's
with his attourney. And there he is.
Now, because he never
profited from his alleged death...
...and because we convicted someone
else of the murder we tried to pin on him...
...we had to let him go.
He was dead just long enough
for the murder rap to blow over.
And then he had lunch.
I don't know about that.
Oh, I don't think you do.
But you say you saw Keaton die.
I think you're covering his ass...
...and he's still out there somewhere.
I think he's behind that
whole circus at the harbor.
My bet is he's using you because your're
stupid and you think he's your friend.
You tell me he's dead?
So be it.
I want to be sure he's dead
before I go back to New York.
He wasn't behind anything.
It was the lawyer.
What lawyer.
What lawyer, Verbal?
You know, back when I was with that
barber shop quartet in Skokie, Illinois, I--
You don't think I know
you held out on the D.A.?
What did you leave
out on that testimony?
I can be on the phone to
Ruby Deemer in ten minutes.
The D.A. gave me immunity.
Not from me. You get no immunity
from me, you piece of shit.
Every criminal I have put in prison,
every cop that owes me a favor...
...every creeping scumbag that works the street
for a living will know the name of Verbal Kint.
Now you talk to me...
...or that precious immunity they
seem so fit to grant you...
...won't be worth the paper the contract
put out on your life is printed on.
There was a lawyer.
Kobayashi.
Is he the one that killed Keaton?
No.
But I'm sure Keaton is dead.
Convince me.
Tell me every last detail.
We arrived in Los Angeles
and met McManus' friends, Redfoot.
He had a good reputation.
Seemed like a good guy.
Still, we should have known better.
How're you doing?
- Good. You?
- Not bad.
- How's it going, Fenster?
No need to open it, right?
You must be Keaton.
Redfoot, Dean Keaton.
Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint.
Verbal. The man with the plan, huh?
You guys interested
in any more work?
We're always looking
for extra work.
We're on vacation.
Oh well... that's too bad.
I have a ton of work and I
don't have any good people.
- Not like you guys.
- What's the job.
There's this jeweler out
of Texas named Saul.
He rents a suite in some
downtown hotel...
...does free appraisals for people.
Sometimes he buys, sometimes he doesn't.
Anyway, the word is he
carries around a lot of cash.
So I figure, I keep the merchandise,
you keep the green.
- It's simple.
- What about security?
A couple of bodyguards.
Nothing you couldn't handle.
Give me time to check it out.
I'd expect nothing less
from you, man.
- Good to see you. We'll call you.
- Good to see you too.
Enjoy L.A., huh?
Get yourself laid.
A friend of mine in New York tells
me that you know Spook Hollis.
The way I hear it...
...you did time with old Spook.
Good man, wasn't he?
I used to run dope for him.
Too bad he got shivved.
Yeah. I shivved him.
Better you hear it from me now
than somebody else later.
I appreciate that.
Just out of curiosity...
...was it business or personal?
A bit of both.
Well, like I said, you give me
a call if you're interested.
Is there a problem?
One job. That was the deal.
One job?
One job!
That's a good one, Keaton.
Keaton followed the best he could,
but a man can't change what he is.
He can convince anyone he's
someone else, but never himself.
It took one day with McManus nagging
and we went back to work.
Give me the case!
Give me the fucking case!
I'm telling you for the last time...
...give me the fucking case!
Now just hand over the case.
Hand over the fucking case!
Bad day. Fuck it.
Looks like a lot of China to me.
Shit.
Guys, c'mon.
- What are you doing?
- What does it look that I'm doing. I'm gonna kill him.
Look, we did it your way.
Now we're gonna do it my way.
- Are you gonna kill him?
- I'm going to deal with him.
You better deal with him--
Shut up.
What I am supposed to do with that?
I don't know. Feed it to the gimp.
Eases pain. I don't know what that is.
- What do you mean you don' know?
- Shut up.
I don't know. I got thrown
this job by some lawyer.
Yeah, who?
I don't know. Some Limey.
He's a middle man for somebody.
He doesn't say. I don't ask.
- You're fucking full of shit.
- Fuck you!
Listen to me. We want to meet him, ok?
That's funny. Called me last night...
...he says he wants to meet you guys.
Ok. We'll meet him.
- I'll call you.
- Good. Do that. No problem.
I don't like the deal.
One more thing, tough guy.
Any more surprises, and I'm gonna kill you.
You're such a top guy McManus.
But do me a favor, right?
Get the fuck off my dick!
Put a leash on that puppy.
It's an awful shame about
Saul getting waxed.
Cops are gonna be looking
for the guys who did it.
Sooner or later they're
gonna come 'round asking me.
You have a sweet night, ladies.
- So this lawyer...
- Kobayashi.
- ...came from Redfoot.
- Right.
And why leave this out
when you talked to the D.A.?
Dave. Someone to see you.
Jack. I've been looking all over for you.
You still after that coke that took a walk out
of that blood bath in the harbor yesterday?
- Yeah.
- Well, you can stop looking. It was no coke.
I've been in L.A. county talking
to a guy they pulled out...
...of a drainpipe in San Pedro
yesterday after the shoot-out.
He came to this morning.
He started talking.
He was part of a Hungarian mob there to do
a deal with a bunch of goats from Argentina...
...and he says it was
definitely not a dope deal.
- But the 91 mill--
- Yeah, we know.
Our man says
no way on the dope.
This Hungarian tells me the whole bunch
was pulling stumps for Turkey the next day.
They had no time to negotiate that kind
of product and no means to move it.
- What's the money for?
- He didn't know.
No one doing the deal knew,
except for a few key people.
They all were very hush
about it, he says.
Whatever it was,
it's very sensitive.
I don't get it.
They tell me you got that cripple there
from New York. Did he mention Keyser Soze?
Who?
Just bear with me here.
Who's Keyser Soze?
Oh, fuck!
We've been going over this
for an hour and a half.
What we need to do is find Redfoot
and get the hell out of here now.
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
Somebody...
...with power.
Somebody who was capable of tracking
us from New York to Los Angeles.
Come on, Dean. What the
hell are we doing here?
We're waiting.
- Bye now.
- Sit down.
- No, I'm fucking bored--
- Mr. Hockney, do stay. Mr. Keaton...
...Mr. Fenster I recognize from his
mug shots, as well as Mr. McManus.
I can only assume that you are Mr. Kint,
the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
My employer sends his gratitude.
A most unexpected benefit.
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
I have been asked by my
employer to bring a proposal...
...to you gentlemen.
- What do you want?
- My employer requires your services gentlemen.
One job. One day's work. Very dangerous.
He does not expect all of you to live.
But those of you who do...
...will have 91 million dollars
to divide between you...
- ...in any way you see fit.
- Who's your boss?
- I work for Keyser Soze.
- Who's Keyser Soze?
- Judging by the sudden change in mood, Mr. Kint...
...I feel sure the rest of your associates can tell you.
I come with an offer
directly from Mr. Soze.
An order, actually.
What do you mean, an order?
In 1981, Mr. Keaton,...
...you participated in the hijacking
of a truck in Buffalo, New York.
The cargo was raw steel.
Steel which belonged to Mr. Soze...
...and which was destined for Pakistan,
to be used in a nuclear reactor.
A most profitable violation
of U.N. regulations.
You had no way of
knowing this, Mr. Keaton...
...because the fellow shipping the
steel was working for Mr. Soze...
...without his knowledge.
Earlier this year...
...Mr. Fenster and Mr. McManus hijacked a
two-prop cargo flight out of Newark airport.
The plane was carrying gold and platinum
wiring. Also set for Pakistan.
Two months ago, Mr. Hockney
stole a truck carrying gun parts...
...through Queens...
...gun parts which where set to be
destroyed by the State of New York.
They would be "lost" in a weigh
station and rerouted to Belfast.
Again, Mr. Soze, using pawns
who had no knowledge.
Which brings us to Mr. Kint.
Nine months ago...
...one of Mr. Soze's
less-than-intelligent couriers...
...was taken in a complicated
confidence scan...by a cripple.
He was relieved of 62,000 dollars.
Now, it has taken us
some time to find you.
Our intention was to approach you
after your apprehension in New York.
You set up the line-up...
Yes. You were not to be released
until I had come to see you.
It seems Mr. Keatons
attourney, Ms. Finneran...
...was a little too effective
in expediting his release.
Holding the rest of you
became a moot point.
- What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Mr. Soze rarely works
with the same people...
...for very long, and they
never know who they're working for.
One cannot be betrayed
if one has no people.
So... why telling us?
Because you have stolen
from Mr. Soze, Mr. Fenster.
All of you.
That you did not know
you stole from him...
...is the only reason
you're still alive.
He feels you owe him.
You will repay your debt.
All right, fuck the debt!
And fuck you!
How do we know
you work for Soze?
I don't think that is very
relevant, Mr. Hockney.
All five of you are responsible for the
murder of Saul Berg and his bodyguards.
Mr. Redfoot can testify to your involvement,
and we can see to it that he will.
- What's your point?
- The offer is this, gentlemen.
Mr. Soze's primary interest...
...is narcotics.
He has been "competing", shall we say,
with a group of Argentinians...
...for several years now.
Competing with Mr. Soze
has taken its toll.
These Argentinians are
negotiating the sale...
...of 91 million dollars in
cocaine in 3 days time.
Needless to say, this
purchase will revitalize...
...the diminishing strength
of their organization.
Mr. Soze would like you
to stop the deal.
If you choose, you may
wait until after the buy.
Whatever money changes hands
is yours.
Mr. Soze would like you to get to the
boat and destroy the cocaine onboard.
And then you will be free of
your obligations to Mr. Soze.
You give me one good reason
why I shouldn't kill you right now.
A gift...
...from Mr. Soze.
Good day, gentlemen.
They've got my whole life in here!
Everything I've ever done since I was 18!
They fucking know everything!
Everybody I've ever worked
with or did time with.
- No... this isn't right.
- I don't know.
Who was that guy who used
to talk about Soze in New York?
Bricks Marlin.
Yeah, he did jobs for him.
Indirect stuff.
He said he always made 5 times
more money than the job was worth.
This guy's a pipe dream.
Kobayashi is using him for window dressing.
I don't know.
This is bad.
That's bullshit! This guy could be L.A.P.D. ...
It's a fucking setup!
Ah, the way I hear it, Soze...
is some kind of butcher.
A fearless psycho...
fucked up butcher.
There is no Keyser Soze!
Who is Keyser Soze?
He's supposed to be turkish.
Some say his father was german.
Nobody ever believed
he was real.
Nobody ever knew him or saw anybody
that ever worked directly for him...
...but to hear Kobayashi tell it,
anybody could have worked for Soze.
You never knew.
That was his power.
The greatest trick
the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the
world he didn't exist.
One story the guys told me
-the story I believe- ...
...was from his days in Turkey.
There was a gang of Hungarians
that wanted their own mob.
They realized that to be in power...
...you didn't need guns,
or money, or even numbers.
You just needed the will
to do what the other guy wouldn't.
After a while, they come into power
and then they come after Soze.
He was small time then,
just running dope they say.
They come to his home...
...in the afternoon...
...looking for his business.
They find his wife and
kids in the house...
...and decide to
wait for Soze.
He comes home...
...to find his wife raped
and children screaming.
The Hungarians knew Soze was
tough. Not to be trifled with.
So they let him know
they meant business.
They tell him they want his territory.
All of his business.
Soze looks over the
faces of his family...
...then he showed these men of will
what will really was.
He tells him he would
rather see his family dead...
...than live another
day after this.
He lets the last Hungarian go.
He waits until his wife and kids are in the ground
and then he goes after the rest of the mob.
He kills their kids. He kills their wives.
He kills their parents...
...and their parents friends.
He burns down the
houses they live in...
...and the stores
they work in.
He kills people that owe them
money. And like that...
...he's gone.
Underground.
Nobody has ever seen him since.
He becomes a myth.
A spook story that criminals
tell their kids at night.
"Rat on your pop
and Keyser Soze will get you."
No one ever really believes.
Do you believe
in him, Verbal?
Keaton always said:
"I don't believe in God,
but I'm afraid of him."
Well, I believe in God.
And the only thing that
scares me is Keyser Soze.
You give any weight to this?
I can introduce you to
Dan Metzheiser from Justice.
He's got a file on Soze in D.C. .
I'ts been a hobby of his for a couple of years.
A lot of guys equate him to that
reporter on the Incredible Hulk.
- You've heard of him?
- What, on the street?
A few times.
Outside stuff.
Somebody working for a guy
who works for a guy...
...who got some money from Keyser Soze.
Y'know, shit like that.
Could be an old badge.
A hex sign to keep people
from fucking with you...
...back when a name
was to mean something.
But you're here.
Shit, yeah.
I got a guy trying to walk out of
the hospital on a fried drumstick...
...because he's afraid of Soze.
I'll run up the flagpole.
I came clean. I told it like it
happened on the boat.
So what if I left out
how I got there?
It's so full of holes, the D.A. would have
told me to blow amnesty up my ass.
So you got what you wanted
out of me, so big fucking deal.
So that's why you
never told the D.A. .
Well, you tell me, Agent Kujan...
if I told you the Loch Ness monster...
hired me to hit the harbor,
what would you say?
Turn state's evidence. We'll put you
on the stand, we'll hear it out.
I've got immunity now.
What can you possibly offer me?
If there really is a Keyser Soze,
he's gonna come looking for you.
Where's your head,
Agent Kujan?
Where do you think
the pressure's coming from?
Keyser Soze, or whatever
you want to call him...
...he knows where
I am right now.
He's got the front burner
under your ass to let me go...
...so he can scoop me up
10 minutes later.
Immunity was just a
deal with you assholes.
I've got a whole new
problem when I post bail.
So why play into his hands?
We can protect you.
Oh, gee, thanks Dave. Bang-up job so far...
...extortion,
coersion...
...you probably pardon me
if I ask you to kiss my pucker.
The same fuckers that rounded
this up and sank us into this mess...
...are now bailing me out?
Fuck you!
You think you can
catch Keyser Soze?
You think a guy like that comes
this close to getting caught...
...and sticks his head out?
If he comes up for anything,
it will be to get rid of me.
And after that...
...my guess is you'll never
hear from him again.
What happened next?
We woke up next morning
and Fenster was gone.
He couldn't handle the
idea of slumming for Soze.
He left us a note
wishing us good luck...
...and took a chunk of the
money we'd scraped together.
Then what?
McManus was furious.
He was talking about tracking him
down and ripping his heart out...
...and all sorts of shit.
That night we got the call.
What call?
Kobayashi told us
where we could find Fenster.
All right, let's get
the fuck out of here.
We've got to bury him.
With what?
With our hands.
Oh, this is nuts!
It's dry fucking sand,
McManus. When he rots...
...the surfers are gonna
smell him a mile away.
Dig, you fucker!
Hey, what are we going to do?
This fucking guy is gonna kill us.
I don't know you,
peg-leg, but I can run.
I got no problem with that.
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have
a problem with that either.
You run? I won't be digging
a hole for you. You got that?
This ain't my boy we're burying.
I don't owe anybody!
Fuck you!
He was my partner
for 5 years.
We did more jobs, and I saw more
money, than you can ever count.
So fuck you!
'Cause now it's payback!
It's not payback.
It's precaution. You want payback?
You wanna run? I don't care.
I'm not doing this for Fenster.
I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing this for me.
I'm going to finish this thing.
This Kobayashi bastard
is not going to stand on me.
And after they killed Fenster,
nobody would run?
I wanted to. I thought
we could make it.
Why didn't you say anything?
Believe me, I tried.
But Keaton wouldn't have it.
It was too far-fetched for him.
Keaton was a grounded guy,
an ex-cop.
To a cop the explanation is never
that complicated. It's always simple.
There's no mistery to the street,
no arch-criminal behind it all.
If you got a dead body
and you think his brother did it...
...you're going to find out you're right.
Nobody argued with Keaton.
They just set their minds to whacking Kobayashi.
They're coming up.
You hear me?
He's coming up.
He's on his way down.
Don't move.
Press twenty.
Do it now.
Move.
The answer is no.
Mr. Soze will be most up--
Listen, you cocksucker,
there is no Keyser Soze.
You mention his name again,
I'll kill you right now.
Strange threat, Mr. Keaton. I can only assume
you've come here to kill me anyway.
We know that you
can get to us.
But now you know
that we can get to you.
I'm giving you one last
chance to call this off.
Mr. So--
My employer has made up
his mind. He does not change it.
Neither do we.
You got Fenster.
But you won't get all of us.
Not before one of us
gets through to you.
I believe you, Mr. McManus.
I most sincerely do.
You would not have been chosen
were you not so suitable.
But I cannot make
this decision.
Whatever you threaten
me with is... ludicrous...
...in comparsion to what will be done to me
if I do not carry out my orders in full.
I'm the guy that's
going to get you.
I just wanted you
to know that.
I'm so sorry, Mr. McManus.
I implore you, Mr. Keaton,
believe me.
Mr. Soze is very real
and very determined.
We'll see.
Before you...
...do me in, Mr. McManus...
...you'll let me finish
my business...
...with Ms. Finneran first,
won't you?
What did you say?
Edie Finneran.
She's upstairs in my office.
For an extradition deposition.
I requested she be put
on the case personally.
She flew in yesterday.
No matter.
Kill away, Mr. McManus.
You're lying.
Am I?
Ms. Finneran's escort while
she's here in Los Angeles.
Never leaves her
side for a moment.
I thought you'd be glad
to know she's in good hands.
Now get some rest. The boat
will be ready for you on Friday.
If I see you or any of
your friends before then...
Ms. Finneran will find
herself the victim...
...of a most gruesome violation
before she dies.
As, indeed, your
father, Mr. Hockney...
...and your uncle Randall
in Arizona, Mr. Kint.
I might only castrate...
...Mr. McManus' nephew, David.
Do I make myself clear?
We will take care of
the two bodies downstairs.
We'll add them to
the cost of Mr. Fenster.
Now if you'll excuse me,
gentlemen.
Geez. It's a logistical nightmare.
Close quarters. Ten, maybe twenty men.
There's no telling how many
more are gonna be below deck.
Can we stealth these guys?
No. With all that coke,
they are going to be ready.
Which brings me to
sunny point number two.
Even if one of us gets through and
jacks the boat, we still get nothing.
What if we wait for the money?
Ten more men at least.
Look, in my opinion
it can't be done.
Anybody who goes in there
is not coming out alive.
I'm gonna wait for the money.
Me too.
Did you hear
what he just said?
- If I'm going in, I want a cut.
- Me too.
There's nothing
that can't be done.
I just can't believe we're just
gonna walk into certain death.
News said it's raining
in New York.
What language is that?
I don't know. Russian, I think.
Hungarian?
Package has arrived.
You kids are ready?
I would be if I wouldn't have
to stop and answer you.
I'm ready.
McManus, you better be
set up in ten seconds.
I'm ready.
I want you to stay here.
But I'm supposed to cover--
Listen, if we don't get out of this
I want you to take the money and go.
Find Edie, tell her what
happened. Tell her everything.
She knows people.
She knows what to do.
If I don't get Kobayashi
my way, she'll get him her way.
Just do what I say.
Please.
Tell her that...
Tell her I tried.
McManus. He's on his way.
I'm there.
Huh. Oswald was a fag.
Hi. How are you doing?
Is there... a problem?
Now...
Old McDonald...
...had a farm...
...ee-aye, ee-aye, oh.
And on that farm
he shot some guys...
...ba-da-boom, ba-da-bing,
bang-boom.
Elvis has left the building.
Why didn't you run?
I froze up.
I thought about Fenster and how
he looked when we buried him.
And I thought about Keaton.
It looked like he might pull it off.
A boy came across a body on the beach
this morning. Thrown clear when the boat burned...
...shot twice in the head. Two guys
from the Bureau just identified him.
What else?
His name was Arturo Marquez,
a petty smuggler from Argentina.
He was arrested last year
in New York for trafficking.
He escaped to California.
They picked him up in Long Beach...
...they're setting up
extradition - he escapes again.
Now, get this...
Edie Finneran is brought in
to advice in the proceedings.
Kobayashi.
New York faxed me a copy
of his testimony. He was a rat.
A big fucking rat.
Arturo was very opposed
to returning to prison.
So much so that he named
close to 50 people.
Guess who he named in finale?
Keyser Soze.
There's more.
I'll tell you what I know.
Stop me when this sounds familiar.
There was no dope on that boat.
Stay quiet!
He's here!
I know he's here!
That's him!
I'm telling you that's him!
I know he's here!
You don't understand.
That's him...
- Shut up!
- That's him, you hear me?
I'm telling you
it's Keyser Soze!
- Where's Hockney?
- I don't know. There's no coke!
- What?
- You heard me, you dumb fuck. There's no coke!
I checked the entire ship!
I've been in every fucking room!
- There's gotta be coke!
- There is nothing!
Nothing!
You're fucking me!
There is... no... fucking... coke!
I'm outta here.
I told them nothing.
I swear.
I told them nothing. Please!
McManus?
What the fuck is going on?
Strangest thing...
That's what you said in your statement:
"A man in a suit with a slim build."
Wait a minute.
I don't have a minute.
Are you saying you saw Keyser Soze?
You told the D.A. you
didn't know who it was!
I know there was
dope on that boat.
- Stop stalling, Verbal!
- I'm not stalling!
- You know what I'm getting at.
- Get out of my face.
I've got immunity, I don't
have to take that shit.
You know... what
I'm getting at, Verbal.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Yes you do... the truth!
- Try to tell me you saw someone kill Keaton.
- I don't know what you're talking about. I did!
You're lying to me!
You know. You've known
this whole fucking time!
I don't know what you're saying.
I did see Keaton get shot, I swear to you.
Then why didn't you help him?
You had a gun! Why didn't you help him?
He was your friend!
Because I was afraid.
Ok? Afraid!
Afraid of what?
I know it was Keyser Soze!
It was Keyser Soze.
I mean, Agent Kujan, the devil himself.
How do you shoot
the devil in the back?
What if you miss?
All right.
Let's get back to the pier.
Arturo Marquez.
Ever hear of him?
What? No.
He was a stool pigeon
for the Justice Department.
He swore out a statement to
Federal Marshals saying that he had seen...
...and could positively
identify one Keyser Soze.
It says right here in the report.
He had intimate knowledge of his businesses...
...including, but not exclusive to...
...drug trafficking and murder.
- I never heard of him.
- His own people were selling him...
...to a gang of Hungarians.
Most likely the same Hungarians that
Soze all but wiped out back in Turkey.
The money wasn't there for dope.
The Hungarians were
going to buy the one guy...
...that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
I said I never heard of him.
But Keaton did.
Edie Finneran was...
...Marquez' extradition advisor.
She knew who he was
and what he knew.
- I don't und--
- There were no drugs on that boat.
It was a hit. A suicide mission
to whack out the one guy...
...that could finger Keyser Soze.
So Soze put some thiefs to it.
Men he knew he could
march into certain death.
You say Soze sent us
to kill someone?
I'm saying Keaton did.
Verbal, he left you
behind for a reason.
Just do what I tell you.
If you all knew that Soze
could find you anywhere...
...why did he give you the money to run?
He could have used you on the boat.
He wanted me to live.
A one time dirty cop
without a loyalty in the world...
...finds it that it's hard to save...
...a worthless rat-cripple
No, sir!
Why?
Edie!
I don't buy that reform
story for a minute!
Even if I did, I certainly
don't believe...
...he would send you to protect her.
So why?
Because he was my friend!
No, Verbal. He wasn't your friend.
Keaton didn't have friends!
What are you doing here?
He saved you...
...because he wanted it that way!
It was his will.
- Keaton was Keyser Soze!
- No!
The kind of man who could
wrangle the wills of men...
...like Hockney and McManus.
The kind of man...
...who could engineer
a police line-up...
...from all his years
of contacts in N.Y.P.D. .
The kind of man that could
have killed Edie Finneran!
She was found yesterday
at a hotel in Pennsylvania.
Shot twice in the head.
What do you think
about Keaton now, Verbal?
- Edie...
- He used all of you...
...to get him on that boat.
He couldn't get on alone...
...he had to pull the trigger himself
to make sure he got his man.
The one man that could identify him.
This is all bullshit...
You said you saw him die?
Or did you?
You had to hide when you
first heard the police cars.
You said you heard
the shot before the fire.
But you didn't see him die.
I knew him.
He would never--
He programmed you!
He programmed you to tell us
just what he wanted you to!
He knew we were close,
you said it yourself.
Where was the political pressure coming from?
Why were you being protected?
It was Keaton!
Immunity was your reward!
Why me?
Why not Fenster or
McManus or Hockney?
Why me? I'm stupid,
I'm a cripple! Why me?
Because you're
a cripple, Verbal.
Because you're stupid.
Because you're weaker than them.
If he's dead...
...if what you say is true,
then it won't matter.
It was his idea to hit the
taxi service in New York, wasn't it?
Come on, tell me
the truth.
It was all Keaton!
We followed him
from the beginning.
I didn't know.
I saw him die.
I believe he's dead.
Oh, Christ!
You're not safe
on your own.
You think he's--
Keyser Soze?
I don't know, Verbal.
Keyser Soze is a shield.
Like you said, a spook story.
But I know Keaton.
And someone is out there pulling strings for you.
Stay here and
let us protect you.
No way. I'm not bait.
I post today.
You posted 20 minutes ago.
Capt. Leo wants you
out of here A.S.A.P. ...
- ...unless you turn state's.
- I'll take my chances, thank you.
If someone wants to get you...
they're gonna get you out there.
Turn states evidence.
You might never see trial.
May be so.
But I'm not a rat, Agent Kujan.
Fucking cops.
Excuse me.
Can I use your fax machine?
You have to sign for these.
One watch, gold.
One cigarette lighter, gold.
And a pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
You still got nothing, Dave.
I know what I wanted
to know about Keaton.
Just nothing.
No matter.
He'll have to know how close we came.
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze...
...if Keaton is alive,
he's not coming up again.
I'll find him.
Waste of time.
A rumor is not a rumor
that doesn't die.
What?
Nothing.
Man, you're a slob.
Yeah, but all has a system, Dave.
It all makes sense when you look at it right.
You've got to stand back from it, you know?
You want to see a real horror show?
You should see my garage.
Convince me. And tell me every last detail...
You know, back when I was in that
barber shop quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
Where's your head, Agent Kujan?
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
I'm sure you've heard many tall tales...
- Bricks Marlin.
- This isn't right.
- I just want to hear your story.
- Tell me every last detail.
It's all there.
And I'm telling it all straight, I swear.
- Some guy in California. His name is Redfoot.
- A gift...
- ...from Mr. Soze.
- Talk to me, Verbal.
What about Redfoot?
Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
- ...using pawns...
- Big, fat guy. I mean, like orca-fat.
Back when I was picking beans in
Guatemala, we used to make fresh coffee...
...he was a good man...
I know he was good.
Tell me every last detail.
Strangest thing.
How do you shoot
the devil in the back?
...this guy is protected
from up on high...
...by the prince of darkness.
What about it, pretzel-man?
What's your story.
- There was a lawyer...
- What lawyer, Verbal?
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
Tell me every last detail.
I work for Keyser Soze.
Convince me.
Every creeping scumbag that works the street
for a living will know the name of Verbal Kint.
The cripple!
Did you see him?
Which way did he go?
Oh, he went out that way.
I know you know something.
I'm smarter than you,
and I'm gonna find out what I want to know...
...wether you like it or not.
To a cop the explanation is never
that complicated. It's always simple.
There's no mistery to the street,
no arch-criminal behind it all.
Somebody with power...
Keyser Soze!
You think a guy like that comes this close
to getting caught and sticks his head out?
Because you're stupid, Verbal!
Because you're a cripple!
What I want to know
is who's the gimp.
You know.
You've known the whole fucking time!
If he comes up for anything,
it will be to get rid of me.
I can't feel my legs... Keyser.
First thing I learned on the job,
you know what it was?
He mentioned Keyser Soze?
Who?
After that...
...my guess is you'll never
hear from him again.
The greatest trick
the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the
world he didn't exist.
And like that...
...he's gone.
Subtitles by Phaeton