THE BUTTERFLY'S TONGUE
Andrés...
Andrés, wake up.
What do you want?
Did they hit you at school?
Of course they did.
Where?
To school.
Besides, I can already read.
I’ll go to America,
like our uncle did
to get out of the war.
What are you saying?
I don't want to be hit.
By who?
By the teacher.
He looks mean.
Go to sleep.
You don't want
to fall asleep in school.
Then you really would get it.
Let me ride before
the teacher comes. - No.
Look, there he is.
- Good morning.
Here he is.
So you know how to read?
His father taught him
while he was ill.
You said he was asthmatic.
Yes, but he's better.
He's shy.
He needs it in case
he has an attack.
He can't breathe.
A kiss, son.
Be patient with him,
he's a sparrow,
out of the nest
for the first time.
Come on, son.
Good morning,
Good morning, Don Gregorio!
You, the new boy,
Stand up!
Your name?
Sparrow!
His name's Sparrow!
Please!
Come over here.
Answer. Or do you want us all
to call you Sparrow?
He's wetting his pants!
Wait... Come back here!
What's wrong, son?
Moncho, what are you
doing here?
Moncho!
Where were you going?
Like I said.
His plan was to go
to La Coruña and get on
a ship to America.
That little devil.
Have some cheese.
You shouldn't
have bothered, madam.
- How is he now?.
- Perfect
I can't believe it.
All night
outside with no food,
freezing, and he didn't
even catch a cold.
Why does he think
I hit students?
They hit me at school...
I don't.
I’ve never hit anyone.
Least of all a child.
Tell him I’ve come
to apologize.
Please, Don Gregorio,
it's not your fault...
He's a sensitive boy.
I want to apologize
and ask him
to return to school.
You won't have any cheese?
- Please call him.
- Yes, sir.
I like that name.
Sparrow.
We'll only use it
if you like it.
And forgive your schoolmates,
they aren't so bad.
Someday you'll
laugh at them.
It's very good.
Quiet! Quiet!
Sit down!
Today we have
a new pupil.
That is a joy for all
and we shall greet him
with applause.
Very good.
Pull up that chair
and sit down next to me.
Today we'll begin
with a poem.
Who?
Romualdo.
What will you read?
A poem, sir.
Which one?
Antonio Machado's
"Childhood Memory".
Very good. Go ahead.
Remember,
slowly and clearly.
And watch the punctuation.
"A cold and grey winter afternoon.
The pupils are studying.
Monotony of rain
behind the windows.
The classroom. A picture.
shows Cain, fugitive,
and Abel dead,
next to a crimson stain."
What does...
"monotony of rain" mean,
Romualdo?
When it rains, it pours,
Don Gregorio. - Good.
Now, a dictation...
Hello.
Come in, come in.
How are you?
I’m fine. But the boy isn't.
I don't understand.
Yesterday I gave him
a math problem,
and he was hopeless.
Yes... It’s true he should
work a bit harder, but...
Spare the rod...
Get those numbers
into his head.
Give them to the teacher.
No, I can't accept them...
You won't snub me?
Please, Don Avelino,
I wouldn't...
They're very good.
Like I said: make
an effort with the boy.
Goodbye.
Take these capons.
What?
Put them in your desk
and return them to your father.
All right.
But he'll be angry.
He'll slap me.
Good Lord...
Well, then...
Tell him I can't
eat meat.
Fowl, I mean.
Right, tell him that.
Speaking of fowl...
lf a rooster lays an egg
on the border between
Spain and France,
which country's egg is it?
Spain's!
Why Spain?
We have bigger balls!
- What do you say?
- Roosters don't lay eggs.
Very good, Moncho. That's
the right answer.
Moncho,
sit there, with Roque.
Romualdo, you can start
the dictation.
"A cold and grey...
winter..." Next line.
"...afternoon."
Period.
I shat my pants
my first day of school.
- Hello.
- Hello, son.
Don Gregorio doesn't hit!
- Really?
- Really.
And he returned some capons
to a powerful rich man.
Who said that?
His son, José Maria, told me.
His dad's more powerful
than the mayor.
And the capons?
A gift to the teacher
to make his son learn.
But his son won't study.
He says he'll be
a big shot anyway.
Know where potatoes
come from?
From fields, where else?
They come from America.
Don't be ridiculous.
It’s true!
Don Gregorio said so!
Before Colombus,
there were no potatoes in Spain.
What did people eat?
Chestnuts. There was no corn, either.
This teacher
is good.
I like him.
Did you pray?
- Where?
- In school.
Yes. Something
about Cain and Abel.
You can't trust gossip.
Don Gregorio, an atheist!
- Atheist?
- One who doesn't believe in God.
Like Daddy?
How can you say that?
He curses God.
Well, that's...
That's a sin.
Just a sin.
But he believes in God,
like all good people.
- What about the devil?
- Does he exist?
Of course he exists!
He was an angel
that rebelled against God.
He got pale in Hell.
So now he's
the angel of death.
Then why didn't God kill him?
God doesn't kill, Moncho.
They say they burned
churches in Barcelona!
Those Republicans
are like that!
They don't burn churches.
And thanks to the Republic,
we women can vote.
So what? I’d only vote
for Christ the King.
Kings aren't elected.
Things are bad.
But I know the solution,
yes, I do.
What solution?
Set fire to Madrid.
Don't be barbarous.
-May l, Don Gregorio?
-Of course.
Come here, Ramonciño.
Listen, Don Gregorio.
- Introibo ad altare Dei.
- ad Deum
qui laetificat juventutem meam.
Agnus Dei, qui tollis peccata mundi,
ora pro nobis.
- Agnus Dei, qui tollis peccata mundi,
- ora pro nobis.
Agnus Dei, qui tollis peccata mundi.
How many times is that?
You see? He can't remember
Dona nobis pacem.
He's going to be an altar boy?
He was going
to be an altar boy.
Go to your mother.
As soon as he started school
he lost interest.
You're not saying
I’m responsible?
I’m not saying anything.
The facts speak for themselves.
Understand him.
After being locked up so long,
it's natural for everything
to interest him.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Your brother?
- He's working. Let's go.
All right.
Mommy, I’m with Aurora!
I see.
Nidos tepentes absilunt aves.
"Birds leave the warmth
of their nests."
Libertas virorum fortium
pectora acuit.
"Freedom stimulates
the spirits of strong men."
God,
that's good.
"Ashes from an arnau lizard
that was burned alive.
lf you mix it
with coffee,
it fires the desire
of even the
haughtiest woman
and makes her
yours for life."
Here, Roque, it's yours.
I started this way
with Carmiña,
Carmiña de Saradón!
She's fire, Roque, fire!
How come we never see her?
She says she can't leave her mother,
but I think it's shame.
Still... She's has
no shame at all in bed!
No, that's for her mother.
Carmiña doesn't need
help warming up her body.
As soon as I show up,
she lights up
and presses those
rock-hard tits against me.
I lay her down, and she melts
like butter in my hands.
-You hump her every day?
- I wish.
Working in Coruña...
What's going on?
But Sunday makes up
for the rest of the week.
- You seem stuck on her.
- She's worth it.
lf I touch her,
my vision is blurred.
She kisses me,
my head fills with bells.
She embraces me
and I embrace heaven...
And her mother?
I haven't even seen her.
She's always in bed,
she can't get up.
But that fucking dog...
- The dog?
- It’s named Tarzan.
- Does it bite?.
- Almost
The bastard.
I drop my pants
and I feel him gnashing
his teeth behind me.
It’s like he was jealous.
Know what Carmiña does?
The more the dog
growls and barks,
the more she
presses herself against me.
Like it excited her.
Well, I’m on my way.
- Careful with the dog.
- I’ll kill that bastard some day.
What will it be?
An Orujo.
Where are we going?
I told you: to see
him hump her.
That's humping?
- Haven't you seen dogs?
- When?
When a dog
gets stuck to a bitch.
People do the same thing.
But men hump women
when they're in love.
When they love each other.
Tie up the dog, Carmiña.
What do you care?
Leave him alone.
He'll hump her now.
The dog will bite him!
Goddamn dog...
- Get out!
- Tarzan!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Tarzan! Tarzan! Tarzan!
You said they
loved each other.
Tarzan!
You know there are races?
Look.
I like Chinese girls.
The teacher says
we're all the same.
Chinese girls are prettier.
When I’m older, I’ll go
to China and marry one.
Do you know why
men hump women?
The teacher
taught you that, too?
They kiss and push each other.
Who?
Men and women.
Go to sleep.
And they touch each other's asses.
And now, the squash...
Make your pencils coincide
with the top
of the squash,
and then...
And then use
your finger to mark
where the bottom is.
We now transfer the object's
height to the paper.
Gentlemen, quiet please.
lf it doesn't work for you,
raise your hand.
Gentlemen...
Quiet... Gentlemen,
quiet.
Fine. lf you won't be quiet,
I’ll have to be quiet.
What?
Andrés!
- What are you doing?
- Roque taught me how.
lf Dad sees you...
He won't if you don't tell him.
How's school?
We were drawing.
Today he should have hit us.
Why?
We were shouting
and ignoring him.
Instead of hitting us,
he got very quiet.
And then?
Then bit by bit,
we quieted down.
- Didn't he say anything?
- "Thank you".
Look. I’m going
to learn to play it.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
You have to hold it
like it was a girl.
You've never held a girl?
Youth today!
This way. This way,
firm but lovingly.
Like a lover...
Exactly!
Your brother may be
the musician.
Music has the face of a woman
you want to love you!
Close your eyes and imagine her!
Imagine her hair,
her eyes.
You are doing well.
You are doing very well.
- Can I play?
- No, there are too many of us.
Stop!
Stop, I said!
What happened?
He hit me with the ball.
He ran into Roque.
You're like a couple
of butting rams. Time for class!
Stand up, rams.
You, José Maria,
change places with Roque.
Don Gregorio...
But...
Yes?
Roque is my friend.
All right.
Shake hands
with José Maria.
Sit down.
Let's see... I don't know if you've
realized, but it's almost spring.
So as soon as
the weather's better,
we'll do the natural history
class outside.
Do you like nature?
Right.
You've never even noticed it.
Nature, my friends,
is the most surprising
spectacle man can behold.
Did you know ants
have herds of livestock
that give them
milk and sugar?
That spiders invented
the submarine
millions of years ago?
Did you know
that butterflies have tongues?
The tongue of a butterfly
is like an elephant's trunk,
but very thin and wound up
like a watch spring.
- You know where Australia is?
- In America.
In Oceania.
You know what a
"tilonorrinco" is?
It’s a bird from Australia.
When it's in love, it gives
its girlfriend an orchid,
a flower that's beautiful
and very expensive.
Hey, kids...
You're the tailor's sons, right?
An instrument?
A saxophone.
I thought so.
- Do you play well?
- Great. I’ll be a musician, too.
What will you play?
The piano. The sax
isn't good for my lungs.
Great.
I have a band,
"The Blue Orchestra".
Your father made
our costumes.
"From the farthest shore,
the sunset behind us,
The Blue Orchestra, from Galicia!"
Come with me.
Then we went
to the chocolate factory
and they asked what
he could play
and I said "In the World"...
Why did he take you
to the factory?
- The orchestra practices there.
- That's news to me.
Look!
In exchange, they advertise
the chocolate.
Between songs,
the musicians say:
"Exprés Chocolate, the best!"
They all say it together:
That's frivolous.
Why should
a dance band be serious?
They'll pay you?
Macías said if I’m good,
we'll see.
You see?
There's no easy
path to heaven.
After all, what has
he got to lose?
Say yes, Mom!
You have to mend this.
It’s big enough for both of you.
First I’ll wash it.
God knows who wore it.
A sax player.
Now I don't want
to play piano, Mom.
Mr. Macías will teach me
the drums.
Great.
Calm down.
- When do you start?
- During the Carnival.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Your attention,
please.
Ladies and gentlemen, we're
going to speak Castillian Spanish,
since we forgot Gallego
on our last tour.
of South America
You don't have to play.
But make it look
like you're playing,
get that body movement going.
One, two, three...
Peanuts...
If you want a little fun,
buy yourself a bag of peanuts.
When the evening is lonely,
my lovely little customer,
the peanut seller belts out
his pretty tune.
If the little girl hears his song,
she'll come down
Little customer, don't go to bed...
You see that?
And you didn't want him to play.
I didn't know he could play so fine.
Peanuts...
Little customer, don't go to bed.
without buying
a bag...
Let's dance!
I don't know how.
It’s time you learn it to.
is lonely, my lovely little customer,
the peanut seller belts
out his pretty tune.
If the little girl hears his song,
she’ll come down from her balcony...
-You know who I am?
-Yes.
- Who?.
- Aurora
How did you recognize me?
I don't know...
- Because you're the prettiest.
- You couldn't see my face.
Look, the sax player
is my brother.
- Do you know how to dance?
- More or less.
Come on.
Well done, Sparrow.
Wait...
Remember what I said
about a butterfly's tongue?
And why?
To reach the nectar
flowers keep in their chalices.
Carefully, without bothering them.
What's nectar?
Nectar is a sugary juice
flowers secrete
to attract insects.
In exchange, insects
spread the seed
of the flowers.
Look, there's one.
When you
touch the sugar jar
with a moistened finger,
don't you already taste it
as if your finger tip
were your tongue?
The tongue of a butterfly
is like that.
Smelling the nectar,
the butterfly
and reaches the bottom
of the chalice.
Look at this anthill!
Don Gregorio!
He's choking!
Thank God you thought
of the water thing.
It happened before.
On his First Communion.
He was about to take communion,
and he was so excited
he got an attack.
A miracle!
We got some holy water,
splashed it on his face,
and he was cured.
Well the river water
isn't holy,
and it worked, too.
I’ll give you some soup,
to warm you up.
She's mystical.
And you're Republican.
I’m in Manuel Azaña's party.
- Don Gregorio...
- Yes?
lf it's not a problem,
I’d like to measure you...
for a suit.
A suit?
A gift...
It’s just I’d like
to do something for you.
And I know how
to make suits.
It’s my trade.
I have a great deal
of respect for trades.
And I appreciate your offer.
But my principles...
Principles between friends?
We are friends, aren't we?
Fifty-four...
Seventy-one...
Forty-three...
MEASUREMENTS DON GREGORIO
- What are you thinking about?
- The teacher.
He's such a good person.
I’m glad you're making
him the suit.
Teachers don't earn
what they should.
They're the light
of the Republic.
The Republic!
Where will we end up
with that Azaña?
What's wrong with Azaña?
What you hear at Mass,
I’m sure.
I go to Mass to pray.
You do, but the priests...
go for another reason.
Well, don't get angry.
Moncho is all right.
Give me a kiss.
Don't be so boring.
Your father
really is an artist.
Look how elegant I am!
My poor wife. I lost her
when she was only 22.
As the poet said,
"An abandoned bed,
a cloudy mirror,
and an empty heart."
"An abandoned bed,
a cloudy mirror and an empty heart."
In other words,
I ended up all alone.
You read much?
Comic books.
It’s time you start
reading real books
Books are
like a home.
THE CONQUEST OF BREAD
In books, our dreams take
refuge so as
not to freeze to death.
Here,
borrow this.
TREASURE ISLAND
You'll like it.
And I have a present
for you.
Open it.
You know what
it's for?
I got it!
Be careful.
Don't hurt it.
It’s an iris. Beautiful!
You see? It has four wings.
The color and shine come from
a series of
overlapping plates,
scales placed one over
the other, like roof tiles.
And the tongue?
- The tongue is called "proboscis".
- Let's see it.
No, right now it's rolled up,
otherwise it couldn't fly.
We'd need a microscope
to see it.
What's that?
A device for seeing
infinitely small things.
I ordered one for the school,
but you known things
go slowly in Madrid.
lf we get one,
we can see its tongue.
A cricket!
It’s a "Prince Cricket".
- How do you know? - It sings
better than a "King Cricket".
Here it is!
- Who could that be at this hour?
- Go see, son.
This girl wants to see Dad.
She says her mother's died.
Go to your room.
- We're eating...
- So take your food!
How did it happen?
It must have been her heart.
I found her dead.
- Did you call the doctor?
- Why? I went to see the priest.
Right.
The coffin and burial
cost 45 pesetas.
But I have no money.
Wait.
- What?
- I didn't say anything.
Do what you must do.
Why can't we see her?
That's a secret.
- Tell me.
- No.
I have a secret, too.
About Carmiña.
Who told you her name?
Tell me your secret,
I’ll tell you mine.
She's Dad's daughter.
So... Why doesn't
she live with us?
Dad had her with that dead woman
before he married Mom.
How do you know her?
Roque and I followed
this man O'Lis
-... up to Carmiña's house.
- And?
They got naked
and he humped her.
That's why Mom sent
us away.
- Why?
- She's a slut.
What does Dad say?
Nothing. What could he say?
Hello, Sparrow!
Hello.
- Is this your garden?
- It’s a friend's.
But he lets me
pick fruit here.
I got some apples.
Want one?
They're delicious.
Very juicy.
What are you doing here?
- Watching a funeral.
- Really?
Who died?
When someone dies,
do they die or not?
What do your folks say?
My mom says
good people go to heaven,
and bad people go to hell.
And your father?
That if there's a Final Judgment,
the rich will bring
their lawyers. My mother
doesn't find it funny.
What do you think?
I’m afraid.
Can you keep a secret?
Between you and l:
An otherworldly hell
does not exist.
Hate and cruelty...
that's hell.
At times,
we ourselves are hell.
APRIL 1 4, 1936
LONG LIVE THE REPUBLIC!
Who wants coffee?
Coffee?
A toast!
- Long live the Republic!
- Long live!
The king's lost his crown,
it's only paper.
The gold one was
taken away by Berenguer.
The king's
Lost his crown, it's only cardboard.
The Spanish crown
will be worn by no thief!
Ramón... The Civil Guards.
So what?
The doctors had me
on porridge for 7 years.
My stomach got worse.
One day I told my wife
to make me a stew
with ham, sausage, and lard.
- And I was cured.
- Hello.
What's that song?
I don't know.
I heard it on the radio.
Rose-colored dawn at sunrise.
Melodious note
of a crying violin.
Like in a novel, the insomnia
where she lived her story of love...
Gentlemen!
Listen up.
We've been hired
in Santa Maria de Lombás.
All expenses paid and 70
pesetas, 70 beautiful pesetas!
Get those shirts clean.
Santa Maria de Lombás,
look out!
Me, too?
Of course!
And me?
You won't be hungry here,
I tell you as the mayor.
Sausage, ham, cheese,
whatever you want.
I’ll smash
your head in, Carolina!
You know I will!
I chose you because
I don't want
men in my house.
Adult men are
as thick as mules.
Baby! Coffee!
Don't be scared.
They make good manure.
She doesn't speak,
but she can hear.
Come on, show
the musicians their room.
Be quick.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
She's the Chinese girl
from the book!
You're right!
No, that's too much.
No one says "no" here.
Eat and grow, kid.
And her?
Who?
She already ate.
She eats like a bird.
Want to see something?
Come here, baby.
Look!
This is where
the wolf bit her!
Cover yourself.
She was only four.
We were
with the livestock.
The wolves were hungry
and they tricked me.
God did they trick me!
Aren't you going to eat?
I’ll get angry.
We were in a meadow
near the woods.
One of those bastards
appeared and then
went back into the woods.
The dogs tore off
after him
and I went with them.
We left her there, alone,
sitting on a sack.
It was just a moment,
but when we returned
she was gone.
God, but those bastards
tricked me!
But she survived.
The wolf didn't want
to kill her.
He just bit her back.
The old people said the bite
was to silence her,
so she wouldn't scream.
And it sure did work.
We found her in a wolf den.
She was fine,
but she never spoke again.
Why is she Chinese?
Who?
Your daughter.
She's my wife.
The wise bird, using
the science of clairvoyance,
picks out your fortune
from the magic box.
Want the bird
to tell your fortune?
She came into my room,
took my hand,
and we escaped
on horseback.
- What did he do?
- He went after us with a knife.
But in Coruña,
we got on a boat to China...
Look!
I remember something
the teacher said.
A bed, a mirror,
and a heart
are all empty.
In other words,
you're all alone.
I’m going to marry Roque's sister
when I grow up.
Today, after a lifetime
dedicated to teaching,
Don Gregorio is retiring.
As mayor of this town,
and in the name
of the authorities,
students and parents...
I want to make clear our gratitude
for what you've done
for our children:
prepare them for life,
and especially,
for being good citizens.
Don Gregorio,
you know I’m not one
for speeches.
Al I can really say...
is thank you.
Thank you from the bottom
of our hearts.
Honorable authorities,
dear children,
and distinguished citizens.
In springtime,
the wild duck returns
to its home to mate.
Nothing can stop him.
lf you cut off his wings,
he'll swim.
lf you cut off his feet,
he'll row with his beak,
like an oar against the stream.
This journey
is his raison d'être.
In the autumn of my life,
I should be skeptical.
And in a way, I am.
The wolf will never lie down
with the lamb.
But I am sure of one thing.
lf we can allow
one generation,
just one generation, to grow up
free in Spain,
then no one will ever
be able to take away
their liberty...
Let's go!
No one will be able to steal
that treasure from them!
Thank you very much.
And now, fly free!
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
We won't go
bug hunting anymore?
Why not?
Now that it's summer,
we can go every day.
Look...
Better late than never.
From the Ministry
of Education.
We get the microscope,
Sparrow!
What's that?
It’s a Lucanus cervus,
a flying deer.
It’s called that
because its mandibles
look like antlers,
and they fight over
females with them.
They're the biggest
beetles in Europe.
There's one!
Give it to me!
I got it!
Careful...
Very carefully...
Now we'll see the tongue
under the microscope.
Won't you come in?
He's scared!
He's chicken!
Don't let him come!
Remember
the tilonorrinco?
That bird that gives
its girlfriend a flower that's
- very expensive.
- Right!
An orchid.
Come on.
Be like a tilonorrinco.
But this isn't an orchid.
That doesn't matter.
- Can you swim?
- No.
Me, neither.
Don't look.
Here.
Shut your eyes.
During his speech, received
with anger in the chamber,
Mr. Gil Robles said
a country can live
as a monarchy or a republic,
with a parliamentary
or presidential system,
soviet or fascist,
but not in utter anarchy.
He affirmed that Spain attends
the funeral of democracy...
That pear-headed bastard!
They want
it dead!
Mr. Calvo Sotelo said
to affirm once again that
a viable government
cannot be based
on the present constitution,
and "instead of this sterile state,
The Republic will survive!
"...Many name this state
'the fascist state'.
If this is a fascist state,
then I,
Careful...
An Orujo.
You've already had a few.
I’ve had...
what I’ve had to.
Driving oxen?
Maybe.
Come on.
Give me that,
it's dangerous.
I need it.
I’ll pay for it... I’ll pay.
Let's go.
I have to go home
with my dad.
They're talking
about politics.
Let's go.
Tarzán!
Moncho!
- What?
- Come to the house.
We're playing a game!
There's a war in Africa.
I heard it on the radio.
Why?
Something about Spain
and God...
- Up with Spain!
- Hooray!
Get the newspapers, Ramón.
Thank God!
Your card...
It’s the war?
Yes.
They say the
military has risen up.
Help me.
lf anyone asks,
Dad never said
anything against the priests.
And he's not a Republican.
Moncho, listen carefully
to what I’m saying.
Dad never gave
a suit to the teacher.
You understand?
- Yes, he did.
- No he didn't!
You understand?
He didn't!
No, he didn't give him the suit.
Long live the Republic!
Long live.
- Who is it?
- Open the door, ma'am.
- Is your husband here?
- No, he isn't.
Know where he is?
Please tell him
the mayor wants to see us.
He needs us.
I’ll tell him.
TREASURE ISLAND
Andrés...
- Up with Spain!
God forgive us.
God forgive us all.
Ready.
Traitors!
Reds!
Atheists!
Red bastards!
Clown!
Red!
Atheist!
Atheist! Atheist!
Ramón, for God's
sake, shout!
Traitors! Criminals!
Reds!
Thugs! Criminals! Trai...
No! Roque! No!
- Roque, no!
- Dad!
Roque, no!
Son of a bitch!
Shout now, Ramón!
Now!
Murderer!
Anarchist! Bastard!
Son of a bitch!
You, too, Moncho.
You shout, too.
Atheist! Red!
Red!
Atheist!
Tilonorrinco!
Proboscis!