We've watched her
for the last 2 weeks.
4 days ago, she signed up
for a Hong Kong tour to Ukraine.
Yesterday she went to the Swiss Bank.
I believe she withdrew a big load of cash.
She's an Ukrainian passport holder.
Her name is Natasha Rekshynski.
(Uncle Bill)
It's all in the file.
She's a Ukrainian.
and she has to join a Hong Kong tour
to go back to Ukraine?
- OK. Thank you, Jackie. Well done.
- Thank you.
Bill, I'd like to talk with you a minute.
Me?
- OK
- Excuse me.
Natasha Rekshyn... difficult name!
13 pounds of weapons grade uranium 235
was uncovered at the New York Airport.
2 suspects were arrested,
both buyers carrying 2 million in cash.
The seller walked.
Natasha is our only lead.
Jackie, the C. I. A. guy
said you did great work.
Try to get out more in future.
Got to have the chance first.
You've got it. Vacation on the Black Sea.
Ticket and accommodation provided.
Uncle Bill, is the case still in our hands?
Yes, and they want you especially.
CIA has lots of men outside Hong Kong.
I don't think I can be helpful.
They suspect that there's a rat, that's
why they want help from outside.
I don't speak Russian and
I can't help there.
You don't have to speak Russian.
All you have to do is follow
this girl to Russia
and they'll take over from there.
You'll spend two nights there and come back
So I just watch her
on the plane?
Exactly. What can she do on a plane?
That simple?
That simple.
I'd go myself if I could.
So this is by your own will, OK?
Just one more thing. Don't forget
to buy me a nice bottle of vodka.
and some really good caviar.
Yes, sir.
I already signed you up
for a tour to Ukraine.
- Good morning.
I'm sorry, sir, your
passport is expired.
Huh?!
Follow me, please.
(Jackie in Cantonese)
She says my passport expired!
(tour guide in Russian)
What's wrong here?
His passport is expired.
Can I come with him?
No.
Don't worry. Worst thing you just go back.
It's OK.
No problem. Someone's working on it.
Jackie, welcome to the Ukraine.
Mark, she scared the hell out of me.
This is Commander Korda,
Department of Security.
Nice to meet you.
Did you find anything?
No, but she went to the toilet 7 times.
Here's the timetable.
She didn't talk to anyone.
Thanks, Jackie.
You're done. We'll take over from here.
Very good!
$1,000.
Any other currency?
No.
Your accommodation is fixed,
your flight is booked for tomorrow,
Here's some pocket money, one billion.
One billion?
A telephone. Dial 0-1
if you need us. Simple, huh?
Yeah, pretty simple.
Marina will show you to your car.
Oh, yes.
Have fun!
Thank you.
Have a good holiday.
Thank you
Line two.
Hello
Hello. It's Natasha.
Wrong number!
Hello? Hello?
Let's go.
I'm sorry because his
passport has expired
Mr. Chan has to take the next
flight back to Hong Kong.
Oh, really? That's a pity!
Then we just go ahead.
Everyone, please get on the bus
(tour guide)
We'll spend 15 minutes here.
We'll check in the hotel in an hour.
Take as many pictures as you like.
- OK
- OK great.
We're watching her.
No one has made contact with her yet.
Take her away!
She's a member of our tour.
We have to take her in for questioning.
Department of Security.
Sorry. It's an order,
we have to take her away.
What? Who's the commander?
Natasha was taken away by the Strike Force.
What?
Two for 5 million?
Yes, it's very good caviar.
(in Cantonese)
How much is 5 million?
(vendor)
Hey!
OK
- Hey, follow the car. Follow the car!
- OK
Quick quick quick!
I go and look. You wait.
OK?
OK.
(Jackie)
Mark, I saw Natasha.
What happened?
What? Natasha? Where?
She went into a church.
Jackie just said he saw
Natasha went inside a church.
There are about 30 churches
around. Which one?
What's the name of the street?
Too foggy. I can't see.
Keep following her.
Don't let them see you.
Try to get a street name and call us.
OK, I try.
(man)
It's Tsui.
Natasha was followed by
the Ukrainian secret police.
but I got rid of them.
You better check what's going on.
I want a safer place to deliver the goods.
Yes, I'll be there on time.
Major Majenko!
Mr. Tsui!
Long time no see.
Thank you for sending your men.
Your problem is my problem.
And I got your stuff here.
(Tsui)
This is just for the boys.
This is your new passport
with an American Visa.
Your money is already
in your Swiss bank account.
(in Russian)
Very good.
Take the shell apart,
separate into 6 boxes
and then send them
to these addresses.
I'll take the guidance system
and the uranium core with me.
(Major Majenko in Russian)
Good! It shall be done!
(Tsui in Russian)
Check the funds.
I'll call you later.
(Natasha)
Be careful.
(Tsui in English)
I love you.
I love you too.
It's Jackie.
What's wrong with your phone?
I shut it off. I found a new suspect.
(Mark)
Who is it?
I don't know.
(Mark)
Where are you?
Let me see.
I can't read the sign.
Looks like a ski resort area.
Can you spell it out?
"C–H–I–K–" no no no, left-right ''K''
Left and right ''K"
H–l–K–A–P–A–T–N... no, no reverse N
P–A–T–N, no no, Reverse "N".
We got it! Good!
We're on our way!
(in Russian)
Do you have anything
for Alexander Nevski?
(man)
Very tired, I find the first time
the snow is not so good for me.
(in Russian)
Can I help you?
– Huh?
– (in English): Can I help you?
Ski or snowboard?
Snowboard.
– First timer?
– Yes.
Receipt. Pay at counter.
Thank you.
Hey!
Thank you
Hello, Natasha?
Is the money deposited?
(in Russian)
Yes, but it's a check.
It will take 3 days to verify.
(in English)
OK, I'll call you again.
Department of Security.
You're under arrest!
Please buy a hat!
Money for the orphanage!
Mister, please buy a hat.
Huh? Oh, how much? How much?
40.
Keep, keep the change.
Where can I get some clothes?
(man in Russian)
Where do you think I can get you clothes?
Who'd have extra clothing
for you in this weather?
You know it's freezing out here
and still you wear so little.
And now you bother others for clothes?
Thank you.
Hello?
Hello, hello? Where are you?
Suspect just passed
the restricted area sign.
Some kind of restricted area sign.
Don't worry. Go in!
Hey, keep moving. Go ahead!
No!
There's a picture!
Looks like if I pass, I'll get shot.
Some kind of restricted area sign.
It's just for kids!
Just for kids! Go ahead.
Come on! Let's go!
We've been expecting you.
How was your trip?
Very smooth.
Hello?
Where the hell are you?
About 2 mile...
East, south, west...
west of the restricted area sign.
2 miles west of
the restricted area sign.
Hurry up. I'm freezing.
Get some clothes.
Huh? OK, clothes.
You got everything here?
I want to talk to your boss.
My boss is waiting.
(in Russian)
There is someone out there!
Who is it?
He looks like a Chinese.
Who did you bring with you?
Nobody.
Inside
(Mark)
Anyone else around?
I didn't see anybody around.
Stay back. We will handle the rest.
(in Russian)
Around.
Forward!
It's bloody freezing here!
Nice hat!
Are you OK?
What do you think?
(in Russian)
All units stand by.
The enemy has entered the ring!
(in English)
Give me the briefcase.
Don't move!
Back off!
Tell your people not to open fire.
I have a detonator
wired to the uranium core.
If it gets shot, the entire city
would be wiped out.
And you and I will be the nuclear history.
(in English)
Freeze, don't move!
Hey, it's a trap!
(Mark)
Jackie, go get the skidoo!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Grab the case! Grab it!
Mark?
Tsui!
It's you?!
Jackie, over here!
Shoot it! Shoot the helicopter!
Let's go!
Mark!
GO!
Don't move!
Go down and get the box!
Hello, Jackie
Who are you?
I'm Colonel Gregor Yegorov of
the Russian Federal Security Bureau.
Huh?
Well, FSB. for short,
the new, improved KGB.
KGB?
Am I in Russia?
(Gregor)
Yes
Where's Mark?
He's still in coma.
We connected the
Ukraine Department of Security.
I know about your
operation with the CIA.
The FSB Generals
want to see you.
You are coming to
Moscow with me today.
Can you help me?
Yes?
Turn off all those things.
I'm very hot!
(man in Russian)
Compliant to the Start-I Treaty
with the United States on December 1994,
both countries have reduced the
number of active nuclear warheads
from 25,000 during the cold war to
around 10,000 on each side at present.
In Ukraine, we have a crisis in our hands
because arms dealers are taking
advantage of Ukraine's late compliance with Start-I.
There are warheads with questionable
status are being smuggled out
by high rank army officials
who have access.
We want you, Jackie,
to work with Colonel Yegorov
to find this stolen
Ukrainian warhead.
the General wants you to go investigating
the case with Colonel Igorov.
I think I have to call my
superior in Hong Kong.
(General in Russian)
We already did.
This is a letter of authorization
from your superior in Hong Kong.
They've agreed to attach you
to our mission.
The General has...
That's a letter of authorization
from your superior in Hong Kong.
OK
(Gregor)
The warhead was stolen from the
Khmolnitsky's base in Ukraine.
Major Majenko was arrested.
How many warheads does
each symbol stand for?
Each symbol stands for
100 nuclear warheads.
And each warhead is at least
10 to 30 times the power of
the one dropped into the Hiroshima.
What if all the bombs
explode at the same time?
That would be the end
of the planet Earth.
The total explosive power
of the world's warheads
equals 15 million tons of TNT.
The power to destroy 7 earths.
That is why our mission is so important.
What do I have to do?
You have to find Tsui.
He graduated from MIT with a
master degree in nuclear physics.
Recruited by CIA, his job was to steal
urainium-235 production strategies
from the Soviet Union.
He's been FSB's main target for years.
Where we going now?
We're going down!
– To the submarine?
– Yes
(man in Russian)
Prepare to submerge!
Sir
(in English)
We're heading to Australia now.
There will be a fisherman's
boat taking us in
Everything is already arranged for you.
Are we being smuggled in?
No, I wouldn't use this term.
We're just arriving quietly.
(Jackie in Cantonese)
Uncle Bill, guess where I am?!
(Uncle Bill)
What's going on?
Here I am talking with you
in front of a great sea view.
I can't believe it.
I feel like a VIP working for the FSB.
This 8,000 sq. ft. president suite
of mine has got 2 stories.
And there's a swimming pool,
a sauna, a Jacuzzi
Hold on. A koala has just come out!
What? A koala in the hotel room?
You mean a toy?
No it's not.
It's real!
Say hello to Uncle Bill.
He's so shy.
Hold on. Let me take it back to the room.
Good boy, come here.
– (Jackie in English): Yes?
– Excuse me, sir. Your tea is ready.
Thank you very much.
(in Cantonese)
So great! If I had known it,
I would have gone too.
(in English)
Go home. Go home. Go home.
(in Cantonese)
It's the real thing. No kidding!
Anything else? Yeah, a great
car, gold card, cash,
and all the clothing with designer labels.
Now I feel like James Bond
except I don't have the gorgeous girls.
Hey, if you are this lucky,
you've got to be real careful.
I will. All right.
OK OK, tata. Bye-bye.
Do you think he's been working
so hard that he's out of his mind?
I don't think so. Maybe he
just doesn't want you to worry.
He didn't sound like that.
Wow, all this underwear!
You're so hot, you even appear on
the underwear. But how can I wear them?
(in Russian)
Put all the parts together
Yes boss.
(Gregor in English)
Could I speak to Mr. Omar Mohammed?
It's Gregor Yegorov.
Hi Omar, it's Gregor!
I got the stuff you need here with me.
My lawyer looked into the contract.
all the terms look good.
You think we can close the deal in a week?
We'll sail out to international
waters outside Indonesia.
You bring a pen
and I'll bring vodka and caviar.
Right, that's it.
I'll talk you later.
(man)
Ah, that's insane!
- Hi
- Hello
– One adult?
– Yes?
$15.50, please.
Excuse me. I'm looking for Annie Tsui.
Annie? Uh, she's in a show right now.
Can I see her?
Yes
Michelle, he's looking for Annie.
Can you take him down, please?
– Sure, nice flowers.
– Thank you.
In case you're in and out. Here's
your change. Enjoy your visit.
Thank you.
– Hi
– Two adults please.
2 adults?
Annie, you want to have dinner tonight?
Uh, I'm busy.
Hi!
So Peter asked you out again, huh?
Oh, once everyday.
– You're gonna go?
– No. Can you help me?
Sure.
(man)
Aw, look at that one over...
There's Annie. Why don't you take a seat and I'll bring her down after the show.
Thank you
Thanks, Michelle
Hi, uh, are you looking for me?
Yes, my name's Jackie.
Do you speak Mandarin?
(in Mandarin)
Oh, of course.
Joe, can you give me ice water?
– Sure
– Thanks.
Your brother and I
are sworn brothers.
He came back?
He did? Actually, I don't know.
He told me
you are working here.
I'm here on vacation, so
I came to see you.
Thanks. Did you need
anything from me?
Nothing.
He said that you love this kind of flower.
So I bought some for you.
He hasn't seen me for so long
He even forgot what
kind of fowers I like.
He didn't even return when
Dad went to the hospital.
(in English)
– Thanks
– No worries
Isn't your job dangerous?
No, not really. Sharks only go crazy
when they smell blood.
When they see anything that
moves, that's when they bite.
As long as you don't move,
nothing will happen to you.
But there's always danger involved.
So the next time I run into a shark,
I'll act like a rock or a coral
and I will not move.
Oh, sorry. I have to visit dad in the hospital.
If there's nothing else, I'll be going.
– Thanks for the flowers.
– Thank you.
(in English)
– Karen
– Yes?
– Put it on my bill.
– Sure, no problem.
(in Mandarin)
– Thank you.
– Bye-bye
Annie
Since I have never met
my sworn dad before,
Can I go to hospital with you?
All right. Why don't you wait for me
at the front gate? I'll be right there.
What a lucky day!
I found his sister.
I'm going to hospital with her right now.
Very good. I'll meet you there.
Hi.
(woman)
Annie
Just a second.
There's a box for you here.
I'm going to the hospital, I will
pick it up later, OK? Bye. Bye.
– Hello, Allen
– Hi.
Hi.
Dad, are you better today?
I've brought brother's
sworn brother to see you.
I've never met Tsui's sworn brother!
My name is Allen. Your name?
– My name's Jackie.
– How do you do?
Let's go out for a while.
Please.
What's wrong with your dad?
Coronary embolism. He's having
an operation this afternoon.
The doctor said it's
not looking good.
Bugs receiving?
All operative.
Daddy
Feeling better? Did the
doctor say anything?
It's OK. Thanks.
How come my kid has
never talked about you?
Actually, I'm not
sworn brother of Jackson Tsui.
I'm with Hong Kong police.
I'm investigating your older
son stealing nuclear weapon.
Can I talk to you privately?
What did he say?
He said he's a policeman.
Do you know what your
son does for a living?
You're a cop, you should
know better than me.
The Tsui family no longer has this son.
Could you please tell him
not to visit my grave?
Thank you.
I hope you get better soon.
I'm sorry I lied to you.
Shh
What happened?
Looks like she's angry with Jackie.
You lied to me. Why
couldn't you lie to my dad?
Let me explain.
Are you trying to hurt him
more before he dies?
Hands off! Listen, don't expect
me to tell you anything!
I don't want to see you again.
Enough!
Please be quiet or leave the hospital!
Please
Annie, it's me.
Brother
Where have you been all these years?
Why are you dressed like that?
What have you been doing out there?
Do you know dad's
having surgery today?
Yes, I know. I already spoke to him.
Jackie
Come in.
That man out there works
for the new Russian Mafia.
He's not a policeman. You
must never believe this man.
Did you get anything from the old man?
Uncle Seven is going
to surgery this afternoon.
What about Tsui?
He said he hasn't see him for a long time.
You believe him?
Well...
I sent you something
yesterday by messenger.
by the name of Nikita Angeloupoulous.
Did you get it?
I got it this morning.
Good. It's something very important.
Please hide it somewhere safe for me.
Tsui is a good son.
I think he'll come to visit.
We should stay in this place.
What if Uncle Seven dies
and the good son doesn't show?
If he die, he will show up for sure.
Why are you so sure?
He's the only son in the family.
He has to...
Carrying a flat bag of water.
What is all this?
That's a Chinese tradition.
It's likely that you're being followed.
Always be careful.
I've got to go.
You'll take this.
You might need it when you follow the girl.
Take care. If anything
happens call us right away.
OK
– Hi
– Hi, Annie
I'd like to pick up my package, please.
(man)
Bye.
- Here you go.
- OK, thank you.
Bye, Annie
I thought you'd gone already.
Oh, not yet.
– OK.
– OK, bye-bye.
You scared me!
Bye-bye
Keep singing
I think he's following the girl.
Come back! Come back.
Come on, Rhett, come on.
Keep him away please?
What are you doing?! Oh my god!
What's going on?
We lost the feed.
Track down Jackie's car.
Give me the location.
He's at the Under Water World.
Obviously, something is going wrong there.
(Tsui)
Now we can talk.
– You speak Mandarin?
– Yes.
I know you're with
the Hong Kong police.
Who are you workin with right now?
Used to be CIA.
and now it's the FSB.
You have a complicated background.
It was quite simple.
You were sent here by Gregor Yegerov?
Do you know him, too?
How do you get in touch with him?
Hello. Yes. This is Jackie speaking.
It's me.
It's Tsui.
I'm here with your  Hong
Kong policeman now.
So you want to get rid
of me without paying?
Fine. I want double now.
In cash. You got 3 days.
I have your phone now. I'll call you and let you know where and when to meet.
I'm sorry I had to do that to you.
but look at what's in your second button.
You'll find them in your car
and everything they gave you,
including this pair
of very ugly underwear.
You're under their surveillance
at every moment.
To them you're just a hunting dog.
The less you know, the safer you are.
By the way, you're a lousy singer.
Everything is here, but the jacket is missing.
Here's the wallet.
Are you OK?
Yes
Where is Tsui?
He's gone.
What did he tell you?
What do you think he told me?
Seems like you two have
some kind of deal going on.
Don't believe what he said.
He is an expert iin playing mind games.
He's a top CIA agent.
He's trained to play
around with people's brains.
Maybe you're right,
but how do you explain this?
We have to look out for you.
It's part of our job.
Why don't you tell me before?
Whatever it is, you wanted me to
find Tsui, now he found you!
I will write a full report to my
superior and your superior.
I'm out.
That's your clothes,
that's your car.
This my wallet.
(in Russian)
Goodbye. Goodbye.
(in Cantonese)
going. Bye-bye.
Now kill him!
Let's have some fun first.
He's supposed to be a good fighter.
Had enough?
Why is it taking so long?
This guy can move like a monkey.
Don't push me
or I jump.
OK. Go ahead.
Come. Come to get me.
Go get him!
You go and get him!
(Woman)
Who is it?
Who are you?
Me?
I'm the window cleaner.
Win...Window clean..? No. No, wait you...
– Who are you?
– Huh?
I'm the dry cleaner.
Dry cleaner?
Anna!
– Who was that man?!
– He's the window cleaner.
He told me that he was the dry cleaner.
What? You mean I'm lying?
But I believed him, I'm sure.
(Jackie in Cantonese)
They want to kill me for knowing too much!
Just a second!
Who wants to kill you?
Gregor? But you are
working for him!
Did you call the police?
I don't have a passport,
I came over illegally.
How could you make
things this complicated?
I'll call the Australian police.
You go and report this tomorrow,
and they will help you.
Just find some hotel
to spend the night tonight.
Stay in a hotel? I've got less
than 50 bucks left.
Keep talking like this and
I can't afford the phone bill.
So what are you going to do?
(Jackie)
I'll sleep on the street tonight.
Good idea! Safer than the hotel.
We're 2 hours in advance here!
I'll wake up early!
(woman on phone)
Go ahead.
Sherry, call the FSB
headquarters for me.
Ask for General Smirnov
Yes, sir.
– Yes?!
– Oi!
Get out of my bed!
Sorry.
Anyone here?
Nah. He's on holiday.
– Hey!
– Yes?
Gimme a hand.
–Yes?
– Hit the wall.
Harder!
Good night.
Goodnight.
(Detective)
Miss Tsui, the killer's still out there
This might be a pretty
dangerous couple of days.
Go back with your friend and get some rest.
And I'll have a uniform
unit take you home
and protect you 24 hours.
(Allen)
Thank you, sir.
This guy is unreal.
We've got a tough on our hands, Louis.
Get this videotape analyzed. See if
the murderer really is the same guy.
Contact Hong Kong police, the CIA
and Russian FSB.
Get a positive I.D. on this guy.
Straight away, sir!
(woman 1)
How was your holiday?
(woman 2)
It was great!
– Good morning.
– Good morning, Hi.
Excuse me.
My wallet get stolen. Can
I borrow some money, please?
I just want to make
a long distance call.
– No!
– Just few coins!
I haven't had breakfast yet.
Excuse me. Your bear.
Oh, thank you.
Can you do me a favor?
Yes?
Can I borrow some money from you?
Yes!
Give me your address,
I promise send you back.
No, no, no.
– Thank you.
– Don't worry.
Thank you.
Your newspaper!
Keep it.
Thank you.
(in Cantonese)
What a nice lady!
There is big trouble in
Brisbane's Chinatown.
The man who controlled it all
the head of the Golden Dragon
Association, Uncle Seven...
Yes, sir?
- Can I have some change?
- Sure.
...at Saint Paul Memorial
Hospital late last night.
Although unnoticed by staff,
the killer was spotted
by the hospital security cameras.
And after looking at the video
– The daughter of Uncle Seven believes
– Sir, here's your money.
to be a Hong Kong policeman
known to her only as Jackie
and who visited Uncle
Seven earlier in the day.
Police have yet to pinpoint
a motive of a murder
The killer is still on the loose
in the streets of Brisbane,
the subject of a city-wide manhunt.
Authorities fear that
the murder of Uncle Seven
– Hey, that was the murder suspect!
–...will mean chaos in Chinatown
– ...for a long time to come
– Look!
...and now to our...
Allen
I didn't kill your dad.
Call the police!
Wait!
Would I be here if I killed him?
Listen to me...
Let me say something!
Do you want me to call the police?
Wait.
Wait!
Listen to me.
Can you tell me where your brother is?
You still want to find my brother?
Once we find him, he can
prove that I'm not murderer.
You got my dad killed just
when you showed up.
Now you want to get my brother too?
Just how did we offend you?
Beat him up first!
There!
Up there!
Tell the brothers to come up!
(Tsui)
Allen
(Allen)
Brother Tsui!
He didn't kill my dad.
You guys go downstairs
Could you come this way, please?
(Allen)
Let's go.
I think I know who's the murderer.
Gregor has found a way
to make you show up.
What exactly is your relationship with him?
Three years ago, I tried to collect
intelligence on nuclear weapons.
in Ukraine for the CIA.
But then the KGB found out.
and two of my colleagues got killed.
Natasha! Natasha! Natasha!
Natasha!
They caught me and made
me spy on both sides.
For the sake of Natasha, I agreed.
Gregor was the KGB agent?
Yes, and he's now the head
of the New Russian Mafia.
His position in the FSB makes it
easier for him to commit crimes.
So he wants to buy
a nuclear warhead?
He's trading nuclear weapons
for an oil franchise in the Middle East.
You should give the warhead
to the police right away.
I won't unless I get the money.
How many people have
you killed for money?
Your father died because
you wanted the money.
If the bomb falls into the hands of a madman
a nuclear war will break out.
World peace will be affected.
You're so naive!
Do you know how many
nuclear weapons have been sold
all over the world by military superpowers?
I'm just selling one for myslef.
The difference is that they
sell it in the name of a country.
But I sell it for myself.
You think there will be
world peace just if I don't sell it?
There's truth in what you've said.
We can't change the world.
But we still can't use it as an excuse.
We humans have done
enough harm to the Earth
and now we're still doing nuclear tests.
keep it that way and
we're destroying ourselves.
Your heroism concept doesn't apply to me.
I'm no hero.
But if we can't stop them,
we shouldn't encourage them.
Annie,
You've got dad killed just because of money.
I will never forgive you for that.
I'll settle with Gregor.
And I'll give you all the
evidence of his crimes.
But I'll need your help.
Stay here for now. And don't use the phone.
I know.
I had great expectations
when I joined the CIA.
But then I found that I've done a lot
of things that I wasn't very proud of.
They wouldn't let me
contact my family.
I've lost my self-respect.
I would have died 3 years ago.
If I didn't make a deal with Gregor.
This is not what I expected.
Brother.
We're at the funeral of Uncle Seven
the head of the Golden Dragon Association,
who was brutally murdered last week.
There's a strong police presence presence
here today to escort a 60-meter long dragon
which signifies the  spirit of Uncle
Seven to the heart of Chinatown.
VKR, this is Bravo 840
We're leaving Holy Trinity with Tsui.
(in Russian)
Lots of police here.
I'm here at Wickham Square.
Where are you?
(Tsui)
Just stay where you are
Not bad.
You even share the same
coffin with your father.
The coffin is for you.
You killed my father!
He had to die somehow.
At least he died for a reason.
You're going to die in front of him!
Tsui, you promised to
hand him to the police!
If you move one more step,
they'll blow your head.
Tsui, it's not the first time we deal.
You really think you can finish me here?
Open!
(in Russian)
I'm blocked by the umbrellas!
Go back up the boss!
(in English)
Now what?!
Killing me won't bring him back.
Give me the bomb, and I'll
give you the money. I promise.
And then you'll never see me again.
You think your money can
pay for my father's life?
No, I guess not.
But I got your sister.
Look!
She's young, sexy, beautiful.
You don't want her to die.
You bastard!
You guys have no rules!
I have wife and kids in Russia.
You could do the same thing.
But it's too late!
Move again, I'll break your arm.
(in Mandarin)
Come here, I'll help you.
(in English)
If you don't give me the bomb,
I'll kill both of you right now.
I know you've got it here.
No. You have
to let her go first!
(in Mandarin)
Brother!
Annie.
Annie, get out of here.
Give my stuff to the police.
OK
Put him in the coffin.
Hurry up!
Run! Quick!
Can I help you?
Yes
(in English)
Yes!
(in Mandarin)
Let's go!
We have officer down, officer down!
We need backup immediately.
Up!
(in Mandarin)
Help! Help! Hurry help me!
(in English)
Please, help me! Help me!
(in Mandarin)
Hurry, help me!
Excuse me
(in Mandarin)
Help me!
(Annie)
(in English)
Please, help me!
- Are you OK?
- Yes
– How did you get on top of the lift?
–Uh...
OK, thank you very much. Goodbye!
Hang on a minute.
We got to write a
report, call the police.
OK?
Central security, we're on the
top floor The girl's all OK.
Please call the police. Mick and me
are coming down to fill out a report.
You're very familiar, I
think I've seen you before.
Don't move!
He hasn't got a gun.
Be careful!
Sorry
Go, go, go!
(in Russian)
They're at the east wing, go get them!
We're live here at Wickham Square
where the funeral of Uncle Seven
has turned into the biggest
gang war in Chinatown
A group of terrorists, allegedly members
of the new Russian Mafia,
gunned down the ceremony
with a rocket propelled grenade.
Police say the murder suspect, Jackie
was last seen escaping through this
mall with Uncle Seven's daughter.
Investigations continue as more
bloodshed is expected in Chinatown.
Inspector, results of the
tape have come back.
That's not Jackie.
I think it's a set up.
Sherry, I want to return a call to officer...
Tung Bill in Hong Kong.
(Annie)
Oh, sorry!
Annie, I've got to make
a long distance call.
Use the phone in the office upstairs.
– Annie, sorry about your dad.
– Oh, thank you.
(Gregor, in Russian)
Where is everybody?
They're on their way
They're in the staff room. Go there.
Yes
Don't do anything foolish
without my command.
Yes, sir!
(in Cantonese)
Uncle Bill, it's me!
Tsui's siter and I are going to
retrieve the uranium core.
Tell me what should I do?
Listen, I've called the head of the FSB.
and told him the whole thing.
So have you informed the police here?
I've told him and had your identity
clarified. You're not the murderer.
But the most important thing to do...
is to hand the warhead to the
Australian police once you get it.
(in Russian)
Go get the boat!
Yes!
(in English)
6 tickets, please.
(staff)
What happened?
Quick, get an ambulance!
Sorry, you can't come in here.
What's going on?
Take him! Get him up!
(Gregor)
Where did they go?
Fix him!
Lock them up!
You two, come with me.
Get him!
Go down. Get him!
(in Russian)
Quick! Quick!
(thug)
He's here!
Go down, get him!
Quick, quick!
(in English)
Go! Go!
(both men)
– Shark!
Shark!
Sharks don't bite
Huh?
Go back!
(both men)
– Shark!
– There's a shark!
It’s just a small shark.
Get a weapon!
Go down. Kill them! Go! Go! Go!
(Gregor, in Russian)
Did you see it?
(in English)
Yes, I think so!
I think Jackie still has it.
Go down, get him!
No! 2 already died!
(in Russian)
That's an order!
– No.
– That's an order!
I can see them from the restaurant.
Let's go!
(in English)
Excuse me, is that a new show?
Yeah, what's going on?
I don't know.
What's going on in there?
(crowdperson)
It's real!
Looks like a new show, or something.
It's unbelievable, mate!
Get back! Get back!
Stay where you are!
(in Russian)
Follow me!
(in English)
Give me the gun!
Get her!
Move. Get back!
(Jackie)
Go, go, go! Move!
Help! Help!
Major problem in Under Water World!
Shots fired, explosions,
terrorists have taken over.
And Jackie's there too. It's chaos!
Get the chopper ready!
Goodbye!
(in Russian)
Watch her!
(in English)
Run!
(in Russian)
You have shamed our country!
Let's go!
(in Cantonese)
When you get back, give me a simple but
detailed report describing
the case from head to tail.
From head to tail?