Beauty and the Beast.
Once upon a time, there was a
rich merchant.
He was a kind and brave man.
After his dear wife had passed away,
he only lived for the happiness
of his six children,
three daughters and three sons.
They filled the house with the sound of
their laughter and their squabbles.
We have a little guest.
She wants to hear the story as well.
We'll all make a wish.
But silently
or it will never come true.
Did you make your wish?
Yes!
Then, one... two... three.
Well then, would you like to hear
the rest of the story?
- Yes! Yes!
The merchant had three ships
that made him wealthy and proud.
The ships' names were "The Mermaid", "The
Triton", and the largest was "The Leviathan".
Their holds were loaded with wonders as
they were coming back from a long voyage.
But, all of a sudden, they were caught
in a terrible storm.
The ships were swept
away by enormous waves.
Lightning tore their sails and
broke their masts.
Under the surface, where coldness
and silence reigned,
the ocean began to sparkle
in thousands of lights.
The armada and its riches
sank to the bottom,
swallowed and lost forever.
After a month, having lost everything, the merchant
and his children had to leave their house,
their friends and their way of life.
Everything that had made them happy so far.
I forbid you to take that!
Go on, help yourselves then.
We will take the most
valuable things with us.
Oh, no!
Put that down immediately
or I'll take your eyes out!
Daddybear, do something.
They're taking everything, our jewels,
our beds, everything.
It's the end, I want to die.
Clotilde, would you please not call me
"Daddybear" in front of these people?
And you Anne, stop talking about dying!
Oh, my heart! It wants to beat no more.
Are you happy now?
Farewell!
As you can see, Daddybear, it's a disaster.
What will become of us?
Someone's calling for you.
Where is Belle?
Belle, Belle. He only cares about her.
- They've lost everything.
- Oh, my God!
- I used to work for them!
Wake up already!
Maxime, come help us!
Put it there.
- What's inside it?
- All my books.
My notebooks, my sketches...
I know them by heart, but I don't want
to leave them here.
Tristan!
- What is it?
- Keep an eye on your father.
And don't let Maxime squander
what little you have left.
Of course. Don't worry. I promise.
Everything will be alright.
Be careful.
- Aha ha ha!
- Ha ha!
If I hear one more of them laughing,
I'll break his nose.
Ignore them.
Now what? Are we going to have some fun
before leaving to the country?
Don't you think it would
be better to stay away?
Belle!
This is for you, Mom.
A new life is beginning for us and
I think I'm ready.
Do you think she would have liked
to live in the countryside?
- She would have loved it.
- I will like it, too.
- I am sure.
- Obviously.
We have pride and courage in our family.
We will stick together as we always have.
They needed some time to get
used to their new life.
The first night, Belle stayed up
to listen to the sounds of the countryside.
And then, with the help of her brothers
she decided to clean the garden and
turn their house into a beautiful haven.
I have a fever.
Oh no, I have a wrinkle!
Aah, this bug just won't stop!
We've been living in this hell for a month.
We'll die alone and crumpled.
Devoured by beasts.
Anne, come right now!
Her again. Her happiness digusts me.
It makes me want to drown her in the well.
And I want to bury her alive
in her blasted garden.
What are you two doing?
Clotilde is feeling sick, so we will
have breakfast in bed.
- No, you won't.
And after lunch we'll all go
work in the garden.
- I'd rather die.
- Get up! Everybody downstairs!
Exhausted...
comma...
...pierced by arrows...
...the young man left the battlefield
and took shelter in the forest.
One could say that they were very happy
to see me at the "Maritime Affaires".
Dumont was very nice. Apparently,
his eldest daughter married a count.
- What? No!
But, the big news is that "The Mermaid",
your mother's favourite ship,
has been found.
She drifted along the shore and
washed up in the harbour.
- What about the load?
- Completely intact.
My children, I belive we are saved!
Let's pack our things. Actually no,
let's just throw everything in the fire.
I can feel my heart beating again.
I am alive, Daddybear. I am reborn.
We can't go back to town in this state. No. We'll
need new dresses, perfume, and... what else?
We'll make a list.
- Yes. We'll have the happiness of the town!
- The town, the real town!
Will you go with me to town?
It is time I introduced
my successor to Dumont.
I will not disappoint you, Father.
Thank you.
After defeating the last one of his
enemies, the young man returned home.
Triumphant and acknowledged by his people.
The end.
- A new novel, my brother?
- Something even better. This one
will be a masterpiece.
What are you doing??
Are you angry?
Obviously. When a girl is sad,
they say she's angry.
And when she's too happy,
they say she's crazy.
How can you expect to be understood?
Everybody's happy but you.
I would have liked to stay here longer.
That's all.
There he is.
We only came here to hide our shame,
but our life is not here.
You know as well as I do
what's going to happen.
Maxime will hang out with those rogues
he calls friends again.
Anne and Clotilde will go out
every evening to look for husbands.
And you will always be busy with your work.
Belle, one day or another we will
no longer be together.
You will grow up and you will want
to start your own life.
But that won't mean we don't love each other any more.
It will only mean that you've grown up.
Be sure not to forget anything.
Clotilde won't take it very well.
And you, what would you
like me to bring for you?
Only a rose.
I couldn't grow any here.
They have taken everything from me.
They even refuse to let me board my ship.
You have to accept the situation.
"The Mermaid" and all its load
don't belong to you any more.
They treat me like I were nothing,
when without me this place would still
be a fishing port. And you allow this!
You seem to be lacking common sense,
my poor friend.
You signed all the promissory notes,
even though I warned you not to.
Don't patronize me, Dumont.
If it weren't for me, you wouldn't
be sitting behind this desk.
Have you lost your manners as well as
your wealth?
- I am going to smash your head!
- Stop that immediately!
Don't you understand?
You no longer have any power.
You're supposed to be a wealthy,
important man, but you're nothing.
I feel sorry for you, Father.
Maxime!
I see a man. You should be careful.
He will bring you important news.
- News? Good or bad?
- You know very well that depends on the other cards.
Don't you want to please me, Astrid?
Tell me something exciting.
I am like the cards love,
I can't lie to you.
Did I not warn you about your scar?
A torrent of gold under an emerald moon.
Your fate is smiling at you.
Gold, emeralds! Ha ha ha!
Come on, my vermins!
Didn't I tell you that we'd become rich?
This is a bad night. It
smells like gunpowder.
- What would you like?
- I am looking for my son.
- I was told that he often comes here.
- I am used to hearing that. But still,
I feel sorry for you.
What is your son's name?
Maxime de Beaufremont.
You should have spoken more quietly. I will have
to let you leave through the back entrance.
- But I have to find my son!
- You're not the only one.
Quickly, go behind the counter.
Your scent...
your prophecies...
You have too much power over me.
Monsieur de Beaufremont.
I have been looking for Maxime for months
and I come across his old father.
I don't know you.
- Who are you?
- Perducas. At your service.
Your little boy owes me a lot of money.
That's why you and I will strike a deal
and everything will be forgiven.
My son is not a gambler!
Serve them a round of drinks so that
they may leave me in peace.
He thinks we are lying to him.
You won't be doing that here, Perducas.
You know that.
Leave the poor man alone.
All right.
Move back.
And you, go quickly behind the counter.
Go on, hurry up!
I wish you luck because he won't leave you
alone. Now leave, quickly!
On his way home,
the merchant struggled with the wind,
the cold and the sadness.
He had left the town without Maxime.
He pictured him wandering, in the gutters,
or worse, lying dead in an alley.
He pulled the reins of his horse,
hoping to return home as soon as
possible, and find his son waiting.
I don't even have a weapon to end
your misery.
Forgive me.
The house.
I made it!
But this is not the house.
Is anyone there?
I've lost my way.
And the door was open.
Who's there?
Am I dreaming?
Or have I died and gone to heaven?
No, I am quite alive.
And I'm hungry.
I will help myself to some of the things
on the table. All right?
The dresses...
The shawls...
The blusher...
Incredible, all these things are here.
Well, almost all.
But who took care of you?
Are my presents not enough for you? Do you
also have to steal what I tresure most?
I won't be treated as a thief nor a coward.
I am a just and honourable man.
Who did you pick this rose for?
My youngest daughter.
She is the most precious thing to me.
Then I will give you one day
to say goodbye to your loved ones.
You only need to whisper the words:
"more than anything in the world,"
to your horse, and he will bring you here.
- I will not return.
- Oh, yes you will.
Otherwise, I will kill all your family,
one after another.
I will kill your youngest daughter last,
since she's your favorite.
Remember...
A life for a rose.
There! Yes, it's him!
I can see him down there!
Father! Father!!
This story about a beast and a rose,
it makes no sense.
Well how do you explain that then?
You can very well see it's real.
More than anything in the world.
- And as if by magic the horse will find its way to the castle?
- It's our fault, it's all our fault.
- It wasn't you who asked for that flower.
- It's nobody's fault!
Silence.
I can not tell you who
this Beast is, but...
for having stolen this rose,
I have to go back there in a few hours.
- What will he do to you?
- I do not know, Tristan.
He said - "a life for a rose".
- And if you don't comply?
- Then we'll die.
All of us.
Don't say anything.
I know what they're all thinking.
- That Mum died while giving birth to me.
- I don't understand what you mean.
I will not be responsible
for your death as well!
Belle! Belle!
Belle!
Don't forget to love me.
Belle! Belle!
Belle!
- Belle!
- Father, no! Father!
Guide me to the castle and
take me to that Beast.
More than anything in the world.
A life for a rose.
Belle was ready to die
as she heard the first strike of the bell.
But as she explored the
castle of the Beast,
a noise, stronger and more beautiful
than that of the bell,
started to resound in all her being.
It was the beating of his heart.
My name is Belle.
I came to exchange my life
for the life of my father.
Sit down.
Eat.
When you have regained your strength,
you can go for a walk
anywhere on the estate.
But when night falls,
I forbid you to go out of the castle.
If I must die, let it be now.
You have more courage than your father.
Every evening, at this hour,
you have to be here.
Don't even think about escaping.
The forest will close in on you.
- Would you like me to stop reading?
- No, I want to hear the rest.
- It makes me sad that she's all alone. Poor her.
- That's true, she felt very much alone.
While she was climbing the immense
staircase, Belle realised that
she had never been away
from her family before.
But what she didn't know
was that in her room
the Tadommes were waiting for her,
the little cratures inhabiting the castle.
They were going to become her best friends.
...sleep... dream...
...sleep... dream... she's sleeping...
listen to our voices...
...come to the mirror...
- They're coming.
- Ah, they yell, they're dirty and boisterous. They annoy me.
- But one of them will win your heart.
- Well, then I'll make his life a living hell.
Here they are.
I always knew you weren't faithful to me.
And now, I am going to eat you.
Get your filthy hands off her!
Well, my friend, since you didn't catch
the doe, you won't be getting a reward.
- You still haven't stopped hunting the doe?
- She has been eluding me for years.
But I will catch her, I can feel it.
An she will be my biggest trophy.
After you.
Look at the present we gave him.
Golden arrows, like the skin of the doe.
Let's go, I'm thirsty.
We need to drink.
Still, he should have joined me.
I've had enough.
You smell like a beast.
Love, I want to ask you something.
- What?
- I want you to stop hunting the doe.
- But why? - I don't want you to be gone
for days on end trying to catch her.
I feel terribly lonely here, without you.
All right.
But under one condition.
Give me a son.
Belle was afraid of leaving her room for a long time. She
was afraid that the Beast would be hiding in the shadows.
But her curiosity was
stronger than her fear.
She wanted to explore the estate and
see just how far her prison stretched.
Princess...
That was how Belle realised
that many years ago,
or maybe even centuries ago,
there lived and loved another woman,
who died in that damned castle.
"Why me?" - she asked the statue sadly.
"Why do you disturb my dreams?"
Feeling very sad, Belle ran to her room,
to wait for the bell that announced
her meeting with her strange prisoner.
You're late.
- Do you like your new dress?
- Don't come to my room ever again.
- I would like to remind you that I have every right to.
- We'll see about that.
Don't look at me. Eat.
- And you, don't you eat?
- No.
Not in front of you.
May I talk or should I eat in silence
like a child?
It's what you are. An arrogant child.
I like it when people think
I am childish and useless.
- That way...
- You talk too much!
I am sure that you like it, the
fact that I fill the void.
- Who does this castle belong to?
- Everything here belongs to me.
You sound like any other men.
It's pretty disappointing.
Do I disappoint you, my love?
Is there anything else
you don't like about me?
Are you not going to say anything else?
I've been waiting night and day for
you to decide my destiny.
You're playing with me as if I were
a mouse in your paws.
If you accept my offer...
I would fulfill all your desires.
You think that a beast like you can make
a woman like me happy?
Don't look at me! Don't look at me!
I know what I am!
You can resist me all you want,
but you will be mine!
"Eat! Don't look at me!"
Do this, do that.
I will show him!
What is this?
Oh, it's me!
It's a spitting image of me.
What a wonderful gift.
I wonder who could have made
such a beautiful doll?
Where are you hiding?
Come out, I won't eat you.
I will put it here. That way I will always
have it close by.
...listen to our song...
My friends,
today is a big day.
Our kingdom will finally have an heir.
And you, madam?
Would you like me to
make you a little heir?
- You need a kingdom for that.
- Let's pray he doesn't look like his father.
- What are you thinking about?
- The first time we met.
At the river.
You approached the bank and you
pretended to be undressing.
You were drowning.
I can swim better than you.
What if we went back to our room?
Don't forget your promise.
Which one?
The golden doe.
When she woke up, Belle went
to explore the castle.
She was determined to solve
the mystery of the Beast.
She got lost in a maze of corridors
and crumbling bridges
but feeling that she was being followed.
I apologize for last night.
You were right. You do
fill an immense void.
Do you like my gifts?
- Why don't you answer?
- I miss my family.
Forget them. They no longer exist.
For you it may be convenient
not to think of the past.
- But I can't give it up.
- What do you know about me? Nothing.
Nothing. You are right.
I would like to propose a deal.
- A few hours with my family.
- For what?
A dance.
You will let me see them in return.
- You're doing this out of pity for me.
- I will lead the dance if it scares you so much.
Dancing with me doesn't scare you?
Just let yourself go.
Can you love me?
We had a deal. Hold your promise.
It's been a long time that I
no longer make any promises.
You wrap yourself in princely clothes,
you think you're a man, but you're
nothing but a cruel and lonely beast.
You can try all you want,
bribe me, beitch me,
but you will always disgust me!
Now you know exactly what I am.
Tell me again that I digust you.
Tell me!
I will let you see your
family one last time.
Really? You're not saying
this to torture me?
You have one day.
No more. You'll leave at dawn.
- Give me your hand.
- Which one?
I don't know. I doesn't matter.
The left one.
- You're not going to give me a ring?
- Just be quiet a little.
Listen.
You know the power of this water.
If you get hurt,
- if anything happens to you at all...
- Nothing will happen to me.
I must get ready.
- Belle, if you don't come back...
- I know, you will kill us all.
No. I will die.
I'll be here tomorrow. At this time.
Who's there?
I'm warning you, I am armed!
Belle!
The house is a mess.
- What are you doing with these weapons?
- Ask Maxime.
- Shut your mouth. Go back to your post, damn it.
- Go back to my post?
- You think you're a general? What an idiot.
- Enough, enough.
- You're not going to start this again?
- Stop defending him.
- You're so scared, you keep drinking wine all day.
- Me scared?
- Stop it! Stop it!
- What is going on here?
Have you all gone crazy?
Come on up. Everything will be fine.
Don't worry.
Selling us as slaves to pay for
Maxime's debts is out of the question.
They will put us on a ship full of
sweating sailors.
Will they make us clean the hull?
We'll tell them that we're sea-sick
and that we don't know how to clean.
Oh, yes!
Anne?
Clotilde?
- I have come back.
- Clotilde, do you see what I see?
It's Belle's ghost, come to haunt us.
- All in red, covered in blood.
- You're not dreaming, my dear sisters.
It's really me.
I came to say goodbye for the last time.
- Even dead she's more beautiful than us.
- Just look at her tiny waist.
- Know that I will always love you.
- We love you too, sweetheart. We think about you all the time.
- She made me take your room.
- Oh no, what have you done?
I will have my revenge.
Where's Dad?
He's been so sad since you left,
that he won't wake up.
What kind of a dress is that?
Dad?
It's me.
Belle.
I'm here.
Wake up, dear Father.
Do it for me.
Dad.
Have you ever seen a stone this big?
- Do you remember the trunks Father brought from the castle>?
- Oh no, don't even think about it. I forbid you.
- It's our only chance, Tristan.
- You'll only go out this door over my dead body.
Look at how her flank is shaking.
I can almost feel her smell.
- Her time has come.
- She's mine, understood?
I am the nymph of the forest.
I had the right to take a human form.
I wanted to know the
thing humans call love.
I had you. My prince.
Forgive me.
Father.
God of the forest.
Spare the one I adore.
He gave me eternal love.
Father... spare him.
A terrible voice resounded in the sky:
"For having killed mmy daughter
I will make you a beast."
Only a woman will be able to save you.
But who would love you?
Be cursed for eternity.
You're betraying Belle.
I'm saving us. She'll understand.
You'd like to have one more
brother like me, right?
What are you doing here, my rabbit?
Weren't we supposed to meet at your shack?
Look.
My boys dressed up just
to meet your sisters.
- I have a proposition for you.
- I'm not making any more deals with you.
I've been very patient.
Look.
It's from an abandoned castle. I'll take you there and you'll
get the rest of the treasure. And you'll forget my debt.
- How many stones like this one are there?
- There are trunks full of them.
Don't disappoint me, my rabbit.
This is your last chance. You know that.
Tell your men to follow me.
Do what he says.
"More than anything in the world."
While they were galloping through
the enchanted forest.
Perducas was thinking about the treasure
that awaited him.
He was cursing his men, not wanting
to share his treasure with them.
He looked at Astrid and wondered wether
he'd prefer love or wealth.
Sometimes the human spirit is troubled, its
beliefs are shaken, and only doubt is left.
Meanwhile, Belle was reliving the story
of the prince who became a beast,
when she heard a heart-breaking groan.
My child!
I missed you so much!
Belle!
Oh my God!
Anne! Clotilde! Come quickly!
I was so scared.
Something in you has changed.
Your eyes.
- And your voice...
- I have to leave, Father.
I have to go back there.
- Wait, I want to stay here!
- This is the happiest day of my life!
Careful, you'll crush me!
Did you feel something?
Danger. I can feel it, it's everywhere.
Everything we desire, right?
Let's go.
You three, go to the west.
The others, take the east.
You my rabbits, you will go in front of me.
...Astrid...
...enough fear... enough blood...
...save your life...
...take the gold in your hands...
...Astrid... Astrid...
Where are my brothers? I have to hurry.
Maxime took the horse.
I tried to stop them, but...
Forgive me, Belle.
I hate it when you're far from me.
Where were you?
If I tell that we have to leave now,
will you follow me?
- Is this gold?
- This arrow is very powerful.
I feel that this will give
us more than just wealth.
We will be respected. We'll
be above everything.
Open your eyes.
We've finally found what
we've always wanted.
How do I know you won't come back
here later to steal my treasure?
If you don't believe me any more,
belive the prophecy of the cards.
- What have you seen?
- Death.
- Yours or mine?
- Which do you prefer?
Neither, my love.
And since you're not sure about anything, we'll
say that this one over here will die tonight.
Well?
This gate will not open by itself.
An abandoned castle you say, ha?
Buck up, my rogues! We have to visit
the floors as well.
We should find another way.
It's the ribbon I lost on my way here.
It can't be too far from here.
Belle, what are you doing?
Belle, stop, you'll hurt yourself.
Belle, come back! Come back, Belle!
Belle, please, come back!
Belle!
God of the forest,
hear me.
Let me go back to him.
It's my only wish.
My one desire.
You were wrong. There was no one
waiting for us on the inside.
Don't spoil the fun. I am rich.
Now, I can fulfill all your desires.
- My desire that we would die together?
- Your cards don't decide any more.
I decide.
What's wrong with him?
Why is he screaming?
- Where are our brothers?
- Over there, with Perducas.
He will kill them!
Maxime!
Save yourself. Ask Belle to forgive me.
- No.
- Go, leave!
You can ask her yourself.
Stop!
You, my little one,
you will help me.
Let her go!
What are you?
- A lion? A big cat?
- The one who will drain your blood.
You can purr as long as you want.
But if you don't want me to damage
your doll, you'll let me go.
I beg you!
Remember that you were a man.
Spare this vermin and let my brothers go.
The important thing is that I'm here.
That I will stay with you.
Help me!
Come on, quickly!
Don't leave me!
Love, your fate will be just like mine.
Come help me!
Hurry up!
Put him in the pool, quickly!
He's not breathing.
Don't worry about us. Come on, brothers.
We've missed our dinner.
You say that as if you regretted it.
Belle.
Do you think that with a little patience,
or maybe out of habit,
you could have...
loved me?
But I already love you.
Well, the story is over.
It's time to sleep.
Come on. Come on.
What about the brothers and the sisters?
What happened to them?
They all went back to town. The brothers
opened a printing house, to print books.
And the sisters married two twins, and they
couldn't tell them apart.
That way they are all happy together.
And their father?
He opened a flower shop.
- Him too?
- Yes, him too.
Sweet dreams.
- Mummy...
- Sleep, my dears.