CAESAR MUST DIE
Fly, Brutus, fly.
Trebonius,
help me to die.
And I should do something like that?
Never.
Take this sword.
No, Brutus, I'd rather kill myself.
Please, stay.
I know your courage.
Hold my sword.
And turn your face away.
Help me to die.
Will you?
Give me your hand first.
Farewell, my lord.
Farewell, good Strato.
Caesar,
you can find peace now.
I kill myself with mice the anger
with which I killed you.
We defeated you, Brutus,
but you were the noblest Roman
among the conspirators.
You believed
with courage and firmness
that your deed should be undertaken
to honor freedom.
Nature was generous with him,
he lived a great life,
in his heart and in his mind.
Thus we can proclaim to Rome
and to the whole world...
this is a man!
Let's go!
Quick!
REBIBBIA PRISON
HIGH-SECURITY WING
SIX MONTHS EARLIER
- Good morning, everyone.
- Good morning.
I'm pleased there's so many of you.
We are here to inaugurate
next season's theatrical laboratory.
As prison authorities,
we want to support this initiative.
Obviously, we need you to believe in it,
give your best efforts and show your
passion as in previous productions.
I'll hand over to Fabio Cavalli,
who will introduce the project.
This year we are going to be staging
Shakespeare's Julius Caesar.
It's about a great Roman general,
who, after making Rome
great and powerful,
gives in to the temptation of tyranny
and for this reason
will be eliminated
by his fellow politicians.
We'll deal with this with the help
of our lead actor, Cosimo Rega,
who has been following the company
on the inside for years.
We'll start with the auditions
next week.
Those of you
who want to be part of the company
simply have to make a request
to do so.
Good morning.
J
Juan Bonetti
I need you to tell me
your name and surname,
place and date of birth, father's name
and your place of residence
in mo different ways.
The first time
you're at a border crossing,
you're leaving your wife
who is back there, on a bench.
You'd like to say goodbye to her,
cy with her.
You have to provide us
with your details.
The second time, the same situation,
but at this point we will force you
to tell us your details.
So the first time you're crying,
the second, you're pissed off.
From now...
J
Juan Dario Bonetti
born on 16/9/71
in Buenos Aires, Argentina.
Father, Felice Bonetti.
J
Juan Dario Bonetti
born on 16/9/71
Buenos Aires, Argentina.
Resident in Avellino.
Father, Felice Bonetti.
Ligorio Leonardo, born in Manduria,
4/11/70,
in Via Magna Grecia.
Son of Pietro Ligorio.
My name is Atri Ivan,
born in Catania,
26/1/90.
My name is Atri Ivan,
born in Catania,
resident in Adrano,
Via Giovanni Mazza, number 12.
Rosario Maiorana,
born in Palermo on 21/1/70.
Resident in Milan
at Via Monte Pelice, number 6.
Oh, God!
Right, my name is Gallo Vincenzo.
I was born in Lentini
on 11/3/78.
I live in Francofonte...
a village
in the Province of Syracuse.
My father is called Gallo Angelo.
Silvano Giacomo,
12/9/1973,
born in Naples.
Resident in Rome.
I'll tell you again, don't worry.
Letizia Roberto,
born in Rome on 28/9/69,
resident at Via Cimabue, number 4.
My father, Letizia Domenico.
Letizia Roberto...
Got it? What do you want?
What? Fuck off!
Giovanni Arcuri
born in Rome 12/3/1'957,
son of Ottavio,
resident in Rome at Via Federico
Confalonieri, number 5.
Vittorio Parella,
born in Italy, Imperia,
13/4/1959.
Resident in Amsterdam,
RJH Fortuynstraat, Netherlands.
Bastards!
Pasquale Crapetti,
815148,
son of Giuseppe,
born in Naples on 8/5/48.
Via Campanile, number 39,
Naples, Pianura.
Wait.
I'm Pasquale Crapetti,
born in Naples, 8/5/48.
My name is Franco Carusone,
I'm from Cava dei Tirreni.
Son of the late Giuseppe
and Senatore Giuseppina.
Understand?
Is that all right, you like it?
You're all going to be
in Julius Caesar,
but for the main roles
what we thought was this...
For Julius Caesar, Giovanni Arcuri.
Cassius, Cosimo Rega.
Brutus, Sasà Striano.
Mark Antony, Antonio Frasca.
For Decius, Juan Bonetti.
And for Lucius, the musician,
Enzo Gallo, who can play
the harmonica. Have you got it with you?
SENTENCE: 17 YEARS
DRUG TRAFFICKING
SENTENCE: 14 YEARS, 8 MONTHS
ORGANIZED CRIME
SENTENCE: LIFE MEANING LIFE
MURDER
SENTENCE: 26 YEARS
VARIOUS CRIMES
SENTENCE: 15 YEARS, 6 MONTHS
DRUG TRAFFICKING
SENTENCE: LIFE MEANING LIFE
ORGANIZED CRIME
Can you close the curtain?
Perfect.
As you know,
the theatre is being rebuilt,
but I think this room is suitable
for rehearsals.
You've read the parts,
now you have to start speaking them.
Julius Caesar, Act 1, Scene 2.
And remember,
everyone in their own accent.
- Apulian.
- Calabrian.
- Roman.
- Neapolitan.
Perfect.
Julius Caesar is in the street
and the soothsayer comes up to him
because he has to speak to him,
ask him something.
Carusone, that's you, go!
Caesar...
Sorry, Fabio,
but in Neapolitan you say Caesar
the same as you do in Italian.
Here I am, who wants me?
Fine as regards the dialect,
but don't be vulgar.
It's not a vulgar dialect.
It's a dialect,
but in the mouth of noble characters.
Here I am, who wants me?
A bit less.
Quiet, all of you, let him approach.
Sorry, Fabio, I don't have a dialect.
I'm a citizen of the world.
You want to see America?
Let's go to New Zealand, Maori,
All Blacks, haka dance.
Fine, that's enough, thank you.
Let him approach and speak,
Caesar is available to all, you know.
Caesar, amidst the glory and the pomp,
beware the Ides of March.
- What does he want from me?
- He's a wizard, a soothsayer.
Bring him here,
I want to look him in the eyes.
Come forward, come from the throng.
The thing you said before,
say it to my face, now!
Fabio, where I come from,
the wizards, the soothsayers,
they're all a bit loopy.
Can I play it that way?
Caesar, amidst the pomp and the glory,
the Ides of March
are telling you history.
Keep him away from me,
but gently, don't hit him.
At this point in the scene,
Caesar leaves with his entourage,
and only Cassius and Brutus remain,
and they say some fundamental things
at the start of the story.
What happened, Brutus?
live been watching you for a bit.
Dig, dig,
where is your old affection
for your friend?
You've forgotten about me,
or am I mistaken?
What was it, Brutus, what is it?
live been watching you for a bit.
Dig, dig,
where is your old affection
for your friend?
You've forgotten about me.
Am I perhaps mistaken?
What?
Cassius, what are you saying?
Poor Brutus is looking gloomy
because in his soul,
between his heart and his head,
a fierce war has erupted.
Look me in the eyes,
you see the field and the battle too
going on between me and myself.
Listen to your true friend, Brutus,
find the strength.
Look at yourself in the mirror,
you will see the soul of a noble man,
the man we all need in Rome.
What are you saying?
What are you tying to tell me?
Cassius,
do you want me to get into trouble?
Trust me, Brutus, gentle friend,
like I trust you.
Don't trust anyone, you great actor.
I did and look what happened to me!
Look!
Listen!
Right now
the people are offering Caesar
the king's crown.
You fear him.
What am I meant to think?
You don't want it either...
No, of course I don't!
Even if Caesar is dear to me.
Look!
Look what he's doing, that liar!
Antony is offering him the crown
in front of the whole people
and he is refusing it.
Look, he's moving it away
with the back of his hand.
Look, Antony is offering him
the crown again.
Three times, come and see.
No, Striano, you can't go to the window.
Brutus doesn't want to see.
You have to find another position,
you choose.
Good.
On you go, Cassius.
Caesar is uncertain,
he's taking it, he's not.
He's dying to place it on his head.
Rome, city without shame.
You as well, my Naples,
you've become a city without shame.
Excuse me,
but it feels like this Shakespeare
lived in the streets of my city.
Our fathers told us:
rather a devil in charge of Rome
than a king.
I know you're a true friend.
I have no doubt.
It seems clear that
what you're thinking and planning
involves me as well.
I have to think about it.
But don't forget this:
rather than bow down to a tyrant,
Brutus will go and work
as a swineherd.
Be careful,
Caesar is coming with Antony.
- Antony.
- Here I am, Caesar.
I don't like that Cassius.
I want fat men around me,
men who eat and drink.
Cassius has a lean and hungry look;
he studies and thinks too much.
I don't like him.
Don't worry, he's a good boy.
Speak in my right ear,
I can't hear very well here.
His family is noble,
there is nothing to fear.
Maybe, but I do not like Cassius' face.
I don't like lean faces.
I have to go now.
Come and see me tomorrow night.
We still have to talk.
I'll be waiting for you, understand?
Wait for us there.
Meanwhile, Brutus,
think of the world.
- We have visitors.
- It's Fabio.
The stalls in pieces,
the trestles, the cables...
Roberto, everything's all over
the place here!
When is the work going to be done?
We're rehearsing around Rebibbia,
wherever we can,
but if the stage isn't ready,
we'll never manage to put it on.
What do you want? First he says
one thing, then another.
We're just the slaves.
Speak to the emperor.
Maybe a woman will sit here.
Lucius, will we try it,
just the mo of us?
- Now?
- Yes.
- Just the mo of us?
No, you stay in bed.
- Lying down?
- Yes, like in the scene.
Stretched out, with your eyes closed.
- Close your eyes.
- Close them?
Lucius, wake up.
I would like that,
a little of the sweet illness of sleep.
Lucius, wake up!
- I have to wake up?
- Yes.
- Yes, master?
- Check what day it is.
He has to die.
If he lives, Caesar will defeat us all.
If it was just about me,
I wouldn't care,
but he will defeat all of Rome.
I loved him, it's true,
but if he manages
to place a crown on his head,
he is no longer Caesar,
but becomes...
becomes...
becomes a poisonous serpent.
No...
I can't be getting the line wrong.
I understand what Shakespeare meant,
but how to get it across
to the audience?
It's starting again.
We saw him yesterday at the Forum.
He is looking for a throne
on which to build his nest.
He went up step after step,
humble and respectful,
because humility and respect
are tools of ambition.
And now that the summit is near,
he will not turn back.
Look at him, it's gone to his head.
Instead of doing his time properly,
he's playing the fool!
He disparages the world
he has left behind
and is chasing the clouds in the sky.
Give him time, give him a crown
and if the serpent
is still in the egg,
up there the egg will hatch
and intoxicate all of Rome.
Caesar has to die now.
We are at the Ides of March.
They're here.
Go and meet them, go on!
THE PLOT
I'm sorry if we woke you up.
I didn't sleep last night.
Welcome, all of you.
Be patient, I have to talk to Brutus.
See, guys?
The storm has passed.
That's the east,
where the sun rises.
- I think. Isn't it?
- No, you're wrong.
He's right, those bluish streaks
on the clouds come before the dawn.
The sun, at this time of year,
rises there, towards the Capitol.
That's east.
Are you laughing at me?
No, I'm not,
you're saying your line well.
I'm thinking about those four fools
who are about to kill the boss
and they're dribbling on
about where the sun rises.
I like them.
In fact, we're all fools
to an extent. Them too, the plotters.
And just as well; that way
the character is more like me.
Right, hands here, one at a time.
Let's confirm our pact with an oath.
No, no oath.
If we're real men, it should be
enough to look each other in the eye.
Pain and anger in the heart,
shame for this infamous era,
are enough to risk our lives,
because, if they're not enough,
why are we mucking about at night?
If we're not ready,
let's go to sleep,
because tomorrow the tyrant
will worry about our lives.
So no oaths.
The priests can swear oaths,
the crappers,
the old bootlickers,
the vile scoundrels,
the windbags
and all the cuckolds,
beaten-up and happy.
Our undertaking is so great
that no villainy can stop us.
Yes, but who else
will meet the same fate as Caesar?
Metellus is right,
Caesar's right-hand man has to meet
the same fate as Caesar.
We know Antony's job is to plot.
He's astute.
He could ruin everything for us.
The same fate for Antony and Caesar!
No, Cassius,
justice is not a slaughterhouse
and we are men of justice,
not butchers.
And that's how it must appear
to the people.
We have rebelled
against Caesar's ideas,
against his spirit.
This is not an assassination,
it's a sacrifice.
If I could remove the spirit
of the tyrant from him
without tearing open his chest.
If I could...
What's wrong, Sasà,
don't you remember your lines?
He knows them.
He's got the character of Brutus
inside him.
live memorized them too,
but it's difficult.
Difficult? But why?
Have we never known bullying Caesars
in our own home?
And betrayal and murder...
Today he doesn't want to remember.
Sasà, what's wrong?
What do you want?
It's to do with me.
To do with me!
Fabio, I'm sorry.
Really, I'm sorry,
It's this line I have to say:
"If I could remove Caesar's spirit,
without tearing open his chest."
I saw the face of a friend of mine
appear before me.
We sold contraband cigarettes
together,
me on one pavement, him on the other.
That evening
he had to shut up some scumbag.
Suddenly he stopped in front of me
and said exactly the same as Brutus.
The words were different,
but the same.
The neighborhood
got to hear about it.
He's a windbag, they said.
Everyone.
And I did too, in chorus.
And now it hurts me.
What happened in the end?
Will we continue tomorrow?
We'll continue tomorrow.
I want to continue.
Without tearing open his chest...
But I'm scared of Antony.
We all know his love for Caesar.
I told you no, Cassius.
Caesar's right hand,
once Caesar's head has fallen,
won't be able to do anything.
So let him live,
let him go back to his revelries,
games and merrymaking.
Let him live his life and soon
he'll be laughing about it all.
Be quiet and count the hours.
Four o'clock.
Four, it's time to go.
We salute you, Brutus,
but be careful.
Caesar has been superstitious
for too long,
after all these bad omens
and signs in the sky,
he might not turn up tomorrow
at the Senate.
Let me deal with that,
I know how to butter him up.
Catch the fox with a trap
and the man with sweet words.
I'll get him to the Senate on time.
All right, men,
everyone takes his own road.
Hey!
Sleep.
Sleep, Lucius,
that's better.
And to think that at school
I found this so boring!
Our Julius Caesar is a great!
A genius,
according to Shakespeare as well.
Come on, Giovanni
let's not waste time and get to work.
What time, Fabio?
live been in here for 20 years
and you say:
"Let's not waste time"...
Greetings.
Are you ready for the walk
to the Senate?
Well done, Decius,
you arrived at just the right moment.
Take this message
to the most venerable senators:
Caesar will not attend today's sitting.
- Don't you feel well?
- Speak into this other ear.
What do you mean?
Caesar does not hide behind a lie.
It's not that I can't go,
let's say it doesn't suit me.
Tell them that:
Caesar doesn't want to come.
Most powerful Caesar,
you have to give me a reason,
otherwise the senators
will take the piss out of me.
A reason?
My word should be sufficient.
Decius...
Because I love you,
I want to tell you a secret.
Last night my wife had a dream.
A hundred wounds
appeared on a statue of me,
a hundred mouths
from which gushed blood.
On her knees, she made me swear
not to leave the house.
And I am going to stay home.
Caesar, this is a good dream
and it foretells the opposite.
Rome is a leech that gets nourishment
from your blood,
and the more it drinks,
the stronger and greater it becomes.
This is the right interpretation, wife.
And now there is more news,
good news for you, the latest.
The Senate is going to vote
on a decree
to give the great Caesar the crown.
If you do not appear,
the senators
might change their minds.
The sitting is postponed
until the great Caesar's wife
has a good dream.
You must excuse my frank speech,
but I'm speaking as a friend.
A friend?
A liar, an arselicker,
a brass neck.
He's really good
at playing the schemer.
What the fuck are you saying?
You're messing up your lines.
You're so good, it really suits you
with that little face.
This isn't in the script,
Caesar doesn't say that.
He would, if he knew you.
But I'm not acting any more, Juan.
- What's going on?
- It's something between them.
I'm telling you
what's been in my heart for years.
I know you, you've always spoken
behind my back, like they know you.
Yes, but they don't know who you are.
Because what do you know?
Spit it out!
Decius would tell you
in your good ear,
but I'll tell you to your face.
Get lost, keep away,
the snake's bite is poisonous.
I'm a snake? Say that again!
Come on, I'll tell you outside!
Gianni, Juan, what are you doing?
Fabio, make them stop,
or they'll spoil it for all of us.
They'll shut up shop and I don't want
to miss out on this thing.
Observers of the ceiling
they should call us,
not prisoners.
Almost the whole day
with our eyes looking up,
on the bed.
Then if they put you
in the bed on top,
you can see the ceiling,
look at it, touch it,
talk to it.
Francesco, my son,
I try to see your face in the ceiling.
I'm not managing today,
but I'm tying,
I'm tying.
I don't know what I'll do tomorrow
if they don't give me a single cell.
It's my right.
Everyone has diarrhea today.
five beds, five cases of diarrhea.
Hail, Caesar!
Caesar, watch out for Brutus,
don't let Cassius out your sight,
stay away from Decius,
don't trust Casca.
They will all betray you.
You're not immortal. Be careful.
Read this, read it!
Caesar, my petition
has to do with you yourself.
Read it, great Caesar.
The ones that have to do with
ourselves are those we read last.
Great Caesar, read it!
- Who's he? Is he mad?
- Yes, he's mad.
Hail, Caesar.
Most powerful Caesar,
I, Metellus Cimber, place
my humble heart at your feet.
Metellus Cimber, I warn you,
I don't like being buttered up.
Your brother was condemned
and exiled as a scoundrel.
If you continue scraping
and whining for him,
I'll kick you out of here like a dog.
Remember, Caesar
does not wrong anyone.
My respects, Caesar,
but not to flatter you.
The sentence on his brother
is a serious thing.
What are you saying, Brutus?
Forgive, Caesar.
Caesar, forgive.
Cassius kneels before your feet,
listen to him.
I could be well moved,
if I were like you.
The skies are full
of a thousand flashes,
but only one remains still
in one place.
Thus it is in the swarming world
of men,
yet in the number
I know but one who remains solid
and that is me.
And now I will show this to you.
Metellus, I refuse to overturn
your brother's sentence
and I confirm it.
Caesar, listen to us.
Great Caesar, be careful.
Be careful.
Is it not enough that Brutus
knelt down in vain?
Sword, speak for me!
You as well, Brutus, my son.
Don't run away!
Freedom, tyranny is dead!
Cy it about the streets!
Someone run to the public rostrums,
and cy out,
"Liberty, independence
and redemption!"
Don't run away,
ambition's debt is paid.
Let's bend down,
dip our hands in
and wash them in his blood.
How many centuries to come
will see actors play
this great scene of ours
in kingdoms that are not yet born
and in languages
still to be invented.
And how often will Caesar
have to bleed on theatre stages,
like here today, as well,
in this prison of ours,
lying on the stone,
no more than dust?
Here comes Antony.
O mighty Caesar!
Lying on the ground like this.
Your conquests, glory and triumph
are reduced to this.
Peace be with you.
I know not, gentlemen,
what you intend.
Whether other blood
has to be spilled alongside his.
If you have to do it, do it now.
The day and the occasion
are the best for me.
To die beside him,
by the hand of real men,
men of honor.
Antony, no one seeks your death,
and these arms welcome you
like a brother.
I doubt not your wisdom, Brutus.
Give me your bloody hand.
Antony, in a new and fair government
your vote will count as much
as each of ours, agreed?
Yes.
All I ask is that I may take
Caesar's body to the Forum;
I would like to say a few words there
in memory of him.
- Coming?
- Let's hear what they say.
Recreation's over.
They have to go back in.
Let them finish the scene.
I'll speak first and
explain why Caesar died.
Then you can speak
and say that the funerary honors are
our concession.
I do not ask for more.
I like Antony. He's obliging.
What? He's a son of a bitch!
We'll go to the Forum before you.
What Forum?
Get into your cells, come on!
Hang on, listen,
he said he was obliging, listen...
Forgive me,
pile of bones and blood,
if I act meekly
in front of these ghastly butchers.
Forgive me.
You know, don't you,
what will happen to them?
Damn their hands that I shook!
We, your men, like mastiffs,
we will take iron, blood, war
through these lands
vengeance as well.
Brutus is coming!
Let him speak!
Come!
Dim murderers!
- We want to know!
- Let Brutus speak!
- Listen, silence!
- Silence!
Listen to me,
to the end, then judge
me with your wisdom.
If there is one among you,
any dear friend of Caesar's,
to him I say, that Brutus' love
to Caesar was no less than his.
If then that friend demand
why Brutus rose against Caesar,
this is my answer:
Not because I didn't
love Caesar enough,
but because I loved Rome too much.
Had you rather Caesar were living
and die all slaves,
or Caesar dead,
and us alive in freedom?
Caesar loved me.
And for this I weep for him.
Fortune smiled on him
and I am happy about that.
He was brave,
and I honor him.
But, as he was ambitious,
I slew him.
Is there anyone among you
so vile
as not to love his county?
If any, speak;
for him
I have offended.
I'm waiting for an answer.
No one, Brutus!
So I didn't offend anyone.
Antony will speak now.
Antony has our permission
to eulogizes Caesar.
Listen to him, please,
out of respect for me as well.
Now before I leave you,
I want to tell you that
if I killed my best friend
for the good of Rome,
I have the same dagger for myself,
when it shall please my county
to need my death.
No, live, Brutus!
Live, Brutus!
Here comes Antony!
Let's listen to Antony.
Friends, Romans,
I come to buy Caesar,
not to praise him.
The noble Brutus
has told you Caesar was ambitious.
If it were so,
it was a grievous fault,
and grievously
has Caesar paid for it.
Brutus said so
and Brutus and his friends
are honorable men.
Caesar was a just friend to me
and loyal.
When he saw a poor man cy,
Caesar wept.
Ambition should be made
of sterner stuff,
yet Brutus says he was ambitious
and Brutus is an honorable man.
You all did see
when I offered him the crown,
three times,
and he refused it three times.
Was this ambition?
And yet Brutus says
Caesar was ambitious,
and Brutus, we know,
is an honorable man.
I speak not to disprove
what Brutus spoke,
I am speaking to say what I know.
But here's a parchment
with the seal of Caesar.
It is his will.
If you could read it...
But I am not authorized to read it.
Read the will!
- We want to hear it!
- Read it, Antony!
Who's stopping you reading it?
Be patient my friends,
it's best you don't know
how much Caesar loved you.
It's best you don't know that Caesar
named you as his heirs.
If you knew,
you would burn the world down!
I have overshot myself
to tell you of it.
And I don't want,
I don't want to wrong those men
of honor who stabbed Caesar.
What men of honor!
They're traitors!
- Murderers!
- Read the will!
You really want
to make me read the will?
- Read the will!
- It's our right!
But first let me show you him
who wrote it.
If you have tears,
prepare to shed them all.
To every Roman citizen
Caesar leaves
75 drachmas.
His orchards on the other side
of the Tiber,
his private arbors,
he leaves to you and your heirs.
We'll burn Caesar's body
in the holy place!
And we will set fire
to the traitors' houses.
We'll rebel!
The revolt has begun.
Let what has to be, be.
I... Brutus, I mean, and Cassius,
they had to flee.
They organized an army,
they weren't short of money.
And the mob?
They burned all the plotters' houses.
It was a slaughter.
There was little to be happy about
in Rome back then.
Just like where I come from, Nigeria.
Cheer up!
Let some fresh air in here. It stinks.
Here. He's arrived.
Here's Octavius.
Guys, this is Octavius,
his name's Maurilio.
Come up on to the stage.
He's just come to Rebibbia.
He really looks
like the young emperor, maybe...
Pizzetto, the costume!
Maybe with a bit more hair.
Octavius is Julius Caesar's beloved son,
his adopted son.
He arrives in Rome
after his father's murder
and decides to avenge him.
He allies himself with Antony,
against the army
of Brutus and Cassius.
They organize a powerful army
and head for Greece,
where the final battle took place
on the Plain of Philippi.
Are you really going
to have a battle?
We'll have a battle,
but be careful, I'll do you.
Cosimo, don't frighten him.
It's Cassius who comes off worst,
isn't it?
Come and try your cloak.
Not today, I don't want to.
- What's up?
- Forget it, not today.
He's just had a visit.
Today's not a good day.
Which is Brutus' tent,
the one we're meant to raise?
I told you, the orange one.
THE PLAIN OF PHILIPPI
This candle is burning strangely!
Who's that coming up behind me?
Who comes here?
Are you a god, an angel,
or a demon that chills,
the blood in my veins?
Speak to me.
- Who are you?
- Your evil spirit, Brutus.
Why have you come?
To tell you you'll see me again
tomorrow on the plain of Philippi.
That's better that way.
I'll see you tomorrow, Caesar.
Yes, in battle.
Who's that? My harmonica!
live lost my harmonica!
Go back to sleep,
nothing has happened.
Sleep.
Go back to sleep. Nothing has happened.
I was having a dream.
Awake!
Blow now, wind,
rise up sea and unleash the storm!
- Everything to its fate.
- Yes, Cassius.
Today we complete the work
the Ides of March begun.
I don't know, my brother,
if we'll meet again.
Goodbye forever, Cassius.
And if we do meet again,
We can smile together
about this moment.
Goodbye for ever, Brutus.
And if we do meet again, we can smile
together about this farewell.
If only we could know
how this day will end.
Evening will come,
and the end will be known.
Run, Metellus, to the legions!
To the legions, comrades!
Let them set out compact
against Octavius' wing.
The enemy front is weaker there.
A sudden push will upset them.
To the victory of freedom!
Men, all together,
victory is within our grasp.
For freedom...
My companions,
Brutus is resisting and attacking,
Octavius' wing is wobbling,
but we are worn out,
our part is giving in against Antony.
Cassius orders a counterattack.
Resist, fight, resist!
The order
is to cover Cassius' retreat,
Brutus orders:
cover Cassius' retreat.
Defend the camps
until the bitter end!
Retreat in an orderly fashion,
comrades!
Comrades, no one alive to the enemy!
Titinius is surrounded
by Antony's cavalry.
The shields, comrades!
The shields!
Where are you fleeing to,
you cowardly beasts?
More than the enemy
you should fear the ire of Cassius.
Come back and fight,
you bastards, it's not over.
The camp is taken.
The Roman sun has sunk.
Our day is done, my comrades,
honor to the sacrifice
of the fallen.
Honor to the fallen.
Silence.
For our farewell, I ask for silence.
I risked all my freedom
in a single battle
and I lost.
One day like today
I breathed for the first time.
Now my time is over
I'll end it without regrets,
to go back there
where everything began.
Cassius is no more.
Honor to Cassius!
Are you still that powerful,
Julius Caesar?
Your shadow roams here
on the Plain of Philippi
and turns our weapons on ourselves.
Trebonius, help me to die.
And I should do something like that?
Never, Brutus.
Metellus, you do it.
What, Brutus?
You're asking this of me?
Never, never.
Take this sword.
No, Brutus, I'd rather kill myself.
Decius, my comrade,
I feel my time has come.
No, it hasn't, Brutus.
It has.
On the edge of the abyss,
it is more dignified
to throw ourselves down
than be pushed by them.
Remember
when we went to school together?
We sat next to each other.
Please.
No.
Let's flee.
Let's flee, Brutus,
let's save ourselves.
Strato, not you, please, stay.
Hold my sword
and turn your face away.
Help me to die.
Will you?
Give me your hand first.
Farewell, my lord.
Farewell, good Strato.
Since I got to know art,
this cell has become a prison.
COSIMO REGA PUBLISHED THE BOOK
SUMIWON 'O FALCO
AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF A LIFER
SALVATORE STRIANO
WAS PARDONED,
AND NOW ACTS
IN THEATRE AND FILMS
GIOVANNI ARCURI PUBLISHED
THE BOOK FREE INSIDE