Subtitles by DramaFever
I really composed this song?
Yeah, it is.
The songs you're going to
compose in the future--
This makes no sense.
Are you asking us to believe
what you're saying?
But how can we not believe it
after hearing this song?
Wait...
then you weren't joking when you said
all that future and past stuff?
Do you always think I'm joking?
I don't know what's going on here.
Me too.
Ah Rin, can you simplify it
and explain it to us?
Ah Rin!
What are you doing?
Let's go.
Are you daydreaming again?
Yeo Reum.
That was my third time back.
And of course I thought that
I came back alone.
- But Eun Woo...
- Yes?
Can't you reconcile with Bin?
- You don't have to worry.
- Huh?
Everything is going to be okay,
it's bound to work out.
Listening to Eun Woo that day,
I was suspicious
but then I doubted myself.
It was the first time coming back
to the past with someone else.
That's a different song from the one
we prepared in the past.
This isn't the song
we used in the future's past.
If it weren't for MJ...
I'd probably think I was still alone.
So what you're saying is that...
Jin Jin, MJ, and I
all came from the future together.
But somewhere along the way,
we lost our memories about it?
There is a chance we could have
all came together from there.
Then it's a matter of remembering or not?
That's it!
Ah Rin and I don't even know
when we'll lose our memories
and just live on like that.
Wow, this is just like a movie.
Hey, why didn't you tell us earlier?
Do you know how many times I did?
You guys didn't believe me!
- We thought you were joking.
- You joke around too much.
Because I didn't want to
interfere with your future.
That's right, haven't you guys
seen "Butterfly Effect"?
If you change something in the past
whether it's big or small
it can have a huge impact on the future.
Usually in a negative way.
Wow, you said the same thing
the day we got here!
Really?
I guess people don't change.
Then in the past
Sun Hyuk plagiarized our song
and made us go through this hell?
No.
Honestly, this is different
from the past that I know of.
It's true, this is all my fault.
What do you mean it's not?
He held in it back all this time,
and blew up and took it out on Bin.
Is that true?
- You scared me.
That little...
- I don't know where to start--
- Hey, Cha Eun Woo!
- We're screwed.
That's when things started
changing from the past that I know.
Us changing the song like this
never happened in the past.
Oh my, it sounds like fun!
I want to time travel, too.
Then, what do we have to do now?
What do you mean, what do we do?
We already know our future
we'll just need to
start working hard again.
There is nothing to worry about.
I really composed this song, right?
I'll put my finishing touches
to the last part of the song.
- Let's head to the practice room.
- Yes.
From the first day I met you
I doubted you.
The second day I met you
that's when I knew for sure.
Uh ho Uh ho Uh ho Uh ho Uh ho Uh ho
I wanted to take more time with you.
They are so good.
- That night you were kind of off
- But...
isn't it similar to the song
Eun Woo's team was practicing?
What do you mean it's similar?
It's exactly the same.
- I tried to avoid it as much as possible.
- They plagiarized Eun Woo's song.
- Oh really?
- All men are the same.
This is not the kind of love I wanted.
Then what's going to happen?
Is Sun Hyuk's team performing
at the festival?
That's what I mean...
San Ha is so upset because of this.
Let's see what San Ha is doing.
All men are the same.
San Ha!
Why are you leaving already
without practicing?
- Don't tell me you guys gave up.
- No...
We're headed to practice right now.
I'm so glad to hear that.
Don't worry. We already have
a killer song we're working with.
Eun Woo already came up with a new song?
Of course, it's so much
better than the last one.
- Right?
- Yes, yes.
Please do a good job.
because I'm your fan now.
Huh, my fan?
Okay, I'll do my best.
By the way...
I don't think we can meet until tryouts.
Of course. Don't worry about me
and focus on practice.
San Ha, can you...
Why is my heart...
pounding like this?
Me too.
What are we like in the future?
You and I?
It's a secret.
Come on, you're going to start
keeping secrets between us.
It's the same.
Same as it is right now.
All right.
If I become disappointed now
subtitlesripped by riri13
then will our future change?
What do you mean disappointed?
Gosh, I guess I got rejected.
I was going to wait
until I was 20 and tell you
that I wanted to be more than
friends and go out with you.
Why are you laughing?
I really got rejected?
No...
you never confessed your feelings to me.
You're better off confessing them
to Yeo Reum first.
Huh, what does that mean?
Just...
things that are bound to happen
will happen.
Ah man, this is driving me nuts.
I swore I memorized everything,
but I can't remember it.
Since our past already changed
according to Ah Rin
it should be fine even if the lyrics
are a little different.
Don't feel too pressured,
and jot down whatever you remember.
Okay.
I think I'm pretty much done.
Ah... I'm the problematic one.
It's almost done
but I can't seem to finish off
this last part.
Am I slowly losing my memories?
Why can I only remember my part?
Why, is something wrong?
I can't seem to finish the last part,
and MJ can't recall the lyrics.
Let me listen to it.
It went something like that.
I can't remember it clearly either.
Oh...
It's game over now.
Yes, Yeo Reum?
Okay.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Rocky can be in charge
of the center stage.
Since we don't have much time left
we can use the choreography
which Rocky and I used
and what we practiced with,
then use the moves that overlap.
- Okay.
Should we try it now?
I always felt like
you kept secrets from me
and that used to make me upset.
Now I can understand.
I didn't want to look like
a weird person.
It's quite amazing.
How does it feel
to come from the future?
I thought if I can come back,
I would make better choices.
But after I got here
it made me realized that
all those choices had a reason.
A kind of weird sensation.
When I found out Bin had a crush on you
it made me regret
becoming friends with you.
But even if we go back
you're saying we'd still
become friends, right?
Yes.
Hey!
You regretted becoming friends
because of a guy?
Huh?
For a moment...
it was really just a moment.
Let's hurry.
The guys should be hungry.
I'll help you not regret
becoming friends with me.
How is it?
- Yes, woah.
- Hmmm.
- It's really good.
- I told you it's this song.
Let's really get it started!
- Yay!
Today is finally the decision day.
There were rough patches along the road
but seeing you guys trust one another
and overcome those obstacle
made me proud of you guys.
The biggest reward for our hard work is...
the reflection of ourselves
making those progress.
You guys are already radiant.
Stars are most magnificent when
they're twinkling in the night sky.
Please show that you're the best
in our school on stage today.
- Okay.
Let's do one more round.
- Should we bet on ice cream?
- Of course.
Rock, paper, scissors!
- Oh wait!
- Okay, okay, okay.
Stop fooling around,
and let's start getting ready.
Sun Hyuk's team goes first
since they submitted the song first.
- Okay.
- Then it's Eun Woo's team.
We're going to start
once the teachers get seated
so get ready quickly.
- Okay.
We'll find out who's the real rat today.
Don't mind what he says.
Yeah.
They had to use what we threw out
they can't possibly be any good.
That's right. Let's just be ourselves.
Eun Woo, my heart feels like
it's shivering to death.
Me too.
We probably have done this before
yet it's still nerve racking.
Should we all cheer together?
One, two, three.
- Fighting!
Let's go.
Subtitles by DramaFever
I don't know what you're saying right now.
Oh no, no.
I don't know when or how
I'll lose that memory
and live on like...
I can't be a hindrance to your future.
I'm sorry.
Went to the future yesterday, I'm sorry.
I thought I was alone... I'm sorry.
How many times did I say it?
You guys once... didn't believe it.
I'm sorry.
Already know... I'm sorry.
What happened to
"the guys will be hungry"?
Bang, bang, bang.
I'm sorry... getting ready for.
My heart feels like it's shivering.
I'm sorry.