This magazine says there's a new hospital
for a new kind of artificial insemination.
The success rate is 30% higher.
You want a baby?
I know it'll cost money...
It's not the money, go ahead if you want,
but don't expect me to be part of it.
What are you saying?
To put it bluntly,
I'd rather be with them than you.
You both look about the same in size,
but at least there's some novelty in them.
When I met you, you said you'd bring me
fortune and children.
Am I rich? In my dreams!
You can't even lay an egg.
Stop lying to me.
You said I shouldn't con people,
or my children will get retribution.
But you're the biggest con artist,
liar of the century!
Con artist, liar...
Don't have a fit over this!
We're out of soya sauce. I'll go get it.
This is good, Sis.
What are you eating? Alright...
Excuse me, auntie.
Auntie? Do I look that old?
Fatty! What a coincidence!
What's wrong? You're all teary-eyed!
My husband doesn't want me!
It's OK! Thanks!
She removed her husband's name.
Is she divorced or is he dead?
Have you ever seen her husband? I haven't.
I know she has 2 sons who are
quite good looking.
The picture on her desk? I know that.
She's always so secretive, what a weirdo!
That's enough!
Mrs Lam...Sorry, Miss Luk.
You have 10 minutes before the
press conference.
LY wants to know if you're ready.
Tell him I'm ready.
I must admit, today's media
have more sources,
and more channels of distribution.
That's why their reaction to each story
is much quicker than the Government.
Our colleagues of the Resource Centre
only wish to verify it.
I emphasise we have no intention
to interfere with the freedom of the press.
You think this is strictly a human error?
Because Mrs Lam was at karaoke.
That's why the press release was late?
Incorrect account of an incident
may constitute libel.
We have pictures to prove it.
Unless Mrs Lam doesn't recognise herself.
Care to comment, Mrs Lam?
I heard you became single again recently.
Is that why you went drinking?
LY is your boss.
Did he spend time to console you?
Mrs Lam and I will not answer
any personal questions.
Rumour has it you'll quit your job
to run for councillor.
Will you two work hand in hand?
That's a personal question.
Rumour has it after you leave
the Government,
you will go into politics.
As your star assistant, will Mrs Lam
follow you?
That's all for today. Thank you.
Wait...
Mrs Lam, care to comment?
Mrs Lam, say a few words...
Come into my office. I want a word with you.
Are you really that stupid?
You knew karaokes are flooded
with reporters.
You let them take pictures of you
when you were blasted,
at a time when you had
just announced your divorce.
You know I hardly go to those places.
It just so happened I went with
my old classmates.
No excuse!
OK...
You should know very well,
what you do affect not only you
but also affect me.
People in politics must
sacrifice their personal lives.
If you want to be the woman
behind me,
you must behave yourself in public.
Don't worry, it won't happen again.
I haven't had a chance to ask you,
you've been divorced for some time.
Why did you choose to announce it now?
Precisely because it has been so long,
I don't want to hide anything anymore.
Don't tell me you were doing it for me.
No, I want no more constraints,
no more secrets.
It has nothing to do with you.
The media will be in hot pursuit.
Except for official business,
it's best we don't see each other.
I won't drop by at night anymore.
You look so cool with that poker face,
I want to eat you alive!
When will you hand in your resignation?
I want to think it over.
I need to make some plans.
I thought we agreed.
What's there to plan?
You know if I quit now, I'll lose everything
housing, medical insurance, pension...
My sons are still in school in the UK.
I don't want them affected.
I need you to help me set up the office.
You know how long I have been
planning for this.
I can only make this happen with your help.
You can't be so selfish
and only think of yourself.
You have to think of me.
Fine! I get it...
I didn't realise our mutual
trust is so fragile.
Let's pretend nothing happened
and I haven't said anything, OK?
What does that mean?
I said I needed to think about it.
I didn't say I wouldn't help you.
I have work to do. We'll talk later.
You should get back to work too.
OK? OK!
Hey, gorgeous!
Does he have to run off like that?
Can't even stay for a chat?
All by yourself?
It's hot!
Do you mind?
Let's find something to do.
(Chun-lei calling...)
When will you grow up?
Even a kid knows drugs can
ruin your life.
Why don't you kick the habit?
You sound more like my Mom than my Mom.
Mom my foot! How can you laugh?
Are you scared?
Not as much as you should be.
The marijuana fell out of your pocket.
The cops already said they wouldn't
press charges against me.
But after this incident,
I must carry my ID card even when
I take out the garbage.
I'm so glad to see you.
The paperwork is done. Let's go.
Bye, gorgeous! Let's do it again.
Thanks! You were the first name
that came to my head.
After all you're a government official.
Have you eaten? Happy hour on me?
Why were you arrested?
Pure bad luck! I went out to buy a beer.
The cops asked for my ID
and brought me back to the police station.
Don't lie to me.
I really forgot my ID.
You forgot to bring it to check into
a love motel.
Who was that guy? He's a delivery boy!
A delivery boy in possession of marijuana.
I can't believe you could be so indiscreet
at your age.
Jenny, what happened to you?
I told you it's bad luck.
I haven't done this in 10 years.
I got arrested the minute
I wanted to get laid.
Chatty, believe me...
Sorry, don't call me Chatty on the street.
OK, Mrs Lam. I don't usually do this.
I've been really dry lately,
so I let myself do something so stupid.
You were quite the free spirit
even back then.
You always knew how to had fun.
I can't believe you'd come to this
at your age.
Forget it.
It's late. Go home, take a shower
and go to bed.
Next time, don't call me.
I don't want reporters on my tail.
I'll pay you back later...
Anyway, thank you,
Please leave a message, we'll reply ASAP.
Honey, it's Mom!
Is it cold in the UK?
Big Bro, remind your kid brother
to stay warm.
He has a sensitive windpipe.
It'll mean trouble if he catches a cold.
Call me when you guys get this message.
I really miss you two. Love you.
(Chu-lei calling...)
Hello? Surprised? Mrs Lam
Yuen-chau! Hello? Are you OK, Chatty?
Say something! Hello? What is it?
It's late. What on earth do you want?
Precisely because it's late, I want to
make sure you're OK.
I heard something break. Are you OK?
I'm fine!
You have a nice ﬂat.
Must be nice to be a civil servant.
Why did you get so drunk?
I'm OK!
Drink some water.
Here...
I know him. He's your boss LY.
Your boys are so big!
Just the boys? No pictures of your husband?
I won't answer personal questions.
I'm not Mrs Lam anymore.
No more Lam Luk Yuen-chau.
My name is Luk Yuen-chau. That's me.
No wonder you're drunk!
Your phone is ringing! You have a message.
(LY: I miss the way you moan in bed.)
Chun-lei!
Slow down. There's no hurry.
I can't carry you if you pass out.
Don't tell them about my husband.
Come on, he said you're worse than a hippo.
A creep like that belongs to the landfill.
Don't worry. The girls are on your side.
I know they are.
According to the Book of Reincarnation,
I'm here to pay a debt in this life.
Nothing I can do can change that.
If you make a big deal out of this,
what will happen to me?
Don't be so superstitious!
You know that's how I am!
Will you help me, Chun-lei?
Do I have a choice? We're best friends.
I'll pretend nothing happened, OK?
Thank you!
Argh!
What is it?
Chatty?
Why didn't you go HP?
We're waiting for you.
Let's go!
Jenny, open UP!
Happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to Jenny,
happy birthday to you!
Thanks!
Make a wish!
I wish Benny would get run over by a oar.
What?
Benny? Is he the guy from the band
whom you saw kissing your Mom?
What has he done to you?
Whatever it is, you shouldn't curse him.
You'll get retribution.
The creep deserves retribution!
He said he wanted to many my Mom,
but he doesn't want to bring me
with them to the Philippines.
That's terrible!
How can he do that?
If she thinks I'm a burden,
she shouldn't have given birth to me.
I don't know who my real father is.
If she leaves me, what will happen to me?
Don't let your imagination run wild.
Auntie loves you, she won't leave you.
I'm not much better.
As much as my Mom loves my Dad,
she couldn't marry him.
People keeps calling her a tramp,
and they look down on me.
I'm very unhappy about it.
Don't start, Cyndi!
You're still better off than me.
You still have your Mom.
My parents are dead,
leaving me all alone living under
someone else's roof.
Don't CW!
Auntie gives me such a hard time,
even her son bullies me.
My brother bullies me too.
He pulls my hair and calls me BBQ pork girl!
Your brother is a real creep.
I feel like Nobita and he's Takeshi Goda,
only there's no Doraemon to save me
when he bullies me.
I'll be your Doraemon.
If he bullies you again, I'll be the first
to stand up to him.
But Fatty looks more like Doraemon than you.
Don't you make fun of me!
Come on, it's just a joke. You don't, OK?
You don't know my sad story.
How sad? You're always smiling.
You don't know because you're new at school.
Siu-sze and I went to the same
primary school.
She knows why I'm called Fatty.
Because I once weighed almost 200 lbs.
You're exaggerating!
One time when I had a high fever,
my parents couldn't carry me.
They had to borrow a hand trolley
to take me to a doctor.
Everyone on the street was staring at me.
I want to cry every time I think about it.
But you're skinny now.
But I didn't grow an inch!
The other day, Mom went to see
the doctor with me.
She asked the doctor...
What?
If I were a dwarf!
That's hilarious!
How embarrassing!
Don't laugh! It's not funny!
It's sad, but I top the cake.
My Dad is a Superintendent of Police
with the Correctional Services.
My Mom is the principal of a
government school.
My sister is a top Arts student with 8 "A"s!
My brother is worse, he's a
straight A student in 9 subjects.
Imagine the pressure on me!
There are rules for everything at home.
I feel like I'm living in jail.
They have a say in everything and I don't.
I was not allowed to watch EYT.
It's quiet like the library after dinner.
My Christmas presents are always
literary classics or encyclopedias.
Alright, we get the picture...
Now we know why you couldn't
keep your mouth shut at school.
Siu-sze, you have no war stories to tell,
you must be so happy.
You're so lucky.
That's what you think. I have my problems.
Like what?
People make fun of me all the time.
About what?
They say I'm ﬂat like an ironing board.
What?
Is it true?
Happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to ]en...
Thank you.
You didn't make a wish!
I'm too old for that.
It's always health and world peace, right?
The same to you, OK?
Same to you...
You all seem a bit weird today.
We haven't celebrated a birthday in years!
I told you we're too old for this.
Can we help you?
Honey, what are you doing here?
She just finished her piano lesson.
I thought we'd come for a visit.
Let me introduce you...
My husband Wong Kwok-leung,
my daughter Wong Ho.
Hello!
Say hello!
Hello, everyone!
Hello!
You're lucky she's grown up.
It's nice to have a daughter.
Pretty too! Youth is everything!
A family of three, very nice.
Luckily she takes after her Mom,
and not a water buffalo like me.
Are you saying Grandma gave birth
to a water buffalo?
I'll tell her!
Good! Get Daddy in trouble!
This place is nice.
I'll show you around.
Wow, your idol...
Cut the cake, I'm dying of hunger!
Bite your tongue, don't say "die".
No holds barred in here...
Don't repeat what was said tonight.
Whoever repeats it
will be an old maid forever.
Why are you looking at me?
What do you think?
I swear I won't say a word, OK?
I wonder what will become of us?
I want to be tall and skinny like a model.
Prettier than the lot of you.
You think we'll be in university together?
That'd be great. We'll remain inseparable.
Auntie would put her son through school
if she had the money,
I won't get a chance.
I think we'll all be housewives with 2 kids,
holding one in the front, one on our back.
What a spectacle!
You'd never agree to it.
Ca" YOU give up your forest?
I'm just saying that.
We'll see when the time comes.
For now, I'm happy to have you all.
We'll celebrate your birthday with you
every year.
We'll always be happy like tonight. Agreed?
Agreed!
We'll always be best friends,
stay the same for 50 years like Hong Kong.
50 years!
The sky next to the meteorite is my home.
The dark sky is my origin.
I live my life for you...
Someone on the street
met me by accident.
She was next to me, leaning against me.
Someone on the street lit up
the fire in my heart
and gave me warmth
that blossomed in my heart.
I close my eyes and pretend I'm in the past
Your heart is close to mine.
Let my love run free
as if I owned everything
that would stay with me forever...
Anything about my daughter?
We've found 5 potential targets.
Really? Where?
One each in California, Hawaii,
the UK, New Zealand
and the last one in Mauritius.
All over the world?
That proves the strength of our company.
Our top-notch staff is stationed
throughout the world.
You should have complete faith
in our efficiency.
But you can't confirm she's my daughter.
That's why we need to escalate
our operation to zero in on the target.
Additional charges?
Of course!
We have to go abroad and look,
which requires additional manpower
and expenses.
Don't worry. We can offer
an international VIP discount.
5 locations, buy 4 get 1 free.
I can't afford that.
That's such a shame!
Because of a little money,
you and your daughter will be
forever apart,
and can't be reunited.
Such a lovely daughter,
will be without the love
of her birth mother.
Keep looking.
And the fees...
I'll have it ready soon.
Hello! Did I scare you?
No! Why would I be? I wasn't doing anything.
You slammed the drawer so hard,
did your fingers get caught?
Are you blind? I didn't close any drawers.
What are you doing limping around?
I wanted to see how
the new fitting was going.
Ka-lai! You're back!
Hello!
“Ms your m?
Fine! I have one more appointment.
I'm so relieved!
Ka-lai wants to see how the
renovation was going.
Show her around.
Come...I have good news for you.
We'll be filming a commercial...
I'm out of lives. Send me a few...
What game are you playing?
You have abandoned the Black Holes Crush
long enough.
Frdbook? You have friends other than me?
I see, Princess Leia!
You've been busy looking up
her Frdbook?
I want to know what she's doing.
Waiting won't get you anywhere.
Is this how you woo a girl?
You should do it like you study
the black holes.
Be daring with your theories
and verification.
Let me help you.
Hey! What are you doing?
Say "I like you"...Send a rose...
Come on, delete it!
Give her a banana too.
She checked in at Chat Kee.
Go find her.
But I don't like beef brisket,
I only like wonton noodles.
You're going there to meet her,
not to eat.
You can eat anything after you meet her.
Even wonton rice, you moron!
Get going! You need a push? Go!
Are you alright? Chi-kin?
Luckily you're not holding ﬂowers,
or Pd think you came to propose!
You came for beef brisket noodles?
Yes, can I join you?
I'm done and I'm leaving.
There's a seat over there...Hurry!
I have to go, bye!
Bye!
How many of you, Sir?
Zero.
The Science Museum has an exhibition
on forests in Norway.
Interested in taking a look at my home town?
Yes!
You'll have to slow down for this cripple.
I can even be your crutch!
Careful!
Lower your arm a bit, OK!
Give me a smile...good!
She's so beautiful!
I must compliment my good judgment.
When I first met Dan-dan,
I knew she'd be the ideal spokesperson
for my product.
What woman doesn't want to look like her?
She has the skin of a young girl,
and the body of a mature woman.
But my aunt's age.
Exactly! How did you know?
That's precisely the reason I like her.
I want this commercial to tell
all the aunts in the world,
when you use this product,
your husbands won't run off.
Isn't it a great idea?
Right...too great! Don't worry, Mr Wong
when the commercial goes on air,
even grey goods traders will fight for it.
I hope so!
Mr Wong! Thanks for coming.
Thanks for your help, Dan-dan.
Are you filming the commercial
the day after tomorrow?
The director told me you could dance.
No, the day after tomorrow is too soon.
Really?
Miss Dan-dan changed our storyboard.
She wanted to add other women.
You're not the star?
I'm too beautiful.
No one would believe I need "Hero".
If we add a few housewives,
women who see the shocking difference
won't want to look like them.
They'll use Hero so that
they can look like me.
The commercial will be very entertaining.
And it'll work for sure.
Trust me, please!
Of course I do! Lun...
Just do as Dan-dan say.
I'll sort it out.
Are you serious?
These women are 20 x Z, not under 20.
How can they wear this uniform?
To show them like this on TV is so scary.
Without a "parental guidance" warning
and it's not Halloween.
You want people to complain?
It's Miss Yung's idea, not mine.
What?
Oh my God! How cute!
Cute? I don't see you wearing it.
Alan, sort it out between you
and tell me what to do.
What game are you playing?
How can I sell this idea to the M Club?
You're so charming you can do anything.
Or just offer to do more hotpots with them.
I'm serious! Either you change this
or let those women off the hook.
I must film this commercial.
Don't get huffy with me over those women!
Because your idea is sick!
Mr Wong is spending so much money
on the commercial.
You shouldn't mess it up because
of a personal vendetta.
If you're not happy with me,
I can quit and your troubles will be over.
Not that again!
I didn't want to either.
If I quit, Mr Wong will blame you.
He'll complain about you and...
And I'll lose my job.
Sol must do as you say.
Please! This commercial will be fun.
Sit back and enjoy a good laugh.
Good, there you are!
Lun's secretary sent over this disc.
They want us to do this dance
in the commercial.
They want us to use this as reference.
My husband definitely won't let me do this.
I'm not doing the commercial.
No, you can't quit.
There are 3 of you.
3 is not enough.
No, 3 is a lucky number.
Look at the Grasshoppers and Little Tigers.
It's only fun if we do it together.
Don't force me. My husband won't let me.
Let her back out. The 3 of us will do it.
I want out too!
What?
Why? You don't have a husband.
I'm not in the mood.
Why? You've been like this lately.
I don't have time to practise.
I don't do facials and I look awful.
I don't want to go in front of the camera.
What should we do?
Lun made it clear he needed everyone
from M Club.
What else? I won't give up this chance.
The show must go on.
Patty's husband forbids her to do it.
Chun-lei needs to look after her Mom.
Only 4 of you left in the M Club?
There are 2 more, but one has gone mad,
the other is quite an introvert.
She can't go in front of the camera.
So that leaves you and Chu Lei?
Z or 4...What's the difference?
No difference? Can 2 people play mahjong?
You signed the contract.
It specifies there will be 4 of you.
Now there are only 2 left.
Sorry! I didn't want this to happen,
but I couldn't convince them otherwise.
I'll talk to the boss
and see if there's a way to sort it out.
Great!
No way! If they don't do it, I won't do it.
Change the storyboard, cut the dance.
Don't make fools out of them.
Then why do I need them?
You really want to do this?
I don't understand. You're a woman too.
Why must you give them a hard time?
You should know how sad it is
to be made fun of.
Have you forgotten what they did at school?
Alan, stop saying I'm vicious.
This is simply a slice of life.
I'm giving them a mirror.
Let them know the world is unfair.
Some women are born to be Miss Hong Kong;
some, country bumpkins.
I'm putting them in a commercial
where they can be themselves.
I'm not mocking them at all.
If you're not vicious, you're cruel.
You build your happiness on
others' pain.
You hurt others without
benefitting yourself.
If you think I'm so bad,
call Mr Wong and have me replaced.
Don't threaten me again.
I'm not doing that. I'm trying to help you.
If you finish this commercial,
you can keep Mr Wong as your client.
You'll get a chance to move ahead.
If you don't grab this chance,
you'll fail again, like you did before.
No! I won't let that happen again.
I agree you have changed.
But you're beginning to fuss
like an old lady,
just like those housewives.
You're the only one who'll never change.
You're still as loathsome as ever.
Take that, Hero oral solution
is a must for menopause.
Down them all. They can clean you up.
You really want the M Club?
I'll get it done.
You're getting me in trouble.
Why?
They are delicious!
Have some more. Don't be shy!
No, my husband already says I'm a hippo.
He needs to get a truck to fit me in.
Is that why you turned down the commercial?
He said I'm fat and ugly.
The commercial would only embarrass him.
No! You're not fat!
You're cute and adorable.
You have very nice features.
You have a better camera face
than Cherrie Chung and Maggie Cheung.
Really?
Of course! Too bad you won't do
the commercial.
I've already hired a star
makeup artist for you.
Sing?
And a luxury brand as sponsor.
Pada?
Top director.
Anyone will do as long as
I look good on camera.
Don't worry, you'll be reborn.
Even your husband won't recognise you.
No. He'll drive you home in a Porsche
to have a baby!
Are you sure?
Of course! Even if you're fatter than this.
When I was an air stewardess,
men of any size, race and profession
have courted me.
But I loved my freedom too much
to pay them any attention.
When I finally met someone I loved,
my Mom broke us up.
That's why I'm so lonely now.
You shouldn't be,
you have your friends from the M Club.
They either talk about their husbands
or the studio,
none of which is my concern.
You don't know how boring that is.
That's why you don't want to
do the commercial with them?
Or you have no confidence in yourself?
Why would I have no confidence?
Though I'm not much to look at now,
with proper makeup and if I set my hair,
I'm still the looker I have always been.
When I was still ﬂying,
a Hollywood director wanted to
cast me in a film.
I only turned it down because
they wanted me to strip.
Rest assured, you wont have to do that
in our commercial.
Will you do it?
I used to be so happy. What happened?
How did I end up like this?
When I get up in the morning,
I don't know what I'm doing.
There's nothing I want to do.
I haven't sat down for a 3-hour meal
in a long time.
I haven't seen a movie,
gone on a trip...
Nothing is worth getting excited anymore.
Nothing makes me happy.
What happened?
I'm so bored and lonely! I want to cry.
Don't cry, you still have me.
Prince!
Only you understand!
Lun said "not one less".
Where can I find him Z more?
What about Mimi and Fifi?
How about Auntie Fong and Auntie Leung?
They're not the M Club.
Any woman will do.
Aren't we practising?
You'll do the commercial?
You husband gave the green light?
I didn't tell him. I'll surprise him.
Hello, everybody!
Chun-lei! You're back!
I was in no mood
because I was having my period.
Now that it's gone,
I'm in the mood to dance.
Great! M Club is back!
They'll start filming in 2 days.
We should start practising.
Hold it! Now that we're doing something
for the studio,
let's use our old motto...
M Club, absolutely not one less...Go for it!
Don't be stupid!