Shh!
I've got an errand for
you in the village.
Have Slocum send me a
crate of brass polish.
Aye, aye, Captain.
My mother was beautiful,
wasn't she, Cap?
Mighty pretty, Star,
accordin' to her pictures.
Gee, we were lucky, weren't we?
- Lucky?
- Mm-hmm.
I'd never have known what my mother
looked like if it wasn't for that trunk.
Did you swim with it
in your teeth too?
No. No, it just washed ashore.
"Lucia Di Lammermoor.”
Do you think they named
the song after my mother?
I reckon so.
She must have been an opera singer...
from the dress she's got on
and the clothes in the trunk.
I wonder.
Could she sing “Asleep in the Deep“...
all ways down?
Pretty deep down
in the hatch for a “sopranny?
How can anybody sleep
in the deep anyways?
That means the last,
long sleep, Star.
- Does everyone have to die?
- Mmm. Sometime.
- You and me too?
- When the time comes.
Do you think we'll last till Christmas?
I shouldn't be surprised if we made it.
You better up anchor
now and get on your way.
Aye, aye.
- Am I seagoin', Cap?
- Seagoin' from jib to taffrail.
- Good-bye.
- So long.
Step on a crack.
You break your mother's back.
- He's a humdinger.
- Yes, sir.
- Here comes Star. - Hello, Star.
- Howdy.
Come on, Star.
We've been waitin' for ya.
Can't now, Paul. I'm on government duty.
Get me tomorrow.
Got a job yet, sailor?
No, but I've been promised one
as soon as the halibut start runnin'.
I hope they start running soon.
Well, you can't rush a halibut.
Well, don't give up the ship.
Hello, Star. How are ya?
- How are ya, lassie?
- I am hearty.
- Why good morning, Star.
- Good morning, Mrs. Croft.
- Is the captain with you?
- No, ma'am.
Tell the dear captain
I asked after him. Don't forget.
I will.
I mean, I won't.
Well!
Better look out, Star, or she'll tie a tow
rope onto January, and you'll lose him.
Not while I'm in charge
of the lighthouse.
We need another case of brass polish.
We need it right away.
And don't forget what we get off
for being government.
Well, you know, we always aim
to please you, Miss January.
The price is still the same,
and we'll make prompt delivery.
Hmm.
Have one on the house, Star.
Oh, they're all the same size.
I measured them.
I know, but the black ones last longer.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Now don't forget about
our special price.
- You know I'm giving you all our trade.
- I-I won't forget.
There's your music, Star. Let's get goin'.
Come on, Star.
- Don't drop it.
- I won't, Star. - Up here.
Sure can dance, can't she?
Well, Star, you can sing about bein'
a sailor, and you can dance like one...
but you'll never be one till you learn
to spit a curve in the wind.
Do you have to know how to do that?
You sure do. You're just
a bloomin' landlubber till you can.
Then I'm gonna learn now.
Watch me.
Stand back, boys.
Let her go, Cap.
Now it's your turn.
Yeah, go ahead, Star.
No, no. That ain't it.
Now, watch me closely.
- Get the idea?
- I got it now.
Watch.
Now you got it.
Try it again.
Who is that child?
She's the adopted daughter
of Captain January-
the lighthouse keeper.
- I-Isn't she a pretty little thing?
- Does she go to school?
Well, no. You see, the former
truant officer wasn't very strict and-
Yes, I know. That's why
she's the former truant officer.
You school teachers will
find me strict enough.
One, two, three-
Little girl! Little girl, stop that!
Disreputable loafers!
You ought to be ashamed of yourselves,
teaching a child to behave this way.
Don't be mad at them.
They always have fun with me like this.
Do you know that Captain Juras
can spit 15 feet in a 20-mile gale?
Indeed!
And the skipper-
he's the one with the accordion-
once he killed three Chinamen
with a table knife.
- - This is dreadful.
You should be taken home and spanked.
What kind of man is this Captain January
to allow you to run-
Cap's the finest man
in the whole world.
See that lighthouse down there?
Well, Cap owns it.
He saved a million
ships in his day.
Go right home and tell him I'm
coming to have a talk about you.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll bet she can't spit
a curve in the wind.
- Don't be impudent, young lady!
- I didn't mean to be.
Cap always tells me
to be polite to old ladies.
- What's her name?
- I'll tell you all about her tonight.
Who is she, Paul?
New truant officer they
sent over from Salem.
- What's a truant officer?
- Stormy weather for kids.
Then I guess I'd better up anchor!
So long! Bye, Star!
- Good-bye!
- So long, Star!
- What did the woman say then?
- She just got mad with me and went away.
Ah, forget about it.
She can't do anything
mean to us, can she?
Nah.
Remember, I work for the government.
I am the government here.
Maybe she's government too.
I heard Captain Juras say
she was some kinda officer.
Well, don't worry.
Havin' trouble, Cap?
- Can I look now, Cap?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
Not yet. Uh, I'll have her
in trim in a minute.
Why do I have to work on this?
All nice little girls
work on samplers.
Don't seem like nothin'
I'll need in a seafarin' life.
That's where you're wrong, Star. A good
sailor's gotta be able to steer a needle.
Can I look now?
Oh, it's Captain Nazro.
- Hello, honey.
- Well, blind my eyes.
Can't I even give a birthday party
around here without you bargin' in?
Pipe down, you catawampus.
I didn't come to see you.
Come on out, honey,
and see the present I brung ya.
Oh!
- Remember me?
- Why should the crane remember you?
Is it a crane?
I thought it was the stork.
No. It's a crane-
something you always wanted.
Wait. You ain't seen
nothin' yet, Star. Watch.
Nice work, Ichabod.
Look at 'em.
- If it wasn't for the ribbon, you
couldn't tell 'em apart. -
You're gonna invite Captain Nazro
to stay for the party, aren't you?
- Well, I wasn't countin' on it,
but as long as he's here...
Goody! I'll fix a place for him.
Whether you was counting on it or not,
I'm here, and I'm gonna stay for a while.
- Oh, you are, are ya?
- Yes, I are.
It's time I was doin' a little inspecting
around this here lighthouse.
They must be daft in Washington,
appointin' you an inspector.
You don't know the difference
between a telescope and a tar barrel.
The way you handle 'em,
I guess there ain't any.
Come and get it, sailors.
Over there, Captain Nazro.
This don't dance around
when you play a harmonica...
and it may not be
what you always wanted...
but I thought maybe
you'd like it a little.
Like it, Cap?
It's the most tremendous
present I ever got.
Thanks, Cap.
- What is that?
- What do you think it is?
How many guesses do I get?
It's a cake.
Cap made it himself.
Oh, did he?
Then I guess I'll just eat the candles.
Go on, Star. Make a wish and catch
her amidships with a spankin' breeze.
- You can have my wish.
- I can?
- Then I wish...
If you wish what I think you're going
to wish, I'll push your face in.
- Why you-
- I'm taking my wish back.
I only gave it away because last year
I couldn't blow out all the candles anyway.
All right, matey.
Blow!
What ya gonna call the doll?
Mother.
But if it was only an ordinary doll,
I'd call it Susie.
- Why Susie?
- After the captain's mermaid.
What? Has he got a mermaid?
Show him, Cap.
Show him!
- No. Go on. Eat your ice cream.
- Please show him.
- Please.
- Oh, all right.
Make Susie dance.
Faster! Faster!
Huh! just a minute.
That ain't nothin'.
Take a look at this.
- Can you make him dance?
- Dance?
Pipe down.
Do you think that's anything?
Huh! Stay out until
you get something.
Well, top that.
It's a pleasure.
What else you got?
Wait a minute.
I'll show you somethin'.
That's stormy weather.
Which one of you
is Captain January?
I'm Captain January.
I'm Mrs. Morgan,
the new truant officer here.
- Why isn't this child in school?
- Well, I was aimin' to send her next year.
What you were aiming to do
is of no importance.
There's a compulsory education law in
this state, and this child is old enough.
How does she know how old I am...
when we don't even know ourselves?
From what I have observed, this child is
being brought up entirely without control.
She's rude, disrespectful-being raised
like an ignorant little heathen.
Look at the kind of clothes she wears-
not even a dress.
Say, what business is that of yours?
- Star's mine, and I ain't listenin' to no-
- You will listen to me.
You forget this
child is adopted.
It's within the power of
the school authorities...
to have her taken from you and sent to an
institution if you fail to raise her properly.
Just a minute, Mrs. Morgan. Now I don't
hold none with this mildewed old pirate...
but you're talkin' through your crow's nest
when you say Star is being brought up ignorant.
Why, she can read writing and write down reading
better than any six-year-old on this coast.
What do ya mean, any six-year-old? Well,
there ain't no eight nor nine-year-old...
from here to Newfoundland
that knows as much as Star.
No! Nor any 10 or 11-year-old
as far as that goes.
Or a 13 or a 14!
You talk about neglect.
Why I've been learnin' her from
the two best books there is;
- the Bible and Bowditch.
- Bowditch-a book on navigation.
Fine reading for a child of six.
Any objections to the Bible?
There ain't better readin' in the world
than the Bible and Bowditch.
They both learn ya
to steer a straight course.
I didn't come here
to discuss reading matter.
Is she talking about
taking me away from you?
Yes, but just talkin'.
Have her report to the schoolhouse
for an examination next Tuesday.
My nephew is also taking
his examination.
And we'll determine then and there
whether or not she's been neglected.
There seems to be some doubt
as to the child's age...
but you say she has the intelligence
of a child of eight.
- Very well. We'll call her eight.
- Maybe I'm only six.
I'll stand on eight.
Now you get outta here.
This is her birthday, and examination
or no examination, I've had enough of you.
We'll see about that.
What was that thing she was
talking about-a “instee“- “instee“-
Never mind, honey.
You'll never be in one.
Now you run outside and play.
I wanna talk to Nazro.
- I'll visit with “Ichybod“ the crane.
- All right, matey.
- You certainly are a lubber-puttin' your
foot in it that way. -
What's the idea, insisting
Star's as smart as a girl of eight?
- Well, she is, ain't she?
- Sure, but why make it tough on yourself?
Would of been enough for her
to pass a six-year-old examination...
- but you have to insist on eight.
- I ain't afraid.
After all,
Star doesn't belong to you, you know.
- Doesn't belong to me?
- That's what I said.
You just took her without saying anything
to anybody or asking anybody anything.
You got no legal right to her.
Ya never even adopted her!
She's more than adopted.
She's part of me.
That's all right, but it ain't the law.
When ya fished her outta the water...
you should have turned her over to the authorities
or tried to find out if she had any folks.
- I did try.
- Yes, you did.
Well, I tried for a little while.
Couldn't keep on tryin' forever.
I didn't wanna lose her.
I wanted to keep her.
Anyway, she has no folks.
They're all dead.
Are they? Did you ever look
through this album carefully?
“Mrs John Mason, 326 Boylston Street,
Boston, Massachusetts.“
They may be relatives, you know.
Just because they didn't answer
your letter doesn't mean they're dead.
They may have been away...
or you might have forgot
to mail the letter.
What business is that of yours?
Star's mine,
and there ain't nobody
gonna take her from me.
- How does this look?
- Looks like a flag at half-mast.
Well, I can't quite make up my mind.
That's just the thing for school.
When I was a little girl, I had
one just like it.
Are you sure you haven't
got one with polka dots?
Hmm, let me see.
Polka dots, polka dots.
4.50.
How 'bout this one?
There ain't no dots on that.
It's your astigmatism.
Oh, look!
Oh, I like this one.
Say, that certainly is a beauty.
- Aw, I don't think so much of it.
- Why don't you try it on, Star?
- Can I try it on?
- Why, certainly. Come. I'll help you.
Nazro...
could you let me
have $50 till payday?
What do you do
with all your money?
I'm puttin' it in a trust fund
for Star.
You just caught me a little short
of ready cash, January...
but I know where
you can get the 50.
- Where?
- The widder Croft will let you have it.
The widder will
let you have anything.
Nah. She might start figurin'
somethin' I don't want her to figure.
Aw, belay that. No matter what you do, a
woman's gonna figure what she wants to figure.
Isn't this pretty?
How do I look?
- Beautiful.
- I think so too. Don't you, Cap?
- Well, I uh-
- It fits her perfectly...
and the whole outfit
only amounts to $41.75.
That settles it.
You wait here, Star.
You're gonna see the widder.
Come on. Come on.
Now wait a minute.
Don't rush me.
Go on on in.
What ya scared of?
- She won't bite ya.
- How do you know she won't? Whew.
I'd rather face a 90-mile hurricane
in a leaky rowboat.
Say, why do “widders“
always wanna get married again anyway?
Are you going in and
ask her for that $50, or ain't ya?
I'll tell ya. Why don't we both
go in and borrow $25 apiece?
- Huh?
- All right. I'll do it for Star's sake.
Come on.
Lust a minute.
Hello, Nazro.
Why, Captain January!
Come in, come in.
Oh, Captain, you should have let me know
you were coming. Why, I look a mess.
- Well, I, uh-
- Uh, Mrs. Croft...
Captain January here has something
very personal to say to you.
Ah.
So I'll just shove off
and leave you two alone.
Dirty, double-crossin',
barnacle-brained, scurvyjudas.
Oh.
What did you come
to ask me, Jan?
Well, uh, I-it ain't
so much for me, as for Star.
- Y-You see-
- Oh, I understand.
The poor little dear
needs a mother's care.
There's nothing can take the place
of a mother... except another mother.
Yes. Yes, of course.
No, no! No, I-I mean, no.
Uh, it ain't so easy
for me to ask you.
Ah!
Why, Jan!
Great, big, seafaring man like you
scared of little, old me.
If you'll only grant me
this one little favor...
- I promise-
- Yes, yes. You'll promise?
Lend me $50!
I've got to get Star a whole new outfit, so
she'll look nice at her school examination.
Why, certainly, Captain.
There's nothing you could ask
I could refuse you.
I'll make out a check for you
right now.
Whew!
- There you are.
- Well, thank you. Thank you.
You know, I've quite an account in the
bank-more than enough for one person.
Yes, uh, well, good-bye, Eliza.
Good-bye, Jan, clear.
Good-bye.
Don't you talk to me,
you lyin', crawfishin' river rat!
Did ya get it, Jan, dear?
That ain't none of your business.
Yes.
“I was. You were. He was.
We were. You were. They were.“
“I was. You were.”
That don't sound right. Hmm.
Gosh. I wish I'd have gone to school
instead of runnin' away to sea.
- I'm just polishin' up a bit.
- But you already polished up this morning.
Can't you stop now, Cap, and help me
some more for the 'zamination?
Pretty soon, honey. But ships and lives
depend upon this light bein' just so.
Suppose that light had been out of order
the night you came. Where would you be now?
- Asleep in the deep.
- That's right.
- Remember the tables I learned ya? Huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, tell me the two table.
Two times one is two.
Two times two is four.
Two times three is six.
- Two times four is eight.
- That's right. Go on.
- Two times five is 10.
- Uh-huh.
- Remember any of the three table?
- Sure!
Three times one is three.
Three times two is six.
Three times three is nine.
Three times four is 12.
Three times five is 15.
Three times six is 18.
- Now we'll do some more geography.
- All right.
- Captain Nazro says-
- Nazro, Nazro. Always Nazro.
- Did I hear my name mentioned?
- What do you want?
Nothing with you, you desiccated
old crawfish, but I thought I'd come...
and help get Star ready for the
examination-you being so illiterate.
Me illiterate?
Why, I can spell you down, read you down,
write you down and figure you down.
And I can do it all with my
hands tied behind my back.
No, you couldn't.
- You'd need your fingers to count with.
- Yeah?
Well, I'll bet you couldn't count over 10
without takin' your shoes off.
Quarreling ain't helpin' Star none
with her examination...
but this might.
You see, I thought it might
help things along...
if we knew the questions
they was gonna ask.
Gee, this is great.
Where'd you get 'em?
Paul “borried“ the key of the schoolhouse
from the schoolteacher...
and him and me paid it
a little visit.
Well, listen, Star. These are the questions
they're gonna ask you tomorrow.
Now, here's the first one:
“What would be the area of a field 87 rods
long and 206 and a half yards wide...
and what would it cost
at 22 and a half cents a square foot?“
What's the answer?
How much is a rod?
How many fathoms?
I thought you wouldn't know.
Hmm. I'll figure this out for you later.
Now let's see what
the next question is:
“Name six animals that live
in very cold countries.“
I know!
Three bears and three seals.
No, Star.
They mean six different kind of animals.
That would be bears and seals
and walruses and foxes and polar bears-
But you've already used bears.
Well, polar bears are different
kind of bears, ain't they?
Gonna act like that, you might just as well
say she-bears, he-bears and baby bears.
Now what other kind of animal did I see
when we were on that arctic expedition?
- Oh, I remember-a skunk.
- Don't look at me, you sea cow.
That's the wrong answer, Star.
What's the next question?
“Can you prove that heat expands?“
- What does “expand“ mean?
- “Gets bigger.“
Can you prove that heat
makes things bigger?
Of course it makes things bigger. The days
are longer in the summer, aren't they?
I guess that's the answer, all right.
“Write down
the 'quality of mercy' speech...
from The Merchant of Venice. "
Bah! It's a put-up job
of that old hatchet face.
No child of eight or 80
could answer that riddle!
It's a mistake.
I must have picked up
the wrong paper.
This is a high school examination.
I just saw the word “examination“
and thought it was all right.
Bah! You can't even steal proper.
Come on, Star. Let's
get on with our lessons.
More 'rithmetic?
No, I guess we've
finished with arithmetic.
Does she know about fractions?
- Sure she does.
- How many halves in a whole, Star?
How big a whole, Captain Nazro?
Every whole would have the same
number of halves, wouldn't it?
But wouldn't a bigger whole
have bigger halves than a little whole?
Sounds reasonable.
Uh, how much does four quarters make-
Never mind that. They're not gonna
ask Star anything about fractions.
Now let's go on with
our geography again.
Tell me what
I learned you yesterday.
This is the Atlantic Ocean.
This is the Pacific Ocean.
- This is the equator. This is the
North Pole. This... N-Not so fast.
Not so fast.
The world goes faster
than that, doesn't it?
A mite.
Now, what's this I'm pointin' to?
- China.
- Mm-hmm. What comes from China?
- Tea.
- And what else?
Chinamen.
You're goin' at this all wrong, January.
Nobody's gonna ask a little girl
like Star anything about China.
How do you know? You never passed
an eight-year-old test, did ya?
- I could've passed one.
- Maybe-when you was full grown.
You know, with me tellin' that Morgan woman
I was teachin' Star from the Bible...
they're pretty apt to ask her
some questions about the Bible.
Well, there ain't many children
as up in the book as she is.
I know, but-
- What are the four gospels?
- Matthew, Mark, Luke and John.
Correct. Now remember the story
I read ya last week about the prodigal son?
Mm-hmm. And the father said,
“Bring out the fatted calf and kill it...
and let us eat and be merry.“
That's fine.
But everyone wasn't merry, Star.
There was a brother
and some neighbors.
Now, who was sorry that
the prodigal son came back?
The fatted calf!
Listen, Mary, you can give
Star a break if you want to.
It's impossible, Paul.
The examination must be conducted honestly.
You know I love Star as much as you do.
Gee, if I was in your place, I'd lean over
backwards to see that kid pass.
I'd like to, but I can't lean either way.
The test has got to be perfectly fair.
Remember when I was
in school once.
I missed every question on the examination,
but they promoted me anyhow.
I guess they needed your desk.
No, that wasn't it. But I did see
the teacher kissin' the principal.
Even if Star saw me kissing the principal,
I couldn't favor her.
Anyhow, Mrs. Morgan is no woman to trifle
with. She'll be watching me like a hawk.
I know, honey. I know, but-
oh, gee, I wish you'd give Star a break.
I wish you'd give me a break, Paul.
Oh, Mary?
I'll see you tomorrow, Mary.
- Here.
- Thanks, Cap.
- That's for the teacher.
- Why?
- I think it's a good idea.
- Excellent.
- Well, lots a luck, honey.
- Aren't you coming too?
No, but we'll be around.
Now, listen, dear.
You've just got to pass this examination.
You've just got to.
It may mean that they'll try to take you
away from me if you don't.
Now-Now, I don't wanna make
you nervous or anything.
He don't wanna make you nervous.
You old fool!
- I'll do my best, Cap.
- Now take it easy, and don't worry.
I'm not worried.
- There ain't nothin' to worry about.
- No. Course not.
You can't go in there now!
- I wish she was stronger on fractions.
- Oh, you and your fractions.
Come on.
Maybe we can see in the side window.
- You clumsy old son of a sea slug!
- Shh!
Why can't I go in now?
Cause the teacher's putting
the examples on the board.
- What's an example?
- Aw, you don't know nothin'.
I'll bet you don't even know
who discovered America.
- Was it a sailor?
- I don't know. Guess so.
- Cap did!
- He didn't do no such thing.
Christopher Columbus discovered America.
And I know when he discovered it too.
It was in 1492.
You don't know nothin'.
Are you awful smart?
Sure. That's why I'm takin'
the examination today.
My aunt wants me to jump
from the first grade to the third grade.
I can jump from the first step
to the third step in the lighthouse.
Oh, it ain't that kind a jumpin'.
Come, children.
What's she doin'?
Nothing. They ain't started yet.
Quit shakin' this barrel!
We're ready to start now, Mrs. Morgan.
That's fine. The sooner the better for me.
I'm sure my nephew is ready.
Uh, Cyril, you sit there,
and Star, you sit beside him.
What's this for?
- No talking, please.
- She's a problem.
Shame, shame, shame, shame,
shame, shame, shame.
We'll begin with arithmetic,
children.
What did I tell ya?
Fractions! Let me up there.
Here are eight fishing schooners.
Those aren't schooners. They're ketches.
You're quite right, Star.
But let's go on.
Here are eight boats.
These five sailed away.
Now, Star,
how many boats were left?
Why would they left?
Did they foul their anchors or something?
Is she havin' trouble?
- Yes, and it's your fault.
- Who are you waving at?
Children raise their hands, Star, when they
know the answer. What is the answer, Cyril?
- Three.
- That's correct, Cyril.
Of course there were three.
Whew. Maybe she's nervous.
But maybe she'll get goin' good.
Bah! I guess Mrs. Morgan was right.
You ain't fit to look after a child.
- Who ain't?
- You ain't. You ain't fit for nothin'.
- Star oughta be took away from ya.
- Why, you lopsided old swab-
- "When George'; father found-
- Listen.
- “his favorite cherry tree- - Gimme your
hand. Maybe there's room for both of us.
“Chopped down, he was very angry.
“So the father said,
'Who chopped down the cherry tree?'
“George replied,
'Father, I cannot tell a lie.
“'I did it with my little ha-
Ha...
- Hatchet. Hatchet.
- Hatchet.'"
Shh! Not so loud.
You've both read very well.
Now I want you
to make up a story...
about being left alone
to take care of a little brother.
- You first, Cyril.
- But I haven't got a little brother.
I know, but make believe
that you have one...
and your mother has left you
to take care of him.
What happened?
I stayed home
with my little brother.
We played games.
We had a good time.
Yes?
That's all.
What can you make up, Star?
One night Cap went away...
and left me alone in the lighthouse
with my little brother.
My little brother's name is Jimmy.
All of a sudden, the biggest wave
in the world came along.
Jimmy was scared, but I wasn't.
Maybe I was a little scared...
but I held Jimmy's hand, and we said
our prayers the way Cap taught us.
Well, the lighthouse-
with me and jimmy in it-
floated all the ways
over to China.
China.
Yeah. They'll probably set
her down for lying so hard.
There were a lot of little
Chinese boys and girls there.
We played games with them.
One of the little girls gave me a nice
“kimona“ and give me some pretty toys.
We were very happy, till a lot of pirates
came off a ship and stole me and Jimmy.
Pretty soon a big storm came up, so Jimmy
and I locked the pirates in the hold.
Then we sailed the boat
to darkest Africa.
After that, we were wrecked
off the coast of Finland...
but we were picked up by a tramp steamer
on the way to Singapore.
There was a bosun on the boat
who scuttled the ship.
- That will be enough, Star.
- But a whole lot more happened.
I know,
but you've told us enough.
But history is hardly a
third-grade subject.
I suppose you taught her
all you know about history.
- She don't know a thing about history.
- That's what I mean.
Very well.
Cyril, who discovered America?
Christopher Columbus!
That's correct.
When did he discover America?
In, uh-
- Yes, Star?
- In 1492!
Very good, Star.
I can do other things.
I can sing, and I can dance...
- and I can read a ship's compass,
and I can... Well, not now.
Come here, Cyril. Go back to your desks
and write the answers to these problems.
- This will finish the examination.
- I don't understand Cyril-
Well, what about my nephew?
Cyril is a very bright child, Mrs.
Morgan...
but I don't think it would be advisable
for him to skip a grade at this time.
Did I pass the 'zamination?
Yes, you did, Star.
You may enter the third grade.
Whoopee!
- Hoo! She passed!
- She passed! She passed!
- What happened?
- Y-You passed, honey. You passed!
- Oh! This is the most flagrant piece of
favoritism I've ever seen. -
I'm sorry, Mrs. Morgan. I tried to be fair.
Goin' to put Star
in an institution, huh?
You better put that dumbbell
nephew of yours in one!
Come here!
If they think they're through with me,
they're very much mistaken.
You village people stick together,
but you forget...
I have my authority from the state board,
and I'll take steps-
Oh, that's too bad.
- - All right?
- I'm going to-
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Have some more cider, Nazro.
Yeah.
Pretty good for a fella
that didn't have much book learnin', huh?
What's book learnin'
got to do with cider?
I ain't talkin' about cider.
I'm talkin' about my
educatin' Star so good,
she jumps right into
the third grade.
You educatin' her? Why, you couldn't
get into the third grade yourself.
Was the things I learned her
that put her through.
Quit your braggin', gooseneck,
and let's drink to Star.
Ya don't think I'd drink to you,
ya blubber-headed blowfish.
- To Star!
Hmm.
Do you think I look as good
in this dress as my mother did?
I expect so.
It's been quite a job
of work cuttin' it down.
Well...
wouldn't you like for me to live here,
sol could cut 'em all down to fit ya?
No. I'd rather grow up
to fit the dresses.
Oh. You mean,
you wouldn't like me to live here?
Well, I like you, but you see,
I'm the lady of the house...
and we couldn't have
two ladies of the house.
Oh. Well, now, you tell Captain January
that I fixed this for ya.
- I'll remember.
- Ah. Here we go.
There.
Too high!
Still too high!
Gosh, you look pretty in that.
Just like somethin'
out of a picture book.
Did you fix that dress over?
Mrs. Croft helped me a little bit.
I've been lookin' all
over for you, Captain.
I thought maybe this telegram
might be somethin' important.
Thanks, bud.
- Bad news?
- Nope, just department routine.
Oh, is that all. I thought maybe they
was gettin' wise down in Washington...
and throwin' you outta your job.
No, not exactly.
What would you like me
to play, Captain Nazro?
Oh, uh, nothing, Star.
Not now. I got some work to do.
Good night, dear.
- Good night, you old albatross.
- Good night, Captain Nazro.
I got seven.
Fifteen-two, 15-4 and each
a dozen.
Well, I've been beatin' you
steady now for 10 years...
and it looks like I'll beat you
for the next 10.
Evenin', boys. Slocum told me
to drop this here on the way home.
Put it on the table over there.
I can't figure out what you're
layin' all these supplies in fer.
You won't need this much
fer just a week.
Automatic.
Automatic!
Pretty soon they'll have a machine to do
yer eatin' fer ya and yer chewin' too.
Go ahead January.
It's your deal.
What's he gabbin' about?
What's all this “automatic“ stuff?
Why, that new light
they're puttin' in here.
- I couldn't get up the nerve to-
- When does it happen?
The 30th.
Now see what you done?
Ya made me swallow my cud!
I'll make ya swallow your cud,
ya lamebrain!
Cap! Oh, Cap!
What's the matter, Cap?
Something wrong?
No. No, nothin' at all, honey.
Nothin' at all.
I don't think I could fall asleep
unless you read to me.
In you go.
Now.
The way you look,
I think I'd better read to you.
Here.
Let me have the book.
I like this one,
because it tells just howl feel about you.
I can't understand why
I don't get no answer to that letter.
In two days,
January'll be out of a job.
That's what old hatchet
face has been waiting for.
Of course it is.
It's a shame January
can't get another job.
He's one of the best navigators
on the whole coast.
Jobs ain't to be had
for the askin' nowadays.
Maybe when the halibut
start runnin'-
or walkin' or somethin'.
Perhaps your letter was lost.
Why don't you send a telegram?
That's an idea. Do you think I'm doin'
right in sending for these people?
Of course you are.
You never did anything
righter in your life.
I hate to think what January's
gonna say when he finds out.
I know. But if someone doesn't come to take
Star, Mrs. Morgan's going to have her way.
The minute she can prove he has
ho "yob and ho means oi support...
she'll get a court order like that.
But I don't know nothin' about these Mason
people, 'cept what I read in the album.
Maybe they ain't even related to Star.
Whoever they are, they're better
for Star than an institution.
Certainly better than any institution
Mrs. Morgan would pick out.
That's right.
And Boylston Street's
a very tony neighborhood in Boston.
Will you phone the telegram
to Salem for me? Here's the address.
We'll take care of it right away.
Come on, Paul.
I wish there weren't any
jobs in the whole world.
Why, Star?
You worry about jobs,
and Cap worries about them.
He feels even worse than you. He sits in
his chair all day just looking and looking.
- Hello, Star. Hello, Paul.
- Hello, Captain.
Havin' a good time?
Not really and truly.
I'm just pretending to.
Cap's feeling awful bad about having
to leave the lighthouse. Cheer him up!
- He looks worried too.
- He was born worried.
What do you want?
Aw, come out of it.
They way you're acting...
you'd think I was responsible
for putting in those newfangled lights.
No, it ain't that.
I'm just plumb worried.
I can't seem to connect
with another job...
with all that ruction the Morgan woman's
stirring up about Star.
I think everything's
gonna be all right with Star.
I've sent for those people.
People? What people?
Those people in that album,
the Masons.
I've asked them to come.
You did that?
You?
You and me have a lot of quarrels, but I
always thought deep down you were my friend.
- I am your friend.
- My friend!
You help 'em to take Star away from me,
and you call yourself my friend.
Why, you dirty, double-crossin'-
I'll brain you! I'll-
- It's for the best January! Don't you understand?
- I'll-
Yeah, I understand. I understand
I've been sold out by a man I trusted.
- You haven't been sold out January.
- I have been!
You're a rotten creep
helpin' 'em to steal Star.
I suppose you've been
figurin' this out for a long time.
- You being without a job... I remember
you tellin' me at the schoolhouse...
that Mrs. Morgan was right,
that I wasn't fit to take care of Star.
- I didn't think you meant it then.
- Oh, January-
But now I know you did mean it!
You've been plottin' with 'em
to take Star away from me.
If you ever come near me again,
I'll break your lyin' carcass in two! I'll-
Did you cheer him up?
Better check up
on that switch box.
All this stuff around here
should have been junked years ago.
I guess you don't know how many ships
Cap saved with this light.
What, that old Chinese lantern?
You could do better with a
candle and a box of matches.
Come on, come on, boys.
It's getting late.
Yes, Star. It is gettin' late.
We better be going.
You get that way sticking around
alone in these lighthouses.
Where are we going, Cap?
Mrs. Croft's.
She's nice.
You know, Star,
I'm kind of glad we're goin'.
I ain't so young anymore, and this climbin'
up and down has been gettin' to my legs.
Mine too, and that's why I'm glad we're
gonna live with Mrs. Croft instead of here.
Eh?
It's nearer the school, and
I won't have to walk so far.
Oh, yeah. Huh.
Yep, I'm relieved to be
gettin' out of here.
So am I.
I'm tired of looking out here
and seeing nothing but the sea.
Nothin' but the sea.
- Quick! It's happened!
- I told you not-
- But she's got the paper. She's got the order.
- Order? What order?
Order to produce Star in court.
Come on. You gotta beat it.
Mrs. Morgan's on her way here now
with a deputy from Salem.
- You don't want him to take Star away, do ya?
- I'm not running away!
- I'm not afraid to appear in court.
- If they get a hold of Star...
you'll lose her as sure as
you're standing there.
- What are they gonna do to me?
- Nothin'.
Don't be stubborn. You can fight later.
In the meantime, take Star and hide.
- Where? I got my boat in the cove.
Paul's aboard waitin' for ya.
Run her out a mile or so
and stay there. Come on!
Come on, Star.
Send the rest of
the things over to Slocum's.
- I'll come out and bring you some food in a little while.
- All right.
Hurry, Star!
Take her, January. Right.
Shove off, Paul!
Now everything's gonna
work out all right.
You won't let them take me
away from me, will you?
Don't you fret none.
I won't let 'em touch ya.
Now you better lie down for a bit.
It's not nearly as pretty
as your light.
Now don't you worry, honey.
You just close your little eyes and rest.
I brung you the things from Slocum's.
Hey, gimme a hand.
- Hello, Star.
- Hello.
Now, honey, you'd better go back.-
There they are!
What's the matter, Cap?
What's the matter?
Nothin', honey, nothin'.
Time for runnin' away is over.
I'm sorry, Cap. They
must have followed me.
- Get your mooring lines ready
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Take this line on board.
- Get out your stern line.
- Aye, aye, sir.
I'm from the sheriff's office.
I have an order to produce that child
before judge Thompson at Salem.
- All right. When do you want us?
- Tomorrow afternoon at 3:00.
- We'll be there.
- You take that child right no w!
He's trying to sneak her
out of the jurisdiction of the court.
- He ain't doin' nothin' of the sort!
- No?
What's he doing on this boat then?
Officer, just a minute please.
You're responsible for the custody of the
child. If he gets beyond the 12-mile zone-
Maybe you're right.
I can't take any chances.
- All right. Come on, bub.
- You let me alone! You let me alone!
- I won't go! Let me alone!
- Now, now, quit it! Cut that out!
- Quit that' Cut that out, I tel/ you!
- You keep your hands off her!
- Ohh!
- You can't take her away from me!
Hey, stop that!
- Oh, please, Cap. Don't
let them take me away.
- Please, Cap!
- Take her'!
Come on, bub.
Come on, bub. Let's go.
Take her.
- Are you hurt?
- I'll be all right.
Go with Star. Don't let
her out of your sight.
Go ahead. I'll
take care of him.
- You let me go! Cap, Cap!
- Cast off.
Cap!
I don't wanna leave!
I don't want to!
That's all right, honey.
Don't cry.
You let me alone!
I want to stay with Cap!
I'll be with you soon.
Be a good girl, honey.
Why are they taking me away from you?
What have I done?
Cap! Oh, Cap!
Now take it easy, Star.
You see, you're just being shanghaied
by a lot of pirates.
But we'll get you away. Why, you'll be
back with January before you know it.
Captain Nazro!
They've come! They've come!
They're up at the house looking for you.
The Masons-Star's Aunt.
So, that's who she is-
Star's Aunt.
Yes. They got your telegram
and came right away.
Oh! How dare you interfere?
This is some kind of a trick.
It's not a trick.
Those folks are Star's relatives.
Well, they can tell it to the judge.
But according to the paper I've got here...
- the child has no relatives.
- They've just been found.
- How providential.
- Listen here.
You've got the authority to take Star away
from January. I ain't denying that.
But have you got the authority
to take her away from her relatives?
- No, but how do I know they are her relatives?
- That's easy.
Drop in at my quarters
and have a talk with 'em.
It's certainly strange that after
four years relatives suddenly appear.
It isn't strange at all.
I've had a long talk with them.
Mr. Mason is American consul in Morocco,
and they've just come back from abroad.
They're fine people, and they've got all
the proof and identification they need.
- Well, I don 't know-
- I suppose you know...
that under section three,
paragraph two of the penal code...
you can get into a lot of trouble
takin' a child away from its kin.
I guess there can't be any harm in talking
to those folks. Let's go see them.
On my lap, honey-
I don't need that. I've
got to go after Star.
Now, Cap, you take it easy.
You might be hurt worse
than you think you are.
I don't care.
I've got to go after Star.
Not now. Nothing can
happen to her tonight.
- Remember, Nazro is with her.
- I know, but she needs me.
You'll feel better tomorrow. First thing
in the morning, we'll run the boat in.
All right.
But the first thing in the morning.
I'm perfectly satisfied,
but maybe the judge would like-
We'll appear before him
anytime he wishes. Here's my card.
Well, good-bye.
Glad to have been of service.
Do you like the doll, Star?
That's a lovely name, Star.
I think I'll call you that.
Your real name is Helen.
She says “Mama“ if you squeeze her.
I know, but I like this one better.
She's a wonderful doll.
Oh, we're going to try
to make you very happy, Star.
I'd rather be with Cap.
Besides, he needs me.
I always take care of him.
Why, he'd be lost without me.
I know. He must be a very,
very fine man.
Are you sure we shouldn't
see Captain January before we leave?
Not now, ma'am.
I don't think it would be a good idea.
You see, he feels Star is his.
It might cause a lot of trouble.
- Please, I want to see Cap!
- Oh, you do?
What do you think we'd better do?
The child feels so badly.
She'll cry and feel bad for a few days,
but after that she'll be all right.
You know children.
They forget quick.
Yes, but it's going to be
hard on Captain January.
No doubt of that.
But he'll see the right of it when I
tell him the kind of folks you are.
Better get it over.
Tell Cap-
Tell him that I love him. Tell him.
Oh, come now.
Well, I got her away from
that old reprobate anyway.
And as for you, young lady, you can rest assured
you'll be dismissed for your part in this.
Ooh! I beg your pardon.
Come on, Mary.
Come on.
It's time for your nap.
I love you better than
all the other things put together...
because you look like my mother, and
the captain made you with his own hands.
- - I guess you better get
Star ready. They're coming for her.
Thank you, dear.
Come on, Star.
Well, Star, are you ready
for a nice surprise?
- How would you like to take a lovely trip?
- Very much, Aunt Mary.
Go on, dear.
I think we've found a
toy you'll really like.
And besides, we're fixing up
a playroom for you.
Thanks, Uncle John.
- Would you like to go up on the bridge?
- Yes, please.
Cap used to tell me about bridges.
Oh, Captain?
Cap! Cap!
Oh, Cap! Cap! Ohh!
Hello, Star.
I'm First Mate.
I'm the crew.
Now that you've got a job,
Paul, you can get married.
Yep, and I don't have
to wait for the halibut to start runnin'.
And now, Captain,
I've got a surprise for you. Look.
Jan, dear!
I'm the cook.