Let's go, let's go.
Ready for them?
Rosie, open up.
Vamos. Afuera. Vamos.
Okay, let's go.
- Just give me five.
- What?
What do you want me to do?
Look, it's not my problem.
All I'm asking, Stevens, is did the old man get seen to?
He was sweating and shaking when I put him on the bus.
He said his arm felt numb.
Jesus Christ, Brogan.
Everything is a humanitarian crisis with you.
You signed off on more orders of recognizance
than the rest of your unit combined.
Don't give me that shit.
The man's about to have a goddamn heart attack.
I want him seen to.
Here he is.
Your guy was given a clean bill of health by Doc Sturgess.
He bused out three hours ago.
You happy now?
Yeah, I'm happy now.
Hey, Max, you're coming on Wednesday, right?
For my dad's nationalization party?
Max, it's an important thing in my culture
to make my father proud.
You know they've been wanting to meet you.
I give you my word, they're not as scary
as I made them out to be, okay?
- You better do it before they blow the lunch whistle.
- All right, let's go, compadres. Let's do it.
Get down!
- Over there.
- I got it. Sorry.
What you waiting for, Brogan?
A marriage proposal?
Come on.
Hey, hey! Gene.
I got her. Thanks.
No, no, no.
No es posible.
Muy bonita. You get her number?
I smell an O.R.
Yeah, he's always giving the pretty ones a pass,
sometimes even the not-so-pretty ones.
Okay?
Now knock it the fuck off.
[singing in Hebrew]
Okay, everybody say, "Thank you, Mr. Kossef,
for singing that beautiful song."
Thank you, Mr. Kossef.
- You know, that was actually a pretty tough crowd.
- Yeah.
- Well, was I shit?
- No, actually.
No, and for somebody who just learned the song last night,
- I thought you did a very good job.
- Oh, good.
- 'Cause I had absolutely no idea what I was singing about.
- Yeah.
- Oh, you could tell?
- Yeah, and also,
please don't take this the wrong way,
but what kind of Jew gets hired at a Jewish day school
who doesn't speak any Hebrew or even really,
like, know the first thing about Judaism?
Well, I guess, the atheist kind.
Excuse me?
No, I'm sorry.
It's just... I just needed a job.
And it was actually my manager's mom
is the principal of the school.
Ah.
- You didn't completely suck.
- Oh, thank you.
I do not want you to say a word about this to anyone.
I mean anyone.
- It could be very serious trouble for the school, and for me.
- No, I'm not gonna say anything.
I want you to know I am only doing this because
of my son, because he says to me,
"Mom, Gavin is going to be an important musician."
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Otherwise, I wouldn't do anything like this.
Well, thank you. Thank you, Rachel.
Honestly, I can't thank you enough.
- She'll be right along, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Oh.
Mmm. Mmm.
Hold on just a second.
Would you like to draw?
Here you go, honey.
I have something else for you this week, too.
Your teacher, Madame Ntende, sent this to me in the mail.
She said that you lost it right before you left
and that you were really sad.
And she found it a few weeks ago.
Honey, it's gonna be a little while longer,
and we are working very hard to find you a good mommy.
She won't ever replace your real mommy, but she will love you.
And I promise that she'll never leave you.
The men involved in this terrorist attack
have been vilified, demonized, and condemned
by the Western world.
But we never want to talk about the 9/11
Jihadists as real people.
The media and our leaders are quick to label them
as terrorists and monsters and murderers.
But shouldn't we try to understand them as human beings?
Fuck, no.
Everybody calls them cowards for murdering helpless passengers
and causing the deaths of thousands of innocent lives.
- What would you call them?
- Hey.
It's the truth.
But cowards do not knowingly sacrifice
themselves for a greater cause.
- I don't agree at all.
- The cause is to kill us?
- You may not agree with their cause...
- I don't understand why she's up there.
But I do not believe their actions were
either cowardly or irrational.
- You know you don't want to hear this shit, Ms. B.
- She's talking.
I feel that, like the oppressed Palestinian
people, or the Iraqi citizens
under occupation in their own homeland,
that they found themselves without a voice.
Hey.
And that the only way for them to be heard is
to scream with the might of tons of steel
- and thunderous jet engines behind them upon impact.
- Okay, okay.
Their voices were heard.
You may not like what they had to say or
how they got their message across,
but for the first time, we heard it.
We gotta listen to this shit?
- What we heard was a cry for justice.
- Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Okay, okay. Yes, thank you.
Hey, Ms. B., thank you.
I am... I am not sure that that was the point of
the assignment, Taslima,
but, uh, yes, it was certainly thought-provoking.
- Bullshit.
- Yeah, bullshit.
You can sit down now.
College is hungry for her.
Fucking traitor.
Crybaby.
Why don't you get the fuck out of our country and
go back to camel-humping Saudi Arabia,
- where the fuck you camel-humpers live.
- Brian. Brian.
I know you're upset, but I'm not going
to condone an outburst like that.
Yo, what's your name? Taslima bin Laden?
Hey, yo, I just got one question, Ms. B.
Did you frisk her? What if the bitch be strapped
with dynamite or TNT or something?
She going to get a grenade!
- Yo, take us all out.
- Boom!
Marcus!
Sure, I'm up for that.
Oh, shit, it's my brother.
Hey.
I thought I told you not to come.
Javier's giving me a ride home.
It's on my way.
I just need five minutes to finish up.
I'm in the middle of an order.
- Look at you. Cover yourself up.
- Just go.
I'll meet you in the car.
Please.
- Um, Heavy-eye?
- Javier.
Hi, I'm Claire. We spoke on the phone, remember?
- Right. Yeah.
- Okay.
Is that okay?
Yeah, it's good. Come back on Friday.
Friday.
- Is that the soonest?
- Yeah.
Okay. See you Friday. Okay.
He's lying. I did it last night.
- Oh, mama's boy taking out garbage.
- Who made you the bitch of the family?
- You got no sister to do your grunt work?
- We take turn.
You gotta keep that shit under control, motherfucker.
Tomo. Let's hit it.
Where to?
Damn.
Oh, shit, I got this little Glock, homie.
Okay, check it out. Wan's uncle's into him for 50 large.
Pays out on Saturdays, gets the cash in the store
Friday night right before closing.
We're gonna roll by and scope it out.
- Yeah, you the bitch.
- Give Yong the Ruger. Sweet gat, yo.
Tell me this don't make your little chachi hard.
- Pussy.
- Yong, you're gonna pop your cherry, fool.
- That's right, man.
- You up for that, Yong?
Better be, homie.
By sunbathing, crocodiles accelerate
the chemical reactions in their bodies.
Once the croc is up to speed...
No, I don't know her name.
I'll recognize her when I see her.
Yes. Andasol Fabrics.
I'm gonna come down and have her released on an O.R.
She's got a minor child left unattended.
Are you sure?
How long ago did they bus out?
Wait, wait, wait.
Did anybody from Children's Services see her?
Yeah. Okay.
Thank you.
Fuck it.
¶ ... in a man with angry rules ¶
¶ It's that bitter pill can make you kill ¶
¶ It don't put me in the mood ¶
¶ So don't talk to yourself ¶
¶ But don't talk to me ¶
¶ There's a river running through it ¶
¶ The devil's not my enemy ¶
¶ So don't talk to yourself ¶
¶ But don't talk to me ¶
¶ If there's poison in the maker ¶
¶ Don't mistake the ¶
¶ Enemy ¶
Whoo!
- That was great.
- Thank you. I'm done.
Glad you came.
So how was your class?
- What?
- I got a recurring role on The D'Angelos.
- You got a part? Are you serious?
- Bitch.
- You did? You got a part?
- I know, it's unbelievable.
Oh, fuck. That's a big deal, babe.
It's big news.
- Yeah.
- We should get a drink.
I'll get it.
Thanks, babe.
So how did you pull it off?
I don't know. I mean the casting director knows my situation.
She's given me until Friday to get my l-9 in.
So there's a fellow I met through someone at Crunch.
He works at one of those photocopying stores on Fountain.
Come on, no, no, no.
You can't do that.
If you get caught with a fake green card,
you could be done for fraud.
It's no different from photoshopping your Social Security
card to remove the "Not for Employment" stamp.
Or passing yourself off as a religious Jew
when you're an atheist, like, an actual atheist.
- Come home with me.
- What?
I'm serious. Come home with me.
It's not practical. You know that.
You know we can't make a go of it without status.
I've gotta get legal, and so do you.
You've got to get legal.
You know that.
I'm working on that, all right?
I just want to know where this guy is.
Your Captain America who's gonna come down
he's gonna sweep you off your feet,
he's gonna marry you, he's gonna make you legit.
- Isn't that what you're looking for?
- Captain America?
I just wonder what's taking you so long.
Here you go.
- Thanks, babe.
- Yeah, listen, I gotta go.
I gotta go. It was a real pleasure meeting you...
- Rose.
Yeah, just give me an email when your TV thing comes out.
Gavin, I'll see you...
before. You know?
Yeah. Yeah, maybe.
She owes me money for the week.
What are you doing, negotiating with me?
Is that what you think you're doing?
- How much?
- $50.
If it's not the right kid, I'm coming back.
- What's his name?
- Juan.
Juan Sanchez.
Thanks, pal.
I need a reverse I.D. on a Tijuana number.
Let's see. It is 661-555-7782.
Appreciate it.
Oh, I think it's this goddamn stomach flu that's going around.
I've been throwing up all morning.
Well, let them know I'll call in later tomorrow.
Okay, let's go.
Uh, I'm not finding any record of your l-539 in our system.
You said you sent it in six weeks ago?
- Eight. Eight weeks ago.
- Okay. Well, do you have a mailing receipt?
No, because I just copied my l-94 and sent it by regular mail.
Okay, well, then how about a cancelled
check for the application fee?
Um, well, I paid by money order.
I don't have a checkbook.
I didn't get a receipt for my money order.
- Listen, I'm starting to get a little concerned here...
- Ma'am, you are not out of status
until you receive a decision on your extension application.
However, if that application is lost in the system
or for whatever reason it doesn't get to us,
then how are we supposed to know
that you even sent it in in the first place?
From our perspective, with no mailing receipt or cancelled
money order, you're out of status, unless...
My application just turns up.
Son of a bitch.
Fuck. It's a brand-new fucking car.
Sorry, didn't l...
I didn't have time to stop.
You just shot out like that.
- I signaled, didn't I?
- No, and even if you did,
it's supposed to be clear before you turn into the street.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah? You look dazed.
- No.
- Do you need to sit down?
Does it hurt anywhere?
- No, no, no, no, no.
- You sure?
Yeah, I'm all right, I think.
I've just had a really, really shitty day.
- Where you from, New Zealand?
- Australia.
It's always one or the other.
I can never quite tell the difference.
I said New Zealand to impress you in case I was right.
Most people usually say Australia, which upsets the Kiwis.
I don't have the money to pay for this.
I'm not insured on my car.
Ouch. That's not good.
I must have fucked someone over really badly in a past life
because shit is just piling up for me today.
I just spent the last three hours in there trying
to convince some bureaucratic bitch
that I actually did file for an extension on my visitor's visa.
Which I fucking did.
- What's your name?
- I'm sorry. I'm Claire Shepard.
Claire Shepard, I'm Cole Frankel,
- and I know of your frustrations.
- You do?
I'm a supervisory center adjudications officer.
What that means is I get to determine whether
a green card application has merit or not.
Ah, that must be interesting.
Yeah, I'll tell you what's interesting,
and what's of a bit of concern to me,
aside from you not having insurance,
and that's someone who's filing for an
extension of their visitor's visa
driving around with a stack of head shots in her car.
There's nothing wrong with a beautiful woman like yourself
having head shots in her car if you were back in Australia.
You're not authorized to be seeking
employment in the United States, Claire.
Am I wrong about that?
All right, here's what I propose.
We call AAA... my card, of course.
If you don't have insurance,
you sure as hell don't have AAA.
Then we get your vehicle sorted out.
Then we go grab some lunch together.
Excuse me?
I want to buy you lunch, Claire,
and explain your options to you.
or we could just take a walk back into the
building and sort it out there.
Juanito! Juanito!
Gracias, Señor.
Sanchez. Mireya.
24.
It would be last night or early this morning.
You positive?
Yeah, okay. Thanks.
That's a great show.
Nothing can touch that on TV.
I thought you said you wanted to discuss my situation.
All right.
Here's the thing, Claire.
You want to be an actress like Nicole and Naomi, obviously.
You know as well as I do the work they do in
Australia doesn't count for shit.
They're stars because they make movies here in America.
If you were to get deported, or even chose voluntary departure,
you ain't getting back into this country
for a minimum of ten years.
And with voluntary departure, they say it's closer to five,
but the truth is, you're lucky if you ever get back in.
- What's your wife do?
- She works for the other side.
- She's an immigration defense attorney.
- Oh. Is she available for a consult?
That's funny.
Sexy, great sense of humor.
You got it all, Claire.
Except for a work permit.
I don't think you'll feel so witty when they introduce
you to a holding cell down in San Pedro.
Strip-search, the whole bit.
Some mama Latina makes you her bitch for a couple nights.
All right. You've made your point.
So where would you like to do it?
You're goddamn amazing.
You really are...
a perfect little fuck machine.
Without a green card.
Well, maybe we could do something about that.
You can get me a green card?
I can't just manufacture one for you.
I'm not in the counterfeiting business.
But I can have your file and application,
which would conveniently land on my desk,
and regardless of the merits of that application,
it would be approved.
You could really pull that off?
Like, on what grounds?
- You're a recognized TV star in Australia, Claire.
- I'm bloody well not. I'm not even close.
I don't know that.
And no one else does.
You fabricate some credits, a few, uh, Aussie awards,
some bullshit testimonials.
And I make it fly.
It's called an EB-1.
It's a green card for persons of extraordinary ability.
Are you jerking me around?
Or is this real?
- Because if you can make this happen for me...
- You'd make it worth my while.
Mm-hmm.
- For two weeks.
- For a green card?
Six months, baby.
I don't think so.
- One month.
- Three months.
Two months
and you get me approved up front, all right?
You can hold on to the paperwork, but I want to see it.
I want to know that it's real.
Done.
But you're on the clock from tomorrow.
I call, and you get your ass over to
whatever address I give you.
All right.
So you through with me for the day?
Can I go grab a shower?
No, wait.
I got one more favor to ask of you, Claire.
I want you down on all fours at the edge of the bed.
You ain't got that yet?
- You cheated today.
- Check it out, yo.
Wait, wait, wait.
- You gonna talk to her, dude?
- Taslima. Taslima!
- Oh, God.
It's the sand-nigger express.
Raghead chick can hide her face and
nobody even know she butt-ugly.
Hey, maybe you can get your sister to convert or something, A.Z.
Shut up.
Ruff ruff ruff ruff ruff!
Put on your belt.
No.
Immigration Customs Enforcement.
Open the door.
What is this about?
Federal agents.
Open the door, please.
We have a warrant.
- Hands against the wall, please.
- Hands against the wall.
What is this?
Why is the FBI here?
Relax, sir. Put your hands behind your back.
Are you Taslima Jahangir?
I'm Special Agent Phadkar.
Will you show me to your bedroom, please?
I don't understand what this is about.
Did you write this?
Why do you have it?
It was brought to our attention by the principal of your school.
He was troubled by the position you took.
I thought there was something like
freedom of speech in this country.
You essay elicits sympathy for the 9/11 hijackers,
- suggests you feel their cause was just.
- That's not what I wrote.
I wrote that I understand why they did what they did.
I didn't write that I support it.
Do you? Support their actions?
I understand their need to be heard.
I don't think they went about it in the right way.
Agent Phadkar.
Do you have an interest in suicide?
Your diary suggests you do.
That's not...
Those are notes on a class paper on
why religions oppose suicide.
And you're not opposed to it?
I wouldn't become a suicide bomber, if that's what you mean.
But you condone suicide bombing as a legitimate
means to make a statement?
That's what you wrote in your essay.
You're twisting my words.
That's not what I wrote.
Well, reads that way to me.
"Upon impact, their voices were finally heard.
You may not like what they had to say or how they
got their message across, but we heard it.
For the first time, we heard it."
I was just saying that they got our attention
and that maybe we should understand why
they did what they did. That's all.
So if someone's pissed off at America,
they should hijack and fly planes into our buildings.
That seems like a reasonable thing to do.
Agent Phadkar, over here.
Take a look at this.
She has a World of Islam account.
She's been frequenting some interesting chatrooms.
Global Jihad,
Jihad Talking Points.
I'm interested in all Muslim points of view.
It keeps me informed.
Taslima, your parents are in the United States illegally.
My brother and sister were born here.
They're American citizens.
True.
But you and your parents are not.
When your brother and sister reach the age of 21,
they're entitled to petition for your
parents to enter this country.
Until then, your family has no status.
Listen to me, Taslima.
Here's what I'm willing to do for you.
I'm not interested in detaining your family.
But I'd like to talk to you further.
Immigration and Customs Enforcement has every
right to take your family into custody,
but if you leave with us now and cooperate with us,
Immigration won't detain them.
They'll still have to resolve their status, but nobody's
looking to make an issue of that right now.
You understand?
Mr. Max, welcome to my home.
- Thank you.
- You honor me with your presence tonight.
- This is my wife.
Very nice to meet you. Welcome.
Thank you. You have a beautiful home.
Thank you.
- Congratulations, sir, on your naturalization.
- Thank you.
Farid. Come over here. Come and meet an important gentleman.
- He's my youngest son. He's a lawyer.
- Ah.
- How do you do?
- How are you?
- It's a pleasure.
- Hi. How are you?
This is Max. He is the partner of Hamid.
You show him the respect, or he will have you deported.
He can't deport me, Baba.
I've already been naturalized.
You're the only person in this house who can be deported.
Until Saturday.
Then he becomes one of us.
Excuse me. I'm gonna go put her down.
It was good to meet you.
- Thank you.
- Okay, come on.
Hey, Max, I'm so glad you made it tonight.
I really appreciate it.
- Get you a drink?
- Yeah, Scotch rocks, please.
Hey, guys, what are you doing?
Inside.
My sister should not have come here tonight.
- What's going on there?
- She puts herself before the family.
She shouldn't expect to be welcome around here.
Baba.
So, Max. Hamid speaks so highly of you.
He looks up to you.
Never understood why he joined the immigration Gestapo.
I think that deep down inside he doesn't feel like he belongs.
I mean, what better way to prove you're red, white, and blue
than by throwing out those who also don't belong?
- You're a lawyer, huh?
- I'm a junior partner at Berkhof, Mazolo, and Klein.
Specialize in personal injury.
We have 35 lawyers under us.
- You're an ambulance chaser.
- I don't chase anyone.
I turn clients away.
Excuse me.
You have another one of those?
Max Brogan. I work with Hamid.
I know who you are.
Thank you.
What does that say on your bracelet?
"Little angel."
My father gave it to me when I was 12.
You realize that they're staring at us.
Very disapproving looks you're getting
for consorting with the outcast.
I'll risk it.
I've never been invited to a shunning before.
What is this? Something you guys brought over with you?
I didn't bring it.
I was born here.
I'm the only one in this family who's an actual American.
Probably decided to naturalize.
Makes 'em every bit as American as you.
Let me tell you about my father.
The great American-to-be.
He was always critical of the Shah.
But after the revolution, one of his business rivals
spread rumors that he was anti-Khomeini.
And the whole family had to flee across the border to Turkey.
He spent most of his savings trying to get everybody over here.
But see, he doesn't pine for the days of the Shah.
And I think he'd be perfectly content in that fucked-up
Islamic shithole that that country is today.
Which is why he resents every day he spends here.
Well, he could go back.
He's too old to start over.
So what's your story?
Any family?
I have a daughter.
I'm not with her mother anymore.
How old is she?
26.
Uh... no.
27.
You better get that straight, or you might piss her off.
I think I did that already.
Max, my father's asking for you.
- It was nice meeting you, Max.
- You, too.
I'm out of here.
Got a date.
Got a real hot date, Max.
Ignore her. She's crazy.
I'm tired, Hamid.
I'm gonna go home.
Max.
My father.
See you tomorrow.
Tell your family thanks for me, okay?
You know what she said to the Yoruban interpreter today?
"Are you my mommy?"
The interpreter says she's losing her
ability to speak the language.
It's 23 months that she's been in there.
23 fucking months.
I feel gutted every time I go.
Ah, it's a shitty situation.
But you can't keep beating yourself up over it.
I was thinking...
we could maybe adopt her.
D.
I'm serious.
Her mother's dying of AIDS in a hospice.
And Leike's dad back in Nigeria denies paternity
and won't accept custody of her.
- We're working on it. One of our own.
- And we can keep working on it.
I've thought about this a lot.
And it feels right.
- It feels like it's meant to be.
- You can't just lay this on me and expect me to...
God.
Will you think about it?
It's important to me.
Please.
Yeah, I'll think about it.
Thank you.
- I can't do this.
- Oh.
I haven't even spoken Hebrew since my bar mitzvah, you know?
I... I didn't even know it then.
You know what? You guys, you're all the same.
All of you. You're all reform at best.
Most of you haven't gone to Shul since your bar mitzvahs.
But first thing you do when you come
over here is play the Jew card.
Haven't you got any shame?
Ouch. That's pretty...
Hello?
Hey, Mum. Hey, hey, hey.
How are you doing?
Yeah, did you get my message?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Well, what about the rabbi?
No, I need you to get him to write a letter
like on the Temple's letterhead
saying, uh, that I attend services regularly.
Uh, I was bar mitzvahed by him.
And that I'm, you know,
I'm strongly committed to the Jewish faith.
All right.
Well, listen, I'm kind of busy right now.
But I'll get back to you, though.
And will you do that for me?
Yeah, you promise? Okay.
Listen, M... Yeah.
I'll speak to you soon.
All right. I love you, too.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye. Bye. Bye-bye.
Ahh...
Iook, l... I got to be home by 10, yeah?
So, um...
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
- With everything.
Oh, what about if I just kind of twiddled these...
these side bits here?
You think I'd get away with that?
If I just stick these out like that?
I can go all night with my wife,
but I'm like a teenager with you.
Doesn't sound like you've gone all night
with her in a long while.
It used to be hot between us.
One day, you're just not into it anymore.
It becomes like an effort.
Easier to jerk yourself off in the shower
than to rub her back for half an hour.
Bloody sad.
Yeah, it is.
Maybe I'll come watch you on the set next week.
That's not part of the deal.
It's not supposed to be.
I just thought I'd stop by and...
Um, I got to go.
I've got a meeting with an agent.
If she signs me, it's major.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Denise Frankel.
- Hello.
Please, thank you for helping my daughter.
Clearly, this is not about her immigration status.
But they're using her lack of status to get around
normal criminal and juvenile proceedings.
- My wife wants to know when we can see her.
- I'm working on that.
I'm pushing for a one-on-one with the FBI
task force officer tomorrow.
Right now, your entire family is at risk for removal.
I recommend you do not go back to your apartment.
Do you have any friends or family with whom you can stay?
Rosa.
Come on, Rosa.
Rosa. Rosa.
Can't find you, Rosa.
And another one bites the dust.
We do our best.
I'm sure you do, sir.
Yes.
Yes, this is him.
Who?
Hey, Hamid.
Hamid? Hey, Hamid.
Hey!
What's up?
I, uh... It's my sister.
What's the matter?
Maybe you can help me.
Do you recognize him?
Agent Baraheri?
It's her boss,
from the print shop where she works.
We've got security video from the motel
of an unidentified male perp in a hooded
sweatshirt leaving the scene.
Time of death somewhere between 11 and midnight.
Did you know that your sister was having
relations with Mr. Bedraz,
who was married with two young kids?
I never talked to her about the details of her private life, no.
Do you know of anyone who may have had it in for her?
Jealous of her, perhaps?
Like I said, I didn't get into her life.
There's something else.
I found these while going through Mr. Bedraz' jacket
looking for identification.
They come in sets of threes.
Green card, driver's license, social.
All counterfeit.
We found more of this stuff at his apartment
earlier this afternoon.
As best we can figure, he was cranking them out
after hours at the store.
We've referred that end of it to your documented
benefit for our task force.
Think it might be Mexican mafia, upset about
him cutting into their action?
We're looking at a number of possibilities right now.
When would be a good time to interview your other
family members, Agent Baraheri?
Can I just...
I'd like to spend a moment with my sister alone, please.
Of course.
Um...
I'm sorry for your loss.
I hate the fucking smell of that place.
I know you're judging me, Max.
- What are you talking about?
- My sister.
What you witnessed last night.
Now I'm mourning her.
You doubt the veracity of my heart.
I'm just sitting here feeling your pain, my friend.
Feeling for your entire family.
It's a sad, terrible thing, your loss.
No way do I doubt your love for your sister.
No way.
Well, if you need someone to talk it through with...
Thank you.
Officially, she's being held for an unlawful
presence in the United States.
Unofficially... and I'll never repeat this outside this room...
she's being detained for presenting an imminent
threat to the security of the United States,
based upon evidence that she planned to be a suicide bomber.
- And what evidence would that be?
- Don't play coy with me, counselor.
The signs are all there.
We're talking about a devout Muslim young woman
who at 15 years of age walks around veiled.
Who engages in internet talk focused on the duty of Jihad.
And writes openly about suicide.
Did you take a look at her bedroom?
How austere it was?
This isn't the life of a normal teenager.
Everything about her is a red flag.
Only when viewed through the distorted
looking glass of your own paranoias.
I could joust with you all day, but here's
the reality of our situation.
She's illegal. She's removable.
And I intend to have Immigration and Customs Enforcement
remove her to ensure the safety of the American people.
Just like that?
You would uproot a 15-year-old American teenager who
came to this country when she was 3 years old?
Who doesn't speak Bangla, at least not with any fluency.
And based on the most circumstantial of evidence,
you would exile her to a Third World garbage dump
that to her might as well be another planet?
That's exactly what I'm going to do, counselor.
What about the rest of the family?
The two younger siblings are American citizens.
Yes, they're American citizens, and they're shit out of luck.
Unless...
Have you got company?
No.
Are you looking for some?
I'm not being funny, all right, Claire.
But I... I just want to know why some INS
guy would commit fraud for you.
- It's not like you're famous enough to get that kind of visa.
- All right.
No, I'm only saying.
I only know 'cause I tried.
Well, they don't call it the INS anymore.
Gavin?
Come on.
I always thought I'd have to marry an American guy.
That's why I didn't see any point in us, you know?
But I don't have to do that now.
I don't have to marry an American guy.
I can be with the guy that I'm into.
This changes everything for us.
You know?
I just, uh...
I just want to know why he's taking all that risk for you.
- You know?
- Oh.
Are you paying him?
- Where'd you even get the case worker?
- Oh, baby.
- Are you paying him?
-No.
It... Don't go there, baby.
Oh, come on, Claire.
How are you paying him?
Well... Come back.
No. How are you paying him, Claire?
How are you paying him?
No. No.
You are fucking kidding me.
I am such a fucking idiot.
You are fuck... Are you serious?
Baby, I want to be with you, baby.
You know I want to be with you.
Were you with him today?
- Please don't do this.
- Were you with him today?
- Baby, please don't do this.
- Just tell me. Were you with him today?
Was he inside of you today?
Were you with him today?
Oh, fuck, fuck, fuck. How many times?
How many times, Claire?
I just want to know.
I just want to know how fucked you have to get
to get a fucking green card!
Fuck!
Um...
as often as he wants.
It's only for two months, and then I never have to see him again.
And I never have to worry about being
deported or being narced on.
I can just...
Hey!
Easy. Easy.
Immigration!
Mireya?
- Hey, hold her!
- Mireya?
Lo siento. Lo siento.
Thanks.
I'm sorry. You have very few options,
none of them favorable to your situation.
You may request voluntary departure as an entire family
and leave the United States immediately.
Or you may choose to fight the matter,
which inevitably would lead to deportation.
There is a third option.
And as painful as it is,
I am required to present it to you.
One of you could choose voluntary departure
and leave with Taslima,
and one of you could remain in the U.S. with Jahanara and Abul.
How is that possible?
Special Agent Phadkar has intimated to me that
if we were to choose that course of action,
Immigration would not seek out the remaining parent,
provided they kept a low profile.
There is something else you should understand.
Whichever of you remains, if you choose that,
if you try to see Taslima before she leaves,
you would be taking a really big risk.
In all likelihood, she will be escorted by Immigration
agents all the way to her departure gate.
All right, girls.
Come on! Lights out.
- Under the covers.
- Lights out in two minutes.
Vamanos, María.
You look like you need a friend.
Are you waiting for your mommy to come get you, too?
Yeah.
Yeah, I am.
When is she coming?
Any day now.
Do you know any good stories?
I know a lot of good stories.
All right, girls. Lights out!
- Come here, and I'll tell you all the best ones.
- Time for bed!
And how could you disbelieve while to you were
being recited the verses of Allah.
Hey, Chin.
- Good morning.
- Black suit.
This is clean and press.
You gotta get the smell out of it.
- Hospital, hmm?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Uh, better not forget this.
Very nice.
Hey, can we do this now or what, huh?
I'm leaving her.
Okay.
We won't have to skulk around anymore.
Skulking's fine with me.
I'm not exactly proud of this arrangement.
I don't want an arrangement.
- Cole...
- Just listen to me.
I know this started in a fucked-up place.
And that you are not here on your own volition.
And that there's a...
there's a good chance I probably make your skin crawl.
I just want us to start over again.
I wouldn't say who I was.
I wouldn't put any kind of scare in you.
- Just ask you out for a cup of coffee.
- I'm not looking to renegotiate.
- You're not hearing me.
- No.
You're not hearing me.
This is what you need to understand, okay?
When I come into one of these fleabag rooms,
I switch off.
You might as well be making it with a rubber fuck doll,
because she'd be giving you more emotion
than you'd ever get from me.
When I get home,
I'm an hour in the shower, getting clean of you.
That is the extent of it. That is as real as it
is ever going to get between us.
Is that clear enough...
for you?
Hmm?
So you want to do this now or what?
You won't hear from me again.
And your green card will be in the mail.
Good luck, Claire.
Hamid.
How are you doing?
Hey, listen,
you left your jacket in the car on the way back from the morgue.
You were complaining about the smell,
so I took it to the dry cleaners.
You can pick it up any time.
That wasn't necessary, but thanks.
This fell out of the pocket at the cleaners.
I was wondering why it wasn't in her personal effects envelope.
She broke it a few days ago.
I said I'd get it fixed.
Repaired.
I got a friend with a shop on Western, and...
Thanks for coming, Max.
Gavin Kossef?
Gavin Kossef!
Uh, yeah.
I have to be honest with you, Mr. Kossef.
I don't see much experience here as a religious worker.
You're not an ordained rabbi, are you?
Uh, no, no, I'm not.
But you know, I've spent many years devoted to my faith.
Uh, I grew up in a religious family,
I attended services regularly.
I was bar mitzvahed.
- I've taken Jewish leadership courses...
- I'm still not sure that qualifies you.
You know, I honor my religion daily. And...
You know, in the Jewish school where I teach,
I lead the class in prayers.
We discuss Bible stories.
And you've been working at this school illegally, right?
Yes, l... I have.
- Yeah. But I've admitted to that.
- You can read the language?
Hebrew, right?
Yes.
And what about the prayers? You can, uh...
You can recite the important prayers of your faith?
You can do that, right?
Uh, yes. Yes.
I can do the prayer for wine, um, the prayer for bread...
Excuse me just a moment.
Shit.
Fuck.
Please come in.
Close the door right behind you.
Mr. Kossef, this is Rabbi Yoffie.
Uh, Rabbi.
Ordinarily, I'd file a request for evidence.
But something tells me this approach will prove more expedient.
I'd like Mr. Kossef to recite a prayer to substantiate his
knowledge of the Jewish teachings above that of a layman's.
If you could suggest something and authenticate
his response, I'd greatly appreciate it, Rabbi.
You may recite the Mourner's Kaddish, no?
The Mourner's Kaddish?
Nu?
Uh, yes. Yeah.
Uh...
Oh, sir It's a tradition that you cover your head.
If you just put your hands on your head like that.
Right?
Um... like that.
Yeah.
Amen.
Very nice.
Very moving.
You should sing in my services sometimes.
Oh, l... I would love to.
Thank you very much, Rabbi.
We'll be with you shortly.
Thank you.
Well, can't argue with that.
Rabbi?
I wasn't kidding about the voice.
I expect you tomorrow morning, Temple Beth Shalom.
About the rest, we can teach you.
I don't want to leave Jah and Abul.
When will I ever see them again?
Or Papa?
He wants to be able to say goodbye to you,
but what if he was to come here today?
They would arrest him and deport him as well.
And then Jah and Abul will have to leave as well.
I don't care!
Why can't we all go?
Why do they get to stay?
Because they were born here.
And if they stay and finish school, they have more opportunities.
And I don't
because my life is shit now.
I'm sorry. We're out of time.
Mommy!
Mommy, please!
Please!
Please don't leave me, Mommy!
Come, my sweets.
Say goodbye to your sister.
You won't be seeing her for a long time.
Please, I need the room for the next visit.
Did Homicide see these tapes?
No. They figured it was gang-related,
so they only looked at the night of the murder.
Slow down. Slow down.
That's them.
Stop.
That's the girl.
Back up a little bit.
This car that just pulled in here.
Move in on there.
Can't make anybody.
Let's put another tape in.
Roll on down.
Slow it up. That's them.
Stop.
Well, I'll be damned.
There he is again.
- Can you go in on the license plate?
- Sure.
2SAM564
Let's go to the next day.
There they are, coming out.
Back up a little bit.
Go in on it.
Same car.
It's the same goddamn car.
Let me run that.
Another, please.
Last call, pal.
- Hey, Yong. You ready to pop your cherry, bitch?
- Fuckin' balls, man! Come on!
Come on, you fuckin' pussy!
Get your fuckin' hands up!
Move, motherfucker! You, too, bitch!
Move it! Come on!
Stand the fuck down, you fucking cunt!
Open the fucking door!
Don't you fucking dick me, old man!
Open the fucking door now!
Open the fucking door!
You making big mistake.
You have no idea who money belongs to.
If I give to you, I die anyway.
Get the fuck back up, motherfucker!
Get the fuck back up!
Shut up!
What the fuck?
What'd you go and do that for?
We weren't supposed to hurt anyone, Seung!
That's it! Search him! Find the key!
Move, bitch! Shut the fuck up!
Shut the fuck up! Get the fuck up!
- Get the fuck up!
- Move!
Yeah, blow her fucking head off if she tries anything!
Let's go!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
- Where's the key?
- Right, which fucking key?
- Which key? Which key?
- I don't know!
Which fucking key, bitch?
Which key?
Which fucking key?
Fuck it. We're all in...
Put it down, man. I'll do it. I swear!
You'll do her?
Where the fuck did you learn to talk like that, huh?
You get that on some American cop show
while you're growing up in Seoul?
I'm not from fucking Seoul.
I'm from...
Hey. How old were you when you came over?
You still got an accent.
- I'm gonna say maybe 11, 12 years old.
- I don't give a shit!
I'm gonna blow this bag's head off if
you don't put down your gun!
Uh-huh. You still on the green card?
I'm American citizen, raghead!
My whole family just got naturalized!
We're doing all ceremony shit tomorrow!
Oh, tomorrow?
Hey. You haven't taken your oath yet.
That means you're not a citizen.
Not until you take the oath.
And I don't see how the fuck that's
gonna happen now, you know?
You're either gonna die here, or you're going away for murder.
You have done your parents proud.
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
They told me no one get hurt.
I didn't kill anyone!
What am I supposed to do?
I don't know what to fucking do!
- How many in your family?
- Why do you keep asking about my family, Huh?
They're not here now, are they?
How many in your family?
My parents.
My younger brother and sister.
My sister was born here.
Well, tomorrow was supposed to be a special day.
And you shit on it for your whole family.
I've been through it.
It was the most spiritual moment of my life.
You know, you're standing there,
looking around you at all these people from everywhere.
Countries you can't even pronounce, you didn't even know existed.
And they're happy.
They're elated to be there
because it's their choice.
You wouldn't be here right now,
in this mess you're in,
if you could ever appreciate the awe you'd feel in that moment.
The worthiness of the journey.
So,
when you're standing there tomorrow, in your new suit
and tie, I want you to look around.
Okay? Look at those faces.
And understand the sublime promise of this moment.
What the fuck, man.
I'm not gonna be there.
You said it yourself.
Stop messing with my head.
All right. The way to end this,
my friend, is for you to put down your gun.
- Now I'm gonna put mine...
- What the fuck!
What the fuck are you doing?
- What the fuck...
- Now you put down your gun.
Let go of that woman.
You go in that back room.
And you take the surveillance tapes out of the system. Okay?
And you keep on walking.
You're fucking with me.
Stop fucking with me!
You think I'm some jackoff? Huh?
I think you made a mistake, and you will never
make a mistake like this again.
LAPD! Put your hands up!
Get 'em up!
Relax.
Situation's under control.
Help me out here.
You're saying there were four of them,
but the owner's wife is positive there were five.
She says you let one of them walk.
She also says you let him take the surveillance tapes with him.
She's confused. She had her head down most of the time.
Hey, I killed four of them.
Why would I let one go?
I look crazy to you?
I can tell you how many there were.
There were only four. She's mistaken.
This man, he saved our lives.
There were four.
The witness has corroborated it.
They must have been lax in surveillance.
Probably just covering up for insurance purposes.
Hamid. Where the fuck are you?
I need to talk to you as soon as possible.
Give me a call as soon as you get this message Immediately.
I don't care what time it is.
One message.
Max, it's Kevin.
Listen, call me when you can.
Just a heads up.
LAPD contacted me a few minutes ago.
Apparently, Hamid was involved in a
shootout tonight in Koreatown.
Don't worry. He's fine, but I'm heading over
to the crime scene now to check things out.
Try me on my cell.
End of messages.
"I'm not interested in you. I'm not interested.
I'm not interested in you.
For one, you're too old for me."
Miss Shepard, I'm Special Agent Ludwig with
ICE's Document and Benefit fraud unit.
This is my partner, Special Agent Howell.
May we have a word with you inside, please?
We discovered these and quite a few others when we
performed a search of Javier Pedraza's apartment.
I didn't, um, use these.
I didn't go back for them.
- So you can't, um...
- You see what's interesting, Miss Shepard,
is we ran a check on your name.
A Claire Shepard arrived on a B2 visitor's visa seven months ago.
And then just two days ago, she has her status adjusted to
an EB-1 green card for persons of extraordinary ability.
According to the Internet Movie Database, the only
Claire Shepard that matches your spelling,
age, and place of birth, has two credits on
little-known Aussie TV shows.
Walk-on roles.
She hasn't won any national or international awards.
Which is something the adjudicator who handled your
case would have to have been aware of.
And yet he approved you for an EB-1.
Miss Shepard.
We'd like you to tell us about your relationship with
Center Adjudications Officer Cole Frankel.
Congratulations, McGill.
Mr. Frankel.
Special Agents Poulson and Womack. OIG.
We have a warrant for your arrest.
What is this, a joke?
I take it you're familiar with Claire Shepard.
She just traded you for voluntary departure.
Turn around, please.
Hands behind your back.
Do you have to do this?
Do you have to cuff me?
Yeah, I'm afraid we do.
What the hell is this?
Cole, where are you go... where...
what's going on?
Ma'am, your husband is under arrest for immigration fraud.
Cole.
Good morning, everyone.
My name is Judge Leslie Freeman, of the Federal District Court.
And it is my great pleasure to welcome you here today.
All of you seated here share one thing in common.
You have all chosen, of your own free will,
to become citizens of this great nation.
For many of you, the road to this joyous moment
has been fraught with hardship and sacrifice.
It is incumbent upon me to remind you of your
newfound responsibilities as citizens,
and also to remind you that an American citizenship
is not a guarantee of success
but rather the promise of opportunities.
Unlimited opportunities.
It has always been my contention that
America is a welcoming nation,
a country that accepts every new citizen
with an embrace of good faith.
You have endless credit to pursue your hopes and dreams,
as long as you honor the rules and laws of our society.
I myself am a first-generation American.
- I guess I called it right.
- Max?
Well, he's gotta put the family first.
Ain't that right, Hamid?
You know what I'm talking about.
- Do we have to do this right now?
- Yes, God damn it. Right now.
An innocent... yes, innocent young woman was brutally
murdered 'cause she flashed a little tit
on occasion, got it on with a married man,
tried to live her life outside your goddamn family.
She was your sister.
She deserved better than that from you.
In this country, we don't abide by that shit.
We got a name for it. Murder.
Cold-blooded murder.
And you and Farid are going down for it.
Will our new citizens please stand?
Raise your right hand
and join me in reciting the Oath of Allegiance.
I hereby declare on oath...
I've got the surveillance tapes from the motel.
From the day before.
From last week.
I.D.'d Farid's Beemer.
He was watching her, reporting back to you,
waiting for you to take action.
I begged him, Max, to leave it alone,
but he was being pressured by our father.
We both were.
He poisoned Farid's mind with this talk about the
shame that we brought on our family,
because of her. But he never...
he never intended for this to happen.
Only that we would teach her a lesson.
We were supposed to catch them in the
act and beat them like dogs.
My father wanted Zahra humiliated,
- brought in line.
- Congratulations to all you citizens.
I wanted no part of it.
I thought if I just turned my back,
it would all go away.
And now will you please stand and place
your right hand over your heart
as we listen to Phil Perry sing our National Anthem.
¶ Oh say ¶
¶ Can you see ¶
¶ By the dawn's ¶
¶ early light ¶
He arrived at my apartment that night.
After he...
Help me, Hamid.
Please, God, help me.
How did you get this?
Where's Zahra?
- I only wanted to scare her.
- What are you talking about?
I couldn't stand it anymore.
- Her seeing a degenerate fucking beaner.
- What did you do, Farid?
I only wanted to get in his face a little bit.
You have to take this.
You're a cop. You know how to do that kind of stuff.
- What did you do, Farid?
- I looked in the door.
They were doing it like animals.
Oh, shit!
What the fuck are you doing?
Get out of here!
- What the fuck is this shit?
- What's your fucking problem?
What did you do to our sister?
Tell me what you did!
She's my girl, man.
She's my girl. Don't be stupid.
Put the fucking gun down.
Get the fuck outta here, man!
¶ In air ¶
¶ Gave proof ¶
¶ Through this night ¶
You should have come to me, God damn it.
I was ashamed.
Ashamed of myself.
My family.
Better get yourself a good criminal attorney, Counselor.
You're gonna need one.
¶... star-spangled ¶
¶ Banner yet wave ¶
¶ For the land of the free ¶
Running out on our National Anthem.
Now, that's just plain disrespectful.
¶ And the home ¶
¶ Of the ¶
¶ Brave ¶
Farid Baraheri, you are under arrest for the murder
of your sister, Zahra Baraheri,
and Javier Pedraza.
Congratulations to all our new citizens.
Good luck to all of you.
820 Bravo. 75 approaching position reported by Foxtrot.
820 on 10-42 Delta.
Approximately eighth of a mile east of Ambush Alley.
Confirming a female victim.
Mexican national.
Approximate age, mid-20s.
Looks like she's been out here a couple of days.
I think she paid the wrong coyote to bring her across.
I copy. You are 10-42 Delta one eighth mile east of Ambush Alley.
I'll contact the PD and the coroner.
10-4, 820. I'm standing by at this location.
10-4, Bravo 75.
I'll also notify your FOS.
Guess who's going home today.
- All of my friends leave.
- Not today, sweetie.
Someone's come for you.
Uh-oh. All right.
When we get in there, it's gonna be a real clusterfuck, so
watch your ass.
You got it.
Here we go.
Wait a second.
Brogan.
Yeah, that was me.
You sure about that?
Mireya Sanchez.
What about the family? Have you...
Uh, do me a favor, will ya?
Hold off on that.
I'd like to take care of it myself.
I just want to do right by her.
Thanks. I'll be down as soon as I'm off shift.
God damn it, Max. We gotta roll, man.
Max! We gotta go!
Don't worry, Lieutenant.
You're not gonna miss anything.