One. Two. Three. Ah, that's equal.
One. Two. Three.
That's you... Ah...
What is this here?
Uncle Robert!
Making the invisible visible!
- Lunch is ready.
- Ah... Perfect!
Thank you, Aunty Margaret.
Ooh, what's going on here?
Making invisible things appear.
And then disappear.
Like sandwiches.
No one comes in.
Even if the building's on fire.
No one.
This shows that the Germans
are working night and day!
So if tension should rise
and if conflict -
As I have been saying for some time now,
it's not a question of 'if', Mr Tizard,
it's a question of 'when'.
I don't think that necessarily...
We have to work night and day
to build up our own reserves and weapons.
Even if we had enough money
we'd still never catch up.
We have to overtake them.
We have to build a death ray.
'A death ray'?
A ground-based weapon system
that focuses radio waves on enemy aircraft
and boils the pilots to death
in their cockpits in a matter of seconds.
Is such a thing possible?
I think these things, you pick
the right people, then they build it.
We can make anything happen.
Let's see who has got some ideas, sir.
I'll put out some feelers.
We'll have to disguise it somehow,
keep a lid on it.
No need to alarm anyone.
I will continue to put
pressure on the director
to let me set up a new committee
for aerial weapon development.
As we know, there is a
limited pot of money available
and the pacifists in the cabinet continue to...
- Sorry, Professor Lindemann...
I am afraid
that committee already exists...
- Excuse me?
- I'm sorry.
Who is chairing this committee?
I see.
I rather wish
I'd done the washing now.
I was told it was going to rain.
It does look like there's a change in the air.
- How can you tell?
Studying the clouds,
watching how they are moving,
barometric pressure...
Excuse me.
- Hello, Skip!
- Hi.
Sorry to disturb on your day off an' all...
We've had a telegram...
You asked the impossible.
By using radio waves only
could we raise the temperature
of eight pint glasses of water
to one hundred and five
degrees Fahrenheit?
You... did it?
Indeed.
We were forced to make one or two slight
alterations to the test conditions...
Very slight alterations.
Such as?
To achieve the desired outcome we reduced
the distance originally proposed.
And neither did you use radio waves.
Forgive me for being a little...
reductive here
but would it be fair to say that in your
experiment you essentially... boiled a kettle?
We failed in our objective...
But we stumbled across
something all together different!
By transmitting high-energy waves
we think it may be possible
to deafen laboratory rats.
Hello, yes, right,
I know what you are up to.
You're worried about the Germans.
Eight pints of water
equal eight pints of blood.
The distance and height
you specified - an aeroplane.
Ergo - you're wanting
some kind of a weapon
that will vaporise pilots
in their cockpits, aren't you?
Sorry!
I haven't slept since I received
your telegram, barely stopped work!
Goodness knows
what my wife must think!
I'm Robert Watson-Watt!
You told your wife about this?
Should I have?
Will you begin your
presentation, please?
The thing you propose doesn't work.
It never will work.
No one will ever get it to work.
Probably cause more damage
to the operator than the enemy.
So you're here to...?
Offer you something that will.
Now, I have an idea
for a listening device...
Listening devices don't work,
we've already built sound mirrors...
This isn't a sound mirror!
As Baldwin said,
'the bomber will always get through'.
How exciting would it be
to prove him wrong?
It's night-time, you're in the woods.
The enemy is out there somewhere
but you don't know exactly where
so you tie a length of fishing line...
between two trees...
and then you hang a bell off of it.
The enemy comes along, touches the line,
which rings the bell...
and we know where he is.
So we use fishing line and bells
to enable us to hear our enemies.
Jolly good.
Good. Thank you for your time, Mr...
But instead of trees we have antennae!
And if I may, thank you very much.
So we have radio antennae.
Now, they send out pulses
which are like a fishing line.
And then if something comes along
the waves will bounce off
and that rings the bell here
and then we can see them.
- He's an idiot.
- Perhaps.
But out of all the ideas
we've heard today...
His is the... least idiotic?
We have to do something.
Get him to give you
a field demonstration.
I thought you said
it would be a clear day?
That's weather for you!
Indeed.
We are going again!
It's not budging!
This... This is fine!
Come on. Let's get the equipment!
We've got forty minutes!
Who are you?
I'm his chief assistant.
So we are tuned in
on the 50 metre wavelength
waiting for 6Mhz transmission
from Daventry
with at least 10kw of power...
This man appears to be living
in cloud cuckoo land.
You have absolutely
no faith in him, have you?
He's building a washing line...
in the rain.
That is going to terrify the Luftwaffe.
We have two aerials...
one in front and one behind.
We have a BBC transmitter sending out...
Where's the transmitter?
Er, over there, in Daventry.
Now, that's sending out pulses
which get reflected down off an aircraft.
These pulses are in effect like our trap.
The fishing line in the woods.
Exactly!
So now we wait for something to hit it
and ring the bell, so to speak?
Yes.
Nothing.
The receiver is tuned
to Daventry, isn't it?
What are you doing?
Well, if...
Just leave it, will you!
Come on...
It's there.
It's... actually... there.
We saw you! We - saw - YOU!
I need to get out of this field
and find a telephone.
We didn't see it
till it was right on top of us.
But we saw it. We saw a plane.
Unfortunately we can't prove it.
The trace recorder failed.
Oh no.
Well, we'll just have to do it all over
again and hope it records next time.
It did work, didn't it?
I mean, we didn't imagine it? Did we?
Now we'll have to build
our own transmitter.
This was just a test.
There are a million and one
things against us, Rob.
And we will overcome them all.
Despite your lack of appropriate
qualifications I've spoken with the ministry.
And we have recognised
the success of the test.
And we would like to proceed
to the next stage of development.
In order to move forward, we require
you to sign the Official Secrets Act.
Thank you.
I trust the idiot boy is still
in the dark about all of this?
He's not an idiot.
He doesn't know what
you're doing though, does he?
No.
Good.
The fewer the better.
You only need to read that the penalty for even
the slightest deviation from secrecy is...
'To be hanged by the neck
until life is extinct'.
Indeed.
Rather a nice pen.
Keep it.
Please.
Someone's cheery!
Why, thank you!
I take it you had a good day?
An excellent day, Mag,
a thoroughly excellent day!
I just need to finish this.
I've been struggling with this
for quite some time.
Could you hold this
while I fasten this clip?
Can you hold this piece here?
Got it... Ok.
You genius!
Well, here's hoping.
SQ?
Tell me all about your excellent day.
You've barely uttered a word
about your work lately.
I'm sorry... I can't.
It's a secret.
A secret?
You're a weatherman!
Not just a weatherman.
Oh no, no... You fix broach clips too.
And bicycle chains.
The list is endless!
So, pray do tell, what's so secret?
Are we going to have a hot summer?
Should we panic-buy sun hats and the like?
I'm working for the Air Ministry.
No, I am.
No. I'm not joking, stop.
There's a threat
and I've been asked to help.
The Government have asked you?
Really?
- You're serious?
- Quite serious.
What exactly is this 'threat'?
I'm not allowed to say.
I'm sorry, Mag.
I'm sorry.
Good morning.
Morning, Professor.
You seem... jolly?
Perhaps I too should
whistle a happy tune?
After all, we have
nothing to worry about.
Aside from Hitler announcing conscription,
secretly practising war manoeuvres
and building aeroplanes.
Or perhaps the lightness of your mood
is related to some success
by your little committee?
We're... making progress.
With the death ray?
The system we're developing
may help us build a defence that...
Hitler will crush.
Yes, you're right,
you're absolutely right.
Good clay, Professor.
Certainly not, Professor.
Ooh.
Well, in that case it's a direct order.
Tell me who Tizard's committee have met.
That's classified.
Oh.
I am sorry. I apologise for my manner.
We're all working in
very difficult circumstances.
I feel...
May I trouble you for a glass of water?
Won't be a moment.
I am afraid our hands are tied.
How so?
The secret nature of the project
does prevent us from taking out
an advertisement in the Times.
Well you better tell Mr Tizard
that we're going to need more time.
There's only two of us here.
Close the door.
You detected a plane
a few hundred yards away in a field.
That won't protect Britain.
You need to think bigger.
I'm going to make some calls
to Oxford and Cambridge,
see who we can drum up.
No, I'd like to use men
from the weather lab.
My dear man, if we want this to work
we will require the very best
physicists and mathematicians
and we find those gentlemen
not at the weather lab
but at our oldest universities.
You don't think
Weathermen are good enough
because they don't wear
the right tie and all that?
Some of your lot don't
wear ties at all, do they?
Look, your little Weathermen friends
are all well and good
and I'm sure they're perfectly harmless
but they simply do not have the expertise
with this particular technology
our best professors do.
They also do what they're told.
Really?
Cavendish... Shall we?
Yes, er, Cambridge 2443, please.
The Cavendish Laboratory,
Cambridge University.
They'll do what they're told?
Is that Sir James Thomson?
Yes. Sorry to bother you, sir,
I'm calling from the Post Office.
Just a wee check on the line.
Do you happen to have a container
of water near to your telephone?
A sink perhaps?
Or maybe a bucket.
A fish tank! Yes, that will suffice.
Now, could you please
pop your telephone into it?
Yes, into the fish tank...
It's the only way we can fully ensure that your
equipment is compatible with the new system.
That's excellent, sir.
PHONE LINE HISSES
But most folk call me Taffy.
I don't know why.
Swansea's miles away from the River Taff.
I was born in Cockett, you see.
Perhaps as well they call me Taffy, eh?
I graduated from Swansea University
with first class Honours
erm, MSc the year after that and
completed my doctorate at King's College
and I've been at the station
in Slough ever since.
So you're an untried PhD student?
Can I ask you
will I be working for you or for him?
Oh, him.
In that case
thanks for the tie, Rob.
And er... I will take the post. Thanks.
Welcome to the team.
Are you sure these men
are the right ones for the job?
I'm positive.
We need free-thinkers,
rule breakers, men without ties.
These men will strive
to make this thing work.
KNOCKS
Higgy. Very pleased
you are going to join us.
Sorry, I knocked but, erm...
That's alright, come on in.
I'll pop back later,
if you still want me?
Mr Tizard is on his way over.
Since you won't listen to me, perhaps
you could discuss your 'team' with him?
Sorry, sir. Sorry.
I don't want to be fobbed off with a bunch
of Oxford academics I've never even met.
These are all people I've
worked with before, I trust them.
It's your team, I'm happy
for you to choose who you want.
Thank you.
Our intelligence says that
Hitler has built three thousand planes.
Passenger planes?
Two-seaters.
By the time the world wakes up to the noise
that's building in Germany it will be too late.
Your theories, experiments, tests,
are all well and good Robert
but you need to understand
that, very soon
German planes may well be
dropping bombs onto our homes.
There are others in the Ministry
who want to channel all our efforts
into striking Germany hard and fast.
There's opposition to what we're doing?
I've managed to get you a little funding
and a base to test and experiment.
I'm backing you every step of the way but
we don't yet know if this thing will work.
It Will.
It has to, Robert.
It has to.
Are you alright Uncle Robert?
What? Er, yes. Sorry.
I just fell asleep with my eyes open!
It's time I took you home.
I'll get my stuff.
You look tired.
I've got to go away for a while.
Work.
The secret thing?
You'll be away from home.
- For how long?
- I don't know.
As long as it takes me
to mess it up and get fired, I expect.
I'm sure that won't happen.
I'm not.
Is there anything I can do to help?
I don't think so.
You could visit.
Not at work of course,
but we could sneak away to a wee hotel.
We can be together,
every other weekend or so.
I'm your wife, this is our home.
You finish work at
the same time every day
you come home, we have dinner,
we listen to the wireless, we go to bed.
That's what we do,
that's who we are.
You are not a secret Government employee
and I am not some girl who visits hotels.
We'll be together, here,
when you finish your work.
Ok.
Professor?
You're in my office.
Tell me what Tizard and
this weatherman are up to.
Tell me.
They're researching a project.
That much I know.
These are my private papers.
What exactly is the project?
Rowe! What is the project?
It's weather related hocus-pocus.
All very dull.
Are your loyalties with me
or with Henry Tizard?
Are we not all on
the same side, Professor?
Hmm.
SINGING Oh, I do like to walk
along the prom prom prom
where the brass band play
tiddly-om-pom-pom.
Oh, I do like to be beside the seaside
I'll be beside myself with glee
and there's lots of girls beside
that I'd like to be besides
beside the seaside, beside the sea.
This can't be it.
I've stayed in worse.
I've lived in worse.
No. This can't be it.
Alright, lads, are we all ready?
- Oh, come on!
- Gently.
We've got to get the pulses strong enough
to detect further away.
We need more power.
We need our pulses to go further.
Pass us that, will you?
Equalise the power.
Keep your fingers crossed.
We're picking something up.
Our new transmitter is working!
I wouldn't call it new.
Our 'cobbled together
with bits of string' transmitter.
But it works!
Barely.
And we're detecting
a plane out there, right?
Estimated at a mile away.
A mile away, Mr Rowe!
I assume you know
this is not good enough?
Yes, it works, well done.
Now, let's pretend you've
located an enemy bomber.
One. Two.
And let's also pretend
it's headed in our direction.
A modern bomber flying at two hundred miles an
hour would cover the distance of a mile in...
what... twenty seconds?
You really think that is enough time
to pass on the information
and get our pilots airborne?
Nineteen. Twenty.
Exactly.
Mags!
I caught the train,
thought I'd surprise you.
How nice.
I struggled to find a little music on the
wireless with all the talk of Germany...
Yes.
It's a nice little place, isn't it?
The hotel.
Yes, it is.
Can you help me with this?
Right...
Your nephew's called round almost
every clay hoping you'd be back.
He's really missing you.
As am I.
S'why I had to come here.
To see you.
To be with you.
That's got it.
I'll just pop this away and then
we can spend some time together...
Yes, erm...
After I have done this...
Look, why don't you go downstairs
and order a spot of dinner...
What about you?
You can order for me.
You know what I like.
And, er... I'll be with you
the moment I've finished.
- And then...
- Yes.
They're sending some supper up for you.
Oh, sorry.
So am I.
This is the future.
Soup warmed with a
high-powered transmitter.
Can I have your attention, please?
Sorry, sir!
Now, we have shown we can detect a plane
when it is flying right overhead.
But we need to go much further.
How do we do this?
It's obvious we have to go
back to the drawing board...
This is the drawing board...
The first obstacle will be power.
We need more power
to transmit our pulses.
And more power allows us
to reach a higher frequency
higher frequency improves accuracy.
To increase frequency
and get the range we need
we need to increase power.
It's like inventing a chicken
and an egg at the same time.
But if we solve one the other will fall into
place! So concentrate on cracking power.
We'll need better valves.
We haven't got better valves.
But the ones we got aren't up to it,
they keep blowing.
You don't have to put
your hand up, Higgy. You just...
Sorry. The equipment,
if you don't mind me saying, sir...
it's stuff left over from the Stone Age. I
think we're going to struggle, that's all.
We should have been in the navy.
They're awash with cash, that lot.
Boatloads of equipment
that they'll never use!
Well, I'm sorry we haven't got
the funding we need
but if we show that this can work
then that will change.
We can't show that it'll work
without the better equipment.
Chicken and egg.
We have to be canny and clever.
It's up to us to prove that this can work.
No one else can.
So, I've got faith in you.
And if we work together,
as a team, we will do this!
Crack power and let's make
the invisible viisible.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Couldn't we have just
asked them for the equipment?
Oh, yes...
Excuse me, we hear you have some much larger
valves in your stores than we've got.
Please could we have some?
We'd have to fill requests in triplicate,
have them signed, countersigned...
We'd all be dead by the time
they approved it.
If they approved it.
Why have I got to do all the talking?
Nobody would believe a Welshy!
Or a Yorkie.
Yorkshire men are reliable,
unlike the Welsh.
Ridiculous.
We pronounce it 'ridiculous'.
I'm gonna belt you after this.
- Evening.
- Pass.
The ministry have contacted you four times
in the last week without acknowledgement...
We don't need a pass.
No, what we need...
No entry without a pass.
FAUX POSH We're here under
direct orders from the Ministry
to find listening equipment
planted by the German agents.
Stand in our way and I'll have you
arrested for treason, understood?
Thank you.
What's the paperwork?
Just some old radio
transmitter technical plans.
Oh.
This stuff is amazing!
We're not out of the woods yet.
Er, this paperwork...
- Ah, yes... Thank you.
- Err...
Ssh... Don't! Just don't!
Ok?
I think so.
Fingers crossed.
It's working!
What is?
Better valves. More power.
- New valves.
- New valves?
Aye, new valves
that arrived this morning.
From where?
From friends... in the navy.
The navy sent us these?
Well, they didn't really 'send' them.
No...
We had to pick them up.
Hey! We're building up to
350 kilowatts of peak power!
I wouldn't celebrate just yet.
Even with more efficient valves,
we're not getting the power output...
Have you not got it yet?
Have you not realised
what's at stake here?
Tizard and the committee
are coming at the end of the week
and we have to show progress...
Hey... We're flogging our guts out here.
It looks like it!
All day, everyday.
On something that'll
probably never work anyway!
If that's what you think,
you may as well go.
I mean it - go. Go on!
That applies to all of you!
Robert!
Robert Watson-Watt!
You're happy to talk aren't you,
but not as happy to listen!
That bunch of men back there
are working til they drop.
- D'you...
- No!
You don't get to speak here,
you've done enough talking - you listen!
You said we were working together
and we are - you're not!
We are, we're not 'your' team,
you're part of it!
And it's high time you rolled up
your sleeves and mucked in, instead of...
You think I'm not working?
You think I'm not rolling up my sleeves
and getting to work. I am!
Yeah, from upstairs maybe.
Behind closed doors,
away from the shop floor!
I'm dealing with everything else!
The ministry, Tizard, Rowe...
All this strife, they're trying to get me to
magic a giant rabbit out of a tiny wee hat!
They are going to come down here,
the ministry, and ask what is going on
and what progress we're making.
I am going mad with it
and I can't tell Margaret or anyone
because I am supposed to be in charge
and know what I'm doing!
Talk to me. Talk to me, Rob.
Look, we are all in the same boat.
You can't do this on your own,
you're part of a team.
Our team.
I'd like... to apologise to you,
to everybody.
And... I'm sorry.
Taff?
What is that game called?
Yes!
Catch it!
Jesus! He couldn't
catch a cold, that one.
Here y'are, Rob!
SINGING
Feed me now and ever more!
You trying to take my head off?
If I wanted to I would have done!
Oh yeah?
Yeah.
Howzat!
No. No.
Come on, Taffy! Back to the Valleys!
SINGING Heigh-Ho!
Come on!
I'm going to bloody kill you!
Lads! Lads!
Taff... Calm down.
Where are you gonna go?
We should start a sweep.
Come on!
Pace yourself, Taff!
Are you alright there, Taff?
What's he doing?
Taff!
Bell!
Our transmitter's five
thousand volts, yeah?
It produces 350kw of peak power.
Aye.
I have never understood cricket.
We can't exceed that.
Blows the valves.
Cos its constantly running.
It's in constant use!
But... if we do quick bursts
- like sprinting...
- Recover.
- Sprint...
The valves have time to recover...
Don't they?
Aye... Yes!
Let's get to it!
The PM will never spend
enough to catch up.
We have to invest all our resources
in building a death ray
and take the fight to them.
That's not going to happen while Tizard's
radio-locator is being considered.
We may be able to push
for our own defence committee.
Above Tizard?
Naturally.
Will Baldwin listen to you?
He will.
He certainly will
when you tell him what Tizard's merry
band of Weathermen are actually doing.
I have a man on the inside, Winston.
One of the weatherman's team.
A saboteur?
No, he simply reports back
what developments they have made.
And?
Precious few, Winston.
I'll call Baldwin.
And you keep talking to your mole.
Aargh! Bell's secret recipe.
I call it Problem Solver.
It sparks the mind, you see.
Ooh, it is strong, that!
It's got to be strong,
to keep the chill off.
You could just wear
normal clothes like me.
Take it off him.
No more for you!
Mr Rowe?
SINGING Row row row your boat...
Ssh!
SINGING Gently down the stream!
- Ssh!
Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily...
Mr Rowe, what are you doing here?
life is but a dream.
I've been sent to ensure that everything
will be in place for the demonstration.
What, may I ask, are you celebrating?
Life!
Er, progress Mr Rowe, progress!
You've built the thing and it works?
Er, not exactly...
But we're well on our way.
- Oh yes!
- Any minute now!
And the power.
We've, erm, solved the power.
Although we've still got
range to deal with.
So there's no improvement in
how far you can send your pulses?
There's quite a large team
coming up from Whitehall
who need convincing of the
worthiness of the radio locator.
If they don't have proof it works
they will pull the plug.
I think we should call it a night.
- Agreed.
- Gentlemen, good night.
- Taff!
- Come on, big boy.
You cannot let this Whitehall...
Here you go Rob.
I don't want it.
You cannot allow the Whitehall lot
to see this backstage nonsense
the strings, the smoke and mirrors.
They need to be dazzled with magic.
Right.
PHONE RINGS
Yes?
Robert. It's me.
What?
Oh... are you in
the middle of something?
Yes, erm... Is everything alright?
Yes, sorry. I won't keep you, I just
wanted to talk to you about the weekend.
The weekend?
You are still planning on
coming home? Aren't you?
I'm sorry, Mag. I can't.
Oh well...
Would you like me
to come to the hotel?
Look, I'm really tied up with work...
I don't think it's... erm...
I have got some very
important people coming down
to see a demonstration
of something I cannot do.
What should I do, Mags?
Look to the sky.
Isn't that what you always do,
when you're struggling...
Look to the sky, Robert.
I'd better go.
Yes...
Goodbye.
Bye.
I love you.
The ionosphere?
It's a layer of the earth's atmosphere -
a band of charged electrons, and...
- Yes, I know what it is.
- Oh.
Well, I named it, you know.
Yes, yes - what about it?
Well, we're going to use it.
Ok, imagine... Excuse me.
Imagine this is the ionosphere...
Right? And... Can you hold that?
And my head is the earth.
So instead of sending pulses
from the earth
that go up and across the earth.
We're sending pulses up from the earth
and bouncing them off the ionosphere
back to earth, ionosphere,
earth, ionosphere...
Bouncing makes our pulses go further.
Like skimming stones across water,
or water with a ceiling.
A swimming pool.
A swimming pool with a low ceiling.
Or throwing a bottle across wet grass,
or a ping-pong ball...
Anyway, that, in a nutshell,
is what we're planning to do today.
Send a pulse up to the ionosphere?
We did it yesterday. We bounced it
off the ionosphere sixty miles!
Sixty miles - can you imagine that?
And your pulse hit something?
You detected aircraft?
Not exactly, no.
Exactly?
- At all.
- Right.
But there may not
have been anything in the air
on that particular frequency
at a particular time.
Don't worry, I've arranged for an aeroplane
to be flying through our net today
so fingers crossed this works.
'Fingers crossed'?
Here you go.
Er, gentlemen.
Apologies for the condition of this hut.
Erm, we have built a new transmitter
which has given us
increased power and efficiency
and also increases our potential of
detecting aircraft from greater distances.
We've also used our extensive
knowledge of weather systems
to send a radio pulse further
than science could ever have imagined.
All of this on a shoestring budget.
So...
Where's the plane?
I don't know...
Any of your Oxbridge chums know
anything about weather systems?
God no!
But they do know how
to mix a decent martini.
This bunch of barbarians
think a martini is a Greek Island.
Funding. Always a tricky thing.
I understand the pressures but
its chicken... Chicken and egg.
Chicken and egg.
If we want more eggs,
we need more chickens.
Which is funding.
It's better not talking about
the chickens and the eggs.
So, this is quite a thing. Erm...
Just do something.
You do something!
Ok...
Erm... So...
Ah... Ah! Can you see this?
If I could just listen there.
Thank you, Higgy...
That is a bounce.
Yes, that... that is a bounce.
Thank you. That is a bounce!
We are detecting
a bounce of our pulse
that is bouncing of the ionosphere
and across the earth!
How many miles is that?
Er... Sixty miles...
Sixty miles. Sixty miles!
If that was an enemy aircraft, that would
give us about a 20-minute warning!
So, there, as you can see...
Help me out, lads!
Er, this is astonishing!
Please, come.
Do... Yes... Absolutely...
Higgy, punch it up on the oscilloscope will you?
- Come for a closer look.
'Punch it up?'
It's not the most attractive of set-ups
but there is a lot of substance,
a lot of sophistication.
AEROPLANE OVERHEAD
Thank you.
They all seemed suitably impressed
with your theatrics.
So we'll get the money?
Getting money for this project was hard
enough when MacDonald was Prime Minister.
And now Baldwin's PM...?
What's going on, Henry?
I mean, something's going on, otherwise
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
Churchill's clawing his way in
from the back benches.
He's persuaded the PM to let him
chair a new research group
and has installed his main advisor -
Professor Lindemann -
on a sub-committee, above us.
Lindemann wants to direct our funding
to build a strike force to hit Germany.
It's early days for Churchill
and Lindemann but they're waiting...
The slightest of hiccups,
they'll seize on it and shut us down.
PHONE RINGS
Hello?
Yes.
The Air Ministry were impressed?
Well, it would appear that Watson-Watt
has a cunning streak of his own...
Yes, thank you.
Keep me informed of
any further developments.
Sir.
Yesterday wasn't a success.
We proved we can bounce
a signal over long distances
but we failed to detect an aeroplane
flying right over our heads.
Why?
Calculation error?
Not a chance.
Range and target?
We've got something now!
What?
Aircraft.
Why couldn't we see this yesterday?
The equipment's not good enough.
It's the same as it was yesterday.
But now it's working.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
The Air Station has confirmed
our blip is one of their aircraft...
We've got a moving target
and it was seventeen miles away!
And we could tell where it's going
and how fast! We've gotta celebrate!
Before we get too
carried away with our success
we have to get this working
all the time, every time.
Whenever the Germans
fly their aeroplanes through our pulses.
That's the problem, right there, isn't it?
Our pulse works in
a range of seventeen miles
but we've got thousands of miles
of coastline, not just seventeen.
One station can't protect
the entire country.
Are you alright? You look awful.
We're ready for you.
The Nazis have passed a law
for 'the protection of German blood'.
It is the act of a megalomaniac!
A man who will wage war
and systematically destroy
everyone and everything in his path.
They are churning out planes
day and night, whilst you lot...
are sat with your thumbs up your arses
building a castle in the bloody sky!
That may or may not work.
And now, you tell us
that one castle is not enough.
I've been entrusted with
overseeing your operation.
It is my neck on the block here.
You've had money
to develop this thing
and now you would like a lot more money
to build a lot more things
that may or may not work.
You wouldn't try to protect our entire
country with just one castle, would you?
One castle...
Our enemies would side-step it,
they would go around it.
So what I am proposing, if I may...
are a series of castles
twenty miles apart,
stretched out along the coastline.
Now, each...
each castle sends out a fishing line
which individually is not that effective
but together it is like casting a net
all working together as a group
to identify enemy aircraft
pin-pointing where they are
and where they're heading.
This gives us time.
Time to prepare our men,
deploy our planes and build our defence.
I suggest we abandon this project
and channel our resources into attack.
We must build more bombers.
We'll never match the Luftwaffe
in terms of numbers!
I think we are all agreed
our resources are limited.
So limited, in fact, that some of your men
took it upon themselves
to steal equipment from a naval base.
Or were they just following your orders?
I know nothing about that.
Of course not.
I believe that we should use
our limited funds on defence.
Attack is the best form of defence!
People will die.
That's what happens in war!
People die!
You can't reasonably think to wage
a war where no one dies, Henry!
Given... recent history
and what each and every one of us
here in this room have witnessed
what would be so wrong in trying?
We are already building
as many more new planes
as the government will stomach.
We can try to build a few more still.
Or... we build this.
If this thing works
the planes we do have
will become much more effective.
It will give us a huge
advantage over the Germans.
A crucial advantage.
But what if it doesn't?
For the time being
we will invest our money,
our faith and our prayers
in your castles in the sky.
Now...
Go and see if you can get
the bloody thing to work.
Lindemann knew about the navy equipment.
HOW?
I don't know...
Careful with that, lads.
This is a step up...
Gentlemen, welcome to Bawdsey Manor!
We're starting again?
We have a whole new set of challenges.
We need to develop five stations.
A chain of stations stretching from here
all the way down to Sussex
covering the approach to London.
- Five stations?
- To begin with.
But we haven't got one
working consistently.
You know that one is not enough.
But it won't work!
Not unless all of the stations are in sync
communicating with each other,
sending out the same pulses.
Ok.
No. We're not ready for all that!
We've got to be.
People are depending on us -
not just Ministry people.
Our people. I mean our loved ones...
Hitler is creating a force
that will vastly outnumber ours...
If Britain is ever attacked
our system may be the only chance
of levelling the playing field.
This is real.
I mean this is very real.
And we few in this room may be
the only people in the country
who can do something about this.
Scale.
You gotta put scale up there.
And range. You think you've
solved range but you haven't.
And what happens if the aircraft
flies perpendicular to our pulses?
What if there is a formation
of small planes?
How do we identify the target if we have
spikey noise returns on the display?
Robert!
The first round is on me
but that's your lot.
I wasn't going to ask you that.
Just after you left, your wife called.
She said to wish you
a happy anniversary.
WIRELESS
by force, in such a way
as to threaten British Independence...
Come on!
It's going well!
Wahey, Taff!
You know what you have to do!
Come on, Taff! Here we go, come on!
Fellas... Keep it down!
The distribution of gas masks
began tonight in all areas.
The Home Office, in announcing this...
Where's Rob?
He's in the doghouse.
His wife called,
he missed their anniversary.
PHONE RINGS
Did you make it up to Margaret?
I don't know where she is.
I should be there,
at home, not here.
This is a waste of time.
Not for them, it's not.
Their first night out in weeks,
a couple of pints...
Not this here, tonight, all of it.
Rowe was right.
They should have professors
tasked to do this, not us.
I should be at home with Margaret
eating dinner, listening to
the wireless, going to bed...
Waiting for the bombs to drop?
We can't do this!
People will die because of us
and our bloody-minded pride
and our ineptitude and our stupidity!
This will not work!
Don't say this won't work!
You are not allowed to give up!
We are - you're not!
Something will shift, something will
happen and we'll get our answers.
Don't you ever give up.
We just don't have time.
It's like trying to catch
a shoal of fish with one line.
We need a net, a big net.
Multiple stations.
And that way we will solve range.
That will solve range.
We need to cover every inch of coastline.
Am I building two for now?
Then five.
If we can make two work.
Five will be easy?
Easy?
Easier...
You are bloody annoying, you know!
Margaret always says that.
Ta.
Something shifts. Something happens.
They've come to see
five stations working together.
And we only have two...
They don't know that.
Exactly.
You think this will work?
I hope so, sir.
All five stations?
There are five? Correct?
We will show you how two stations
communicating together
can detect planes at greater distances.
The planes for today's demonstration
are already in the air.
Due to the obvious
time constraints, gentlemen
we have decided to go for quality
rather than quantity.
All our energies are being thrown
into showing and demonstrating
the capabilities of this particular station,
linked to a second station just along the coast.
So I think the time is just about right.
Our two stations are now sending out
pulses across the coast, like so...
And waiting for an echo back
from something out there.
Something out there...
A formation of aircraft are right now
just turning towards us
and heading back in our direction.
They will be called the invading force -
bombers, gentlemen!
Which we shall detect,
heading our way
ready to drop their deadly cargo
upon our heads...
Just waiting here...
The invading force should
be due any minute.
AIRCRAFT OVERHEAD
Red leader, in position.
We've got 'em.
We've already heard them.
With our ears.
The 'invading Force'
have dropped their deadly cargo.
We are all dead.
As you can see, gentlemen
we're having a slight technical issue
with our first demonstration.
So if you'd like to avail yourselves
of the light refreshments we've laid on
and we'll commence with the second
demonstration in forty-five minutes.
Thank you.
Second demonstration?
I couldn't leave you hanging there,
I had to say something.
We're going to fail twice?
I've got a plan.
I've had concerns for some time
about this radio locator.
Yes of course, of course,
there are benefits
if it is proven to work
but as we've just seen...
We didn't have time to test
our beautiful new receiver
I don't think it works.
What are you doing?
Old faithful!
Shouldn't take long.
- Will it work?
- Honest answer?
How is it that Lindemann is
up to speed on everything we do?
He asked about the five stations,
straight away, the moment he arrived.
Lindemann has been up to speed
on every problem we have ever had.
And why is it that the first person to point
out the flaws in whatever we are doing...
always Higgy?
It's like he's looking for problems.
Do us a favour will you, lad?
Go fetch a roll of cable. Might as well
wire up the new one just in case.
- Covering all bases?
- Aye.
We know.
What?
That you've been spying on us.
I don't know what you're talking about.
It's treason.
They will hang you.
Lindemann said nothing would happen!
He said I had to do it
that the safety of the nation
depended on it!
You compromised the safety of the nation!
Rob. They're only in there.
I trusted you!
I want this to work as much as you.
No, you don't!
You go on about the problems,
how it's not going to work -
And if I hadn't we might not have found
the faults with it until it was too late!
I want to help you build it, Rob!
You report everything
back to Lindemann!
You promised the impossible.
Did you really think they'd just
leave you to get on with it?
What is going on?
We can all hear a row.
Did you put a spy in my camp?
Excuse me?
Is this just Lindemann
or are you in on it too?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
How much longer do you expect
the Air Chief Marshall to wait?
I'm sorry, sir.
We'll be with you in just a moment.
Two minutes.
Let us make this thing work!
NOT you!
Your time is over.
Goodbye.
Chaps?
I am in favour of anything
that helps us win this war.
Your failure helps no one.
If you'll excuse us, gentlemen
it's time we were
heading back to London.
We've got a trace.
Clear signal on visual display.
What range?
How far away are the aircraft?
Sixty three miles!
It's working?
It's working.
We can see them,
sixty three miles away.
Our sister base have
confirmed the sighting...
five aircraft sixty three miles out,
heading in our direction.
That gives us twenty one minutes
to scramble our aircraft and intercept!
Gentlemen - we have a castle in the sky.
Air Chief Marshall!
You must be very pleased?
I am indeed. Overwhelmed.
Thank you, Swingate, track 165.
Five aircraft heading north.
Congratulations!
Track 165. Range fifty eight
miles and closing.
Robert...
We are rather pleased
your radio-locator is working.
Despite your efforts
gathering information against us?
Your mole, Higgy?
We don't need him anymore.
Neither do I.
He's quite dispensable.
Our radio locator is imperfect,
as you know.
It's range is limited and unreliable
and the system's not yet
proven at low altitude.
We're working on that.
Germany is building new aeroplanes -
smaller, lighter aircraft
that can fly lower.
They might just get under your net.
You have to prepare
for such eventualities.
If you don't feel quite up to it,
we can call in the right people.
There's no shame in handing it over.
For the good of the country.
You've done your bit, Robert.
Have a think.
Robert?
We have to develop equipment that can
detect aircraft at lower altitudes.
Equipment that's smaller -
small enough to be mobile.
You've seen what we're working with -
it's the size of a kitchen.
We have to shrink it,
there's no other way.
We can't shrink it! Just look at
the size of the valves we're using!
We'll have to build smaller valves.
HOW?
I don't know yet.
PHONE RINGS
- Hello?
- Robert.
Is everything alright?
Everything's fine... yes...
I'm calling because I'm alone,
listening to the wireless
and AI Bowlly just came on
and the you not being here-ness
just hit me like a wave.
I'm listening to it.
You can hear it too?
Yes, my darling.
Dance with me.
Dance with you?
Yes, it'll feel like we're together again.
Come on, close your eyes and imagine.
You're a magician aren't you?
Make the invisible visible?
I remember dancing
like this with you once.
Our wedding.
All of them around us in a circle.
All of them there yet
none of them there, just you and me...
I need you to hold me, Robert.
I need you with me.
Come home.
Please.
When all of this is over,
when all your work is done.
Come home, Robert.
Yes, I promise Mags.
WIRELESS
The BBC will soon be broadcasting. ..
The world's first high-definition television
service. Their dual-system service...
EMI's new high frequency
405-line television system
and Baird's new 240-lined standard
will be transmitting directly
from London's Alexandra Palace
to your business and your customers.
Operator.
Oxford 143 please.
- Yes?
- Professor...
I need your help.
Yes.
What is this about?
I don't know.
Hello.
Now, last night...
I was thinking of walking away
handing the whole project over to
Lindemann and just going home.
And then I heard on the wireless
an advertisement
for these very expensive,
but wondrous televisions.
And...
they have engineered for television
very small valves.
Smaller valves means smaller equipment
and they have also been designed for a
higher frequency on a shorter wavelength
which means we'll be able to stop
planes flying underneath our net!
Take a look!
Don't drop it!
- 60MHz...
- Right, ok.
- That's a 100MHZ.
- Hold, hold...
130MHz.
We are now transmitting
at a frequency of 200MHz!
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes!
Twenty stations?
To begin with.
We'd best get started then.
I want to go home.
Not yet, Rob... Not yet.
NEVILLE CHAMBERLAIN
I have to tell you now
that no such undertaking
has been received.
And that, consequently,
this country is at war with Germany.
Mags!
I'm home!
Mags?
Mags.
Robert WW's arrived,
this is a restricted area.
It is our show now,
get rid of him, please.
You're still here?
Your work here is finished now, Robert.
You're free to go.
Yes, thank you, but I'd just like
to see the system works.
Ah! My pen, isn't it?
Now, if you wouldn't mind...
No. I do have to see
if the system actually works!
And I need you to leave.
German bomber group, 85 miles out.
South-southwest. Track 167 WN8554.
- Go ahead, Swingate...
- Roger...
Swingate have detected a group
of aircraft approaching the channel.
Track 167 are German.
Track 167 WN8554.
That is them, RAF Debden.
Scramble fighters to intercept.
Debden, Ops calling...
Red section, blue section scramble east.
New track WN1562.
6 Hurricanes heading east and climbing.
Branscombe calling Filter Operations.
Go ahead, Branscombe.
Roger. Track 167.
Branscombe have detected aircraft.
Make 167 a German bomber,
scramble fighters to intercept.
Darsham have picked up aircraft.
Leaving the French coast.
My new track is 171.
Red section. Blue section.
Enemy bombers heading towards Lowestoft.
Red leader. Maintain angels 18.
Your target 15 plus now at
one o'clock. And slightly below.
Red leader to red and blue section.
Bandits, one o'clock. Low, coming in fast.
Tally ho!