Um...
I'll take this one.
That one.
Oh, look.
This.
Oh, really?
This one's for me.
Oh, I want that, too.
I like those.
You do?
Oh, Maude,
isn't that stunning?
I'd rather have mink.
You would?
Mink is so every day.
I don't care.
We're wishing for
what we want, aren't we?
Yeah.
Well, I want mink.
Well, all right.
Have mink.
I want chinchilla.
What do you
spend on lunches?
Depends.
Can't you give me
an average?
Well, 65 cents.
(TALKING UNDER BREATH)
Four... Two...
65.
(UNDER BREATH)
65 times six, that's
3.90 a week. Hmm...
How about car fare?
30 cents a day.
(SPEAKING TO SELF)
Well, I'll have
to say the same,
it's the same...
Well, if you don't spend
more than a quarter
a day for lunch,
and if you don't wear
stockings, you don't
go to the movies,
unless somebody takes you,
you can go to school.
Oh, yes,
and you can't buy
any more magazines.
Gee, maybe
it isn't worth it.
Maybe you want to spend
the rest of your life
as a carhop, huh?
Oh, don't be a stoop.
Ooh, my feet
are just killing me.
Everything swells up
in the heat.
It isn't the heat,
it's the humidity...
It's the humidity, yeah.
Whose turn to wash?
Yours, I dry.
Well, I'll get started.
No, I just meant,
why couldn't you help me
get a modeling job now?
I've told you 10 times,
I don't want to
use my influence
'til you're ready,
and you won't be ready
'til you go to school.
According to this, I won't
need your old influence.
Hmm.
"Dorothy Dale places
all her graduates
in the finest positions."
Mmm, she looks
like a pretty nifty number.
MAXINE: Yeah.
I'll bet this was retouched.
You know, you're
not going just
to get a better job.
A charm school's like
college and finishing
school combined.
I can read, Maxine.
Well, all I can say is
without a social education,
you're never going
to meet a real man.
And what's the matter
with George?
He'll never be able
to buy you a mink coat.
"Girls," Dorothy Dale asks,
"What is your most
important asset?"
Answer, "Your smile.
Be charming."
Uh-hmm, be charming,
that's what I told you.
(SIGHS) Oh, dear,
I'd love to go back to
Denver with a mink coat
someday, Maxine.
Mmm-hmm.
Two mink coats,
one for my mother.
I guess it won't kill me
to have 25-cent lunches.
No. You still
have to wear
stockings anyway.
How long a course
should I take, Maxine?
Six weeks.
Gee,
wouldn't it be wonderful if...
If after I graduate, I start
working in the model...
And modeling in the store
like you for
a few weeks and...
And then one day,
in walks a handsome,
young millionaire.
Yeah. Wouldn't it
be wonderful?
And he's standing at the
perfume counter and...
And then suddenly
he turns around
and sees me.
And we don't say a word
for a long time and...
And then he says...
Will you start
drying the dishes?
(SIGHS)
Okay, but, it could happen.
Uh-hmm.
Dorothy Dale says,
"A charm school
girl's future
is unlimited.
"Once she leaves
our doors, she is ready
to meet anyone socially
"and ready
to hit her jackpot."
See?
Good evening,
Miss Chambers.
Good evening, Miss Blaine.
Good evening,
Miss Chambers.
Oh, Miss Eames...
About your tuition...
You know, each week
must be paid in advance.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Miss Chambers.
(RINGING)
Dorothy Dale
School of Charm.
Oh, yes, we'd be glad
to recommend a model.
All of our models
are highly qualified.
Yes, Mr. Lawrence,
she'll be there at 9:00.
Thank you.
(RECEIVER REPLACED)
Look, could I give
you five now and...
And the other five
when I come Thursday?
Thursday?
Thursday.
Certainly.
Miss Maude Eames,
five dollars.
Oh, would you mind
making that Leonora Eames?
I've changed it.
Not at all.
"Leonora."
"Leonora," that's charming!
Thank you.
It was a lovely luncheon,
Mrs. Burton.
"Burton."
"Bur-ton."
Thank you so much
for having me.
Pick up your bag.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Good afternoon.
Bravo that was
quite nice.
Cross your legs,
my dear.
Now, may we have
Miss Eames?
Yes, Miss Dale.
More confidence, my dear.
Speak out, full tones.
What is your favorite fur?
Mink.
Mine too.
Well, believe it
or not, this is
a beautiful mink coat.
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
WOMAN: Fourth floor,
cosmetics, jewelry,
perfume and furs.
Oh, Miss, just a minute.
Only 4995, plus tax.
Five thousand,
that's not too bad.
Do you like
the full back?
Oh, I adore it.
The skins are divine.
Simply heavenly.
Wally signed
his contract
with Metro yet?
No, not yet.
Come along, darling.
Better have
the old one glazed.
Oh, you're right.
I'd rather make
him buy me
a new bracelet anyway.
Of course
you would, darling.
Like it, darling?
Oh, I hope you're
not offended, because
I call everyone darling.
What a charming coat.
Uh, may I see the lining?
Only 4995, plus tax.
Plus tax, charming,
darling, charming.
I think we
haven't been working
here long, yes?
Yes.
Hold this a moment,
will you, darling?
I'm giving a party,
a lovely party
this weekend, on a yacht.
There. (BLOWS)
We go to Catalina.
No, thank you.
There'll be lots
of people, darling.
Fresh air, sunshine, and,
if you don't like it,
you can leave.
No, thanks.
Now, don't be a silly
bourgeois, darling.
You have work to do,
I have work to do. Now,
we can chat here for
hours but...
We would still
get to the same point,
wouldn't we?
The yacht belongs
to my business associate,
charming.
We leave from my place
at 6:30 on Friday.
Uh...
It will be divine, darling.
Nice relaxation.
Toodle-oo.
Did you get
an invitation?
I'm not going.
You're out
of your head.
9995, handmade from...
Sorry, just looking.
Don't you know
who the party's for?
Smith Ohlrig,
whoever that is.
Only the "Wall"
in Wall Street, dearie.
The little poodle
works for him.
Mmm-hmm?
Mmm-hmm.
9995,
handmade from...
Here, darling.
Those parties are
supposed to be terrific.
They'll have to do
without me.
Poor you.
Only 4995, plus tax.
I'm not going, Maxine.
How else do poor girls
like us get to meet
guys like Ohlrig?
It's just no use, Maxine.
I just... Look terrible.
I'm not going.
All in your head.
I'm not the type
for this dress and...
This zipper!
And I'm not
the type for the
yachting party either.
How do you know?
You've never
been on one.
That's the only
reason I wanted to go.
Just to find out
what it would be like,
but not with those characters.
Any man that goes
to a party like that
has just one idea,
and that's one idea
too many for me.
You can take care
of yourself.
I don't want to go to a
party where I have to worry
about taking care of myself.
Unzip me, please.
Well, it's up to you.
But the party is an
investment, Nora.
I know, I know,
I should think of security.
That's right.
(KNOCKING)
Hi.
Who is it?
Velma.
Velma, see?
And what is
security? Money.
Period.
Exclamation point.
Hello.
Hi.
Um, here's
the fur, girls,
and I'm sorry I'm
late, but I had to...
Oh, thanks, but...
Maybe you
ought to go home.
Oh, well...
I brought some gloves
in case you needed them.
Thanks.
They're stunning,
Velma, thanks a lot.
Well, I really don't
have to go yet...
I'll see you tomorrow.
What's the matter?
Please, Velma, I'll
talk to you tomorrow.
Can't I see how she goes
with my own wrap?
Go on now, Velma.
Well, have a good time
anyway, Honey!
Yeah, yeah.
And spill some
champagne on...
Yeah, goodbye.
Thanks a lot.
And if he has friend,
don't forget about me.
I'll look terrible
in that too.
Wait 'til I finish
pressing your coat.
Well, you can put this
around your shoulders
and it will look just fine.
Please don't
get mad, but it's...
It's just that...
Well, I resent
the whole setup.
Resent it?
Yes, right from the beginning
when that slimy little man
crawled up to me in the store
and wiggled
his eyebrows. It...
It just makes me feel cheap.
Let's face it.
Girls like us
can't pick the way
we meet like men like...
Men like Smith Ohlrig.
Why, you
should be grateful.
Well, I'm not.
Oh, no,
you want to keep
dreaming about little
ol' prince charming
on a golden horse.
You feel cheap.
Well, that's touching.
Now, let me tell you,
I'd be very glad,
believe me, to be
in your shoes.
For Pete's sake,
here you are with a chance
to meet some decent men.
Men that could take you out
of living in dump like this.
You...
Oh, you don't know
a break when you get it.
(WATER LAPPING)
(APPROACHING MOTOR)
(MOTOR CUTS)
Are you from
the Ohlrig yacht?
MAN: That's right.
Oh, thank goodness.
I thought they'd never send
somebody to pick me up.
They didn't send me.
Oh.
I have some business
to take care of.
Well, couldn't
you take me
to the yacht first?
Don't say yacht,
say boat.
Boat, then.
Couldn't you, please?
It's not a very good
party. In fact, it's one
of the dullest they've had.
Oh, I don't care,
I've got to get there.
Why?
Well, because...
Oh, I don't think that's
any of your concern.
Well, if you're in
such a hurry, why didn't
you come with the others?
Well, I couldn't
get off work in time.
I'm a model.
I phoned Mr. Kartos
before he arrived, but
he said he'd send a taxi
out and then somebody
would pick me up.
If you want to wait 'til
I finish my business,
I'll take you out.
You couldn't
take me now?
No.
Well, in that case
I'll just have to wait
'til you're ready then.
Come on.
Where?
Come drive
to the office with me.
Oh, I couldn't
do that.
Why not?
Well, in the first
place, I don't know
who you are,
except that you
say you're from
the Ohlrig yacht,
and in the second place,
I owe that taxi driver $6.50
which Mr. Kartos said...
I'll take care of him.
My name is Leonora Eames,
what's yours?
Smith Ohlrig.
MAN: Well, it can't be done
that way, Mr. Ohlrig,
but if you're
willing to spend...
SMITH OHLRIG: I do not make
money by throwing it away.
Good night.
Goodbye, Mr. Ohlrig.
Sorry, it had to be
so long, but I'm
trying to set up
a new organization here.
Oh, that's
perfectly all right,
I was having
a delightful catnap.
(SHIP HORN)
There's so many people
on the boat, do you mind
if we drive back to town?
Oh, not at all, Mr. Ohlrig.
I'd love to.
Well, that's fine.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't see what's so funny
about learning how to walk
with a book on your head.
I'm sorry.
What did you
say the name
of that place was?
Dorothy Dale
School of Charm.
(SNICKERS)
It's quite famous. It is!
I wish you wouldn't
drive so fast.
I like it, and I'm
a good driver.
I'm sure you are but...
Didn't your Charm
School teach you to be
agreeable to your escort?
Yes.
What else did
they teach you?
Oh, diction and make-up
and fencing.
Mr. Devough taught that.
And posture
and social usage.
Social what?
Usage, you know.
Conversation etiquette,
how to pour tea,
how to listen
to music, how to...
Please watch the road.
Mmm-hmm.
Where are you from?
Denver.
Family poor?
Yes.
How long have you
been in Los Angeles?
Almost five years.
Doing what?
Working.
Who paid...
Modeling.
Who paid for
your charm school?
I did.
How many weekend
yachting trips
have you been on?
None.
All right, how many
Hollywood parties then?
None.
Come on.
I haven't!
Why not?
Nobody else asked me.
There's some cigarettes
in the glove compartment,
light one for me.
What do you
know about me?
Oh, uh...
I know you're
from the east.
New York.
And I know you're
sort of a...
Of an
international something.
Well, that just about
describes it.
What else?
And you're rich.
How rich?
Oh, very rich.
(EXHALES)
What else?
Well, I know that
you've never been
married before.
And I'm not
going to be either.
Where are we?
At the house,
my house.
No.
Come in and have a drink.
Don't be a silly girl,
you knew you weren't
just taking a drive.
Please take me home,
Mr. Ohlrig.
Come on, don't you
think I like you?
Take me home.
Didn't the charm
school tell you
how to handle this?
I'm sorry.
I just want to go home.
Skip it.
OHLRIG: I took her home
and we said good night.
That happens three
or four more times
and then I dropped her.
Why?
They come a dime a dozen.
I thought from
what you said before that
she was sweeter
than most of the girls.
Psychoanalysts
and elephants,
they never forget.
Oh, I think this is
all pointless anyway.
Well, why did you
come here?
'Cause I don't like
getting upset so easily
and you're supposed
to be able to calm me.
I can, if you'll work
with me, not against me.
Let's go back to the girl.
Well, for your information,
she's after precisely the
same thing everyone's after,
my money.
Well, maybe the girl
feels that you just want
to play around with her.
Well, she's right if she
does. You don't think I
want to marry her, do you?
I certainly hope not.
If I persisted long enough,
I could get where I want.
I wish business
were as easy.
Yesterday, I had
to battle with some
grubby little man
from noon until
2:00 in the morning,
and I had one of those
idiotic attacks.
A heart attack?
Yes, and I go to
a specialist for that.
I think they're just
a nervous reaction.
About a year ago,
you wanted to buy
out a rubber company
and the owner didn't
want to sell.
So you had an attack.
The next one occurred
in that South American...
I get it.
I get the connection.
Whenever I can't
get what I want,
I have an attack,
is that your theory?
Yes. There's nothing
organically wrong
with your heart,
so why the attacks?
Well, let's consider whether
it's just a way of saying,
"I'm not all-powerful,
I'm weak,"
"take pity, give me
what I want."
I have these
attacks because
I have a bad heart,
but that's too
simple for you.
You have to find some
insane Freudian reason.
Heart attacks
because I want pity.
And what are some of
your other little gems?
I must destroy
everyone I can't own?
I'm afraid all anyone
wants is my money?
Well, it...
I'll never marry
because I'd only
be married for my money?
I didn't...
Don't say you
didn't say that
because you did,
admit it.
I only said that...
Well, you're
wrong, Doctor,
dead wrong. I am
going to get married.
I'm not afraid of anyone.
And what's more, you
want to know something?
(DIALING)
I'm going to
marry that girl.
You don't
believe me, do you?
Hello, Franzi?
We're taking a plane
to Yuma as soon as
you can get a hold of,
uh, Leonora...
Uh, what's her name?
Yes, Eames.
Why do you think?
I'm going to get married.
Sorry to cut off
a major source of
your income, Doctor,
but you won't
see me again.
It's up to you.
Completely.
And I do as I please.
Yes, that's why
you made your call.
I said I didn't think
you'd marry,
and so you've made
arrangements
to prove I'm wrong.
You don't really
want to marry this girl.
You've only done this
because you're angry at me,
and to prove
that no one has
authority over you.
A marriage like this
will only ruin
the girl, and you.
That's your opinion.
Beg pardon, Madam,
luncheon is ready.
Oh, thank you.
But, do you mean
he actually doesn't
get home until midnight?
Sometimes even later.
What do you do, wait up
and polish your jewelry?
Thank you.
Oh, they look so
good, I'll take two.
Well, I usually pick him
up at whatever warehouse
or office he's at.
Yes please. Warehouse?
Uh-huh. What then?
No, thank you.
What then? Oh, then
we drive to the beach
or some little joint.
Money and romance,
lucky girl.
No, thanks.
Yes, except that Franzi
or one of the other men
is always along.
Sounds cozy.
Well, he's just
there, I guess.
Altogether, we're
a very cozy couple.
What's the matter, Hon?
Oh, I just think that
Smith wishes that
he hadn't married me.
Oh, the minute
you get rich,
you get neurotic.
No, but I mean it.
I don't blame him.
I don't know how to
fit in to all of this
or how to behave.
Enjoy it, that's how.
And I'm sure he thinks
that I married him
for his money.
No comment.
You know I didn't.
I could never
do a thing like that.
You really love him,
don't you?
Yes.
May I have
the butter, please?
Now, look, so everything
isn't billing and cooing.
So you didn't have
a honeymoon, so you
don't see him alone.
When you get
married, you want...
So you think this
and he thinks that,
who cares?
Look at that house!
Look at the charge
account, look at us!
Lunch by
the swimming pool,
and look at this
silver and this glass,
look at this table.
Oh, honey, you're rich.
Yeah, rich but...
(SIGHS)
Things will be better
in New York.
The house is
on Long Island.
Same difference.
(PIANO PLAYING)
(HUMMING)
Franzi, will you
please stop playing?
(MUSIC STOPS)
(MUSIC STARTS)
FRANZI: Just this one,
darling, it's so lovely.
FRANZI: (HUMMING)
I wish I could
go to bed.
So do I.
It's almost 3:00, Franzi.
Tough, take a pill.
I've lived on pills
ever since I came east.
That's 10 months.
I won't anymore.
Then play with the
necklace he gave you
for your anniversary.
Yes,
instead of that honeymoon trip
we'll never take.
Instead of going to
Denver to see my family,
instead of having
dinner together,
spending time together,
and being together like
other married people.
No.
All he wants me to do
is sit here and wait until
he phones or comes home.
And I see him exactly
for one hour.
Two if I'm lucky.
FRANZI: Tough, you got
what you wanted, darling,
you're wearing it.
You mustn't expect
him to pick up your
handkerchief too.
Maybe money is
enough for you.
Of course, isn't it for you?
No.
Why else marry
a madman like that?
But he wasn't like this
before we were married.
He was a bachelor.
He was a human being.
Tough, buy yourself
a new hat.
Tough, darling, tough.
(SHOUTING)
Will you stop saying that?
Will you stop playing
that piano? Will you stop?
You know, you're
a greedy little
girl, darling,
and you're getting
greedier every day.
This part is divine.
(UNDER BREATH)
Greedy?
How dare you. Greedy?
I remember hearing
it at...
No!
(SLAPS)
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it, I'm...
It's all right.
I'm sorry.
It saves him
from getting hit.
(BEGINS PLAYING)
It's what I get paid for.
Stop playing.
(PLAYS FASTER)
Will you stop playing?
(SLAMS)
(CAR HORN BLARES)
Here he is, get ready.
Report for duty.
Where is it?
My comb, Franz.
It's all right.
I think I have it...
Here it is, darling.
I'm sorry, Franz.
No, it's all right.
I just...
Come right in, boys.
Just drop your
coats any place.
Good morning,
Mr. Ohlrig.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Leonora. Tired?
No.
You look done in.
You know where
the projection room is?
Sure, Mr. Ohlrig.
We'll start right away.
That's a movie
for my new project.
Make yourselves
comfortable, boys.
The picture will
be on in a minute.
Help yourselves
to a drink.
You got any food?
Well, there's
some sandwiches...
Nothing hot?
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
Anybody that wants
anything to eat,
just ask Mrs. Ohlrig.
Where do you
think you're going?
Well, I... I thought
you'd be alone.
There's so many men,
well, I think
I'll go to bed.
You're my wife,
and as my wife,
you're the hostess
in this house.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(INAUDIBLE)
OHLRIG: Wait 'til
the next shot,
the one after this.
Is this the ones
where you had the men
working late?
(LEONORA LAUGHING)
Lights. Turn on
the lights.
Tell them to hold screen,
we're not through yet.
FRANZI: Lights,
hold the screen,
we're not through yet.
What was
so funny, Leonora?
Nothing.
Well, I'm glad you can get
a laugh out of me, I'd just
like to know what it was.
I wasn't laughing
at you, Smith.
It wasn't anything
in the picture.
What was
so funny then?
I'm sorry, I'm afraid
it was something I said.
Something about me?
No.
Something private, then.
Perhaps if you watched
the picture, Leonora,
you wouldn't be so bored.
I'm not bored, Smith.
Thanks to Mr. Gentry.
Ohlrig, please...
Smith...
Good night, Gentry.
Now look, Ohlrig,
I think you're
making a mountain...
I'm no longer
interested in what
you think. Good night.
Start the picture.
FRANZI: Harry,
start the picture.
I can see now why they
install love seats in
movie balconies, Leonora.
But please try to
remember you're not
sitting there anymore.
Leonora, don't
leave this room!
(DOOR SLAMS)
Get out.
Get out, all of you.
I said all of you.
Of course.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Tell my wife
to come down.
Darling, watch out.
You might
get slapped this time.
Why don't you
turn around?
You know I'm here.
(SHOUTING)
Look at me!
Look at what
you bought!
Don't scream.
(YELLING)
Shall I call
your friends back
so you can insult
me again in front
of an audience?
You merely got
what you deserved.
(SHOUTING)
I wasn't doing a thing
and you know it.
You look ridiculous.
Yes, I am ridiculous,
you made
me ridiculous.
I don't think
you meant to,
I just think the
moment you married me
you were sorry.
You don't want me,
not really. You just
want me to want you.
My, aren't we sorry
for ourselves?
Do you want a divorce?
Oh, I get it.
It's all clear to me now.
You think you've been
married long enough to
deserve a big settlement.
No, I don't want
a divorce, but you do.
I don't, I want you.
Your trouble is
you want too much.
You want to marry rich,
you did.
I loved you!
This is the sort of thing
you tell yourself,
don't waste it on me.
I thought you
loved me, I thought
we could be happy.
You thought if you
had enough money,
you'd have everything.
Well, it's not
that easy.
The world is clammy
with people who think
that way and they sicken me.
I was born rich. My father
left me four million dollars,
but I didn't drink it away,
I didn't gamble it away,
I didn't marry it away.
I know what to do with it.
I've got exactly
22 and a half times
that much now,
and I'll have 50 times
that much before I die.
That's what everyone
wants, isn't it?
Well I've got it,
and I made it myself.
Every one of my corporations,
every single one
has a different staff,
a different lawyer,
a different accountant.
Not one of them
knows anything
about each other.
I run it all.
Each one has his place
and he stays there,
and why not?
They're well paid,
and that's what you've
got to learn, Leonora.
You're better paid
than any of them
and you've got your
place, this house.
And that's where
you'll stay.
But you want more,
don't you?
Yes, I want
more of you.
Are you bored?
Do you tire of money
so easily that
you're bored?
Oh, Smith,
I just meant that...
I can't, I...
Go away then, take a trip.
Go to Palm Beach,
Sun Valley, go anywhere,
you're rich.
You should anyway,
there's still some
of that charm school
paint sticking to you
that needs scrapping off.
Well, I guess that's
all there is to do.
Go away, I mean.
Do you think I should?
By all means.
Okay, I will.
Not to Palm Beach,
and not to Sun Valley.
I'm going to get a job.
How long will you be
waiting table or sweating
in the factory, Mrs. Ohlrig?
That depends on you.
Oh, I see.
Cold, tyrannical husband
is supposed to miss
his loving little wife
and beg her to
come back to their
million dollar cottage.
Well, I'm afraid
you've picked the
wrong husband, Leonora.
You've had more than
a year of being rich.
You like it.
I can't live
like this, Smith.
I can't!
(FADING FOOTSTEPS)
You'll be back.
(BALL KNOCKS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(CLATTERING)
(GLASS CLINKING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(BUZZING)
Leonora?
MAN:
This is the projectionist.
Is that all for tonight?
Yeah.
Are you all right,
Mr. Ohlrig?
Yes, I'm all right.
Go home.
(WHISTLING)
Are you waiting to be...
Kevin, will you
please be quite?
Are you waiting
to be examined?
No, to apply for the job.
Oh, thank heavens!
Well, the doctor will
see you in a minute,
he's busy right now.
And Kevin, please
stop that whistling!
I hope you're
looking for work
and not for a husband.
Oh, work, believe me.
And that's
what our last
receptionist said.
We had to fire
her the other day.
Miss Murray?
Yes, Doctor?
(WHISTLING)
Kevin, please
be quiet!
Emergency call.
Oh, and help Mrs. Dobroeh,
will you, Miss. Murray?
Yes, Doctor.
Oh, what a world.
Uh, Mrs. Dobroeh?
Mrs. Dobroeh?
I'm Mrs. Dobroeh.
Will you step into
the doctor's office?
I was on time.
Oh, yes, I know you were,
but he's been called
out on an emergency
but he'll be right
back, right back,
and I'll go and see
if the doctor can
see you now, my dear.
(WHISTLING)
Doctor?
(KNOCKING)
Dr. Quinada?
Kevin, please stop that!
Kevin.
Will you see Miss...
Miss, what is your name?
Eames.
Miss Eames
about that job?
Let's do it again.
Okay, but do it
with me this time.
(BOTH)
Here is the church,
here is the steeple.
Open the door...
No, open the door
like this.
That's right.
MAN: Miss Eames?
Oh, just a minute.
(BOTH)
And see all the people.
That's right, that's good.
(KEVIN BLOWS WHISTLE)
(WHISTLE)
Would you
come in, please?
Keep it down, Kevin.
Kevin, if you
don't be quiet,
I'll break your neck.
You have
a knack with kids.
I like them.
They come pretty
tough down here.
They did where
I came from, too.
You weren't born
under the elevators.
Neither were you.
No, a little closer
to Park Avenue,
but I could hear it.
You know what
the job is, Miss Eames?
Receptionist.
Yes, for Dr. Hoffman
and me.
He's an obstetrician,
I'm a pediatrician.
He brings children
into the world,
I try to keep them here.
I'm sure you
succeed, Doctor.
Well, I don't always.
It's easier to write
prescriptions than
to pay for them.
What experience
have you had?
Well, I was trained
to be a receptionist.
Where?
In Los Angeles,
the Dale School.
Dale School, huh?
Have you worked
in New York?
No.
I see. How long
have you been here?
Less than a year.
Well, that's a long time,
what have you been doing?
Well, I've been
living on Long Island...
Oh?
Yes, but I've got to make
some money now, Doctor.
I'm sure we have
a cup somewhere...
Oh, that's all right,
I've had my breakfast.
Where?
Yup.
Oh, in the automat.
(CHUCKLING)
I'll use that one.
I'd have I bet you'd
never been in an automat.
Oh, I was!
Now look, Miss Eames, this
job only pays 25 a week.
That's all right.
Well, the work
isn't tough, but
the hours are long.
I don't mind.
I've seen you somewhere.
Haven't been
in a hospital recently?
No.
You obviously
don't live down here.
No.
Do I look familiar?
Well, I must be wrong.
Look, you've got
a little smudge on
your cheek right here.
Oh, that's a beauty mark
over a mole.
Well, why cover it up?
There's nothing wrong
with a mole.
Miss Eames, can you
type and take dictation?
Yes, I can type, some.
I could brush up on it.
Where?
Well, I could go
to night school,
and study shorthand too.
On 25 a week?
Well, thank you
very much for
coming in, Miss...
Dr. Quinada,
I need the job.
So do many people.
Please, Dr. Quinada,
I've been job hunting
for two weeks.
I haven't got $25
to my name.
Forgive me,
you don't look it.
But it's true.
Honestly.
The work isn't
very hard, you said
yourself it wasn't,
and I can
answer telephones
and keep records.
And type?
I'll practice...
And take dictation?
Well, if you didn't
speak too quickly I could
take it down in longhand.
I write very fast
and I'm good with children.
Yes, you are,
and that's important.
And for 25 a week, well,
I'm sure it's hard
to get somebody
who's really perfect.
Well?
I'll give you a try.
Oh, thank you.
Well, could
you start now,
or would you like
to look around and
come in tomorrow, say?
Well, I might as well.
Start, I mean.
Okay.
If that's all right with you.
Sure, that's fine.
I'll get Miss Murray
to show you around.
I'll wait for her
out there.
All right.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye. I mean...
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Good afternoon, Dr. Quinada
and Dr. Hoffman's office.
Yes? Oh,
hello, Dr. Hoffman.
Will you hold on, please?
Any calls, Le?
Yes, there was one from...
Mrs. Palmer called,
and Mrs. Burnstein's
in your office
with Miss Murray.
Oh, thanks. Say, Le,
would you mind
calling her Burnstein?
She said she never knows
who you're talking about.
Oh, I'm sorry, Doctor.
(LAUGHING)
It's no tragedy,
these days, nobody knows
what anybody else's
talking about anyway.
What a world.
Well, Mrs. Burnstein,
seems like you're
looking fine today.
Hello? Yes...
DR. QUINADA: If you worried
more about her stomach
and less about this other
nonsense, the child
Yes, I will.
Would be a great
deal better for it.
Now, you take her home,
I don't want to hear
anymore about it.
Yes, Doctor, I will.
Goodbye.
Come on, girl,
pick your feet up.
DR. QUINADA: Now,
Mrs. Rudecki,
don't forget to be back here
at 7:30 with your husband.
Yes, doctor, I will.
Some doctor he is!
He's a very good doctor.
I think you better
come in, Miss Eames.
Yes, sir.
Do you often chat
with Mrs. Rudecki
and the other mothers?
No, not often.
Did you suggest to
Mrs. Rudecki that she give
Lorraine elocution lessons?
Yes.
Why?
Well, Mr. Rudecki has
a thick foreign accent,
and Mrs. Rudecki is
afraid that they might...
Yes, I know all
about that, but wasn't
it some other reason,
something about if
Lorraine learned to
speak well and walk well
and do half a dozen
other things well, she'd
end up by marrying well
and that that's
the most important
thing in a girl's life?
Isn't that
what you said?
Yes, I said that.
Now, look.
Your beliefs are your
own business until you
start pumping them
into my patients,
then they become
my business.
Where did you
get these ideas anyway?
Is it your burning
ambition to marry rich?
Well, is it?
(STAMMERING)
Is that all, Doctor?
No.
Do you want this
job permanently?
Yes.
Well, you act as though
it's a temporary
stopgap for you.
Your typing, your filing,
all your desk work haven't
improved one iota
in the two weeks
you've been here.
I'm sorry.
Well, why don't you
do something about it?
Now, I don't want
to irritate you
by bringing up
your personal
standards again,
but you're letting
them slop over
into your work, Leonora.
You're a receptionist
in a doctor's officer
on the East Side,
not a hostess
on Park Avenue.
The way you treat your
patients, that way you...
For Pete's sake,
look at that hairdo.
You're so fancy,
you're scaring
people away.
They may be poor,
but they're patients
and we want them.
(TEARFULLY)
Well, you can keep them.
If everything I do
is wrong, I might
as well quit.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Stupid.
What?
She's a stupid girl.
Who?
I criticized her work
so she got mad and quit.
Did she?
Her work was bad.
Was it?
The point is, she
isn't really stupid.
She could be quite good
if she wanted to be.
Well, put the ad
in the paper again,
unless you want to ask
her to come back.
I didn't fire her,
she quit.
I don't know
what's the matter
with that girl.
You don't suppose
there's anything
the matter with you.
Ridiculous.
(KNOCKING)
Yes, who is it?
Just a minute.
(SINGLE KNOCK)
May I come in?
May I sit down?
How did... How did
you know I was here?
I had you watched
from the day you left.
I know I wouldn't
hear from you.
I wanted to be sure
you were all right.
It's not a very nice
way, but it's the
only way I knew.
I guess everything turned
out as you predicted, Leonora.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I've missed you.
More than I thought
I could miss anyone.
Thanks.
I've come running
after you.
To beg you to come
back to me.
How's doctor...
What's his name,
Quinada?
All right.
He works you pretty hard,
doesn't he?
Not as hard
as he works himself.
Where does this go?
Any place.
It's too bad he isn't
more successful then.
He isn't just
interested in success.
I'm sorry.
That wasn't fair.
Truth is, I'm a little
jealous of him.
You don't have any
reason to be, as much
as I wish you did.
Why?
Because I'm glad
to see you
and I wish I weren't.
What are you looking for?
A cigarette.
I have one here.
Leonora.
It's no good, Smith.
I won't go back
to the way it was.
I don't want you to.
I was wrong.
I admit it.
No. Please, Smith, no.
It won't be that way
anymore, Leonora.
It won't.
We'll make a fresh start.
We'll make everything
just the way it ought
to have been.
I'm so used to having
my own way that...
It was hard for me
to come here.
But I missed you
and I wanted you
so much.
I missed all the things
we ought to have done,
like, being together,
finding new places,
having a honeymoon.
Let's go and wander
more, Leonora.
Let's start over again.
I can't see you
living in this
dirty, little room.
It's not dirty, Smith.
It's shabby.
It's awful.
Ragged.
Let's get out
of here, Leonora.
Well, I don't need anything.
We'll just take a drive
or have a cup of coffee.
I don't care.
I just can't talk
in this room.
I'll bring you back
the moment you ask me.
Is that a promise?
Yes.
Turn out the light.
(CLICKING)
Here?
No, the other side.
You really don't
like living here.
No one's poor
by choice.
It really isn't such
a bad room.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Not if you
haven't seen better.
Darling, good morning.
Good morning, sir.
Wait, may I relieve
you at this moment?
Oh, no.
I would like to serve
breakfast myself today.
Oh, no.
Just today.
I have a special reason.
You can trust me.
I've done this before.
Believe me.
(WHISTLING)
Good morning, darling.
Welcome home.
What are you
doing here, Franzi?
I know you would be
hungry so I brought
you a lovely breakfast.
Three eggs, darling.
I don't wanna get up yet.
But you must.
Smith told me
to wake you.
He did?
FRANZI: Yes.
We leave in an hour.
LEONORA: Who's we?
All of us, darling.
Smith, Tim, Charlie,
me, the whole crowd.
Where are we going?
On a great tour of every
Ohlrig plant in the country.
Publicity tour.
FRANZI: It'll be a lovely
vacation and I
certainly need one.
Franzi.
When did Smith decide
to make this trip?
Day before yesterday.
You got back just in time.
I always said you're
a smart little girl.
This is a lovely suit
and cap and just take
this with your mink.
Where is the mink?
They even buy...
(INAUDIBLE)
I'm through
with that coat.
What?
I'm through
with that coat.
Darling, this is an
expensive thing.
You can't afford, I mean...
I can.
Dr. Quinada's
office?
Miss Murray,
this is Leonora Eames.
I'll wait.
Don't be stupid, Leonora.
Take this away, please.
Look I told you,
all these once before.
Take it.
Darling, be a darling.
All right.
Some darlings never know
when they are well-off.
No, but give
them time, Franzi,
and they'll find out.
Dr. Quinada?
I'm very sorry
about yesterday
and I was wondering...
Yes, I'd like to come
back very much.
Yes, I'll be there
as soon as I can.
Come on.
Come on, Le, go home.
Beat it.
Here, for tomorrow
morning.
I wanna finish
sending these out,
the monthly bills.
Oh, why bother.
Nobody ever pays
the doctor, anyway.
(CHUCKLING)
Has Quinada left?
Uh-uh.
He hasn't come back
from the clinic yet.
Well, if he doesn't show
up by 9:00, you know
how to lock out.
Sure. Goodnight.
Goodnight, Le.
Uh...
Don't wait later
than 9:30, anyway.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Dr. Quinada's office.
No, not yet,
Mrs. Rudecki.
Yes, I did tell him, but...
Yes, I'll tell him again,
Mrs. Rudecki.
LEONORA: Yes.
Hello.
LEONORA: Hi.
LEONORA: Tired?
Beat.
Is this becoming
a habit?
Staying overtime?
Coffee will be ready
in a minute.
Take your coat off.
Mrs. Rudecki phoned
again for you
to come over.
I told her this morning
there was no sense
in my coming over.
Well, this is the 10th time
she's called which
is a new record for her.
You know what
I'd like to do
with Lorraine
next time she comes
into this office?
Cut off those
awful curls.
And you know how
she could cure that
stomach trouble of hers?
By sending her mother
to a good psychiatrist.
Any temperature?
No. She says it's normal,
but she claims
Lorraine's seeing double.
Seeing double?
LEONORA: Yes.
Miss Murray's gone,
isn't she?
LEONORA: Yes.
Le, grab a taxi
and get over
to the City Drugstore.
Okay.
You know where it is?
Yeah, I'll find it.
You have some money,
haven't you?
(CHUCKLING)
Sure.
Have this filled
and look me up at
the Rudecki's right away.
Okay.
And hurry.
Yeah.
(MOANING)
That light's a little
bright for her eyes.
Find something
to shade it with.
I'm afraid
it's botulism.
Botulism?
Yeah, that's a doctor's
fancy word for a very
bad kind of food poisoning.
(SPEAKING POLISH)
Mama means...
Will she get all right?
I don't know.
I think so, but
I don't know for sure.
You're so busy telling
me I'm sick,
but you haven't
got time to come
and see for yourself.
Can you just
keep quiet, please?
That canned meat that
she had this morning
must have been
the cause of the trouble.
Anyone else eat it?
(SPEAKING POLISH)
No.
Is there any left?
Kitchen window.
Why did you open
the can, you fool?
You were not
supposed to open.
(ARGUING)
I'll give her another
injection every six hours
until it takes effect.
If it takes effect.
It will.
Even when you
treat cases like
this immediately,
18% of those treated die.
I know all the statistics.
I'm a very good
textbook doctor.
What's the matter, Quinada?
I slipped up.
Just because Lorraine's
always had stomach trouble,
I assumed that's what
it was this time.
A doctor has no
right to assume.
Anyone can make
a mistake.
Not when it comes
to a kid's life.
I should have come
straight over this morning
instead of being such a...
What are you doing?
Well, you were shouting
a little and I didn't want
the Rudecki's to hear it.
Good idea.
You know, you might
just as well go home.
It's after 1:00.
No, no, I'll stay.
Okay.
LARRY: Well, I'll be back
here about noon.
To give her another
injection, all right?
Thank you, doctor.
Thank you.
Sleepy?
Uh-uh, not a bit.
I'm used to staying
up all night.
LARRY: You wait
'til about 9:00.
That's when it
catches up on you.
Aren't you cold?
No.
Why did you wear
that ridiculous coat?
Don't you wanna be warm?
I thought it was going
to rain yesterday.
You must be freezing.
How much would it cost
to buy you a warm coat?
Oh, no, please.
Now, look, Rudecki
has just paid me
for the last two months.
I don't need
an overcoat.
I got one.
Oh, it's very nice
of you but...
All right.
You go home
and get some sleep.
I'm going home to take
a bath, but I'm coming
back to work.
What do you think I am,
a Park Avenue hostess?
No, not a bit.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Good morning, Le.
Good morning.
Don't you ever go home?
DR. HOFFMAN: Come in.
DR. HOFFMAN: It's really
too early to be sure.
LEONORA: I know.
DR. HOFFMAN: Are you worried?
(CHUCKLING)
That's a silly question.
How long will
a lab report take?
Well, if you went over
there now yourself,
(SIGHING)
they'd probably
let you know first thing
tomorrow morning.
Can I just go?
I'll call and tell them
you're coming if you like.
Please.
I...
You won't say anything.
To Quinada?
Yes.
No.
(CHUCKLING)
It's none of my
business, Le, but don't
you think that you should?
I...
I couldn't.
DR. HOFFMAN: He's really
a marvelous fellow.
I know, but...
It's too much of a mess.
DR. HOFFMAN: Okay.
Anyway, thanks.
MISS MURRAY: I must say
you don't look it.
Look what?
Well, you've been up
all night.
Mrs. Rudecki just
phoned and told me
about the seizure.
Good morning, Doctor.
Good morning,
Miss Murray.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Mrs...
Where are you going?
I think I better get some
sleep. It's catching
up with me.
Le?
I know you'd
rather freeze, but...
Will you try it on?
It's not mink, but
it will keep you warm.
That's the main thing.
It fits.
It doesn't look bad.
Turn around.
Let's see the front.
Now, Leonora.
(SNIFFLING)
Don't do that.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
We still have
our date tonight?
(CLAPPING)
(PIANO PLAYING)
I was mad at you
that day.
Did I ever apologize
for bawling you
out so badly?
And what made
you think of that?
Was that because
of the way I talked
about marrying rich?
It always makes me
see red when
people talk that way.
My parents
made themselves
absolutely miserable
by having an exaggerated
idea about the importance
of money.
Got a light, sweetie?
Sure.
By the time I came along,
they'd lost most of it.
Muchas Gracias.
Your hair looks
good that way.
Thank you.
You look very lovely.
Is something
worrying you?
No, I'm very happy.
Go on about your parents.
Oh, they just wasted
their lives pretending
to be rich,
conniving and finagling,
never working, of course.
Thanks, sweetie.
Oh, thank you.
This isn't mine.
What?
Don't you want it?
No, thank you.
Well, muchas gracias.
I can't imagine you
pretending to be rich
or pretending anything.
Oh, I did for a while
until I pulled out of it.
Two more, sir?
No, we're fine.
Thank you.
Unless...
Oh, no.
Thank you.
Larry, was it
very difficult?
No.
That's because you
don't care about money.
One has got to care
about money
to a certain extent.
How else could I take
you out to the dinner
when I want to?
Well, I care more
about others things
like...
Doing the kind of work
that interests me.
Is that why you work
in the East Side?
Sure.
I can learn more
of there in one day
than I can learn any
place else in a month.
All right, sweetie.
Let's go.
I beg your pardon?
What?
Perfectly okay.
Buenas noches.
(CHUCKLING)
That's a wonderful
smile you've got.
Charming.
What?
Nothing.
I was just remembering
something.
I wish I could remember
where I saw you before.
I don't think
you ever did.
Didn't you ever
come into town
from Long Island?
No.
Hardly ever.
What were you
doing there?
Oh, I was sort of a paid
companion to somebody
who was very rich.
Let's dance.
All right.
I'm not very good.
Oh, we don't have to.
Oh, I'd like to
if you would.
I haven't danced in ages.
Perhaps, you'd rather not.
No, not unless
you would.
Well, I'm just as happy
sitting here, but I just...
Oh, so am I.
Oh, come on.
Let's dance.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Oh, I'm sorry.
I stepped on your foot.
You didn't.
(GIGGLING)
Good. It's probably
somebody else's.
This public dancing
is quite an invention.
You can get away with murder.
(GIGGLING)
I'm having
a wonderful time.
(CHUCKLING)
Oops.
(LAUGHING)
We ought to have
done this ages ago.
Why don't we go out
again on Saturday?
And then spend
Sunday together?
And Monday too.
Sure.
And Tuesday.
And we can go dancing
again Saturday night.
And then spend
Sunday again.
You know, it would be
much simpler
if we were married
and we wouldn't
have to make dates.
Did you hear
what I said?
Yes.
I was proposing.
You weren't.
Sure.
Why not?
Larry, I...
I want to marry you
more than anything
in the world but...
But?
Well, there's something
I have to straighten
out first.
Let's not talk about it.
Okay.
I'll propose again
tomorrow.
LARRY: What's new?
Brought in a nine-pounder
this afternoon. Boy.
LARRY: Congratulations.
It was a madhouse today.
DR. HOFFMAN: A rat race.
LARRY: Mrs. Cricket at the bar
swallowed a dime.
DR. HOFFMAN: (CHUCKLING)
No news from Leonora.
DR. HOFFMAN: Well, maybe
she isn't feeling well.
She'll be back tomorrow.
Yeah, I dropped by her place
on the way from hospital.
She's moved.
Gone.
Where to?
Long Island,
the landlady said.
(PIPE CLANKING)
You know, there's pipes
are on the brink again.
We ought to send
for the plumber.
What's the matter
with the landlord?
Ah, they'll never
catch him.
I was out with her last night.
Well, didn't she
say anything?
About leaving?
No.
You didn't criticize
her again?
No.
(CHUCKLING)
I proposed to her
as matter of fact.
I thought I'd run out
to Long Island.
Oh.
Well, Larry, was last night
the first time you went
out with her?
Yes.
Long Island?
Hmm...
I don't know.
I ended up pretty
silly anyway.
All I can get out of her
was that she was
a paid companion
to somebody rich.
(CHUCKLING)
Nice work if you
can get it.
(CHUCKLING)
I can just hear
the conversation.
"Good evening,
Mr. so and so.
I'm Dr. Quinada."
"Are you by any chance
keeping one of my
former employees,."
"A Miss Leonora Eames?"
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah. Yeah.
Well...
Why don't you
forget her?
LARRY: You think so?
Well, yeah.
LARRY: All right.
Good night.
DR. HOFFMAN: Good night,
Larry.
MAN: Well, it adds
up to be nothing more
Yes?
Than a windy
analysis which, uh...
I'll tell him.
SMITH: Which shows absolutely
no conception of the problem
in plain terms
of dollars and cents.
As to paragraph four,
this too is completely
ridiculous.
Yes.
If you want me
to invest one penny...
Who was that?
Dr. Quinada is calling
to see Miss Eames.
Who?
Miss Eames?
I'll get rid of him,
darling.
Get rid of yourself.
Send him in.
Of course, darling.
If you want me
to invest one penny,
you will do it my way
or not at all.
Sincerely yours.
That's all, gentlemen.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Ohlrig.
Good night,
Mr. Ohlrig.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
FRANZI: In here, please.
Good evening.
I'm Smith Ohlrig.
Would you like a drink?
Thank you.
Is Miss Eames here?
She'll be right down.
Champagne?
I'd rather have
something else
if you don't mind.
Scotch?
That'll be fine.
I might have known
you'd be good-looking.
Leonora was very
impressed with you.
I was very much
impressed with her.
She started from scratch
and learned to a good
job very quickly.
Soda?
Plain water, please.
Also, she's very
attractive.
That always helps.
Yes, it does.
I'm glad you and Leonora
are hitting it off
so well together.
There's nothing
like a little extra
curricular romance
after office hours,
is there, Doctor?
It's hardly any business
of yours, Mr. Ohlrig.
Just interested
in employer-employee
relationships.
After all, Leonora
was an employee of mine.
In a way, she still is.
How do you mean?
We're still married.
I always had a curious
feeling that I'd seen
Leonora before.
Now I know where.
In the newspapers.
A picture, right after
your wedding.
I better go.
I'm afraid I've
made a mistake.
I'm afraid you have.
Thank you.
(WHISPERING)
Larry!
Larry, meet
me outside.
Where?
In the garden
around the side.
(DOOR OPENING)
Larry!
Why didn't you say
anything to me?
How could you run
away like a child?
I tried to tell
you, Larry.
When?
Well, the very
first day, but I wanted
the job and I...
How could you sit
at that bar with me
and you say nothing?
(STUTTERING)
I just couldn't.
Did you know you were
gonna go back to him?
No, not then.
What you made
you do it?
I had to.
You said you loved me.
I do. I...
Then what is it?
Are you afraid of him?
No, I...
Then what?
Tell me.
I'm going to have a baby.
Le, listen.
Forget that I love you.
Larry...
No, no, I mean it.
Forget that I want you,
that I want to marry you.
But believe this.
You can't stay here.
You got to leave him.
I can't.
I'm not saying this just
because of how I feel.
I was with that man
for three minutes.
But I know
he's not normal.
He's dangerous.
You've got to get
out of here.
Larry, it's his baby.
So because of convention,
you'll let him destroy
you and your child?
No, I won't let him.
You will help.
Without meaning to,
you'll help!
You sat in my office
too many times
not to know
what happens to a child
whose parents
are messed up.
But I know what happens
to a child whose parents
haven't got anything.
That's why you came
back to him, isn't it?
No, I came back
for my baby, for his future.
I want security.
You want money.
Isn't that why
you married him?
No, no.
For security?
I thought I loved him.
You mean you made
yourself think that.
(SIGHING)
Don't.
You found out it
was wrong to marry
just for money,
so you had
to make yourself...
No.
You still got those
same ridiculous ideas.
Marry rich, live rich.
I didn't know
what to do.
You know what you want.
Yes, I want you, but I...
But you want your
child to be rich.
Well, make up
your mind, Leonora.
I'd be the last man
to say that anyone
can be secure without
money in this world,
but money alone
isn't security,
as you ought to know
it by now.
What should I do?
Tell me.
Grow up!
If you're still gonna
be wishing for mink coats
and houses like this...
I don't want you.
(CLICKING)
Trying to recapture
the feeling of
the East Side, Leonora?
Smith, we were...
I understood you
were such a moral
character, Doctor.
Not the type to make
passes at somebody
else's wife.
Of course, Leonora
doesn't surprise me.
That's about enough!
Now, look...
And stop clenching
your fists.
I would be only
too glad to take
a crack at you
but it wouldn't
settle a thing.
The only one of us who can
settle this is Leonora.
Smith, Larry was...
Don't try to act...
I'll tell you exactly
what's been going
on, Ohlrig.
I told Leonora that
I love her and I want
to marry her.
Did you bother
to tell him
about the child?
LARRY: Yes, and I warned
her that you'll ruin it.
You take a lot
for granted.
LARRY: Nothing.
I don't even want
Leonora until she decides
how important money
really is to her.
SMITH: Oh, I can answer
that without even...
It's not your answer
I'm interested in!
It's hers.
If you make up
your mind,
you can always call.
Whose child
are you having?
From the moment
I came back,
I've had to listen
to your filthy
insinuations.
Well not anymore.
Come down here, Leonora.
I said come down here.
You came back to get
a divorce, didn't you?
You wanted to divorce me
and live happily ever after
with him on my money.
I don't want your money.
But you do wanna
leave me, don't you?
Yes.
We're all wrong
together, Smith.
It's been a mistake
from the beginning.
You can have a divorce
on one condition.
Come down here.
You know, Leonora,
you still walk like a model.
And not a very
good one at that.
Are you in love with
your doctor friend?
Smith.
You are, aren't you?
What does...
Admit it.
Do you care whether
I am or not?
Yes, I want you
to be in love with him.
Why?
Because then it's easier
for me to win.
Win what?
What is it you
want, Smith?
You can have your divorce,
but I get the child.
That's the condition.
You know I wouldn't
do that!
Of course I do.
I also know I can get
custody of the child
anytime I want.
How?
By suing you
for divorce and naming
Quinada correspondent.
But we haven't done
anything wrong.
If you have money,
you could always
get enough people
to swear to anything
you want.
You wouldn't!
Oh, yes, I would.
And what's more, I will.
If you ever so much
as talk to him
on the phone.
You once told me
you thought I was sorry
from the moment we married.
That's pretty mild.
I hated myself
for being such a fool.
I never wanted you
in the first place.
The more you fought me,
the more I began
to dislike you.
I think now I hate you.
All I care about
is breaking you.
And if I have
to use the child
to do it, I will.
You know enough
about me to know
that I can't stand losing.
Only nice people lose
and you're obviously
a nice girl.
All you came back
for is that child.
And as long as you
want it, you're stuck here.
And that's probably
for the rest of your life!
Smith.
Smith, wait!
Wait, Smith.
Smith!
Oh, Smith, you don't mean it.
You're just angry with me.
(CRYING)
LEONORA: Smith, listen,
please let me have my baby.
Don't take my baby,
Smith, don't!
LEONORA: Oh, Smith!
(RINGING)
(CRYING)
Oh, Smith.
FRANZI: "From the way
that multimillionaire"
"has been treating
his car hop wife
the last three months,"
"we understand she is ready
to call the Long Island
estate, Wit's End."
"Ha! Ha!"
I can't even get her
on the phone.
Tell Leonora
I wanna see her.
Smith, it's so late.
Tell Leonora
I wanna see her!
Right now.
(CLICKING)
(MOANING)
(KNOCKING)
FRANZI: Leonora.
FRANZI: Leonora, I know
you're awake.
Leonora.
(KNOCKING)
Leonora, he's in a rage.
He'll come up himself.
You know that.
(KNOCKING)
FRANZI: Leonora!
It's really plain, darling.
Why you didn't answer
the phone when he called?
He's in a terrible rage.
I didn't hear.
He let it ring for five
minutes by the clock
and he was in a conference.
I pulled it out.
I won't let him call me
night after night
and week after week,
every night, never.
Yes, yes, yes, I know,
darling, but...
(SIGHING)
But he wants you
to come downstairs.
No, no.
Just a few minutes.
No, I won't.
Leonora, please,
he's terribly furious.
I've never seen him
so upset in my life.
The doctor told
him we mustn't...
The doctor told him
I mustn't go out
of the house.
I must get some sleep.
Darling, I...
He knows that.
The doctor told him
he mustn't call me
and wake me,
and take me out
of the house
at all hours.
Just this last time.
No, I can't.
Please.
No, no, I won't.
I won't.
Larry.
Larry, I need you.
(CRYING)
Larry, they won't
let me sleep.
I wanna sleep, Larry.
I want help.
(SOBBING)
Please, Larry, make
them leave me alone.
Smith.
Is she coming down?
She's very sick.
I feel sorry for her.
I think it's a mistake.
A woman in her condition,
to treat her like...
Is she coming down?
Why the devil do you think
I sent you up there,
you dirty little parasite?
Get her down here.
I think I'd prefer
to be a headwaiter
again, Mr. Ohlrig.
You know, you're
a big man but not big
enough to destroy that girl.
Goodbye.
Dirty little snake.
Not big enough to...
If she doesn't come down...
(BANGING)
(CLATTERING)
SMITH: Leonora!
(YELLING)
(GROANING)
SMITH: (WHEEZING)
Leonora.
Get me some water.
Please...
Get me some...
Water.
Leonora.
Leonora...
I need some...
Water.
DOCTOR: Blood pressure,
110 over 70.
EKG, normal.
He'll live.
Discontinue the oxygen.
(MURMURING)
Le?
LEONORA: I killed him.
Le.
I killed him.
He was lying
on the floor and
I left him there.
I killed him.
I called you.
I'm here, darling.
I'm here.
I killed him.
I did.
LEONORA: I wanted
him to die.
Larry.
Larry, I need you.
I want...
I want you back.
Here, take
a drink of this.
I want you back and...
Put your head back.
There.
One of his pills...
And I called his doctor...
Now, hold on.
Take another drink.
There now.
You'll be all right.
And the doctor...
Says he's going
to die.
He won't.
I wanted him to die.
Now, be quite.
Be quiet now.
I'm with you.
You're gonna be safe.
Nothing's gonna
happen to you.
Oh, Larry, I wanted
you so...
Mmm-hmm.
When he said he'd take
my baby away...
He said...
(GRUNTING)
Oh, Larry.
Larry, it hurts!
LEONORA: (GROANING)
Oh!
Stay here.
Don't move.
I'll be back in a minute.
Is there a telephone
down here, sir?
Yes, sir, the left
of the front door, sir.
Okay, I got it.
Is it over right here?
Thank you.
MAN: Right in there, sir.
Operator.
(SIREN WAILING)
He isn't gonna die.
You didn't kill him.
I had a long talk
with his doctor.
He'll live to be
an old man.
But you...
Hey, listen,
can you hear me?
You can only live
if you want to
and you must want to.
That's why it's so
important that you
hear what I'm saying.
He wanted to take
your child away,
maybe he succeeded.
Your child will die
and it's a terrible
thing, I know, but...
You'll be free
to start living.
Isn't that true?
He can't hold
you anymore.
He won't even want to.
All he wanted was
to dominate you and kick
you around like
everybody else.
Only care about
the child was to use it,
to keep you
under his thumb.
But now you'll be free.
Free to start living.
Free to be happy,
doing the things
that are worthwhile.
You can be
happy, darling.
That's why I want
you to hear me.
I hear you, Larry.
Larry, Larry.
She's okay.
Pre-mature birth,
the baby died.
LARRY: He can't hold her now,
even if he wants to.
She's free.
She shouldn't see anybody.
Oh, sure.
(CHUCKLING)
I'll give you
two minutes.
DR. HOFFMAN: Where are you
taking that?
In here.
No, no, she can't
be disturbed.
But Jacqueline doesn't
want to be responsible
for the darn coat, Doctor.
Don't worry about it.
If my diagnosis is correct,
she won't want that anyway.
All right.