Right now- Right now-
Right now it's time
to kick out the jams, motherfuckers!
- Come on, man. Take
this horrible shit off.
What the hell?
I'm listening to that.
- When Mom comes home,
she'll make me shut it off.
Well, I'm doing her a favor then.
Dude, you know what?
This is really making me crazy.
♪♪ Then leave.
What? I just got here.
What are you doing, by the way?
I'm starting a magazine.
Like--
Like 19 instead of 16?
Or 21.
Or-- Oh, no, no, wait.
We should totally go younger-- 13.
- Get in on the newbie chicks.
- No.
It's a magazine for fuck-up kids.
Like kids who have parties when their
parents are away and destroy the house.
Cool. I can be, like,
the editor or something.
No. I'm the editor and the illustrator.
- Well, what does that leave me?
- You're just a punk.
I am just a punk.
"Punk."
- That's a great title.
- Yeah. And that was my idea.
- Dude, I thought of that idea.
- What? No, you didn't.
- I just said, "That's a great title."
- Who gave you the idea for "Punk"?
Who said it was a great title?
♪ Heard of a van
that's loaded with weapons ♪
♪ Packed up and ready to go ♪
♪ Heard of some grave sites
out by the highway ♪
♪ A place where nobody knows ♪
♪ The sound of gunfire
off in the distance ♪
♪ I'm getting used to it now ♪
♪ Lived in a brownstone,
lived in a ghetto ♪
♪ I've lived all over this town ♪
♪ This ain't no party
This ain't no disco ♪
♪ This ain't no fooling around ♪
♪ This ain't no Mudd Club or CBGB ♪
♪ I ain't got time for that now ♪
♪ Heard about Houston?
Heard about Detroit? ♪♪
♪ I said Chatterbox ♪
♪ I said you squawk a lot ♪
♪ Come on, give me some lip ♪
♪ Yeah, Chatterbox ♪
♪ I call you up ♪
♪ Don't give me no line ♪
♪ I'm comin' in your home ♪
♪ On the chatter line ♪♪
- Hillel, where are you?
- Hillel!
Kidnapped?
Bertha, no one kidnaps from the poor.
- What?
- Hilly's missing.
Get your truck.
How did he get here?
He must have walked.
Three miles?
- It's two and a half.
- That is not normal.
Hillel Kristal, you currently
reside at 21 East 2nd Street?
And what is your marital status,
Mr. Kristal?
My wife and I are split.
- Separated or divorced?
- Divorced, yeah.
- Children?
- Two.
And this is your second
failed attempt to run a bar.
A club.
Divorced and two bankruptcies.
Perhaps you should try something else.
♪ I'm sick of the parties
I'm sick of the ravers ♪
♪ I'm sick of the dogs
and my noisy neighbors ♪
♪ I'm sick of the subways
and I'm sick of the crowds ♪
♪ I'm sick of hot water
always runnin' out ♪
♪ I'm sick of the crap
I gotta take in this town ♪
♪ If I didn't love it,
I swear I'd burn it to the ground ♪
♪ I'm sick of the tourists
I'm sick of their stares ♪
♪ I'm sick of all the girls
who ain't showin' their wares ♪
♪ I'm sick of the queens
and I'm sick of the whores ♪
♪ I'm sick of bad plumbing
and those backed-up sewers ♪
♪ I'm sick of the crap
I gotta take in this town ♪
♪ I'm sick ♪
♪ If I didn't love it,
I swear I'd burn it to the ground ♪
♪ You know, I'm sick ♪
♪ If I didn't love it,
I swear I'd burn it to the ground ♪
♪ I'm sick of the crap
I gotta take in this town ♪
♪ I'm really sick ♪
♪ If I didn't love it ♪♪
Do you play?
Used to.
Me too.
Mother required it.
Hilly Kristal.
They call me Idaho.
- Why's that?
- I like potatoes.
Buy you a drink?
All right. All right. Big shot.
The Palace Bar.
I like the irony.
- What'll you have?
- Whiskey.
Brandy and Fresca.
No Fresca.
Soda.
Anyone play music in here?
No.
Nobody would complain
about the noise this far downtown.
They'd complain, but
no one would listen.
Think what a coat of paint could do.
Or a bulldozer.
I wanna buy this bar.
Got any money?
Look around, Hillel.
You know that I'm not made of money.
Mmm.
This rugelach looks amazing,
Mrs. Kristal.
Ah, you're such a good boy, Merv.
Take some more.
Mmm.
Merv, are you gonna be
working with Hillel...
on the new club?
Only if he pays me.
He'll pay you.
Am I correct, Hillel?
♪ All the boys, they're putting me down ♪
♪ I know what they say
when I ain't around ♪
♪ He can't make it
He 'll have to stake it ♪
Can't play with broken strings, Idaho.
♪ One-way street ♪
♪ Yes, I'm talking about
what street now? ♪
♪ One-way street ♪♪
Thanks, Hilly.
Hilly's on the Bowery.
Very nice. Another promising
investment opportunity for your mother.
This way to the kitchen.
And lose that phony accent, Merv.
Two more blasts of ketchup.
- How many is that so far?
- Uh, 15.
It's a train wreck.
- What a surprise.
- Nice to see you too.
- I'm droppin' out of school, Dad.
- Well, you shouldn't.
- Well, I can't afford it.
- So that's my fault?
Yeah.
I need a place to crash, just for a couple
of nights until I get things back on track.
- You leave that boyfriend yet?
- You consider getting a real job yet?
♪ Come on, operator ♪
♪ Let me roll it on my line ♪
♪ You know what I need
to ease the pain ♪
♪ In my mind ♪
♪ A hundred-dollar smile ♪
Well, it's a start.
We have a stage.
Now we need an income.
I was thinking 50-cent beers and topless
waitresses like that joint down on--
Look, the music will do it all for us.
You start playing that disco shit,
I'm gone.
Country and blues.
In New York City?
This club's gonna be different.
- Country and blues?
- Country, bluegrass, blues.
- I should've never left my other job.
- That place was a shithole.
This place is a shithole.
Idaho, come on.
I'm lookin' up.
It's the only bar in the city
with Fresca on tap.
Yeah, but that shit will kill you.
Uh, hello.
We hear you have a stage.
We have a band.
The perfect band
to perform on your stage.
What kind of music do you play?
Uh, new music.
Uh, what does CBGB stand for?
Country, Bluegrass, Blues.
They play a little of that.
A little rock, a little country,
a little bluegrass, a little blues.
Hey, didn't you use to manage
the Village Vanguard?
Hundred years ago.
One moment.
Terry Ork.
I manage the band Television.
Oh.
Uh, you just met the guitar players,
Richard and Tom, outside.
It's a win-win.
CBGB gets new customers buying drinks,
and we get to play for an audience.
They any good?
They are raw...
and they-they're primitive.
- They are going to be huge.
- I bet they stink.
But maybe if they perform...
they'll get better.
All right.
You've got some vision, man.
- Only original music.
- You got it.
Ah! That way, you get to avoid
paying ASCAP fees.
It's a philosophy.
You might want to consider
an exterminator, just to--
You got a good sound engineer?
You're talking to a man who sang
at Radio City.
♪ Oh, my and a boo-hoo ♪
Hilly Kristal.
My hands are dirty, okay?
What's your name?
Taxi. Look, I'm not much
of a dog person.
But you're mechanical.
Are you musical?
Yeah, I played in a band once.
My guitar was stolen.
I have a position in my club.
Are you paying?
Yeah.
♪ Oh, my and a boo-hoo ♪♪
Hey, what-- I don't know-- Uh--
This is Taxi...
my sound engineer.
Hey, man, you're gonna want
to crank it.
You play too loud...
I'm walkin' out.
Hey, whenever you're ready.
♪ You know I ♪
♪ I jump outta bed ♪
♪ I pull down the shade ♪
♪ I used to have such sweet dreams ♪
♪ Now it's more like an air raid ♪
♪ I see the opposition clear ♪
♪ I set up flare ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
- ♪ All that matters to me ♪
- ♪ I don't care ♪
♪ That's all right, bitch, I ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ Slip out of myself like a shadow ♪
Second verse is a lot better.
♪ Somersault through walls ♪
♪ I can't tell
it's really so odd ♪
♪ Is this spring or fall? ♪
I thought it was good.
Not very country.
Going to have to change that name.
False advertising.
There's something there.
I can see there is something there.
Jonathan, your stomach's growling.
Do you want to go get a bagel?
Lisa, do you want something to eat?
No.
I ate your chili last night.
So...
if you're not going to school,
you getting a job?
It's 7:30 in the morning.
You've gotta have some plan.
What is it?
To not be here when you get back.
Oh, shit.
♪ I was saying let me out of here ♪
♪ Before I was even born ♪
♪ It's such a gamble
when you get a face ♪
♪ It's fascinatin' to observe
what the mirror does ♪
♪ But when I dine,
it's for the wall that I set a place ♪
♪ I belong to the blank generation ♪
♪ And I can take it or
leave it each time ♪♪
Excuse me. I have to open up.
He's dead.
I've been watching him for you, Hilly.
- Has anybody informed the police?
- Nah.
Cops don't care too much
about dead guys in the Bowery.
Where'd he come from?
Upstairs.
Somebody answer that!
Hey, answer the phone already!
There's a dead body outside.
Do you wanna come see if
it's one of your guests?
Not particularly.
That guy stabbed in the shower
here last month-- Big mess.
Had to call the cops three times.
Pain in my ass.
What? You want a room?
- What's goin' on, Stan?
- I'm arresting this man...
under suspicion of murder.
- Whose suspicion?
- Look, Kristal...
let me do my job, okay?
What about the body?
Welcome to CBGB's, gentlemen.
Compliments of the house.
And who the hell are you?
Hilly Kristal.
Police took a guy for murder today.
- Yeah, we heard.
- He didn't do it.
Plays the violin.
We call him "Idaho."
- Yeah, he's a little guy.
- Yeah, he's a junkie.
I'd like to help him,
but I need some guidance on that.
What do we get out of it?
I'm your neighbor.
Got lots of neighbors.
You treat me right...
I'll treat you right.
I'll make a call.
Merv...
another round of beers...
for our neighbors here.
- Hey, Hilly.
- Hello, Idaho.
I'm sorry about this.
Jail's not so bad.
At least they got heat.
Why did you come?
Because you needed me.
♪ It's hard bein' a man ♪
♪ Livin' in a garbage pail ♪
- You read much?
- I'm a junkie, Hilly.
Do I look like I read
fucking books to you?
♪ I can't stand it anymore, more ♪
Small Is Beautiful:
A Study of Economics
as if People Mattered.
Just came out.
Talks about how economics
has become...
the dominant ideological force
in society.
How we need to rethink that...
with art, music--
♪ A purple dog who wears spats ♪
- You're out of gas.
- It's only a few more blocks.
♪ They're livin' out in the hall
And I can't stand it anymore ♪
You got vodka?
♪ I can't stand it anymore, more ♪
♪ If Shelly would just come back,
it'd be all right ♪♪
♪ I remember ♪
♪ How the darkness doubled ♪
♪ I recall ♪
♪ Lightning struck itself ♪
♪ I was listening ♪
- ♪ Listening to the rain ♪♪
- Oh, shit.
Whoa!
It's no good.
Damn showers!
This place is cool, man.
Hey! Hey! 2.50!
Jesus Christ!
You're blocking the drain.
- Good working with you.
- Yeah.
- Uh, I'll see you tomorrow?
- Yes.
♪ Don't look now
Don't heed the warning ♪
Seven dollars?
How am I supposed to live on this?
Hey, man, art sucks.
♪ Isn't it about time? ♪
Not a bad night.
Nearly electrocuted a guy.
Doubled the attendance.
♪ Fire, flood, familiar famine ♪
♪ The jungle so far away ♪
♪ Blood baked into blackened soil ♪
♪ How many tons a day? ♪
♪ Isn't it about time? ♪
♪ Isn't it about time we learned? ♪
♪ Isn't it about time? ♪♪
"OMFUG"?
Other Music For Uplifting Gormandizers.
Ah, yeah.
Well, that explains it.
Your mother called. She wants to know
when you're paying her back.
- Tell her we need a little time.
- I did.
And that things are picking up.
- So what's the problem?
- I lied.
I am working...
on some other financial opportunities.
Excellent.
Watch it.
You book any country yet?
Close as I got was some guy
named Wayne County.
He was thinking of becoming
Jayne County.
I was hearing "country."
He was saying "County."
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
Good luck.
Wa-Wa-Wa-Wait, wait, wait.
I gotta pee.
- Hold it!
- I can't!
You are not going!
I'll be back.
Maybe it was a mistake to hire
a junkie as the third hand.
Hurry up!
Excellent.
So much for the lucrative world
of piano delivery.
Hey, I'm quick.
Uh-oh.
In all of my years of public life...
I have never profited--
never profited from public service.
I have never obstructed justice.
Because people have got to know whether
or not their president's a crook.
Well, I'm not a crook.
I've earned everything I've got.
- All right.
- Right there.
Ah!
If you guys weren't neighbors,
I'd put that chair on your bill, Bert.
Fuck you, Hilly.
This table, it tilts.
They shorted us
on the hard liquor order.
If we don't pay the bill,
they'll cut us off.
- Lisa.
- Hi.
You leaving that rotten boyfriend
and going back to school?
- No.
- If it's money you came for--
- You seen this?
- No.
"The great thing
about this band, Television...
is that they have absolutely
no musical or socially
redeeming characteristics,
and they know it."
- Who wrote that?
- Josh Feigenbaum.
- Who's he?
- He's important.
So, people are gonna read this,
and they're gonna start talking.
And bands are gonna start showing up,
wanting to play here.
And all bands have fans.
Even the shitty ones.
And everybody wants to be in a band
and have fans...
so new bands are gonna start up
and show up.
You have no idea
what's about to happen here.
So, gimme a job.
The pay sucks. The music sucks.
But far be it for me
to refute the words of Josh Feigenbaum.
- What do you expect to do around here?
- What do you do around here?
Do you want a job,
or do you want to fight?
I asked you for a job.
Fine.
Okay. To start with... bands will
sound check from 4:00 to 6:00.
Yeah.
I'll post the lineup at 7:30.
Bands don't get to decide the order.
They fight and they're out.
- Got it. Anything else?
- Yeah. Bikers don't pay for their drinks.
When?
- A lot.
- Ever.
- Why not?
- Policy.
CBGB.
Collection services.
Willy Kristal?
Hold on.
Bill collectors. You're hired.
Clean up on aisle 10.
Oh, he is not talking to me, is he?
Yes, he is.
Number 14.
Fifteen.
♪ It's hard bein' a man ♪
♪ Livin' in a garbage pail ♪
♪ My landlady called me up ♪
That's 11,12.
Idaho, hey.
Where's the beer?
- There's no beer.
- What do you mean?
Hilly didn't pay the bill.
For the same reason there's no phone.
We don't need a phone. We have
a pay phone. We're a bar. We need beer.
Jesus Christ.
Look at this--
Look at the size of that rat!
- Don't point at him.
- Why?
- It upsets him.
- Who?
Bert.
- Bert. Bert the rat?
- We have a deal.
- What are you talking about?
- He doesn't bite me if I feed him.
Hilly spent a fortune on
exterminating cockroaches...
and you're feeding a fucking rat?
Shh!
He's listening.
You're gonna make him mad.
- How's the chili?
- Bert likes it.
If Bert doesn't eat it,
I know I can't feed it to anybody else.
- Well, as long as Bert likes it.
- Mm-hmm.
Get rid of Bert, right now.
And find some beer.
I like Lisa.
I like Lisa a lot.
Here you go. Television.
Check 'em out. Right around the corner.
Here you go. Television. CBGB's.
I prefer the term "underground rock."
Underground implies secretive.
There's something precious
about that to me.
Like, "punk," on the other hand,
it's in your face.
It's sarcastic, ironic, cutting.
- So you're a punk?
- Yeah, I am too.
I'm an illustrator,
and I'm starting a magazine.
Yeah, it's called Punk
Hmm.
And your Punk magazine is going to
hold forth the losers as winners...
deify the freaks and outcasts
of the underground--
I mean downtown music scene.
- Yes.
- Thou shalt keep no gods...
especially fossils like Eric Clapton
and Zeppelin.
You wanna write for the magazine?
What's a degree
from Oxford for anyway?
It was to impress
your parents' friends.
- I'm John.
- Mary.
- Hey. Eddie McNeil.
- Hi, Eddie.
Nice to meet you.
- A. K.A. "Legs."
- All right, Legs.
- CBGB.
- Yeah, how late you open tonight?
- Until 4:00.
- In the morning?
A.M., right.
CBGB.
You got that
TV set band on tonight?
Yes, Television.
David Bowie says that Television
is the most original band in New York.
CBGB.
If that's what you want,
I can take care of it for you.
Coming to you
from the Bowery of New York City...
Television.
♪ You know I ♪
♪ I jump outta bed ♪
♪ I pull down the shade ♪
♪ I used to have such sweet dreams ♪
♪ Now it's more like an air raid ♪
♪ I see the opposition clear ♪
♪ I set a flare ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
- ♪ All that matters to me ♪
- ♪ I don't care ♪
♪ That's all right, bitch, I ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ Slip out of myself like a shadow ♪
♪ Somersault through walls ♪
♪ I can't tel, it's really so odd ♪
♪ Is this spring or fall? ♪♪
I always thought a punk
was someone who took it up the ass.
Said they met at art school.
Looks like they sniffed some fumes
from all that paint and glue.
- Tell 'em to wait.
- Okay. Why?
Let me see if I can increase
the size of the house.
Chief. Just a minute.
We're gonna see if
we can get more people to...
come in and listen to you.
Okay.
Stan...
I'd like to invite you into the club
to hear a band...
I think you will appreciate.
Hmm.
I'm working here, Kristal.
How 'bout if I buy you a beer?
Uh, look at that. Off duty.
Two beers.
The name of this band is Talking Heads.
We live across the street.
♪ I can't seem to face up to the facts ♪
♪ I'm tense and nervous
and I can't relax ♪
♪ I can't sleep 'cause
my bed's on fire ♪
♪ Don't touch me
I'm a real live wire ♪
♪ Psycho killer
Qu'est-ce que c'est? ♪
♪ Fa, fa, fa, fa, fa, fa,
fa, fa, far better ♪
♪ Run, run, run, run,
run, run, run away ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Psycho killer
Qu'est-ce que c'est? ♪
♪ Fa, fa, fa, fa, fa, fa,
fa, fa, far better ♪
♪ Run, run, run, run,
run, run, run away ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Ay-ay-ay-ay-ay ♪♪
Television. The Shirts. Orchestra Luna.
The Magic Tramps.
The Fast. Tuff Darts.
Dorian Zero.
The Mumps. The Miamis. Planets.
Leather Secrets.
Dancer. The Dictators.
Blondie.
You're so fuckin' hot.
You're gonna kill.
All right, stupid.
All right. Clem?
Hi. We're Blondie.
You're gorgeous.
Thank you.
You like my shorts?
New York has gorgeous garbage.
♪ Oh, Denis, be-do ♪
You gotta get
your ass down there!
Fuck!
Get your ass down there right now!
♪ I'm in love with you ♪
Bowery? I know there's stuff
happening down there.
It's just such a fuckin' shithole.
♪ Oh, with your eyes so blue ♪
♪ Denis, Denis,
I've got a crush on you ♪
I'm so in love with you ♪
All right, all right. I'll go.
♪ Oh, when we walk,
it always feels so nice ♪
♪ And when we talk,
it seems like paradise ♪
- Becky!
- Yeah, Mr. Gant?
Becky, come here--
Moist towelette.
♪ You're my king ♪
♪ And I'm in heaven every time
I look at you ♪♪
It's called a cover charge.
You gotta pay to enter.
- I don't have any money.
- Let 'em in, Lisa.
- Let 'em in.
- Thanks.
Fuck Max's.
This place has dog shit.
This is for all you drunks
and rednecks...
and punks.
"As long as the blade
has not yet pierced this grain...
this fat package...
of listless vapors."
Shut the fuck up!
This is art.
This is Rimbaud, and it's the only
sustenance life might ever give you.
So eat up, motherfuckers!
All right, I'll start again.
"As long as the blade
has not yet pierced"--
♪ Take me now, baby,
here as I am ♪
♪ Hold me close
Try and understand ♪
♪ Desire is hunger is
the fire I breathe ♪
♪ Love is the banquet ♪
Excuse me!
Could I get through?
Let me in. Let me in. Let me in.
I'm Nicky Gant. I produce records.
You want me in your club.
Nice.
I hate the Bowery.
♪ Now ♪
♪ Because the night belongs to lovers ♪
♪ Because the night belongs to lust ♪
♪ Because the night belongs to us ♪
♪ Have my doubts when I'm alone ♪
♪ Love is the ring, telephone ♪
♪ Love is an angel disguised as lust ♪
Hey, Iggy.
Hey, Ork.
Let's go downstairs.
I'll give you head.
Why don't you just lick my stomach?
Everybody wants to suck my cock.
All right.
♪ They can't touch you now ♪
♪ Can't touch you now ♪
♪ Because the night ♪♪
Here you go.
Dad, is there or isn't there
a cover charge?
Someone's gotta pay.
Hey, John, John--
isn't that the guy that made
that awful feedback album?
- John, it's Lou Reed.
- That's Lou Reed.
Oh, shit, that's Lou Reed.
We have to interview him.
Hey, Lou. Um, we would
like to interview you...
for the first issue
of Punk magazine.
We'd like to put you on the cover.
Cover of the first issue.
If you'll agree to do an interview.
Circulation must be enormous.
Do you like Patti Smith?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
What about Bruce Springsteen?
Oh, I love him.
Y-You do?
- Oh, yeah. He's one of us.
- Thank you.
He's a shit.
What are you talking about?
What kind of stupid question is that?
- Okay.
- Do I ask you what you like?
Who gives a fuck what I like?
I don't even give a fuck what I like.
Well, you're a rock star, man.
Oh, yeah, I keep forgetting.
Sontag called it "the sensibility
of failed seriousness."
♪ I'm waiting for my man ♪
♪ Hey, white boy,
what you doing uptown? ♪
What's their name?
The Ramones.
Look like they were raised
on the police lines.
♪ Oh, pardon me, sir♪♪
What do you guys have for me?
W-We got four songs.
"I Don't Wanna Walk Around With You"...
"I Don't Wanna Be Learned"...
"I Don't Wanna Be Tamed" and
"I Don't Wanna Go Down to the Basement."
Lot of things
you don't wanna do.
Yeah.
Anything you wanna do?
We're workin' on something now.
Something positive?
Yeah. it's-- it's called...
"I Wanna Sniff Some Glue."
Good to have a point of view.
One, two, three, four!
What the fuck are you playing?
Goddamn it. Fuck!
- I'm gonna get the fuck out of here!
- You guys want to try it again?
- Yeah.
- Is Johnny coming back?
What-- What are we playin'?
Johnny? Johnny?
Fuck!
- Lively!
- One, two, three, four!
♪ Sittin' in a hospital bed ♪
♪ I, I want life ♪
♪ I want my life ♪
♪ I got knocked down
, but I'll get up ♪♪
Nobody is gonna like you guys.
But I'll have you back.
City's going bankrupt.
It's like a disease.
Which I would prefer not to catch.
Meaning?
We have to get our affairs in order.
I'm working on it.
Your working isn't working, Hilly.
Coming to you from
the Bowery of New York City...
Wayne County.
Hello, sex kittens.
Eat my pussy.
Wish I had one. Ooh.
Here we go. Here we go.
You ready, ready, ready, ready, ready.
One, two, three-- L'Chaim.
♪ Wanted nothing more ♪
♪ I know you wouldn't go
You'd watch my heart burst ♪
No, no, no, no. Come here.
I'm Nicky Gant.
Nicky fuckin' Gant.
I produce records.
Hilly told me this was on the house.
Come on.
We're good?
♪ You were a marksman ♪
♪ Told me that law,
like wine, is ageless ♪
Got any-- any chips or something?
We're gonna have to do something
about that stage.
Where is he?
You might want to think about having
fewer guests of Hilly...
and more paying customers
if you want to pay for it.
I'm with Lisa on this one.
You gotta spend money to make money.
You gotta have money
to spend money to make money.
And since you spend all the money you
make, you don't have any money to spend.
So you might wanna think about
saving the money you make...
instead of spending
the money you make.
All right, we're gonna
try that one again.
What are you doing?
Goddamn it, Dad.
What, two bankruptcies
wasn't enough for you?
- Why not go for three?
- Stop.
- Well, I'm taking over the finances.
- No, you're not. You're fired.
- You're firing me?
- Yeah. Get the hell out.
♪ I want my life ♪
Things are not gonna work out
with her.
Everything all right, Hilly?
Hey, so, Deb, who were the people
that you idolized as artists?
Fuck, you know,
I always really liked Brigitte Bardot.
- Uh-huh.
- She was sort of...
- continental punk, you know?
- Yeah.
I always thought sex was
a cool thing to sell-- a sure thing.
I wish I'd invented sex.
You like sex?
God. Look at this. I'm sick of
the goddamn fleas from Hilly's dog.
- Have you considered boots?
- Boots?
Fuck.
♪ Can I describe what it's like
to have sex with the light on? ♪
♪ And would you feel right
if I did you tonight ♪
♪ And put the bite on? ♪
♪ All this and more, little girl ♪
♪ How 'bout on the floor, little girl? ♪
♪ No time to implore you, girl ♪
♪ I'm just a dead boy ♪
♪ You know that I'm just a dead boy ♪
♪ I wanna be a dead boy ♪
♪ I'll die for you ♪
♪ if you want me to ♪
♪ Got a feeling in my knees
that tell me the degrees ♪
♪ I been loved on ♪
♪ You got dents in your head
that tell me all the beds ♪
♪ You've been shoved on ♪
♪ All this and more, little girl ♪
♪ How 'bout on the floor, little girl? ♪
♪ No time to implore you, girl ♪
♪ I'm just a dead boy ♪
♪ You know that I'm just a dead boy ♪
♪ I wanna be a dead boy ♪
♪ I'll die for you ♪
♪ If you want me to ♪
Don't tell me.
There's something there.
There is definitely something there.
The Dead Boys. As long as they don't
take their name too seriously.
♪ A teenage feelin',
rockin' and a-reelin' ♪♪
- Hilly Kristal.
- Cheetah Chrome.
That was good. I mean--
it was really good.
- Thank you, sir.
- That means a lot, you know?
Your dog is crappin' on the floor, sir.
Yeah, he does that.
I piss in ice machines.
- Where are you guys from?
- Cleveland, sir.
Well, I'm impressed
with the youth of Cleveland.
- You shouldn't be.
- Why not?
Lot of losers.
Well, you--
you seem awfully polite.
Yeah, well-- We were altar boys.
Yeah. That was a while ago.
Look, Mr. Kristal.
We get the gig here or not?
Yeah.
- No shit.
- Holy fuck.
Spoken like a true altar boy.
Some say punk
promotes a message of violence.
I mean-- What we're doing
is not really destructive, you know?
So it's not a statement of aggression?
No. We're just letting out
a lot of energy and frustration.
And where better to do that--
here or on the streets?
- Good point.
- Hi, Mom.
Yeah. it's actually really healthy.
So, what kind of girls do you like?
All kinds.
I like the ones that like to fuck
and leave in the morning.
Stiv. She just wants
to give you a blow job.
Oh!
Cut.
I dare you.
You know better than to dare me.
Oh, yeah.
♪ Oh, yeah! ♪
Yeah.
♪ Hot flashes burning my brain ♪
♪ Your tongue lashing
drive me insane ♪
♪ From New York City to L.A. ♪
♪ You're known as the hottest lay ♪
- ♪ Oh, your pink canopy
gonna shackle ya down ♪
♪ You lost everybody in town ♪
♪ From a cherry runaway
to a fairy queen ♪
♪ Used up before your sweet 16 ♪
♪ Everyone knows you were caught
with the meat in your mouth ♪
♪ Said everyone knows you were caught
♪ Look for love on a one-way street ♪
♪ Bedding down with every-- ♪
♪ A-stripping and a-dancing
and a-buying some downs ♪
- See? it's not all about violence.
- ♪ Support the latest sensation in town ♪
Cut. Cut!
Yeah, Stiv. He's getting his
dick sucked. Holy shit.
Fresca.
On the house.
Stan.
You know I got
nothing against you, right?
I'd like to think anyone who shares
a drink in my club is my friend.
Mmm.
Well, as your friend--
We've had some complaints.
About what?
Hey, Hilly.
♪ She's my dragon lady, yeah ♪
♪ I'm her jumbo jet ♪
- ♪ She got a Saturday night special ♪
- Excuse me.
♪ And I'm her steady driving man
I'm her steady driving man ♪
I'm just the messenger here,
you know.
But I understand the complaints
are about the...
element your club attracts.
Are you kidding me? If anything,
I'm cleaning the street up.
I am just the messenger here.
People bigger than you and I are tugging
the strings and stirring the shit.
And I also understand that you're
three months behind on your rent.
That kind of thing just doesn't help.
Pay your bills, Kristal.
Pay your fucking bills.
♪ You know I need you ♪
♪ Yes, I do
Yes, I do ♪
♪ Yes, I do ♪
♪ You know I love you ♪
♪ Yes, I do
Yes, I do ♪♪
I don't like that guy.
♪ Got a spirit in my house
and I know it ain't no mouse ♪
We know you got more dough.
Come on. Give me the fucking dough.
Come on, Idaho. Give me the fucking dough.
♪ My house ♪
I gave you all-- I gave you already.
- Again!
- Ugh!
- In my club!
- Said I won't! He's not gonna talk, man!
Come on, Hilly. Be cool, man.
Like I was saying previously, Stan.
These two gentlemen were not abiding...
by the rigorous code of ethics...
I strive to maintain
in my establishment.
Well, that's not very good,
now is it, boys?
♪ In my house,
in my house, in my house ♪
- What are we stopping for?
- Joey fell off the stage, John.
Fuckin' think I didn't fuckin' notice?
Fuck it.
♪ I know a girl from a lonely street ♪
♪ Cold as ice cream,
but still as sweet ♪
♪ Dry your eyes, Sunday girl ♪
♪ Hey, I saw your guy
with a different girl ♪
♪ Looks like he's in another world ♪
♪ Run and hide, Sunday girl ♪
Hey, all you wannabes.
I'm fuckin' Iggy Pop.
Let's play some real fuckin' music.
- "I Wanna Be Your Dog."
- Fuck you, Iggy.
One, two, three, four!
♪ So messed up
I want you here ♪
♪ In my room
♪ Now we're gonna be face-to-face ♪
♪ And I'll lay right down
in my favorite place ♪
♪ And now I wanna be your dog ♪
♪ Now I wanna be your dog ♪
Fuck the bogus claims.
I'm the pioneer of punk
and stage dives.
I was the first.
The bands are not political,
but the disavowing of politics...
in and of itself, it is political.
I belong in the blank generation.
- And relevant.
- And timely.
John, Hilly is a modern-day salonist.
Like a drug I never did before.
No, no, no. I like that. it's true.
Yeah. Modern-day Mabel Dodge, right?
- Gertrude Stein.
- Yeah, yeah.
Picasso painted Gertrude Stein
sitting in her chair in her salon.
You should draw Hilly
sitting on his couch at CB's--
the grand curator of punk.
Mother always said
you have to listen to hear.
Fifty cents, please.
Thank you, Annie.
'Scuse me.
You're up first tomorrow, Annie.
Shirts, then Ramones, then Dictators.
Let's go by Arturo's.
- You scare them.
- Yeah. Probably.
This place is starting to happen.
It's still shit-ass music,
you ask me.
It's not the Grand Ole Opry.
It's hard to get Conway Twitty
down to the Bowery.
One day.
Maybe me and the boys
will hang back till then.
Since I'm scaring the kids.
Let you grow this place into a, uh--
something.
Then when you're famous
and old Twitty shows up...
I'll be back,
and I'm bringing all my friends.
Mission on the house.
Don't forget we're right down the block.
Thanks, Leslie.
Nobody calls me that.
Except my grandma.
All right, boys. Let's get the hell out
of this punk-ass excuse for a bar.
You want a rematch,
you know where to find me.
Oh.
One more thing.
Clean those fucking toilets.
They just-- You can't--
It's the s--
They're disgusting.
Cool.
- Fuckin' cool.
- It's fuckin'-- fuckin' cool.
Hilly.
Sire Records.
This is the contract.
Congratulations.
You pissed?
I'd be fucking pissed.
You're always fucking pissed.
Are you kidding me?
I'm proud of you guys.
Can't believe we got signed. We suck.
Now you gotta make a good record.
You think we're gonna be rock stars?
You already are.
♪ All by myself ♪
♪ Not everybody else ♪
♪ I don't need no wedding hall ♪
♪ I just watch your rollerball ♪
♪ Forget your friends and what they do ♪
♪ Got to get inside of you ♪
♪ All by myself ♪♪
Happy birthday.
You're not gonna sing?
If you want to apologize, I accept.
If not, then shut up.
Yes, ma'am.
CBGB.
Ask your dad,
what time are we goin' on tonight?
Zeke wants to know
what time they're going on tonight.
- I don't know yet.
- Bastard won't tell me.
All right. I guess we're
just gonna hang out.
Yep.
See you tonight.
This is good for you.
"The Ramones
are the apotheosis of punk."
Frank Rose again.
"They are an acknowledgment of the
failure of glitter." That they are.
"Brevity is the soul of wit, and it is
right at the heart of the Ramones' music.
They could not be accused
of dragging out a number."
We just gotta hope
they don't kill each other.
Call Leslie.
Number is on the wall.
Hilly Kristal? My understanding is that
there is a problem with the rent.
And when the rent doesn't get
paid, it comes to me to collect.
But you see, I'm forced to double it
to cover my overhead.
So now, we have a compounded problem.
- How many are there?
- Three.
- They packing?
- Yeah.
The rent check's on its way,
but I just--
if you could think about the doubling.
There's nothing
to think about, Mr. Kristal.
You guys thirsty?
Cut the shit. You have a
thriving business that
operates at full capacity
almost every night...
so let me explain something to you.
I'm not a very patient man.
So I suggest you give me
what I came here for.
- How you been, Leslie?
- I ain't been feeling too good.
Think I got a tapeworm.
- Mmm.
- Quit calling me that.
- You know who you're dealin' with?
- Get in the fuckin' car.
- Don't dent my car.
- Let's go. Let's go!
- What was that?
- A shakedown.
New York style.
I don't understand.
You paid the rent, right?
Everything all right?
Why wouldn't it be?
I wrote a rent check last week.
- So it was a misunderstanding?
- I didn't send it.
What? Why not?
I forgot.
- Dad!
- What?
I am taking over the books
whether you like it or not.
Because if I don't, someone is going
to come here and kill you.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Yeah. Okay.
Hello there.
Kristal. This your truck?
You know it is.
I'm gonna have to write you up.
Why?
Did you read the sign?
You and I both know...
how long this truck has been
parked here-- in this exact spot--
without getting a ticket.
New York is going bankrupt.
There's pressure to
bring in some revenue.
Well--
This car has been here all day.
Move the truck.
City's cracking down.
- You're not telling me the whole story.
- What's that supposed to mean?
Where does the cash go
at the end of the night?
After I count it?
- Stop it.
- What?
What happens to the cash
at the end of the night?
I put it in the freezer.
What?
- In my apartment.
- You got an apartment?
I can't sleep on a mattress when bands
are getting signed right and left.
I'm going to go through
all this paper...
and then we will know where we're at.
Terrific.
You go to the freezer
in your apartment...
and get the money, now.
Pay the rent, now,
and take the rest to the bank, now.
I don't know how this is gonna work out
with you ordering me around.
I don't know how it's gonna work out
if I don't.
♪ I don't want to talk too much ♪
♪ I just want to get to you ♪
♪ I don't want to see you there ♪
♪ I just want to get you there ♪
♪ All by myself ♪
- ♪ All by myself ♪
♪ Not everybody else ♪
♪ I don't need no wedding hall ♪
♪ I just watch your rollerball ♪
♪ Forget your friends and what they do ♪
♪ Got to get inside of you ♪
♪ All by myself ♪
Hilly!
Damn it, Hilly.
Oh! Shit!
Goddamn it!
Turn the water off. Water everywhere.
Jesus Christ.
You know, Bert, I've been thinking I
should start managing some of those bands.
And Jonathan shit in
the front room here.
The Dead Boys. Talking Heads.
The Shirts.
Punk isn't about decay. It's about
the apocalypse. it's about annihilation.
Nothing works, so let's skip
right to Armageddon.
If the world is ending, you might as well do
away with pretense and say what you think.
Uncensor sex.
And drugs.
The violence!
Just everything.
Decadence sounds great right now...
compared to what's happening
in the real world.
Yeah.
♪ I don't need anyone ♪
♪ Don't need no Mom and Dad ♪
- Come on, Genya. They're charming.
- Hilly, they're punk and they're charming?
♪ I got some news for you ♪
I want you to produce them.
I think they're special.
♪ I got my time machine ♪
♪ Got my electronic dream ♪
♪ Sonic reducer
Ain't no loser ♪
I've been waiting for you in the office.
In a minute, Lisa.
♪ People out on the streets ♪
♪ They don't know who I am ♪
♪ I watch them from my room ♪
- Mrs. Kristal!
- Oh. Merv.
- So good to see you.
- Mother.
- Oh.
- Welcome to CBGB's.
Hillel.
Listen. I need a drink.
On the house.
Glenlivet with a twist.
- Coming right up.
- Okay.
- We don't have any Glenlivet.
- We'll take care of it. Go talk to Lisa.
Come this way. Mrs. Kristal, I have
a special spot for you right up here.
Excuse me. Watch your backs.
This is what you're spending.
This is what you're making.
- I have to get back out there.
- Give her a minute, Hilly.
You're spending too much.
You cannot afford
to personally take on a band.
- I agree with Lisa on this.
- Uh--
This is about the Dead Boys.
Yeah. Before we branch out, we need
to get our primary business in order.
We need to put
proper vendor agreements in place.
We need to have billing cycles.
Look here. Okay?
This is what you're
spending on toilet paper.
I don't believe that.
You're getting it from the deli.
A lot of it.
If you buy it in bulk, you can get
it for a fraction of the price.
This is what you're spending on beer.
This is what you are bringing in
on the bar in general.
Too many customers are
drinking for free.
- This is bullshit.
- Hilly, cut it out.
What are we talking
about toilet paper?
I have Genya Ravan out there, ready
to produce the Dead Boys album.
You're wasting my time.
- Fine.
- Goddamn it, Hilly.
This is quite good.
- Hilly's chili, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Word is Stiv Bators
jerks off in that chili.
I've had worse in my mouth.
Everything okay, Mother?
Delicious.
What are you doin'?
Trying to light a cigarette.
You shouldn't smoke.
'Cause it'll kill you.
I don't smoke.
You know, your old man--
He's really not such a bad guy.
You obviously don't know him very well.
Oh, God. Zip, Idaho, please!
Excuse me.
Sometimes you hurt
the ones you love the most.
What fortune cookie
did you read that in?
Nah.
I got it from a poster in the subway.
Across from this bench I kinda like.
I prefer Rachmaninoff, Hillel.
Yeah, I prefer that Beethoven myself.
That punk rock shit gives me a headache.
No shit.
Mom was right to leave you.
You're an asshole.
- Lisa.
- What?
In my capacity as asshole...
I am promoting you
to vice president of business affairs.
Is that supposed to be
some kind of apology?
The Dead Boys
are gonna change things for me, Lisa.
I am gonna get them a record deal,
and they are gonna be big.
♪ I'm so sick of TV ♪
♪ You know, I'm gettin' bored
of the tubes ♪
♪ And I'm so sick of romance ♪
I used to chase you, Lisa.
♪ ...Sick of you ♪
♪ I wanna get on out of here ♪
I've had it, Hilly.
I can't take it anymore.
Please end this shit.
Your dog is crapping everywhere.
It's disgusting.
This is not a kennel.
Either Jonathan goes, or I go.
Taxi, you don't like it...
you don't have to work here.
♪ I'm gonna play my stereo too ♪
♪ Just one good eye
on the streetlights ♪
♪ Just like nothing to do ♪
♪ Yeah, get on out of here ♪
♪ I'm so-- ♪
♪ I've just got nothin' to do ♪♪
So is that your real hair color,
or you just dye it that way?
- Who wants to know?
- Me.
It's real.
So, now you know.
Yeah. We're good.
So, they vomit...
they drop trou,
they slash themselves, they bleed...
they hang themselves,
and that's just on stage.
I think their on-stage antics
are evidence of commitment.
Hilly, I don't want to produce a shit
album for a flash-in-the-pan band.
Fine. I'll find somebody else.
- We're gonna need money.
- Yup.
And we're gonna need
to take 'em out on the road.
Yup.
Cheetah doesn't trust me.
Cheetah takes too many drugs.
Sarah's interested in signing you
if we can show the band is reliable...
and people will pay to see you.
We are the definition of "reliable."
What'd I miss?
Let's make a demo...
and get out on the road.
Hilly, how much money is this?
We are gonna rock and shock.
Don't screw this up.
Scout's honor.
Yeah.
I heard she fucked Bowie at-- at CB's...
in the bathroom.
Fuck in the bathroom at CB's?
That's not sanitary.
What the fuck is that?
What?
Get rid of those fuckin' things.
They're just stickers.
Hilly, your manager--
Hey!
Hilly, your manager, the guy who is
footing the bill for all of this...
he's Jewish.
Me, your producer, I'm Jewish.
And the guy who owns this studio,
who is doing us a favor...
by letting us record
at these ridiculous prices...
he's got numbers
tattooed on his arm.
Do you know what that means?
Not really.
Auschwitz.
Hitler. Nazis.
Now get rid of the fucking swastikas.
Okay. Fuckin' lighten up.
We'll get rid of 'em.
Look, you guys,
you're not Nazis, okay?
You're punks, and anything bad,
anything wrong, you wanna do it.
I get it.
Now let's go have a bagel.
- What's a bagel?
- What's-- What's a bagel?
What part of Cleveland are you from?
Cleveland, Germany?
What is punk rock?
Well, call it street music.
Look...
all I care about is originality.
These kids have something to say.
We really... should listen.
We're the Dead Boys.
♪ I don't want you to hang around ♪
♪ Yeah, I don't need you
to drag me down ♪
♪ Well, I ♪
♪ I don't really wanna dance ♪
Hello, Poughkeepsie.
♪ ... In your pants ♪
What's up, Cleveland?
- Fuck you, New Haven.
- Fuck off, Boston.
Suck my balls, Bridgeport.
♪ You know I'll prick you in the end ♪
♪ Don't look at me that way, bitch ♪
♪ Your face is gonna get a-- ♪
Hello, White Plains.
♪ Don't need no cook, girl ♪
♪ I need lunch ♪
♪ Now listen to me, baby ♪
We're the Dead Boys.
I swallowed my gum.
What the hell--
I mean--
Do you want a record deal?
Said sorry, you know.
Go!
♪ I found out the hard way ♪
♪ There wasn't nothin'
that you wouldn't do ♪
- ♪ Everybody says ♪
- Have a nice day.
♪ That you better watch out ♪
♪ They say watch out, uh ♪
♪ Watch out for-- ♪
May I help you?
Why would you save...
for your dreams?
Why not live your dreams?
Absolutely.
Hilly Kristal.
How much do I have in my account?
♪ I found out the hard way♪♪
$312.17.
Keep the 17 cents.
I'll take the rest.
What are you doing, Hilly?
- Are you following me?
- Me? Follow you now?
Why would I follow you?
Yes, I'm following you.
- What are you doing?
- Investing.
In what? Treasury bills?
I'm taking the money
out of the CBGB account...
to float the Dead Boys'
development fund.
That's the stupidest thing
I've ever heard. You can't.
- You watch me.
- We got bills to pay.
You have no vision, Merv.
- Well, I quit!
- I'll call you later.
- I won't answer.
- Oh, yes, you will.
No, I won't.
Went to a pawn shop.
Sold everything.
My father's watch.
Hey, you asshole!
They destroyed your truck.
And their equipment.
They're gonna need equipment.
Oh, yeah.
- Why are you doing this?
- I believe in them.
Hey.
Thank you.
Why are you thanking me?
Somebody should.
It's not the end of the world.
I mean, this could be good for us,
if we manage it right.
We are punks, after all.
Blitz might be dead.
The last thing I care about
is publicity...
for a band who's about
to cost me my club.
How is he?
He's, um, critical.
Fuck.
Do you still have the money?
Yeah.
Blitz is gonna need it.
Make sure he gets good medical care.
- Where you going?
- I'm not your father.
I'm just your manager.
I can't do this anymore.
Jersey. Hightstown.
♪ Say a word for Jimmy Brown ♪
♪ He ain't got nothin' at all ♪
♪ Knocked the shirt right off his back ♪
♪ And say a word for Ginger Brown ♪
♪ Walks with his head down
to the ground ♪
♪ Took the shoes right off his feet ♪
♪ And threw the poor boy
right out in the street ♪
♪ And this is what he said ♪
♪ Oh, sweet nothin' ♪♪
Can I help you?
I'm sorry.
I grew up here.
Uh-huh.
Hilly Kristal.
Hilly.
Are you the kid
that started that rock-and-roll club?
Unfortunately, that's me.
My nephew's band played there once.
Teenage Jesus and the Jerks.
Uh-huh.
- Coffee's inside. Come on.
♪ Saw a little bird sittin' in a tree ♪
♪ Who wanted to start a family ♪
♪ He went tweet, tweet ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet ♪
♪ He were lookin' for a she ♪
♪ He couldn't wait ♪
♪ To find a mate ♪
♪ Sat in a tree ♪
♪ And sang a plea ♪
♪ He went tweet, tweet ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet ♪
♪ He were lookin' for a she ♪♪
Where the hell are you?
Everybody is worried about you.
I'm done. it's over.
No. No way.
I won't let you.
I can't even pay the rent.
Yeah, you can.
And, yes, you will.
Look, you may be
a lousy businessman, Dad...
but, damn it, you are the father
of underground rock...
and OM FUG, whatever the hell that is.
And it's not all about you.
Okay, there are kids out there
in bands or forming bands...
hoping to play at CBGB one day.
Stop feeling sorry for yourself
right now, and get over here.
Lisa, stop shouting and feed Jonathan.
CBGB.
- Hey, Lisa, you got the lineup?
- No. I don't have the lineup for tonight.
All right.
CBGB.
- Hey, Hilly.
- Hilly.
I just don't get it.
Why did you risk everything
on the Dead Boys?
Was it the auto-asphyxiation
or the self-mutilation?
- They could have been a bellwether.
- That's debatable.
I'm going to law school.
Really?
- How come?
- 'Cause I know you're gonna need me to.
Even though I know
you'll never admit it.
Your friends have been waiting
out there for you all fuckin' day.
Get your ass out there.
You know, I really don't appreciate
all the swearing.
I know you all counted on me...
but the thing is, I'm broke...
and I think we're gonna have
to close the club.
Oh, God!
How many years
have we listened to your shit?
Lisa and I made a few calls.
A lot of calls.
And people wanted to help.
Yeah, like people that you helped,
even when you didn't have money.
But, uh--
Lisa's gonna take care of this.
She's gonna pay the bills.
She's gonna get the place back on track.
Want you to have this.
It's all I got.
I have a-- Don't tell anybody.
I have a gold filling
in my tooth in the back.
You could probably
take it off like this.
Thanks, Idaho.
Looks like I'm not gonna need
either of those.
Okay.
When you're ready.
Thank you, sir.
It's an honor to be here.
If you play too loud, I'm walking out.
Go ahead, guys. Anytime.
♪ Roxanne ♪
♪ You don't have to put on
the red light ♪
♪ Those days are over ♪
♪ You don't have
to sell your body to the night ♪
♪ Roxanne ♪
♪ You don't have
to wear that dress tonight ♪
♪ Walk the streets for money ♪
♪ You don't care if it's wrong
or if it's right ♪
- Well, there is something there.
- ♪ Roxanne ♪
♪ You don't have
to put on the red light ♪
- ♪ Roxanne ♪
- There is definitely something there.
♪ ... Put on the red light ♪
- ♪ Roxanne ♪
- ♪ Put on the red light ♪
I opened CBGB because...
I thought country music
was gonna become the next big thing.
And it did...
in Nashville.
♪ I know my mind is made up ♪
♪ So put away your makeup ♪
♪ Told you once
I won't tell you again ♪
♪ It's a bad way♪♪
♪ Heard of a van ♪
♪ That's loaded with weapons ♪
♪ Packed up and ready to go ♪
♪ Heard of some grave sites ♪
♪ Out by the highway ♪
♪ A place where nobody knows ♪
♪ The sound of gunfire ♪
♪ Off in the distance ♪
♪ I'm gettin' used to it now ♪
♪ Lived in a brownstone ♪
♪ Lived in a ghetto ♪
♪ I've lived all over this town ♪
♪ This ain't no party
This ain't no disco ♪
♪ This ain't no foolin' around ♪
♪ No time for dancing
or lovey-dovey ♪
♪ I ain't got time for that now ♪
♪ Transmit the message ♪
♪ To the receiver ♪
♪ Hope for an answer someday ♪
♪ I got three passports ♪
♪ A couple of visas ♪
♪ You don't even know my real name ♪
♪ High on a hillside ♪
♪ The trucks are loading ♪
♪ Everything's ready to roll ♪
♪ I sleep in the daytime ♪
♪ I work in the nighttime ♪
♪ I may not ever get home ♪
♪ This ain't no party
This ain't no disco ♪
♪ This ain't no foolin' around ♪
♪ This ain't no Mudd Club
or CBGB ♪
♪ I ain't got time for that now♪♪
Talking Heads,
get the hell up here, please.
We wanna start where we can
by thanking Hilly Kristal.
We'd like to invite Hilly up here.
Hilly is the reason that we're here,
that the Ramones are here...
that Blondie are here.
He kept us alive.
He fed us and he supported us
in every way possible.
He told us we needed
to expand our sound...
and he taught us a lot about ethics...
about how to treat people.
I'd like to thank Hilly again.
When we were starting out,
there really weren't clubs...
where bands could play
their own material...
and poor Hilly wanted to have
a bluegrass bar on the Bowery...
and to have some other music as well.
I guess the road didn't go that way.
The road took another turn...
and, uh, thanks to--
We're thanking him 'cause he went
that direction and didn't mind.
It was just extraordinary,
the fact that...
bands came out of the woodwork.
They were everywhere.
They were coming from out of state.
Nobody knew they were there.
They came out because
there was somewhere to play.
Hilly brought the music into existence
in many ways.
Kill me!
♪ I saw a little bird ♪
♪ A-sittin' in a tree ♪
♪ Who wanted to start ♪
♪ A family ♪
♪ Who went tweet, tweet ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet ♪
♪ He were lookin' for a she ♪
♪ He couldn't wait ♪
♪ To find a mate ♪
♪ Sat in a tree and sang a plea ♪
♪ He went tweet, tweet ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet ♪
♪ He were lookin' for a she ♪
♪ There was a little bee ♪
♪ A-feelin' mighty free ♪
♪ Some honey, he said ♪
♪ Is good for me ♪
♪ He went a-buzz, a-buzz ♪
♪ A-buzz, buzz ♪
♪ He were lookin' for a she ♪
♪ You love me, I love you ♪
♪ Let's both do
what the birds and bees do ♪
♪ Buzz, buzz, buzz ♪
♪ Tweet, tweet, tweet ♪
♪ That means I love you,
love you, love you ♪
♪ I love you all the time ♪
♪ Isn't it a pity ♪
♪ That the lady from the city ♪
♪ Went inside a pen ♪
♪ And was taken for a hen? ♪
♪ Turned her back on a rooster ♪
♪ And when he promptly goosed her ♪
♪ She received such a booster ♪
♪ More than she was used to ♪
♪ That she went back to the city ♪
♪ And never came here again ♪
♪ Isn't that a pity? ♪
♪ That means I love you,
love you, love you ♪
♪ I love you all the time ♪
♪ That means I love you,
love you, love you, love you ♪
♪ All the time ♪
♪ That means I love you,
love you, love you ♪
♪ I love you all the time ♪
♪ That means
I love you, love you, love you ♪♪