Hello.
Dec 16, tomorrow,10:50 pm on JTBC,
Mari and I will be aired.
Let's go.
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
Come like a windlove like a flame
flow like a cloudLa-la-la-la-la-la-la
Sing along
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
Go Hyung-tak
Like a river flowsinto the ocean
love will flow on and onLa-la-la-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
Love is not kiddingLove is all about trust
Love is hopelove is joy
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
We love youI love you
Sing alongLa-la-la-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
A bridge.
A bridge?
Is it not ended yet?
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
Love like jewels iscoming down from the sky
You love meLa-la-la-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
B.I.
Love you, love youI love only you
I love you for my lifeLa-la-la-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la-la-la-lala-la-la-la-la-la-la
Mari and I
So Mari and I will beaired when?
When will it be, Jinhwan?
Is it tomorrow?Dec 16?
Yes, it's tomorrow.
Right.Tomorrow 10:50 pm.
Each of us will introduceourselves on V app.
On Wendesdays, at 10:50 pm,you'll see the love between
humans and animalson Mari and I.
I'm Kang-vely, Kang Ho-dong.
And who are you?
I'm Sim Hyung-tak.
I'm not surewhat I'll do on the program.
I'm sorry.
But I'll do my best.
It's okay.
Hello.
I'm Mari's mother Seo In Guk.
Nice to meet you.
And?
I'm a toddler of entertainment,Jinwhan.
Wow, a toddler.
Hey, Minjae.
I'm Mari's father, Kim Min-jae.
I'm the expert of pets,Lee Jae-hoon.
It was nice.
I'm in charge of la-la-la.I'm B.I.
Why did we singthe song anyways?
Last time, on V app,I sang this song
for peace and union.
And I sing it today again.
So many of you may not know
about our program.
So please explain.
Mari is the unitto count animals in Korean.
And we'll babysit pets.
Right.
So we're like animal sitters.
Pet sitters.
Pet sitters.It's so warm and human.
Where is Jiwon though?
Here he is.
He's right here.
He's not here because ofother schedule.
It's okay, Jiwon.Come on here.
- Come on.- So he's not here.
Here he comes.
So it's being airedonly domestically?
No. To those who're onV app right now.
- All around the world.- Really?
- What nationality are they?- What people?
You can read their real timereaction here.
There are English, Korean,
and
- English.- English.
- Korean and- Chinese.
There are Chinese viewers, and
- Japanese too?- Korean language.
Sure.
So it's being aired globally.
What's even better isthere are subtitles
to help the viewers abroadunderstand us real time.
Then can we say helloto our Chinese fans?
You're studying the languagerecently. Go ahead.
Any of you can speakJapanese or English?
I can speak Japanese.
To Japanese viewers.
What did you say?
Don't miss our showtomorrow.
I also said, our program istitled Mari and I,
and please watch it.
Then try English B.I.
In English?
To those abroad.
He was surprised.
I'm not ready at all.
How about our lovely Minjae?
In Thai language?
Hello everyone.
Please watch our show,Mari and I.
It'll be aired on JTBCtomorrow 10:50 pm.
Please don't miss it.Thank you.
We promoted
our show and ourselves on V app.
And we hopeour viewers will share
our happiness and emotions.
Right.
So let's contact our friends
to promote the show moreon V app.
- Good.- Great.
Our 1st episode will be airedtomorrow, so...
not to miss it?
Shall I try first?
But I'm not sure he'll takethe call or not.
Is it he or she?
Listen.
Hello.
Hello?
Jongmin.
Yes?
What were you doing?
I just ate and I'm waiting.
Ate with whom?
With my family.
Your family?
You're being aired liveon V app.
Can you do a short interviewfor us?
V app?
Yes.
Is it Internet broadcasting?
Yes. It's being aired live.
Being aired right now?
Yes. Have you raised any pet?
A pet?
I don't.But my family does.
Then...
you're not livingwith your family?
If you have one,what do you want to raise?
If I have one?
Yes.
But I don't.
I said 'If' you have one.
It's live.
I've never thought about it.
You're so resistent.
Anyway, tomorrowon Dec 16.
Tomorrow?
Yes.On Wednes day evening, 10:50.
Yes.
It's on JTBC.And the title is Mari and I.
I know it.I read the article.
Did you?
If you watch it,
Yes.
you'll want to raise
a pet too.
Really?
When will it be aired?
Wednesday evening10:15?
Alright. Turn on the TVfrom then and wait for us.
Okay? It's JTBC.
The time is 10:50 pm, Jongmin.
Is it?
Yes.
Jongmin, it's Jaehoon and I knowyou're free tomorrow 10:50 pm.
Tomorrow?
Yes.
I've got a schedule.
A schedule?
Yes.
Then you should postpone it.
I'll watch it later for sure.
OK, OK.
So when will it be aired?
Wednesday evening 10:50.
Do not miss it, everyone.
Please say it one more time.
Hello everyone.Mari and I will be aired
on Wednesday evening10:50 pm.
Please do not miss it.
And you should tell thisto your friends
at least to 3 people.
Okay, I will.
To my family.
Not just them.
To 3 of your friends.
- And please prove it.- Send us a picture.
How can I?
You've been betterthan I expected.
Thank you Jongmin.
Jongmin.
Yes?
I think this is it.
Is it?
Jongmin, thank you forbeing so kind
to this unexpected call.
No problem.Bye, bro.
Good.You didn't say any bad words.
Though it is live.
Thanks.
Thanks. Bye.
See you.
When it'll be aired?
On Wednesday,at 10:50 pm.
On which channel?
JTBC?
You don't sound confident.
Thanks, Jongmin.
No problem.
Thank you.
It was good.
Now, it's Hyung-tak's turn.
To his friend.
Is he an actor?
Yes, he is.
Hide the number.
Hello?
Hello.
Yes, bro.
I'm on air now.
Yes.
And um...
Tomorrow, at 10:15 pm...
No, it's 50.
Right. At 10:50 pm.
To remind it one more.
JTBC.
On JTBC, Wednesdayat 10:50 pm.
Right, Minjae.
Are you calling next to him?
I was there for a short time.
So will you watch it tomorrow?
Sure. At home for sure.
Keep your promise, Minjae.
Because you'll be there.
Really?
So I hope you'll watch it.
Alright, bro.
And pleasetell your friends this.
Okay.To more than 3.
Right. More than 3.
Thank you for your timedespite your busy schedules.
Thank you too.
Alright.
- Here you go.- What was it?
And In Guk?
I'll call...
this one.
Who is it?
It's a woman.
Look out the window,See the snowflakes fall.
Hello?
- It's a girl.- Hello.
Hello.
Yes.
What are you doing?
I'm just chilling.
Now...
Yes.
I'm on air.
And nobody knows who you are.Will you introduce yourself?
Hello.I'm Jang Nara.
Who?
Jang Nara. Jang Nara.
It's Jang Nara.
Hello, I'm Lee Jae-hoon.
We're doing
Yes.
a program on JTBC.It's called Mari and I.
We're calling our friends
to promote our program.
Okay.
It'll be aired...
I know when.
Do you?
Yes.
When will it?
Tomorrow at 10:50 pm?
Wow.Unbelievable.
I can't believe this.
She loves pets so much.
We're also fans of her.
Thank you. But I thoughtyou just said Marijuana.
It's live.
Oh, I didn't told you.It's live.
Oh, right.
It's live.
We can edit itwhen we upload it.
But the pronunciationwas confusing.
Would you repeat it?Mari and I.
Mari and I.
Good, good.
Please don't miss it.
Sure.
And please promote itto your friends too.
Sure. I will.
Congratulations.
And you love pets so much.
- I do.- Ask her if she can
sing the song for us.
She loves K-pop too.
Do you know iKon?
Yes.
Do you know their songMy Type too?
Sorry?
Do you know the song?
Do you know iKON?
Say hello.
Hello.
My Type. My Type.
Nice to meet you.
We're iKON.
Hello.
We want to see you.
Okay. See you.
She's an angel.
They're so energeticbecause they're newbies.
Thank you so much.
Good luck.
Thank you.
- Alright. See you.- Thank you.
Talk to you later.
Thank you.
She's the best.
She even knew our time.
That was so kind.
How does she know that?
And it's Minjae's turn.
I will...
Don't call Hyung-tak.
I think he was planning to.
You look you would.
He might not get it.
Hello?
What were you doing?
I just came from toilet.
Toilet?
And now I'm in a waiting room.
Are you shooting something?
Who is this?
I was at Open Concert.
Hide the number.
Open Concert formiddle-aged people.
Isn't he?
- We're now on V app...- Is there someone else?
I'm with some others.
I'm on a live show on V app.
Alright.
And they don't know who you are.Please introduce yourself.
Hello everyone.
I'm Roy Kim.
Roy Kim.
I didn't know it.
Hello?Whom are you with, Minjae?
I'm with Hodong, Jaehoon,
Hyung-tak, In Guk,
B.I of iKON, and Jinhwan.
Huh?
Roy, it's me In Guk.
Oh, hi.
People all around the worldheard you just went to toilet.
I've got a stomachache.
Now, that too...
be heard by all the people.
It's okay.How have you been?
Roy Kim got a stomachache.
We're doing a programcalled Mari and I on JTBC.
Right.
Do you know that?
I know. Oh...
That's why you're with them.
There'll be lots of animals andwe'll communicate with them.
That's a great program.
Tomorrow, at 10:50 pm.
Your fans all around the world
now wants to hear your song,
Roy Kim.
My latest song is good.
Could you sing for us?
Sure I can.
Two, three, four.
Can you see the Cassiopeia?
I hope you'll be waiting for mefor long
with the twinkling starsin the sky
That's it.
You just heard the sickRoy Kim's song.
And they reacted like,
Good luck to yourbowel movement.
So many good comments.
They're worride about youso much.
I feel so good.
There's a mission though.
What's that?
You have to tell aboutour program
to at least 3 of your friends.
Is that it?
Yes.
What's the reward for me?
Happiness.
An exemption fromHodong's punch.
He'll be where you're.Just give us your address.
I'll tell itto 5 friends of mine.
Thank you.
When is it aired?
Tomorrowat 10:50 pm?
On which channel?
JTBC?
Do not miss it.
Alright.Thank you.
Thank you.
- Thank you.- Talk to you later.
He's so sweet.
No one was panickedat our calls.
No one yet.
Like we discussed it before.
Roy even told ushe just went to toilet.
It can't be planned.
Shall I call some special one?
Sure.
Go, Jinhwan.
It's my first time to call him.
Really?
- First call?- Is he a singer?
- For our program.- To help promote
our program.
Great.
I can't believe this.
- Really?- Will he take it?
I really hope he'll take it.
Hello.
Hello?
Yes, Jinhwan.
It's my first call.
Right.
So awkward.
I'm on V app.
Okay.
Our program called Mari and Iwill be aired tomorrow.
I'm really sorry, but can youintroduce our program?
How?
I will introduce you.
Here's Seung Ri of Big Bang.
And I'm here with Hodong
Okay.
Jaehoon, Hyung-tak,
In Guk, Minjae,
and B.I.
- But when...- Hey, Seung Ri.
Hello, Hodong.
What are you doing now?
Do you have time for this call?
I'm in the US now.
We're on vacation now.
So Big Bang's in the US?
We're all indifferent countries.
Then you won't be able towatch our program
tomorrow?
I will on my lap top.
Good.
Great. You can.
- When can he...- How are you Hodong?
He just asked that.
I've been good, Seung Ri.
So good.
How about you?
I'm missing you so much.Really.
Me too.
You're so different now.
Don't be so sweet to me.It's so awkward.
- See you next time.- I'll be there.
When you have time
please be on our program.
Sure. I promise.Thank you.
Thank you so much for your time.
Jinhwan.
Yes, bro.
You and B.I. should begood with Hodong.
We'll do our best.
He's so reasonable.
Alright.
He tell those goodfrom who aren't.
We'll do our best.
Anyways.
Ask him if he was good or not.
If he was good or bad.
How were you?
I was so good thatI even could sit on his lap.
Right...
I was sitting on his lap.
I remember that.
I'll do that too.
I hope iKON will be also able tosit on his lap
and get his compliment.
Alright.
Thank you.And ask him to say
please do not missMari and I.
It'll be aired tomorrowat 10:50 pm.
Yes.
So please promote it.
Thank you.
Is it on KBS?
- No, it's on JTBC.- JTBC.
Oh, is it?I'm sorry.
It's on JTBC, at 10:50 pm.
Thank you.
Besides our program,I hope you and Jinwhan
will be closer.
Jinhwan is sweating too much.
Why are you, Jinhwan?
Don't be so nervous.
You sweat too much.
I'll call you more often.
Really?
I want to tell you something.
The most friendly person to iKONfrom Big Bang
is me.
Right?
Right.
I see.
And I know you're havinga hard time now.
So I'm encouraging them.
It's okay to make mistakes.
And that's my job
to encourage and support them.
So I thinkwe need to meet up more often.
Alright.
Why are you so calm, B.I?
Hello.It's me B.I.
Why do you say hello now?
I'm sorry.
I missed my moment
to say hello.
Be humble.
I'm always.
Please be humble.
I know.
And...
Then I'll see you later.
I'm doing something.
Yes.
Mari and I will be aired on JTBC
at 10:30 pm.
Where are the other 20 mins?
Please don't miss the program.
And YG's newbie,Big Bang's...
with you. Thank you.
We'll talk to you later.
Thank you Jinhwan.Be a good boy.
Alright?Be humble.
Okay.Don't miss our program.
You're sweating like...
Okay.Cheer up.
- Thank you.- Good luck.
Thank you, Hodong.
Thank you Seung Ri.
Jinhwan is sweating like rain.
I think iKON really repects you.
Support them please.
At your service.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Go, Seung Ri.
Go.
Thank you.
I could really
feel his love for you.
I think you should visit himin the US right away.
You're like right aftera performance.
- So exhausted.- Right.
You look like you just hada concert.
After using up all your energy.
And finally, it's B.I's turn.
I'll...
I'm so expecting.
You have to sweat a lot too.
But I'm a bit closer to him.
Anyway, we talked with Seung Ri.
Right.Even he's in the US.
None of us failed yet.
Like we planned in advance.
Exactly.
What happened to your mobile?
Is it iKON thing?
It's the best one.
He should take it.
Who is it?
Hello.
Hello, it's Hanbin.You know me.
I already know who he is.
Sure. I've got your number.
I'm on V app now.
Really?
So no slangs, bro.
Sorry?
No slangs, bro.
I shouldn't say any slsangs now?
I'm okay with that,but right now,
there's DJ Tukutz, a.k.a.Kim Jeong sik is next to me.
Really?
Why you're not calling me?
Hello.
He's Tablo of Epik High.
We'll do a program calledMari and I.
It's on JTBC.
Alright.
And we're promoting it now.
What?
What's the name again?
Mari and I.
Who is Mari?
We're with pets, andMari is like
when we're counting
animals.
Like puppies?
Right.
I knew it.
And it'll be first airedtomorrow at 10:50 pm.
It's applaud.Thank you.
Hanbin.
Yes.
Are you a regular?
Yes, I and Jinhwan.
Oh, really?
Yes.Hodon's here too.
Hello, Hodong.
It's been a while.
How have you been?
I'm so well, bro.
Yes?
How's Hanbin?
He's so good,
and now,
iKON and Hodong are united.
Then what's it called?
iDong?
Let's put it aside now.
So iKON is family ofMari and I.
and you should promotethe program
to all the peoplearound the world.
It's needless to say thatiKON will be
an icon of this generation.
And among them, especially,Hanbin and Jinhwan are the
funniest two.Trust them.
And since when Jinwhan hasrespected Seung Ri
so much?
Like how much?
Seung Ri.
Seung Ri of Big Bang?
Yes. Jinwhan sweated like2L when he talked with him.
I've never heard of it.
Alright. It's okay.
Anyways, Blo,
have you ever raised a pet?
We have. But I'm not sureif iKON has.
They don't have, I think.
What kind of pet do you like?
What animal?
I like puppies.
And I love cats too.
And I'm in to hedgehogs lately.
They are so cute.
Why do you like them?
They're sharp.
Oh.
That's why.
Then please be on our programnext time
with your hedgehog.
Show us how much you love him.
We'll be therewhenever you want us.
Thank you for your time.
And I really mean it.
When you have time,please be with us
and have some good timewith your pet and iKON.
Alright.
We'll shout out the nameto support your program.
Mari and I.
We really thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, bro.
Go.
Thank you. Let's go.
No failure.
I just texted him, and...
But before that,
our staffs told me that
- Nara just posted something.- On her social network?
Like this.
That's what I've got.
It means a lot.
Thank you.
I think Jongmin's also willingto, but he doesn't know how.
He's enthusiastic,but ignorant.
He's so willing to help you
but he doesn't know how to.
So difficult.
Nara is the best.
Jongmin's the best too.
I'll try this one.
He's also very bad atsuch things.
Now, Jaehoon's callinghis friend.
I don't think he's taking it.
Hello.
Hey.
What are you doing?
I'm home.
Are you?Do you know V app?
It's a Internet broadcastingchannel.
And we're live.
On the Internet?
Yes.
Should I watch it now then?
Before that,
please introduce yourself
to us.
Myself?
Yes please.
Do you think will it be okay?
It's okay.
Hello. I'm Bae Seong woo.
Not your real name.Your name for TV.
Mr. Bae.
Oh, my broadcasting name?
It's Peter these days.
Peter?
Just tell us yourfamous name.
Oh, the famous one.
I'm Tak Jae hoon.
It's him.
We're now
Someone else's there?
It's quite noisy.
We're being aired now.
And at 10:50 pm tomorrow,
Yes?
Where should I be?
You should
sit in front of TV.
And turn on JTBC.And from 10:50 pm
Mari and I will be airedfor the first time.
Mari and I?
JTBC?
Congratulations.
For the first time?
Please support us.
How could you choose meto support you?
I'm not sureif it's good or not.
Congratulations on your start.
And I think many things arechanging
in the broadcasting.
So I hope this kind of shows
will prosper.
Hey, Jaehoon.
Who's this?
It's me. Hodong.
Why are you there?
I'm also doing this program too.
Really?
I'm an animal in this program.
I know you're a busy man.
But I'm feeling good because
while we're talking with youon the phone, our live show
got more than 1 million hearts.
Really?
The hearts?
Right. The hearts of love.
Is it heart?Not star balloons?
Hearts cost nothing.
And I know you love pets.
And you're now raising one.
Right.
If you have some occasions of
leaving your pets to others,
we'll take care of your pet
with much of love and care.
I see.
And how about saying something
to our viewers?
When you can't staywith your pet
for some reasons,
just let us know.Then we'll take care of it.
Like a hotel
of puppies?
Exactly.
We'll be pet sitters.
Alright.
Isn't it assuringto let your pet
be with us?
Not really.Because I know you're all
too busy to care my pet.
You and Jaehoon,
all are so busy.
But it's my honor
if you'll take care of
my pet.
Not at all.
I think you should watch us
on tomorrow's episodeat 10:50 pm.
Here's Mr. Shim Hyung-tak too.
Hello.We've met before.
Right. We've met before.
And it was...
You do that too?
Yes. I'm trying my best.
Congratulations.
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
Here's In Guk too.
Hello.I'm Seo In Guk.
Right. I know you.
It's been so long.
Yes. I'm seeing you on TV.
Thank you.
And here's Minjae.
Why Hyung-tak is sorry though?
I haven't contacted you a lot.
You shouldn't be sorry.I'm worse.
If you're sorry for that,I should die.
I'm sorry.
And here's iKON
and Minjae.
Hello. We're newbies.
- We're iKON.- Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.We really want to see you.
I'm not sureif I can talk friendly
because they're so many people
who are close to me.
It's okay to talk friendly.
We're way too younger.
Really?
Nice to meet you anyway.
Nice to meet you.
So what time tomorrow?
10:50 pm.
And the title is?
The title?Mari and I?
Yes. Mari and I.
Please don't miss it.
I was so happy.I thought you wanted to meet me.
But it wasn't.
Please watch us tomorrow.
Okay. I will.
- Thank you.- Thank you.
It was Tak Jae hoon.It's so nice to hear him.
So we called our friends
to promote our program.
And now
iKON's B.I and Jinhwan...
it's so upcoming.
It's tomorrow evening.
So please wrap this up
by saying don't miss it.
Mari and I will be airedon JTBC at 10:50 pm.
We hope many of you will
enjoy it a lot.
Thank you. Let's go.
La-la-la-la
1, 2, 3, 4.
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-laLa-la-la-la-la-la-la-la
Mari and I.