the party
It's Christian. I'm here.
I arrived this morning.
sorry ?
If I washed ?
No, did shave though, at the airport.
I shaved at the airport.
Good. I'm watching the landscape.
From my father. It's beautifull here.
I wish I could live here again.
But that's impossible.
I'll manage.
Yes, it will be a shock.
What ? I'm loosing you.
Oké. Bye.
Damn. That's my brother.
Why are you so quite ?
I didn't recognise him.
Have to do everything myself.
Christian, what are you doing here?
You see that, Kasper ?
He came all the way from Paris by foot.
No, I didn't. Only from the station.
Hi.
- Cool, man.
I'll get you.
Giddyup. I'll get you.
Damn.
- You're in a good mood.
It's been a long time. Unbelievable.
How are you ?
I'll give you a lift.
Get out, kids.
I'm giving Christian a lift.
- There's room enough.
Come, Mette.
Get in the frontseat.
- I'll walk.
I have to talk to you.
- Do we have to walk all the way ?
What are you whining about ?
- It's an end.
He's my brother, damnit.
Stop whining.
Shut up.
Come on be quite.
You think dad is already there ?
- No, not yet.
Hi, what's your name ?
- Lars.
Lars. Listen up.
I always have problems with new staff.
Just to let you know.
Who do you think we are ?
This is Christian, my brother.
He owns two restaurants in Paris.
I run a cafetaria at the harbour.
We've grown up here,
so we know how to treat customers.
A good receptionist
knows everybody's name.
We would like room 9 and room 19.
You're not on the list.
What's that ?
- Look again. Michael Klinkenfeldt.
Your father said you're not welcome.
Listen, Mads...
- My name is Lars.
Lars, last year I've gone a bit too far
, because I was drunk.
When I drink too much "schnaps",
I completely lose it.
I brought my wife and children.
Michelle is here too.
I didn't know about that.
Do you have a room for us ?
Where's my father ?
- He went hunting.
Then you'll take care of it yourself.
That's your job isn't it ?
Give him a room.
I'll talk to my father.
One of the small rooms.
They're never used.
3 and 1.
This one is okay.
Don't you want a key ?
- O, yeah.
I'm on his list.
Is little sis' already there ?
Hurry up.
My father turns 60 today.
Those people are family.
I'll have to welcome them.
Your name is Nadim ?
- That's wright.
Nadim, if you speed up,
I'll give you my phonenumber.
Hello, are you ready ?
They should be here any minute.
Have you been drinking ?
- Not today.
What a fantastic funeral, ey ?
I'm ready.
- What are you doing here ?
You where not at your sisters funeral.
What business is that of yours ?
I want to know why you were not there.
You where not at the funeral.
You don't call on birthdays,
You don't show any interest.
Now you got her started too.
I'm going home.
Have a nice trip.
- Wanne lend my bycicle ?
I'm not in the mood for this.
- O stop it. Let bygones be bygones.
Yes, stop it.
- You sound like Christian.
Don't.
Come.
Stop it.
- Listen to Christian.
Stop. Don't do it.
Honk again. Maybe they'll hear us.
That's his wife, with a son.
That's Mette.
And the three chickens.
Everything okay ?
Quite guys, we're here.
Behave yourself.
That's impossible. I'm your sister.
Luckily we only do this
once every decade.
Welcome, grandfather.
- Thank you.
Thanks for the nice funeral.
Good to see you again.
Hello. Warm here.
I'm going to unpack my wife.
Hi, daddy.
I'm the master of ceremonies tonight,
okay ?
Do you know Lissy  ?
How do you do ?
- It's sad...
and then the beautifull weather...
You haven't changed one bit.
- Thank you.
Welcome. Helge is waiting for you inside.
Hello, uncle.
Christian, sweetheart.
Glad to see you here.
You're looking good.
- The guests are here.
Go to your father.
Don't forget to congratulate him.
Daddy, happy birthday.
Everyone's waiting.
- I have to tell you something important.
Sit down.
Please.
You want some cognac too ?
- No, thanks.
This is very important.
I've been thinking about it for days.
Listen.
Two hookers are in a train.
Don't make fun of your old father.
On his birthday.
How dare you ?
I should tell your mother.
We're waiting for you.
- He's making fun of me.
You shouldn't, Christian.
- Tell a joke.
I would like to have a word with my
oldest son. How are you ?
Good.
I have a company in Lyon...
I read the papers too, you know.
Business is good.
How's that girlfriend of yours ?
Can't you come back ?
She already has children with another man.
- Then find another girlfriend.
I'm getting older.
I want to have you near me.
And then your mother...
- What's wrong with her ?
She's fed up with my jokes.
- I can understand that.
What do you mean ?
What's wrong with my jokes ?
Where's your respect ?
So how are you ? You have a girlfriend ?
O, I asked that already.
Come now.
- We're comming.
Come, son. One more thing...
Would you like to say something
about your sister tonight?
I can't.
Alright. I've written something down.
- You did ? great.
Michael is here too.
- I'll have to talk to him then.
Our visitors are here.
Michelle, are you maried ?
- No.
Ask someone else.
O yeah, that was my other son.
I'll discuss this with him.
It's Helge's birthday.
hurrah, hurrah, hurrah.
he's getting lots of presents
and cookies and chocolat.
Hi. Where do you sleep ?
- Room 17. Why ?
I have to use your bath.
I mean, can I use your bath ?
And the sound of the sea.
I'll put them down here.
The main course is secret.
You've been hunting ?
- As usual.
You're listening ? Good.
We were moving to Copenhaven
for the third time.
But then Bettina H. moved in with him.
Bettina H. ?
So I'm still here.
I walked throught the park yesterday.
I'm in the room where my sister died.
Better you then Christian. She was his twinsister.
That no one wants to talk it is one...
but it's stupid to act like nothing
happeded.
Look at that, like a fairytale.
- You can say that.
Spooky. She wouldn't have like this herself.
Shall we take of the sheets ?
I'll stay with her then.
I don't mind.
Yes, ofcourse.
- Good.
Here's where it took place.
In the bathroom.
Or shall I take another room?
- If you want to.
It's so...
It doesn't feel good.
Did you hear that ?
She's in the bathroom.
It can't be. She's dead.
I'll have a look.
Come on, let's go.
- No, let's have a look.
Mette, I can't find them.
- Did you look in the suitcases?
I can't find my shoes.
- They'll have to be in there.
I already looked there.
- Just relax.
I can't wear brown shoes.
- They should be there.
I looked everywhere.
Then I just forgot them.
- You must be kiddin'.
Go get them then. You have two hours.
By car.
Don't be crazy.
- My father's going to be furious.
Shall I get them ?
What will your parents think ?
I can't wear these shoes to diner, idiot.
Pack your own stuff then.
I packed for all of us.
Everything's got to be perfect.
If you have complaints,
you can pack your own stuff next time.
I'll tell you something.
You're the one who's packing.
And every time you forget my shoes.
You wanted to visit your stupid
parents.
I worked for a confectioner once.
I'm making dessert tonight.
What does that mean, an arrow up?
If you lie down in the bath,
you'll maybe see something.
Do I have to lie down in the bath ?
Do I have to ?
- Try if you see something.
A sign or an arrow.
A fish or a bird.
Remember tracking?
Doesn't work.
- Sorry.
I ironed it on purpose.
- Yes, I'm sorry.
Shall we lie down
Are you not going to the party ?
Come on, lie down for a minute.
There, a fish. That means "thin"
and that means "down".
I don't get this game.
Strange.
We were always tracking back then.
Come here. Sit down.
Have a look at the other leg.
How nice of her.
I almost can't take it.
I'm the only one left. You are all going
to Paris and God knows where...
Don't start crying now.
- Sorry.
Please.
- If you want me to leave, just say so.
I thought you wanted to take a bath.
Another arrow. And another.
Could you...
How can I help ?
- loose this.
I have beautiful buttocks.
Don't they get more then a bath ?
Look, there.
The other side.
Wher the light is attached.
Dear finder of this letter.
You must be...
Jezus.
There's nothing in it.
Damn.
Did you put all that soap here ?
Why is all that soap here ?
You used it yourself.
Shit.
- Did you hurt yourself?
Ofcourse I hurt myself.
There have always been ghosts here.
It makes no sense.
I'll sleep here.
Thank you for your help.
Where you really scared ?
- O, no.
a little ? Sorry.
Thanks for your help.
Why was that soap there ?
- You did that yourself.
No I didn't.
- You used it.
Where are my trousers ?
- How should I know. There?
For once take care of your stuff.
I'm not a babysit.
Shut up.
- Please, come on.
The damn thing has come down.
Then don't hang it up again.
- Hell not.
Fun, You used to be the one to argue
Now it's your brother.
You don't even look at beautiful girls.
You think I'm too skinny.
I'll hide it here.
No one should find it.
There.
Where have you gone,
dear Christian ?
6 o'clock. Time to get up.
Tickets, please.
Or other papers...
My pants.
Hello, grandpa.
- Hi, dad.
In five minutes in the livingroom.
Damn shoes.
Everything okay.
Hello Poul, you're okay ?
Hello, dad.
It'll be fine.
We have to go in now.
I've been told to ask you if
you're interested in the lodge.
It just doesn't look like it's
something you're interested in.
but Christian recommended you to
Preben. He isn't interested himself.
So I guess they'll ask you for the
freemasons.
Bend the iron while it's still hot.
We will help you to get on.
But behave like a normal person tonight.
And keep your hands of
whats-her-name , Michelle.
Will you take care of things tonight?
Can you ?
Give him something to drink.
Watch out.
Do you have a drink already ?
- We have to talk.
I don't have time.
You do remember something ?
Sure.
- Fine.
I think I'll make a speech tonight.
I thought so.
Not suited for little girls.
I bet.
You were fallen asleep.
Don't you sleep well ?
Only when you're here.
I'm honoured to be master of
ceremonies...
on this party of
Klingenfeldt-Hansen family.
My name is Helmuth von Sachs.
I'm from Germany.
Cologne, "Ruhr-area", steel industry.
Helge is also a man of steel.
Unbreakable.
Helge, friend, Danish stepfather,
the audience is yours.
As I see you all in front of me,
I have to think about recent years...
and everything that happened.
It's not special turning 60.
It all seems like yesterday...
the moment we closed the negotiations
and bought the landed estates.
Still, it was 1971...
the year our family walked up the stairs.
My beloved wife, Helene...
Michael, the twins...
Yes, the twins.
All of us we settled in this
beautiful house.
We had...
high expectations.
I'll stop here.
Let's make it a wonderful party.
Let's eat.
First course.
Ready... go.
There.
Wasn't it a beautiful ride ?
- It was extremely hot.
You do have airconditioning ?
- It gets me a dry mouth.
It doesn't feel comfortable.
The kids are here too.
Give me a little water.
I'm all wet.
She spilled.
What's your name, girl ?
- I'm Mette.
M-E-T-T-E.
- That's true.
Lobstersoup. Delicious.
- No, it's salmonsoup.
Salmon ?
It tastes like lobster though.
It's delicious soup.
- Yes, tomatosoup.
It's no tomatosoup..
It is lobstersoup.
Exactly.
- Cheers.
Oldest son holds speech.
Morten...
It is almost seven and I would like
to propose the first toast.
That's my duty after all
as the oldest son. Isn't it Helmuth ?
But first a speech.
I've written two, dad.
A green and a yellow.
You may choose.
Green or Yellow ?
- Green.
That's a good choice.
It's a confession speech
It's called: when dad goes in bath.
When we moved here,
I was still small.
Our lives changed entirely.
We had lots of space to do
naughty things.
In those days this room was
a restaurant...
and I don't know how often my sister Linda,
who is dead now...
and I played here.
She put things in the food,
but no one noticed...
And then we had and she laughed.
She had a great laugh...
and pretty soon we were both
laughing out loud.
That's how we got caught.
But we never got punishment.
It was much more dangerous
when dad took a bath.
He took a bath quite often.
First he called for Linda and me to come
because something happened before bathing.
He closed the door and the curtains.
Then he undressed
and we had to undress too.
He put us on the green couch...
and raped us.
He used us sexually.
When my sister passed away
a couple of months ago...
I thought: Isn't Helge a proper girl,
with all the bathing..
That's what I wanted to share with you.
He bathed in the summer, winter,
in the morning, in the evening...
He's very clean.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
It's his 60'th birthday,
after all.
He watched his children and
grandchildren grow up.
But you're not here for my speech...
But for Helge's 60'th birthday.
Thanks for all the wonderful years.
Happy birthday.
I have nothing to drink.
Fill the glasses.
Christian, you were always the first
ofcourse. But now it's my turn.
Elsie, It's your birthday today.
Helge.
- What's he saying ?
That it's Helge birthday today.
Helge, it's your birthday. That's nice.
You're a big boy now. You can handle
the story of the seven seas now.
Way to go, grandpa.
- I have to leave.
When Helge was a little boy...
He told me once he couldn't find
a girlfriend.
Kim...
Hello, Christian.
- Hello. I've got to catch my plane.
Attention.
This is my childhood friend Christian.
You already know most of them.
How do you do ?
Good.
- Everything fine ?
Good. You held your speech and
now you're going home
The battle is lost.
Nothing has changed.
Are you drunk ?
- Otherwise I can't cook.
How long do we know eachother ?
Since the year nil ?
We used to steal apples together.
I've waited for years for this
and now you're walking away.
For your father, who decided on yours
and your sisters fate..
Brilliant, to let him decide
on his fate in your speech..
What's your point, Kim ?
I would like to say something too.
I hope you won't take Christian
too seriously.
He's my brother
and I love him very much...
but his story is not completely true.
and I should know.
Sorry that I speak up so late,
but I'm still shocked.
At a quarter past seven,
your father will give me instructions.
He'll say:
I think they like it.
And then he drinks a drop.
Give me two minutes.
I thought you had left already.
A drink for me and my son.
The food is delicious.
They liked the first course.
Here.
- No, thank you.
You don't want it ?
It tastes good. Damn good.
I take your word.
Have one too and put the bottle away.
Come. Alone.
Come.
How are you doing ?
- Good.
Really ?
I don't understand it.
I can't remember.
- What do you mean ?
What you told...
I can't remember.
Help me here.
What has happened ?
I'm sorry. I guess I'm wrong.
Don't apologize.
I'm kind of busy at work.
And then there's Linda...
Don't think about it.
Where you're aiming at, is a crime.
We have to go to the police.
No, we don't.
Don't think about it anymore.
I don't sleep well, lately.
I feel a bit strange.
Everything alright upstairs?
- Yes, fine.
They're not shocked that easily.
Everything's okay.
Have a good journey and thanks
for being here.
I have to go back.
Helge, it's your birthday today.
- not again, grandpa.
You're a big boy now. You can handle
the story about the seven seas.
When Helge was a little boy...
He told me he couldn't get
a girlfriend.
I told him, listen boy...
buy a big potatoe
and stick it in your swimmingtrunk.
Then you'll go to the lake.
They will push eachother aside for you.
When the summer came...
What do you think ?
- Me ?
I don't know what he's up to.
He was desperate.
It was even worse then before.
No one wanted to talk to him.
Obviously, I said.
You have to stick that potatoe
in the front.
Michelle, Pia, I want to say something.
Come here. Listen.
We steal their carkeys.
We ?
- Okay.
This night is for Christian.
They can't go home yet.
But he apologized.
We'll wait.
Don't tell the old servants.
And now get out.
We can't leave any traces.
- No, we're careful.
I got them.
Next.
Everything okay ?
Are there any problems ?
No, everything's fine.
Is my brother staying over ?
- I don't know.
There's a cab.
I'll take a look.
Hello, Charlie Brown.
You're wrong here.
Do you speak English?
It's a private party.
Not for passengers.
I'm invited.
- Can I leave ?
One moment.
We don't need any music.
No trumpet.
Ga home. Here,  500 kronen.
That's for the cab too.
Go home.
- I'm not playing. I'm invited.
You're not Helene's brother ?
I don't know how you know my sister
and I don't even want to know...
Hello. I've missed you so.
Good to see you here.
What are you doing here ?
- He tried to send me away.
What's happening ?
- Behave yourself.
How dare you invite that monkey
on my fathers birthday?
How dare you call Gbatokai a monkey.
- Relax.
Filthy nazi.
Go.
Mum, this is my friend, Gbatokai.
This is my mother.
Welcome. Nice to see you again.
You never met him.
That was someone else.
Nice to meet you.
- Same here.
Good. This way.
I almost forgot the most important.
We're gathered here for my fathers
birthday.
I fooled you all.
I would like to propose a toast
to my father.
Could everyone rise please ?
- Well done, Christian.
Lift your glasses.
To the man who killed my sister.
To a murderer.
I suggest we take a break .
Cigarettes, hurry up.
Hurry up.
Play something. Something light.
Play.
We'll stay for a minute.
We can't leave anyway.
Have you lost your mind ?
Do you hear me ?
Have you completely lost your mind ?
Make sure no one leaves.
He's sick, for christ'sake.
Again, I've called...
I want a taxi.
- one minute.
I can't stand this.
I'm already depressed.
There won't be a cab. I'll walk.
I'm fed up with their parties.
Do you know where the car keys are?
I can't find the keys.
- Problems ?
I can't take it.
I'm already depressed.
The line's still busy.
The waiting-time is 11 months.
- Could I have Kim please ?
Take it easy, Lars.
Hide those keys.
- In the oven.
No, in the refrigerator.
They're gone.
Where is Michelle, damn it ?
Come in, damn it.
I want to have a word with you.
And you.
Go away.
- I want to talk to you.
Do you know what happened, Mette ?
- Come.
This way.
Let go.
- Take it easy.
What do you want fro me ?
- Last year you promissed me something.
Then you came at night.
And now you won't even talk to me.
I'm sorry. But my wife is here too.
She used to be unimportant.
I got pregnant that time.
I had it removed.
But you should know.
My father turns sixty today
and everything is out of control.
Hey there.
Hello, Bent. Is this your room ?
I was just leaving.
Have you seen my car keys ?
I'll just look around if I see them.
You really haven't seen them ?
If I don't find them, I'll get depressed.
I know. Just go downstairs.
Pack your things and go home.
Here's your wage. Now fuck off.
You're as crazy as your father.
I won't let you piss of my family.
Imagine I hold a speech.
About you.
About how unstable you where.
That you always spoiled everything
for other children.
Burned their toys.
That you've always been a complete
lunatic.
That we had to come to France...
where they kept you in a mental
institution...
because you were completely crazy
and drugged.
at despair of your mother.
That you were extremely uncomfortable
with women.
Year after year you passed on
beautiful women...
because your a man of nothing.
I could tell about your sister,
you and your sister.
What about that ?
Did she say goodbye to you?
Was there a card or a letter? No.
For the others though.
She must have had her reasons.
You just abandoned here.
Like always.
You abandoned your sick sister.
She kept asking about you and
runned for the phone...
but you never called.
You were only interested in yourself.
And now you're dissing your family.
While we just want to see you happy.
Your mother wants you to leave.
I think you should stay.
Then you know how it feels to
blacken your family.
After this little pianical intermezzo...
table's ready again.
I'm hungry.
May I ask you ?
They're ready.
Christian doesn't look happy.
haunch of venison and cranberry's. Go ahead.
cheers, grandpa.
You speeched wonderfully.
Don't shout in my ear.
You still got us.
Salt and pepper. Cheers.
Champagne. I want champagne and caviar.
Hello, Christian.
Looks like you're very popular with
the servants.
Sometimes it gives good results
if you stir things up.
The way you dare to say with all
the servants around:
Mum, dad, you're no good.
I'm sorry.
Keep up with it just a little longer.
If you only survive this evening.
If the birthdayboy is my Danish father...
then Elsie is my Danish mother.
She is everybodies "Mutti".
Elsie, the word is yours.
Applause, please.
Thanks Helmuth and the others.
I would like to thank you all
for coming today.
And I would like to say some
thankful words to my husband, Helge.
It's not easy. Words can not
describe...
how much you still mean to me.
Besides your lust for life
and good care for your family...
you've gave me everything a woman
can ask for.
It has been 30 wonderful years.
Thank you very much.
I would also like to say a few
words to the children.
It is wonderful to see you're
all doing well...
Especially when I think how small
you all have been.
Michael, you're our youngest.
the benjamin.
We've never seen much of you.
You went to boarding-school when
you were still a little boy.
And after that to the hotel
school in Switzerland.
You never became a cook,
but that can still be.
You're given us 3 wonderful
grandchildren.
And we're thankful for that.
And ofcourse little Mette.
And Helene,
the "weirdo" of the family .
That's what you are ?
Ever since you told us you wanted
to become a singer...
and you joined the Trotsk...
the socialistic youth...
we knew you would go your own way.
and you have.
in life and in studdy.
You've become an antropologist.
though we hoped you'd gone to
lawschool.
But there are hardly any cultures and
countries...
which you didn't visit.
With this I want to welcome your
boyfriend to the family. Gonzales.
His name is Gbatokai.
Welcome, Kai.
And then we have Christian.
You were always very special.
a creative child.
He made up some wonderful stories.
I always saw him a great writer.
When Christian was little,
and only few know...
he had a loyal friend, mug...
who didn't exist.
Mug and Christian
could not be seperated.
If Mug didn't want something,
then Christian would neither.
And no one could change that.
But, dear Christian...
You have to seperate reality
from fiction.
You were never good at that.
Ofcourse you're sometimes angry of
your father. I am sometimes too.
But you'll have to solve that between
the both of you.
You've told us exiting stories tonight...
maybe a bit too exiting.
I think Mug was with you tonight.
You've scared daddy very much.
It seems apropriate to me if you
stand up now...
without Mug...
and apologize yourself.
It's not a shame to apologize
yourself.
It's even good.
So just rise please.
Come on, Christian. Do something.
He is confused.
- Christian.
Sorry to bother you again.
In 1974 my mother entered the
study once.
Her son was on his knees.
Her husband had his pants down.
Her husband said, go away.
And she did.
You are so hypocrite.
Please just die.
That you assholes even listen to this
woman.
I'm sorry that you all for thirty
years...
Let me finish.
- Let's go.
Relax, man. Let's go outside.
Give me my coat.
- You'll get your coat.
You were ate school. You knew nothing.
But now you know.
You're crossing the line.
- Now you know. Don't you ?
You're going to far. Fuck of.
- Go away.
Lock the door.
Is it locked ?
- I think so.
Where was I?
Mother, my loyal witness.
In 1974 you saw how father
rubbed his hard cock through my hair...
Filthy bastard.
You're an asshole.
- Fuck of.
Assholes.
He's not okay.
Sad, go on mother.
ther's a quite idyll
in the lonelyness of the forest
where troubles are taken away
where silence and piece reigned
Throw him of the stairs.
Get lost, man.
Get the hell out of here.
Don't, Leif. He's still my brother.
Go away.
Get him.
Christian, come here.
The game is over. Is that clear?
Have you had enough ?
Not with that, he's my brother.
Come.
- Where are we going?
To the forest.
This has got to stop.
How far ?
- As long as we'll get rid of him.
What do you mean?
- Shut up. Here.
We'll leave him there by the tree.
Damn. That's alright.
Do we really have to tie you to this
tree, Christian ?
How did you come up with all that
nonsense?
Come on.
Let's go.
- Shut your mouth.
Did you tie him?
I've had enough of this.
Slow down.
- That's good enough.
Keep quite, Christian.
Do you have a smoke for me?
I dropped mine.
I'll just check if the doors are locked.
Where's your brother ?
- I won't talk to him.
What have you done with him ?
- Relax.
I had a word with him. He's gone home.
He was sorry.
You'll hear the rest later.
So you put him to bed and said
goodnight.
Are you looking for trouble?
- Piece of shit.
Stop it, Michael.
What did you say ?
- Stop it, Michael.
Stop it, damnit.
Get out..
Hello, Kim.
- Hey, Leif.
We should lock the backdoor.
Where is it?
That way.
It's not good.
You didn't hit him?
- He's not coming back.
Here it is.
This is the wineceller.
- Exactly. There.
What's this ?
Kim, what are you doing ?
Did you lock him up ?
All these troublemakers running around...
Don't touch.
- Where is Christian ?
No idea.
Don't get drunk now.
To your brother.
- What's that ?
- Why no speech ?
A speech ?
I know what that's like here.
Watch out, or I'll do it.
Time for a happy song.
I saw a little nigger just lately...
a racist song.
he talked really weird and
had a ring through his nose.
I asked him what kind are you ?
why are your legs covered with tar ?
he smiled and said:
It looks like a christmas song.
fidliha kola tomrassi gassi bum
the black mass comes from Umblagidarum
I saw a little Indian just lately...
his face was fire-red
he talked very weird.
I can't stand it.
They'll kill eachother.
I'm going crazy.
I've got a terrible headache.
Could you get me my pills ?
Hve you seen Christian ?
- He's gone home.
That's good.
- I'm going to get your pills.
You are all crazy, aah ,my head.
Aren't you drunk yet?
- It takes a lot.
It's almost ten o'clock.
Something special is going to happen
in a minute.
Alfred Hitchcock wanted on his
grave:
That's the way it ends with
naughty boys.
Helge, you too will not escape the
strange traditions of this family.
Time for the big finale.
It's daddy's birthday today
daddy's birthday today
listen...
how we play the trumpet
it's daddy's birthday today,
listen...
how we play the flute
You've dropped something.
Be carefull for once.
I want to go home.
- I can imagine that.
Are you leaving already ?
I want to go home.
- Don't be foolish. There's still dessert.
Listen. It's going to be okay.
Trust me.
I can feel it.
Really ?
- Come.
Doesn't this family have some
neat traditions.
After the polonaise the master of
ceremonies finds a note on his glass.
And that's also the way it is today.
A man asks his sister...
to read a letter to her father.
Helene is a bit too shy to do it
herself, isn't that so Helene?
Whatever...
it's sweet of your brother
that he helps you to get started.
I think piece has returned to the
family.
Applause for Helene, please.
Go ahead, Helene.
Don't be shy.
Michael, just ignore him.
He is...
He is from my sister.
Dear finder of this letter.
You are probably my sister or my
brother.
Because you're good in tracking.
Hi-hi, laughter-laughter.
I know it's scary to find me in a bath
full of water.
But it's not scary for me.
My brothers and my sister...
are happy, gay people.
I love you.
Don't think too much of me.
Christian, sweet brother...
You were alway here with me.
Thanks for everything.
I don't want you to get involved.
I love you too much for that.
And you, Helene
and you too Michael, idiot.
Daddy is raping me again.
In my dreams, again.
I can't take it anymore.
I'll leave.
I should've done it much earlier.
I know I will fill your life with
darkness, Christian.
I tried to call you...
but I know you're busy.
I don't want you to feel sad.
I think it's light and beautiful on
the other side.
I'm looking forward to it.
Although I'm a bit scared too.
I'm scared to go without you.
I 'll love you eternaly.
Linda.
What a beautifull letter.
Give her port...
so we can raise our glasses.
Pour my daughter some port,
so we can raise glasses too.
Give her port, damnit.
Give her port.
Show some respect.
Have you ever seen something like this.
What are you looking at. Well ?
Is it my fault my children have no talent?
I never understood why you did it.
You were no good for anything else.
It's not easy being master of
ceremonies tonight.
And it's my first time too.
I'm pretty drunk.
Like all of us.
And still I consider it...
- I'm leaving.
my duty to finish diner in a positive
way.
So let's go on and have some coffee and
cake.
Goodnight.
I've put the carkeys back.
Can I have a glass of water?
Shall I call a doctor ?
Are you okay ?
Come.
I was sleeping.
Pia, my sister is here.
I love you.
I miss you.
I miss you too.
Shall I come with you ?
I'm off again.
It's Helene.
- What time is it ?
Three o'clock. I slept too.
If you can call it sleeping.
You know... I have...
Maybe you too.
What do you mean?
- Forget it.
Come here. Michael is gone.
What's going on ?
He's gone and his wife is furious.
She's in my room.
Is the party still going on ?
- I don't think so.
Don't worry.
They've all gone to bed.
Where are the glasses?
Where is Michelle ?
With Kim.
Everybody sleeps in a wrong bed.
Not us, ey darling ?
We don't do that.
We don't sleep in the wrong bed.
I have a glass for Christian.
- I want one too.
As long as it's not someone else's.
Play the weddingmars.
Gbatokai and Helene must dance.
Because I think you should get married.
Dad ?
It's me, Michael. I'm on my way.
Open up.
I'm the postman, damnit.
Open up, damn it.
Open up.
Go inside and close the door.
Michael, stop it.
Stop it.
- Go back inside.
Shut up, I said.
I told you to shut up.
Come.
Lie down.
And stay down.
I heard enough filth.
Lie down, I said.
I won't see your grandchildren again.
Never again, is that clear?
You destroyed the family.
Lie.
lie down, I said.
It's me. Michael.
I'm ringing the frontdoorbell.
It can't happen.
Be quite.
What's wrong ?
- It can't happen.
They need to stop.
Go there, Gbatokai.
- Your father...
Stop it, Michael.
You're killing me.
Ober, could I have something to drink ?
I like to start the day with a drink.
Morten, what are you thinking of ?
O... it's happened.
At least she's feeling okay.
Goodmorning.
- Have a sandwich.
Where is Leif, damnit ?
O, there you are.
How's your wig ?
- Wher do you have your clothes
wrinkled?
In Naestved.
Would you like to come live with me
in Paris ?
I'd love to.
That was all.
Hey, are you in love with the new waitress?
Shut up and eat.
- I will eat a loaf of bread.
Goodmorning.
Goodmorning everyone. Enjoy your breakfast.
Dorthe, come to grandpa.
Your father will read it to you.
I know that this is not the right moment.
You're all having breakfast.
I'll keep it short.
I only want to say that I know...
That I,
When all of you have gone home...
never will see you again.
And I understand now...
that it's unforgivable
what I've done to my children.
And I know that all of you...
and especially my children...
will hate me for the rest of my
live.
Still, you'll always be my children.
I always loved you and will keep
doing so for the rest of my life...
where ever in this world you may be.
Christian, to you I would like to say...
you put up a good fight.
Thank you.
That was a beautiful speech.
But now you'll have to leave.
So we can have breakfast in peace.
Ofcourse.
Are you coming ?
- I stay here.
Translation by doctor_virgin  :-)
visit:    www.filenexus.com