Subtitles by josmndsn
I'll be doing it.
What y'all digging around for?
A dead body.
Well, it's bad for business.
A cold beer?
No, thanks. I'm not thirsty.
Oh, who says you gotta be thirsty
to drink a cold beer ...
mister FBI man?
[speaking in French]
My name is Nicholas Mark Randall.
I'm sixteen years old.
My mother's name is ... Kimberly Miller.
My sister's name is Kathy Jansen.
I was kidnapped.
Kimberly Miller?
Yeah.
I was raped ... tortured.
I was scared, all the time.
I just want to go home.
Mom ...
What are you doing here?
Is there anyone in here?
They say they found Nicky.
Your sister is here.
Oh, Nicky ...
Nicky.
Hi, guys.   Hey, babe.
Hey, Nick.
How are you, man?
So, Brian and me thought it would be
better if you stayed with us for now.
Right, Brian?
Yeah.
We got a room all set up for you.
It's just, um, Mom ain't ready to have
you at her place ... yet.
You know, she needs time to get
used to this.
You'll be just fine with us, Nicky.
You'll see.
Yo.
Welcome home, Nicky.
Welcome home.
So, when you're use the shower
Watch out.
Hot and cold are the wrong way around.
It's the faucets.  Brian's been talking
about fixing it for years.
What are you babbling about, Kathy?
You're acting like Nicky never had
had a sleepover here, before.
Yeah, of course.
I know, I'm just so happy ...
I don't know what I'm saying, sorry.
I love you, Mom.
Let's go.
We, a, we went fishing.
Babe, this is so good.
What's up, man? Don't you like
your sister's cooking, anymore?
Fried chicken's your favorite.
Brian, let him be, okay. He's not
a child anymore, his tastes have changed.
Well, I'll eat it tomorrow.
Did, ... did I come here often?
You, ... you don't remember?
Things come and go.
Sometimes, I have flashes of memory
and other times, ...  it's like big
chunks of my life are missing.
But, the doctors say it's only natural
after what I went through.
They'll come back,
bit by bit.
Hey, wait a second.
Album time.
She does this a lot.
Let's see what I got here.
Okay, so ...
Here's you in the yard,
it was your birthday ... 10 years old.
Isn't he cute?
Yeah.
And, ...God ... this is that, um,
that trip we took to Disneyland.
You remember that?
Vaguely.
Here's Mom and Brendan.
You haven't forgotten about Brendan,
have you?
Brendan is his brother.
I'm sure he's gonna come see you soon.
No big rush. Right, Nick?
Who's Nicholas Mark Randall?
A sixteen year old.
Found after he went missing four years ago.
Kidnapping. When he first disappeared,
the BRPD headed the look for him.
He turns up, just like that.
After, four years?
Alive and well?
It's a miracle.
You mean, you still believe in miracles.
Oh, yeah. Absolutely.
Hey, just like old times, huh?
Here, ...
Take some corn to Mom.
She'll like that.
Go on, off you go.
Here.
I'm sorry.
Go on, go get me another.
Not too cold, huh?
All right.
Clumsy as ever.
I'll get it.
Do you have another beer for Mom?
Yeah, in the cooler. Help yourself.
Not too cold. That, I remember.
She is just so happy to see us
all here together.
And, ... she can barely believe it.
Yeah, me neither.
Look, ... she needs time.
More than we do.
Yeah, ... right.
That was Brendan. He's almost here.
Shit.
Why don't you open it for me?
I don't want him to see what Nicky,
okay?
I'll take care of it. Trust me.
Yeah, but ... it's not that I don't
trust you, I just don't ...
I'll bring him inside, okay?
No, I should go, okay?
Okay.
This is your fault.
This is your fucking fault.
Get him the fuck out of here.
Don't you fucking give me orders.
This is my home, I do what I want.
I don't give a shit what you think.
I'm not scared of you.
Is this the heroine in you?
Some kind of fucking saint?
Is that what you're trying to be?
Get the fuck out of my home.
Fuck you.
And don't you dare let Nicky see you.
Dumb bitch.
[Mom's voice coming from digital camera]
Brendan, stop that.
Just leave him alone.
Leave him alone.
Cut it out now.
Goddamn it.
You're a strung up shit.
Brendan, quit that.
Just leave it alone.
Baton Rouge teen, Nicholas Randall,
reported missing four years ago ...
has been found in the French Alps.
He has told authorities that he was
abducted by kidnappers ...
and taken to Europe, where he was
tortured and abused.
French authorities are working
with federal agencies ...
to bring the captors to justice.
They even tried to change my
physical appearance.
They tried to make me
into someone else.
The French accent,
where does that come from?
Claims the kidnappers made
him speak French.
Want to see the rest of it?
No.
He, he looks totally at ease
in front of the camera.
It seems like he enjoys telling his story.
Has he seen a social service psychologist?
Family is refusing.
No one in the family questions
his identity?
Nope.  Not a one of them.
Otherwise, we'd already
done a DNA test.
Come on, Mitch, there's something
fishy about this whole business.
Okay.   Go for it, but go easy.
Family's in shock.
[knocking on door]
YES
Hi.
Mom wanted me to give all your
stuff away, or burn it.
She couldn't bring herself to do it.
She didn't think you were
coming back, you know?
It hurt her too much.
But, I ...
I kept this stuff, anyway.
Good thing I did, huh?
Thanks.
Okay, um, ... I'll just ...
He was a problem kid.
Violent, difficult ...
Arrested three or four times
at age twelve ...
Minor offenses, ... usual stuff.
He was headed for trouble, I guess.
He lived with his mother, right?
Yes, and his half brother Brendan, ...
junkie.
Twelve years old and had been in and
out of rehab over the years.
What about Nicholas' father?
Vanished when the kid was born.
Nicholas was due to be in a home for
troubled children.
I guess he wasn't keen on that idea.
He wouldn't hear of it.
The day he vanished ...
he was due to be in front
of the juvenile judge.
Left home on time, but didn't arrive
at the courthouse or at school.
According to the report,
the family claims
that was the last time they
heard from Nicholas.
Which is why everyone thought
he had run away.
Makes sense.
But, kidnapped?
Poor kid.
Oh, we'll see.
Kid's been found.
His sister formally identified him.
After 48 hours, the probability
of finding a kidnapped kid alive ...
is close to zero.
As for four years later,
you do the math.
Miss Jansen.
Jennifer Johnson, FBI.
Your brother claimed on TV he
was kidnapped by a French sect.
So, if it had been aliens,
what difference would it make?
We just want Nicholas to tell us what
he told the reporters.
Look, if people keep making him talk
about those terrible things ...
how can he ever get over it?
He's just a kid.
Ever since he got back,
people have been out here every day,
stirring up this shit.
Hi, Mom.
What the hell are you doing here?
Why did you come here like this?
Is there some kind of problem?
No, no, I just wanted to surprise you.
I thought you'd be pleased.
You want to please me.
The boss doesn't like us to have visitors
during working hours.
A surprise, huh?
You never really bothered about
me much, before.
Just in case you've forgotten,
it wasn't exactly sunshine
between you and  me.
You made my life hell.
You sure have changed, though.
Only natural, I suppose.
What are you all staring at?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Go on, eat this outside.
Go on back to your sister's house now,
I, I gotta get back to work.
And don't becoming around here
again without calling me.
I can get fired from my job.
Go on, get.
Brendan Kerrigan?
Brendan Kerrigan.
Yeah.
Could you turn that off, please?
Jennifer Johnson, FBI.
I'm clean.
I'm in rehab, you can check.
I'm here about your brother Nicholas.
Oh, yeah?   What's he done now,
up to the the same old shit?
What "shit"?
You know as well as I do.
You probably have his file memorized,
right?
Have you, uh, seen Nicholas
since he got back?
Yeah.
Hows that?
You know, four years is a long time.
Is he different?
I'm not playing the cat
and mouse game here.
I do not know what you're looking for,
Frankly, I really don't care.
Yeah, I saw my brother.
I went to go see him, wanted to see
what he looked like,
I was curious, you know?
One thing I do know,
is four years ago, Nicky was a
mean low-down piece of shit.
I don't have the impression he's
changed that much, either.
That's it.
I'm not going to pretend
to love my brother.
Me and him just didn't get along, ever.
Yeah, he's back.
It's great for the ones who
are happy to see him.
Nicholas?
It's Nicholas, right?
I'm, a, investigating your kidnapping.
Why is there an investigation?
Well ... because kidnapping is a crime,
and you're the victim.
It's our job is to find out who did it.
I don't really want to talk
about this anymore.
The doctor said ...
Which doctors?
The ones you've refused to see
since you got back?
[In a whisper] Don't hurt me.
What?
Nicholas, I just ...
I, I just want ...
Don't hurt me!
Don't touch!
Don't you dare touch him!
Let's get out of here.
Just leave our family be!
This article is unbelieveable.
His loving sister can't praise you enough.
Harassment of her brother?
Verbal attacks?
And, what the kid has to say
is heartbreaking.
I mean, I told you to go easy, Jennifer.
The kid's a minor ...
his family's in a state of shock.
Mitch, he's lying.
He's lying about his age, his accent,
his kidnapping.
That fit in the parking lot was
impressive, but it was all an act.
And, the mother, the brother,
the sister ...
They're all lying?
Look, Mitch, just ...
just give me one more week.
Two, at the most.
Okay, fine.   But, I want evidence,
hard evidence, scientific evidence.
Hey. You haven't forgotten me,
have you, Nicky boy?
Come on, get in.
Come on!
Well, Nicky's really grown up, huh?
You're a man now. ...
Right?
A real fucking man.
Are you happy to see me?
Yeah.
Well, me too.
I'm very happy, Nicky boy.
Very happy, indeed.
Little Nicky.
Huh?
Yeah, you can walk back from here.
Just, don't lose your way, huh.
Get run down by a fucking car.
Be a real shame, too.
Right after you've come back from
the dead and everything.
Go on, have a little bit.
No, it's fine.
Come on, have a little bit.
Come on.  Come on!
Come on!
There you go.
Hey, little bro.
No need to tell that bitch Kathy
about our little drive, okay?
Okay.
Good old Nicky.  We had a good time,
didn't we?
I thought I told you not to come here.
Did I run away because of Brendan?
Run away?
Weren't you kidnapped?
Isn't that what you told the cops?
TV reporters, everybody you
talked to?
What happened exactly the day I
went missing?
You don't remember nothing?
Maybe, that's for the best, huh.
Please tell me,
I really need to know.
You know what I tell you, kid,
there's a lot of people who
do just about anything ...
to forget their past
and start over from scratch.
Might be your lucky break.
You ought to make the most of it.
Mom, wait.
Let go of me!
I was never a very good mother to you.
I guess you forgot that too, huh?
He was always weak.
Never had any backbone.
You wouldn't know.
You don't have him on your hands
all day long.
What about the money that Brian
and me borrowed for a plane ticket?
How the hell will we ever ...
You were stupid to borrow that money.
I told you, so.
You know, Brendan's right.
We never should have gone over to get him.
Don't say "we."
You were.
Come on Nicky, we'll be late to school.
I'm not going.
Come on, cut the bullshit, Nicky.
You sister's doing this for you ...
Hey.
Trust your sister.
And, just try to help me make a
fresh start, you know?
I don't want to go.
No one's going to make me do
what I don't want to do.
Nicky ...
So, everything is just like before, huh?
Are you here for a manicure?
I, uh, want to apologize for
the other day.
I was out of line. I shouldn't have
insisted like that.
Forget it, spare me your pity.
So, what do you want done?
So, are you here on your own?
Maybe, he's waiting for mommy.
Mommy gave me permission to
stay 'til midnight.
Until then, I can do what I want.
Where'd you get the sexy accent?
France.
France? ... You're French?
What are you doing in this dump?
It's hard to, um, to bond again with
a family member when they return.
You don't dare talk about what
happened, not even between yourselves.
So, you start imagining things,
which is worse.
And, little by little,
you become afraid.
Then you hate yourself for that.
You're ashamed.
Does, um, does Nicholas scare you?
A little.
And, um, before, did he scare you, too?
I mean, Nicky has never been
easier to deal with.
Before, he was young,
he was just a kid.
He was difficult, of course, but ...
You know, Kathy, it, um, it might help
Nicholas to, um, to see a psychologist.
He ain't sick, okay?
No, no, no, of course not, but ...
He's been through a traumatic experience.
He needs to talk to somebody about it,
somebody who's not part of the family ...
somebody who can, um, who can listen
to him without judging him.
Get out!
Are you out of your fucking mind?
He's scared too, you know?
He's ashamed.
[siren starts]
What's gotten into you?
I needed a change.
What is that?
What?
Hey, what is she doing here?
You knew about this?
Nicholas, it's okay.
I'm the one who convinced your sister.
You need to see a doctor. He specializes
in post traumatic disorders.
Don't worry.
He's there to help you.
I just want you to get better.
I just want to help you get better.
Yeah, right.
You just want to get rid of me ...
like everyone else!
Don't say that, Nicky!
It's not true!
Can you put the radio on, please?
You're not going ask me what
the guys who kidnapped me did?
That's why I am here, right?
Turn your hands over, please.
You want to tell me about it?
Answering one question with another ...
You're a real doctor, huh?
Don't move, hold still.
Okay, you can relax.
You can take your vest off.
Have you seen a lot of doctors?
When you've see one, you've seen them all.
You don't trust them?
Noone trusts me.
Why would I trust other people?
Did you do a lot of sport
when you were younger?
I don't know ... maybe.
Like most people.
You know why I'm asking, don't you?
My brother and I, we used to fight.
Don't you mean he used to beat you?
Him or someone else?
We used to fight, okay?
He was bigger than me,
but he didn't scare me.
Because, one time, I whipped his ass.
For real.
When I was done with him,
he wasn't moving.
[chuckling] I thought he was dead.
Well, that was real interesting,
huh, doc?
May I see you?   Alone.
Kathy?  Uh,Jennifer Johnson speaking.
Listen, um, ...
I know this is going to be hard to hear,
but, uh, ...
the doctor doesn't think
this boy's your brother.
I'm, I'm real sorry.
Can you hear me?
Kathy ... Kathy, calm down.
From now on, this case is in the
hands of the FBI, okay?
I'm going to need you to sign
an affidavit, so I can press charges.
So, what did the doctor tell you?
What do you think?
I'm not Nicholas Mark Randall?
Otherwise, you wouldn't look so happy.
I'm not happy.
It's what you wanted to hear, right?
No, I wanted to hear the truth.
[scoffs] The truth ...
Kathy, I've got the documents
for you to sign.
Hey, are you okay?
It's best that he stays in the car.
Open the door, please.
Get away from the car.
Hey, come on.
I got it.
He's my brother, okay?
I identified him, my mother did, too.
I mean, Nicky's a minor and you can't
do anything without my consent.
Not a damn thing.
Open the door ... Now.
Let him out of the car, all right?
Get out of the car.
Get out of the car!
Don't ever come here, again.
Did they tell you why I, um, left the
department for missing children
in New York?
No, they didn't.
Alec, a ten year old boy,
goes missing.
His parents think he's run away.
After 48 hours, still no sign of Alec.
His parents are devastated.
Luckily, they have the support
of their neighbor, Alec' godfather.
I went to his place several times,
for, for the case.
Then we went other places, together ...
not only for the case.
One night, he, um, he invited me
over for dinner.
We drank, ...
laughed a lot ...
and over dessert, he slipped up.
Lied.
Useless, unimportant,
dumb little lie.
I stood up, stammered I was tired ...
I smiled, he didn't insist and left.
The next day, I came back with
a search warrant.
All I had to go on was this
one little lie.
We had to break down the door.
I had the house searched.
We found Alec in the basement ...
dead.
During dinner the night before,
he had been in the room below us ...
alive.
Maybe, he could heard us talking,
laughing, joking ...
That guy pretending to be
Nicholas Randall is not a boy,
he's a man.
A liar.
Perverse, dangerous ...
Just like that other guy.
Pancakes and jelly ...
just like when you were a kid.
I'm not hungry.
Come on, it's your favorite.
Why did you do that?
I'm not Nicky.
What are you talking about?
I made it all up.
The kidnapping, the torture ...
I'm a liar, passing myself off as Nicky.
Stop it, stop it Nicky, don't ...
don't say that, it's not true.
Then, why did you let that FBI
woman arrest me, huh?
Why did you let them drag me
to see that doctor?
Noone believes me!   You, Mom, Brian.
Noone believes I'm Nicky!
Stop it ...
I'm so sorry.
She kept insisting ...
You're, you're my little brother,
right? I know.
I know it.
How do you know that, huh?
How can you be so sure?
I can't handle this ... I can't.
You stop messing with my wife!
Okay, Nicky ...
Nicky not?
I don't know, anymore.
I mean, Kathy's a mess.
You see what you're doing to her?
In any case, everyone around here
says that the real Nicky's dead.
So, if Kathy is your sister,
which I highly doubt ...
you better stop messing
with her, okay?
Jennifer, it's Nicholas.
I have to talk to you.
At Fred's, on the river near,
it's next to the bridge.
I'll wait for you there.
[shouts]
Nicholas.
I can't believe this.
Are you tailing me or what?
You wanted to talk to me.
What's up?
I have nothing to say.
Nothing, at all.
Right, cut the crap, okay.
You, a, you called me in here.
Let's go outside,
it's too noisy in here.
Me, calling you?
In your dreams, maybe.
You should go see a shrink or something.
Get off my back, will you?
You think you're a hot shot?
A manipulator, ... fabulous liar.
You're just some poor lost kid.
Right now, you're scared shitless.
Guess what, pal?
I'm tired ... of playing games with you.
Hello.
Who is this?
Nicky?
Nicky, is that you?
My name is Nicholas Mark Randall.
I am sixteen years old.
My mother's name is Kimberly Miller.
My sister's name is Kathy Jansen.
My name is Nicholas Mark Randall.
I am sixteen years old.
My mother's name is Kimberly Miller.
My sister's name is Kathy Jansen.
I was kidnapped.
Your sister is here.
I was raped ...
Tortured ...
I was scared all the time.
I just want to go home.
Hello, this is Kimberly, I'm not here...
Are you okay?
Did Kathy send you?
No.
You've got guts.
A lot of guts.
You have the will power.
You're very smart, too.
With all of that,
you could do something else
with your life.
My life ...
Yeah, your life, your own life.
Not someone elses.
I know how you feel.
You're alone, ...
totally alone.
Twenty-four hours a day in
someone else's skin ...
it's got to be unbearable.
I can help you.
You feeling better?
You don't look too bad.
Don't you got nothing to say to me?
You're not pleased to see your old Mom?
I am.
You'll be staying with me now.
Humph, did you find the beer there?
Well, grab yourself one.
Why you standing there
like some damn fool?
Come on, sit down next me.
I ain't gonna bite you.
Cheers.
Welcome to hell.
You sure screwed up with
that knife, huh?
Clumsy as ever.
I ain't working tonight,
so I thought maybe we'd a ...
Get something to eat, go to a movie,maybe.
How does that sound?
Sounds good.
Sounds really good.
You gonna be sleeping here ...
like before.
I rented out Brendan's room.
I do not think he'll
be coming back.
You understand, huh?
Yeah, ... I understand.
You understand everything, don't you?
[knocking at door]
Maybe, I'll go and fix
your dressing now, ...
that nurse gave me everything I need.
It's in my room.
I'll go get it.
Don't move, I'll be right back.
You got a problem with this?
You going to call the cops on me?
I'm all you got, boy.
I started after you left.
I didn't leave.
I was kidnapped.
First you,
then Brendan ...
You know what that means?
I'm all alone.
Why did Brendan leave?
For that ...
fucking bastard...
Rise and shine, sleepy head.
It's Sunday.
Come on.
That'll put a little meat on your bones.
Where are we going?
Let's go.
Why are you crying?
Why did we came here?
You can tell me.
You drive, I'm tired.
I don't have my license.
Just drive.
Brendan.
Brendan should go to hell ...
and God will never forgive me.
Get away from me!
Get away from me.
You made me life like hell since
the day you were born.
Stay away ... you fucking dealer.
You can go to hell with that too.
But she never should have
turned you over to the cops, Nicky.
You don't rat on family. Family.
It's no good. No good.
The night you called,
I was so drunk.
I didn't mean for that to happen.
I swear ... I swear, I didn't
mean for it to happen.
You can't die twice, kid.
You can't die twice.
Hi, Nicky boy.
Let's go for a ride.
I don't really feel like it.
Well, I do.
Come on. Watch your toes.
Just think ...
before you got back ...
you know, there were jerks out there who
thought that I had actually killed you.
That's incredible, huh?
All because we were at each others
throats, now and again.
Is that what your girlfriend
at the FBI thinks?
She's not my girlfriend.
Anyways ... she can't suspect
you of killing me.
I'm alive.
Hey, ain't that right, baby bro?
Ain't that right?
Come on, let's take a little drive,
just the two of us.
Where?
That depends.
Depends on what?
It depends on you, it depends on me.
And, your FBI girlfriend, too. Come on.
Why her?
Come on, let's drive to the bayou, huh.
Why would you want to go to the bayou?
There's nothing out there.
You know, when you were gone ...
when the little green man came
and took you away.
Mom used to go down to the bayou a lot.
All alone, ... you know why?
To talk to you, man.
She went down there to talk to you.
Yeah.
Have you guys driven own there?
You always were a fucking liar, Nicky.
What, are you scared, huh?
What are you scared of, huh?
Of me?  What the hell am I going
to do to you now?
Come on, let's get baby home to Mommy.
You're not scared of Mommy too, are you?
She's a good Mom, all right?
She's nice and cuddly.
I'm going to keep my
eye on you, Nicky.
You never know what might
happen in this part of town.
Hey, give my love to mom!
It's a Court order, Mrs. Miller.
You have to comply,
like it or not.
I won't do it.
I heard you can do the same
test with saliva.
Did you know that?
Going out.
Open the fucking door.
Open the fucking door!
Open it, you fuck!
Is he in there?
Get out of here, Brendan.
Open this Goddamn door,
Let me see the little prick's face ...
I know about the test!
The whole fucking town knows!
You listen to me listen to me,
you fucker,
if that test will comes back
and proves you're a goddamn liar ...
you've destroyed our family
for a second time!
You've ruined my Mom's hopes!
Fuck!
I will kill you, do you understand?
I will fucking kill you
with my bare hands!
You got it?
Get out of here!
You are nothing to me.
You ain't my son.
Oh, come on, Brendan.
Hit me. Just once, do it.
I ain't scared of you, boy.
And, I never was.
I'll fucking kill him!
His name is Frederic Fortin.
He's French.
Twenty-five years old.
As soon as the results came through,
I sent his fingerprints to Interpol.
He is the illegitimate son
of Giselle Fortin
who was eighteen and poor
when she gave birth to him.
He was place in the custody of his
grandparents when he was two ...
and sent to a junvenile home
when he was twelve.
He has more than 150
different identities.
I know I've been cruel,
but I'm not a monster.
He invented the first one
when he was a teenager.
Calls the cops, says a
lost kid has been found ...
He's been abused or raped,
the parents are dead or kicked him out.
He's been in and out of a hundred
homes for minors all over Europe.
They found no evidence of sexual deviance
or financial motive.
His profit seems to have been
purely emotional.
What took you so long?
Why did you come see me?
They treating you okay, in there?
Yeah, I speak a little bit of Spanish,
so ...
Has Brendan ever been in prison?
Two times.
Did you visit him?
Did you go back to the bayou?
What?
The bayou.
The place you took me after Mardi Gras.
I go there often.
It does me good.
What do you say to Nicholas?
I ask him for forgiveness.
Thank you.
For what?
For coming here.
YES
I heard about your mother.
I'm very sorry.
Why?
I know it wasn't easy to ...
You do not know anything, at all.
French police sent me your file.
What now?
You think you understood everything?
You just have to put me behind bars and
all of a sudden the case is closed?
The others must be laughing
their asses off.
What others?
You really can't see shit, can you?
They always knew I wasn't Nicholas.
Since the beginning they knew.
The mother, the sister,
the brother, everyone knew.
Kimberly knows things about Brendan
that she won't tell.
What things, what are you talking about?
Well, you're the cop, right?
All right, goodbye, Frederic.
There's a place in the bayou
where she goes all the time.
To talk to him.
And Brendan ...
well, he does not like it.
He doesn't like it one bit.
Who does she go talk to, Frederic?
Nicholas.
Any news of Brendan?
He quit his job, left the clinic.
Vanished.
Two days ago.
You could give Kimberly a polygraph.
She has the right to refuse.
It wouldn't be in her best interest,
but she's got the right.
Do you accept it.
Is your name Kimberly Miller?
Yes
Is your birth date August 8, 1955?
Do you have any doubts whether Frederic
Fortin was your son?
the first time she saw him?
No.
Did you realize Frederic wasn't your son
while you were living with him?
No.
Did you always know this boy
wasn't your son?
No.
Do you miss Nicholas?
Yes
Do you know where Nicholas is?
No.
Do you think you'll ever see
Nicholas alive one day?
Do you think you'll ever see ...?
Yes.
No.
Do you think you'll ever see
Nicholas alive one day?
No.
I know he's dead.
It was all Nicky's fault,
he made everybody's life hell.
All right, what are you going do with this?
You can't use it in court.
Frederic, I believe you.
I believe that what you told me is true.
Kimberly is coming.
We're going to put you both in
the same room ...
to see if she'll slip up.
If we can prove you were manipulated ...
that you were used as an alibi
in this case ...
you could go free.
But you have to tell me
everything you know,
again ...  Right now.
Okay?
The truth.
It's your only chance.
Come on in.
Have a seat, Mrs. Miller.
When, uh,  Kathy Jansen saw you
for the first time ...
Did she hesitate before identifying
you as her brother Nicholas?
No.
She called me Nicky and then she cried.
Oh, Nicky.
And, with, um, Kimberly Miller,
when you got to Baton Rouge,
how did that go?
Didn't really look at me ...
as if she didn't dare to.
She kind of hugged me and
she didn't say a thing.
When did you first realize that Kimberly
and the rest of the family ...
knew you weren't Nicholas?
What the hell kind of question ...?
Let him speak, Mrs. Miller.
When Kathy told Kimberly ...
that she never should have
come to get me.
I think Kathy was trying
to rebuild something with me ...
to save her family or something ...
because he felt guilty.
Guilty, what for?
Not having protected ...
Who?
Nicholas.
Do you think Kimberly Miller knows
what happened to her son?
What about Brendan?
Tell me about Brendan.
He came to see me a few times.
To take me for a ride in his car.
Good old Nicky.
He played with me like a ...
like a cat with a mouse.
Did Brendan Kerrigan tell you about a
place where his mother would ...
go talk to Nicholas?
No smoking allowed in here, Mrs. Miller.
Did Kimberly ever mentioned this
place in your presence?
Did she ever take you there?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Do you have any reason to believe ...
that Brendan Kerrigan killed his brother?
That's what you want me to say ...
but it's not true.
Nothing is true.
I made it all up.
I'm afraid of prison, and,
and you promised me that ...
if I would testify against my family,
I wouldn't go to jail
if Brendan was charged.
The whole family thought I was Nicholas.
They all tried to believe,
and so did I
I'm sorry.
You want to take me home now?
Yeah.
I, I just don't understand it.
I don't understand why someone
would do something like that.
It makes me sick.
Makes me feel so sick.
He must be a pretty unhappy kid
to do what he did.
I don't hold it against him.
He sits on his knees when
he watches TV ...
My boy did that.
I felt I had found a family that would
accept me and love me.
They were so happy.
They kept telling me how much
they loved me.
Right, Kathy?
You know, I never wanted to hurt anyone.
Far, from it.
Love ... that's all I wanted.
To be loved, to give love ...
I'm guilty of what,
of looking for love?
In my ten years as a prosecutor,
rarely have I seen such
a morally repulsive crime.
This defendant has no remorse,
whatsoever ...
and now he dares speaks of love?
No. In Louisiana we got values,
we have true values.
Frederic Fortin:
Based on the evidence
presented here today ....
The Baton Rouge federal court,
sentences you to a prison term of five
years and eleven months ...
in the Big Spring penitentiary.
You will also pay a fine of $10,300 ...
and serve three years probation
after your release.
This court is now adjourned.
Deceased name: Brendan Kerrigan.
He deceased last night about 11,
believed to be about 11:10.
The manager called it in about an hour ago.
Looks like an overdose.
I ... I'm sorry.
It had to happen, sooner or later.
Your mother's not here?
She doesn't live around here, anymore.
I don't know where she is ...
and I don't want know.
Hello .... Hello?
Your voice hasn't changed, Jenny.
They say that if you work on it,
your voice never ages.
Where are you?
In France.
What do you want?
I have a lot of things to tell you.
Like what?
I know where he is.
Hang up and take a look,
I'll call back.
Two photos, Jen.
One phone call and two photos,
sent by this lunatic, that's all you have ...
you're raring to go.
You got a search team for
a couple of days,
it's the best I can do.
Thanks.
Ma'am?
Could you come with me, please?
We found something.
Not sure if it'll interest you.
Must be the boss's dog.
We keep digging,
maybe, we'll find his wife.
Keep going.  Just ...
dig behind that tree.
Thanks.
It's over, Jen.
Did all I could.
So, have you.
The kid isn't here.
You can't dredge up all the
mud in this swamp.
He lied to you, one more time.
Maybe, he isn't the one who lied.
Lady ... phone for you.
Thanks. Sorry.
Hello.
[Kimberly] Can't you leave Nicky in peace?
Can't you just leave him where he is,
once and for all?
He's not here, Kimberly.
Nicholas is not buried here.
We found nothing.
Brendan lied to you.
Who cares where he is?
The only thing I'm sure of is,
I'll never see him again.
Where are you?
What do you care?
If you ever hear from that
kid Frederic, again ...
you tell him I said to take care.
Kimberly!
Kimberly, wait!
Subtitles by josmndsn