Blastoff!
He's smart.
Something has entered
the earth's atmosphere.
He's courageous.
We've gotta show these aliens
what we're made of.
He's inventive.
Bubble travel is the way of the future!
And he's got a really big head.
I can fix that.
He's Jimmy neutron,
star of his very own adventure,
from Paramount pictures
and nickelodeon movies.
Gotta blast!
Jimmy neutron is a boy genius.
We're ready for intergalactic travel!
He's one-third Einstein,
one-third Bart Simpson,
and then one-third Jim carrey.
You rock.
I can't really tell you
the whole story of "Jimmy neutron".
Basically, aliens come to earth
and abduct all the parents.
You must erase all impressions
of any kind of alien that you've seen.
You let us go, you big ball of phlegm!
Even "star trek" never
produced aliens like this.
That's no way to talk to the king.
He is the royal phlegm!
Parents are abducted
by the evil yokians,
and Jimmy and all the kids need to
work together to get their parents back.
That gives us about two days
to build our interstellar warships.
We'll also need to bring snacks.
And now, blast behind
the scenes on "Jimmy neutron".
There you go again!
Meet the stars.
Throw these minuscule vermin
into the dungeon!
Explore the gadgets.
This is my hypnobeam.
Experience the cutting-edge animation.
Here we go! Here we go!
It's all part of bringing
Jimmy's world to the big screen.
Fasten your seat belt.
It's gonna be a bumpy ride!
Gotta blast!
My goal was to try to hit as many
kid-fantasy buttons as possible.
DNA match confirmed.
In the movie,
Jimmy's got a lot of neat stuff.
He's got an underground lab,
this huge complex under the house,
trap doors everywhere - cos trap doors
are cool, secret passages are cool.
And in his lab he concocts all these
amazing experiments and inventions.
The latest burping-soda formula.
A guaranteed one burp per sip.
He's constantly launching rockets
off the roof, setting the drapes on fire...
He builds all this stuff and takes off,
and when they think he's asleep
in his room he's out rocketing around.
Basically, a little hellion.
His coolest invention is Goddard,
his robotic dog that he built.
And Goddard is like Jimmy's batbelt:
He can turn into anything at any time.
Thanks, boy. Oh, good dog!
Jimmy's constantly tooling with him
and trying to come up with new things
that Goddard can do.
He can transform into a radio
and a disco ball
and a fire extinguisher at any moment.
It's pretty amazing.
Jimmy neutron is a bit of
an outcast - he's so bright
that a lot of the other kids don't
understand where he's coming from.
Behold. The shrink ray!
Help me. Help me.
I'm so tiny - just like Jimmy's brain!
Some of the greatest inventors started
as complete, hopeless failures too.
Carl is Jimmy's best friend,
and if he has an experiment to try out,
Carl is his Guinea pig.
I don't know, Jimmy.
You know, I get carsick.
Well, luckily, this is a rocket.
Carl wheezer is named Carl wheezer
for one obvious reason,
and that is, in fact,
because Carl wheezes.
He's not nearly as handsome and
young-hero-like as Jimmy neutron is,
but it's Jimmy's show, so he's the hero.
We need to ask ourselves
"what would ultra lord do?"
Sheen's just quirky and a little different,
and he's really into ultra lord.
Sheen loves ultra lord
to the point of it being a problem.
In episode 224,
he fried the zeebot's brain with his
heat-seeking infra-thought. It was cool!
He's very nervous, but once
he gets that ultra lord thing going,
he has no fear, no nothing - he gets
an ultra lord mask, it's all over.
Neutron!
Cindy vortex is
the know-it-all from school.
Nice invention, nerdtron!
Cindy and Jimmy
actually like each other a lot,
but they're at a time and they're at
an age where they're very competitive.
They like sparring
with each other mentally.
It's kind of a love-hate friendship.
I didn't think we liked girls yet, Jim.
Oh, we don't! We don't, no.
Is this one of those macho things?
Cindy is all-out crazed,
and Libby is the best friend of Cindy.
Libby tries to tone her down, and is
pretty much the conscience of her.
What's wrong with you, Cindy?
The cool thing about the movie is
all of the characters are entirely unique.
Retroland!
It's really like a fun family.
I can hang out with ultra lord!
And there's a petting zoo.
Well, look at this.
Let's go!
The look of Jimmy neutron
is done with 3-d computer graphics,
so it's not like a 2-d show,
it's not hand-painted.
All the characters
are constructed on the computer.
It's like having a live-action set
in the computer.
The first thing they'll wanna see
is the animatic.
When we're designing the characters,
we'll design them on paper,
and sculpt maquettes
out of some of the main characters,
and then the modellers can take those
and build the same thing
in the computer.
We can make modifications right there
in the computer, and it works great.
Engaging pulse rockets now!
We love the "squash and stretch" and
action of the looney tunes heritage,
and to take looney tunes into cgi
and make a cartoon-animated world
that takes advantage
of what computer graphics can do,
you've got something
very different and very special.
It's original, it seems to me,
the art for this.
It's extraordinary, animation today.
Whereas once upon a time we were
used to a classic style of animation,
now you never know
what you're going to see.
How many times have we told you
not to launch yourself off the roof?
Probably nine.
Exactly nine. They say repetition
is good for a developing brain.
Jimmy's parents are fantastic because
they accept the fact that he is a genius.
I received a message from outer space
but it was garbled in the ionosphere...
Message from space? Wow!
They're great characters in themselves,
cos his mom can fix the car,
and she's obviously
the engineering part of the family.
The father has sort of
a wide-eyed innocence himself.
He loves the toys in the cereal box.
This is a good one!
And he totally loves Jimmy's gadgets.
Anytime he sees him he's, like,
"boy! Wish I had that toy!"
Is that a brainteaser puzzle?
I'm so good at these!
I was President of the brainteaser club
in high school. Watch this.
Jimmy's got a great relation
with his parents, and respects them,
and tries to do what they say,
but sometimes it's just hard.
You'll spoil your dinner.
We have told you time and time again
about playing with rockets.
Your father will have a few words
to say when he gets home.
Oh, and by the way.
Mom says you're grounded. Sorry!
The kids are down on their parents.
They feel they're being treated unfairly.
They wish they'd go away. "Wouldn't
it be great if our parents disappeared?"
We could do whatever we wanted,
whenever we wanted.
We could have fun all the time!
Jimmy?
Basically, aliens come to earth
and abduct all the parents,
leaving the kids in charge.
No parents!
So it's just kids running amok.
It's like every kid's fantasy.
The whole town is taken over,
and the kids do everything that they
can imagine doing without the parents.
After a couple of days,
the kids start to miss the parents
and realise "oh, my God..."
The earth's been visited by aliens!
The parents have been abducted
by aliens that are eggs: The yokians.
So it's almost like having
your breakfast kidnap you.
Don't look so surprised.
We are an advanced alien race.
What did you expect?
These characters are
eggs outside their shell,
and if they're not contained in
some way, they run all over the floor.
They must be an advanced species,
millions of years ahead of us.
When I sneeze, it looks like
an advanced species too.
They fly around in giant chicken ships,
and they worship this chicken God,
and they're bent on stealing
the parents of retroville
to sacrifice them to their God poultra.
Jimmy didn't mean to ruin our lives
and get our parents eaten
by a giant space monster!
Nobody eats my parents
unless I say so!
Come on!
Roll tape.
Hello, and welcome to our special
edition of "poultra: God of wrath".
If you're watching this, chances
are your friends and/or relatives
are about to be sacrificed
to the mighty poultra -
which is a great honour indeed.
And very painful.
Mary and I play yokian newscasters,
not unlike ourselves here on earth.
There's a lot of prestige
to being a yokian anchor.
They're from outer space,
reporting on the human sacrifices
that are about to take place.
I, king goobot the fifth,
give you sacrifice!
I play king goobot,
and the king is an angry sort, and...
No, no, Martin. I'm playing king goobot.
You are? Then I would
have done it differently.
Do it again. Take two.
- I play king goobot.
- Yes.
King goobot is
a very powerful alien leader.
When did it become acceptable
to approach my royal throne
unannounced?
And this is my prime minister.
Oh, please, oh, please...
I would love for that to stop.
... Oh, please.
His name is ooblar.
Ooblar - me.
He's kind of the servant to the king,
and the king is, shall we say, moody,
and can freak out and kill people
arbitrarily - so he's frightened.
Space him!
So Jimmy has gotta
get his parents back,
or they're gonna get eaten
by a gigantic chicken.
And you just don't want that.
Ok, so me, you and a dog
are gonna battle an alien civilisation.
But he's a good dog, aren't you, boy?
The idea of building a rocket
in the back yard
where you can jump in with your
buddies and your dog and some tang,
like real astronauts, and go into outer
space, will appeal to the audience.
Sensors lead to the orion star system
three million light years away,
so we'll need to leave by Friday.
Any questions?
Jimmy organises this
great armada to go into space
by retrofitting all of the rides
at the amusement park in town.
So he takes the Ferris wheel
and the roller coasters
and everything in the amusement park,
turns them into these spaceships
powered by neutronium.
You heard the man! Stop sucking
your thumbs and let's light this candle!
My theory is that the more fun
the audio session is,
and the more the characters laugh,
the better the show.
- You stay here, I'll be back.
- All right.
Stay! I go. You stay.
- I'm staying.
- Ok.
It's really trying to find people that also
have the ability to work off each other.
That was great. I felt...
No, seriously. I felt like you were
really being abducted by aliens.
Voicing an animated character
is such a liberating experience.
There are no boundaries, because
the animators can do anything.
You have that opportunity
to be that broad.
And childish, in a way -
it's like being back in playschool.
I am awarding permission
to commence with the commencing!
The commencing shall commence!
All hail the commencee,
for he alone doth do
the commencing, which I think is fun.
Ooblar.
It is a very creative process,
doing animation.
You can come up with
a new voice, a new character,
so creatively it's most interesting.
- Poultra will be quite pleased.
- That's great. Thanks. Really good.
We're working on
"Jimmy neutron" right now,
and we enhance the sound
of the film, we bring it to life.
We create sound effects by the use
of various props and sound gadgets
that create a world of sound.
Jimmy neutron
is a wonderful project for us,
because we get to
entirely create the soundtrack.
In animation, you really have free rein,
and you can be as creative
and as crazy as you want.
All the sounds that
you hear are made up,
and I particularly like the egg creatures,
because they have a gooey kind
of sound, but they're in armour,
and they're really fun
to create sound effects.
Jimmy neutron is a little boy genius
who creates wonderful inventions,
and one of his inventions is his dog.
Normally when we do dogs, we'll use
gloves with little nail clips attached.
But Goddard,
he is the coolest robot ever,
so we had to come up with
some great sounds for him.
And he looks like he has little tin cans
for feet, so that's what we use.
The most fun I have is going to work,
and we just get together, and we play.
We create these sound effects,
and we play.
That sounded great.
Now I'd like to go into the ending.
If it's fun to work on,
it's gonna be fun to watch.
That's how we treat the whole process,
in terms of voices, animation,
everybody that's working on it.
There are as many jokes
for adults as for kids.
But, dad, all my friends
are gonna be there.
I know, son. But if all your friends were
named cliff, would you jump off them?
It's clever, and funny, and slapsticky,
all rolled into one delicious
bonbon of entertainment.
It's wackier than I expected.
And you will find that wackiness
reflected in our performances.
I can't wait.
Gotta blast!