I came to tell you
Today I have been sworn in
as a lawyer.
You must be sorry,
but I am sworn in...
...and this is the last time
I'll come here.
Farewell for ever.
You no longer exist for me.
Congratulations.
You congratulate me?
I can't take your hand.
The hand of someone
who always opposed me.
Or helped...or helped.
Or helped...or helped!
CHARACTER
The victim congratulates you...
He says "congratulations",
extends his hand...
you take it and then leave.
It must have been quite
a handshake!
On the way downstairs...
...you stumbled on the stairs.
Have you seen this before?
You don't recognise it?
It's a lovely knife.
But not as lovely as this...
Take it...
Go on! Take it.
You know the feeling? Do you?
Call a doctor.
Would you like something
to drinkng? To eat?
For me too, please.
Mr Jacob Willem Katadreuffe...
Is that the right pronunciation?
"Katadreuffe?"
You are suspected of murder
or manslaughter of bailiff...
Arend Barend Dreverhaven.
That name sounds like
imminent thunder.
So you visited Dreverhaven
this afternoon...
...but nothing unusual happened.
What was your relationship
to Mr Dreverhaven.
Mr Katadreuffe?
Dreverhaven...
The name was a legend long
before I heard it.
It won't be long, sir,
maybe tonight...
God bless you, sir,
you're a good...
Bastard! Dirty bastard!
Dreverhaven,
Bailiff...
Law without compassion...
...the curse of the poor.
I know Dreverhaven's reputation...
but what was your relationship
to him?
You did business with him?
You worked for him?
He worked for you?
When did you first
meet Dreverhaven?
At home...
At home he had a housekeeper.
...Jacoba, Joba for short.
She was a surly young woman,
but he didn't mind.
He didn't say much either.
She worked for him for
a year when one evening...
it happened only once.
Nothing changed between them...
...but six weeks later
she broke the silence.
I am pregnant.
Well...
I'm leaving.
The father has to
support the child.
You will make him pay, won't you?
No.
Have you written to him?
But you will write?!
No! No!
Dreverhaven is your father.
I am named after my mother.
You mean... Dreverhaven wouldn't
take responsibility?
No...
It wasn't that. After the birth
we moved to the other side of town
She moved to East.
She rented a room
at 142 Zeilstraat...
...for 7 guilders a week.
She keeps house for
three middle-class families...
...and a doctor on East Quay.
And the child? It has a name?
Jacob.
Jacob Willem.
Dreverhaven's message
was three words.
WHEN'S OUR WEDDING?
The proposal was accompanied by
a postal order for a suitable sum
"Returned to sender"!
Dreverhaven took the money back...
...and sent it to
her again a month later.
And she sent it back again...
...and the sent it again
the next month.
"Returned to sender"!
The postal-order duel lasted
more than a year.
Would you like to come in?
The money went back and
forth 13 times...
...so she decided to
reconsider his proposal.
BASTARD
Your monther is a whore!
It wasn't the first time
my father's "absence" was mentioned.
When I asked who or where he was
she always answered:
We need nothing of him
We need nothing of him.
Then she was silent, as always.
I live across the road
Am I intruding?
My wife died.
Well I thought, just seeing you...
that you may want to
know I'm available.
You don't have to decide at once.
I shall consider your proposal.
I thought it was a good idea
to marry him.
Unfortunately
we soon left the area.
Your mother's a whore.
Jacob, Jacob...
Go home!
Whore!
Go away!
That same day,
mother packed our cases...
...and we looked for
another house.
My mother said nothing
all evening...
...but I know I had hurt her...
...because I had lost control.
I decided to
control myself an all times.
That is a good intention,
Mr Katadreuffe.
Did you stick to it today?
Yes.
That didn't help Dreverhaven.
That's what you say.
Anyway, you met Dreverhaven
this afternoon.
I assume it wasn't the first time
Yes.
Our move took us closer to him.
By the harbour.
Mother bought a sewing machine
to earn the rent.
That house also had something that
was to play a major role later.
The books were in
a foreign language...
and the previous inhabitants had
moved abroad, so I could keep them.
From then on it was easier to
be silent with her.
I studied the wonderful pictures
for days...
and the strange words
were less alien than I thought.
Elephant.
Elephant in English.
My monther's eternal silence made me
think...she could not bear my company.
Only later did I realise
our characters clashed.
Our contacts were awkward and...
...would always remain awkward,
because we were opposites.
Jacob!
Joba!
Come on...
Jacob! Jacob!
- There's a boy at the door.
- He's looking for his father.
Name?
Smith...
De Beer.
Maas...
Verkerk...
Dreverhaven.
Dreverhaven, 11 South Quay.
I'm sorry, I've never seen
this boy before.
Shit
We need nothing of him.
Wait.
From then on I decided to
leave him alone.
I can understand that. Cigarette?
Thanks.
How did you get on then?
You're a lawyer,
you must have studied.
After school,
Mother didn't let me learn a trade
There was no money.
I had to take care of myself.
I had one job after another.
Van Zwavel, Huizing, Kerk...
...Katadreuffe!
I'm sorry. Try again next month.
Off you go.
Work was usually temporary,
with weeks unemployed in between.
I filled the time reading
my encyclopedia.
It only went up to T,
but I didn't care.
I used a dictionary to decipher it.
I absorbed the knowledge pate by page.
Meanwhile we increasingly got on
each others nerves.
I wanted to leave
and earn my own living.
She apparently wanted
exactly the same.
It's small, but dry and warm.
My son is moving to
the back room.
How much?
Seven guilders, full board.
I'd rather you didn't smoke
in the room.
I'm Jan Maan.
Jan Maan was a Communist.
A lathe operator who moved in...
...after quarrelling with
his parents about his fiancee.
Trudy...I met her in a lunchroom.
My mother said; Lunchroom?
She lives off tips.
Four weeks later
the engagement was off.
But Jan Maan always stayed
with us.
I looked outside this morning,
summer is late this year, madam.
No sign of it yet.
It could be quite a while.
- She never speaks.
- Something between you?
She thinks
I should get out more.
Look for work.
Build something, climb the ladder
This society doesn't want climbers.
You're going to change that?
The Party is growing steadily.
That's because of unemployment.
Everyone will be a Communist by
the end of the century.
You have time to come along
with me.
Good afternoon, we came about
the advert.
You have a shop for sale?
You're standing in it, Mr...?
Katadreuffe.
The name's Lucas Meijer.
What will it cost, Mr Meijer?
Nine hundred.
200 for the stock and 700 for
the goodwill.
I don't know
but 700 for the goodwill?
I don't think he has any customers
I can see something in it.
You see any customers?
It's early and about to rain.
And who's going to pay the money?
I want to loan.
How much?
Nine hundred.
I assume
you have enough collateral.
You have collateral?
You have no collateral?!
I don't think we can do business.
I'm very sorry sir.
MONEY FAST?
PEOPLE'S CREDIT SOCIETY
Good afternoon.
I wondered if I could...
Yes, how much?
I borrowed 900 to take over a cigar shop.
I'm moving out.
You could say something.
Do as you please.
Do as you please!
She's in for a surprise.
It's very quiet here.
It's early.
And it's about to rain, right?
You might be right.
Look,
if you need me,
you can always find me.
Good luck.
Good luck and thank you.
The best of luck...
Tell mother not to worry.
I've come to see Mr Meijer,
it's urgent!
Meijer!
Mr Lucas Meijer?
Yes, what do you want?
Bak with mother I realised
I never wanted my own business.
Certainly not a cigar shop.
It was just an attempt to
escaped her.
But with serious consequences.
Dear Mr Katadreuffe,
you were not home...
but your bankruptcy
has been requested...
bankruptcy requested by
the Peoles's Credit Society.
That bank?
Your property has been
inventoried today.
My books!
Please report to
my office tomorrow...
with a summary of the bookkeeping
bank debts and rent...
and a list of other debtors.
Yours truly, J. de Gankelarr,
receiver.
Good afternoon,
you have an appointment?
Yes, I came to see Dr de Gankelaar
Mr Katadreuffe?
Mr Katadreuffe
for Dr de Gankelaar.
Sir, come this way.
Jacob? Well?
"Come back tomorrow."
I told them all about the business
the bank, everything...
I have to come back tomorrow.
They can't get money
if you're broke.
They need someone
and I said you had experience.
I know it isn't true,
but you just have to use your head
Yes, but listen...
I have a job...
I will have a job...at that office
What office?
That law office. I'll work there.
You asked for work there?
I'm going to ask. I'll work there
At a law office?
Yes.
But lawyers work think.
- Then you...
- I'm going home, to think
Jacob!
Your property is worth 15 guilders
That is the value of your books
and that's all you have?
Fifteen guilders is not enough
for a bankruptcy...
I shall advise the court to suspend
your bankruptcy of lack of funds...
I assume you don't object?
You mean...?
I mean I shall ask the court to
suspend your bankruptcy,
agreed?
Good.
Sir, I would like to
ask you something else.
What will you do?
Your plans for the future?
I have been looking for work.
Work, terrible.
Office work.
Even worse. Don't do it.
I thought of an office like this.
Don't, it's so boring.
I could use an assistant,
of coures...
You mean that?
It's been nice meeting you.
Don't let me keep you.
You want to know
my qualifications.
Excuse me?
I don't want to sound arrogant,
but I know more than
you would think.
You mean your books?
Your encyclopedia?
It may be outdated and incomplete
It only goes up to T...
To "T"? That means...
that you can't "type", but can
do bookkeeping and shorthand.
There are things I shall have
to learn...
You are zealous, but what are
your skills, Mr Katadreuffe?
Could you come down?
A client of Dr Stroomkoning.
Mr F. from E.
I'm coming.
You've fascinated me,Mr Katadreuffe
but you haven't convinced me.
Please excuse me.
Mr Forester, what a suprise.
What's wrong? He did'nt pick me.
He's not here.
There must be an explanation,
Miss Sibculo...
Yes, Dr de Gankelaar?
Dr Stroomkoning wrongly went to
the station an hour late.
We're trying to reach the station
How's it?
Sorry for interupt
The man gets wrong
He's late for one hour
We're looking for him
He's at station or home.
I see, who are you
Dr Stroomkoning called
and he's on his way!
Young man, who are you
and what on earth are you doing?
Sorry.
- I'm very sorry.
- It's ok, but..
Who's this young man?
He applied for a job,
as my personal clerk.
Clerk?
He speaks good English, does'nt he?
Sir? To be honest...
I think we could use him.
That has to be now?
May I be allowed to comment?
I think he will be an asset.
Sixty guilders a month and
that's all.
- Come on...
- Sir? Sir...
Congratulations.
My mother said nothing
about me leaving. Nothing...
Not even "do as you please".
You will drop by, won't you?
And you know where to find me.
I decided not to worry.
I rented a room with
the office caretaker.
I was free and we were free of
each other at last.
Thank you.
If you need anything, just ask.
Jacob Willem,
here are two new shirts.
Be careful with them. Mother.
My work was to start in 5 days.
At night I taught myself to
type at the office...
and during the day
I practiced shorthand in my room.
Mr Katadreuffe: Miss Sibculo,
Dr Carlion, Dr Rustenburger...
Miss Born, behind Dr Sprengers,
then the Buregijks...
And of course Mr Rentenstein,
meet our new colleague.
No introduction necessary.
I saw his show last week.
I hope we shall be spared more of
such performances.
And invite you to consider
a mutually acceptable solution.
What are you doing?
Counting the syllables per minute
It could be faster, couldn't it?
I think so, sir.
You think so...
Do you realise the consequences?
If you get faster, I must too.
I don't mean to rush you, sir.
Miss te George, just in time.
My new clerk is too fast.
Please take over.
You have met?
No
Mr katadreuffe, miss te George
is Dr Stoomkoning's secretary.
Don't worry, she only came to
tack down some French.
You don't speak French too,
do you?
No...That's a relief.
I propose you find
a machine downstairs...
To type this morning's dictation.
Don't hurry.
What a wonderful case.
I knew I had found my destiny.
In this place...
In this office,
the world opened up to me.
No one could stop me.
Mr. Katadreuffe,that was very nasty
of Mr. Rentenstein earlier.
Don't take any notice.
Not even Mr. Rentenstein.
Miss Sibculo...
The man who just went to
see Mr. Rentenstein?
What's he doing here?
Bailiff Dreverhaven,
you don't know him?
Does he work here?
No, thank goodness.
That bolldhound only comes
for Rentenstein...
Or if we need a bailiff.
What did you say?
If we need a bailiff.
"Bankruptcy J.W. Katadreuffe,
books, most in bad condition.
Encyclopedia, incomplete,
value 15 guilders.
He came to our house.
I'm de Gankelaar. I have come for
Mr J.W. Katadreuffe.
Where is it?
I fear the People's Credit Society
wants his bankruptcy.
He borrowed 900
Guilders in April 1923.
It is known that his cigar shop
was not particularly successful.
Could I take a look?
It seems you've look it before.
Mr. Katadreuffe.
Mr. Katadreuffe, come with me.
Dear sir,
we inform you that the bank
has again requested bankruptcy.
Please appear in court
next Wednesday.
Yours truly, Dr Schuwagt.
- You can't get money
- If you're broke, but now you aren't you have an income.
They'll take your wages, unless
we can make a deal with Schuwagt...
But Dreverhaven will never agree.
Why Dreverhaven?
You borrowed from him, didn't you?
Didn't you know it was his bank?
Everybody knows.
It's not easy to get out of it.
Please excuse me.
It's his bank!
I borrowed the money from him!
He pronounced me bankrupt!
Well?
Debt is debt.
Why didn't you say he was here?
Why don't you ever say anything?
I'm going out. See you later?
I'll go with you.
Why don't you go and see him.
Go to him?
I did once. It wasn't a good idea
So you do nothing?
I do: I go bankrupt...
Lose my job and get drunk.
The situation is in danger of
escalating...
Do we watch helpless...
as our comrades are thrown in jail?
No
Or...
do we go to
Ruigbroekstraat tonight?
To show the enemy
we're not afraid...
Look him in the eye...
And fight for our rights!
Go on!
Jacob Willem.
You came to pay your debt?
Did she send you?
No, she couldn't.
Why are you doing this?
To you?
Yes, to me, To her. Why?
You didn't come to do business.
No. I came to...
I came to say
I'm not afraid of you.
Good, then I'll see you tomorrow
in court.
Hello
Stop!
I want to know
why you're doing this.
Good... We'll come to terms.
I suggest payment is 36 instalments
on the same conditions as the loan.
This is a once-only offer...
I didn't ask for that!
If you don't like it...
Never mind.
Take him home.
He can think about my proposal.
I need nothing of you.
I'd rather go bankrupt.
Bailiff Dreverhaven with
an eviction order in Ruigbroekstraat.
Tonight? He can't be serious.
That's suicide. Come back
in a week.
Dreverhaven!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Don't shoot!
Dreverhaven was not in court
for my bankruptcy.
His interests were represented
by Dr Schuwagt.
And Dr de Wever
was appointed receiver.
Plus fifteen guilders from
your wages.
Are you sure you can spare it
every month?
The sooner the debt is payed off.
You have no other possessions?
No.
De Wever, may I speak to you
in private?
Dr de Wever...
The books. I hope we can avoid...
Them being seized.
The value is 15 guilders.
What do you suggest?
The boy is in your debt.
Based on my present wages... My
bankruptcy would last at least 18 months.
It was a miserable time
but there was hope.
Good evening.
Good evening, miss.
You shouldn't work too hard
You don't ollk too good.
It's good to study,
but in moderation.
How do you know I'm studying?
We all know. You read books.
I do.
But I don't have much time now.
What are you working on?
A plea, and you?
I'm translating a contract
for Dr Stroomkoning.
In French.
Yes. Is your room satisfactory?
Yes. I'm satisfied with it.
May I see it?
Not now. Later, when we Finish.
It was already there.
Can you open this?
To be homest... I never tried.
Your own roof garden. Not bad.
Where do you live?
At home, with my parents.
I lived in the suburbs.
I lived with my mother too.
You have other relatives?
I bear my mother's name.
I'm her only child.
I mean: a friend of mine lodges there.
He's a communist.
We have heated debates about it.
Who? You and him
or you and your mother?
He and I.
My mother never says much.
It's good
if people can be quiet together.
You aren't afraid of heights?
It's getting late.
On 1 February 1924,
my debt was paid.
I took mother and Jan Maan out
to celebrate.
I was free of Dreverhaven...
But did not feel at all satisfied
The whole sum. In cluding interest,
paid punctually in twelve instalments.
"Exceptional."
I'll drink to that.
To you, Jacob Willem.
Because you are "exceptional".
Tomorrow morning... At 8 a.m.
you will be evicted...
In the name of the law.
You don't have the right!
Filthy bastard!
I want another loan from you.
I need money.
How much?
Two thousand guilders.
Tomorrow at 9 a.m. at the bank.
You wanted another loan?
You were free of him at last.
You didn't need to see him again.
But you went back and
started again?
I wanted to challenge him.
To beat him.
There's a lawyer for you, and
the coroner wants to talk to you.
Mr Katadreuffe,
your militancy comes from
your mother.
Your birth was a fight too.
I remember, she suffered
strange contractions.
As if she didn't want you bom.
You approached Dreverhaven
because you wanted to defeat him.
I can understand that, but why...
Did Dreverhaven accept?
Dreverhaven didn't need to.
He had already won...
Several times.
What did Dreverhaven want?
At first I thought
it was business.
Next morning
he lent me the whole sum.
The interest was only 8 percent.
But there was one explicit clause
You realise Mr Dreverhaven
can reclaim his loan at any moment?
- You mean that...
- That at any moment, we can reclaim the money,
whether it suits you or not.
Agreed.
Are you sure?
Details?
Is the contract.
The signature?
Despite Dreverhaven's condition,
I felt sure of myself.
I used his money to dedicate myself
to private lessons for two years.
It is not truth that counts...
Truth doesn't count in law...
but proof.
But that which can be proven...
proven...
You'll soon pass your exams,
young man...
The sooner better, madame.
The sooner The better.
Good-bye
Good-night
Miss te George...
Good-bye
I see you are leavintg,
but wondered...
If you could show me
Dr Srtoomkoning's library.
Go on in.
It's lovely.
That's where you work?
You can go in.
I'm on holiday from tomorrow...
Until the end of July.
You'll like that.
I'm not so sure.
The prospect of staying at home...
I like working here.
I like being here.
So do I.
You know...
I want to tell you something.
I'm not so sure I should.
You may think I'm silly.
But when I first came here...
And saw the office from
the outside...
The sun shimmered...
And I saw...
I saw my own name on the front.
Between Messrs Carlion
and Rustenburger.
That's strange, isn't it.
Miss te George...still at work?
Mr Katadreuffe wanted to
see the library.
That's very good,
but I want to lock up.
Don't let us stop you,
we've finished.
Good evening, Mr. Katadreuffe,
Mr. Rentenstein...
Mr. Katadreuffe...
Mr. Katadreuffe!
You've worked here for some time.
I see you are still just
as ambitious.
I even hear from Dr de Gankelaar
That your study
is progressing very well.
Dr de Gankelaar overestimates me.
I don't think
you can be overestimated.
But I should warn you that this office
offers opportunities. For people of your class...
But they are not unlimited.
Understand?
I understand.
I'm grateful for your reminder,
Mr Rentenstein.
That's all right.
I assume you speak from experience
The encounter with Miss te george
Her reaction to my vision...
Kept me awake for several nights.
She was still on my mind...
When Jan Maan introduced
his new fiancee three weeks later.
That's not true!
You'd forget to feed him.
She forgets everything.
Listen to him! Scoundrel!
What a temperament.
Coby.
I met Coby in a store.
My parents don't approve.
"All sorts pass by there.
That's no good," said mother.
Coby ran off three weeks later
"With another".
Mr Katadreuffe!
I know what you think.That meeting
here is an incredible coincidence,
but there's no such thing...
Who says there's no such thing?
I do. But I'm sure there
are theories. I'm over there.
Have you been swimming?
I only just arrived, And you?
This morning, briefly.
But if you go,
I'd love to come too.
Unless you object.
Not at all,it's just...
You can swim?
I don't have a costume...
Just books.
- You came here to...
- Just to study, yes.
I should have known.
How about a stroll?
A stroll... You have time?
Of course.
Lorna?
- Hello.
- Changed already?
And who's this?
He's from the office.
Van Rijn's the name.
Katadreuffe.
Right you are. Cigarette?
No thank you.
How about you, Lorna.
No thanks.
Lovely here, isn't it?
Lorna.
It was the first time
I heard her first name.
This man called her Lorna.
Jacob, Jacob!
Friends of yours?
We're back, yoohoo.
Cheerful types.
I'd better go and see.
Nice to meet you
Mr...Van Rijn. And you.
Strange fellow...
Who are they? From the office?
I'm going home.
We just got here.
Sorry,I have a terrible headache.
Jacob?
Van Rijn.
She never mentioned him before.
Never! She was never brought
or fetched by a Mr van Rijn.
Mr. Katadreuffe?
Mr. Katadreuffe.
I'm sorry to interrupt... But Dr. Stroomkoning
wants to see you urgently.
He expects you in half an hour.
That's a joke.
You haven't seen the last of me.
Mr. Katadreuffe,
maybe you've heard...
That there have been
cash deficits recently.
As a result I have just dismissed
Mr. Rentenstein.
I assume you are not sorry.
Nor me.
Would you like to eat?
No thank you.
Then I'll come to the point
and make a proposal.
I was appointed office manager...
But we'd not seen the last of
Rentenstein.
Mr. Katadreuffe...Congratulations
on your well-earned promotion.
Secondly...
Dreverhaven wants his money back
at once.
The whole sum within three days.
Now?! Just before my exams!
He's already applied for
your bankruptcy.
But that's impossible.
Last time I was in debt to
the bank and the landlord.
Now I only have one creditor
so I can't go bankrupt.
That's right,
but Dreverhaven knows that too.
He's bluffing.
I'm not in debt to anyone else.
If you go bankrupt, Stroomkoning can't
keep you. You'll lose everything.
Dreverhaven doesn't have a chance
I'll represent you.
Thank you, but no.
The PCS bank
versys J.W.Katadreuffe.
I see Dr de Gankelaar
represents you?
Yes, your honour.
Very good.
This concerns a debt to...
The people's Credit Society.
Is this debt recognised?
Yes indeed, your honour.
Does the petitioned havae
any other debts?
No, your honour,
just one.
Sorry, your honour.
My client has no other debts.
Is that correct, Dr Schuwagt?
That is incorrect.
You are misinformed, sir.
Dr de Gankelaar!
Your honour, let me state that
the petitioned has been bankrupt.
That did end with repayment but... The petitioned
has since incurred other debts.
That is not true, your honour.
Dr de Gankelaar,
I am warning your client.
Not necessary, your honour.
I have my information form
the best source, Mr Katadreuffe.
The list of your previous bankruptcy
includes an entry under assets...
"Private sale of books,
fifteen guilders."
Dr de Gankelaar paid the fifteen guilders...
To prevent seizure of the books.
Your honour...
But the petitioned still has
the books, so that means...
Your honour...
Dr de gankelaar is a creditor for
the sum of fifteen guilders.
I would like a brief adjournment,
your honour.
May I?
I'm sorry. He's right.
I bought your books to
prevent seizure.
I don't want that!
I'll give you the fifteen guilders.
You don't understand. I give it
to you and the case is closed.
I can't possibly accept it.
Excuse me?
Dreverhaven has won,
I should never have taken him on.
Are you crazy? I give you
the money and it's all over.
That's very nice,
but I can't accept.
What?
A debt is a debt.
Who taught you that?
Who taught you that
senseless self-chastisement?
I give you the money
and you take it!
People who can't accept a gift,
can't give either,
Jacob Willem!
And you have so much to give,
boy!
I won't let them take it away
from you.
De Gankelaar decided the case
in our favour.
The second debt is irrelevant
and the bankruptcy is rejected.
The loser could take
two more steps.
He can force stroomkoning to
deduct from your salary or appeal.
But Dreverhaven
didn't do anything.
He didn't really want me
bankrupt either.
He just wanted to show
who was in charge...
What?
Three months later
I took my exams.
When I came home,there was no one
to congratulate me.
On the way home I thought of
visiting the enemy.
But I would have nothing to
say to him.
Just as I realised that...
He was standing in front of me.
Jacob willem...
What do you want?
I came to say
you didn't defeat me in court.
And that you'd better
leave me alone.
Or else?
Do something to me.
Do something to me!
Do SOMETHING!
MR Katadreuffe.
Could you come in.
Miss George?
Surprise!
What? You didn't fail?
Bravo!
This is the latest edition.
And complete, all 24 parts.
"Knowledge" up to "Z".
Most is from Dr Stroomkoning...
But everyoune contributed.
It's from all of us.
Congratulations!
Thank you.
I fear I startled you.
You looked very shocked.
It's a strange evening.
I had my doubts.
You mean...
About tonight.
Whether I should do it.
I really appreciate it.
That afternoon, by the sea...
I think I owe you an explanation
I think you should know...
you don't need to.
I'm the one who should explain.
I don't know what was wrong
with me.
But this evening I know.
Mr. Katadreuffe, if I may...
Friends,
I'm very happy
Thank you for
the wonderful evening.
But I have something else to say.
Some may already have suspected,
but...
In september I start law school.
Bravo!
Everyone has certain gifts.
Each has to discover them.
Then he has to develop them...
So he can make propress.
I'm sure
each of us can make progress...
However low he starts.
Anyone with one goal who fights...
And is willing to
sacrifice everything...
Shall overcome all resistance
and setbacks.
As long as just one goal remains...
And he is not distracted..
And puts everything else aside.
Of that I am convinced.
I just wanted to say...
That I hope we all work together
in harmony.
I fear it was more of a sermon.
Thank you.
Nicely spoken, sir.
Are you tipsy?
Mr. Katadreuffe?
And so to bed...
I couldn't see it.
I didn't understand the signals.
I was so full of myself...
of my future...
Miss te George?
Miss?
I have to show you out.
Come back in,
the party's not over yet.
Miss te George did not come to
the office any more.
Next day she wrote to Stroomkoning
offering her resignation...
Without stating a reason
and she was never heard of again.
Mr. Katadreuffe, you are not well
You are very nervous
and physically exhausted.
You have no resistance.
But do you think I...
I don't think you can work.
You are burnt out
and a mental wreck.
Is that all?
No,one other thing.
Your mother is not well.
You know she has weak lungs.
It got worse recently.
There is no immediate cause
for concern.
Her illness is slow and
she could remain stable for years.
I wanted you to know.
She never mentions it.
Yeah
One day I might have to leave her
But I shall never marry.
I'm not the marrying type
and nor are you, Jacob.
A quiet period ensued,
the still before the storm.
I was still in debt...
But for two years
I heard nothing from Dreverhaven.
I heard his business was ailing
and about alcohol abuse
and fights...
When is the wedding, Joba?
When will we marry, joba?
Why not leave our boy in peace?
That boy...
I'll strangle him for nine tenths and the
last tenth will make him strong.
I shall never marry you.
But I assure you,
there has never been another.
Maybe I'll strangle him for
the last tenth too.
I'm giving notice.
You have three days to get out.
You have three days.
You have three days
before I evict you.
The eviction tomorrow...
I'll call the police.
Tomorrow at 8 a.m...
You'll be evicted...
In the name of the law.
Come on. Let's go home.
Yes, be sensible...
And head for home.
Be sensible.
Go home.
Dreverhaven had
the floors removed...
For a lift
he would never install.
He's angry at them.
But the longer
he left me alone...
The more he haunted my thoughts.
But that first boarding
was quite something.
The ship had to be chained up
that afternoon.
We went looking for a bailiff.
When we found Dreverhaven,
the ship had sailed.
We chased it in a boat.
Then we saw
the ship heading down the river.
It had not picked up speed...
So Dreverhaven ordered the boat
to the bow.
Guess what he did? He jumped...
He jumped in the water.
How did you know?
I must have told the story
a hundred times.
Indeed, he jumped in the water
and everyone shouted:
"man overboard!"
Our boat was on the other side of
the bow...
Joba!
So they had to
hoist Dreverhavaen aboard.
When he showed his bailiff s badge
to the captain...
Joba!
It was all over.
That man was brave.
Dreverhaven?
Brave or tired of life?
Yes, you could say tired of life.
He was afraid of nothing.
Someone like that
may know no fear, but isn't brave.
He's indifferent and
that makes him dangerous.
Dangerous? Come, come...
If dreverhaven hadn't stopped
that ship, we wouldn't be here.
Jacob?
I'm leaving the office.
I have applied for a position abroad.
When?
In four weeks time.
I'm about to graduate.
You'll be all right.
I wish I could come too.
No, you still
have some unfinished business.
Will you take care?
A month later,
De Gankelaar left for New Guinea.
He had been my mentor
and I was his protege.
I would miss him.
Good-bye.
Now he had left the office...
I decided to celebrate my graduation
With mother and Jan Maan.
You should thank God for
giving you such a good brain.
God?
Since when is God mentioned here?
To the next round.
Jacob? I'd like to go outside.
A lot's changed here.
These trees...weren't here.
Planted after the war.
Mother? When he first asked you
Why didn't you marry him?
You could see East Quay from here.
It was ugly, this is much better.
Mr. Katadreuffe!
Mrs ten Have.
But Miss te George to you.
Do you still live where you...?
No, but not far from here.
I persuaded my husband
to move here.
He's a bookkeeper.
How are you?
Fine. I start my doctoral studies
tomorrow.
Of course you'll pass
You always succeed.
Then you'll be a lawyer.
To begin with, yes...
Being a lawyer is only the start.
Then I have to specialise...
Then things really start.
And then I'm still not there,
because if I asid that...
You haven't changed.
I shall never marry anyone else.
I never forgot you.
You see that woman?
That's my mother.
She's special.
She must be...
If she's your mother.
Will I see you again?
By chance...
I will wait for that chance.
An old acquaintance.
She was Stroomkoning's secretary.
Was she spoken for?
No.
Really, you were an ass,
Jacob Willem.
My mother died in
her sleep 18 months later.
I hadn't seen Dreverhaven for
six years.
He had left me alone.
I wondered if this was the momnet
he'd been waiting for.
Now she was not between us,
he could strike at any moment.
But Dreverhaven did nothing.
When I was sworn in
four months later...
I started to realise
why he had done nothing.
You sit over there,
Mr. Katadreuffe.
If you'd excuse me a moment...
As you wish.
Come on, sit down...
I had achieved all I wanted...
But
at the same time nothing.
Dreverhaven knew that.
He had known all along.
Dreverhaven knew I would come
to see him today.
Mr. Katadreuffe,
may I congratulate...
I came to tell you:
Today I have been sworn in as lawyer.
You must be sorry,
but I am sworn in...
And this is the last time
I'll come here.
Farewell for ever.
You no longer exist for me.
Congratulations.
You congratulate me?
I can't take your hand.
The hand of someone
who always opposed me.
Or helped...
Or helped!
Help, help... Jacob.
Help me.
Jocob
Dreverhaven begged you to stab him
but you didn't
you walked outside.
You left Dreverhaven alive.
Yes.
Rubbish.
It's the truth.
Come with me.
Dreverhaven was found by his lawyer
yesterday just before midnight.
Not in the attic, but on
the ground floor...
With a knife in his belly
and a broken neck from the fall.
Witnesses saw Katadreuffe leave
at five p.m.
This shows that the fatal wounds
were not inflicted before 11 p.m.
I think the man is telling
the truth.
Mr. Katadreuffe?
What do you think happened
in the meantime?
You think an "accident"?
Jan!
Christ, you look awful.
I've been sitting here all night.
I thought
you'd done something stupid.
Good-bye
I have something for you.
Brought personally by
Dreverhaven's lawyer.
Dear Jacob Willem...
Of his houses, the bank...
his property.
That's all.
That's all!
- You're becoming a Capitalist!
- You expected more?
- Not from him.
- I wish you all the best.
I say...
"Estimated total value:
320,000 guilders...
"Please contact
my lawyer soonest..."
"Signed A.B. Dreverhaven,
bailiff."
That's not what it says.
"Please contact my deputy,
Mr Schuwagt,
yours truly...
"FATHER"!
You have been watching
"Character"