Oh, dear, oh, dear.
- Good night, officer.
- Good night, sir.
(Screams)
(Woman) Evening, dear.
(Horse and carriage passing by)
(Driver) Whoa, whoa.
(Carriage stops)
Thank you.
He's so charming and elegant.
He has such wonderful taste.
Yes, he has,
when it comes to models.
Now I shan't be seeing you again.
Of course you will.
Just because the statue is finished
that is not a reason
why things shouldn't stay as they are.
But I shan't be posing for you anymore.
Surely we are past the stage
where we need an excuse to meet.
We have but what about other people?
Have you...
Are you going to tell them about us?
Let's not think of other people, hm?
Let's think of ourselves.
Excuse me a moment.
Janine.
This is a surprise indeed.
- How are you, Georges?
- I'm fine.
And you look wonderful.
Thank you.
Oh, Georges,
this is Dr Pierre Gerard.
- Georges Bonner.
- How do you do?
How do you do?
- Janine, it's getting late.
- Oh, no, we've plenty oftime.
Pierre and I are on our way
to the theatre.
I heard you had a reception here tonight
so I asked him to bring me along first.
I'm glad you did.
I was just about to show a few friends
my latest sculpture.
Please.
Georges.
This isn't my statue
you're unveiling, is it?
No.
Did you ever start it?
No, I'm afraid
I left the sketches in Italy.
Shall we go?
I'm glad Mademoiselle Dubois
brought you along, Doctor.
Oh, thank you. I've always wanted
to see the inside ofyour place, Bonner.
- It has quite a reputation.
- A good one, I trust.
Very. Tell me, how many patients
can you accommodate at one time?
Oh, not more than 15.
I have the house next to this one,
which I use as the clinic.
There is room for more
but I find that the patients I get
require a great deal
of individual attention.
- Difficult cases?
- Difficult people.
Their money gives them an overblown
sense oftheir own importance.
- Yes, I've met them.
- Yes, I'm sure you have.
But now I think
it really is time that we...
(Clears throat) Excuse me.
- Well?
- No sign of him, sir.
I waited till all the passengers were gone.
He just wasn't there.
- What time is the next train?
- In about six hours, sir.
All right.
Make sure you meet it.
Yes, sir.
I am extremely sorry
to have kept you waiting.
I would like to say at this stage
that any credit due
for what you are about to see
should be laid at the feet
of my charming young model.
An artist cannot form
a thing of beauty
unless he has a thing of beauty
from which to draw his inspiration.
And now there is
nothing else for me to do
except to throw myself
on your mercy.
- (Man) A most wonderful likeness.
- (Woman) Yes, isn't it?
Oh, Dr Bonner.
But it's...
- It's...
- A very fine piece of work, Bonner.
- Thank you very much.
- It's extremely beautiful.
You wouldn't be interested
in selling it, I suppose?
You can see I still have to cast it.
Anyway, sculpting is something I do
for my own pleasure.
Having not yet reached
the perfection I seek,
I find it quite impossible
to give up the completed work,
so I'll keep it.
- Oh? Where?
- Oh, not here.
Somewhere I can go occasionally
to look at it and...
be reminded
of my beautiful young model.
- Are you feeling all right?
- Yes, yes, of course.
It's just that I think
we ought to go, Pierre.
- Would you mind getting my cloak?
- Yes, of course.
Erm...a remarkably fine sculptor,
Bonner, don't you think?
Yes, very fine.
I wanted to buy it
but he wasn't interested.
Says he always keeps his stuff
when he's finished.
- Really?
- Yes.
I wonder where...
Hello! What's this?
I thought there'd be
something else here somewhere.
Mm, a torso. Oh, yes!
Oh, yes, a very beautiful woman
she must have...
Terribly sorry.
Very clumsy of me.
Your cloak, Janine.
Thank you, Pierre.
You are leaving?
We are already late
for the theatre.
I hope you have
a very pleasant evening.
Yes? What is it, Roger?
It's half past six, sir.
Already? Are you sure?
- Yes, sir. I've checked with two clocks.
- My watch says ten past.
It must be slow, sir.
The time is definitely half past six.
I need a new watch.
I need absolute accuracy.
Goodbye.
I am afraid I must ask you
to leave now.
You all know that my main duty
is the care of my patients.
Their needs must come
before everything else.
I would like to thank you all
for coming here
and...
and I must apologise
if I seem rude
by bringing this party to so...
to so sudden a close.
Strange fellow, Bonner.
Did you know him well
when you were in Italy?
- Why?
- Oh, I don't know.
It was just that he didn't seem
too anxious to see you again.
Yes, it did seem that way, didn't it?
Well, apparently
it doesn't worry you very much.
No.
No, it doesn't.
Oh, it was beautiful, Dr Bonner,
but beautiful.
- Thank you very much.
- Good night.
Ifyou change your mind about selling
any ofyour stuff, do let me know.
Good night. It has been my pleasure,
I assure you.
What time is it?
- It's a quarter to seven, sir.
- Thank you.
Tell Roger, if he has any news for me
when he gets back from meeting the train
he can come and wake me.
- Whatever the time is.
- Very good, sir.
- Good night.
- Good night, sir.
(Gasps)
- I thought you had gone.
- I want to talk to you.
- Nobody knows I'm here.
- I'm sorry but you must go.
But I must talk to you, Georges.
Not now, later.
- I'm very busy.
- Not later, now.
I want to know
what's going to happen to us, Georges.
Look, Margo, I'll talk to you tomorrow.
It's Janine Dubois, isn't it?
You're in love with her.
- Please leave.
- I'm not leaving.
Ifyou think you can just forget me
you're mistaken.
I won't let you.
You can't!
You know I love you.
You made me tell it to you
time and time again.
You made me humiliate myself.
I'm not going to step aside
so you can be with someone else.
Get out. Get out!
Your eyes.
What's the matter with your eyes?
All right, Georges.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Georges?
- I'm sorry.
- Too late.
Too late.
Margo.
I tried to make you go.
I tried...
very hard.
(Knock at door)
Wait a moment.
Yes?
Hello, Georges.
I saw the statue last night.
Why did you lie to me?
Why didn't you want me to know
that you'd started work on it?
Why did you start work on it?
I like to finish what I start.
Oh. Is that why you ran away
from me in Italy?
Is that what you call
finishing what you start?
My holiday was over.
I came back to work.
- So suddenly?
- Yes, so suddenly.
There was a case.
It was urgent.
I waited for you to come back to me.
I waited for you to write to me.
Then I realised that if I ever wanted
to see you again
I had to be the one
to make the first move.
Why? Why are you so afraid
of loving me, Georges?
I watched you towards the end
ofthe holiday in Italy
and you were like a man
heading towards something
which he wanted to avoid.
I began to think that I'd won
and that you were going to admit
to yourselfthat you really loved me.
Was I right?
All right, Janine.
I did fall in love with you in Italy.
This could not be so I left.
- Why couldn't it be?
- It just couldn't.
- But you knew how I felt about you?
- Yes, I knew.
And you still ran away from it.
I'm not going to give up
so easily, Georges.
Oh, tell me
you don't want me to give up.
No, I don't...
Oh, I knew I was right.
May I see your statue again?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
It's very lovely.
It's you who are lovely.
I only copied.
Is it finished?
Nearly.
Would you like to pose for me again?
When?
Now.
You still haven't accepted
that we love each other.
Yes, I have.
But it doesn't make you happy.
That's because it doesn't alter things.
- What things?
- Oh, the...
the impossibility ofthe situation.
(Knock at door)
Come in.
The gentleman's downstairs, sir.
Ludwig!
Oh, please excuse me, Janine.
I have been waiting so long
for Ludwig to arrive.
You'll understand.
Ludwig!
Let me... look at you.
Oh...it is so good to see you.
That's good. You look wonderful.
Just the same. I was worried.
- Worried?
- Because I am late.
I... I knew you...
you wouldn't let me down.
You have found the ultimate answer.
Is that it?
Oh, we'll talk about that later, Ludwig.
- Aren't you forgetting something?
- Yes, of course, our little ceremony.
I haven't been too well.
It has affected my memory also, I think.
Ah, you have not forgotten
how to live.
What is the point
of what one is doing
ifyou don't enjoy life,
what it offers?
What is the point, as you say?
The...
The usual toast.
- Ludwig, your hand.
- Oh, yes, my hand.
- Let me have a look at it.
- No, it's not necessary.
I had a stroke.
That is why I was not here sooner.
It has left me with this legacy.
- Why didn't you let me know?
- I was frightened to.
I hoped you would have found
the answer by now.
- You have not found it, Georges?
- No.
No, I haven't found the answer.
The operation is still necessary.
I cannot do it.
- With your left hand.
- No.
We must find someone else.
- But that is not possible.
- Well, try.
We always knew
if we didn't find the ultimate solution
there would have to be
another surgeon someday.
- The stroke might have killed me.
- But it didn't.
Three weeks I have been waiting,
Ludwig.
Three weeks!
I have been taking this fluid
every six hours now.
Six?
It is what keeps me alive.
So you see, you must operate.
You...you know
what will happen ifyou don't.
Yes, I know. You will die.
You're old. You can see
death staring you in the face.
But I can't... I'm not going to die.
Then you must find someone else
to do the operation.
But who?
Who can we get?
We need a young surgeon, that's all.
Just a surgeon.
We tell him just enough to satisfy him
and I'll be with him
all the time he's doing the operation.
That's the best way, Georges.
For the first time I'll be with him
to show him what to do.
Next time,
ifyou still need the operation,
I shan't be here.
I'll be dead.
Find someone else? Huh.
It's easy to say.
- There is so little time.
- You are a doctor.
You must have met other doctors,
someone who will do it.
(Knock at door, door opens)
Mademoiselle Dubois is leaving, sir.
Janine.
I'm terribly sorry, Janine.
Let me introduce you
to my oldest and dearest friend,
Ludwig Weiss.
Ludwig, this is
Mademoiselle Janine Dubois.
It is delightful to meet you, my dear.
How do you do, Professor?
I'm sure that you have a lot
to talk to the professor about
so I'll say goodbye.
- Goodbye, my dear.
- I'll see you at dinner.
Janine, why not bring
Gerard along this evening?
- Pierre?
- Yes.
Yes, tell him Professor Weiss
of Vienna is here.
I'm sure he would love to meet him.
I thought we were going
to be on our own tonight.
Ludwig is here only for a few days.
We'll have so much time together.
Oh, Georges, you don't know
what it means to me
to see you again.
It means everything to me.
This Monsieur Pierre,
is he a doctor?
Even better, a surgeon.
And...do you think he'll do it?
If he's convinced that you give
the operation your blessing,
then he'll do it.
Why should he be influenced
by what I do?
Ludwig... Ludwig, you're still the same.
You just cannot accept the fact
that you are a great man.
One ofthe greatest in your own field.
There is no medical man in the world
who would miss the chance
of meeting you,
let alone work with you.
Half of what makes up this reputation
belongs to you, more than half.
You and I know that.
No one else does.
Listen, Georges.
Why not tell them?
Publish our findings.
Please, Ludwig, allow me
to decide when to publish.
Probably you are right.
You have invested more in this
than I have.
Yes, indeed.
Nevertheless,
I probably shan't be here
to see the consequences.
I am tired, Georges.
As you said just now,
I can see death staring me in the face.
I'm sorry, Ludwig.
Believe me,
I didn't mean it that way.
Strange, getting old.
One suddenly has no future
to look forward to
and is forced to look back and...
survey the past.
Do you remember our original toast,
the first time we knew
we had succeeded?
Of course I do.
Say it.
- For humanity.
- That's right.
For humanity.
Not for me, not for you, Georges,
but for all.
I know what it means.
Do you, Georges?
Sometimes I wonder a little.
You have changed so much
since we have started.
That is hardly surprising.
I'm talking about our original ideas,
bright, shining ideas,
full of hope for a brave new world.
What happened to them?
Where did they get lost?
Why...
Why do you say they are lost?
I think they are.
The years have brought me
an added insight
that enables me
to see more clearly
- the fact...
- Wait a minute, Ludwig.
You are forgetting something,
aren't you?
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
- Do you still have that photograph?
- Photo...photograph?
- Our photograph.
- Ah, yes, of course.
- Give it to me.
- Mm...
Look at it, Ludwig.
And what do you see there?
I see the two of us.
- As we were at the beginning.
- Exactly.
So, remember,
when you talk ofthis wisdom
and this insight
that old age has brought to you,
remember I too have
this wisdom and this insight.
- How old are you?
- 89.
89.
Have another look.
Let it remind you,
while you have the wisdom
that comes with a life of 89 years,
I have that
which comes with a life of...
104.
Yes, sir, I know
what you're saying is possible
but it's not proven.
(Chuckles)
Proven!
If we doctors waited
until something is proven
before we moved,
there'd be no patients left.
They'd all be dead.
Look, I have seen it done
in three different ways,
none ofthem completely effective.
- The first is to make an ingress through...
- Ludwig.
Just a moment, Georges.
An ingress through...
Ludwig, why not take Dr Gerard
down to the study?
- It will be so much easier down there.
- Yes, of course.
Come on. Come on, Dr Gerard.
- You'll excuse us?
- Oh, of course they will.
Come on.
I'll get pencil and paper
to show you what I am talking about.
You know, the incision
must be made directly...
Pierre seems very interested
in your Professor Weiss.
Yes, I told you he would gladly come
once you mentioned
Professor Weiss of Vienna.
He's a wonderful old man.
Have you known him long?
All my life.
We...used to work together.
A long time ago.
That makes you sound very old.
Janine, I can't tell you how much
it means to me to have you back.
I missed you so much.
You needn't have. You know that.
Yes.
Yes, I knew.
Georges, you still haven't told me
why you tried to avoid
falling in love with me.
You started telling me something
this morning but you never finished it.
Because I had to go away.
Because I have to go away again.
Go away? Where?
Where is not important.
What matters is that I shall have
to leave Paris very soon.
But you'll come back?
No.
Why?
I can't, that's all.
You can't just stand there and tell me
you're going away and never coming back
without giving me an explanation.
My work makes it necessary.
Because you're a doctor?
Yes, partly.
I have to travel
where no one has ever been before.
I want to lift the curtain of life
and see what lies beyond.
To do this it is necessary
for me to go away.
Is it necessary for you to go alone?
All right, you've convinced me
but it's not something I'd care to try.
Ah, you lack the spirit
ofthe pioneer, Dr Gerard.
Being a surgeon is a practical business.
It's necessary to make a living.
It doesn't leave much time for pioneering.
But ifyou had the opportunity
of becoming one ofthe pioneers
by performing one simple operation,
what would you say then, huh?
First I'd say that no operation is simple.
Then I'd want to know
what this operation involved.
If it were impossible to explain it,
ifyou were asked to leave it on trust?
Then I should have to say no.
Regardless of who was talking to you?
Professor Weiss,
when we started this conversation
I was under the impression
that we were speaking hypothetically.
Are we?
No.
We are not.
I see.
I suppose I should be annoyed
at this verbal subterfuge.
I don't know why I'm not, really.
Look, suppose you tell me just exactly
what it was you asked me here for.
See this?
My right hand.
The one I would have used
if I were going to operate.
I came here for one single reason.
To save the life of Georges Bonner.
- What?
- Yes.
By performing an operation
that only I know how to perform.
You see? I can't do it.
Therefore, I am asking you
to take my place.
This operation, Dr Weiss,
what exactly does it involve?
In spite of what you said,
this one is really simple.
It involves the removal
ofthe uter-parathyroid gland.
I thought you said
this was to save Bonner's life.
I haven't finished.
To remove the gland
and substitute an alternative.
An alternative? Why?
Is it necessary to know the reason
just to perform an operation?
Physically, no,
but morally, I think so.
Would you be prepared to leave
the protection ofyour morals
in my hands?
I...
I'm not sure.
Look at it this way.
I am asking you to perform
a very simple, straightforward operation
and I am guaranteeing to you
there can be no ill effects.
On the contrary,
unless this operation is done,
and very soon,
Georges Bonner...
will die.
I agree that the operation is simple.
I wouldn't exactly call it straightforward.
- It's never been done before.
- Actually, I've done it myself many times.
- You've done it?
- Mm.
There are no moral
or legal aspects involved.
I suppose not,
as long as the patient is willing.
He is willing.
- You will be there yourself all the time?
- I will.
- And will you lend your name to this?
- Mm.
Very well, I'll do it.
Good.
Now, come on.
I'll show you what's to be done.
Thank you.
This is Georges Bonner's laboratory,
where we will do the operation.
Wouldn't it be better in a theatre
next door to the clinic?
No, no, it's better here.
We don't want people to know
the doctor is sick.
It's bad for the morale ofthe patients.
(Chuckles)
- That's a fine piece of work, isn't it?
- Mm-hm.
Oh, Georges, I love you so much.
And I love you.
I've tried not to.
I've tried very hard.
Is it so bad
now you've given up the struggle?
I don't think I could have let you go.
I'm not going to let you, ever.
(Ludwig) Georges,
Dr Gerard must go now.
Yes, coming, Ludwig.
It's late.
I think you'd better let
Gerard take you home.
Whatever you say, Georges.
It's been a very great honour
to meet you.
My colleagues will be most impressed.
Please, Dr Gerard, I must ask you
not to mention our meeting.
You see, I am old and tired.
Ifthe medical fraternity
knew I was here,
they would request lectures,
addressed meetings.
Oh, you understand of course.
As you wish.
I'm sorry about this, Bonner,
but I have to go back to the hospital.
- Thank you for coming.
- Not at all.
- Will you see me home first, Pierre?
- Yes, of course.
(Doorbell rings)
- Dr Bonner, please.
- Yes?
I am Inspector Legris ofthe Surete.
I wonder if I could have a word with you.
Of course, Inspector. Come in.
Thank you.
- Evening, Mademoiselle, Messieurs.
- (All) Evening.
- We were just on our way...
- I shan't be long.
Don't leave on my account.
Oh, we can wait a few more moments,
can't we, Pierre?
- Come into the study, Inspector.
- Thank you.
- Sit down, please.
What can I do for you, Inspector?
Just a couple of questions, sir.
Routine.
Relating to what?
Relating to the apparent disappearance
of a young lady, one Margo Philippe.
Did you say Margo?
But that's impossible.
- You do know the young lady, then?
- Oh, yes. Yes, of course I do.
- When did you last see her?
- Yesterday.
I had a small reception here
and she was the guest of honour.
You...you met her here, didn't you?
Oh, yes, the young lady you modelled.
Yes.
Did you see her leave?
I think so.
Why, yes. Yes, I'm sure I did.
What's happened to her, Inspector?
Well, we don't know, sir.
She has just disappeared.
It seems the last time she was seen
was here at your reception.
But that's terrible.
What could have happened?
Quite a number ofthings
could have happened, Mademoiselle,
and it's up to me
to find out the one that did.
This statue you did of her,
could I see it?
- Why?
- I understand it's an excellent likeness.
As I have never seen the young lady
it would help me in my investigations
if I knew what she looked like.
I...
I'm afraid, Inspector,
I no longer have the statue.
But I just...
Yes, Monsieur?
You were going to say?
Nothing, nothing at all.
It doesn't matter.
Perhaps you can tell me
who does have it.
Nobody.
A stupid accident this morning.
It was broken.
I was touching up a section ofthe plinth
and I knocked the whole thing over.
I'm afraid it was smashed to pieces.
I see. Most unfortunate.
Well, thank you, Monsieur.
That will be all for the moment.
You will let me know
ifthere's any news?
- I'll let you know.
- Thank you.
- Good night, Inspector.
- Good night, sir.
- And thank you.
- Not at all.
- What could have happened to her?
- You know the statue is in the laboratory?
- Yes. Yes, I do.
- He only wanted to look at it.
He would have wanted
to take it away with him.
I know how the police mind works
and, I'm afraid, I know myself.
It's probably very silly of me but...
I simply cannot part with my sculptures.
I see your point.
Well, thank you for the dinner, Bonner.
Janine.
Good night, Professor.
- Good night, Gerard.
- Good night.
- Well?
- He'll do it.
Oh, good.
What happened to the girl?
When is he going to operate?
It is me, Ludwig, who is talking to you,
not the policeman.
What happened to her?
What is the matter with you, Ludwig?
I will tell you what's the matter with me.
Ten years ago when I came
to London to do the operation
a girl you modelled just disappeared
and was never seen again.
Ten years before that
another ofyour models just disappeared.
Two could be a coincidence.
Three cannot.
What have you done to her?
You're very tired, Ludwig.
So am I. You should go to bed.
I'm not tired, I'm frightened.
Frightened for you,
what you might have done.
Good night, Ludwig.
- When is he going to operate?
- Tomorrow morning.
I thought I told you to go to bed.
Are you going to take
another dose ofthe fluid?
You'd better go to bed,
unless you want to see what happens
when the dose is overdue.
I have been examining the gland.
- What about it?
- You tell me.
What is the matter with it?
Oh, don't distress yourself.
It will do what is wanted of it.
- I am not referring to that.
- Then what are you referring to?
This gland is not like the others.
It was taken from a...
from a living body.
- You're talking nonsense, Ludwig.
- Don't tell me nonsense.
I am not such a senile old fool
that I have forgotten the difference
between a revitalised and a living organ.
This gland has been taken
from a living body.
All right, Ludwig.
As you say,
it was taken from a living body.
But it was because ofyou
that I had to do it.
Now it's my turn to say "nonsense".
You were due here three weeks ago.
As always, I had
a uter-parathyroid ready.
As always, I had removed it
and revitalised it, but...
you didn't arrive.
I managed to keep that gland
revitalised for four days.
Then another one.
Four separate glands
I've removed and revitalised,
only to have them die,
and still you didn't arrive.
I just...
I just couldn't get access...
to any more cadavers.
No.
Oh, no, this...
This was the only answer.
The answer for whom?
For you?
Or for the poor man
you have murdered?
But I'm sorry.
It was my fault, wasn't it?
You had to do it because of me.
No, Georges.
I can't see how this can be justified.
You would rather
I had not been able to get a gland at all.
You would rather this was the end.
Is that what you would have liked?
Yes.
It is.
Knowing how it would happen
you still say that?
But I'm not afraid of death.
If I were,
I too could have remained young.
Do you remember how we talked about it
and you tried to persuade me?
But what is death
that it should be feared so much?
You don't know
what you're saying.
Of course I know what I am saying.
Why should the death
ofthe other man
be of less importance
than your own death?
By what right can you decide
a thing like this?
This is a thing
that only God can decide.
Have you become God all of a sudden,
to judge that you are
more important than the other man?
Of course I'm more important.
He was nothing, nothing at all.
A nonentity.
He had just as much right to life
as you have, more perhaps,
because he didn't attempt to tamper
with the progression of life.
While you are on this pedestal
of moral indignation
you seem to have forgotten
that you are as involved as I am.
No.
I do not forget.
That is perhaps because I am so sad.
I am sad for you too.
You have changed so much.
I'll tell you why I have changed.
It's being alone,
so utterly alone,
again and again.
Every few years having
to sever all contacts, cut all traces.
Having to disappear
and start a new life.
You knew this would be the case
when you set out.
Knowing something
and living with it are...
...are two very different things.
I often think I can't bear it any longer.
Georges?
We have come to a time
where we must consider with great care
whether what we are doing
should continue.
No, let me say what I have to.
No man can live alone all his life.
It's not natural.
It rebels against human nature.
But as long as you continue
you must remain alone.
No.
No, there is an answer.
Not to continue.
No, to continue.
But not to continue alone.
Georges, you're not being serious.
Of course I'm serious.
Do you think
I've never thought about it?
This must be the answer.
Georges.
What you are suggesting is monstrous.
But why?
Why is it monstrous to want
to be with the person you love, always?
Mademoiselle Janine?
It is she you talk about?
Yes, Janine.
I will not hear of it
and I must ask you to promise me now
not to consider it again.
I cannot promise that.
Then you are truly alone now.
For I will have nothing more to do with it.
Ludwig.
No, Georges, you mustn't do it.
Don't be stupid, Ludwig.
Give me that key.
It is past time already.
Yes, Georges, it's been
many years past time.
Ludwig, that key, quickly.
All right, I promise.
Now, give me that key.
You're lying.
I can see it in your eyes.
You are lying to save yourself.
Give me that key!
Ludwig.
Look.
Please.
No.
It is better that it end here
before further damage is done.
This must be the end.
No, you must...
You mustn't do it.
You fool! This...
- This is all I've got.
- Yes, I know.
And I know it will take you two years
to make a fresh supply.
No, no.
No, don't.
Don't do it.
(Screams)
(Knock at door)
Dr Gerard, sir.
Oh.
- Good morning, Dr Gerard.
- Good morning.
Everything is ready,
including the patient.
Where is Dr Weiss?
Oh, I'm afraid
he had to leave late last night.
He received an urgent message
from his home in Vienna.
He asked me to...
to apologise on his behalf.
Monsieur Bonner.
Without Dr Weiss it is out ofthe question
for me to perform this operation.
Last night you agreed.
The Doctor's reputation is such
that under his patronage I agreed to do it,
but if he is not here, it's...
it's impossible.
You must or I shall die.
I recommend you to see another doctor.
Wait.
- I'll pay you well.
- That's of no consequence, Monsieur.
Ifyou are in the critical condition
that you say you are in,
I advise you to go
to a reputable hospital immediately.
It's possible that they may be able
to do for you what I cannot do.
Good day.
- (Knock at door)
- Come in.
Inspector Legris to see you, sir.
Oh, yes. Show him in.
Good morning, sir.
- I hope you'll forgive this intrusion.
- Morning.
- Please sit down.
- Thank you.
- What can I do for you?
- This is a little difficult, sir.
Are you a particular friend
of Monsieur Georges Bonner?
No, I'm not.
I only met him for the first time
the day before yesterday.
Then there's not much
you can tell me about him.
No.
When we met last night
I received the impression
that you wanted to say something.
Yes, that's quite correct, Inspector.
Remember that statue
that he said was broken?
Well, he didn't break it.
It's in his laboratory.
That's strange.
I take it you haven't managed
to find the girl yet.
No, sir, we haven't.
And you think Bonner knows
something that will help you?
I don't know what to think.
The deeper I get into this case,
the more complicated
and unreasonable it becomes.
Unreasonable, Inspector?
How old would you say
Monsieur Bonner was?
- About 35.
- Yes, that's what I would have said.
Why do you ask that?
Look, sir,
I need your help,
I don't mind admitting it.
- To find this girl?
- No, it goes deeper than that.
Far deeper.
I'm going to tell you something
and then perhaps you may be able
to give me the help that I need.
Please do.
Ten years ago in London
a young woman disappeared,
later presumed to have been murdered.
That's not very interesting, you'll say.
It happens all the time.
Well, exactly ten years before that
the same thing happened
in San Francisco
and ten years before that,
in Bern, Switzerland.
Three completely isolated cases.
Then, two years ago,
the international files
at the Surete were being tabulated.
A fact was noticed that tied
these three disappearances together
and pointed towards them
all having been perpetrated by one man.
In each case
the girl in question had been posing
for a statue prior to her disappearance.
In each case the sculptor was a doctor.
And in each case
the doctor disappeared shortly after.
All this is carrying coincidence too far.
You see what I'm getting at,
don't you, sir?
Yes.
I see what you're trying to get at.
But if Bonner is the man
you suspect, sir,
- he'd be over 60 by now.
- Yes.
That's where the whole thing
becomes unreasonable.
You said yourselfthat he was about 35,
certainly not more than 38,
and I agree with you.
I assume you haven't said anything
to Bonner about this?
What's the point?
These statues ofthe women
who disappeared,
- were they ever found?
- No.
That's another peculiarity.
The statues were seen by a small number
of close friends ofthe sculptor
and remarkably fine pieces of work
they were too by all account.
Then they were never seen again.
How can I help you, Inspector?
Well, as you've met Monsieur Bonner,
I had hoped that you might
be able to give me a lead.
I have checked
his background thoroughly.
His movements seem all perfectly normal
as far as I can trace back.
And then I reach a complete dead end.
How far back
before you reach this dead end?
Ten years.
Look, I think I may be able
to give you some sort of lead.
It may not mean anything
but it's worth a try.
See what you can find out
about Professor Ludwig Weiss.
- You've heard of him, of course?
- Weiss? Vaguely.
- He's a doctor, isn't he?
- He was one ofthe very greatest.
He was at Bonner's house last night.
You saw him there.
Try to find out if he was in London,
San Francisco and Bern
at the time that those girls disappeared.
You don't think Professor Weiss
could have been responsible?
No, I don't, not directly.
But you will try?
Dr Gerard, I'll try anything.
Needless to say, you won't say a word
about this to anyone, will you?
Naturally not, Inspector,
ifthat is your wish.
Thank you.
I don't know your reasons for wanting
me to do this, Monsieur Dumont,
but whatever they are,
I must decline.
I'm sorry.
But you're not making sense, Pierre.
You come here with a story
which you admit is mostly guesswork
and you expect me to believe it.
All I'm trying to do is to warn you
against Georges Bonner.
I gathered that,
but you still haven't explained why.
I can't give you all the details
until I am sure ofthem myself.
But...the man's abnormal.
For heaven's sake, Pierre.
Try to talk sense.
Last night Professor Weiss asked me
to perform an operation on Bonner.
I agreed, and today
Weiss isn't there anymore.
Well? What's so mysterious about that?
By itself, nothing, but added
to other things that I have discovered...
Oh, not that idiotic story
about those statues again.
I've never heard anyone talk
such nonsense in all my life.
I admit it does sound far-fetched.
That is why I want you to wait...
until I can get more information.
Spy on him.
That's what you mean, don't you?
You came to make an impression
upon me with your story about Georges.
Well, you've done that.
But it was about you and not Georges
that you made the impression.
You are jealous of him.
You're jealous of his work
and about me.
Well, I love him.
And I'm going to marry him.
It's unusual, Monsieur Dumont.
You will grant me that.
So is the fee I am offering you.
Yes, that's true.
Very well, then. When is it to be?
I, er...
I think I could manage next Tuesday.
It is to be now, tonight,
and at my place.
Very well, then.
I'll put my things together.
One needs many instruments
for an operation.
What's this?
This is a scalpel, Monsieur Dumont.
You couldn't be expected
to know what that is
but to us doctors
it is the principal instrument,
like a spade is to a farmer, you know.
And just about as filthy too.
Leave all this.
I have all the equipment you need.
You have? Very well.
I always have a small one
before I operate.
My hand is not as steady
as it was, you know.
Wait for me.
Oh... Oh, Janine.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
I hope you don't mind
my coming here like this.
No, of course not.
I was looking for you all afternoon.
- The clinic didn't know where you were.
- I have been busy.
Janine, there is something
I must tell you.
I...
Georges, are you ill?
No, no, of course not.
- Why?
- Oh, it's just that...
Pierre was here earlier this afternoon.
He said something about an operation.
He's got some fantastic story in his mind
about you and Professor Weiss.
What sort of story?
Oh, it's too ridiculous for words.
Something to do
with glands and statues.
I really didn't know
what he was talking about.
Darling?
- Are you sure you're not ill?
- No, of course not.
I'm just tired.
Yes, just tired.
I was so worried about you
this afternoon,
thinking you were ill
and not knowing where you were.
- Janine...
- Yes?
- Would you do something for me?
- Anything in the world.
Then come with me.
Georges, what a strange place.
- Is it yours?
- Yes.
There's my statue.
What's it doing here?
I'll...
I'll explain in a minute.
I love you.
But it's simply wonderful.
So many beautiful things.
- It must have taken years to do.
- Yes, yes, a long time.
Wait, I'll...I'll show you something.
This is the very first thing I ever did.
I was 12.
It's charming.
1798? Oh, Georges,
you've got the wrong date on this.
Ifyou modelled this when you were 12
then this date makes you...104.
Georges?
Georges!
Yes, I heard what you said.
104.
I don't believe it.
Whether you believe it or not
is of no importance.
It is important that you do this operation.
My answer is the same
as before, Bonner. No.
Wait a minute, Gerard.
Listen to me once more.
Then we'll see
ifyou feel the same afterwards.
Weiss and I...
were fellow students.
I was his senior by 15 years.
- His senior?
- Yes, his senior.
I met him when I returned to university
for a refresher course on surgery.
Quite by accident we discovered
we were interested
in the same line of research.
And then...
finally we discovered
the secret of immortal life.
But we had to prove
what up till then had been only theory.
So...
I volunteered to be the first guinea pig.
Since I embarked on this experiment,
I have never been ill,
never had a blemish on my skin.
Sickness and disease
have passed me by.
So you see,
not only did we discover
the secret of perpetual life,
but of perpetual health as well.
Then why didn't you
publish your findings?
We haven't published
because to do so would bring disaster.
The balance of nature is such
that the population ofthe world
is kept at a level
where the world can adequately provide
food and living space for our people.
If it were suddenly made possible
for people to remain
alive and healthy indefinitely
the whole structure of nature
would collapse.
Within one generation
the population ofthe earth
would be doubled, then quadrupled.
There would be famine
on a scale never before dreamed of.
This is one reason we haven't published.
- One reason?
- Yes.
There is another.
Every ten years it is necessary
to have the uter-parathyroid replaced.
In order to replace an organ
you must first find a replacement.
With no one dying
there would be no replacement.
You told me earlier on about a fluid
that you have to take to keep alive.
Only in the latter stages
of each ten-year cycle.
If, for any reason,
the operation is delayed,
it is possible to remain alive
for four weeks
by taking this fluid.
Not desirable,
for it has an unpredictable effect
on the mental balance.
And you have none ofthis fluid left?
Enough to keep me alive
for another six hours.
I shall become the inheritor
of all my 104 years,
of all the sickness I have never had,
of every pain, blemish, disease,
a lifetime of illness,
in one moment.
That is why you must perform
this operation.
I'm sorry, Bonner, but I still can't do it.
Why not? Tell me why not.
You are asking me to participate
in an offence against nature.
You said so yourself.
An offence against God.
Nothing you can say
will make me change my mind.
You're in love with Janine, aren't you?
Yes, I am.
You wouldn't like
anything to happen to her?
What do you mean?
At this moment
Janine is somewhere only I know.
Ifyou perform this operation
and perform it successfully,
I shall release her.
Ifyou don't perform this operation,
or if anything should happen to me
while you are operating,
Janine will not be seen
by you or anyone else again.
You have two hours to verify the facts.
Then I shall expect you at my house.
Two hours.
Remember.
Here you are, dearie.
Drink it up.
Why? What's the hurry?
No hurry, no hurry at all.
But I'm a working girl, remember.
Time is money after all.
You'll get paid so stop nagging.
(Door opens)
Cognac.
I'm sick of waiting here
for you to fill your great fat stomach.
- I'm going.
- What are you doing? What about...
What, do you think I'm a girl
who can be bought for money?
- I've never been so insulted.
- You said 50 francs.
It isn't safe for a respectable girl
to be around on her own.
My escort's here now, anyway.
(Cat screeches)
Mind the dustbins, dear.
(Woman screams)
(Doorbell rings)
Never mind, Roger.
You go to bed.
Yes, sir.
Good evening.
Everything is ready.
Please.
If I perform this operation
you will release Janine immediately?
I give you my word.
It will be extremely unfortunate
if I don't survive this operation.
(Train passing)
(Woman laughing)
No!
No, no!
Drink this.
I am very grateful, Doctor.
You can show your gratitude best
by taking me to Janine Dubois.
Of course.
You'll be strong enough to do that
by the time I'm ready.
It means nothing to you that you saved
me from an extremely horrible death?
Nothing.
Try getting up and moving around a little.
How does it feel?
I said, how does it feel?
- Did you see Bonner go out?
- No. I heard him, though.
- Have you any idea where he went?
- No, sir, I haven't.
Find Inspector Legris and bring him here.
- Yes, sir.
- And hurry. It's desperately urgent.
(Train passing)
(Grunting and groaning)
- Where have you been?
- Later. Come on.
You said you wanted to be with me.
Always.
- Is that still true?
- Yes.
Yes.
Whatever it may mean?
Whatever it may mean, yes.
Janine,
I'm going to tell you about myself.
It all started 70 years ago.
Those are Monsieur Bonner's
private papers.
Never mind that.
You leave this to me.
Now, then, sir. What's the matter?
Bonner has abducted Janine Dubois.
He's hidden her.
Wait a minute, sir.
Please will you start at the beginning?
Earlier this evening
Bonner came to see me.
He asked me
to perform an operation on him.
This has been my...existence.
Not life,
existence.
Until I met you.
Now you're going to
come with me, Janine.
But first you must become
exactly as I am.
Think of it.
Never to grow old,
always to stay as we are,
as we are now,
never to be ill.
To stay as beautiful
as you are now.
- No.
- Always.
Through all time.
And this fluid affected his reason?
For the few moments before taking it
he became without reason at all.
Homicidal, completely mad.
That's when he killed those three women.
- And at other times?
- At other times rational, sane,
charming, intelligent.
Here's a carrier's receipt.
"Unspecified crate, 3x2x2,
collect at this address,
"deliver to railway arches,
Gare du Nord."
Today's date.
The statue.
It was here yesterday.
It's gone now.
We must try it.
It's the only clue we've got.
If what you say is correct
then he must be all right
now that you've performed the operation.
I made the incision
but I did not perform the operation.
It will be all right, I promise you.
- No, no!
- Janine!
No!
He didn't.
He didn't do the operation.
He didn't do the operation!
(Groaning)
(Second woman laughs)
I am going to die.
(Screaming)
- Janine! She's in there.
- What?
Break that door down quickly.
Get out of here.
(Woman screams)
(Bonner screams)