Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
I'm thirsty.
- Untranslated -
Jacob...
Jacob, you should sit down.
You're still in shock.
I just killed someone.
He would've killed you.
And me and your brother.
You didn't have a choice.
I took a life.
Give me your phone.
Why?
Call the police.
Jake, you sure
that's a good idea?
That's what you do
when you kill someone.
Screw that!
They could
put you away for that.
It was self defense.
You bashed the guy's head in.
Like, a lot.
Police. Open up.
What the shit?
How'd they get here so fast?
Quiet.
Jake. Jake, wait. Wait. Jake.
Fuck.
What are we gonna do?
Fire escape.
We can go out the fire escape.
Then what?
I don't know.
Jake, you can't go to jail.
I won't.
I can't end up in foster care.
Okay, okay.
It's gonna be fine.
It's gonna be all right.
I'm not going anywhere.
You're not going anywhere.
You just gotta trust me.
Last warning!
Listen...
He broke into our home.
He put a gun
to my brother's head.
Are you even listening?
In case you need to reach me.
Is that it?
Did that just happen?
Those were real police, right?
Those were real EMTs.
I work with those guys.
Are they a part of this?
Is everyone a part of this?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm just dizzy.
You're gonna need another shot.
Remember that convertible
we had?
The one we took to Yosemite.
Top wouldn't go up.
Driving through the park
at night.
Freezing our asses off.
We drove through
the entire park.
Yeah, we had to go through
the entire thing.
God, that ranger
getting us lost in there.
If I find that guy,
I can kill him.
I can't stop thinking
about his face.
I know.
It's just...
Almost done.
Look at me.
Okay. One more shot tomorrow,
and you should be good to go.
You know, maybe you should
just leave it here.
You know,
you should get out of here.
Do you have any idea what
you're getting yourself into?
Do you?
I really don't want
to be alone right now.
Top dresser drawer.
Take whatever fits.
You can shower first
if you want.
No, go ahead.
I have to... I have to call work.
Okay. I can do that.
I'll text you after.
Sorry.
Be right back.
What's going on?
We're here, honey.
You okay?
Yeah.
We're home.
Raj said the guy
had a generator, so...
Hey, this'll work, right?
Yeah.
Who is he?
It's okay now.
Doesn't look okay.
He won't come near me.
He won't have to.
You'll go back.
My mom tried to leave,
like, a dozen times.
I was...
I was a teenager.
King was like 5, 6.
My folks would argue.
My dad would have his drinks.
And they'd start in.
I always knew
when it was coming.
I mean, they'd always argue,
but when he got that way...
I always knew what was coming.
So I'd grab King...
I'd take him into the garage.
We had this, uh...
This old PlayStation.
Just turn the volume up
real loud
so he wouldn't hear
what was going on.
You know what's funny?
We'd be out in the garage
just beating the shit
out of people on TV.
Bruises would heal,
and she would come back.
She always came back.
King?
You okay?
Mm-hm.
You sure?
We can talk about this
if you want.
I'm fine.
Swear to God.
What's this?
Avery's, aren't they?
No, Avery drives a Ford.
Be right back.
You know...
if you sell this car,
halfway to your surgery.
Who knows what they'll give me
after this box?
How do you know you're
going to get anything?
I don't.
Just open it.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.