Go.
Please leave.
- Please leave.
- I'm not going to leave you here alone.
- Go.
- I'm going to go with you.
Please leave.
Bong Soon.
Don't cry.
We don't have much time left.
Please leave.
Bong Soon.
There is something I want to tell you.
Please leave.
There's not that much time left.
I'm not leaving.
I will stay by your side.
Don't be afraid.
Okay?
Please open the door.
Please let me save him.
Step aside!
You're fine.
I'm relieved.
[Episode 15]
[Level Up]
That must hurt.
Does it hurt a lot?
I'm okay.
Your clothes are torn.
When I get my paycheck,
I will buy you pretty clothes.
- Really? You promise?
- Yes.
Bong Soon.
Let's go.
- Who is it?
- It's Dad. He says come home early.
Hurry up. Let's eat and go home.
He must be very worried.
Shall I not go home tonight?
Gosh.
What are you thinking?
I wasn't thinking anything.
Gosh.
It's hot in here.
You're driving me crazy again.
Dad told me to hurry up and come home.
Let's hurry up and eat.
Your hand... I will drive.
I'll drive.
- Tonight... We...
- Huh?
Let's stay together...
Hello?
- Yes, Father.
- My dad?
Yes, of course.
We're heading home now.
Yes. We will be there soon. Don't worry.
Okay.
What? Did Dad tell you to hurry up?
- Let's go home.
- Okay.
- Go in.
You should go home and sleep.
Why did you say that then?
I...
Today was the happiest day of my life.
I will get going. Bye.
Seems like I won't be
getting any sleep tonight.
Gosh.
Leave. Please leave.
There is not that much time left.
Please leave!
How can I leave?
You were trying to save me...
I'm never going to leave you here alone.
Please leave.
I'm not leaving.
I will stay by your side.
Don't be afraid.
I will protect you.
So that no one in this world
can hurt you.
I will protect you.
I...
Today was the happiest day of my life.
Shall I not go home tonight?
I'm losing my mind here.
Shall I...
not go home tonight?
Gosh.
I just...
I wanted to see you.
Did you have a good night sleep?
Let's go.
Please blow air here.
- Do I have something on my face?
- No. I just like looking at it.
Please stop.
- Hello.
- Secretary Gong, when did you get here?
I've been here since yesterday.
- Is your head okay?
- Ah, yes. I have a hard head.
It's a relief that at least
your head is hard.
- Look at me.
- Secretary Gong is here.
- It's not okay.
- It's okay. Who cares?
- It's okay.
Secretary Gong, tell Team Leader Oh
to come to my room.
He went to the hospital.
- Why?
- He was trying to escape yesterday
and his foot got
stuck in the emergency door.
He gets himself stuck everywhere.
Okay. Keep up the good work.
Thank you, ma'am.
Be careful.
Get away from me.
Kwang Bok...
Oh my.
Who are you?
Why do I feel like I'm seeing myself?
We look very much alike.
You could be another me.
I'm in your heart.
Title: Won Bin.
That's so funny. Did you say
the title is "Won Bin?"
Mine is Hyun Bin then.
This is the poem collection
that fake monk left behind.
It's so touching.
There is this poem here. Listen.
Title: A dog that has been
chasing after a duck.
The dog chased after the chicken.
The chicken was faster than the dog.
The dog ended up staring at the roof.
The dog later found out that
the chicken had a long leg.
A long leg.
- It gives me chills.
- It's not bad at all.
I think he left the building
when things got chaotic here.
The police will be here to check
the CCTV and the office.
- Okay. Be cooperative.
- Okay.
- You can get going now.
Where did she go again?
Kim Jang Hyun.
I'm going to get you.
Step up the inspection. Don't let
a single person run away.
Don't let him escape.
Okay?
- Please take a look at this.
- It's him.
- It's him. The one who was on the news.
- He is the bad guy.
He looks just fine.
- I'm scared to go home alone at night.
- It's him.
This is nonsense.
Gosh, this is giving me a headache.
What is going on here?
Where am I supposed to begin?
That bastard.
He is driving me crazy.
He fell from a cliff, right?
He fell and he drowned.
How is he still alive?
That's what I mean.
Team Leader Yook.
According to the Bomb Squad
the bomb exploded in the sky.
They said that CEO threw the bomb.
- What?
- But I don't think it makes sense.
No one could throw it that far.
It's strange.
He threw the bomb up at the sky.
- That Avengers Girl. Do Bong Soon.
- Yes.
She works there, right?
Yes.
His target was not CEO Ahn Min Hyuk.
It was her.
Do Bong Soon.
He knew about your secret power
and set a trap?
That's right.
Kyung Shim told me that
you lost your power the other day.
Are you okay?
Well, Gook Du...
I got my power back now.
I'm strong again.
- Then, that bomb...
- Yes.
- I threw it.
- That's a relief.
How could that be possible?
That's miraculous.
I prayed.
I prayed that I could save him.
Did CEO Ahn know that you had
a bomb strapped to your body?
Yes.
Then he knew it...
And he still stayed by your side?
Yes.
We can't write a report.
No one is going to believe us anyway.
- You should get going.
- Okay.
- Here you go.
- I should go check the scene.
Okay. Don't skip meals.
- Bong Soon.
- Yes?
It's a relief that you are safe.
And it's a relief that you are
back to the old you.
- Thank you.
- I have always got your back.
- You know that, right?
- I know.
I feel safe.
Bye.
I'm not sure yet, but...
[Most Wanted]
[Reward: 10 Million Won]
The police went back to the station.
We cooperated with them.
I let them into the Machine Room
and the rooftop.
Good job. Secretary Gong.
- Yes?
- Let's set up a pop-up window
so that people can see it when they
log in to our game server.
Let's make Kim Jang Hyun's picutre
pop-up when people log in.
We should also include the description
and the reward.
Let the users see it.
As many as possible.
Don't ever let him escape ever again.
I'm going to get him.
- That moron.
- Okay.
CEO Ahn.
I'm not sure if I should tell you this...
Never mind.
What is it?
Well.
About that detective
who came here today...
- I think his name is Bok Du.
- Gook Du, Gook Du.
Yes.
- That detective...
- What?
Do Bong Soon...
He...
He hugged Do Bong Soon.
What?
- He hugged her?
- Well.
When? Where?
- How?
- Well.
A while ago at the lobby...
How could he...
- Do it.
- What? Do what?
Do a simulation. Show me how
he hugged my girlfriend.
- What do you mean a simulation?
- I said do a simulation.
Oh, okay.
Don't you hesitate.
Show me that situation.
- You are Gook Du.
- Okay.
Show me. Think of me as Bong Soon.
- I will be Bok Du then.
- Gook Du!
- Okay.
- Gosh.
Bong Soon is a bit shorter then this.
Bong Soon is a bit shorter.
And he is quite tall.
Yes. I think she is about this tall.
Gook Du came closer and hugged her.
He seemed manly.
He wrapped his arm around her
like this and hugged her.
She looked comfortable resting
her head on his chest.
She seemed like
she was in her mother's arms.
It's warm.
No, no, no.
Hey.
Let's get out of here.
I'm sorry, CEO Ahn.
About Monk Zanimooddean.
- He is Monk Nijamuttin.
- Right?
I thought so. Anyway.
Did you do a background check on him?
I had a chance to get to
know him in person.
Why do I have to do a background check?
Sir, when did you first meet him?
Do you remember how I got stabbed by.
Mang Gu from Garibongdong
three years ago?
I remember that.
That "Don't ask" case.
- You ran for your life...
- Hey!
When did I do that?
Anyway.
Back then, a monk treated me by
using his "energy technique."
I didn't have to get actual surgery.
I have been sponsoring him since then.
It has been two years.
I saw him at the dry sauna
the other day.
He had a tattoo on the side.
It was the map of our country.
He could have done that.
He loves South Korea very much.
But...
Somewhere near the South Sea
he had an arrow and
it said "My Hometown."
Maybe he used to live there when
he first came to South Korea.
That could be his second hometown.
Don't waste your time worrying about
those things. You go do youe job right.
Right?
Right.
Don't look for me.
I want to live my life too.
Is he out of his mind?
- Is he trying to run away from home?
- Ma'am, what should we do?
We don't have pie or tart.
We have nothing.
We have to close the bakery today.
How... Run away?
Oh. Hello, Secretary Gong.
Do you know where CEO Ahn is?
He must be on the rooftop or he could
be wandering around the building.
As you know, when he gets angry
or hyper he does that.
He is upset again? Why?
- I'm sorry.
- What? Secretary Gong.
My goodness.
Do Bong Soon!
Yes?
Oh, no. Sir...
Does it hurt a lot?
Don't worry.
I will make coffee for you.
You were brewing already.
What are you? Who are you?
What's your identity?
I told you I'm Do Bong Soon from
Dobong-gu, Dobong-dong.
You go back to your planet.
Get out of this Earth. Leave.
Sir, I'm not Dooley.
How can I leave Earth?
You like a spoonful of sugar
in your coffee, right?
Stop being coy.
I'm going to see the end of you.
I won't miss it for the world.
Gosh, Sir.
When the new employee gets here,
please be nice to her. Don't bother her.
Oh, it's a utensil set.
Isn't this so pretty?
This is my gift to you.
Bye.
- Hello?
- It's me, Ahn Min Hyuk.
- What's up?
- Are you free today?
I have something to tell you in person.
I have something to
tell you in person too.
I will text you the time
and the location.
You can do...
Hello?
I just don't like him.
I just can't like him.
You didn't eat your only
meal today, right?
Let's go eat.
I don't have to eat.
- Let's go somewhere else.
- What?
- I just want to make sure this...
- Min Hyuk.
Can I call you like that when
we are by ourselves?
Gosh. I have to get
the lead in the beginning.
Don't fall for her.
I don't care how you call me.
What matters is how you feel...
Can I call you "Min Min?"
I'm hungry. Let's go eat.
Let's go. Wait.
Weren't you going to tell me something?
I don't have to tell you now.
I give my employees a hug too.
That's not a big deal, right?
- Shall we go eat? Let's go eat.
- Yes.
She is so annoying.
What in the world is this?
Are you a chieftain in Africa?
What are all these things dangling here?
- What?
- You have spoons and chopsticks here.
What do you need those for?
Do Bong Soon made these for me.
She is the weirdest creature
I have ever seen.
Do you take lessons at a pottery studio
or something? Do you do metal work?
Oh my.
Forget it.
Don't you think you should tell me
about what happened in the office?
Why were you guys hugging each other?
We were doing a simulation.
- Were you jealous?
- Oh my.
Why are you laughing at me?
Don't look at me.
Are you crazy? People are looking at us.
Since when did they become close friends?
You can eat it just like this.
- It's going to take forever to cut it.
- It's delicious.
I have too meet someone after work.
- Who?
- There's this guy who I just can't like.
Wow, isn't she amazing?
Who is this model?
- Should we pick her?
- She is a perfect match for our game.
Who should I choose?
Just pick her. You used to like her.
Look at this... look.
Isn't she amazing?
There are more pictures.
Would you like to see?
When? When did I like her?
Secretary Gong,
what are you talking about?
Didn't I tell you to use a male model?
CEO Ahn, why are you being like this?
We've never used a male model.
You said male models cost more,
and you don't like them.
What are you saying, Secretary Gong?
Are you not feeling well?
You said that, remember?
You've always liked this model.
She looks so scary.
Why are her legs so uselessly long, huh?
Get out. Get out.
Why you acting like this?
Really, CEO Ahn...
Gook Du, I need to talk to you.
See you later tonight.
Why you being this way to me?
CEO Ahn likes male models.
- Bong Soon...
- Go ahead.
- No, you can go first.
I need to make one thing clear with you.
- Bong Soon and I...
- Wait.
Why do you keep using informal speech
with me?
Gosh, this punk...
Then you can do it too.
I have manners, unlike you.
I don't speak informally
to people I'm not close to.
Do you think I'm speaking
informally to you because we're close?
Do you think I want to get close to you?
That's what I'm saying,
so why are you speaking informally to me?
Do you want to get closer to me?
You're a funny guy.
You...
Do you like Bong Soon?
What? Do I like Bong Soon?
How dare you ask me that?
Who are you to ask me that?
You're seriously a piece of crap.
I should be the one saying that.
Hey.
Don't hang around my girlfriend anymore.
I let you mouth off long enough.
Well, I suppose this was bound
to happen sooner or later.
Yeah, it took longer than I thought.
- Should we go?
- Don't complain after I beat you up.
- You punk!
- Oh...
What are you doing here?
How did you know to come?
She came to meet me.
Why would you meet my Bong Soon?
What's it to you if I do?
Stop it, already.
Seriously, what's wrong with you two?
People are staring.
Wait, then the guy you said you were
going to meet is...
Anyway...
Let's catch Kim Jang Hyun together.
I asked to see you to say that.
But, today doesn't seem like
the right time to discuss that.
Let's just drink.
- No.
- Why?
Why, why?
- Who are you to say no?
- She's my friend.
- What about you? You... punk.
- You...
- What kind of cop says... punk?
- It's up to me, you... punk.
You must be... crazy. Hey!
I'll just pour it.
I'll just pour it for you.
Cheers.
Get up there. Gosh, these legs.
Why are their legs so long?
Mom, I'm going to work.
Mom, I'm going to work! Dad, I'm going!
Your dad didn't come home yesterday.
What?
What? Dad didn't come home?
Your dad ran away.
- Ran away?
- But...
- Why?
He left on his own.
You hit him, right?
No, I didn't.
You did hit him again.
He chose to leave on his own.
You think you're right?
Seriously...
I feel really nauseous inside.
Yet, I'm in a really good mood.
You must be uncomfortable there.
She could've given him at blanket,
at least.
Good morning! Did you sleep well?
Yes. You should eat something
for your hangover.
What is it? Why are you so down?
My dad... ran away from home.
Ran away?
Bong Soon, thank you for the meal.
It's food from my house,
so you should thank me.
You did this before, too.
Thanks for the food.
Yum.
Then I'm going to talk about
what I brought up yesterday.
I'm going to catch Kim Jang Hyun myself.
Help me out.
Why are you insisting on doing this
here on our own?
All the focus and attention is on
the police right now.
We need to make a move from a
different direction than the police.
But... why is he going to be involved?
I really hate working with you too.
- What did you say, punk?
- You're the punk.
Enough!
Can you put aside personal feelings
for just a moment?
If you two aren't going to help me,
I'll do it on my own.
- No!
Fine. I'll help you.
But, you can't make moves on your own.
My condition is you have to
discuss everything with me first.
Well, okay.
Anyway, this is what I think.
Kim Jang Hyun knows that I'm alive.
Then he will want to target me.
That is a valid conclusion.
He's very obsessive.
There's a nationwide warrant
out for his arrest.
Things are different for Kim Jang Hyun.
He can't move around freely.
Then we have to make it
so that he can't stay hidden.
Now that he is in this predicament,
what will he end up doing?
The police believe he'll be looking
to smuggle himself out of the country.
- Smuggle himself out?
- It's the last resort for criminals.
Everyone knows his face, so it will be
hard to make a fake passport.
It's more likely he'll use a broker
and get on a cargo ship.
Illegal smuggling.
Broker.
We need some information right about now.
Hello, this is Ahn Min Hyuk.
Mister, you still owe me, don't you?
Yes.
I'll look into it.
What is the trend for smuggling people
out these days?
There's a high chance that a criminal
will be smuggled out via cargo ship.
Look into the brokers for smuggling.
You know Choong Shik,
one of Wol Sa's guys?
You can ask him, he'll know.
Do Bong Soon and Choong Shik.
Why aren't any of the talented people
working for me?
Why? Huh?
- You're right.
- I'm talking about you guys.
I have to do something
to get him to make a move.
You shouldn't have used
the knife with him.
You can't do it like that.
Should we kill them all? They all died.
Who's calling now?
They really died.
Sister!
You're doing well, right?
I've been reading your blog.
- Yes, Sister.
- I have a favor to ask.
Yes, yes.
- I accept your orders.
- We accept them.
- Have a good day.
- Goodbye.
I love you.
Hey, she wants us to put up
a picture of that punk, Kim Jang Hyun.
- She wants everyone to see.
- The order came directly from her?
Then this is an order from the boss.
Yes, this is our first real job.
- We shall catch him!
- Let's do it!
Let's go!
Come on!
That looks amazing.
- Put it up.
- Press the button.
Good job, good job.
Hey.
Have you seen him?
Have you seen him around here?
I think it's him.
Should I report it?
Hello. This is the police, right?
I need to buy something.
Okay.
It's kind of expensive.
Two more.
The gun is loaded.
It's from Russia.
The KGB uses this.
It's me. You know that guy Baek Ta's
guys are looking for?
That guy with the warrant out for him.
He just came by here.
Yeah.
Oh, really?
Okay then.
Boss, Kwang Bok can't come to Seoul.
- Why?
- He went to his hometown.
He was walking around
because he was bored.
He accidentally touched a beehive
and got attacked by bees.
All over his jaw, at that.
Did he commit treason in his past life?
He might as well die.
He has no luck at all.
It's Choong Shik calling.
Choong Shik.
What!
Okay.
Why are you getting angry?
Did he find him?
There are six guys in total.
For the 15th, one young guy chose the
time, ship number, and paid upfront.
I think it's him.
- Then find out where he is.
- The problem is...
He bought a gun from Deuk Gu
at the pawn shop.
A gun?
A long one.
A rifle.
Say it quickly all at once. Hurry up.
- Hello.
- It's me.
11:00 p.m. on the 15th.
It's a cargo ship heading to
Shandong, China.
But, he bought himself sniper rifle.
Do you need a bag?
He asked if there's a reward
for calling in with the tip.
It's not a prank call, right?
I checked the CCTV,
and I'm sure it's him.
Okay.
He showed up at a store in Songdo.
He's already in that area?
The information was right.
He's getting ready to smuggle
himself out.
Still, he won't leave so quietly.
I think so too.
The weapon he got is a sniper rifle.
He will hide somewhere and try to
shoot Bong Soon before leaving.
He'll want to call Bong Soon out to
a place where it's easy to shoot her.
We need to get him to a place we want,
and not where he wants.
That's how we can catch him.
How can you become more and more
fearless with each passing minute?
Don't worry. I'll do a good job.
I'm Do Bong Soon.
Yes, you're Do Bong Soon,
not Wonder Woman.
Now, you're not even scared of guns.
Bong Soon, by any chance...
if he happens to call you,
you need to hurt his pride.
He can't handle being looked down on
by a woman.
That's when you need to tell him
to come to a place we choose.
Then hang up first.
He will take the bait.
Okay, I got it.
According to the information
Gook Du has gathered...
he may be going from Incheon Port to
China's Shandong on the 15th.
There's a very high chance
this will happen.
This path goes to the trade ports.
We will be staking out this area here
very quietly.
Then we'll get him, got it?
Please, let's get him this time.
- Yes.
- Let's go.
How can you sell something like this
in a neighborhood store?
It's not even cheap.
The egg tarts smell like eggs.
That just means they're that fresh.
Egg tarts would smell like eggs.
Would it smell like sweet potatoes then?
Give me a refund right now.
What?
You ate four out of the dozen.
It's not right to ask for a refund.
Just give me the refund.
Gosh, I was suffering
eating those yucky tarts.
- It's yucky?
- Yes, it is.
Just refund it for her.
How much is it, anyway?
- How much do you want?
- It's 1,500 won per tart so...
No, don't do that.
This customer is saying nonsense.
You've done this before, too.
You're an expert at this.
- What did you say?
- I'll show you.
This isn't the first time.
What makes you think
you can act this way?
What kind of person are you?
Yes, customer. It smelled like eggs.
It must have bothered you a lot.
Of course I will give you a refund.
Soon, what are you doing?
Oh, you look so pretty today.
Really, you do.
Next time, I'll do a better job
making it for you.
Here you go. Thank you.
Come back again.
Your makeup looks so great today.
Please get home safely.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Yes. Thank you.
Oh, CEO Ahn.
- Hello.
- Oh, yes.
What about Bong Soon?
I dropped her off at home and
thought I should say hello to you.
Oh my!
My goodness.
I'm a friend of Bong Soon's mom.
CEO Ahn, shall we sit for a bit?
- Yes, of course.
- Sit, sit.
- Soon.
- Yes.
- What would you like?
- I'm fine.
You should drink something.
- Coffee?
- Sure.
- An americano here.
- Okay.
I will make sure to bring Father
back home.
What do you mean?
Bong Soon seems very worried.
Um...
I just gave him freedom.
Freedom, freedom.
We have such deep love in
our relationship.
Every now and then,
we need to be apart.
It's necessary.
It's not healthy if it's too passionate.
That's true.
By the way, CEO Ahn.
Yes.
Could you possibly tell me your birthday
and time of birth?
Why do you need to know, Mother?
Well, it's just...
Is it to check my marital harmony
with Bong Soon?
Well, not necessarily for that...
Please do that.
And let me know the results.
If they say we're not a good match...
- If they say that?
- If they do?
Keep going until you find we're a great
match, the perfect match!
Can you do so until you find
someone who says that?
Yes!
Amazing.
I knew I liked you.
I'm curious about it too.
- Right?
- Well, then...
CEO Ahn, I need your birthday.
Shall we get your time of birth too?
We shall.
I, Do Bong Soon, used my strength
to save three women and my friend,
Kyung Shim.
This time, I will make sure to catch the
kidnapper who took them.
Hello.
Somehow, you managed to live.
Kim Jang Hyun?
Where are you?
Are you curious about where I am too?
Shouldn't we meet?
Why? You found your strength now.
You want to catch me now?
You're not going to run out of fear
from a little girl like me, are you?
Scared of a mere girl?
You are scared.
You're no match for me.
You say I'm no match for you?
You can show up if you're confident.
You remember that construction site
we met at before?
I'll wait for you there tonight.
It's tonight.
Don't worry. I'll never get hurt.
Okay.
Hey, but I need some time too.
I need time to accept my girlfriend's
unique situation.
Look at me, okay?
Don't worry. Nothing will happen to me.
Okay.
Kim Jang Hyun, I will catch you today.
- Can you hear me?
- Yes.
Yes.
Kim Jang Hyun will be hiding
in a good place to shoot.
Be careful.
Kim Jang Hyun,
stop hiding like a coward.
Face me in a proper fight.
The roof, to the right.
Bong Soon, Bong Soon!
Bong Soon, are you okay? Bong Soon!
In Gook Du, follow Kim Jang Hyun.
I know where he's going.
He decided to leave earlier.
He's going to Incheon Port tonight.
Incheon Port.
Hey, Kim Jang Hyun.
The container to the left,
50 meters ahead of you.
Go around the right.
Head right from there.
No, that's a dead end.
Right from there.
Turn to the right.
You're almost there.
Okay!
But, you...
I'm sure I shot you.
I'm the type of person who won't be
satisfied until I complete my task.
This is a bulletproof vest.
Nothing will get through this.
Bong Soon, Bong Soon!
Bong Soon, are you okay? Bong Soon!
Gosh...
This is strong.
I'm going to go crazy.
In Gook Du, Bong Soon is safe.
- Get going.
- All right.
I told you that you're no match for me.
Oh, you're here.
Kim Jang Hyun!
Oh... nice shot.
Kim Jang Hyun, you try being locked up.
You'll have to live forever
locked up like this.
Hey!
[Strong Woman Do Bong Soon]
Do you know what's different about him?
I see myself in his eyes.
When I see myself in his eyes,
I look so happy.
Bong Soon is like me.
She has to be there in order for me
to feel like I exist.
If she's not there,
I feel like I don't exist.
I like CEO Ahn.
Thank you, Dad.
You should fly free now.
I don't think I can save the world
on my own.
I really want to make good use
of this strength I was given back.
I wonder how I managed to fall in love
with such a great woman.
I'm going to protect you too, Min Hyuk.
Like a girl
standing in front of a dungeon.