subtitles,
remember?
that heavy rain we stood under the eaves
i was there?
yes
in hamamatsu
you lived there with us for 1 year
you stayed here from 5 to 8
then you entered izu school
grind wasabi
kanazawa high school, kyoto university
journalist in osaka, writer in tokyo
you've been all over japan
school wasn't in izu but numazu
it's next door
the rain was pouring
that day you sent us to the station
i'll take this one
every time you come you take something
mom's upset
very valuable on the market
it's just catching dust here
right… that time
i remember dad's face
but he was waiting in taiwan
here
we joined him there
a whole year in taiwan
you were so lucky to stay
i wasn't
sure
no
you were lucky
i was abandoned
what?
you were lucky
indeed
it was tough there
you want some?
mom's not joining us?
thank you
thanks
akio, so early
the library car gave me a ride
thank you
brother-in-law you arrived last night?
from tokyo after noon
we don't need funeral clothes anymore
when dad saw his son, he recovered
that's a father's wish
rather when he saw kuwako
when he saw you
no way
stubborn
i'm not
dad looked good on these army photos
villagers used to call him "excellency"
he retired as a major general
still young when he came to these mountains
he refused a position at the hospital…
to work in the fields
what a weird guy
you too were attracted to wasabi plantation
for 3 minutes
3 minutes?
there was enough family here…
in igami to work it
i would have thrown it all away one day
kuwako you were the same
skipping marriage to start business
i was young and confused
now i'm in antique art
he's so similar
yes… you too chose an artistic career
no, i meant similar to his father
surely not
fiddling with a cigarette case
you like soba cake as he does
i hate it
surely not
you're here
yep
mourning outfit?
there
you forgot mine
sorry
idiot
i go get it
enough… can't rely on you
i take this too?
father's check book?
father's funeral record
it reads "funeral expenses"
it's all scrupulously recorded
we had to pay so much
you & kuwako were both in tokyo
i had to handle it
take care of our status here
there are funerals expenses
there are two funeral accounts
that's mom's
so old-fashioned
how about your bus?
soon… you kuwako?
i stay another night
to what purpose?
tidy up storage
excuse me
what?
i'll go greet
he looks so much like father
right
your father said
write the obituary, not a verbose one
going back to tokyo
next week here again
my all time best-seller
so popular
my kids complain
if you read it
from cover to cover
it's 500,000 words
story of our family
i'll be back, goodbye
aki-chan
you enjoy that
so busy writing about genghis khan
no time to visit your father
it's my livelihood
what?
wasabi
bye
you don't have to come
i'm visiting honkei
hi, hiroshi
hello
thanks for the food
come greet honkei
in a hurry
you're the only son
your father asks you
can't hear you
write the obituary, not verbose
i know
who told you?
you did
you're ok?
i am
have a doctor check your head
hello
bye
eric paroissien, minimal subtitles, paroissien.com
let's go
tamada, the glue
sure
your slip shows
i'll take it
sorry
it's slow
how many volumes, mr. saburo?
12,000
12,000… mom…
kotoko is back from school?
she has a photo exhibition for school
her father will be mad
but it's good for her
what does the printer say?
he went 2 hours ago
he's at the restaurant
i'm back
welcome back
we're busy with the prints
i like home's liveliness
how's your father
i'd be more worried about mom
how?
whatever
wasabi, again
beautiful selfless dedication
service is a form of love
next week's lecture trip
later
sir, your meal
have you eaten?
-not yet
call for delivery
which restaurant?
wakamatsu
a soba cake
additional orders
they don't like phone calls
i'll run there then
hello
excuse me
sorry
welcome back
hello
how many prints today?
12,600
1 pen, 2 chopstick
that's what feeds a family
mother fiercely disapproved me
a writer is a waste
you started at 43
father moved to izu at 48
i became a writer at 43
i quit osaka newspaper, came to tokyo
had to be tokyo?
sure
why?
well
tokyo is the place
always dreamed of working in tokyo
you too
same for me
he's a good writer too
segawa can speak for himself
you have to hurry
thank you
thanks for your work
leave it
where's kotoko?
busy with her photos
what photos?
a photo competition at school
we ordered food for her
thank you
that kid is stubborn
she knows how busy we're all with the print
she has no love
no love, no service
your voice is loud, you scare noriko
my voice isn't loud
18 years old, she's scared?
you're fine
coming in
what's this?
snails
while we're busy with the print
you play with snails
it's for the photo competition
when, tomorrow?
next month
no urgency
the print is more important
as long as we enjoy helping
but you force it on everybody
you live on my money
ah, the snails
how do you feel?
i'm fine
sorry about yelling
hello
dear
what?
your father
died?
just before i left him…
he took my hand
don't know why
he held my hand
then tossed it away
he's rejecting you?
he was surprised to see me
at first he, like, hooked me
he just wanted to hold
last tender gesture
father and son is not that simple
why kotoko rebellious?
puberty
because i make her write?
who knows
i became a writer to feed the family…
and launch my family into the trade
the history of genghi kahn
the whole family writes
ikuko and noriko agreed
different personality
cup of tea?
please
i'll go to the livingroom
this slope… you ok?
don't force it
sorry to be a burden
kotoko you go, i take care of noriko
we're together
father is mad at you lately
or he'd be mad if she left you behind
better stick together
i'm segawa the snail
i was called to help
"segawa the snail"?
because i helped you pick up the snails
that's where it comes from?
could you help?
all right
thank you
he'll carry you
she's light
please
heave ho
all right
thank you very much
grandma
sound of the mountain stream
what kind of kid was my father?
read his autobiography
your angle?
a seeker
seeking what?
anywhere on this planet
a small boy searching
amazing
grandma you're a poet
not a poet
it looked like verse
cold
you too
summer 1960
grandma
you liked mr. shunma
did i?
you said you did
more than grandpa?
he was about your age
he'd be 90 now
he didn't last that long
you'd have married him
we would not be born
enough… creepy
just a possibility
but his face
no way
are you talking about mr. shunma?
she comes again
precisely
how do you know about him?
you always talk about him
mr. shunma
talking about him
he's still in my heart…
after all this time
grandma is so cute
this week's letters from readers
just today's
fan lovers too
your slip shows
-she's hopeless
grandma, cards could predict your union with mr. shunma
come sit here
wait, after we finish here
married! none of us were born
neither dad is born
grandma marries mr. shunma
why do you talk about mr. shunma?
here we go again
welcome back
heavy rain
kids are all in?
they would be able to come back
everyone's in?
your mother is here
i'm not alone
come in
good
segawa, driver and student
this is koneko
nice to meet you
whose driver?
mine
he'll stay here
sorry… hand him a towel
back ache?
welcome back
not only that, my thoughts are confused
you took care of mom for a year
indeed
i told you i could take her at my place
let's try for a week
she couldn't bear 2 days
experience taught us
mom said "i'm so old"
"moving to a home with kids"
what is she mumbling?
we have to do as she says
come quick
you know him, segawa the snail
the snail
fired from a printing company
no place to go, i took him in
a 2nd secretary?
my driver
what car?
we buy one
you take such decisions
it's bought, coming tomorrow
a pair of socks
talk about your wages
nice to meet you
this way
not selling antiques today?
mom wants to talk to mr. kosaku
surely not a big deal
she says it's important
she chats with the kids
keeps mentioning mr. shunma
shunma?
a friend who died 70 years back
yes, that genius who died young
his dad was struck by lightning
what grandma
she totally ignores your dad
she never mentions him
not as if she'd forgotten, but…
strange
they were such a good couple
mom's memory is fading
it's coming
gather the middle
away from window
kotoko, you wanna die?
kuwako, sit down
what's the fuss
it's coming
since father's death
in an instant
it's like he lives in me
going to the garden
wearing my clogs
slouching, reading the newspaper
playing with the cigarette box
suddenly the mouth of death facing me
next it's my turn
however, in my case…
mother is still healthy
half of me in the sea of death
mother preserving the other half
that gap between me and death
in fact will disappear
when mother passes away
excuse me
please
staying up late?
tell you something
what?
my brother living in the usa
is 70 this year
right
i want to send him a gift
last week i sent him a silver watch
you did?
we wrapped it in front of you
he's received it by now
don't touch please
i'm not sure you did it
what's that about?
you don't understand the world
leaving you in yugashima was my mistake
there you go again
right after shinako's birth
i should have come for you
but my health wasn't good
a year later you came it was too late
too late…? dramatic!
you didn't want to leave yugashima
you didn't come for me
i did many times
you saw your brother several times
you abandoned me
warehouse onui grandma became my mother
find the funeral record
the funeral record?
that book recording funeral expenses…
we found at dad's death?
why would anyone record funeral gifts
you know about that book
why should i care?
our family's funeral record
you lost me there
it is very important
times have changed now
we're wealthy enough to leave it
we pay back funeral gifts…
what we received in times of grief
when they are in grief we help them
suppose you died, and no one paid it
that wouldn't be fair
i get it, i'll find it
that dismissive tone
typical of onui grandma
so self-righteous
that warehouse woman
but i left you with her
it's not my place to talk
i'll go back home tomorrow with kuwako
i want that book back before, please
elvis
dad?
shit
one more
my father's handwriting
the 1920's
they're funerals gifts
japanese society was based on barter and exchange
"give and take", just like americans
not at all
they'd share all they had
nothing was left
a buddhist principle
don't get it
a funeral in 1920
your mother's mother?
warehouse onui grandma
what does it mean?
from age 5 to 8
onui grandma and i lived together
in a warehouse?
deep in izu mountains a small warehouse
onui grandma did something bad
in a way
she's not your mother's mother?
that's the official status
the truth?
my mother's grandfather's concubine
his lover?
my great-grandfather abandoned his wife and my mother
started a new family
he married that woman, changed her status
why?
strange question
to take care of her future
our family's genealogy
study, research it
grandma's grandpa had a lover
it's indecent
thanks a lot
tired
we're here on this map
shigako
we just arrived
how's mother?
she's great… in the lounge
my name's igami
do we have the orchestra tonight
they have arrived
classical?
sorry they're not
it's a latin group
a latin band
try again
it's like writing, just practice
i'm sorry
from the right knee
segawa enough, move on
don't be weak on him
kuwako
akio, it's them
segawa is put to the task
never loses heart
it's grandma's birthday
coming here makes dad happy
it's a duty for all the family
this too is a duty?
serving is a form of love
is why we love to serve
it's dad's motto
his service and love are coerced
take it easy
mom… mr.tamaya
it hurts
wait kotoko
i'm out
stood kotoko
wait
kotoko
hello
for dad it's not a service
but a payment for his sin
kotoko talks nonsense
paying for what sin?
he used grandma's life and ours
to write his novels
he robbed us of our soul
his sin would rather be hubris
lucifer
admission to hawaii university
you study abroad?
once i graduate here
i may never marry or leave home
if you don't marry, neither shall i
who cares who marries first
grandma is 75
twelve candles
indeed
unexpected
grandma now
is more and more like a child
she's like a 10 year old
right
as she regressed
her memory dwindles
selectively forgetting
only bad memories
remembers good things
it started at dad's death
aging is an eraser going over memories
can't erase them all
she forgets a lot
she remembered someone who died in izu
she wanted to attend the funeral
and send them money
i'm fed up with her whims
she found an old funeral record
she searched it
how much she owes to such family
just like accounting
i've had enough
this for my mother
eric paroissien, minimasubs, paroissien.com
so tired
back to your room?
i could see the pool from my room
i thought this was it
your room is above
i'd rather be here
spacious and comfortable
why did you bring the records?
sure didn't
it just fell from your shawl
don't be weird
maybe shigako brought it
she's here
you can't just disappear
i had to talk…
with your brother…
i called him to my room
what with her?
your room?
nothing
about visiting the graves tomorrow?
i'm patient
you don't visit grandpa's tomb.
i'll follow him soon
no one knows
your grandpa
was working
during the war
it was so hard
he can rest now
i had to go meet him in the snow
the roads were icy
next door lady slipped and fell
i prepared his lunch every day
there was so little food
i polished his boots
military boots
were so long it was hard
let me rest
grandma your nightgown
i'll lay like this
brush your teeth
all right
well
wait
mother wait
i help you
easy
you're too slow
grandma wait
she has no loving memory of dad
she's forgetting him
she also forgot the harm he did to her
his coldness too
their mutual debt is erased
tonight at last…
this is made clear
what?
you've changed
first time you mention mom affectionately
say…
still i have not forgiven her
she abandoned me in yugashima
but she lost that memory
we can't fight over it
the memory gone, you can love her
too later for such racket
3 years ago, marilyn monroe
john wayne, 5 months
cheers for john wayne
cheers
amazing akio
kotoko how's grandma?
mom is with her
you can play with us
akio
shigako is dancing tokyo boogi-woogi
tokyo boogi-woogi?
i'd like to see that
men against women
dad, you can play?
of course
great
segawa and i
next big event is ikuko's wedding
in 2 two months
should have brought him here
it's our last family trip
thank you for all these years
noriko, woman against men
it's ok
okay
bears love their cubs
you know how they help them find food?
you know?
they abandon them
they throw them in a tree
they must come down the tree
otherwise they lose their parents
hello
something happened?
is it grandma?
come in
we don't have to stay
what are you saying
we celebrate the child's first food
we don't cancel
all right
the bag please
mom
i'll find a way
something wrong with grandma?
you're here
accident in yugashima
akio was hit by a car
say
you loaf around all day
easy life
mom, what did you just say?
if you don't work, you don't eat
gimme a break
you're raising your voice
he's doing his share of work
this is so unfair
he's your son-in-law
get out of my home is you don't like it
i wish we had done it
you have some nerve for a servant
she mistook me for a servant?
mom
mom, you just called me "servant"?
we have to take care of grandma
she'd come here with us?
akio's will be hospitalized two weeks
just while he's absent
dad don't laugh
but grandma doesn't like tokyo
in hard times you negotiate with the enemy
what enemy?
we celebrate her first food
kotoko, help me
it's the first time
come with mom
let's use our villa in karuizawa
karuizawa?
i'll take care of grandma
what kind of idea
she won't stand 2 days in tokyo
we take her to karuizawa
the air is good there
grandma will love it
reopenig the villa is a big task
wasp nesting around
rain and wind opening windows
birds inside the house
kotoko would be scared
no one cares how grandma feels
as if she was an enemy
you should take better care of her
enough, kotoko
we celebrate her first food
kotoko, it's your idea, you do it
you can't deal with it on your own
i can pick up grandma
not on your own
you're over-protective
over-protective
you're always careful nobody would touch us
as if you feared an assault
on a typhoon alert you call my school
it's that type of situation
did i say that
you called me back from the cinema
during a storm
the wind and rain
who knows what could happen
moreover noriko, you're weak
the movie was "virgin spring"
"virgin spring"
you watch erotic movies?
an ingmar bergman movie
a father take revenge
for his daughter's murder
he kills 3 brothers
even the smallest boys
i couldn't see it till the end
i so wanted to see it
until the end
you shouted on the phone
you decide for everything
we're deprived of freedom
noriko, you okay
go outside breathe fresh air
i'll serve tea
a fight about "virgin spring"
my brother was shocked
so shocked
but she should do something
or she'll never leave home
she's our version of "virgin spring"
you're laughing, mr. dutiful?
i am sorry
he's not dutiful
sure, he's too
madam
your ride to tokyo
grandma you're going to tokyo
mont ubasute is famous
mont ubasute?
kids abandon their elderly there
I'd be relieved
get ready to go
kids are so ungrateful
i'll use the bathroom
segawa come in to rest
a vast entrance
was a hospital before the war
here there was a pharmacy and waiting room
medicinal drawers are still here
how d'you do!
how do you do?… you?
excuse me
grandma?
sorry
there's no respect for elderly
grandma it's your ride
grandma you're ok
an american
i'm the driver, segawa
an american who can speak japanese
so happy he came for me
this one is smart
grandma means her brother
5 years younger
he lives in the states
i'm so glad
mom, you look great
you ladies are so pretty
losing her mind or playing fool
difficult to discern
i take this
you can't take these ornaments
who's that kid?
family taking care of grandma
she also comes to tokyo
did you greet our hosts?
ah did
did not
he went to numazu college
when we were in taiwan
mr. american, you hear me
i hear
you speak only japanese
"really"
let's go see the ocean in numazu
this is where my son used to swim
"yes indeed"
later i managed to get him back
however, his father
was garrisonned in taiwan
we also went to taiwan
sir
everything fine, shigako?
she came without fuss
we arrive in the evening
she protested a lot?
she complained she's abandoned
that legend, at 70
she said kids throw their elderly in the mountain
and she'd be relieved
she said we should abandon her
she would be better off
she's hard to deal with
say
she's not making fun of us
she does too
like in that movie about tokyo
she considers us nasty kids
coming back to our parents to abuse them
like the son and daughter of that movie
you remember?
i haven't seen it
after the war food was scarce
such stories might have happened
mom is very stressed
you're so kind to her
not that kind
I'm just saying she's a proud person
she would give up in front of no one
OK, gotta go
OK thanks
ms tamadai
we have a folder on mont ubasute
a haiku and song collection about it
a picture book too
picture book?
please find it
sorry to bother
come
still up
something bugs me
i may be repeating myself
i didn't notice that
I'm always bothering you
you probably have enough of me
no such thing
I'm relieved
i won't harass you
as soon as possible
not today, but tomorrow
let me go back home
back to izu home
today you spoke about mont ubasute
i may have mentioned it
you remember this book
mont ubasute
when i arrived in izu
you gave it to me
these were hard times
kids were abandoning their parents
on my summer vacations back in izu
i found it at onui grandma's
warehouse onui grandma
she'd kept it preciously
don't forget about my returning home
segawa will drive you to karuizawa
i'll join you later
first book you loved?
i was 5
i burst into tears
i had to leave my mother
very painful
at 11 i read it again and cried again
i was about to leave onui grandma
sir
i was told, the first 3 days she was mad
so to speak
even her american brother couldn't soothe
as soon as we arrived here
she thought i was the janitor
grandma?
this way
how is she?
good today
yesterday not too good
today she's fine
hey, grandma
on board from the pier in yokohama
peaceful
aging ideally
she finally gave up on the 5th day
i told her she had to be here
you've done a great job
the house is damaged
don't push me
look
humidity is eating it away
i'll wait at the post office
this way, grandma
I'll manage, you can go
go where?
tokyo
i can't
must take care of you
no one is asking you
until you become reasonable
me and Sada-chan and segawa stay
like a house arrest
2 guards and that janitor
that's so sad
what?
a woman asked me for direction
i wanted to show her the way
but kotoko was impatient
it's not true
you're impatient
she told her she was grace kelly
like a swan flying
she didn't ask she was just passing
she wasn't lost
kotoko enough
she asked me
segawa say something
that woman didn't ask
a janitor follows his boss
you embarrassed him
always impatient, you're pathetic
i've had enough of you
sure, you and me we're "bye-bye"
he's gone?
who?
that creep
man with a hat
that would be me
careful, i saw him
spies wear such hats
american spies
who am i?
you're the american
uncle keiichi?
i missed you today
i wondered where…
keiichi is still in the states
how old?
keiichi is 5 years younger than you
for some time…
i wanted to ask you
you received the silver watch?
silver watch?
for your 70th, i asked my son
'course i received it long ago
never knew if he really sent it
'course it was sent
my son is spaced out
since that warehouse onui grandma ensnared him
he wouldn't leave her
he was in numazu
lucky she died suddenly
had she lived longer…
about the silver watch
you received it?
kotoko?
tennis club
with a man
you ready?
"nice"
an elegant movement
that man in white pants?
he's her classmate
they often meet?
not often
you go back
good
kotoko, you did good
cuba libre
your father is waiting
your boyfriend? in white pants?
nope
whenever you feel like introducing me
writing today's events?
also about me too?
"you and me we're bye-bye"
finally, what are we to you…
but novel raw material
using grandma thus…
i'm quite a match to dickens
Alzheimer is such a book-seller, you
Saturday-chan infected me with her parlance
just ending a sentence with "you"
doesn't make it izu dialect, you
easy
heavy
I'm beginning to understand
what?
how you see grandma
we go back
are you a writer or a son?
we discuss this when you're sober
look at you
too shy when you're sober
you never talk
enough kotoko
the writer is kind to grandma
but the son resents his mother
resentment is the drive
without it the canary doesn't sing
"the canari forgot the song"
eric paroissien, minimasubs, paroissien.com
"let's abandon it in the mountains"
"no, you can't do that"
heavy
grandma
what's this?
grandma gone
what?
at the shrine
go to the shrine
check the pathways
grandma
go back
please
I'm fine
you're closing
thank you
going inside?
sorry to bother
it's raining
let's go
i'm busy
it's raining
segawa
the car
all right
grandma liked karuizawa
we stayed until winter
father didn't show up
your nap
good
forgot that prayer
it's ok to forget
where do you go?
outside
be careful
ok
if i bother
i go in my room, miss
stop calling me miss
a bit unexpected
and stop being dutiful
what do you mean?
if you're not too serious we could be dating
but not as a house employee
why are you so restrained?
i'm the boring type
to be honest, your kind of person
is a mystery to me
you took this line
from a novel of my father's
the heroines of your father…
are unconcerned by love
at odds or disconnected
and should their apathy…
ever be disrupted by actual sex…
love is terminated
this sterilized type of love
doomed from the egg, is not my…
segawa
I'm not marrying you
all right
in short
chose my father the writer…
or chose me
both
i won't take it
you chose the glass, the bottle will hate you forever
my student abused my trust
he may hinder your future literary prize
i quit being dutiful
grandma, sorry
help us
Sada-chan your chores
is it all right?
all in line
grandma
good ceremony
i wish it was every day
you know for whom?
for whom?
my memory is fading it's terrible
we commemorate warehouse onui grandma
she's been dead for 50 years
that puts an end to it
we don't owe her anything more
thus she joins the ancestors
thank you for your trouble
where's kurokawa?
not yet
you heard that?
death reconciles old enemies
dad?
in the salon with noriko
hawaii?
he agreed i'll study in hawaii
congratulations
thank you
i saw he was alone so…
i mustered the courage to ask
easier than i expected
good for you
I'll announce it now
a photo here?
you promised you'd be with me today
to find a title for the special edition?
your taking a break in the country
who came up with that?
segawa the snail
thought so
it's a conservative magazine
you snatched Mr. dutiful away from me
he decided on his own
he dropped me to date you
you're getting the hang of abandonment
i love it
he wrote good stuff under my guidance
he's not just a good editor, get it?
onui grandma's celebration in that side room is creepy
when we'd visit my parents place
she'd enter through the back door to greet people
never enter the main room
even dead, today she's forbidden
but you'd enter through the front door?
onui grandma told me to do so
you'd have dinner here some times
never
grandpa and grandma…
would not feed offer a meal
we were often invited…
but I'd refuse
in my kid's heart i knew onui grandma's feeling
so we'd go back to the warehouse
i remember writing poetry on this swing
what poem?
forgot
your memory is excellent
not for what i wrote at that time
nothing's left
you were protecting grandma
had she entered the main room
the whole family…
were her enemies
here she held my hand for the first time
who?
onui grandma
a sunset like this one
mother, had dropped me in yugashima
onui grandma raised me
go back
that year in yugashima
shigako was so busy
dad took in grandma
grandma not on your own
help
lock the door yone-chan
grandma come on
the luggage upstairs
grandma
easy
come on
easy now
come
easy
in our tokyo home
we had such rackets that could last an hour
especially in the afternoon
she was agitated
the rest of the time she would be peaceful
it was tough today, grandma
I'd rather forget it
putting you in such trouble
among us…
she'd listen only to dad
but i doubt she knew he was her son
that was creepy
grandma
let's go
all right, kotoko
all right
this way
you can't sleep like that
your nightgown
this is it?
grandma go back to sleep
grandma sleep
she went to your study this time?
she's doing this every night?
keep it quiet
thanks noriko
for 2 weeks, every night
at first i thought
she couldn't find the bathroom
she came to my room
she is disoriented
she checks every room in turn
until she finds her own
in yugashima she'd wander 3 times a night
even in yugashima
in my room and in madam's room
the kitchen too
then back to her room
so she's not looking for her room
we should close her door
like a child looking for her mother
if it was so
we'd feel sad for her
but she's spooking us
or a mother looking for her child
kotoko take the flashlight from her
but…
when we hid the funeral book she forgot
hide it
she won't wander
you're wrong
do as i say
ok
yesterday
she lost the flashlight
you searched?
the 2 of us in the night
for the flashlight…
she's wandering
no way
that flashlight has legs
forgot
here, flowers
thanks "slip-showing" yone-chan
"slip-showing" yone-chan
good weather
the amaranth is beautiful.
we call it tampala…
this is so nice
I'd like a garden too
indeed
wait here
the new secretary
sir
today deadline for the series
i know
they want to split it in 3 volumes
they need to know where to split
good
there was a person writing every day
he went
dead?
all too soon
3 days after he died
the 3rd day
he was popular
many people mourned him
there's one thing
i always wanted to tell you
we won't meet again
need to tell you
what?
that woman living with me
shigako?
she's just a servant
any other person living with you?
that woman who took my son
every night
i ask her for my son
she would not tell me
if i could see him just once before i die
grandma
you left your son back
never considered his sadness
"the rain stopped"
what?
"left many puddles"
"the pacific, the mediterranean, the sea of japan"
"each to its own"
"but my favorite"
"is not of this earth, a small, new channel"
"links mother & me"
"but my favorite"
"is not of this earth, a small, new channel"
"linking mother & me"
"is not of this earth"
"a small, new channel"
teacher
hello
soap
i was right about the flashlight
grandma is not roaming anymore
something happened?
nothing
you're different
the usual
kuwako is not here?
she's joining us at the harbor
cheeeeese
good?
thank you
we're on our way
thank you for your kindness
noriko
next year, I'll visit you
good luck with your photos
i'm gone
good
everyone going back
she knew it
because i took a photo
she wanted to look good
didn't have her dentures though
indeed
lost it
her dentures
haven't seen her with it lately
haven't seen it
neither did i
power outage
the fuse
i'll check
you found it?
it's on
good
farewell
kuwako is late
she'll take the plane then
i look for her
maybe she fears the sea
like grandma
never heard that one
she can't swim
she loves the firm ground
when did you hear that?
at our wedding
an awful long time ago
she said she'd die
when she left for taiwan
a ship sank just before their trip
she thought the whole family would die
at least she would save her son
she left me because of that?
a survivor son had to be left behind
no matter how painful it was for him
to preserve the family for the ancestors sake
what did she have in mind
a sole survivor
his temperament will be strong
you knew this all along?
why didn't you tell me?
you became interested…
only recently
surely not
you'd feel abandoned in any case
it's your drive to write excellent novels
excuse me
Mr. Igami
i need a phone
1,2,3,4
and those you ate before
eat too much of them you'll turn yellow
already yellow
indeed
my feet are yellow too
can't see them
i'll have one too
it's dad
entrance door is open, check on grandma
the entrance…
dad?
30 min left, can't see kuwako
she didn't call you?
no
grandma
kotoko
let me hang up
what's with grandma?
grandma is gone
what?
we call the police
i'll be there in 5min
grandma
when you reel in a strong fish…
grandma, what happened?
looking for someone?
go to numazu to see my son
numazu on the seaside?
so what you'll go there…
find him floating…
and reel him in ashore?
where in numazu?
behind the imperial villa
want to see him?
want to see him
i need your attention
quiet please
moment please
sorry to bother
one of you truckers
going toward numazu imperial villa
numazu
grandma here
wants to see her son
here
who?
shige
shige, great
hurry
shige go
grandma, this is shige
shige, this is grandma
if i go i could see my son
on board
made it on time
kuwako
welcome
made it
please
i'm sorry
couldn't find swimsuit
excuse me
you saw an old lady
an old lady
holding a purse
a white-haired old lady
she was walking unsteady
grandma?
holding a flashlight
in shige's truck
shige stop
she'll be fine, come
kotoko is riding a truck
kotoko driving a truck?
she's not driving
a nice trucker is helping
to catch another truck with grandma
a truck chasing a truck
grandma is going to numazu
she want to see the ocean
she is going to where you used to swim
the imperial villa?
better let her go
enough
kotoko is handling this
grandma is scrared of water
we take care of noriko here
i've had enough
wait, a person is getting off
i'll be fine
she's in your hands
noriko, I'm not forgetting you
i'll take a plane
don't worry
sweet potatoes, freshly baked
dad
you missed the boat?
well I'm here
quite an adventure
grandma got car sick we when to a hospital
truck driver was so kind
quite an ordeal, i tried to call
all is well…
that ends well
it all ends well
sorry for all the trouble
you worked hard
grandma, get on
don't know who you are
but you're so kind
the ocean is scary
grandma
long ago
there was a diving board there
all numazu school students
were diving from here
kosaku, you know I'm scared of the ocean
21 november 1973
i'm back
welcome back
you're early
didn't want to stay for the banquet
kotoko?
she shows her photos from hawaii
she went to hawaii
welcome back
segawa received his award?
unanimously approved
he's got his award
your futon is already set for the night
kotoko you stay here.
for old time's sake
noriko's new boyfriend
3rd in 3 years… she's surprising
the clock is loud tonight
really?
particularly tonight
mom, have you seen this?
no need to close
so unusual
only some light commentaries to write
he always keeps it open now
since i left it's quieter
maybe
grandma has been 3 years in izu
she's peaceful now
the whole house is getting peaceful
you mean we have become old and sluggish
we were in constant grandma alert
indeed
the clock is loud tonight
dad
aunt shibako calling
she died?
grandma's condition suddenly got worse
doctor put her on intravenous drip
set the phone line in my study
all right
better find a car
it will come in the morning
the inauguration ceremony in numazu is on the 25th
so i packed your suit and shirts
car?
departure 7:00
kuwako and me ride along
when is kuwako coming?
she'll be here soon
ok
y'all go to bed
can't sleep
if grandma makes it tonight
she'll live another 5-10 years
i'm here
what's going on?
phone is ringing
hello
just now
grandma breathed her last
at 1:48
mother died peacefully in her home…
and we owe this to you as a couple
I'm so grateful
mother is at peace
you two took good care of her
till her last moments
thank you
so many years of dedication
suddenly mont ubasute's landscape came up
suddenly my legs are unsteady
for all i carried her on my back
i felt i had no choice
couldn't find her a suitable place
mother was angry
she said i wasn't looking hard enough
for my only mother
a place to get rid of her
to find such a place…
it is not a sin
you found her dentures?
it was nowhere to be found
minimasubs,