Subtitles by KBS World
Episode 50 End
Hello, everyone.
I'm Best Global's Jang Taesu,
who recently won Businessman of the Year.
There are many senior entrepreneurs
and colleagues who deserve the award,
so I feel a very big responsibility
to win this accolade.
And it's
a great honor to have the position
to represent all entrepreneurs.
Sitting here brings back
old memories.
I had a friend.
He trusted me when I had nothing,
and helped me get to where I am today.
He was the president of Taehu Industry,
where Best Global began.
Kim Sangjun.
That was my friend's name.
He was naively trusting
and honest
even to a fault.
I considered his company
as my own,
and worked hard.
Mr. Jang Hyeondo.
How dare you come here!
Jang Hyeondo?
You're that guy?
How dare you show your face here?
Get out.
I'm sorry.
That's all I can say.
But
I
Stole...
All his money.
Hello?
He did?
Yes.
I tricked my trusting friend's family,
and bought their shares for pennies.
And I even kicked his family out
from their house.
And I used
the stolen money
and built my own company.
Best Global's Jang Taesu made a confession
during the chairman's acceptance speech,
at the Korean Businessmen's Association.
President Jang Taesu stated he embezzled
Taehu Industry's money
on the day his friend
and president Kim Sangjun passed away...
Can you make a statement!
At the Korean Businessmen's Association's
chairman's acceptance speech, Best Global's (KBC NEWS, Breaking
News, Best Global's Jang Taesu confesses to embezzlement)
Jang Taesu made a surprise announcement.
President Jang Taesu...
During his speech, he confessed to
embezzlement on the day his friend and
former president Kim Sangjun passed away.
The president of Best Global, Jang Taesu,
formerly known as Taehu Industry,
won Businessman of the
Year Award last January.
Controversy over the selection
process seems inevitable.
Reporting from the KBA inauguration,
this is Kim Taehyeon of KBS.
(Best Global's Jang Taesu
Confesses to Embezzlement)
What are you staring at?
Oh, my!
Look who it is!
The president of Jiwan's
company and his son!
Right?
Yes, you're right.
Oh, my, what happened?
This is why you need to date with caution.
Wait, they broke up.
Oh, still, Jiwan...
It's over.
But aren't you relieved?
Maybe Eunsu had a hunch.
Maybe that's why they broke up.
Minja...
Right, I'm needed at the big room.
(Jang Taesu)
Have you been well?
(The late Kim Sangjun's Grave)
I'm sorry I haven't visited much.
Perhaps
Sangjun died because of me.
That day
I was supposed to meet Sangjun,
and I was late.
Sugyeong, why are you doing this?
Stay there. I'll be there by five!
Okay?
Everyone had gone home,
and when I got back to the office,
I saw a pill bottle on the hallway.
This is Sangjun's medicine.
Why is this...
Sangjun.
Sangjun!
Hey, Sangjun!
After that day,
I knew I would regret it
for the rest of my life.
Why didn't you stop then?
My mother and I would've forgiven you.
Jiwan and my mother
would've considered you
as a father and a son,
and we could've been a family.
Dad!
It was all because of my greed.
I tried to convince myself I did it for
Sugyeong and Hyeondo, but it was my greed.
I'm sorry, Seonhui.
If it were Sangjun,
he would've forgiven you already.
You should
free yourself from that guilt.
I'm sorry.
Once again, I'm sorry, Seonhui.
How have you been?
Lots of things have been bothering me,
but I've been alright.
Why? Are you worried?
Yes.
I am worried.
You have to be firm to run a company.
You said you wanted to be like me.
A businessman like me.
Although I'm sure you've changed your mind.
You're soft, just like Sangjun,
but you can be firm, so you'll do well.
Sangjun gave me that company,
so giving it to you is
the right thing to do.
You developed the company.
I believe the only person who can
run it well, is you.
If I stay at the company,
it will suffer.
So I must resign.
Discuss with your elders
at home and decide.
He's giving you what?
Stocks.
And he's resigning from his position.
So the stocks,
how much are they worth?
We didn't do this for the money, Haengsuk.
But if we can get it, why not?
Seonhui,
let's accept it, okay?
Just accept it.
We can buy a house.
The landlord will ask for extra deposit,
and I'm tired of moving.
Jiwan and Eunsu need money to get married.
I don't need anything.
I can take care of myself.
I can't believe you!
We need money for so many things!
You don't know how important money is!
We can't just accept it, Haengsuk.
Why not?
Mom.
Your opinion is more important than hers.
Seonhui,
you and Jiwan decide.
Why? When you're the elder of the family?
I wasn't expecting your call.
Jiwan told me
what you plan on doing.
I kept putting it off,
but I couldn't put it off any longer.
Right.
I was wondering why I
haven't heard from you.
If you're hesitating,
there's no need for it.
I'm not saying I'm handing
it over to Jiwan now...
I'm sorry for cutting you off.
No matter how much I think about it,
my family can't accept that money from you.
But Seonhui...
Sangjun gave you that company.
He did it because he believed in you.
Do you believe in Jiwan
as much as Sangjun believed in you?
He has the qualities of a good businessman.
You're saying he has the potential,
but you don't believe in him as much.
But I want to give him a chance.
I know you feel you owe my family
a lot.
But I don't want to take away
Jiwan's chance of making it on his own.
The moment Sangjun decided to give you
the company, it became yours.
I'm sure it was the best decision
he could've made for us and the company.
So now,
the decision is yours.
You're the one who love and cherish
Best Global the most.
Were you disappointed?
No.
Okay, Hanseok.
There is
one last thing you can help me with.
Since establishing this company in '93,
I was confident I worked
harder than anyone.
But now that I look back,
I wasn't the only one
who built this company.
I believe it was built by
everyone sitting here, and the love our
customers have shown Best Global.
So I am going to resign from my position,
and donate my shares to society.
I believe that is the only compensation
I can offer the people I hurt.
I appreciate all your hard work.
Thank you.
(Best Global's Jang Taesu
Donates His Fortune)
He could've bought me a few houses first.
Seonhui, what did you say?
Wait,
what are you doing with that money?
Oh, my!
Has poverty driven you mad?
Seonhui, why don't you
give it to me?
I can spend that money
in a really good way.
- So...
- Minja, you're funny.
Wait!
I mean...
Seonhui!
You know me, don't you?
The watermelon is really sweet.
That's so much money.
How could they give it all up?
How can people have no desire for money?
Do they like living like this? Like this?
Oh, be quiet.
They say they want to make it on their own,
so what can I do?
I've seen people who suddenly become rich,
and bad things happen to them.
I'm scared of money now.
Bad things, yeah right!
You never had that kind of money before.
- What?
- If they gave me a bit of it,
I could have a decent...
Decent what?
You need money?
Of course I do!
I have lots of things I want to buy!
I don't have any clothes to wear!
Oh, when will you ever grow up?
I'm sick of stealing Eunsu's clothes.
I'm never going to grow up!
Do you have any plans?
I'm just going to take time off.
Okay.
You should do that.
What about you?
You told me to learn to
become a businessman.
I should do that now.
You established Best Global.
The records and journals in your study,
if I take from that,
I'd become the most valuable employee.
I'll start training for real.
I'm going to start from the bottom,
and become the head executive director.
(Ms. Jeong Sugyeong)
Oh, boy.
My son finally grew up,
but I have no one to brag to.
You come here too often these days.
I came before I get too busy to visit.
Do you like it here?
Of course I do.
Are you here to spy on me?
Are you going to let Father be?
We're divorced, so we're strangers.
You don't want to get back together?
No.
I love being legally single and free!
What are you going to do?
What do you mean?
We'll live this way, seeing other people.
Have you met someone?
I am going to.
Do you want me to live alone forever?
I mean, I think Father's waiting for you.
But it's up to you two.
Who is it?
Oh, Ms. Lee!
Welcome.
Oh.
Have you been well?
Yes. What brings you here?
Have a seat over there.
Here.
What's all this?
I heard your husband likes this herb.
I had some at home, so I brought it over.
Oh, you brought so much.
Thank you very much.
Did you have something to tell me?
Minja, let's not beat around the bush,
and be honest with each other.
What about?
Is there something to be honest about?
Hi, Mom.
I'm on my way home from school.
You want to see me now?
Okay.
Hi, Grandma.
But I can't get off work until later.
I'll be there right after work, then.
Bye.
You said you wanted to see a movie.
Why all of a sudden?
You're not feeling well?
But why...
Okay, Grandma.
Okay. I'll call you later.
That's too bad.
I'll see you at home.
But why so suddenly...
My grandmother is sick, so she can't come.
My mom has to see someone.
What should I do with the movie tickets?
What time is the movie?
There's an hour left.
Then cancel them.
One hour is plenty of time.
Jiwan!
See?
We have to get involved.
They are young, so if we give them
a nudge, I'm sure they'll get it.
Hey!
You...
Why aren't you on a date?
Why did you come here?
You said you were sick,
so I came here to get some porridge.
Grandma,
don't you have to see a doctor?
Let's go. I'll take you.
Oh, silly boy!
Taking me to a doctor isn't what I want!
Where's Yeongju?
So?
What do you mean, so?
We had shaved ice and said goodbye.
I have so much work to do,
so stop playing jokes on me.
Jokes?
You think I'm doing this
because I have nothing better to do?
I can't understand you at all.
We provided you with the perfect chance,
so you should see a movie, have dinner...
What does he take my daughter for?
What's his problem?
You're such a pretty girl!
What more does he want?
He doesn't want anything.
So please stay out of my business.
At this rate, you'll die single!
I'm really scared for you!
I would love to find out
what you're thinking.
It's not like that so stop!
Why are they so dense?
They should at least go on a few dates,
when I am helping them out.
You should give up.
Maybe they aren't meant to be together.
Oh, I think I've tried just about,
no, I've tried everything I could
possibly try, given the circumstances.
I thought Jiwan was the dense one,
but I think it's Yeongju is the problem.
What?
What's wrong with Yeongju?
She knows how Jiwan is,
so she should take charge, and...
Oh, my!
That's nonsense, Ms. Lee!
Yeongju is a teacher!
She's a lady, so she can't do that.
What if a rumor starts?
Well,
to be honest,
Jiwan is the problem.
He's a man, but he's not bold.
He lacks passion and drive.
He's so lukewarm and bland.
What?
Lukewarm and bland?
That's because he's cautious.
If he's anymore cautious,
he'll be single forever.
Wait,
are you cursing my grandson?
You started it.
Oh, boy.
Why is this coffee so bland?
You said it!
Yes.
I'm grateful for your offer,
but I don't want an honorary position.
Yes, tell them I said thanks, but no.
Yes. Thank you anyway. Goodbye.
Ma'am, get me a glass of water!
- With ice, hurry up.
- Ms. Jeong...
You're always so slow!
Wait,
what are you doing in my house?
I was in Seoul, so I dropped by.
But you have no business here.
So this house is all you have now?
Yes.
I've no business with a poor man.
Good.
You have no business with me,
and you divorced me.
No money, and legally a stranger.
You can't hold on to me anymore.
I have no intention of holding on to you.
But I still came to see you,
I guess you're still attractive.
Ma'am!
I asked for ice water ages ago!
I'm going to get some rest,
so don't make any noise.
What's this?
Jeong Sugyeong!
We're divorced,
so why is the credit card under my name!
Be quiet!
Don't be petty. It's not a lot.
I told you I'm taking a nap.
What is she trying to do?
How much is this?
Hundred, thousand,...
You went on a shopping spree?
Hi, it's me.
Yes.
The advisor position you talked about?
I thought about it,
and I do kind of want to take it.
How much is the annual salary?
Yes, that sounds good.
That's a pretty good offer.
When should I start?
(1 year later)
Sign there.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
(Yeongju)
Hi, Yeongju.
Of course I got the contract.
Tell Mr. Kang not to worry.
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
(To Kang Yeongju)
It's been a year already.
Jiwan must have gotten his, too.
Yeongju,
you'll read this a year from now,
and I want to say I'm waiting for Jiwan.
I'm going to
tell Jiwan how I feel about him.
Yeongju.
You're writing?
You came to get coffee?
My days of being his friend's sister,
perhaps...
Perhaps this will be the last time.
If he turns me down after I tell him,
your heart...
The year you will spend waiting
might make Jiwan feel uncomfortable,
so you might try to avoid him.
Yeongju.
You got off work?
Yes.
Good. Go home and get some rest.
But Yeongju,
be brave and tell him.
How desperate...
Jiwan!
You feel.
Enjoy your food.
- All of it is good.
- You like it?
It's so delicious.
Being the owner suits you better!
You look better now than in your uniform.
You look so much better.
Thank you.
Enjoy your food.
Oh, you're here! Eunsu, you're here, too?
Hello. Congratulations.
I heard the headquarters has high hopes
for this branch, and I can see why.
What high hopes?
But isn't this smaller than my branch?
What? You should go in there.
It's much bigger.
All you need to do now is make money.
Right.
But where is your mother?
- She'll be here soon.
- Okay.
You should get something good.
Honey.
No, no need to escort us.
Go inside and have a seat.
Oh, Ms. Lee!
- Congratulations.
Jiwan didn't send you a plant?
He must be very busy with the wedding.
Where's Yeongju?
She'll be here soon.
She went to deliver rice cake upstairs
and the parking lot, but
she hasn't returned.
You're getting more and more beautiful.
Thank you.
You should get something to eat.
Yes, please let us have some.
Sure.
Honey, can you take care of them?
Okay.
No, it's okay.
If there's work, I should
go, even on a weekend.
It'll take me a little over an hour.
Honey!
Yes?
What about my meal?
I made side dishes. They're in the fridge.
You can just take them out and eat.
I can't eat alone.
You won't even let me hire a housekeeper.
Just today. It's only for today.
I'm busy. I'll see you later.
I told you to apologize,
not donate your entire fortune!
You even sold the house!
I'll be back.
Wait, honey!
Keep next weekend open.
We have to be somewhere.
Okay.
I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.
Oh, what's taking her so long?
Seonhui!
Yes, mother. I'm coming.
What took you so long?
Where's Eunsu?
She's already there.
- She is?
- Yes.
- Let's go.
- You look beautiful.
- I do?
- Of course.
Is someone getting married today?
Yes.
Hyeondo, you come up, too.
You have to say hi.
Me?
But it's hard to get a parking spot here!
Go park and come up. It's the 3rd floor.
Hurry up.
Oh, you're here. Thank you.
Are you not going to see them ever again?
You have to see them, sooner or later.
- Let's go.
- Honey.
Taesu!
Oh...
Welcome.
You made it all the way here, so stay.
You can't just leave.
How much longer do you think I have?
Don't cry at my grave after I'm gone,
and show me your face from time to time.
That's how you can be a good son.
We don't have a lot of guests,
so go in and have a seat.
Let's go.
I'm glad you came.
Had I left him be, he'd never come see you.
You don't even know whose wedding this is?
Eunsu...
I'm Han Eunsu.
You're my brother's friend,
Jang Hyeondo, right?
Kim Jiwan, you're dating now?
I'm Jang Hyeondo.
Hello, I'm Han Eunsu.
For a picky guy, you sure have
average taste in women.
I'm sorry for being average.
Right.
Kim Jiwan's friend.
Hello.
Excuse me, can I see the bride's face?
I never thought I could be so happy!
Where's my most handsome husband?
I want to see him!
Darling!
Oh, darling.
You become more beautiful every day.
You look just like Won Bin.
If I'm Won Bin, you must be Lee Nayoung!
I don't know!
You must know!
Won Bin?
Nayoung, we'll see you later.
Good luck.
Everyone agrees!
- You're Won Bin?
- Aunt!
- You're Lee Nayoung.
- Eunha!
- You're here?
Haengsuk, congratulations.
Eunha, you look so pretty.
Twirl for me.
You're the prettiest.
You're the prettiest in the world today.
- Oh!
- She's not.
She's old.
If you're jealous, just say so.
Who, me?
I can get married today if I wanted to.
Then go ahead.
She's getting married today.
Next is the bride's family photo.
Please gather around.
Oh, wait.
Mr. Photographer, just a second.
Taesu!
She wants us in the photo.
Let's go.
But honey,
let's go.
It's embarrassing.
Please come.
Everyone's waiting.
We'll just leave.
Can't you stand in Sangjun's place?
My mother needs a son today.
To her and my children,
you are Sangjun's replacement.
That's what Sangjun
wanted to ask you to do for us.
- Come.
- Hey,
Taesu,
what can we do?
We don't have relatives,
so you have to fill in for them.
Mother, I...
Yes, I'm your mother.
I fed you and Sangjun for years and years.
I'm your mom.
What are you waiting for?
Come and stand with us.
Yeongju, bring your mom and dad.
Okay.
Eunha.
Let's go.
Please stand together.
Everyone, smile.
Smile.
One, two, three!
(Thank you for watching Bluebird's House.)
(KBS 2TV Weekend Drama, Bluebird's House)
You're a sidekick, you bastard.
- Seriously?
- I'm sorry.
You'll drop them all.
Thank you.
Squeeze your brains!
Jang Hyeondo!
Squeeze your brains if you have to,
and bring me some ideas!
Don't laugh!
Go to Daejeon and deliv, deliver...
I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- It's not...
Let's go see a doctor. I'll go again.
That's... Uh...
I'm so sorry!
I can't believe we...
That really hurt!
It's not sweet.
Why?
So awkward. I'm sorry.
You have nothing to say, right?
What's wrong with you?
I'm sorry.
With that money, I can...
I can't last 10 minutes...
You told me to train for... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You told me to train for...
Seriously...