Year 1993, the ethnic war between Serbs,
Muslims and Croats is raging in Bosnia.
Most of the Muslims civilians decided
to remain in the town of Trebinje,
which is on the territory
controlled by Serbian army.
Trebinje
Bosna and Herzegovina, 1993.
CIRCLES
/ Based on actual events /
- No, no. No, too early for me.
- I can.
- How long are you staying?
- Only for the weekend.
If the shooting starts,
I have to go back.
Easy, easy.
I'll suprise Nada.
I didn't tell her I was coming.
- She's not going anywhere,
don't you worry. - I don't.
She looks at you like you're
the only man in the world.
- Don't plan anything till all
this is over. - We won't.
- I'll wait for you for lunch.
- Alright. I'll be here.
Cigarettes!
Marko!
Ah!
You fool!
I'll be right back.
Come here.
Why didn't you tell me
you were coming?
Whenever I do, shooting starts
and they don't let me go.
This is better, no bad luck.
- You're wearing it.
- What did you think?
It's war, you promise
yourself to one man,
- and leave with another...
Who could blame you? - Get off!
I'll be done in a hour.
Go, on, leave!
- What are you doing here?
- Come down.
What's up...
Great to see you man.
What? What?
What do you think you're doing?
Hi.
- What's up?
- Got "Drina" without filter?
- You're lucky, only two left.
- Thanks, cheers.
Take care.
What happened
the other night?
We heard explosions here.
I thought we are all finished.
They brought guys from your unit,
I was stiching them up.
Two days I didn't sleep.
Look what I got for you.
What is it?
You fool...
Where'd you get this?
Stole it from the captain.
For you to write prescriptions.
Thank you.
- Come on...
- Pissing, are you?
- Give it!
- I won't...
- What'll you have?
- "Drina", what else.
Give me two packs of
"Drina" without filter.
None left.
What do you mean, none left?
Just sold the last one.
You see I haven't got any.
None?
None left for me?
Do you know who I am?
I know Todor, of course I do.
I've none left, I swear.
- The Muslim's fucking with you.
- Wait!
Give me your ID.
Don't Todor, please...
You know me.
Give me your ID!
So?!
I don't have it with me.
Don't have it with you?!
Ah, Haris...
Move! Move!
Where do you
think you're going?
Bring him out!
Motherfucker!
Who do you think
you're fucking with?
Fucking Muslim fuck!
Get up!
Get up, motherfucker, now!
Motherfucker!
Your people are killing us
and you're fucking with us...
you Muslim fuck!
Wait.
Where are you going?
Hey!
- Todor!
- What?
It's ok.
Leave him alone.
12 YEARS LATER
Halle, Germany
Nada?
- I'm Haris.
- We've met.
This is Dusan.
What's up, Dusan?
Next week they'll perform
in a school performance.
Go on, set the table.
- Where do you work?
- With BMW.
- And your wife?
- She's a nurse.
The head nurse.
Go, go, go...
Does anyone know you're here?
Nobody.
Dusan, please eat.
- I'm not hungry.
- Dusan...
- Thank you for everything.
- Don't mention it.
Haris has explained
your situation.
I think you should
notify the police.
No, no... don't worry.
- You'd work the day shift.
You can't start tomorrow. - Thank you.
Don't thank me, when Haris
brings someone, that's it.
He helped me when I got here
as if I was his brother...
Don't worry. As long as this man looks
after you everything will be alright.
Who's that looking at the sausages?
We'll eat them up, instantly!
Is this alright for you?
- That's it. Couldn't find anything
better in two days. - It's fine.
We just need to be somewhere
until I figure out what to do.
- I have an old TV in the car.
- No need.
For the boy not to get bored.
I'll go get it.
Mum... who is he?
Nobody.
Sit there and don't move.
Belgrade, Serbia
Doctor... A car crash,
heavy bleeding, condition critical.
Doctor, he is ready.
Do you remember me, Todor?
Trebinje
Bosnia and Herzegovina
Did he really tell you
he needs a worker?
He did, two weeks ago.
But no one wants to work.
Great, I'm totally broke.
You're fool to study.
Should I drive a lorry
all my life, like you?
Why would he build
a church here?
We're moving the old one,
because of the power plant.
They unloaded the stone blocks and
now we're assembling it as it was.
He's a bit odd,
but he pays up fair and square.
You're late.
Sorry, boss. But I've brought a mate,
he wants to work.
He's an excellent worker.
- What's your name?
- Bogdan Rakita.
I don't need you.
Can I give him
a lift back to town?
No! You're already late.
Load the trolley.
It's me, Mother.
- Where were you?
- Looking for work.
What work?
With that Ranko who's
moving the church.
- With Ranko?
- Yes, with Ranko.
He wouldn't hire me.
What's the matter?
You mustn't work for him.
- Why not?
- Because.
Where are you going? Do you
here me? Where are you going?!
- Why didn't you tell me?
- I didn't know.
Liar.
I forgot,
we were drunk last night...
You should've told me,
it's not a joke.
Sorry...
Hello Esad...
It's me...
When?
He threatened Esad.
He said you kidnapped child.
And that you were in rehab...
Alcohol rehab.
What's up Dusan?
No one at the shop
knows where you live.
There's no way for
him to find you.
He always finds a way.
Take us to the station.
I can talk with him if you like.
Mum...
...I'm hungry.
I'll make you a sandwich.
Go back in there.
Hello.
No, I'm not coming home.
I'm at Nada's.
I can't explain now,
I need to stay here tonight.
I'll come in the morning.
Bye.
Is it true what
he said to Esad?
When that thing
happened with Marko...
I did not know what
to do with myself.
I just wanted to leave Trebinje.
When I came to Germany,
I got a job as a
waitress in his club.
And this is how I
met my husband.
Everything in my
life happened wrong.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to sleep.
What do you want?
To work.
You need work that badly?
No. But it's not fair.
That I can't stand.
And you know what's fair?
I'm no worse than Petar.
Don't put so much load,
we will brake our back.
- Boss, don't!
- Show me the hand.
Bring some 'rakija'. (Serbian strong
baverage made from various fruits)
See what you've done?
There's no other like this one!
Clean it.
I told you I didn't need you.
Leave now and don't come back.
What are you looking at?
What?
Leave!
- What happened? - Nothing!
- Let me see that! - I'm alright!
- He wanted to hurt you?
- Leave me alone.
Don't you, "leave me alone".
- Don't you see he wants revenge?
- I hurt myself!
- You don't know anything!
- I know much more than you think.
- I can't bear to lose you too.
- You're totally out of your mind.
No! I won't let you leave the house!
I'll lock you in.
Do you hear me?
I'll lock you in!
- Todor, how are you?
- Better.
They told me...
you're the Doctor...
... who saved me.
Yes.
Unfortunately.
But you'll need
another surgery.
Your life depends on that one.
Why of all people I had
to fall into your hands?
Oh, fuck...
Do you believe in anything?
I go to church.
I believe in God.
Does your conscience bother you?
My conscience is clean.
What did you expect?
Nothing.
You're not alive yet.
Your surgery's on Wednesday.
- What do you want?
- To work.
- Want something to eat?
- No.
- Want water?
- I'm fine.
Come tomorrow.
Just don't break anything.
Where are you going?
Wait, we'll go together.
What do you want?
Stay away from my son.
He's not guilty for anything.
Good morning.
Is Haris in?
No, he's not.
Can I help you?
I'll wait for him.
Thanks.
Sorry, who are you?
Good morning.
Enjoy your meal.
May I sit down?
Haris, come at once.
There's a man here looking for you.
Straight to school.
Bye.
How old are the girls?
Seven and nine.
My Dusan is seven.
But I haven't managed
to preserve my family...
Where's my son?
With his mother.
And where is she?
I don't know.
I only helped her find the job.
- Don't lie to me.
- I don't.
I'm telling you the truth.
She's an alcoholic.
Fucked up in the head.
She's not a good mother.
Sorry, what is going on?
You realise I'll do
anything to get my son.
Do you realise?
Haris?
Let's go for a little ride.
Let's go.
- Can I do something?
- No.
Have a nice day.
Is this the school your
daughters go to?
Look, there's Elke.
You have a nice family.
How would you feel if
someone took your child?
Huh?
I'm glad you understand me.
I'll come tomorrow
at noon to your place.
And you will give
me my son back.
Elke?
Elke, where is Alma?
Where is Alma?
Alma?
Alma, we have to go home.
- Why?
- Quickly.
I went to the court.
I asked them to renew the trial.
They said the
case is outdated.
That wasn't a trial,
that was nothing.
Only Rakita regreted...
...and got killed
immediately afterwards.
This guy didn't even
blink at the trial.
I'm supposed to
operate him again.
I don't know what to do.
I'm not interested
in that man at all.
It can't bring my Marko back.
There's just one
thing bothering me...
Was it all for nothing?
A life, just like that...
You know?
It's not about that Haris.
He's a good man.
But it's like he thrown
his life away...
Into nothing.
When you throw a stone in
water something happens...
Those circles appear...
and spread...
And yet this...
That's what I fear...
...that when a man
does good thing...
It means nothing
to other people.
Don't, no...
I have to drive back.
I work in the morning.
- Hi.
You have to go somewhere,
first thing in the morning.
If I had anywhere to go,
I would not come here.
Is there anywhere a place
where he can't get to you?
Nowhere except Trebinje.
He can't enter Bosnia,
there's a warrant on him.
Then you have
to go to Trebinje.
I don't have Dusan's passport.
He'll be at my place
at noon tomorrow.
If I don't bring him to you
he will kidnap my children.
You can't be on the
run al your life.
Hello?
Esad, hi...
I need that cousin of yours.
Who can get passports...
It doesn't matter
what it costs...
Alright. Yes...
Just a second.
- Do you have the boy's picture?
- No.
Yes, she has it all.
Yes.
Alright.
I'll wait for you to call. Bye.
They're asleep.
Please Haris, call the police.
I'm scared.
That man is dangerous.
I'll call them, then.
We mustn't call the police!
In the morning you have
to go to your parents...
...to hide, for a while.
Why don't we go together?
To get away.
Andrea...
You know why I'm doing all this.
I do.
Dad, I can't sleep.
Let's go to bed.
Boss!
Are you alright?
You alright?
Get water! Do you have
medications or something?
- We have to get him to the doctor.
- I'm not going anywhere.
Drive me home.
It's enough for today.
Should I stay with
you for a while?
No need.
Come on.
Wait.
What do you want?
How are you?
Alright.
Can't eat, though.
I've asked for another doctor.
They told me you're the best.
You're the only one
doing these operations.
Yes, that's why I came.
To tell you...
I can't operate on you.
You can't, huh?
No.
You want money, is that it?
I don't take money.
What do you want then?
To torture me?
I wanted to see...
...if you repent...
Why would I repent?
I don't understand.
That was an accident.
If he hadn't interfered,
everything would've been alright.
But the idiot pops up in the middle
of the war to decide what is right.
Fuck him,
it was his own fault!
I don't owe anything to anyone...
...to anyone!
Was there a trial?
Huh?
Was I sentenced to two years,
sent to the front line?
Digging trenches till the end of the war,
waiting for a grenade to hit me.
All because of an idiot.
You know what?
When I saw you on the table that day,
when you thought you're finished,
you were not this cocky.
I thought there might be
something human in you.
That a man like
you might change.
Even if on his dying bed.
But a beast remains a beast.
And a pussy remains a pussy.
Why didn't you step in,
to save your mate, huh?
That's what bothers you.
I'm not your problem,
you're your own problem.
You want me to tell you I repent
to make you feel better.
You stood there watching.
You didn't even move, hey!
We can't carry suitcases.
Pack their things in this...
Where are we going?
You're going to your Granny and
Granddad's just for a couple of days.
Pack your things in this bag.
Alright, alright.
One taxi, please.
The old shopping mall.
- Mum, can we take the flutes?
- Yes.
From the side street...
Yes, Hermanstrasse.
- Where are we going now?
- Towards school.
To the train station.
- Dad...
- Yes.
Why aren't you
coming with us?
I can't.
You'll be back soon.
Come on.
I'll pick you up
when this is over.
You're early.
Come.
- Here, count the money.
- Here you go.
I wouldn't take the money,
but you know where it goes to.
My friend...
I don't mean to pry,
but I don't know why are you doing this.
- Thank you.
- You can go out this way.
Hey.
Hi.
Go back to bed.
Why aren't
you getting ready?
Haris, I can't.
I'm not well.
Come and wash your face.
Here.
What do you want?
Huh?
To hide this child, keep him in a cage,
not beaing able to go out in street...
For how long?
Till he or the police finds him
and takes him from you forever.
And you're never allowed
to see him again.
Hey...
...Dusan.
Please get dressed.
Go on, hurry.
I'll do it.
I made you a coffee.
I'll replace those bars
in the cellar tomorrow.
Cats come in...
I saw some nets on the market.
I'm off.
In the fridge... I made food
for you to take to work.
There's enough for Petar too.
Thank you.
- How late is he?
- Twenty minutes.
He's never been late before.
He's not answering.
We should've taken him to
the doctor's yesterday.
We should've...
I'll go up.
What?
You thought I died?
We came to pick you up.
We're not working today.
I told you.
- You didn't.
- I didn't?
I'm telling you now,
we're not working.
Are you alright?
Do you want to see a doctor?
No. I have something
else to do.
- We're not working today.
- Is he not well?
Don't know.
You go.
Can I give you a hand?
Dragan Rakita
Marko Kovacevic
Come in.
Leave that there.
Come here.
No, thank you.
- You don't drink? - I do...
but don't feel like it now.
I'd rather have some water.
I'm thirsty.
Well, go get some.
Who's stopping you.
Open the blinds.
Over there too.
It's better like this.
Have a smoke if you like.
Now have a drink.
You know what
day it is today?
I do.
Don't be late tomorrow.
Cigarettes.
You forgot your cigarettes.
Hello?
Ah...
It's you, Haris.
You remembered.
You're the only one
who never forgets.
I don't need anything,
don't worry.
How's your family?
How are the children?
Bless them! Thank God.
Bless them!
Go on, this is expensive.
Nice to hear you,
I'm glad you're all well...
...and thank you, Haris.
Bye.
Come in.
Come on.
Let's go.
I'm not going anywhere.
- Where is my son?
- They left for Bosnia.
Ranko, hello...
It's Haris.
I just thought I'd call...
I will never forget that.
Do you need anything
from here?
Thanks for asking,
they're well.
Andrea is fine, the children...
They grow.
It's not really expensive,
calls are cheaper from here.
Goodbye, Ranko.
We'll stay in touch.
There...
You're alive.
Get down,
we have to wait for Petar.
He has to load the material,
he won't be here before dark.
- We can't do it ourselves, come down.
- I'll give it a try.
We both have to lift it at the same time,
come down I'm telling you!
Don't move!
- Fine, fine, I'm fine.
- You alright?
Can you move the left one?
When I tell you, you yell.
Yes, that's right, yell!
That's it. Help me.
Come on, that's it.
Why did you do it?
Why didn't you listen to me?
You had to do it yourself.
Fool!
Doing things no
one ask you to.
What did you want to prove,
being so stuborn like that!
That you're brave? That you know
what's the right think to do?
Now look where
that's got you!
Moan... so I know
you're alive. Moan!
Here.
I'll lift you, and when I say so,
help me to move you.
Good, that's it.
That's it.
Moan...
Let me hear you,
so I know you're alive. Moan!
Let me hear you...
... we are almost there.
What happened?
An accident,
take us to the hospital.
Come on, give me a hand!
Is that your son?
Yes.
My son.
It's ok.
Rakita!
Put the gun down.
Please.
Stop!
Hey! Hey!
Motherfucker!
Hey!
Dedicated to:
Srdjan Aleksic (1966 - 1993)
Based on actual events
  