OF COURSE YOU'VE GOT
TO TAKE CARE OF IT.
IF WE GET
A TRAFFIC TICKET,
THE OTHER DRIVER
HAS GROUNDS TO SUE.
ROMANIAN STEAK ?
ROMANIAN STEAK, FRIED POTATOES,
CARROTS AND CAULIFLOWER.
CAULIFLOWER, CARROTS,
CAULIFLOWER:
DON'T YOU GET TIRED
OF THE SAME  CHAZZEREI
ALL THE TIME,
YEAR IN, YEAR OUT ?
WHY DON'T YOU TRY SOMETHING
NEW FOR A CHANGE ?
DARLING ?
MINE'S OKAY.
YEAH ?
HOW DOES IT LOOK,
A JUDGE'S CAR IN VIOLATION ?
YOU WERE DRIVING IT
AND YOU HAD TO ARGUE
THE LAW WITH THE OFFICER.
HE WAS RUDE.
HE WAS RUDE
AND HE USED LANGUAGE
THAT HE SHOULDN'T HAVE USED
TO THE WIFE
OF A JUDGE.
HEY, YOU, WAITER.
I CAN'T EAT THIS.
SEND IT BACK.
WANT SOMETHING ELSE,
DARLING ?
YES.
HE HAS HIS OWN
REUBEN SANDWICH.
HE CAN'T EAT THIS.
TAKE IT BACK.
BRING HIM A BREAST
OF VEAL ?
BRING HIM A BREAST OF VEAL.
HOW WAS THE
OFFICER TO KNOW
THAT YOU WERE
THE WIFE OF A JUDGE ?
SHE TOLD HIM.
YOU TOLD THE COP
THAT I WAS A JUDGE ?
I AM YOUR WIFE.
HE SHOULD NOT HAVE
GIVEN ME A TICKET.
HOW DOES IT LOOK ?
OH, AL, MAKE A CALL.
DORA, LISTEN TO ME.
IT IS A VIOLATION OF JUDICIAL
ETHICS FOR ME TO INTERFERE.
IT'S DISHONEST.
AL...
I AM FIRM
ABOUT THIS.
LOOK AT THE WAY YOU
TALKED TO THAT WAITER. HMM ?
IF YOU HAVE FRIENDS
INSTEAD OF ENEMIES,
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO
WORRY ABOUT YOUR BACK.
GET THE POINT ?
YOU'RE A MAN
WITH POWER
WHO WON'T EVEN USE IT
TO PROTECT HIS OWN.
LOYALTY.
LOYALTY. DOES THAT WORD
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU ?
YOU'RE TELLING THIS BOY
HOW TO LIVE ? YOU ARE ?
THAT'S THE IDEA.
DON'T.
HE'S MINE.
THIS IS ONE BOY THEY'RE
NEVER GOING TO FORGET.
WHAT'S THE NAME
OF THE JUDGE ?
( slow instrumental music )
( narrator )
THE COMMUNIST PARTY OF THE UNITED STATES
IS A FIFTH COLUMN
IF THERE EVER WAS ONE.
IT IS FAR BETTER ORGANIZED
THAN WERE THE NAZIS
IN OCCUPIED COUNTRIES
PRIOR TO THEIR CAPITULATION.
THEY ARE SEEKING
TO WEAKEN AMERICA
JUST AS THEY DID IN THEIR
ERA OF OBSTRUCTION
WHEN THEY WERE ALIGNED
WITH THE NAZIS.
THEIR GOAL IS THE OVERTHROW
OF OUR GOVERNMENT.
THERE IS NO DOUBT AS TO WHERE A
REAL COMMUNIST'S LOYALTY RESTS.
THEIR ALLEGIANCE IS TO RUSSIA,
NOT THE UNITED STATES.
THE COMMUNISTS HAVE BEEN,
STILL ARE AND ALWAYS WILL BE
A MENACE TO FREEDOM,
TO DEMOCRATIC IDEALS
TO THE WORSHIP OF GOD,
AND TO AMERICA'S WAY OF LIFE.
I FEEL THAT ONCE
PUBLIC OPINION
IS THOROUGHLY AROUSED,
AS IT IS TODAY,
THE FIGHT AGAINST COMMUNISM
IS WELL ON ITS WAY.
VICTORY WILL BE ASSURED
ONCE COMMUNISTS ARE
IDENTIFIED AND EXPOSED.
( Adolphe Menjou )
THIS IS A FOUL PHILOSOPHY,
THIS COMMUNISTIC THING.
I'D MOVE TO TEXAS
IF IT EVER CAME HERE
BECAUSE I THINK THAT TEXANS
WOULD KILL THEM ON SIGHT.
( laughing )
( questioner )
YOU REFUSE TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION?
( witness )
I'LL HOLD UP MY BELIEF
MY AFFILIATIONS
AND EVERYTHING ELSE
TO THE AMERICAN PUBLIC.
THEY'LL KNOW MY STANCE
AS THEY DO FROM
WHAT I HAVE WRITTEN.
I'VE WRITTEN ABOUT AMERICANISM
FOR YEARS AND I'LL CONTINUE.
( questioner )
STAND AWAY FROM THE STAND !
I AM NOT AND NEVER
HAVE BEEN DISLOYAL.
HAVE BEEN A COMMUNIST.
I AM NOT AND NEVER HAVE
BEEN A SUPPORTER OF
A MEMBER OF,
OR A SYMPATHIZER
WITH ANY ORGANIZATION
KNOWN TO ME TO BE
OR SUSPECTED BY ME
OF BEING CONTROLLED
OR DOMINATED
BY COMMUNISTS.
THERE IS NOT A COMMUNIST
BONE IN MY BODY.
I HAVE NEVER
READ KARL MARX
AND I DON'T KNOW
THE BASIS OF COMMUNISM
BEYOND WHAT I'VE PICKED UP
FROM HEARSAY.
FROM WHAT I'VE HEARD,
I DON'T LIKE IT,
BECAUSE IT ISN'T
ON THE LEVEL.
( radio announcer )
Communism in reality
is not a political party.
It is a way of life:
An evil and malignant
way of life.
It reveals a condition
akin to disease
that spreads
like an epidemic.
And like an epidemic
a quarantine
is necessary
to keep it from
infecting this nation.
( man )
IF I HAD MY WAY,
THEY'D ALL BE
SENT BACK TO RUSSIA
OR SOME OTHER
UNPLEASANT PLACE.
( applaud, gavel banging )
( woman's voice )
DR. SANFORD, PLEASE COME
TO THE 3RD FLOOR
FAMILY CONFERENCE ROOM.
DR. SANFORD,
PLEASE COME
TO THE 3RD FLOOR
FAMILY CONFERENCE ROOM.
( Cohn groaning )
NURSE.
( beeping )
( nurse 1 )
DOCTOR !
( nurse 2 )
CHECK HIS B.P.
( nurse 1 )
I GOT IT.
( orderly )
WHAT DO YOU NEED ?
( nurse 2 )
IS THE O2 ON ?
( nurse 1 )
O2 IS ON,
BUT I'M NOT GETTING
A READING ON THE METER.
( nurse 2 )
TRY THIS.
( orderly )
I'LL TRY.
( young doctor )
IS HE BREATHING ?
HE'S BREATHING.
( nurse 2 )
PULSE 120.
( doctor )
GET A BLOOD GAS.
( orderly )
RESPIRATION 36.
WANT TO GET A RESPIRATORY
TEAM UP HERE ?
GET A CRASH CART,
A GURNEY AND
A STAT CHEST X-RAY.
WHO IS THIS GUY ?
THE WHITE HOUSE CALLED
AGAIN LAST NIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT WANTED TO KNOW
WHAT THEY COULD DO FOR HIM.
THEY WANTED TO MAKE SURE
HE WAS DEAD.
THE BLOOD GAS
DOESN'T LOOK TOO HOT.
I NEED A FACEMASK
OVER HERE !
DID YOU KNOW
THIS GUY ?
ROY COHN ?
WE KNEW HIM
ALL RIGHT.
JOE McCARTHY'S
STRONG RIGHT HAND.
OXYGEN, 4 LITERS.
( young doctor )
MY FATHER SAID
I REMEMBER HIM SAYING THAT.
GREAT PATRIOT ?
( young doctor )
THOSE SPIES, THE ROSENBERGS,
HE GOT THEM
EXECUTED.
$20 SAYS THE GREAT PATRIOT
DOESN'T MAKE IT TILL DAWN.
AAH !
FUCK YOU !
I DON'T NEED YOU.
I DON'T NEED ANYBODY.
ROY COHN CAN
TAKE CARE OF HIMSELF.
I TOOK CARE OF
THE FUCKING ROSENBERGS.
ALL RISE.
THE JUDGE IS THE
HONORABLE IRVING KAUFMAN.
BE SEATED.
JULIUS AND ETHEL ROSENBERG,
APPROACH THE BENCH.
( judge )
YOU STAND CONVICTED IN THIS COURT
OF GIVING TO RUSSIA
AMERICA'S ATOMIC SECRETS.
IT IS NOT IN MY POWER,
JULIUS AND ETHEL ROSENBERG,
TO FORGIVE YOU.
ONLY THE LORD CAN FIND MERCY
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE DONE.
THE SENTENCE OF THE COURT UPON
JULIUS AND ETHEL ROSENBERG
IS THAT FOR THEIR CRIME,
THEY ARE SENTENCED
TO DEATH BY ELECTROCUTION.
ORDER IN THIS COURT !
I LOVE YOU. WE MUST BE STRONG
FOR THE CHILDREN, ALL RIGHT ?
ORDER! ORDER IN THIS COURT !
BAILIFF, TAKE THAT MAN OUT !
SILENCE OR I'LL
HAVE YOU REMOVED.
BAILIFF !
SILENCE !
( slow instrumental music )
( bang, screaming )
OH, GOD.
PETER.
GOOD MORNING.
DID WE SLEEP WELL
LAST NIGHT ?
AAH.
( chuckling )
I BEAT THEM AGAIN.
AAH.
( Peter )
HAVE WE BEEN BEHAVING OURSELVES TODAY?
HUH.
PETER, WHERE WERE YOU ?
PETER, WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN ?
I BROUGHT YOUR
FAVORITE FROG.
THEY TRIED IT AGAIN
LAST NIGHT, TO KILL ME.
THE BASTARDS DIDN'T
MAKE IT, THOUGH.
WHAT DO YOU SEE THERE ?
YOU SEE THE SUN !
THEY HAVE THIS ONE DOCTOR.
THEY PAID HIM TO KILL ME.
THEY COULDN'T DO IT--
I DON'T THINK SO, ROY.
THEY GOT HIM TO DO IT.
YOU DON'T THINK SO ?
YOU HATE ME NOW, TOO ?
MY FRIENDS AND
MY ENEMIES HATE ME,
YOU HATE ME,
EVERYBODY.
YOU KNOCKED OFF
YOUR ENEMIES LONG AGO.
YOUR FRIENDS LOVE YOU,
YOU KNOW THAT.
ARE YOU TRYING TO
MAKE ME FEEL GUILTY ?
I GAVE UP ON THAT ONE, DEAR.
WHAT IS THIS--
NO, NO. IF YOU LOVE ME,
YOU'LL HELP ME FIND MY CLOTHES.
YOU'LL GO A LONG WAY
TO FIND A BETTER FRIEND THAN ME. GET BACK.
WE'LL FLY BACK.
WE'VE DONE THIS BEFORE.
GET OUT OF MY WAY.
( nurse )
PLEASE, MR. COHN. PLEASE GET BACK INTO BED.
( Peter )
JUST GO BACK TO BED.
OH...PETER.
ROY.
AAH...AAH.
PLEASE.
IT'S ONLY GOING TO HURT
MORE THIS WAY.
HELP ME !
HELP, PLEASE !
I DON'T KNOW YOU.
YOU'RE NOT ON MY LIST
OF VISITORS. GET AWAY !
I DO THIS AT HOME.
I'M GOOD AT IT.
I KNOW WHO
YOU ARE.
YOU'RE THE ANGEL OF DEATH,
BUT YOU'RE NO FUCKING ANGEL !
YOU'RE DEATH !
GET AWAY FROM ME !
NO...NO !
ROY.
YOU KNOW
WHO I AM.
YOU KNOW I'D NEVER HURT YOU.
YOU KNOW WHO I AM.
ROY !
YOU CAN'T KEEP ALIENATING
EVERYONE WHO TRIES TO HELP YOU.
EVENTUALLY, A PERSON JUST
SAYS TO THEMSELVES:
"I DON'T HAVE TO TAKE THIS,
NOT EVEN FROM ROY COHN."
ROY.
YOU'RE GOING TO END UP
ALL ALONE, LOVE.
PLEASE--
ANGEL OF DEATH.
JUST RELAX. RELAX AND TRY
AND STAY STRONG.
AAH...STRONG ?
I NEED TO FIGHT SOMEBODY
TO STAY STRONG. GET OUT !
FIGHT THE DISEASE,
NOT YOUR FRIENDS.
WHAT DISEASE ?
I DON'T HAVE A DISEASE.
OH, PETER...
DON'T LET THEM DO TO ME
WHAT THEY DID LAST NIGHT.
OKAY ?
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'LL BE OKAY.
I'LL FIGHT THIS
THING ALONE
NO HELP.
I DON'T NEED
THEIR HELP.
IF I DIE,
I DIE.
BUT I WON'T.
RIGHT ?
RIGHT, LOVE.
SLOW DOWN.
STOP EATING ME.
( slow instrumental music )
SO HELP ME GOD.
I REMEMBER.
DEAD.
HOW COULD
I FORGET ?
I KILLED YOU, SPY.
WAS I ?
YOU'RE NOT REAL.
WHY AM I TALKING TO YOU ?
PETER ? SPY.
WAS I ?
OR DID YOU JUST MAKE IT UP ?
HERE'S A SECRET, BOYCHICK.
THE ELECTRICITY MAKES
EVERYTHING BRIGHTER.
I COULD SEE.
ALL THE JEWS
WERE AFRAID,
BECAUSE THEY THOUGHT
IF YOU KILLED ME,
ALL THE JEWS
WOULD DIE.
( Cohn )
WE DON'T WANT TO BE DISTRUBED, OKAY ?
( man )
YES, SIR.
I'M GLAD YOU ASKED TO SEE ME.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO TELL ME ?
I DIDN'T ASK TO SEE YOU.
I WAS SUBPOENAED.
WE'LL STOP RIGHT NOW
WITH THE LAWYER TERMS
AND THE WEASEL WORDS.
ALL RIGHT ?
YOU'RE UNITED NATIONS'
CHIEF COUNSEL.
IF ANYBODY KNOWS WHO
THE REDS AND PINKOS ARE,
IT'D BE YOU,
OR IT SHOULD BE.
I'VE ALREADY BEEN ASKED THIS--
WHY ARE YOU HAVING A HARD
TIME ANSWERING THIS ?
I UNDERSTAND.
IT'S PERSONAL, RIGHT ?
TALKING ABOUT
YOUR FRIENDS.
NOBODY LIKES TO TALK
ABOUT THEIR FRIENDS.
NATIONAL SECURITY
CAN'T BE ENDANGERED
BECAUSE OF FEELINGS
FOR YOUR FRIENDS.
UNDERSTAND ME ?
ASK ME ANYTHING
ABOUT MYSELF.
YOU SEE THAT ?
SEE THAT FLAG ?
THERE'S A WAR
GOING ON RIGHT NOW
BETWEEN AMERICANISM
AND COMMUNISM.
IF YOU'RE A FRIEND OF
AMERICA'S ENEMIES,
THEN YOU'RE AN ENEMY, TOO.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME ?
I KNOW YOUR FATHER,
ROY, YOU KNOW THAT ?
YOU'RE LIKE  MESHPUCHA  TO ME.
NOTHING TO HIDE ?
I SAW YOU WHEN
YOU WERE A KID.
YOU CERTAINLY GOT NOTHING
TO HIDE FROM ME.
WHY DID YOU
CHOOSE TO HIDE
BEHIND YOUR
CONSTITUTIONAL PRIVILEGE ?
IT'S NOT A PRIVILEGE, ROY.
IT'S A RIGHT.
YOU MUST HAVE A SECRET,
OR YOU WOULDN'T
INVOKE YOUR PRIVILEGE.
IT'S NOT A PRIVILEGE.
IT'S A RIGHT.
OKAY.
GIVE ME THAT.
NOT UNDER OATH, OKAY ?
YOU'VE NEVER
BEEN SUBPOENAED.
YOU CAN STOP
HOCKING ME.
HERE WE ARE:
A COUPLE OF JEWS SITTING
IN A ROOM TALKING.
OKAY ?
HEY.
WANT SOME COFFEE ?
LET'S HAVE SOME COFFEE.
THE FBI KNOWS
THESE PEOPLE.
HOW DO YOU THINK
WE GOT YOUR NAME ?
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU'RE
BETRAYING ANYBODY.
ROY, I....
ROY, I DIDN'T BECOME
CHIEF COUNSEL AT THE UN
TO BECOME CHIEF EXECUTIONER
OF MY FELLOW MAN.
THE WHOLE PURPOSE OF MY WORK
AT THE UNITED NATIONS
IS TO HELP CREATE A
WORLD FREE OF STATES
THAT HAVE INHUMAN
INTERROGATIONS LIKE THIS.
YOU TAKE CREAM ?
I DON'T WANT
YOUR COFFEE.
OH, GOD. GOD. GOD.
GOD. GOD. GOD.
WHAT WILL YOU
DO TO THEM ?
WELL...
NOTHING.
WHAT WILL YOU
DO TO THEM ?
NOTHING.
YOU COULD, THOUGH.
YOU COULD FIRE THEM.
THAT WOULD SHOW
YOUR LOYALTY.
OR
YOU CAN JUST
GIVE ME THE NAMES.
( reporter )
SEN. McCARTHY,
( McCarthy )
HAND WRINGING ABOUT THESE TRAITORS
INFILTRATING OUR GOVERNMENT.
THEY WANT THE COMMUNISTS--
THEY WANT THE
BRUTALITARIAN COMMUNIST
NETWORKS EXPOSED.
THEY'RE SWINE.
I'M NOT AFRAID TO POINT
THEM OUT AND GET THEM OUT.
I'LL GET THEM OUT OF
THE STATE DEPARTMENT,
OUT OF THE COLLEGES
AND UNIVERSITIES.
DON'T GET ME STARTED.
WHEN WILL YOU ACTUALLY
RELEASE THOSE NAMES ?
THIS ISN'T A PRESS CONFERENCE.
IT'S FOR CHRISTMAS.
YOU'LL GET THE NAMES.
SORRY.
EXCUSE ME.
ROY COHN.
WITH THE...
UNITED NATIONS, YES.
CAN WE HAVE
A PRIVATE MOMENT ?
A LOT OF HANDS TO SHAKE,
BUT LATER.
JUST A MINUTE.
DON'T WORRY.
LATER.
HI, I'M ROBERT KENNEDY.
I KNOW WHO
YOU ARE.
WELL, YOU...
YOU KNOW ME ?
YOU BETTER
CATCH HIM EARLY.
OH, OH.
I'LL CATCH HIM RIGHT NOW.
THANKS, I OWE YOU ONE.
HOW ARE YOU ?
YOU'RE A LITTLE WET
BEHIND THE EARS.
I GOT THE ROSENBERG
CONVICTIONS
AND THE DEATH PENALTIES.
SAYPOL GOT THOSE. YOU
WERE A PAPER PUSHER, KID.
BUT CREDIT WHERE
CREDIT IS DUE:
YOU DID WELL ON THAT THING
FOR PAT McCARRAN.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I'M MOVING FROM RANKING
MINORITY TO CHAIRMAN.
IT'LL BE MY SUBCOMMITTEE.
WANT TO COME ON OVER ?
YOU'VE GOT BOBBY KENNEDY.
AS CHIEF COUNSEL PROBABLY,
BUT NOT APPOINTED YET.
I CAN'T SIT BEHIND HIM AND
WATCH HIM DESTROY YOUR WORK.
DESTROY MY WORK,
HOW DO YOU MEAN ?
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH NAMES
WORKING FOR PAT McCARRAN.
YOU'LL BE HAULING UP
JEW AFTER JEW,
ALL THOSE
EUROPEAN NAMES.
WITH McCARTHY AND
KENNEDY TOGETHER,
IT'LL LOOK LIKE AN
IRISH-CATHOLIC RUN POGROM.
THAT WILL DISCREDIT
EVERYTHING YOU DO.
I KNOW.
BECAUSE I'M A JEW.
BUT THEY'RE COMMUNISTS.
THEY BETRAYED THE FAITH
OF THE FATHERS
FOR THIS SOCIALIST
GOD OF IRON.
THAT'S THE ISSUE,
NOT ANTI-SEMITISM.
THAT'S NOT WHAT YOUR
OPPOSITION WILL SAY.
IT'S VERY HARD SOMETIMES
TO CONTROL WHAT
AN ISSUE REALLY IS.
IF YOUR ENEMIES CAN FIND
A WAY TO TWIST YOUR MOTIVES,
BELIEVE ME,
THEY'LL DO IT.
YOU'VE GOT A LOT OF
PEOPLE PUSHING YOU,
BUT IF IT WERE
ME CHOOSING, SIR,
THAT KENNEDY WOULD
BE MORE AT HOME
WITH THE DEMOCRATS.
MAYBE HE COULD BE
MINORITY COUNSEL,
IN MY ESTIMATION.
YOU MAKE UP
YOUR OWN MIND.
YOUR FATHER IS
A LIBERAL DEMOCRAT.
SENATOR,
IF I THOUGHT THAT MY FATHER
WERE DISLOYAL TO THIS COUNTRY,
I'D PUT HIS NAME
ON THE LIST.
I'D PUT HIM IN A WITNESS CHAIR
AND TEAR HIM TO PIECES.
YOU THINK BOBBY KENNEDY
WILL DO THAT WITH JOE SR. ?
WHY AREN'T
YOU DRINKING ?
WHY ? DO I HAVE SOMETHING
TO CELEBRATE ?
YOU'VE GOT
A MOUTH.
TO THE BIRTH
OF JESUS.
RIGHT.
ANOTHER TOUGH JEW.
I THINK I LIKE IT.
GOOD EVENING, AMERICA.
LET'S GO TO PRESS.
FLASH! WASHINGTON, D.C.
WEDDING BELLS BECOME
WARNING BELLS.
THE NEW ALLIANCE BETWEEN
SUPER RED HUNTER
JOSEPH McCARTHY
AND WONDER-BOY
COMMIE-CATCHING
U.S. ATTORNEY ROY COHN
WILL WHEEDLE OUT ALL
THOSE AMERICAN-SKIS
SECRETLY ON MISSIONS
FROM MOSCOW.
MUSIC TO MINE EARS.
( Dora )
ROY !
HA !
A MAID COMES IN
TWICE A DAY.
YEAH.
ROOM SERVICE,
I PICK UP THE PHONE.
WORKING WITH McCARTHY,
I OWN THE TOWN.
OWN THE TOWN.
THAT'S WONDERFUL STUFF.
THESE ARE ALL IN PREPARATION.
LOOK AT THIS.
THIS ONE?
FBI INVESTIGATION,
ARMY, G2 SUMMARIES.
VARIOUS DEPARTMENTS, ALL VERY
SENSITIVE INVESTIGATIONS.
I WORKED
VERY HARD.
HALF A PAGE !
OH !
YOU LISTEN
TO WINCHELL ?
OF COURSE I DO !
DOES HE LOVE ME ?
ABE FELLER IS A COMMUNIST
LIKE YOU'RE A COMMUNIST.
I DON'T THINK
YOU KNOW, SIR.
A FRIEND OF MINE
CALLED ME TODAY.
ABE FELLER'S STAFF
HAS BEEN FIRED
BECAUSE HE GAVE
THEM THE NAMES.
THEN THEY FIRED
ABE FELLER.
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND, DAD ?
ABE FELLER IS A JEW.
ABE FELLER IS A LIBERAL.
ABE FELLER
IS A VISIONARY.
FOR THOSE THINGS,
HE DOES NOT DESERVE THIS.
I JUST GOT THE HOTTEST
JOB IN WASHINGTON.
DO YOU THINK YOU COULD
BE PROUD OF ME ?
WHY YOU HAVE DONE
WHAT YOU'VE DONE
IS A PROFOUND
MYSTERY TO ME.
WHAT DOES IT TAKE
TO GET A NOD FROM YOU ?
YOU THINK COMMUNISM'S A JOKE ?
HITLER WASN'T A JOKE.
WELL, TO ME,
A COMMIE JEW
IS AS DISGUSTING TO YOU
AS A NAZI JEW WOULD BE.
YOU SHOULD BE SAYING,
"GOOD WORK, SON.
I AM SO PROUD OF YOU."
HAVE THOSE WORDS EVER
COME OUT OF YOUR MOUTH ?
IF YOU HAVE SOMETHING NICE
TO SAY, SAY IT OR GO.
THE BOY IS HOME
FOR THE WEEKEND,
SO JUST LET IT BE.
I AM TRYING TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT WHAT IS RIGHT.
YOU KNOW
WHAT'S RIGHT ?
WHAT'S RIGHT CHANGES
EVERY 10 MINUTES.
WHAT IS RIGHT
NEVER CHANGES.
I AM ASHAMED.
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND ?
NO, FORGET IT.
( Dora )
ROY !
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND ?
ROY ! ROY !
ROY !
DAD.
HE DOES NOT GRASP THINGS
THE WAY WE DO.
HE HAS NO GRASP
OF THINGS.
HE, HE, HE, JUST...
THEY'RE CLUBHOUSE BOYS.
THEY STICK TOGETHER.
I AM PROUD OF YOU--
ALWAYS.
SO, UM...
YOU LIKE THIS GIRL ?
YOU MET HER BEFORE.
SHE'S A FRIEND.
WITH A HAIRDO
LIKE THIS ?
YEAH, I LIKE HER.
YEAH.
SHE'S NOT FOR US, IS SHE ?
WE CAN DO BETTER.
IT IS NOT THE
LESS FORTUNATE
OR MEMBERS OF THE
MINORITY GROUPS
WHO HAVE BEEN SELLING
THIS NATION OUT,
BUT RATHER THOSE WHO
HAVE HAD ALL THE BENEFITS
THE WEALTHIEST NATION ON
EARTH HAS TO PROVIDE.
I HAVE THEIR NAMES.
THESE NAMES WILL BE
CALLED TO ACCOUNT:
THE BRIGHTEST AND
THE MOST PRIVILEGED ,
WHO SWORE TO PROTECT
THE CONSTITUTION
AND DEFEND THE
SAME AMERICA
THEY NOW PLOT
TO BRING LOW.
I WANT IT TO
LIGHT THE SPARK
OF A MORAL UPRISING
THAT WILL END
ONLY WHEN THE WHOLE
MESS OF TWISTED ,
WARPED THINKERS ARE SWEPT
FROM THE NATIONAL SCENE
AND WE HAVE A REBIRTH OF
NATIONAL HONESTY AND DECENCY.
( applauding and cheering )
THE LAST TIME WE MET
WITH ABE FELLER,
HE CONFIDED RATHER
OPENLY ABOUT
THE PRESSURES FROM
SPECIAL INTERESTS
WITHIN HIS OWN
ORGANIZATION.
APPARENTLY, SADLY,
TRAGICALLY,
THEY OVERWHELMED HIM.
TO GIVE ABE FELLER'S
DEATH MEANING,
WE OWE IT TO HIM
AND TO OURSELVES
TO CONTINUE TO ROOT
OUT THIS CONSPIRACY,
TO BRING IT TO LIGHT,
AND TO BRING IT TO AN END.
THAT WAY, THERE WILL
NEVER HAVE TO BE
ANY MORE
ABE FELLERS.
( McCarthy )
MR. PRESIDENT, I...I...I...
I DON'T CARE
WHAT THE BUREAUCRATS
THINK OF YOUR WORK.
IT'S SICKENING TO ME.
AMERICANS ARE FED UP.
I WAS TOLD I COULD
READ MY STATEMENT.
I'VE NO DOUBT YOU WERE,
MR. KAPLAN.
WE CAN DO IT. WE'LL JUST INSERT
A STATEMENT INTO THE RECORD.
WINCHELL'S MY MAN,
SO JUST LET ME DO IT.
SENATOR, I INSIST
ON THE PROMISE
THAT I BE ALLOWED
TO READ MY STATEMENT.
I WANT THE OPPORTUNITY
TO MAKE MY STATEMENT
IMPUGNING UN-AMERICAN
MOTIVES...
CHECK MY MAIL.
NOW, PLEASE.
AT THE CONSENT
OF THE COMMITTEE,
YOUR STATEMENT WILL BE
MADE PART OF THE RECORD.
CHIEF COUNSEL WILL
BEGIN THE QUESTIONING.
IF YOU'LL GIVE YOUR
STATEMENT TO THE CLERK.
( Cohn )
STATE YOUR NAME AND THE NATURE OF YOUR WORK.
STATE YOUR NAME--
RAYMOND KAPLAN.
I'M AN ENGINEER WITH
THE  VOICE OF AMERICA.
I'VE BEEN IN THEIR
EMPLOY SINCE, SINCE...
SINCE, IT'S BEEN AROUND,
ABOUT 10 YEARS.
I THOUGHT THAT TO
BE A GOOD ENGINEER,
YOU'D HAVE TO
BE INTELLIGENT.
WOULD YOU AGREE ?
THERE ARE ALL KINDS,
LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE.
LET ME REPHRASE IT:
A "C" STUDENT ISN'T
GOING TO MAKE IT,
A "B" STUDENT
MIGHT SQUEAK BY.
YOU MUST BE SMART.
IT HELPS.
AN EYE FOR DETAIL,
AN UNDERSTANDING OF HOW
THE RECEIVING, THE TRANSMITTING
OF RADIO WAVES, ETC.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE
THAT DOWN PAT.
YES, SIR.
AND YOU DO,
OTHERWISE YOU MIGHT
MAKE A MISTAKE.
YES, SIR.
SINCE WE HAVE ELIMINATED
INCOMPETENCE,
WOULDN'T IT BE
FAIR TO SAY
WHEN YOU ORDERED
TRANSMISSION TOWERS ERECTED
WHERE THEY COULDN'T SIGNAL
COUNTRIES WE'D LIKE TO REACH,
IT MUST'VE BEEN
DONE ON PURPOSE.
I'M SORRY.
WHY--
I'M SORRY. EXCUSE ME.
DID I SAY SOMETHING FUNNY ?
DID I...
DID I SAY
SOMETHING...
I DON'T THINK
IT'S FUNNY.
...TO EMBARRASS MYSELF ?
WHY WOULD WE ?
WHY? BECAUSE THERE
ARE DISLOYAL PEOPLE
WORKING FOR THE
VOICE OF AMERICA.
WE KNOW AND
YOU KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
THINK ABOUT WHAT
YOU JUST SAID.
YOU ADMITTED THE TOWERS
WERE INTENTIONALLY PLACED--
IT'S MORE COMPLICATED
THAN THAT.
FOR EXAMPLE, SUNSPOTS:
THEY AFFECT THE TRANSMISSION.
IT'S NOT EXACTLY
CLEAR HOW...
SUNSPOTS ?
( laughing )
DID HE SAY
SUNSPOTS ?
PERHAPS DISLOYAL AMERICANS
SELLING OUT OUR COUNTRY.
YOU KNOW
WHO WE MEAN.
NO.
NO, SIR, I SIMPLY DISAGREE.
MR. KAPLAN, SIR.
IF YOU WANT TO HELP
THE  VOICE OF AMERICA ,
GET BACK TO WORK,
AND WE ALL WANT TO HELP
THE  VOICE OF AMERICA ,
THEN WHY DON'T YOU TELL US
WHO MADE THESE STUPID MISTAKES,
AS YOU SAID.
I DIDN'T.
BUT AS YOU SAY NOW,
THEY DID MAKE MISTAKES.
THEY PLACED,
VOA  TOWERS
WHERE THE AMERICAN MESSAGE
COULDN'T GET OUT--
WHERE IT WAS INAUDIBLE
IN THE COUNTRIES
THAT WE WANTED
IT TO REACH.
YOU KNOW WHO
WE MEAN.
NAMES, RAY ?
IF THEY'RE DISLOYAL,
WE'LL FIND OUT.
IF YOU ARE DISLOYAL,
WE CAN UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU DON'T
WANT TO TELL US.
MR. KAPLAN,
YOU'RE TRYING THE PATIENCE
OF THIS COMMITTEE
AND WASTING
VALUABLE TIME.
YOU'RE UNDER
SUBPOENA.
( Cohn )
YOU COULD BE HELD IN CONTEMPT.
( McCarthy )
AND JAILED.
( Cohn )
COULD WE HAVE THOSE NAMES, PLEASE ?
( McCarthy )
NAMES TELL THE TRUTH.
( Cohn )
MR. KAPLAN, GIVE US THE NAMES, PLEASE !
( Kennedy )
YOU PUT ME IN AN IMPOSSIBLE SITUATION.
I'M NOT THE POSTMAN.
( Cohn )
I'M NOT ASKING YOU TO BE.
I ASKED YOU
A SIMPLE FAVOR.
I'M IN THE STUDIO
EVERY DAY.
CAN WE TALK
TOMORROW ?
CALL ME THERE.
DICTATE TO MY SECRETARY,
I'LL PUT IT
ON THE AIR.
ANY SUNDAY,
ANY ITEM.
I ONLY WANT
EXCLUSIVES.
THANK YOU.
NO GANGBANGS.
NAMES FROM
EXECUTIVE SESSIONS,
I'VE GOT TO SPREAD AROUND.
THANK YOU.
I'VE GOT TO SPREAD AROUND,
SOKOLSKY, LYONS, AND SO ON.
YOU'LL GET ALL
THE EXTRAS.
GOOD. I'LL MAKE
YOU A STAR.
I USED TO BE
A TAP DANCER.
NICE WORK.
THANK YOU,
APPRECIATE IT.
WALTER WINCHELL,
THE  VOICE OF AMERICA .
YOU BET YOUR ASS.
HEY, HEY !
HOW WOULD THE
SUPER JEW BOY
LIKE TO MEET THE ACE
CATHOLIC MICK IN NEW YORK ?
( Winchell )
THERE WAS THIS TEXAN AND THIS JEW ON THE MOON
( Cohn )
I'LL TELL YOU RIGHT NOW, THIS IS A  GOYISH  JOKE.
A JEWISH JOKE THEY
WOULDN'T BE ON THE MOON.
WHERE WOULD THEY BE ?
MIAMI.
( Winchell )
MIAMI BEACH, THEY WOULDN'T GO TO MIAMI.
( Cohn )
THAT'S A JEWISH JOKE. A JEWISH TRAGEDY IS TAMPA.
GOOD TO SEE YOU,
CARDINAL.
WALTER.
JOE.
THIS IS HIS CHIEF
LEGAL COUNSEL.
ROY COHN,
FRANCIS CARDINAL SPELLMAN.
YOUR EMINENCE.
MR. COHN.
GENTLEMEN,
A GOOD GROUP.
ROY.
ALWAYS ENJOY MEETING
A FELLOW PRIEST.
IN HEBREW, "COHN"
MEANS "PRIEST."
THEN CARDINAL SPELLMAN,
YOU WILL HAVE TO BE MY RABBI.
FAIR IS FAIR.
EVIL EXISTS. IT'S AROUND
US ALL THE TIME.
IT'S SO PERVASIVE
THAT WE DON'T SEE IT,
LIKE THE PATTERN
IN THE WALLPAPER.
PEOPLE LIVE IN AN EVIL WORLD
LIKE FISH IN THE SEA.
THEY SWIM IN IT.
WALLOW IN IT.
FUCK IN IT.
THEY DON'T THINK
OR TALK ABOUT EVIL,
BECAUSE THEY
DON'T SEE EVIL.
WE NEED PEOPLE LIKE
YOU AND MR. COHN
TO MAKE THEM SEE.
TO FORCE THEM
TO STOP AND LOOK.
TO DISCOVER COMMUNISM
FOR WHAT IT IS:
THE MARCH OF THE SOLDIER SLAVES
OF CAIN INCARNATE AGAIN.
IT'S NOT EVEN SUNDAY.
WHAT AMAZES ME IS THE
NUMBER OF HATE LETTERS I GET
WHEN I TRY TO UNMASK THE REDS
IN OUR GOVERNMENT.
HATE LETTERS FROM
ALL THE BLEEDING HEARTS.
EXCELLENT CHOICE.
THANK YOU.
DOES THAT MEAN THAT
THE COMMITTEE CAN EXPECT
THE SUPPORT
OF THE CHURCH, CARDINAL ?
I'M NOT A CATHOLIC,
OF COURSE,
BUT WE BELIEVE
IN THE SAME GOD.
WE BELIEVE IN
THE SAME VALUES.
I DON'T SPEAK
FOR THE CHURCH.
THE POPE SPEAKS
BUT ANY ENEMY
OF SATAN
IS AN ALLY OF THE
ARCHDIOCESE OF NEW YORK.
( Cohn )
WELL SAID. WAITER.
WAITER ? MORE WINE
FOR THE SENATOR.
AND A BOURBON ?
AND A BOURBON.
"MURDERER'S ROW" ?
WHO SAID THAT ?
WHO CALLED US THAT ?
WHO CARES ? IT HAS
A NICE RING TO IT.
THEY HAVEN'T SEEN
ANYTHING YET, HAVE THEY ?
HOW'VE YOU BEEN ?
EXCUSE ME, HONEY.
CAN I BORROW ROY
FOR A SECOND?
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
WALTER'S GOT SOMEBODY
HE WANTS US TO MEET.
HI, SENATOR.
THANK YOU.
MR. VICE PRESIDENT.
YOU GOT TO
INTRODUCE ME.
SURE.
MR. VICE PRESIDENT,
THIS IS ROY COHN.
GOOD WORK.
IT'S AN HONOR, SIR.
I'M A GREAT ADMIRER, SIR.
THANK YOU, SIR.
SEE, EVERYBODY WANTS TO COME
TO THE PARTY. I LOVE THIS.
EXCUSE US.
EXCUSE US, PLEASE.
OH, HELLO.
BOBBY ?
BOBBY.
A LITTLE PISSED
FOR A GOLDEN BOY.
YOUR SHOW WAS FANTASTIC
LAST NIGHT. IT WAS JUST GREAT.
THANKS. I THOUGHT IT
WAS DYNAMITE MYSELF.
I WANT YOU TO MEET
A VERY SPECIAL PAL OF MINE.
G. DAVID SCHINE, THIS IS ROY
COHN, AND THAT OF COURSE IS--
THIS IS A GREAT PLEASURE
AND HONOR FOR ME.
THANK YOU.
DAVID'S HERE FOR THE
NORTHEAST SECTION
OF HIS FAMILY'S
HOTEL CHAIN.
HE ALSO WROTE A BOOK
ON COMMUNISM.
FOR OR AGAINST ?
I PUT IT IN EVERY ROOM
IN THE ENTIRE SCHINE
FAMILY CHAIN OF HOTELS
RIGHT NEXT TO THE GIDEON BIBLES.
YOU'RE IN IT.
AGAINST.
I'M SORRY, IT'S FUNNY
BECAUSE--
NO, I'M SORRY.
I DON'T HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR.
I ADMIRE WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
YOU WANT TO BE
A PART OF IT ?
ME ? I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I COULD DO.
SEN. McCARTHY,
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
CAN I GET YOU
ANOTHER DRINK?
BOURBON.
ANYBODY ELSE?
WE'RE FINE,
JUST FINE.
EXCUSE ME.
THANKS.
YOU HEARD
WHAT HE SAID ?
CAN YOU EXCUSE US FOR A SECOND ?
GO POWDER YOUR NOSE.
YOU HEARD
WHAT HE SAID?
HE SAID HE HAD
NO SENSE OF HUMOR.
NOBODY SAYS THAT.
NOBODY EVER ADMITS TO THAT
OR BEING A LOUSY LOVER.
I'VE NEVER HEARD IT.
BUT LOOK...
HE'S AS DEVOTED
AS A PUPPY DOG,
AND RICH AS
A ROCKEFELLER.
I OWE HIS OLD MAN
SOME FAVORS.
MAYBE YOU CAN FIND
A SPOT FOR HIM
ON THE COMMITTEE
OR SOMETHING.
I SAY, I'D BE
FLATTERED, BUT
YOU GO INTO WORK
EVERY DAY. IS IT EARLY ?
I DON'T KNOW,
MAYBE NOT.
HE'S KIDDING, RIGHT ?
YOU ARE SO FUNNY.
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT
WORKING ON THE COMMITTEE.
JOE, I THINK THIS COULD
BE A POSSIBLE ASSET.
THINK OF IT AS A CHARACTER
BUILDER OR JUST,
YOU KNOW,
A HOOT.
TO BE PART OF
SOMETHING GREAT--
YOU KNOW THAT--
BOY, THAT WOULD BE--
WELL, GREAT.
I'M BACK.
WHERE DID YOU GO ?
AAH.
BETTER TIMES.
FULL OF HOPE.
OH, GOD.
WE WERE SO YOUNG.
WHAT'S THE INDICTMENT,
DOCTOR ?
THEORETICAL ?
PRINCIPLE ? PERSONAL ?
GIVE IT A NAME.
I DON'T NAME NAMES.
WE KNOW THEM ALREADY,
SO WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE ?
WHAT DID I EVER DO TO YOU ?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU.
I HAD AN UNCLE,
A NUCLEAR PHYSICIST,
KIND OF A DREAMER.
HE LOST HIS JOB AND
HE NEVER WORKED AGAIN.
THE SHIT HIT THE FAN
AND A LITTLE GOT ON YOU.
AMAZING.
WHAT A SMALL WORLD.
A LOT OF DREAMS DIED.
NOW YOU'VE GOT ROY COHN
RIGHT WHERE YOU WANT HIM.
NO WONDER YOU'RE
TRYING TO KILL ME.
THAT KIND OF MALICE IS JUST
BEYOND MY STRENGTH.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THAT ?
YOU WON'T TRY
TO HURT ME.
YOU WANT TO
KNOW WHY ?
BECAUSE YOU'RE
STILL AFRAID OF ME.
TAXPAYERS ARE SPENDING
$100 MILLION A YEAR
TO MAINTAIN OUR LIBRARIES
ACROSS THE SEAS,
TO GET OUT THE
AMERICAN MESSAGE.
IS IT RIGHT THAT THOSE
LIBRARIES SHOULD BE
STOCKED WITH BOOKS
BY COMMUNISTS ?
WE HAVE A LIST OF THOSE BOOKS
AND THOSE AUTHORS.
THAT IS WHAT
G. DAVID SCHINE
AND ROY COHN ARE
CRUSADING AGAINST.
ANY PROBLEMS
WITH THAT?
( man )
WHAT'S YOUR JURISDICTION ?
OUR JURISDICTION?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
THE WHOLE DAMN GOVERNMENT,
THAT'S OUR JURISDICTION
AND DON'T FORGET IT !
( air controller )
THIS IS ORLY TOWER. ROGER 93.
LESS THAN 55 MINUTES
TO ORLY STATION.
( Cohn )
MR. SCHINE AND I ARE HOT ON THE TRAIL.
WE ARE FINDING
THIS INSIDIOUS
MIND-WASHING GOING
ON EVERYWHERE.
WE FOUND ENOUGH
TO QUESTION SERIOUSLY
THE LOYALTY OF OUR
OWN ADMINISTRATORS.
PLENTY ON THE SHELVES
BY SUBVERSIVES,
DASHIELL HAMMETT
BUT NOT A SINGLE COPY
OF THE  AMERICAN LEGION MAGAZIN.
NO MORE QUESTIONS.
THAT'S IT. GET IN THE CAR.
DO THEY HAVE
CHAMPAGNE?
THESE FROGS NEVER STOP.
SHUT UP ! GET AWAY.
MR. SCHINE IS AN EXPERT ON
THE COMMUNIST CONSPIRACY.
HIS BOOK IS READ ALL ACROSS
THE UNITED STATES.
SHOULD I TELL HIM TO PUT THIS
NEXT TO THE BIBLE?
WE'LL KNOCK THEM
DEAD IN SPAIN.
( speaking German )
VERSTEHEN, LIEBLING ?
( reporter )
ARE WE TO UNDERSTAND THAT
THAT THE MALTESE FALCON
AND THE THIN MAN
ARE ACTUALLY
MARXIST PROPAGANDA ?
MR. COHN, IS WILLIAM KARL MARX
OR TROTSKY, WOULD YOU SAY?
IS ASTA LENIN OR ENGELS?
MR. COHN, DO YOU INTEND
TO BURN THE BOOKS?
MR. SCHINE, HAVE YOU
READ THE BOOKS?
WHAT ABOUT
MR. HAMMETT, SIR?
( Cohn )
MR. HAMMETT?
THANK YOU.
YOUR BOOKS USED TO BE IN ALL
THE OVERSEAS LIBRARIES.
BUT NO MORE.
?NO MORE, NO MORE,
NO MORE, NO MORE?
BEING ON YOUR LIST IS AN HONOR
AND I AM FOREVER IN YOUR DEBT.
LOOK, HAMMETT--
THE ONLY PERSON WHO CALLS
ME HAMMETT IS HELLMAN.
MR. HELLMAN--
MR. HAMMETT.
YOU'RE NOT HURTING THIS
COMMITTEE WITH YOUR REMARKS.
YOU'RE ONLY
HURTING YOURSELF.
WE ARE GIVING YOU THIS SHOT
AT SAVING YOUR CAREER.
DESCRIBE THE APPARATUS
OF YOUR ORGANIZATION:
TO WHOM YOU REPORTED,
WHAT THEY TOLD YOU TO WRITE,
OTHERS YOU MAY HAVE
SEEN AT MEETINGS.
YOU'LL HAVE TO TESTIFY
TO A CERTAIN AMOUNT
OF THIS IN PUBLIC SESSION.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
THINKING ABOUT,
BUT IT ISN'T SO,
NOHOW.
CONTRARIWISE, IF IT
WAS SO, IT MIGHT BE.
IF IT WERE SO, IT WOULD BE,
BUT AS IT ISN'T, IT AIN'T.
THAT'S LOGIC.
VERY FUNNY.
THAT'S  ALICE IN
WONDERLAND.
YEAH.
TWEEDLEDUM AND TWEEDLEDEE.
SO LONG, KIDS.
MR. HAMMETT.
I MEAN, IT'S A FREE COUNTRY,
ISN'T IT ? SO FAR ?
( McCarthy )
MR. HAMMET ?
( Cohn )
LET'S HAUL HIM UP
BEFORE THE COMMITTEE
AND MAKE HIM
SWEAR THE OATH.
HE PULLS THAT SHIT ON US THERE,
WE STICK HIS ASS IN JAIL.
LET'S DO IT.
THEY DRAFTED DAVID.
THE MEDIA FOUND OUT HE WAS
REGISTERED IN CALIFORNIA.
THEY TRANSFERRED
HIM TO NEW YORK.
THE BOARD GOT SCARED,
HE'S IN THE ARMY.
I ALWAYS LIKED  THE THIN MAN.
HAMMETT'S A GOOD WRITER.
COME ON, JOE. WE JUST
NAILED UP A REAL RED.
HE LIVES WITH LILLIAN HELLMAN.
SHE'S PROBABLY A DYKE.
SHE WRITES PLAYS
ABOUT THEM.
DOES THAT MEAN
AYN RAND IS A DYKE, TOO?
PROBABLY.
NO.
HOOVER'S BEEN WATCHING HELLMAN,
AND SHE DOES IT WITH GUYS.
JOE,
JUST BECAUSE LILLIAN HELLMAN
LIVES WITH A MAN
DOES NOT NECESSARILY MEAN
SHE'S NOT A HOMOSEXUAL.
EVERYBODY STARTS
OUT STRAIGHT.
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF ANYBODY
BEING BORN HOMOSEXUAL.
TIME GOES BY AND...
SOMETIMES, I GUESS...
IT HAPPENS TO THEM WITHOUT
THEM EVEN KNOWING IT.
HOW MUCH DO YOU REALLY
KNOW ABOUT SCHINE?
WHAT ABOUT DAVID?
JOE...JOE.
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO SAY
ANYTHING TO GET YOU.
IT WAS HIS WORK FOR US
THAT MADE THE PRESS
INVESTIGATE HIS
DRAFT STATUS.
THEY'LL DO ANYTHING
TO UNDERMINE YOU
AND YOUR CONFIDENCE IN US.
YOU'VE LOST CONFIDENCE
IN ME? I'LL RESIGN, SIR.
DON'T GIVE ME
THAT "SIR" SHIT.
JOE, I KNOW YOU LIKE
HAMMETT'S BOOKS.
HE'S A GOOD WRITER,
PROBABLY A GOOD GUY.
MICHELANGELO WAS
A GREAT ARTIST:
A PAINTER, INVENTOR, SCULPTOR.
AND YET, HE WAS A PERVERT.
AND
HE WAS DISLOYAL
TO HIS PRINCE.
GO AFTER THAT SUPERCILIOUS
HAMMETT SON OF A BITCH.
I WANT TO HELP DAVID, TOO.
OH, YES. GOD FORBID,
G. DAVID SCHINE
SHOULD EVER HAVE TO
SLEEP ON THE GROUND.
GOD FORBID.
( telephone buzzing )
YES ?
PUT HIM ON.
MR. COHN ? THIS IS BOB STEVENS.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU ?
THIS IS ROY COHN,
CHIEF COUNSEL TO THE
McCARTHY COMMITTEE.
I know that.
OUR ASSISTANT COUNSEL,
G. DAVID SCHINE,
WILL BE ENTERING
THE ARMY SHORTLY.
THE SENATOR'S REQUESTING
A COMMISSION FOR MR. SCHINE
THAT HE BE ATTACHED
TO OUR SENATE COMMITTEE
AS HIS MILITARY ASSIGNMENT.
THAT'S NORMALLY HANDLED
THROUGH THE OFFICE
OF LEGISLATIVE LIAISON.
You're the secretary
of the Army
of the United States
of America.
You can do this.
TELL THE SENATOR TO PUT IT
THROUGH REGULAR CHANNELS.
IF THERE'S A PROBLEM,
THEY CAN DEAL WITH IT.
WHY DON'T WE JUST MEET
AND YOU GET TO KNOW HIM?
COHN, THEY'RE READY FOR US.
Put it through the legislative
liaison officer, that's major-
BOB, JUST DO IT.
ANNIE LEE MOSS.
( Cohn )
YES, SIR. I JUST SAID IT.
YOU KNOW YOU'VE TAKEN AN OATH
TO BE TRUTHFUL IN YOUR ANSWERS.
YES ?
YES, SIR.
DO YOU WORK FOR
THE U.S. ARMY SIGNAL CORPS
WITH ACCESS TO THE CONFIDENTIAL
AND SECURITY FILES?
NO, SIR.
NO, SIR. I DON'T.
YOU DON'T WORK IN THE PENTAGON?
YOU'RE SWORN TO TELL THE TRUTH.
I DON'T WORK ANYWHERE.
I'M ON SUSPENSION.
( laughing )
( McCarthy )
THIS ISN'T FOR LAUGHS.
AND DON'T THINK
A PLEA OF SYMPATHY
IS GOING TO DISTRACT US.
PLEASE, ANSWER THIS:
ARE YOU NOW OR
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
A MEMBER OF THE
COMMUNIST PARTY ?
NO, SIR, I'M A DEMOCRAT.
( laughing )
WE HAVE TESTIMONY
BEFORE THIS COMMITTEE
THAT YOUR NAME APPEARS
ON A LIST OF THE
COMMUNIST PARTY.
MY JOB WAS IN THE CAFETERIA,
CLEANING UP.
I WANT THOSE FILES
FOR THOSE TWO MEN.
DAVID, YOU SCREWED THIS UP.
GO HELP HIM.
EVERYTHING IS IN CODE
AND I DON'T KNOW ANY CODE.
WHAT? YOU DON'T
KNOW CODE?
NO, SIR. CAN I GET
MY JOB BACK?
( laughing )
CHIEF COUNSEL WILL CONTINUE
THE QUESTIONING.
THIS AMUSES YOU,
DOESN'T IT?
YOU WON'T GET
YOUR JOB BACK
AND YOU'LL BE IN
PRISON FOR PERJURY.
MR. CHAIRMAN,
IF I MAY--
THIS CAN WAIT--
I UNDERSTAND THAT
MRS. ANNIE LEE MOSS
HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED BY NAME
BUT NOT BY SIGHT, CORRECT ?
WE'VE WITNESSES--
CHAIRMAN AND CHIEF COUNSEL
SHOULD HAVE THIS INFORMATION.
THERE SEEM TO BE
3 ANNIE LEE MOSSES
IN THE DISTRICT
PHONE DIRECTORY.
THIS WOMAN, WHO MAY HAVE
BEEN DONE AN INJUSTICE HERE,
COMES OFF
STRAIGHTFORWARD TO ME.
I SUGGEST THAT WE'D
BE DOING OUR DUTY
RESPONSIBLY TO
EXCUSE THIS WITNESS
AND LOOK TO OUR OWN PROCEDURES
FOR INVESTIGATION.
IF IT TAKES A VOTE,
I'D LIKE TO VOTE.
UH, MRS. MOSS...
YOU ARE EXCUSED FOR NOW.
( Cohn )
WONDERING HOW WE'RE DOING ON
THAT COMMISSION FOR
OUR ASSISTANT COUNSEL.
( Stevens )
WE'VE RUN INTO A PROBLEM ON THAT.
I HOPED THAT MR. SCHINE HAD
HAD SOME ROTC THAT WOULD'VE--
( Cohn )
I DON'T KNOW IF HE HAS.
( Stevens )
HE DIDN'T, IT APPEARS,
SHORT OF GOING TO
OFFICERS' CANDIDATE SCHOOL...
DAVID SCHINE AND
McCARTHY AGREE
THAT OFFICERS' CANDIDATE
SCHOOL IS JUST THE THING.
EXCELLENT. PVT.
SCHINE CAN APPLY
AS SOON AS HE'S OUT
OF BASIC TRAINING.
HOW LONG IS ALL
THIS GOING TO TAKE:
APPLICATION, SCHOOL
AND TRAINING ?
A year.
MAYBE I WASN'T CLEAR.
I SAID SEN. McCARTHY,
McCARTHY, McCARTHY, McCARTHY !
DON'T GIVE ME ANY OF THIS
BUREAUCRATIC BULLSHIT
ABOUT PROCEDURE, OKAY ?
JUST REMEMBER THAT NAME,
AND THIS ONE:
ROY COHN.
ROY COHN !
YOU DON'T WANT TO
MAKE ROY COHN ANGRY.
( Cohn )
STATE YOUR NAME.
ANNIE LEE MOSS.
( McCarthy )
ARE YOU SURE ?
THE REAL ANNIE LEE MOSS.
YES, SIR.
YOU DO, IN FACT, WORK
AT THE PENTAGON ?
YES, SIR.
ARE YOU A COMMUNIST ?
HAVE YOU EVER ATTENDED,
UH, PARTY MEETINGS
OF A COMMUNIST
PARTY CELL ?
WHERE AND WHEN
WOULD THAT BE, SIR ?
DON'T BE EVASIVE
WITH ME, MRS. MOSS,
BECAUSE I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I'LL DO.
WE'VE SUBPOENAED
YOUR GROUP,
INCLUDING ITS
COMMUNIST LEADERSHIP,
AND WE'LL PARADE THEM FOR
ALL THE AMERICAN PEOPLE TO SEE,
INCLUDING TWO LEADERS OF
YOUR CELL WHO'LL COME HERE
AND SWEAR THAT YOU'RE LYING
TO THIS COMMITTEE.
THE COMMITTEE IS TAKING
A BRIEF RECESS. COME ON.
( man )
ROY, ROY, ROY !
WHAT DO YOU MEAN WE'RE TAKING A RECESS ?
IS THIS NECESSARY ?
WE GOT WORD THE WITNESSES
WON'T BE APPEARING.
THEY DIDN'T GET
THEIR SUBPOENAS ?
WHO SCREWED THAT UP ?
KENNEDY ?
CAN YOU EXCUSE US ?
IF THEY DON'T SHOW UP,
WE'LL LOOK LIKE ASSHOLES.
THE FBI CALLED AND SAID
THEY CAN'T FIND THEM.
THE FBI CAN'T
FIND THEM ?
YES.
WHO CALLED
FROM THE FBI ?
J. EDGAR HOOVER
HIMSELF.
HOOVER ?
YES.
I DON'T BELIEVE THIS ! WE
SHOULD GO AFTER THE FBI NEXT.
ROY.
JOHN.
EXCUSE MRS. MOSS
FROM ANY FURTHER TESTIMONY.
YOU'RE MISSING THE POINT.
NOW IS NOT THE TIME TO LET UP,
BUT TO ATTACK.
WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO DO TO ME ?
I'M TRYING TO MAKE
A GREAT MAN OUT OF YOU.
TAXI !
( Hoover )
ROY COHN ?
MR. HOOVER.
THEY'RE FBI AGENTS, ROY.
I'M SORRY ?
THOSE COMMUNISTS
YOU SUBPOENAED.
THEY'RE UNDERCOVER OPERATIVES
OF THE BUREAU.
WE WANT TO KEEP
THEM UNDERCOVER.
I DON'T WANT
PHOTOGRAPHS OF THEM.
YOU CAN'T
CALL THEM.
WE GOT TO THEM THROUGH
ANOTHER FBI AGENT.
LET NOT THE LEFT HAND KNOW
WHAT THE RIGHT HAND IS DOING.
THE AGENT YOU MENTIONED HAS NO
KNOWLEDGE THE OTHERS ARE OURS.
I'M CONFIDING IN YOU.
I HOPE YOU UNDERSTAND THAT.
BUT THE OTHERS WERE
THE LEADERS OF THE CELL.
WE WERE ABLE TO SEE THAT
THEY HAD THE MONEY
TO PAY ALL THEIR
PARTY DUES,
HAD THE TIME TO ATTEND
ALL THE PARTY MEETINGS.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT AMERICA
OWES YOU A DEBT OF GRATITUDE
FOR PROTECTING THE
IDENTITY OF MY MEN.
THERE'LL BE EMBARRASSING
MOMENTS FOR YOU,
IN YOUR HEARINGS,
WITH THE PRESS.
BUT I WILL ALWAYS
BE INDEBTED TO YOU.
REMEMBER THAT.
AND REMEMBER,
THIS NEVER HAPPENED.
( military music )
AAH, HE IS THE FIGURE
OF A SOLDIER, ISN'T HE ?
-THAT'S WHAT HE IS.
-WOO HOO !
HE'LL SERVE HIS COUNTRY
IN THE U.S. ARMY
AND HE'S GOING OVERSEAS.
OVERSEAS ? WAIT A MINUTE.
WE HAD A DEAL. YOU AGREED.
I AGREED TO NOTHING.
YOU'VE DONE IT. YOU'VE MADE
ROY COHN SORE. SEE ?
WE'RE NOT DONE YET.
AS FAR AS I'M
CONCERNED,
SEND THE KID HALFWAY AROUND
THE WORLD. I'LL BE HAPPY.
HEY, HEY !
LOOK AT YOU.
HOW ARE YOU ?
ALL RIGHT.
FIX YOUR TIE.
THIS IS A VERY IMPORTANT
MEETING. COME WITH ME.
HMM ? AND THAT
CUTE LITTLE HAT.
STOP IT.
SECRETARY OF THE
ARMY, BOB STEVENS,
IT'S TIME YOU MET
PVT. G. DAVID SCHINE.
HOW DO YOU DO ?
YOU WITH
THE CAMERA, HERE.
GET A NICE SHOT OF THE
2 OF THEM TOGETHER.
BOB, RIGHT HERE.
DAVE, SMILE.
( Cohn )
You're holding Dave Schine hostage
to keep us from
investigating the Army
and it won't work
because I'll wreck you.
The Senator has got names of
a homosexual ring of generals.
We're going public.
You've got a nest of Communists
in Fort Monmouth ?
Why haven't you
gone after them ?
TAPE AFTER TAPE.
IT'S RIGHT THERE.
34 PAGES OF CALLS AND MEETINGS
PRESSURING THE ARMY.
YOU WERE TRYING TO SET UP
A SOFT TOUCH FOR DAVID SCHINE
AND IT STINKS LIKE HELL.
( McCarthy )
SCHINE WAS A VALUABLE MAN.
NOW, ASK YOURSELF WHY THE ARMY
DOESN'T WANT HIM HELPING US.
WHAT ARE THEY HIDING ?
WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO HIDE ?
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
CAN WE BE MODERATELY
CIVIL THIS AFTERNOON ?
LIFE IS SHORT,
GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE ALL RESPONSIBLE
TO THE COMMITTEE
AND TO THE LEADERSHIP.
NO MALODOROUS INFERENCES
ARE TO BE DRAWN.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT ?
YOU'RE ABOUT TO BE AMBUSHED
ON THE WAY TO YOUR OWN AMBUSH.
BUT IF THESE TAPES
GO OUT THERE,
THE PRESS, AND I DARE
SAY THE PUBLIC,
WILL SURELY MOBILIZE
AGAINST ALL OF US.
THE ARMY ?
THESE ARE OUR BOYS
FIGHTING IN KOREA.
THEY'RE HEROES.
WHERE DID THESE
TAPES COME FROM ?
WHAT IS THE NAME OF THE JUDGE
WHO AUTHORIZED THESE WIRETAPS ?
HAS ANYBODY BOTHERED
TO CHECK INTO HIS BACKGROUND ?
BOB STEVENS ALWAYS
MONITORS HIS PHONE CALLS.
COME ON, ROY,
YOU SHOULD KNOW THAT.
THIS IS A TREMULOUS TIME.
I BELIEVE THAT WE SHOULD
SPEAK PRIVATELY
WITHOUT STAFF.
BUT I FIRST WANT
TO EXPRESS
MY CONFIDENCE IN YOU,
MR. COHN.
YOU HAVE THE TALENT
OF RELENTLESS PURSUIT
AND INCISIVENESS
AND A SENSE OF MISSION THAT
BOTH INSPIRES AND CHALLENGES.
ROY,
I KNOW YOU HONOR
THE TRUTH
AND WHILE YOU DO,
I'LL SUPPORT YOU.
NOW I KNOW HOW A PANCAKE FEELS
HAVING SYRUP POURED OVER IT.
HA, HA.
STAFF...
WILL LEAVE.
WITH THIS REMINDER
TO EVERYONE HERE:
LOYALTY.
THE ISSUE IS LOYALTY.
LAY IT OUT.
THE ARMY FEELS IT
HAS BEEN WRONGED.
THEY FEEL THAT MR. COHN
IS HARASSING THEM
BECAUSE OF A SPECIAL
RELATIONSHIP TO SCHINE.
THEY WANT A
SOFT CONCLUSION
TO THE INVESTIGATION
AND THE PRESSURE
OR THE CHRONOLOGY IS
PUT OUT TO THE PUBLIC.
WHAT'S SCHINE DONE ?
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING.
GET RID OF COHN.
HE GOES OUT.
HOW CAN I ?
AND WHY SHOULD I ?
HE'S GOT A GRASP OF THE...
HE'S DEVELOPED
SO MANY CASES, IT...
THERE'S NO ONE
WHO COULD STEP IN.
IT WOULD BE A SURRENDER.
A SURRENDER !
I DON'T SURRENDER.
AND HIM. HO, HO.
HE'D HOLLER. HE'D SCREAM FROM
THE ROOFTOPS, "ANTI-SEMITISM."
MAYBE HE'S RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL LANCE THIS BOIL
ON THE BODY POLITIC
WITH THE CAMERAS ON.
LET IT ALL COME OUT.
( musical beeping )
GOOD EVENING, AMERICA
AND ALL THE SHIPS AT SEA.
LET'S GO TO PRESS.
MAINE TO CALIFORNIA AND
ALL THE STOPS IN BETWEEN,
keep your TVs
humming this week
for the battle
of the century.
Mr. America, first,
last and always,
Sen. Joseph R. McCarthy
and his Commie-cornering
comet, Roy Cohn,
will be taking on
the secret skeletons
in the U.S. Army
in the person
of Robert Stevens.
The bet in this corner ?
McCarthy and Cohn
by a knockout.
That's Army loses,
America wins.
( gavel banging )
( Mundt )
IT IS MY DUTY TO CALL THIS HEARING TO ORDER.
IT IS A DUTY I DO
NOT WELCOME
AND UNDERTAKE WITH
GREAT DISTASTE.
WE ARE HERE TO
HEAR EVIDENCE
RELATED TO A CHARGE BY THE
DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY
OF HARASSMENT BY SEN. JOSEPH
McCARTHY AND HIS STAFF
AND THAT THEY IMPROPERLY
ATTEMPTED TO INFLUENCE
THE ARMY OF THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA
FOR THE BENEFIT OF ONE
PVT. G. DAVID SCHINE,
A FORMER STAFF MEMBER
OF THE COMMITTEE.
CHIEF COUNSEL FOR THIS
HEARING IS MR. RAY JENKINS
AND REPRESENTING THE
DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY
IS MR. JOSEPH WELCH.
( Welch )
THANK YOU, SIR.
( Mundt )
THE FIRST ORDER OF BUSINESS:
THE CLERK WILL SWEAR
IN ROY MARCUS COHN.
( clerk )
ROY MARCUS COHN,
DO YOU SOLEMNLY
SWEAR TO TELL THE TRUTH,
THE WHOLE TRUTH
AND NOTHING BUT THE TRUTH,
SO HELP YOU GOD ?
I DO.
BE SEATED.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
THIS PHOTO ILLUSTRATES
THE GOODWILL
BETWEEN PVT. SCHINE AND
SECRETARY OF THE ARMY STEVENS.
THERE WAS NO
ANTAGONISM.
AS IN ANY RELATIONSHIP,
THERE'D BE
OCCASIONAL MISUNDERSTANDINGS
AND TEMPERS WOULD FLARE.
BUT HOWEVER ONE
CHOOSES TO READ
CERTAIN STATEMENTS
OUT OF CONTEXT,
IT WAS ALWAYS A CORDIAL,
COOPERATIVE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN SECRETARY STEVENS
AND OUR OFFICES.
UH...
NOW, MR. COHN...
UH, YEAH,
MR. WELCH.
AS COUNSEL
FOR THE ARMY,
I FEEL WE NEED TO MAKE
THESE ISSUES CRYSTAL CLEAR,
SO PLEASE CORRECT
ME IF I'M WRONG.
SIR, YOU KNOW
VERY WELL THAT I SHALL.
ROY COHN IS HERE
SPEAKING FOR ROY COHN
TO GIVE THE FACTS.
DO WE NOT HAVE BEFORE
THIS COMMITTEE
A LIST OF YOUR ATTEMPTS
TO GAIN SPECIAL TREATMENT
AND PRIVILEGES
FOR MR. SCHINE--
THE LENGTH OF WHICH IS
JUST AMAZING TO BEHOLD ?
ARE YOU ASKING
HOW I PLEAD ?
( laughing )
I WOULDN'T PUT IT THAT WAY.
THIS IS A HEARING, NOT A TRIAL.
POINT OF ORDER,
MR. CHAIRMAN.
WHAT IS YOUR
POINT OF ORDER ?
MY POINT OF ORDER IS THIS:
WE DON'T HAVE
TO BE ADVISED
ON POINTS OF LAW BY
THE COUNSEL FOR THE ARMY.
WHY, I THINK YOU DO.
I THINK YOU DO.
I PLEAD "NOT GUILTY" ANYWAY.
JUST FOR YOUR RECORDS.
( laughing )
MR. COHN,
PERHAPS YOU COULD EXPLAIN
TO THE COMMITTEE, PLEASE, SIR,
WHY YOU SUBMITTED A DOCTORED
PHOTOGRAPH TO THE COMMITTEE.
I DO NOT THINK
THAT PICTURE IS...
I DON'T THINK THIS PICTURE
HAS BEEN CHANGED.
COME NOW, SIR.
WHAT EXACTLY IS YOUR
DEFINITION OF CHANGE ?
CAN I SEE THAT
UP HERE, PLEASE ?
NO, SIR,
YOU CANNOT.
MAYBE I'M A LITTLE NEARSIGHTED,
I CAN'T SEE THE PICTURE.
YES, I DO BELIEVE
YOU HAVE BETRAYED
A CERTAIN NEARSIGHTEDNESS.
HAVE IT THE WAY YOU WANT.
COME DOWN HERE.
I THINK YOU'LL SEE,
AS DO WE ALL, THAT
IN THIS ORIGINAL PICTURE,
THERE IS A NEW CHARACTER
IN THE SCENE:
A COL. BRADLEY, AN AIDE TO
SECRETARY STEVENS. CORRECT ?
IF YOU TAKE THESE
2 PICTURES,
YOU WILL SEE
THAT THIS PART
WITH STEVENS AND DAV--
PVT. SCHINE IS THE SAME.
ANYONE WITH
COMMON SENSE
CAN LOOK AT IT
AND SEE WHAT'S IN IT.
ARE YOU SAYING THESE
PICTURES ARE IDENTICAL ?
THE RELATIONSHIP:
SECRETARY STEVENS IS
SMILING AT MR. SCHINE--
AT PVT. SCHINE.
IS HE ?
IS HE INDEED ?
I THINK NOT, SIR.
I DO BELIEVE THERE IS
JUST A TRACE OF A SMILE--
A GRIM SMILE DIRECTED
AT COL. BRADLEY.
DON'T YOU THINK ?
YOU CAN CHARACTERIZE HIS
SMILE ANY WAY YOU WISH.
I SEE HIM SMILING
AT PVT. SCHINE.
IN THIS PICTURE, WHERE
YOU'VE CUT OUT BRADLEY.
BUT IN THE REAL PICTURE
HE'S LOOKING TO HIS RIGHT,
AT COL. BRADLEY.
DO YOU SEE JUST A TOUCH
OF A SMILE HERE ON BRADLEY
IN RETURN, LOOKING BACK
AT SECRETARY STEVENS? CORRECT ?
I'D SAY THAT I'D KNOW
COL. BRADLEY HAD
A GOOD STEAK DINNER
THAT NIGHT
AND PERHAPS HE WAS
THINKING ABOUT THAT.
IF BRADLEY WAS
THINKING OF A STEAK,
SCHINE MUST'VE
BEEN CONSIDERING
A WHOLE HAUNCH OF BEEF,
WOULDN'T HE ?
( laughing )
I CAN'T REALLY TELL.
WELL...
PERHAPS, MR.COHN, YOU
COULD TELL ME THE SOURCE
OF THAT DOCTORED
PHOTOGRAPH.
I CAN, BUT I'VE A LOT
TO ATTEND TO.
IT'S NOT IN MY POSSESSION BUT
THE INFORMATION IS SOMEWHERE.
IT MUST HAVE COME
FROM SOMEWHERE.
DID YOU THINK THIS
CAME FROM A PIXIE ?
( laughing )
( McCarthy )
MAY I HAVE THE LAST QUESTION RE-READ ?
THE LAST STATEMENT.
( clerk )
"IT MUST HAVE COME FROM SOMEWHERE.
DID YOU THINK THIS
CAME FROM A PIXIE ?"
WOULD THE COUNSEL,
FOR MY BENEFIT,
DEFINE, AND I THINK YOU MAY BE
SOMETHING OF AN EXPERT ON THAT,
WHAT A PIXIE IS ?
WHY, CERTAINLY.
I SHOULD SAY THAT A PIXIE IS
A CLOSE RELATIVE TO A FAIRY.
( laughing )
MAY I PROCEED HERE ?
HAVE I ENLIGHTENED YOU ?
I DEMAND A
POINT OF ORDER.
WHAT'S YOUR
POINT OF ORDER ?
THE COMMITTEE HAS NO RIGHT
TO CAST THESE ASPERSIONS--
THAT IS NOT A
POINT OF ORDER.
THE COMMITTEE DID
NOT CAST ASPERSIONS.
IF IT WAS ANYONE,
IT WAS I.
OR IS IT IN YOUR MIND ?
NOW, MR. COHN,
IF I TOLD YOU NOW
THERE WAS A COMMUNIST SPY
AT FORT MONMOUTH
YOU'D WANT HIM OUT OF THERE
BY SUNDOWN, WOULD YOU NOT ?
MR. WELCH,
IF WE ARE TALKING ABOUT
COMMUNIST INFILTRATION,
THEN I THINK WE SHOULD TELL
MR. WELCH HE HAS IN HIS FIRM
A YOUNG MAN
NAMED FISHER
WHO HAS, FOR A
NUMBER OF YEARS,
BEEN A MEMBER OF AN
ORGANIZATION NAMED, OH...
YEARS AND YEARS
AGO AS THE
LEGAL BULWARK
OF THE COMMUNIST PARTY.
I'VE HESITATED
BRINGING THIS UP,
BUT I HAVE
BEEN BORED
BY HIS PHONY IMPLICATIONS
ABOUT MR. COHN.
UNTIL THIS MOMENT,
I NEVER REALLY GAUGED
YOUR RECKLESSNESS
OR YOUR CRUELTY.
FRED FISHER IS BEGINNING
WHAT LOOKS TO BE
A BRILLIANT CAREER
WITH US.
WHEN I ASKED HIM TO
COME HERE AND ASSIST US,
HE TOLD ME
THAT IN COLLEGE
HE BRIEFLY BELONGED
TO THE LAWYERS GUILD--
THE ORGANIZATION
TO WHICH YOU REFER.
I TOLD HIM, "I JUST DON'T THINK
"I AM GOING TO USE YOU
ON THIS CASE
"BECAUSE IT MIGHT
GO TO THE NETWORKS
"AND THAT WOULD HURT
LIKE THE DICKENS."
SO, SENATOR, I SENT HIM
BACK TO BOSTON.
LITTLE DID I DREAM,
THAT YOU WOULD BE SO CRUEL
AND SO RECKLESS
AS TO DO INJURY
TO THIS LAD.
IT'S TRUE HE WORKS FOR US,
IT'S TRUE THAT HE WILL
CONTINUE TO WORK FOR US
AND IT'S TRUE, I FEAR,
THAT HE WILL ALWAYS
BEAR A SCAR NEEDLESSLY
INFLICTED BY YOU.
LET US NOT ASSASSINATE
THIS LAD ANY FURTHER.
SENATOR, YOU'VE
DONE ENOUGH.
HAVE YOU NO SENSE OF
DECENCY, SIR, AT LONG LAST ?
HAVE YOU NO
SENSE OF DECENCY ?
THIS HEARING WILL
COME TO ORDER.
YOU CAN'T RUN AWAY.
THEY'RE TRYING TO SMEAR
THE STAFF OF THIS COMMITTEE.
( Mundt )
YOU WILL COME TO ORDER IN THIS HEARING ROOM !
( gavel banging )
DO YOU HAVE ANY EVIDENCE
OF ANY KIND ?
YOU SHOULDN'T DO THIS.
IT'S DISHONEST.
IT'S THE SAME THING
COMMUNISTS DO.
( Mundt )
YOU'LL TAKE YOUR SEATS.
THIS HEARING WILL
COME TO ORDER.
MR. COHN.
I DON'T NEED IT.
YOU NEED IT.
YOU'VE BEEN SHOUTING.
GET USED TO IT.
I'M GETTING STRONGER.
I DON'T FUCKING NEED IT.
AAH.
WHY NOT TAKE IT ?
WE'LL HAVE NO DEMONSTRATIONS
OF APPROVAL OR DISAPPROVAL.
WELL...
HOW DID I DO,
MR. COHN ?
( Cohn )
THE TRIAL IS OVER.
YOU GOT McCARTHY,
BUT YOU DIDN'T GET ME.
YOU THINK YOU'RE
ON TRIAL HERE.
WHAT WOULD YOU
BE ON TRIAL FOR ?
MIGHT I SAY, THAT FOR
YOUR SEXUAL PREDILECTIONS,
I BEAR NO GRUDGE, NO MALICE.
NOR FOR THE SECRET PRACTICES
OF YOUR FRIENDS,
NOT MR. HOOVER, NOT HIS
EXCELLENCY THE CARDINAL.
BUT SHAME,
MR. COHN,
FOR PERSECUTING IN PUBLIC
THOSE WHO IN PRIVATE
ARE NO DIFFERENT
THAN YOU.
I'M NOT GAY.
SURE, AND YOU'RE
DYING OF MUMPS.
I DON'T GIVE A SHIT
WHAT YOU THINK.
( McCarthy )
YOU WERE THE LOUSIEST WITNESS I EVER SAW.
I GOT A LOT OF THE STAFF
OTHER JOBS. I DID THE BEST I COULD.
I COULDN'T HELP DAVE,
BUT I HELPED THEM.
THEY'RE HACKING
AT ME ALL AROUND.
LONG KNIVES.
YOU BROUGHT IT ON YOURSELF.
I WARNED YOU.
I DID ?
YEAH.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL THEM
ABOUT G. DAVID SCHINE ?
YOU WERE GETTING
INTO SOMETHING.
I JUST COULDN'T
FIGURE OUT
WHETHER IT WAS
HIS WALLET OR HIM.
HE'S A FRIEND, JOE,
AND I WAS LOYAL TO HIM,
AS I WAS TO YOU.
WANT SOME ?
TRY THINKING ABOUT
THAT CONCEPT, JOE,
BECAUSE THAT'S
WHERE GREATNESS LIES.
I ALWAYS TRIED TO
DO THE RIGHT THING.
THE RIGHT THING ?
WHAT A DISASTER !
IF, FOR ONE DAY, EVERYBODY
IN WASHINGTON
TRIED TO DO
THE RIGHT THING,
YOU'D COME INTO
BOTH HOUSES OF CONGRESS,
THERE'D BE
MASS SUICIDE.
YEAH, WELL, IT DIDN'T
USED TO BE THAT WAY.
ARE YOU TRYING TO TELL
ME SOMETHING, JOE ?
WHAT, THAT I CAUSED THIS ?
I DIDN'T INVENT
DIRTY TRICKS.
NO, YOU DIDN'T.
YOU KIND OF MADE THEM
INTO AN ART FORM.
LOOK WHAT
YOU DID TO ME.
HEY.
HMM.
YOU EVER LISTEN
TO BOB AND RAY...
MAKING FUN OF ME ?
AWFULLY, AWFULLY FUNNY.
( boat man )
ONE OF THE GREATEST LUXURIES
YOU CAN HAVE IN
NEW YORK CITY IS A YACHT .
THE ONLY PLACE
A MAN STILL PITS
HIS STRENGTH AGAINST
THE FORCES OF NATURE.
IT'S CLEAN, UNTAINTED.
( Cohn )
I JUST LOVE IT.
( boat man )
YOU LOVE "HER." A BOAT IS ALWAYS A WOMAN.
THERE'S A REASON.
DO YOU KNOW IT ?
( Cohn )
NO.
I'LL TAKE IT. I'LL GIVE YOU A
CHECK FOR THE DOWN PAYMENT.
WE'LL ARRANGE
THE FINANCING.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S A STRONG BOAT, DESERVES
TO BE TAKEN CARE OF.
A LITTLE LOVE
WOULDN'T HURT.
HOW MANY PEOPLE CAN DANCE
ON THAT FRONT PART ?
I WOULDN'T KNOW.
WHAT'S THAT CALLED ?
THE BOW.
MY HUSBAND ?
HE WAS A PIG.
NICE.
BUT I GOT ALL THE CARS
IN THE GARAGE,
THE GARAGE, THE HOUSE
IT WAS ATTACHED TO,
THE MAIN HOUSE, AND EVERYTHING
IN THAT, THE PICASSOS, THE DOGS,
AND THE IBM STOCK OPTIONS,
AND DO YOU KNOW WHY ?
WHY ?
BECAUSE ROY COHN IS THE
BEST LAWYER IN NEW YORK.
MY DEAR,
HE'S A KILLER.
SHE KNOWS.
( Iva )
HE'S MY KILLER.
( Cohn )
SHE KNOWS AND SHE'S RIGHT.
( chuckling )
HEY, COHN.
RESCUE ME ON THIS.
I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU,
I HATE TO BRING IT UP.
CARMINE.
YOU'RE LEAVING ?
YOU HATE IT.
GOT YOUR COAT ON AFTER
THE FIRST ACT. WHY ?
THE TENOR'S VOICE IS
LIKE RUSTY SKATES.
THE SOPRANO'S SKINNY LIKE A
BONE YOU THROW TO SOME DOG.
I LIKE MEAT
ON MY BONE.
IVA SCHLESINGER,
OUR MOST SATISFIED CLIENT,
CARMINE GELANTI.
I WORK WITH CARMINE'S
ASSOCIATION.
CAN WE HAVE
A TALK ?
CALL ME TOMORROW
AT 10:00 AT THE OFFICE--
CAN WE HAVE A LITTLE
DISCUSSION, NOW ?
OH...AH.
I'LL SEE YOU
IN A BIT.
THIS CAN'T WAIT ?
I'M WITH PEOPLE.
THE PROBLEM'S A LITTLE
COMPLICATED: LEGALITIES.
LEGALITY-SHMEGALITY.
TELL ME THE JUDGE'S NAME.
THAT'S ALL I NEED.
I'LL DO THAT, THEN.
OKAY.
HOW MUCH YOUR BOAT
SET YOU BACK ?
HOW'D YOU KNOW ABOUT
THE BOAT, CARMINE ?
YOU CAN ALWAYS COME
TO US FOR MONEY.
YOU NEED IT, YOU GOT IT.
WE'RE FAMILY, RIGHT ?
YOU THINK A SMART
JEWISH BOY'LL GO TO
AN ITALIAN BONE-BREAKING
ORGANIZATION FOR MONEY ?
ARE YOU  MESHUGENEH ?
LET ME ASK YOU.
FEEL THIS ARM FOR ME.
DO I HAVE TO ?
GO AHEAD,
FEEL IT.
MAY I ?
DO I WANT THIS ARM
AROUND MY NECK GOING,
"HEY, WHERE'S
OUR MONEY ?"
RELAX. WILL YOU TELL HIM
TO GET A SUIT THAT FITS ?
HE TAKES CARE OF ME.
ROY.
THE FEE ARRANGEMENT
ON YOUR DIVORCE ?
YES.
I'M STICKING BY IT.
IT WAS A DISASTER FOR US.
WE OVERSPENT VERY BADLY.
THESE SOUTH AFRICAN DIVORCES
ARE LIKE QUICKSAND FOR CASH.
MY PARTNERSHIP
IS CASH POOR.
I WAS WONDERING--
HOW MUCH ?
$100,000.
A LOAN,
JUST A LOAN.
I CAN DO THAT.
MY DARLING, THAT'S
THE LEAST I CAN DO.
? A LAW WAS MADE
A DISTANT MOON AGO HERE ?
HOW ARE YOU ?
? JULY AND AUGUST
CANNOT BE TOO HOT ?
? AND THERE'S A LEGAL
LIMIT TO THE SNOW HERE ?
? IN CAMELOT ?
? THE WINTER IS FORBIDDEN
TILL DECEMBER ?
? AND EXITS MARCH
THE SECOND ON THE DOT ?
? BY ORDER, SUMMER LINGERS
THROUGH SEPTEMBER ?
? IN CAMELOT ?
? CAMELOT ?
? I KNOW IT SOUNDS
A BIT BIZARRE ?
? BUT IN CAMELOT ?
? CAMELOT ?
? THAT'S HOW CONDITIONS ARE ?
? THE RAIN MAY NEVER FALL
TILL AFTER SUNDOWN ?
? BY 8:00, THE MORNING FOG
MUST DISAPPEAR ?
? IN SHORT, THERE'S SIMPLY NOT?
? A MORE CONGENIAL SPOT ?
? FOR HAPPILY EVER-AFTERING ?
? THAN HERE IN CAMELOT ?
( Winchell )
Barely more than 100,000
votes out
of 70 million cast.
That, Mr. and Mrs. North
and South America, is a squeaker.
Opinion here? A rich,
Irish kid with King Midas
for a daddy has just proved
that in this country
you can buy anything,
including the White House.
Good luck, America.
A FUCKING PHOTO FINISH !
HOW CLOSE WAS IT ?
LESS THAN 120,000
( Cohn )
UNBELIEVABLE.
SAY THE POPULATION OF A TOWN
ABOUT THE SIZE OF, OF,
OF PATTERSON SWINGS
THE WHOLE COUNTRY.
I'M ALREADY WORKING UP
LEGISLATION, THINKING MAYBE I'LL GET IT THROUGH.
COME ON, WE'RE
DEMOCRATS. SMILE.
I'M SMILING.
THOSE RICH PRICKS.
ROY COHN CAN WORK WITH ANYONE,
EVEN THE KENNEDYS.  MOLTO BENE .
HOW'S THIS COMPARE
WITH THE REAL THING IN ITALY ?
MUCH BETTER, MUCH
MORE ELEGANT, THIS.
ELEGANT, YOU BET
YOUR ASS IT IS.
YEAH, SEE.
I CAN DO BUSINESS WITH HIM,
IF HE'LL DO BUSINESS WITH ME.
IT DEPENDS ON BOBBY.
HEY, WALTER.
HEY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY ? THE PLACE
IS DEAD. LIFE IS DOWNHILL.
WHO ARE
THESE GUYS ?
WALTER WINCEHLL,
CONGRESSMAN NEIL GALLAGHER.
YEAH, NEW JERSEY.
MILO GANDINI.
WRITE IT DOWN.
WHAT IS HE ?
I HOPE TO BE A PRODUCT
REPRESENTATIVE:
MEN'S PERSONAL PRODUCTS,
PROFUMO,  SHAMPOO.
HE'S A MODEL.
( Winchell )
FORGET ABOUT IT.
SAY, ROY.
YOU HEAR WHAT I HEAR ?
KENNEDY IS GOING TO NAME
HIS BROTHER ATTORNEY GENERAL.
MY FRIEND J. EDGAR SAYS
IT'LL BE, "GET HOFFA AND GET COHN."
FUCK THE LITTLE COCKSUCKER
AND ALL THE SHIPS AT SEA.
HEY.
I CAN WORK
WITH ANYONE.
I GOT CONGRESS, RIGHT ?
( doorbell ringing )
WHAT DO YOU WANT HERE ?
FBI FOR ROY COHN. BARTLETT,
HENDRICKS, STAY AT THE DOOR.
MONROE, WHO ARE
THESE MEN ?
( Monroe )
I'M SORRY, MRS. COHN, I TRIED--
FBI. WE HAVE A WARRANT
FOR ROY MARCUS COHN.
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT.
MY HUSBAND WAS
A NEW YORK STATE JUDGE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING ?
ROY !
( FBI agent )
I CAN'T GET IN.
OH, SHIT.
( FBI agent )
NOTHING DOWN HERE, SIR.
SHH SHH SHH.
YOU BETTER HAVE A WARRANT.
I WANT TO SEE SOME ID.
FBI, FEDERAL WARRANT.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
THIS IS ROY COHN.
YOU'RE MAKING A BIG MISTAKE.
JUST WAIT. LET ME JUST READ
THIS THING IN THE LIGHT.
HELLO.
CLYDE TOLSON.
WE'VE MET. MR. HOOVER ASKED ME
TO COME ALONG THIS MORNING.
MR. HOOVER'S A PERSONAL
FRIEND OF MY SON'S.
HE WOULDN'T APPROVE.
MOM.
PLEASE.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW.
MR. HOOVER ASKED ME
TO MAKE SURE
NOTHING BE TAKEN THAT
THE WARRANT DOESN'T CALL FOR.
IT'S WRITTEN IN A WAY
YOU COULD TAKE ANYTHING
AND DOESN'T SPECIFY
A GODDAMN THING.
UH, MONROE...
OPEN THE OFFICE
AND LET THEM IN.
( Dora )
WAIT A MINUTE.
MOM, THEY'RE WITHIN THEIR
RIGHTS. THEY HAVE A WARRANT.
MR. HOOVER ALSO ASKED ME
TO ASK MR. COHN
IF HE WOULD COME DOWN
TO WASHINGTON.
FOR WHAT ?
TO JOIN US FOR DINNER
TOMORROW NIGHT.
THAT'S NICE,
THAT'S BETTER--
WHY DON'T YOU GO
IN THE KITCHEN,
MAKE COFFEE
FOR EVERYBODY.
DIO, DIO.
AGAIN, I APOLOGIZE,
MR. COHN.
THANK YOU.
BUT WE WERE FORCED
TO IMPLEMENT
THE DEMANDS OF
THE ATTORNEY GENERAL.
UNDER THE CURRENT REGIME,
WE TAKE OUR MARCHING ORDERS
FROM THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT,
WHETHER WE AGREE OR NOT.
IT SEEMS THAT YOU
HAVE DISPLEASED
THE PRESIDENT'S BROTHER.
BOBBY KENNEDY IS
A DANGEROUS MAN.
HE'S A SPOILED RICH KID THAT
NOBODY'S EVER SAID NO TO.
AND HIS BROTHER.
LOOK, SIR...
YOU'VE CREATED THE ONLY FEDERAL
AGENCY THAT TRULY WORKS.
IT GIVES THE PEOPLE VALUE
FOR THEIR TAX DOLLARS.
YOU ARE THE ONLY
FEDERAL EXECUTIVE
THAT PEOPLE KNOW
AND TRULY RESPECT.
YOU ARE A HERO, SIR.
THANK YOU.
I THINK YOU OVERSTATE,
BUT YES, AND CALL ME JOHN.
MY POINT IS,
JOHN,
THE KENNEDY ADMINISTRATION
WILL RESENT YOUR INDEPENDENCE.
THEY'LL WANT TO, AND I
UNDERSTAND HUMAN NATURE,
PUT YOU UNDER
BOBBY'S HEEL.
BOBBY WANTS ME OUT.
( Cohn )
WHICH WOULD BE A
CATASTROPHE
FOR THIS COUNTRY.
WHAT I NEED
TO KNOW,
IS THERE ANY WAY
THAT I CAN BE OF HELP--
THAT I CAN BE...
A SOLDIER IN
YOUR ARMY ?
DID YOU EVER
HEAR THE WAY
JIMMY DURANTE SAYS
CATASTROPHE ?
"A CATASTRASTROKE."
A GREAT ENTERTAINER.
MR. COHN,
WE'D LIKE TO PLAY A SHORT
ENTERTAINMENT FOR YOU.
( moaning )
THE SOUND OF MARTIN
LUTHER KING IN A MOTEL.
YOU NOTICE THAT
COMMUNISTS MAKE
THE SAME TELLTALE
SOUNDS AS PATRIOTS.
ROBERT KENNEDY
HAS ORDERED US
TO BUG KING'S HOTEL ROOM
WHEREVER HE GOES.
AND NOT JUST
MR. KING.
CAN YOU IMAGINE WHAT
AMERICANS WOULD THINK
IF THEY KNEW THEIR
GOLDEN BOY LIBERAL HERO
PUT MICROPHONES IN MARTIN
LUTHER KING'S BEDROOM ?
I'M NOT WORRIED.
YOU SEE,
I'VE BEEN DOING
THIS SINCE 1924.
I'VE SEEN HOTSHOTS
IN THE WHITE HOUSE COME
AND I'VE CERTAINLY SEEN
THEM GO: 6 OF THEM.
THIS ONE HAS 7
MORE YEARS MAXIMUM,
AND THEN HE'LL
BE GONE, TOO.
MEANWHILE, MY FILES
ARE A GREAT SOURCE
OF COMFORT
AND PROTECTION.
THIS PARTICULAR TAPE
I OFFER TO YOU.
WHAT CAN YOU
DO WITH IT ?
"AS CHAIRMAN OF
THE COMMITTEE
"FOR THE PROTECTION
OF INDIVIDUAL PRIVACY--"
THIS IS NOT--
"I HEREWITH DEMAND
THAT YOU, ROBERT KENNEDY--"
YOU'RE CRAZY !
JUST...
"PRODUCE THE AUTHORIZATION
"FOR THE ELECTRONIC
SURVEILLANCE
"OF MARTIN LUTHER KING."
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU CAN CALL MY SECRETARY
AND DICTATE A
LETTER LIKE THIS ?
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO DO: INDIVIDUAL PRIVACY.
I'M ONE LITTLE MEMBER
OF CONGRESS. THIS STUFF--
"IS AN OUTRAGE.
I AM OUTRAGED BY THIS."
IT ISN'T NEWS.
HOOVER'S BEEN TAPING EVERYBODY
HE DOESN'T LIKE FOR YEARS.
HE HAS MORE
TAPE THAN 3M.
( Cohn )
HOOVER ? I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM.
HE HAS NOTHING TO DO.
LISTEN, LISTEN.
FORGET HOOVER. I'M TALKING
ABOUT THE CONSTITUTION--
DON'T DO THAT.
SINCE WHEN ARE YOU THE
PROTECTOR OF OUR CIVIL RIGHTS ?
HOOVER PLAYS THESE
TAPES AT PARTIES.
PRESIDENTS CAN'T STOP HIM.
I CAN'T STOP HIM.
FORGET ABOUT HOOVER.
THE POINT IS, YES, THIS IS THE POINT:
IF AMERICANS AREN'T
SECURE IN THE PRIVACY OF THEIR OWN BEDROOMS
FROM POLICE-STATE TACTICS
OF THE WHITE HOUSE,
THEN DEMOCRATIC
GOVERNMENT IS DEAD.
THE CONSTITUTION,
THE BILL OF RIGHTS ARE DEAD.
NO ONE IS SAFE.
THE GOVERNMENT
IS OVERTHROWN.
AND YOU HAVEN'T
STOOD UP
AND SAID OR DONE A
DAMN THING ABOUT IT.
THIS IS FUNNY, RIGHT ?
OKAY, ROY,
I UNDERSTAND.
YOU DON'T WANT BOBBY KENNEDY
IN YOUR BEDROOM UNINVITED.
YEAH.
I DON'T WANT
BOBBY KENNEDY ANYWHERE.
THIS SHIT IS TOO DEEP
FOR ME. FORGET IT.
NEIL ?
I SURE HOPE YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY SKELETONS IN YOUR CLOSET.
BECAUSE BOY, DO THEY HAVE
A WAY OF COMING OUT.
OKAY.
I ACCEPT THAT AS A THREAT.
YOU LEAVE ME ALONE, PAL.
IN FACT, YOU STAY AWAY
FROM ME. WE'RE ENDED.
DON'T !
WHOO HOO...
WHOO...
HE SAID IT WAS
A THREAT ?
( Cohn )
Yes, sir, a threat.
IT'S CLEAR HE DOESN'T
HAVE THE GUTS
TO GO AGAINST
THE KENNEDYS.
NEIL GALLAGHER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'LL TAKE THIS
ONE STEP AT A TIME.
NEIL GALLAGHER.
( phone ringing )
MR. COHN'S OFFICE.
I GOT IT.
MR. COHN.
ROY, IT'S IVA.
IVA, SO NICE TO HEAR FROM YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN WONDERFUL ?
WELL, ALMOST. LOOK, YOU KNOW
YOUR LETTER ABOUT MY LOAN ?
THERE MUST BE
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
I DON'T THINK SO. COULD WE
DO THIS AT SOME LATER...
You refer to it as
a payment for services.
IT WAS A LOAN,
YOU REMEMBER.
And I do need it--
YOU KNOW, I-I-IVA,
IF THERE'S BEEN A MISTAKE,
WE'LL FIND IT, ALL RIGHT ?
THIS IS REALLY
A BAD TIME.
WHERE'S COHN ?
OUT OF MY WAY.
WHAT ? NEIL.
SON OF A BITCH.
WAIT.
READ IT.
READ IT !
YOU KNEW
ABOUT IT.
YOU AND THAT BASTARD HOOVER
YOU LOVE SO MUCH.
LIFE MAGAZINE  ?
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT ?
IT'S NEWS TO ME.
IT'S AN FBI PLANT,
TYING ME IN WITH THE MAFIA.
DEAD BODIES IN MY BASEMENT ?
CHRIST, WHAT A STORY !
HOOVER'S COMPLETELY--
GET OUT OF HERE ! HOOVER IS
COMPLETELY OUT OF HIS MIND.
HE WAITED UNTIL I'M RUNNING FOR
RE-ELECTION AND THEN BANG !
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THIS'LL DO,
HOW I'LL BE KILLED BY THIS ?
MY WHOLE CAREER,
MY REPUTATION.
I DON'T FORGET WHEN
I'M THREATENED, YOU LITTLE COCKSUCKER.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
DO WHAT HE WANTS ?
OH, NO,
NO, NO.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT I'LL DO.
LET ME EXPLAIN IT--
DON'T !
IF I HAVE TO CHOOSE
WHO I WANT FOR AN ENEMY,
THE U.S. PRESIDENT AND HIS
ATTORNEY GENERAL BROTHER,
OR J. EDGAR HOOVER,
THAT'S EASY.
GIVE THIS TO
YOUR G-MAN.
NO NEGOTIATIONS.
GET OUT OF
MY WAY.
IVA, COULD I CALL YOU BACK
IN JUST 2 MINUTES ?
THANK YOU.
( Gallagher )
"AS A MEMBER OF THE CONGRESS,
"IT IS NOT MY INCLINATION
"TO JUDGE THE
SEXUAL PROCLIVITIES
"OF ANY PUBLIC SERVANT
OR ANYBODY ELSE.
"HOWEVER, IT'S BEEN
CALLED TO MY ATTENTION
"THAT THE DIRECTOR
OF THE FBI
"AND THE DEPUTY
DIRECTOR OF THE FBI
"HAVE BEEN LIVING TOGETHER
AS MAN AND WIFE"
"FOR THE PAST 28 YEARS
AT THE PUBLIC'S EXPENSE.
"NOW, ROY, I'VE LISTED
NEAT LITTLE THINGS
"LIKE THE ARMORED CAR THAT
PICKS THEM UP AT THE AIRPORT,
"TAKES THEM TO A HOTEL
WHERE THEY SPEND
"THE TAXPAYERS' TIME AND MONEY
DIDDLING EACH OTHER."
EVERY DAY AT NOON,
AS YOU KNOW, SIR,
ANY MEMBER OF THE CONGRESS
CAN MAKE A SPEECH
ON ANY SUBJECT HE WISHES.
YES.
EVERY SINGLE DAY,
GALLAGHER WILL BE
MAKING THIS SPEECH...
UNTIL ELECTION DAY.
AND...
HE WANTS YOU TO GET
LIFE MAGAZINE
TO PRINT A RETRACTION
ON THE STORY ABOUT THE BODIES
BURIED IN HIS BASEMENT.
( clearing throat )
IT'LL BE DONE.
HOW WILL WE GET
BOBBY KENNEDY ?
GO AWAY.
PLEASE, GO,
MR. COHN.
I'VE BEEN OF
USE TO YOU.
ROY.
I THINK IT'S
TIME YOU GO.
BOBBY KENNEDY.
YOU WERE AFTER ME
AND YOU WERE AFTER HOFFA.
"GET HOFFA AND GET COHN."
YOU THINK I'M STUPID ?
WHY ME ? YOU WERE NO ANGEL.
HAD McCARTHY STOPPED SHORT,
YOU'D HAVE BEEN UP HIS ASS.
BUT I LEARNED SOMETHING.
I LEARNED.
YOU NEVER LEARNED.
WHAT A MISERABLE
LITTLE MAN YOU ARE.
FOR ONE, BRIBING WITNESSES,
INTIMIDATING WITNESSES,
THREATENING WITNESSES,
FALSE TESTIMONY INTRODUCED
INTO A COURT OF LAW.
BRIBING WITNESSES,
INTIMIDATING WITNESSES,
THREATENING WITNESSES,
MANUFACTURING EVIDENCE,
GIVING EVASIVE,
FICTITIOUS, VAGUE
FALSE, MISLEADING AND
MANUFACTURED TESTIMONY,
AND CORRUPTLY, BY
THREATS AND OFFERS,
ATTEMPTING
TO INFLUENCE,
IMPEDE AND FRUSTRATE
INVESTIGATIONS
BY THE DEPARTMENT
OF JUSTICE.
HOW DOES MR. COHN PLEAD ?
MY CLIENT PLEADS--
NOT GUILTY TO 48 OF
THE MOST OUTRAGEOUS,
OUTLANDISH,
EGREGIOUS,
MALICIOUS, CONCOCTED,
SURREPTITIOUS,
SOLICITOUS,
SUPERCILIOUS,
OUTRAGEOUS,
MENDACIOUS
CHARGES I HAVE EVER
HEARD IN THIS COURT.
THANK YOU FOR MAKING YOUR
POINT SO CLEARLY, MR. COHN.
BAIL RECOMMENDATIONS,
MR. WALPIN ?
I SUGGEST--
IN THE MATTER OF BAIL,
THE GOVERNMENT IS
WILLING TO RELEASE
THE DEFENDANT INTO
HIS OWN RECOGNIZANCE.
OH, OH. WHAT'S THE CATCH ?
WE WOULD LIKE THE DEFENDANT
FINGERPRINTED, YOUR HONOR.
HE WANTS FINGERPRINTS,
PHOTOGRAPHS, MUG SHOTS.
( gavel banging )
YOU MAY DO SO.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE MOST WELCOME.
DID I MENTION SEMEN SAMPLES,
STOOL SPECIMENS, BLOOD COUNTS,
WHITE-BLOOD-CELL COUNTS,
PAP SMEARS,
IRRIGATION OF THE TONSILS ?
HOW DID IT FEEL TO HAVE A
WHOLE ARM OF THE GOVERNMENT
REACHING OUT FOR YOUR
THROAT FOR A CHANGE ?
I LIKED IT.
MAKE SURE THAT GOES IN OUR
LITTLE COURT RECORD HERE TODAY.
THE CHALLENGE
INVIGORATED ME.
GAVE ROY
A HARD ON.
( Walpin )
MR. GARFIELD,
DID THERE COME A TIME
WHEN MR. COHN
INDICATED TO YOU THE PAYMENT
HAD ALREADY BEEN MADE ?
( Garfield )
HE SAID THAT HE NEEDED ANOTHER $40,000
FOR PAYMENT
OF BRIBES.
DID HE SPECIFY HOW THE $40,000
WAS TO BE DISTRIBUTED ?
HE SAID $10,000 EACH
FOR 2 WITNESSES
AND ANOTHER $20,000
FOR AN ASSISTANT PROSECUTOR.
OBJECTION.
I'D NEVER PAY AN ASSISTANT
PROSECUTOR MORE THAN $50.
ARE YOU NUTS ?
MR. COHN ?
YES, SIR ?
SIT DOWN.
IF YOU ARE LATE
ONE MORE TIME,
I'LL PUT YOU
INTO CUSTODY.
I APOLOGIZE,
YOUR HONOR.
$20,000 ?
THE GUY'S DREAMING.
HEARSAY.
IT'S ALL HEARSAY.
JESUS, ROY.
RELAX, WILL YOU ?
( judge )
IS THERE ANY MORE ?
NO.
( Cohn )
SMART MOVE.
MR. RAICHLE,
FINISH THE REBUTTAL.
SEE THAT BLACK GIRL,
THE JUROR ?
SHE'S GOING TO SLICE ME UP
AND SERVE ME ON TOAST.
YOU USED UP YOUR CHALLENGES
TOO FAST. BLACKS HATE ME.
I'LL NEVER DEFEND
ANOTHER LAWYER.
YOU WON'T DEFEND
ME AGAIN.
MR. GARFIELD,
IS IT FAIR TO SAY
THAT BEING SUDDENLY
CONFRONTED WITH
ADDITIONAL COSTS,
FOR WHATEVER PURPOSE,
IS UPSETTING ?
YEAH, IT WAS.
INFURIATING ?
DID IT MAKE YOU ANGRY
AT THE DEFENDANT ?
ME ?
NO, I REALLY DO
LOVE THE GUY.
BUT THIS IS BUSINESS.
I'VE GOT TO TELL THE TRUTH.
( Cohn chuckling )
I LOVE YOU, TOO,
GARFIELD. MMWA.
YOUR HONOR.
RELAX.
I'M SORRY,
I REALLY DO APOLOGIZE.
IT WAS JUST THE SINCERITY
AND GOODWILL OF THE WITNESS.
I ALMOST CRIED.
IT BROKE MY HEART.
MR. COHN,
WHILE I AM ON
THIS BENCH,
YOU WILL OBSERVE THE
RULES OF THIS COURT.
BOBBY KENNEDY.
THIS IS KENNEDY'S COURT.
IT HAS ITS
OWN RULES.
YOU ARE PERILOUSLY
CLOSE TO CONTEMPT.
( dance music playing )
HI.
REMEMBER ME ?
PETER.
SAY SOMETHING
NICE TO ME.
EVEN WHEN YOU'RE SAD,
YOU'RE VERY EXCITING.
EVEN WHEN
YOU'RE LYING...
SO ARE YOU.
LAST TIME I WAS HERE,
YOU DANCED WITH ME,
WITH EVERYONE.
IT WAS A GREAT NIGHT.
AFTER READING ABOUT
YOUR TRIAL AND TRIBULATIONS,
DO YOU WANT TO HEAR
AN OPTIMISTIC WORD ?
BE AN OPTIMIST
FOR ME TONIGHT.
I DON'T THINK A FIRST CLASS
BASTARD LIKE YOU
WILL GET BEAT BY
A BUNCH OF AMATEURS.
( judge )
MR. COHN,
YOU HAVE BEEN CONSISTENTLY
AND ARROGANTLY UNPUNCTUAL.
I AM PREPARED TO CITE YOU
FOR, UH, FAILURE TO, UH...
MR. RAICHLE,
YOUR CLIENT MAY...
WOULD YOU LIKE TO REQUEST
POSTPONING THESE PROCEEDINGS ?
NOT AT ALL, I THINK THIS COURT
HAS PROCEEDED IN A TOUGH,
HONORABLE, NEW FRONTIER
KIND OF WAY.
ARE YOU IN PAIN ?
IT'S JUST THESE DRAINAGE
SACS, THE STITCHES.
IT'S JUST FROM A LITTLE
COSMETIC SURGERY I HAD.
JUST A LITTLE NIP
AND A TUCK.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO CONTINUE,
I'M PREPARED TO DO SO.
VERY WELL.
PLEASE RESUME THE STAND.
MR. RAICHLE,
ARE YOU PREPARED
TO CONTINUE WITH
THE QUESTIONING ?
YES, YOUR HONOR.
THIS COURT'S
CALLED TO ORDER.
THE WITNESS IS REMINDED
THAT HE IS STILL UNDER OATH.
MR. COHN,
WHEN WE ADJOURNED,
YOU WERE DESCRIBING
YOUR DUTIES
AS COUNSEL TO SENATOR
McCARTHY'S COMMITTEE.
WHAT WAS THE PURPOSE OF THAT
COMMITTEE'S INVESTIGATION ?
TO UNCOVER
COMMUNIST INFILTRATION
IN VARIOUS PARTS
OF THE GOVERNMENT,
INCLUDING THE
TREASURY DEPARTMENT.
WHO WAS THE SECRETARY
OF THE TREASURY AT THAT TIME ?
HENRY MORGENTHAU, JR.
IS HE THE FATHER
OF THE PRESENT U.S. ATTORNEY
WHO'S BROUGHT
CHARGES AGAINST YOU ?
YES.
HE'S BEEN
CONSPIRING WITH
THE ATTORNEY GENERAL,
ROBERT KENNEDY,
EVER SINCE I INVESTIGATED
THE TRANSFER OF MONEY PLATES...
GET INTO IT.
OBJECTION.
FOR RUSSIA,
UNDER HIS FATHER.
THEY ASKED, THEY MUST HAVE
SET A RECORD, LIKE 8,450--
OBJECTION. THE DEFENDANT
CAN'T KNOW
WHAT'S IN THE MIND
OF MR. MORGENTHAU
OR THE ATTORNEY GENERAL.
QUESTIONS ABOUT MY PERSONAL
AND PRIVATE LIFE.
THE DATE I HAD
MY ADENOIDS REMOVED.
SUSTAINED.
THE OBJECTION IS SUSTAINED.
MY FIRST ERECTION,
ANYTHING TO TRY,
YOUR HONOR,
TO TRY TO TRAP ME, AND YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY GOT ? NOTHING.
YOU GOT NOTHING, RIGHT ?
YOU WANT MY BLOOD ?
HERE, TAKE IT.
THE OBJECTION
IS SUSTAINED.
IT IS SUSTAINED. YOU KNOW
BETTER. YOU'RE A LAWYER.
ARE YOU QUITE THROUGH ?
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
FINISH ME THAT EASILY.
THESE REMARKS'LL BE
STRICKEN FROM THE RECORD
AND THE JURY WILL
DISREGARD THEM.
EVERY SINGLE
PROSECUTION WITNESS
IS A CONVICTED FELON
GIVEN IMMUNITY.
DON'T YOU SEE THAT EVEN THE
STUPIDEST JURY IN THE WORLD
WILL KNOW THEY'VE ALL
MADE THEIR DEALS ?
THEY'D SAY ANYTHING.
DON'T YOU THINK THE JURY
KNOWS THAT ? DAMN RIGHT.
EVEN MY FATHER
WOULD FIND FOR ME.
HMM.
EVEN HIM.
YOU WANT A CHARACTER
WITNESS NOW ?
I WAS FOUND GUILTY, ROY,
BUT WAS I GUILTY ?
THE JURY DETERMINES
THE GUILT.
I PRESENTED THE FACTS.
THEY DECIDED YOU WERE GUILTY.
DID YOU DO IT ? I DON'T KNOW.
WHO KNOWS ? WHO CARES ?
WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO RIGHT OR WRONG ?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU NEVER DID KNOW.
( man )
THE JUDGE WANTS TO SEE YOU.
THE JUDGE ?
( judge )
THE FATHER OF JUROR NUMBER 9
WAS KILLED IN AN AUTOMOBILE
ACCIDENT EARLY THIS MORNING.
I HAVE TO DECIDE WHETHER OR
NOT SHE SHOULD BE TOLD.
OPINIONS ?
THE JURY IS CLOSE
TO A VERDICT.
A FEW HOURS MORE, POSSIBLY
LESS. IF THE FATHER WERE ILL,
WE MIGHT AGREE, BUT--
IF HE'S DEAD,
STOPPING NOW
WON'T BRING THE
GIRL'S FATHER BACK.
SHE JUST LOST
HER FATHER !
LET HIS LAWYER SPEAK.
I'M NOT TALKING TO YOU.
STOP IT.
UNLESS THEY'VE BEEN
LISTENING AT THE DOOR,
THEY DON'T KNOW
WHEN THE VERDICT'S COMING.
9 IS THE BLACK GIRL.
YOU'VE GOT TO TELL A PERSON
THAT THEIR FATHER DIED.
OR WHAT ? ROY COHN GOES
ON NATIONAL TELEVISION
AND TELLS THE WORLD
THAT THESE PRICKS
WANT HIM IN JAIL SO BADLY
THEY'LL PUT A JUROR'S
FATHER IN THE GROUND AND NOT TELL HER ?
( Walpin )
THAT'S THREATENING THE COURT WITH BLACKMAIL.
WAIT.
SHOULD I CHOOSE
TO INFORM HER,
WOULD BOTH
SIDES AGREE
TO ALLOW 11 JURORS
TO BRING OUT A VERDICT ?
NOT EVEN REMOTELY.
THE DEFENSE
WOULD NOT AGREE.
MUMSY !
THE SYSTEM WORKS !
I BEAT THE BASTARDS !
MUMSY !
THIS IS A GREAT COUNTRY,
MONROE. EQUAL JUSTICE FOR ALL. YES !
MUMSY !
MUTTI  !
YOUR LITTLE FROG PRINCE
HAS DONE IT AGAIN.
MUTTI, MUTTI,
SLEEPING BEAUTY.
( slow instrumental music )
( speaking Hebrew )
YIS-GA-DAL, V'YIS-KA-DASH.
DORA, I LOVE YOU.
GOODBYE.
WE HEREBY CONSECRATE
YOUR ASHES
TO THE WINDS AND
WATERS OF THE WORLD
FROM WHICH
THEY HAVE COME.
AND NEW JERSEY,
FROM WHICH
YOU DIDN'T.
I'M MOST DECIDEDLY
NOT SUBORNING PERJURY .
MAYBE THE GUY'S
MEMORY COULD BE LESS
ACUTE THAN IT WAS
DURING THE DEPOSITION.
SORRY, MR. COHN.
THANK YOU.
OH.
WELL, AT LEAST MONROE
HASN'T FORGOTTEN ME,
THOUGH APPARENTLY
YOU HAVE.
I NEED TO SPEAK TO YOU.
CAN YOU HOLD ON
A SECOND ?
HOW DARE YOU NOT
RETURN MY CALLS !
THAT'S BECAUSE I DON'T
ACCEPT THREATS.
I'D BE CAREFUL
WITH ME.
YOU WANT TO KEEP
ME AS A FRIEND.
WHAT DID YOU CALL
YOURSELF ? A FRIEND ?
YOU STOLE MY MONEY, LIED TO ME.
WOULD YOU PUT DOWN THE PHONE ?
CAN I CALL YOU BACK ?
IT WAS YEARS AGO.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER--
I HAVE THE IOU.
IT'S SIGNED, "ROY COHN."
ALL RIGHT ?
THE DIVORCE ? GOING TO
WHEREVER IT WAS,
SOUTH AFRICA, IT ATE UP--
PLEASE ! YOU CAN SCARE
IMPORTANT MEN,
THEY KNOW HOW DANGEROUS
YOU ARE TO THEM,
BUT YOU DON'T SCARE ME.
I'M SHELTERED.
I'M SHELTERED ENOUGH
TO BELIEVE THAT I'M RIGHT
AND IF YOU'RE WRONG, YOU'RE
WRONG. THAT'LL BE ENOUGH.
THAT IS NEVER ENOUGH.
FROM THE BEST LEGAL MIND
IN NEW YORK,
THIS PIECE OF
ADVICE IS FREE:
IT'S NOT ENOUGH
TO BE RIGHT.
FIGHT ME, IVA.
BECAUSE ROY COHN
NEVER LOSES.
REALLY ?
WE'LL JUST SEE
ABOUT THAT.
WHY DO I FEEL
LIKE CALIGULA ?
BECAUSE I TREAT YOU
LIKE AN EMPEROR.
RIGHT.
OH, WAIT...AAH, AAH.
LOOK AT WHAT
YOU DID TO ME !
SORRY. I DON'T THINK--
DUMB QUEER.
LOOK AT THIS.
PUT THIS ON.
THAT'S NICE.
RELAX.
IT'S FINE, IT STOPPED
BLEEDING. IT STOPPED.
AAH.
I'M SORRY.
WHAT IS WRONG
WITH YOU ?
HAS IT STOPPED ?
MY GOD.
GOD.
HOLD ON.
GIVE ME SOMETHING QUICK.
WHAT DID YOU DO ?
GIVE ME SOMETHING.
PUT THIS ON.
CALM DOWN.
IT'S FINE,
IT'S FINE.
WHAT IS WRONG
WITH YOU ?
THAT LOOKS BETTER.
THAT'S FINE.
THAT'S OKAY.
I'LL JUST PUT A LITTLE
PRESSURE ON IT.
GOD.
GOD !
GOD. IS IT ALL RIGHT ?
NO, IT'S BLEEDING.
OH, GOD.
OH, MY GOD !
IS IT OKAY ?
DO SOMETHING.
CALL THE DOCTOR !
DAMN DOCTORS.
SOME QUESTIONS THEY
HAVE NO RIGHT TO ASK.
WHAT QUESTIONS ?
ABOUT MY LIFE.
IT'S NOT HIS BUSINESS.
WHERE TO ?
ANYWHERE.
JUST DRIVE.
SORRY ABOUT
THE BAD NEWS, SIR.
BAD NEWS ?
HOW DID YOU HEAR ?
IT'S ON THE RADIO.
RADIO ? WHAT'S
ON THE RADIO ?
THE STATE IS BRINGING
DISBARMENT PROCEEDINGS
AGAINST YOU.
IT'S ON RADIO AND TV.
WHAT ELSE DID
THEY SAY ?
THEY MENTIONED IV-I-I...
IVA SCHLESINGER ?
YES, SIR.
THAT COW.
AAH.
AAH. AAH.
I GOTTA GO.
WHAT'S HE DOING NOW ?
CAN YOU...
I HAVE TO GO TO COURT.
THEY'RE TRYING TO DISBAR ME.
THE HEARINGS ARE OVER,
DARLING, ALL OVER.
DID I WIN ?
NO.
NO ? THEY DISBARRED ME ?
OH, THEY DID.
WHY WERE YOU
SO NAUGHTY ? WHY ?
WHY DID YOU GET ME, HMM ?
BECAUSE I WAS
A WOMAN ?
NO.
BECAUSE I WAS A JEW ?
I KILLED YOU FOR THE HEADLINES,
FOR THE FUCKING HEADLINES.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER ?
I'VE GOTTA GO.
THE LAST STAGES: IT GETS
IN THE BRAIN, YOU KNOW ?
( Kennedy )
JUSTICE.
JUSTICE HAS A WAY...
THE FACT IS, HE NEVER
FOUND A COMMUNIST.
HE NEVER FOUND
A COMMUNIST.
I HAVE A LIST.
YES.
A COMMUNIST,
YOU WERE A COMMUNIST !
A LIST THE LENGTH OF WHICH
IS JUST AMAZING TO BEHOLD.
IT'S YOU, PIXIE !
I KNEW WHAT
YOU WERE.
YOU WERE A COMMUNIST WITH YOUR
SUNSPOTS. I GOT YOUR SUN...
AND YOU, YOU DRUNK.
I DON'T NEED ANY DRUNKEN...
LOOK AT YOU NOW.
( Black juror )
WHY DON'T YOU HELP HIM ?
HE'S DEAD.
HE WILL BE SOON.
FUCK THAT.
YOU KNOW WHO THIS IS ?
THE LITTLE GIRL I DIDN'T
WANT ON THE JURY.
BUT THEN HER FATHER GOT KILLED,
AND I GOT SAVED.
MY FATHER DIDN'T
NEED TO DIE, MR. COHN.
HE DIED FOR MY SINS.
I WAS THE ONLY JUROR
WHO WOULD'VE SAVED YOU.
I WOULD'VE SAVED YOU.
I WOULD'VE VOTED FOR YOU.
YOU WERE ALL ALONE
IN THAT COURT,
NOBODY ON YOUR SIDE.
THEY WERE ALL AFTER YOU.
I KNOW HOW THAT FEELS.
WAIT. WAIT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT HE THREW
MY ASHES IN ? THE EAST RIVER !
YOU WOULDN'T LET
YOUR DOG SWIM IN IT.
MA...
AND YET,
HE'S MINE.
YOU'RE MINE.
I DIDN'T MAKE YOU THE
WAY YOU ARE. YOU DID.
YOU MADE
A MONSTER.
WHY ?
LOOKING FOR THE...
A CONFESSION ?
WHY I LIVED THE WAY...
JEW THAT PERSECUTED JEWS.
GAY THAT CRUCIFIED GAYS.
I PRACTICED LAW BEFORE
THE GREATEST COURTS
AND STOLE, CHEATED
FROM EVERYONE.
I HAD A FULL LIFE.
( chuckling )
THAT'S WHY.
I LOVED EVERY
MINUTE OF IT.
DID WHATEVER
I WANTED TO DO.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU LET ME
GET AWAY WITH IT.
MR. COHN...
HAVE YOU NO SENSE OF
MORTALITY, SIR, AT LONG LAST ?
WILL YOU NOT RID US
OF YOUR PRESENCE ?
THEY NEED THE ROOM.
( beeping )
AAH.
HEY, WHERE ARE
THEY ALL GOING ?
WE'RE NOT THROUGH YET,
ARE WE ? I NEED...
I NEED TO FILE
AN EXTENSION.
DORA,  MUTTI , MOM ?
DON'T LEAVE ME.
DON'T LET THEM TAKE ME.
THEY CAN'T CATCH ME.
I'M THE GINGERBREAD BOY.
ROY, ROY.
( steady beeping )
NURSE ?
NURSE ! SOMEBODY !
GET IN HERE !
CODE BLUE STAT !
( another nurse )
( voice on P.A. )
CODE BLUE IN 918.
NO.
IT'S OVER.
LET HIM GO.
ROY ?
( slow instrumental music )
AT LAST, HE DID
SOMETHING HUMAN.
WHAT WAS HE SAYING ?
( Peter )
HE SAID, "TELL ME THE NAME OF THE JUDGE."
( voice on P.A. )
CANCEL CODE BLUE.