SubText: NoRMITA.326
Democracy comes from
the Greek root "demos"..
meaning "the people"..
and "kratein" meaning "to rule"
In other words..
to govern according to..
the will of the majority
Lincoln once said
Of the people
by the people
for the people
It represents the ideals of the
future China that I truly believe in
A people's republic!
Prof. Yang
Will we ever see that day?
I know that day will come
Even if I don't live to see it..
You will!
Professor! Professor!
Yang Qu-yun, the former leader of
the Revive China Society..
was gunned down on October 1st, 1901
It was the first political assassination
in Hong Kong's history
Hong Kong was once a British colony..
a haven for political exiles
and revolutionaries
After the assassination of Yang darkness
loomed over Hong Kong
On October 1st, 1906
Sun Yat-sen, aka Sun Wen, left Tokyo
on a perilous journey to Hong Kong..
THE FORBIDDEN CITY
BEIJING
Your Majesty
The traitor Sun Wen left Japan
for Hong Kong yesterday
He must not leave Hong Kong alive then
Summon General Yan
China/ Hong Kong Border
ENTRY PERMIT
What is the purpose of your visit?
To visit ancestral graves
That policeman, he's the one
Tail this man
CHEN XIAO-BAI: FORMER HONGKONG
CHAIR OF THE UNITED LEAGUE OF CHINA
Young master was accepted at
a Western college!
The master is giving away
rice in celebration!
Line up only once!
Take only as much as you can carry
with one hand!
Come!
Jin Li Yuan Estate
Step right up!
Master, all the guests have arrived
Young master is also ready
You're going to a western college,
you should wear a western suit
Yes, father
Congratulation, Yu-tang!
Mr. Chen, you're late
Please follow me
What the hell..
The son is poised to take
over from his father
Chong-guang will be the first
Chinese Taipan in Hong Kong!
Yale University in America!
You're taking too much!
But you said "one hand"!
Thank you, brother!
Three, two, one!
Not bad.. but the queue
looks a bit odd with the suit
Where's my present?
Mr. Shi, allow me to introduce you to..
Burmese tycoon, Mr. Deng Youlin
Hong Kong's Chief of Police, Mr. Shi Mi-fu
Mr. Shi is the pride of
the Chinese community!
What is it?
Sun Wen is coming!
How much money do you need this time?
Do you know why he's coming?
Yu-tang
Dr. Sun is meeting with United League..
delegates from the thirteen provinces
He's going to unite the
various factions and..
launch a mass rebellion within
the next few years
It will take place..
across the country..
in Guangdong, Guangxi,
Fujian and Yunnan!
Yunnan's Lui Zhi-yi,
Guangdong's Xu Xue-qiu..
Shandong's Xu Jing-xin and..
Hubei's Liu Jing-an..
Delegates from all over are coming here..
to discuss the grand plan with Dr. Sun
Huang Xing and Sung
Jiao-ren are coming too!
We're on the verge of a great change
China will be shaken to its core
A new world is coming!
Yu-tang, just imagine
The Revolution begins right here
And you will be part of it!
How much?
Three thousand Hong Kong dollars
You ask for more each time..
I'll think of something
Offer them each 25 cents
and treat them to cakes
Yes, madam!
Ma..
Shush or I'll take you away and sell you!
What the hell!
Mama!
The time and day are confirmed
9 a.m. on the 15th
Dr. Sun will arrive at Star Ferry Pier
I need to know who's
leading the Qing assassins..
and how many men they have
Our comrades in GuangZhou
will do their best to find out
The Qing court will try to eliminate..
Dr. Sun at all costs
You and your men are our
only defense in Hong Kong
We've been waiting for this day!
After Cixi placed the Emporer
under house arrest..
at the end of the Hundred Days Reform
I led 300 brothers out
of Tientsin to escape..
persecution from the
conservative fraction
Only thirty of us survived
As long as Cixi remains in power..
we will fight to restore our honor!
General Fang, we're counting on you!
Brothers!
Our day of reckoning is here!
Four days from now, we'll
fight to the death!
Our time has come!
Yes, sir!
Father!
Go to bed
Do you remember why we came
to Hong Kong?
Why mother died? Why can't I go to school?
We've lived in 15 towns
over the course of 6 years
We've finally found a place to settle down!
Why do we need to run again?
One day we will return home to Tientsin
and never run again
I've heard the same lie too many times!
KOWLOON WALLED CITY:
LAST CHINESE ENCLAVE IN
BRITISH-RULED HONGKONG
I cried the day I received
the imperial decree!
My prayers were finally answered..
after years of disgrace and humiliation
Thank the heavens for giving me..
the chance to fight for my country
I'm a soldier, we're all soldiers!
Soldiers are meant to die in battle!
Brothers, drink up!
Death to the traitor!
Long live the empire!
4 DAYS BEFORE SUN'S ARRIVAL
Rise
Where did he go?
He went to Li Yu-tang's house..
then Gao Sheng Theatre
Thank you!
I hear you like to gamble?
Gambling is a passion!
Passion means getting what..
you want at all costs
I like people with a passion
If I get paid, I'll do anything
Brother, it's already dawn!
It's closing time!
One last round! Just deal!
I can do this..
Yes, yes.. l knew it!
You're going to lose this time!
Reveal!
I win!
We're closed now!
One last round!
Good morning, master
Good morning, father
Where is he?
He's taking his breakfast in his study
Can't he sit down to a proper meal?
You..
You're studying?
Yes, father
Tomorrow is your late mother's birthday
Your face..
A-si
You can read?
Young master taught me 53 words!
But now he's busy with his studies
You want to learn to read?
I do!
I'll ask Tang Jiu to find you a teacher
Thank you, master!
DA-YOU PHOTOGRAPHY
Master Liu!
Prepare an opium pipe for Master Liu!
Master, have you seen that woman before?
People say he squandered..
the family fortune..
all because of that woman
Nosy!
Brothers and sisters!
Fellow citizens of Hong Kong!
Not far to the north..
Our fellow countrymen are suffering..
under the corrupt and dying Qing Empire
My fellow countrymen,
the Chinese United League was founded
in Tokyo..
to overthrow the corrupt Qing regime..
and bring democracy to China
Support democracy! Support Dr. Sun!
Donate to the Chinese United League..
Chong-guang?
But master..
Support democracy!
Support Dr. Sun!
Support Dr. Sun! Support..
Come home with me!
I will not forsake my country!
Go home!
I will not be a coward!
We will not be cowards!
We will not forsake our country!
You're turning against me too?
Young master is a grown-up..
Move over!
Chen Xiao-bai!
Did you know that my son took part in..
the street riots?
Did you have anything to do with it?
What were you thinking
when you gave him these books?
He's my son, my only son!
I was forty before I finally had a son!
I gave him these two
These were gifts for you
I set ground rules when we first met
I provide the money but
I don't get involved.
I don't care how you waste my money!
But how could you get my son involved?
Do you know what Police Chief Shi
told me?
The Qing court sent assassins!
They have guns!
Did you bother to warn me?
I'm a businessman!
My son will be a businessman!
No, You're a rebel!
The day you donated your first cent
to the cause..
you became a rebel!
You hired me to be
Chong-guang's teacher!
You willingly gave money to the cause!
No one forced you!
Now you say what's right for you..
isn't right for your son?
I don't care
I'm saying this for the last time
I'm an old man.
I don't care if I'm labeled a rebel!
But my son a rebel?! I will not allow!
3 DAYS BEFORE SUN'S ARRIVAL
I waited all night for you!
Did you do what we asked?
I promise there will be no police
at the theatre tonight
Mr. Chen, a telegraph!
General!
We have news!
Yan Xiaoguo is leading the assassins.
He's now hiding out at the Walled City!
It's too late!
Protect Mr. Chen!
Hurry! Go!
I told you to step back!..
I'm a member of this opera troupe!
Step back!
I need to find my father!
My name is Fang Hong!
Father!
One day we will return home toTientsin..
and never run again
I've heard the same lie too many times!
Revive China, Sun Wen
We can't find Mr. Chen
Yu-tang, my brother
We've been best friends..
since we met eight years ago
I'm deeply sorry..
for upsetting you today
But Dr. Sun's visit to
Hong Kong is extremely important
The Qing court will send assassins
I may be in danger so I
must ask one last favor
If anything happens to me..
you must see the mission through!
The hope of China rests with Dr. Sun
The future of China depends on Dr. Sun
In China, there is only one Dr. Sun
I bid you farewell
I will fight to the end
Get up! Get up!
All of you! Outside!
The Chief of Police has
ordered China Daily..
to be shut down immediately..
for publishing propaganda..
inciting civil unrest
and disturbing the peace!
Proceed!
You have no right!
We'll fight back!
Master Li..
Stop fighting!
Stop!
What's going on?
As your friend, I already warned you..
I told you not to meddle!
You beat up my staff and
destroyed the press
How can call yourself my friend?
The Qing court is determined
to eliminate Sun at all costs
My British superiors ordered
us not to interfere!
You're playing with fire.
Have you forgottened that
you're just a businessman?
Have you forgotten that..
you're also Chinese?
Well said!
Very brave of you..
China Daily published propaganda..
and incited student protests
We are under British rule!
Shut down the newspaper immediately!
More than thirty people were killed..
at the Gao Sheng theatre last night
And Chen Xiaobai is still missing!
How could you let this happen?
What has the Chief of Police been doing?
Well said!
I warned you
Officers, shut it down!
I dare you!
Arrest anyone who resists!
Attention!
We will put out the news
of Dr. Sun's arrival..
even if we must do it by hand!
Who's that old man?
That's my father!
Master Li
Resistance Leader Dr. Sun Wen
Due to Arrive in Hong Kong October 15th
Hong Kong Government intervenes
We've reached a turning point
If the revolution is to succeed..
we cannot fight divided!
We need a plan
that will bring us together
Dr. Sun is coming to..
unite the different factions..
of the resistance..
and launch a rebellion
within the next 3 years!
The very foundations of
China will be shaken!
We're on the verge of great change!
A new world is coming!
The great revolution..
starts here!
And we're all part of it!
Please trust me
I, Li Yu-Tang, promise to..
..lead you through this!
We can still safeguard Dr. Sun!
2 DAYS BEFORE SUN'S ARRIVAL
It's your family heirloom
So, what do you want in return?
I need you to protect someone
the day after tomorrow
Alright..
Give the most dangerous task to me
Master Liu, don't you want to know
who you're protecting?
Master Li
What's wrong with
falling in love with a woman?
You had your pick of women
Why did you have to fall
for your father's woman?
Stinky tofu!
You have superb fighting skills!
I know you.
You're the hero, Li Yu-tang!
You put on a good show today!
Oh?
Come..
You told off that man..
who works for the British!
I hate cowards who bully the weak!
You stand up for the truth
I.. admire that!
Hero Li, call me if you
need me in the future!
My size helps even if..
I just stand by your side!
How about the day after tomorrow?
Who are we fighting? The British?
The bad guys!
Great!
Take care of the child..
Why did you sneak into my house
the other day?
We went our separate ways long ago!
Don't bother me or my family
ever again!
Stay out of my life!
Are you done?
Master, count me in
I grew up on the streets
I have my shares of wounds,
I'm not afraid of anything!
But A-si, the mission
is extremely dangerous
I just want the master to be safe
Alright then
Master..
I must ask a favor?
I'm in love with the
daughter of the photographer
When this is all over..
Will you help me propose?
Yes..
Of course!
Long live Boss! Long live Boss!
A-si!
Turn around!
Where to?
To see the photographer
Got it!
Sir, may I help you?
I'm here to discuss
a marriage proposal
Come, A-si!
A-si has been with us at Jin Li Yuan
for over 10 years
He's thoughtful, honest and caring
Please accept this money
More will come later
Please don't joke with me
I promise you..
Once your daughter joins our family
at Jin Li Yuan..
I will treat her like my own
Let's discuss this inside
My daughter would be honored..
to be part of Master Li's household
A-chun, bring some tea for Master Li!
Master Li..
Let's discuss the wedding arrangements
and the dowry
Where shall we hold
the wedding banquet?
When shall we set the wedding day?
Master Li, what do you think?
Master Li?
Let's take a family portrait together
Yes, of course!
Three.. two.. one!
Master
Father
Where is he?
Stop playing..
Son, it's not safe outside
Promise to stay home for
the next few days..
please?
Let's eat!
Professor, not eating, drinking
or talking is bad for your health
As your former student, I'm concerned
I've brought the Professor..
his favorite wine: Shanxi's Fan Jiu!
Is this is my last meal?
Of course not!
You're my mentor!
I've been taught to respect my mentors
You're like a father to me
If you still consider me
your mentor, set me free!
So that you can thwart my plans?
Yan Xiaoguo
Do you remember the advice..
I gave you at your graduation?
Talented
But foolish
Will probably never achieve greatness!
Professor, you've misjudged me
Do you think that I blindly..
serve the imperial court?
It's not true
I have a question, Professor
Other than war and suffering..
disgrace and humiliation..
What have the foreigners..
brought us?
The belief that we are all born equal!
In China some can be born emperors..
and into privilege..
while others are born into slavery!
The Emperor has the "mandate of heaven"!
That needs to change!
We need to establish a
democratic republic!
Xiaoguo, you received a western education
How could you remain blind to
the world outside?
The world is much bigger
than you imagine!
My western education taught me to see..
how evil and greedy..
the foreigners really are!
Do you think you can save China..
with meetings and protests?
Professor
You're just a teacher,
you'll never achieve greatness
You still can't stomach the
sight of blood, can you?
You're all the same, useless and weak!
If your revolution
succeeds, China is doomed!
I won't kill you,
but I don't ever want to see you again!
I need 100 silver coins to bury
my father and his men
Bring her the money!
Yes, sir!
I'm hungry
More rice
Yes!
I want to see your friend
My father died because of him
He disappeared at the same time
your father was killed
He went to ask your father for help
I will take my father's place
At 9 a.m. tomorrow, Dr. Sun
will arrive on shore
There will be a crowd of a thousand..
at the Star Ferry Pier
The assassins can easily blend into
the crowd of coolies, merchants..
foreigners and civilians
We must be on the alert!
The large police presence at the pier..
will be our best defense
The assassins won't dare
make a move there
Master!
They're my brothers, they all run fast!
We need someone to keep watch..
from the roof and signal us
I'll do it
Dr. Sun will make three stops tomorrow:
Yashuhito Society,
Mrs. Sun's residence and the China Daily
We need to be extra vigilant
at these locations!
Understood!
From Queen's Road
to Yashuhito Society..
Fang Hong will lead the procession..
Wang Fu-ming will bring up the rear
Remember, do not break formation!
Tan Jiu warned me yesterday that..
3 vacant properties along Queen's Road
were leased on the same day
We don't know who rented them
We must get through the
these areas quickly
Do not stop!
Reporting for duty, sir!
At your service, sir!
1 DAY BEFORE SUN'S ΑRRIVΑL
Thank you all
It's for you!
After tomorrow, I will marry you, A-si
A-si, do you know who
you're protecting tomorrow?
I just want the master to be happy
This book was written by him..
it's young master's favorite!
Read it to me, please
Alright
I gave up medicine in order to help
overthrow the Qing Empire..
and free my fellow countrymen
When I left Hong Kong..
I endured great hardship on the road
My mother was worried
She said: the revolution
will save lives..
but practicing
medicine also saves lives
Why choose the harder path?
I said: mother, there's much
you don't understand
Practicing medicine can save a few lives
But the revolution can save millions
After 260 years of foreign rule..
and 2000 years of autocratic rulers..
China is in decline
The Manchurian regime
is corrupt and oppressive
it will only bring..
further suffering
The tide of revolution is rising.
The will of the people shall prevail
We need to gather our courage..
to overthrow the Qing Dynasty..
and establish a true democratic nation!
The road to revolution
is paved with blood
My life is destined to end in time
But the republic will herald
a new era..
of lasting peace and prosperity
We must continue to struggle..
and overcome obstacles..
in order to end the
suffering of millions
and allow the exiled millions
to return to their homeland
After I was kicked out of Shaolin..
I headed south and ended up in Putian
I kept going south until
I reached Hong Kong
If I went any further..
I would have fallen into the sea!
Try the tofu
Stinky tofu! Stinky tofu!
These are for you!
Do you have one that's green?
Stinky tofu! It's for you!
Thank you!
You're a Shaolin monk?
Grab a chair..
Will you show us your kung-fu tomorrow?
I've never actually been
in a real fight before
I'm not sure if my kung-fu works
But after tomorrow's mission..
I will proudly return to Shaolin!
You can't leave!
I'm getting married soon!
Really?
You must come to my wedding! I will!
Miss Fang, you're invited too!
After tomorrow,
I'm taking my father's ashes home
We will never leave home again
Dinner's ready!
It smells good!
Let's eat!
Master
Chief inspector Shi sent this over
Master Liu..
I haven't been called
Master Liu in a long time
My father told me on his deathbed:
The most important thing in life is..
Integrity
But tomorrοw..
I'll fail! I will be a liar!
Do you know what
is the most painful thing in life?
To watch the one you love die..
To fall in love with the wrong woman..
I drove my father to his death..
She killed herself in front of me..
I'm tortured by that knowledge
each day..
I'm like a ghost
Nothing could be more painful
All for a woman, was it worth it?
Tomorrow, will it be worth it?
Thank you, Master Li..
Tomorrow, Liu Yubai will be set free!
What..
What're you doing here?
I need your help
What can I possibly do for Mrs. Li?
You must help me!
Alright! I'll help you
for old time's sake!
But you have to pay
I need you to protect someone tomorrow
I'll pay any price to keep him safe!
I'll do anything for money! Who is it?
Li Yu-tang!
What?
You want me to protect your new man?
Shen Chong-yang!
Get out of my house!
Can't you do something worthwhile..
for once in your life?
Get out! You must help him!
Get out!
He's raising you daughter!
You know that?
I was with you for 8 years
and you gambled the entire time
But I stuck with you!
I never asked for anything!
I stayed and accepted my fate..
because I loved you
But when I became pregnant..
I didn't want my child
to suffer the same fate
I needed a man who could be a good father
a man who could raise a child
Come over here!
Look, your daughter is down there
When she grows up..
What do you want me to tell her
about her real father?
If you come tomorrow
When she grows up, I'll tell her that
her father's name is Shen Chong-yang!
Stop
Go
Loser! Where's the gun?
You were told to steal a gun
from the police station!
Look! It's money!
Take it all!
Loser..
Master, you're back
Master..
Mr. Chen?
There's a change of plans for tomorrow
We need a decoy to ensure..
the safety of Dr. Sun
You want to use our people as bait?
We're dealing with an invisible army!
It's the only way to keep Dr. Sun safe!
No, that's out of the question!
Dr. Sun hasn't been home in ages!
But he's sacrificing his one chance..
to see his ailing mother!
Revolution is not just
about spending money..
printing newspapers
and distributing pamphlets
Li Yu-tang!
Revolution is about blood..
and sacrifice!
Since joining the cause..
I've faced death many times!
I can still die at any moment!
Revolution is about
sacrificing our generation..
for your son's generations!
Enough!
I'm just a businessman
We're drawing straws..
to determine who
will pose as Dr. Sun..
on the last leg of the journey tomorrow
We must stall for one hour..
no matter what!
We need to give..
Dr. Sun time..
to meet and organize with..
the thirteen delegates
The fate of 400 million countrymen..
will be decided in that one hour
Who drew the short straw?
Who?
No! It can't be!
You shouldn't even be here!
Draw again!
Why? Because I'm the son of Li Yu-tang?
You don't understand!
I promised your father that
you wouldn't get involved!
Uncle Chen, this is a
historical turning point
The entire nation is involved!
How can I be the exception?
But you're his only son!
Only son?
Isn't this exactly
the type of feudal thinking that..
the revolution hopes to change?
Aren't we striving to
establish an equal society?
I can't sacrifice my life, but they can?
You want them to draw straws again..
because I'm the son of Li Yu-tang
How can you justify it to them?
Chong-guang
I..
I just can't let this happen..
General, we've got the gun!
Are you clear about the mission?
Yes, sir!
Thank you!
Tomorrow we'll use this
foreigner's invention..
to kill that traitor Sun
Xiao-bai, thank you!
Don't stop!
Run!
Use the covered walkway!
Grab the sacks of rice!
Tell A-si to get the rickshaw!
A-si has left; he said master
wasn't going out today!
Who fiddled with my watch?
Charge straight ahead! Go!
Go!
Hurry!
Stinky tofu!
Go!
My name is Wang Fu-ming!
Wang Fu-ming, born in ZhengZhou,
Henan, 1878; deceased 1906
A-si!
Young master? Go away!
Come here.. You shouldn't be here!
Come here!
I won't let you do this..
What are you saying?
You can't do this
Do you know how important this day is?
Do you know how much preparation
it took and..
how many lives were sacrificed?!
I don't care
A-si
The future of our country..
is at stake!
I don't care! I can't let
young master do this!
It's now 9:59
We'll depart at 10:00
And then Dr. Sun can leave safely
Young master..
It's now 9:59 and 30 seconds
A-si, will you stay with
me for the final hour?
15 seconds to go..
It seems I've waited seventeen years..
for this hour!
Young master, don't do this, I beg you..
55, 56, 57..
58, 59!
Asi, let's go!
Go!
Young master..
A-si, you told me once that..
Each night when you close
your eyes in bed..
you see A-chun
When I close my eyes..
I see China's future!
They're coming!
Stay away!
Father, forgive me!
Yu-tang!
Fang Hong, born in Jinghai,
Tientsin, 1890; deceased 1906.
You, out in front, don't move!
Step out of the carriages! Αll of you!
Stay put!
We were only passing through..
Don't move!
Were you involved?
But it has nothing to do with us!
We were heading that way..
Nobody moves!
You two may go!
But this is a serious matter!
We can leave yet
You're relieved of duty!
We should wait for orders..
Where did you find this man?
He's sabotaging our mission!
Get him!
You idiot!
Are you trying to start a rebellion here?
This is Hong Kong
A colony of the Great British Empire!
Round them up!
Li Yu-tang
You practically own Hong Kong
But you've never had a police escort..
have you?
Here's your chance
Move!
Li Yu-tang
Let's go!
Yu-tang
In 5 minutes, there will be no police
in the streets of Hong Kong
Our superiors have ordered
all of us to retreat
He said that China's affairs
are to be resolved by the Chinese
I'll take you as far as I can
on the last part of your journey!
Go!
The beggar! The beggar's here!
Run!
Get up there! Hurry!
We'll go upstair to meet with Mrs. Sun!
We must stall for another 15 minutes!
How old are you?
Seventeen
How are your parents?
My mother is dead
My father is nearly sixty
I must thank you on behalf of my son
I must also thank your father
Farewell!
Use the tunnel!
Liu Yu-bai, born in Yangzhou,
Jiangsu, 1871 ; deceased 1906
Get in!
Chong-guang!
Go!
Take this to Nianci..
Go.. just go..
Go!
Shen Chong-yang, place and date of
birth unknown; deceased 1906
Our main targets are Guangdong,
Guangxi and Yunnan
We'll start rebellions in ChaoZhou
and HuiZhou at the same time
Meanwhile, Guangdong and Guangxi..
will join in to thin
out their forces..
Go back!
Bao-shi, take my place!
Chong-guang..
Go!
Sit tight!
Let go!
You asked for it!
Deng Si-di, born in Xiangshan,
Guangdong, 1884; deceased 1906
Ten years ago..
Qu-yun and I discussed "the revolution"
I said:
revolution will bring prosperity to
400 million countrymen and put an end..
to hunger and poverty
Ten years have passed
I saw many comrades sacrifice their lives
My exile ended; here I am again
"Revolution" no longer has
the same meaning for me
Today if you asked me,
"What is revolution?"
I would say:
A nation cannot progress
without sacrifice
The road to modernization
is paved with blood
And that blood..
is called revolution
Sun is indebted
By imperial decree,
execute Sun the traitor!
Yan Xiaoguo..
Don't do it!
It's all over!
Sun Wen is gone!
Death to the traitor!
Long live the empire!
Sun Wen has already left!
Death to the traitor!
Long live the empire!
Chong-guang! Run!
No!
Chong-guang!
He's not Sun Wen!
Yan Xiaoguo! He's not Sun Wen!
No!
Chong-guang!
Yan Xiaguo!
Your student has fulfilled his duty
to his country!
I told you..
stay home for a few days
Why didn't you listen..
Li Chong-guang, born in Taiyuan,
Shanxi, 1889; deceased 1906
May, 1907 - Huanggang Uprising
May, 1907 - HuiZhou Uprising
September, 1907 - Fancheng Uprising
December, 1907 - Friendship Gate Uprising
March, 1908 - QinZhou Uprising
April, 1908 - Yunan Uprising
February, 1910 - GuangZhou Uprising
April, 1911 - Huanghuagang Uprising
On October 10th, 1907
The Wuchang Uprising ended with
the success of the "Xinhai Revolution"..
that finally toppled the Qing Dynasty