- Hey, you. Keep moving.
- Which way, officer?
- I should worry which way, keep moving.
- But which way?
You figure that out for
yourself, just keep moving.
"Just keep moving." Hospitality
at the end of a nightstick.
In or out, come or go. Who cares? Nobody.
There's no welcome sign out in New York.
You get off a freight train and the railroad
bulls slap you around just for the exercise.
Every day, the big parade
comes in, shaking their fists...
...but nobody gives them a welcome.
All you get is a stop signal at every corner.
Hey, daffy, didn't I just
tell you to keep moving?
Officer, I'm city-struck.
This is my breakfast,
talking up to the big town.
Look at it. Seven million people,
fighting, biting, clawing away...
...to get one foot on a ladder
that'll take them to a penthouse.
Yes, siree. They come by the
thousands, every which way.
By water, by wheel, by foot,
by ferry, by tunnel, by tube.
Over, across and under the river.
They come like locusts,
from all over the nation.
From every nation on the
globe. Seven million people.
New York is like a snake.
Strike the head in Queens and
the tail waves in Staten Island.
Rattle a milk can in the Bronx and
a corpse turns over in Brooklyn.
Seven million people, divided
by a river and joined by bridges.
Go from the subway to the
sky in 10 seconds flat.
Make a million. Make a
penny. That's New York.
And I know this town, brother.
Because I got clothes on my back.
But before I turn you
in, you better get moving.
I heard you, officer,
and I wanna keep moving.
- I still can't figure out which way.
- You better figure out which way...
...or I'll give you a
taste of this. Now, go on.
You coming with me?
Hey. Just a minute, young fella.
- I didn't do nothing.
- Well, we'll discuss that later.
- What's your name?
- Googi, Googi Sabatini.
Well, Googi, you mustn't steal bread.
You can steal boats, you can snitch
nickels or shake down trousers...
...but you mustn't steal bread.
But I'm hungry.
Who isn't in this town?
Come on, give it to me.
Hand it over. Come on, come on. Hurry up.
And remember, Googi, if you must steal
bread in New York, don't get caught.
Only one cent, two cent, three cent.
What a town. Right out of
the asphalt flower's grove.
That's Peggy, Danny's girl.
- And who's Danny?
- That's me.
Attaboy, Danny.
Use your right, Danny! Hit him in the discus!
- Don't get so excited, son. He'll win.
- You're doggone right, he'll win.
- Attaboy, Danny!
- Scram!
The winner.
Danny, I now dub you
knight of the Round Table.
King Arthur was no braver
in defense of his fair lady.
Sure, I'm taking Peggy's part and
I always will because she's my girl.
- Peggy couldn't have a better protector.
- You said it.
- You hurting much, Peggy?
- No, it's nothing. Thanks, Danny.
- You know what, Peggy?
- Yes, Danny?
- You dance good.
- You fight good.
Come on, Danny, let's
finish this game. Hurry up.
Eddie, your brother wants you to come
on over. We're gonna play Kick the Can.
- Tell Danny I can't. I gotta practice.
- You give me a pain.
Every time we need you,
why, you gotta practice.
Well, I can't give it
up. I'm teaching myself.
You know, someday I'm gonna get a piano.
Heck, a piano!
Yes, siree, brother. The air
of New York smells of ambition.
Blessed is he who goes after what he wants.
Every man climbs over the backs of
the others, swinging his spiked club.
Fighting, dancing, playing away.
Up from the gutters, into the sun.
And yet, if you look close,
there's love in the city.
And there's hope in the city too.
The pavements may be hard
and the tenements high...
...but that won't stop these children.
Googi may steal his way through life.
Peggy, well, you've seen her dance. Her
nimble feet will carry her to the heights.
And Danny will fight his way
through with his bare fists.
- Lay off those peanuts.
- They're good for your nerves.
- They're bad for the figure.
- I never worried about me figure. Want one?
Get through with that bag,
Danny. Callahan's here.
- That Kid Callahan?
- Yeah. Up from the West Side.
Just knocked out Tony Mazzini. Remember Tony?
- When he busted his thumb on your head?
- Tony was tough. This guy must be good.
Yeah. You could be good
too, only you don't wanna.
Hey, look out there, will you?
- Hi, Kid. You sure gave Tony the flatiron.
- He was a pushover. He ain't seen nothing.
- Hey, Kid, when's your next settle?
- Don't ask me.
- Just sit tight, boys. Leave it to Goldie.
- Hurry up. Get through with the bag.
- I'll be through when you're dressed.
- You'll be through when I'm dressed?
You're through right now. Scram.
You big lug. You think you own the joint?
Danny could knock your
block off with one hand.
- Beat it, dope, beat it.
- Keep your mitts off him.
A wise, guy, huh?
- What's the big idea, you jerk?
- He started it. He slapped him with the bag.
Let me at that guy. Let
me at him. Let me at him.
Break it up. This ain't the
ring. What's eating you guys?
Listen, jerk. The next time I see
you, you're gonna wish you hadn't.
Save it for the ring, Kid.
Look, Goldie, cool off that
buzz saw of yours, will you?
Say, Kenny, stick around.
I wanna talk to you.
Don't worry, Pinky. We'll be there.
Listen, Samson. It's a chance in a million.
A main prelim, and you ain't taking...
Skip it, Pinky. You're wasting your time.
I come down here for a little exercise
and you try to pull me into a fight.
Danny, 100 bucks. A hundred.
And I can handle your corner.
Better handle that truck back to the garage.
- Look, Danny...
- Stop hopping me up, you ringworm.
Danny, you can knock most of
these guys around here cold.
- Why would I do that?
- A hundred bucks, Danny.
Lemonade, chocolate! Five cents! Five cents!
Get out of here. Get out of
here. Get out of here. Five cents!
Going into the third round, Primo
Carnera, world's heavyweight champion...
... and challenger Maxie Baer.
California jabs with his left. One, two.
Now a right hook. Carnera
staggers. He's going down.
- Looks like it's in the bag for Maxie.
- That's the cold packs for that big baloney.
His share of the gate tonight is
estimated at a minimum of $ 100,000 cash.
You hear that, Danny, $
100,000. That's for one fight.
What are you crying about now?
I won't be a truck driver's assistant forever.
I got ambitions. I'm gonna be somebody.
Baer stabs two to the jaw,
a hard right to the heart.
Carnera tries to hold on,
a desperately groggy champ.
I got four bits bet and I'm gonna collect.
He's my boy. I don't care
what you think of him.
He's all right, and I still have
3-1 to bet on Jess Willard to win.
Hey, Danny, there's Peggy.
- Hello, Peg.
- Hello, Danny.
I'll walk you over, huh?
- Don't you want to listen?
- I heard enough.
- Where you been, dancing again?
- Learned a lot of new steps today.
You'll wear yourself out if
you keep dancing without supper.
- I'd much rather dance than eat any day.
- I know that.
Boy, was it crowded tonight on the subway.
Talk about sardines. They got it easy.
At least they're floating in olive oil.
Look, Peggy, I'm making 27.50 a week now.
This time next year, we could be all set...
Always whispering, you two.
Carrying on. Sneaking in the hallway.
I won't stand for it, Danny Kenny.
We're a respectable family, we are.
If you wanna marry my Peggy,
you come into the parlor.
- Who's talking about marrying, Ma?
- Don't give me that sass.
My daughter talking to me
like that after all I've done.
Mrs. Nash, we're just sitting
here talking like always.
Talking. Whispering behind my back.
Afraid I'll hear you in the parlor.
There is no parlor. Just a kitchen and
a bedroom, if you wanna call them that.
What's the use? See you later, Danny.
Come on in, Ma, and please stop worrying.
I swore my daughter would
never go through what I did.
Skimping and saving, penny by penny, and
losing it all and starving ever since.
All right, Sydney, that'll be all. Practice
those scales an hour a day at least.
Here's a dollar. Mama said you
should give me change. Fifty cents.
What about the two dollars from last month?
- Mama said it should be just on account.
- Say, Danny, got any change?
- How much you need?
- Half a buck.
There it is.
- Give this to Mama with my compliments.
- Okay.
Oh, yeah. And Mama says when you
gonna give me a piece to learn?
She says to tell you she
likes "The Blue Danube."
So do I. That's why you're
not gonna play it yet, Sydney.
Okay.
I don't know why I keep giving that kid
lessons. He throws the piano out of tune.
You get it from Sydney. I
get it from the traffic cops.
- How's your music
coming, Eddie? - So-so.
Look, Danny.
I wanted to ask you if there's a
chance of getting a job with your boss.
- For who?
- Me.
- You?
- Yeah.
- Driving a truck?
- Or a helper, till I got a license.
Are you nuts? Another year,
you'll be through music school.
- I'm through right now.
- What?
- What about your scholarship?
- Yeah, they cut it in half.
- Gotta pay the rest in cash.
- What happened?
Like everything else, donations
slowing up, so they cut expenses.
It's no use, Danny. I've got
to start making my own way.
But when will you find time
to work on your own music?
- I'll find it sometime at night.
- You'll be all worn out.
Besides, you might even hurt your hands
shoving those cases around on the truck.
- How much you gonna need for that school?
- Hundred and fifty bucks.
- And it might just as well be 150,000.
- Look here, Eddie.
I don't wanna hear any more talk like that.
- You're gonna finish up.
- Well, I wanna finish, Danny...
...and I wanna finish my own music too.
You know I've been
working on it every minute.
Here, look. I've even
got a new idea on it now.
To make it into a symphony of New York.
The song of the magic
isle, a city for conquest.
A full symphony of it, with all
its proud, passionate beauty...
...and all of its sordid ugliness
and of its great wealth and power...
...and its everlasting hunger.
And of its teeming seven millions
and its barren loneliness.
Here, listen, Danny. It starts
with that part that you like.
That part that I call "The East River"...
...with the rumbling el over Allen
Street with its crowded gutters and slums.
With all of its mounting, shrieking jungle
- cries for life and sun.
And then carrying on the theme
up to the towering skyscrapers...
...and the story of all those who
tried to scale their dizzy heights...
...but crash, frustrated and
broken, to the concrete pavements.
And then of those few who
finally reach the top...
...only to find out that above them
are still the unattainable stars.
Gee, Eddie, you have ideas like that
and you're talking about driving a truck?
Play me that first part
again. The part I like.
Sure.
- Maxie knocked him out in the 11 th.
- Quiet.
- What's the matter?
- Tell Pinky that fight with Callahan is okay.
- No kidding, Danny?
- Have you got no ear for music?
- Sure, I can hear it.
- All right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
next bout of the evening.
At 146 pounds, the West
Side Terror, Kid Callahan.
And in this corner, at
144 and a half pounds...
...the former Golden Gloves
winner, Danny Kenny...
...entering the professional
ring as "Young Samson."
Take a bow, Danny.
- Where'd you get that moniker, Samson?
- The Bible. Wanna make something of it?
Hey, Danny, it's a cinch!
- Looks like a West Side turnout.
- Yeah.
Keep your left in his schnozzola.
When you see an opening, give
him the old one-two. Good luck.
Folks, I just wanna say that
these boys better be good...
...as we're honored to have with us tonight
no less than manager Scotty MacPherson...
...down from Madison
Bowl. Take a bow, Scotty.
Who's the new lad, Pinky?
From the East Side. Won the
Golden Gloves five years back.
First fight since. Nothing much, Scotty.
Tell you what I'll do, Scotty, I'll
lay you 20-10 that Callahan wins.
I'll tell you what, Bill. Make it a
real bet and I'll lay 2-1 on Samson.
- For how much?
- I'll bet 200 to 100.
- You've got a bet.
- Let me in on that.
- Okay. Same bet with you.
- Goldie. Goldie.
Ain't you even gonna back up your own
champ? Scotty's laying 2-1 on Samson.
It's a pleasure to oblige. Scotty,
I'll take 100 of that easy jack.
You're on. Anybody else?
If you're gonna be that generous, I'll
double it. And I don't mind telling you...
Hey, what's going on? What's happened?
Two, three...
...four, five, six...
- What's happened?...seven, eight, nine...
...ten.
- You got me into this. I lose a fortune.
- Accident.
Holy smoke. A welterweight
with a sock like Dempsey.
- Who's his manager, Scotty?
- I don't know, but I'll find out.
Listen. I don't usually go after a lad,
but I'd a hunch on you the minute I saw you.
I believe I can manage you
right up to the top rung.
That's very good to hear, but
I guess I just can't see it.
You'd sooner stick to
that truck-driving job?
- Sure. I like it.
- You're very hard to figure out.
You've got the makings of a
fighter but you don't like to fight.
I guess that's just it. I don't like
it. I don't know how to explain it...
...but I need a good reason to sock a guy.
A reason? I'll give you a good reason.
I'll guarantee you $500 on
your next card. How's that?
Skip it, Pinky. It's no go.
I've seen pugs who figured they
had it licked. Where are they?
Walking around on their heels,
punchy, all before their time.
Here. See that guy back there? Remember him?
Yes, I believe I do. Mickey Miller, isn't it?
- Nobody else. Great fighter, wasn't he?
- He certainly was.
- Mickey, come here.
- Me?
Yeah, you. Come here.
- You got that picture with you?
- Picture? Sure, sure.
Sure, I've got my picture.
That's me. That's my picture.
- Remember? Mickey Miller, that's me.
- Very nice, very nice.
- Thanks very much.
- That's all right. A good picture, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- I can get in shape again. I can fight.
There you are. Mickey
Miller, before and after.
You were right. One chance in a million.
One guy makes the grade. The
rest fall like flies in winter.
A million to one odds? That's pretty heavy.
I think I'll stick to driving a
truck. How about some soap, Mutt?
Listen. Let me know when
you change your mind.
- My office hours are noon till midnight.
- Thanks very much.
Don't be mad if I don't
show up. How about that soap?
- Good music, huh?
- It's beautiful.
I've always wanted to come
here. You like it, don't you?
- Sure.
- Danny, why don't you dance faster?
- You won't have to do any road work.
- How we doing?
She's doing all right, but
you're better in the ring.
Danny. I ought to congratulate
you on the fight. I forgot.
- The fight? Sure, the fight.
- It must have been thrilling.
All the lights and thousands of people.
I was so excited, I could hardly talk.
Yeah, I couldn't hear you.
Murray, I'm awfully sorry
about the contest last week...
...but I just couldn't get
out of bed, I was so sick.
I didn't mean to hurt
your feelings, you know.
- You know I wouldn't let you down.
- Let's dance, Lilly.
Gee, I'd love to. Thanks.
Murray, if you'll let me dance
the contest with you tonight...
...you won't be sorry, I promise.
Just give me this one last
chance. Won't you, Murray?
- All right, break it up.
- It's all right. She's my girl. We're together.
Don't be so much together.
Oh, how's this?
- Happy?
- Oh, yes. Of course.
Better watch your step, big shot.
That boy with her is Young Samson.
Who's the dame? You know her?
I met them one night at
the dance at the Forsyth.
Say, the kid's got something.
I think I'll try her out.
- It's hot.
- Sit down, have a gin freezola and cool off.
Peggy, your dancing was awful swell.
She beat everybody else in the hall.
Hello, Peggy. I saw you dancing by.
I'd like to introduce Mr. Murray
Burns. Peggy Nash and Danny Kenny.
- I'm pleased to meet you, Mr. Burns.
- Likewise.
I guess you boys have heard about each other.
- Murray's the best this side of 14th St.
- The other side too.
Yes, I know. I've heard a
lot about you, Mr. Burns.
Thanks. Say, how about this dance? I
guess you could follow me all right, huh?
- Do you mind, Danny?
- No, go ahead. Enjoy yourself.
Don't worry. I'll see she does.
Thanks, Danny. Just this dance.
If you fellas don't mind,
I'll sit this dance out.
Sure. Sit down. That's a chair.
I certainly can use it. Murray
just about danced my feet off.
Here. Knock yourself out.
I don't mind saying, kid, you're
a natural. You sure can spiel.
Believe me, I've tripped the
light fantastic with the best.
Thank you, Mr. Burns. I'm nervous now.
- I've never before had a partner like you.
- Sure, but that's okay.
You'll get over that nervous feeling.
That's the idea. You'll
follow me like a ghost, kid.
And now, folks, for the
regular Rose Garden contest.
To the winners, this beautiful silver loving
- cup.
The judges will conduct eliminations
from the bandstand. Please come up.
Will all the palookas and clucks...
...kindly save their shoe leather and our
time by sitting this one out? Let's go.
How about it? Wanna try? We'll
show them some real stepping.
That'd be wonderful, but
I ought to ask Danny first.
What's that mug got, a mortgage on you?
Just relax, kid, and that cup's in the bag.
- Thanks.
- Looks like that snake's got a monopoly.
- You gonna let him get away with it?
- She's having a good time.
- I don't worry about Peggy.
- You ain't never worry.
Like with MacPherson. You could
be champion, only you don't wanna.
- Just to show me.
- I got nothing else to do.
Listen, we're gonna cop this cup, now, see?
We'll shake these clucks
off on the next number.
- We're dancing alone.
- We've won?
Sure, what'd I tell you? Now
we'll give them some fancy stuff.
- Who's the dame?
- I don't know.
- Some newcomer.
- Not bad.
You got the class, kid.
You got what it takes.
- Do you mean it, Mr. Burns?
- Sure.
And I'm the guy that
knows how to bring it out.
Gee, Danny, ain't she great?
I'm certainly proud of her.
I guess I'd better be going.
Murray doesn't like me to sit
out dances with strange men.
- Scram then.
- Danny, look.
- You were great.
- Isn't it beautiful?
Are you sure you want me to keep this?
I got a flock of them, one every other night.
Last weekend in a tournament
at Hunts Point Casino.
- I danced that one with Murray.
- Yeah? I thought he danced it alone.
I don't believe I can eat
any of this. I'm too excited.
Danny, Mr. Burns told me that
I could be a professional.
No reason why not.
With a little training, I might be able to
break her in, after I polish the rough spots.
She didn't do so bad just now.
Wouldn't you like to join the table?
Well, it ain't exactly
my kind of crowd, baby.
Yeah? Too much of a crowd, see?
Mutt. Don't let him talk
to Mr. Burns like that.
Don't worry, I was going anyway.
Any time you want to drop these mugs,
slip over. I'll give you another spiel.
I don't mind you dancing with my
girl. I don't like those cracks.
- Your girl? You let me dance with her?
- Yeah.
That's right. You wanna
make something out of it?
What's going on here? Are you
having some trouble, Murray?
- I stepped on some personal property here...
- You stepped on something.
Danny, stop!
- Hey, cut it out.
- Yeah, this place respectable joint.
- Beat it, Danny. Beat it.
- Come on, Peggy. Let's get out of here.
Stand back, everybody. That was an accident.
Stand back, now. Come on, Peggy. Get out.
It was an accident, everybody. An accident.
I hope you ain't sore.
I didn't mind you dancing, but he
tried to make you look like two cents.
I guess he was pretty fresh.
But, Danny, the cup, it's all broken.
- Mutt figured it was your cup or my bean.
- I had a swell time anyway.
- You ain't sore at me, huh?
- Of course not, Danny.
That's better. I'll see you tomorrow.
Hello. Hotel Halifax?
Mr. Murray Burns, please.
Hello, Mr. Burns? Peggy Nash.
No, no, I didn't lose your
number. I kept it in my purse.
I just wanted to tell you
I'm sorry for what happened.
I hope you weren't hurt.
Tomorrow night? Why, yes, I think I could.
The Irving Place Casino, 10:30. All right.
For crying out loud, Danny, take it easy.
- Kenny, you're 20 minutes late.
- So what?
- You're holding up the works.
- Sue me.
- Okay, Kenny. I'll talk to you later.
- We'll make it up next trip.
You know us. I don't know, Danny.
I don't know what's the matter
with you lately. You're so nervous.
If I sound nervous, I'm nervous.
All right. Peggy stands you
up and I get the grief of it.
What do you take it for? I wouldn't
take it from the Queen of Sheba.
You'd take it and like it.
Hey, fellas, do a hurry-up job,
will you? We're 25 minutes late.
Hurry it up, will you, guys? Be good guys.
- Hey, wise guy. You almost scraped me.
- Cool off, fella.
- Danny.
- Mutt, look who's here. Googi.
Gee, and if it ain't the
old mutt face. How are you?
- Hello.
- It's been a long time.
- How you doing?
- I just checked in.
- You been away someplace?
Yeah, I been a lot of places and no place.
Tell you the truth, Danny,
I've been sightseeing.
I spent a year and a day on that sweet
little island they call Blackwells.
Then I took a little trip up the Hudson too.
There's a beautiful view up there.
I ought to know. I looked
at it for 36 months.
- I heard you were doing a stretch.
- I had it coming to me.
I was playing for peanuts.
But from now on I play for high stakes
and with nothing in my pocket either, see?
And I'll chop off the hand of the
first guy that tries to stop me.
Hey, look, Danny. Gee, I hate to
ask this, but could you stake me?
I could use a shave and a haircut and
a pair of shoes with soles on them.
I'll give you a stake. French
fried potatoes too. Come on, get in.
Get in that limousine, Googi. Okay, fellas?
- Okay!
- Give her the gas, Danny. Let her go.
Gee, it's good to see you guys.
What a break bumping into you.
It's funny, Danny, the old
bunch, every one of them.
They keep turning up like bad
pennies. First Pete, now Googi.
The other day, I heard that Mushy
Kelly finished his stretch for burglary.
What a bunch.
It must be pretty late.
You gotta get some sleep.
No, that's all right.
Keep on playing, will you?
Play that part you just played.
What? This?
Now I know something's
wrong. Who is it, Peggy?
I thought so.
Peggy's old lady nailed me on the stairs
tonight and lit into me like a bantam.
Where was Peggy, and what did I
mean keeping her out all night?
- Your fault, huh?
- Yeah, how do you like that?
Peggy chasing around with that
sharpie from 65th Street...
...and I gotta take the schlack.
Danny. You're still pretty
set on that kid, aren't you?
You ought to know. She's part
of me by now. Like my right arm.
Everything was going good
until that sharpie came...
...and gave her a fancy line of gab.
Danny, I don't know this guy
Burns, but I think I know the type.
And he's not the one to worry about.
You got a lot more
competition than that spieler.
What do you mean? I don't get you, Ed.
Danny, I know Peggy,
and I certainly know you.
I can't exactly explain this to you...
...but call it applause,
ambition, call it what you like.
But it'd take a lot more than
a man to come between you two.
You see, when she rubs her
eyes open in the morning...
...she sees her name up in bright
lights: "Peggy Nash, dancer."
All day long, keeps moving those lights
around different theaters, different cities.
At night, she goes to sleep
with applause in her ears.
Danny, she can't see you
and she can't hear you...
...because she's blinded by those
lights and deafened by that applause.
It looks like you nailed it, Ed.
But whatever it is, I'm not gonna
let it take her away from me.
Come in.
I waited downstairs since 10:00.
You didn't show up. I thought
I'd see what was the matter.
What are you trying to pull on me?
Why, I thought we had a date for today.
- It's Sunday, isn't it? - So
you're getting big-hearted, huh?
Why, don't you want to, Danny? Or
are you trying to give me a stand up?
Stand up? That's what I've been getting
since that creepy cake-eater horned in.
- You got soap in your ears.
- So I got soap in my ears.
- You needn't yell.
- Who's yelling?
Not me.
- What are you trying to do, cut my throat?
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
- You didn't mean it.
- Here, let me wash it.
Honestly, I was only fooling.
- First you cut me, then say "only fooling."
- You got a right to be sore.
I thought since it was
Sunday and so nice and warm...
...maybe you'd take me to the beach.
We could have the day together.
- Why didn't you say so?
- You jumped down my throat.
- You know what I ought to do to you?
- What?
I certainly missed you, Peggy.
We had a swell time last
week and the week before.
We won't have a swell time today
unless we get started, so...
You know, Danny, someday I'd
love to take a long ocean trip.
We could do that on our honeymoon. We
could take a cruise to Atlantic City.
I think I can get my boss
to give me a week off.
No, I mean far away. Europe, South America.
Traveling on big ships, seeing
the world from a front seat.
Danny, if I'm successful, I can go anywhere.
Get off that express and take a local.
- Still dreaming about being a star, huh?
- Why not?
Danny, I just know I could be a great dancer.
Maybe even up there someday,
up on Broadway, in a big show.
- My name in bright lights.
- What do you want that for?
We could be happy together
without all that noise.
- Together?
- Yeah, sure. Married. Why not?
Well, I wasn't exactly
thinking about that yet.
- No?
- Don't you see, Danny?
We're hurting each other if we let
ourselves into the lives our families had.
Always struggling, trying to make a dime do
for a dollar. I want out of Forsyth Street.
We don't have to live down there.
We can move up to the Bronx.
Danny, sometimes I don't understand you.
Everybody in New York wants to do
something, be somebody, except you.
- I just wanna be happy.
- But you've got to have ambition.
You can't drag around this town on one foot.
You've got to run like the
rest, or you'll be left behind.
I didn't know you wanted me to, Peggy.
I'd do anything if you'd
tell me you wanted me to.
Danny, I guess we want different things.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
I'll tell you what. We go over
to Chinatown, have some chop suey.
Then we go over to
Settlement and have a dance.
I'd love to, but, well, I wanted to tell
you this before, only I didn't know how.
You see, I can't tonight.
I promised to go to Palace Gardens.
There's a contest there, a big city contest.
There's going to be a booking
agent. Maybe I can get a job.
Yeah, I guess we are talking
about different things.
That sharpshooter gonna be there?
Oh, I don't know, Danny.
I don't care about him.
- We'd better go.
- Look, Peggy.
Suppose I do stop dragging one foot?
Suppose I do join up with
the pack and run with them?
I can do something besides
juggling a packing case.
I got two fists to beat
the way for both of us.
All you gotta do is say
the word and I'll get going.
But, Danny, I don't want you to do it for me.
I want you to be somebody for yourself.
All right. Any way you want it, Peggy.
But tell me one thing so I won't
always be worrying about you.
Promise me that you'll always
be my girl, no matter what.
I promise, Danny.
Always. No matter what.
Okay, but do I have to start the show?
The house is as cold as a
corpse. They'll freeze us.
Can't you make it three or four?
Wait a minute. You're breaking
in. You can't pick your spots now.
I might fix it for you so you'd
have number two. That's all.
- All right, skip it. What's the route?
- We open in Baltimore...
...play the last half in Philly, jump to Akron,
lay off last half, play Cleveland a week...
...pick up the Delahanty time in
Buffalo, finish that, then Brooklyn.
You call that a route. If you can't do...
Listen. The woods are full of dancers
who'd break their neck for a booking.
- Well, if you don't like it...
- Okay, okay. Sold.
That's the way. You got
nothing to worry about.
All you gotta do is knock them dead.
What about the billing? Burns and Nash?
- You bill it Burns and Company.
- What about the 80 bucks?
- Make it payable to me.
- Okay with you, Peggy?
Of course. I leave everything to Murray.
Blank check, huh? Well, it's okay by me.
You'll have to sign too,
Peggy, by this cross.
Gee, this is the first time
I ever signed a contract.
I'm so nervous I can hardly write.
Attagirl.
Don't forget, you leave Thursday.
Train pulls out for Baltimore at
8:15. Grand Central. Don't be late.
I'll have two tickets for you on Wednesday.
Goodbye and lots of luck.
You'll need it in Akron.
- You said it. See you Wednesday.
- Okay.
How'd you like it, baby?
Boy, oh, boy. Am I
dreaming, or am I dreaming?
What did I tell you? Did
I sell him a bill of goods.
I can't believe it. I won't
believe it until we really open.
Don't worry about that. It's a cinch.
I know I can get a gown at Klein's...
...but I should have a
real pair of dance slippers.
Murray, I'll be able to send Ma
a few dollars every week, won't I?
That'll be all right, won't it?
Sure, baby, sure. Everything's gonna
be all right with us from now on.
It's getting late. I'd better go.
I want my shoe, Murray.
Please let me go, Murray. My shoe.
Don't worry about that.
Please let me go, Murray. Murray, please
let me go. Please let me go. Let me go!
You may come in now, Mr. Kenny.
Remember what you said. I'm depending on you.
- Don't worry.
- I won't. I got my fingers crossed.
Hello, Kenny.
Took you a long time. I was expecting you.
- Got an empty stall in your stable?
- Is it money or a dame?
Both. Now look, Scotty, I don't
wanna waste your time or my own.
I'll take a few fights.
I've gotta get real dough.
I think you've got the wrong number.
I don't know what reasons you've got.
I've only got one. I want a
champion. So get this straight.
If you're gonna fight for
me, you're gonna fight my way.
All right. When do I start?
As soon as we get you in shape.
Right now, you're all musclebound.
We'll start working out
those truck-driver's bumps.
In the meantime, I'll line up
an out-of-town card for you.
There's another thing you
might as well know now.
You'll get no setups. If my boys haven't
got what it takes, I'm just not interested.
- I don't want any setups, Scotty.
- Well, that's fine. Now let me see.
You can open in Detroit and then
I'll run you up into Cleveland...
...and then we'll go to Toledo.
That ought to get us Chicago.
Scotty, I was wondering there might be
a bout in Pittsburgh about Christmas.
What's in Pittsburgh? Who is she?
Now, the way I understand
it, you take care of business.
All I asked was, could
you arrange Pittsburgh?
All right, I'll see if I can.
- By the way, do you need any money?
- Not yet.
All right, I'll see you at Stillwell's
to see what shape you're in.
- Remind me to pick a second.
- You got one here. Can't shake him.
I'll second him. I'll even third
him. Let me tell you, I can...
Tell it to him.
- No kidding. Is it all set?
- Yeah. You can relax.
Danny, Danny, you can't imagine
what you've done for my career.
Yes, Mr. MacPherson?
We're lining up an out-of-town
card on Young Samson.
But remember, no fights near
Pittsburgh. That's one town we detour.
- It's a massacre.
- Looks like you guessed it right.
I always guess it right. I
never have to look no more.
I can it tell from the yelling.
That was the blood yell.
It's a cold pack! He's in the canvas.
It's over. Give me that four bits.
- Who won?
- I never know till they come through.
I can tell you who won.
- Yeah? Who?
- Young Samson.
- He's got to win.
- Why?
Because he doesn't care
whether he wins or not.
You mean...
...if he wanted to win, he'd lose?
- Maybe.
What did I tell you?
And I knew because I got clothes on my back.
What's the secret behind that sleep-making
left-right? Those curls, maybe?
Danny, watch out for a gal named Delilah.
Are you in shape. You sure put that guy away.
- Yeah, don't take a haircut.
- Put your hand in there.
- It's cold.
- Not half as cold as Hanson is right now.
- You said it.
- How about another?
What's the matter with
you guys? Go on. Get out.
All right, fellas. Let him get his clothes
on. I'll give you all the smoke-up stuff later.
- Get up to my office.
- Danny, it was terrific.
- He didn't even hit you once.
- See that?
What's the matter?
Nothing. He sprained his thumb.
I put the wrong hand in the ice water.
- Danny, someone here to see you.
- Who is it?
Remember me? This is Googi under these duds.
Well, Googi. Where did you come from?
The same place you come
from, Forsyth and Delancey.
- How are you?
- Well, get Googi.
Hundred-and-fifty-dollar suit, monogrammed
shirt and buttons good enough to eat.
- Kid, you look like a success.
- You're not doing bad.
As a matter of fact, I won on
you. I brought you a present.
- I want you to meet some pals. Let them in.
- Hey, girls.
Come on in, girls. This
is Sally, Irene and Mary.
Come right down out of the
scandals just to see you fight.
You were wonderful. You
stopped the show cold.
He sure did and he won me ten grand too.
Now, look, Danny. I got a big blowout
waiting for you. Everybody's invited.
- You're full of surprises.
- There's a big party arranged.
- Come on. Get dressed. Let's all go.
- Sure.
Okay, now.
We got a real snappy treat here.
I want you all to meet Samson's kid
brother, a great musician, Eddie Kenny.
He's gonna give us some real classy
music, so I want a little quiet, see?
Come on, Danny let's have him.
Come on, Eddie boy, give.
- Gee, Danny, this is no time, no...
- They'll love it. Play the part I like.
All right.
If you ask me, this stuff is too ritzy.
What happened to Dorothy?
She's so dumb, she didn't even
know what he was talking about.
Hello, Max. Where you been?
Wouldn't you like to know, huh?
Where's Danny? Oh, there he is.
Samson, that fight was a real honey.
I collected two grand on you tonight.
Max, this is Danny's kid brother,
Eddie, a composer of real class.
Eddie, meet the biggest producer
on Broadway, Max Leonard in person.
How are you, young fella?
Say, Danny, is that true?
That Cannonball Wales is hiding out from you?
Say, where's that gossip hound Mulligan?
He's got me stepping
out with Cutie d'Amour...
...breaking up my home life.
I think we'll find him
right there in the corner.
Don't worry, kid. They just
like to hear themselves talk.
I knew they wouldn't listen.
I could've told you that.
We don't care. We'll show them.
I'll show them right now.
Hey, Max. Listen to that swing.
That kid's got something new.
Say, that's not so bad.
Danny, if he can give me a score for my
next show, he can write his own ticket.
Say, Eddie sure can swing it, can't he?
Hey, what about some
caviar? Come on. Just try.
Chef, fix him up a nice plate.
Caviar. Remember what we used to do for
a frankfurter and a swig of lemonade?
I never forget that. Hey, listen, what's
new about Peggy? You seen her lately?
- No.
- I heard she's dancing in vaudeville.
- I know she's doing a lot of traveling.
- Yeah?
Hey, boss, them show cuties
just blew in. They wanna...
- Okay, I'll be right over.
- All right.
Sorry, Danny. I'll see you later.
Next time on that waltz,
don't lean all over me.
Don't get up out of your curtsy till I bow.
- Remember that, Pavlova.
- All right, I'll remember.
- Just a minute.
- Say, if that's Art Baron, tell him to wait.
How long does he think that
club deal is gonna hang?
All right, I'll tell him. Just a second, Art.
- Danny.
- Hello, Peggy.
Oh, Danny!
Come in and let's look at you.
Gee, I didn't know you were in town.
- It's good to see you.
- It's good to see you, Danny.
What's all the noise? Who you got there?
Oh, it's just a friend, Murray.
Oh, just a friend.
Excuse me for butting in.
- Danny, you remember my partner, Murray.
- Yeah.
So how's the little champ?
- Peggy, I'd like to talk to you alone.
- Giving me the brushoff, huh?
- Danny, I've read about you in the paper.
- I've been keeping track of you too.
I've seen your bill in the Variety.
What are you doing here? This ain't
no third-rate gym for palookas.
- You're asking for it, Burns.
- Come on, sock me.
- That's the only thing you got any head for.
- Murray, Danny and I are old friends.
All right. I'll let you make a date
with your old friend, sure. Next year.
I'll see Peggy now or any time I wanna, see?
- Get wise to yourself. Three's a crowd.
- You can't talk to Danny like that.
Since when you giving orders?
Shut your trap or I'll...
- Strong arm stuff, huh?
- Sorry, Peggy. Did I hurt you?
You probably broke her shoulder.
- Get that mug out of here.
- Peggy.
No. It doesn't matter. Please leave
me alone. Why'd you have to come here?
Because I was crazy to see you. I wouldn't
hurt you. I'd cut my arm off first.
Danny, don't talk like that.
I can't see you. You've got to go. Don't
you see, you've gotta leave me alone.
You heard what she said. Scram.
Now you see what happens when
you give a mug like that a break.
You should have thrown him out
the minute he opened the door.
I don't mind telling you, baby, that
means a lot, you standing up for me.
- Let's see what that gorilla did to you.
- Keep your hands off me.
- Why, what's the matter? Come on.
- Just remember that.
Don't ever put your hands on me again.
Get out of here. This is my dressing room.
Okay. But you keep your mind on your
routine or I'll find me somebody who will.
Danny! Danny, wait.
- I wanna talk to you. Give me a chance.
- Yeah, sure, Peggy, sure.
Danny, I didn't wanna be
mean. Please understand.
I was afraid they'd cancel if you cut his
face. I know you had a right to hit him.
- You even had a...
- That's all right. Don't worry.
Does your shoulder still hurt?
You sure?
You should've let that guy
take it. He had it coming.
- You sure it don't hurt?
- No.
I know I've hurt you worse than that.
You know, I meant to write you many
times. I was scared you'd be angry.
I couldn't be sore at you, Peggy. I certainly
missed you every minute you was away.
You know, you haven't changed a bit.
- I haven't?
- No.
- Are you sure, Danny?
- You're still the same little Peggy.
- Still my girl, ain't you?
- Yes, Danny. Always.
Oh, I love you so much.
Hey, what is this?
Come on, break it up. Hire a
hall. What do you think this is?
- You wanna make something out of it?
- Go on. Get out.
- How long you gonna be in town?
- Till tomorrow.
- Only tomorrow?
- Then Hartford and Providence.
And after that?
That's the end of the contract. After that...
After that I'll be free again.
Does that mean you're
not gonna leave anymore?
If that's what you want, Danny.
- You mean that, Peg?
- Yes, Danny.
- For sure?
- For sure.
- For keeps?
- For keeps.
Well. Two weeks. Why, that's
nothing. That's nothing at all.
That'll just give me time
to get everything ready.
- You know, Peg...
- Yes, Danny?
Well, what do you know about that?
Hey, didn't I just tell...?
Holy smokes. Some people in
this town is just plain nuts.
Here you are, Manchester Hotel.
Wait here a few minutes, will you, bub?
- Then it's a date for tomorrow?
- Paddy's Tavern. I'll meet you there.
I want you to meet Scotty and Mutt
too. He's gonna fall all over himself.
- After that, what do you wanna do?
- I don't care, as long as we're together.
We'll go and visit the East Side. We'll
go to Moscowitz's Romanian restaurant.
After that, we'll go to
Forsyth Street Settlement.
- There's always something there.
- That'd be wonderful.
Danny, I'm so happy.
It's just like running
through a dark alley...
...and suddenly finding your
way out in warm sunlight.
Come on, come on. You gotta
get some shuteye. On your feet.
You can't do your kind of work
with only eight hours sleep.
- Still looking after me, aren't you?
- Right.
I started a long time ago. Can't quit now.
It's awfully nice to find
somebody you can depend on.
That's what I'm here for. Any
trouble, I'll be standing by.
Now, go on, get to bed.
- See you tomorrow, huh?
- Yeah.
I'm not trying to butt in, but you're
acting like a kid with his first crush.
You guessed it, jockey. She is.
- Good night, Miss Nash.
- Good night.
So you showed up, huh? I thought
you took a powder for good.
- What are you doing?
- Since when are you asking...?
Murray, haven't I got enough headaches?
- What's the trouble?
- There's no trouble. You're in.
I've landed you in the
circuit. Read it and collapse.
Club Madrid, Chicago, Club Paree, Philly...
...the Deauville, St. Louis,
Paradise, Casablanca, Ritz Roof.
Ain't that sweet music, baby?
The big time, the big money.
Well, when does all this...?
- AI, have you really got that?
- I've got it in the bag and sewed up.
Eight-fifty a week, 40 weeks.
Start in Chicago in two weeks.
We've got to do some tussling in them
two weeks to get those routines down.
Got your tongue tied? You leave it to Al.
- I told you I'd put you on top.
- Top or no, we've gotta buckle down.
I've got a slant for a new kind of number.
But, Al. Al, I thought maybe after these
next two weeks I'd take a little vacation.
- A vacation at $850 a week? Are you nuts?
- We start off with eight bars of bolero.
Then the spins we did in the tango.
It's something you've never seen.
- That's what they want.
- Then do an open step.
From that, slip into the rumba.
Al, get busy on that music. Don't hold me up.
Now, how about a flashy name?
How about Maurice and Margalo?
That's your new billing. You like it?
Maurice and Margalo: Club Madrid.
Maurice and Margalo?
Yeah. Margalo spelled right out in lights.
"Maurice and Margalo."
You know who just went in? Danny Kenny.
- Young Samson.
- No kidding?
Let's go around the back. We can see better.
Okay, come on. Let's go.
Wasn't that Danny Kenny that came in?
Yeah. Young Samson. They always come back.
- Say, you better go tip off Walter.
- Okay.
There he is, Young Samson.
What did I tell you?
What do you say, Peg? How about a dance?
Later, Danny. Let's watch a while.
- Anything you say. This is your night.
- No, Danny. It's your night.
Well, then let's say it's our night.
Attention, please! Attention!
We've got with us tonight...
...one of our own Forsyth boys...
...who has socked his way right up
from Essex Street to Essex House.
I mean, the next welterweight
champion of the world, Danny Kenny.
It looks like orchids for Danny and Peggy.
I'll be back in a flash with a flash.
- Did you tell him, Danny?
- I didn't say a word.
- How'd they find out then?
- I guess we just look that way.
Okay, you truckers and shaggers, on with
the jitters, and let joy be unrefined.
Now, come on, let's see some real stepping.
Danny and Peggy are elected honorary judges.
Let's go!
Boy, keep it hot!
- Happy, Danny?
- Very.
It's a real celebration, ain't it?
And now, by special request, folks, a
little number by the judges themselves.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I don't know about dancing. Ask the champ.
Come on, Peggy, be a sport.
- All right, but Danny's got to do it with me.
- Come on, Dan.
- Can't refuse a lady.
- Attaboy.
- Go on, do this by yourself.
- No, I'd much rather not.
Go on, you're among
friends. Give them a treat.
- Good evening. What train, sir?
- 11:15, Hartford.
Track 14. Would you like your
luggage in the car with you?
Yes, thanks. Danny, please
don't see me down to the train.
- He'll be there and it'll cause...
- All right.
Well, it's two weeks from tonight?
- You're gonna wire me which train to meet?
- Yes. Yes, Danny, I'll wire you.
Tell me, were you really happy tonight?
The biggest day of my
whole life. Don't I look it?
Hold me close.
Train would be leaving.
- What are you bawling about?
- It's just that I don't want it to end.
There's gonna be lots more.
This way, please.
Good afternoon. I represent
the Bluepoint Vacuum Cleaner.
- Sorry.
- lf you let me demonstrate, you'll say...
..."I don't see how I got along without it."
- Hello. Got a telegram for me?
- No. Look, we're bachelors...
- Not for long.
What are you selling? Vacuum cleaners?
Come on in. We can use one of those.
- Looks like a sale.
- Thanks.
Waited for two hours to get a license.
Looks like everybody's getting married.
- You getting married?
- You said it.
Your wife will appreciate the Bluepoint.
Now, allow me to demonstrate its efficiency.
- Go right ahead, son.
- Thanks.
So I gets to the window and I
discover there's a new law in New York.
- You gotta wait three days to get married.
- As you see...
...you can protect and clean the
most expensive rugs with no effort.
Are you sure there was no wire?
Nope, only some mail and
photos to autograph there.
You'll find that our cleaner sucks
up every bit of grit and dirt...
...and adds years of
wear and life to your rug.
And preserves the sanitation of your home.
What's the matter with you?
Here's a letter from Peggy.
I didn't look for a letter.
You asked if there's a wire.
Now, for your upholsteries,
drapes, curtains or hanging...
...you simply attach this gadget.
It's simple. A child can operate it.
You attach this end, push this button and...
- Say, Pinky. Danny's here.
- Hey, you're late.
Where you been? Scotty's
been raising the deuce.
We're waiting an hour already.
- What's the matter? Can't you talk?
- Pipe down, Pinky. Pipe down.
- You're in his hair.
- Another prima donna.
You can't say nothing around here.
Okay, Sailor, hop in for a couple
rounds. Guy's getting hard to handle.
Danny just blew in. I don't
know what's the matter.
- Where is he?
- He's in the ring.
- Hi, Danny. Hi, Mutt.
- Hi, Sailor.
You sure look in the pink.
Did you see the Telegram?
- Boy, Sullivan sure went to town on you.
- Let's get started.
Why, what's the matter,
Danny? What are you sore about?
Sure, I know Cannonball. I don't
trust him. He's mean and dangerous.
- Danny'll stop him.
- He might stop Danny.
- I'm taking no chances.
- Danny will throw a right in his breadbasket.
By the time he pulls his glove
out, he'll be champ. Look at him.
Danny, wait a minute, will you?
- This ain't for keeps.
- Come on, stop crying.
Say, what's going on there?
Just a second, Danny, will you?
- Say, Mutt. Call him off me, will you?
- Take it easy, Danny. Take it easy.
What do you want him to do, break his hands?
What are you slugging
him for? What is the idea?
- I'm sorry, Sailor. You all right?
- Sure, sure, it's okay.
- I'm sorry. I didn't know what I was doing.
- All right, get yourself a shower.
Wait. What's going on? Spill it.
I don't know. Honest I don't.
He just come in like that,
sore, like somebody crossed him.
You mean double-crossed him.
And I think I can name her.
All right, what's use eating your
heart out? That won't bring her back.
I know something about human
nature, including women.
You've got to pull yourself together.
Once you got the crown, you'll
find that gal on your doorstep.
They all like the limelight.
Peggy ain't different.
Once you're on top,
she'll die to be with you.
Look, I can book the southpaw.
Then later, Cannonball Wales.
- How about Cannonball now?
- He's too tough.
You're not ready for him. Look.
- First the southpaw, then later...
- Quit stalling me, Scotty.
You said the crown would mean something.
Well, get me Wales. I can whip him.
Sure, Scotty. Danny'll bring
that Cannonball down to buckshot.
- Get the match and I'll bet 50 grand on him.
- What will Danny get?
Wales' manager's cagey. We get peanuts.
So? Once we get the crown, we get cagey.
Till then, you can call me banker.
Sure, go ahead, Scotty, do it!
All right, you've got the match.
That's a good fella.
We can beat him. We can beat him, Danny.
Samson battles Wales for
welterweight crown tonight!
Read all about the New York fight!
Samson battles Wales for
welterweight crown tonight.
Come in.
Miss Margalo, Mr. Maurice, on stage, please.
Yes, yes, coming.
... one of the toughest to out-punch.
It is said Samson packs a terrific right.
If Wales isn't on the
watch, Samson may floor him.
If you don't mind my saying,
Samson's gotta put up a fight to win.
- Yes, yes, I suppose so.
- He better. I bet two bucks on him.
Will you stop bothering about that radio?
I'm ready, Murray.
- You mind if we use your radio, Peggy?
- Of course not. Go ahead.
- Thanks, Peggy.
- Oh, thanks a lot.
Murray, let's hurry our first
number. I want to listen in.
What for? That palooka of yours
won't last two rounds anyway.
Danny, this fellow Wales is
bad. Don't fall for his fight.
He knows tricks. Watch when
he backs into the ropes.
I'll watch, don't worry.
Look, when he acts
groggy, that's just a pose.
I got it down. I always fight the
way you tell me. Quit worrying.
You always tell me that
and do the same thing.
- All right, kid. Go in there and beat him.
- All right.
- Good luck to you, Mutt.
- Thanks, Danny.
Scotty.
It's a funny thing, Mutt.
Here I am, fighting for the championship
of the world, and didn't wanna be a fighter.
This is Sam Hayes, all set to give a
description of this widely publicized fight.
Both fighters have entered the ring,
the referee is giving them instructions.
There's the warning whistle. In
just a moment, the fight will be on.
- Has it started?
- You're in time. It's the first round.
That's the bell. The fight's
on. They start sparring.
Samson leads his left to Wales'
nose. So fast you can just see it.
Wales rips a right jab
for the face but misses.
- Danny's in fine shape, isn't he?
- Sure is.
Hey, Dutch, don't forget that big
blowout I'm giving later to celebrate.
I got the whole club reserved
for all my friendly enemies.
How you gonna pay the bill after
you get through paying me off?
You look fine. Settle down.
- One...
- Come on, Walesie!
...three, four, five...
- Take a count.
...seven.
- Close in on him. Tie him in knots.
- This guy ain't so easy. He hits like a mule.
Dutch, what do you say instead of cash...
...you give me 50 percent
of your uptown take?
Now, don't forget, close in on him.
Steady, Danny, steady.
Come on, Danny. Keep it in there.
See that? See that foul?
That dirty heel, Wales.
You can take it easy, brother.
That don't worry Young Samson.
Fouls ain't nothing to him. This is a cinch.
- Champion!
- Three...
...four, five...
- Stay down!...six...
- Stay down!...seven, eight!
- The last count sure helped.
- You need it.
Hey, what's your hurry? Take
your time. You got plenty of time.
That's right. Get cagey,
like we talked about.
- We gotta work fast.
- What do you want me to do?
What do I want you to do?
Here, let me fix your gloves.
If they can't see you, they can't hit you.
He'll try for a knockout. Don't clinch.
Keep him off with your left lead.
Just keep jabbing at his lamps.
Give it to him!
Danny! Cover.
Watch it, Danny. Watch.
Now, keep them up. Keep...
Cover up!
- Come on, Walesie!
- Danny, watch his left! Box him!
- What's the matter? He don't listen.
- Danny oughtn't lead him around the eyes.
- Box him, Danny!
- Come on, Danny! Like we talked about!
Referee, can't you see he's fouling my
man? Watch your eyes, Danny! Your eyes!
This is a great comeback Wales is making.
Wales keeps stabbing Samson's
face, one, two, one, two.
Samson seems a little confused.
Wales now leads quick
rights to Samson's face.
He left himself open for that.
Danny caught him a hard right,
but he came back with two jabs...
...to Danny's other eye.
That right one is bad enough.
Danny's trying too hard. He ought
to watch that left on his eye.
Yeah, it's red and swollen.
You can see it from here.
Can't you hear the bell?
What's the matter, thumb in the eye?
- Both eyes.
Why don't you listen? I
told you to watch his left.
That's what I been doing but
he stuck his thumb in my eye.
- I can hardly see him.
- Crowd your man and fight to the body.
Now, come on. Fight to the body now.
- You're looking fine.
- Come on, boy.
Keep belting him right in
the body, Danny, all the time.
Watch it, Danny.
Come on.
Both of Samson's eyes are nearly closed.
Wales throws caution to the winds,
and punches the body and the head.
Come on, Danny. Come on!
Come on, hit him, Danny. Come on, Danny.
Danny, come on!
...three, four, five, six, seven.
- Danny, get up!
Come on, Danny!
- How are your eyes?
- I can hardly see him.
You can't see? Do you want to stop?
No. They're coming along. They're
clearing up. Keep throwing water on them.
- Is he hurting you much?
- He can't.
Danny, keep circling and
keep your guard up. All right?
All right, I'll nail him.
What's the matter, Googi?
Looking for a miracle?
Keep your guard up now. Your guard up, Danny.
Samson misses with a wild swing.
Danny's eyes are almost closed.
How he stands up to this this torture
is a miracle of will and courage.
Wales tears in with a hard left.
Don't let him get you up against the
ropes. Come on, get away from them ropes!
Three, four, five...
...six, seven.
- How's that feel?
- That's good, Mutt.
- I can see better already.
- Danny, I'm gonna stop the fight.
- I never should have let you in for this.
- No, Scotty, don't do that to me.
All I need is one shot at this
guy. Scotty, promise me something.
Promise you won't throw
the towel in. Promise me.
I gotta win. I gotta beat this guy.
All right, Danny, all right.
You'll win. You're gonna beat
him. Just keep that guard up.
When you feel him near
you, keep pounding the body.
It isn't worth it, Danny.
Scotty, stop it, stop it!
Let me through. He'll murder
him. Scotty, you gotta stop it.
Danny. Danny!
Wales comes back with a hard
right, right on the button...
...but Samson refuses to go down.
Miraculously on his feet after
three rounds of punishment.
His eyes just narrow slits. I
doubt if he can see a thing now...
... but he's game as ever,
standing right up there.
Wales crowds Kenny, slugging him to the
head and face with savage lefts and rights.
Now a stiff right to the heart.
Ain't that too bad. Mind if I listen in?
Not that I wanna hang around
you, I just want all the details.
Lock the door, Della.
Yes, ma'am. Excuse me, Mr. Burns.
She'll be ready in a minute.
Okay, but hurry up.
There's the referee trying to
talk to him. Samson waves him off.
Referee steps back and
Wales comes charging in.
You can bet the referee wanted to call a
technical knockout. Danny wouldn't have it.
Wales jabs three stiff lefts to
Danny's face, looking for an opening...
And there's the final bell.
With this fight over, with Young Samson...
... like his ancient namesake,
blind as a bat, but still game...
... a human punching bag, beaten to a pulp...
Miss Peggy, it's time for your next number.
Miss Peggy, you just got to hurry.
Come on, come on, step on it.
You're holding up the works.
Ain't you coming, Miss Peggy?
I can't, Della. I can't.
Well, what will I tell the folks?
What will I tell Mr. Murray?
I don't know. I don't know. Tell him
anything you like, but leave me alone.
Just another moment and I'll
be all through, Mr. Kenny.
There. Feels better, doesn't it?
Yeah. It don't sting as much now, doc.
Prepare a sedative, please.
- Three grains dissolved in a glass of water.
- Yes, doctor.
This is entirely my fault. I
never should have let him in this.
Scotty.
Yes, Danny?
You ain't sore at me, are you?
I did the best I could,
but I just couldn't see him.
- Couldn't find him.
- Sure you did, Danny. We know.
Now, take it easy and
everything'll be all right.
Excuse me, please.
Now, drink this.
- Is he hurt badly?
- He's taken a lot.
His excellent condition helps.
Look, how about his eyes? Are they okay?
Well, that's of more consequence.
The conjunctival membranes are
seriously injured in both eyes.
Some infection has already set in.
I found, too, evidence of gritty
substances. Granular material.
- Probably rubbed in every time he was hit.
- Look, doc...
...could it be something like rosin dust?
- Very likely.
I don't know how he ever stood the pain.
If we're to save his sight, I advise getting
him to the hospital at once. Excuse me.
Rosin rubbed in his eyes
with the tip of their gloves.
The dirty, low-down rats.
Wait a minute, Scotty.
You take care of Danny. That's
your job. This is my department.
Please send an ambulance right away.
Connect me with the chief of staff.
Find out where the car is and
take care of it like I told you.
Okay, boss. I'll be ready for you.
Say, Dutch, how long will
it take to get him in shape?
- About 30 days.
- Dutch.
Relax. Still giving that blowout, Googi?
Sure. The party's still
on. Why not? I never welch.
You had tough luck, Googi.
We gave up hope already.
It was one of them surprise comebacks.
- Sure. That happens.
- No hard feelings?
What for, 50 grand?
Listen. I got my limousine downstairs.
What do you say we drive over together?
Just a second. I don't wanna disappoint
you, but I'd rather go in my own car.
See, I get kind of nervous
driving in strange cars.
Sure. Anything you say. What's the diff?
Come on, boys, let's go. We're wasting time.
Okay, fellas. I'll see you later.
Googi, tell you the truth, if you
need the 50 G's bad, I can wait.
Say, a couple of months.
No, I'm paying off. I don't
like to have nothing on my mind.
Well, Googi, if it was just between
me and you, I'd say call it off.
- But there's Wales. I gotta pay him off.
- Sure. I understand.
Well, that reminds me. I meant to ask
Cannonball for one of his gloves...
...you know, like a souvenir to show around.
Hey, we're going the wrong way.
Archie, where are you heading?
Say, what's the idea?
- Who's that guy?
- Take it easy, Dutch.
Don't get nervous. Happy's a swell driver.
Now, like I was saying, if I
had one of Cannonball's gloves...
...I might like to take it to
the state boxing commission.
They might like to look it over.
Especially after they get the
doctor's report about Samson's eyes.
You're going screwy. What
have you been sniffing?
Just a little rosin dust.
- Let me out of here.
- Shut up!
Let that be a lesson to you, Cobb.
When you're carrying a
gat on your left side...
...you wanna sit on to the right of the
guy you mean to bump off, like I did.
And as for you, you don't have a gat.
I made sure of that with my shoulder.
Look, Googi, it was all his idea.
I was against it. You don't owe
me a cent. I'll take care of Wales.
Listen, rat. You and Wales are gonna have
to take care of a lot of other things...
...if Danny's lamps go out.
- Stop the car!
Pipe down. Quit yapping.
Now, wait here. Monkey around as
though you're fixing the engine.
And no tricks. Do you understand me?
- All right, boss, grab his feet.
- Okay, Hap. Let's make it fast.
- Sure, boss.
- Now, right around this way.
There's no use stripping those
labels. They got his mug and prints.
- Okay, boss.
- That reminds me, I better ditch this.
When they fish him up, all we say is:
"He didn't have to go
swimming with his hat on."
- Hey, that's a good one, boss.
- Okay, now...
Hey.
Hey, boss, what hap...
Hey, Hap.
Gee, never figured on that at all.
How you think they're gonna be?
You certainly are in a hurry, young
fellow. This is only a checkup.
Nurse, you better draw those
blinds. The light's too strong.
- Gee, you ought to seen the papers.
- They got Cobb.
No, I mean about the swell
notices the fight got.
Best fighter since Bob
Fitzsimmons. That's what they said.
That's fine, Mutt. Thanks.
No kidding. They really went to town
about the great fight you put up.
What do you think, doc?
Think they're gonna be all right?
Will I be laid up here long?
Well, it's difficult to say just
now. Possibly a few weeks or so.
Nurse, continue with the drops
and compresses as ordered.
- I'll see you again tomorrow, son.
- Yeah, sure. Thanks, doc.
You hear that, Eddie?
Three weeks. I'll go daffy in here.
But Danny, you need rest.
You took a lot of punishment.
Yeah, I guess I did. Can't figure
out how it happened so quick.
Had him on the run, and all of a
sudden the lights went out on me.
Excuse me, doctor. You must do something.
Anything at all. I don't
mind the expense, any cost.
It isn't a matter of expense. As I
said, it's only a question of time.
Now, perhaps in a year or two
we may chance another operation.
A year or two? Why, that means
Danny's finished, he's through.
As a fighter, I'm afraid he is.
He'll be able to see differences of
light, and make out shapes and forms.
So that's the sweet wind-up.
That's Danny's finish.
I'm sorry.
Scotty.
Scotty, where's Danny? Is he all right?
- Yes, he's all right.
- Can I see him?
He's in there, isn't he?
He's in there, flat on his
back. And you put him there.
Only you, not Cannonball Wales. Danny
never would have fought this fight.
He took a worse licking from
you than he took from Wales.
I've got to see him. You've got to let me in.
Now, just a minute, Peggy.
I'm gonna tell you something.
I'm not gonna pull punches.
I've seen you give that boy the rawest deal
ever and I'm not gonna let you do it again.
I'm not gonna let you go in there and say
hello for a while and then break his heart.
No, no, I'm all through with that. Please
let me in. I wouldn't do anything to hurt him.
You bet. You've done all you're going to do.
- Scotty, you don't understand.
- You're no good for him...
...and he's no good for you, because...
...well, never mind, he's no good for you.
- Now try to get that through your head.
- Excuse me. Thank you.
Danny's through with you and
wants you to stay away from here.
- Nurse?
- Yes?
Who was that, Eddie? Who came in?
Why, just another nurse, Danny.
- I thought maybe it was...
- What?
Oh, nothing. Nothing.
You know... You know, Eddie...
...I can't hardly see you at all.
You're just like kind of a shadow.
Well, the room's pretty dark
with the blinds down, Danny.
- Yeah, but you can see me good, can't you?
- Well...
Danny, you'd better put those bandages back.
You know, Ed, I figured
that where we came from...
...we were born with our back to the wall...
...and nothing more could happen
to us and nobody could hurt us.
Then along comes something like this, and...
Eddie, it's got me scared.
- Really scared.
- What are you talking about, Danny?
Don't be foolish.
Scotty. Scotty, tell him he'll be all right.
- What? Oh, yes.
- Go ahead, Scotty.
Tell him he'll be better.
Why, sure. Sure, Danny,
everything'll be all right.
- Look, the doctor says...
- The doctor didn't say nothing.
Just routine talk.
What are you trying to do?
Why don't you tell the truth? I know it
and you know it. I'm as blind as a bat.
Take it easy, Danny. Don't lose your head.
This is the first round. You
got a long fight in front of you.
Yeah, I know. Left hand out and keep moving.
Great stuff. That's two sure-fire
hit numbers so far. We can't miss.
- Terrific. Wait till you hear the second act.
- Eddie, it's swell.
- One thing you've got is rhythm.
- Come on. I've got to see a hundred people.
- I'll telephone you later.
- Okay, fellas.
Goodbye, Eddie. Good luck.
Don't worry, honey. If there's
anything to sell, I'll sell it.
- Bye.
- Thanks, bye.
What's the matter, Ed? Ed, anything wrong?
Oh, no, nothing, Danny.
How'd it sound to you? Did you listen?
Oh, all good. Those are really nice tunes.
Nice tunes?
Yeah, it sounded like they ate them
up. All sure-fire, every one of them.
Look, Danny. Danny, I want
you to tell me the truth.
I want you to tell me what
you're really thinking.
Ed, I don't know anything about
music. What can I tell you?
Listen, Danny, somehow you do know.
Maybe it's because music is
something you feel down deep.
Something you feel as much as I do.
Well, that's all I can do,
just tell you what I feel.
I don't know nothing about it.
Ed, do me a favor, will you?
Keep moving around so I
can see you better, huh?
Sure, sure, Danny.
Would you like the shade pulled up?
No, no. The lights all
right, Ed, thanks. It's okay.
Well, look, kid.
Here's the way I feel about it.
Your business is like any other business.
You either do it or you don't.
You're either a main eventer
or a four-round preliminary boy.
Down on Forsyth Street...
...you used to play by
the hour, and I'd listen.
You'd tell me about those
big shot composers...
...who took it on the chin
and went through the mill.
Beethoven, who got the toughest
break of all. Lost his hearing.
He didn't quit, he didn't
lay down. He just moved in...
...and kept on punching.
- Yes, but then what?
You work, you tear your heart out,
and in the end, nobody's interested.
Nobody wants to hear it.
They're only interested after
you're dead a hundred years.
Ed, that's an alibi.
That's an alibi used by
guys who can't deliver.
But you can do it, and if it's
good, they listen. They gotta listen.
Well, maybe you're right.
You know, Danny, you can see
things a lot clearer than I can.
I can see things now that
I could never see before.
Come on, kid. Do it for
us. Do it for both of us.
You used to talk about the music
that you heard in the subway...
...and in the streetcar tracks.
Music in the 101 different
languages you heard on all sides.
Music that everybody can hear,
all part of one great big song.
Yeah, the song of the city.
The symphony of New York.
The symphony of its seven millions with
all its color of a hundred different races.
And the harmony of its thousand discords.
Like the dizzy mad howl of an ambulance...
...screaming across Forsyth and Delancey.
Good evening, Mr. Gaul.
Where could I find Mr. Gaul?
- Right over there.
- Oh, yes. I see. Thank you.
Mr. Gaul, I tried you at the office,
but they told me you were here.
- I thought maybe...
- I'm busy. See me later.
How many times have I told
you not to dim those foots?
But I've tried to see you
all week. You remember me.
Peggy Nash from Burns and Company.
Burns and Company? Yeah, sure.
So, what happened? I thought
you were in the big time.
Yes I was. Maurice and Margalo. But I left...
Don't tell me. I know. You got a bum break.
You were good, but the show
stunk. So what? So you want a job.
Oh, I'd be so grateful.
Would you? Swell. Maybe my next show.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- That's okay, that's okay.
But, say, you'll have to
put on a little weight.
The customers down here
don't know from nothing.
Mr. Gaul, I thought maybe I could ask for...
A little advance? Sure.
Step up to the office.
I'll give you five bucks...
- Oh, thanks.
- Don't mention it. Don't mention it.
You won't have to mention that
advance, baby. He will soon enough.
Say, looks like you're
really gonna need that fin.
No. No, it's just a headache.
Yeah. Strictly from hunger. You're
telling me. Here, have a drink.
- Thank you.
- Anybody looking after you, kid?
- No, but...
- I don't care particularly about sharing...
...but maybe you better move in with me.
That's awfully nice of you but l...
I'll do the worrying.
I'll get you an aspirin.
Once I lived a whole week on them.
A lot cheaper than sandwiches.
- Anything new?
- Mr. Kenny is here. He's waiting inside.
Danny?
Hello, Danny.
What are you doing here alone? Trying
to get a little whiff of old Broadway?
I came down to hear the traffic.
Don't get much of it uptown.
It's like a graveyard there.
Danny, you didn't have to come
downtown. I'd come to your apartment.
No, I wanted to come. Glad
for the chance to get out.
There it is. I wouldn't know it was
you without that bow tie, Scotty.
Yeah, that's right. Let's sit down, huh?
No, I'd rather move around. Do you mind?
Not at all, Danny. What's on your mind?
I sort of figured you
could help me out, Scotty.
Why, Danny, just name
it. Do you need some cash?
No, no. Not this time. I've taken
plenty of that from you already.
Danny, how do you mean?
It's your money. You made it.
I've known all along you've
been carrying me, Scotty.
I'm gonna pay you back, every penny of it.
Danny, everything I've got
is yours. Don't you know that?
I know. It's just that I can't stand
sitting around in that room any more.
Well, that's simple. We'll
just get you a better place.
No, the place is all right.
It's just that I gotta get something
to do. The whole world doing things...
...and me stumbling
around in a 2-by-4 grave.
No morning, no sun, no nothing.
I can't take it, Scotty. Can't take it.
I keep talking to myself by the hour
and I got too much time to think.
About Peggy?
Scotty, get me something to do
where I can be around people...
...and feel life going on.
Where everything isn't just a
cold, gray fog smothering me.
I'll do anything. I don't
care what it is, anything.
Coming up here, I heard a
newsboy yelling and I remembered.
I used to do that. I used to sell
papers and I'd like to do it again.
Well, that's a fine idea,
Danny. Sure, why not?
Just to get something to do. I don't
care what. Just something to do.
Look, rest assured.
Whatever it is, we'll do it.
If we have to comb the whole town.
Just look at that. They guaranteed
me it was gonna be a permanent wave.
Ain't permanent, ain't a wave, ain't
nothing. It's just hair. But it's all my own.
You know, Gladys, it's funny.
After all the places I've
been, things I've done...
...l've just moved across town, that's all.
From East Side to West Side.
You look out and see the same back alleys...
...the same fire escapes,
the same clotheslines.
I'm back just where I started.
Wished I was back where I started...
...with a guy named Jake Smith
right over in Jersey City.
He was just a grease
monkey in a junkyard garage.
He only made 20 bucks a week, but he
was great on this thing called love.
I was a dizzy dope. I was
gonna burn up the world.
I got burned myself. Ever
watch a moth fly in the flame?
Can't stop them till their wings burn off.
Believe me, if Jake would take me back now...
...l'd crawl on my knees right
over to Jersey City, so help me.
We girls never get wise until it's too late.
Let me tell you...
What's the matter, Peggy,
got hay fever or something?
Peggy.
I'm sorry, Peggy. I really didn't mean to...
Well, I didn't care for that routine
that Gaul put in the show today either.
Nowadays the public wants class.
Give them their money's worth, that's
what I say. Here, have a cigarette.
Let's see what's fit to print today.
"Blond beauty marries her fifth."
She gets five and I don't
get one. Call that democracy?
"Fifty more millionaires reported last year."
Reported for what? Wish one
of them would report to me.
Say, here's a guy with the same
name as that pug you told me about.
"Edward Kenny, who will
conduct his own symphony...
...with the Philharmonic at
Carnegie Hall this Thursday night.
This will be the world premiere of
Mr. Kenny's symphony, An American..."
Kenny. Could he maybe be a relative
of that old heartache of yours?
Let me see.
Doing all right, Mutt?
We'll paste these clippings in a scrapbook.
Tomorrow we'll put the write-ups in.
Sure. This is gonna be
a very fancy scrapbook.
I'll put them together with yours.
Keep away from mine. I
don't wanna jinx the kid.
- Hi, Danny.
- Hello, Mr. Sinclair. Evening Post up yet?
- Right here. Late final.
- Final Variety hot off the press, Danny.
Okay, Smitty.
Oh, Mutt? Will you look in that
Variety and see if there's anything...
...about Peg this week?
- Sure.
How are you, Danny?
Well, did you see my scrib in
the column yesterday about you?
Yeah, Mutt read it to me. I didn't like it.
Why? What's the matter?
I only wanted to be nice.
Don't like that tear-jerking sob stuff.
"One of life's little tragedies."
I don't want nobody crying over me.
I don't want no benefits. I'm on my own.
- I got no complaints.
- All right, Danny. I just didn't know.
All right, Pep. So now you know, huh?
Okay. Well, I'll be seeing you, Danny.
- Find anything, Mutt?
- No.
Maybe I missed it. I'll start over again.
Look in the vaudeville gossip
column. Maybe something there.
Wait for me. Hello, Danny. Mutt.
What are you doing? You ought to
be at Carnegie. What's the matter?
Nothing, just skipped out
a minute to shake hands.
Getting kind of jumpy, huh, kid?
The nearer it gets to 9:00,
the faster my heart goes.
Well, hold that ticker down, it'll
hurt your timing. We're not worried.
We know it's good, don't we, huh?
Hey, what am I, a French
general getting a medal?
- See you later, Danny. So long, Mutt.
- Good luck.
- Well...
- Good luck, kid. Hold that ticker down.
I will. Carnegie Hall, and hurry.
We're gonna be proud of him, Danny.
I'm proud of him right
now. Well, come on, Mutt...
...you run home quick and get
yourself all dolled up, see?
And I think you better get a shave too.
Why? I'm staying right here, ain't I?
Oh, no. You're going up to that
concert. Here's the pasteboards.
That ain't right. This
is your brother's show.
I'm staying here. This is your night.
I don't want to go up there
and jinx the kid. Here.
What Are you talking about?
If it wasn't for you, he wouldn't be there.
I don't wanna be no skeleton
in the closet. Now, take these.
Danny, why don't you go up and see it all.
Go ahead. Hear everything for yourself.
I know all that music backwards.
Backwards and forwards.
Besides, I got it all right
here. Will you take these ducats?
Thanks, Danny. As soon as
it's over, I'll come back...
...and tell you all about it.
- I'll be here.
- Sure you won't change your mind?
- No, no. You go ahead. Go on.
- So long, Danny.
- Good night, Mutt.
Speech!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...once in each man's lifetime...
...there comes a supreme moment.
For me, here and now, this is it.
Not only because of the generous way...
...in which you have received my symphony...
...but because I can share this moment
with one whose contribution to this music...
...is far greater than
any that I could have made.
I am speaking of and to my brother.
He truly inspired the music
that you have heard tonight.
For in his life story...
...was a story of the great city
as I felt it in terms of music.
No, he's not a musician.
He couldn't read a single note...
...but in his heart and soul...
...there was such wealth
of music. Music of the city.
The music that led him on to glory,
to conquest, to tragedy and defeat.
But in that very defeat, he conquered.
For of all the men that I have come
to know, who have loved and lost...
...this boy retained a great nobility...
...that far surpassed any possible conquest.
Yes, my brother made music with his fists...
...so that I might make a gentler music...
...the symphony that you have heard tonight.
It is his as much as mine.
And so, with deep pride and gratitude...
...I dedicate this music to my brother...
...known to most or you...
...as Young Samson.
Mutt. Mutt.
Hello, Danny.
Hello, Mr. Cahn. I wondered
what happened to you.
- Kept you working late tonight?
- Why aren't you at your brother's concert?
I heard over the radio. Judging from
applause there must've been 5000 people.
- It was a success.
- I'll say.
They're crazy about Eddie's
music. Kept cheering and hollering.
Begging him to make a speech.
Imagine that brother of mine...
...talking to all those people.
- What'd he say?
Oh, nothing much. Just
thanks and appreciation.
It must be wonderful to click that way.
- You should be proud.
- I certainly am.
I'll bet. Well, that's fine,
Danny. See you tomorrow.
- Yeah, thanks, and good night.
- Good night.
What paper, please?
What do you read?
Hello, Peg.
Hello, Danny.
Well.
Hey, this is all right.
This is really a night for the books.
I just finished listening to
Eddie's concert on the radio...
...and it's a big success.
And now Peg's here.
That's all right for one night. Did you...?
Did you hear about the concert?
Yes, Danny. I was there.
You were? Well, great, wasn't it?
Can you imagine that
skinny-legged, redheaded kid...
...used to practice out on the fire escape...
...writes a symphony that
sets a whole town on its ear.
Well, I guess we ain't got no squawk coming.
Looks like everybody from
Forsyth Street's doing all right.
Oh, Danny.
What's the matter, Peg?
What are you crying for?
You just came to visit an old pal.
Aren't you glad to see me?
I can't tell you how much, Danny.
Are you all right?
Sure, I'm better than that.
I got a soft touch here.
Keeps me out in the air.
I sell a hundred papers and make a buck.
Besides, I got a lot of good
customers and they keep me busy.
I don't get much time for moping.
Then you are all right.
Oh, sure, I'm fine.
I still got my two eyes and
they're getting better all the time.
That's what the doctor said. A
year, maybe a little bit longer.
I can wait. Used to waiting.
Besides, I can always
see anything I wanna see.
I saw you, Peg.
Danny, if I could help now, I'd do anything.
Well, you have.
Look, I never told nobody this...
...but...
...I always knew that
someday you'd pass by here...
...and you'd see me.
Always knew that...
...because...
- Yes, Danny?
Because you were always my girl.
That's right, ain't it, Peg?
Always, Danny. Always.
Yes, brother, it's beautiful.
Didn't I tell you there was
a heart beating in the city?
I've been all over. East Side, West Side...
...down in the subways,
up in the elevators...
...flat with the river. And I report success.
There's a heart beating in the city.
You wont find it in the timetables,
and you'll never see it advertised.
But take it from me, brother...
...there's love in New York.
And I know...
...because I got clothes on my back.
[ENGLISH]