This movie is based on true events.
Juan, wake up,Juan, we're here.
Come on.
- What is it?
- l have to pee.
l told you to go before leaving.
- What is it, kiddo?
- We're almost there.
l'm out of cigarettes,
be right back.
Hurry, Mom! Quick!
Cristina!
The bastards!
Fuckers!
Horacio!
They hit me on the leg!
Horacio, what happened?
- Are you alright?
- l'm fine.
You okay, kiddo?
Go with him. Take him!
lt's okay, honey.
Daddy's alright.
Horacio, what'll we do?
Let's get outta here!
After the death of President Perón.
paramilitary groups started
persecuting and murdering
social activists and revolutionaries.
The military seized power.
unleashing the most violent repression
in Argentina's history.
Exiled in Cuba.
the revolutionary leaders
of Montoneros
initiate
the "Counterstrike Operation."
Some activists go home
with their children.
Hello, hello, 1, 2, 3, 4, testing.
Ready. Shall we?
Okay.
Hey, handsome.
lt's funny l'm taping this
rather than saying it to you.
But hey, it's so
that you can listen to us
as many times as you want
till we meet again.
Today we begin our journey
back to Argentina,
but we'll take different roads,
which means
we'll be separated for a while.
Here's Dad.
Go on.
Hey, kiddo.
Here l am.
We'll be separated for a while,
so l'll miss you like crazy.
But the good thing is,
we're going back.
And that
we're doing this because...
because we think it's the right time
to carry on fighting.
We're going back separately.
You and Vicky go
with Carmen and Gregorio.
They'll be your parents.
You'll be going through Brazil.
lf anybody asks a question, you say:
"l don't speak Spanish."
Eu no falo español.
Good.
Move it!
Kiddo.
remember how I told you
all about when El Che left Cuba?
You did those drawings.
Amazing. I still have them.
Now it's your turn
to do as he did.
Remember that time
he went to Congo.
dressed as a business man.
suit, tie and all?
With a Uruguayan passport
under the name
"Ramón Benitez Fernández."
That's how nobody recognized him.
And in Bolivia he went by the name
"Adolfo Mena González"
and also wore a suit.
And you laughed that he shaved
his head as if he had gone bald.
And those glasses...
But your favorite detail
was the hat he wore...
So, handsome.
this is your mission.
You've already chosen a name.
You're no longer Juan.
From now on you're...
Ernesto.
So, what about the World Cup?
We don't discuss soccer,
but congratulations
on winning the Cup.
World champions -
gotta give it to us, huh?
Welcome to our country.
l'll go make a call
across the street.
Meet you at the bar.
Stay here. We'll be right back.
What's up, kiddo?
Uncle!
- Why're you here?
- Cool it.
We don't want to attract a crowd!
- What're you doing 'ere?
- "Doing 'ere?"
That Cuban accent will get us killed!
Pretend we saw each other yesterday.
Now we get up,
calmly walk over there
and continue the trip.
Carmen and Gregorio?
Carmen and Gregorio are gone.
You're with me now.
- How awesome is this van?
- Oi, awesome van.
What do you mean
"oi", awesome van?
We say "hey" here.
Stay calm. Don't talk.
l'll do the talking.
- Documents.
- Hello, officer.
Juan, you have to repeat it
over and over.
You can't hesitate. remember.
You're no longerJuan.
you're Ernesto.
Kiddo!
CLANDESTINE CHILDHOOD
Mom?
Dad?
Morning, kiddo!
Put some shoes on,
you'll freeze.
Morning, handsome!
Had a good night's rest?
Boy, did l miss you!
- Okay...
- Don't you love me anymore?
- Chilly, huh?
- We miss the tropical warmth.
- So what's this place?
- The shed.
Here we pack the peanuts,
hang our things, everything.
Not this, You know better.
Good, aren't they?
Somebody left
the fridge open outside!
- l already said that.
- Who do we have here? Fidel Castro?
That accent again!
Wait.
Actually we come from Córdoba.
So you want him
to do the Córdobes sing-song?
Too hard.
Try the Buenos Aires accent.
- Our papers say we're from Córdoba.
- The kids won't notice.
lt's easier for him.
Give it a shot,
see what you got.
Practice, kiddo!
lt's hot.
l'm Ernesto Estrada.
Hang on...
Give me your glasses.
- Cut it out.
- Give me your glasses.
Please!
Sir...
Go on.
All set...
l'm Ernesto,
l come from Córdoba,
an Argentine province.
Look.
This is your hiding place.
lf anything happens, you come here.
lt opens like this.
Come on in.
- Really?
- Yes.
lt opens here
and closes here.
Neat!
Awesome!
Good morning.
Stand up!
Good morning, Headmistress.
Sit down.
Children...
l want you to meet
your new classmate, Ernesto.
He's from Córdoba
and lives in our neighborhood.
Ernesto, this is Zulma,
your new teacher.
Hello, Ernesto,
nice to meet you.  Welcome.
- Cat got your tongue?
- Hello.
Now go and sit next to Maxi.
Will you make room for him?
Good day.
Good day, Zulma.
Good day, Headmistress.
You may sit now.
Get your things out, Ernesto.
So, we've covered Columbus,
his arrival in America.
Now, what was the most important thing
the Spaniards brought?
Yes, Esteban.
The Spaniards brought Spanish.
That wasn't the most important thing.
- Anybody? Yes...
- Culture.
- Well done!
- The Catholic religion.
Culture, our Catholic religion...
Civilization.
The Spaniards brought civilization.
Hand me that.
And why is ours missing the sun?
Because we use the original one,
created by Belgrano,
just blue and white.
- Hand me that.
- Belgrano? Who's he?
He's the creator
of the Argentine flag, kiddo.
And he made it based on the rosette.
Remember that?
The blue and white thing
we wear on national holidays?
Yeah, the little circle.
Hand me the last one.
But the flag with the sun
was later chosen
as the war flag
and that's the one that stuck.
Hey!
What are you up to, kiddo?
Don't touch, remember?
Come in.
- Can they remove the blindfolds?
- No, the blinds first. Beto...
You can take off the blindfolds.
- Good to see you.
- This way.
Form a line, please.
Attention!
Eyes on compañero Daniel.
At ease!
Right, compañeros, from now
until this meeting is over,
the house and group
are under my command.
On this day, we assemble
the Special Agitation Troops,
Platoons 1 and 2.
Compañera Charo
will hand out your defense tools.
Signal interference tools
will follow presently.
Charo...
Compañero Pedro,
here are your gun, magazine,
chamber empty of ammo.
Compañera Lucía,
here are your gun...
Easy...
Before we start the instruction...
Beto.
A moment for our compañeros
fallen in the revolutionary fight.
- Compañero Marcos.
- Here!
- Compañero Gregorio.
- Till victory.
- Always.
- Perón or death!
- Long live our homeland!
You suffer because I'm pushed away
By a hope of tomorrow
That I look painstakingly
Only for you
A string of stars
Warmly breaking
Your beautiful eyes
Mourning me thus
Dreams of youth
that die in your good-bye
Timid remembrance that I will miss
Songs of hope that I kindled
Caressing your soul in my solitude
My poor heart doesn't think straight
And when it gets pushed away from you
It can only weep
It can only moan
Bleeds to death in your good-bye
lt's one of those complex decisions,
but that's why we're here,
to raise awareness, reinforce our ideas.
Justice, justice for all!
- My turn...
- Forget it.
- Why?
- You can't see.
- Check Natalia out.
- Get outta here!
There's some serious eye candy.
- Which one?
- Not that one, she's ugly!
- With the blue stripes?
- No, the red one.
That one in blue, stretching.
Yeah, some pair of legs!
You don't know
the first thing about legs.
Oh, shut up!
At least l got juice.
- Well done, Natalia!
- Quit it!
Feli, look,
your sister's up next.
Hope she falls,
after what she did to me.
- She's always up to something!
- She's impossible.
She's hot.
Can't be that bad...
She's horrible!
You're crazy!
- l'd totally screw her.
- What?
You prick!
Córdoba, are you on the moon?
Somebody else
has a crush on your sister.
Me? Not at all.
"Me", Córdoba!
You ruined this picture.
First time in front of a camera?
You could at least smile!
Mom...
l have a camping trip.
When?
October 12th.
lt's just one night.
l suppose it's alright.
What is it?
Anything else?
l wanted to ask you something.
How did you know that dad was...
Well, not that...
that you liked him.
l dunno.
You get a feeling in your tummy like...
just different.
- Sounds strange.
- lt is strange.
A mutual friend threw a party
and that's how l met him.
lt was in a basement.
When he showed up,
he looked at me,
gave me a big smile,
and l just fell for him.
So, it was love at first sight.
You could say that.
At least for me.
Your dad played hard to get.
lt took two months to win him over.
We became friends,
he talked to me.
l loved his eyes,
his way of putting things,
so earnestly.
And those glasses he wore!
- What's your story?
- What?
- What are you up to?
- With what?
- Don't beat about the bush.
- There's nobody.
Seriously.
l just wanted to know...
how it felt.
You fancy a classmate.
l could kill the little brat.
You're mine, all mine!
Mine, mine!
Who is it? Who is it?
Nobody.
What happened?
lt was a set-up.
Fuck!
- Are you alone?
- Yes, l am.
- What happened?
- lt was a trap.
Gallego, the son of a bitch!
Are you alright?
- Let me see.
- What is it, Beto?
- Stop it!
Let me see.
Tell me everything, dammit!
l got there 10 minutes early
to scout the place.
lt looked OK. At the arranged time,
l turn the corner.
The guy's sitting on the sidewalk.
He gets up,
pretends to drop his wallet...
Son of a bitch!
He stoops to pick it up...
He glances sideways.
l follow his gaze
and these two guys see me staring.
Fuckers!
So l ran away,
firing three shots,
down into the tube station
and hid in a bathroom.
What's going on, Daniel?
We've been snitched on.
What do l know?
Shit!
- Sure you were alone?
- Yes!
Hide, Juan!
You checked, Beto?
Yes, l checked!
Easy there, Vicky.
Easy.
Hush, please.
Here, baby.
Everything alright?
lt was nothing, nothing.
Hi.
- l saw you yesterday.
- You did?
- Real good, that thing you do.
- Thank you.
l'm Ernesto.
Yes, l know.
l'm María.
Arms' length!
Ernesto, as you're new,
you have the honor of raising the flag.
l can't.
- What do you mean?
- lt's just l don't want to.
Don't be shy, come on.
- l'm not going.
- Ma'am, can l go?
Coward!
Didn't they teach patriotism
in your province?
Coward!
Fight! Fight!
l can't figure this out.
To fight for not wanting
to raise the flag?
First time ever.
You see, Ernesto is very shy.
He doesn't like crowds.
We can't tolerate fighting.
But he's adjusting, isn't he?
Well, boys, stand up,
and shake hands.
Go on then!
Stand up and shake hands.
Just silly squabbles, ma'am.
Shake hands.
A man must learn
to forgive certain things.
Shake hands, then.
Go on.
Shake hands with your friend.
Go on!
There. And don't let this happen again!
What's wrong
with the school flag?
- What?
- What's wrong with it?
- The sun!
- And?
"And?"
lt's got the sun on it.
lt's the war flag.
The one used by the military.
Every school in Argentina
uses this flag.
Yes, well, they shouldn't
have the war flag,
but the blue and white one,
created by...
- Belgrano.
- Exactly.
l don't see that changing
any time soon,
so it's stupid
to get into a fight over that.
Hang on...
What's your name in school?
So?
Yeah, you're right.
Come again?
Come again, soldier?
You are right, Colonel!
That's better.
Now go polish!
Plate,
knife...
Ready?
OK, that's enough.
By the way, don't forget
to have those authorizations signed
or you won't go camping.
Can we carry on?
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday. Ernesto
Way to go, Córdoba!
What happened?
lt's my birthday today.
Right, October 7th.
- Did they say anything at school?
- Say?
They sang happy birthday and...
there's a party on Saturday.
What do you mean, a party?
They were all singing,
even the teacher.
They chanted ''When's the party?''
And l said it.
- Said what?
- Party on Saturday.
Dammit!
Couldn't you have said something else?
We're throwing a party!
Party, party!
lt's OK.
lt's only a party.
With everything that's going on!
l don't want presents.
That's not the point, honey.
We're not in a party mood now.
Don't worry, sis-in-law.
Here's what l'll do: l'll make a piñata.
A shit-loaded piñata?
No shit.
Better fill it with trinkets!
- And the cake?
- l'll bake it.
Why not dress up like a clown?
- Hi.
- For you, troll!
- No.
- l wanted a word with you.
- Me?
- Today's my birthday.
- So l heard.
Who told you?
- Wassup, Córdoba?
- This troll.
- Shut up, stupid!
- Go clean up.
Hey, what's up?
Get lost, will you?
No, wait, don't go.
l came to confirm my party.
You already did in school.
- But l came to invite her.
- Her? What for?
- She said she wasn't going.
- l didn't.
- You said it was a rug rats party.
- lgnore him.
Can l bring a friend?
Yeah, sure.
Thanks.
Thanks for the invitation.
Bye, María.
"Bye, María."
What bit you, Córdoba?
Great!
Where the fuck's your uncle?
Wake up!
Where's your uncle?
He went to get
my present in the van.
Listen, kiddo.
l'm OK with the party,
but you have to help us
keep things under control.
Sure, Dad, don't worry.
These boxes go in my room,
l'm locking it.
Your friends
can't touch the door.
OK, Dad.
This is important! lt's serious.
Finally, dammit!
- Where were you, Beto?
- Wait...
l have a surprise.
A surprise?
A little surprise.
Well, maybe not for you.
Alright?
What is this?
Grandma!
- Out you get.
- Pumpkin!
Careful with the head.
Like before. Sit down.
Perfect.
- Pumpkin?
- Here.
Well done, Amalita.
Let me remove the blindfold.
Curtain call...
Pumpkin, dearest!
How big you've grown, my love!
So tall!
Hello there!
How are you?
Charo! Come here!
Mom!
What're you doing here?
Vicky, look, granny!
Almost a year old?
So, what do you think
of uncle's present?
Asshole! Why did you bring
Amalia here? Are you crazy?
Calm down, man.
l took every precaution.
l don't care
about the precautions.
This is totally against
our safety measures!
Relax, trust me.
l took every precaution.
Listen, how many times
must l repeat myself?
Life isn't a big adventure.
You're not a kid anymore!
You got it all figured out
and executed, Commander!
Lower your voice, it's not funny.
Chill out, bro.
When will you enjoy this?
Enjoy, Beto? Cut the crap.
Enjoy, brother.
Enjoy that we're here, together.
Appreciate what we're doing.
This is no time to be thrilled,
stupid!
lt's time to be committed!
To grow a pair of balls
and see this through!
- Fuck you!
- Commitment, asshole!
l've been pulling my weight
since l can remember!
- Pull it in the right direction!
- What's that?
This is also
necessary and important!
Or else why do we do
any of this, huh?
This is not the time, Beto!
Not now.
On the contrary. lt's now!
lf l've learned anything
from all these years of shit,
we're building for right now.
Here. With this.
Not with this.
You're a hopeless romantic.
What're you doing there, kiddo?
Come, come, hear us out.
Come here.
- Why do you fight so much?
- 'Cause your dad's clueless.
Your uncle's a jerk!
That's why.
A jerk with his balls
in the right place.
ln the right place?
An Argentine macho!
Run along and pamper Amalita.
Run your little show.
Oh, so you're pissed off
l brought your mother-in-law.
You could've said that
and spared us the drama.
lf it bothers you,
you should've done without a family!
Look at me.
Free as a bird.
You're an asshole, Beto!
- Big Argentine dick!
- Asshole!
OK...
Attention, ladies and gentlemen.
Allow me to quote
on this fine evening
the great poet
whose name l can't recall
and quote his fine verses:
"ln and outty, in and outty,
Beto's in the house,
let's party!"
See how l move my hips!
What're you all standing there for?
Compañero Ernesto, do us
the honor of kicking off this party.
Yes, sir!
A hard choice
between all these fine ladies.
Who'll be the lucky one?
One, two, three!
Bravo!
That was quick.
Who's up next? You.
Let me see those hands!
A free lady for this gentleman
in need of attention.
Don't let me see anyone
without a date.
The night breathes love,
matches will be made,
couples are being born.
Such style!
Look, such style!
Alright!
A drink, Amalita?
- Thank you.
- Something strong?
- Definitely.
- Coming right up...
- l'll never be a doctor.
- No?
There, she's asleep.
- lsn't she cute?
- A cherub.
You can't imagine
how happy l am to see you.
Strange as it is
to see you here,
l'm thrilled you came.
Mom...
l know l'm repeating myself...
but you can't tell anybody
we're here.
Yes, l know
l can't breathe a word.
You're not thinking of staying?
l can't say.
You can't say, but...
Amalita, relax.
Let's just enjoy tonight, OK?
- Cheers, Mom!
- Cheers!
l'll be right back.
Look, l know...
l'm in no condition to discuss...
what you can and can't do,
you're well aware,
but the thing is,
with the situation the country's in...
Well, l just can't understand
why you chose to come back now.
l love you so much!
Tell me about auntie.
- ls she still at home?
- l don't want to discuss her.
l don't want to discuss what you were
discussing. Don't make it harder.
Go to bed, kiddo.
Amalia, relax.
The children and us are alright.
l can see you're alright, but...
l wanted
to propose an arrangement.
The kids come with me
and you...
Are you crazy?
They're my children!
- They're my grandchildren!
- They're my children.
- Don't forget it.
- Don't insist. You know how she feels.
- l won't take orders from her!
- Kiddo, why are you here?
l sent you to bed.
Off you go!
What happened?
Did l miss something?
C'mon!
- This is a party.
- Right.
Cake, anyone?
You haven't drunk anything.
- Cheers.
Horacito...
Surely you understand me
on the children.
l do, Amalia, but it won't happen.
Don't push it.
Here, Mom.
But listen, Horacio, it's risky.
The situation's very...
Amalita...
We're fine, the kids are alright,
you saw them,
they live a normal life.
Normal?
You consider it normal for a kid
to use some name
and have his birthday
on some random date?
Poor pumpkin!
That's normal?
Know what l can't stand about you?
Your fear, your panic.
All your life locked up in fear.
Leave, you're in danger!
They're killing people!
You're such a coward!
Dad was right!
You never did a thing
for anyone!
- You have to leave!
- You don't know me!
You know nothing about my ideas.
lf l die, l'd rather have
compañeros raise my kids
than you.
Hey, Charo...
You want your children
to be guerrillas?
What's the problem?
- Do you know what the point is?
- Yes.
What?
- Getting killed.
- Bitch.
You bitch! You're just pushing my buttons?
Stop it! You must leave!
Enough, enough!
Lower your voices!
No yelling here.
Cut it out, both of you.
And you're an asshole, Beto.
An asshole.
Giant asshole, yup, that's me.
Let's all calm down.
Cool it.
Amalita, you know Cristina.
You know your mother.
So, cut the crap.
Amalia... l see
where you're coming from.
And l see
that you never got any of this
and you don't get it now.
But don't say it's madness,
because it's not.
Deep down you know it.
Horacio...
l know you speak from the heart.
We've known each other for ages.
But l'm scared.
And that's fine, Amalita.
lt's OK to be scared.
We're all scared.
But you have to leave.
lt's very dangerous to stay.
You have to leave.
lt's getting late.
We love you.
Beto...
lt'll be fine, Mom.
- My little darling.
- lt'll be fine, Mom.
l swear it'll be alright.
Juan,
say good-bye to grandma.
My pumpkin.
I remember when you were born.
Your grandma came to meet you.
She was so excited.
You were her first grandchild.
When I told her
we'd decided to call you Juan.
she got all worked up:
"Juan?"she'd say.
"surely after Perón."
It's true.
it wasn't very originalI
Of course we'd named you
after Perón.
She was never able
to call you Juan.
So she calls you Pumpkin.
She said when she first saw you.
you reminded her of a pumpkin.
For how long?
Just two days.
ls your cute friend going?
Yeah, sure.
Well!
There'll be some fishing at camp.
Get off my back.
Why?
Nothing like them!
Nothing in the whole world
beats chicks.
Chicks?
Chicks, chicks...
María's not just any chick.
Sorry.
No need to clarify,
plain as daylight.
l'll let you in on a secret.
OK.
- lnterested or not?
- Yeah, sure.
Take a seat.
Chicks are like...
chocolate-coated peanuts.
- That's rubbish!
- Rubbish?
lt's a secret
only a handful of people know.
You have to know
how to eat them properly.
People just suck all the coating
and are left with the hard peanut
or just bite it right away.
lt's sacrilege.
lt works like this.
No, slow down!
See? You rushed that one.
Now swallow it.
Here, do exactly as l do.
Breathe, deep breath...
Now...
put it on your tongue.
Let it melt slowly.
Feel it?
Nice, right?
Now roll it onto your teeth...
and bite it. Taste it slowly.
See how those two flavors
melt into something else.
Not peanut nor chocolate...
but chocolate-coated peanut.
Got it?
Yes, but... what does all this
have to do with María?
What do you mean?
Everything!
You have to soften chicks up,
but not too much.
And in my opinion, you are
nearly, nearly ready to take the bite.
- You sure?
- Positive.
But how?
lt's in her eyes.
She's ready.
Believe me, do as l say
and you'll do fine.
Thanks, uncle.
I wipe my feet
I climb and climb to the treetop
Fly and fly to the mountaintop
Descend. descend to the basement
Swim and swim to the bottom
I wipe my eyes
I can't see right
To the treetop
I can't see. I can't see
To the mountaintop
To the basement
I can't see. I can't see
To the bottom I can't see
What can it be?
What can it be? What can it be?
I can't see the mountaintop
if I'm at the bottom
I don't see. I can't.
I don't see. I can't
So, am l blind?
No!
You could use a pair
of decent folks' eyeglasses
Decent folks' eyeglasses
You could use a pair
of decent folks' eyeglasses
Decent folks' eyeglasses
I wipe my feet
I climb and climb to the treetop
Fly and fly to the mountaintop
Descend. descend to the basement
Swim and swim to the bottom
Land in sight!
Finally, the lndies!
"What Columbus ignored
is that he had arrived
in an unknown land: America."
Welcome to America!
Oh, Columbus!
We bring you offerings as...
a sign of...
- Fra...
- Fraternity.
Oh, Columbus!
Our lands are your lands.
Our wealth is your wealth.
Oh, Columbus!
We thank God
and the Queen of Spain
for the discovery
of these wonderful lands.
And we embrace the mission
of building a great Christian nation.
We shall educate
and civilize them as per God's will.
Oh, Columbus!
Bravo!
Take a bow, like true actors.
- Shall l touch it?
- No.
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Come here.
Want some?
No, thanks, l don't like it.
You don't?
l just don't.
How can you be friends
with my brother?
He's a jerk.
What's the matter with him?
l don't know, you're different.
You're more...
More what?
Fuck!
Such a foul mouth.
Know where l'd like to go?
Where?
Brazil. Ever been there?
No.
They say the beaches are beautiful,
soft powdery sand, like flour.
My dream's to go there.
Let's go now.
Come on!
Faster, faster!
Look at the palm trees!
l'll kill you, fucking troll!
Such bad taste, Córdoba!
Here, turtle doves!
l look cute, right?
Sort of.
- Shut up.
- Sort of ugly.
Ernesto!
l've gotta run.
- l'll keep it, OK?
- Yeah, my dad would kill me.
Because of a photo?
OK, bye.
We're in that car.
That car?
Dad's driving it. Get in.
What's going on?
Hey, Dad.
Hey, kiddo.
What's going on?
We're leaving for a few days.
Safety reasons.
Why?
What happened?
Uncle Beto.
What?
You heard, love.
Uncle Beto.
Compañeros, on this sad day,
l'd like to remember my brother
with the dignity he deserves.
He once said to me
happiness wasn't about smiling,
but about believing,
having faith.
Believing so hard something is possible
that you make it happen.
And that's how he lived.
He had that characteristic.
Though he enjoyed
everything he did...
he never lost his beliefs.
l'm convinced
he was happy to his last breath.
Here's to my brother's balls!
To compañero Beto!
Here!
- To compañero Beto, dammit!
- Here!
- Perón or death!
- To the motherland!
What happened?
- These things just happen.
- l know.
But l want the truth.
Alright.
We were making a delivery downtown.
Everything was under control.
As l was leaving the place...
l see your uncle with his hands in the air
against the van. A cop behind him.
l don't know what happened.
He must've seen something,
he freaked out, started screaming.
Your uncle tried
to calm him down, but...
suddenly it was swarming with cops.
Beto made a move.
He shouted:
"You won't take me alive!"
Pulled the pin from a grenade...
and pushed the cop into the van.
The whole thing blew up.
Goddammit!
lt was all a matter of seconds.
But l needed him alive.
Who does he think he is?
Kiddo...
l'm going away for a few days.
To see if we can go back home.
l'll miss him too.
l'll never forget him.
Me either.
Uncle!
What's up, kiddo?
Want some?
So, how did it go?
Sweet!
Seriously?
l knew it, that's my boy!
Didn't l say she was ready?
Yeah.
So, now?
What's your next move?
l dunno.
What do you mean?
You're a big boy now!
With María, you mean?
No, that's already in the bag.
l mean your life.
l dunno.
ls that the best you got?
What do you suggest?
l can't help you there.
All l'm saying is...
don't betray yourself.
No matter what,
And you? What happened?
Nothing.
l've got those fuckers under control.
Don't you worry.
You won't take me alive!
Shoot!
Don't move!
I've got those fuckers under control.
Juan!
You have a fever.
Let me see.
Why?
Leave me alone!
Easy...
Hello?
Hello...
María?
Yes. who is this?
Ernesto?
Yes.
Hello?
Yes, l'm here, l'm here.
Hi. how are you?
So sorry about your grandpa.
Yeah, it's too bad.
Poor thing.
Hello? Are you there?
Hi, l'm here.
l wanted to invite you
somewhere you'll love.
What about school?
We'll skip school today.
- Now?
- Come on...
We can miss one day.
What are you doing?
Who was that?
Answer me,Juan,
who was that?
- What's the matter?
- He was on the phone.
- Who was it?
- On the phone?
Answer me!
María.
- Who the fuck's María?
- My girlfriend.
Fuck,Juan!
Girlfriend, my ass, cut the crap!
Just what we need now! Know how
dangerous it is to use the phone?
- Yes, l know.
- So, what's wrong with you?
You know you're not going back
to school anymore. That's over.
Kiddo, you have to help mom pack
and suck it up like a man.
What am l supposed
to stay here for?
Doing what, dammit?
Hey, calm down, lower your voice.
This isn't easy on any of us.
No point getting worked up.
We have to take things
as they come.
Easy for you to say.
Excuse me?
- Nothing.
- Cut the crap,Juan.
You're a big boy!
Bye.
María!
How are you?
Fine.
So you're back?
No, l'm still there,
l'm a ghost.
ldiot.
How was the funeral?
Fine, it was fine.
- Shall we go?
- OK.
l have a confession to make.
l have strong feelings for you.
Here in my stomach.
l feel that too.
You do?
There are things you don't understand,
and that's fine.
And there are other things
you won't understand now.
You know?
l know
l'm not making myself clear.
But this thing l feel is real.
Remember when you said...
l wasn't like the others?
That's it, you see.
l am who you think l am,
only... different.
You know?
Not at all,
but l still think you're cute.
l want to be with you forever.
Promise?
Cross my heart.
Look.
l have a surprise for you.
l've got money, loads of money.
So?
So we can be together.
We can be together forever.
We're together now.
Yes but we'll be able to go
wherever we want.
Go? Now?
We'll be able to go to Brazil.
Brazil? l don't get it.
Didn't you want to?
Look.
This money will get us there.
l can get a job in Brazil.
l can do all sort of things.
Are you crazy?
l won't leave my family!
What about your family?
l love them,
but l want to be with you.
Kiddo...
do you know what I did last night?
I sat in your room watching you sleep.
remembering you
as a little baby breast-feeding.
And to see you now...
All those years gone by so fast!
You're huge, kiddo, a man.
Well... almost a man.
I wondered when I'd next be
taken by surprise to see you.
Perhaps when you're 15 or 20.
what do I know?
But I want you to know
I love watching you grow
and you make me very proud.
I love you very much.
One year after the 1978 World Cup
won by Argentina.
a team of players
from all over the world
came to commemorate this day of glory
for our national sport.
Now. let's change the subject.
The forces oflaw and order
continue their fight on subversion.
Very early this morning.
a clash with several subversives
took place in Munro.
The clash occurred when officers
tried to stop
a suspicious-looking vehicle.
The criminals
were ordered to freeze.
but responded with heavy fire.
During the clash.
the armed forces shot
Horacio Carnevale.
a senior member
of the subversive group Montoneros
and a wanted man
for 6 years...
Dad!
- To compañero Ernesto.
- Here!
- Perón or death!
- Long live the motherland!
To Ernesto, kids.
I rub my eyes
I can't see clearly
To the treetop
I can't see. I can't see
To the mountaintop
To the basement
I can't see. I can't see
To the bottom
What can it be? What can it be?
Shall we rub them properly?
I can't see the mountaintop
if I'm at the bottom
I can't see. I can't
I can't see the treetop
if I'm in the basement
I can't see. I can't
Have l gone blind?
No!
You could use a pair
of decent folks' eyeglasses
Decent folks' eyeglasses
You could use a pair
of decent folks' eyeglasses
Decent folks' eyeglasses
Juan!
He's gone.
Hide!
Calm down, Vicky.
Who's there?
What's your name?
- Ernesto Estrada.
- What?
Ernesto Estrada.
What's your name?
Come on, brat.
Come on.
What's your name?
Ernesto Estrada.
l'm Ernesto Estrada.
l'm 11 years old, l'm in 5th grade.
We come from Córdoba.
Córdoba, and your dad works
at the peanut factory.
So you said, you little brat.
So you said.
lsn't your dad Horacio?
Was.
And your mom's Cristina?
Juancito.
Huh, Juancito?
Go on, we know all about you.
Tell me your name.
Be a good boy, you little brat.
Where's my sister?
Little brat.
You're a little piece of shit.
Think you're so clever!
You little fuck!
Pick up your clothes.
Pick up your clothes!
Pelusa!
C'mon, we're outta here!
ls this your grandmother's place?
l don't know.
What's your grandmother's name?
ls she Amalia?
Get out, then.
- Get out!
- Where's my sister?
Fuck you, kid! Get out!
Who is it?
ls anyone there?
Who is it? Answer me.
lt is Juan.
In memory of my mother Sara E.Zermoglio.
missing since October 13. 1979.
To my brothers, my father, my children.
To all the Children. Grandchildren.
Activists.
and all those
who have kept the faith.
l want to be with you forever.
Promise?
Cross my heart.
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1726888
Infancia Clandestina - Clandestine Childhood (2011) English.srt
FPS: 23.976
With special thanks to: "kev"
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) ALL DVD's to be subtitled.
2) ALL VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled.
3) ALL videos/DVD's used in lessons at school to be subtitled.
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV.
____           __            ___   __              ___        __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _   /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /    /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
- Bringing you free subtitles       /                  Online  /  Since 1993    - /
-  |Africa| |Asia| |Australia| |Europe| |North America| |South America|   -  /
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+                          A big Thank You to EVERYBODY                            +
+        involved in making [closed capture] srt files and supporting us       +
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+