CLAPHAM JUNCTION
30 degrees plus expected today.
In fact we could beat
the record, which stands...
as the 12th of June this year, when
we've got 32, we could even make it...
to 33 degrees today.
And of course it's the persistence...
of that heat - no respite at all.
No let up tonight. 15 degrees...
minimum 15 degrees, one or two
cities could well be pegged into 20s overnight,
and that is really really hot.
How long is this gonna last for?
Well, we've got the breakdown on the way
tomorrow so at least another 24 hours...
Look to the right.
Look up.
That was very good Danny.
- You're keeping well, are you?
- Yes, thanks.
- I must say you're looking well.
- Good, thank you.
- Surviving this heat, heh?
- Just about.
- Pretty scorching innit?
- Yes it is.
O-K!
So, fire away.
The giving of a band,
signifies the promise of a love...
...that is ever lasting,
and is a public affirmation, ...
that the contract between
Will and Gavin will be honoured.
- Will?
- This ring is a token of my abiding love...
...and a sign of the promise
I make to you today.
Bishop can be a bit of a prick
when it comes to poofs.
And as for old Wurzel down at Lambeth Palace,
she's got her knickers in a right twist.
- Would you like a top up, sir?
- Oh, how kind.
- How do you stand the strain?
- I may be ++++
...but I still believe in
Jesus Wants Me For A Sunbeam.
Oh, er, waiter.
Bring us a few more lovely sausages, will you?
So then we go back to
where we were at the start...
...with that guy in the truck...
...and we realise Chris has said
fuck off to the lot of them, and...
...decided to make a new start in London.
And, um, well, that's about it.
Er, you see, Robin, the thing is, erm,
you know I am a great fan.
- Oh you don't like it.
- You do know that, don't you?
- You don't, do you?
- I just feel we've been there before.
- No we haven't?!
- I mean, the whole gay thing.
- Is that an issue anymore?
- It is if you're gay.
That's what you have to ask yourself.
Is it still an issue?
- Anyway, this is more than that...
- Because, I don't think it is.
You know what, with
Elton and David,
and Ian and, well, everyone.
You know, what's the problem?
It's been done.
We've moved on.
- It's accepted.
- But, the way this would approach..
I mean, if you make it
a bit more like Gary Glitter.
- Gary Glitter?!
- Vietnam, Cambodia, the whole sex tourist thing,
then, maybe, maybe.
But the whole sex tourism thing
has been done to death.
As it is, it's not for me.
I'm sorry, it just isn't.
Look, I'm so keen to
work on something with you.
I mean you know that.
But this, sorry, it's a no.
- You're still married?
- Yes.
Well done. I'm seeing
Dunstan next week.
- Are you?
- Shall I send him your love?
- I wouldn't bother.
- No, best not.
Well I leave you then.
He reached grade seven.
Miss Richard says if he carries
on like this, he could get to...
- the Royal College of Music.
- That's marvellous Dolly
- He is a good boy.
- You must be so proud.
You know, it makes me weep for joy.
I want so hard to get him that fiddle.
You know, you should
give him Mrs. H.
- Well, I'd love to, Dolly.
- He play like an angel.
- So, what you're having then?
- Monkfish cheeks and ceps.
Excuse me, sir. The sausages.
- Thank you. That accent, I can't quite...
- Shropshire sir ++++.
30 degrees I've got here that says it all.
That's for the central London.
Nan, I'm back!
Of course that's where
most of the population are.
Hello nan!
- Darling.
- Bleeding hot, isn't it? D'you want anything?
- How about a nice cuppa, eh?
Hi, me. Yes, I'm gonna be a bit late.
I've got to pop over to St Luke's.
Oh, some mini-crisis or other.
Probably nothing, but you know how it is.
Well, of course I'll try.
But tell them not to wait.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Yes, I will. I promise. Bye.
- You look at my arse, innit?
- Are you looking at his arse?
- Was there any calls nan?
- Just the one.
- And which one was that, then?
- It was your mum.
- Oh, yeah?
- She wants to see you, darling.
- Don't start, nan.
- She said she hasn't touched a drop in weeks.
- She is a liar, Nan.
- She ain't, Terry, she's a good girl.
- No, she ain't, Nan.
- Might be lots of things, but she ain't no liar.
- She is a good girl at heart.
- No, she ain't, Nan.
- She IS Terry, she is a good girl.
- No, she ain't.
- D'you want an 'am salad?
- Give her a call, Tel.
- I ain't calling her.
- She wants to see you.
- No she don't, Nan.
- She does, Terry.
There was a time she could've
me all she liked.
If anything happens, you won't
be able to live with yourself.
D'you want an 'am salad
or something hot?
- Do it for me, darling.
- I'll do you a salad but I ain't speaking to her.
Gavin has taught me how to love.
To love him, to love myself.
This is forever, honey. And if it ain't,
well, you've got one hell of a pre-nup.
So let's all get slaughtered.
Bottoms up!
Come on, then, gorgeous.
- Skiving off, are you?
- No, sir, it's my break.
I'm paying for all this, you know.
It doesn't come cheap.
I don't expect it does, sir.
You know it's very, very charming
that you should call me sir.
You really don't have to.
- So, Ludlow.
- Yeah.
- Very nice.
- Yeah. Bit on the quiet side.
- Mm. It is a bit, I suppose.
Nice enough.
- Ludlow. Nice castle.
- Yeah.
Very nice. I love that part of the world.
- You've never been, have you?
- Somewhere up north, isn't it?
- Help yourself.
- No, no. Not when I'm on duty.
It's my wedding.
- It's a beautiful ring.
- We had them made specially.
- He must think the world of you.
- It's too big though. The jeweller fucked up.
- Could have it altered.
- You don't wanna go loosing it.
You're right there.
Gotta watch your ring, haven't you?
- Y'know that's incredible.
- What is?
This wedding. I never, ever thought
I'd live to see the day...
...two blokes getting married. I mean,
it's just fantastic, isn't it?
I suppose it is.
Gavin and I have lived together for so long.
Yeah, it is pretty fantastic.
- You're blushing.
- It's hot.
No, no, I'd better get back.
Where have you been?
I was expecting you ages ago!
- I had to go to the library.
- Christ, we're gonna be late as usual.
Darling, use a glass.
You will be allright, won't you?
Of course I will.
Why don't you go and
see Benjy or someone?
I don't like the thought of you being by yourself
and it is going to be such a lovely night.
- Mum, I'll be fine.
- Got that gorgeous humous which you like...
- ...and some lovely yummy fresh baguette from.
- Mum, I'm OK.
Oh, I know you are darling.
Must go and put a face on.
If your father calls tell him to get his arse in gear
- Not going, are you?
- Yeah, I'm finished.
- Pity.
- End of my shift.
I'll tell you what.
I'm living with a mate at the moment,
south of the river, ...
...but I'm moving into my own
pad next week.
I mean it's only rented, like,
but I'm really excited.
- I bet.
- I left home, made the move to London, ...
...got my own job and then
my own pad. Brilliant.
Brilliant.
So what is this place then?
Pantry.
- What did they use it for?
- ++++.
You're full of it, aren't you?
I just love London. Always knew
I would and you know something?
- What?
- I do.
Charlie with the groom, ...
- ...I'll lose my job.
- Not with me behind you.
Christ, I'd like to lick the hairs
on the back of your neck.
You just got married.
You should have other things on your mind.
You going somewhere nice
for your honeymoon, then?
Eventually.
Gav's back to work tomorrow.
- What is he do?
- He makes people better.
- What do you do?
- I just make money.
Will you be missed?
- Not here?
- Where then?
- We shouldn't be doing this.
- Come on.
As honest as the day is long, huh?
Don't want to end up lonely, Tel.
No Nan.
I've got you ain't I?
Who are you going to have?
- I'm worried for you.
- I'll be alright, Nan.
I do. I worry for you.
Leave it out, Nan.
We all need someone, darling.
Oh, I'll find someone, Nan.
Don't you worry.
Come here.
- My mobile.
- Oh, what?
- I want to see you again.
- You can't.
- Call me.
- No.
- You will, you know.
- You're sure of yourself, aren't you?
Bye then.
You've gotta lovely arse.
And you've gotta lovely husband.
- Where the hell have you been?
- I'm sorry.
I was running out of excuses,
what have you been up to?
Oh, for christ's sake, give me some.
I've been twisting with the vicar.
- Very pure, don't overdue it.
- I was beginning to thing you'd had second thoughts.
- Where's the ring?
- It's in my wallet, kept slipping off.
- I know I gave him the right measurements.
- It's allright, I'll take it in tomorrow.
A pint please.
- Hot, innit?
- Yeah.
- I think you'd gone.
- Nah I ain't gone.     - Good.
- I'm Alfie, by the way.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- You don't meet many Alfies.
Let me introduce you to...
No, it's OK.
My mun rang just before I left. I told her
I was doing a wedding, but I didn't tell her it was gay.
- She wouldn't have minded it, would she?
- I don't know. She probably knows everything anyway.
Yeah, mums usually do.
- Nice.
- Yeah, if you like that sort of thing.
- Pissed all down my trousers.
- Oh, yeah?
Still, you won't mind that, will you?
I said it don't go there.
But he don't listen, know what I mean?
He's a knob.
He kept pushing. And I kept telling him
and then the fucking thing snapped.
- A right knob.
- About 30 quids worth.
- He should get the boot.
- I've been fucking saying that.
- Hello, Rog.
- Hey, Robin.
- How are you?
- Oh, I'm OK.
- Fucking knackered.
Come on and have a drink.
What can I get you?
- Robin!
- Fancy one of these?
You're looking so well, isn't he, Roger?
- Greatful clients sent me a couple of cases of that.
- Oh, I've got you this.
- You shouldn't have.
- And I must say, it's bloddy nice. Here you are.
- And you've put on a little bit of weight.
- Do you think?     - Yeah, it's good.
- See what you think.
- Thanks, cheers.
Fucking...
See how I trust my lovely
Shropshire lad! You've got to call me now.
Silly bastard!
- Something about summer, isn't there?
- Yeah.
Gets the old sap rising. Ever get the feeling
sometimes that you're missing out.
- That the party is going on without you.
- You don't feel that, do you?
It's all a bit aimless, you know.
Sort of chugging along.
Something about the kids going to university.
I feel a bit itchy in the foot department.
I want to play the field again.
Well, I've been playing the field since I
was 15, it's not all it's cracked up to be.
I need women.
I just love them, you know?
Well, you've got one.
It's not the same though, is it?
So what's your name then?
Smithy.
Smithy? I like that.
Yeah?
What's yours then?
Mickey.
Irish, are you?
No.
You said you live around here.
Not far.
- So is this your patch then?
- Yeah, sort of.
How about you?
No.
I'm from outside London.
Oh, yeah?
And where is that then?
Sussex.
Sussex, hey?
Very nice, very nice.
Whereabouts in Sussex?
Nutley.
Nutley?
I ain't never heard of Nutley.
- That's my mum.
- Oh yeah?
She died.
Few months ago, of a heart attack,...
...she is out of the blue.
I don't half miss her.
- My mum died not so long ago.
- Did she?
What did she die of?
She got run down.
What?
You mean depressed, like?
No. By a mailvan.
- You're kidding.
- No, I'm not.
They drive like fucking maniacs, those guys.
That's terrible.
- You know what?
- What?
She was posting a
letter at the time.
Christ, I'm...
Yeah, it makes you think, don't it?
- I envy you. You've got freedom, no ties.
- But look at you, you've got a proper job.
Big-time barrister and a criminal
amount of money. Wife and kids.
You're a proper grown up. I live in a
state of perpetual adolescence.
I'm an adolescent at heart.
I still enjoy football,
good wank.
It was good, wasn't it?
The school and that.
Yeah, yes it was.
Christ, I need a fuck!
Hot, isn't it?
Orphans in the storm, heh?
Yeah.
I like this one.
Can we just...
Can we have it up a bit?
Yeah.
Yeah OK.
- Such a bloody nightmare.
- It doesn't matter.
- He was so late back!
- Big recycling meeting about this filing business.
- You just have to put your foot down!
- I just couldn't leave.
- Bloody council!
- I'm sorry.
- It doesn't matter, really.
- I had a costume fitting and I was ready.
- Why are you doing this?
- Cos I hate fucking Pet Shop Boys!
- Is Minty here?
- I'm afraid she had to cry off.
- Oh, no.
- Well, she's practically dead with hay fever, so...
- Let me get you a drink.
- Have you been at the Botox?
- No, I haven't!
- Oh, I must say you're looking suspiciously fresh.
Roger and Robin are in the garden.
Robin?
Yeah, I'm sure you've met.
He's that old school
friend og Roger's.
- Oh, isn't he the..
- Writer.
That's right.
White?
Yeah, please.
Shut the fuck up!
Won't mind a bit of piss,
you said.
How do you like it
you filthy cocksucker?
Huh?
That's nice, is it?
How nice is that?
You pathetic little shit!
How proud would Mummy
be now, hey?
- I'm doing Howards End.
- Very nice, what are you playing?
- Mrs Willcocks.
- Oh, great!
I'm afraid I don't know it.
Oh, you must! Vanessa Redgrave
played her in the movie.
So, it's been done before, then.
Everything's been done before.
They only do things now that have been done before.
- That seem to be the case.
- It's never been done on television.
- I think it has.
- No, I'm sure it hasn't.
I think you're right. In the '70s.
- How would you know, you never watch TV.
- I did in the '70s.
- Who is doing it?
- Well, Frank Winston has commissioned it.
- Did he now?!
- Do you know him?
I had a meeting with him this morning
as a matter a fact.
Darling, isn't he?
Top up?
Something's always
intrigued me about Howards End.
It's such an intriguing novel.
Whether or not it's
got an apostrophe.
Isn't it supposed to be the end of Howard,
well the end of several Howards?
Or is it just Howard's end?
Anyway, I'm thrilled to bits.
I'm sorry Belinda. I just have to pop
something into little Albert.
I've bought him the cutest little cap.
He looks so adorable.
Hello, mate.
Where are you off to, then?
Excuse me.
Come here!
- Hello there, mate.
- Sorry I'm late, Roger.
Christ, you look fucked!
Do I?
You could do with a stiff one.
Gotcha!
Beinda and I met at Pilates. I showed her
some photographs of little Albert.
He is my grandson and we just
hit off immediately.
- She is lovely, isn't she?
- Yes, she is.
- Are you married?
- No, I'm gay.
Oh, how nice!
Have you got a.. what do they call it..
a civil partner?
Not at the moment, no.
Oh...
Would you like a Pringle?
Oh, my hubby at last!
Sorry, darling.
You don't know Robin, do you?
No, we don't.
Close your mouth, darling,
you look like a carp.
Robin and I were at school together.
Pleased to meet you.
God, what was that?
What?
It sounded like a scream or something.
It was probably a fox being fucked.
I've got your pen.
Your Parker ballpoint.
You dropped it in the library
this afternoon.
I found it.
And I thought I'd bring it over.
Can't I come in?
Why?
So I can give it to you.
You can give it to me here.
But I'd like to...
What?
...come in.
You can't.
- Why not?
- Because I don't want you to.
- Because I don't.
You're not doing anything.
How do you know?
Look, you give me the pen
or I'll shut the door.
- Move.
- I thought it might be nice...
...to have a chat.
A chat?
Yes.
I don't want to have a chat.
I don't know you.
- You would if we had a chat.
- Look, just shove off!
Move your foot and piss off!
No more games. Just get back
home to Mummy and Daddy, OK?
- They are out.
- Go back and wait for them.
Don't you want your pen?
- What are you so worried about?
- I'm worried I'm gonna belt you one
if you don't get the fuck out.
You wouldn't.
Don't push it.
I beg you.
Why can't I stay for a minute?
What's wrong with that?
We've always seen
each other in the library.
What's the problem?
I'm bored to death over there reading and
I don't want to go to bed yet.
I just...
...thought we could have a chat.
Five minutes, that's all, then
I'll go, I promise.
You're doing history, aren't you?
I'm doing history too.
Amongst other things.
Are you at college?
What's your favourite period?
I quite like Hitler.
Not the bloke.
But, you know,
the Third Reich and all that.
Is that it, then?
What?
Our chat.
We'll probably find a few
other things to talk about.
You needn't have pushed so hard.
Well, you put your
foot in the door.
Do you think I could have
a glass of water?
- Ah!
- Your arse looks nice.
Here we go.
We're married!
We are fucking married!
Keep it down!
Thanks.
Thank you.
Have you had a fire?
Yeah.
What happened?
I had an accident.
I left the toaster on.
You should tell someone.
I told you.
It's a lousy neighbourhood, isn't it?
This side of the street, it is.
I don't like people around here
too much, do you?
I wouldn't know,
I keep myself to myself.
That's difficult to do, though,
sometimes, isn't it?
You haven't been here long,
have you?
No, I haven't.
I don't know about you
but I'm tired. Good night.
Good night.
It's not that late.
You wanna be home for your
mum and dad.
They won't be back for ages.
I wanna turn in.
My foot hurts.
I told you, you shouldn't
have put it in the door.
I'm Theo by the way.
- Who are you?
- Tim. Now fuck off!
Do you think I could have
another glass of water, please, Tim?
He is 18 months.
- Yes, you said.
- Little Albert.
I wasn't so sure about the "Albert"
but it's starting to grow on me.
Good job he wasn't called Ivy.
He does make me laugh. I popped in
earlier - I was telling Belinda - I...
...had to give him the cutest little
cap. Like Andy Roddick wears.
- Now, he IS cute.
- And he was prancing around without his...
He is so proud of his willy.
I think it is a stage that boys go through.
And it is surprisingly big,
isn't it, Julian?
And he climbed onto my lap and
tried to push it into my button hole.
- It can't be that big then.
- Oh, they were very big buttons.
And in the end I just couldn't
resist and had to kiss it.
Mmm, lovely!
Why are you always by yourself?
It's how I like it.
Don't you have any friends?
All the chat...
All the rubbish.
It needn't be like that.
Yeah.
Well...
I've never mugged in.
I've always been ever
so slightly shunned.
By my lot, ...
...your lot.
Not quite up there.
You get used to it out on a limb, ...
...not quite up there enough.
We could be friends.
No, we couldn't.
Of course we could.
You're, what, ...
14?
15?
I'm coming up for 30.
We don't have anything in common.
We can naver be friends.
You've seen me before, haven't you?
You live up the road.
I mean, you've noticed me.
You've looked at me, haven't you?
And in the library...
You've looked at me like I've
looked at you, that's all I'm saying.
You'd better go.
Can I have some lager, please?
No.
Go on...
- Mom and Dad let me have a drop sometimes.
- Then go home and have a drop!
You are very quiet tonight, Julian.
You all right?
Poor bloke's knackered!
Give him a break!
I am pretty tired, actually.
- Working late, were you?
- He is always working late, aren't you darling?
Oh, that's no good,
all work and no play!
- That's what I tell him.
- You should let your hair down once in a while.
Exactly! Do you know something, Robin, ...
- I think you should take him in hand.
- You don't need me to take you in hand, do you, Julian?
That's enough. Enough, OK?
I'm sorry, I really am pretty wiped out.
- Darling, would you like us to go?
- No.
I'm sorry.
No, please, don't.
We all get a bit scratchty
when the pressure is on.
Another stiff one, eh?
That should do the trick.
Thank you.
You got a light?
Oh, yes.
Sorry.
Nice, innit? The moon.
Oh yes, yes it is.
- You been here long?
- Not long, no.
- What, live around here, do you?
- No.
Whereabouts then?
- Out west.
- Out west, eh?
Yes.
Very nice.
Yes, it is.
So how did you get in here then,
on a bus?
I drove.
Oh yeah?
What car you got?
- Very inquisitive, aren't you?
- Bother you, does it?
No. No.
That's allright then.
It's an Audi.
An Audi, eh? One of them big fuckers or
like one of them little hairdresser type?
A4 estate.
You've got a family then?
No.
It makes you wonder doesn't it?
Why that star is next to that one?
That one is next to that?
I suppose it does.
Do you know what I think?
No.
I think it means fuck all!
It's bleeding hot, innit?
Yes, it is.
I wouldn't half like
to see your A4 estate.
- Would you?
- Oh, yeah!
I love a big motor.
Mickey.
Joe.
Hello, Joe.
What was that?
It was over there.
Joe!
Fuck!
Help me.
Alfie, innit?
Is this yours, Alfie?
Please, help me.
That's a little diamond, innit?
What's this next to it?
Looks like a sapphire to me.
What do you reckon, Alfie?
Sapphire, is it?
And it's not yours you say.
Get help.
Well, that is nice.
Very nice indeed.
By the middle of 2010, we aim to cut
our carbon emissions by at least...
Darling, we really don't want
to hear about Camden's carbon footprint.
... by at least 20 per cent.
Do we, Robin?
- Julian?
- Actually, I think it's rather interesting.
See, darling, no one does.
No, I've always got on with gay men.
I have, really.
They are so funny,
and unthreatening.
In fact we've got quite a few
gay friends, haven't we Julian?
I have never counted.
But I have to admit, there is
a part of me that's rather old-fashioned.
I do love the idea of strong, protective man,
battling out in the field, and then...
...returning home for some vigorous impregnation!
- No dissention there, old chap!
- Don't you think you should go outside?
- Does anybody want me to go outside?
- No, it's fine.
But you wouldn't do that
sort of thing, would you, Robin?
I'm sorry, I don't know
what you are talking about.
- Well, you know, having it away in bushes.
- Marion!
It does seem rather irresponsible.
It depends, doesn't it?
I'm sure any of us would have it
anywhere if you felt desperate about.
Hmm?
And, some of them, and I
don't mean you, Robin, ...
...they do tend to push it in your face.
You could say that.
None of this sniffing around in the dark.
It is a bit doggy like, isn't it?
- And is it really necessary?
- Marion!
I mean, we accept you now,
can't you behave like normal people?
- I think you've made your point.
- Perhaps we enjoy sniffing around in dark places.
Perhaps we find this acceptance
you refer to is slightly boring.
Perhaps we miss that
little jolt of excitement.
What do you think, Julian?
I think we can all do with a little
bit of excitement in our lives.
So I suppose I'd have to agree.
Really?
There's so much for you lot with all that...
...clubs and things and cottages
and black rooms.
Dark room.
Do you go clubbing much?
No, I don't.
No, I don't suppose you do, considering.
Considering what?
That you haven't been too well, have you?
I don't go clubbing any more probably
for the same reason that you don't.
We're past it.
Anyway, how do we know that this...
...poor chap outside was...
...sniffing around as you say.
He could have just been walking.
And we don't even know that he is gay.
In any case...
...even if he was sniffing around and fucking
like a dog in the bushes, does it matter?
He was in the most dreadful,
appalling state.
And no one, no one deserves
to be treated like that.
Have you seen me at night?
Watching you?
I kneel by the window.
With a fag.
Haven't you noticed?
When your curtains are open...
...I watch you.
I watch you and I wank.
You watch me...
...and you wank...
...with a fag.
Why?
Isn't it obvious?
I mean...
...why have you got a fag?
I always smoke when I wank.
You're not angry, are you?
It's not funny!
No.
No, I know it's not.
It's OK.
Really.
There's a man opposite us lives in
that council block - ghastly place.
Here we go.
What do you mean "here we go"?
Young man...
Not unatractive, but something about him.
Simply because he is a quiet type?
- Have you ever spoken to him?
- No.
- Well, there we are then.
- I haven't spoken to lots of people by us.
You have no idea what he is like!
- They do say...
- Ahh, they!
...that he has been inside...
- ...for interfering with youngsters.
- That's a rumour.
- You smoked the whole pack?
- Who the fuck cares?
Wouldn't he be on a list or something?
These things aren't foolproof!
Have you ever seen him
with any youngsters?
Of course I haven't!
I'm far too busy.
People are...
...they are scared being different.
You are not gonna understand that.
It takes a lot of courage.
But...
...if you can be what you are...
...not what you think you should be...
...you'll be happy enough...
...and understand yourself...
...and you can face anything.
If you get sad...
...your luck goes.
I've seen you.
I've seen you lots.
But it's no good.
You've got to go.
You've...
Please, go.
Please!
I know for a fact that
his flat was attacked.
Poor chap.
- Petrol bomb, through the window.
- It's terrible.
- Fortunately he was in so the flat didn't burn down.
- Did he get hurt?
I don't know.
Probably the kids.
Well, it was! And they did it
because of what they heard.
And they are fucking
bigoted parents!
- I want to go.
- Nat.
- I want to see how my baby is.
- He'll be fine.
- I don't like leaving him.
- We've done it before.
I want to go!
I really find your complacency
quite unbelievable.
Just because he is keeping himself to himself
doesn't mean there's anything sinister going on.
Those stories don't come out of just
thin air, there must be some reason for them.
Well, imagine if they're true, hm?
What if he started interfering
with Theo?
Sorry.
Hang on.
OK.
Try again.
Slowly.
Slowly. Yeah.
Oh yeah!
- You do understand, don't you?
- Of course.
Funny old night with all that nastiness over the road.
And I just want to go and give him a big hug.
- I'd love to see him again.
- He is gorgeous, he is a bit moody, but...
- How old is he now.
- Nearly 15.
What a lovely evening.
Monkfish cheeks!
You're a card!
Thank you.
Did you see anything?
I'm sorry?
Well you were obviously there
for the long haul.
- Where exactly?
- So you must have seen something.
I don't know what you are on about.
You did, didn't you?
Excuse me.
Because if you did,
you really should tell the police.
I'm aware of my resonsibilities.
I don't give a toss
about your peccadilloes.
You really have been somewhat
tiresome tonight with your snide looks.
But I do care that some poor
bastard's had the shit beaten out of them.
It's rather puerile,
if you don't mind me saying.
If you saw anything that could be remotely
helpful in finding the bastards who did it...
Everything OK?
Yeah, fine, thanks.
Then you have got to tell someone.
Because next time Julian...
...it could be one of us.
By the way...
...nice cock.
Theo, darling!
No.
You've gotta go.
This is such a mistake.
First or second.
There'll be a perfectly
reasonable explanation.
Which door?
I don't know.
I think this is the wrong floor.
Oh for God's sake!
You're not gonna say anything,
are you?
Of course not.
Becaue if you did, that would really
really fuck things up!
Why would I?
It's what I wanted.
It's what I want.
Who is that?
- Where is he?
- Sorry?
- Theo?
- Please.
What is it? What's wrong?
You are his parents.
- Get out of there.
- Why?
Tim.
Pleased to meet you.
- Peter.
- Hi.
What the hell are you doing?
- Get out for Christ's sake!
- Mum, what?
What are you doing here?
What's wrong with you?
If you don't tell me what's going on
I am going to call the police.
The police?
If he has laid one finger on you...
- If you have touched my son!
- Nat, please.
What do you mean Nat please?
He is 14!
Mum!
Well, have you?
Have you touched him?
- Have you touched him?
- Dad, tell her!
Nat!
No I haven't. Why would I touch him?
- You're half naked.
- It's very hot!
Oh, will you shut up!
Tell me. Theo.
Why are you here?
- To give him this.
- What?
I picked it up by mistake this afternoon
in the library and found it in my things.
How do you know it's his?
Because I've seen him using it.
It is quite distinctive, black and gold you see.
You mean you see each other in the library.
Sometimes in the history section...
...I see lots of people. What's the problem?
I told you there'd be an explanation.
Yes, so I thought I'd bring it over.
- At midnight?
- I couldn't sleep, and I could see his
light on, so I thought, "Why not?"
Darling, you didn't have to get into his flat
to give it to him.
- It's very nice of him, very thoughtful.
- Yeah.
Most lads would've nicked it.
So why do you still got it?
- There you go.
- Thanks.
Right.
Let's go.
You've been smoking, and alcohol.
You stink of alcohol.
- So do you.
- Don't you dare speak to me like that!
Have you been feeding my son
alcohol and cigarettes?
- Feeding him?
- Nat, come on!
- Well, have you?
- Mum!
Well, say something, why don't you?
Let's go home.
I know you've been up to something.
Nothing has happened.
- I can smell it.
- Dad tell her nothing has happened.
- Come on Nat!
- Get off me!
Great!
Just great!
Can I put something on then?
If you so much as look at my boy again...
Sorry.
Sorry about all this.
Hate Mob Slays Gay.
Fuck.
I have Mr. Cape on the line.
Cape?
Robin Cape.
Did he say what it was about?
Only that it was very important and he
should speak with you.
- Julian.
- What do you want?
- Have you called the police yet?
- Now listen to me.
He is dead.
He died in the night.
So unrecognisable that the police said that
he had to be identified by his fingerprints.
I thought you should know.
Hot, innit?
Live around here, do you?
It's not bad I must say.
Nice view.
Fresh air.
So...
- Where do you live then?
- Not around here.
You have got a tongue then?
You see all sorts up here.
Walking their dogs...
...flying their kites...
...pulling up the nettles.
I saw George Michael up here the other day.
Did you?
Yeah.
He has got a place around here.
What's your name?
Alf.
I like that.
Merv.
Pleased to meet you Alfie.
It's very smart, where did you get that?
From an admirer.
Must have thought a lot of you.
Yeah, he did.
I can see why.
Hello, Alfie.
You know something?
I think you're pretty new at this.
I think I'm gonna have to teach you.
Teach me a lesson?
Oh yeah, I'd enjoy that.
Try again.
- Danny?
- Yes, miss?
- If there is ever anything you want to tell me?
- What should I want to tell you, miss?
If there is anything bothering you?
There's nothing bothering me, miss.
- Or if there is anything on your mind.
- There's nothing, miss.
- If there is.
- There isn't.
Good. Good.
- I'm here to help, you know.
- Thanks, miss.
What happened to you?
I walked into a door.
- On the heath.
- I walked into a door on the heath.
Sorry.
Did you report it?
What's to report.
He shouldn't be allowed to
get away with it.
The police need to know what's going on.
Does that hurt?
No.
We're not living in the
Dark Ages any more.
It's time these
Neanderthals caught on.
Yeah.
Dead right, Doc.
I mean, all I was doing was
sniffing out a bit of knob.
There's nothing wrong in that, is it?
You know where I'm coming from?
Look to the right.
Left.
Who knows doc...
Up.
One day we might bump
into each other again.
Down.
And you wouldn't know
what had hit you.
Right.
Left.
You better watch you.
Up.
I'm a married man.
Down.
Oh yeah?
We don't want my husband getting jealous.
Do we?
Oh no, we wouldn't want that,
would we?
If I could just...
What's up?
Hello?
Gav?
Are you allright?
Did you take the ring back
to the jewellery's today?
The ring?
Yeah, the ring.
Did you?
Yes, yes of course I did, yes.
You did.
There was no problem or anything?
No.
They said it'll be ready next week, why?
You didn't drop it or lose it,
because if you did I'd understand.
I wouldn't mind.
I could get another one made, I mean...
...it wouldn't be a problem.
I told you, I took it into
the jewellerys.
Gavin, do you want to
tell me what's going on?
Gav?
Gav, what is it?
I'll see you later, OK?
The 24 year old waiter,
originally from Ludlow...
...was found last night on Clapham
Common by a pensioner walking his dog.
He was taken to hospital,
but doctors were unable to save him.
A police spokeswoman said it was one
of the most vicious attacks they'd ever seen.
And one more depressing statistic
confirming the steady increase of...
English subtitle by pinkfloyd.