CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS., INC.
CLACK, CLACK, STEP
ABOUT, THE MAID IS HERE.
MAID IS HERE.
COME BACK LATER.
THERE'S NOTHING
FOR YOU TO DO.
BUT YOU GOT YOUR
"DO NOT DISTURB" SIGN
ON THE DOOR
FROM MORNING TILL NIGHT.
AT LEAST LET ME
DRAW THE CURTAINS.
PLEASE DON'T.
JUST LEAVE THEM.
YOU DON'T LIKE
OUR ISLAND?
HAVEN'T SEEN IT.
EXCUSE ME.
ARE YOU STILL HERE?
YES, MISS.
I HAVE A RAZOR
ON THE TABLE BY THE BED.
COULD YOU BRING IT
TO ME?
YES, MISS.
[HUMMING]
WE FINALLY
MEET FACE TO FACE
WITH YOU
IN THE BATHTUB
WHERE YOU APPEAR
TO HAVE BEEN DEAD.
I DON'T SEE
WHAT DIFFERENCE IT MAKE
IF YOU MISSED
A SPOT OR NOT.
YOU DON'T
LEAVE THE ROOM.
I TELL YOU TRUE,
MISSUS.
YOU GOT TO BUST UP
THE GLOOMY.
THANK YOU.
I ASKED YOU NOT TO OPEN
THE CURTAINS.
SOMETIME I THINK
I KNOW WHAT'S BEST
FOR OTHER PEOPLE.
IT'S A FLAW I'VE
LEARNED TO LIVE WITH.
I'M HUNGRY.
ARE YOU?
YES. I HAVEN'T EATEN
A THING ALL DAY.
HOW ABOUT I ORDER YOU UP
SOMETHIN' TO EAT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
ALL RIGHT.
YES. THIS IS CLARA MAYFIELD
IN BUNGALOW B.
COULD YOU SEND ME UP
A TRADITIONAL PLATTER
WITH A SIDE
OF CHO CHO?
I GOT A LADY HERE
GREW UP IN JAMAICA
LONGIN' FOR THE TASTE.
CHA, MAN.
THANK YOU.
COME IN NOW.
FOOD IS READY.
IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT,
WE'LL THROW IT AWAY.
YOU'RE ON VACATION.
YOU'RE ALLOWED
A LITTLE CAPRICE.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
SCRAMBLED EGGS.
NO. YOU MUST TASTE IT FIRST
BEFORE YOU SAY THAT.
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
GOOD CIGAR.
YOU CAN GET IT FRESH
IN PORT ANTONIO.
MAYBE I'LL HIRE A DRIVER
AND SEE THE TOWN.
DON'T HIRE A DRIVER.
JUST TAKE THE BUS.
IT RUNS BY THE HOTEL
EVERY DAY.
YOU NEED YOUR FEET
AND A FEW CENTS.
I HAVE TO GO.
THANK YOU, CLARA.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY KIND.
IT'S NOT DIFFICULT
TO BE KIND.
NOW TAKE YOURSELF OUT
AND BUST UP THE GLOOMY.
EXCUSE ME.
YEAH?
DO YOU KNOW
CLARA MAYFIELD?
SHE LOOKING
FOR CLARA MAYFIELD.
SHUT YOUR MOUTH.
WHERE DID YOU
GET HER NAME?
I MET HER
AT MY HOTEL.
MAMA,
THIS LADY DON'T
KNOW THE SONG.
¶ IN JAMAICA, REMEMBER
WHEN THE ANGELS FALL ¶
¶ I AS BABYLON,
BUT MISS CLARA-- ¶
DON'T BE RUDE.
WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO MISS CLARA
ISN'T THIS
LADY'S BUSINESS.
IF YOU MUST ASK
FOR HER,
IT'S BEST TO ASK
ELSEWHERE.
I WISH I'D KNOWN YOU'D
BE IN TOWN YESTERDAY.
I WOULD HAVE MET YOU.
NO, REALLY?
HOW MUCH TROUBLE
COULD IT BE?
WHAT DID YOU DO
YESTERDAY?
I WENT TO CHURCH.
THEN I CAME HOME,
WROTE LETTERS
TO MY FRIENDS
IN BALTIMORE.
WE LIVE JUST OUTSIDE
BALTIMORE.
NO, REALLY?
MY BEST FRIEND OWNS
A BEAUTY SALON THERE,
AND OTHER FRIENDS
WORK FOR HER.
SHALL WE HAVE
OUR TEA?
YOU DON'T MIND
IF THEY SEE YOU?
THEY COULD
DISCHARGE ME.
I'VE LIVED
THROUGH WORSE.
YOU'RE MARRIED,
AREN'T YOU, CLARA?
YES.
DOES YOUR HUSBAND
WORK IN TOWN?
I'M SORRY. I'M BEING
TOO INQUISITIVE.
NO, NO. HE WORKS
OUTSIDE THE COUNTRY
JUST NOW.
SO YOU'RE ALONE
RIGHT NOW?
BY CIRCUMSTANCE.
I NEVER ALLOW MYSELF
TO GET TOO REGRETFUL.
NOBODY WANTS TO BE
AROUND SOMEONE
WHO SPREADS
BLACK CLOUDS AND DOOM.
YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I MEAN.
YES, BUT YOU SEE,
MY BABY DIED
IN HER CRIB RECENTLY.
DIDN'T KNOW
THE FACT,
BUT I KNEW
THE SUBSTANCE.
I HAVEN'T BEEN
TERRIBLY RESILIENT.
THAT'LL COME IN TIME.
THANK YOU.
IT'S A FUNNY THING
ABOUT BEING ALONE.
YOU START TO TALK
TO YOURSELF.
THEN YOU STOP
LISTENING,
AND THEN YOU FORGET
THAT YOU'RE THERE.
I FIND THAT I GET
INTO SUCH DULLNESS,
BUT YOU LET SOMEBODY
CALL ME ON THE PHONE
AND TELL ME
THEIR TROUBLES--
I CAN SAY
SUCH MARVELOUS THINGS.
THINGS I DON'T KNOW
WHERE THEY COME FROM
FALL FROM MY LIPS
LIKE PIECES OF FRUIT,
AND I MUST PAUSE
TO WONDER
WHO IS IT
INSIDE OF ME
I DON'T EVEN
KNOW IS THERE?
LEE?
OH, BILL.
COME MEET THE MOST
WONDERFUL PERSON.
MOM! DAD!
HI. HI.
HOW
YOU DOING?
GREAT. I'M GLAD
YOU'RE BACK.
OLD GLENDA--
SHE'S THE PITS.
WELL, WE'RE
LETTING HER GO.
REALLY?
YOU GREW.
HOW MANY BAR-UPS
YOU DOING?
ABOUT FIVE.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
WHO'S THAT?
DAVID,
THIS IS CLARA.
CLARA'S GOING TO
BE LIVING WITH US
FROM NOW ON.
HELLO, DAVID.
YOU DON'T GOT TO
BE AFRAID OF ME.
ME NOT GONNA BITE YOU...
UNLESS YOU DON'T BEHAVE.
HERE, CLARA.
NO, THANK YOU.
I GOT IT.
OK, BIG GUY.
CARRY THIS.
DAD! WHAT'S SHE
DOING HERE?
SHH!
YOU DIDN'T SAY
ANYTHING!
YOUR MOTHER JUST NEEDS
SOME HELP, DAVID.
YOU'LL HAVE STRANGERS
TAKE CARE OF ME NOW
SO YOU DON'T
HAVE TO!
WHAT IS THIS?
JUST TAKE IT
EASY, DAVID.
I UNDERSTAND
THE LITTLE BOY.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I'LL MAKE YOU LEAVE.
STOP IT!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LISTEN.
NOBODY MAKES ME DO
NOTHIN' I DON'T WANT TO,
SO AIM THAT MEANNESS
AND NASTY TALK ELSEWHERE.
YOU GOT ANOTHER
THING COMING
IF YOU THINK YOU'LL ACT
SO DREADFUL AROUND CLARA.
COME THIS WAY,
CLARA.
WHERE ARE YOU
TAKING HER?
LEE?
WELL, COME UP
IF YOU MUST.
DON'T STAND DOWN THERE
MARAUDING LIKE A SPY.
YOU'RE OUR MAID.
THIS IS A GUEST ROOM--
A ROOM FOR GUESTS.
PERHAPS YOUR MOTHER
WANT ME CLOSE TO YOU
SO I CAN CHANGE
YOUR DIAPERS.
VERY FUNNY.
HOW COME YOU TALK
SO WEIRD?
YOU AIN'T HEARD WEIRD
TALKIN' YET, CHILD.
I TALK SO BAD YOU'LL
THINK IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
WHAT'S THAT MEAN?
DON'T ACT PROPER, I'LL
TURN YOU INTO A TOAD.
OOH. YOU'RE SOME KIND
OF WITCH, OR WHAT?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
YEAH.
YOU'RE NOT IN CHARGE.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
AT THE START.
THAT IS OBVIOUS,
SO WE MOVE ON
TO OTHER THINGS.
SHE'S NOT WELL--
MY MOTHER.
YOU DON'T SEEM
TOO HEALTHY YOURSELF.
YOU'RE A JERK.
WELL, IF I'M A JERK,
YOU'RE A BOBO.
THEN YOU'RE
A SUPER-DWEEB.
IF I AM A SUPER-DWEEB,
YOU ARE A BUBU-YAGA.
DON'T SAY
ANYTHING ELSE.
BEST YOU AND ME,
WE LEARN TO BECOME
PART OF ONE ANOTHER.
PERHAPS THEN THERE
IS SOME HOPE FOR US.
LISTEN,
WHAT CAN I SAY?
I'M SORRY, BUT YOU'RE
NOT WINNING ME OVER.
THAT'S THE BEST
I CAN DO FOR TODAY,
SO JUST TAKE YOURSELF
OUT OF HERE. GOOD-BYE.
GET YOUR DIRTY HANDS
OUT OF THERE.
I HOPE THEY LIKE
HIYAKI
AS MUCH AS I DO.
IT STRONGLY RESEMBLES
BABY PUKE.
IT'S GOT SOME OF THAT
IN IT, ABSOLUTELY.
MY, BUT YOU'RE
OBSERVANT.
I LEFT SOME TOTOS
IN THE OVEN
FOR THE LITTLE BOY.
I'M NOT
A LITTLE BOY.
YOU ACT LIKE ONE.
I GOT ALL CONFUSED.
SHIRTS.
I NEED SHIRTS.
WHAT DO YOU
CALL THOSE?
WHERE ARE YOU
GOING?
VANCOUVER.
HOW COME?
TO SETTLE THE WORLD'S
MARITIME CRISES.
THEY'RE NOT STARCHED.
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
LEONA, DIDN'T
YOU TELL HER
I LIKE MY SHIRTS
LIGHTLY STARCHED?
SHE DELIVERED ME
THE LIST
OF EVERYBODY'S
FAKEY-FAKEY HABITS.
I EXPLAINED STARCH
RUINS YOUR SHIRTS.
IT DOESN'T.
IF IT DOES,
I'LL GET NEW ONES.
MR. HART, YOU LET ME
SHOW YOU A GOOD IRONING
GIVES THE FEEL
OF STARCH.
THE MONEY YOU SAVE
ON THOSE NICE SHIRTS
YOU CAN SPEND
ON GOLF BALLS.
FINE.
TASTE?
NO, THANKS.
[HUMMING]
AND WHAT ARE THOSE?
TOTOS. COCONUT
RAISIN COOKIES.
I MADE THEM
FOR YOU.
THAT'S VERY KIND
OF YOU,
BUT I RARELY
EAT SWEETS,
AND DAVID SHOULDN'T
HAVE ANY.
HE'S TRAINING
FOR THE SWIM TEAM.
LOOK AT HIM.
HE'LL MAKE IT THIS YEAR.
I COULD'VE MADE IT
LAST YEAR.
YEAH? SO WHY
DIDN'T YOU?
BECAUSE I WAS
TOO NERVOUS.
THAT'S PRECISELY WHAT
IT'S ABOUT, KIDDO.
I KNOW, DAD.
ONE WON'T
KILL THE CHILD.
BESIDES, I KEEP ME EYE
ON THE BALANCE
BETWEEN THE GOOD FOOD
AND THE EVIL.
HEY, IT'S HART
THE FART.
SAY IT, HART.
NO.
SAY IT!
FART.
WHAT?
HART THE FART.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[SLAM!]
CHA, BOBO,
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
NOTHING.
OH, IT LOOKS
LIKE NOTHING.
YOU WOULDN'T
UNDERSTAND.
PROBLEMS OF A BOY
ARE SO MYSTERIOUS.
WOULD YOU GO AWAY,
PLEASE?
I ASKED YOU
POLITELY.
NO, IT WAS NOT POLITE.
IT WAS ONLY
PRETEND POLITE.
NOW, LET'S SEE
WHAT AGONY
YOU'VE BROUGHT HOME
FROM SCHOOL
WITH YOU TODAY.
YOU.
THE AGONY IS YOU.
CHILD, YOU CAN
BUILD UP YOUR ARMS
WITH THESE WEIGHTS,
BUT IT AIN'T GONNA
MAKE YOU TALLER.
IN THE MEANTIME,
YOU MUST NOT
INDULGE IN PITY
AND SHOOT OFF
YOUR MOUTH.
[MUSIC BOX
PLAYING BRAHM'S LULLABY]
I JUST THOUGHT
I'D SEE WHAT'S HERE.
MAYBE WE CAN HAVE
A GARAGE SALE OR SOMETHING.
IT'S TIME TO DISMANTLE
THE NURSERY, MRS. HART.
I DON'T WANT TO HAVE
ANY MORE CHILDREN.
YOU GOT ONE CHILD LEFT.
YOU POUR YOUR SOUL
INTO HIM.
CHUCK IT IN THE BOX.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
KEEP ONE.
WHY? WHY YOU NEED
A TOKEN OF SOMEBODY
ONLY TO BE HAUNTED
BY THEM
THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE?
WASN'T YOUR FAULT
SHE DIED.
IT WAS NOT YOUR FAULT.
[HUMMING]
THAT CHILD,
THAT LITTLE BOY
CHANGED MY LIFE
FOREVER AND ALL TIME.
THAT LITTLE BOY
TAUGHT ME THE JOY
OF LIVING FOR SOMEONE
OTHER THAN MYSELF.
AND YET,
WHEN HE WAS KILLED,
I CONTINUED TO SLEEP
AND WAKE AND BREATHE,
AND IN MY AGONY
AND MY ANGER
I CONTAMINATED
ANYONE AND EVERYONE
THAT HAD THE MISFORTUNE
TO TOUCH ME.
SO AFTER I DEMOLISHED
MY MARRIAGE,
I TRULY REALIZED
THAT IF I WASN'T
GOING TO KILL MYSELF,
I HAD TO GET ON
WITH MY LIVING.
SO ALL RIGHT,
IT'S A SORROW WITHOUT END,
BUT WE DON'T HAVE TO DIE
THE REST OF OUR LIVES
TO PROVE THAT WE HURT
OR THAT WE'RE LONELY.
SO ALL RIGHT.
WELL, THAT'S JUST
TOO BAD, ISN'T IT?
I'M TELLING YOU,
THAT'S IT.
CAN WE JUST
DROP IT?
I'M NOT DROPPING
ANYTHING.
EDITH IS GONE.
IT'S NOT ABOUT EDITH.
LET'S STOP BLAMING
EVERYTHING ON THE BABY.
IT'S JUST FINE
WITH ME.
SO WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO DUMP EVERYTHING ON NOW?
HMM?
IT'S NOT
THE OTHER WOMEN.
IT'S NOT ANY ONE THING.
WHAT OTHER WOMEN?
IT'S NOT ABOUT THEM.
IT'S ABOUT US.
I REALIZED TODAY THAT'S
WHY I GOT PREGNANT.
I THOUGHT IT WOULD
CHANGE THINGS.
YOU WANT TO KNOW
THE WORST OF IT, BILL?
THE WORST OF IT IS
WE'RE NOT EVEN
FRIENDS ANYMORE.
WHEN WERE WE FRIENDS?
REALLY, WHEN?
ONCE.
THAT WAS
A LONG TIME AGO.
I'M TRYING
TO CHANGE THINGS.
THAT'S FINE, LEE.
THAT HAS REAL MERIT,
BUT DON'T REDESIGN ME.
BLANCHE LOUDON.
OH, CLARA MAYFIELD.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
YOU'RE LOOKIN'
LIKE A BABY.
CHA, MAN,
YOU'RE TO LIE.
COME AND SEE THE HOUSE.
HOUSE IS HOUSE.
THE TAXI'S WAITING.
TAXI WILL STAY.
COME IN.
OH, CLARA. IT'S
SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
THERE BE THE TORMENT
OF ME EXISTENCE.
THEY CALL HIM DAVID.
CHA, BOBO. ME NOT A TORMENT
IN YOUR EXISTENCE.
IN DIS HOUSE DE TORMENT
IS EVERYONE.
A JAMAICAN WOMAN
TORMENT ME
FOR CERTAIN
AS MUCH AS ME TORMENT HER.
WHERE HIM
LEARN PATOIS?
ONLY ONE PLACE
I CAN THINK OF.
DON'T TALK THAT WAY.
ONLY LOW-CLASS PEOPLE
TALK THAT WAY.
DON'T ENCOURAGE HIM.
COME ON.
ME NOT LOW-CLASS.
ME NOT NOTHIN'.
ME DUM-DUM.
ME DORK. ME DODO.
THIS IS
MY GOOD FRIEND BLANCHE.
BLANCHE, THIS IS MRS. HART.
THAT'S MR. HART.
MORNIN'.
RICE FOR BREAKFAST?
AND STEAMED
VEGETABLES.
FOR BREAKFAST?
YOU WANT TO GET
STRONG AND HEALTHY.
I SAID I WOULD
EXPERIMENT.
YOU SAID OK.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU MEANT
RICE FOR BREAKFAST.
I'LL GET TIRED OF IT
IN A WEEK.
JUST INDULGE ME.
¶ BROWN-SKINNED GIRLS
STAY HOME AND MIND THE BABY ¶
¶ BROWN-SKINNED GIRLS-- ¶
WHERE YOU LEARN
THAT SONG?
I DON'T KNOW.
AROUND.
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I WANT YOU
SINGIN' THE SONGS
FROM ME HOMELAND.
SOMEBODY WILL THINK
YOU LIKE ME.
CLARA, COME, MAN.
LET'S GO.
THE TAXI MAN
GET CHAKA-CHAKA.
WE'RE OFF TO THE WILDS
OF BALTIMORE
TO HAVE
A SWEET WEEKEND.
DON'T GET
INDIGESTION.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
EVERYONE.
HELLO.
HELLO. CAN YOU HEAR ME
OUT THERE?
YES. LET'S GATHER
AROUND UP HERE, PLEASE.
I WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO OUR HOST,
OUR COUNSELOR,
AND A DEAR FRIEND
TO ALL OF US,
PETER EPSTEIN.
COME ON IN.
GET COMFORTABLE.
IT ONLY WORKS
WHEN I CAN SEE YOUR EYES.
TODAY--LISTEN.
TODAY, ONE DAY ONLY.
SPECIAL. SPECIAL.
WE ARE GATHERED HERE
TO BURY SORROW,
NOT TO PRAISE
AND WALLOW IN IT.
WE'RE JUST A BUNCH OF FRIENDS
GATHERED HERE TODAY
TO CELEBRATE LIFE,
ENJOY THE WEATHER, THE DAY,
THE FOOD, EACH OTHER.
IF ANY OF YOU ARE SO MOVED
EVEN TO ACT SILLY--
SING SONGS, PLAY GAMES,
ROLL IN THE GRASS--
YOU CAN DO IT BECAUSE TODAY
I'M NOT YOUR THERAPIST.
I'M NOT YOUR GROUP LEADER.
NO, I'M A 15-YEAR-OLD BOY
WHO DREAMED OF SINGING
IN A ROCK 'N' ROLL BAND.
IF ANYONE WANTS TO JOIN ME,
I'LL SHOW YOU HOW
I ALMOST SUCCEEDED
EXCEPT FOR ONE SMALL
DISABILITY--
I COULDN'T SING.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S BREAK, GO,
AND IMMEDIATELY COMMENCE
TO HAVE FUN.
HI. WHAT'S
YOUR NAME?
SO AFTER MY SINGING CAREER
WENT INTO
THE PORCELAIN FACILITY,
FOR A TIME THERE, I THOUGHT
I WANTED TO BE A RABBI,
BUT I COULDN'T IMAGINE
SITTING THROUGH BAR MITZVAHS
FOR THE REST
OF MY LIFE
OR THINKING OF GOD
AS A THREE-SYLLABLE WORD.
FIRST OF ALL,
LET'S NOT EXCLUDE
THE WORD GUILT.
MOM?
DAVID, YOU KNOW
DR. EPSTEIN.
HI. MOM, DAD AND I
WANT TO GO NOW.
CAN YOU GET A RIDE?
IT'S NOT THE RIGHT TIME
TO ASK ME THIS.
LET THEM GO.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD MEETING YOU,
DAVID.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
AS I WAS SAYING,
GUILT, IT'S NECESSARY.
IT EXISTS FOR A REASON.
IT EXISTS FOR ANYONE
TO TELL THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN RIGHT AND WRONG.
YOU'VE GOT TO SEE
THE POLARITY...
WHAT YOU DOING?
TRYING TO FIND MYSELF
AN APARTMENT.
YOU'RE LEAVING?
YOU THINK I WANT TO
GIVE YOU THAT MUCH PLEASURE?
HOW COME
AN APARTMENT?
SO I GOT SOMEPLACE
TO GO WHEN I'M NOT WORKING
INSTEAD OF
WITH ME FRIENDS.
THEN WHEN MY HUSBAND
GETS HERE,
HE'S GOT SOMEPLACE
TO STAY WHILE I'M WORKING.
WHEN'S HE COMING?
I DON'T KNOW YET.
OK, DAVE,
THIS IS IT!
DON'T BE GIVING
THE CHILD DIARRHEA
BEFORE HE EVEN
GETS THERE.
LET ME BE
THE PARENT, CLARA.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
THAT'S JUST
AS IT SHOULD BE.
DON'T PUSH IT, OK?
BUT OF COURSE.
DAVE, PEOPLE WHO
DON'T HAVE KIDS
ARE THE BIGGEST
EXPERTS ON HOW
TO RAISE THEM.
GOOD LUCK, DAVID.
REMEMBER, THE SUN
WILL CONTINUE TO RISE
WHETHER YOU'RE
ON THE SWIM TEAM OR NOT.
SWIMMERS, TAKE YOUR MARKS.
TRY TO LEAVE
SOME WATER IN THE POOL
WHEN YOU IMITATE
ARNOLD SCHWARZNEGGER
HITTING THE WATER.
SET...
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[CHEERING]
THAT'S IT!
PULL, DAVE!
WHEN DID YOU
DECIDE THIS?
LAST NIGHT.
WHY DIDN'T
YOU TELL ME BEFORE?
WE THOUGHT IT BEST
TO WAIT TILL
AFTER THE TRIALS.
WHO WILL I LIVE WITH?
ME.
YOU CAN COME INTO THE CITY
AND STAY WITH ME ON WEEKENDS.
[COUGHING]
NO. YOU'RE NOT GOIN'
NOWHERE WITH ME
DRESSED LIKE THIS.
IF THIS IS SOME
NEW PERSON YOU'RE TRYING TO BE
BECAUSE YOU'RE THE VICTIM
OF A BROKEN HOME, THINK AGAIN.
HI, HONEY.
GO UPSTAIRS
AND CHANGE.
PICKY, PICKY.
I REALLY
APPRECIATE THIS.
I'M GLAD TO DO IT
FOR HIM.
IT HELPS ME
AS WELL.
I CAN'T CONCERN MYSELF
WITH WHAT MAKES IT
EASIER FOR YOU
WHO GOT ALL THE CHOICES.
I HAVEN'T CORNERED
THE MARKET ON CHOICES.
SHOW HIM A GOOD TIME.
YES, I'M SURE HE'LL
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
HIS FATHER'S MOVIN'
OUT THE HOUSE,
THE MOTHER'S FUMIGATING
THE FAMILY HOUSEHOLD,
AND HE'S OFF TO THE CITY
WITH A STRANGER.
A WONDERFUL TIME,
MRS. HART.
CLARA...
SURELY YOU SEE ME TRYING.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO TOLD ME
TO CHANGE MY LIFE.
NEXT TIME I'LL BE
MORE SPECIFIC ABOUT
WHAT'S ALLOWED.
BY ALL MEANS.
YOUR OWN HAPPINESS
CAN NEVER BE
AS IMPORTANT
AS THAT CHILD'S
UNTIL HE GROWS
TO BE A MAN.
THE TWO AREN'T
MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE.
IF I'M HAPPIER,
HE'LL BE HAPPIER.
NO.
KISS.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
TO THIS PART
OF THE CITY BEFORE.
NOT A LOT
OF WHITE FOLKS.
TRUE.
CLARA!
OH, GIRL, IT'S BEEN
SO LONG.
CLARA MAYFIELD.
LET ME TAKE
YOUR BAG AND COAT.
GOD, IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
YOU BRING THE BOY
AFTER ALL?
OH, YES.
THIS IS DAVID.
DAVID, COME.
DAVID, THIS
IS FELICIA...
AND LYDIA
AND RITA
AND BOBS.
CLARA,
THERE YOU ARE.
SO GOOD TO
SEE YOU AGAIN,
AND THE SHOP
IS BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S JUST BEAUTIFUL.
THANK YOU,
CLARA.
I BROUGHT DAVID IN
FOR A HOT COMB.
YEAH, RIGHT.
YOU PUT ON
SOME BODY
SINCE I SEE YOU.
THE CHILD
IS SPROUTIN' HAIR
IN THE UP AND DOWN PLACES.
OH, GOD.
I SHOULD
BE SLAPPIN'
YOUR BACKSIDE
FOR ALL THE TROUBLE
YOU'RE GIVIN' CLARA.
THAT'S ANOTHER MUMU
YOU'RE TALKIN' 'BOUT.
DIS CHILD GIVE THE WOMAN
NOTHIN' BUT JOY.
THE BOY SOUND LIKE
HE COME
FROM PORT ANTONIO.
CAN ME HELP IT
IF THE CHILD IS CLEVER?
CHILD, HA!
WOO!
WOO! THERE SHE IS!
FLIP IT UP, BABY!
HEY, HEY,
LYDIA, RITA,
STOP THE ROMPIN'
NOW.
YA, YA.
SO, CLARA, WHAT WE
GOIN' DO HERE?
GIVE THE CHILD HAIR
SOME STYLE.
FORGET IT.
YOU DON'T LET US
STYLE YOUR HAIR,
OFF YOU GO BACK HOME.
THAT'S BLACKMAIL.
YOU MAKE THE CHOICE.
CLARA, IT'S OK.
NO, I PROMISED
THE MOTHER.
HOW CAN I DISAPPOINT
THAT POOR WOMAN?
OK, THAT'S IT.
SIT DOWN.
NO.
YOU'LL SIT DOWN NOW.
RIGHT THERE.
BEHAVE YOURSELF.
I'M GOIN' TO THE SUPERMARKET
TO PICK UP SOME THINGS.
YOU BEHAVE YOURSELF
WHEN I'M GONE.
YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YES.
SEE YOU LATER, CLARA.
OK, DAVID, SIT UP.
RAISE YOUR
BACKSIDE, BOY!
TAKE OFF THEM GLASSES.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE GOIN'
TO LOOK GREAT.
OH, YES, MAN.
THAT'S GOOD.
WHAT YOU THINKIN'?
AH.
MY DAD WILL KILL ME.
NO. CLARA TAKE CARE
OF YOUR FATHER.
HELLO, DORA.
BOBS, WE WANT AN APPOINTMENT
LATER FOR A MANICURE.
WHERE YOU GET
THIS WHITE CHILD?
SHE GET ME
FROM A CHURCH BAZAAR.
I WAS LEFT THERE
IN THE MANGER.
LORD JESUS!
WHERE HIM COME FROM?
IT'S CLARA'S BOY.
MY, MY.
CLARA'S BOY.
WHERE SHE IS?
SHE BE HERE
SOON ENOUGH.
SO, CLARA'S BOY,
DID SHE TELL YOU
ABOUT RALPHIE?
WHAT TROUBLE
YOU CONCOCTING?
IF YOU MUST TALK SO,
ME DO YOUR HAIR ANOTHER DAY.
ME APPOINTMENT TODAY.
YOU'RE EARLY.
ME WAIT AND
CHAT UP THIS BOY
ABOUT RALPHIE.
TELL ME.
DON'T LISTEN
TO HER, CHILD.
SHE KNOW WHEN CLARA COME.
SHE COME FOR JUKE HER.
IF SHE KNOW YOU TALK SO,
SHE TUMP YOU TO YOUR GRAVE.
ME NOT 'FRAID OF HER.
TUMP ME?
YOU A PROFESSIONAL LIAR.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
WHICH OF YOU GIRLS
WOULD BE RUNNING AROUND
WITH SUCH A PIMP.
WHAT SHE CALL ME?
I THINK YOU HEARD ME.
WOMAN, YOU SHUT
YOUR FACE.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
SHUT IT FOR ME.
¶ IN JAMAICA ¶
¶ REMEMBER
WHEN THE ANGEL FALL ¶
¶ I AS BABYLON ¶
¶ BUT MISS CLARA
DID FALL ¶
¶ THINK SHE BE THE ANGEL,
FREE US ALL ¶
¶ BUT ANGEL, ANGEL,
AH, DID FALL! ¶
YOU GOT NO CAUSE TO SING
THAT SONG TO ME.
TELL YOUR WHITE CHILD
ABOUT RALPHIE.
DON'T YOU HURT HER!
HE WON'T HURT ME,
WILL YOU, PIMP?
BECAUSE YOU BEST
KILL ME
'CAUSE IF YOU DON'T,
I'LL COME BACK FOR HER.
FOR YOU,
DORA CAMBRIDGE.
LEAVE HER, BUNDY.
SHIT!
BUNDY, LISTEN TO ME
WHEN I TALKIN'.
YES, BUNDY,
LISTEN TO HER.
OH, GOD!
I WAS AFRAID
SOMETHING WOULD HAPPEN.
AND IF SOMETHIN'
HAPPENED,
WHAT WAS YOU GONNA
DO ABOUT IT?
I...I'D...
I'D KICK HIM
IN THE BALLS.
YOU'RE PERFECTLY RIGHT.
AND THIS
IS THE CHILD
WITH THE HAIRDO
TO DO IT.
NO, I'M GOING
OVER IRENE'S.
CLARA, WHO'S
THAT RALPHIE BOY
THAT WOMAN
WAS TALKING ABOUT?
I DON'T WANT YOU
DISCUSSIN' ME BUSINESS
WITH NOBODY.
I MAKE SOMETHING
EVIL HAPPEN TO YOU.
I WAS JUST ASKING,
JUST MAKING AN INQUIRY.
OH, WOW.
WHAT A BIG CEMETERY.
IT REMIND A PERSON
TO MAKE THE MOST
OUT OF LIFE, DON'T IT?
I HOPE YOU DON'T LIVE
TOO CLOSE...TO IT.
[BABY CRYING]
[YELLING]
COME IN. DON'T STAND
OUT IN THE HALLWAY.
WELCOME TO MY NEW
APARTMENT.
YOU CAN SIT DOWN,
YOU KNOW.
RELAX. TAKE OFF
YOUR JACKET.
BY THE WAY,
THAT'S YOUR BED
TONIGHT.
CLARA...
YES.
DO YOU WISH YOU COULD
GET A JOB HERE
SO THEN YOU'D
BE HERE ALL THE TIME?
I HAVE THOUGHT
ABOUT IT, YES.
AND?
HOW COULD I EVER LEAVE
SUCH A WELL-DRESSED,
HANDSOME GENTLEMAN AS YOURSELF?
¶ LET THE BOY GO HOME ¶
¶ LET HIM GO BACK HOME ¶
¶ HE'S UNDERAGE ¶
¶ HE'S NOT FIT
FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ LET THE BOY GO HOME ¶
¶ LET HIM GO BACK HOME ¶
¶ HE'S UNDERAGE ¶
¶ HE'S NOT FIT
FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ HE'S UNDERAGE ¶
¶ NOT FIT
FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ HE WAS THE BEST
LITTLE BOY ¶
¶ HIS DADDY EVER HAD ¶
¶ HE WAS THE BEST
LITTLE BOY... ¶
CLARA?
WHAT'S WRONG?
I GOT SOME THINGS
THAT ARE JUKIN' ME
DEEP IN MY BRAIN...
AND I CAN'T SEEM
TO FALL ASLEEP.
WHAT STUFF?
PERSONAL THINGS.
WHAT'S THAT FOR?
THIS?
WHY, THIS IS AN OLD
JAMAICAN REMEDY
FOR HEADACHE,
FOR HEARTACHE.
CLARA, WHY DID YOU
GET MAD AT ME
WHEN I ASKED YOU
ABOUT THAT RALPHIE GUY?
BECAUSE I TOLD YOU ABOUT
ASKING ABOUT ME PERSONAL.
YOU SAID NOT TO
ASK YOUR FRIENDS.
I DIDN'T THINK
I COULDN'T ASK YOU.
WHAT A LIFE
THIS TURN OUT TO BE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
RALPHIE...
WAS MY SON.
I THOUGHT YOU DIDN'T
HAVE ANY CHILDREN.
I DON'T.
NOT ANYMORE.
YOU MEAN...
HE'S NOT ALIVE?
OH.
DAD, WHO ANSWERED
THE PHONE?
WEREN'T YOU
EXPECTING ME TO CALL?
THEN WHY DID YOU HAVE
THAT LADY ANSWER?
YOUR DECORATOR'S THERE
ON A SUNDAY NIGHT?
I HAVE TO COME SEE YOU?
HI.
COME ON IN.
NEAT, HUH?
LOOKS A LITTLE WEIRD.
IT'S NEW.
THE WORLD'S CHANGING.
THE 21st CENTURY'S
UPON US.
LOOKS LIKE
IN THE 21st CENTURY,
NOBODY HUMAN
WILL BE LIVING HERE.
NO. I'LL GET SOME
MAGAZINES AROUND...
HEY, HOW ABOUT
THIS VIEW?
WHAT'S YOUR PLEASURE?
BALL GAME, MOVIE--
WHERE ARE THE BLINDS?
THEY'RE IN THE BEDROOM.
COME ON.
I'LL START WITH OYSTERS
ON THE HALF SHELL
AND THEN THE VEAL CHOP.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
TELL ME WHAT
THERE IS FIRST.
HOW ABOUT SCAMPI?
YOU LOVE SHRIMP.
FINE.
CIAO, BILL.
HI.
DAVID, MEET CATHERINE,
MY DECORATOR.
CATHERINE, THIS IS
MY SON, DAVID HART.
HELLO, DAVID HART.
HOW ABOUT HAVING
SOME LUNCH WITH US?
I'LL JUST STAY
A MINUTE.
UM, DAVID, WHAT
DO YOU THINK
OF YOUR FATHER'S
APARTMENT?
IT'S PRETTY GOD DAMN
OSTENTATIOUS.
OF COURSE, THAT'S JUST
A KID'S OPINION.
I MEAN, I DON'T
EVEN SPEAK ITALIAN.
ARE YOU
SEXUALLY INVOLVED
WITH MY FATHER?
SON, DON'T BE SHY.
JUST JUMP IN.
ASK WHATEVER YOU NEED TO.
ARE YOU?
YES, I AM.
I CARE
ABOUT YOUR DAD A LOT.
WELL,
ENJOY YOUR LUNCH.
IT WAS NICE
TO MEET YOU, DAVID.
BYE.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
SHE REALLY LIKES YOU,
DOESN'T SHE?
WHY NOT? I'M NOT
SUCH A BAD GUY.
YOU AND MOM
JUST GOT SEPARATED,
AND YOU ALREADY HAVE
SOMEONE ELSE.
AT LEAST I'M NOT HIDING
WHO I'M SEEING.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHO'S MOM SEEING?
THE GREAT SINGING
PSYCHOLOGIST
WE MET THAT SATURDAY.
THAT DR. EPSTEIN GUY?
IT'S GOOD, DAVID.
YOUR MOM DESERVES
TO BE HAPPY, TOO.
SO IN OTHER WORDS,
YOU AND MOM...
YOU AND MOM
DESERVE TO BE HAPPY.
SOUNDS RIGHT.
MAKES SENSE.
HE HAD NO RIGHT
TO TELL YOU THAT.
WHEN WOULD YOU HAVE
GOTTEN AROUND TO TELLING ME?
WHEN I FIGURED OUT
HOW I WANTED TO
EXPLAIN IT TO YOU.
COME HERE, BABY.
PETER'S MAKING
A LOT OF THINGS
FALL INTO PLACE
FOR ME.
I FEEL JUST NOW
I HAVE TO PUT
ALL MY ENERGY
INTO HELPING MYSELF
BEFORE I CAN HELP
ANYONE ELSE.
I KNOW THAT SOUNDS
REALLY SELFISH,
BUT I'M DOING
THE BEST I CAN.
AND I LOVE YOU.
I DO.
KISS.
[CAR DOOR SLAMS]
HI. HOW WAS
YOUR WEEKEND?
OH, CHILD,
IT WAS WONDERFUL.
GOOD LAVISHING.
WE GIRLS
CAN CERTAINLY CHAT.
WOO!
WHO CAME OVER?
IT WAS ME, BLANCHE,
LYDIA, AND BOBS,
AND THE GIRLS WANTED
ME TO TELL YOU HI.
BLANCHE DID YOU UP
IN SOME PINKIE HAIRDO?
IT BE LOOKIN'
VERY NICE ON YOU.
AREN'T YOU
THE SILVER-TONGUED
DEVIL.
HOW WAS IT
AT YOUR FATHER'S?
TERRIFIC.
REALLY MEMORABLE.
AREN'T THEY SUPPOSED TO
KEEP UP APPEARANCES
OR SOMETHING
FOR A CHILD'S BENEFIT?
AND MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
THEY'LL GET BACK TOGETHER?
DAVID, CLARA,
I'M LEAVING.
WHERE TO?
PETER HAS
A WORKSHOP TONIGHT.
I'M LATE. I'LL TALK
TO YOU LATER.
OH! MY TWO-CENT TOOTSIES
ARE KILLING ME.
HERE, LET ME
RUB THEM FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
WHAT'S IN THAT
RED SUITCASE?
WHAT RED SUITCASE?
THAT ONE YOU KEEP
UNDER YOUR BED
AND TAKE
TO YOUR APARTMENT.
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
MY ROOM
IS ME PRIVACY.
HOW WAS IT
AT YOUR DAD'S?
HOW COME YOU DON'T
HAVE HAIR ON YOUR LEGS?
BECAUSE I'M
NATURALLY HAIRLESS.
HOW WAS IT
AT YOUR DAD'S?
WHY YOU TOUCH ME
LIKE THAT?
LIKE HOW?
DON'T YOU NEVER
TOUCH ME LIKE THAT
AGAIN.
I'M SORRY.
KEEP YOUR HANDS
OFF MY PERSON, CHILD.
WAIT.
GET OUT,
NOW! GET OUT!
[DOOR OPENS]
YOUR DINNER'S DOWNSTAIRS.
YOU'D BETTER GO AND EAT.
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
YOU MUST
KEEP UP YOUR STRENGTH.
I'LL ALWAYS JUST BE
A PUNY MIDGET.
I GUESS I'M SUPPOSED
TO FEEL SORRY FOR YOU.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU
IN MY COUNTRY
"PUNY PUNY" MEANS MEN
WITH MANY WOMEN
AND LOTS OF LAND.
I SHOULD MOVE THERE.
NO. YOU NEED TO LEARN
HOW TO LIVE HERE,
BUT YOU MUST ALSO LEARN
NOT TO TOUCH A LADY
UNLESS YOU'VE BEEN INVITED.
CLARA?
YES, DAVID?
WHY DID EDITH
HAVE TO DIE AND
MESS UP EVERYTHING?
THEM THAT DIE
DON'T CREATE THE AGONY
AND STRANGENESS OF LIFE, DAVID.
ONLY THE LIVING DO THAT.
I FIGURED
YOU'D SAY THAT.
THEN WHY YOU ASK ME?
DAVID.
DAVID, LOOK UPON ME.
KNOW THIS--
YOU CAN DEPEND ON ME.
ALWAYS?
ALWAYS IS MUCH LONGER
THAN YOU'RE GOING TO NEED ME.
I DON'T GET IT.
THE GUY KEEPS ROLLING
THE BOULDER UP THE MOUNTAIN
EVEN THOUGH HE KNOWS
IT'LL ROLL BACK DOWN.
SISYPHUS IS CONDEMNED
TO ROLL THE BOULDER.
HE HAS NO CHOICE,
BUT HE COMMITS
EVERY FIBER OF HIS BEING
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
IT'S STUPID.
HE'S AN IDIOT.
BECAUSE IT'S THE EFFORT,
DAVID,
THAT GIVES MEANING
TO OUR LIVES.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YEP.
YOU MAKE
ALL THIS STUFF UP?
NO. A FRENCH WRITER
NAMED CAMUS.
I JUST STOLE IT.
UH, I'M GOING TO
LEAVE YOU GUYS
AND GO CHECK
ON MY SERVICE.
USE THE PHONE
IN THE LIVING ROOM.
YOU'LL HAVE
MORE PRIVACY.
DAVID, PETER
HAS ASKED ME
TO HELP HIM
ON A WORKSHOP
THIS WEEKEND
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
NOW, I TOLD HIM
THAT I WOULD
SPEAK TO YOU
ABOUT IT FIRST,
THAT IF
IT BOTHERED YOU
TERRIBLY,
I WOULDN'T DO IT.
SURE. GO.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO?
OH. NO, MOM'S
NOT HERE, DAD.
SHE IS SACKING OUT
IN SAN FRANCISCO
WITH THE OLD
SINGING PSYCHOLOGIST.
YEAH. SHE WENT TO HELP HIM
RUN A WORKSHOP.
YEAH. THAT'S THE WORD HERE, DAD.
FILM AT 6:00.
I'M JUST HANGING OUT
WITH CLARA,
SITTING IN FRONT
OF MOTHER'S MIRROR
AND PUTTING ON
THAT WOMAN'S COSMETICS,
SO TALKIE-TALKIE
NEXT WEEK, FATHER.
SO LONG, NOW.
YOU KNOW SHE NOT WANT YOU
TO TROUBLE HER THINGS.
ME NOT TROUBLE
HER THINGS.
COME ON. SIT UP.
CLARA.
THAT IS MY NAME.
WILL I BE LIKE--
LIKE YOUR SON NOW?
I MEAN,
I AM YOUR FRIEND
AND EVERYTHING.
BUT OF COURSE.
BUT, DAVID,
DON'T
THE LITTLE GIRLS
INTEREST YOU YET?
IT'S NOT THAT
THEY DON'T INTEREST ME.
I JUST DON'T
INTEREST THEM.
OH.
WELL, SOMETHING
TELLS ME
THAT VERY, VERY SOON
THOSE LITTLE GIRLS
ARE GOING TO BE
INTERESTED IN YOU, TOO.
YOU SWEAR?
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT A STRANGE CHILD
YOU ARE.
SOMETIME YOU FEEL
SO STRANGE TO ME
I THINK I DON'T
KNOW YOU AT ALL.
OF COURSE
YOU KNOW ME.
YOU KNOW ME
BETTER THAN ANYONE.
NOT TRUE.
NOBODY EVER
REALLY KNOWS ANYONE,
AND JUST WHEN
YOU THINK YOU DO,
PEOPLE CHANGE RIGHT
BEFORE YOUR EYES.
¶ I HOPE
YOU LIKE JAMMIN', TOO ¶
4, 5, 6.
7, 8, 9.
7, 8.
7. 8.
1, 2, 3.
¶ JAMMIN' TILL
THE JAM IS THROUGH ¶
SO, CLARA'S BOY,
YOU MUSTN'T BE
FRIGHTENED OF ME.
MUST BE CLARA
TELL YOU SOME
BAD THINGS ABOUT ME.
I'M NOT SCARED OF YOU.
SHE DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT YOU.
ALL YOU NEED
TO KNOW, THEN,
IS THIS--
WHEN MAYFIELD GO,
DEATH AND ALL
BE A-FOLLOW.
I'LL GO UPSTAIRS
AND MAKE SOME KOOL-AID.
DON'T MOVE YET.
JUST STAY
RIGHT HERE.
WHAT THE HECK.
I'VE GOT SOME TIME.
SO TELL ME
SOMETHING.
DID SHE TELL YOU
ABOUT RALPHIE?
I KNOW
SHE NO TELL YOU.
YEAH? SHE DID.
SHE COULDN'T
TELL YOU
THE WHOLE STORY.
WHAT DO YOU CARE
ANYWAY, HUH?
ME HAVE ME REASONS
FOR CARE.
YOU ASK ABOUT RALPHIE.
MAKE CERTAIN YOU DO THAT, MAN.
WELCOME, CLARA.
YOU...
THEY TOLD ME
YOU WAS OUTSIDE.
I HAD TO.
WHY?
IT WAS BURNING UP
IN HERE.
I'M NOT USED
TO THE TROPICS.
THEN DORA COME BY
WITH HER FRIEND.
SHE WAS TRYING
TO JUKE ME UP.
JUST WHAT DID DORA
TELL YOU?
TO ASK YOU
ABOUT RALPHIE.
WHAT DID I SAY
ABOUT ASKING
ABOUT MY PERSON?
I DIDN'T SAY
ANYTHING.
SHE SAY
ANYTHING ELSE?
NOTHING.
THAT'S IT.
I SWEAR.
CLARA?
YES, DAVID?
NOTHING.
¶ GOD HAS SMILED ON ME ¶
¶ HE HAS SET ME FREE ¶
¶ GOD HAS SMILED... ¶
NO. YOU STAY HERE.
¶ ON ME ¶
¶ HE'S BEEN GOOD TO ME ¶
¶ GOD HAS... ¶
EXCUSE ME.
DIDN'T I TELL YOU
TO STAY BACK THERE?
I WANT TO DO IT, TOO.
I NEED IT.
YOUR PARENTS
WOULD HAVE A COW
IF THEY KNEW.
WHO WOULD FIND OUT?
SHH.
WHEN I'M HERE,
I FEEL LIKE ONE OF YOU.
YOU TAKE YOURSELF
BACK THERE
AND SIT DOWN.
¶ HE'S BEEN GOOD TO ME ¶
¶ HE IS THE SOURCE
OF ALL MY JOY ¶
THE BODY
OF CHRIST.
AMEN.
THE BODY
OF CHRIST.
AMEN.
¶ IN THIS BODY OF MINE,
SEE WHAT THE LORD HAS DONE ¶
¶ IN THIS BODY OF MINE ¶
¶ SEE WHAT THE LORD HAS DONE ¶
¶ COUNT YOUR MANY BLESSINGS ¶
I DIDN'T
MEAN THIS, CLARA.
I DIDN'T DO THIS
TO HURT YOU.
HOW COULD YOU
DO THIS TO ME?
HOW?
AFTER THE TRUST
AND FAITH I PUT IN YOU--
HOW COULD YOU
DO THIS TO ME?
THERE WERE
SO MANY THINGS.
WHY DID
ALL THOSE LETTERS
COME BACK?
DID--DID HE DIE, TOO?
IT'S NONE
OF YOUR BUSINESS,
IS IT?
I KNOW.
I'M SORRY.
THAT IS NONE
OF YOUR BUSINESS.
I'LL DO ANYTHING
YOU SAY.
YOU HAVE RUINED
OUR FRIENDSHIP,
AND YOU'LL GET OUT.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN
LIVING AT HOME
REGULARLY.
IT SUDDENLY
DAWNED ON YOU
STAYING OUT SO MUCH
MIGHT NOT BE
THE BEST THING
FOR A KID
WHO'S DEPENDENT
ON A BLACK WOMAN
WHO'S NOT
SPEAKING TO HIM.
WE'RE NOT DISCUSSING
MY LIVING ARRANGEMENTS.
I SEE DAVID AMPLY.
AMPLY?
WHAT IS THAT?
AN ACCEPTED WAY
OF SEEING SOMEONE?
MAKE YOUR POINT,
BILL.
YOU SAY
YOU ARE STUDYING
TO BE
A LAY THERAPIST--
NO PUN INTENDED.
DOESN'T IT OCCUR
TO YOU
PUTTING YOUR CHILD
IN THERAPY
WITH A STRANGER
WILL MAKE HIM
FEEL MORE SEPARATE?
IF I THOUGHT THAT,
WOULD I BE DOING IT?
PREDICTING
YOUR MOTIVES
IS NOT
SOMETHING I CARE
TO MAKE BOOK ON.
YOU WANT ME TO PAY
FOR THIS TREATMENT?
I ONLY WANT
YOUR SUPPORT.
THAT'S WHY
I ASKED YOU
TO COME HERE.
I WISH I COULD
BELIEVE THAT.
I CANNOT BELIEVE
YOU'RE SENDING A CHILD
INTO THERAPY.
STAY OUT
OF THIS.
MESS UP YOUR OWN LIVES.
DON'T DRAG HIM INTO IT.
DON'T TALK TO US
THAT WAY.
DON'T YOU TALK TO ME
LIKE THIS.
WE HAVE
A JAMAICAN SAYING--
NOBODY
GIVES A DAMN
ABOUT THAT.
I DO.
STAY OUT
OF THIS.
"THE HIGHER
THE MONKEY CLIMB,
THE MORE HE EXPOSE."
YOU TELL HER
YOU'RE NOT
INTERESTED,
SHE TELLS YOU
ANYWAY.
CAN I ASK A QUESTION?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME?
NOTHING'S WRONG WITH YOU.
PSYCHIATRISTS JUST
HELP YOU TO UNDERSTAND
YOURSELF BETTER.
WILL CLARA TALK
TO ME AGAIN?
HE MIGHT HELP YOU
UNDERSTAND WHY YOU
DISREGARDED HER PRIVACY.
THEY'LL MAKE FUN
OF ME AT SCHOOL.
DON'T YOU SEE
THAT'S PART
OF THE PROBLEM?
CAN DR. EPSTEIN
STRAIGHTEN
THIS OUT?
I MEAN, LOOK
WHAT'S HE'S DONE
FOR YOU.
BILL, I SWEAR TO GOD--
YOU LEAVE GOD
OUT OF THIS MESS.
I'LL MAKE SURE THE CHILD
GOES TO A PSYCHIATRIST,
BUT YOU LEAVE THIS BOY
OUT THE MIDDLE.
I REALLY RESENT
YOUR INTRUSION
INTO THIS.
THEN FIRE ME,
MR. HART.
HE'S NOT FIRING
ANYBODY.
DAVID,
YOU COME WITH ME.
I DON'T BELIEVE
I QUITE FOLLOW YOU, DAVID.
PHOTOS FROM OLD
FAMILY ALBUMS.
YOU AND CLARA?
WE PIN THEM
ON THE WALL
AND THROW DARTS
AT THEM.
WE HAD A 5-3-1
SCORING SYSTEM.
PHOTOGRAPHS
OF YOUR FATHER?
THEY WERE OLD ONES--
WHEN HE HAD HIS
MUSTACHE.
HE HATES THEM.
YOU SWEAR YOU WON'T
TELL ANYONE WHAT
I CONFIDED IN YOU
BECAUSE, FRANKLY,
IF MY DAD FOUND OUT,
HE'D REALLY
BE UPSET.
I'M SURE HE WOULD BE.
I MEAN,
HE REALLY THOUGHT
HE LOOKED
LIKE A STUD
IN THAT MUSTACHE.
I TAKE IT
YOU'RE NOT CRAZY
ABOUT YOUR FATHER.
WHAT ELSE
DID THE TWO OF YOU DO?
US TWO WHO?
YOU AND CLARA.
WE DID THINGS
TOGETHER
WHERE SHE DIDN'T ASK
AS MANY QUESTIONS
AS YOU DO.
OUR TIME'S UP
FOR TODAY.
WHY DON'T I NOT ASK YOU
ANY MORE QUESTIONS
UNTIL NEXT WEEK?
YOU TOLD THAT MAN
THAT WE THROW DARTS
AT PICTURES OF YOUR FATHER?
I TOLD HIM WE HAD
A SCORING SYSTEM.
THAT WAS WRONG.
NEVER PUT ME UP
AGAINST YOUR PARENTS,
NOT EVEN IN JEST.
YOU TOLD ME TO LIE.
I KNOW,
BUT I DID NOT MEAN...
THAT MAN MUST THINK
THAT I LOVE BOTH
OF YOUR PARENTS EQUALLY.
MMM.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH, I SEE.
NOW, I'M NOT UPSET.
I JUST GOT
A LITTLE OVEREXCITED.
THERE MUST BE ROOM
FOR MISTAKES WHEN YOU
PLAY GAMES SUCH AS THESE.
I'LL BE MORE CAREFUL
NEXT TIME.
NOW, DAVID HART,
WE MUST THINK OF SOMETHING
ABSOLUTELY DEVILISH
TO TELL THIS MAN
NEXT WEEK.
YOU REALLY WANT
TO HEAR THIS?
PLEASE.
WHEN BILL GETS HOME
FROM WORK,
HE AND LEONA LIKE--
LIKE TO GET
DRESSED UP,
IF YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN.
NO, I'M AFRAID
I DON'T.
WELL, BILL LIKES
TO DRESS UP
LIKE LEONA,
AND LEONA LIKES
TO DRESS UP
LIKE BILL.
WE'RE TALKING
INCLUDING UNDERWEAR.
MM-HMM, AND THEN?
WELL, THEN THEY
START ACTING
LIKE EACH OTHER.
BILL STARTS WAVING
HIS ARMS LIKE THIS
AND POURS HER
A DRINK,
AND LEONA'S IN THIS
THREE-PIECE SUIT,
AND SHE STARTS
BITCHING ABOUT
THE MARITIME UNION.
HOW COULD YOU KNOW THIS
UNLESS YOU SAW THEM?
OH, I NEVER
SAW THEM,
BUT CLARA DID ONCE
BY ACCIDENT.
SO SHE TOLD YOU
THAT SHE SAW THEM?
NO. SHE WOULDN'T
DO THAT.
SEE, I OVERHEARD
A TELEPHONE
CONVERSATION
SHE HAD WITH
HER FRIEND BLANCHE.
MRS. HART,
MAY I SEE YOU
FOR A MOMENT, PLEASE?
WHERE ON EARTH
DID YOU GET
THAT MATERIAL?
I MADE IT UP.
YOUR FATHER WOULD...
WHAT?
I WOULD LOVE
TO SEE YOUR FATHER
IN SOME
OF MY UNDERWEAR.
HELLO, DAVID.
AREN'T YOU
DAVID HART?
UM...
UM, YES. I MEAN--
I MEAN--
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO HESITATE,
LIKE I DIDN'T KNOW
I WAS DAVID HART.
I JUST--
YOU JUST DON'T KNOW
WHO I AM.
WHO ARE YOU?
ASHLEY LAFFERTY.
I JUST MOVED INTO
THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
OH, SURE. YEAH.
DO YOU
KNOW ME NOW?
NO, BUT I'M GLAD
TO MEET YOU.
I--             I--
I'M SORRY.      I'M SORRY.
GO AHEAD.       GO AHEAD.
WHAT WERE YOU
GOING TO SAY?
I LIKE YOUR GLASSES.
I WAS AFRAID
THEY'D MAKE ME
LOOK LIKE A GEEK.
OH,
DEFINITELY NOT. NO.
THANKS.
THANKS A LOT.
OH, IS THIS
YOUR DOG?
NO. IT'S SOME
STRANGER'S DOG.
ACTUALLY,
IT'S MY MOTHER'S
NEW HUSBAND'S DOG,
BUT WE SORT OF
ADOPTED EACH OTHER.
YOUR MOM
AND YOUR REAL DAD
ARE DIVORCED?
SURE.
WHOSE PARENTS
AREN'T DIVORCED, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
WELL.
UM, YEAH.
SO--SO I'LL SEE YOU, OK?
BYE.
WELCOME
TO THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
HELLO, DAVID.
HI, DAVID.
COME IN,
SWEETHEART.
COME IN.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
SIT DOWN,
DAVID.
I GET
THE FEELING
I SHOULD STAND.
YOU'LL MAKE US ALL
LESS UNCOMFORTABLE
IF YOU SIT, DAVID.
DAVID, PETER HAS
ACCEPTED AN OFFER
TO RELOCATE THE MAIN BASE
FOR HIS WORKSHOPS
IN CALIFORNIA.
IT'S ALL VERY SUDDEN,
BUT WE'RE LEAVING
IN TWO WEEKS.
AND WE WANT YOU
TO COME WITH US.
I PREFER, OF COURSE,
YOU LIVE WITH ME.
YOU GUYS
ARE JOKING,
RIGHT?
NO. NO JOKE.
WOULD CLARA
BE ABLE TO COME?
CLARA DOESN'T EXPECT
TO BE BURDENED
WITH YOU
FOR THE REST
OF HER LIFE.
BURDENED?
WHAT WE'RE SAYING
IS THAT YOU'RE
A STATISTIC KID,
BUT WE WANT YOU
TO BE A HAPPY
STATISTIC.
BOTH YOUR MOTHER AND I
WANT YOU TO BE HAPPY.
I'M VERY HAPPY.
I THINK
WE HAVE TO RE-ESTABLISH
AS NORMAL
A FAMILY ENVIRONMENT
AS POSSIBLE FOR YOU.
YOU, IN TURN,
HAVE TO UNDERSTAND
THAT WE'RE
GOING TO BE A FAMILY.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
DAVID UNDERSTANDS THIS.
WHAT?
THAT WE'RE IN
AN AWFUL SITUATION
NOT ENTIRELY
OF OUR OWN MAKING,
BUT WE LOVE HIM AND
WANT WHAT'S BEST FOR HIM.
WE'LL LET HIM
THINK ABOUT THIS.
HOW'S THAT SOUND?
NOT GOOD.
WHY NOT, SWEETHEART?
I DON'T WANT TO MOVE
TO CALIFORNIA,
AND I DON'T WANT TO
LIVE WITH YOU.
WHAT, DO YOU WANT
TO LIVE WITH CLARA?
[REGGAE MUSIC PLAYING]
OH, YES.
LOOKS LIKE DAVID'S
HAVING A GOOD TIME.
DAVID, WE WANT YOU
TO TALK PATOIS
TO SOME GIRLS
OVER THERE.
OH, NO. ME NOT
A DISPLAY, YOU KNOW.
YOU GOT TO SING
THE TOOTS SONG.
ME NOT A PUPPET SHOW,
YOU KNOW.
YOU'LL LOVE IT.
THE GIRLS WILL
LOVE YOU, TOO.
OK, GIRLS,
THIS IS THE DAVID
I TOLD YOU ABOUT.
HIM NOW WILL SING
SOMETHING DEEP, BAD,
IN OUR VERY
LANGUAGE.
YOU GOT TO SING
WITH ME.
PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
CLARA AND ME WILL
COME IN AT THE TOP.
OK.
¶ LET THE GIRL GO HOME ¶
¶ LET HER GO RIGHT HOME ¶
¶ SHE'S UNDERAGE,
SHE'S NOT FIT FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ LET THE GIRL GO HOME ¶
¶ LET HER GO RIGHT HOME ¶
¶ SHE'S UNDERAGE,
SHE'S NOT FIT FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ ONLY ADULTS CAN GO ¶
¶ TO SEE
THE STREET CORNER SHOW ¶
¶ I'M THE ONE LITTLE BOY
MY MOMMY EVER HAD ¶
¶ HE'S THE ONE LITTLE BOY
HIS FATHER EVER HAD ¶
¶ LET THE GIRL GO HOME ¶
¶ LET HER GO RIGHT HOME ¶
¶ SHE'S UNDERAGE,
SHE'S NOT FIT FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ LET THE GIRL GO HOME ¶
¶ LET HER GO RIGHT HOME ¶
¶ SHE'S UNDERAGE,
SHE'S NOT FIT FOR THE PICTURE ¶
¶ HE'S UNDERAGE,
HE'S NOT FIT FOR THE PICTURE ¶
SO, CLARA'S BOY,
YOU HAVING YOURSELF
A GOOD TIME?
EXCUSE ME.
ME WANT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING FIRST.
ME WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
THAT SHAMEFUL RALPHIE,
ABOUT HOW HIM WAS FOUL
AND HOW HIM HURT ME.
DROP DEAD, BLOOD CLOT.
YOUR MOUTH DIRTY.
DON'T YOU DARE
INSULT ME.
TAKE YOUR HANDS
OFF MY BOY.
DON'T CALL HIM
YOUR BOY.
YOUR BOY IS DEAD.
MY BOY IS DEAD
IS MY BUSINESS.
TELL HIM WHY.
DORA, GET OUT.
ME TELL HIM
WHY YOUR BOY DEAD.
CLARA, YOU MUST
TELL HIM THE TRUTH
ABOUT RALPHIE,
ABOUT THE CLIFF.
HIM HAVE A RIGHT
TO KNOW!
DAVID.
SIT DOWN.
YOU ASKED ME
ABOUT RALPHIE.
I THINK
THE TIME HAS COME
FOR ME TO TELL YOU.
MY SON RALPHIE...
WAS BEAUTIFUL--
STRONG AND HANDSOME,
BIG AS A MAN,
BUT HE WAS
VERY TROUBLED
ALL HIS LIFE.
NOBODY KNEW
WHAT TO DO FOR HIM,
NOT THE DOCTORS,
NOT THE PRIESTS,
NOBODY.
AND WHEN HE WAS 15,
HE FELL IN LOVE
WITH DORA CAMBRIDGE.
SHE PLAYED WITH HIM.
WHEN SHE WAS DONE
PLAYING WITH HIM,
SHE THREW HIM AWAY.
AND MY SON RAPED
DORA CAMBRIDGE.
WHEN I FOUND OUT
THAT RALPHIE
HAD RAPED DORA,
I WENT
AND CONFRONTED HIM
ABOUT IT...
BY TELLING HIM...
THAT HE WAS
NO LONGER MY SON...
AND THAT
HE HAD DISGRACED ME.
AND RALPHIE...
GRABBED ME
BY THE THROAT.
AND I KEPT TRYING
TO TELL HIM IT WAS ME.
MY SON BEGAN
TO TOUCH ME IN A WAY
THAT NO SON SHOULD
EVER TOUCH HIS MOTHER.
MY SON RAPED ME...
AND THEN THREW HIMSELF
OFF A CLIFF...
INTO THE SEA.
AND I'VE LIVED
WITH THIS...
UNTIL I COME TO AMERICA
AND FOUND YOU.
HEY, LIPSKY,
COME ON.
YEAH, WHAT DO YOU WANT,
SCHWARZENEGGER?
LET'S GO.
GO? WHERE
ARE WE GOING?
THE LENGTH OF THE POOL,
YOU AND ME.
A RACERINO?
YEAH, A RACERINO.
FOR WHAT, STUDLY?
LET'S GO,
OR ARE YOU CHICKEN?
I'M SHAKING ALL OVER.
CAN'T YOU TELL?
SAY "READY, SET, GO."
READY,
SET, GO!
COME ON,
GET HIM, LIPSKY!
CLARA?
DAVID.
I'VE MADE
A DECISION.
I'VE DECIDED I'M GOING
TO LIVE IN BALTIMORE.
AH. SO YOU ARE GOING TO
LIVE WITH YOUR FATHER
TO BE CLOSER TO ME.
NO.
NO, NO, NO.
I THINK A CHILD'S PLACE
IS WITH THE MOTHER.
THEY'RE BOUND
TO THE MOTHER
MORE THAN THEY ARE
BOUND TO FRIENDSHIP.
YOU'RE MORE
THAN MY FRIEND.
NO. THAT'S WHAT I AM.
BESIDES, WHAT HAPPENS
IF I GET A WEEKEND JOB?
I'LL COME TO YOU
AFTER SCHOOL.
NO. DON'T YOU SEE
THE RELATIONSHIP
HAS CHANGED?
SURE, IT'S CHANGED,
BUT IT'S ALSO JUST
BECOMING WHAT IT SHOULD BE.
NO. IT'S GONE BEYOND
ALL IT EVER COULD BE.
THAT'S LIFE, CHILD.
LIFE IS CHANGE.
SO WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
I THINK YOU KNOW.
YOU'LL BE
JUST LIKE MY PARENTS.
YOU'RE GOING TO DUMP ME
WHEN THINGS GET TOUGH.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
YOU CAN'T COMPARE ME
WITH THEM.
NO?
NO. THEY ARE YOUR BLOOD.
I'M JUST A HOUSEKEEPER
WHO LOVES YOU.
WHAT ABOUT
WHAT YOU TOLD ME?
"KNOW THAT YOU CAN
DEPEND ON ME," YOU SAID.
YOU'RE A LIAR.
YOU JUST LOVE ME
BECAUSE YOU HAD NO ONE ELSE.
MAYBE THAT'S
WHAT HAPPENED TO RALPHIE.
MAYBE HE SAW
YOU WERE A SELFISH PIG,
THAT JUST CARED
ABOUT YOURSELF.
THAT'S WHY
HE DID WHAT HE DID.
YOU'RE A NASTY CHILD
TO CALL ME SELFISH.
I'M DOING THIS FOR YOU.
YOU MADE ME LOVE YOU.
NOW YOU'RE DUMPING ME
BECAUSE IT'S TOO MUCH FOR YOU.
YOU'LL GET ANOTHER JOB
AND NEVER SEE ME AGAIN.
YOU'LL JUST BE A NIGGER
IN THE END.
BYE, CLARA.
GOOD-BYE, MRS. HART.
EXCUSE ME.
I'D LIKE TO SEE
CLARA MAYFIELD, PLEASE.
COME WITH ME.
¶ BROWN-SKINNED GIRLS STAY HOME
AND MIND THE BABY ¶
¶ I'M GOING AWAY
ON A SAILING SHIP ¶
¶ AND IF I DON'T COME BACK ¶
¶ STAY HOME
AND MIND THE BABY ¶
JESSICA, YOU'RE
SINGING THE WRONG WORDS.
YOU AND I,
WE SING IT ALONE.
¶ BROWN-SKINNED GIRLS STAY HOME
AND MIND THE BABY ¶
¶ I'M GOING AWAY
ON A SAILING SHIP ¶
¶ AND IF I DON'T COME BACK ¶
¶ STAY HOME
AND MIND THE BABY ¶
HI, CLARA.
HELLO, DAVID.
CHILDREN, YOU REMEMBER
I TOLD YOU ABOUT A LITTLE BOY.
WELL, HERE'S THE REMAINS
OF THE LITTLE BOY.
HE'S CALLED DAVID.
YOU SAY HELLO.
HELLO, DAVID.
I'LL BE BACK
IN A MINUTE.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE CLIFFORD
AND MAKE HIM BEHAVE.
DID YOU
HEAR HIM TALKING?
HE WAS TALKING UP
A STORM.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I CAME TO VISIT MY DAD,
SO I THOUGHT...
LET'S TALK.
YOU'RE NOT MAD
THAT I CAME?
CHILD, NO.
I EXPECTED IT
AT SOME TIME.
MY, YOU GOT SO BIG.
NOT WEARING
ANY GLASSES ANYMORE.
HOW IS YOUR MOTHER
AND PETER
AND THE WORKSHOPS
AND THE RICE
AND THE VEGETABLES?
MY MOM MAKES
A PRETTY FAIR TOTO.
I HATE TO ADMIT IT,
BUT EVERYTHING'S OK.
I'M GLAD. I'M GLAD.
CLARA, SO MANY TIMES
I WANTED TO WRITE YOU
TO APOLOGIZE
FOR WHAT I SAID.
I KNOW.
BUT YOU ALWAYS
MADE ME SO UPSET
BECAUSE YOU WERE ALWAYS
RIGHT ABOUT EVERYTHING.
I KNOW.
AND I JUST WANTED TO COME
TO LET YOU KNOW I'M OK.
I'M GLAD YOU DID.
AND I JUST--
I JUST WANTED
TO SAY THANK YOU, CLARA.
I DON'T KNOW.
I KNOW.
BUT YOU SEE, DAVID,
YOU AND I
ARE BOUND TOGETHER
BY A SPECIAL FORCE,
AND IT'S A FORCE
SO PERFECT
THAT IT GOES
BEYOND BLOOD.
WELL, I HAVE TO GO.
YEAH, SO I'LL SEE YOU
THE NEXT TIME
I'M IN BALTIMORE, OK?
WHETHER YOU SEE ME
THE NEXT TIME,
OR WHETHER YOU
EVER SEE ME AGAIN,
YOU MUST
KNOW THAT NO
MATTER WHERE I AM,
FOR AS LONG AS I LIVE,
THAT I WILL CARRY YOU
RIGHT HERE IN MY HEART
ALWAYS.
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT 1989
WARNER BROS., INC.