You know, I was waiting
for a ride here tonight
watching the headlights
go by.
And I got to thinking
how different it was
back in the old days.
Standing in front
of a burger stand and waiting.
Yeah, those were the days
of the really
important headlights.
"That him?"
No. Too narrow."
"That him? No."
"Is that him?
No, no."
You know, you'd think
after several hundreds cars,
you'd lose interest.
But that's the one thing
about waiting for drugs.
You never lose interest.
Yeah?
Hey, Martin. What?
Uh...
Whoa, slow down.
What account?
Oh, yeah, that account.
That account, okay.
What problem?
No, no, no. Uh-uh.
No, no, no.
That's just a...
You know, the balance on that
is gonna shift
from time to time.
Yeah.
Yeah. Well,
it's a very fluid account.
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
So you're telling me
the whole $80,000...
All right.
The entire 92,000 isn't there?
Martin, it's there.
Are we talking about
the same thing?
The escrow account, right?
Yeah.
Believe me, it's all there.
Check with the bank
on Monday.
Check with the bank on Monday,
Martin.
Martin, check with the bank
on Monday, would you?
Yeah. No.
No problem. It's okay.
All right, man.
Absolutely. Monday, Martin.
Fuck.
Mm. Yeah.
Where do you get this stuff?
Here.
Get your heart started.
Mm.
Come on,
you little munchkin.
Appears to be comatose.
Yeah, respiration's shallow.
Got anything for me?
Where's your coke?
Excuse me?
Hey, I hardly knew her.
Give me a second,
will you?
Yeah, but now
is not a good time.
It has nothing to do
with the quality.
It's just a bad time.
No. Don't.
Hey, I won't be here.
Hey, I will pay you!
Listen...
Listen to me, kid.
I know you wanna win a bike,
but I already subscribed.
Hey, uh,
she's gonna be all right,
isn't she?
Well, you better hope so,
asshole.
Stay close to home, huh?
Absolutely.
There will be a 20-minute
weather delay.
Attention please.
Flight 38 to Boston
is now boarding
at Gate 9, terminal...
Give me a ticket on the 8:45
to Toronto.
Sir, I see a delay in our
connecting flight in Buffalo.
Fine. What else you got?
What do you mean?
Going where?
I don't care. Vancouver,
Ottawa. It doesn't matter.
I'm afraid we're not getting
an authorization on this card.
Bullshit. It's paid.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
If you have another...
How about cash?
You want cash?
You take that, right?
Give me the fucking card!
Fuck!
You always remember
the moment you knew.
You know, the time you went,
"This is it."
Mine was July 14th, '79.
I was in the shower
after a little
two-day extravaganza.
And I slipped.
So I looked in the mirror
and my nose
was completely bent
all the way over
across my face.
All the way to one side.
So I decided to fix it.
I got a hammer
and began banging it back
to right angle with my face.
Suddenly,
I saw myself in the mirror.
You know, hammer in my hand,
blood on my face.
And something inside me
said,
"Richard,
your life
is no longer manageable."
Either gonna go
to the lake of fire
or in heaven.
God won't force it.
It's your decision.
And I pray in Jesus' name that
you need to pray that prayer.
You, uh...
You want something to eat
or something?
Uh, no, thanks.
Do you have any beer?
I think so.
Wow.
Thanks, honey.
You have
the most amazing hands.
Seriously.
I knew this chick once.
She had...
She was a hand model.
You know, she used
to get paid 7 grand
to hold up a can
of creamed corn.
Thanks, Debbie.
Yeah, Deb.
I'm sorry, man.
Some girl had a heart attack
in my bed.
What?
The cops think
it might have been drugs.
Who was she?
I don't know.
Some girl I met in a mall.
Hey, Martin,
I need a place to stay.
Honey.
Uh, hey,
I don't mean to be rude,
but we have this
tennis thing.
You...
Go ahead, man, go ahead,
you know.
Finish your beer.
Hey, Martin.
Just for a couple of weeks?
Here?
If she dies, they're gonna say
I did a John Belushi on her.
Hey, how am I gonna handle
the escrow thing
when God knows I'm in a fucking
interrogation chamber?
You took the money, didn't you?
No!
Well...
Look, it's real complicated.
I can't explain it now.
Martin!
Look, Daryl.
I don't think so.
You don't look very well,
you know?
Maybe you should see
a doctor.
Okay, I get it.
So then, basically,
it's "Fuck you, Daryl," right?
Okay.
Hey.
You mind giving me another one
of those beers?
WCAU news at 10. Philadelphia.
Did you know that alcoholism
and drug addiction
affect the lives of more than
70 million Americans?
Seventy million? Jesus.
I'm Dr. Paul...
Who do I believe?
Director of Crossroads Center
for chemical dependents.
Hi, Paul, Daryl Poynter.
Nice to meet you.
...lost control of his life
with the disease of addiction,
please know effective treatment
is available now.
Now! Now! Now!
Our 21-day program
is conducted
under a caring
medical supervision
with absolute discretion
and confidentiality.
No one need ever know
you're here.
Furthermore, the program...
Call the insurance company?
Absolutely.
You can write them.
It'll just take
a little longer. Um...
That's fine.
All right. Let me know
if I can be of any help.
Hi.
How you doing?
Good.
These your barns?
No. Afraid not.
Can I help you?
Nice barns.
Yeah. Um, I heard
about the program
and it sounds good to me.
I just wanna make sure
I understand the deals
as far as the, uh,
confidentiality aspect
is concerned.
Yes. Well, The program
is completely confidential.
So no one
would know I was in here?
Not unless you wanted them to.
No.
Great. You take Blue Cross?
Yes, we do.
Good.
Let's say someone,
um, found out I was here
and tried to call me
or wanted to get in here
and bother me or something.
Let me tell you why I ask,
uh...
I'm gonna level with you.
Uh, I got the police
after me
for some old bullshit
traffic violations.
And, you know, I think
it'd be a really good idea
if I just avoided any
outside pressure for a while.
Well, then, this is probably
the safest place you could be.
It's a 21-day program
which begins here in detox.
I'll see what chemicals
you've been using,
prescribe medicine.
Probably Librium
to moderate the effects
of detoxification
on your body.
Most patients using combination
of alcohol and cocaine
remain here detox
for about 48 hours.
Wait a minute,
when you say 48 hours...
The time necessary
for full detoxification varies
with body weight, levels of...
Yeah,
but is 48 hours the norm?
Give or take.
You got a phone I can use?
Sorry,
no calls till downstairs.
You'll probably suffer
from acute nausea
and repeated vomiting.
If you don't make it
to the bowl, fine.
Just push that button, someone
will come by to clean it up.
We keep the room cold, as those
chemicals leave your body,
you're gonna begin to sweat.
There's a television lounge
down the hall,
but most patients end up
spending their time in bed.
You'll sleep on and off.
But you'll sleep.
Probably have one or two poison
dreams, little nightmares.
The thing to keep in mind is
it only last a couple of days.
Yes, about 48 hours, right?
Because that's what the doctor
said. He says about 48 hours.
If you need anything,
have any discomfort,
just hit the button.
Can I use a phone?
Lie down and go to sleep, baby.
It's gonna be all right.
...95, Evergreen Streets
of 20 to 25 miles an hour,
and the Ben Franklin Bridge
backed up to the 30.
Repeating our top story
of the hour.
A group
of unidentified terrorists
have seized an American
passenger plane in Lima, Peru,
and claim
to have set explosives
timed to go off approximately
46 hours from now.
Turning to local weather...
Fucking bitch.
Putting me in this rat hole.
It's your ass.
Even names of the flight crew
at this point
are being withheld from us.
How are you doing?
Any communication
between the jetliner
and any government sources,
that is to say
any communication of any...
And my sources back in America
tell me
that nothing is forthcoming
on their end as well.
So all we can do
at this point is...
Hey.
Forty-three hours
until the threatened time
when this terrorist group
had let be known
that they're prepared
to blow up this jetliner
and everyone on board
in order to prove their point.
What their point is this point
is a mystery to everyone's...
Anybody care
if I change this?
We'll keep you informed,
giving you information,
as we secure it.
Um, it is cold day
here in Lima...
That's all right, I guess.
Fuck it! Fuck it!
Fuck this goddamn place!
Hey!
Open up! Open up!
Open this fucking door!
Call the doctor!
Open it up!
Stop it!
Someone call a doctor.
Get the hell fuck away
from me!
Get the fuck out,
you goddamn it!
Get the fuck out of here.
Where is that exit?
Where is that goddamned door?
Goddamn it.
You wanna say it?
You see that?
Nurse!
Where is that goddamn door!
I told you to keep away
from me!
Don't touch me!
Don't touch me, goddamn it!
Get out of my face,
you motherfucker!
Xavier, we're here to help you.
Stay away from me!
Fuck.
Nurse!
Can I please have a Librium?
You are free to move around.
And in here,
we normally have TV and coffee.
Oh, great.
Is that what I'm gonna
look like tomorrow?
This word just in.
And it has been confirmed
by our American ambassador
here in Lima.
The passengers
will be released.
Here we go.
Goddamn.
And the passengers...
Oh, my God! I don't believe it!
The bomb went off!
It's a fireball!
All those lives!
So, what's next?
Welcome
to the Social Rehab Center.
This is the where you'll spend
the rest of your time.
Someone will get you
a schedule.
All therapy, education,
and activities are mandatory.
If you leave the area
for any reason,
you'll be tested
for chemicals.
If you fail to participate
or comply,
you'll be discharged.
Now, each patient is given one
24-hour pass during their stay.
When their counselor feels
they're ready for the outside.
When you return,
you'll again be tested
for drugs.
If you have any questions,
just ask your counselor.
He's a recovering addict
himself.
His name is Craig
and this is his office.
He'll be back in a minute.
Okay.
Hey, Spence. Big D, man.
How you doing?
Yeah. Look, you've gotta do me
a favor, okay?
Oh, fuck you.
Look, you've gotta send me
some product, okay?
I don't know,
about 5 grams, probably.
What do you mean
you don't have any?
It's your fucking job, man.
Of... Hey, come on, man.
I'm gonna pay you.
I always pay you.
Come on. Hey, Spence.
Hey, Spence.
You fucking asshole.
Coronary Care, please.
Yeah.
I wanna check the condition
of a Karen Peluso.
I don't know
how to spell it.
Yeah. No.
Look, I just wanna know
if she's gonna be all right.
I just wanna check
her condition, please.
Fine. What's ICU?
Never mind that. Never mind
that. Who's her doctor?
What do you mean
you don't know?
You wanna hang up the phone,
please?
Obviously, I'm a relative.
Of course, I'm a relative.
Hang up the phone.
Hey, you wanna give me
a fucking minute, man, okay?
I'm her uncle, all right?
I'm her uncle.
We like to get patients
focused on the program
before they start dealing
with the outside.
You must be Daryl.
I'm Craig.
Well, it's a real pleasure,
Craig.
Except you interrupted a pretty
important fucking phone call.
You can tell me what the big
deal is about the phone here.
I don't understand this.
I mean, what's the story?
I mean, life goes on,
right, Craig?
It's my phone.
Oh, fuck.
Fine. Here.
Tell you what,
we're even.
I think not.
You know what the addict's
least favorite word is?
"No."
Ask me if you can use
my phone now.
Say, Craig,
may I use your phone?
No.
Come on,
I'll show you to your room.
Ah.
I'm feeling better already.
Hi!
I think
I'm your roommate.
Is this yours?
Go ahead.
Your bed?
I'm Donald.
Donald Towle.
Daryl.
I was in detox
for five days.
Five days is the longest
I've ever been without a drink.
Ever.
I've been drinking
since I was 9.
So how about you?
What's your...?
Bob. Alcoholic.
I'm with American Cyanamid.
And I wanna stop.
I know I can stop.
I gotta stop.
Roger Tiller.
Alcoholic, addict.
I'm a hair consultant.
Color and whatnot.
I promised a friend
I'd do this.
Oh, um, Iris.
Listen. I gotta run down
the bathroom for a minute.
I mean, I don't know what
I'm supposed to be doing here.
I take that back. I'm here.
And I'm glad I'm here.
I guess.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hey, Spence, how you doing?
Big D again.
Listen, I gotta talk to you
for a minute.
Don't hang up on me.
Don't...
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Here's a healthy liver.
It weighs
about 3 and a half pounds.
This liver
of a chronic alcoholic
weighed 15 pounds.
The microscopic picture here
shows healthy liver cells.
Alcohol replaces them
with massive deposits of fat
which obstruct
the liver's functions.
I had been drinking vodka
for a long time.
But there was no indication
that I was sick.
I didn't consider myself
an...
Look, all you gotta do
is go to my desk, okay?
There's an envelope, bottom
right-hand drawer in the back.
It's a little
recreational stuff.
Now you take that envelope,
seal it up,
take it to Federal Express,
and you tell them
it's a priority delivery.
A top fucking priority.
Bang that into their heads,
Martin.
Daryl, I'm with clients.
All right, all right.
Give me the address.
It's a hospital?
You're in a hospital?
Yeah,
I'm having some tests done.
I'm just having some tests
done.
Exercise.
Good for the body,
good for the soul.
Helps us build up
a little appetite for dinner.
Some of our
chemically-dependent bodies
are not used
to a little physical exertion.
Huh, Daryl?
Best way to break old habits
is to start new ones.
One, two...
Right, Bob?
Yes, sir.
Fun, huh?
One, two, three, four,
five, six.
Focus on the program, huh?
Three, four, five, six...
"That's right, Daryl.
Thanks for asking."
And basically,
Fuck you, Daryl. Okay.
Cheryl Ann.
I'm an alcoholic,
I'm an addict.
I'm a mother too.
At least I was
when I got here.
I'm having
a pretty hard time here.
No shit.
I just really
wanna get my life back.
Me too.
Give me a drink.
Come on, come on, come on.
Oh, come on, Gordon,
just tell me where we stand
on DW Industries, all right?
Fuck it.
Yeah, I'll hold.
Craig said
I could use the phone.
I don't understand, did Craig
say you could use the phone?
Then use somebody else's
terminal.
I gave you $90,000,
for Christ's sake!
And you want me not to know
how my money is doing
because some asshole spilled a
Tab on your fucking terminal?
You're gonna be here long?
A minute, yeah.
Come on.
Pardon me, asshole.
You're a delicate young thing.
Fuck you!
Gordon.
Oh, no shit. Really?
Yeah. If it went from 60,000
to 40,000 in three fucking days,
I guess it is sloping downward.
You fucking jerk.
Sell it all
and we'll short it.
Yeah. Yeah.
Listen, I want you to do me
a favor, okay?
I want you to call this guy
at my office.
Yeah. His name is Martin.
Yeah.
I'll call you back, okay?
Thanks.
I just had to make a...
I think you better leave.
Is there a problem?
Just take this
to the front office.
Wait a second,
I don't understand, uh...
Was there a problem?
I want you out of here.
Why? Because I used
your fucking phone?
That was a 90,000-dollar
phone call, man.
Ninety thousand dollars.
Ninety grand, man!
That's the stock market,
babe!
It doesn't give a fuck
if I'm in the hospital or not.
Hey,
the American Stock Exchange
really doesn't care
if some asshole
makes $300 a week,
says I can't use
the fucking phone!
I'm close, right, Craig?
Like 310, maybe 315, right?
Right? That's about it,
isn't it, Craigy?
Yeah.
Oh, boy, big 307 a week.
Boy, you gotta allocate
that motherfucker, don't you?
What, that lean cuisine?
Maybe some pork and beans?
Hey, why don't you get yourself
another pair
of those plastic shoes?
Fine!
You want me out of here?
I'm fucking out of here!
I'm gone!
Motherfucker,
look at his back.
Fuck!
Gone, baby. The big fade.
Fucking A, baby.
Fucking B, C and D too, man.
I'm out of here, asshole!
Fuck you!
I don't fucking
believe it.
Fuck!
Fuck.
It's okay.
I work here.
I come back.
I got an emergency deal.
I need to find this contract,
really. It's okay.
This guy, he's nuts.
He never sleeps.
I'll come back.
Okay. Hey, I'll straight up
all this paper work, okay?
By the time you come back,
you wouldn't even know
I was here, all right?
It's all right, really.
It's okay.
Okay?
It's all right.
Hi. Daryl.
How are you?
Oh, jeez, I'm sorry, Ma.
I... Is it really?
Yeah, I was working
in the office here
and I didn't realize
how late it had gotten.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
No, I'm fine, really.
I just remembered
how I hadn't called you
in a while, I thought...
No. No, everything's great.
Great. Yeah.
How are you, guys?
Well, make him get somebody
to do the lawn, Ma.
Well, then, you know, you get
somebody to do the lawn, Ma.
I mean, the lawn
is not gonna look much good
with a dead guy
lying in the middle of it
clutching his heart, is it?
Yeah.
No, everything's fine,
I'm telling you.
Yeah. I'm great.
Well, you know, I mean,
there is one thing I...
I'm in a little bit
of a, uh...
I'm in the middle
of a cash-crunch thing here,
a little bit.
I was just wondering
if I maybe could hit you guys
up for a little advance.
Um...
About $30,000.
Yeah. No, I know.
I know how much money that is.
You didn't bring me stupid, Ma.
Yeah.
Well, as a matter of fact
I do know where you can get
that kind of money.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm talking about the house.
Right. You do a second.
And then,
you send me the payment book.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute... Ma.
I know exact...
I know how long you've lived
in that house.
Yes, this is not... No!
Calm down.
Nobody's telling you to move.
You don't have to move.
You just go to a bank.
It's done all the time.
It's...
Forget that.
Forget about that.
Let me talk to you
about something else.
Do you remember last year
when you and Dad went
to Fort Wayne
and you had the will
drawn up?
Are you gonna leave me anything
in that?
Ma.
What are you crying for?
Ma, what are you crying for?
I'm just trying
to figure out a way...
Ma!
Wait a minute.
What's gonna give you
more pleasure?
more pleasure than, you know,
give me that money now
while you're still alive,
when you get a chance to see me
get some use out of it?
Or later
when I may or may not?
Ma.
Ma, stop crying, would you?
Stop crying and put...
Put dad on the phone.
Put Dad on the phone.
You got somewhere to go?
You better go there.
Look.
Just leave me alone
for a minute.
I call police.
You got somewhere to go,
you better go there.
So, yeah, you know.
I'm out there driving around
and looking for a program.
Thanks.
And I say to myself,
"Well, hey, I'm already in one.
They got all the paperwork.
I know all the people.
I really like that counselor,
Craig."
Yeah.
They're gonna be pretty happy
with this one, Craig.
Pretty fucking happy.
How many of you have been
to an AA meeting before?
Okay.
Now, your job tonight
is to find a sponsor.
What's a sponsor?
Somebody you can relate to.
Somebody who's heard
all your bullshit before.
Somebody who...
Well, you'll know who.
You'll know him right away.
Hi, I'm Jane,
your Alcoholics secretary.
Hi, Jane.
Sheila is gonna be leading the
meeting this evening. Sheila.
I'm okay.
Hi. I'm Sheila.
Alcoholic addict.
Hi, Sheila.
"Rarely have we seen
a person fail
"who has thoroughly followed
our path.
"Those who do not recover
are people who cannot
"or will not completely
give themselves
to this simple program."
You wanna be my sponsor?
"Usually, men and women
drew a constitutionally..."
No, thanks.
Hey, I'm serious on this.
"They are not at fault..."
It's a good deal.
"There are those too
who suffer
"from great emotional
and mental disorders.
"But many of them do recover
if they have the capacity
to be honest."
Thank you.
We have a 30-day chip
going to Mark
for his first 30 days
of sobriety.
Hi.
Daryl Poynter.
Addict, alcoholic.
You know, I thought you did
an amazing job
of running the meeting
tonight.
Really.
I mean, I... You know,
this is my first meeting
and actually, I was...
I was really moved.
Really?
Truly.
Truly. You know, it's funny
we should be talking here
because, actually,
I'm, uh...
Kind of, you know,
looking for a sponsor.
A sponsor?
Yeah.
You know, a sponsor, and...
Um, I'm sorry.
I don't think so.
You know,
but I you could help me.
See, I think
you could help me a lot.
A whole lot.
That was very nice.
Very smooth.
Yeah. You like that?
I got a million of them.
Yeah, I'll bet you do.
Hey, sorry about that situation
at the phone the other day.
Don't worry about it.
I was kind of wrapped up
on something.
Yeah.
What's your name?
Charlie.
Charlene. Charlie
Charlie? Okay.
You having any luck, uh,
finding someone?
No. Not really.
Yeah, well, me neither.
I guess guys
aren't supposed to have
female sponsors
or something.
That's too bad.
Tell me about it.
You're a newcomer.
Excuse me?
Sheila said
you're looking for a sponsor.
Yeah. Well,
I just came out here
to get some fresh air.
Really can't wait to get
to that phone, can you?
Here. Give me your back.
If you're looking
for a sponsor,
you phone this number.
Name's Richard.
Good night.
Someone's here to see you.
Said it's important.
Martin. You dog.
How are you?
All right.
How are you doing, buddy?
Jesus.
I practically had to beg
the guy to let me in here.
Yeah, a classy joint.
You didn't tell me
what it was.
Yeah. Well, how you doing?
How's the office?
Good.
Well, somebody broke in
a couple of nights ago
and trashed the place.
Jesus.
Mm.
Hey, I really appreciate your
coming down here this late.
You know, you could have gotten
a messenger to do it.
It's empty.
It's what?
There's nothing in it.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
I flushed it
down the toilet.
Look, Daryl.
We had an incident
yesterday morning, okay?
Some crazy guy came in
shouting and screaming.
What guy?
A man named Peluso.
He came in, said you gave drugs
to his daughter.
But half the staff heard him,
including Kramer.
Fucking great.
She died, Daryl.
What?
He said she died.
Night before last.
He threatened
to make a lot of trouble.
And then a guy
from the DA's office came by,
and interviewed all of us,
Daryl.
Kramer too. I mean, Kramer...
Kramer really wants
to talk to you, Daryl.
Now, I can tell him you're
in the hospital, but, hey, man,
at some point, you're gonna
have to deal with him.
And you gotta to come up
with the money you took.
Look, I gotta go.
I had to work late.
Debbie's waiting.
Daryl, you okay?
Look, Daryl.
I really gotta go now.
Shall we?
Tell me how happy I'm gonna be
with this one, Daryl.
Am I going to be happy?
Let me ask you something.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
You got a problem, Daryl?
You don't even know
you've got a problem, do you?
You know how long
you've been straight, man?
Twelve days.
Twelve whole days.
Twelve days,
three hours and 20 seconds.
Twenty-four seconds.
Twenty-six seconds.
That's how we do it, Daryl.
A second at a time.
A minute at a time.
One day at a time.
But you gotta know
you got problem.
Drink up, will you?
Hey.
All right, uh,
ladies and gentlemen,
can I have
your attention please?
Hello?
Good morning.
My name is Craig.
And I would like to welcome you
to family group.
Now, I know how hard this is
for everybody.
A lot of us have been...
very angry,
very worried
for a long time.
But don't be afraid
to speak honestly.
What do you mean, bitch?
You took my fucking rock!
What the hell
do you expect?
Your old man steals
your visa,
kicks your ass every day!
You'd jam his damn freebase
down the sink too!
I wanna ask a question.
I wanna know
what is she doing here?
Jesus, Lenny.
They were gonna fire me,
right?
And they didn't fire me,
which is good.
Because I like buying gas
so you can make it to your
probation officer, okay?
Good. Thanks.
Everybody hear that?
I'm on probation.
Way to go, Charlie.
I'm sorry.
And fuck your job!
Hey, no.
No, I can't fuck my job!
I like having a steel mill
to go to
when you're throwing fucking
telephones to the window.
Beats throwing her
through the fucking window,
Doesn't it?
Oh, Christ.
Fuck!
All right, people,
time for shower.
How you feeling, Daryl?
I was feeling just dandy,
Craig, old pal,
till you shoved your foot
up my ass.
Listen.
I'm starting to give
some of the people passes.
A little time
to be on their own.
You think
you can handle that?
Possibly.
Yeah.
You gonna fuck with me?
No.
All right.
This is Spence.
I'm out for a while.
Leave your name and number
where you can be reached
at the beep.
Spence. Daryl.
Pick up, will you?
I wanna do some business,
man.
Come on, Spence, pick up.
This is Daryl.
Shit!
We're sorry, you have reached
a number that...
Hello?
Hey, Larry.
This is Daryl.
I'd like to do
some business.
You would, huh?
Well, I would too, Daryl,
but I think you dialed
the wrong number.
This is Richard.
We met the other night.
Oh, Richard.
Jesus, I got the wrong number.
I was just...
Where are you?
Daryl, Daryl. Listen to me.
I... I wanna see you.
I can't get away now,
but how about 12:30?
Why?
Why? Why do you think why?
Daryl, lets... I want you to do
something for me.
Do you know
what an inventory is?
It's a list of everything
you've done
that caused harm
to other people.
I want you to make one.
A fearless and searching
moral inventory, Daryl.
Write it down
and have it with you at 12:30.
Fearless and searching
moral inventory.
Hey, look...
Daryl, Daryl.
Now, just do it.
It will take your mind off
calling Larry.
There's a coffee shop
at the corner
of Second and Market.
Yeah, I'll bet there is.
What are you gonna bring?
Drugs. Lots of drugs.
An inventory.
Now, you got an hour
and a half.
Go park yourself someplace
and do it.
Sorry, I'm late.
Addicts are always late.
Thanks, hon.
No.
What is it with you guys
and food?
You're like wild dogs.
Addicts are compulsive.
You got your inventory?
Uh-huh.
Call Larry?
No.
Do you want something to eat?
No, it's all right.
"Halloween, 1964,
"I put a cherry bomb
in this guy's air conditioner.
"1970,
I faked a stamp on my hand
"to get into a church dance.
"1976, I told some girls
"I played
in the Pam American Games
"when I really didn't.
"Two weeks ago,
I borrowed $92,000
"from an escrow account.
"1981, I guess,
I first moved out here.
"Took a blender back to Sears
that I broke.
Told them it was fucked up
when I bought it."
You asleep yet?
What's with this 92,000?
I was a little short.
For coke?
I needed a few
thousand dollars, so...
I put some money
in some stock options.
Made a little at first
then the market got weird.
How much you lose?
Fifty-two thousand dollars.
You get along
with your boss?
There some way
he'll let you pay it back?
I don't know.
You see,
this guy...
His daughter had a heart attack
in my bed.
And he went into the office,
screaming, yelling
how I killed his daughter,
because I gave her drugs.
Did you?
No. She gave them to me.
What about the police?
You know,
told me not to leave town.
You an addict, Daryl?
Funny how the mind works.
Proof that you're not an addict
because you're not dead, right?
I don't believe this shit.
What?
That I'm fucking here.
Are you an addict, Daryl?
Fuck you.
Yeah, I tell you, Craig,
old pal.
All you're gonna find
in this one,
a couple of milkshakes,
baby.
Well, more than that,
actually.
Five. Five milkshakes.
The chemical equivalent
of nitro-fucking-glycerine.
Yeah, I can barely
see straight, man.
Get that snake out of there.
Come on, you python.
There you go.
I got him all coiled up
after lasso practice.
Well, we've been together
a long time.
It's hard with him,
you know.
Why? What makes it hard?
I don't know. He's stupid.
Like I...
He... He... He ripped off
all this cable, you know,
from the phone company,
uh...
You know,
all those spools they've got
that lie underground,
you know?
I come home one night
and there's 152-ton spools
of wire in my backyard.
And there was this
Mafia fuck
who was supposed to broker
it all for the copper.
So Lenny and him,
they got into an argument.
and Lenny shoots him
in the foot.
Then the cops come
and Lenny goes to jail.
You do any drugs
while Lenny was away?
How you doing, Daryl?
Just groovy, Craig.
Iris?
Okay.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, I'm fine. Thanks.
Where'd you get the stuff?
What do you mean?
I mean the stuff you took
before you came in here.
I can see it in your eyes.
My eyes are fine.
Then you don't know
what I'm talking about?
Afraid not.
There are a lot of people
here trying hard
to stay clean, Iris.
I think you owe it to them
to tell me the truth.
All right, Iris,
if you're using,
I want you to leave.
Right now.
Hey, Chuck, what's shaking?
Besides you, I mean.
Hey, too bad about Iris,
huh?
Yeah, too bad.
She was your roommate,
right?
You take two desserts?
Okay.
So I guess you're gonna be
all alone up there
for the last few days.
Tough duty, Chuck.
Tough duty.
Look. I just want you to know,
you know,
if sleeping alone
starts to get you down...
You know what I mean.
I mean, sometimes...
I just know
how tough it's gonna be
to have to sleep alone.
I'll bet you do.
He went away
And you hung around
And bothered me
Every night
And when I wouldn't go out
With you
You said things
That weren't very nice
My boyfriend's back
And you're gonna be
In trouble
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Come on.
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
You been spreading lies
That I was untrue
Ooh.
Go, girl.
So look out now
'Cause he's comin'
After you
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Hey, he knows
That you been trying
A little jerk?
And he knows
That you been lying
He's been gone
For such a long time
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Now he's back
And things'll be fine
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Here we go.
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
No.
No, I can't do it.
Come on, Bob.
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Hey, he knows
I wasn't cheating
Now you're gonna get
A beating
What made you think
He'd believe all your lies?
Wah-ooo, wah-ooo
You're a big man now
But he'll cut you down
To size
My boyfriend's back
He's gonna save
My reputation
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Hey
I can see him coming
Now, you better start
A-running
Go!
Wah-ooo, wait and see
My boyfriend's back
He's gonna save
My reputation
Hey-la, hey-la
My boyfriend's back
Yeah
Look out now
My boyfriend's back
Well
I can see him coming
So you better get a-running
Right now
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah
Oh!
Hipsters.
Now, take a little stroll
down memory lane to 1962.
Kennedy
was in the White House.
Bobby was in
Marilyn's house.
Haircuts were a dollar
apiece.
The baby boom was on.
And everybody wants
to be happy.
If you wanna be happy
For the rest of your life
Never make a pretty woman
Your wife
So from my personal
Point of view
Get an ugly girl
To marry you
If you wanna be happy
For the rest of your life
Never make a pretty woman
Your wife
So from my personal
Point of view
You're staring, man.
Who?
A pretty woman
Makes her husband look small
And very often
Causes his downfall
As soon
As he marries her
Then she starts to do
The things that...
Oh.
And she's out of there.
What?
Oh, God, it's Ike.
Checks in here all the time.
Ike Turner.
She'll always give you
Peace of mind
If you wanna be happy
For the rest of your life
Never make a pretty woman
Your wife
What are you talking
about?
Did you read about
what he did to Tina, man?
It took her 15 years
to get away from that guy.
He's like some fucking
Svengali guy.
Tina said he has his tongue
the size of an anteater's.
He'd bore it
down her throat.
Her whole body would go
into a trance.
Never make a pretty woman
Your wife
Fuck you,
the guy's name's Gary.
Get an ugly girl
To marry you
If you wanna be happy
For the rest of your life
Never make a pretty woman
Your wife
So from my personal
Point of view
Get an ugly girl
To marry you
If you wanna be happy
For the rest of your life
Never make a pretty woman
Your wife
So from my personal
Point of view
Uh-oh.
What?
Oh, God.
She told him she doesn't use
birth control.
So now Ike's going to Xavier,
see if he's got one of those
huge rubbers those guys use.
Big lambskin mothers.
Look like
Tomahawk missiles.
I think I'm gonna move in
while she's still hot.
Hey, put it in park,
you little pecker.
You like to dance?
Yeah.
Yeah. I know.
I mean with me.
Oh.
Oh, with you.
Yeah.
Come here.
When you just give love
Oh, wonderful.
A slow one.
You want me to have them
kick it up to '78?
Oh, it's okay.
You'd better let love
Depart
I know it's so
And yet I know
I can't get you
Out of my heart
Jesus.
What?
I haven't done this
in a long time.
Not straight anyway.
You made me leave
My happy home
Are you scared?
Of what?
I don't know, you know?
You're gone
Tomorrow, you'll getting out
of here and everything.
Yeah, a little. Are you?
A little.
Yeah, I'm a little...
you know?
Love brings such misery
And pain
I guess I'll never be
The same
So, what do you do?
I run a crane.
A crane?
A gantry crane
in a steel mill.
I'm the token cunt.
No kidding?
No kidding.
Well, it's too bad
So you like it?
I like the union.
I like the medical
and the dental.
I like the job security.
What, a job security
running a crane?
Yeah. Long as once a month
I forget to wear a bra
and show them my high beams
there is.
You love me
Then you snub me
What do you do?
Real estate. I sell
commercial real estate.
What's so funny?
Nothing. I just knew.
Just knew what?
I knew.
A slick guy like you
had to do
some kind of bogus
tap-dancing for a living.
Why, thank you.
Thank you very much.
I get the blues
Most every night
So you wanna get together and
do something when we get out?
I live with somebody,
remember?
Yeah, I know.
Right. I know.
I'm talking about
something casual, you know.
You bring Lenny.
Ah, you can't talk.
Listen to me. You come
to my house for dinner.
I go to your house for dinner.
You're coming to my house?
Yeah. I wanna come
to your house for dinner.
You, me and Lenny?
People do it all the time.
You're nuts.
For you
Be honest with yourselves.
Go to your meetings.
Talk to your sponsors.
And for Christ's sake,
talk to each other.
If you need a phone number,
call me.
I'll put you in touch.
You'll make it.
Jesus.
You got ants in your tuner.
Where's your stash?
Stash?
What stash? The cops
were all over this place.
You mind if I take a look?
Now, I'm going to assume
that more to your friends
these days
are selling drugs.
So I want you to screen
all of your calls.
What's your situation
at work?
Damn, you don't let up,
do you?
I want you to spend
the next day or two
figuring exactly how you're
gonna straighten things out.
Don't worry,
I'll handle it.
How?
You mean,
you dance around the problem
till it gets so big
you can't handle it?
Pretty good excuse
for getting high, right?
Hey, look...
No, no, no. You look.
Now, what you do
is you sit down
and write out exactly what
you're gonna tell your boss.
If you're afraid of him,
you take the paper
and use it like a script.
But whatever the case,
you tell him everything.
You tell him the truth.
Yeah, right.
And he congratulates me
and give me a raise.
It's an AA schedule.
Don't lose it.
Anytime you wanna go
to a meeting,
look in there.
You'll find one.
Motherfucking...
Motherfucking god...
Hi. Is this Mrs. Towle?
Yeah.
My name's Daryl Poynter.
I was your son's roommate
at the clinic.
Yeah. I'm thinking about going
to one of those AA meetings.
I was just wondering
if Donald wanted to go
or he needed a ride.
I don't know.
Oh, he's not.
No, no. That's all right.
Just tell him I called.
Okay. Thank you.
Dum, dum, dum-do-dum
Do-do-do
Do-do-do-do...
Dum, dum, dum-do-dum
Do-do-do
Come softly, darling
Hey, Chuck.
I was just
in the neighborhood.
I thought I'd stop by.
Yeah? Well,
I'm fixing dinner.
Yeah, well, uh...
Yeah, I just wanted to see
how you're doing.
How are you doing?
I got an 8:00 shift.
Okay.
Okay. We don't want...
I'll stop some other time.
Hey.
You could join us
if you like.
This is nice.
Are you sure
this is okay?
Sure. Why not?
Lenny!
What?
This is one of the guys
from the clinic.
Hi. How you doing?
Daryl Poynter.
Doing all right.
So why do debutantes
hate group sex?
Oh, Jesus.
They have to write
too many thank you notes.
You live around here?
Oh, yeah. Kind of.
I... Sort of... Yeah.
No. I thought it was,
you know, a good idea
to just keep in touch
with some of the people
in the program.
You wouldn't believe
what a mess this guy was.
Yeah, well.
So, Lenny,
what kind of work are you in?
I'm a doctor.
A brain surgeon.
Hmm.
I'm through.
You know,
I don't know you very well,
and probably
none of my business,
but you figure that's really
a smart thing to do
around Charlie and me,
you know?
Dinner's over.
She's gotta go to work.
Why don't you get
the fuck out of here.
I don't think
you understand...
Lenny,
are you driving me to work
or am driving myself?
Sorry.
It's okay.
It keeps life
interesting.
It keeps Lenny
on his toes.
It was really
kind of nice.
So, what's next?
What do you mean
what's next?
I don't know.
I wanna take you to a movie
or something.
I... I don't think so.
Come on.
There's a movie theater
right down the street.
Tomorrow's Saturday.
Just tell him you're going
shopping or something.
Tomorrow at 3.
Hi. This is Daryl.
You know what to do
and when to do it.
Daryl? Richard Dirks.
Now, what's the deal
with your boss?
You gotta take care of that
right now.
You know that.
All right, you made it.
Ugh!
They got a good flick today.
The Care Bears Movie
and five color cartoons.
You seen them?
I screwed up.
Matinees, you know.
Yeah, well,
I don't have too much time,
you know, so...
Oh, yeah. I guess
this isn't too cool out here.
Okay. Come on.
No.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Just looking at you.
It's nice to see you.
Why?
I don't know.
I'm alone all day, you're nice.
Would you stop?
Would you staring at me?
Oh, okay.
All right, I'm sorry.
You're right.
I just kind of wanna talk
about something.
Why'd you bring me to a movie?
You don't talk in the movie.
Okay, let's go someplace.
I don't wanna go someplace.
What it is, is...
What? What it is is what?
Well...
What it is...
I'm trying to organize
my life.
You know what I mean?
I am, and I know you are...
Yeah. So?
So, I mean...
Why don't we try
and do it together?
I mean, you know, honestly,
this is not about sex
or anything.
It's not about cooking.
I don't know what it's about.
Wait. What the...?
Charlie!
What?
What? What the fuck
do you want me to do?
If I stay home, I get high.
If I come here,
I get steamrolled by you!
What the fuck
do you want me to do?
I'm getting out of here.
Why?
None of your goddamn
business!
Hey!
Fuck.
It's been damn near a week.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm just getting
everything I need to say
on paper.
Like you suggested.
It takes time.
Not a week.
Do you want me
to drive you?
No. No, I'll... I'll go.
I'm going right now.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Well, I came to apologize.
Will you just
leave me alone?
Here. Let me give you a hand
on some of this.
I got it, I got it.
Look, if I get a little
out of hand sometimes,
it's because...
Yeah, because you don't think
about anybody but yourself.
What am I to do?
Say, "Fuck you" to a guy
I've been with 10 years?
Look, what I'm trying
to say is...
I know what
you're trying to say.
Here. Let me get this.
I...
Look, I admit it.
You know, I'm not functioning
great these days. I'm sorry.
Uh, I don't know what for,
but I'm sorry.
I just wanna see you again.
That's all.
Come see where I live,
all right?
There's no hot TVs,
no spools of telephone wire.
What do you say?
You work tonight?
No, I'm off.
Let me cook you dinner.
Call me, all right?
I'm in the book!
I brought some tequila.
Nice touch.
Eighteen, huh?
Eighteen.
Married,
pregnant and happy.
I was.
I mean, that's the way life's
supposed to go, right?
Grade school, junior high,
high school, married, baby.
All right.
So, what happened?
The bump died.
We called it the bump.
I was seven months
pregnant.
I got real sick
and the bump died.
And then Charlie left.
Charlie and Charlie.
Charlie and Charlene.
Oh.
We were a hell
of a couple.
But he left.
And that's
when I moved to Darby.
My uncle got me a job
in the steel mill.
Six dollars an hour to start,
and that was '72.
So here I am.
Here you are.
You want some more coffee
or something?
I think I better go.
Why?
I told Lenny I was working.
So?
So, what if he calls,
I'm not there?
Live with me.
I can't.
Why not?
I can't leave Lenny.
Because...
Because why?
Because it's not that easy.
It is.
All you gotta do is want it.
Well, I don't know
if I want it.
Well, you know,
you deserve somebody
who cares about you.
You know,
maybe it's not me.
I mean,
it might be somebody else,
but it sure ain't Lenny.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
All you gotta do is tell him.
Fuck it, I'll tell him.
No! Hey, no.
Hey, I'll tell him!
I can't tell him.
Why?
Because you're afraid?
Don't be afraid.
Don't you get it?
You never gonna have to see
this guy again. Ever.
I'll go to the house.
I'll get your stuff out.
He won't have to deal with you,
he'll have to deal with me.
Just tell him.
You know what?
I've been writing this script
for myself
for this thing
I got at work.
Here.
Let's write one for you.
Jesus.
You really buy
into all this shit, don't you?
Look, let's just try it,
okay?
I mean, Christ,
let's just try it.
Okay, here.
That's you and that's Lenny.
"I love you
for what we had,
but now my life
is a lot different."
Give me a fucking break.
Hey, you wanna write it?
Go ahead, put it in your words,
I don't care.
What's that?
That's his probable response,
okay?
But if you stick to that,
you can't get confused.
Oh, man.
Here.
You wanna tell him tonight?
Listen, I'm here, okay?
And I wanna help you.
Lenny, hi.
Yeah, it's me.
I'm still at work.
Um, listen...
Listen, I got something
I wanna say to you, okay.
Yeah, okay.
Well, will you just listen
just for a second. I got some...
Okay, just listen to this.
Lenny, I've had lot of time
to think lately
and sort out my feelings
and make some hard choices.
"Where are you,
you fucking douche bag?"
I don't see that there.
"Get your ass home now,
bitch."
Tell him
you're not gonna go home.
Tell him you not gonna do
anything, anything,
until he listens
to what you have to say.
Do it.
Lenny.
Uh...
Uh-huh.
All right.
Fuck.
Charlie!
Hey!
Daryl. Hey, look at you.
Yeah, look at me.
You're back, fella.
Yeah, I'm back.
I'm back, I'm smoking
like a fucking chimney.
I had to go to the can
every 10 minutes but I'm back.
What's it like up there?
Good. It's good.
Yeah?
I told Kramer you were laid up.
Yeah, thanks,
I appreciate it.
No, man. It's nothing.
Really.
Uh, you're gonna have
to talk to him, Daryl.
I know. I know that.
What should I say? I mean,
what's the thinking in there?
Come on, Martin,
my ass is on the line here.
I know that. I know that.
Kramer's not a bad guy,
Daryl.
You know,
it'll be okay.
It'll be okay.
They figure
they gonna fool him
and bring in the lead pipes
and bought all kinds of stuff.
He guesses them all.
Then they bring in this hooker.
I'm sorry,
there's a meeting here.
Yeah, I know that.
Uh...
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but I, uh...
I think, uh, I should
kind of clear up
the situation
of the escrow account
before it really gets blown
out of proportion.
But, you know, I can come back
at another time
if it'll be more convenient.
No, Daryl. Not at all.
This is as good a time
as any.
Well, uh, here it is.
I, uh...
I was just in the hospital
for a while and, uh...
The best that I can
put it together is...
What happened was, um...
I had one of the girls
do a telephone transfer for me.
I wanted to consolidate
the 92,000
with another account.
And, uh, by mistake,
it was a stupid thing.
I accidentally gave her
my own personal
checking account number.
And, uh...
Like I said,
I was laid up in the hospital,
and I really didn't know
what had happened
until just a little
while ago.
So you've corrected
the problem?
Yeah. Almost.
Almost?
Well, I owe the IRS
a couple of hundred dollars
and they've frozen
my account.
But as soon as I get a check,
everything will be fine.
Honestly.
Did you take the money, Daryl?
Did you spend it, Daryl?
Did you have
an emergency?
I put most of it
in the stock market.
Why, Daryl?
I had a drug problem.
And I went into a program
at a clinic.
And now I'm back
on my feet again.
Well, that's fine.
But we're still talking
about embezzlement here.
People go to jail
for that sort of thing.
Fuck! You people...
Go to jail?
Hey!
Hank, we could go to jail...
All of us could go to jail,
man.
On a lot of stuff.
Did you ever look at one
of this guy's appraisals.
They're not that bad.
Oh, fuck you!
"Not that bad," man.
This guy, this Vietnam vet,
this All-State athlete,
he gets 90 percent financing
on a $300,000 building
that's only worth 2.
Right?
Then he takes the extra cash
and he buys
an apartment complex.
Sells it for double, gives
the bank back their money,
and then takes what's left,
he puts into a company boat.
Get the fuck out of here,
company boat.
How's the fishing, Ron?
Hank, Bob?
Better
than the stock market.
Yeah? Maybe.
I think we see your point,
Daryl.
Look...
I fucked up.
But, you know...
Hey, you know,
take a look at my sales record.
And I promise you
I'll pay you back
you know,
out of my commissions.
Well, why don't you give us
a few minutes?
All right.
Okay.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Right away.
He sees this naked woman
standing in a window
looking down
and driving a car at night.
I'll tell you later.
We've gone over everything,
Daryl.
And we've decided to give you
a break on the embezzlement.
So long
as you make restitution.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thanks.
However,
we have no alternative
but to terminate you
as of today.
We'll decide whether to report
you to the licensing board.
Wait a minute.
That's all, Daryl.
Whoa! Wait a minute!
Whoa!
You guys know how many
properties I sold last quarter?
Twenty-three.
Twenty-three properties.
Please tell security...
Me! By myself. For you, man!
Charlie,
you got a phone call!
I don't know what happened.
I don't know what I'm doing,
you know.
I don't know
why I called you.
what I'm doing.
Listen,
I'm gonna take you home.
I'll drop you off around
the corner from your house.
No, no.
No, don't take me home.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Just drive the car.
Just...
Oh, man.
"Oh, man," what?
Just, oh, man.
Daryl,
I've been through a lot.
Yeah, I know. So have I.
I mean, really a lot.
Are you attracted to me?
Yeah.
You haven't been
through nothing yet.
Hey.
Here's a thought.
Why don't you
call in sick today?
Ha! You're not worth it, babe.
Someday, when you have a job,
you'll understand.
Very funny.
I want you
to know something.
I've had hundreds of offers.
Hundreds of them.
Well, thousands even,
actually.
It's really gonna boil down
to who's got the best parking
and the nicest cafeteria.
Is this what you do
with Lenny?
Maybe that's why I'm here.
Flush it down the toilet.
Gonna be some happy rats
in the sewers tonight.
You gonna stay?
Do you wanna stay?
I don't know.
This is pretty much of a dump
you got here.
Why don't you get a job,
you bum?
Uh, Daryl. D-A-R-Y-L.
Poynter, P-O-Y...
Yeah, that's Poynter.
P-O-Y-N-T-E-R.
That's a Y, not an I.
Poynter.
What does that mean?
It means, uh...
It means hard worker.
Uh, 34. I was born in 1954.
April 3rd, 1955.
Twenty-seven.
Twenty-seven last month
as a matter of fact.
Yeah, well, the thing is I was
up to 47,500 in my last job.
So I couldn't possibly
take anything less than that.
Low 40s.
You know, that ballpark.
I'm flexible, I guess.
Money? Salary?
I don't know. It isn't really
the main consideration for me.
Oh, oh
My, my, my, my
I'm so glad
You stopped by
To say hello to me
Remember that's the way
It used to be
Ooh
It seems like
A mighty long time
I'm sorry.
If I did stuff
to make it hard for you
it's only because
I was having problems too.
You always have problems.
I know.
I always have problems.
I do always have problems.
But if you're not around,
I don't make it at all.
Somebody wanna to tell me
what's happening here?
Nothing.
Nothing's happening here.
Really?
I'd like him to leave.
Fuck you.
Fuck me?
Fuck me? No, no, fuck you!
You're in my house now,
asshole.
So get the fuck out!
Where are you going?
You don't need me, Daryl.
Whoa, whoa,
where do this come from?
Look around you.
Look at all you've got.
Your plates match.
You don't drink
out of jelly jars.
Wanna say something,
you sit down
and you figure out
how to say it.
You cut your goddamn grass!
What the hell
do you need me for?
What do you mean?
I do need you! And you need me!
Wait, didn't you see this
coming to you?
He's gonna do this, come back
and work you like this again.
What are you gonna do now?
Go home and light
his fucking pipe for him,
let him snort coke
off your tits?
What part of him
you gonna snort off?
Bye.
Yeah?
Hi. Hey, listen,
I think I've got something.
I mean, you know, it's gonna
take some negotiating.
Daryl,
don't call me anymore.
Six, nineteen to go
in the half.
WIT in Philadelphia
as the Eagles
leave the Cowboys.
Hello?
No, she's not home
right now.
Who's this?
Who was that?
Where are you going?
Cigarettes.
I need cigarettes.
Hello?
I know what you're thinking,
Daryl.
You're thinking you could've
done something for her, right?
That it's your fault, right?
You can give up
on yourself now, right?
That's what you're thinking,
isn't it, Daryl?
But you've gotta understand.
That's absolutely conceited,
Daryl.
It's self-important
and conceited.
Are you getting this?
It's important.
Because a guy who thinks
he can control
somebody else's addiction
needs to know how overblown
his thinking is.
Could anybody make you stop,
Daryl?
No, sir.
Nobody but you can.
Not me.
Nobody.
Sorry.
Maybe we ought to go inside,
Daryl.
We're in the line of fire.
About a month ago...
I had a few problems.
And, um, I figured
the only way to deal
with these problems
was to, uh, disappear.
One of the problems
was I didn't have any money.
So I asked myself,
where could a guy go
to be totally anonymous
and get somebody else
to pay for it?
Well, the answer I came up with
was pretty brilliant.
I, uh...
I figured what I would do
would be I check myself
into a drug clinic.
And the only trick
was I had to convince
the people in the drug clinic
that I was an addict.
So I sat in front of the place
in my car.
And, uh,
I had a couple beers.
And I figured out
all the language
and all the gestures
and moves
so I could give this really
convincing performance.
And, uh, somehow, I did.
And you, fools, bought it.
And now it's 30 days later
and, um...
I've been to a funeral,
I've been throughout
nine million job interviews.
I'm $52,000 in debt.
And I got this chip...
I got this chip.
And I got this
startling belief
that...
Uh...
That I'm an alcoholic
and a drug addict.
God knows what we got going
next month.
But if it's anything like this
last one,
Jesus Christ.
So here we go and thank you.
And thanks for my chip.
And thanks for not smoking.
Don't wanna discuss it
I think it's time
For a change
You may get disgusted
Some thinking
That I'm strange
In that case
I'll go underground
Get some heavy rest
Never have to worry
About what is worst
And what is best
Oh, oh, domino
All right
Roll me over, Romeo
There you go
Lord have mercy
I said, oh, oh, domino
Roll me over, Romeo
There you go
Say it again
I said, oh, oh
Domino
Dig it
There's no need
For argument
There's no argument
At all
And if you never hear
From him
That just means
He didn't call
Or vice versa
That depends
On wherever you're at
All right
Oh, and if you never hear
From me
That just means
I would rather not
I said, oh, oh, domino
All right
Roll me over, Romeo
There you go
Lord have mercy
I said, oh, oh, domino
Roll me over, Romeo
There you go
Say, all right
Say it again
Oh, oh
Domino
Hey, hey
I said, oh, oh
Domino
Hey, Mr. DJ
I just wanna hear
Some rhythm and blues
Music
On the radio
Oh, oh, all right
Oh, oh
And the band
One more time