[Rabbi]
Savree maranun
verabonun verobotay.
Barooch ata adony
elohaynou melech aholam.
Borah pree hagafan.
Barooch ata adony
elohaynou melech aholam.
Asher kideshano bemitzvotaiv...
verazha banou veshabat kodsho...
behava hencheel lanoe.
Zecaron lemase berashit
ke hoe yome...
techelah lemekray kodesh...
zecher letziat mizraim.
Kee banoe bacharta
veotano kedashta mekol hameem.
Veshabat kodsho
behavat razone.
Henchaltanoe.
Barooch ata adony mekadesh
hasabat.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
September 1939, the German forces
defeated the Polish Army in two weeks
Jews were ordered to registered all family members
and relocate to major cities. More than 10,000 Jews
from the countryside arrive in Krakow daily.
- Name?
- Horowitz, Salomon.
[Indistinct Talking,
Various Languages]
Schneider, Sarah.
Birnbaum, Olga?
[Children Crying,
Indistinct Talking]
Over there.
Over there!
Kommen Sie Doch.
- Isak Hudes.
- Hudes, Isak.
Zucker, Helena.
Hirsch, Salomon?
Mandel, Maria. Hirsch,
Salomon.
- Hauptman, Chaim!
- Weisman! Weisman, Marcus!
- Feber, Ludwig!
- Feber, Ludwig.
Elsa Bauman.
- Josef Klein.
- Klein.
- Davidowich, Ignacy.
- Paula Biffer.
- Nadel, Rachela.
Steiner, Gertruda.
Steiner, Hilda.
## [''Gloomy Sunday'']
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Whispering]
####[Orchestra Playing]
[Maitre D'] Jerzy,
you know who that man is?
I don't know.
[Woman Laughing]
####[Orchestra Continues]
Let's get together,
please.
Smile. Good.
Yes, sir.
Bring them over
a round of drinks.
Very good, sir.
And who shall I say
th-they are from?
You can say
they are from me.
From the gentleman.
Where?
Do you know him?
Find out who he is.
Yes, sir.
Agnieszka, I would
give anything...
to hear you
sing tonight.
[Sighs]
But I know you won't.
[Laughs]
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman
alone at the table
in a place like this?
Sweetheart,
you're the picture
of loneliness.
Oh.
Mmm, what a lovely
fragrance. You are
breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please.
Vodka for my friend.
And for the lady?
Pernod.
# Im Grunewald, im Grunewald
ist Holzauktion #
[Men Laughing,
Whistling]
# Ist Holzauktion #
# Im Grunewald, im Grunewald
ist Holzauktion #
Come to the table, girls!
Drink with us!
# Ist Holzauktion #
# Links um die Ecke 'rum,
rechts um die Ecke 'rum #
# Ueberall ist heute
Holzauktion #
Come to us!
Marry us!
[Whispering]
# Der ganze Klafter
Suessholz kostet 'nen Taler #
# 'Nen Taler, 'nen Taler #
# Der ganze Klafter Suessholz
kostet 'nen Taler #
# 'Nen Taler-- ##
Thank you.
I'll tell you what
I mean by cooperative.
Two days after the law
is passed that all Jews
have to wear the star,
theJewish tailors
are turning them out
by the gross...
in a variety of fabrics
at three zloty each.
Tell me about
your cellar wines.
I have an excellent
German Riesling. 1937.
Mmm, French.
A Bordeaux.
Chateau Latour, '28, '29?
No, I'm sorry.
It's as if they have no idea
what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem
of a riding club.
A Margaux, '29?
No, no,
we don't have that.
Burgundy then?
A Romanee-Conti, '37?
Yes.
It's human nature.
''We'll do this to avoid that.''
That's what they have done
since thousands of years.
It's what they do.
They weather the storm.
But this storm is different.
This is not the Romans.
This storm is the SS.
## Wem Gott will
rechte Gunst erweisen ##
##Den schickt er
in die weite Welt ##
## Wem Gott will rechte
Gunst erweisen ##
##Den schickt er in die
weite Welt ##
##Faleri, Falera ##
##Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha ##
##Faleri, Falera ##
##Den schickt er
in die weite Welt ##
Martin?
Yes, sir.
Who is that man?
That--
That's Oskar Schindler!
##Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha ##
##Den schickt er
in die weite Welt ##
##Faleri, Falera ##
##Den schickt er
in die weite Welt ####
[All]
To Krakow!
## [Singing In German]
[Soldiers Laughing]
####[Singing Continues]
[Loudspeaker]
An alle Juden!
Ab sofort ist es allen Juden
untersagt...
Fleisch aufkoscher Art
zuzubereiten.
Meldung an alle Juden.
Ab sofort--
The Judenrat: The Jewish Council comprised of
24 elected Jews personally responsible for
carrying out the orders of the regime in Krakow,
such as drawing up lists for work details, food
and housing. A place to lodge complaints.
Rabbi--
Private property
cannot be confiscated.
- How long are the schools
going to be closed?
- I do not know.
- Article 47: Pillage
is formally prohibited.
- You don't know anything!
I am familiar with
the Hague Convention.
Religious--
They come into our house
and tell us we don't
live there anymore.
It now belongs
to a certain SS officer.
Please. I only know
what they tell me.
And what they tell me
changes from day to day.
Aren't you supposed
to be able to help?
I mean, what if I just
took this thing off?
- What are they going to do about it?
- They will shoot you.
- Why don't you stop this silly talk?
- Itzhak Stern!
I'm looking for Itzhak Stern.
[Schindler]
Are you Itzhak Stern or not?
- I am.
- Where can we talk?
There's a company
you did the books for on Lipowa Street.
Made what?
Pots and pans?
By law, I have to tell you,
sir, I'm a Jew.
Well, I'm a German.
So there we are.
A good company, you think?
Modestly successful.
I know nothing about enamelware.
Do you?
I was just the accountant.
Simple engineering though,
wouldn't you think?
Change the machines around,
whatever you do,
you could make other
things, couldn't you?
Field kits, mess kits.
Army contracts.
Once the war ends,
forget it, but for now
it's great.
You can make a fortune,
don't you think?
I think most people right now
have other priorities.
Like what?
[Sighs]
I'm sure you'll do just fine
once you get the contracts.
In fact, the worse things get,
the better you'll do.
Oh, well, I can get
the signatures I need.
That's the easy part.
Finding the money
to buy the company,
that's hard.
You don't have
any money?
Not that kind of money.
You know anybody?
[Closes Case]
Jews, yeah.
Investors. You must
have contacts...
in the Jewish business community
working here.
What community?
Jews can no longer own businesses.
That's why this one's in receivership.
But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it.
I'd pay them back in
product-- pots and pans.
- Pots and pans.
- Something they can use.
Something they can
feel in their hands.
They can trade it
on the black market,
do whatever they want.
Everybody's happy.
If you want, you could
run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd put up all the money,
I'd do all the work.
What, if you don't mind
my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure it's known
the company's in business.
I'd see that it had
a certain panache.
That's what I'm good at,
not the work. Not the work.
The presentation.
I'm sure I don't know anybody
who'll be interested in this.
[Exhales]
Well, they should be,
Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
[Loudspeaker]
Achtung! Achtung!
An alleJuden...
Ab sofort ist es verboten--
[Priest]
Vere dignum et justum est,
aequum et salutare,
nos tibi semper et
ubique gratias agere,
Domine Sancte, Pater Omnipotens,
Aeterne Deus.
I've got a client
who'll sell marks
for zloty at 2.45 to 1 .
Wool, mink collar.
It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it
for ration coupons.
Wicks, for lamps.
You have a truckload of wicks?
What am I going to do
with a truckload of wicks?
Nine by 12, nine by 14.
I don't know.
Big, beautiful, Persian.
[Priest Continues]
Lumen aeternum mundo effudit--
Psst.
What?
You don't recognize this?
It's shoe polish.
In metal containers?
You asked for shoe polish.
In metal containers.
This is glass.
- It's not what I asked for.
- What's the difference?
[Others]
Shh!
My client sold it to his client,
who sold it
to the German Army.
Only by the time it got there,
because of the freezing cold,
it broke. All 10,000 units.
Mmm,
ooh, ooh, ooh.
This is not my problem.
- This is not his problem.
- This is not your problem?
- This is not my problem.
- All right.
The German Army wants to
find out where it came from.
- I am going to make sure they find out.
- Now it's your problem.
You be quiet!
[Chuckles]
Metal containers.
Hello.
Pardon me for interfering,
but that's a nice shirt.
Nice shirt.
Do you know where
I can find a nice shirt like that?
[Priest Continues]
...laudare, benedicere
et predicare.
Like this?
It's illegal to buy or sell
anything on the street.
We don't do that.
We're here to pray.
[Priest Continues]
Jesum Christum Dominum Nostrum
- Do you have any idea how much
a shirt like this costs?
- Nice things cost money.
[Priest Continues]
...adorant Dominationes,
tremunt Potestates.
Coeli coelorumque
virtutes ac Beata Seraphim...
socia exultatione
concelebrant--
How many?
I'm going to need some other things, too,
as things come up.
- This won't be a problem.
- From time to time.
[Loudspeaker]
Achtung! Achtung!
Edict 44/91
establishes a closed Jewish district south of the Vistula
River. Residency in the walled ghetto is compulsory
All Jews from Krakow and
surrounding areas are forced from their homes and
required to crowd into an area of only 16 square blocks.
[Children Crying]
[Officers]
- Name? Adresse?
- Formular ausfuellen!
Weiter, weiter!
Nicht draengeln!
Kommen Sie hierher!
Stellen Sie sich doch an!
[Silverware Clattering]
[Loudspeaker]
Achtung, achtung!
AlleJuden sind verpflichtet...
im abgesonderten
juedischen Bezirk zu wohnen.
Nichteinhaltung der Meldepflicht
bei der Einwohnerbehoerde...
verstoesst gegen das Edikt 44l91
und fuehrt zur Anzeige...
beim Militaergericht.
This is obviously the right
place. How are you doing?
Herr Schindler.
[Indistinct Shouting]
Good-bye,Jews!
[Girl Continues Yelling]
This iz the vechteka,
Moyshe.
Ojciec.
Nyne, this kan
neash zyane.
[Sighs]
[Baby Crying, Woman Singing
Polish Lullaby]
Oh, my God.
Oy, God.
[Crying Continues]
Oh, my God.
It could not be better.
It could be worse.
How? Tell me.
[Shouting]
How on earth could it
possibly be worse?
[Slams Down Suitcase]
[Man]
Dzien dobry.
[Indistinct German]
Hey, Goldberg.
Poldek.
What's this?
Uh, the Judenrat has
its own police now.
You don't say.
Ordnungsdienst.
I'm a policeman now,
could you believe it?
It's hard to believe.
Oh, no,
it's not hard
to believe.
It's a good racket, Poldek.
The only racket here.
Look, maybe I could
put in a good word for you
with my superiors.
Your superiors?
Come on, they are not
as bad as everyone says.
Well, they're worse
than everyone says,
but it's a lot of money.
A lot of money.
Give me my
housing assignment.
Come on.
You look funny
in that hat, Goldberg.
[Laughs]
You look like a clown,
you know?
[Stern]
He's a very important man.
Just give him
two minutes of your time.
Since when did time cost money?
Just sit down and listen.
Please.
Sir?
[Schindler]
For each thousand you invest,
I will repay you with...
Two hundred.
200 kilos
of enamelware a month,
to begin in July
and to continue
for one year.
After which time, we're even.
That's it. It's very simple.
Not good enough.
It's not
good enough.
Not good enough?
Look where you're living.
Look where you've been put.
''Not good enough.''
A couple of months ago you'd
be right, not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not.
That's why we're here.
Trade goods--
that's the only currency...
that'll be worth
anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed,
my friend.
Did I call
this meeting?
You told Mr. Stern
you wanted to speak to me.
I'm here.
I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be
a percentage in the company.
[Laughing]
Forget the whole thing.
Get out.
How do we know that you
will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want a contract?
To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do.
That's our contract.
[Indistinct Polish]
...mielismy racje.
[Man]
Piec, szesc, siedem...
osiem, dziewiec.
[Machinery Buzzes]
[Schindler Clapping]
The standard SS rate for
Jewish skilled labor
is seven marks a day,
five for unskilled
and women.
This is what you pay
the Reich Economic Office.
TheJews themselves
receive nothing.
Poles you pay wages.
Generally, they get
a little more.
Are you
listening?
What was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
TheJewish worker's salary--
you pay it directly to
the SS, not to the worker.
He gets nothing.
But it's less.
It's less than what
I would pay a Pole.
It's less.
That's the point
I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
[Sniffs]
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory
over at, uh, Lipowa Street.
It, uh, it, um--
It's owned by a German.
But it's outside
the ghetto, so you can
barter for extra goods--
for eggs, I don't know
what you need--
with the Polish workers.
You can't get it here.
Also, he's asking for ten
healthy women for the--
I am healthy.
[Crowd Laughing]
Bring your sister, okay?
[Shouting Orders
In German And Polish]
Chodz.
You need to convince them
you have a trade, something
valuable to the war effort.
Like what?
What if you don't?
I'm a musician.
Your name goes on a list.
And they put you on trucks--
No, no, no,
that's not true.
You're a musician?
Yeah.
I'd find a good
hiding place if I were you.
I'm not going to hide
like some animal.
There are places to hide.
[Whistle Blowing]
Der Naechste!
I'm a graduate
of the University of Lwow.
I used to work at the
hydroelectric station
in Roznow--
Blauschein.
I'm gonna get the necessary
papers because this card
is no good anymore.
You can stay in this line
all day, you'll still get
one of these.
They are no good.
You'll have to leave
the line now,
then you'll get a blue card,
a Blauschein, to say that
you are an essential worker.
I'll get these papers
for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist.
Just there, look.
Guess who is here?
[Goldberg]
Poldek! Enjoying
the weather, Poldek?
Enjoying the lines?
Need some shoe polish?
In a metal container
maybe?
[Goldberg Laughs]
Not essential?
I think you misunderstand
the meaning of the word.
No Blauschein, sir.
Stand over there.
Move. Next!
What do you mean,
''Not essential''?
I teach history and literature.
Since when is not essential?
He's a metal polisher.
It was not right?
It's very good.
He's 53 years old.
It's too new.
Mmm.
Thank you.
You're crazy.
You left it
in your drawer.
How many times
have I told you?
Your work certificate
you keep in your pocket
at all times.
And you leave everything
in your drawer.
[Stern]
How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher.
[Man]
Take the round sheet of tin,
dip it in soap emulsion.
[Liquid Splashing]
Then place it centrally
in the press.
We obtain the soup pot.
The soup pot.
Soup pot.
Grosz, Mrs. Grosz,
stay together.
Sir, I have ten work permits
here for the Deutsche
Emailwarenfabrik,
cosigned by Mr. Bankier
and myself.
[Foreman]
If it's carbonized,
clean it with a file.
But don't touch
both the electrodes
at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted.
Here, have a try.
[Foreman]
Roll the metal
under the press,
but be very careful
unless you want your fingers...
to become part
of the teapot.
Occupation?
I'm a writer.
I play the flute.
But Moses is
a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots.
He can make tanks.
He can make whatever
Mr. Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled.
Give him your card.
Moses, give him your card.
[Foreman]
Now, dip the basin
with the tongs...
into the enamel solution.
And after swiveling it around,
carefully place it aside
to drip dry.
And whatever he asks you,
allow me just to represent
you and speak for you.
Don't say a word.
[Schindler]
Filing, billing, keeping track
of my appointments, shorthand.
Typing, obviously.
How is your typing?
Uh, all right.
Please.
[Typing Slowly]
[Typing Slowly,
Bell Rings]
[Typing
Extremely Slow]
[Barely Typing]
[Typing Quickly]
You need a secretary.
Pick one.
I don't know how.
They're all so...
qualified.
You have to choose.
[Sighs]
Prosze sie ladnie usmiechac.
Big smile.
Uwaga.
[Camera Shutter Clicks]
####[Piano]
If you would,
look after my guest.
[Schindler]
Um, boxed teas are good.
Coffiee, pate, um...
kielbasa sausage,
cheeses, Beluga caviar.
Yes.
And, of course, who could live
without German cigarettes?
Get me as many
as you can fid.
And some more fresh fruit.
The real rarities--
oranges, lemons, pineapples.
I need several boxes
of Cuban cigars. The best.
Yes.
And dark, unsweetened chocolate.
Not in the shape ofladyfigers,
the chunk chocolate.
Yes.
Big as my hand,
you sample at wine tastings.
We're going to need lots
of cognac. The best, Hennessy.
Dom Perignon champagne.
Um, get L 'espadon sardines...
and, oh,
try to fid nylon stockings.
[Schindler]
It is my distinct pleasure
to announce...
the fully operational status
of Deutsche Email Fabrik...
[Foreman]
Patrzjakies szmaty!
manufacturers of superior
enamelware crockery...
expressly designed
and crafted for military use.
Utilizing only
the most modern equipment,
D.E.F. 's staffi of
highly-skilled and experienced
artisans andjourneymen...
deliver a product
of unparalleled quality,
enabling me to proffier,
with absolute confidence
and pride,
a full line
of field and kitchenware...
unsurpassable in all respects
by my competitors.
See attached list
and available colors.
Anticipating the enclosed bids
will meet with your approval.
Made in Havana, Cuba.
Looking forward to a long and
mutually prosperous association.
Look at this.
I extend to you in advance
my sincerest gratitude...
and very best regards.
Oskar Schindler.
Yeah, I need 700 gross
from here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred--
No, make it ten
for Wednesday.
All this stuff here goes
to Madritsch's factory
on Tuesday of next week.
[Horn Honking]
[Schindler]
My father was fond of saying,
''You need three things in life
''a good doctor,
a forgiving priest...
and a clever accountant. ''
The first two... [Chuckles]
I've never had much use for.
But the third--
Just pretend,
for Christ's sake.
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying I couldn't
have done this without you.
The usual thing would be
to acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also, by the way,
be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
[Sighs]
Get out of here.
[Door Buzzer]
[Schindler]
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed.
Look at her.
You know something?
You would like her.
Oskar, please.
What?
I don't have to like her...
just because you do.
You would, though.
It doesn't work that way.
[Door Closing]
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
- Be careful of the step, miss.
- Mrs. Schindler, Marek.
## [''Gloomy Sunday'']
It's not a charade, all this?
How could it be a charade?
The clothes, the car, the apartment.
Wait a minute.
Take a guess how many
people are on my payroll.
Oskar.
My father, at the height
of his success, had 50.
I've got 350.
350 workers on the factory floor,
with one purpose.
To make pots and pans?
To make money.
For me.
[Sighs]
Does anyone ask about me?
Back home?
Everybody.
All the time.
Hmm.
They won't soon forget
the name Schindler here,
I can tell you that.
''Oskar Schindler,''
they'll say.
''Everybody remembers him.
''He did something
extraordinary.
no one else did.
''He came here with nothing--
''a suitcase--
''and built a bankrupt
company into a major manufactory.
''And left with
a steamer trunk--
''Two steamer trunks
full of money,
all the riches of the world.''
Hmm.
It's comforting to see
that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
[Kissing Sound]
There's no way I could have
known this before,
but there was always
something missing.
In every business I tried,
I can see now, it wasn't me
that failed.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it
was, there's nothing I could
have done about it...
because you can't
create this thing.
And it makes all
the difference in the world
between success and failure.
Luck?
War.
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you
if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar,
no doorman or maitre d'
will ever presume...
I'm anyone other than Mrs. Schindler,
and I'll stay.
Good-bye, darling.
[Indistinct German]
I could try to read this
or I could eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
- Yes.
- Better this month than last?
- Any reason to think next month
will be worse?
The war could end.
- What?
- There is a machinist outside...
who'd like to thank you
personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes. He's very grateful.
It'll just take a minute.
Mr. Lowenstein?
I want to thank you, sir,
for giving me
the opportunity to work.
You're welcome.
I'm sure you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up.
They would have killed me,
but I am essential to the war effort,
thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
- I'm sure you do.
- I'll continue to work hard for you.
That's great.
Thanks.
- God bless you, sir.
- All right.
You are a good man.
- He saved my life.
- Yes, he did.
- God bless him.
- Yeah. Come on.
God bless you.
[Stern]
I'm sorry, Herr Direktor,
but you're running very late.
This is for the
Obersturmbannfuehrer, sir.
And this is for his niece,
Greta. It's her birthday.
Greta as in Garbo.
By the way, don't ever
do that to me again.
Go. Go, go, drive!
Don't bow.
- Did you happen to notice that
that man had one arm?
- What? Did he?
- What's his use?
- Very useful.
[Shouts]
- How?
- Very useful! Success!
##Achrar kach loe nedah ##
[Officer]
Besen und Schaufeln
werden ausgeladen...
jeder nimmt sich eine und dann
wird die Strasse gereinigt.
We'll be late for work.
[Horn Honking]
[Rolf Czurda]
You shouldn't think of them
as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand that
some of the officers here...
don't give a damn
about production.
To them, it's a matter of,
um, national priority...
that Jews
be made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do
with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shoveling snow--
It's got a, um,
ritual significance.
Come with me.
I am an essential worker.
Essential worker?
[Laughing]
Yes.
[Officer Laughing]
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Essential worker for Oskar Schindler.
A one-armed Jew?
Twice as useless!
Yes, yes.
I lost a day
of production, Rolf.
[Lowenstein]
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow.
Look at the snow.
Look at the snow!
[Gunshot]
I lost a worker.
I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance
with the Economic Office.
It's your right.
Would it do
any good?
Of course not.
[Chuckles]
A big shot from the SS Budget
and Construction Office
came to lunch...
and he told us that to believe
theJewish skilled worker
had a place...
in Reich economics
was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was
a metal press operator.
Quite skilled.
[Moaning]
[Panting, Moaning]
Herr Direktor?
Shit.
I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No, it's Poldek.
It's about Stern.
[Soldier]
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Given name first,
then your surname.
Do not bring
your baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Clearly label it.
[Loudspeaker]
Lassen Sie Ihr Gepaeck
am Bahnsteig.
Stern?
He's on the list.
He is?
Well, let's find him.
I'm sorry.
You can't have him.
He's on the list.
If he were an essential worker,
he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk.
What is your name?
Sir, the list is correct.
I didn't ask you about the list.
I asked you your name.
Klaus Tauber.
Tauber.
Hauptscharfuehrer,
this gentleman thinks
a mistake's been made.
My plant manager is
somewhere on this train.
If it leaves with him on it,
it'll disrupt production...
and the Armaments Board
will want to know why.
[Loudspeaker]
Achtung, dieser Zug
faehrt jetzt ab.
Is he on the list?
Yes, sir. Itzhak Stern.
Well, the list is correct, sir.
There is nothing I can do.
What is your name?
[Loudspeaker]
Close and secure all doors.
My name? My name is Kunder.
This train is now leaving.
Kunder.
Hauptscharfuehrer Kunder.
K-U-N-D-E-R.
And what's yours?
Schindler.
S-C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R.
Gentlemen,
thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you
you'll both be in...
Southern Russia before the
end of the month. Good day.
[Conductor]
Zamykac dokladnie drzwi.
Dokladnie zamykac drzwi.
Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
[Train Whistle Blowing]
Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
[Kunder, Tauber]
Stern! Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern!
Sir?
Herr Direktor.
[Coughing]
My apologies.
Stop the train! He's here!
I apologize.
- Stop the train!
- Stop the train! Stop it!
Sign here. Initial there.
[Whistle Blowing]
Makes no difference
to us, you understand.
This one, that one.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
It's the inconvenience to the list.
It's the paperwork.
I somehow left
my work card at home.
I tried to explain them
it was a mistake, but--
I'm sorry, it was stupid!
What if I got here
five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
Shechel.
Sacrean,
sacrean end tzukeer.
Tzukeer end sacrean.
I woke up from a dream this morning.
I was broke and sharing a room
with 12 people I didn't know,
only to discover I was broke and sharing
a room with 12 people I didn't know.
[Chuckling]
You laugh about it?
I have to laugh.
You are living behind walls.
The walls I can deal with.
It's the restrictions
to my life I'm tired of.
Those walls keep them out.
That's all I care about.
I like it here.
There's a kind of,
I don't know,
ancestral squalor to it all.
You are a slave to these people.
No one envies us anymore.
I'm smart.
Oh, yes, you're smart.
You're a real genius.
You had your chance.
Today, today I actually found time
to organize a thought.
I can't remember
the last time I did that.
When's the last time we did this?
When's the last time
we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me
onto a truck today.
No one took my business away from me.
You don't really have
a business to take.
There's nowhere down from here.
This is it. This is the bottom.
The ghetto is... liberty.
This street divides the ghetto
just about in half.
Right side, Ghetto A:
civil employees,
industrial workers and so on.
Left side, Ghetto B: surplus labor,
the elderly and infirm mostly.
Which is where you'll
want to start, huh?
Do you have any questions, sir?
Ja, why is the top down?
I'm fucking freezing.
[Wilhelm Kunde]
We expect a labor force
of 25,000 to 30,000.
Segregated, of course.
The men in the barracks near the quarry.
The women on the other
side of the wire.
[Goeth]
My place is where?
There, sir.
There?
You call that a villa?
Yes, the villa.
Their synagogue, can you see it?
That's not a villa.
We're planning to turn it
into the camp stables.
It's a house.
[Goeth]
What's that over there?
[Kunde]
Kindergarten.
Fifty-one.
And we have a dentist, shoemaker,
practical physicians.
[Guard]
There they are, sir.
[Goeth Sniffs]
Hmm.
One of you is, uh,
a very lucky girl.
There is an opening for a job,
away from all this...
backbreaking work,
at my new villa.
[Sniffs]
Uh, which of you has...
domestic experience?
Ja, on second thought,
I don't really want
someone else's maid.
All those annoying habits
I have to undo.
[Chuckles]
I don't want to give you my cold.
Uh, what's your name?
Helen Hirsch.
What?
[Coughing]
Helen Hirsch.
What? I can't hear.
Ja.
[Woman]
Take it all down!
[Officer Blows Whistle]
To work!
[Woman Arguing]
Take it down!
It is not safe!
She says the foundation was poured wrong.
She's got to take it down.
I told her it's the barracks,
not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking Jew bitch engineer.
You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant.
The entire foundation...
has to be torn down
and repoured.
If not, there will be
at least a subsidence...
at the southern end
of the barracks.
Subsidence, and then collapse.
And you are an engineer?
Yes.
My name is Diana Reiter.
I'm a graduate...
of Civil Engineering
from the University of Milan.
Ah, an educated Jew,
like Karl Marx himself.
Unterscharfuehrer!
Jawohl?
Shoot her.
What?
[Gasps]
Herr Kommandant,
I'm only trying to do my job.
Ja, I'm doing mine.
But, sir, she's foreman
of construction.
We are not going to have arguments
with these people.
Okay.
No. Shoot her here, on my authority.
It will take more than that.
[Goeth]
I'm sure you're right.
Take it down, repour it,
rebuild it. Like she said.
We have more to see,
but we have only one more hour of light.
## [Humming]
[Goeth]
Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now, the young
will ask with wonder...
about this day.
Today is history,
and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago...
## [Singing
Morning Prayer]
when elsewhere they were footing
the blame for the Black Death,
Kazimierz the Great, so-called,
##Ke laolam chasedo ##
told theJews
they could come to Krakow.
Chaja, bread.
[Goeth Continues]
They came.
Not that fat. No, less.
They trundled their belongings into the city.
Yes, a bit less.
They settled.
They took hold. They prospered...
in business, science, education, the arts.
They came here with nothing.
####[Praying Continues]
Nothing.
And they flourished.
For six centuries
there has been a Jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening,
those six centuries are a rumor.
They never happened.
Today is history.
Absitzen und in Zweierreihen
antreten!
Kameraden!
Schneller!
[Whistle Blowing,
Indistinct Shouting]
I think we will start...
with Ghetto B.
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
[Dogs Barking]
All right?
Start from
both sides?
I would like you
to start there.
The right side?
The right side, yeah.
And then move around.
Okay.
[Loudspeaker]
Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
Lassen Sie
Ihr Gepaeck stehen.
Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
[Soldier]
Aufmachen!
Lakoom.
Loe ani loe yodahat olay
kaday lehachnese at hayladeem
mitachat la shoolchan.
Mitacht la meeta.
Bohow.
[Soldiers]
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
[Soldiers Shouting
In German]
[Soldier]
'Runterkommen!
[Soldiers Shouting,
Banging On Doors]
[Soldier]
'Rauskommen,Juden!
[Soldiers Shouting]
[Soldier]
Ziehen Sie sich warm an!
Kommen Sie 'raus!
[Soldier]
Na Platz!
[Whistle Blowing]
Gold, Chaim!
Platz Chodi.
Yes, Chaim Gold.
Shoot him.
[Speaking Polish]
Nie zabijaj!
[Woman Screams]
[Soldier]
Ziehen Sie warme Kleidung an
und begeben Sie sich zum Platz--
[Whistle Blows]
Keine Koffier!
Gehen Sie durch!
Keine Koffier! Keine Koffier!
Hey, little boy.
Wie alt bist du, huh?
Na, wie hiesst du?
Wie heisst du, huh?
Keine Koffier,
hab'ich gesagt!
[Screaming]
Packt keine Koffier!
Keine Koffier!
'Rueber zum Platz Chodi!
Koffier hierlassen!
Blauschein.
Platz Chodi!
Was soll
der Koffier hier?
Alles 'rueber
zum Platz Chodi!
[Shouting Continues]
[Footsteps]
We're getting out
through the sewers.
I have to check
if they're clear.
Mila, pack some things.
Nothing bigger than this.
I can't go in the sewers.
I told you I won't go
in the sewers.
You can go.
Yes, you can.
I won't go in the sewers.
[Whistle Blows]
[Soldier]
Move! Over there!
Over there! Move!
Your card,Jew!
Deine Papiere,
Jude!
Deine Papiere,Jude!
That line.
[Whistle Blowing]
Deine Karte!
Ich geh'nicht 'rauf
wegen Deiner verdammten Karte!
Deine Scheisskarte!
[Whistle Blowing]
[Woman Wailing
In German]
Was soll denn die Scheisse?
Bist du denn verrueckt geworden?
Mit diesem Scheissgewehr
haettest du mich
erschiessen koennen!
Du hast so nah an mir
vorbeigeschossen!
Was heisst hier Entschuldigung.
Du bist wohl verrueckt geworden!
[Soldier]
Zurueckbleiben!
Nicht sprechen, nicht sprechen!
Einfach zu den Lastwagen gehen!
Weiterlaufen! Weiterlaufen!
Nicht sprechen!
[Whistle Blows]
Komm her, du Judensau!
Bleib stehen, hab'ich gesagt.
Bleib stehen!
[Whispering
In Polish]
[Indistinct Polish]
Chodzcie tu szybko!
[Footsteps]
[Door Bursts Open]
[Chattering,
Baby Crying]
[Whistle Blowing,
Soldiers Shouting]
She's good as dead.
Leave her.
Give me a moment.
Just let me bring her inside.
[Gasps, Screams]
[Man Speaking German
Over Loudspeaker]
You can join her...
or join the line.
[Soldiers Shouting,
Whistles Blowing]
Women to the left!
Wilhelm!
Rose!
Men to right.
Women to the left.
[Protesting In German]
Women
to the left.
Let me go!
I won't leave my husband!
[Shouting, Wailing]
Women to the left,
and men to the right.
Promise me, be safe.
[Man]
Your government
is in the wrong country!
[Shouting,
Wailing Continue]
Mama! Mama!
[Shouting In Polish]
[Dogs Barking,
Soldiers Shouting]
[Machine Gun Fire]
[Gasping, Panting]
[Grunts]
[Gasps]
Mila!
[Women Panting]
[Distant Machine Gun Fire]
[Bell Chiming]
Oh, God, Danka!
[Gasps, Whimpers]
You have a Blauschein.
Blauschein doesn't
matter anymore.
They are cleaning
out the ghetto.
There's not enough room for you.
What are you talking about?
We tried it before.
There's more than enough room.
- I changed my mind!
- Mama!
Look at the space in there.
Now look at me.
You are just scared.
I can fit the girl,
but not you.
- Mama, I'm coming out!
- Stay where you are.
I'd rather you be here
than who knows where.
Mama!
[Soldiers Shouting
In German]
[Dogs Barking]
Herr Kommandant!
[Soldiers Laughing]
Very good saluting.
I respectfully report
I've been given orders to clear
the bundles from the road...
so there will be no obstructions
to the thoroughfare.
Finish and join the lines,
little Polish clicking soldier.
[Chuckles]
[Dogs Growling]
[Laughing,
Muttering Continue]
[Distant Machine Gun Fire]
[Blows Whistle]
Mrs. Dresner?
Yes.
Oh, you are a friend
of my son's.
Don't worry, I'll go quietly.
I'll be no trouble.
No, get under the stairs.
They'll be done searching soon.
You'll be safe there.
Please hide! Please!
[Muttering]
...warmed by the sun.
Hide under the stairs.
[Boy]
I've searched the building.
There's no one here.
Also, gehen wir
zum naechsten Block.
Einverstanden.
Danka! Ah!
Mama!
[Panting]
Hello, Adam.
H-Hello, Danka.
[Soldiers Shouting
In Distance]
Come with me.
I will put you
in the good line.
Do you know the saying, ''An hour
of life is still life''?
You are not a boy anymore.
I'm saying a blessing for you.
[People Shouting,
Machine Guns Firing]
####[Children's Choir Singing
''Oyfin Pripetshok'']
## Ofyn pripetshok
brent a fayerl ##
## Un in shtub iz heys ##
## Un der rebe lerent
kleyne kinderlech ##
##Dem alefbeys ##
[Machine Gun Fire]
## Un der rebe lerent
kleyne kinderlech ##
##Dem alefbeys ##
[Gunshot,
People Screaming]
##Zetzhe kinderlech
gedenktzhe tayere ##
## Vos ir lerent do ##
##Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol ##
##Komets alefo ##
[Shouting]
##Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol ##
##Komets alefo ##
## Ofyn pripetshok
brent a fayerl ##
## Un in shtub iz heys ##
[Officers Shouting]
## Un der rebe lerent
kleyne kinderlech
Dem alefbeys ##
[Shouting,
Gunshot]
[Dog Barking]
[Gunshots]
Oh, please, let's go.
Let's go, please.
Come on.
##Zetzhe kinderlech
gedenktzhe tayere ##
## Vos ir lerent do ##
##Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol ##
##Komets alefo ##
[Whistle Blowing]
##Zogtzhe noch amol un take
noch amol ##
##Komets alefo ####
[Whimpering]
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Whistle Blows,
Dogs Barking]
Markieren.
[Speaking Polish]
Nie!
Prosze pana, niech pan--
## [Hits Piano Keys]
[Girl]
...nie znajdziemy!
[Machine Gun Fire]
####[Piano]
[Shouting In German]
####[Piano Continues]
[Machine Gun Fire Continues]
[Both Panting]
Was ist das?
Ist das Bach?
Nein, nein. Mozart.
Mozart?
Ja.
####[Piano Continues]
[Machine Gun Fire,
Piano Continue]
[Dog Barking]
Das wollen wir heute
noch schaffien?
Nee, schaffien wir nie.
Jemu niedobrze sie robi.
Nee, das schaffien wir nie.
I wish this fucking
night were over.
####[Piano Continues]
[Machine Gun Fire
Continues]
-[Whistle Blows]
-Appell! Fuenferreihen!
Antreten!
Halt, alle anstellen!
Fuenferreihen!
Muetzen ab!
Namen verlesen!
Wer aufgerufen wird, hebt seine
Hand und ein deutliches Jawhol!
[Shouts Name]
[Man]
Jawohl.
[Shouts Name]
[Man]
Jawohl.
Keller, Fanni!
Adalbert, Hermann!
[Man]
Jawohl.
Faber, Dorothea!
[Woman]
Jawohl.
Goldstein, Pola!
[Woman]
Jawohl.
Warmberger, Markus!
Edelstein, Max!
[Soldiers Continue
Shouting Names]
Appell
abtreten!
Do pracy!
The worst is over.
We are workers now.
[Man Speaking German
Over Loudspeaker]
[Officer Shouting
In German]
[Officer]
Keine Muedigkeit vorschuetzen!
[Woman Shrieks,
People Shouting]
Oh, God, Amon.
[Officer Shouting
In German]
[Loudspeaker]
Sofort in der Baracke
zurueckmelden!
[Gunshot]
[Man Shouting
In German]
[Reloading Rifle]
[Woman Shrieking]
[Officer Shouting
In German]
[Bones Crack]
[Officer Shouting]
Komm du mal schoen her!
Komm du schoen!
Na komm!
Amon, you're such
a damned fuckin' child!
Wakey, wakey.
[Sighs]
[Woman]
Make coffee.
Make it yourself.
[Grunting]
[Man]
...
The SS will manage certain industries itself
inside Plaszow
a metalworks, brush factory,
another for reprocessing
Jewish clothing...
from the ghettos for use by
bombed-out families back home.
But it's private industry like yours
that stands to benefit most...
by moving inside the wire of
Commandant Amon Goeth's camp--
No, no, no. Sit, sit.
Julian, how are you?
How are you?
Good to see you, my friend.
Oskar Schindler.
Leo John.
[Whispers, Chuckles]
- Franz, good to see you.
- Hello, Oskar.
- Glad you could join us.
- My pleasure. Julius.
- How are you?
- You lost weight.
- Only in the shoulders.
- Please, everybody, sit down.
- How are you doing?
Oskar Schindler.
- We started without you.
- Fine. I missed anything good?
I was explaining to Herr Bosch
and Herr Madritsch...
some of the benefits of moving their
factories into Plaszow.
I meant the food.
[Chuckles]
Since your labor is housed on-site,
it's available to you at all times.
You can work them
all night if you want.
Your factory policies, whatever
they've been in the past,
they'll continue to be.
They'll be respected.
I have to know, where
do you get a suit like that?
What is that? Is that silk?
Of course.
Ja. It's-- It has
a nice sheen about it.
Thank you.
Very nice.
I'd say I'd get you one,
but the man who made it is probably dead.
I don't know.
[Schindler's Voice]
I go to work the other day.
Nobody's there.
Nobody tells me about this.
I have to find out. I have to go in.
Everybody's gone.
No.
[Sighs]
They're not gone.
They're here.
They're mine!
Every day that goes by, I'm losing money.
Every worker that is shot costs me money.
I have to find somebody else. I have to train them.
We are going to be making so much money
that none of this is going to matter.
It's bad business.
[Sniffs]
Thank you.
Leave the bottle.
Take that.
Lena... thank you.
Scherner told me
something else about you.
Yeah?
What's that?
That you know the meaning
of the word ''gratitude.''
That it's not
some vague thing with you...
like it is with others.
You want to stay
where you are.
You've got things
going on the side.
Things are good.
You don't want anybody
telling you what to do.
I can understand all that,
you know. I-- I know you.
What you want...
is your own sub-camp.
Do you have any idea what is involved?
The paperwork alone?
You've got to build the thing.
Getting those fucking permits
is enough to drive you crazy.
Then the engineers show up,
they stand around, they argue
about drainage, foundations,
codes, exact specifications,
fences four kilometers long,
1,200 kilograms of barbed wire,
[Chuckling]
6,000 kilograms of electrified
fences, ceramic insulators,
three cubic meters
of air space per prisoner.
I'm telling you, you want to shoot somebody.
I've been through it. I know.
Well, you know.
You've been through it.
[Spits]
You could make things
easier for me.
I'd be grateful.
Aus dem Weg da!
[Dogs Barking]
Weitergehen!
[Speaking Polish]
[Whistle Blows]
Wlewo zwrot!
Trzymac szereg!
Weitergehen.
Nach links.
[Dogs Continue Barking]
[Whistle Blows]
Where's Stern?
Goldberg and Chilowicz...
make sure I see my cut...
from the, uh,
factory owners in this camp,
leaving you to take care
of my main account--
the Schindler account.
He wants his independence.
I gave it to him.
But independence
costs money.
This you
understand?
Look at me.
Don't forget who
you are working for now.
[Chattering, Shouting]
####[Accordion]
Jawohl!
[Schindler]
Make sure he kisses
each and every one!
Ja. Now, girls,
everyone.
We need more wine.
More wine!
Stand in my place.
Don't let him leave.
[Laughing, Singing]
[Chattering,
Shouting Continue]
## Was passiert denn
in einem Leben ##
Prost! Prost!
Thank you,
Herr Direktor.
Prost,
Herr Direktor!
What are you
doing?
What?
Scratching my head.
Makes them think we have lice.
Helps them keep their distance.
[Exhales]
Do you have lice?
Do you have your notebook?
The calendar on my desk has
the birthdays of our SS friends'
wives and children.
Don't forget
to send something.
Record payoffs
to the Main Administration
and Economics Office, the Arm--
Slower, Stern, slower.
The Armaments Board,
Governor General's Division...
of the Interior
and Chief of Police as ''fees,''
and make them
on the first of each month,
as opposed to individual payoffs
to our SS contacts.
The list is in the lower drawer
of my desk, which you--
''First of month--''
SS contacts: list,
lower drawer of my desk,
which you handle...
as cash contributions
to legitimate charities
sent to each official's office.
Dealings with
our black market contacts,
listed as suppliers...
in the legitimate ledger,
are more complicated.
Forget it.
What do you mean, forget it?
You can't forget it!
It gives me a headache!
[Dogs Barking]
[Sighs]
I couldn't get you
out of here.
I'll be all right.
Anyway, I'm here
almost every week.
Wednesdays, usually.
I'll look in on you,
see how you're doing.
Here, put these
in your pocket.
Come on.
[Inhales]
Herr Direktor,
don't let things fall apart.
I've worked too hard.
Thanks for--
Good luck.
## [Music, Shouting
Continue]
Achtung, Muetzen ab!
- Work!
- An die Arbeit!
What are you making?
Hinges, sir.
Ja, I've got some workers
coming in tomorrow.
Where are they from again?
Yugoslavia,
Herr Kommandant.
I've got to make room.
Make me a hinge.
Yes, sir.
[Guards Muttering]
Keep going,
you're doing well.
Says he's
doing well.
Oh, that's very good.
But I'm a bit confused,
and perhaps you can help me.
What I don't understand
is that you've been working...
since I think, what,
about six this morning?
Yet such a small pile
of hinges.
[Train Whistle Blows]
[Gun Clicks]
Oh, Christ.
May I try that, sir?
Check the angle-lever.
Maybe it's bent.
No, no.
You wouldn't hear a click
if it was the angle-lever.
Maybe it's the pin.
Maybe the pin shaft is greasy.
Ja, come on.
What did I just say?
Here.
[Gun Clicks]
Herr Kommandant,
I beg to report
that my heap ofhinges
was so unsatisfactory...
because the machines
were being recalibrated
this morning.
[Gun Clicks]
I w-was put on
to shoveling coal.
[Gun Clicking]
[Grunts, Yells]
[Gasps, Sobbing]
Strange, huh?
Yeah.
Thank you, Muek.
Ah, Lisiek.
Don't touch the leather,
it's just been oiled.
Rottenfuehrer.
Oh, for me?
Oh, thank you very much,
Herr Direktor. Thank you.
[Stern] Herr Direktor!
Herr Direktor!
He was making
hinges slowly.
So the man can turn out a hinge
in less than a minute.
Why the long story? Hmm?
[Machines Rumbling]
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Nobody knows
who stole the chicken, hmm?
Tell him about the chicken.
A man walks around
with a chicken and
nobody notices this.
Save yourselves.
Tell him
about the chicken.
Still nobody knows.
[Sobbing]
It was you.
You committed this crime.
No, sir.
But you know who, though.
Yes.
Who?
[Sobbing]
Him!
He's very gifted.
Yeah, sure.
Bring him over.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you again,
Herr Direktor.
You're welcome again.
It's an honor to work
for such a great company.
It's great to have you.
I promise to learn everything
about enamelware production.
That's great.
Hello?
Miss Elsa Krause is here.
I only need five minutes.
She wants to speak
to the Herr Direktor.
[Typewriter Keys Clicking]
Yes.
He won't see you.
Please, sit down.
Pernod?
Cognac?
Uh, no.
No, thank you.
So, what
can I do for you?
[Nervous Chuckle]
They say that no one
dies here.
They say your factory
is a haven.
They say you are good.
Who says that?
Everyone.
My name is Regina Perlman,
not Elsa Krause.
I've been living in Krakow
on false papers since
the ghetto massacre.
My parents are in Plaszow.
Their names are
Chana and Jakob Perlman.
They are older people.
They are killing older people
now in Plaszow.
They bury them
up in the forest. Look...
[Sighs]
I don't have any money.
I, I borrowed
these clothes.
I'm begging you.
Please, please
bring them here.
I don't do that.
You've been misled.
I ask one thing:
whether or not a worker
has certain skills.
My father is an importer,
not a metalworker.
[Continues Arguing]
Such activities are illegal.
You will not entrap me!
Cry, and I will
have you arrested.
I swear to God!
[Mutters, Sobbing]
People die.
It's a fact of life.
He wants to kill everybody?
Great! What am I supposed
to do about it?
Bring everybody over?
Is that what you think?
Send them over to Schindler.
Send them all!
His place is a haven,
didn't you know?
It's not a factory.
It's not an enterprise
of any kind.
It's a haven for rabbis
and orphans...
and people with
no skills whatsoever!
[Sighs]
You think I don't know
what you're doing?
You're so quiet all the time.
I know, I know!
Are you losing money?
That's not the point!
What other point is ...
It's dangerous! It's dangerous to me!
You have to understand.
Goeth is under enormous pressure.
You have to think of it
in his situation.
He's got this
whole place to run.
He's responsible for everything here,
all these people.
He's got a lot of things
to worry about.
And he's got the war
which brings out the worst in people.
Never the good, always the bad.
Always the bad.
But in normal circumstances
he wouldn't be like this.
He'd be all right.
There'd just be the good
aspects of him which--
[Chuckles]
He's a wonderful crook.
A man who loves good food,
good wine, the ladies, making money
Killing.
He can't enjoy it.
Bejski told me the other day,
somebody escaped...
from a work detail
outside the wire.
[Gunshots]
Goeth lined up everybody
from the missing man's barracks.
He shot the man to the left of Bejski,
the man to the right of him.
He walked down the line
shooting every other man with the pistol.
Twenty-five.
What do you want me to do about it?
Nothing, nothing.
We're just talking.
''Perlman.''