- Are you bored?
- No.
CLIMATES
Should we give Arif a call?
Bahar!
Sure.
- Semra, dinner was great. Thank you.
- I hope you enjoyed it.
- How about some coffee?
- How do you take it?
- Medium-sweet for me.
- Me too.
- It must be interesting living here.
- It's kind of boring actually.
- Why are you living here then?
- What else can I do?
The weather's great but that's about it.
If there were a few more people
like us around...
Why don't you come down more often?
Actually this is the first time
we've been away in years.
Bahar has that TV series.
The schedule's always uncertain.
And I have the university as you know.
I'm free in summer
but then Bahar is usually busy.
- What's your job on the series, Bahar?
- Art director.
Is that the one with Ugur Yucel?
No, that's a different series.
There are no big names in ours.
It's getting cold.
- Aren't you cold?
- No, I'm fine.
- Why don't you put your jacket on?
- I told you, I'm fine.
You seem kind of fed up.
What's wrong?
What's going on?
Is there a problem?
Why are you using that tone?
Why do you keep nagging?
If I'm nagging,
it's for your own good, isn't it?
If I was cold,
I'd be wearing the thing anyway.
Can't we go anywhere
without you making problems?
Hey, come on!
Don't go over the top.
Don't worry.
They enjoy seeing us miserable.
- Come on. You wrecked dinner...
- No, it's okay. Don't worry.
Hey, come on, guys!
Just forget it.
So you can hear the waves
all the way up here.
Is that the sea just down there?
Yes, it's right there.
- Just behind those trees?
- Yes.
Kas has got so big.
I came here back in 1977.
There was nothing here then.
It's tourism.
The Germans started coming. So then...
Shall we go for a swim?
What, now?
- Yes.
- You'll freeze.
Are you crazy? For God's sake!
Where do you get these ideas?
- Why not if you want. But...
- Forget it. It's bad for lsa's neck.
It's late.
Let's have our coffee and get going.
Semra, where's the coffee?
- You can stay here if you like.
- No, it's okay. The hotel's fine.
- Are you comfortable there?
- Yes.
I love you.
- What's up? You're covered in sweat.
- I must have fallen asleep.
You shouldn't be sleeping in the sun.
It's really dangerous.
Bahar...
I want to say something,
but please don't get the wrong idea.
Maybe we should go our own ways
for a bit. What do you think?
We'd still be good friends.
It wouldn't change things a lot.
We'd still go out together,
for dinner, to the movies.
We don't have to be friends.
I don't mind.
Come on, Bahar.
Don't be like that for God's sake.
This would be better for you as well.
Even that meaningless "Serap" incident
has screwed you up.
You call it meaningless?
For God's sake,
don't get started on that again.
It's better that way for you as well.
You know it yourself.
You don't have to worry about me.
I'll be fine.
That's what I mean.
You're young. You're attractive...
You can get all the men you want.
Maybe it's true what you said.
Maybe I am too old for you.
The age difference
really has become a problem.
It just isn't working.
We can't seem to get along.
I don't need convincing, you know,
I agree with you.
I'm not trying to convince you,
just pointing out the facts.
You know I'm right.
Are you crazy?
Are you trying to kill us both?
If you're that keen to die,
shall I throw you off?
- Shall I throw you off?
- Get off me!
Come back here.
Bahar!
Come back!
Fucking hell!
Your baggage receipt.
Don't lose it.
Do you have a sweater with you?
It gets really cold at night.
Yes, I do.
Excuse me.
- Okay, then. Have a good trip.
- Thanks.
- I'll call you when I'm back in Istanbul.
- Don't.
- What?
- Don't call.
Okay, people.
I want you to compare
the architecture of these two temples.
You have 15 minutes.
Any questions?
- How are you doing?
- Fine.
- How did the exam go?
- Okay.
Who switched on my computer?
I have no idea.
Probably one of your students.
- Come on! Was it you?
- No. Why would I switch it on?
- Are you leaving?
- Yes, I have to.
I'm going to an art exhibit with Pinar.
Join us if you like.
Thanks, but no.
I want to go through these exam papers.
Can't you do that later?
I don't like taking work home.
I'll get it done here.
I've booked the court for Saturday.
Hopefully that's okay with you.
- What if it rains?
- Always excuses. lf it rains, it rains.
- In that case, we play even if it snows.
- It's a deal.
- No getting out of it.
- No.
- We'll even go for a swim afterwards.
- In the sea?
All right, we'll do that too.
Okay, see you then.
- Let's have coffee before you go.
- I don't have time.
She'll only complain if l'm late.
I should go.
- Okay. Have a good time.
- Thanks.
Isa... Isa!
- Hey, how are you?
- Great.
- What are you up to?
- Same as ever. Work and all that.
- You're still in advertising?
- Yes. They won't let me go.
- Hey, Serap! How are you?
- Fine. And you?
Fine. It's so nice that you're still
together after all this time.
Did you get married?
I have an hour to kill.
Shall we have a drink together?
Let's see.
Sorry. I have to meet someone.
Come on.
We hardly ever run into each other.
- I can't. But let's be in touch.
- Okay.
- Don't forget.
- You never call either.
Neither do you.
We're both as bad as each other.
- How are you doing?
- Okay.
We're just looking
at books and magazines.
- Okay. I'll see you then.
- See you. Take care.
The place has changed.
Why are you looking at me like that?
I can leave, if you want.
How did you know I'd come home alone?
Guven said so, didn't he?
At the bookstore.
And I guess I wanted to try my luck.
- Aren't you going to offer me anything?
- You want something to drink?
What should I have?
Something alcoholic?
Have whatever you want.
Okay, I'll have coffee.
It's coffee then.
Then we'll move on to wine, okay?
Sure.
You haven't been around for a while.
Is Bahar out of town again?
What's it got to do with Bahar?
What are you trying to say?
What are you laughing at
for God's sake?
Okay, okay, calm down!
l am.
- These are stale.
- Don't eat them then.
Open your mouth.
How can you wear those pointed shoes?
They're so ugly.
I like them.
You want it?
- Nothing's wrong with it.
- No!
- Don't be so picky.
- It's been on the floor.
- So? The floor's clean. Go on.
- I told you, I don't want it.
There, it's done.
That's much better.
I was treading on them before.
They're just right now.
- Was there anything else?
- No. Thanks.
You're welcome.
I have to go, Mom. I'm running late.
I'm still working on my thesis.
I have to meet someone.
- You haven't eaten anything.
- I'm not hungry. I can eat at home.
- Drop by now and again.
- I can't but I will try.
If I could just finish my thesis...
You should be thinking
about having children.
Mom, don't keep going on about that.
What does it matter
if I do or don't have children?
- Of course it matters.
- Why?
We're not getting any younger. Who knows
how much longer we'll be around?
- Children add so much to your life.
- But I don't even like kids.
It's different when they're your own.
Just wait and see.
Dad, why are you wearing that hat?
That's a new habit.
He even wears it when guests come over.
This hat has more uses than you think.
For one, it protects the blood vessels.
It makes the blood thinner
so it flows more easily.
Well, don't get too used to it, Dad.
He'll soon need another hat on top
whenever he goes outside.
I keep telling him but he never listens.
It's late. I'd better be going.
Come and visit more often.
- That was in.
- What do you mean? It was out.
- For me, it was on the line.
- Are you blind?
So we'd planned the whole wedding.
Imagine, everything's ready.
We go out for dinner one night.
Then suddenly, what do I see?
A finger wagging in my face.
That was a great image.
Unbelievable!
I said to myself,
just get out while the going's good.
I walked out and that was it.
Really!
I just left her like that.
- That dress looks great on you.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
- I like it a lot too.
You look good in black.
Thank you.
Guven got it for me in London.
Yes.
The bastard has good taste.
Why's he gone to Kazakhstan?
He's setting up an advertising agency
there. With some friends of his.
God! The stuff he gets into...
When does he get back?
- In a week or so.
- That's good.
So you're free for a whole week.
What's Bahar up to?
She's okay.
Does she come back
to Istanbul now and then?
- Where from?
- From the east.
What do you mean "the east"?
I heard she's working
on a TV series there.
Who told you that?
Nevzat. I ran into him the other day
at the opening of the Istanbul Modern.
Who's Nevzat?
The architect, you know.
You mean Nevzat Sayin?
- How does he know?
- I've no idea.
- When's she supposed to have gone?
- I really don't know.
Wait, didn't you know?
No.
Why not?
I just didn't.
- We broke up.
- Come on! I don't believe you.
- Didn't I tell you?
- No.
Weren't you together
when you last came here?
Well, why didn't you say so?
You didn't ask.
How was I supposed to know
you'd split up?
So why did you break up?
It happened ages ago. In Kas.
Back in the summer
when we were in Kas.
Go on! What happened there?
I love hearing about break-ups.
Forget it.
It's a long story.
It's all dust and ashes.
Just like the song.
- Can I have more wine? It's good.
- Sure.
Thanks.
There's been an earthquake somewhere.
But I didn't catch where.
I wonder if it was here in Turkey.
Are you going to watch that?
No, it's Cuneyt Ozdemir's thing but...
Come over here.
The earthquake...
You said she wagged her finger
in your face.
Well, you should see Pinar now.
She's meek as a lamb.
There's no more wagging fingers.
Believe me.
After I walked out that evening
she really got scared.
It's the truth.
She knows where she stands now.
She won't revert to her old ways
when you get married?
No chance of that.
The girl's terrified!
The way I acted that night
she really thought it was all over.
I wouldn't be so sure.
What are you doing
for the winter holiday?
Maybe take a trip to Russia,
but we're not sure yet.
Are you crazy? At this time of year?
I promised Pinar some time ago
so l have to go through with it.
What are you up to?
You have any plans?
Wow! A trip to the sun, huh?
I need some decent weather.
The cold here gets to my bones.
You'll get bored on your own.
Why would I get bored?
I've been dreaming
of a trip on my own for years.
I'm sure to meet someone there anyway.
It sounds good at first,
but the more I think about it...
I find places like that a bit vacuous
and kind of empty.
What places?
Faraway places.
Especially when I'm on my own.
- Other countries.
- But you're going to another country.
But at least I have Pinar with me.
You'll be fighting every day.
Just wait and see.
No, we won't. Not anymore.
Hopefully you're right.
I have a class to go to.
The students will be waiting.
- Are you here after class?
- I'll be around.
- I'll see you later then.
- Have a good class.
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
- Do you have a room?
- Yes.
- How much?
- 20 lira.
- Isn't the lift working?
- No.
- How much is this?
- 25 lira.
- Are there any different tunes?
- Sorry, no.
- I called but your number's changed.
- Yes. It has.
- How long have you been here?
- Four months.
Really? It's been a long time.
Haven't you been back
to Istanbul at all?
- When did you get here?
- Yesterday.
- Where are you staying?
- At the Ortadogu Hotel.
- You look well.
- I am.
You look well too.
I guess I'm okay.
- What photographs did you bring?
- What?
What photographs did you bring?
The ones from Kas.
I though I might run into you here.
That's why I brought them with me.
- I got this for you.
- What is it?
I found it wandering around last night.
- It's nice.
- Smuggled in from Dubai.
There's so much smuggled stuff here.
Yes, Cenk?
I gave them to Zafer.
What do you mean they're not there?
Okay, I'll call him right away. Okay.
Sorry.
- Is there a problem?
- No, not really.
Zafer? Don't you have
the Aga's costume for today?
But you told Cenk you didn't have it.
Can't you get anything done?
When are we leaving?
Okay. Okay then.
Sorry.
Shall I get you another tea?
No, I have to go.
I should leave in a minute.
What happened with your thesis?
I still haven't finished it.
I want to photograph
the ruins at lshakpasha tomorrow.
I thought the photos
would look good in the thesis.
I thought I could drop by on you
while I was here.
Right.
Okay. I'll be going then.
- Will I see you this evening?
- Unlikely. We don't get back 'til late.
That's okay. I'll wait up for you.
How much longer are you here?
I don't know.
- Okay.
- What?
- I'm going.
- Okay.
- Give me a call anyway.
- I won't have time.
- I don't have a spare minute.
- All right then, okay.
- Good luck with your work.
- You too.
- You're crew, aren't you?
- Yes.
- Can you give this to Bahar?
- She's in the van.
- That van?
- Yes.
I'll give it to her if you want.
No. It's okay.
I'll do it myself.
Bahar?
Sweetheart. Why are you crying?
Come on, sweetheart.
Why are you crying?
Why are you here?
To see you, of course.
Sweetheart...
I've really changed.
I'm a different person now.
I know I never made
you happy in the past.
But I've really changed.
I say you quit this job and come back
to Istanbul with me tomorrow.
Sweetheart, stop crying.
Bahar, stop crying for God's sake.
I really feel capable of changing.
I feel like I'm ready
to start a new life now.
You know, to get married, have kids.
Even to leave Istanbul
and move somewhere else.
To turn over--
I feel ready
to give up material things...
I don't want anything more for myself.
I'm done with all that.
I know I can--
I know I can make you happy.
I want to ask you something
but answer me honestly.
Sure.
Ask me whatever you want.
Did you see Serap again
after we broke up?
No, of course l didn't.
- Are we going, Ozcan?
- Pretty soon. The fog's lifting.
Bahar, what do you say?
Forget this job.
Come with me to Istanbul tomorrow.
I'm sorry. It's too late now.
Well, fine then. I'm going.
- Here you are. Have a good trip.
- Thanks.
Make sure you're there an hour early.
- What?
- You have to be there an hour early.
- At the airport?
- At the airport, yes.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
Is the road to lshakpasha open?
- Are you done?
- Yes.
What a great view
from down here as well.
I should take a photo from here.
Can you stand in the foreground?
It would be nice to have someone
in the picture for a change.
Come a bit closer.
Is this okay?
That's good but don't smile.
Look serious.
Tilt your head forward a bit.
Look more serious.
Look!
- Nice, isn't it?
- Yes, it's a good one.
Is there any chance
you can send me a copy?
Sure.
Write your address
on a piece of paper then.
I'll write it on the back of this.
How long will it take to get here?
A couple of weeks or so.
What are you going to do with it?
Send it to my girlfriend.
Aren't there any photographers
in Dogubeyazit?
There are,
but they do mostly passport photos.
It's nice to have
a scenic photo for once.
I'm putting my phone number
here as well, just in case...
Here you go.
- Sorry for the trouble but...
- No problem.
- Are we going straight back then?
- That's right.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- You were up early.
- I couldn't sleep.
- Did you manage to get some sleep?
- Yes, a bit.
I was even dreaming.
You forgot your present that day.
I was going to give it
to you in the van but...
I had such a nice dream.
What about?
It was a beautiful day.
Perfect sunshine.
There were these rolling green meadows.
And I could fly.
I was gliding gently over the meadows.
It was so beautiful.
Then I looked down
and saw a cemetery or something.
I flew gently down towards it.
Suddenly I could see my mother.
She was waving at me.
I thought:
"Wow! She's still alive!"
It was really nice.
It made me so happy.
What time do you have to be on set?
You don't want to be late.
At 9:00.
Let's get going then.
I'll buy you a good breakfast.
I can go from there to the airport.
Okay?
Aze, you're not crying again, are you?
Come on. That's enough now.
I won't stop until my father's avenged.
That's going to happen.
Don't worry. I'm here.
I'm going to avenge your father.
I'm going to stop those tears.
We'll be able to walk with pride again.
Can we cut, please?
There's an aircraft.
Oh God! That's all we needed.
- Tell me when it's gone.
- Okay.
A cigarette, someone!
Guys, what's the problem?
You keep forgetting your lines.
Zeynep,
what happened to the rehearsals?
But they only forgot...
Apo, when you put your rifle down,
don't block it.
- Okay.
- Watch out for that.
For my son, Ayaz