All of it.
X-ray!
To the censor.
You need a new I.D. card it's illegible.
Finish the inspection.
I got two different sized shoes
at the induction center.
- I thought would be better...
- Not now
if you have any question I'll be outside.
You can get dressed.
Get to the booth and do you job.
- I'm not going in!
- You are going in!
- Dana get into the booth right now!
- I can't.
You can. Get into the booth.
I can't do it anymore. I can't!
Don't you understand? I can't! I can't!
Lower your voice!
I want to see a mental health officer!
You know I can't get you one now.
We'll take care of it later.
Now do your job. You have no choice!
Are you going in?
I won't undress this woman. I won't do it!
- Can you here?
- Go ahead smoke.
Dana keep your personal opinions at home.
You don't have a choice.
What's going on?
You can home.
Go!
- Why?
- I don't believe in it.
You always get into trouble.
I'll show her an inspection!
Can you tell me what you're doing!
Dana calm down!
Everyone come in! You go home!
Go Home! Get out!
- How many are you letting in?
- As I feel like.
Everybody stand still.
Take their ID's least.
Everyone go home!
- What are you doing?
- Whatever I have to.
You Idiot! Dubek will screw us!
Dubek my ass!
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Excuse me... Step into the booth.
- Don't go in!
- Go in!
- Step into the booth!
- She's not!
The hell with you "step in"!
- What do you care?
- Why do you car!
I care!
Everyone go home! Go Home! Goodbye!
Step inside. Everyone go home!
Go home everyone go home.
Go home.
Enough. Go home!
You and you. Everyone go home!
Goodbye.
What's going on here!
Excuse me everyone please leave.
Go out.
What's going on here?
I'm waiting for an explanation!
We'll step here all night!
I want answer!
I have no problem...
...having you all court-martialed!
I want to say that I didn't participate.
What?
I didn't do it.
What she's trying to say is that I did it.
Everyone get into the booths.
Get into the booths now!
Dana come outside with me.
- How was your day?
- Fine.
- What did you do?
- Nothing.
- What do you mean nothing?
- It was okay.
- Did something happen?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Nothing happened.
If something happened! I want to know.
Nothing happened!
Then what?
Maybe I should move to another unit.
Wait a while you don't know anything yet.
Give it some time.
You thing someplace else will be better?
Maybe you'll make some friends.
What friend?
Not everyone does what he likes
...in the army. You mother used...
to make tea did she complain?
I made tea? I didn't only make tea!
I did other things too.
Why are you getting upset?
I'm not upset. Besides what did you do?
Never mind.
We're not talking about you now.
So what do you want us to do?
Maybe you can help me.
Daddy don't you know anyone?
I don't like it.
- What don't you like?
- Pulling strings.
Mom pull up over here.
Why? Are you ashamed of us?
Pull over okay.
- Mom Pull over already!
- okay.
- When are you coming home?
- I don't know.
- At five?
- It's the army how should I know?
okay girls as far as
I'm concerned summer camp is over!
Dana is in prison and she won't be back.
You don't realize what happened
at the border crossing.
therefore I have no problem whatsoever
to put more girls in jail. Is that clear!
I'm splitting up the old pairs
and I don't want to here a peep.
There'll be new couples now.
Rotem and Yedida. Tamer and Ruthie.
Lee and Jeanette. Adi and Nitzan.
Jackie and Ronit. Yifat and Perach.
Michal and Shiri. Tali and Rachel.
- What about me?
- Have I finished?
You'll join a different couple each time ok?
We forget the new ones.
I haven't finished yet!
I haven't finished talking.
Two new soldiers have joined the util.
Smader Mirit.
Say hello. You'll be patrolling together.
You're screwed.
You sector begins where we stared out
and ends over there.
Do you see that yellow pole?
The one with the sign on it.
That's where it ends.
Don't move away from this area.
Don't sit down. Don't lean.
Don't talk on the cell phone.
Don't eat don't smoke.
No no no no!
What do you do? This.
- Do you know what to do with this?
- Yes.
there are stores and coffee shops
but they don't exist for you.
- Understand?
- Yes.
- Don't we get a break?
- Have I finished?
Between 10:00-10::30 and 14:00-14::30
and you'd better stick to the schedule...
because we check.
I see that...
the problem with your shoes is solved.
They gave me new ones but they're tight.
They'll stretch on patrol.
Go on get to work.
Your ass will stretch on patrol.
- Shall we go?
- Where to?
To the signpost.
Why the signpost? We can go over there.
I don't care.
If you don't care we'll go to the signpost.
It's good that you put her with the squealer.
What's good about it?
Nothing it's just a feeling.
You don't say. Drive!
- Are your shoes tint?
- Yes! Why?
No reason. You're walking slowly...
If you don't like my pace...
you can walk faster.
Do they Look like Arabs?
Why are you asking me?
I thing we should go over to them.
Then go.
- Excuse me good morning.
- Good morning.
Can I see you ID please?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Please.
It's not here. I can't find it.
Why don't you Look again.
Soldier our bus.
Sir I need your ID card.
Soldier I'll Lose my job.
It's okay you can go.
No he has to show his ID.
- Soldier my bus.
- Let him go.
No he must show the ID.
Sorry sir I must see your ID
otherwise I'll have to report you.
Relax I'm Looking for it.
I also have to check your bag.
- Can I go.
- Yes my bag.
- Bye.
- I'm coming.
- Come now.
- Just a minute.
Come.
I found it.
I'm sorry I...
Why are you sorry?
You're such a moron.
Thank you.
- Where are you forms?
- Mirit has them.
Do we have to hand them in?
What did you thing?
Do you want to keep them as a souvenir?
You didn't white anything down.
As for tomorrow
we won't accept such forms.
- Excuse me!
- What?
- It doesn't  good.
It really... really doesn't  good on you.
You don't say?
- Will see you when I get back?
- Maybe.
- What'll we do?
- We might go to a movie.
- Will I see you in ten hours?
- Twelve.
Excuse me.
May I see your ID care please?
Yes.
My name is Bashir Hassan abu-Mussa.
- From Ram Allah?
- Yes Ram Allah.
Thank you.
- Are you cold?
- A little.
Why don't we warm up somewhere?
Go.
Hey.
- Nice hat isn't it?
- Yes.
- Go in and try it on.
- No not now.
You like it try it on. We'll keep watch.
It's too expensive.
But you can try it on can't you?
I'm not going to buy
it so I won't just try it on.
Too bad.
Come in come in.
Do you want to try the hat on?
- No not now.
- okay.
I'm making some tea.
She makes me nervous.
Don't you want to sit down?
No it's okay.
Sit down! Let her keep guard.
Julia haven't you finished that sweater?
It's a new one.
What will you do with all of them?
I see them.
- Dose it pay?
- of course.
- Hello.
- Listen Dubek is in the area.
C'mon let's go. Inspection!
Move!
Give me two bagels please.
- Hello.
Dubek is on the way.
Forget the bagel thanks.
- Dubek is on the way?
- What's on the way?
C'mon I don't think they'll be back.
That's it I'm going.
- Bye.
- Hello.
I'd like to make an appointment.
Why make an appointment?
I'll be right with you.
I only have half an hour...
I'll be done in a minute...
No I don't want a haircut.
I only want to take a Look
I Love these challenges.
In my opinion...
we can play with the bangs.
I'll bleach your bangs blonde.
when you were your beret
you can put some gel on it.
And when you take off the beret
it's still sculptured and flowing...
If I'm not mistaken...
someone is Looking at you all time.
Don't Look. I'll turn the chair around a bit.
What a pain in the ass!
She's just like clockwork!
I'll come back some other time.
Why are you following me?
The break is over.
So I'm worried about you
Don't worried about me!
Yes.
May I speak to you?
Yes?
I don't want to make any trouble maybe
it's too early but I want to know if there's...
a chance of moving to another unit?
Sit down.
- Is something wrong with our unit?
- No.
- Is everything okay on patrol?
- Yes.
- You get along with the girls?
Then why do you want to move?
I don't know I...
I asked to be stationed far from home...
but I'm close to home.
Something wrong at home?
No... I just wanted a different kind
of army service far from home...
- Like what?
- I don't know.
An operation sergeant?
or a tank instructor?
Yes something like that.
You con move to another unit
but only after 6 months.
You can't do much about it now.
But if you'll be okay
and everything works out well.
I'll recommend you later on.
- So nothing can be done now?
- I'm sorry.
Yes, thank you.
Hi Smadar.
You've already left for the army?
We don't get to talk
we have to set fixed days.
Sweetheart I'm sorry I didn't catch you.
Regards from Dad and Ronni
As far as the maintenance fee...
I hope you remember to pay the dues.
Kisses. Bye.
Girls.
Things here are wrong.
According to your forms...
it Look like the Arabs have vanished.
But what's worse is that...
you're not doing your jobs properly.
These forms weren't meant
to be taken out for a morning walk.
These forms have a very specific purpose!
If there's a terror attack
what do you think I can do with such forms?
Here's a random form.
Adi and Nizan.
Erasures illegible handwriting.
Do you understand what's written?
I don't!
Let's go on.
Rotem and Yedida.
only 5 Arabs are listed in the form?
Next. Yifat and Perah.
This is a proper form.
This is how a form should Look.
When there are no complaints...
I don't complain.
Next.
Smader and Mirit.
3 people listen on the form.
only 3! What do you say about this?
Go ahead.
They were the only ones there.
"The only ones there". okay.
- Here's a map of Jerusalem.
- Shut up.
Sector 3. The entrance to the old City.
Jaffa Gate Jaffa Street
the entrance to the City.
There are no Arabs in the morning?
Nobody goes to work?
No more suspects? Everything is okay?
- Explain it please.
- I can't explain it.
How do they get into the city?
They fly over this sector!
Find another explanation.
I don't have one.
In sector two Yifat and Perah's sector
which is right next to yours
the page is full of names.
Some of the people must have passed
into your sectors.
What do you say about that?
Maybe I don't know what an Arab Looks like.
You don't know...
You don't know what an Arab  like?
okay.
No problem.
Where are Smader and Mirit today?
on buses.
I'll patrol with you today.
I'll show what an Arab Look like.
Sit down.
You sit on the other side.
Look straight ahead.
- Go over to him.
- To whom?
You know who. Get up and register him.
Get up!
Excuse me. I need your ID card.
Yes.
Thank you.
Be careful. I suggest you be careful.
From today bring your forms directly to me!
Don't start with me!
Don't start with me at all!
I'm sick and tired of you
and all your girlfriends!
okay I'm sorry.
It's always the same thing...
in every bus I take.
Excuse me soldiers.
What's the problem?
There's bag by itself
and nobody noticed it.
- Where?
- Right here on the seat.
Dose this bag belong to anyone?
- Let's stop the bus.
- Driver!
This bag happens to be mine.
I'm surprised you didn't see it.
- What?
- This bag belongs to me.
It was on the seat by itself
and no one noticed it.
- That's very serious!
- I'm sorry.
What good dose that do?
What do you do?
I only want her to understand. That's all!
If you all blew up now
her apology wouldn't help us!
Leave them alone.
I only want her to understand.
What you understand?
Who do you think you are?
Do you think we're playing here?
Do you thing we're enjoying?
Give me you ID now!
You're disturbing an officer on duty.
- You want my ID?
- Yes.
- Then I want your ID.
- No!
Give me you ID...
No... give me yours!
What is this?
What do you mean what is this?
You're psychopath!
- You're fresh!
- Driver we have to get off!
- What nerve!
- What a psychopath!
- You better watch out.
- A psychopath!
I'm dying of hunger.
Haven't you eaten all day?
I didn't get a chance.
I'm dying of the cold.
Julia come on I'll give you a lift home.
I'm coming.
Nice bike!
- Come no.
- This is so cold.
Come no.
- Stop it!
- Just a second.
I don't want to take just anything.
Take something that
you thing I want most.
And I'll take something...
I thing you want most.
- Did you here me?
- I hear you.
Look.
Didn't you bring anything sweet?
- No.
- I did.
Really?
- What's that?
- Nothing special.
Nothing special?
- Why did you take it?
- Why did you care?
It has nothing to do with a meal.
So what?
So why steal it I don't get it?
What don't you understand?
I needed some get... so I took it.
What's the matter?
I don't know I don't like it.
- What don't you like?
- That wasn't our plan.
We didn't plant our lives either.
I could have also stolen shaving cream.
So why didn't you?
Because if I need shaving cream.
I wound have bought it.
Why to go! You're really okay!
That's right. I'm really okay.
I might be a little boring
but that's how it is.
You are boring.
I think...
I'll go to sleep.
- You know what?
- What?
I don't know why I got into this.
- Stealing doesn't excite me.
- I know it.
- You're simply boring.
- oh really?
- You're totally fucked up!
- Excuse me!
You're totally fucked up!
They told me you were fuck up.
- They told you?
- Yes.
Go to whoever told you that...
- ... and tell them they're right.
- Terrific.
- I'm going.
- Go on.
Who said that I'm totally fucked up?
- Hello.
- Hi.
Is it ok if I sit down and you'll...
Yeah it's okay.
I'll keep an eye open.
Don't worry. What do I get out of it?
- What?
- Do you want anything?
okay give me a cream puff.
Thank you. Have a nice day.
Hi Julia it's Smader.
Is the guy at the kiosk okay?
- Did you buy something?
- A Cream puff.
- Then it's okay.
- Good.
Do you want to do some thing
on the break?
I can't.
That's okay. But the kiosk...
Excuse me where are you going?
What?
okay bye.
Excuse me sir please register with her.
But...
I ask you to register with her.
This is my card.
She told me to register with you.
I don't have the forms she does.
- Really?
- Really!
The other soldier said...
that you have the forms.
Come with me, please.
Take it! Register him.
You can go. Have a good day.
Why didn't you register him?
I didn't feel like it!
Do you intend to sit here for a Ion time?
I haven't decided yet.
When will you decide?
I don't know.
Excuse me I want to open the shop.
Forget it! I'll do it myself.
Give me the forms.
Give me the forms already!
Take you bloody forms!
Where is my bag? I can't find it...
My bag...
Where's my bag?
I can't fine my bag.
I have to go.
Come help us will these people...
Don't let anyone pass...
Mirit help me!
Are you Mirit Shimoni?
No I'm her friend.
Let her pass.
An hysterical woman is Looking for her.
Who's Looking for Mirit?
- I am!
- Come over here.
Are you Mirit's mother?
Have you seen her?
- I saw her she's fine.
- Are you sour?
Yes she's fine.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Mom?
No I'm okay. Everything is okay.
I wasn't at the bombing...
I was nearby.
I don't know Mom it was a mess.
Stop it Mom I'm okay.
it was a mass...
I don't remember what happened.
I'm not going to any neighbor...
and I'm not alone.
Who told you that I'm alone.
okay I'll call.
Mommy...
I miss you.
okay bye.
It's not only because of the bombing
Mirit didn't want to beginning that unit
form the beginning.
Listen sweetie...
No problem I'll phone someone.
But it takes time have a little patience.
He's right.
It's not a good idea to expect things.
Forget about it
and then one day you'll get a surprise.
From my experience the best thing to do
is to go to your commander and talk to.
I'll like you all to meet my angel.
She's the one who told me
that Mirit is okay.
I brought you your bag.
How sweet of you. eat with us.
No I only come to bring the bag.
Sit next to Mirit.
Where did you find the bag?
A policeman gave it to me
after you left he thought it was mine.
- Are you in Mirit unit? -Yes.
Poor thing you had an awful day.
Have some bread.
Maybe she doesn't feel like it.
Actually I only dropped by to bring the bag.
- People are waiting for me at home.
- Sorry.
Maybe you can leave me...
your parent's phone number
so I'll have someone to talk to...
in case something happens.
My parents are abroad.
They're abroad?
They work overseas.
So why are you going? Stay overnight.
- okay.
Do you sleep with one pillow or two?
I sleep with two but...
one.
Actually two.
You can sleep in these.
Choose whatever you like.
okay... If you need something I'm...
- What's your mother's name?
- Yael.
And yours?
- Betty.
I'm only kidding it's Frieda.
Listen to it it's really a nice piece.
I like your headband.
open ranks for the Co's inspection!
open ranks. March!
one Close!
Smadar Mirit.
These girls were at the bombing.
The troop will close ranks.
ranks. March!
one Close!
Two three attention!
At ease.
Girls I know how difficult your job is.
It was important for me to come here
And to personally tell you
that I greatly appreciate your work.
Thank you.
Thank you really.
In view of the last events.
I'm escalating the alert level in the city
and our presence will be felt everywhere.
I am asking every one of you to
...open seven pairs of eyes and...
to understand the importance of your job.
while demonstrating sensitivity and
restraint towards the people you inspect.
That's all.
I think we can begin the day.
Do you want to add something?
Actually. You covered what I want to say.
I would like to mention the hole puncher.
okay girls pay attention.
As we said...
we have hot alerts on terror attacks.
All the girls who work...
...on buses pay attention.
In order to make sure that...
you were there and did you job properly.
we decided that from today not only do...
you write down the bus number.
but you punch' your patrol forms
with the bus driver's hole puncher.
Everything else as usual.
That's the guy who helped me...
at the bombing.
- He's hot.
- He sure is.
That's far enough let's go back.
No way! Walk over to him.
I can't.
Go ahead he'll be gone soon.
What should I do attack him?
You don't have to be so aggressive. Say...
"Thanks for helping me at the bombing. "
Do you want me to go?
Cut it out Smadar I can't.
He's going!
Mirit!
Maybe next time.
There won't be a next time.
You might not see him again.
I will I'll see him.
Are you going?
I won't have time to do this again.
Forget it.
That's it he's going!
of course! What boredom!
" Base commander"
How many buses were you on?
It's all written down.
The bus numbers too.
- Did you take a break?
- Yes.
For how Ion?
Half an hour.
- What about you?
- The same.
okay that all. see you tomorrow.
- Do you want me to give you a ride?
- No!
- Don't miss the game.
- I won't. Bye.
- What did that guy buy?
- Cigarettes why?
What brand did he buy?
- Why?
- No special reason.
- Is there a problem?
- No, nothing, really.
- okay, never mind.
- okay, I'll tell you.
He bought "Camel Light".
You know what? It's strange.
He usually buys Camel regular.
In my opinion,
he'll smoke more of the lights.
Give me a Camel Light too and a lighter.
- How much is it?
-20 shekels.
Thanks.
Did you notice the prices want down?
Really?
Why don't you buy a hat
and make my day?
- That hat is very pretty.
- So buy it.
Not now. What if they check up on us?
- So don't buy it.
- Don't force her.
I'm right here. Where would I go?
I can't go in now.
Someone just went by...
and we didn't register him.
Don't change the subject.
It's like the guy we followed...
and you did nothing.
It's same with the hat.
Hat and nothing!
Buy the already. Do something!
Who said I didn't do anything with the guy?
What did you do?
I passed by the place.
- And...
- I don't know what'll happen.
I asked what happened?
There's nothing to tell.
Did you talk to him?
Did he offer you a cup of coffee? What?
- Nothing special.
- What do you mean?
- We sat down?
- Sat down?
Do you want a cigarette?
where did you get a cigarettes?
It's his. He forgot them at my place.
He smokes " lights" now
because of all the muck in his lungs...
But I think he smokes more now.
He smokes light now
but I don't know what you did.
You know... since they reduced the prices
I think I'll buy the hat.
Smadar? Dubek is in your area. Bye.
What's the matter?
Hurry up Dubek's in the area.
Great!
Don't Look back walk normally.
Are they on foot or in the jeep?
How am I supposed to know?
Too bad you didn't ask.
Where is she?
Maybe she wants to trick us.
Good thing,
I registered some in the morning.
Look straight ahead!
She's not her don't you get it?
She must have been here...
while we were in the store...
and she saw that we were missing.
Where can I do?
We're screwed.
All we need is for her to see us okay?
Let's go back to the store.
Maybe she's there.
Hi.
- Hi.
Can we go?
okay girls.
The Israeli Festival is a head.
our unit is participating.
Tomorrow morning you'll report...
at the Sheraton Hotel.
The bands participating in the festival
are staying at the hotel
and we're securing the place.
I want to remind you that these
are foreigners who agreed to come here.
So God forbid!
God forbid if something happens to them.
Is that clear?
I want you to be on maximum alert!
And of course keep your hair neat...
and your uniform ironed.
madar and Mirit
you'll be at the hotel's main entrance.
Yifat and Perach
you're at the back entrance. That's all.
I hope you'll enjoy the change.
She gave up a bonus.
- What are you doing now?
- I don't know.
You're probably going to meet...
your dude aren't you?
Yes actually.
Do you want a lift?
No I don't remember what
we planned but..
I think he's picking me up.
- okay.
- Bye.
Excuse me. What time is it please?
A quarter to seven.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
- Hi.
Thank you.
- What's he Looking at?
- You turn him on.
I know this not the right moment but
would you like to join me
for a little drink?
Now?
- I'm sorry I can't now.
- I can wait.
He's still Looking at you.
Thank you.
Well?
I think I'll go with him.
- But only for a short while okay?
- Excellent.
Well?
Good evening Where is Mirit?
Good evening.
- Where is Mirit?
- In the ladies room.
- Is everything alright?
- Yes.
I think we'll wander about for a while.
Actually,
they asked us not to wander about.
They asked you not to wander about.
- What?
- Nothing.
That's nice.
Excuse us.
I'm sorry I need to go.
You're lucky.
What's the charge?
Degrading an IDF uniform
and abandoning a post.
- For how Ion?
- A week.
- okay.
- She has to come back to me.
- Do you need anything?
- No.
I have a request.
I don't want to continue patrolling
with Smadar when I get back.
May I ask why?
- No.
- okay.
I'll pass on your request
but I don't promise anything.
- Hello.
You don't know me
I'm Smadar Mirit's friend.
She never told me your name...
...doesn't matter. Dubek, our commander,
you must have hard about,
shoved her into jail and she didn't
get a chance to let you know.
It would be nice
if we visit and surprise her.
You're talking to the wrong person.
I'm not confused. It's you.
I have a motorbike but.
Do you have car?
Yes.
okay do you want us to go together?
I don't know what you're talking about.
What don't you want? Mirit is in jail.
I'm very sorry but who's Mirit?
What do you mean who's Mirit?
You don't know Mirit?
No.
She's so Cools!
She gave you a different name.
Do you smoke Camel Light?
- Yes.
- So?
There must be some mistake...
You don't know Mirit?
The girl at the bombing?
I'm sorry it's not me.
- I'm sorry...
- Bye.
What do you say?
Why don't we surprise her anyway?
What do you care?
Do you something nice. I'll be cool.
Sorry I don't have the time.
What do you mean?
What do you have to do?
I'm sorry I can't.
It's just that... okay.
Fuck you.
okay? Go fuck yourself.
Rise and Shine! Good morning.
Get up!
You're not at the Regency Palace!
- Dana good morning.
- Good morning.
You've got 7 minutes
to get into your fatigues.
Get up. Rise and Shine.
Good morning.
- Did you get cigarettes?
- I don't smoke.
From now on you smoke...
and you give me your cigarettes okay?
Good morning wake up!
Get up! Get up!
- What's your name?
- Mirit.
Mirit.
You don't say? That's great.
I don't know what I'd do... I'd...
You're so great.
What!
Jusmin!
- What's up?
- You don't say.
That's great...
No way...
- You Look familiar.
- I don't know...
I'll get right back to you.
Dana move it! keep up with the pace
Why it's not fast enough?
- No.
- Why not?
Don't get wise I'm warning you.
What'll you do send me to jail?
What did you say?
Nothing.
What are you Looking at?
Keep working!
Hey.
You still don't know where we met?
No.
At the border crossing.
I'm the one who said
" I didn't participate".
oh yeah!
What am I supposed to do
with that information now?
Nothing.
There's nothing you can do with it.
Absolutely.
What's going on here?
The minute I turn my back...
you start fooling around!
You won't go to sleep tonight!
I thought you weren't coming.
We got Lost on the way.
We brought you a cheesecake...
the kind you like.
- Be careful.
- Gently so it doesn't fall apart.
Have are you honey?
You don't have much time left
so be strong.
I spoke to Shaul.
He's working on your reassignment.
Really?
And we brought you a visitor.
Let's go.
You poor folk I clung to them.
I had to see you.
You left me all alone.
I got you something.
open it.
Go ahead try it on.
I'm dying to see it on you.
Well It doesn't go too well with green.
Move it sideways a little.
A little more... that's it.
Cut it out. This has is just not me.
I think it Look very nice on you.
I mean... maybe not right now
Not now or ever.
- But you like it.
- And now I don't like it.
- I don't understand.
- Why?
This hat doesn't solve everything.
What's wrong?
I don't think we'll continue together.
What are you talking about?
We'll go to Dubek and fight for it.
I asked them to separate us.
Fine.
obviously!
Easy calm down.
My husband is inside.
All our husbands are inside.
He won't find me.
- It's better that way.
- Let us enter.
If my husband won't find me hoe will...
I get home?
Never mind your husband... Enough!
We're waiting all day!
- You feel like smoking?
- okay.
Let's ask Dubek
if we can patrol together.
But I'm being discharged in days.
That's it. And then I'm leaving.
- Where to?
- To Russia.
Why do you think...
I knitted all those sweaters?
I've got everything ready.
I have a ticket I have money.
This is Sasha. I'm going to him.
He's so cute. Who is he?
He's my boyfriend.
- But he's just a kid.
- So what!
This picture is 10 years old.
Don't you have a current picture?
He doesn't send any.
He's afraid I'll disappointed.
great you opened a coffee shop.
Madam come here please.
Sweetheart were you promoted?
No I promotes myself.
I can't stay unit 11 p. m.
because of you.
okay.
open the bag. Take everything out.
Throw away the pita.
Why?
Throw away the pita in the garbage!
He hasn't eaten all day Ion.
Do you see what's writing here?
What does it say?
" Do not enter with food".
What's that?
Throw the pita into the garbage.
I won't throw the pita into the garbage.
You don't have a choice.
Throw it into the garbage.
What's in the pita.
I don't care what's in the pita.
- But what's in it?
- I don't care!
What's in the pita?
Cheese a pickle and olives.
Take it out of my face!
What's in the pita?
- Go to hell.
- Fuck you!
Fuck you!
- Hello.
- You don't remember me.
- No.
You don't remember me
from the bombing?
I'm the girl you helped.
- Wait a minute is your name Mirit?
- Yes.
You were released from prison?
Yes how do you know?
Do you remember the soldier...
I told you about?
No.
The one who knocked on our door
and to go with her begged me
to come asked me with her to visit
her best friend in prison.
Did she have black hair
and a light complexion?
I think so.
Was she short like me
with Ion eyelashes?
Yes, that's the one.
Is that the girl she wanted you to visit?
I think so.
Would you like to join us?
No I...
I just wanted to thank you for helping me.
I was glad to help.
Who wants chocolate cake?
I do!
Rotem darling this is for you.
But I want it...
I'll give you another one.
Julia.
Lucky her.
Commander Liat...
- Yes Julia?
- I have a gift for you.
I knit it myself.
- Really?
- Yes.
It's beautiful thank you.
Thank you thank you.
Girls be quiet for a minute
I want to say some thing.
Julia is leaving us today...
So I wish her success in her future life.
Julia I hope...
that when you Look back at these days
you'll have...
a few nice moments to remember.
Let's make a toast
- Cheers!
we don't have much time
we've got to get back to work.
- Good luck Julia.
- Thank you.
Pay attention!
Girls Julia may have all the time
in the world but we have to move.
So... I'll read the work roster
and you'd better listen.
Rotem and Yedida sector 1.
Lee and Jeanette bus number 18
Mirit and Smadar sector 3.
Adi and Nitzan sector 4.
Yifat and Perah bus number 6.
Jackie and Ronit border crossing.
one more bite and we're out of here.
Come get the forms please.
Are you coming?
Smader...
Take care of yourself.
Take care of Sasha.
- Bye.
Go on get out of here.
I forget my bag.
- Bye.
I see that the entire unit is here.
Sit down.
I don't nee a haircut I want to talk her.
I don't want to.
- Why not?
- Do you mind not interfering?
Will you listen to me?
If she's here I'm out.
I only want to you talk to you!
Get out of my sight!
I only want to tell you some thing!
Say it already!
You're like glue!
Sit down.
I apologize. I'm sorry.
Who's angry anyway?
So why won't you talk to me?
Because you don't interest me!
So why did you go to that guy for me?
I was bored.
And why did you buy me the hat?
I don't know okay!
I don't know!
It doesn't flatter you it's ugly!
It doesn't Look good?
So you lied to me?
Yes I lied. You liar.
Maybe I'm a liar but I don't know
why you bought me that hat.
I don't know okay!
What do you mean? " I don't know"?
- Tell me!
- Just because.
Why did you bring me the hat?
I don't remember.
Maybe you've become attached to me?
Bullshit.
That's it you've become attached to me.
Let me spoil you. I'll shampoo your
hair put on a mask for split ends...
How about it?
I know...
We haven't registered anyone.
That's right we're way out of line.
okay we'll do it now.
Who will we register?
What are you worried about?
We'll find people.
We should have done it in the morning.
If they leave in the morning...
they come back in the evening.
It's not the same thing.
Mirit stop being uptight
we'll find people okay?
Come on.
Excuse me may I have your ID please?
- We were here first.
- It isn't your area.
It's not yours either.
It's closer to us.
Don't fuck with me.
We saw him over there.
Really?
Excuse me may I please have your ID?
- Let her go.
- Moron.
What if don't give it to you?
What do you mean?
What will you do if don't give it to you?
- What will we do?
- Come on give it to us.
- I refuse.
- You have no choice.
What will you do to me?
Come on cut it out.
Well what will you do me?
What do you mean?
I'll report you right now.
They'll arrest you interrogate you...
Shall I continue?
You can decide not to report me.
What do you say?
Why don't you say something?
Excuse me.
Take your hand put in into your pocket,
take out your ID and give it to me.
- Come on Smeder...
- No...
where will I find you someone else?
Where are you going?
Give me your ID and lets get it over with!
This is understand of!
When I ask for an ID you give it to me.
What's the story? Hey Come on!
No hands!
Shmuck get your hands off me.
- What's going on here?
- Give me your ID!
I saw him raise a hand on you.
You're raising a hand...
on a soldier you maniac!
- I didn't raise a hand.
- Give me your ID.
I don't need your help okay?
Move back Move back. I can manage.
Give me your ID.
Can't you see that I'm meaning?
You weren't here either. Get out here!
I saw him raise a hand on the soldier.
- Get back!
- You maniac!
Get back!
Leave him alone!
What are you doing?
Get back! Leave him alone!
Get back!
Stop it!
Leave him alone! Stop it!