You know the code?
Nope, they don't open up.
Give back my bag!
Wait a moment!
Give back the fucking bag!
Come on!
Give already back the bag!
But who do you wanna talk to?
You may guess.
Don't take that tone.
Well, guess now where I am.
Seriously, I want my things back.
Who doesn't want that?
I'll set the cops on you!
Wait. What do you mean,
"I'll set the cops on you"?
Listen now. The first step is:
Let your phone get blocked.
That's sick, you're a jerk.
Finally.
Who are you actually?
Come on, open up.
Hi Paul, new girlfriend?
- Fuck off, go find another meadow!
Go to the bathroom.
You're dripping all over.
My mother's bad again.
I was with her the whole night.
I just came in now.
Don't be angry, please.
And how was it?
Best wishes to your mom.
How's your name?
- Guess.
You shall guess.
Steffen.
- Nope.
Steffen, Thomas.
More.
Tom.
- With "Z".
"Z". Zorro.
- Right, that's my name.
"Z".
- Yes, Zorro.
Tom. I believe your name's Tom.
Open the door.
Can you please
take it with you.
Good evening, Anna.
Has anything happened?
- No.
Just a routine check.
Sit.
Sit!
We didn't meet for a while.
- No.
So I thought I'd have a look.
They don't get you out of here, right?
You're still not afraid,
all alone here?
Not me.
The flat in the backyard of our place
is still available, I asked again.
Thank you.
Well,
don't let them push you around.
I better take this with me, okay?
Have a nice evening, Anna.
Come on. Heel!
Did I wake you up?
Good night.
Well, and now?!
Come down here!
Someone's going mad here.
Hello, Anna isn't at home.
I'm downstairs at your door.
It's really annoying,
I fix a date to look at that flat and
meet up there and you don't come.
Is it about your mother again?
Shit!
You're okay, Anna?
You must write the letter.
Otherwise they'll get you out.
Here's the number: 482 42 472.
Look at the flat, okay?
And then call me back.
Hey, you're Susanne, right?
- Anything happened?
Anna isn't at home.
We had an appointment.
She's at her mother's for a few days.
She wasn't well again.
Patrick.
She'll tell you eventually.
At the moment she's busy.
Understandable, right?
Can I take a message?
No.
Ciao Susanne. It was nice.
I know you're there.
You're hiding, right?
And Susanne doesn't get it.
I've understood.
You don't want to go there.
It's really good I'm here.
If only for your mail.
Well that clinic looks cool.
From your ill mother.
From Madeira.
And here, bill, reminder.
House administration.
AOL.
Inkasso. Bank, credit card cancelled.
Dear Anna, all the best
for a new year in your life...
I hope you'll visit me soon.
Good luck, darling. Your grandma Mimi.
20 Euro.
Open up.
Why don't you open the door?
Want to eat something?
I've been shopping.
Been shopping?
Just before with Susanne, right?
It doesn't work with everybody!
What will you do when
your mother gets really bad...
Mrs. Meissner!
Property Administration
Anna's not at home...
Who's there?
Guess.
Won't you let me in?
It's late already.
How's the code?
Where are my things?
And the rest?
- Let me in first.
I don't even know your name?
- Guess.
Anton.
Right, Anton.
Buy me a beer
and you get your phone.
Have a light?
Keep it.
Didn't he say keep it?
Do we know each other?
'Cause you're informal.
Leave him.
If you don't stop now...
- Don't get provoked by him.
Who knows what's wrong with him?
It's enough now, okay?
Enough now!
Don't move.
You like it?
It hurts.
Go to the apotek and get something.
- Soon.
I'm hungry too.
That soup doesn't help.
I'm dizzy.
You're dizzy?
Come on now, I can't even get up.
I want you to get me some pills.
Can't I rest a little more?
Well, alright.
It suits well for Anna that
I'm lying here, right?
Is it really so difficult to go to
the closestW apotek? - Come on!
Susanne's coming tomorrow.
She's bringing films for us.
Anything you want to watch?
That's annoying. Get lost.
I'm not your lapdog.
Get lost, neurotic bitch! Don't
touch me with your yellow fingers!
What are you spying here?
You're sick.
Come on, get lost.
Come on.
Now you can see...
Untie me at once.
Untie me!
Get off the bonds!
You shall get off the bonds,
stupid cow!
Sorry, I didn't mean it.
You can breath through the nose.
Don't panic, okay?
Don't move so much.
How shall this go on?
You're sick. Completely schizo.
- Really?
Well, you must know it.
Wanna smoke?
Have you been to the doctor?
No, it's just migraine.
- It looks awful downstairs.
Someone has emptied the rubbish.
They really want to gross you out, huh?
Finally it's finished.
Have you talked with Sacha?
- Susanne, please not now...
Don't be angry.
Thank you for the stuff.
Here.
I'm freezing.
I'd like to lay down again.
Go to bed. I'll make you a tea.
Tomorrow it'll be better.
When's your next tour?
Monday I'm in Istanbul with René.
Kind regards.
I think he still has a crush on me.
It's more than a year ago.
I don't care about it right now.
Can't you leave me alone today?
Any noise is painful for me.
You must go to the doctor.
Birthday present?
It felt strange
when I met him on the stairs.
How is he?
- Leave me alone.
Anna,
the excavators will start in 3 days.
You aren't well.
Let's talk another time.
Okay?
I'll get my lamp.
I wanna go back to bed.
What's going on now?
Come on.
I want back in bed now.
Let go, Anna!
Are you crazy?
- Everything's fine.
Why are you lying, huh?
You're lying to all of us.
Your mother isn't ill actually.
Go away, please.
Anna, I'm your friend!
What shall I do, Anna!
- You shall go away!
Am I just hysterical?
Will you call me?
Get off my back!
You shall leave!
Come on. Open up.
You shall open the door!
- No.
Now we'll go out!
- No!
Come on.
Here we go.
Come on now.
You're sick.
Let go, you swine!
You're even sicker than I am.
Then just die up there!
Get out.
Get out!
Subtitles:
The Huge Animal From The North