CLOSE TO LEO
Give me an "acorn" too.
- Are the rum babas fresh?
- Give me a break, Leo.
I'll take two. That'll be all.
Put it on the account. 'Bye!
No more baguettes?
What's that?
I fancied some cake.
Got any strawberry tarts?
Put them in the fridge.
Catch!
Mom said put them in the fridge.
Where the hell have you been?
Tristan was worried.
Not at all.
I just asked where he was.
We haven't finished the game.
So where's the champagne?
Champagne, cakes...
What are we celebrating?
Tristan...
Ever had sex?
Knock it off.
A first day at work
is worth celebrating.
For a job in a factory, maybe.
But in Daddy's shop...
Just wait till you find a job.
Yours took a lot of finding.
No preferential treatment.
Tristan works, like everyone else.
How come you're still up?
It's late.
- I want some champagne.
- Don't hold your breath.
Put your pajamas on
and say goodnight.
In a minute.
Marcel...
So how much do you pay him, Dad?
Don't tell him.
It's no secret.
I don't want him to know.
Really? Is that all?
Champagne, then?
- Since when?
- Never you mind.
How'd you get it?
What does it matter? You idiot!
I'm 20, and I'm a goner!
Don't say that.
HlV doesn't necessarily
kill you these days.
Where are you going?
Stay here.
Marcel mustn't know, agreed?
Agreed?
- Why, are you ashamed?
- That's not what he means!
I've never been ashamed of you.
He's too young to understand.
- When I'm dead, it'll be too late.
- Stop it!
Stop it, Leo.
Goodnight, Dad.
Goodnight, darling.
- Goodnight, Tristan.
- See you tomorrow.
- Goodnight, Mom.
- Goodnight, love.
- Goodnight, Pierrot.
- Goodnight, Marcel.
What are you doing?
Getting a tan.
I'm keeping my trousers on.
Why? Are you wearing
Pokemon underpants?
What the hell's this?
Anyone got a smoke?
We just had the last one.
You mean you did!
You don't smoke?
Leo, did it sting you?
What do we do?
It'll go away.
Stop being so scared all the time.
Hello, Mrs. Shopkeeper.
With APS, you have a choice
of 3 different formats:
panoramic, large rectangle
and small rectangle.
Let me show you...
It's easy. Look...
- Excuse me, I just wanted a film.
- Marcel!
I didn't recognize you.
- Come on, make your mind up.
- Don't rush me.
I'll chew it over and call in again.
I'd like your father's opinion.
He knows Brigitte.
As you please, but I think
this is the one for you.
You'll soon be as big
as your brothers.
What's wrong with you?
Are you stupid?
It was just a laugh.
You just blew an 800-franc sale!
Calm down, she said she wanted
to see Dad first.
You're irresponsible, Marcel!
You'll end up like Pierrot.
Good!
As long as I don't end up like you!
A slave in Dad's shop.
That's easy to say.
You'll understand when you're older.
Asshole!
- What's up?
- Screw you.
Thanks!
It's only us.
What are you doing?
Waiting for you.
What do you want?
I've done nothing.
No need to get nasty.
Look, Pierrot and l
had something to tell you.
We wanted to tell you...
that some things...
Some things prevent you
from growing up.
Even for you,
things won't always be
as you want them to be.
What are you babbling about?
I need a hand here.
What Tristan means,
what he's trying to say...
is that till now,
everything's been rosy for you
but one day, there may well be...
a disaster.
Maybe not a disaster
but something less rosy.
See?
Is that it?
Yeah.
People go to mass on Sundays.
That means customers.
You think they'll want to buy a film
after mass?
I reckon it'll be dead.
OK?
You should eat a bit.
People take photos
on Sunday afternoon.
Walking, picnicking,
on the beach, playing sports...
At orgies...
Pierrot!
I don't care what
they take pictures of.
I'll gladly develop them!
Either you're a pro or you aren't!
Everyone finished?
I'll have more!
Tough luck.
It ain't raining.
Speak properly.
"lt ain't raining"?
Ain't raining!
Marcel...
- Orgy!
- Are you crazy?
- Leave the table immediately!
- Run your bath.
It'll calm you down.
Your eyes are red.
It's the soap.
Your brothers set a bad example.
It's easy to show off
in front of someone younger.
You want to be like them
but you're younger.
You're 12.
You don't say "orgy" when you're 12.
Do you know what it means?
You see?
Never use words
you don't understand.
I bet Pierrot
doesn't understand it either.
He deserves a slap too.
Will you give him one?
I should.
So why don't you?
Forget about it.
Cut it out!
Here's a joke for you.
Go on.
It's disgusting but you'll like it.
What's the definition
of self-confidence?
Farting when you've got the runs.
Time to sleep.
Goodnight.
Leave the door open.
Are you awake?
Move over, Marcello.
Move over...
OK, you can get dressed.
I admit I'm not an expert
in such matters.
Leo should consult a specialist
in infectious diseases.
There's a good hospital in Brest.
Better than the one at Quimper.
They'll know how to proceed.
Whether to begin treatment
right away.
Or do nothing for the time being.
It depends on your general health.
We should keep an eye
on your swollen glands.
But that may have
nothing to do with it.
- Can you fix us an appointment?
- Of course. I'll call them.
What are you doing at the moment?
Revising.
Like my daughter.
Exams at the end of the month.
Is it your final year?
No, first.
Will these tests take long?
They're all done in a day.
How about tomorrow?
I'll call them from next door.
I'll be right back...
I'm not going.
We can't just ignore this, Leo.
Pretend it hasn't happened.
What will you do, then?
You always know best.
Look after you.
You regard me as a patient.
Just shut up!
So where do I stand?
I don't know.
Let's think about it.
If this is a drag...
No, it's not a drag.
Just tell me what to do.
We could try there, beside the tree.
What do you think?
Nothing. I'm no photographer.
Let's do it.
Catch.
Look up...
The other way...
Lower...
Happy?
With what?
To be behind the lens.
Will you do it all your life?
Yeah, I'd like to.
Why do you ask?
It's important.
I want you to be happy.
I am. Really happy.
Well, maybe not at the moment.
You're OK, kid.
We need a veil.
I could've played the bride.
Could you lie down?
I'll try a close-up.
You look beautiful.
Stop it.
Really, I think you're beautiful.
You should've told me.
You said you didn't mind!
I only said you look beautiful
because you do.
What's the point in helping me?
Idiot.
That's life.
No, that isn't life.
Just the opposite.
It could have happened to any of us.
Maybe not any of us.
Being a virgin's the best way
to stay healthy.
You don't know everything.
I'm not a virgin.
As for health...
Here's to yours.
Come on, Leo.
I'm stopping.
You've drunk a lot.
I'm giving it up tomorrow.
No aperitifs over there.
Pack a vial of pastis
and hook it up to a drip.
You can't beat intravenous hooch.
I knew a guy who did that.
When he had no smack,
he'd shoot up rum.
Works well, I hear.
- Some people are fucking crazy!
- Who was it?
Nobody interesting.
- Did you try it?
- Shooting up?
No. I knew it was bad.
Anyway I didn't like him.
His dick was too small.
Shall we hit the sack?
Are you crazy? It's my last night.
We're celebrating.
Your last night of what?
You're a pain.
Your tests won't last forever.
Hey, brothers, cool it.
I just want a bit of fun.
Sing, laugh, go for a swim.
Give us a break.
What are you doing?
How come you're swimming
without me?
Why didn't you tell me?
Marcel, you were asleep.
Who's swiped my trunks?
I'm sick of being excluded.
You treat me like a baby!
Don't get wound up.
The water's nice!
Come on, get a move on!
Mom, I've got no pajamas.
Shut up!
Ave mamma!
You know, it's 1 1 :30.
Really?
Any croissants?
Yes, but it's too late
for croissants.
Breakfast finishes at 1 1.
Oh, go on, Mom.
Lunch is in an hour, so get washed.
Where are the others?
Pierrot's still in bed,
Tristan's at the shop
and Leo's out with Dad.
Where did they go?
Marcel, stop pestering me!
Where's Leo?
He's gone with Dad.
To Brest.
He's going to do a course there.
That's in July.
This is a trial.
For how long?
I don't know. He'll be back later.
This evening.
He didn't say.
They called this morning.
Now get dressed
before you catch cold.
What's with the sheet anyway?
Did you wet the bed?
Did you?
- Why don't you tell me the truth?
- What truth? Leo's in Brest!
Don't worry, everything's fine.
It's just that...
How about a trip to Quimper,
just me and you?
Don't mess about,
I'm not in the mood.
Want a croissant?
Here's your croissant.
Don't tell Pierrot!
- I'm running out of patience...
- Get off!
Open this door right away.
Why did you lock yourself in?
Answer me, Marcel!
Leave him, he'll get over it.
We're not angry, darling,
but you have to come out now.
OK?
Is that OK?
What's up?
Your Dad just called.
They're keeping Leo for a while.
Did they say anything?
What should I do about Marcel?
He hasn't come out?
What do I say?
Don't say anything.
He'll come out.
Yes... he'll come out.
Marcel!
It's for you.
Did you bring your toothbrush?
You OK?
Yvan!
Thanks.
Hi.
Is your mother on antidepressants?
Why do you ask?
She never usually invites me.
It was your Mom's idea.
Mine?
She wanted you to come.
But you called.
But your Mom called here first.
Stupid bitch.
Can I tell you a secret?
A real one.
You must never repeat it.
What?
Swear first.
I swear. Go on.
Swear on what?
On your life.
Stop it, this is deadly serious.
OK, I swear on my mother's life.
- Were your fingers crossed?
- No, come on!
It's Leo.
Not Leo. Me.
You're bullshitting me.
I smashed the neon lights
in the library.
Why?
It was an attack.
What?
You know, an attack.
Did anyone see you?
No, I don't think so.
It was serious, then.
It was a serious attack.
I could go to jail.
I'll never manage it.
Never mind. Forget it.
No, I have to do it. Like you.
We don't have to attack every day.
Shut up!
What are you doing?
Come back!
What shall we do with it?
Bury it.
Can't we chuck it in the container?
Chickens have a soul too.
If you don't respect its memory,
its soul will haunt you
all your life.
Wait!
Now grab the head.
Sure?
Never seen any voodoo?
Suck the blood and say,
"I'll never forget."
You too?
No, I didn't kill it.
That would be sacrilege.
"l shall remain on earth
to honor your memory.
I swear your life
won't have been in vain."
I shall remain on earth
to honor your memory.
I swear your life
won't have been in vain.
Now bury it.
Can I let go of the head?
Is that the florist?
How may I help you?
I'd like to send flowers.
To your mother?
That's right. It's her birthday.
That's a nice gesture.
Where are they to be sent?
Up your ass!
Let's do another one.
I love that. "Up your ass!"
It's my turn.
Let me choose.
" Adofil, teenagers' helpline.
Friendship, love, health.
All questions answered."
What's the number?
What will you ask them?
Are you the telephone prankster?
Because I really
don't find it funny.
And Iet me tell you,
I won't put up with it...
It's not funny.
You don't say that to a florist.
Or anyone, for that matter.
I thought you'd grown up a bit.
But no, you're babies.
Rude babies at that.
Don't start looking all tragic.
It's too late.
I'm disappointed in you.
I thought you were
more sensible than Yvan.
Will you tell my Mom?
I don't need your Mom.
This is between you and me.
Tell her if you like. I don't care.
No.
I want you to tell her.
That's enough, Marcel.
Eat up.
Let's hear no more about it.
What are you doing?
I want my mother to know.
Sit down.
It'll go away.
Can't you sleep?
I just wanted some water.
Be quick, then.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Marcel.
What's wrong?
Tell me.
Leo's going to die.
Stop it, you mustn't say that.
It has to be said. He has AlDS.
He's going to die.
Who told you that?
I bet my mother told you.
She didn't tell me.
Everyone knows.
She will tell you.
Some things are hard to say.
Don't say Leo's going to die.
People don't just die.
It's a serious illness
but there are drugs now.
Come on.
Come here.
My brother isn't gay.
That isn't important.
Is he gay?
Well? Are you?
Have you got a girlfriend?
You won't say?
You think it's none of my business?
Well, Leo's private life
is none of yours.
Anyway, I know he's gay.
You're so nosy!
Can you keep a secret?
Not even Yvan knows this.
We're in the same boat.
Your brother is sick,
so is my mother.
She's sick?
But she's older, so it's different.
It's more common.
You wouldn't be falling asleep...
I think so.
Aren't you sleepy?
Take me up...
Let's go.
Don't I have to sign anything?
I signed it. I'm over 18.
I wanted to talk to a doctor.
What did they say?
They said I've got AlDS.
Do you need details?
Yes, I want some details.
Primary infection.
I'm on a four-way treatment.
It adds up to more than
15 pills a day.
Will that do? Or do you want
the names of the drugs?
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Can we go now?
I'm going away for a while.
Where to?
Don't ask.
I have to see someone.
And I need to think.
I'll take a few days off
and take you, if you like.
That's nice of you, but no.
You can't go away on your own.
Let's go.
I want to get home.
Are you OK?
Yeah, I won.
No. First to get a kiss off Mom.
- Kiss me!
I won't!
It's too late now.
- Have you got your toothbrush?
- Give me a break!
Where are you going?
Don't worry.
I'll call you.
We'll be back in a few days.
It's not like I'm going to camp!
Is that you, dear?
I'm here, Mom.
When am I ever not here?
Careful, it's hot.
I don't want any.
Oh, stop it.
So who's this guy?
A friend.
It doesn't concern you.
Then why bring me along?
It's nice to be together.
I'm glad you're here.
Tell me who it is.
It doesn't matter.
We're just going to say hello.
We're on holiday.
You're so full of it!
Anyway, I didn't want
any hot chocolate.
Did you bring any tapes?
We can't sing all the way there.
We can?
I warn you, you won't know
the songs I know.
Marcel sends his love.
If you're going to sulk
we'll go straight back to Brittany.
I thought you liked Paris.
So why did you want to come?
Driving for 5 hours
in total silence is no fun.
Until I'm told the truth,
my lips are sealed.
What truth? It's just a pal.
Stop going on about it.
You're ill.
Who told you that?
Don't cry.
There's no point in being sad.
I'm ill, that's all.
Let's change the subject.
I'm sick, but I'm still here.
I don't want you to be ill.
I know.
Me neither.
I'm doing my best.
Why didn't you tell me?
You're too young.
All right...
I'm...
I'm really ill...
And I'm really gay.
Great, huh?
- lsn't the Eiffel Tower great?
- That's not the Eiffel Tower!
Don't cry.
I'm not crying,
you're suffocating me!
Let's go get a crepe...
Sure, the Breton cause
has attacked targets
but only ever property,
rarely are there any victims.
It has happened, though.
There are always accidents.
Would you carry out an attack?
Yes.
But I've never infiltrated
any groups.
It's stupid.
You're right. I have to infiltrate.
Finisterian - always.
Breton - maybe. French - never!
Why didn't you tell me before?
I don't know.
We were afraid it'd upset you.
We wanted you to be happy.
I'm going to be unhappy?
I hope not.
You're not going to be unhappy.
Are you unhappy?
I love you.
Fuck you!
Is it ready?
So what's the name of this guy?
Aymeric.
Lousy name.
It's raining buckets
on the genius of Iiberty
Of the PIace de Ia Bastille
We walk beneath a grey sky
Soothed by thousands of needles...
Excuse us.
- Which room is it again?
- 1 01.
"Active ingredients... "
"Excipients... "
"Microcrystalline cellulose... "
"Sodium starch glycolate... "
"Magnesium stearate... "
"Methyl hydroxypropyl cellulose... "
"Titanium dioxide... "
What are you doi ng?
Shall we get ready?
I ' ll take you out.
- You need them.
- I need to be "not sick"'.
OK? Not sick.
But the drugs work.
Don't lecture me. Help me.
Spit them out!
Are you nuts?
I hate you!
Go ahead and die. I hate you.
Come here.
OK?
Yeah.
Let's go.
In a moment.
Stay there, and don't mess around.
What can I get you?
Actually I'm looking for Aymeric.
He'll be back after classes
this afternoon.
Thanks. Goodbye.
He's not here?
I'll read it out loud
but you mustn't laugh.
"Every evening I recite your words.
"For me,
repeating the words you said
"feels like rubbing stones
in your pocket.
"Your words have become secrets,
"Rabbits' feet. Good-luck charms.
"You bring me good luck.
"Not only do I recite your words.
"l know your body by heart too.
"Leo's little body.
"Your little eyes,
your little mouth,
"your little...
"and your knees."
"l never expected to fall in love
with someone's knees."
Aymeric sounds a bit stupid.
Speak for yourself.
- Are your knees nice?
- Not really.
Let's see them!
Cut it out!
Let's see!
They're nothing special.
Nice, huh?
- What's special about them?
- Nothing.
And the other?
Same.
Let's compare them.
This one's redder.
I was expecting better.
No, it's fine.
Mine are nice.
Yours have a funny bone.
It's weird.
Ready?
Are you?
Go on, do my hair.
Do I look good?
Like a prince!
Go and play.
What are you doing here?
I dropped by to say hello.
Hello.
So what brings you to Paris?
Like I said, I came to say hello.
What will you have?
Martini.
And a Coke.
For my brother.
The kid over there?
Marcel.
Can we talk?
- It's a bad time.
- Just for 5 minutes.
Are you with anyone?
Not now, Leo.
Then you are.
Why?
Should I have waited for you?
Well, yeah.
We've been through that.
Something's happened.
I don't want to know. Don't bug me.
It's no concern of mine.
I know.
But I needed to talk to someone.
Talk about what?
Can't you take a 5-minute break?
What are you after?
You haven't called for a year.
You don't answer my letters.
You left me, remember?
You turn up
and expect me to drop everything.
I'm not available.
It's over between us.
I love you.
You'd better leave.
We're leaving.
Telephone.
Anything else to drink?
Not if you want something cold.
- No alcohol?
- It's against the rules.
"Against the rules"?
So there may be some around?
We'll have to go through there.
That way?
- Wait...
- No.
You're in a hurry.
What are you doing?
Sorry.
What's wrong?
I'd better go.
No, stay.
Sorry, I'm going.
You're hard to figure out.
Something wrong?
No, it's me.
Are you OK?
- Let's have a drink.
- I can't.
Come on, don't just leave.
Have a drink with me.
Have a drink with me...
Time to get up.
We're off.
Where to?
You're taking the train home.
Without you?
I've got things to do.
Come on, we're late.
Not unless you come.
You have no say in the matter!
Get dressed and get up!
Hurry, or you'll miss it.
It's a smoking car.
Got your ciggies?
Marcel... wait!
Goodbye, then.
- Shall I get on?
- I can manage without your help.
Do I get a kiss?
Give me a kiss.
I'm counting on you.
Shake things up a bit at home.
Make them get on with it.
Don't let it get them down!
Can you spare a ciggie?
It's my first ever.
You'll always remember me.
Yeah.
How about this?
I can't do it!
Are you buying?
No, it's OK.
You're mad, you've got two stations.
OK, Marcel?
I get 20,000.
20,000!
Just going to the bog.