(train running)
(train horn blowing)
Maria Enders will not be doing Jakarta.
- Or Lima. No, no.
-(phone: man speaking, inaudible)
Yes, it's okay on the Annie Leibovitz shoot,
but just for that one day.
And in New York, like we agreed.
Yes, I know it'll be tight.
I'm sorry about that.
Hey, you're - you're gonna have to excuse me.
I have to jump on another call.
Get back to me by tomorrow.
All right? Okay.
- MAN." Yes?
- Hello?
Yes, this is Valentine, Maria pers -
(chuckles) Maria Enders' personal assistant.
Yeah, we received the date of the hearing,
but she will not be in Paris that day.
We've told the lawyer two times.
(phone: man speaking, inaudible)
She's the one who filed for divorce.
Why would she be holding things up?
That's - That's ridiculous.
Okay, well, we're gonna -
Hel - Hello?
I'm sorry, we're on a -
(ringing)
- Hello?
-(phone: man speaking, inaudible)
I'm sorry. I can barely -
W-We're just - We're -
We're on a train and I'm not sure if I -
Fuck!
(phone ringing)
Hello?
(sighs) No, I still can't - I'm -
We're in the Alps. There's a ton
of mountains and tunnels and I -
Yeah.
Did you read this article about Google
and users' private information?
It's disgraceful.
They're too powerful. Thanks.
So, I have no service in here because of
all the tunnels, but I did reach Gwen.
She said that she's gonna take
the X-Men thing off of IMDb.
I did one. That was enough.
No way am I playing Nemesis again.
Well, they have to do it now because
everyone's blogging about it already.
Yeah. I'm sick of acting hanging
from wires in front of green screens.
I've outgrown it.
Fans are gonna be devastated.
Oh, did you speak to, um -
What's his name?
- Um... Urs. Urs Kobler?
- Yeah, I did.
Is the agenda set for tonight?
Yeah, you're all set.
You have just the three interviews.
And then it's the presentation of the award
and the official dinner.
He's gonna meet us at the train station
in Zurich to take us to the Dolder -
Dolder. (chuckles)
Th-That's where you wanted to stay, right?
- I've written a first draft. Want to hear it?
- Sure.
“I'm very honored
that Wilhelm Melchior asked me
to accept the prize
you're awarding him tonight.
As you all know, he decided a long time ago
to stay away from all public events.
Not because he's shy or proud.
He's a modest and generous man.
But he insists on protecting
the peace and quiet he needs to write.
I wish that I could promise you all
that I myself will place this prize in his hands.
(chuckles)
But Wilhelm has forbidden me to do so.
He asked me to join him tomorrow
in Sils Maria,
where he lives for part of the year,
but on one condition -
that I come empty-handed.
(sighs) If I'm here tonight,
it's because I owe everything to him.
He chose an unknown 18-year-old actress
for the lead in the play you all know,
Maloja Snake,
and then for the film.
That unknown actress
who played Sigrid was me.
In two months of shooting
he gave me everything I needed to bui -
build a career on - my career.”
Up to here it's fine.
And then it's all downhill.
Just fragments.
- You want me to finish it for you?
- No, I'm the one who has to pay tribute to him.
I have to find my own words.
If I'm stuck, I'll ask you. Okay?
Mappy says it's gonna take two and a half
hours to get to Sils Maria from Zurich.
We have a driver.
Um, also, I texted Wilhelm's wife.
She hasn't got back to me yet.
- That's not like Rosa.
-.I'.I' (phone: ringtone)
You sure I gave you
the - the right number?
- N (ringtone continues)
- (sighs) I have to take this.
(in French)
Good evening, counselor.
(in French) As I told your client,
my future ex-husband,
I can't make the arbitration hearing
for the simple reason
that I'll be abroad.
Furthermore, I know he wants
my half of the apartment.
I made a fair offer.
(in French) Check the price of real estate
in the 7th arrondissement.
I'm accommodating, but not dumb.
I know I'm on the losing end.
I really need to talk to you.
- (phone ringing)
- You know the law better than me, don't you?
I am entitled to force a sale.
I know. I heard.
Just a second ago.
Um, I know, I know.
I haven't told her yet, but, um -
As soon as I can, okay?
I got it. Yeah, yeah.
(in French) If he wants to sell
and split the money, fine with me.
We'll put it up for sale
and you'll see the market price.
Yeah - Hmm?
Yeah, there's really nothing
on the net yet.
Just this press release and, um...
comments.
What kind of comments?
You don't want to know. They're stupid.
It just says, you know -
“Zorglub228:
I thought he died a while ago.
Besides, he hasn't written
anything of interest in 20 years.”
“Wiseguy666:
The media pays too much attention to writers.
People die all over the world
and no one ever mentions them.”
Zohrarose didn't know
who this guy was
but offers her condolences to the family.
So I spoke to Urs Kobler
and we canceled the press, obviously.
I'm gonna work it out
when we get in tonight.
L-it's gonna be really... different.
It'll be gloomy.
Official and stiff.
Everything Wilhelm hated.
Yeah, and people are going to be sad.
What do you expect? He's...
He's dead.
If I wanted to be true to him,
I'd turn around and go home.
You'll find the words once you're there.
I think they'll come naturally.
I think... You know...
Who could do him justice
better than you? A stranger?
You love him. it's different.
I love him.
I know so little about him.
♪♪ (ringtone)
You kn - You know what I mean.
If you want to be true to him,
you have to be there.
Hello.
(phone: woman, inaudible)
Um, sure.
Yeah, we're on a train, so we might lose you,
but I'll - I'll ask her.
Okay.
- It's France Inter.
- (sighs) Oh, God.
You kind of have to. I'm sorry.
Oui.
(in French)
This is Maria Enders.
I know. Thank you.
♪♪ (ringtone)
N (continues, stops)
(in French)
A sequel to Maloja Snake?
Yes, he did mention it to me.
He wanted me to play Sigrid
20 years later.
But I have no idea
what he had in mind.
It was very vague.
He must have given up on it.
Do I regret it?
Of course I regret it.
- Rosa just called.
- I'll call her right back.
She's actually not gonna be
available till tonight.
She's really busy.
She still has to go to the morgue.
Did you find out anything?
Yeah, um...
Wilhelm was home in Sils Maria.
Rosa went for a check-up in Basel.
She thinks that he was
home all day writing as usual,
went for a late afternoon walk.
But she called to check on him
and couldn't get through,
so she got worried
and sent the neighbors over.
Doors were locked,
the lights were out, he wasn't home.
When did they find him?
Late afternoon,
like, the middle of nowhere.
They think it was a heart attack.
(man speaking German)
-(radio beeps)
-(radio: man responds in German)
(men conversing in German)
MAN: it's so exciting having you here.
Nice.
The cockroaches
must have taken a later train.
(in German)
Join us at the hotel.
WOMAN (in German):
See you there.
We are...
in a - in a loss for words.
I have to say, my first reaction
was to head right back.
I understand.
We were wondering as well,
should we move forward
or cancel everything?
You know, here in Switzerland,
we are not big
on public displays of anything.
Especially grief.
This should have been a celebration.
And now it will be
a posthumous homage.
It's gonna generate
the kind of press that we do not want.
URS:
We'll try to keep them on distance.
Paparazzi are going to be all over her.
You realize that, right?
I have to think it over.
Everything's hitting me at once,
so I... I don't know.
Of course.
That's why we invited Henryk Wald.
Henryk Wald?
Yes.
-(Maria exhales)
- He's devastated as well.
But he agreed to hop on a plane
to be with us tonight.
If you'd prefer not to accept the prize,
Henryk can do it.
It's up to you.
He's associated with Wilhelm's theater.
Most of the plays were written for him.
- You don't appreciate him?
- We did two films together.
No, we didn't get along very well.
But I'm glad he's here.
He and Wilhelm were very close,
and Rosa likes him a lot.
He's a...
a great actor.
Yeah.
One last question.
Oh, I forgot to tell you this thing.
Sorry.
- Chanel.
The press attache from Chanel is waiting for you
at the hotel to try on your gown.
-(sighs)
- You don't have to.
No, you do not have to.
Can we turn this off?
- And no fruit. Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, all good. Thank you.
So, what do you think?
Would she stay?
Yeah, she'll - she'll stay.
Because if not,
I have to change the tickets.
I know. She'll stay. Trust me.
Thank you.
MARIA: I can't deal with this.
It's impossible.
I'll never find the right words.
N (phone chimes)
His body isn't even cold yet,
and everybody wants a piece of him,
starting with Henryk Wald, of course.
Of course he'd be happy
to accept the prize.
If only I could just not see him.
Henryk?
Why are you still so upset with him?
I have no reason
to have stopped being upset with him.
- So he was in love with you or something.
- Not at all.
He was just furious
I didn't give in to him.
He's perverse, violent.
He hits women.
He likes to humiliate them.
(chuckles)
Look it up on the Internet.
I thought we despised the Internet.
- Caroline?
- Yes.
Hey. Valentine.
- Hello. Hi.
- Hi.
Thanks for agreeing to this.
I know it must be really difficult for you.
-(shutter clicking)
-(Caroline clears throat)
-(speaks German)
- Uh, this is Berndt.
- Oh. Hi.
- Hi.
- Berndt. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
You know those really trashy photos
I showed you of Lindsay Lohan?
This guy's responsible.
But I'll try to be more elegant today.
(man speaking German)
Mmm.
(German)
it's Rosa.
Am I bothering you?
I just wanted t-to tell you -
to thank you.
It's good that you're there.
It's good...
that you're accepting the prize.
It's what Wilhelm wanted.
(laughing)
Henryk? No.
You know what he thought of Henryk.
The less he understands, the better he is,
and when he understands nothing he's excellent.
(sighs) I would like to have
given you a hug, but...
but I'm leaving.
I can't stand being alone at Sils.
It's too difficult.
But there's something I want you,
and only you...
(sobs)
to know.
(chattering, laughing, faint)
Mmm.
(laughing, chattering continue)
So he knew about the illness
for a long time?
Did the autopsy say
what he swallowed?
Oh, I see.
He left nothing to chance.
- Beautiful.
-(shutter clicking)
Turn your body a bit sideways, please.
Yeah. And chin up
a little bit, please. Thank you.
Great. Yeah.
- Maria?
- Hmm?
- Sorry. it's, uh, your future ex.
- And again. All right?
- Hold on a second.
- Right, right.
Hello? Allô"?
(in French) Spare me the gloom.
I'm not the one who died.
I know Wilhelm died.
I happen to be in Zurich.
PHOTOGRAPHERS (shouting):
Maria! Maria!
-(man shouts in French)
- Maria!
The press is all here.
I don't know how
we'll squeeze them all in.
MAN: One thing you should know -
we met very early, at the university.
We were both studying
literature and theology.
And I had the privilege of acting
in all of his plays, here and abroad.
He had become a recluse -
mysterious, inaccessible.
Wilhelm was the simplest man
in the world.
He liked to ski in the winter
and go hiking in the summer.
Those are the fondest memories
I have of him.
His later work depicts
a bleak, destructive vision.
I acted in those plays.
Mmm, it's true.
At times I found them scary.
A sea of gray hair.
Completely.
So, first I'll say a few words.
(chuckling)
I hope I am up to the task.
And then I'll introduce Henryk.
Once he has finished,
he asks you to join him on stage.
You'll introduce the film.
That's it.
I saw Wilhelm two weeks ago.
We went hunting.
He was his usual self.
There and not there.
He mentioned the prize,
said he wouldn't be attending.
I told him he'd miss
an opportunity to see you.
I was on Long Island six months ago.
I spent a week with him and Rosa.
- I know.
- I don't give a fuck that you know.
(door opens)
Henryk, you are almost on.
-(speaks German)
- Excuse me.
(Urs speaking German)
We had an affair when we
were shooting Maloja Snake.
- Yeah, I couldn't tell.
- I was 18, kind of dumb.
And he really took advantage.
After the shoot,
I never heard from him.
- It destroyed me.
- I'm sure you've run into him since.
We made another film together
afterwards.
- Which one?
- Oh, you don't want to know.
Tolstoy adaptation.
German producers.
(laughs) Who cares, huh?
Well, 10 years later, I was famous.
Then he was interested.
And he kept harassing me,
calling me in the middle of the night.
But I didn't give in, and that he hated.
And he made me pay for it
every single day of the shooting.
He was really amazing in that one movie -
Um, what is it called?
He plays a Soviet defector
with, like, missile codes and shit.
- Um, do you know?
- No, I don't know.
Never heard of it.
He's great in it.
So intense, especially
in the more physical scenes.
That stare. He is like...
- I like him.
- Yeah, I kind of got it.
I mean, as an actor
I really like him. I -
(Speaking German)
(in German) Unfortunately,
he must leave tomorrow morning.
Henryk Wald!
(m Germany.
I stood on this stage four years ago
in the play The Reichstag is Burning
by Wilhelm Melchior.
Little did I know
it would be Wilhelm's last play.
He was sitting there in the third row,
staring at me.
My acting was never so lousy.
Maria, you're on in five minutes.
(audience applauding)
HENRYK (in German):
Wilhelm Melchior will be with us always...
in his plays.
(whispering)
Maria.
I will have the privilege of performing them
here, in London, everywhere.
So I say not “Farewell,” but...
“See you, Wilhelm.”
(audience applauding)
URS (in German): Thank you, Henryk,
for that wonderful tribute.
Now please welcome
an old friend of Wilhelm's.
A warm round of applause for...
Maria Enders!
(audience applauding, cheering)
(whistles)
Thank you.
Go get 'em, tiger.
MARIA:
Thank you very much.
- Hi.
- Good evening. Welcome.
I'm honored to welcome you here.
I wish it had been
under happier circumstances.
It's, um -
it's great to celebrate his work.
Especially today.
I was eager that the city of Zurich
pay tribute to him.
He was very grateful to you.
He told me so.
Hey. She'll just be two seconds.
I'm sure she's gonna be thrilled
to be relieved from officialdom.
- You know that his last play was set in Zurich.
- Oh, yes.
He paints a rather dire portrait
of our political class.
That's an understatement.
- You should know. Your character was evil.
-(chuckles)
Klaus Diesterweg is here to see you.
Excuse me. Sorry.
I already told him no.
- He's here just to see you.
- The project doesn't interest me. Okay?
He's a great director. Just hear him out.
You don't have to do it.
- He's probably the best of his generation.
- I know. We saw the same productions.
If you'd like to go on chatting with the mayor
and Henryk, you can be my guest.
- No, thank you.
-(chuckles)
Okay.
Do you mind if I cut out for a bit?
I'm just gonna meet Berndt.
Berndt?
- The photographer.
-(whistles)
We're just going to find somewhere
a bit livelier. This place is a dead zone.
Oh. No problem.
I don't plan to hang around.
Enjoy.
- Thank you for finding time for me.
-It's a pleasure to meet you.
- I hope you don't find me too insistent.
- Not at all.
I've seen quite a few of your productions.
I enjoy them, and...
I know we'll find an opportunity
to work together in the future.
Give me one more chance.
Klaus.
I played Sigrid in Maloja Snake
when I was 18.
For me it was more than a role.
In some way, I am still Sigrid.
That's my point.
If Sigrid seduces Helena -
And it has nothing to do with being a lesbian,
by the way. I've always been straight.
That's not at all what I meant.
Sigrid is free, beyond everything.
And most of all,
she's disruptive, unpredictable.
I know.
And right or wrong, I've always
identified with that freedom.
It's a way of, uh...
protecting myself.
Do you smoke?
Uh, no, no. I - I try not to.
And for you,
Helena embodies the opposite?
Helena is 40.
She's runs a company.
She falls head over heels in love
with a girl who doesn't love her
and leads her to suicide.
Yes. She's completely the opposite.
But what is it that attracts Helena
to Sigrid, if they are so different?
It's obvious. Her youth.
Well, if you're telling me that I'm Helena's
age now, yeah, you're right, it's true.
But that doesn't mean I can play her.
The way I see Helena is totally different.
Despite her bourgeois life,
despite her responsibilities,
she's not the epitome of order
and not at all the opposite of Sigrid.
Well, she is married, with children,
her social life is a huge success,
and she sacrifices it all.
Yeah, she's destructive.
Sigrid revives
this hidden violence in Helena.
Was it hidden or tamed?
Time's gone by
and she can't accept it.
Me neither, I guess.
There's no antagonism.
It's the attraction of two women
with the same wound.
Sigrid and Helena
are one and the same person.
One and the same person.
That's what the play is about.
And because you were Sigrid,
only you can be Helena now.
Hmm. How can you be so sure?
You know as well as I do
that Wilhelm Melchior
had been working
on a sequel for years.
Yes, but it was about Sigrid
at 40 years old.
No, it was about Sigrid
20 years later became Helena.
(sighs)
So who's to play Sigrid?
Jo-Ann Ellis.
She did a superhero movie
that just opened in the States.
- And besides that?
- Not much.
She's 19. She's a lot more interesting
than her interviews and profiles.
She has a theatrical background.
She doesn't want to be
swallowed up by Hollywood.
She admires you, and she's willing
to pull out of her other commitments.
Well, I've listened carefully.
But to be honest,
um, the role scares me.
Helena scares me.
I'm in the middle of a divorce.
I feel alone and vulnerable.
Probably too vulnerable to do this.
If you refuse, I'll understand, but...
it will be a missed opportunity.
Especially for Wilhelm.
-(chuckles)
I should get going.
Excuse me,
but I won't be staying for dinner.
Good evening, Maria.
Klaus.
I have another reason.
Susan Rosenberg.
She played Helena with me.
I remember Susan Rosenberg.
She died in a car accident a year after.
It's a superstition. I've always associated
her death with Helena's suicide.
She was a lousy actress who didn't
understand a thing about the role.
But her conventional style of acting
highlighted the modernity
of your performance.
You should be grateful to her.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
Oh, is there a way of changing this?
- Can you put him in another place?
- I'm - I'm sorry. Oh, he's coming.
(chattering)
You were with Klaus Diesterweg.
Are you going to accept his offer?
- What offer?
- You know.
He's a very good director.
If he'd offered me a role,
I'd accept it on the spot.
So that means, um, I should accept it?
- God, no!
-(laughing)
This much-talked-about sequel of his -
Remember, he never finished it.
Sorry to be brutal,
but I'm a simple man
and the play tells a simple story.
An older woman falls in love
with a scheming girl
that has her
wrapped around her little finger.
The girl takes advantage of her,
squeezes everything she can
out of her, then dumps her.
Helena's love for Sigrid
makes her stupid
and blind to what everybody
in the audience can see right away.
But then, that's really
all she's ever wanted.
She's fascinated by her own downfall.
It's as clear as day.
That's why the play was such a hit
and is still being performed today.
Why stage it
if you want to tell another story?
I think your reading is simplistic.
I know Sigrid,
and believe me,
she's more interesting than that.
Yes, she takes advantage of Helena.
Yes, she fascinates her and she knows it.
You can decide not to look any further,
but I had to because I played her.
You're just talking about
what's on the surface.
The play is about
what attracts them to each other.
It's harder to see,
and it's more profound and truer.
The impossibility of their relationship
is as cruel for Sigrid.
(scoffs)
“Cruel for Sigrid.”
- I'm sure she'll get over it.
- What do you know?
Time. Youth.
She has her life ahead of her.
Well, Helena is young too. She's not old.
She has her life ahead of her too.
But she decides to give it all up.
Helena is not used to
being turned down.
She discovers her own frailty
and she can't accept it.
We'll drop Mr. Wald off first, please.
Grand Hotel du Lac, please.
So Klaus has persuaded you.
You're going to play Helena.
(laughs)
I didn't say that.
But I'm considering it.
Yes.
Are you sure you don't want
to have a last drink?
(laughing)
I'm already drunk, darling.
Henryk!
- Yes?
- Hold on.
(engine starts)
ready for recovery,
recently appointed governor
Mark Carney
promised to keep interest rates low
as long as unemployment remains high.
(TV: anchor continues)
(TV: man talking, faint)
♪♪ (classical)
Wow.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I just found the main road again.
I'm sorry. I must have set the GPS wrong.
Like an hour or so, probably.
I had a... dream, um -
We were already rehearsing and...
past and the present
were blending together.
- I'm confused.
- No kidding.
I shouldn't have said yes to Klaus.
But Wilhelm's death, mourning -
I couldn't refuse.
He is a sick director.
Jo-Ann's a superstar.
It pays well.
I don't need the money.
Okay.
Hi.
ROSA:
Stay as long as you want.
I like the fact
that you are working on the part here,
where it was written.
You promised - no ghosts.
There - There aren't any.
(laughs)
I was joking.
No. It was half-joking.
(both laughing)
ROSA:
This is what I wanted to show you.
This is where Wilhelm killed himself.
But that - that stays
between you and me.
Is that the Maloja Pass over there?
Yeah.
- The snake, right?
- The snake.
Why a snake?
In the play, it's, uh - it's ambiguous.
The Maloja snake.
It's a cloud formation.
Fairly rare.
Partially unexplained.
It's a sign of bad weather.
And the clouds, they are coming
from the Italian lakes,
over the pass
and winding through the valley
like a serpent.
Therefore, it's a snake.
They call it a snake.
(translated from German)
Cloud Phenomena of Maloja.
Its harbingers.
(translated from German)
The clouds wind up the Maloja Pass.
The so-called Maloja snake.
ROSA:
Wilhelm was fascinated by this film.
He used to marvel at the fact
that the true nature of the landscape
revealed itself in these images.
Yes, um,
but the black-and-white
creates a distance.
It sets the passing of time.
ROSA:
it's almost a century old.
Actually it comes from very far away.
That's the beauty of it.
-(laughs) Thank you so much.
- Lovely to meet you. Thank you.
Thank you.
(Rosa sighs)
I won't promise
to come and see you in London.
I hope you change your mind.
All right?
(laughs)
Theater is only theater.
Oh, Maria.
It belongs to Wilhelm.
Keep it.
(engine starts)
You were 18 years old.
You weren't a child.
There had to have been
some kind of attraction or...
Wilhelm was far from a saint, right?
-(laughs)
- Maybe.
Mmm.
He did choose me,
so he must have felt something, but...
it remained unspoken.
- So you admit -
- And it's not very important.
-(both laughing)
-it's not very important.
Mmm.
If that's not important,
what the fuck is important?
All that matters is what's in the movie.
So you admit there was attraction.
Stop.
Why? Was it mutual?
- Yes.
-(both laugh)
No! I don't know. I don't know.
You don't understand.
Yes, I was attracted to Wilhelm,
but it's normal.
I was fine with just feeling attracted
and with the intimacy.
So there was intimacy too.
(laughing)
Stop picking apart every word I say.
Anything more would have
endangered our relationship.
I was, uh -
My intuition told me that it was
far more valuable than desire.
L-I feel you.
- You were in love with him.
- Of course I wasn't.
Stop oversimplifying.
It's too easy.
It was less than that.
And it was better.
I don't know anymore. Maybe I only
remember what suits me to remember.
Yeah. I think so.
-'Cause the story changes every time.
- Bitch.
(laughs)
Do you want to christen
a shopping mall in Nanking?
No.
How about a series of commercials
for eyeglasses?
- No.
-It's only in Latin America.
- No!
- All right.
Um, there's a Spanish horror flick.
It's pretty gory.
You'd be playing a mother superior.
There are werewolves involved,
for whatever reason.
No.
An interview with an Italian magazine
targeting active women.
“Seduction After 40.”
No!
(laughs)
But it's the cover.
-(laughing) No!
- Okay.
- Mario Testino is shooting it.
- I don't care.
Jo-Ann Ellis' movie
is opening up in Europe.
She wants to meet you.
- When?
- Next week.
Where?
Wherever you want.
She'll come here if you'd like.
- Definitely not here.
- Maybe I'll tell her to book the Waldhaus.
When is her movie opening?
It opened last week.
Have you read a paper lately?
- I'm sorry. You want one?
-(mutters)
it's playing in St. Moritz,
if you want to see it.
I'd rather wait until rehearsals start
and... keep the image of Sigrid
as myself at 18.
I know, I know.
It's a little disturbing.
But I find it more interesting.
Well, I didn't know you at 18,
but I'm almost positive
Jo-Ann's a lot worse.
How can you be so sure?
- Have you googled her?
- Well, I just looked at the pictures.
Well, you should dig a little deeper.
Won't take you long
to find all the naked photos,
the latest updates on her exploits.
Such as?
Her breakup.
With Andrew Beltram?
Any idea who that is?
Not at all.
What world do you live in?
He's, like - He's the biggest star.
Says who?
- Preteens.
- Oh.
Hey, there are a shit-ton of them,
so be careful.
Um, he broke up with her because
she wouldn't stop getting wasted
and cheating on him in public.
So she went to his house with a gun,
and he went bat-shit.
Threw her out.
But, like, violently threw her out.
Not exactly the way Klaus described her.
The neighbors had to subdue her
'cause she was, like, shooting up the place.
Apparently it wasn't easy.
She went to rehab to get out of doing time.
She's better now.
According to her press releases.
Well, yeah.
And, uh, the classical training,
the theater background,
is that all bullshit?
No. No, that's all true.
She took off
and just started really fucking up.
Um, I think she probably got jealous
of, like, Hollywood trash.
TMZ deemed her the A-list actress
that dreamt of making it to the Z-list.
You could have told me sooner.
You despise Internet gossip.
This is not gossip.
It's information.
It's celebrity news. it's fun.
- I thought you liked her a lot.
- I do.
I love her. She's not completely antiseptic
like the rest of Hollywood.
Well, you just said
she was a self-destructive crazy girl.
- I didn't say that.
- Sorry. I must have misunderstood then.
Where are my fucking cigarettes?
They're right in front of you.
Where?
- Hello!
- Ah!
She's brave enough to be herself.
At her age,
I think that's pretty fucking cool.
I don't see what's so cool
about fucking around,
getting wasted out of your mind and almost
killing a boyfriend that's sick of you.
I think she's got a bright future.
In fact, I think she's probably
my favorite actress.
Oh.
You mean more than me? Hmm?
No, I - I didn't mean that.
Hmm?
I'm more... what?
Conventional?
Boring.
(scoffs)
And I can't reach her intensity. No.
(exhales)
I didn't say that.
Of course not.
VALENTINE:
Good night.
Hey!
Motherfucker!
Hey! Stop fucking following me, all right?
I'll fucking kill you!
I'll fucking kill you.
So, let me ask you
a tough question.
You were fired from
the Forbidden Planet remake.
- I don't know about that.
-(audience laughing)
You were supposed to play
the old Anne Francis role, Altaira.
- I don't know. Maybe.
-(laughing continues)
And after your DUI arrest,
your studio canceled the contract.
You know, even if that were true,
that would have cost them
an arm and a leg.
- (audience laughing, applauding)
- $0 just say it were true.
Which I'm not saying it is.
But, hypothetically speaking, I wouldn't
be able to even talk about it right now
because I would've signed
a confidentiality agreement with the studio.
Sure.
$0 let is imagine
you were arrested for a DUI
and you had insulted the police officer.
No. No, no. That's not hypothetical.
That's a verified fact.
I did get arrested on a DUI,
and I did assault police officers.
So it's the studio's reaction
that's hypothetical.
Exactly.
And their hypothetical
bat-shit crazy response
would have cost them
a hypothetical seven-figure sum,
which I guess I wouldn't
be able to talk about right now, right?
(chuckles) So, will you be appearing
on the remake for Forbidden Planet?
Uh...
- I'd rather die...
-(audience laughing)
very, very slowly
of, probably, food poisoning.
-(people shouting)
-(sirens wailing)
(no audible dialogue)
♪♪ (light jazz, flute) ♪♪
REPORTER: Rumor has it
that we 'll see you on stage.
Yeah, um, I'm gonna -
I'm gonna do a play
called Maloja Snake,
uh, with Maria Enders.
Um, she's gonna play the older woman,
and I will play the one
who drives her to suicide.
-(laughing)
- JO-ANN: I mean, that's kinda rad, fight?
Where in London will you play it?
They told me the name of it.
- This theater -
-(reporters chuckling)
it's still being negotiated.
- REPORTER: Who's directing?
- Klaus.
- Klaus who?
- Klaus Klaus.
Like, you know, the Klaus.
- (reporters laughing)
- Klaus Klaus?
- Klaus Klaus!
- Yeah. Fucking Klaus.
You should do your job and look him up.
You're a fucking reporter, for God's sake.
- Well, you apparently don't know him.
- REPORTER #2: Santa Klaus?
(reporters laughing)
REPORTER #3:
Klaus Kinski?
- REPORTER #4: Klaus Barbie.
-(laughing continues)
- Oh.
-(audio stops)
(exhales)
(footsteps)
(footsteps continue)
Okay. This is the armchair.
Um...
office door.
Desk.
Okay, go ahead.
Come in.
Sigrid, I asked you here because
your internship is almost over,
and I wanted to congratulate you
personally.
Have a seat.
No, there.
The - The armchair.
(clears throat)
Everyone in my office
sings your praises.
Including the nastiest ones.
The ones who think that I shouldn't have
taken over the company after my father died,
that I'm running it into the ground.
The ones who consider me incompetent,
not because I'm a woman
but because they look at the figures,
and the figures
aren't what they should be.
I know it's true.
It keeps me up at night.
It's been eating away at me.
They've persuaded me,
and now I think they're right.
Why are you telling me this?
It's none of my business.
You want people to know?
You think if you arouse their pity,
they'll back off.
I've been around a lot less than you,
but in my experience it's quite the opposite.
Wouldn't you agree?
When they tell me about you,
how much they appreciate you,
they're using you to humiliate me.
Shit! I messed up. Fuck!
IFS - What?
- It's to remind -
-it's to remind me!
Oh! Sh-
(Crying)
I hate this fucking scene.
Oh, I have too many memories
of Susan Rosenberg
and the disgust she made me feel
while she was slipping into the skin of this...
defeated woman.
She got such obscene pleasure out of it
night after night.
Wh-Why “defeated”?
Defeated by - by... age,
by - by... her insecurities.
Letting this kid
lead her around by the nose.
Come on. That's not -
That's not all there is to it. There's -
I'll start over.
This poor woman is ready to kill herself
before the play even starts.
She's using Sigrid as a weapon,
that's all.
I'll start over.
(exhales)
Okay.
(sniffles)
When they tell me about you,
how much they appreciate you,
it's to remind me how happy they are
to grant you
what they never granted me.
They're using you to humiliate me.
It's not just your youth,
or your powers of seduction.
No, it's your aplomb,
your unshakable self-confidence.
- You don't know me.
- Nothing gets to you.
You radiate... self-confidence.
And you don't?
(scoffs)
I wear a mask.
It works with some people.
Others see right through it.
I can tell which is which right away.
If there's one thing I excel at,
that's reading people's behavior.
So how should I be reading yours?
How do you think?
I don't know. I'm reluctant to say it.
It's pretty clear.
Don't be reluctant.
Helena nervously crosses and uncrosses
her legs, reaches for a cigarette.
(giggles)
You talk about your insecurities.
Your vulnerabilities.
You open up to me,
and I'm not exactly sure why.
It's as if you're expecting something.
Can I be frank?
I don't think it's company figures
that are keeping you up at night.
- What's keeping me up then?
- Desire.
For me, I think.
I noticed it the second you hired me,
and I'm sorry, but I've had fun playing with it.
You've let me play with it.
“Fun.”
What a strange word.
Not what I was expecting.
Oh, this text is impossible.
Oh, my God!
So now the play is bad?
No. But everything is weighted
to make Sigrid look good.
(exhales)
I didn't read it like that.
I see her arrogance, her cruelty,
and Helena's humanity.
She's able to talk about her own pain.
It's moving.
I'll start over.
“Fun.”
What a strange word.
Not what I was expecting.
She's such a stupid cunt.
Oh.
And I didn't expect you
to talk about desire either.
Let me be frank now.
It makes me uncomfortable.
And it forces me
to see you differently.
And that gets under your skin.
Pause.
You can tell me.
Stands, lights a cigarette.
In fact, it's exactly
what you want to say, so say it.
Yes. it's true.
You get under my skin.
I wanted to ask you to stay on
and become my personal assistant.
(chuckles)
She doesn't accept.
- I mean, she does accept!
-(laughing)
Without hesitation, she accepts.
♪♪ (guitars: classical)
(Maria exhales)
Oh, I've been feeling sick all morning.
L feel dirty.
I don't like Helena, no matter
how much humanity you see in her.
- Want some?
- No, thanks.
Or maybe because of that humanity.
I don't know. I don't care.
I don't feel good in her skin. I don't know
why I have to inflict this on myself.
Then don't do it.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm not doing it.
(Valentine coughing)
I'd like to take the car tonight.
Berndt rented a house on Lake Como
with some friends.
That's pretty far.
I mean, it's... two hours by car.
If I left at 6:00,
I could probably be back by sunrise.
- Would you be okay alone?
- Yeah.
Yeah, just - just be careful
on the mountain roads at night.
Are you involved with him?
I mean, I-is this a thing now?
I like him.
Oh, you like him.
That's all we'll get.
(chuckles)
You're jealous.
Jealous?
I don't know. Of my time.
My thoughts.
- Maybe my affection.
- No.
I'm not jealous.
I'm thrilled
that you have a boyfriend.
There haven't been that many,
and when there is one,
you burn through him pretty fast.
-(Maria laughs)
- I'll tell you.
No, you won't.
And I never know if I should believe
what little you do tell me.
That's up to you.
- (squealing, laughing)
- Why the fuck are we doing this shit?
- (gasps) Fuck!
- (Maria continues laughing)
Can you pass me those?
I'm a little late.
(keys drop on floor)
- Sorry.
- See you.
(thunder rumbling)
(clattering)
(pen scratching paper)
We can do anything,
but you did sign a contract.
- Pulling out will cost yo u.
- You know, I've thought it over.
I worked on a scene. I can't.
I mean, I can, but... it's too hard.
I feel too much disdain for Helena.
I'm Sigrid. I want to stay Sigrid.
Sigrid is 20.
I don't care. I know I'm right.
It doesn't interest me anymore.
It spoils my memories.
It's not constructive.
They'll sue, and it'll go on
for months and months.
They can replace me.
It's too late. Klaus doesn't want
anyone else for Helena.
So I'm a hostage!
You 'll be appearing
in a prestigious production
that's been waiting for you for 20 years.
I'm asking you to get me out of this.
Great. But like I said, it won't be cheap.
Figure something out!
There's no use getting upset.
We'll take care of it.
But I'm giving you due diligence, okay?
♪♪ (radio: electronic rock)
MAN". ♪ Kowalski ♪
♪ >J' Vanishing point, Kowalski' ♪
♪ >J' Vanishing point, vanishing point' ♪
(retching)
♪ Like a butterfly on a pin ♪
♪ >J' Soul on ice, soul on ice' ♪
Fuck.
MAN". Hey, what's happening?
What's happening?
- What you do?
- Quite masterful.
♪♪ (fades)
Wait! You have to stay with us.
We're mutants, just like you.
But we all have doubts.
Doubts about our powers -
Are we worthy of them?
Do we have the right to use them?
After all, what is good...
and what is evil?
And who are we to decide?
Scarlet Witch and Dr. Pretorius both agree.
What you did was not treasonous.
Forgive yourself.
Don't judge your own actions so harshly.
(electricity crackles)
Don't you understand?
This is no mistake.
I have been double-crossing the Alliance
for a very long time now
and reporting directly to Sargon.
And you know why?
Because I am madly in love with him.
Do you remember
when he attacked our guild's outpost?
I tried to fight him then,
but I was alone and I failed.
You weren't there.
Neither was Dr. Pretorius,
and neither was Scarlet Witch.
He led me into a gravitational field
that neutralized my powers.
- He bolted me.
- We tried to find you.
I woke up alone...
a prisoner in his fortress.
And I know that he raped you.
Yes.
He didn't rape me.
I fell in love with him.
I refuse to believe this.
Sargon is not a mutant,
but he understands mutant desire.
I became his lover.
It's the only reason he set me free.
You are crazy. Sargon loves no one.
He used me and then he cast me aside.
But maybe if I obey him,
maybe if I follow his orders,
he might just take me back.
(gasps)
(man on film, indistinct)
(speaks French)
And place your bets, please.
(ball rolling)
The last bets, thank you.
No more bets.
Rien ne va plus.
Twenty-eight, black.
And five places here.
Place your bets, please.
Nine, red.
Well, I stayed because of you,
but I could feel my brain cells dying,
one by one.
Okay, but you don't find her amazing?
I think she's totally fascinating.
It's such a stupid character. Come on.
Because it takes place on a spaceship?
I know that if it was set on an assembly line
or like a farm or something,
you'd love it.
It's true. I have a hard time
taking bimbos in astronaut suits
mouthing off some generic
pop psychology seriously.
- Been there, done that.
-(sighs) I like it.
I know. I know you do. I'm sorry.
There's no less truth than
in a more supposedly serious film.
She goes deep into the darker side
of her character.
-(laughing loudly)
-it's daring. it's really daring.
In a - In a big movie like that,
it's fucking cool.
Well, she's got great presence,
but I don't see what's so daring about it.
Despite her superpowers...
(stifled laughing)
- Her superpowers.
- Yes, her superpowers.
- Her superpowers?
- Yes, her superpowers. So what?
It's a convention, but it's no dumber
than any other convention.
Despite her superpowers,
she's emotionally defenseless.
She's in love,
but she's not loved in return.
This impossible love for Sargon,
the Alliance's worst enemy,
leads her to betrayal and madness.
Fuckin' shit. Are you telling me
there's nothing there worth playing there?
I don't know. I don't know, Val.
I don't know.
Thank you.
She knows that it means her downfall,
but that is the ultimate truth
of her desire.
- WAITER: Cheers.
-It's fuckin' powerful.
Oh, my God.
I hate you sometimes so much.
You're making my head spin.
And Sargon?
You find him interesting too?
- Yeah, I do.
- Good.
No, Sargon sucks. it's -
Jesus Christ!
CROUPIER:
Vos jeux, mesdames, messieurs.
Last bets, thank you.
No more. No more bets.
Rien ne va plus.
All of it?
Ho!
Did you see that?
My magical door-opening powers?
I can open a door too.
Sure you can drive?
- I had the same drinks as you.
- That's my point.
(crashing)
(car alarm wailing)
(quietly)
Go, go' go!
So...
what you were saying earlier was that,
unlike Jo-Ann, I don't take
that kind of role seriously, hmm?
What? No.
I don't know what you're talking about.
That I have disdain for those characters
and their... cartoonish psychology,
but she doesn't.
- Mmm.
- Which makes her superior to me.
Uh-oh. Don't get jealous.
That's not an attractive quality.
She dives headfirst into
a character's ambiguities, but...
I don't.
That's why you admire what she does.
Yeah.
You know, I think that when you watch her
in a movie like the one we saw tonight,
there is... there is no distance there.
It's normal.
It's, uh... her culture. Right?
Yeah, agreed.
- What's wrong with my acting?
- Nothing.
What do I need to do
to make you admire me?
Do I think too much? Huh?
Am I too classical?
Not liberated like Jo-Ann?
You're here to talk to me,
so start talking.
Hmm?
I don't know. You...
You can't be as accomplished as you are
and as well-rounded as an actress
as you are
and still expect to hold on
to the privileges of youth.
It just doesn't work like that.
Oh!
So I'm allowed to not be old,
as long as I don't want to be young,
is that it?
Yeah. I don't know. I guess so.
Yes. Totally. Well put.
Fuck.
I think, maybe, good night.
(exhales)
Wait, wait! Wait.
Hey. Hey-
You - You didn't tell me
how it went with Berndt.
Yeah, well, you know, um, fuck Berndt.
(laughs)
I thought you wouldn't believe me anyway.
Try.
Maybe you'll manage to persuade me.
I'm... exhausted.
I don't know. I don't have the energy.
Okay. Good night.
Oh, I spoke to Jay.
He doesn't think
he can get me out of the contract.
Yeah, I figured.
Please knock when you enter my office.
You summoned me.
I didn't summon you.
I asked you to come.
What's the difference?
There's differences. When I summon you,
it's for professional reasons.
When I ask you to come,
it's for... personal reasons.
- So it's personal.
- Yes.
All the more reason not to knock.
Everyone knocks
before coming into my office.
I could have been in a meeting
or in a private call.
I'm surprised Josephine let you through.
I told Josephine it didn't concern her.
She understood perfectly well.
Understood what?
That we have a personal relationship.
Since when does Josephine know
that we have what you call
a personal relationship?
Don't be stupid. She has eyes.
- You want me to draw you a picture?
- Please don't draw me a picture.
I thought it was between you and me.
I'm appalled.
Who else knows?
I don't know,
but in an office,
word gets around pretty fast.
You hired me as your personal assistant.
I'm under-qualified.
Everyone understood right away
that I could come and go as I pleased.
I created a vacuum around you,
to keep my hold on you.
Created a vacuum...
to keep your hold.
Don't you realize?
No.
I don't see things that way.
Then everyone else got it before you did.
MARIA: Shall we stop here?
Sure.
Can you repeat Sigrid's last lines?
(grunts)
“Then everyone else got it before you did.
Helena pauses and stares at Sigrid.”
What started at my place that night...
I won't deny a thing.
I probably wanted it. I don't know.
It's as if you put this idea in my head.
If you allowed yourself to be manipulated,
it's because you wanted it.
- I don't want anything.
- Stop!
I can't stand
that condescending tone of yours.
You want to be clear? This can't go on.
- Whatever you say.
-It's - I've thought it over.
-It's finished.
- So I'll leave.
No, you'll stay. You do your job well.
I have no complaints.
- I stay, and it's finished.
- We stop.
- And act as if it never happened.
- Yes.
Helena, you're not capable of that.
If I stay, nothing will change.
You'll be my lover.
No.
You will. And I'll keep
driving everyone else away.
I'll have a tighter
and tighter hold on you.
- Is that what you want?
- No, not necessarily.
I'm just telling you how it is.
But if you want me to leave,
just say so.
She doesn't speak. Say it.
It's time.
End of act 2.
- You hungry?
- Yeah.
(laughing)
“You'll be my lover.
I'll keep driving everyone else away.
I'll have a tighter
and tighter hold on you.”
Honestly,
you don't find this ridiculous?
- Why, 'cause she speaks brutally?
- No, because it's phony.
I don't believe it.
So you don't think people can be blinded
by their own emotions.
No, I do, but not to that extent.
It's too theoretical.
Even a little stupid.
It's theater.
It's an interpretation of life.
It can be truer than life itself.
Sigrid puts Helena's desires into words.
She says the unspoken.
She... formulates it.
- Cruelly.
- Okay, cruelly.
Yeah, cruelly,
because she's up to no good.
You're not in the character's skin. You -
I have no choice. I have to be them.
I have to identify with them.
When it's phony, I - I feel it.
Viscerally.
(sighs)
it can be, uh...
literary, but still be true.
I can feel the difference.
I can hear it.
(bell jangling)
(goat bleating)
(goat bleats)
- Maria.
- Hmm?
We've got to go.
Sun's about to go down.
I know a shortcut a little further up.
It's steep, but, uh,
it'll take us straight to Val Fex.
- I thought Val Fex was that way.
- No,no,no.
VALENTINE:
You're sure this is the right path, huh?
MARIA: Well... actually, not really.
I'm not even sure it's a path.
Or we might have forked off
somewhere, I don't know.
I think you're right.
I'm pretty sure Val Fex
is, um... not this way.
Anyway, we're heading down.
We'll end up somewhere.
I think this road takes us to Maloja.
What do we do when we get to Maloja?
We take the bus.
You know, you don't have to keep me on
if you find my ideas simplistic.
What makes you say that?
If you find my point of view...
uninteresting, I -
I don't really know what I'm doing here. I...
I can run lines with you,
but I don't really see the point.
You can find anyone to do that.
No, all I'm saying is that thinking about a text
is different from living it.
It's nothing against you.
Y-You...
You hate the play. You hate her.
You don't have to take it out on me.
I'm just doing my job.
Ready?
- You're ready?
- Yes!
Don't lie to me!
You received a confirmation
for a flight to Tokyo.
You're reading my mail now?
Aren't you ashamed?
I haven't felt shame in a long time.
I went through all your desk drawers,
your notebooks,
and I'm doing it
because you want to leave me.
Now I know when and how.
Helena is restless.
Sigrid remains poised.
All you had to do was ask.
Yes, I accepted a job in Tokyo.
A pharmaceutical lab.
I think it'll be much more interesting
than the work I'm doing here.
More interesting
than what you're doing here?
Haven't I given into
every demand you've made?
No other company would have given you
that kind of responsibility and power!
Exactly.
It's weighing on me.
I know this place in and out.
The world moves. I want to feel that.
I want to be a part of it.
I want to travel.
Switzerland's too provincial.
(screams)
(crying)
(crying continues)
She takes a deep breath
and regains her composure.
And with me you don't feel free?
You've become too dependent on me.
It's unhealthy.
What do I get in return?
I give you whatever you want.
You know that.
Oh.
Like a job at a dead-end company
that's about to go down the drain?
How could you say... a thing like that?
Open your eyes, my poor Helena.
I'm not your poor Helena!
- Nothing I've learned here is of any use to me.
- I'm not your poor Helena!
You'll never last.
You should listen to what
the bankers are telling you.
And your board members.
That's not true! For God's sake.
Oh, this relationship
between these women, it's - it's...
Fuck. it's disturbing.
MARIA: Disturbing.
Nowadays people say “disturbing”
about everything,
even the most conventional ideas.
(laughing)
Anyway, it's, uh - it's a male fantasy.
Uh, no, it's not.
I don't know why
I should be helping to bring it alive.
I bet you weren't saying stuff like this
when you were playing Sigrid.
I was a kid when I was playing Sigrid.
L-I wasn't asking those kind of questions.
Like Jo-Ann in her science-fiction film.
Yeah, probably.
Don't you want to get that innocence back?
You can't get innocent twice.
You can.
If you just accepted Helena
the way you accepted Sigrid.
Obviously, it's easier to relate to strength
rather than weakness.
Youth is better than maturity.
Cruelty is cool, suffering sucks.
But she's...
She's mature and she's innocent.
She's innocent in her own way.
That's what I like about her.
I'll make some coffee.
You want some?
Cruelty is cool and suffering sucks.
You didn't answer me.
You have your interpretation of the play.
I think mine's just confusing you.
It's frustrating me.
It's uncomfortable.
It's not good.
Stay.
(sighs)
No. No.
Please, stay.
I need you.
N (classical)
N (continues)
(whispers, inaudible)
Thank you.
I prefer 18th-century music to any other.
It's so bright and lively.
Yeah, me too. Romantic music
is so sad and depressing.
But I'd rather listen to rock music
any day of the week though.
- Even the worst.
- Not me.
I've heard too much of it.
I'm sick of it.
Well, you're such a snob.
No. Tastes can get worn out,
kind of like desire.
I've never listened to Handel properly.
I think he's excellent.
I haven't been this moved
by music in ages.
You're making fun of me.
I'm not, but I just...
I find it really cute that you're trying
to fit in with my ideas.
But you know I'm not a music whiz.
I mean, besides what my family
practically spoon-fed me,
which is incredibly specialized,
I don't know a thing about music.
Thank you.
So, how'd it go with your wife?
Really well.
No, I'm kidding. It was horrible.
But, you know, she's... she's not the type
to wear her heart on her sleeve.
I think she was expecting it.
- Did you tell her about me?
- No, I said, you know,
I'd be going off on my own to write my book
and wouldn't be back.
She must be suspecting something.
She has no idea
you and I know each other.
Well, she will.
I mean, once it hits the tabloids.
- They're not going to find us here.
- They're going to find us anywhere.
It's their job, you know.
Did you say anything to Maria Enders?
Just that I would be taking advantage
of my press tour and come say hi.
She didn't find that strange?
I talked to her assistant, and she didn't
seem to question it, so I guess not.
♪♪ (jazz, faint)
Hey. There she is, just there.
- Hi.
- Hi. Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
- Wow.
- What?
- I never would have recognized you.
- Really?
I mean, if you've only seen me
on the Internet or in movies,
-that's not really a big surprise.
- Still, it's a little weird.
You, on the other hand,
look exactly like all your roles.
(chuckles)
I hope not all of them.
No,no,no.
Only the better, only the better ones.
Rest assured,
you don't look like Nemesis.
-(all laughing)
- This is Chris. He's a... He's a novelist.
Hi. Nice to meet you, Chris.
My assistant.
Hey. it's so good to meet both of you.
Seriously.
Yeah.
Hello. May I get you anything to drink?
- A cognac for me, please.
- Yeah?
- I'll have the same.
- Okay.
- I'm fine, thanks.
- All right.
What herbal teas do you have?
We have vervain, mint and chamomile.
- Um, can I get a chamomile, please?
- Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
(sighs) I don't think you understand
how much of an honor this is for me.
When I was 15, I saw...
Oh, my God, the movie you did
with the CIA and Harrison Ford.
- I'm so sorry. I'm blanking.
- Um...
Beetle on Its Back.
- A Beetle on Its Back, with Harrison Ford.
You blew my mind.
You -You...
You were the epitome of class.
You were everything
I ever wanted to be as an actress.
And I mean, the way that you
battled those politicians
and the military brass men,
it was captivating.
It was my first Hollywood film.
I was a little lost.
Um... Sydney Pollack was really nice,
but sometimes I didn't understand
what he was saying,
so I was too shy to ask.
But fortunately,
Harrison was there to help.
-(laughing)
- A lot.
Well, then of course, after that,
I begged my parents to let me
see you on stage, in The Seagull.
And they didn't know who you were
before then, because...
well, they kind of hate movies.
- Well, I hope they tolerate the theater.
- No,no,no.
They don't just tolerate the theater.
I mean, they're absolutely in love with it.
In fact, they see everything and... and...
Well, you know,
when they saw your performance,
they said it was the best Nina
they'd ever seen.
And that meant a lot to me.
Because after -
You know, before that I -
I'd never been able to tell them
that I wanted to be an actress.
But because of you,
I could pursue my vocation.
I prefer your early French films.
There was a cycle at the ICA in London.
I saw almost all of them.
And you came.
You probably don't remember.
Oh, I remember perfectly well.
I was fascinated by how freely
you spoke about your work.
And, um, yet someone asked you
if you had any regrets,
and you said, “We're not allowed
to regret anything.
If we're sincere, then we're
the sum total of our experiences,
with no exceptions.”
I said that?
Well, not word for word.
Something like that.
- You don't think that anymore?
- Oh, I... No.
I completely agree with that, 100%.
(all laughing)
You know, I am incredibly intimidated
to take on your role.
I mean, no one's going to
be able to do it like you did.
- I hope you don't judge me too harshly.
- Oh.
We all have our own way into a character.
They're all good.
Well, I cannot wait to do
the read-through tomorrow.
We'll work in Wilhelm's chalet.
I hope that's okay with you.
Yeah, sure, as long as his ghost
isn't watching over us the entire time.
I can't promise you that, but don't worry.
He's a well-meaning ghost.
Ooh. Well-meaning?
I don't know about that.
Nor do l.
You know, it's incredibly brave of you
to take on the role of Helena.
It's... it's a way of dealing with time.
Yes, well, I don't know, sometimes I...
I tell myself that it's just a job.
And I'll be happy to move on
when it's over.
Hey. Thank you.
You still want to see the snake
you asked me the other day?
Oh, yeah.
The weather they're predicting
for tomorrow seems ideal.
So you better make sure
you're out there at daybreak.
It's wonderful to see it
coming over the Maloja Pass.
Great. Awesome. That's amazing.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
I thought they were really nice.
It's true. I... She's a lot more interesting
than the person you described.
I didn't know her parents were musicians.
I liked him '[00. He's...
(car door opens)
-(laughs)
- What's so funny? Did I say something funny?
They spent the whole evening
flattering you.
Of course you liked them.
- That has nothing to do with it.
- No, no. Of course not.
(laughing)
-(laughing)
- What was that movie again?
Beetle on Its Back!
What was that meme'?
(Maria laughing)
I can't believe we got this scoop tonight.
What scoop?
She's with Christopher Giles.
Chris? His name is Christopher Giles?
- Yes.
- Is he famous?
He's... fiber-famous!
I can't remember
which major book prize he won, but...
He's married. He's with Dorothea
Von Duisburg, the German artist.
She had a show
at the Serpentine last year.
Never heard of either of them.
You should Google him.
How do you spell his name?
Giles. G-I-L-E-S.
Well, he's obviously with her.
Yeah.
When word gets out,
it's going to be, like, a tsunami.
Well, yeah, on their planet.
Their planet has a name.
It's called the real world.
Welcome!
Careful with that.
Come here. Give that to me.
(Maria laughing loudly)
Here.
MARIA: I spent all night thinking
about Helena's death.
Her death?
She doesn't necessarily die.
She just... She disappears.
That's your interpretation.
Well, it's... it's pretty ambiguous.
She goes out for a hike
and never comes back.
Seems clear enough to me.
You don't know that.
She could reinvent herself
somewhere else.
There's really no way of knowing.
Yeah, you can imagine
whatever you want.
Are we going the right way?
I mean, I don't mind waking up
at the crack of dawn,
but not to get lost in the mountains
and miss the snake.
Well, we're basically here. You happy?
What makes you think we're here?
I've got a map!
You want me to show you?
Come here.
This is the bend we just went around
10 minutes ago.
And just around there
is the view of the valley. You see that?
- How do you know?
- How do -
Such a fucking pain in the ass.
Jesus Christ.
I don't know why you're so dead set
on making this play
say the opposite
of what it was meant to say.
At 20,
you saw Sigrid's ambition
and you saw her violence
because you felt it in yourself.
- So?
- That's what I'm saying.
The text is like an object.
It's gonna change perspective
based on where you're standing.
I don't know.
We should go.
We're gonna miss the snake.
There won't be any snake.
Fuck it.
Look there!
Is that the snake?
No.
No, it's just mist.
A little fog.
But it breaks up.
Still pretty beautiful though.
It's like it's gathering
and pouring out into the valley.
Maybe it is the snake.
We have to be patient.
No, it's not the snake.
Oh, yes!
I think it's turning into the snake!
How 'bout you?
Val?
What the hell are you doing?
Val!
Answer me!
♪♪ (classical)
How's the hotel?
The hotel's fine.
Oh, thanks for the flowers.
So, did you reach Klaus?
He was really impatient to see you.
You have to return his calls, you know.
He thinks you're avoiding him.
We're having dinner.
He's a half hour late.
Oh, so you called me to kill time.
Just kidding.
I'm not avoiding him
I - I want to talk to him one-on-one.
You know how reluctant I was.
I'm over that now.
You know, Klaus understands
the risks you're taking.
I know he's sincere. He's doing this
for you and for Wilhelm's memory.
And for the publicity.
Twenty years after being Sigrid,
I'm Helena.
That's all the press is talking about.
You know, he's like every artist
of his generation.
He has a flair for PR.
Oh, and is that a crime?
To excel and to know how to show it
is to excel twice.
Baltasar Gracián said that.
I have no idea who that is,
but he was right.
The press is talking about you
and your work.
Oh, I said okay to pictures. No interviews.
It's too soon, too fragile.
-(phone rings)
- Hold on.
Yes?
Tell him I'm on my way down.
Thank you.
- It's Klaus.
- You 'll be fine.
Hi.
- Hi.
Excuse me, I'm late.
But something terrible has happened.
Dorothea tried to commit suicide.
She's in a coma.
Dorothea?
Christopher Giles's wife.
Chris. Um, Jo-Ann's friend, you mean?
Yes, but you are not supposed
to know he's Jo-Ann's friend.
Well, they were together in Sils, so...
I thought it was more recent than that.
Excuse me, sir. We can go.
Well, she slit her wrists in her studio.
The housekeeper found her
in a pool of her own blood.
Oh, that's awful.
She's a well-known artist, right?
Dorothea is an amazing girl.
Beautiful, talented,
everything going for her.
I love her work.
I don't understand.
Jo-Ann is devastated.
She was at an exhibition.
She can't go back to the hotel.
The paparazzi have surrounded the place.
I suggested she join us. You don't mind?
No, of course not.
(turn signal clicking)
It was still just a rumor,
but the press knew something was up.
Someone posted in her blog
that it was the real reason
that Jo-Ann had accepted
to do a play in London.
And is that true?
She doesn't need a pretext to act in London,
but the paparazzi will never let go.
They need a picture with Christopher.
They're going wild.
(phone buzzes)
She's in her car.
She'll be here in five minutes.
- You wanted to talk to me?
- Sorry. I'm confused.
I had a long conversation
with Rosa last night.
I told her you were in London,
that we were about to start rehearsals.
That made her happy, I think.
Now all we have to do
is not disappoint her.
- Um, let's take Chateau Larousse.
- Thank you.
Rosa gave me fragments
from Wilhelm's follow-up to Maloja Snake.
A sign of her trust.
Some of the pages
make no sense out of context,
but there are a few others
that put the play in a new light.
How old was Wilhelm
when he wrote Maloja Snake?
Thirty-five or so? How -
Hmm. Thirty-eight.
- Thirty-eight?
- Yeah.
- Little older when he made the film.
- He was still a young man. All action.
Twenty-five years later,
obviously he was more analytical,
trying to put things in perspective,
maybe thinking about posterity.
Who knows?
Isn't it better to stay faithful
to his youthful energy?
- And forget the new scenes?
- Yes.
Wilhelm never had
any distance or maturity.
On the contrary, his last texts got bolder
and bolder and more and more enigmatic.
Here's another way of looking at it.
We think like him.
We - We project ourselves
into the future
instead of freezing ourselves
in the past so that we -
- Jo-Ann.
- Hi.
- What's happening?
- She's hanging on by a thread.
She's lost a lot of blood,
but the doctors won't tell us anything.
I mean, Chris said she was
really relaxed when he told her.
She was just getting used to
the new situation.
Where's Christopher?
Dorothea's family got home
from Germany, so he...
They told him to leave the hospital,
so he's going to come join us.
Here? But that's ridiculous.
He will have all the paparazzi
from the hospital on his trail.
No. He said there were no paparazzi.
He'd know.
He's being naive.
Of course they're tailing him.
They're just doing it discreetly.
Tell him absolutely not to join us.
His - His voice mail's turned off.
I'll just text him.
If they follow him here, we are stuck.
- Do you have your driver?
- Yeah. He's outside.
Okay. Tell Christopher
to meet us at my club.
At least we'll have
some peace and quiet.
- Here's the address.
- Chris!
Hey, hey-
Are you all right?
- Did you get my messages?
- Um -
Klaus thinks the paparazzi
are following you from the hospital.
I don't know. I... I didn't see any.
They can't get a picture of us tonight.
It'd be a total disaster.
It'd spread like wildfire.
I'm going to call my driver.
Hey. Will you come pick us up?
- All right.
- Here.
The address of my club.
We'll go first.
Wait five minutes, take a taxi and join us.
(engine starts)
(tires screech)
- Fuck, they're following us.
-(phone chiming)
Hey, Ari?
No, there's no news here
from the hospital.
Yeah, I could really use you right now.
Whatever the first plane out is.
I'm stuck here in London
till the end of the year.
Rehearsals start tomorrow.
If she doesn't make it,
it's going to be a nuclear fucking winter.
KLAUS: What do you want to do?
Change hotels?
No way. Wherever I go, they're just
gonna find me and chase me down.
I'd rather just stay where I am.
You know, it's... I'm fine with it.
It'll just be hard for Chris.
- The media is going to crucify him.
- No,no.
I'll take the heat.
I'll be the home wrecker.
I'm used to getting nasty shit written about me.
I could honestly care less.
You want us to cancel tomorrow's rehearsal?
Maria, would you mind?
- No, of course not, no.
- No way.
No, no, no. I'd rather work.
- We didn't get to talk much.
- No.
I'll have the new scenes dropped off
at the front desk.
And we'll talk about them seriously.
Yeah, we can do that tomorrow,
after rehearsal.
Mmm, I'm drained after a workday.
It's not the best time for me.
I know. Same for me.
And next weekend I have to
see my kids in southern Italy.
We'll manage. Okay, good night.
Good night.
(door opens, closes)
“When they tell me about you,
how much they appreciate you,
it's to remind me how happy they are
to grant you what they never granted me.
- They're using you -”
-(knocking)
- Hi.
- I printed everything out.
Thanks.
If you want an English solicitor
to take a look at the papers, tell me.
I know a bilingual girl
who specializes in Paris real estates.
That's the sales agreements.
Your ex-husband is buying your half
of the apartment for the price you agreed to.
No, I didn't want to discuss it.
Maybe I was wrong.
That's the sales agreement
for the studio on rue du Chemin Vert.
Yeah. it's expensive, but it's worth it.
- So it's ready to sign?
- Tomorrow, as planned.
You take the Eurostar at 8:15,
leave Paris at 5:00,
and you'll be back in London
in time for dinner.
- Okay.
- If you want, I can travel with you.
No, I'm fine.
WOMAN: What do I tell Piers Roaldson?
Remind me who he is.
He's shooting a film next summer
called Electric Shockwave.
What's he done?
Nothing. He's 25.
But Jay says it's good
and that it's been green-lit.
- What's the part?
- They haven't sent it over yet.
It's the lead.
I think your character would be
some sort of... hybrid.
Mm, a creation of modern genetics,
but with a soul.
It's set in the near future,
the 23rd century.
On Earth?
Maybe. I'm not sure.
(knocking)
Hello. Over there, please.
Thank you.
Well, tell Piers I'm interested,
and I'll read the script next week.
Okay?
And, uh, there are the new scenes
Klaus sent you.
- Ah, yes, I forgot.
- You want to run the lines?
No. I haven't read the pages yet.
He wants to know what you think.
Why doesn't he just call me?
Maybe he's waiting for your reaction.
You've had the scenes for two weeks.
I understand.
But I'd rather discover them
at the last minute and not overthink it.
It's the only way
I can keep it spontaneous.
That's how I, um, prepared Sigrid
20 years ago.
I'll do the same thing with Helena.
If he asks you, just tell him
I think they're very good.
♪♪ (orchestra: classical)
(files hit floor)
KLAUS:
Very good, but it's still a little long.
- Jo-Ann, can you hear me?
- Uh,yeah.
- Do the same thing, but speed it up a little.
- Okay.
Why don't you just forget one of the files?
There are plenty.
- We do it one more time.
- Okay.
Excuse me.
- Tomorrow is our final dress rehearsal.
- I know.
- Thanks for taking the time.
- My pleasure.
I'll just switch this on.
Uh, may I have a cup of coffee, please?
You can imagine my first question.
Will the media frenzy around Jo-Ann Ellis
steal the spotlight?
All that matters is the show.
The rest is of no importance.
And fortunately, Dorothea pulled through.
I know you have a new take on it,
but will the audience be receptive
or might they be too distracted?
I suppose that's my question.
I hope they'll be receptive.
So you think the shows are airtight?
No connection to the outside world.
No.
No, each theatergoer
brings his own subjectivity.
And it's generally not defined
by tabloid headlines.
Some will go for the smell of scandal.
So will they see the show you had in mind,
or something else?
- MARIA: Jo-Ann?
- What's up?
I wanted to ask you -
You know the scene
at the beginning of act 3
when you tell me you want to leave
and I get on my knees and beg you to stay?
You're on the phone ordering pepperoncino
pizza for your coworkers in Accounting.
Well, you... you leave
without looking at me,
as if I didn't exist.
Um...
if you could pause for a second,
you know,
Helena's distress would last longer
when she's left alone in her office.
Well, the way you're playing it, um,
the audience follows you out,
but instantly forgets about her, so...
So... So what?
Well, when I played Sigrid,
I... I held it longer.
I thought it was more powerful,
dramatically.
I mean, it really played well.
Well, no one really gives a fuck
about Helena at that point, do they?
I'm sorry, but I mean, it's pretty clear to me
this poor woman's all washed up.
I mean, your character, right? Not you.
And... when Sigrid leaves Helena's office,
Helena is a wreck, and we get it.
You know, it's time to move on.
I think they want what comes next.
If you just held it a few seconds longer.
It doesn't really feel right for me, Maria.
(forced chuckle)
You're right.
Yeah.
I, um...
I think I'm lost in my memories.
You think you've forgotten
your old habits,
but they all - they all come back.
I have to break them.
I guess you do.
(chuckles)
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Maria Enders' room.
-(bell ringing)
-(woman, indistinct)
Thank you.
- Hi. Come in.
- Hi.
Thanks so much for seeing me tonight.
I really appreciate it.
We're leaving early tomorrow morning
for a location scout in the Ukraine.
That's where we're gonna
be shooting our exteriors, mostly.
So, I - I read your script.
Yeah, well, um, I know we've never met,
but I actually wrote it with you in mind.
(sighs)
As a mutant?
I'm trying to consider genetics
from a more human point of view.
When I was reading it, um,
I imagined someone much younger.
Maybe me younger, actually,
but you're seeing me in movies
that were made years ago.
I've changed.
She has no age.
Or else she's every age at once,
like all of us.
Can I be frank?
Maybe it's because I'm working with her,
but... as I was reading it,
I kept thinking about Jo-Ann.
Yeah, well, personally,
I never think about Jo-Ann Ellis.
You're wrong.
She's smart... and talented.
She's modern, just like your character.
My character isn't modern.
Not in that way, anyway.
She's... outside of time.
Outside of time.
I don't understand.
It's too abstract for me.
(chuckling)
Sorry.
I, uh - I don't like this era.
You're wrong. it's yours.
Hey, man, I didn't choose it.
And if my era is Jo-Ann Ellis
and viral Internet scandals,
I think I'm entitled
to feel unrelated, aren't I?
I mean, it's nothing against her.
I guessed I just assumed you'd understand.
(knocking)
Curtain in five minutes.
- How's the house?
- Full.
♪♪ (orchestra: classical)
Take your cue, please.