Subtitles by DramaFever
I won't die.
What I want the most
these days is to die.
What I want never comes true.
So... I won't die.
Why don't you say "thank you?"
Thank you.
Buy me a drink, then.
You're so gullible.
Forget it.
I'm thinking of getting
surgery on my nose.
I hear you're supposed
to inform the assailant.
It's going to cost about
two to three million won.
I was going to call it even if you were
willing to buy me a drink.
- Excuse me.
- It's too late.
Can I go wherever I want?
- Are you close to Hee Ran?
- What?
Are you close to Hee Ran?
Producer Kim Hee Ran!
No, not really.
- Good.
- What?
I said it's good that
you're not close to her!
I don't like it when
relationships are complicated.
Someone's friend works at
the same company. Ugh.
It's just you and me.
It's nice and clean and there's no one
involved if we bicker or fight.
What did Hee Ran say about me?
What did she say when we bumped into
each other at the coffee shop earlier?
She said I'm the friend
she talked about.
What did she say about me?
I don't remember.
Whoa.
Your eyes just told me everything.
"Ah, this is the woman she talked about."
- What did she say about me?
- She said you were pretty!
Excuse me! Please turn the volume down!
You're too nice and it doesn't suit you.
Useless men like that never say
I'm pretty wherever I go.
They all think I'm smart and sexy.
It's been like that
ever since I was at school.
You act like number one,
but you're really number three.
Number two and three kids
tend to be jealous.
If you're number...
Unpopular kids aren't like that.
It's too quiet in here.
Mister, turn up the volume please!
What's your name again?
I heard it earlier.
- It's Park Do Kyung.
- Park Do Kyung.
It's pretty.
I'm Oh Hae Young.
The "Hae" is spelled like this.
Oh Hae Young.
There were five Hae Youngs
when I was in school.
Lee Hae Young, Kim Hae Young, Park Hae
Young, Oh Hae Young, and Oh Hae Young.
There were two Oh Hae Youngs.
One other girl had the same name as me.
My name is so common.
Why don't you drink?
- Just because.
- Do you get red if you drink even a sip?
No, I just don't drink.
How can you not drink
when it's so wonderful?
I don't drink because I'm afraid of
making mistakes.
You must have made a mistake in the past.
What mistake did you make?
No matter how drunk us women get,
we don't ever say things that are taboo.
Even if we get plastered.
It might be different, though, if you
know you'll never see that person again.
Should we never see each other again?
Goodbye!
I'm Oh Hae Young.
The "Hae" is spelled this way.
Oh Hae Young.
[Episode 2: A relationship
due to willful negligence]
So you didn't tell that woman
everything, right?
That she almost got married
and that you know Han Tae Jin?
- I didn't tell her.
- Even about Oh Hae Young?
I didn't tell her.
You really need to be careful. Just try
not to run into her from now on.
You're a horrible liar.
What? "She said you were pretty"?
Are you serious?
What woman would brag about how pretty
her friend is to a man?
You're so clueless about women.
Turn around and run if you ever see
that woman in the future.
If she finds out that
you're the one who ruined her wedding...
I don't even want to think about it.
Do you know how she's doing?
You know, the other Oh Hae Young
you used to date.
- I don't know.
- Have you heard from her or not?
I haven't heard from her.
There should be rumors about her by now.
Just where on earth is she? You can't
catch a glimpse of her anywhere.
Ever since the incident, there's not a
single person who kept in touch with her.
In fact, no one has seen her.
That's it. She knows too.
She knows that she's dead
if you catch her
so she went into hiding. I knew it.
She's very clever.
So, what do you think will happen?
Do you see anything?
You're kind of clairvoyant.
Have you been seeing things lately?
- Oh please.
- You've seen that woman in your dreams.
I didn't see her in my dreams.
What is it, then?
She just... she just popped
into my head like a memory.
Ah... so you're just blatantly
having visions, huh?
I don't know.
There are a lot of things that can't be
explained when it comes to the past.
So if it can't be explained,
then it's not necessary to explain it.
But say you experience it
or it's been experienced.
That's the truth, then.
So?
You have that kind of ability,
but you can't explain it.
It's impossible, so don't say
anything about it.
If you do, then you're going
to have to abandon it.
Honestly, if you're a clairvoyant...
I would be super excited.
What are you, a child?
I'm the only one who knows that you're
psychic. Don't say a word to anyone else.
Go to bed.
Do you know there's a village guard
in our neighborhood?
I don't know. Go to bed!
There were two ladies at the bus station
wearing village guard vests.
Some girl and I got off
the bus together.
They looked at us back and forth
and they went to that girl!
We are the village guards.
We will safely escort you to your house.
Why? Why did they go to her? Why?
Apologize, punk!
I... came home safely by myself.
Soo Kyung, I was wrong. I apologize.
I'm always safe.
I will always forever be safe!
- Soo Kyung, I apologize.
- I said go to bed!
Get some rest.
I'm sure you had a rough day today.
- You're leaving now?
- You're late.
- Say hello.
- Hello.
This is my brother and his friend. She
works at the convenience store below.
I'm Yoo... Anna.
- What about Da So?
- They broke up.
I hadn't seen her for two weeks
and she cheated on me.
How could she do that in two weeks?
She's just that kind of girl, I guess.
So this is what it looks like.
It's nice and sweet.
- How old are you?
- 21.
- Give me your ID.
- I'm serious.
Come on, what do you take me for?
Give me your ID!
Just show it to him.
I hardly ever got carded
when I was in high school.
- She's telling the truth.
- See, I told you.
- Do you know how old he is?
- 33.
Exactly, so why would a young lady like
you go out with a old geezer like him?
You can communicate with him?
Age doesn't matter when
a woman is past the age of 16.
All men are up for grabs.
- Let's see each other often.
- Why would I do that?
- I'm going to come visit often.
- Why?
Date outside and don't bring women to
the house in the middle of the night.
Jin Sang always comes over.
Why can't my friend visit?
- You two are friends?
- We're friends.
You crazy bastard.
Friends don't do weird things.
We don't do that kind of stuff,
you old farts.
- Do we do weird stuff?
- We only kiss.
Why are you in my room?
You're young.
The village guard will
take you home safely.
Hey!
Wow.
Just use your words! Why are you
being so loud this morning?
Let me ask you one question.
Are you getting beaten up by someone?
Tell me if you are.
This was just an accident.
Some random guy came out of nowhere at
the coffee shop and I bumped into him.
You broke your arm and bruised your nose.
My one and only daughter
is living with such excitement--
- It's not boring, so it's nice.
- It's not fun either.
Put a mask on before you leave.
The neighbors are going to talk again.
I'll be fine.
Where's my cell phone?
I'm going nuts.
Hello.
Here. You dropped this in my car.
I was looking for it all morning!
You could've just given it to Hee Ran
and I would've picked it up from her.
You came all the way here, thank you.
Wow.
- Look... I'm asking just in case.
- Sure.
- By any chance...
- Yes?
Do you know where I live?
Where do you live?
It's nothing. I thought I saw you, so I
was wondering if you remembered or not.
I do have a pretty common face.
- Excuse me then.
- Yes.
Thank you! Goodbye!
Oh, what a relief!
- You got your cast off.
- Yes, just a little while ago.
They say the bone gets stronger
once you take the cast off.
- Should we duke it out someday?
- No.
Why? I hear you're pretty strong.
I got so drunk on an empty stomach
I wasn't seeing straight
that time. Please forgive... me.
Come to think of it,
I didn't do anything right.
I did a poor job of managing the store
and I'm sorry. I shouldn't have
taken care of personal matters that way.
Let me know if you ever
want to duke it out.
I'm curious too.
I wonder who will win
if we fight to the death?
Of course... it would be me.
I'd win.
There's no way I would lose to you.
I really want to fight her.
What is it?
Can I pretend I'm crazy
and ask you a question?
How do I look today?
Let's say it's been a while.
- You saw me 10 years ago.
- I didn't know you 10 years ago.
Then let's say it's your first time
seeing me. How do I look?
You're pretty.
- You're no fun.
- What's going on?
I have a class reunion today
and there will be a really pretty woman
there and I'm not sure if I should go.
I understand.
- You women.
- She's not just pretty.
She's pretty and we have the same name.
There's the beautiful Lee Young Ae
and the obnoxious Lee Young Ae.
Would you understand if they went
to the same school together?
You're not obnoxious!
Right? I'm not that bad.
She was a natural.
She was smart and her family was wealthy.
She's sexy, skinny, and sweet.
I was a quiet and normal girl in school
and she was a star.
I can't imagine you being quiet.
I started talking
after I graduated from high school.
I was intimidated by her, I guess.
I would only get my feelings hurt
if I got involved
so I pretended like I didn't exist.
Just thinking about it makes me cry.
Oh Hae Young! Hae Young!
- Oh Hae Young!
- Hae Young!
I'm going to go eat spicy rice cakes.
Let's go!
Whenever I heard someone say
"Oh Hae Young!"...
9 out of 10 times it wasn't me.
Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
- Hey!
- Oh Hae Young!
- Let's go!
- Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
Hae Young, you don't have eggs.
You can eat mine.
Thanks.
Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
Hae Young! Hae Young, are you okay?
- Hae Young!
- Are you okay?
No, she's hurt!
Hae Young! Hae Young!
Hello.
Tell Oh Hae Young
to come to the office.
Which Hae Young?
Hae Young! Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
The teacher is asking for you.
- Me?
- No, not you.
The pretty Oh Hae Young.
Since there's two
Oh Hae Youngs in one class
she's the pretty Oh Hae Young.
- I'm....
- Hey, "Dirt" Oh Hae Young!
Are you dead? Erase the board.
I was just Oh Hae Young.
Just Oh Hae Young.
Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
Everyone was shouting,
"Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!"
But I knew that Oh Hae Young wasn't me.
Pretty Oh Hae Young!
I lost intentionally.
I felt like I had to.
Get up and run! Hurry!
You lose if you hate.
You lose if you're jealous.
I'm a strong woman who doesn't
get hurt over these matters.
I gritted my teeth
and told myself that every day.
It must have been so hard for you.
Why didn't you just change your name?
Of course I begged my parents
to change my name.
I cried and pleaded every day to get my
name changed. My dad wouldn't budge.
So, what is that popular girl doing now?
I don't know. I haven't seen her
since I went college.
I didn't even want to know.
I made sure I didn't go near Seoul
University when I was going to college.
- I didn't want to run into her.
- She went to Seoul University?
So they say.
She's pretty, sexy, sweet,
and went to Seoul University to boot.
- She's horrible!
- Right?
Men don't like women like that
because they're too intimidating.
You say that because you're not
good enough for her.
You would totally go after her
if you were competent.
Then are you saying I'm not competent...
Wow, it makes me sad to hear you say that
about me. I always spoke highly of you.
Sorry.
Go to the reunion today. Surprisingly,
there's a lot of people who change.
One guy was so tall and cool in grade
school. I was so shocked at the reunion.
He's exactly the same height.
He didn't get taller!
Oh no!
So go. That girl could've totally
changed in a bad way.
Right? She probably gained
a lot of weight too.
Isa-dora is coming!
Cut!
It's not remotely scary.
The scene isn't scary.
The scene isn't scary,
so the sound should be!
Recalculate the tempo and do it again.
Be careful! Do you know
how much that costs?
Sorry, sir.
[Unknown caller]
I'm almost there.
What's the name of the place again?
I see it.
Hey, hey, hey! Hae Young is here.
She's out front.
- She's here.
- Over there.
There she is.
Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young...
Oh Hae Young...
Ah, it's Oh Hae Young.
Sit down, sit down.
- Hey, it's good to see you!
- It's so good to see you!
- Do you recognize me?
- Hey, it's been a long time!
- You've gotten so pretty.
- Thanks.
Ah, right, you were Oh Hae Young too.
Yes, I was Oh Hae Young
and I'm still Oh Hae Young.
Can you make it any more obvious?
Oh Hae Young! You're that Oh Hae Young!
I thought it was our pretty Oh Hae Young
there for a second.
Sorry for not recognizing you.
You've gotten prettier, though.
- Hey, move over.
- Oh please, you don't even remember me.
Of course I remember you.
You're just Oh Hae Young.
- Just Oh Hae Young, let's drink.
- Goodness.
What about pretty Oh Hae Young?
She didn't come?
She didn't come.
No one has kept in touch with her at all?
We talked two years ago,
but she's been quiet ever since then.
I heard she quit her job
and left the country for good.
She even broke up with her boyfriend.
That's right, I heard it was pretty
serious. They broke up?
They broke up.
She should've come to me then.
Why leave the country?
You can pretty much keep in touch
with everyone through SNS
but I looked for her everywhere
and I can't find her.
She's just gone.
- Do you think Oh Hae Young is dea...
- Hey.
We would've been notified
if she was dead.
Right?
I heard Oh Hae Young was getting married
and I thought it was the pretty one.
I'm so glad it's just
the regular Oh Hae Young.
So, did you have a wonderful honeymoon?
You are so slow to find out.
- Wasn't he like this at school too?
- Always the last to find out.
- Why? Did you get a divorce already?
- I didn't get married.
- I called it off.
- Why?
Okay, this is going to be the final
time explaining why I called it off
and I will never talk about it again.
Because I'm sick and tired of it!
Listen carefully.
I love men so much.
Spending my life with one man...
is going to be difficult.
Oh Hae Young!
Oh Hae Young! Oh Hae Young!
At first, they wanted a simple wedding.
Looking at the wedding list they sent,
there's even comforters for the in-laws.
No one does that these days.
I'm on the fence about it.
I'm getting upset as time goes by.
We're not too happy about this whole
process since Hae Young called it off.
And it seems like they want
custom hanboks as well.
It's just too expensive.
Just wear ours. They were custom made,
but we never wore them.
No, it might bring us bad luck.
Who would want to wear hanboks from
a bride who called off her wedding?
They say you're not supposed to reuse
the family gifts from a previous wedding.
My husband doesn't even
like me coming here.
He's afraid I might bring
bad energy into our home.
He didn't say anything because I told
him we were making mandu.
Deok Hee, what are you doing?
Are you hot?
Oh my gosh! Oh my gosh!
What? Bad luck?
Your mouth brings bad luck!
Who do you think you are
to say we're bad luck?
- Kyung Soo!
- You're going to get it!
Hae Young. Oh Hae Young.
It must have been hard.
They all liked the pretty Oh Hae Young.
- I liked you.
- Yeah right.
I'm serious.
I always root for the weak team
whenever I watch a sports match.
Why? Because it breaks my heart.
Move your arm.
I really mean it. I used to like you.
Oh, you are so cool!
You said you couldn't come!
My grandfather passed away and I didn't
even pay my respects. Where's Hae Young?
- Over there.
- Where? Where?
Oh Hae Young! Hae Young!
- What is going on?
- Sorry, it's just me.
You little...
What? It is Oh Hae Young!
I'm going to kill you!
Come here! Come here!
- Hey.
- Move!
Sorry that it's just me!
I'm really sorry!
It's midnight. Go home.
I'm going to.
I'm waiting for Hoon to finish his work.
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Are you fixing the scenario again?
Are you crazy? I'm tired
and don't have time for that.
- What were you doing, then?
- I just surfed the internet.
If I catch you working on
your scenario, you're dead.
I'm not, so don't worry!
Someone's calling.
It's a message.
- For real?
- Hurry up and answer it!
Isn't this voice phishing?
You idiot, who would do voice phishing
through messaging?
Who would send a message
this late at night?
They must want to hear your voice.
Hurry up and answer before they hang up.
Why don't you pick it up?
Please answer it!
- Should I do it?
- No.
You're so mean. Can't you just let
that person hear your voice?
- You must know who it is.
- That's enough.
The only person who would call him
like that would be that rude woman.
What did she do?
She ran away on the day of their wedding.
No way! They were going to get married?
My mom was against it,
but my brother loved her so much
so they set the date
and got everything ready.
She didn't show up and we don't know
if she's dead or alive.
I was looking for my brother all night
hoping he didn't get into an accident...
What are you doing?
I was looking for my brother all night
hoping he didn't get into an accident.
He was looking for her
like a crazy person back then.
I thought my brother would die
if she died too.
I hope she dropped dead somewhere!
That's harsh.
Who is harsh? Me? That bitch is harsh.
How could she betray him like that?
- Why didn't she show up?
- How would I know?
We haven't talked about her
ever since that day.
Her name is forbidden in this household.
Oh Hae Young.
Please leave a message after the beep.
- Help us here.
- Hae Young.
- Wait outside.
- Who is this man?
Why do I get hungry
every time I drink?
This is why I puff up.
I should award
whoever invented this instant rice.
subtitles ripped and synced by riri13
This is ingenious.
Good job. Good job.
It looks delicious.
Thank you.
I appreciate that she eats well.
Thank you. Thank you.
[Ten missed calls from Mom]
Why didn't you answer the phone?
Aren't you seeing Mom today?
- I'm going now.
- Don't make her call me instead.
Please answer her calls.
Stop recording all that.
You’re like a pervert.
You won't listen to it anyway.
No one says you're not a music director.
I came in and cursed the other day.
Did you hear that?
Come out. Come out.
You two could eat alone. Why call me?
Please address us appropriately.
You two could have
a romantic meal alone. Why call me?
Chairman Jang wants to see you.
- What for?
- How would I know that?
It's like he's trying to test me.
He acts like he is going to give
me money, yet nothing so far.
Don't talk about money between you two.
You sound pathetic.
What are you, a gold digger?
Hey, why would I date
a poor man at my age?
Plus, when he's already investing
here and there, can't he invest in me?
I'm his soon-to-be wife.
Whether you will become his wife,
we will have to wait and see.
We may get into an argument.
Let's drop it.
Hey, long time no see.
- Do you still work through the night?
- I still do.
- Who put your outfit together today?
- I did.
Do you like it?
It's better than
what your daughter puts together.
Please do it yourself from now on.
We will have the usual, please.
I'd like that too.
By the way, how do you know Han Tae Jin?
- Who is he?
- He's a young businessman.
I invested in his business.
Do Kyung asked me to take out
my investment in his business.
I couldn't say no when he asked me.
It was a headache for a while.
He kept coming by to ask me the reason.
I didn't have much to say.
So I told him
Park Do Kyung asked me to do that.
By the way, I hear he is in jail.
Then you got your revenge.
This is your treat today.
Thank you.
What did he ever do to you?
You had to go to an extreme like that?
This friend of mine met this hotshot guy.
He was in the economy newspapers and all.
His name is Han Tae Jin.
Can you see that man sitting
in front of Chairman Jang?
He's the one, Han Tae Jin.
He's marrying Oh Hae Young.
He's the one, right?
The guy who was in Europe with
Oh Hae Young on the day of your wedding.
I don't know.
Is this why you asked me out here?
Chairman Jang invested
tons of money in his business.
Do Kyung, this is a chance to crush him.
- Why would I want to crush him?
- Hey.
Then will you leave them alone?
Those two humiliated you.
What are you, a saint?
If you say something to Chairman Jang,
you can have your revenge.
Why wouldn't you want to do it?
I don't care any more.
You need to drink.
Your true intentions will
come out when you're drunk.
If you still say the same thing
after you're drunk
then I will accept that. Drink.
I said drink, man. Bottoms up.
There you go.
One more glass.
Now tell me if you have
no feelings for Oh Hae Young.
She left you at the altar
and now she's marrying some other guy.
Is that okay? Are you really okay?
Wouldn't you want to hurt them, huh?
Seriously, man.
What are you doing?
I will let fate decide.
If I hit it right in the center
I will crush that guy.
Hold on.
Why stand so far away?
Come closer and do it.
You're being petty.
- Hey, this means you're giving up.
- Shut up.
Yes! Yes!
Hey, you! Wow!
Let's talk later.
How did it go? Did you look into it?
Yes.
When people talked about
Chairman Jang taking out his investment
everybody else started to
pull out their money and filed lawsuits.
That's why he was sent to jail.
According to what I've heard
his business wasn't
that transparent to begin with.
He pulled in wealthy people
to give the titles.
So when Chairman Jang
pulled out his money
those people went against him.
Find a way to get him out.
We can't get him out.
We didn't file a lawsuit.
So we give up? We're not going to fix it?
Oh my, this was all my fault.
I'm to blame.
I encouraged you for no reason.
The fraud charges against you...
will be dropped 90 percent.
Don't worry. You will be set free soon.
You shouldn't have been arrested.
How is Hae Young doing?
She's getting by.
Did you have to do that to Hae Young?
Then I should've asked her to
wait for me while I'm here?
Then her family would have let her?
Did I do something wrong?
- No.
- Then why?
I suddenly can't stand seeing you eat.
But...
can I tell others I'm the one
who canceled the wedding?
Please say it was me who didn't
want to go through with it.
Please do that much.
I'm so humiliated.
I should go see a fortune-teller.
I think there is something
else going on with her.
Unless she's possessed,
she can't be in that state.
Even if she wasn't the daughter
we're most proud of
she wasn't the daughter
we're ashamed of either.
I run when I see her
on the street these days.
She's embarrassing me.
Park Do Kyung is
close to Chairman Jang, so...
he simply told him to be more cautious.
He had no idea things would come to this.
He said he'd help you to
get out in any way possible.
And plus...
Well, I'm also
a very good lawyer and all.
I came to help you find a way
as soon as possible on behalf of Park.
Just tell him that
I will find a way on my own.
Tell him to take
good care of himself until I get out.
By the way, why did he ruin me?
What did I ever do to him?
No matter how hard I think,
I never even met the guy.
Can you ask him why he did this to me?
That won't change much at this point.
He wants to see you when he comes out.
Gosh, he's pissed.
Tell him the truth, okay?
There was this bad woman you dated.
You confused her with the one
he was marrying. That's what happened.
Come on. We had
every reason to be confused.
How could we have known that there were
two Oh Hae Youngs in the same grade?
This is literally...
it was an accident
from willful negligence.
Wouldn't you be more
pissed off if you heard that?
I don't know what to do.
Honey, let's abandon Hae Young.
She's a crazy woman we can't handle.
What is all this?
Now Dad will let you go.
Mom agrees with me.
Have a good and proper life.
What is he doing?
Where are you? When will you be done?
No, no reason.
You think I'm some kind of alcoholic?
I drink every day?
Okay. Get back to work.
Hi.
- How have you been?
- Good.
- Good as usual.
Nice to see you. It's been so long.
- You're off somewhere.
- Yes, I'm meeting someone.
Wow, it is really nice to see you.
- You've been well, right?
- Yes.
- Tae Jin is doing well, right?
- Yes, he's well.
That's great.
It's been a while since we spoke last.
- Say hi to him for me.
- I will.
- Then.
- Sure, bye.
How can he possibly be well?
How can he possibly be well? How?
[Restricted number]
Hello?
This is Oh Hae Young, isn't it?
I'm grateful that you recognized me.
This is why
we shouldn't be too nice to others.
They think you're a joke until the end.
Someone who calls me and can't say
anything because of what she did
is only you, do you know that?
- I miss you.
- Crazy!
Excuse me, can you turn down the music?
I asked you to turn down the music!
This is noise, not music!
Shall we become total strangers?
Why are you crying?
Did someone hit you?
You shouldn't think you're
the most miserable person in the world.
Because I'm the most miserable person.
Shall we talk about why we're miserable?
We will talk about it and...
we will completely forget it.
I was dumped the day before my wedding.
It's my first time to say that out loud.
He said he wasn't sure if
he'd love me for the rest of his life.
And...
He said he couldn't stand seeing me eat.
How could he say such a thing?
But do you know what I said back to him?
Okay, let's not get married.
But...
tell people I was the one
who canceled the wedding.
Why am I laughing?
I wanted to tell someone this once.
To someone I won't see again.
And...
To someone who is as miserable as I am.
Now it's your turn to talk.
The reason why you're miserable.
I will hear you out.
Talk to me.
Don't if you don't want to.
Let's never see each other again.
I'm sorry.
About what?
Just live no matter how.
Even if it hurts, still live.
If you survive, it means you've won.
It is tough luck
for you guys that I own you.
Let's go.
Together.
There.
She's just left.
Live. No matter how.
Live even if it hurts.
Let's get along.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
What is that?
What kind of lousy place is this?
What's with this?
Is this wood?
Oh my goodness.
Wow. Thank you.
We're strangers.
I was dumped the day before my wedding.
Wow.
Subtitles by DramaFever
I don't need anything.
Just get her out of there.
Am I someone you'd want to scream at?
Am I that awful?
Shut up! If you call
my brother again, I will kill you.
Does this make sense unless I'm crazy?
Find out about Park Do Kyung.
- Scared that we might sleep together?
- Hey.
Do I look like someone who would be
obsessed with you if we slept together?
You know how it feels to be unfair.
You told me to live even if it hurts.
You're suddenly a different person.