My God, forgive me.
Teacher, all four are dead.
The Sénéchaux and the
Grand Master himself.
Then I assume
you have the location.
Confirmed by all.
Independently.
I had feared the Priory's penchant
for secrecy might prevail.
The prospect of death
is strong motivation.
It is here.
In Paris, Teacher.
It hides beneath the Rose
in Saint-Sulpice.
You will go forth, Silas.
I chastise my body.
Silas has succeeded.
The legend is true.
It hides beneath the Rose.
My part of our bargain
is nearly fulfilled.
I meet the council in an hour.
I will have your money tonight,
Teacher.
Precisely.
Officer Neveu.
This is not the time.
I received the crime-scene JPEGs
at headquarters...
...and I've deciphered the code.
It's a Fibonacci sequence.
That's the code Saunière
left on the floor.
Headquarters sent me
to explain, captain.
The numbers are out of order.
Hello, you've reached
the home of Sophie Neveu.
Church of Saint-Sulpice.
Good evening, Sister.
I need you to show someone
our church tonight.
Of course, Father.
But so late?
Wouldn't tomorrow...?
This is a request from an
important bishop of Opus Dei.
It would be my pleasure.
He's still in there?
What's he doing?
Saunière was reading his book.
"Blood trail"
Excuse me, captain.
Crypto called.
They identified the code.
Neveu told us already.
I should have fired her on the spot,
barging in like that.
Yes.
Except they didn't send Neveu.
What?
Captain, look at this.
He jumped!
Shit.
He's moving again. And fast.
He must be in a car.
He's going south
on Pont du CarrouSel.
Bastard.
Look at this. He must have
thrown it from the window.
Smart to hit the truck.
What, you admire him now?
We're stupid.
Who did we leave at the museum?
Ledoux? Get him on the radio!
Stay where you are!
Let go of the painting...
...and put it on the ground.
No. You put your gun down.
Now!
Or else I will destroy the painting.
Hurry up!
Slide your gun to me.
Be careful.
I never really liked this painting.
Christ, give me strength.
You are a ghost.
Stealing in a house of God!
You are an angel.
Christ, give me strength.
Gray Smart Car. Black roof.
Corner of Denain Boulevard
at the train station.
How could you let them get away?
Why not just shoot the damn painting?
Imbecile!
You should put his cigar
out in your hand!
Get out of here!
They found Neveu's car
abandoned at the train station.
And two tickets to Brussels paid for
with Langdon's credit card.
A decoy, I'm sure.
All the same,
send an officer to the station.
Question all the taxi drivers.
I'll put this on the wire.
Interpol? We're not sure he's guilty.
I know he's guilty. Beyond a doubt.
Robert Langdon is guilty.
Police.
What do you want?
Fifty euros for all your stuff.
Go and get something to eat.
This is Jacques Saunière.
Please leave a message
after the tone.
Please, Monsieur Saunière,
pick up the phone.
This is Sandrine Bieil.
I have called the list.
I fear the other guardians are dead.
The lie has been told.
The floor panel has been broken.
Please, monsieur, pick up the phone.
I beg you.
Come, you saints of God.
Hasten, angels of the Lord.
To receive her soul.
And bring her to the sight
of the Almighty.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
May Christ be with you.
And also with you.
Two prostitutes identified
Langdon and Neveu...
...getting into a taxi
in the Bois de Boulogne.
How may I help you?
The door to the right, please.
Good evening. I am André Vernet,
the night manager.
I take it this is your first visit
to our establishment?
Good evening, sir. Police.
I just drive from here to Zurich.
Not French, English?
I firmly resolve, with the help of
thy grace, to confess my sins...
...to do penance
and to amend my life.
Amen.
I chastise my body.
Feeling better, Sophie?
It seems you're not a driver at all.
Apparently, you lost your tongue
along with your truck.
Aiding and abetting
two murder suspects.
That carries jail time.
Speak to my lawyer.
All this confusion, violence,
vanishing property...
It might get around that your bank is
less than ideal, don't you think?
You think you're in pain now,
André Vernet?
My cause is worth your life.
Understand?
What do you want?
Your truck carries a homing device.
Activate it.
The truck's signal is coming online.
It's about time.
Locked on and tracking, sir.
Very good. Tell Collet not to move in
until I get there.
Attention! All of Collet's units
to Château Villette.
The suspects Neveu and Langdon
are likely at that location.
It's an honor to welcome you...
...even though it's late.
Château Villette. Yes.
Fache says to wait, so I wait.
What's Fache thinking?
The truck is here. They're inside.
Rip the gate down.
Shit.
What the hell do you mean,
you lost them? Collet.
You're the one who lost them.
You control every step
of this investigation.
You don't let anybody breathe.
You're acting like
you lost your mind.
What is it with these two birds?
Interpol just registered a new
flight plan from Le Bourget.
Stay out of my way on this, Collet.
I need the flight plan.
Ten minutes.
I asked you to get it for me.
I'm on break.
Come back in 10 minutes.
My nose! My nose!
The flight plan, please.
You asshole!
I suppose this is a new technique
for investigations.
I've lost them.
They flew to Switzerland.
No extradition.
The controller filed charges.
Ari was on dispatch. He called me.
What's going on, Bezu?
You know that I am Opus Dei?
Yes.
A bishop of my order called me.
He said a killer
came to him in confession.
His name was Robert Langdon.
He said I couldn't imagine
the evil in this man's heart.
That he would keep killing.
He said I had to stop him.
The bishop broke his vows
to tell me this.
He charged me
to stop Robert Langdon.
Tell me, Collet, who have I failed?
The bishop?
God himself?
They've changed their flight plan
to London.
Go on, Fache.
I'll take care of the controller.
Maybe he needs a few extra euros.
Just tell me next time.
Do you have the bonds, bishop?
Yes, I do, Teacher.
I have chosen an Opus Dei
residence for the exchange.
I am honored.
By the time you get to London,
I will have the Grail.
Lieutenant!
One flag off the prints.
Remy Legaludec.
Petty theft.
Skipped out on a hospital bill
for a tracheotomy.
Peanut allergy.
Like Marie.
This way. Marie?
My daughter.
Over here.
Where?
Up there.
What's all that?
Very advanced surveillance.
It's a listening post.
Get me Fache.
Four of these names are
the men killed last night.
I understand.
I am a ghost.
Leave us, please.
Come along, Sophie.
Sophie, where are you, princess?
I told you, no.
But why can't I?
They're dead. Dead and buried.
Never look for them, Sophie.
Promise me.
Swear it!
Swear it to me!