Mom, do you remember that one time
when we were little
and Gail made that huge dinner
out of nowhere?
Oh, my God, yeah!
That was amazing.
Mom, he made this soup, by the way.
Really?
Did you know he did his
internship in Chicago?
You did an internship?
I did an internship
at this kitchen.
I saw him chopping the carrots,
and he was like a professional
carrot-chopper, with a knife.
How long did you intern?
Two months, erm, like,
20 hours a week.
I could have kept going,
but I kind of quit,
because I didn't get paid
and I started getting bored.
Yeah.
How do you go from
forensic science
to cutting up vegetables
in a restaurant?
I don't know. I mean, it was like
a fleeting interest.
I don't know.
Would you consider going
back to school?
Erm, I mean, not immediately.
I just want to get a job and get some
money, and then, I don't know.
It's not...
It's still a possibility.
I'm glad you came home.
I bought us a coffee table.
- Did you?
- He did.
- Oh, really?
- I'm assembling it.
It's coming right along.
And by coming right along,
I mean not at all.
Still in the box.
So, how's it going?
I know you guys have
only been here a week, but...
It's really good, actually.
Yeah?
Yeah. I really like it.
I really like the place, and we're
not screaming at each other yet.
Yeah.
Well, that's good.
It's nice to see you guys together.
We did...
Never mind.
- What?
- Nothing, nothing.
- Oh, come on.
- No, I forgot.
How about you?
How's work going?
It's good, it's good. Everybody's
really nice, and I'm lucky.
Yeah?
Yeah, it's really good.
All right,
I'm going to go to bed now.
OK.
- Good night.
You going to go to bed soon?
Erm, I don't know.
Not really tired.
It's weird you're never tired.
Tired in the morning.
Yeah.
Me too.
All right.
- Going to bed.
- OK.
- Good night.
Gail.
What up?
How's it going?
What are you doing here?
What do you mean?
You're, erm, you're at my office.
Yeah.
All right.
Hey, you want to go to the coast?
What?
I have, like...
No.
It's whale watching week.
Doug, I've got, like...
I have a job.
I can't just leave
and go whale watching with you.
Yeah, but it's a special occasion.
Can't you just do this
stuff tomorrow?
Not... I mean, no, I can't.
People just can't,
like, just leave work.
- Just once?
- They have things to do.
You can do it one time.
What if everybody here just went
whale watching today?
I made sandwiches.
Look at this sea life.
Going to take this home
and put it in your bed.
That's what you get for bringing
me out here!
Thanks for coming in.
I appreciate it.
What I'm looking for is somebody
that can work, you know,
start now, here in the spring,
and through the summer, fall.
Winter's kind of slow,
but there'd be work year-round.
Got a couple of other guys
that work the night shift for us,
and we're looking for another man
to help out with that.
Got insulated coveralls
and everything for you.
- Yeah, that's fine.
- All right.
Forensic science, criminal justice.
That's a pretty interesting field.
What, are you just taking a break?
Planning on going back to it?
Er, yeah.
Maybe eventually.
Eventually.
That's pretty neat stuff.
If it's anything like on the movies,
it's pretty darn neat.
Yeah.
OK.
Let's see.
Ice factory.
I thought you might
get a job, like...
..in something crime-related,
like in a lab, or something.
No. I don't think you can get those
jobs if you don't finish school.
Are you sure you're going
to be OK in an ice factory?
Yeah.
Why wouldn't I be?
I don't know...
I didn't even know
they had ice factories.
Yeah. Where do you think they get
those bags of ice you buy?
I don't know,
I never thought about it.
Hey, man.
What's going on?
Not much.
Do you usually take the bus?
Yeah.
I thought you had a car?
Yeah, I do.
Some asshole broke my window.
Now it's in the shop.
But it'll be ready tomorrow. I won't
have to put up with this bullshit.
Dude, think of me.
I've got to do this every day.
I'm only kidding.
I'm only half kidding.
Where you heading?
I've got to go meet my ex-girlfriend.
Oh, yeah?
Like a date or something?
No, like, just checking in, kind of.
She's here from out of town.
That's cool.
Hi.
It's raining.
I'll be right back.
That's a lot of stuff.
What is it, tea?
Yeah.
How are you?
Pretty good.
Good.
How's living with your sister?
It's good.
It's nice.
You like it more than
living with me?
I don't know.
Maybe not.
So, what are you in town for?
For work.
I got a job in a law
office in Chicago
and their main office is here, so
they sent me up for some training.
Yeah, I got a hotel room
and they paid for my ticket.
You work in a law office?
I do.
That's strange.
It is. I've worked in an office
before, though, so...
How about you?
What are you doing?
Oh, God.
I got a job working overnight
in an ice factory.
I, like, load bags of ice into
crates, put them onto a truck.
I don't know.
This is the only thing I could get.
Can I come and see
your place sometime?
Erm, yeah, I guess so.
Guess so?
I mean, there's nothing there.
But yeah, of course.
Actually, I invited all the people
that I work with
on the nightshift to come over
and play poker.
Oh, yeah?
Just, like, drink beer, play cards.
You want to come to that?
Sure.
Don't just take a tiny...
Just knock the rest back.
- The whole thing?
- Yeah.
There's, like, tons in there.
Well, it's like a shot.
No.
You're supposed to sip it.
Spade?
No?
Left of the dealer.
Did he just go?
No, he didn't go.
Hello?
'Hey, it's Carlos.'
Hey, one second.
What's happening?
It's your turn.
Why do I have eight cards?
Because you need to discard.
You never discarded.
Come in.
How's it going?
- How are you doing?
- Good, thanks for coming.
Thanks, thanks for having me.
Hi.
Hi, I'm Gail. Nice to meet you.
Yeah, that's my sister.
This is Rachel.
This is my friend Carlos, from work.
It's a nice place, man.
Thanks.
It's not fully done yet.
It's kind of nice, though.
Sorry.
It's OK.
Do you want some potato chips?
Sure. Thank you.
We're playing rummy.
It's your turn.
- It's my turn?
- No, Doug.
I don't think I know
how to play rummy.
I've got a question for you.
Oh, yeah?
Listen, I don't want
you to get offended.
Why am I going to be offended?
I don't know. I feel like some people
don't like being asked this question.
Erm...
Will you tell me how much
you get paid?
1,240. Why? How much you make?
Eight.
Oh, don't worry.
They raise pay pretty good here.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You'll get a raise soon.
If you don't quit first.
Why would I quit?
I don't know, man.
You seem like the kind
that ends up quitting.
I mean, no offence,
it's just that, well,
people only work here for
like a month or something.
- Really?
- Yeah.
A lot of people want bigger things.
I don't mind it, though.
I mean, I can think and move
ice at the same time, you know.
Yeah, that's how my sister is.
She can multitask.
Hey, you know, that reminds me.
You should come to
one of my DJ nights,
and bring your sister
and Rachel, too.
What DJ nights?
I DJ sometimes, man.
You do?
Good shit. Latin shit from the '60s.
Shit you never heard before.
This blows my mind!
Why?
I don't know.
You think, just because I move ice
I can't do something like that?
No, I just, I don't know.
I never pictured you as a DJ.
So, what else do you do?
Nothing.
Well, I mean, I know you're not like
an ice professional, or anything.
What did you do before?
I used to study forensic science.
Really?
Yeah.
That's much more surprising
than me being a DJ.
Is it?
Yeah. What, do you want to
be a detective or some shit?
Yeah, exactly.
For real?
Don't mess with me, man!
I am going to be a detective one day.
What, like CSI and shit?
I don't really want to be like
a CSI-type detective.
I want to be more like
Sherlock Holmes.
Sherlock Holmes?
Yeah.
You've got to be kidding me, man.
What?
Yo, Mike.
Hey, Mike.
Our friend Douglas wants
to be Sherlock Holmes!
No shit!
Sherlock fucking Holmes!
Why is that funny?
"Elementary, my dear Watson."
All that shit.
No, dude.
He doesn't say that.
He doesn't?
No, he doesn't say that, he
doesn't smoke a stupid pipe.
He doesn't wear that stupid hat.
Oh, shit, really?
Yeah. In the books, he's just,
like, the man.
Sherlock fucking Holmes.
You want to borrow one of the books?
What, a Sherlock Holmes book?
Yeah.
I guess, man, sure.
I'll bring you one.
All right.
How's your milk shake?
It's good. Do you want to try it?
I've got mine.
Yeah, but, like, mine
is really good.
That may be true.
Mine is just as good.
That's why I ordered it.
Dude, just try the milk shake.
I don't want to try it.
I'll try your milk shake.
See?
She ordered coffee! Of course she
wants to try the milk shake.
She wants to try everybody's,
I'm sure!
It's really good.
I'll try your milk shake, Carlos.
She's just trying to be irritating.
I wanted to ask you something.
What?
What are you doing on Wednesday?
I don't know. Why?
Well, I've got an extra ticket
to this thing.
My cousin was supposed to go
with me, but he kind of bailed.
What is it?
Well, it's this really fun thing,
but you're not going to think
it's so fun at first.
What? What is it?
It's a Star Trek convention.
Get out of here! Are you serious?
I don't want to do that!
Dude, it'll be fun, even if
you don't like Star Trek.
I don't like Star Trek.
Marina Sirtis is going to be there.
I don't know who that is.
Dude, Marina Sirtis is famous,
even if you don't know Star Trek.
She's Counsellor Troi.
I don't know what that means.
Forget it.
No, don't forget it.
I know somebody who would love
to go to a Star Trek convention.
I know someone at this very table
who has been to several
Star Trek conventions.
Well, it's not me.
What about you, Rachel?
You have any idea who
Counsellor Troi is?
You finish it?
- Wow, that was fast.
- It's amazing.
Really?
It's brilliant shit, man.
Sherlock Holmes is the pimp.
Told you, man!
That's so cool.
Yeah, I had no idea.
You going to let me
borrow another one?
Yeah, totally.
I think my favourite
was The Speckled Band.
Yeah, that was awesome.
Yeah, that was great, man.
I loved it.
- Who knew? All this time.
- I know.
Sherlock Holmes.
I knew.
Yeah. I guess so.
Did you just get here?
No, I've been out
backed up with snow.
Oh, my God, I hate that.
Yeah, it sucks.
I'm severely suffering
from post-lunch fatigue.
Yeah.
You look...contemplative.
What are you thinking about?
Well, er, nothing, man.
I just wanted to ask you
if it's really cool
if I take Rachel to the Star Trek
convention tomorrow.
Yeah, of course.
I know she's your ex-girlfriend
and everything.
I'm not bothered by it.
I don't want you to think
we're on a date or anything.
It makes me uncomfortable.
I'm totally fine with it.
And you guys are dorks.
All right, I'm heading in.
All right.
What's up?
Hey, what's going on?
Not much, man. What's happening?
Nothing.
Did you go to the convention?
Yeah, man. Did you talk to Rachel?
No.
It was pretty fucking great, man.
We met Marina Sirtis.
You know Marc Alaimo, who plays
Gul Dukat on Deep Space Nine?
- He was there.
- I don't know who that is.
Gul Dukat, man!
One of the best characters
in Star Trek. He's amazing.
I got a signed 8 x 10.
Pretty fucking great.
Did Rachel get one?
Yeah, except hers
says, "To a lovely lady",
because she's a chick, you know.
Anyway, we went to her
hotel room after
to watch an episode
of Next Generation.
It was cool, it was chilled.
We just hung out, watched it
and went home, no big deal.
Yeah, that's cool.
You never told me
she was into baseball.
Is she into baseball?
I don't think so, man.
Well, we didn't talk about it,
but she had a stat books
thing on her night stand.
- Really?
- Yeah.
That's weird. I used to try to
get her to go see the White Sox
all the time, and she never
wanted to go.
I don't know, I guess you
rubbed off on her or something.
So, hey, I wanted to tell you.
You should come and see me
spin on Saturday.
I think Rachel's coming too.
What time is it?
Eight o'clock.
You go on at eight?
Yeah, yeah. I'm not the main DJ.
Shit, that's early.
Yeah, well, you should come out,
man. It'll be fun.
I don't know.
There's a Blazers game.
Why don't you blow off your DJ gig
and come to my house?
Yeah, right!
You should come, man.
- I highly recommend it.
- We'll see.
- All right, bro.
- Bye.
OK.
The new goal is to just see it
splatter.
Not to hit a mark.
We'll just see how much
we can splatter the grape.
Am I allowed to, like,
rough it up beforehand?
Yeah.
OK.
It was already broken
before it left your hand!
Yeah, I know. That's all right.
That's not against the rules.
Oh, that was beautiful!
If you open it, squeeze a little out
and get it juicy.
Oh, hit the wire, though.
That was fun!
At least you dropped it.
Erm, so, guess
what I'm doing tonight?
What?
You can't make fun of me.
I won't make fun of you.
You might, actually.
What are you doing?
Erm...
..I'm going on a date.
So?
All right. I thought you'd
make fun of me.
Who are you going on a date with?
This guy named Swen.
Swen?
- What?
- That's his name?
How do you know him?
He works across the street from me,
in an internet advertising company.
Is he nice?
Yeah, he's nice.
So, where are you going?
I don't know. I don't know
if it's a date.
We're just going to
see this band play.
He works with these girls.
I don't know.
I mean, I don't really talk
to him, ever,
or hang out with him.
So I guess it's probably a date.
Yeah, that's a date.
Yeah.
'It's Carlos, man. Let me up.'
Dude, it's late as hell.
'It's an emergency.
Please, just let me up.'
All right, hang on.
I called you five times, man.
I was asleep.
Five fucking times.
Jesus, what?
It's Rachel.
What about her?
She said she'd come to my show
tonight and she didn't.
She just didn't show.
So what?
She said she'd come for sure.
She went out of her way
to call me to say
she was definitely
going to come.
OK.
So I called her after my set,
and she didn't answer,
and then I keep trying to call her,
but it goes straight to voicemail.
This is what you woke me up for?
It's just weird, man!
I went over to her motel room
and all the lights were on in her
room, but when I knocked, no answer.
She's probably asleep.
Why were all the lights on, then?
I don't know, Carlos. The lights are
on in here and I was asleep.
Well, how come she didn't
answer her phone?
How the hell should I know?
Just... It just doesn't
make sense, man.
Goddamn, dude, how much Sherlock
Holmes have you been reading?
This has nothing to do
with Sherlock Holmes!
I just got this weird feeling when I
was standing outside her motel room.
Weird feeling about what?
I need you to go over there with me.
I'm not going over there!
Dude, you know about
these kinds of things!
What kinds of things?
Mysteries.
Hey, man, the light was on before.
So what? What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
Do you ever think that maybe
you shouldn't be snooping around?
Ssssh! Quiet!
Quiet. You be quiet!
Man, the door's open.
So? Was it closed before?
Yeah.
Rachel?
Hello? Can you not go in there?
Are you serious?
It's just weird.
Didn't I tell you something
weird was going on?
Maybe she checked out.
Maybe something came up.
Like what?
I don't know, man.
Maybe going to see you play
isn't that important.
All I'm saying is that she told
me she was going to come
even if you decided to stay home.
OK, fine.
What are we supposed to do?
I don't know. I just feel like
we've got to do something.
Is there anything in there?
Her phone charger.
She left her cellphone charger.
Are we done here?
I don't know.
I'm sorry, man, I don't know.
Maybe she went to get a drink.
Maybe she went to another place,
maybe she hated her hotel room.
Maybe she went back to Chicago.
There's really nothing out
of the ordinary in here, man.
This isn't the most suspicious
environment.
Don't react to anything
I'm about to tell you.
Just stay still.
OK.
There's a guy in a pick-up truck
in the parking lot.
What?
There's a guy in a pick-up truck
parked in the parking lot.
And he's watching us.
No, no, no, Carlos!
Fuck!
Did you see that?
Yes.
Who the fuck was that?
How the hell should I know?
I told you something fucked up
was going on!
I'm sorry. I thought
you were overreacting.
What do we do?
I don't know.
We've got to find Rachel.
I agree. I don't know
where to start looking.
You know what we need?
We need common sense.
- Common sense?
- We've got to call your sister.
No, we're not calling my sister.
Why not?
- She's on a date.
- So what?
No, we're not calling my sister.
You know...
I think...I remember
hearing about a situation
that was actually a little bit
like this.
A situation like what?
A situation, you know,
where people disappear
and there aren't any clues,
it's a dead-end, and...
Thanks.
Any food?
No, man. Coffee's fine.
I can't remember.
I think maybe they use DNA.
Or... I think that was
a different article.
Maybe they never actually found him.
Not the one I'm thinking of.
Shit.
What do we do?
Hello.
How are you?
Good evening.
What can I help you guys with?
Er, we'd like to get a room.
A room?
Yeah.
What kind of room?
I actually stayed in this
hotel before, in room 35,
and I had a really good
experience in there.
So if I could get that room again,
that would be really nice.
35.
Er, it's occupied, so...
..something else?
Do you think I could have room 34?
Meet me at the door.
All right.
All right, where do we start?
You want to try the phone?
The phone?
Redial.
Yeah, good idea.
Never mind. Thank you.
What happened?
It's the front desk.
Anything in there?
No. Apple core, boarding pass.
What's that?
Look, look, look.
That's her handwriting.
Rachel's handwriting?
Crown Motel, Amanda Brooke.
Amanda Brooke?
Who the hell's Amanda Brooke?
I don't know.
Well, we're at the Crown Motel.
I'm going to find
the number for the motel.
Why?
I'm going to call and ask
for Amanda Brooke.
Hello?
Hi, yeah.
I need you to put me
in touch with a guest.
Her name's Amanda Brooke.
Thank you.
What are you looking for?
A pencil.
What do you need a pencil for?
There's a thing with the notepad.
7206,
218,
367, 418.
What is that?
It's like a...
Is that a code, or something?
Hello, again.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but we actually want to check out.
Check out?
Yeah. I mean, we can pay full price
or whatever,
but we don't need this room any more.
That's weird.
Weird in what way?
Well, you're the second person
to do that tonight.
Do what?
Check into this room, 34,
and then check right out again.
Some cowboy did the
same thing earlier.
Cowboy?
Yeah, cowboy hat.
Oh, damn.
You know what?
I think I forgot something
in the room.
I'm actually going to take
this and head back up.
We'll be back in a little bit.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Look at this.
No.
That.
Jim.
Hey. You waiting to get in?
Good morning.
I thought you'd changed
to the day shift?
I did.
Why aren't you at work?
I called in sick.
What are you doing?
Reading about breaking codes.
Breaking codes?
Why are you reading
about breaking codes?
Doug, did you actually
go to this website?
- What website?
- The website on the card.
Look, look.
Amanda Brooke.
Click on "Yes, let me in".
It wants me to join.
Go back.
Scroll down a little.
Take the free tour.
You seem pretty familiar
with how this kind of site works.
Just click on it.
- Hey, Gail.
- What?
Would you mind if
I smoked a pipe in here?
You have a pipe?
No, but I'm going to go buy one,
I think.
You're going to buy a pipe?
Yeah.
Sherlock Holmes smokes a pipe
to help him think.
Not a ridiculous, stupid, enormous
one like Basil Rathbone,
but he does have one.
Hello, there. Welcome to Broadway
Tobacco. I'm Virgil.
Hi. Doug.
Hi, Doug.
Nice to meet you.
What can I do for you today?
I'm looking for a pipe.
What type of pipe
are you looking for?
I'm not really sure.
Erm...
What appeals to you?
What about that one,
second in from the right?
That's a Georgia.
That's a very nice pipe.
How's that feel in your hands?
It's nice.
How much is this?
$465.
Actually, I was looking for something
more like around $20.
Are they all that expensive?
We've probably got one
down there for you.
This one here.
That one might be in your budget.
How does that feel?
It's OK.
You know how the other one has,
like, that hook?
I kind of like that.
Yeah, the design of them
makes them more expensive.
Yeah.
I guess this one's pretty
utilitarian, huh?
Yes, it is.
Oh, shit!
What?
I forgot to get tobacco.
- They had it?
- Yeah. And look.
- What's that?
- It's the magazine.
Why do you need that?
Maybe there's clues.
Is it good?
Mmm. It's OK.
It's not really helping me think.
Gail!
What?
Why didn't you answer?
I just called you!
I didn't know you rang.
You and Carlos.
Why didn't you answer?
I didn't hear it!
Listen, I have it!
I figured it out.
What?
The numbers. Baseball stats!
The numbers. It's batting average
and on base.
You know how the first number's
smaller than the rest?
I knew Rachel didn't like baseball!
She's using that book
like a code book.
The first number in that
set of numbers is 70.
1970.
Then all the other ones
are in two and three hundreds.
That's because they're baseball stats
and they correspond to
a certain player.
I guess you add them up and
maybe it spells something out.
I didn't figure that part out yet.
You've got to take me
to the library now.
This is it.
Clete Boyer.
B O Y E R.
Batting average, 287.
On base, 367.
Bob Robertson.
Batting, 270.
326.
Al Oliver.
Batting, 270.
266, 367.
Let's say it's the first letter
of the first name of a player.
So we have L-J-I-B-B-H.
That doesn't sound like anything.
All right. First letter
of last names.
T-H-R-E-E-P-M.
3pm.
3pm, all right.
S-U-N-S-E.
B-R - 3pm - S-U-N-S-E...
Sun. Sunday?
- Sunday.
3pm, Sunday. Today.
It's 2.48 right now.
All right.
S-E, hold on.
S-E-B-R-O-O-K.
S-E, South East Brook.
Southeast Brooklyn.
Southeast Brooklyn Street!
We've got to go.
But we don't have the cross street.
Doesn't matter. We got to go.
Bring this book.
I have to check it out first, Doug.
What is that?
It's a knife.
Doug, why do you have a knife?
Just in case.
Doug, give me the knife, please.
No!
Doug!
I'm going down there.
I'll be right back.
I'm just going to...
It's fine.
Doug!
'61.'
What?
'..357.
Hello?
'42.'
'301.'
Doug, it's Rachel!
'242.'
What the fuck are you doing, Doug?
What the fuck am I doing?
What the fuck are you doing?
Me?
Yeah! Why are you checked in
with a fake name?
You said you were training
for a law office job!
- What are you doing snooping around?
- You lied to me.
Tell me what the fuck is going on.
I already figured out
most of it anyway.
Amanda Brooke, Sunday, 3pm,
Southeast Brooklyn.
I did some investigating,
and I've concluded that
you're involved in
some fucked-up shit!
Don't walk away and try to blow me
off. I'm trying to help you.
Let me help you.
Fine.
I was watching the phone.
I found a place where I could see
the phone and not be seen.
Why didn't you want to be seen?
Because I don't have what I'm
supposed to have.
What are you supposed to have?
I got sent here from Chicago
with a briefcase of money.
What do you mean? Like an actual
briefcase full of money?
How much money?
I don't know. The briefcase
was locked.
Who was it for?
I don't know, exactly.
Well, what do you know
about what happened to it?
I went out for a couple of minutes
to get some coffee,
and when I got back, it was gone.
Did you notice anything else gone?
Anything move?
No, I don't think so.
I don't know.
Did anybody know you had it?
Do you know a Jim?
Somebody named Jim ate Chinese
food in the room next to yours.
Jim Warden.
Who's Jim Warden?
He's the one who set this whole
thing up in the first place.
He's a photographer from Chicago.
You go to his apartment
and take photos.
Anyway, I needed money again.
Really badly, so I called him.
And he wasn't in Chicago any more,
he moved here.
He said that he had something
better than pictures, that he
had some friends who needed money
moved from Chicago to Portland,
you know, by someone who wasn't
involved, someone neutral,
someone who didn't want
to ask questions.
So I said yes,
and I took the briefcase.
And now it's gone.
Well, the people that you're
delivering it to
don't know
that you don't have it.
They want you to drop it off two days
from now, somewhere by Mount Hood.
What are you talking about?
Got the code from the payphone.
Even so, how am I going to find
the briefcase in two days?
This asshole Jim Warden has it.
We'll just have to find him.
I'll find him.
OK.
'Yeah?'
Hey, I need to borrow your car today.
'Huh?'
I need to borrow your car.
'OK, er, can we talk about this when
I get out of the shower, please?'
Yeah, I guess so.
You can borrow my car.
Huh?
Yeah, if you need it today,
you can borrow it.
Yeah, but don't you work at 12?
Yeah.
I'm going to need it longer
than that.
Dude, you've got to work, too.
I'm not going in. You'll have to
say I'm still sick.
Why, what's going on?
Look at this.
Look at the photo credit.
Yeah?
It's Jim Warden.
The alleged cowboy.
Rachel said that he shoots
out of his apartment,
at least he did in Chicago,
and this is the most recent
issue of this magazine,
so I can only assume
that this picture
was taken from his
apartment here.
So what?
So look at the picture.
It's a naked chick, man.
Look out the window.
It's a palm tree.
Exactly.
How many palm trees do you
know of in Portland?
Not many.
Right?
Yeah.
Right.
Did you find anything?
Yeah, he definitely lives here.
His name's on the buzzer.
I feel like we should have
pistachios or something.
Isn't that what people
do on stakeouts?
I don't know.
Yeah, we should have pistachios.
There might be food in the glove box.
Swedish fish.
Want one?
No, they get stuck in my teeth.
What we going to do
if we see this guy?
Follow him.
I feel like we should be doing
something right now.
Nah.
We've got to hang back.
Just wait.
Man, I feel like somebody
should be with Rachel.
Can you blow off work?
Yeah, man.
Doug, what's going on?
Hey.
Took a long time.
Yeah, the bus was really slow.
Has anything happened yet?
Not a thing.
Are you sure this is
the right place?
Yeah, the name's on the buzzer.
I can only be in the driver's seat,
actually.
What difference does it make?
I just feel uncomfortable
when you drive.
Happy now?
Yes.
Maybe we should play a game.
What game?
I don't know. 20 questions?
I don't really like those
road trip games.
Well, just talk about something.
I don't know.
I've got a question for you.
And don't get offended,
I'm not trying to make fun of you.
OK.
Do you have any friends?
Of course.
I haven't seen you hanging
out with anyone.
Don't you hang out with anybody
from high school or anything?
No. The only people that are left
from high school
are people I do not want
to hang out with.
I guess I didn't tell you I had
a boyfriend recently, huh?
When?
We broke up in November.
- What was his name?
- Sam.
How long did you date?
Six months.
Six months?
Why didn't you say anything?
I don't know, just...
Where did you meet this guy?
I don't really want to say.
Did you meet him on the internet?
No... Yes.
What a loser!
I know, I know.
That's not so bad.
It's pretty bad.
I know a kid in Chicago who's
getting married to a girl
he met on the internet.
Yeah, I know, it happens a lot,
but it's still weird.
Sam was cool.
I liked Sam.
What happened?
Our first date was walking over
the Hawthorne Bridge.
That's considered a date?
I think that the cool thing about
it, because it's not really a date.
We met at the fountain on Salmon
Street and just walked across.
It was pretty fun.
That's it?
Well, we had dinner.
Who's this guy? Look.
Turn the car round.
- We should just park here.
- Yeah, just pull up.
- He's got it.
- I know.
He's pulling into a parking space.
What should I do?
Keep driving.
Look at that!
That's the truck from the motel.
That's it?
Here, pull up here.
Put into this space.
What should we do?
Think.
We should call the cops.
No. If we call the police, we're
never seeing that briefcase again.
How are you guys doing?
I'm all right.
You need another drink, or...?
Er, no.
I think I'm all right.
Good, OK. Let me know.
Thanks.
Looks like they're almost done.
Doug.
Do you think we should just take
the briefcase? Just grab it?
No.
Why not?
It's just sitting there.
We'll just come out of the bathroom,
and I'll just walk
in between that aisle, and then
I can just grab it and run.
Shouldn't I do it?
No! I am a much faster runner
than you. I ran track.
Listen, you've got to go outside.
You've got to get the car
and just meet me out front.
We have to do this, like, now.
I don't know. I feel our strength is
that we know who they are,
and they don't have a clue who we
are. We should keep it that way.
Oh, I have an idea.
I have a really good idea.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Do you guys have a lost-and-found?
Yeah.
I was just wondering.
I know this is going to sound
really weird,
but I'm going to this costume party
later tonight,
and I don't have a costume,
and I was just wondering if you had
some weird, old
lost-and-found stuff that's been
sitting there for months.
Yeah.
That's all right?
That's fine.
Whatever's been there longest.
Yeah, we have loads of stuff.
I'll be right back.
Great. Thank you so much.
All right, give me a dime.
Why?
Because I'm going to use it to take
the licence plate off your car.
Why?
So then they can't follow us.
As soon as I leave,
count two minutes.
OK.
Don't do anything until two minutes.
You ready?
Keys.
Oh, yeah.
Doug!
- What?
- Get in the car!
What took you so long?
I don't know!
I was nervous, and it took me a
minute to get all my nerve to do it.
All right.
It wasn't that hard, though.
It was actually really easy,
I just took it and ran,
and he didn't even expect it.
Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah. Why did you
get out of the car?
Because you were taking too long.
Oh, my God.
Gail. What?
I slashed their tyres.
What?! How did you do that?
I got the idea when I was coming out.
I figured if I slash his tyres,
they couldn't follow us.
I told you my knife was useful!
Wait, I've got to drive slower.
I've got to drive slower, because
I don't want to get pulled over.
I can't believe we did that.
We just did that.
Yeah, we totally did.
OK, wait.
I'm just going to keep
going straight.
You OK?
Yeah. Yeah.
All right. I'm going to call Carlos,
tell him to bring Rachel here.
OK.
I'll just be a minute.
You want to listen to music?
Yeah.
I don't know what's on
most of those.
Think they're mostly mix tapes you
made me in high school, actually.
Hold on. I think there's something
at the beginning you might like.
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media Ltd