If yet your blood does not rage, then
it is waterthat flows in your veins.
For what is the flush of youth,
if it is not of service to the motherland.
Just a minute Mr. McKinley,
one revolutionary is meeting another.
Thank you.
Shall we go?
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
This isn't the end Mr. McKinley.
This is just the beginning.
There will be others after
we have gone. Many others.
Shove it.
Get out of the way! Scoot!
You come India first time madam?
Yes!
Sorry about the short notice.
Gosh! Your Hindi has
really improved.
Don't worry,
all the preparations are done.
Hey Sue, no need to worry...
...everything has been taken care of
posters have been put up everywhere.
It's also been announced on radio.
...just see, they'll be lining
up forthe auditions.
What's wrong?
I didn't tell you.
The truth is that I've come alone.
...no money, no producer is going to arrive.
You knew it!
After Alice, there was a
call from a certain Beth Williams...
...she informed me of the cancellation
of the show and also my services.
...did you abuse her in Hindi?
She wanted to know what it meant.
I explained to her in graphic detail.
You are amazing... Sonia.
This is Delhi University.
Let me help you with your luggage.
How much?
- Ma'am I've already told you.
Ravi, please get all the
luggage to our room.
Get some rest now.
I'll see you tomorrow...
...lf you need anything
you have my number.
Let's go Ravi.
I can't do this.
I deserve a role because
I have dimples just like Priety Zinta.
Don't sing. Just recite "Vande Matram".
- Vande Matram?
Raise your hand and say VANDE MATRAM!
VANDE Matram!
Speak loudly, VANDE MATRAM!
Vande MATRAM.
Loudly and proudly, VANDE MATRAM!
Vande MATRAM
VANDE MATRAM!
Vande Matram...
I have dedicated my life
to the freedom of this nation.
I know you want me to get married.
...but FREEDOM is my bride.
I know... I know... that...
I know... that you want me to get married...
...but my bride is FREEDOM
...but my bride is FREEDOM.
Your obedient son, BHAGAT SINGH.
BHAGAT SINGH.
Bhagat Singh.
My name is Bhagat Singh.
Tea!
Thanks.
Depressed huh?
One ortwo of them can
be used for minor roles...
...but no one's even close for
Azad or Bhagat Singh.
I guess it's all my fault.
No Sonia. You're my rock.
Sue, don't get so dejected.
Let's go and have some fun.
I'm in no mood Sonia.
Hey Aslam.
Aslam... Sue McKinley.
You too study at the University?
Wow! Her Hindi is great.
We live there, eat there but no one
has ever accused us of studying there.
What are those maniacs upto?
That's DJ...
DJ I love you!!!
That's Sukhi.
I love you too baby!
Damn exhibitionists.
The idiots will never change.
Come on dude, let's rock it!
Sukhi I love you!
Is he OK?
That's his natural state.
Sukhi, all parts working?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Sue this is DJ.
DJ this is Sue.
Hi!
Sue? She's so pink her name
should be Gulabo (Rose).
She's quite hot...
Perfect forthis cold.
Karan you saved my life.
I love you!
Aslam...
...you too saved my life,
I love you too!
It's ok.
She must have saved my life too...
No! Sukhi!
She didn't save your life.
No problem. One day
she'll save my life.
Relax Dude!
She is your sister-in-law.
LOOSE CONTROL
I'm a REBEL.
There's aren't any students here,
no teachers to suffer.
It's a school without rules out here
Hey Genius, go figure.
Sukhi you just sit and
watch like a dumb-ass...
DJ doesn't waste a second.
He's a stud.
Hi! How's everybody?
Hi Rahul! What's up?
Got a few gigs lined up.
How's your radio thing going?
Did anything work out?
All India Radio has
given me a night slot.
Cool...
Not really. When the whole world's
sleeping I'm on air.
But people stay up late...
Criminals, insomniacs,
watchmen and idiots!
Have yourfun at my expense.
Speaking of expenses...
Can I...
See you guys.
Got a cigarette?
Fabulous!
It's my Dad's money.
He's got lots of it...
Stop this Western music,
this obscenity!
How many times do
I have to make you understand this!
Polluting the culture of this country...
Leave this place right now.
LEAVE!
Can't you understand, idiot!
This is your last warning...
...from now on, nobody plays
any Western music out here.
No lewd dancing!
Or I'll break your legs.
Who are you to warn us?
If you don't like it, don't come here.
You bloody Pakistani!
Let's finish it.
Last warning! Got it?
Long live India!
You touch Aslam and
see what I do to you...
...even your mother won't recognize you.
Ever seen a baboons arse? Yours will
be as red after I've finished with you.
Sir, I'm sure we can work it out.
Keep this...
Anyone hungry? I'm famished.
How're you?
Hey honey! Come here you...
If something happened to you,
I'd have killed you.
Is this any way to greet your boyfriend?
How're you?
Hurry guys, I'm famished.
You won't get any food here.
Stay away!
...I carried you in my stomach
for nine months...
...and washed your bum foryears.
Get lost!
Does anyone botherto check
if Mitro is alive or dead?
What's up?
You're drunk again.
No. No. No.
First give us food ma,
and then yell at us all night.
None of you have eaten?
Sonia you've lost even more weight.
Really... Mitro
The girls of today have
more bones and less flesh...
How will you bear children?
Aslam, how are you my son?
He is my true son
who bothers to check on me.
And you...
Look ma, what I brought foryou.
Your daughter-in-law.
Her name is Sue.
What? Aforeigner?
Brought her especially from London.
That's why I was away for so long.
Give me your blessings Ma.
Your son's such a brat.
God! She understands Hindi!
You really understand everything?
Yes.
I'm going off to sleep. Your beds are
all ready. No need to drive so late at night.
Sue, where are you?
Will you guys act in my film?
What?
Hey, why are you guys laughing?
I'm the hero of herfilm.
Yeah we guys are champions
when it comes to acting...
...clowning around is all they do.
The four of you will be
perfect forthe roles...
And Sonia will be my Durga Bhabhi.
She really knows Hindi!
All this talk of patriotism is boring.
Boring? These guys gave their
lives forthe freedom of your country.
What freedom? Have you seen
the state of this country?
Excuse me! I believe in this country, Karan.
Otherwise, why would
I be fighting for it?
Maybe because it's cool!
Being a pilot... flying an expensive plane.
You get to wear sexy jackets...
And the women...
women love men in uniforms.
Sure I love being a pilot.
Sure it's cool.
But I also feel proud of my country,
and I can give my life for it.
Proud of what?
...this country's exploding population?
...or unemployment...
or corruption?
Which of these are you really proud of?
No country's perfect Karan.
We've got to make it better.
Right.
Ok, Ajay you make
this country perfect.
The minute I get my degree
I'm out of this dump...
You won't be able
to leave us and go.
She speaks Hindi so well!
Why didn't you tell me you idiot.
I was making a fool of myself.
At least ask them once.
So you won't give up.
Ok. But nobody will turn up.
I'll get them. That's a promise.
Karan put your cigarette out.
Grandpa!
God bless you.
When did you come?
Just last night.
Good morning Karan.
Back so early?
I didn't know you were in town.
Just arrived an hour ago.
It was a long flight...
Everything Ok at college?
Everything's fine Dad.
Have you decided which American
university you want to go to next year?
Michigan, Carnegie,
Mellon, Wharton...
I know the list.
Hello...
Karan wait!
I can't hearyou clearly
call me later.
I know that you know about the lists.
But life doesn't just happen to you.
You've got to plan it...
Every second someone
is born in this country.
Nobody cares about them.
Neitherthe government nor God.
Do something.
Or else you will be one of them.
Please, don't start with your lectures.
SMS generation.
Any conversation that goes beyond...
...four lines becomes a lecture.
Signal's weak here. Give me a second.
Excuse me Karan.
The deal is off then,
we are not interested...
You know Russian quality is doubtful,
they can't afford to be arrogant.
Anyway in the open market they'd not get
anything close to the price we're offering.
And you know how many fathers
there are to every deal in India. Nothing.
Tell them we won't bargain,
they should wire the money to us.
I did try to warn you...
they won't turn up.
DJ promised me.
Oh! DJ promised you!
So you really are a filmmaker?
Karan... Why are you so late?
And where are the others?
The Young Guns Of India.
Very dramatic.
Where are you going?
Well that's one part cast.
I am sure Karan can tell us
where his friends are.
She's an eight. Yeah!
Wow! Nine.
What a girl!
Oye Chotu...
...get me a cup of tea...
Two, looks like she's got the flu...
Six...
Ten!
What?
Dude... Iooks at those legs!
Shake it baby, shake it...
Oh shit!
Don't be silly,
that's at least an eight.
Thought I'd find you
stuffing yourfaces.
You lazy good-for-nothings.
We were about to come... but...
...we are waiting for Karan actually.
Oh! So you were waiting for Karan.
Yeah!
Karan was there on time.
We are waiting for him here
and he was waiting for us there.
What confusion...
You're Ashfaqulla Khan.
You're Rajguru.
The hero right!
And you know who you are?
The Master of Disguise
and Deception.
Chandrashekhar Azad.
What lips...
Learn the lines properly,
we meet tomorrow.
8 a.m. Sharp!
Nine.
Sharp at eight.
That's fine.
We've already wasted a day...
Aslam, your sister-in-law looks
even better when she's angry.
What are you doing Laxman?
Greetings Mishraji.
Party High Command is really
happy with your work.
These demonstrations that you have
started against Western culture...
...they've helped us
overshadow other parties.
This is foryou.
And this is foryour boys.
It's not necessary, Mishraji.
I'm not doing this for money.
I really believe in the
principles of my party.
That's fine Laxman...
...but every movement
needs fuel... Keep it.
There is nothing
you can do to break me.
"Because I have made pain my friend."
"...As I hold Death's fingers."
DJ idiot, don't spoil my concentration.
Look, Death's finger.
"I've committed my life
to the freedom of this country.
...I know you want me to get married,
but I have made freedom my bride..."
"Your obedient son, Bhagat Singh."
Who talks like this for
God's sake?
My bride is freedom...
I think it's a good line for Sukhi...
Since no girl is ever going to marry him...
Let freedom be his bride.
Laugh bastards, laugh.
This is the sari round
of the Miss Freedom contest.
Just thought it would help
me get into the character.
Look guys this isn't going to work.
You have to work hard to bring
out the characters.
Unless you emote from within...
...you won't understand these characters.
Try... it will come from within you.
BURP
See, he's got a hold of his character already.
You understood the character pretty fast.
See! Now you look like a revolutionary!
Whateveryou say Gulabo,
you need me to create the mood.
DJ watch it.
Now she's upset!
Those are the words of a 23 year old.
That's how old Bhagat Singh
was when he died: 23.
Those were different times Sue.
Today, if you tell people that
you want to give your life foryour country...
...they'll call you nuts.
Exactly.
I don't think I can relate to this...
That's it. Don't think.
Feel. Just read the words,
Feel them.
Why don't we try again?
Let's try again...
I've committed my life to
the freedom of this country.
...a job... a well settled life...
these things don't matter anymore.
...I know you want me to get married,
but I have made freedom my bride...
I swear on Mother India...
This Aslam is a real stud...
Take a look at the packaging.
Poetry, palmistry!
DJ, I'm scared at times that
I'll remain a bachelor all my life.
Trust me I won't let you die a bachelor.
Promise?
It's DJ's promise.
You'll be writing people's destinies...
Your love line is very strong...
The man of your dreams will come
along in a black T-shirt and say:
Do I even have a love line?
You must have washed it off in the loo.
"Defence Minister Shastri has also been
implicated in the MIG-21 kickbacks scandal,"
This is really depressing.
"This is a blatant lie.
I am ordering an investigation."
UTv
See you guys.
You're my buddy...
I'll drop you home.
I don't need any help,
it's just two lanes away.
We aren't so drunk...
that we've forgotten where you live.
Idiots!
You're very lucky to
have friends like them.
One day this will all end.
We'll all go our separate ways.
But you can always keep in touch.
Doesn't happen.
Life gets busy.
Too many problems.
Getting a job, a house, money.
In college we are the
masters of our destinies...
But after college we have
to dance to fate's tune.
You know Gulabo.
I passed out 5 years ago...
...but I still hang around...
I don't understand.
...I don't ever want to leave college.
Why?
At least in the campus
I'm someone... people know me.
DJ's somebody...
People expect me to do
something big in life.
But when I'm out on the streets...
I'll just be like the rest of
the slobs in this country.
Nameless. Faceless. Scared.
Just walking the streets...
It's the beer...
Everything came out.
You know what else
I'm scared of?
Acting in yourfilm.
Don't worry... you're in safe hands.
Where have you been?
Hello Uncle... How are you?
We'll catch up tomorrow Aslam...
You've been drinking?
Dad, you know I don't drink.
Good-for-nothings...
Whatever, they're my friends.
Friends! They feel no
shame standing in front of...
...yourfather with alcohol on their breath.
Why can't you get friends
in your own community?
Why do you make friends with people
who corrupt you, disgrace your religion...
This has nothing to
do with religion, Father.
Shut up! Don't raise your voice
in the presence of yourfather.
He's right.
This country has never accepted
Muslims and it never will...
How can you be so passive!
Do you ever see me
mixing with a Hindu?
I'm not you and I don't want
to be like you brother.
I can't fill myself with so much hate...
Coward that's what you are.
Stop it!
I feel suffocated in this house.
It's the same old thing every single day...
Carnivals will be held on our
graves every year,
That's all that will be left of us,
when we die for our country.
Well said Ashfaq Sahab...
If the English could hearyou they
would leave this country in a moment.
So what has been decided?
We'll steal the Empire's money
from the train that passes Kakori.
And with that money we will buy arms.
Bismil will explain everything.
Yes Bismil... Where is my Ram?
Ljust can't find my
Ramprasad Bismil.
Relax. We will find him.
But where? How?
Very soon. Don't you wo...
You won't get Ramprasad
Bismil out here.
You need a true Indian.
How can you find Indian
revolutionaries amongst...
...people who want to be Westerners?
Ignore him. Let's go.
Ramprasad Bismil wished to
be reborn a hundred times...
...so that he could give his life for his
country a hundred times over.
Let's go Sue.
So where do you think
I can find my Bismil?
I don't believe this.
This day, we walk along with death,
and laugh at its pale spectre.
We will not fearthose cruel swords,
our courage is far sharper.
Mistake not our silence for submission.
For beneath lies lava, molten.
O Martyre, O men of valour.
One day the enemy will sing your praises.
We will show our mettle
when the moment of truth arrives...
...for courage lives in deeds,
not boastful lies.
We've gathered in the enemy's lair,
my friend...
In the hope of dying for our motherland.
We will not fearthose cruel swords,
our courage is far sharper.
This day, we walk along with death,
and laugh at its pale spectre.
We will not fearthose cruel swords,
our courage is far sharper.
Sue, this isn't London.
You don't know what kind...
...of scum, men like Laxman Pandey are.
Look Sue if he is a part of this,
then I can't do the film.
If you have any problems
with me say it on my face.
Don't stab me in the back like a coward.
Pandey leave!
We don't want trouble...
Speak you coward.
What were you saying?
Aslam, where are you going?
Coward, what were you saying?
Hey you! How dare you hit Aslam?
SUKHI
Thrash him.
I'm sorry,
I took you guys in my film.
God knows what made me come here...
You know we've got a problem
with Pandey. There's a lot of bad blood.
And if I stay, it's sure to happen again.
No, Sue.
We've worked it out.
You won't have any problems.
Sue... we all know how much
this film means to you.
We want to help you finish
what you came here to do.
Everyone wants you to stay.
I want you to stay.
Say something...
Don't worry, you're in safe hands.
Come on... Get up... Come here.
She's not going anywhere.
Now just chill.
UTv
Take some soil of my land,
the scent of this air...
Add the breath of my being,
the throbbing of my heart...
And the zeal, that
races through my blood...
Take all these, and stir it.
Then watch as it brings out the colour...
Watch as it brings out
the colour of patriotism, my friend.
Watch as it brings out the colour.
Bismil's sent a message...
...that the Lucknow train...
...carrying the Empire's money...
will be looted by us in Kakori...
...while eating Kakori kababs.
And we will buy bombs with that money.
Leave her alone...
She will stop giving milk.
Give colour to your dreams.
And those of your people.
Give colour to your happiness.
And your sadness too.
Give colour to generations...
Give colour to the field...
Give colour to the beat of your heart.
And that of your music.
Give colour to every cheek.
Give colour to your eyes...
Watch as it brings out the
colour of patriotism my friend.
Watch as it brings out the colour...
Take some soil of my land,
the scent of this air...
Add the breath of my being,
the throbbing of my heart.
And the zeal, that races
through my blood.
Take all these and stir it.
Then watch as it brings out the colour.
Watch as it brings out the
colour of patriotism, my friend.
Watch as it brings out the colour.
Hey Short-stuff!
Did you get Bismil's message?
No.
No! Then Listen...
The train that's Kakori...
will be looted in eight days.
It's loaded with the Empire's money.
Will you loot it?
No.
We will be buying arms from it.
What will we buy?
Arms...
Yes... Very Good... go now.
On a slow fire, won't you,
put this passion to cook.
Then as it simmers,
add a babbling brook.
Add a river, and an ocean.
Maybe a pot of water.
Then sprinkle a bit. Stir it all up.
And watch as it brings out the colour.
Watch as it brings out
the colour of patriotism, my friend.
Bismil has sent a message...
...the Lucknow train...
...which carries the Empire's money...
...will be looted by us in
seven days, in Kakori...
And we will buy bombs with that money.
Now paint the whole town with it.
Paint your very being.
Paint your every vein with it.
Paint it with a smile.
Paint those childhood years, won't you.
Paint the flush of youth.
Don't hesitate, my friend.
Paint your patriotism over everything.
Watch as it brings out the
colour of patriotism, my friend.
Take some soil of my land,
the scent of this air.
Add the breath of my being,
the throbbing of my heart.
And the zeal,
that races through my blood.
Take all these and stir it.
Then watch as it brings out the colour.
Watch as it brings out the
colour of patriotism, my friend.
Watch as it brings out the colour.
Watch as it brings out the
colour of patriotism, my friend.
British Officers...
around 20 to 25 of them.
We have to call it off! We've nearly
reached Kakori. Stop Ashfaq, quick.
Ashfaq, stop!
It's too late to back out now...
Come on... Move!
Get inside!
Keep the windows shut...
Come on!
The keys!
You won't get away with this.
Give me the keys!
- I don't have it.
Banwari get the sledge hammer.
I'll handle them.
You go get the money...
I've committed my life
to the freedom of this country.
Comfort, and other worldly
desires do not attract me.
I know you want me to
get married and settle down...
...like all parents do.
But freedom is my bride.
I hope you'll forgive me.
Your most obedient son, Bhagat.
Let's take a break.
Breakfast?
No...
Put it there.
General Dyer? How can one even think
of doing something like this?
I can't believe that he actually killed more
than 400 people at Jallianwala Baugh.
379... that was the official figure.
Actually nearly 1000
people were butchered...
Last year at the tomb of Peer Sai,
I prayed for Daljeet's well being.
Who's Daljeet?
We were the epitome of tolerance.
Even an ant reacts. But we are conditioned
to take everything lying down.
Rubbish! It's today's generation
which lacks the will to do anything
Have you ever heard of
Shaheed Uddham Singh?
He went all the way to London
and killed that Dyer.
...because he was also a part
of the Jallianwala Baugh massacre.
Eat it Sonia.
The butter will strengthen your bones.
In Punjab every mother sends
at least one son to the army.
Why should we retreat?
Sacrifice runs in our blood.
Only idiots like DJ retreat.
Why does it always come back to me?
Shut up and eat your paratha.
What is the most used word in this country?
ADJUST!
Six people sitting on a seat forfour... someone
will squeeze in and say - 'Please adjust! '.
Hey! Why are you adjusting?
Strange. Isn't it?
We are being hunted like
animals in our own country...
...Ashfaq you should cross the border
and get to Afghanistan...
...We have many Muslim friends there.
You will be safe with them.
After all, you're one of their own.
One of their own?
Hmm...
Why don't you think of me
as one of your own?
Ashfaq... I never meant...
...Ashfaq...
I didn't mean to hurt you.
This is your country as much as it is mine.
You have a right to fight and die for it too...
...Forgive me.
Ram, let us not talk of dying...
I pray, that we all live to see
our grandchildren grow up in a free country.
Ram run!
Where are your otherfriends?
Where's Azad?
Banwari!
I loved those songs and dances.
Do they happen in yourfilms?
That's the reason we grow trees
in this country... to dance around them.
So where are we going?
Special day, special place!
Special DAY?
Ever since I was a kid
I used to come here...
...to watch planes take off... and watch them
till they don't disappear in the sky.
What the hell are they doing?
I don't believe them.
Men!
Come on, face it,
you'd love to do that really.
What? Take my shirt off
and howl at planes.
I won't mind if you do.
Dream on buddy...
Boys and girls
and Sukhi...
Why me all the time?
I want to make a special announcement...
I was wondering if you'd like
to spend the rest of your life with me...
...that's in case you aren't
doing anything important...
Will you please marry me?
UTv