Notes and testimony on
Neo-colonialism,
Violence and liberation.
NEOCOLONIALISM
AND VIOLENCE
This film was made with the
collaboration of peasants, workers,
students, intellectuals
and revolutionaries.
To all these we express
our deep appreciation.
Data from: the Second Declaration
of Havana; the U.N.
the General Confederation of Labour
and contemporary publications
Scenes have been taken
from the following films:
Tire Die by Fernando Birri,
Mayoria absoluta by Leon Hirxmann
El cielo y la tierra>> by Joris lvens,
Extracts from Faena by Humberto Rios
Theatre Frankestein
We thanks l'AGER FlLM
of Rome for their collaboration
This film speaks of
neo-colonialism
and violence in Argentina
and in most of the countries
of Latin America not yet liberated
For this reason, It does not deal with
Cuba, the first free territory of America
To Che Guevara and to all those
who have fallen
In the struggle for
Latin American liberation.
THE GREAT COUNTRY
THE GREAT UNFINISHED NATION
my first name : VICTIM
my surname : HUMILIATED
my condition: REBEL
A common past
A common enemy
A common possibility
THE GEOGRAPHY OF HUNGER
DISPOSSESSED, SHUT OUT, DAMNED
WE HAVE BEEN TAUGHT
A FALSE HISTORY
FALSE HOPES OF WEALTH
A FALSE INTERNATIONAL VIEWPOINT
FALSE ECONOMIC BELIEFS
A FALSE FREEDOM
OUR FIRST ACT
OUR FIRST WORD
TO BE FREE
THERE IS ONLY ONE CHOICE
PUT THE PEOPLE IN POWER
INVENT
IDEOLOGY
ORGANIZE OUR REVOLUTION
THE DUTY OF THE REVOLUTIONARY
IS TO MAKE THE REVOLUTION
NO SOCIAL ORDER COMMITS SUICIDE
A LONG WAR
A CRUEL WAR
IMPUNITY
THE PRICE OF BECOMING MEN
A PEOPLE WITHOUT HATE
CANNOT TRIUMPH
COLONIZED MAN
FREES HIMSELF THROUGH VIOLENCE
THE UNCIVILIZED WILL TEACH
THE CIVILIZED
POWER
RELEASE MAN
ALL OUR ACTION
IS A CRY AGAINST IMPERIALISM
AND A PLEA FOR UNITY AGAINST
THE GREAT ENEMY: THE U.S.A.
"for having loved too much...."
Latin America is a continent at war:
For the ruling classes,
a war of oppression
For the oppressed peoples,
a war of liberation
1: HISTORY
The independence of
the Latin American Countries
was betrayed from birth
It was betrayed by the exporting elite
of the port cities.
In the same year Bolivar consolidated
independence in Ayacucho
Rivadavia signed a Trick-loan
in Buenos Aires
with the Baring Brothers Bank
British merchants took over
the national bank
that issued the country's currency
and, in the name of free trade,
their manufacturers invaded
the internal market
From that moment on. England
replaced Spain
In dominating almost
all the continent.
what it had not obtained before
with armies
It now obtained with its loans
The country exported wool
and imported textiles
It exported meat and leather
and imported grand pianos
The exporting agricultural bourgeoisie
thus became an agrarian appendage
of European industry
For the first time in history,
here, in Latin America,
a new form of domination
began to be applied:
the exploitation of colonial commerce
through the local bourgeoisie
This was the birth of neo-colonialism
To impose neo-colonialism
it was necessary to divide
the continent
The unity of America
was destroyed.
Canning's diplomacy balkanized
the South of the continent
The Yankee empire then completed
his work in the North and Center.
The colonial ambitions
of the two great empires
were satisfied with
Latin American blood...
from Mexico to the river Plate
One people was pitted against another
one province against another
In less than a century,
20 nations emerged
from what had been four viceroyalties
The Monroe Doctrine and the big stick
legalised open aggression
against the continent.
In less than a century the United States
carried out 41 armed interventions
in Latin America.
Today the impunity of such aggressions
Is guaranteed by the O.A.S.
(Organization of American States)
Balkanization first,
pan-Americanism today
Both are aspects of a single policy:
Neo-colonialism.
2: THE COUNTRY
Argentina: Over 4 million square
kilometers of surface area
and 2,800,000
of continental surface area
A long triangle that could hold
Spain, Italy, England, France,
Germany, Belgium, Poland
Holland, Czechoslovakia,
Austria, Denmark, Bulgaria, Hungary.
From the Antarctic to the Tropical
Forest, all climates
Immense untapped natural resources
A million square kilometers
of woodland.
Four thousand Kilometers
of ocean coastline.
A million square kilometers
of continental shelf
La Pampa, the most famous
prairies in the world.
A country that produces 8 million
calories of energy per capita.
that consumes 10 million
and needs many more
but exploits barely 3%
of its water power
and 10% of its arable land.
An immense country,
practically deserted
23 million inhabitants,
of which 70% crowded in the cities
45% in only one of its 23 provinces
Buenos Aires
where 60% of industry is concentrated
and the proletariat.
In the federal capital,
the population exceeds
24 thousand inhabitants
per square kilometer.
While in Patagonia, the ratio,
is less than 2 per square kilometer.
In it's socio economic structure,
Argentina is the country
that least resembles the rest of Latin America,
It is proportionally the most industrialised.
Its rural population is the smallest,
The percentage of middle class citizens
and the living standard
are among the highest.
Its working class is unionized.
Its intellectuals are many
and brilliant
but perhaps the least Latin American
on the continent.
This country often called
>>>
"Ranch" country"
"Cannery" country,
"Breadbasket of the World"
is for the Oligarchy the product
of three factors: English gold
Italian hands...
French culture.
3: DAILY VIOLENCE
THE VIOLENCE VISITED
ON THE LATIN AMERICAN PEOPLES
IS A CONSTANT, PLANNED,
SYSTEMATIC VIOLENCE
I am a worker, one of the sacrificed
I have always worked, even on Sunday.
Now there isn't any work....
Many factories are closing...
The government told the police
to surround the building...
When they found out I had been
a union delegate...
A DAILY VIOLENCE
TO DOMINATE MAN,NAPALM AND POISON GAS
ARE NOT YET NECESSARY
THERE IS AN INFINITY OF ECONOMIC,
POLITICAL AND CULTURAL MEANS
JUST AS EFFECTIVE AS ARMIES
Sure, I'm afraid of losing my job.
Think of your family, like me.
The police killed three
of our friends...
They fired me because when Peron tell...
..they changed the whole personnel
They were shooting at us,
not in the air!
The police kept the doors under guard
Persecution in the factory
NEO-COLONIAL VIOLENCE DOES NOT
HAVE TO BE PUT INTO PRACTICE
IT IS ENOUGH FOR IT TO EXIST
POTENTIALLY
OUR WAR IS THE PEACE, THE ORDER,
THE NORMALITY OF THE SYSTEM
75% of Argentine workers cannot satisfy
their basic needs with what they earn.
The buying power of wages
has fallen by 40% in recent years.
Working hours for wage-earners
have risen to 11 hours a day.
Our country has one million
farm workers
but only half have a permanent job.
Latin America, out of a surface area
of 20 million square kilometers
only 6% of arable land
is under cultivation
The latifundio :50% of the land,
is in the hands of 1.5%
of the landowners,
while 80% of the population
has no land at all.
90% of the rural population
lives in shacks and hovels
no different from pre-Colombian times
Electricity, drinking water are lacking,
and so is common sanitation.
This is the breeding ground
of malnutrition, disease, and hunger.
In Argentina, there are 900 thousand
abandoned children.
In the rural zones, of every
100 babies,70 are illegitimate.
Of every 10 babies born alive, 4 die.
In Brazil: 43% of the infant population
dies of hunger,
300 thousand a year.
More children die of malnutrition every year,
than died in Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
40% of the urban population
lives in absolute promiscuity.
In Buenos Aires and surrounding areas,
800 thousand people live
in sub-standard housing.
45 million Latin Americans
lives resigned to poverty,
in slums and shanty towns,
"corventillos, villas miserias"
favelas, ranchardas, cantegriles
In Argentina:
one million cases of syphilis,
One and a half million cases
of tuberculosis
Two million cases of "mal de chagas".
In Latin America,
the average worker's income
Is 20 times less than that
of the upper classes.
For 110 million people
(half the population)
income does not reach
120 dollars a year,
Ten dollars a month,
-Thirty cents a day.
If the present rate of development
continues, the Argentines...
will  have to wait 70 years
to reach the yearly income
of today's Frenchman...
and 200 years to reach
that of today's American.
"High in the Heavens"
"a warrior eagle"
"Wings boldly upward"
"in triumphant flight"
"Blue one wing"
"the color of the sea"
"The other blue wing"
"the color of the sky"
"Hovering high above"
"Radiant dawn"
"arrow's point"
"it imitates the golden face"
"and forms a wake in the purple sky"
"The wing is the patio"
"The eagle is the flag"
"it is the flag"
"of my country"
"born of the sun"
"which God gave me"
4: THE PORT CITY
Buenos Aires nerve center
of neo colonial politics,
White city in a half-breed America
City built at the expense
of the whole country.
7 million inhabitants
1 million foreigners.
The biggest city in Latin America.
The fifth in the world.
Buenos Aires:
appendage of the great metropolises.
Here  a " gaucho" is as exotic
as in Paris, London, or New York
.
City of executives
and professional people.
of the caretakers
of neo-colonial interests,
overseers of the settlers.
Cradle of the vast middle class
which once used,
and protected by the Oligarchy,
now thrashes about more defenselessthan ever before
.
The petty bourgeoisie:
snivels over an upset world.
For it, the country is intolerable,
but unchangeable.
Change is necessary, but impossible.
Deeply attached to its own status
and prestige,
but quick to follow
the latest European fashions
the latest European fashions.
Satisfied by edifying speeches,
by psychologists,
and moralizing TV programs.
Buenos Aires: city that turns
its back on the country,
In the huge Rio de la Plata.
Here the statues inspire more
distrust than awe.
Seat of government of the curia,
of the press,
of Army headquarters,
and 80%  of the country's gangsters.
Here the interest in life
of the nation is concentrated.
Here monuments have been raised
to the man who said:
"These provinces want to belong
to England"
"to obey it's laws,
be subject to it's government
"Live under it's powerful influence"
CARLOS MARIA DE ALVEAR
5: THE OLIGARCHY
2 million 500 thousand,
2 million 500 thousand...
Prize champion two-year-old
Excellent quality,
wonderful expression...
very male, powerful, well-boned...
A bull of the San Juan type,
with all the qualities
A bull that belongs to the modern line.
On sale here, Pereira's
prize champion two year old..
We have an offer of 2 million pesos.
Agrarian Argentine society,
the traditional center of our Oligarchy.
Here they are  the
50 families of Buenos Aires
who have taken over
ten million acres of land
One family, the Braum Menendez Behetys,
owns 15 million acres. Here they are
2% of the cattlemen,
own 40% of the livestock.
Barely 5% of the active population
which every year makes off
with 42% of national income.
The owners of the country!
Yesterday clinging to the one-crop
system and English capital.
today associated with the
industrial bourgeoisie
and American financial capital.
87 million acres
in the hands of foreign corporations.
Our ancestors built
the country's greatness,
Furthermore, you see, our aristocracy.
in many ways resembles the European.
I remember once in London,
guest of Lord Grifford.
speaking of our aristocracy
he himself compared it
to the Polish nobility.
As in the case of one
of the Carcano girls.
who married Lord Astor.
And then the other girl, Janita Diaz.
the foundling they adopted,
who married the Duke of Luin.
We don't really have much money.
Today we're as worthless.
as a businessman who sells cloth.
And yet we have lived drinking mate
with "espinillo" or "tala" wood.
Because at one time we had soldiers,
who were great civilians.
I want you to know that General Mitre
translated Dante.
wrote poetry and was a well-known
journalist.
who invented the paper "la Nacion"
General Rocca was also
a highly educated man.
And General Augustin P Justo,
who few remember
Had the best library
of Argentine history in the country.
What do these modern folks know?
Up to a year ago you could go
to Punta del Est. But now?
Last year it was already unbearable.
There wasn't a corner not full of upstarts!
I'd like to live in the United States.
There, if you want to go out somewhere, you find
thousands of places to go, things to see
For example, you walk around Paris.
and Paris really...
if the French built it,
It's already a demonstration.
et to know Klee, and at least
3 of Miller's works.
and Saint-John Perse
and Antonio Artaud
and abstract and concrete art,
Pop and Op.
Really it's unbelievable.
She takes these country girls
into the house to work
and last time she gave them
a mattress of my sister's
Within two days she's burned it.
Now she makes her sleep on the floor.
Present, the government
really intend to straighten things out.
That's what the people need.
During all these years,
the General Confederation of Labour
promised things
and gathered in the money.
This General Confederation of Labour
is a huge enterprise.
It's actually a very powerful bank.
But what does it do with all that money.
Nothing!
The Union delegates go around
in cars and silk suits
and if you meet one on the street dressed
like that, well they're just like hicks.
You can't compare them
with a boy from a good family
raised in a prep school,
Saint George's for example,
who associates with human circles,
ethic circles, that’s the right
word ethic!.
He grows with a Christian conception
of the family and society.
you can’t compare him with
one of those sorts.
They're completely uncultured
individuals. Downright illiterate..
Generally, they either learn to write
or get someone else to write
their speeches.
They feel themselves foreigners
in their own country.
They are recalling their golden years.
La Belle Époque !
Here They are,. Yesterday they boasted
of their Spanish descent
today, of their ties with Europe
and the United States.
Here they are.
In the name of liberalism,
They have exterminated
the native population.,
They have turned the country
into a blood bath many times.
Here they are. Guilty of the violence
daily visited on the people.
much to the frustration
of many generations of Argentines.
This is their cemetery.
To crystallize history.
To stop time.
To take the past as a future.
This is the dream of the Oligarchy.
6: THE SYSTEM
The Vietnamese has only
to raise his head
to find the enemy.
For us, it is infinitely
more difficult.
Neo-Colonialism speaks our same language,
has our same skin colour,our nationality
our religion.
It is not easy to recognize the enemy.
Working in Argentina, he operates with
the greatest possibility to manoeuvre.
There would be no neo-colonialism,
If internal power factors
did not make it possible.
In our country, these factors,
are today the agrarian Oligarchy
and the big industrial bourgeoisie.
The armed forces coordinate
and legalize the policy.
The interests of all converge under
a single sign:
The system.
The system
An internal enemy that throws
open the country's doors
to neo-colonial penetration.
Courtesy missions arrive
in every city.
Hundreds of "Peace Corps" organizations
Infiltrate the rural areas.
Missionaries of all religions
swarm over the remotest parts
of every country.
Scholarships and loans
are freely awarded,
and subsidies to universities,
unions and intellectuals.
A common goal unites this infiltration:
The corruption
of the national consciousness.
to facilitate the domination
of the country.
we must unconditionally respect promises
made by our allies,
to maintain their military presence
unequalled service to the
stabilisation of the dollar,
to extend our overseas investment,
to promote our programs
of help and collaboration
in Asia and Africa,
and to reinforce
Allies favorable to the progress of
our hemisphere.
7: POLITICAL VIOLENCE
The Latin American peoples
have no chance of changing their lot
through the institutions of
bourgeois democracy.
of 20 governments, 17 are the product
of rigged elections,
or coups d'etat.
For 12 years now, the Argentine people
have lived politically outlawed.
Their majority movement, Peronism,
is illegal.
Their leader, condemned to exile.
The goal the Latin American pursues,
in his fight for liberation,
is the restitution of his humanity,
that humanity which neo-colonialism
constantly denies him
NÉO-RAClSM
The man of a dependant country
will always be for dominant nations,
a segregated man,
an underdeveloped man,
a subhuman.
of a colonized country
implies direct forms of racism.
In the dependant,
neo-colonized countries,
the forms of discrimination
are more subtle,
but just as effective.
The Argentine Oligarchy
has on many occasions ,
enforced them in the course of history.
Following Sarmiento's motto:
"Civilization of barbarity"
the first national form of
resistance was crushed,
in the massacre of
"the Monorena".
Consequently, an anti-national,
foreign civilization was imposed.
Yesterday 'gauchos' or 'montoneros'
'crilleros' or 'chusmas'
Today 'descaminados' or 'grasa'
and to a certain extent ' mersa'.
Without question,
The people have always been denied
a human dignity.
In certain rural zones of the country
racism can do without the niceties
it uses in the cities
and operate out in the open.
The Indian is worth nothing.
And it's not true because
we all have the same blood.
We have the same blood,
but speak a different language.
That's why you see me naked,
About us, the 'criollos' years ago
didn't even bother themselves.
Nobody helped us.
until today.
We used to go around with the dogs,
looking for the means to stay alive.
Or we would take an empty can
and go down the river to fish.
That was our whole life.
Nobody helped us...
because the Indian was worthless.
Only a Christian had value.
Now they think they treat us
like brothers
because they have had to accept
their own religion.
They thought they
could be done with us
that the Indian was worthless.
Just like that without any reason.
And yet we have the same blood
and walk like them.
But will the colonizer ever admit
that the blood of the man
he has colonized is the same as his?
Here, in a vast region of the country,
men, women, individuals do not exist.
There are only the survivors
of the ancient Indian tribes,
the 'mataco' , the 'coya'
the 'chulupie'.
Names that in the mouth of the master
deny the victim of exploitation
his condition as a man.
80% of the Argentine native population
has tuberculosis and syphilis
They remain men, or potential men,
who flee the movie camera
to avoid the 'criollo'
or the white man.
Interiorized, but not convinced
of their inferiority.
Men who hardly speak, who hardly sing.
9: DEPENDANCE
THOSE WHO LIVE IN RUEAL AREAS SAY
THERE ARE MOUNTAINS WHERE
THEY MINE ENDLESS GOLD.
The thing that characterizes the Latin American
countries Is their dependence.
Economic dependence, political
dependence, cultural dependence.
First Spain, then England,
now the United States.
The history of our countries is the history
of an endless colonial sack.
Political independence does not exist
without economic independence.
Jose Marti said:
"A people that wants to be free
must first be free in business".
"Dependence does not permit
any possible development,"
The apparent development
of a few cities like Buenos Aires
only translates the growing expansion
of the great powers within our economy.
Yesterday, Mitre, Pellegrini, Pinedo,
Today Prebisch, Prigerio, Alsogray.
Loans and investments,
have always been part of the same
politics of subjection.
So called imperialist aid
Is an aid that always costs
he who receives it
more than he who gives it.
For every dollar invested
in Latin America,
imperialism gets back four.
Gold and coffee, meat and oil
grain and tin:
the labour of a people
reduced to cheap manpower,
has built the wealth
of the great powers.
In this exploitation lies the cause
of the backwardness,
poverty and oppression,
that in turn guarantee the financing
and prosperity of the rich nations,
lies the origin of that obscure word
invented by imperialism:
Underdevelopment
EVERYDAY WE EXPORT MORE,
AND GET BACK THE SAME.
EVERYDAY WE WORK MORE,
ARGENTINA'S FOREIGN DEBT
IS SIX BILLION DOLLARS.
THE FOREIGN MONOPOLIES
AND THEIR LOCAL ALLIES
CONTROL ALMOST
ALL THE NATIONAL ECONOMY.
al the meat industry,
energy, oil.
cereal commerce, the chemical industry
the production of cellulose,
70% of tungsten, 92% of lead,
98% of zinc
Money, Gold
also press agencies and the mass media.
10: CULTURAL VIOLENCE
The majority of the population
in Brazil,
in Bolivia, in Peru, in Venezuela,
in Guatemala, Nicaragua,
in Haiti, the  Dominican republic,
is illiterate,
70 million people. A third of the
Latin American population
does not know how to read and write.
Illiteracy and educational colonization,
go hand in hand
In an openly colonized country,
ideological penetration is not necessary.
But in a semi colonized country,
ideological penetration
plays an essential role.
It destroys in the people
the idea of a nation,
and institutionalizes and
normalizes dependence.
The primary goal of ideological penetration
is to keep the people
from becoming aware,
from understanding their
neo-colonialized position,
and from wanting to change it.
In this form, educational colonization
effectively replaces
the colonial police.
The middle social strata
of the population
are the carriers
of neo-colonial ideology.
The university the principal instrument
of this colonization.
Behind the myth of academic freedom,
generations of students
have been led to believe
that the university an island of democracy
within an oppressed nation.
The university
is an organ of existing
political power,
designed to mould minds suited
to the system.
Behind the farce of academic freedom,
are hidden the  ideologies
that legalize Dependence:
the philosophy of the one-crop economy
liberalism,
trade, neo-colonial development,
technocratism.
All authentically national thought
has been censured or simply ignored.
Thus an intelligentsia has grown up
that has no ties with the people
or the reality of the country.
Now lets visit the Pepsi Cola Salon.
Here Manuel Mujica Lainez,
member of the Argentine Academy
of Letters
member of the National Academy of Fine Arts
is presenting his latest book:
"Royal Chronicles"
Mujica Latinez was recently awarded
the "Kennedy" Prize
and before that the National
Literature Prize
the Municipal Prize,
the Gerchunoff Prize,
and the Pen Club Prize
and the Writer's Society Prize
the most important award hereabouts
and the Gold Medal
of the Italian Government
and the decoration of the French writers
and many other awards of the 'Gerchunhoff'
type that I really don't remember.
Have you been influenced
by European culture?
Yes, a great deal. I am a man
of European formation.
Even as a child I received
a classical formation.
For that matter,
I've done some translations.
impossible without such a preparation,
It's not just a matter
of knowing English.
but of capturing the
Elizabethan spirit.
Where would you like to live?
In Venice, always,
to the very last moment.
I'd like to live there forever.
Here everything is complicated.
There everything is easier.
All those kids when they have
a vacation
they hop on a train and go to
Venice, or Vienna, Madrid, Paris
wherever they please.
They're so close to everything!
We're so far away.
so out of place!
This opinion is shared by an intelligentsia
subordinated to neo-colonial power
An elite that translates into Spanish,
the ideology of the oppressor countries.
for the petit-bourgeois intellectuals.
A hybrid, depersonalized elite,,
always hiding behind something
apoliticism or objectivism
indifference or intelligence.
11: THE MODELS
NOTHING IS MORE LOGICAL AMONG US
THAN A RACIST HUMANISM,
SINCE THE EUROPEAN HAS ONLY BEEN ABLE
TO BECOME A MAN
BY CREATING SLAVES AND MONSTERS
COMRADES, LET US NOT HONOUR EUROPE
BY CREATING STATES,INSTITUTIONS AND SOCIETIES
IN ITS IMAGE.
HUMANITY EXPECTS MORE FROM US
THAN THIS CARICATURAL
AND GENERALLY OBSCENE IMITATION.
As soon as he learns to read,
a child in a dependant country
is assailed by all the models
of a civilization
he is forced to accept as a single,
universal value
Universalizing themselves
as a class and system,
the bourgeoisie and imperialism
universalize the culture
that supports their domination.
Behind the myth of a universal culture
they have hidden, in Latin America,
their interests as a colonial class.
Hegel said:
"The best thing a child can do
with his toys is break them".
But breaking down these values,
in which one has believed
since childhood,
To maintain itself, neo-colonialism
needs to convince the people
of their inferiority.
Sooner or later, inferior man
will recognize Man with a capital M,
And this recognition will mark
the collapse of all his defenses.
If you really want to be a man,
says the oppressor
you must be like me,
speak my language,
deny your essence,
alienate yourself in me.
Neo-colonized man, the intellectual,
the artist
have value only when they are
recognized by the metropolis.
The paternalism of European culture
conceals the deeply rooted racism
of the colonizing powers.
As early as the XVII Century,
Jesuit missionaries praised
the extraordinary ability of the native
in copying European works of art.
Copyist, translator, interpreter,
at best, spectator.
Neo-colonized man will always be led
to leave his own creative capacities
untapped.
Far from assimilating and transforming
the values of other cultures
to build his own,
he gives up all efforts at research
and invention.
The result is inhibition, uprooting,
escapism, cultural cosmopolitanism,
artist imitation,
the betrayal of the country.
The model of a universal man,
with universal values,
Universal culture,
will always win out
over historical and class values.
CULTURE WILL BECOME A UNIVERSAL FACT
AT THE SERVICE OF ALL MEN
WHEN WE HAVE DESTROYED
AT THE UNIVERSAL LEVEL
IMPERIALISM AND CLASS SOCIETY
WHEN WE HAVE UNIVERSALIZED
THE COMPLETE LIBERATION OF MAN
Christ touched the sick,
the dead eyes of the blind,
and made them see.
He touched the ears of the deaf
and made them hear.
He put his hands on the cripple
and they got up and walked.
The dead came back to life.
Good men of Jerusalem
unnail those two hands gently
all powerful, merciful
you will understand
like Veronicas
who understand all the suffering
of humanity!
I see the gentleman has a ring
on his finger.
A metal ring,
And his tie?
It is green.
any question you want to ask her.
She'll receive you in private,
because naturally, there’re questions
that can't be answered in public
Madam Diana will offer ten free
consultations.
Now you can ask her a free question.
Anyone who has problems,
about money, love, health
If you have no money, Ask away.
Madam Diana will answer free.
All you need is
faith and hope.
I see the gentleman has taken
the 7 of spades.
The 7 of spades means he's not well
he's depressed.
All he has to do is ask me about it.
"Soledad!
I've finally made Pepito confess"
Now I’m going to the police
They'll know I’m innocent
"Mamma! My luck
has finally turned!"
Priests, fortune tellers,
faith healers, counselors,
astrologers, professors of morals,
Between the system and the people,
there is a network of persons
whose task is to sow confusion.
Neo-colonial violence thus
also takes on sublimated forms.
God, Fate, destiny, Immortality
are made to seem responsible
for a situation created
by the ruling classes.
12: IDEOLOGICAL WARFARE
In Latin America,
the war is waged principally
in the minds of men.
Ideological frontiers
replace conventional ones.
The means of mass communication
replace conventional weapons.
For neo-colonialism,
mass communications
are more effective than Napalm.
An army of psychologists,
sociologists
motivational analysts
try to divide and conquer
the trade unions
political and student organizations
The popular movements are
suffocated or slandered,
their leaders smeared.
Films, magazines,
the radio and periodicals
try to de-politicize the people,
to spread skepticism and escapism.
Prejudices and complexities are developed
against everything native.
People are taught to think in English.
ALL MEANS OF MASS COMMUNICATION
ARE CONTROLLED BY THE C.I.A.
CENSORSHIP ABD IDEOLOGICAL
REPRESSION ARE TOTAL
REALITY,
TRUTH,
REASON
ARE,
LIKE THE PEOPLE,
ON THE EDGE OF THE LAW.
ARTISTS AND INTELLECTUALS ARE
INTEGRATED INTO THE SYSTEM.
VIOLENCE,
CRIME,
DESTRUCTION
BECOME
PEACE,
ORDRER
NORMALITY
I am a man of European formation
universal, cosmic
We not are citizens of a country,
but of the world.
humanity, peace, love.
The 7 of Spades means he's not well
Ethic , that's the right word , ethic
Abstract art,  pop and hop,
MONSTROSITY DISGUISED AS BEAUTY
13: THE CHOICE
The Latin American peoples
are condemned peoples.
Neo-colonialism does not permit
them to choose
either their own life
or their own death.
Life and death both bear the mark
of daily violence.
This is our war.
Of hunger, of curable diseases
of premature age...
4 people a minute die in Latin America.,
5,500 a day.,
2 million a year.
This is our war!
A genocide that in 15 years,
in the First world war.
What is the only thing  left
for the Latin American?
To choose through rebellion
his own life.
and his own death.
For the man who dies in the struggle
for liberation
death is no longer the end.,
It becomes an act of liberation,
a conquest.
The man who chooses his own death
is also choosing his own life.
He is already life
and liberation itself...
In his revolutionary action,
the Latin American
recovers his existence.
The end of "Neocolonialism and
violence", First part of the film
The hour of the Furnaces X
2nd part "The time of liberation",
3rd part
"Violence and liberation",
The accounts of the Argentine people
during the 20 years preceding 1967.