COLONEL REDL
Colonel Redl's story...
is not based on
authentic documents.
Actions of the characters
are entirely fabricated.
This film was inspired
by John Osborne's play
"A Patriot for Me"...
and by historical events
of our century.
Your grandfather was friend
of his majesty, The Emperor.
The Emperor once
asked him...
"Well, my friend,
what's new?"
Like the dew
from heaven sent...
May on him
be blessings spent.
May they give the strength
for all of his deeds.
In all lands
may he glory earn...
our welfare
is his one concern.
Woe to those
who dare reject...
his hand of peace,
so circumspect.
His holy wrath
shall strike them now...
with laurels
to adorn his brow.
Very nice, young Redl.
Sit down.
Maybe you'll become a great
poet of our motherland.
l haven't heard
such a glorious poem...
about His Majesty
for a long time.
Sir, this is the boy,
Alfred Redl.
l humbly ask
for your support...
to help him enter...
the Imperial and Royal
Cadet School.
Always remember to keep
a straight posture.
We will be
so proud of you.
And we shall never forget
what the Emperor...
has done for us.
How wonderful
it would be...
if you would return
as an officer.
What an honour.
Your grandpa was just
a poor peasant.
And you suddenly
get this honour.
Never forget that the Emperor
made this possible.
Always be grateful.
Up, down, up, down,
up, down...
Hands behind your head!
Jump in place!
Up and in position.
Get ready!
Attack, defence, go!
Redl, Kubinyi! Be careful.
You'll get a beating
if you break your weapons.
Third grade,
stop the drill!
Line up in two ranks
for punishment!
Redl, Kubinyi, shirts off!
See Redl, it's snowing.
Christoph Kubinyi
reporting to his grandma...
would like to introduce
a friend.
Harry! Come here, Harry!
Don't worry, he just wants
to make friends. Good dog.
Sit down! Sit down!
Tell me Redl, our Monarch's
empire is so vast...
I've a hard time telling...
which of the many people
of our Majesty you belong to.
- l was born in Galicia.
- Polish?
No, my father is Ukrainian,
partly of German descent.
l believe my mother's
grandfather was Hungarian.
Yes, they were Hungarians.
The family was noble
but lost everything.
Their entire estate.
But later His Majesty
helped them...
and gave them a position
in the Civil Service.
Fine.
Then you certainly have
Hungarian blood in you.
Yes, my mother would always
sing a Hungarian song.
A Csitari Hegyek Alatti.
He is very nice!
He doesn't speak
French, grandma.
He has to learn it,
sweetie.
It's as important
as horseback riding.
But horses are the most
important, aren't they?
He is charming,
your little friend.
Come on up, Christoph,
it's a good view.
Yes, but do l have to
climb the tree for that?
You smell good, soldier,
like a foal.
Are you ticklish?
Let's see.
One, two, three, four...
five, six, seven...
eight, nine, ten, eleven.
Could you please help me?
Katalin!
What can we expect
from civilians...
if soldiers act like
animals? Is this a zoo?
Class raise!
- Are you the orderly?
- Yes, sir.
Who was it? File a report,
l want names.
I'm sorry, Colonel,
l don't know who it was.
But l do, Cadet Redl.
l know the name.
Christoph von Kubinyi.
Sir, I'm sure
it wasn't him.
- Who then?
- l don't now, l was singing.
Redl, report. Are they
the usual gentlemen?
Von Freyberg, Galliena,
von Gencsy, von Kubinyi?
No, it wasn't
Kubinyi, sir.
Who then? Redl,
I'm losing my patience.
Then l am forced to expel
all four of then...
led by Baron Kubinyi...
because of this
outrageous incident.
- l think it was von Gencsy.
- Very good, Redl.
You'll be a loyal soldier
to His Majesty.
You are a bright
peasant boy.
Dismissed!
Judas!
l am a Judas.
l am not a soldier.
Those over there
are soldiers.
l am a treacherous peasant.
Colonel Feldhauer wants to
see Cadet Redl in his office.
Well... l have to
tell you something.
Redl, you father has died.
Here's the telegram.
You'll get leave of course.
lf you should need anything...
money for the journey or
a wreath for the grave...
please tell me.
You can count on me.
Colonel, may l ask for
permission to stay here...
l want to take part
in His Majesty's...
name-day celebration.
Now that Emperor
Franz Josef the First...
has become your godfather
and by the bond...
of our Holy Church,
you have become his sons.
Our Father, Franz Josef.
You may call him that
from this day forward...
with humble pride
and the right to do so.
By the sacrament
of confirmation...
you're accepted
as his sons.
This will make the bond
between you all...
between you and the army...
between you and His Majesty
even more indissoluble.
May your filial gratitude,
your filial loyalty...
preserve this bond
with the Lord God...
with your Emperor and your
Motherland for all eternity.
Why has Detachment D...
still not rejoined
the main troop?
Lt. Schorm! Send an adjutant
to find out the reason.
l want a report.
The medical personnel
is still in the valley!
Lt. Hidegkuti! l ordered
the reserves into action...
to break through the enemy
lines and occupy section QX.
QX, yes sir.
Alright, then.
Colonel, the enemy lines have
been attacked and taken.
Good, Redl.
You have executed this tactical
exercise perfectly.
This is a command post,
not the Officer's Club...
Where we smoke and watch
friends play pool.
Lt. Schorm.
The other ranks out there
may not smoke either.
Smoking is forbidden
on manoeuvres. Carry on.
Lt. Schorm, give the order
to finish.
Yes sir, order to finish.
Colonel, l gave Lt. Schorm
permission to smoke.
That was an error, Captain.
Self-control always
and everywhere.
We shouldn't have
compromised...
with the Ungarians in 1867.
Why not take
the whole country...
as the English did Ireland?
Without that, Austria wouldn't
be a great power now.
Vienna curbed us,
thanks to our politicians.
Kubinyi's lamenting the fate of
oppressed Hungarians again.
But he forgets
that Hungary, too...
oppresses it's
neighbouring peoples.
Everything has its price.
Arad and Haynau, generals
executed like criminals!
Come on, Kubinyi...
The compromise
was a great deed.
Redl, you look so sad.
- Perhaps because of you.
- Don't be sad because of me.
Let's drink to the health
of Captain Redl.
- Let's drink to it!
- Do you like him?
- Yes, he's very nice.
- You hear, old man?
She likes you, so drink!
Drink from the bottle.
What l put in my hand,
l put in my mouth.
Should l hold it?
This Redl was born
in Lemberg, wasn't he?
And you in Pomerania.
- You think it's all the same?
- It damn well is!
Oh, you are a cosmopolitan.
No, Hungarian. Secondly,
an officer and Redl's friend.
What did His Majesty say?
"The Hungarians,
a beloved nation!"
Are you trying
to provoke me?
No, why should l?
Let's go.
Baron, are you being
unfaithful to me?
Indeed.
Jealous?
l don't know you yet,
but it can soon be arranged.
Do you wanna come with me,
or prefer to sit and stare?
Have you ever done it?
Or is your biggest thrill
to shout at you soldiers?
What's special about Kubinyi
that make you all crazy?
He not only knows how to do,
he likes doing it.
- What?
- Everything.
- Then teach me, too.
- You can't teach that.
- You have it, or not.
- Kubinyi is handsome.
And wonderful.
What do you like best?
His hairy behind?
Yes. He has a lovely
little rock-hard bottom.
And muscular thighs.
Just like a little boy.
One has something
to hold on to.
- The scar on his knee?
- Yes, l like that, too.
How does he do it?
Quickly? Slowly? Rough...
- or gentle?
- Is he gentle?
No, he comes in, grabs hold
of me and my breasts...
and he bites.
And l bite him, too.
So, he bites?
And you?
How do you want to do it?
Are you really related?
Then watch how your
big brother does it.
It happens during a parade.
I'll rode up
to colonel von Roden...
and report to him
on horseback.
l said: "One, my mother's
parents were Jewish.
Two, my father was
a Jew from Budapest."
Just imagine
von Roden's face.
At a parade,
with all sorts...
of distinguished
people present.
Consuls, Attachés
and the Goszleth.
Daughters,
Dominika and Daniela.
Alfred, I'll tell it
to them straight one day.
Don't you think they know
you're a Jew?
I'm not just a Jew.
I'm a Hungarian Jew.
We can talk about it,
not just in whispers.
My father fought for Hungarian
freedom and was exiled.
My father played cards with
the Rabbi of Lemberg.
They were good friends.
How about becoming a Jew?
It would be much simpler.
All right, then I'm a Jew.
It's all the same.
You know, l think your
holidays are beautiful.
Yom Kippur, Passover...
Redl, I'm very fond of you.
You're so wildly ambitious.
Let's fight about
the Goszleth daughters.
Would you please
look at these drawings.
Who do they represent?
Or it's hard to identify?
You're famous for your
observation.
This one? Lt. Beatz?
- No.
- But?
- Captain Tannhoffer.
- And this handsome face?
- Kubinyi.
- And him?
That's myself.
- Continue please.
- Dr. Sonnenschein.
- Jaromil Schorm.
- Schorm? Jaromil?
Tell me, this lieutenant
here, is he a invert?
Excuse me?
- l mean homosexual.
- Not that l know.
Bohemian? Jew?
Major, l suggest you
to ask him yourself.
A straight question
will get a straight answer.
Your an idealist.
This is about debt-ridden
officers.
Who will protect the army
in the event of war?
This article appeared
in a Prague newspaper...
written by one "senior."
Do you know who hides
behind this name?
Your direct inferior,
Jaromil Schorm.
He belongs to the army,
but talks about us.
Corruption, debt, cards,
booze, whores!
He writes that,
in the event of war...
the army would need
protection.
Schorm.
Senior... Senior!
Well...
tell me Captain, do you
still play the piano?
At Cadet school l took
lessons with Captain Ruzek.
Alright.
Keep an eye on Schorm.
In due time,
l want a report.
Tell me...
can you make me a list,
by this afternoon...
of the officers'
local contacts?
This Schorm!
Keep him out of my sight!
He will be fired!
A disgusting object!
Outside the Club other day!
This look, this deceit...
And you supported him.
He provokes me
in my own regiment.
We absolutely
cannot afford...
to be exposed
to attacks like this!
l detest traitors, Captain.
Making me sick!
Kick him out...
or let him go voluntarily.
Just get him out of here!
You will do that.
And one more thing, Redl...
tell your friend Kubinyi,
to stop his '48 tirades.
l don't want any criticism
of the compromise, alright?
Why does he always mention
Haynau when he drinks?
Haynau's been dead
for years!
Haynau is not the Monarchy.
We are the Monarchy!
And so is Kubinyi.
We couldn't object to the
articles if they were true.
But they are false.
I'm ashamed that an officer
express himself in this way.
He lives among us,
accepts the privileges...
of uniform and rank,
laughs and swears like us...
and then it turns out,
he's not one of us.
Instead of talking to us,
he spies on us secretly...
and denounces us
under a false name.
Schorm must face
the consequences...
and leave those
he's betrayed.
Taking notes, Schorm?
l could dictate for you.
Gentlemen,
in my own name...
and that of the
officers regiment...
l suggest that Lt. Schorm,
at his own request...
should leave the
regiment and the army.
Schorm, l...
Go voluntarily. You can
state the reasons yourself.
Yes.
Gentlemen, is this a big
moment or a small one?
l can't tell.
- This is not a cabaret!
- You're right, doctor.
Brief and soldierly.
What's going on? Has our
Bohemian gone crazy?
Schorm, if you expect
a certificate...
saying that you've
gone insane...
which l personally agree,
you're mistaken. No!
Lieutenant,
name your seconds.
l consider the desecration
of His Majesty uniform...
a personal insult.
l therefore challenge you
to a duel!
Shooting?
You're near-sighted.
Want to fence?
But don't confuse fencing
with an appendectomy.
Don't take this personally,
but everybody knows that...
doctors who join the army
aren't the best ones.
Summa cum laude, you jerk.
Who will be my seconds?
I'm not fighting you.
I'm the third-best shooter
in the regiment.
Allow me to send
for my civilian clothes.
The duel takes place
at dawn.
I'll choose my seconds
among you.
Sonnenschein,
l said there won't be a duel.
l will take off my uniform.
But l can't duel
with a Jewish doctor.
You're not from whom one
may expect satisfaction.
And me, Schorm?
Do l meet your
high requirements?
Baron Kubinyi...
yes, you do.
But gentlemen,
this is really...
Done!
Tomorrow at dawn.
With a bullet, since you're
such a fine shooter.
3 steps, 3 exchanges.
Redl, you're my second.
Excuse me.
l hate early rising.
I'd prefer noon
or afternoon.
But honour come first.
Pistols at dawn, then.
- Those articles, Schorm...
- I'm sorry.
You were such
an excellent soldier.
The duel is nonsense.
- Let it go.
- l didn't force it.
- Then I'll lock you up.
- It's too late, Captain.
I'm duelling as a civilian
with Kubinyi.
Lock him up, if you fear
for his life.
The army is not
dismissing you.
You are leaving the army.
- In two or three years...
- Two or three years?
Where will
this army be then?
It will be at its post
and so will l.
Do you know what l hate
most about this army?
Getting up so damned early.
- Who's there? Who is it?
- Redl.
It's you, Schorm.
l thought it was you.
Sorry.
- You're here early.
- Yes.
l couldn't sleep.
- Could you?
- l never sleep well.
Kubinyi probably
sleep like a dog.
Don't underestimate him.
Cigarette?
No, thanks.
He overestimates himself.
- You are full of energy.
- And you?
l don't belong with you.
What do you mean?
l want to remain
Jaromil Schorm.
l don't understand.
l can't take leading
a double life...
everyone playing
their part perfectly.
Sickening. All of it.
l still don't understand.
Tell me, Schorm...
are you really
a anti-Semite?
My grandmother is Jewish.
l hope that's sufficient.
l shouldn't have
insulted him.
l just enjoyed keeping
that Jew at a distance.
- Very possible.
- Not really my style.
- You play with people.
- No, you do.
Me?
Why me?
You're demanding
too much of yourself.
- What else can l do?
- Well, you might be right.
Maybe we haven't talked
enough to each other.
- Why couldn't you sleep?
- l don't know.
l think l had a dream.
- Do you believe in dreams?
- No.
Or do l?
It is cold.
Yes.
- The weapons?
- Here they are.
- Redl will tell his dream.
- That's not of interest now.
- Gentlemen...
- Please, go on.
l ask you to discuss
your disagreement...
and use your weapons
symbolically.
l guarantee
complete secrecy.
Until then, l shall leave
the gymnasium.
Redl, stay!
Gentlemen, l am ready.
l think we must
get the doctor.
Yes.
- Was Schorm your friend?
- No, Colonel.
lf your part in this incident
is known...
- it will harm your career.
- I'm aware of my position.
We have decided to act
discreetly.
Thank you, Colonel.
With Kubinyi, it's
a different story.
He's been in trouble
before.
However, he survives such
incidents more easily.
Redl, l must say...
you were only a second,
but that was a grave error.
Never get involved in
anything like this again.
Yes, Colonel.
Do you think an officer
without family connections...
remains unnoticed?
Is that your opinion, Redl?
I'm convinced the army
seldom allows merit...
to go unacknowledged.
Correct, Redl,
and for obvious reasons.
The future of the Monarchy
and Europe...
- depends on the army.
- I've noticed that...
officers who complain
about privilege...
are of average ability,
mostly below that.
Exactly. A good soldier
always recognizes another.
That's the basis
of comradeship.
Redl, as a Commander...
l must inform
to the War Ministry...
about officers
of outstanding merit.
Your merits have surpassed
your present rank.
Here's your promotion
to Major.
And here's your order
to report to Vienna.
His Majesty has
appointed you...
second-in-command
of a garrison.
It's a pity, it had to arrive
on this unfortunate day.
Nevertheless,
congratulations.
Thank you, Colonel.
It means a great deal to me.
After all, l trained you.
That's the way it is.
A wallet and a briefcase.
l had them made in Vienna.
A.R.
l grew very fond of you,
my son.
Dismissed!
Colonel...
I'd like to take
Lt. Von Kubinyi with me.
He's a good soldier.
An odd team, you two.
I'm not sure it will
help you, but...
It can be arranged
through his...
family connections
in Vienna.
- Katalin, did you see him?
- Who?
The Emperor,
admiring the view?
He has a hunting
lodge here.
The Emperor!
What if we'd stopped
to greet him?
What would you have said?
"Major Redl
begs to report?"
I'd have wished him good
health and a long life.
Wait, turn in to the Inn.
I'm tired, Major.
We'll take a room.
l can't believe l saw
the Emperor today.
Come here.
Horse and saddle,
a fine soldierly smell.
Christoph never smells
like a soldier.
Do you smell
the soldier on him?
Me?
Here you are, madam.
Soldier,
uncork the champagne.
I've made a lovely,
big bridal bed for us.
What will your husband say
if you don't come home?
I'm sleeping at my mother.
You're my witness.
I've neither time
nor inclination...
to be a gracious
society hostess.
l like riding,
eating, drinking.
Why don't you have
any children?
We just don't.
l can't stand
my husband anymore.
Shall l marry you? Do you
want a pretty Kubinyi?
You deserve it.
Let's drink.
Why do you close your eyes?
l don't know.
Are you thinking of
someone else?
Yes.
- Christoph?
- Yes.
Were you always
thinking of him?
Whom do you love more?
Whom?
- I'm very fond of you both.
- And now?
l feel fine, but l don't
know for how long.
You know,
Christoph and l...
we're...
actually,
I'm afraid of him.
- But now you're over him.
- No.
You're wonderful Katalin.
l like touching you.
l have nobody l can
embrace, just you.
Don't forget, you're here
in Galicia...
not by the Adriatic.
We have many Poles, Jews,
gypsies, thieves and whores.
Be on your guard.
Many of them smuggle vodka
across the border.
We are right at the border,
not Bad Ischl or Alt-Ausee.
There's so little to do...
the officers
go hunting for chamois.
You get my meaning.
Lt. Ehrlich reporting.
Manoeuvres proceeding
according to plan.
Major, Lt. Mészaros
reporting.
Manoeuvres proceeding
as planned.
Throw grenades!
Up!
Fire! Throw grenades!
Up! Stop! Go back!
Didn't you instruct your men
in the use of grenades...
unexploded grenades
or those falling short?
Assemble the platoon!
Throw away your cigarette.
Repeat the regulations.
I'm sorry, l don't know
them all.
Not all? Item one?
Item two? Three? Five?
Your order, officer?
- A schnapps, please.
- Coming right up, Major.
You get many officers here,
don't you?
- How did you guess?
- You knew my rank.
You recognize ranks when
you're as old as me...
but you never know people.
I'll get your drink.
- And vodka?
- No, that's contraband.
Maybe a glass of aquavit?
We're serving His Majesty
on the Russian border.
We're not here to impress
or chase the women...
play pool and get drunk,
on duty or on manoeuvres.
I'm referring
to Lt. Schinszky.
Our men blow
themselves up...
due to a lack of
grenade instruction.
Lt. Mészaros is not here
to fall off his horse...
drunk at 11 am.
Contraband vodka,
drunk at the Inn...
where you go to keep warm,
while your men train outside.
And by noon you are kept in
the saddle by their horses.
We are not here to dishonour
the Emperor's uniform...
by making deals
with civilians...
like Kferrer and Halmi...
getting involved
in God knows what.
We're not here to seduce
a girl a week...
meaning raping her
in the woods.
Like a poor servant-girl
who dares not say a word...
for everyone would believe
the almighty officer.
Almighty officers, indeed!
Officers of the Monarchy...
must set a good example
so the people trust us...
and know the Emperor
will protect them.
My question is,
does the Monarchy...
need each one of you
personally...
here in this garrison?
Answer the question
yourselves. I'm waiting.
lf you think your presence
here has a meaning...
then you know
that with your rights...
you have certain
obligations.
Only then can you
claim privileges.
You need not be
Imperial Army officers.
The post office
or the railways...
guarantees a pension.
Colonel Ruzitska wishes to
see you in the conservatory.
Colonel?
l have bad news
for you, Redl.
When did you
last see Mészaros?
This afternoon,
during the manoeuvres.
- He has deserted.
- Really?
To the Russians.
Tonight at six he appeared on
the other side of the barrier.
And shouted
to our soldiers...
"Say 'hello' to Mr. Ruzistka
and Redl for me!"
And then he did this.
I've had enough of
the Russians border.
I'm applying
for retirement.
I'd like to recommend you
as District Commandant.
You have a great future.
l was no more than a troop
commander. That's fate.
One doesn't necessarily have
to be on the General Staff.
These damned Habsburgs!
l hate this Habsburgs,
do you hear? l hate them!
What do you think of them?
Maybe you think
they're wonderful.
But I'm drunk tonight,
so l must tell you honestly.
You can have them.
l hate them!
Galicia and Cracow would
join Poland so fast...
Vienna would be left
gasping.
And our Monarchy?
It would vanish
from the map of Europe.
This Empire can only
be saved by war.
But after so many
lost battles...
the senile Emperor
has to go first.
Are you crazy?
Trying to play switchman,
are you?
I'm forced to put you on
increased duty for one week.
Dismissed.
- Yes.
- It's Alfred.
Are you busy?
- What do you want?
- To talk.
I'm expecting someone
who wouldn't like to see you.
Duty inspection.
- Major, the password please.
- "Schenitterin ruht."
- Who is the duty officer?
- Lt. Kubinyi, sir.
Where is he? Where?
He fell asleep
in the cafeteria.
- Why didn't you wake him?
- l did.
- Why isn't he here then?
- He said, sir...
he told me to go to hell.
I'll take over.
A serious breach of duty.
At war, you would be
court-martialled.
- Understood, Lieutenant?
- Yes, Colonel.
I'm now forced to
transfer you.
Within 24 hours you'll report
to Helmut Haynert...
at the War Ministry.
He already knows.
Your future
will be decided in Vienna.
Oh, you fools.
Dismissed.
A farewell drink.
I'm almost sorry for you.
l wonder if Redl's a Jew...
but instead of a caftan,
he wears uniform.
A great camouflage.
Redl will soon be
on the General Staff.
A Jew on the General Staff?.
Our top moron already is
in the hands...
of the Rothschild family.
l didn't thank Redl
for this trip.
Watch him, he might be
useful to us.
Go away.
Get lost!
Go!
Go away!
What do you want from me?
Major, may l ask you,
are you also a Jew?
Through your mother?
Several people have say so.
l also heard, you don't like
to mention it.
Maybe you're right.
l won't tell anyone.
My heart's just overjoyed.
- May l sit down, Major?
- Please.
lf you excuse me, Major...
my wife would like to
invite you...
to our Friday night supper.
Lt. Ehrlich feels quite
at home with us, too.
A large family and
beautiful children, Major.
Don't!
Don't touch me!
l have to warn you,
Lt. Ehrlich...
and all other gentlemen,
including our doctor...
that close contact with
the Jews is to be avoided.
Our supreme Commander,
His Majesty...
allows Jewish soldiers...
to entry into the Officer
Corps of the Royal Army.
lf most comfortable with
junk merchants in a caftan...
you shouldn't be
in uniform.
There's something else.
Some of the Jews here...
no, let's say
most of the Jews here...
have trading connections
with Jews across the border.
Vodka, fabrics, God knows
what else is being smuggled.
We suspect that information
is traded as well...
gathered from some
officer during...
the family's
gefilte fish dinner.
We must decide.
Either you're an officer
of the Imperial Army...
or a Slovak...
or a Ukrainian...
or a Jew.
Dear Sonnenschein,
old doctor.
l haven't hear from you
for awhile.
A woman wants to see you.
She said she's your sister.
- What does she look like?
- She's elderly.
- Tell her I'm busy.
- Yes, sir.
Hold on! Send her in.
- Alfred?
- Soferl!
Soferl, what are you
doing here?
Mother sends her love.
We heard you were here.
- From whom?
- A soldier, Schilhanek's son.
Yes, mother sends her love.
Ilse and the children, too.
Magda has moved
with her husband.
- Are there any problems?
- No more than usual.
Something important
to tell me?
No.
Please. You need money?
- No.
- Take it.
l can give you every month.
I'll send it to you...
or I'll bring it myself.
l don't mind.
Here.
Please don't ever
come here again.
You can't do that.
These are barracks!
This isn't like
a post office.
You shouldn't come here
using my name.
No.
Now l have to...
Take it. Put it away.
- Christoph is really hurt.
- I'm the one that's hurt.
He said and did things
l couldn't accept...
as an officer
or his friend.
Alfred, don't be ridiculous.
Stop lying to me.
Stop pretending
for your own sake.
The concept of the Monarchy
is good.
l can't imagine anything
better in its place.
The Emperor's old
and makes mistakes.
Some reforms are due.
But l must show
that from where l stand...
The Monarchy isn't
crumbling, but strong.
lf a few others
felt like me...
things wouldn't depend on
the old man alone.
Then we could save
this Monarchy.
Everything l can do,
l shall do.
And what do you
want to do?
And you wonder
why people hate you?
l know everything...
everything about them.
l can strike them down
whenever l like.
Gentlemen, will you please
line up according to rank.
By rank, l don't necessarily
mean military rank.
l assume you know your
closeness to Vienna...
although that can change.
The lower ranks should
line up according to height.
Short people first.
There's no disgrace.
The Heir-Apparent
isn't tall, either.
Neither am l, so obviously
no disadvantage here.
When the Archduke enters,
we stand to attention.
Receive decorations,
head high.
At his handshake,
bow your head.
You won't lose it just yet.
Line up now according to
your rank and position...
facing the door.
They're coming.
I'm glad l did transfer
you here. l really trust you.
The decisive factor was
you not belonging...
to any fraction.
We must do our duty,
independently...
and do the best
of our ability.
Your task is to modernize
military intelligence.
You've done excellent work,
but largely as an amateur.
From now on, you're
the number one specialist.
lf you have any problems,
come to me and I'll help.
And when you become
War Minister...
I'll let raise my pension.
Just one more advice.
Choose subordinates
who have...
reason to look up to you.
Men who are grateful to you,
because you selected them.
l welcome you as members
of this newly formed office.
Please get to know
each other.
Don't be bothered that you
speak different tongues.
Your task will be
in the provinces...
with people whose language
you know.
Our mutual task is
to preserve and protect...
the strength
of the Monarchy.
Whatever we say or don't say
in order to reach our goal...
is not lie,
but our mission. Duty.
We must know everything
about everyone.
The smallest town
holds people we need.
It's up to us entirely
to find them.
Suitable types abound, nearly
everyone is susceptible.
Details of our work
are strictly confidential.
lf you are successful...
you'll be praised by
nobody but me.
Mistakes, nobody will defend
you, the same goes for me.
But we belong to a group...
whose hand is on the pulse
of the Monarchy...
and can make decisions
in its interest.
This trust, after long
and careful consideration...
was lent to you.
Lent, not given.
As hard as it was to gain
this trust...
as easy it is to lose it.
To lose everything.
That's power.
Note everything about
every officer.
Who was he with? Where?
What did they talk about?
How much they spend, what
they like, their passions.
Which officers are
regular customers.
Name, rank and garrison.
Redl, Albert.
Career driven, concerned
only with his own welfare.
Likes to be considered
an aristocrat.
Admires power
and often stresses...
his gratitude
to the Habsburgs.
No contact with
his family...
and sister,
resident in Lemberg.
Poses.
Insincere.
It's not pleasant for me
to repeat this question...
but Marshall Korad asked me
if you're homosexual.
And if l think it odd...
that even the Archduke
has made inquiries.
What do you say?
They're plotting
against you already.
Unless it's a plot
against me.
They don't dare touch me,
so they starting with you...
because they know
that I'm backing you.
That's the world around you.
Take stock of it.
I've got the impression
you make enemies easily.
Avoid that
whenever possible.
For my sake, too.
You should marry.
That would calm people down.
I'll introduce you to a girl
from a good Viennese family.
Or we'll pack our bags
and go to America.
Should we?
We may face an offensive
in the Balkans.
The Emperor wants peace.
He knows what war would do
to the Monarchy.
Yet he makes bad mistakes.
He puts in key positions...
men who represent
everything he fears.
The Archduke works
openly against him...
and he pretends
not to notice.
When the Emperor dies...
the Monarchy
will fall to pieces.
Look at this here,
from an earlier empire.
What does remain?
Stop that!
That civilian suit is the
greatest lie in your life.
l know.
Are you coming?
Of course.
Alfred.
Yes, I'm coming.
Welcome, Lt. Colonel.
May l check your uniform,
according to regulations?
Colonel, your sword, please.
Thank you.
Kindly wait a moment.
- Kubinyi.
- Hello, Redl.
l thought you were
in St. Petersburg.
I'm now on General Staff
for Hungarian affairs.
lf you need anything
from that area...
please come to me first.
And if l can do anything...
l don't snoop
on fellow officers.
Take care.
Lt. Colonel, His Imperial
Highness is expecting you.
Imperial Majesty...
Colonel Alfred Redl
begs to report.
Colonel Redl. I'm glad
we can have a talk.
I've heard so much
about you.
How do you like
your position?
Thank you, Imperial Highness.
l have a lot to do.
And l like to work.
Do you enjoy the power
in your hands?
Sometimes?
Just for a moment?
What l feel rather
is the weight of my task.
They say your loyalty
is unshakeable...
and based on gratitude.
You want to serve and
prove yourself, am l right?
l am deeply honoured,
if they say that about me.
You're a good
toll-collector, then.
You won't side with those
who've gained eminence...
by their noble blood.
Are you Catholic?
Yes.
We understand each other.
People say things
about me, too.
I've read your reports.
You write very well.
Or rather, convincingly.
You like to work hard...
like in Galacia, where
you proved your ability.
We'll see whether you are
just as talented here.
We have to focus on the
interests of our Manarchy.
World becomes dangerous.
Army morale is shaky.
The Imperial Army has begun
to resemble a casino...
playing pool, drinking
and chasing women, right?
Yes, unfortunately.
The spirit of liberalism
undermines everything.
Please, sit down.
In such a situation...
one has to make a clean
sweep to restore order.
Don't stand there,
sit down.
The army must be as rock-hard
as ice on a frozen lake.
Your Highness,
fish swim under the ice.
We must take
lasting examples...
as your previous
activity proved.
We must arrange some actions
that will shake the army...
to take clear to all that
the liberalism must end.
The Emperor must see that
an effective army...
needs a new spirit.
In my view, the people
of the Monarchy...
must be shown a distinct
face of the enemy.
The picture of
a common enemy...
who threatens them.
The feeling of fear,
you see...
is the only thing
that makes an army tough.
Think it over, Colonel.
Check your files and submit
a suggestion to me, soon.
It should relate
to the Balkan...
and the action
of Russian forces.
Or possible French.
You have full authority.
How long have you known
Colonel von Komjathy?
Since l was in the 32nd
Maria Theresia Regiment.
Cognac? Grappa? Liquor?
What would you like?
Cognac, please, if l may.
Who are the confidants
of Colonel von Komjathy?
Komjathy?
I'm sorry, l can't remember.
Thank you.
l thought you were
a bright peasant boy.
Think it over.
Will one afternoon
be sufficient...
to give me
an accurate list...
of officers relations
in your garrison?
The building material
contract...
for the Przemysl fortress
was signed by Ullman.
The engineer responsible
was Worowka.
To whom did you pass
on the material?
Whom did you hand
the material? Where?
And how?
There are five cases at our
disposal, unfortunately...
each case amounts to
high treason.
l suggest
we remove a case...
from the military court
and make it public.
With special reference...
to the equality
guilty environment.
We do it so spectacularly...
that it creates tension
throughout the army...
and among the civilian
population.
l suggest a public trial
with press coverage...
and many witnesses.
The idea is excellent,
Redl.
It all depends on
the person accused.
l suggest either the case
of Max von Dornheim...
or Colonel György von
Komjathy, from Budapest.
Please.
Look, Lt. Colonel.
This trial must show
the army and the officers...
that the enemy's
in our ranks...
and that we'll
strike down anyone...
who neglects his duty.
At the same time, we must
show the whole world...
a united and strong
Austro-Hungarian army.
That's politics.
So, the accused
cannot be Austrian...
certainly not
Austrian aristocrat.
It'd weaken the trust
in the leadership.
He cannot be Hungarian...
since we live
in a dual Monarchy.
We don't want to irritate
the enemy within.
Also cannot be a Czech.
They keep demonstrating.
Too many
independence movements.
They would see
as a provocation.
It certainly can't be
a Jew.
The Dreyfus affair
enraged all of Europe.
We'd stir up an international
storm of indignation...
and upset the Emperor's
important links...
with the Rothschild bank.
And finally...
no Serb or Croat.
That zone is too hot and
must be tackled otherwise.
You have Hungarian
blood in you?
Ukrainian.
That's what we need,
a Ukrainian.
Look for a duplicate
of yourself, Redl.
I'd have to search Galicia.
Then look there.
Similar background,
career and connections.
That can't be a problem
for you.
You have files
on everyone...
with your
wide network of agents.
What happened?
I'm included in the
Archdukes schemes.
The bullets are whistling
past my ears.
Colonel, we have
the answer for you.
Dismissed.
Salapska! Salapska!
Were you asleep?
l need a special train
from the Ministry...
and notify
Commandant Lemberg...
to put Victor Ullman
under surveillance.
But not open action before
my arrival. Immediately.
Good evening.
- Are you Victor Ullman?
- Yes. How can l help you?
l must speak to you
in private.
- Why?
- Please come.
- This way.
- Go ahead.
Excuse me.
- Salapska.
- András!
Give me the keys to the
safe and your desk.
- May l have an explanation?
- l am searching the premises!
l could fabricate evidence
and nobody would ever know.
But l don't want to.
The key.
- l won't tolerate this!
- Give me the key. Major...
take Mr. Ullman next door.
I'll interrogate him later.
By the way, where's
the engineer Worowka?
l don't know.
In Vienna, l presume.
András!
Take him away.
Przemysl.
Major, make a list of
all firms, all engineers...
and their army partners.
Possible private contacts
aside from business relations.
But first a telegram
to the Vienna police.
"Find and arrest
engineer Worowka."
- Put it back, please.
- Leave me alone.
I'll have to handcuff you,
if you don't.
Stop! Don't move.
Stop!
Get a doctor, quick!
Heir-Apparent.
"Christoph Kubinyi,
St. Petersburg."
Turn right, please.
Right, l said.
Announce me to the General.
The General is retired
since yesterday.
The chief of the General Staff
handles all open cases.
Understand.
l understand.
Please allow me,
Imperial Highness...
to question
Major Christoph Kubinyi.
What about?
I'm sure that
engineer Worowka...
and army supplier
Victor Ullman...
conspired to pass plans
of the Przemysl fortress...
to Petersburg.
Galicia again.
Have you arrested them?
No. Ullman
committed suicide...
and Worowka
was murdered in Vienna.
Once you go into action,
death follows.
Przemysl. What do you want
to know from Kubinyi?
lf Ullman had any military
diplomatic contacts.
Tell me, Redl...
are you a cruel man?
Imperial Highness,
l am doing my duty.
- What faith?
- As l told you, I'm Catholic.
- Do you like children?
- Yes, but my wife is ill.
Excuse the questions.
l just wonder why Roden
always backed you.
Because you graduated
with honours...
and you're
a good mathematician?
l see no point
in you interrogating...
members of the
General Staff...
or harassing our
most reliable men.
But this concerns
high treason.
l shall decide
who is the traitor!
Przemysl is of minimal
military importance.
The guilty have sentenced
themselves. Case closed.
You haven't succeeded
this time.
A dead duplicate
is no duplicate.
Spin your web better
and do it faster...
or will von Kubinyi
replace a Ukrainian?
- He's not like you.
- But you misunderstand me.
l don't misunderstand you.
Open your eyes when you
look for the enemy, Redl.
You're not senile yet...
like this Roden with
his watery eyes.
Whom we finally managed...
to put into well-earned
retirement.
You admired him, or not?
Your Highness, he indeed
was a bit emotional.
Look, Redl.
The Emperor's Waltz
isn't danced anymore.
War is coming.
Can we avoid it? Maybe.
However, the Monarchy
needs a spectacular case.
A bit of a fright.
A few days of threat and
fear, then a quick victory.
War, then?
A retaliation for some
assassination.
Then a small, local war
for a couple of weeks...
to save what can be saved.
Mr. Redl. This profile
an extremely ruthless type.
But something about it
suggests sensuality.
- Slavic face.
- Yes, the cheekbones.
Looking at this photo,
clearly a brutal personality.
Lt. Colonel Redl.
First we'll promote him.
The whole thing
is monstrous treason.
The Archduke plans a military
coup, to seize power himself.
He doesn't believe
in the old Monarchy.
The only one who does
is the Emperor.
l hate politics!
l hate politicians!
My world, yes, my world.
Today l wish it would
fall apart.
A quick hero's death. Done.
Then we're even,
the Monarchy and l.
I'm forty. Do l admit that
I've been on the wrong side...
when all other possibilities
are just as miserable?
Nothing matters, Alfred,
only life itself.
To breathe this wonderful
morning air.
It's no sin to be involved.
It's a sin to remain involved.
Montaigne.
l learned it
in my French Class.
Why do you keep this?
- l wanna know what he thinks.
- About you?
l can't prevent
what's brewing up.
What l wanted to defend
doesn't exist.
l dreamt my father
sat on my shoulders...
pressing me into the earth.
You no more about me
than anyone else.
lf you ever misuse that...
I'll shoot you.
Colonel,
it's a masked ball.
Even for me?
Yes, until midnight,
for everyone.
Colonel Redl, whom we all
tear. And your wife?
Unfortunately,
in a sanatorium.
- May we ask why?
- A shadow on the lung.
l wish her
a speedy recovery.
Good evening.
lf there were an explosion
in this room now...
it'd be the solution
for Europe.
And would we be
inside or outside?
Trieste will fall to the
Italians, so don't buy it.
Every battalion's safe
has an envelope...
with the secret
mobilization order.
Colonel Redl?
What do you say to that?
l heard that Austria-Germany,
not Hungary...
will save the Habsburgs.
Katalin, dear...
excuse me.
Would you introduce that
Esterhazy to my daughter?
We'll meet later.
Yes, but the Germans are
in Silesia.
The Ukrainians will join
the Russians.
They prefer the Tsar.
l couldn't think of any
other reaction from them.
Pardon me.
Long live to the Habsburgs,
even it might not be long.
And to the army of course.
It is midnight.
All masks are falling!
Alfred, may introduce
our new guest.
- Tenente Velocchio.
- Alfredo Velocchio.
Redl.
The most important thing
for me is...
that you love me...
protect me and trust me.
All my life I've been weak.
l need your help.
Tell me what to do.
Tell me how to be.
Cynical, maybe?
Why cynical?
You don't believe in the
whole thing, but you go on.
You said war is coming,
but you'll lose it anyway.
Am l supposed
to seize power?
Enough officers
share my views.
Should we support
the Emperor...
who is old
and may be dying?
It's the war we should stop.
Or...
a bullet from this pistol
might be the solution.
No, there is a better way.
- Who sent you?
- Excuse me?
Who sent you?
The Italians? Russians?
French? English?
Who?
l don't know who.
I'm getting 12,000 crowns
for it.
For what?
I'm supposed to get
military secrets from you.
They're most interested in
the plans to attack Russia.
Over.
The code letter for war
with Russia is "R".
Yes. R.
On the northern front
there are 788 battalions.
377 cavalry squadrons.
379 batteries
with 2,222 guns.
69 technical companies.
6 companies of bicyclists,
1,234 machine guns.
Understood?
In the fortresses Lemberg,
Cracow, Przemysl...
22 battalions.
7 cavalry regiments.
1 battery with 6 guns.
83 artillery regiments.
And now get lost.
From where did you know
Alfredo Velocchio?
l didn't. l met him
that night in October.
Who introduced him to you?
- l forgot.
- Think.
Who was it? Who told you
to introduce him to me?
- Excuse me?
- Who commissioned you?
No one. He asked me
to introduce him.
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
- You're lying.
- I'm not.
You're lying!
l swear,
he mentioned Christoph.
Why don't they arrest me?
What are they waiting for?
They need a Ukrainian.
Our Father...
who art in Heaven...
Perhaps l should have
tried this earlier.
Thank you.
Salapska. Colonel,
we must speak to you.
Come in.
We have orders to disarm
and arrest you.
Which is
Colonel Red's room?
First floor, number 71.
He has officers visiting
already.
Major Salapska reporting.
This way.
You'll be court-martialled
for passing military secrets.
The court-martial will decide
your fate in an open hearing.
- I've been provoked.
- No, we were!
Since you were in Fiume,
you've been a traitor.
The Archduke chose me
because our friendship...
and your relations
with my sister...
make you part of our family.
He asked me to deliver his
message to you personally.
Behave properly in court
and admit the charges...
then the sentence
will be light.
Or you'll be sentenced
for treason and betrayal.
Betrayal.
Is a national
virtue nowadays.
I'm sorry we're meeting
again like this.
lf it's any consolation,
some people know...
and I've told them...
no officer has been
more reliable than you.
Alfred, l really would like
to have your child.
Do what you're
expected to...
and nothing will happen
to you.
Haven't you noticed
that no one's on your side?
Nobody but me.
Children?
Now...
l don't like children
anymore.
They telegraphed me
to come here from Fiume.
May l?
How do they know
we were friends?
They know everything.
- Did you betray secrets?
- Not the way you heard.
Then stand up in court
and defend yourself.
The court only accepts
evidence that can be proved.
The Emperor would never
allow an unjust verdict.
lf the charge is false,
they can't take the uniform.
They'll take yours, too,
if it suits them.
They might need
a better scapegoat soon.
Then it'll be your turn.
The Jews.
The simplest solution.
Popular, too.
None of us will be wearing
this uniform much longer.
l converted to Christianity,
you know that.
And what shall l do?
My grandfather...
Doctor Ignaz Sonnenschein,
always said...
"Lord, you didn't make me
Moses or an Emperor.
So you can only hold me
accountable...
for being Doctor Ignaz
Sonnenschein all my life".
Tell them what
they want to hear.
It's just
another year or two.
l dreamed about you.
l walked in darkness and
you showed me the way out.
We should live together.
We're talking about
the head of Intelligence.
He was the head, Captain.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir. But Colonel Redl
was my superior.
Didn't you ever notice
anything about his behaviour?
Yes, Colonel.
His will to work.
He rarely slept or ate,
just kept working.
Gentlemen...
Remain seated. How are
the trial preparations?
He won't cooperate.
I'd have this traitor shot.
The paper could call it
an accident.
He was run over or fell out
of a hotel window.
Then a military funeral.
I'm not sure yet what's best
for the Monarchy.
No other aspect matters.
Well, gentlemen.
Solution 1:
an open hearing.
But Redl won't cooperate.
- Correct?
- Yes, Your Highness.
Not to mention that Redl
has a lot of information...
which he might disclose
at the trial...
with unpleasant results.
Solution 2:
a closed hearing.
Sentence made public
after execution...
in such detail that it
alarms the whole army...
and also the whole civilian
population. Do you agree?
Whoever agrees
should raise his hand.
Lt. Colonel Kubinyi,
you don't agree?
Imperial Highness,
l beg to reply, no.
What do you suggest?
Redl should have the chance
to decide his own fate.
You were his school friend,
hence prejudiced.
Principally, you're right.
How can Redl decide
his own fate?
He won't even agree
to a public trial.
We're speaking of a traitor.
One can only deal with
a traitor when he's dead.
l won't inquire
how this man...
managed to get
into the Ministry.
Who backed him,
or whom he deceived.
These questions will be
answered later.
For the people
of the Monarchy...
we're dealing
with an officer...
in the Imperial
War Ministry.
So, l suggest he should be
allowed to end it himself.
And we can publish the
version acceptable to us.
A third solution.
What is the public told
in this case?
He picked a certified letter,
two detectives saw him...
he was captured
trying to escape...
and committed suicide.
Yes?
Your Highness,
in this case...
journalists will insist
on details.
He might have torn
the envelope...
and mislaid the pieces
or left it in a car.
Or his penknife he used
to open the envelope...
or the penknife case.
Very good. It should be
published like this.
l suggest it's not published
like that. It should leak out.
But not in Vienna.
In Lemberg,
Budapest, or Prague.
Let some bright reporter
uncover it.
We just plant the clues
that lead to Redl.
We should check a list of
all journalists in Prague.
Any counter-suggestions,
gentlemen?
l also think this is
the best solution.
Lt. Colonel Kubinyi...
your opposition
led to this solution.
You'll visit Redl,
as an old comrade...
and hand him
your service revolver.
Your Highness, l can't
perform this task.
An officer cannot take
action against a superior.
By the grace of the Emperor
and by my own decision...
l promote
Lt. Colonel Kubinyi...
to Colonel of the
Austro-Hungarian Army.
My orders takes effect
immediately.
Colonel...
you know how to use
the weapon.
You will have a moment,
but please be brief.
Then there is no trial.
Is there anyone you wish
to say goodbye to?
Make sure you get
out of here, quickly.
A briefcase and matching
wallet, leather...
with the monogram A.R.
Eighty crowns.
One bid for eighty.
- Ninety.
- One hundred.
- One hundred...
- A hundred twenty.
One hundred and twenty.
Going once, twice, sold!
Next a child's poem,
handwritten.
"Dedicated to our
Emperor and King.
Like the dew
from Heaven sent...
may on him
be blessings spent.
May they give the strength
he needs...
for all of his
majestic deeds.
Alfred Redl, elementary
school pupil."