Previously
on "666 Park Avenue"...
It's beautiful!
We have an interview.
Henry Martin, Jane Van Veen.
For the position of Manager ...
Mr. Doran
personally selects
tenants.
obviously something that
you said impressed him.
It is our way to Henry.
You and I are the same;
we came from nothing.
We must fight
tooth and nail
to break through
in the world.
Apparently Councilman Sullivan
has broken the rules;
his seat will become vacant.
Henry does not approach
the man with the compass rose tattoo.
As it happened, Nona.
Did you know that Henry was in danger?
I found something else.
I think you might be interested.
-What about that girl? Who is she?
-That's you.
You are the other girl from the Drake.
Hey, baby, come meet
my new assistant.
Brian, this is Alexis.
You have been busy
with my assistant.
Please, can we fix it?
I'll kill you too ...
Oh my God, I killed her!
Henry, I do not feel safe here.
Do you understand that?
I'm affraid.
If I were you,
I would do anything for Jane to stay.
Are you going to tell your father?
You do not want to know anything about me,
Henry.
Details are in the invitation,
in case you change your mind.
You're the only family she has.
This building is Evil
and you are in danger living here.
I think the gray conveys
maturity and experience,
things that have become
rare nowadays.
I think
it looks just as good
as the other two that you've tried.
Yeah, well, it's my first day,
I want to make a good impression.
The candidate for city council,
Henry Martin.
Enjoy it,
but don't become obssed with it.
Well, you know I'm obsessive,
that's why I must
have everything perfectly organized.
I will begin to enjoy it
when I win the election...
and when you find my lucky socks.
Have you seen my blue socks?
They should be
perfectly organized in you drawer.
Yeah, well they're not.
And it's a disaster,
because I wore them
when I passed the bar exam;
wore them when we got
this apartment.
I also wore them when I proposed to you.
You don't need those lucky socks, councilman.
I think I have ten minutes
for my favorite voter...
If you want my vote, Mr. Martin,
you'll have to give me twenty...
We are murderers...
No, we're not.
The dead blond in our living room
says otherwise.
It'd be a big blow to my mother
to see my in handucffs again.
We can not go to jail.
Our life would be ruined.
She was crazy, Lou.
Not only did she come here to kill you,
but she challenged us both to do it.
Why should we have to pay
for a hand
that we were forced to play?
Because we played his game, Brian.
And the cards on the table
look very bad.
Your adventure, my accident...
We have to call the police,
we have no other options.
Yes, there is another option.
Nobody has to know what happened.
Is it your family?
Yes, the...
the baby is my daughter, Jane.
I came to the city for the
engagement party.
How time flies, huh?
- Yes
Was the same with my two children.
And this is my wife, Catherine.
A wonderful woman
and terrible cook.
I know I've made many mistakes
in my life, but...
Catherine and then Jane.
I did not know how lucky I was.
Luck changes, huh?
Yes, Catherine died suddenly.
How did she die?
Well...
it was very strange,
Catherine drowned...
in the bathtub.
Help...
666 Park Avenue
S01E13 Lazarus
Translation, editing and sync by:
Jerry Shadoe
Good morning, Mr. Doran.
-Good morning, Tony.
Patrick Corey, from 2D,
is permanently gone.
I want you to help Jane
prepare the apartment for rent.
Yeah, no problem.
Mr. Corey
didn't last long here, huh?
Longer than I hoped.
To tell you the truth, I don't really care.
Why not?
I didn't really like Mr. Corey.
Me neither.
Good morning, Jane.
Oh, hello, Gavin.
Thanks again for the party
last night. It was wonderful.
Champagne hangover?
No, I'm fine.
I didn't have the opportunity to speak
with your father.
I think he left here
rather abruptly.
Yes, the situation is complicated.
I don't want to intrude.
-No, no...
I stayed with him for coffee, to...
clarify a few things.
You don't have to explain.
-Thanks, Gavin.
Wow, impressive to see your name here.
Yes, thank you.
Have you already started working?
Yes, I bring coffee
as my contribution
to the campaign
And I thought you weren't
interested in politics.
The future worries me.
I want to thank you all
for being here...
and... participating in this...
We undertake a good fight.
Clean, fair, and with integrity.
We will accomplish great things
for District 53 of Manhattan.
Well, nothing more. I promise
I will improve my speech.
And now... let's get to work.
Mr. Martin, I'm Earl.
Anything you need, I'm here.
Well, Earl, thank you.
You are the candidate
that the city needs.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Well, all you have to do is win.
I don't understand much about politics,
but... I have a good feeling.
Yes, good morning, tell me.
There are many things to explain
about what happened.
You would not understand.
I know I'm connected to the Drake.
I know that my grandmother was
raised here.
And now I find out that you and Mom
lived there when I was a baby...
It can not be a coincidence,
it has to mean something.
I don't know what it is, Jane.
Well, you can not come into my life
and just tell me that I am in danger.
I already know I'm in danger.
But there must be a reason
why I'm back where it all began.
Daddy, tell me.
Why have I returned to the Drake?
You know, your mother asked
herself the same question?
And that's what led her
to the abyss...
What do you mean?
When you were just a baby,
I thought she was just experiencing
a period of depression
that was due to the stress of moving
into a new place or something.
But since then, I realized,
The Drake has changed, Jane.
I don't even want to think about
something similar happening to you.
During all these years,
the only thing I recieved from you...
were a handful of letters...
a couple of calls...
a couple of visits...
Dad...
was there a reason you abandoned me?
I was trying to protect you.
From what?
From the truth.
But you living in that terrible place
means I failed.
Yeah?
- Of course.
Henry?
Mr. Doran wants to see you.
Well, Mr. Polumbo,
that's a very generous amount
Well, thank you sir,
I am grateful.
All right. Goodbye.
A "generous amount";
sounds promising.
$ 10
Mr. Polumbo is 88 years old
and is willing to support us.
You have a gift for connecting with
people, Henry.
I hope that you will have
the opportunity to prove it.
For that we have to win the elections.
I havce noticed that all
the candidates
have attacked our dishonorable counselor.
All, except you.
Yes, I do not have to crush
Sullivan or anyone
to show people who I am.
Yeah, I suppose that's a way of looking at it.
What's the other?
Que tácitamente
Tacticly adopt the behavior.
What are you saying, Gavin?
Of course not!
Yes, I know.
But you already know that in politics
you are against
or you are in favor.
"Vote for integrity."
Your sights are high.
But many people will try to bring you down.
Let them try.
Henry, I have no doubt that you
can be a great politician.
And I worry that ethics
will not let you get there.
One, two...
It's impossible for this to work.
Lou, we burned the caarpet,
cleaned the floor,
we burned the fire poker
to remove all traces of DNA.
What else are we missing?
A dose of sanity?
Everything will be okay,
I promise.
Right?
-Yes.
Right.
- Well...
What part of the basement?
The boiler room.
Let's go...
What is it that you wanted to talk to me about, Jane?
I don't mean to impose,
but why didn't you tell me...
I had already lived in this building?
I had no idea that
you were the same girl
we saw out walking in Central Park.
When we interviewed you,
you had given us a different name
than that of your mother and father.
So you had no clue?
Not until last night when we saw
Nate at the party.
Forgive us, Jane.
We wanted to tell you,
but found
your engagement party
was not the right time
to... bring up... a... traumatic matter.
Why do you say traumatic?
What are you saying?
You must know something...
about the death of your mother.
I know she drowned
when I was a baby,
while swimming in the lake.
No, Jane...
It happened in her apartment,
here at the Drake.
No. The accident was in the lake house in Indiana.
No, it happened here, Jane.
And it was no accident.
How was it not an accident?
Nothing was proven,
but the police talked about a murder.
But...
I'm sorry to say,
but the main suspect in her death...
was your father.
This is not a good idea, Brian.
Hiding the body of Alexis
here in the basement?
Lou, it's impossible to
get her out of the building
without someone seeing us, ok?
Furthermore, nobody ever comes down here.
And what do we do afer we walled her in, huh?
Then what?
We go home and forget all about this.
No murder goes unpunished.
No. It is impossible to get rif of it.
Yes.
It happens. All the time.
We will wake up tomorrow
and pretend none of this,
none of this... happened.
Huh?
And we can do it
with a clear conscience
because we both know
none of this
would have happened
if not for her.
I just want us to be who we were
before she came into our lives.
Yes, I do too.
I haven't thanked you...
for saving my life.
We saved each other, Lou.
All the sites say the same thing;
My mother drowned in the bathtub.
She didn't fall,
she didn't hit her head...
The only logical explanation,
is murder
Not for nothing, but
he leaves you with relatives
and completely disappears
out of your life...
Sounds like guilt.
And why come back now?
I don't know.
Suppose it was murder.
Should we wonder why he did it?
It says my father
killed my mother
because she had an affair.
You were eight months old when she died.
I don't know,
breastfeeding, changing diapers,
and cheating on her husband
at the same time?
It's true. It seems odd.
Well. I have to go back.
My first day of internship
and I'm out two hours.
Imagine.
What?
Something happened to me
this morning while I was in the bathtub.
Tell me, don't be affraid.
It was before we knew any of this.
I hooked my foot
on the chain stopper and...
slipped underwater.
You slipped?
Felt like something was
thrown at me;
I couldn't sit up;
I thought I was drowning...
The Drake killed your mother and
now wants to kill you?
I don't think so because,
when I was under water,
I saw someone watching me.
A man.
Who?
I don't know, when I got up
he was no longer there.
The Drake pulls you up here
from 1000 miles away...
and the ghost of your grandmother
shows you fragments
of your family's past.
I can't help but think that your mother
is trying to tell you something.
That my father killed her?
Or who did.
How are you?
I'm Henry Martin...
I present myself as councilman
in this special election,
Thank you.
I ask for your vote.
You have decieved us all, Martin.
They think you're a good man.
Have a nice day,
Mr. Sullivan.
Great diversionary maneuver.
I did nothing.
Leave me alone.
Sure, "Mister Right Place Right Time."
An opportunist.
Which basically means we are the same.
Hey, Henry?
Look at me.
This is what awaits you.
Been drinking?
Yeah, Irish Whiskey.
But I guess you are
more Scottish.
He slept with an intern.
He ruined his career
and his marriage;
It's his fault, not mine.
Very well.
You continue to pretend
that you're different
But we all end up with blood on our hands.
I'll tell you a secret, Henry,
The blood will eventually be yours.
I love you.
I love you too.
It seems that things
are getting better.
We will try, Mr. Doran...
It's worth it to fight
for your relationship.
It's admirable.
Later.
-Good-bye.
Louise, I think you've lost an earring.
Oh, God, we will not...
be walled in with Alexis...
Brian!
Think Lou, When waas the last time you saw him?
The truth is that I haven't thought
about my earring the last couple hours.
Maybe you left them at Patrick's
like the others.
Oh really?
That's how you want to fix this?
Well I don't think you adventure
has contributed anything
to our marital happiness.
No, you're right.
I'm sorry.
We must remain united in this...
or everything will fall apart.
We gotta think about how.
I never wanna see that basement again.
We have done everything possible
to erase our tracks.
We can't risk something so small
betraying us.
We have to go back down.
All right.
Did you kill her?
Don't ask me that, Jane.
No. The conversation...
you've been avoiding all my life,
we will have it now.
Yeah, I guess so.
The papers said that she had...
an affair.
She did and it was over.
So you killed her for it?
Absolutely not.
We managed to overcome it;
She left him and I convinced her
to come with me to New York
to start all over.
A new life with our baby.
So why did the police
suspect you?
Because there were
no signs of forced entry.
The door was locked when
I arrived. Okay?
And the police thought I was
the only on who could enter.
I did not kill your mother!
Listen, come here...
Come here!
Listen,
I tried to help your mother.
Help her how?!
Dad, what are you telling me?
All right.
Jane..., your mother was insane.
She was obsessed with the Drake.
She said that the building was full
of secret rooms,
and then she started having hallucinations.
The building "spoke to her," you know?
It showed her things.
I had to get her out of there
before she went mad.
And I failed.
What if it was true?
Dad...,
strange things happen...
in that building.
I see them too.
Jane,
you have to get out of there.
No, no, do it...
or you will die there just like your mother.
Seriously...
-I can't...
No, Jane! Listen to me!
-No, you listen to me!
Jane...
You've never been a father to me
since I was born.
And threatening me is not the best
way to start. Do you understand?
Heh! Is there a problem?
No, no...
Look...,
stay way from my life.
Understand?
I'll take that whiskey now..
Jane?
Jane, are you here?
Sullivan!
What are you doing here?
No go, Henry.
Look at what they made you...
They take and take until
there is nothing left...
He's wounded, let me help.
-You've already done enough.
Henry!
Yeah, what's up?
God,
you gotta see this...
Shocking news,
recently disgraced
councilman
Frank Sullivan, of New York,
was found dead
in his apartment
on the Upper East Side.
According to police,
Mr. Sullivan
allegedly committed suicide by
shooting himself in the head.
According to police sources,
Mr. Sullivan's neighbor
saw him enter his apartment alone
shortly before hearing
a single gunshot...
The police officers who responded to the call
forced their way into the home and made...
Call Henry.
-Hello, Henry.
Gavin, what happens now?
The first rule in politics
is to admit
when you made a mistake,
and I made one.
You know about Sullivan?
While other candidates,
preyed upon him,
you chose the way of ethics.
And I think it was worth it.
His problems began
when an anonymous source
leaked information to the press
about his affair...
Sullivan's life crumbled.
It made no sense to point out
what the whole city already knew...
I don't want to seem gruesome,
but I hope your noble intentions get
their results at the polls.
I told you Henry,
you were born to be a politician.
Gavin, this wasn't calculated.
Of course not.
Stop on by later for a drink.
I'll be awake.
Thanks, but I'll pass.
This is crazy, I can't
believe we're doing this.
The only thing that could lead
them back to us
is your earing.
You said no one would
find the body here.
We can't risk it, okay?
Lou, I know your earrings will be here.
It must be...
wait, I need to be alone.
Now...
Well, the flashlight...
It can't be...
-What? Brian, what?
Brian!
-Look...
My God... And the body?
I don't know.
Alexis is with me.
I believe this is yours.
Well, this is an ugly topic.
She tried to kil me, you know?
It was self-defense...
We had no choice...
- Yes...
Brian, once told me that
you'd give everything to
succeed again.
I have good news.
Your work will be a great success.
But I'm afraid
you will not celebrate...
I don't understand.
Louise, from that night
that you ran Alexis over with your car,
she lived on borrowed time from me.
What do you mean?
You belong to me,
both of you.
And I declare the lease terminated.
Oh, Gavin...
-Gavin, wait!
Please!
It's payback time.
-Wait...
-Gavin!
Gavin!
Gavin, please! Gavin!
Gavin, get us out of here!
Gavin! No!
-Gavin!
No coverage...
Brian, I'm afraid...
We're together, right, Lou?
I'll never leave...
What are you doing here?
I told you to get away from me! Dad!
If you see things like your mother,
you are in danger.
I will not let this building
take possession of you too
Dad, you're drunk and you don't know
what you're saying
Why don't you come back...
- I'm not leaving here without you!
Do you hear me?
My God, why do you have a gun?
I can't leave you here...
I can't, it's not safe;
this place will kill you likke it killed
your beloved mother.
I couldn't save here,
but I will save you.
Please let me call Henry...
Please...
You can call him from the street,
now, let's go.
Dad, please...
Get off me!
Don't look at me like that,
it breaks my heart.
How do you want me to look?
The day you were born
was the happiest day of my life.
You and your mother...
you were everything to me.
Hey, I know I haven't been
a father to you, I know.
I never helped with homework
wasn't there for your dance recitals, but
I'm here now.
And I'll protect you.
Even if it means
you'll never speak to me again,
I'll know you're safe.
Dad, please, let's go
somewhere to talk.
Why are we going?
-I don't know.
What are we doing here, Gavin?
The doorman told me from the lobby.
I brought you here so that we can
talk like gentlemen.
Jane, no!
Well, Nate. It appears that
circumstances have changed.
Nate. Drop the gun.
This shouldn't end up like
it did with Catherine.
I did not kill my wife!
Dad, please, let's go...
Let's talk about this...
I didn't kill your mother. I swear
on your soul that I didn't.
You were completly drunk.
Do you even remember
what happened that night?
Drunk or not, I would have
never hurt Catherine...
Yet, here you are
pointing a gun at your
own daughter.
Ironic or predictable??
Come on, Jane, let's go.
Jane?
Nate, drop your gun
before someone gets hurt.
I can't, it wont let me.
You know what that sound like?
Nate, you need help.
Dad, please...
Everything will be alright...
Give me the gun.
I'm trying but,
I can't move my arm.
Jane?
-Henry, get out!
Nate, what the hell are you doing?
-Dad, no!
Sorry, I can't stop!
Henry!
Oh, my God...
Honey, you'll be fine...
Help him, please!
Look at me,
you're gonna be okay... huh?
No, no, no...
Hang on, my love, hold...
I didn't shoot him.
Dad, help!
Henry... No, no, no...
Look at me baby, look at me...
Dad!
Oh, my God!
The button for the lobby
doesn't work, Mr. McKenny...
We should go down to the basement.
Help him, please.
First I have to tell you something.
-Henry is dying!
You have to know the truth about the Drake.
You have to know why you're here.
Why am I here?
You're here because...
I loved your mother.
She had a special connection
with the Drake.
It's something that runs in your family.
The affair, it was you?
You betrayed me, Jane.
What could I do?
I couldn't let you
get away from me.
You killed her because of me?
Nate McKenny is not your father.
No. No!
Catherine knew and
I think Nate suspected.
He... fled with you in the middles of the night...
and had you hidden with family...
I hoped with all my soul
to see you again,
to meet again with my daughter...
And that one day,
you'll come back home.
I can save Henry.
Please.
Please, I'll do anything.
You have to understand, Jane,
that there is a price to pay
for what one wants most.
ONE YEAR LATER
"Author of theater and his wife disappeared."
Baseman Theatre Company presents:
"Invisible Ink"
Henry Martin wins the councilman
position by a landslide
The renovation of the Drake is started.
You're finally here!
Dinner is almost ready.
I'm sorry, Olivia, it was my fault.
Yeah, got stuck in
a duct on the fifth floor,
I had to go rescue her.
-My hero to the rescue...
I was getting ready.
-This is for you.
Chateau Monet, my favorite.
Come in, Gavin is in the lounge.
Mr. and Mrs. Councilman.
We have seen the hall of starlings.
It's magnificent. Seriously Jane,
the restoration
deserves an award.
I'm dying to show it to my
friends of the Architecture Digest.
Thank you. But, there's
still plenty to do.
At the rate I'm going,
The Drake will take a lifetime.
I never get tired of these views.
Do you know what today is?
-Of course. -
A year ago, you knew the exact truth
and you made a choice.
Are you happy?
I have everything I want,
a husband...
incredible success, safety, luxury...
Why wouldn't I be happy?
I told you that there
was a price to pay
to save Henry's life.
Was it worth it?
Sometimes... I have doubts.
What we do, Dad...
- Is... meet needs.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
We offer desperate people
a taste of what they want most
and in return we can live well.
A life without fear or doubt.
The power to make the world
what we want,
not what we are given.
The Drake is
you natural right, Jane.
Your legacy.
You and Henry...
will have a son.
Soon, I hope.
He'll be a very powerful
figure in this country.
The most feared leader...
that will heal the world
under his control.
Great things, Jane.
A new order.
Hey, Jane...
Olivia is collecting;
we should go now.
Well, I'll see you inside.
Are you okay?
Henry...
I have to tell you something...
Yeah?
I'm pregnant.