Oh shit!
Come on!
Get out, people!
Liberate all tortured animals!
They will go!
Look at you!
For you are poor little babies
Those nasty men wouldn't hear.
Be free little ones!
here...
Nothing's gonna hurt you now... nothing!
How could they...?
could they...?
These horrible beastly people!
Come free my feline sister!
No. Stop!
Aaaahh.... No...
Karma, no!, nooo!!!
OK, guys. I don't need to tell you
how successfull that was!
I am very proud of you.
- We have to burry them...
Don't blame yourself Sonia. It could
have happened to anyone
It's not your fault. It's the fault of
this whole rotten animal hating society!
You are right. I'm sorry about your loss,
really.. I am.. but we just really don't have
time to burry them.
No.... We must burry them!
O' nobely born...
In your journey through the formless void
remember the unity of all living things.
We really should be going now, Sonia!
Sonia, come on!
Aahhhh...
A night watchman was found
with first degree burns,
and severe head injuries
This is not the first time that militant animal rights activist
have undertaken operations of this kind
A few days ago, we interviewed an
anonymous representative of T.W.A.A.T.S.,
True Warriors Against Animal
Torture and Subjugation.
There is a lot of fuckins nuts out there!
People are going to start
to take notice
-hmmm...
Not only are we gonna step up our attacks,
we are gonna hit harder
From this day no one responsilbe for the
torture of animals should feel safe.
And l mean no one!
They are enemies of the animal kingdom.
And all enemies of animal kindom are enemies of us.
Even every day meat eater should be aware
Actually...
talking about fuckin asses...
You know mmm...
Ivan!
- O... He is a fuckin, no?
- Yeah, well, l owe him 4000 big ones
He helped me shift some motors.
Trouble is l ah...
managed to blow the money
before going to pay the bastard.
I See...
So you are gonna cough up the cash then!
Well... thats the kind of the thing...
I couldn't tell him l have been screwing around
with his cash
So l ah...
I've just passed that l have been busted by the cops!
Yeah... So...?
So... he wanted to know how it happened...
You know... and it just sorta...
Slipped out...
What?
That mmm... you grossed me up
Me...?
Yeah, So now he is after your ass too
Open the door! Will ya!
It's me.. Flea!
- No way man.
- Hello Hello Hello...
- Boys... Look who he is man?
- It's Roy fuckin Arnie!
- It's fucking Roy Arnie!
Haa.. Iong time no see mate!
What brings you back to the old country?
What you are up to man?
Still in the circus game?
Not you getting a little old to be messing
around with circuses?
Look...
you don't know how it is man!
The circus is like a drug.
Once it gets in your blood, you are hooked.
You are in it till you are crooked.
You obviously never felt that way
if you had knew what l am talking about
Okay, What ever you say arnie boy...
How about you lady?
Whats up?
- O..., you know... Same old shit.
- Nice shit too...
Give me the colsteria...
I can fix it
A deal good to you
So, what brings you back here, then ayee?
Yeah... What's getting on?
- Yum.. Hey, aaa... gazz... odd
- Listen to this!
Boys l have got an offer for you.
This is the chance you've been dreamin about
The big time. The big top.
The Circus!
I'm hereby offering you a job
- This is exactly what he said to me...
- A job?
What you are talking about
"a job"?
A job at the circus.
It this fuckin great circus from Russia.
Party every night.
Sex, drugs and soda
You'll love it
Believe it or not,
There are actually circus groupies.
- Circus groupies?
- What about Cash? You ain't said nothing about money yet.
- I'll give you 3000 big ones for three weeks.
- Thats what swung it for me... The big one
3000...aa?? but if you are so low dig,
you could probably stretch to 4000
4000 of it... get on now, that that that that
thats a little steep, ain't it?
Alright, well...
you just have to do without me then!
Sorry,  l can't do without you lad!
You gotta be at on it...
C'mon now...
- For old time's sake.
- Okay, Okay, But only for 4000.
Alright man!
But only because it's you Odd!
- 4000! It's just getting better and better
- Yes, but flea, we've already made our deal
- I know you know we agreed on 3000 and deal is a deal
- Yeah, but that means Odd's gonna get more than me.
- Flea! 3000 for three weeks...
C'mon man... where else you gonna get a deal like this..
- But it's not fair! You can't do... fuck with...
- Ohh just a little bit more on the barb for you Flea!
Business is business, buddy.
Business is business.
- What part l'll do Arnie?
- We don't have a... deal, Gaz!
- Yeah well man, 4 grands are cool with me.
- Sorry Gaz! Can't do it bro.
- What? but... Uh o
- Here goes with that saying...
...If Odd gets 4000, Flea gets 3,
how can l possibly afford another 4 for you
you see that don't you?
- Yeah but...
- Fact is, recent down into my honest bag, l got 2 and a half
- 2 and a half? I'll get less than Flea.
- Well, Business is business, buddy.
- Sorry about that Gaz, but..
- 3, just fine for me, mate. he he he...
Stop!
Stop this fucking car!
If l don't get my 4000,
you will have to do it without me!
Really? Well thats a pitty.
Okay, if you decided...
I'll just have to get by
with Odd and Flea, so...
Oh, shit! There is lvan.
Can we please get out of here before he sees us?
- Well, whats it gonna be, Gaz?
- Huh?
- I'll do it for 3000. Thats my final offer.
- Sorry, l can't do it
Fuck!
Alright...
Okay, Okay...
2 and a half!
ENJOY YOUR STAY lN Norway
LAND OF THE MlDNlGHT SUN
LAND OF MlDNlGHT FUN!
Shhh... Are you gonna be finish soon?
I think someone is coming.
All you gonna have orgasm.
Yeah of course....
Otherwise its opression.
Yeah yeah of course but...
your orgasm ain't my problem, right!
- Actually it is.
- No,  isn't.
Yes it is.
No... it... isn't
Yes... it... is...
- No... it... isn't
- Yes... it... is...
Whats goin on here?
I thought you guys were "straight edge".
I've always been under the impression...
...that the two you...
were straight.. edge!
Bettina and l...
Bettina and l!
We! were together eight...
eight months, before we even kissed
- Whats wrong with having sex?
- It's casual sex, Erik.
- Yeah but it wasn't casual. We've been shagging for months.
- O' really?
Alright, what am l alowed to do?
Well if you asked me... I think
everyone should just be celebrate because...
- ... coz isn't.. isn't it like.. I mean its its human beings that... that...
- Celeber! Forget it.
well they eat animals.
and use their skin for fashion...
...and exploit them for labour...
and exhibit them in cages!
- What the hell does casual sex gotta do with animal rights?
- It is about opression you idiot!
and therefore...
In the interest of animal kind we...
- ...we! as their defenders should stop reproducing
- We've talked about this all the times before Sonia!
that suicide...
Yes but aren't we suppose to be willing to
give up our lives in the name of animal liberation Marius?
Look! I joined this group
because l was promised some action!
Action?
What do you call our last operation?
Wasn't that action enough for you?
- Oh, My God, the makissmo is so tidious.
- We have to stop with ourselves!
You want some action?
You! want some action? Alright!
I'll give you some action, and plenty of it.
The circus... is coming to town.
- Circus?
- Yes! and really dirty circus from Russia.
- And if there is stables or anything to go by...
- No!!!
- We're looking at some pretty serious offenders here guys!
- Oh God No!!!
- We've had that Sony! don't cry again...
We'll take care of it
- Ah haaa......
- Yeah, We'll set the big top on fire...
Count on it.
- We'll blow those bastards sky high!
- We've gotta stop to that cruelty!
And this is just the first battle in a crusade
that will finally lead us to a totally circus free world.
"Operation Circusicion"...
starts now!
No, no, no.
It's not the Hot-dog, doughnut, and coke thats on offer...
It is the Hot-dog and Coke "or"
the doughnuts and Coke.
- Thats what it says on the poster.
- No, thats not what it says on the poster. Says...
It says "Special Offer" pal.
"Free coke and doughnut with every hot-dog!"
Cannot cause any trouble, Hudmaspecs!
- Special offer: Free coke or...
- O' c'mon Hudmaspecs. Don't include tha hot-dogs.
Oh, God... Don't!
Oh... yo.. yo.. you'll have to pay for that
you stupid fat bastard!
- Hold my specs.
- No don't!
We don't want to spend our weekends in jail.
- Please Hudmaspecs! be nice.
- ...going moose hunting would be fun, relaxing...
Yeah well!
I'm gonna be that pissed off...
I don't take myself off mooses yet.
Thats gonna be all for me
I can tell you that!
Yeah! but it ain't that simple mate.
We won't get a moose just coz we want one.
We've got to work for it, old buddy!
I've got my grand-daddy's hunting rifle...
See this here...
Right from short-put game
Hunted in Africa.
I'm gonna shoot me a moose.
And you can bet your ass...
I'm gonna shoot it with my grand-daddy's rifle
May be you should aa...
- ... cut down the booze a little?
- You see, we ain't getting mooses coz...
- No,  it is not the case.
- No, no, no.
we ain't getting any mooses.. coz of all them
amaterus up there in there mountains.
This is the cruelest rule in the game.
I never got used me to that!
It is better are ready!
O' look Hudmaspecs!
Motor Bikes!
- They'd look that they were from Lapland.
- Is it, which kind of Lapland?
- Lapps on bikes!
- Lapps, Hudmaspecs. Laaps on motorbikes.
Oh, yeah.
Whoo well, let's get movin, shall we?
- The moose would be waiting...
- Up we go... ha.. ha.. ha...
It was Sick mate!
Totally disgusting!
The worst bloody porn film l've ever seen.
Everyone was over 50!
Varicose veins, Big Butts, Wrinkles...
It seemed a fuckin elderly orgy!
This is my home.
Let's take a look at the stables...
That'll be your main job.
You're goin to be meetin Circus Stromowski's greatest attraction.
He's been with us more than 15 years.
- Jesus, this place stinks mate!
- Hey stupid! You've ever met a stable that doesn't stink? Yeah...
But this bad?
Okay! Here...... is Jimmy!
He's an elephant... fuck!
Whoa... Thats so cool!
Is he alright?
He looks kinda sick, kinda... wasted.
- Yeah yeah, that is one fiction.
- Way cool! yeah.. yeah..
You see we have to drug the animals...
...we have to! otherwise they can get out of control.
Thats not something you want.
- Elephant?
- Imagine an elephant go bananas in the ring...
People getting tremble, kids getting squished to death...
Crushing little bones...
You know it's not cool.
Curshing your arms is not definitely cool mate na!
- So he has had his drugs yeah...
- Na... hm hm hm ha... way...
Yeah! he's hooked now obviously..
he was bound to...
- Whoa? He's really hooked?
- O' Yes, thats the reason dummy!
He's mad for this stuff.
Uses four plastic bags like this every week...
A whole fuckin bag full of junk?
Unbelieveable!
Luckily l've got a whole pool of this shit in the Russia.
- Won't be so good if you really ran ha?
- No! He gets freaked to the second past he don't get his daily doze.
Yeah! but you know whats really weard?
He can't stand cops.
Yeah it's weard, and he knows they're pigs you see!
it's all paranoiac.
Should l be thinking about it...
I really do think he's gotta deal with him being a junkie..
You just naturally get paranoiac, You know what l'm saying?
hmm...
What you gotta do here, is basically...
shovel out the shit and feed the animals.
I ain't shoveling shit!
- Okee dok, pal you gonna have to do that.
- Hey, why should l do it?
Somebody's gotta do it.
You ain't getting paid for your looks.
- Then l want as much as Odd!
- Jesus! I'm startling with bringing you little butt holes in on it...
Thats not fair...
I've got the dirtiest job and l'm getting the worst money.
I get the worst money.
What the ever lovin fuck!
Alright, Flea! and Odd! you take care of the feed.
Thats more like it...
That only fuckin fair aye???
- So! whose gonna shovel the shit?
- Guess it'll have to be you!
Oh, brilliant!
I get fucking marbles in it.
It is me! the one who gets the shit money...
and l've gotta shovel the shit? No way!
- Hey Now Gaz! I've got a extra special job for you!
- Oh yeah!
I need you to take a really good care of Jimmy
That'll be your special responsibility.
- How come Gaz gets to do that?
- Yeah! why is Gaz gettin the coolest job?
Why is that so fucking cool?
The most important thing you gonna have to do is
make sure Jimmy gets the right medication at the right time.
Now what you gotta remember is that
the smack is in the Come'n'Shop bag...
...and the speed is in the Shop'n'Come bag.
He only gets that when he's goin in the ring.
- I got ya.
- I can't over emphasize this coz, if he gets the uppers when he   wants the downers, he goes... deep shit...
Memory lock this Gaz! the smack is in the Come'n'Shop bag,
speed is in the Shop'n'Come bag
Downs in the Come'n'Shop bag
Ups in the Shop'n'Come bag.
- And this is Jimmy's stuff right!. That goes for them too.
- Got Ya!
He gets it regular times early in the morning
and late at night.
Downs in the Come'n'Shop bag.
Ups in the Shop'n'Come bag.
l usually have a little play with him.
Hey, Jimmy! Hey Hey Hey Jimmy!
Where is it, Jimmy?
C'mon now! where is it?
Can't you find it? Can't you fi..
Where is the dope, Jimmy?
- Where did the dope go?
- Jimmy Wants it back...
I tease him a little bit you know but aa...
You don't wanna go too far
coz that'll get him wild. Don't it, Jimmy?
Thats when you get a smack on the head with his trunk
and its not something you gonna forget in a hurry, l can tell you...
- Don't shit mate!
- Yeah don't shit mate!
Okay, so thats the stable.
This area would be your main responsibility.
Gaz, you'll be taking care of Jimmy... and then...
...shovel out the shit.
- We bet ya!
- Now strap in on big cow.
Oh.. wait a minute, Mother Fuck!
I ain't cleaning out this shit!
Fear not ele-friend!
They'll pay for this.
Jesus Christ!, l can honestly say...
I've never seen anything like it!
The stables are completely disgusting!
Th.. The state of the animals...
Th.. They.. They are appalling...
- And the elephant is a..drug dependent!
- Thats Horrible!
Let's blow these whole freaks out back to Russia.
Animals liberators!
Straight... edgers!!!
He's a drugged Elee!
This...This is big! Our war... has become greater...
and more significant than ever...
- ...but if it's not crowned with a symbol...
- A symbol???
An elephant... Drugged up, kept down
and exploited in the ring.
Living in degradation...
wallowing in his own muk.
And addicted to drugs!
Jimmy! The junkie... Elephant!
He's addicted!!! Ow...
O' Marius! if there is a re-hab for elephants...
can we take him?
Yes! We are going to free him
from the brutality of the circus!
We are going to rescue him
from the hell of substance abuse.
And with Jimmy in front, we! the
True Warriors Against Animal Torture and Subjugation...
shall crush the circus men once and for all...
not just here...
but throughout the world!
But still gonna blow it up, alright?
Roy Arnie!
Roy Arnie! these are your friends?
That is good!
- Good strong boys! Are they be trusted?
- Guarantee, the stable be safe as aa...
- ...well aa.. safe!
- This is calls for a great celebration!
There won't be any intruders sticking their nose in there!
Vodka my friends!
Real Russian Vodka!
- This circus guy in alright? Arnie!
- Yeah! I could get used to this...
Ye.. ye.. ye.. ye.. fill'er up till right to the top...
- Anyone's gonna pick me up?
- Yeah! Let's get up man!
- Hey Arnie! What about them groupies you was talking about?
- Yeah yeah them circus-groupies!
I'd really like to meet them! Ah...
Are you sure you wanna meet them?
Roy Arnie!
Roy Arnie! Wake up Roy Arnie!
You have to wake up.
Get off, will ya...
You've over slept.
We open in one hour!
Catastrophe!
- Eigh... 8 'O Clock!
- O' son of a bi... O' Shit...
- My head is to million!
- What about our bloody Russian Vodka?
Aya... There is already a queue!
- Well what we suppose to do now then?
- O' bloody buttocks!
- Oh, Christ! Don't a.. beg, it's showtime.
- Showtime?
Roll up! Roll up!
Thankyou madam! here you go.. Iovely!
Roll up, Roll up, Roll up.
There... c'mon folks, don't be shy...
- ...Russia's very best circus. Step right up...
- Oh O....
...and buy your tickets right here.
- Experience top artists...
- Get your tickets.
- ...from the former Soviet Union!
- Get your tickets right here. Thankyou! there you go...
- C'mon then...
- Five tickets please!
Yeah, no problem. I'll.. I'll be five tickets!
- Howdy... How!
- Clowns, and a... balance in that tube...
...is suitable for kids.
- Give me three tickets!
- No problemo Sir!...
...three tickets.. comming right up,
and l hope you'll have a lovely time. Thankyou!
Is it myselve's technique or what?
Oy you! where exactly is the circus from?
Ladies and gentlemen!
Boys and girls!
Madam Svetlana
and her horses!
I thought there was right...
you know fake birds at the circus.
I don't know l.. fancy more
Ha... or the oxes!
Oh, poor thing...
Aa... Umm.. Okay! aa... Let's See...
Ladies and gentlemen!
Boys and girls!
The legendary, the incomparable,
the world famous wizard of balance... from Belarus!
I.. give.. you... Baloustrado!
- The wizard of balance, my ass!
- That don't look good, Oh...
...must've really hurt.
As Baloustrado demonstrate, just how deeply good
these tricks... really are!
So, ladies and gentlemen!!!
Baloustrado!
Do me the favor.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the great Baloustrado.
Baloustrado will perform his most daring..
and absolutely amazing...
- Somebody stop him!
- I can't watch this anymore.
lt is of the utmost importance that l have...
the greatest... possible...
...Silence.
- Was he suppose to be entertaining?
- It's just bloody sadism, if you ask me.
It's just playing nasty...
...hilarious clown!
all the way from Ukraine.
Ladies and gentlemen! I give you...
Flipp.. Flapp.. and... Flopp!
- These clowns are rubbish mate!
- I thought they were suppose to be funny!
- Yeah, like my sides are really aching.
- It's hardly the greatest show on earth. Is it?
What the hell do you know about it anyway... huh?
When it was a nip, the circus was my favorite place in the world.
There is a lot of fooling
if you ask me!
Oh, by the way... there was a guy asking a lot of questions
when l was selling the tickets.
- What kind of questions?
- Complicated ones...
...you know! If they have work permits... I mean...
- Undercover cops?
- Yeah, that's exactly what he looked like.. a fucking cop!
Don't worry man! I just told him, Roy Arnie takes care of all these
men, so everything is caucious, You can count on him.
- You said that?
- Thats what l said.
No... I got a record you stupid prick!
Elephant is ready.
I'm glad l've all sorted out.
I hope so too.
Yeah... my fucking wages depend on this game right!
I'll be having so shit..
if he does crumble...
Jimmy
The indian elephant!
- Ha...
- Thats it Jimmy... Good boy
Good boy.. yeah.. ya thats a... good boy...
Thats fine Jimmy!
Thats fine.
Okay... you'll be right..
That's good, Jimmy!
- O' God No....
- Jimmyyy... his name is boys and girls!
Jimmy
Good running, Jimmy!
God running!
Slow down!
Now you piss me off.
Stop him!
Take it easy!
Calm Jimmy!
Those poor animals are being delivered right into the hands
of the worts animal abusers of all.
The ones that do the real dirty work.
Veterinarians
DlSTRlCT VETERlNARlANS
TRONDELAG
O' Shit man! that was a close one.
We could all ended up in a camp for Christ sake.
- It wasn't my fuckiing fault.
- Yeah, lt it wasn't his fucking fault.
Was his fault. He gave him too much speed.
Got him paranoiac.
- Look! It was my first time of the job.
- Yeah, lt is was his first time.
- Flea, you grassed me up, you little rat bastard..
- Grassed you up? Excuse me! How was l supposed to know...
- ...that the circus was...
- Shut your fat fucking face, bunch of bleeding butt-hole...
- ...I can't believe l hired you!
- Anyway, no matter we can do about it now, is there?
Now we got an emergency on our hand!
Whats the problem?
Stromowski is the one taking the flack?
- What about my tour?
- There won't gonna be no tour. Is there?
- They confiscated all the animals
and threw them out of the country.
- Look! Iook! they've got beer.
Well its always hardly gonna set the world on fire.
Was it?
- No one had shaken shit circus!
- Look! beer!
I don't reckon you'd got far.
- Beer! beer beer beer.
- Fuck you! what about Jimmy?
Hey! you'll never guess what? I just fasten gear in my pocket.
Filth didn't even bother to search my pocket.
What would l say?
Let's get pissed up! and have a puff!
- Poor Jimmy.
- Yeah its no picnic being an addict.
They don't know.
Put yourself in Jimmy's shoes right now.
Imagine what its like?
You standing there, no familiar faces...
...no Roy Arnie inside with a..
Shop'n'Come bag.
Shop'n'Come bag?
Were not the downers in the Come'n'Shop bag?
Yeah, l meant the Come'n'Shop bag...
...and you are just in a sorta limbo, in..
in a cold sweat, you feel the... the cramps starting...
- You can't sleep, you just lie there...
- Yeah forget sleeping man!
- You puke and you crap.
- Yeah, you puke and you crap...
- ...and you're all alone, time passes.
- But passes so.. fucking.. slowly.
And after a while you get it.
No one is coming.
Not No one is gonna come around and stroke your trunk,
and give you a shit man!
- Oh, shit. You got me all tearing eyed.
- Think about it man!
I really.. really feel bad.
I don't suppose you guys could help me out for my...
for Jimmy's sake
- Is it really as bad as all that?
- He'll be taking good care of him, May be he'll mate!
You don't know what you're talking about.
Don't you understand anything, he'll be sick now.
- Might be right mate!
- Sick as a dog!
- But it is not our problem, is it?
- Well...
- Can't you just help the cops and let them take care of it?
- Oh, yeah, sure right Flea!
You guys ever want to participate in a good deed?
We must follow them!
We must follow them and discover where the stolen goods are hidden.
- Whats really going on here man?
- C'mon guys, you scratch my back, l'll scratch yours.
- Whats the fucking deal with Jimmy?
- Hey stop it! I'm growing very attached to him for Christ's sake.
Hey, this reminds me of a guy Arnold,
crazy about animals.
Just like Roy Arnie!
Yeah, he used to buy dogs abroad
and then, brings them back over.
Thing is.. he wasn't animal lover at all.
He was a dog smuggler.
He'd all knit them up and stick backs a gear inside, so it...
Iike.. fakes boobs you know.
- Smart.
- Very Smart.
Why don't you just start from the beginning, Roy Arnie?
Aa.. right right, the thing is that Jimmy is like..
He's worth about a... a million.
- A million? And Am l only getting 3 grand?
- Look, l'll give...
- Now, l'll give you 10%.
- 10%, No!
Buying beers now, are you?
Animal abusers?
Okay. Tonight's the night.
We're gonna break in and we're gonna liberate Jimmy.
And then.. we're gonna...
we're gonna...
What we're gonna do with him again?
Jimmy is about to be become the ultimate symbol of
the animal liberation movement
Jimmy The Elephant! is going to be bigger than...
bigger than...
- The World Wildlife Fund Panda.
- Thats not difficult is it? The Pandas aren't that fucking big.
- I'm talking figuratively Erik. And do you mind not swearing so much.
- Oh, l'm so sorry. Is swearing not considered Straight Edge either?
No, it's not...
It's got to do with a...
Go ahead, tell me.
What am l allowed to do?
Davias Fucker just can't open Jimmy and sold 7 K's
of heroin, it was backside.
Seven bloody K's of heroine which he...
ripped of the Russian mafia.
- I didn't rip it off man! I found it.
- Found it, yeah right!
In the boot of a wrecked car on smuggler's trail.
You must've known it was mafia property, you toilet!
- Ofcourse they'll want it back.
- A.. a.. Roy Arnie!
- what about that is...
- l don't think they'd trace it back to the circus man!
- There's something l wanna know about it okay?
- Good thing l got it well stashed.
Yeah and lucky, you've managed to
shack off them Russian gangsters.
Plumb in the depths of my honesty man,
thats not entirely true.
What do you mean?
You see when we got to border with Jimmy.. we got searched
by Russian customs, dogs and everythings...
...seeing as how the dogs didn't find nothing, l assumed
the Russiana thought we were, you know.. clean!
But you know!
Who comes after us then?
- Aa.. No?
- The Lapps. The fuckin Lapps mafia. Get in on the act now...
Lapplanders are mafia?
Real hard bastards. Got close connections
with the Russians, and the drugs, prostitution...
We've got the Lapps mafia on us?
For they, you was a...
Iittle mouse.
- I'm a mouse!
- I'm a mouse?
A little mouse has found
a well deserved piece of cheese...
...but before you know whats going on.. a cat
comes after you.. then.. a dog comes after you.
I am that mouse and Jimmy
is that bit of cheese.
And he is the key to my dream...
The Roy.. Arnie.. Circus!
Okay.. but how we're gonna
get the dope.. out of Jimmy?
Aa.. well.. unfortunately Gaz!
There is only.. one way.
Huh? You're not!
Are you gonna...
...kill Jimmy?
Look! before you get weepy... there is
a million worth of heroine in that elephant's ass!
I never thought, l'd hear somebody say that!
Hey! where the fuck is Flea, anyway?
Relax, Arnie. We've got to get ourselves
a car big enough to hold an elephant.
- Well l hope he turns up, the clock is tickin...
- Cheerly! there is one thing Flea is good at...
...is nicking cars!
Ten seconds, mate!
Jimmy?
There you are Jimmy, Cool!
Hey! I found him!
Hey Jimmy!
I'm your friend.
I'm on your side Jimmy...
Come to help...
Ha ha ha... Ya.. Good boy! Good boy!
We're gonna be friends, you and me Jimmy!
Huh.. yeah.. how're you there? okay..
You wanna be friends too?
But aa...
What the...?
He's getting away!
Well Go after him, Erik!
Me? why Me?
Where the fuck's Marius?
Fuckin easy once l found it.. It was just there..
you know.. parks! or finding it in the fields...
You've got the Come'n'Shop and the Shop'n'Come bag?
So.. how did that bloke get the stuff
out of them.. dogs again?
- Kill them.
- That's what Roy Arnie is gonna do with Jimmy.
- Fuck off. Is he?
- Yeah mate! He said so.
- How the hell are you gonna kill something that big?
- You can't just whack over him with a pipe.
Coz, it's not what you're killing
something small, like a cat!
This is unreal man!
Me and mate, used to put an ad in the papers..
just before the summer holidays...
Going on holiday... Need any unwanted pets!
Taking care of...
Couldn't be simpler...
Stick'em in the sack and then.. whack him with an iron bar.
Yeah man! how are you gonna do it, aaye..?
Puch Jimmy off the cliff or somthing..?
- That's not a bad idea.
- No kidding as it were easy.... Just whack the bag up the exhaust pipe.
- I can't believe you're carrying on, lot you gave a shit, Arnie!
- Talk about fucking crocodile tears mate!.
- Yeah, how low can you go?
- Pretty.. fuckin.. Iow!
Did you hear him?
That you guys ever done a good deed?
Yeah! if someone murder an elephant
thats really a good deed, a really good deed for ya..
Luckily, if thats a good deed..
I'm glad, uncle found out the scouts mate!
Shut up!
You're all in as much as l am.
- It's cold.
- Ya l'm freezing my ass off.
Everything's working men!
Look! Look, the heater is doin blast.
- My lips are paining!
- I'll stop howning this awful blast.
Ya, well it don't seem to be helping.
Not even a little bit.
You stole a truck without a windsheild? You stupid bastard!
What sort of a thief are you?
There's no window!
Jesus Christ! I don't fucking believe it!
Are you saying you didn't notice that?
What will you say? You say l shouldn't have
taken it because lt didn't have a wind-screen?
- This hardly gonna be pleasent, is it?
- Are we suggesting, we drive over the mounts...
...in a truck that don't have a windshield?
Have you lost what little mind you had?
- How could you not see it?
- I just didn't okay! I just.. didn't!
It's not your technique.. as if you know
what could've taken either of it!
What the hell...?
- What the hell are you doing now?
- It's a red light, for Christ's sake
- Jimmy?
- It's definitely an elephant.
How did he get here?
Stop!
Well we better get him on the truck quick.
I mean he sticks out a bit. Doesn't he?
No, shit Gaz!
You think he sticks out?
Jimmy, Jimmy...
He he he he... Ya ya ya...
Come here, Jimmy!
Ya look! I've got your goodies.
Thought you could come, and get it!
Come and get it Jimmy!
It's medication time!
C'mon, c'mon now.. thats.. thats it!
Ya, thats a good boy!
- He's eating them.
- O' yeah! He'll be fine now, he had them.
It's gonna be okay now.
Everything is gonna be finel.
Get your asses out here. We've got to get
him loaded onto the truck and right now!
I don't believe it.
The elephant!
They've hidden the loot inside the elephant.
Inside the elephant?
What do you mean inside the elephant?
We must call the Russians!
Tell them that we have found it!
Not Ante!
Are you stupid?
The Russians are not to know a thing.
We'll keep it all for ourselves.
Hello!, hello!...
- Elephants don't disappear in the thin air just lilke that.
- Maybe it just wanted to go back to the circus.
Do you think he'd willingly go
back to the animal abusers?
Are you completely stupid?
It's those Lapps again!
The ones from the circus!
- What are they up to?
- Maybe they're after the elephant too...
Ooo, Whaaoo!
Thats just genius Erik!
Actually, l think that is exactly
what they are doing.
You know what Lapps are like?
Animal abusers!...
...the lot of them.
Lets follow them.
- What if it starts to rain?
- Or snow.
It's below zero man!
My nuts are frozen to the seat!
Jesus Christ, man!
Shouldn't he had calm down by now?
Yeah, He should be nicely toasted.
Totally my ass!
I am losing the control!
Give him some more stuff for christ's sake.
Give him some more dope!
Hey cool it Jimmy!
- Get'em of him!
- No! no, don't hurt Flea! Don't do it.
- For Jesus Flea! Do you mind not driving in this way?
- He's not letting me driving.
Well then, Brake!
No, Jimmy!
Jimmy Jimmy.. now it's me!
It's Roy Arnie. Now.. You know..
I've got...
I've got drugs!
It's okay.. it's aa.. I got it..
Jimm...
Jesus! elephant puke!
Odd? Odd?
O' shit, Odd!
You almost drowned man!...
...just like Jimi Hendrix.
Like, that was a real close one man!
- Jimi Hendrix?
- Yeah he drowned in... he drowned in vomit, right?
Yeah, in his own vomit?
- Oi! oi! over here!
- Pull over!
- Let me out!
- Oi! Boys! Are you gonna thank me or what?
- Shit! I can't open the door!
- Yeah! Now you're glad l picked...
...the truck without a windscreen aye..?
- What the bloody hell are you doing Gaz?
- I can't open the door!
- Of course it won't open. It hitting a fucking rock, stupid!
- Oi! I just think we're all a great bunch of bastards.
- What happened to Jimmy?
- He ran off.
Up there!
That way...
Why the hell didn't Jimmy calm down?
- Please, let me out.
- Whats the matter with you?
- Whats the matter with him?
- The door won't open.
- I think he swallowed one of Jimmy's pills.
- Oh, no! we gave him the wrong shit man!
- We gave him from the Shop'n'Come bag.
- Aye?
What we gave Jimmy is the wrong stuff. He got the
Shop'n'Come bag when he should've got the Come'n'Shop bag!
Jimmy has got the speed instead of the dope.
Thats...
- ...bad news!
- Oh!, that explains why Gaz is so mounted!
For heaven's sake, get me out guys!
The door won't open... will ya.. the door won't open.
- Roll out of the front window there you fucking moron!
- Roll out of the front window you idiot!
Aye?
What?
- We got to find Jimmy!
- He went that way.
Jimmy, split man! Where has he gone?
We've got to find him, for fuck's sake...
...we can't just stand with the thumbs up our asses.
We've gotta...
- Say! wha?
- ...find Jimmy. He can't just dissapear
He's off his head.
Give us one of them.
Hey, wait up now!
I... I guess to get the Shope'n'C..
I mean the Come'n'Shop bag.
- Jimmy!
Get your grey ass down here for fuck's sake.
- I can't take this out much longer. I'm naked!
- Jimmy!... Jimmy!
I can't go on.
- Stop whining man!
- Can we find him some place?
- O' Please! I wanna go home!
- Help us! Please...
...please help us find Jimmy, please...
for love of God man!
- Please!!!
- He's got to be a serious cold turkey by now...
- Shit! I ain't feeling any good.
- O'...
- He can't be far.
- Let's just give it up. This is fucking hopeless.
We can't give up. I'll lose everything.
We! Iose everything.
My whole fucking circus'll go to hell.
We ain't giving up.
- A place there'll be rest up, l'll take it.
- You can't take so more, c'mon!
Drugs!
- No!
- Check it out!
We'll blow all those bastards sky high!
- Aahh...
- We've had that Sonia! don't cry again.
- I'll screw this. I'm nacking.
- We have to find Jimmy!
- I'm freezing...
- We've to find...
- I am freezing my balls off!
- ...to find.
- Oh.. we've been looking for ages man!
- So cold!
- This is so fucked.
- rrreally cold.
- Totally pointless.
- I can see my mommy.
Ah.., that beauty of the mountains is so great..
to get away from the city, honey!
From the noise, the cars, the pollution!
Away from the frantic pace..
the crime! and all.. those.. people.
Everything is so clean and untouched.
Somehow lnnocent, you know...
These self-service cabins are really terrific.
A place to meet peace for gentle nature lovers.
- Like us!
- Yup! It's quiet satisfactory.
- This is gonna be the best holiday we've ever had.
- hmmm...
- This is bloody brilliant!
- Thank Christ, we're saved!
- About fucking time.
- Tell me it's real. Tell me l'm not triping.
Fucking Coffee!
Oh, Shit!
- Jesus! I'm hungry!
- Hey mister! I could eat the hay out of my home pit.
- hmm.. ya.. well.. you gotta be quick then, ain't ya!
- Don't worry boys, there's tons of food.
I won't forget ever! in my life.. ever tasted food this good.
We should open another can.
They've even got beer down here.
That is fucking unbelievable!
Hey! you know what we need now?
Some decent sounds.
- Alright slut! a gift from God.
- I can smell puke man! Who's blowing chunk?
It's Jimmy puke in it.
- Thats what stinks
- We'd started to fall...
Shit, you know if we stayed out there much longer
we'd have froze to death man!
Oye! Chaps! It's beds in here..
Fuck me! they look good.
- And there're sleeping bags too.
- You know what? I think I'll just turn in for a night.
Oye! how come you and Odd get the sleeping bags?
Coz our clothes're completely
drenched in elephant puke. Thats why...
...Am I asking too much? huh...
Am I being unreasonable?
Ah Yeah! I'm starting to get warm now.
- I can honestly...
- Thats so fucking good...
Put in my head... on a pillow...
has never felt this good...
Never...
- That was the fucked day without even a glimps of moose!
- Aye, and Hudmaspecs has been a nightmare!
Do you think he'll ever get over about what
happened last year with that Pakistani fellow?
Are you crazy?
Never!
Aye, I suppose for him it was a pure sack of rage..
An... asian shooting his moose!
O' he did take it very hard.
Had the moose in his sight...
Finger on the trigger... when that Pakistani
fellow came along and.. you know... "Bang!"
Aye.. good thing we got'em back to the camp..
you know what I'm saying...
Well Hud expect you both what had happened.
Aa Yeah! lucky for the Pakistani fellow..
maybe also lucky for us!
You're telling me? Up your showers and
we could gave me at a day.
Yeah me too. There was something in his eyes...
Something dangerous!
- Aye!
But as long as he's bolt with all that anger
over last year.. it ain't safe...
...for man or beast up here.
We have to just go again on the moose tomorrow.
If not! then the shake thats well and truely gonna have to fan!
Reports're coming in that an elephant has been released
on to the road by a unidentified party!
Be warned! not to approach or attempt to capture
the elephant.. as it is considered... very dangerous.
The public are advised that they can recoginze
the elephant by it's trunk and face!
President Bao flies to Asia...
You know honey! I am sure that if we aa...
treat these gentlemen with respect...
They'll understand that the sleeping bags.. are infact...
- ...ours!
- They are non-Americans, Harv! Speak to them!
You are good with the ethnically challanged!
Yeah...
Hey! they are here...
The little shits.
You know! I think that mm...
maybe we just got the wrong impression here.
We'll smoke the ass holes out of there.
- He... he he he he...
Fucking wankers!
If we just.. maybe talk to them..
you know.. very politely!
It's burning...
- Harvey, the cabin is on fire!
- Haa....
Shit man!
Whats all this noise?
Fucking...
Too hot!
Who filthy fuckin smoking in bed?
Open the window, will ya?
- See its hot in here?
- Open it yourself.
Oh.. hey.. just getting up..
Take it easy..
I'm sleeping here!
Oh, shit!
Where... is... the elephant?
Hey, Hudmaspecs!
I bet there's a whole lot of gross is in those bushes over there!
- No
- Lets find it together.. shall we?
I'm after something big!
O' Jesus!
I feel sick.
Oh fuck! I have never been this hung before.
You're goona feel a whole lot worse if Hudmaspecs
doesn't manage to bag himself a moose!
What if we spread out. Maybe we'll have
a bare chance of finding one!
We shouldn't have got so far.
Coz not much moose are in here.
Aae! But also not many peoply either!
Wow!
This is such an exciting operation!
You're just in this for a ride. You don't care that there
is an elephant out there hooked on drugs!
I can't be asked for this!
When I was an eco terrorist.. atlleast we all owned cars!
A car is eco friendly!
Come on! we can't give up now.
This is the mission of our lives!
Liberating an exploited circus elephant
from the pits of drug addiction.
- We!
- Hey! listen!
- He is a drug addict right?
Let's get some drugs and use them as bait.
That way.. when he comes to get them..
we can just... grab him.
- O' that is just genius Lise!
- Yeah! come on genius! got any better ideas?
Here we are!
fighting... Putting our lives on the line.
for...
The animals!
And the only thing you two can do is...
argue and complain about everything.
- It's Erik!
- Yeah you really need to examine your attitude Erik!
You girls always stick together..
don't you? Well I'm so fucking sick!
- A a a.. Remember what we agreed about your swearing.
- And you! Marius! you're always on their side. You...
You fucking creep! Cock sucking...
Camel fucking.. Pee See.. Nasty...
One! I am not siding with the girls.
Two! l am... by no means a camel.. fucker!
- What do you mean you're not siding with the girls?
- Oh, fuck this.
- I am out of here.
- Where are you going?
Erik please! whats your problem?
Perhaps you should re-consider you behaviour.
- O' Fuck off!
- You can't just walkout of our relashionship that is...
- Not even you're doing?
- I'm coming with you.
Just forget about Lise and Erik.
They havn't been truely with us for a long time.
Anyway, there are more important things on the agenda.
Check it out!
There thay are!
Come on!
You'll be free.
For God's sake stay on your feet.
Odd! Oodd!
Hey! Aaoo!
Oy! Roy Arnie!
Listen! Odd!
Listen up, please!
- Odd! listen!
- Shut your face Flea! Give it a rest, will ya?
Ya but look! look over there...
It's Jimmy!
The elephant!
Hey, Hudmaspecs! I'm gonna run up
to the ridge there... and have a look...
Is that a good idea?
Aahh...
O' well...
O' God No!
- Whats happening?
- I'm seeing things... I'm having visions.
I knew it! The doctor said to go easy
on the booze.. and now it's happened!
I'm seeing things for Christ's sake.
That does not sound too good,
what're you seeing, spiders or what?
Elephants!
I'm seeing Elephants in the middle of the day.
It's too late.
I've always been shaky scared to get that this would happen.
What are you talking about,
pink elephants! like in the cartoons?
Eddie has been overdosing in bloody cartoons!
- I didn't say it was pink!
- Don't do it Eddie!
- We can see him too.
What the hell is an elephant doin up here?
And where the devil did he come from?
There was a circus in town when we left.
Maybe he ran away.
- Yeah! but how did he get that far?
- What do you think we should do?
The elephant!
is mine!
This isn't the same as shooting a moose.
- He belongs to someone.
- And they're probably right behind that hell over there.
- They're gonna...
- What are you saying?
That...
They're gonna...
- Whats goin on?
- They're gonna shoot Jimmy!
- But Hudmaspecs.
- He shot.. my moose...
so I'm gonna shoot his elephant.
An Eye for an eye!
Its really fair.
Oh, shit! It saw that, expensive?
They exploded his head.
What happened?
Oye Look! Look!
I've losen my ropes.
O' That was an accident.
No doubt about it.
A prime example of an accidental discharge.
Absolutely no doubt it could have happened to anyone.
There was the moose! Did you see it?
It was the moose that pushed Hudmaspecs!
Aye, the moose, yeah.. it was.. it was just almost the..
The moose came to help the elephant!
- You saw, that the elephant...
- The elephant!
The elaphant!
The elephant must not escape.
Holy Jesus! let's get out of here.
- Where's Jimmy, man?
- Jimmy, gone!
- Where to.
- He just.. disappeared.
To Warriors Against Animal Torture and Subjugation!
Put down your weapons!
Hold my specs!
- Where the fuck did he come from?
- Let's get going.
Thats all we need that animal live!
- Go home for God's sake.
- I don't care. I'll blow us all to hell.
- I am going to fuckin flaten his ass.
- Throw your weapons, or it'll go off
I think you should know...
I am prepared to kill myself.
Die in peace, Marius!
You may die Marius! but you'll take some
damn the animal abusers along with you.
We will save Jimmy!
- Is he a little slow in the end or what?
- Definitely!
Jimmy!
Jimmy?
Ye ha!
- Motorbikes!
- Wait.. No!
Stay away from the elephant!
He is mine!
- I mean it! or its all up!
- Get away from him you eel shaped!
- Give up... or we die!
- I'll miss your elephant. Now you better be ready!
- Hudmaspecs, you are alive!
- Fucking foreigners!
The elephant...
should've been mine!
- You hear me?
- We hear you buddy.
O' atleast we didn't get blown into pieces.
- Come on!
- Are you out of your mind?
This is stupid!
Aye, that elephant is not right
at the edge, mate!.
Come on in, Jimmy!
It's medication time!
Thats it, C'mon...
Every little thing going to be alright, Jimmy!
Don't you recognize me baby?
Don't you recognize me?
Check'em now, He's taking those...
- I'm shaking like a leaf.
- Nearly shot myself there...
Oh, shit!
No, don't do it Jimmy!
No, no, no! Karma!
Karma!!!
Once upon a time, there was a little mouse...
And this little mouse found
himself a well.. deserved...
...piece of cheese.
Now its our turn man!
- Come on! He can't be far off.
- Oh, just leave it, will you Arnie!
- Jimmy!
- I mean what we're gonna do if we find him anyway?
Come on! We'll split it up equal...
Four ways.
What the fuck?
Stop.. that.. beast!
Stop!
No!
I thought we'd dead our chips then.
I want to go home.
- Where is Jimmy man?
- Jimmy!
We are goin home...
Now!
up till now the police have
no theory regarding the six people
found dead on the mountains.
According to a spokes person it seems probable..
two tourists shot dead...
Did you hear what I said?
We're setting all this circus crap!
- You owe us, man!
- You just fucking try it!
Odd! C'mon man! we'll split it fair.
Just help me find Jimmy.
You know what? I don't give a
shit about your stupid.. fucking...
- circus!
- No!
No! I will find Jimmy.
I don't care if he's dead or alive.
He's out there somewhere, and
I just gonna find him.
I'll start over again from scratch. Maybe slow!
but my dream... my dream will come true..
The Roy! Arnie! Circus!
Roy Arnie! For Christ's sake, do me a favor.
Stop slamming that fucking whip round...
- ...makes me nervous.
- Ya, and will you please get out of that circus club...
...or it is getting on my tits.
You are obsessed, mate!
Hey Flea! why the fuck are you
wearing that clown costume?
Well I was just a..
It was.. just thinking you know.. maybe
Maybe I could become backup...
curcus clown!
- Oye?
- Don't you think I'll make a good clown? Fellows!
Yeah! certainly man!
You'd make a great clown.
Yeah Certainly!
Flea ain't a fucking artist.
He'd never make a clown!
Just look at him!
What the hell you're doing, you silly bastard!
My eyes! oh my eyes!
Flea?
You blinded Flea!
You knocked his eye out!
Come on now!
I didn't hit you that hard!
Aahhh!
That... really... hurt!
- What do you know about a circus anyway Aey?
- Yeah go on Flea! Give'em chilling...
- He has messed things up once too often...
- You fucking, cock sucking fl...
- O' Flea! beat it there!
- You shit.. fat.. fucking.. fl..
Bust his nuts, Flea!
- Actually... I'll do it... Myself!
- ...fucking.. I'll rip your bone off...
- ..I'm gonna hit you fucking hard.
- This is for your stupid circus!
- And this is for Jimmy you bastard
- You fucking bastards!
- He was cool man!
- Ya! he was really cool...
- ...even if he was an elephant.
- Especially consider it, it was...
I'll find Jimmy.
I'll get my circus.
Jimmy!
Jimmy!!!