FEMALE PRISONER #701
SCORPION - BEAST STABLE
"Flowers are beautiful"
- his words flatter you today.
But once you're in full bloom,
he'll just toss you away.
Foolish, foolish,
foolish woman's song...
Her song of vengeance.
"You cling to your dreams"
- they scorn your world of lies.
So you try to wake up,
but you can't open your eyes.
A woman, a woman,
a woman's heart is her song...
Her song of vengeance.
A bright red rose has thorns
that you might not see.
I don't want to pierce you,
but how else will I get free?
Burning, burning,
burning woman's song...
Her song of vengeance.
Shedding blood once a month
should help, and yet...
Try as I might, I can't ever forget.
A woman, a woman,
a woman's life is her song...
Her song of vengeance.
Big Brother...
You've had enough, haven't you?
Hey, mister!
Hey, mister.
Would you like to see something hot?
20 yen for one match. 3 for 50 yen...
I'll give you a discount!
Sure.
Here you go.
Hurry up, will you?
Come on, come on, deeper!
I can't see anything!
Goddamn you! If you want a
good look, give me more money!
What the hell. Let's go.
No!
My brother can't help himself.
He doesn't know what he's doing.
There was an accident at the factory...
it's left him brain-damaged!
I don't believe you, either!
How could you do that?
Don't I always give you
all the sex you want?
Let me stay the night.
I'm not going home to my brother.
I don't care about him.
He can just starve to death!
What? Is that wrong?
Kill him for me, then.
You would've the other day
if I hadn't stopped you...
The cops are after you, anyway!
Yuki...
That's right. I'm pregnant.
It's my brother's baby!
Yuki!
Hey, there, mister!
Want to see something hot?
Damn!
Look at this bitch. Thinks she's
gonna do business here, huh?
Goddamn you...
- Caught her again, huh?
- Teach her a lesson!
Ha! Serves you right!
You, slut!
Taking business away from us!
You moron!
Hey, the moron's calling her a moron!
You're not really gonna
have that baby, are you?
She doesn't even know who the father is!
Goddamn you, bitch!
Slut!
Please, stop!
Boss.
What's going on?
We caught her working our
territory without paying us.
Give her to me.
If you want to do business,
you've got to pay your dues.
Understand?
You get out.
Go on, get out!
I'm having this baby.
Call me a beast if you want.
I'm going to have this baby!
Just as I thought!
You've got a great body.
You're so starved for sex...
your whole body's on fire!
Come on, I'll show you a good time.
Look at you. Full of defiance!
But listen...
...I know who you are.
WANTED
For Murder, Escaped Convict
You can either be my woman or get
yourself handed over to the cops.
You think it over tonight, got that?
Tonight's the night.
Hello? Hello? Who the hell is this?
Better watch it, or you’re
going to lose your man.
"Better watch it, or you're
going to lose your man."
Better watch it, or I'm just going to
find myself another man to love.
Who knew that anything else
could be so sublime?
Those nights I swayed in your arms
like a shimmering wave of heat.
Once in a while I shed gentle tears...
Am I always that kind of woman to you?
I just want to catch fire
and drive you insane...
Tanida died this morning at the hospital.
The cops are calling it
an accidental death...
But his woman says
you cooked up the whole plot.
How are you going to make up for this?
He was a valued employee
of mine, you know!
Listen, that kind of talk isn't
going to get you anywhere.
She's got to pay us damages with
her body, if she's got no money...
Just come right out and say it...
Scorpion!
Look, Katsu...
Honey, you can just work the hell
out of this girl until she drops dead.
No way is she ever going
to squeal on us to the cops.
How could she? She was in prison
for murder, and now she's on the run.
Next time she gets arrested,
she's going to Death Row for sure!
Damn you, Matsu!
You really made my life
hell when we were inside.
Now it's my turn to do a number on you!
CLINIC
Work hard, now!
Aren't you going a little too far?
Just shut up and come.
Hey, you're coming with us!
Well... you've gotten so big
before anyone noticed.
So about how far along is she?
I'd say... six months or so.
It's a little too late, huh?
She's setting a bad example
for the other girls...
What are you going to do about this?
Calm down, now, honey.
Shinobu, you're so far along,
you'd better go see a doctor.
I'll take you to the hospital now.
That's a good girl.
No need to be afraid.
You're going to a doctor
who'll take care of your baby.
No! It's my baby!
Leave me alone!
I'm going to have this baby!
I'm not going to any doctor!
No! It's my baby!
No!
No! No! Leave me alone!
O.R.
Next.
No!
No! No!
No! Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
My baby!
Thank you for coming.
I'm Lieutenant Yamazaki.
That woman... she'll
be coming back for us!
You idiots, she got away
because you were so inept!
Easy, Katsu.
One girl... big fucking deal!
What the hell?
Goddammit!
Bastard!
You know that the doctor was murdered.
And you're next on her list.
Hey, lady.
I'm sure you haven't forgotten how
dangerous Nami Matsushima can be.
Don't fool yourselves,
she's no ordinary woman.
Prisoner 701.
Do you know what they
all called her in prison?
The Scorpion.
Goddammit!
Out of my way!
Mister, why don't you stop by?
Move it!
Out of my way!
Goddammit!
- Serves them right.
- That woman must be something else.
Thanks to her, we can do
whatever we want here.
Mister?
Want me to show you a good time?
I won't charge you much.
Escaped Convict Wanted For Murder
Emergency Warrant For Fugitive
She's turning herself in for
forcing women into prostitution.
I guess rotten prison food seems
more appealing than getting killed.
Do you think she'll come?
What a vengeful bitch...
I've been possessed by
the soul of the dead girl.
All right! Surround her!
Hey!
There!
Don't go too far in!
Block off the exits!
Yes, sir.
- Any problems?
- No, sir.
- I'm counting on you.
- Yes, sir.
Scorpion?
Scorpion!
Light 4 or 5 of these matches...
and stick them between your legs.
That'll warm you to the bone. That's
what we do whenever it's cold outside.
That's it. That's the way.
Doesn't that warm you up?
The cops are coming, so...
Yuki...
What about your baby?
It's been a week now. There's no
food down there in the sewers...
And I doubt she could've
survived all that rain.
Detective Gondo...
I understand you've locked up your
retarded brother in the closet.
I wonder what will happen to that moron
unless you get home to feed him?
Why don't you let us know
when you feel like cooperating?
Scorpion?
Scorpion!
Yuki...
All right, come along.
Yes, sir!
All right, go get her!
Big Brother...
Big Brother!
About face!
Get in there!
Get a move on! Hurry the hell up!
Hey, everybody. Here's a newcomer.
Be nice to her. Go on.
Hey Guard, what's the new girl in for?
Arson. She's in for three months.
Three months? That's
just a spit in the ocean.
Three months, eh?
Go to sleep, go to sleep...
drift away to sleep...
Such a good little boy...
go to sleep now.
The little boy's nanny,
where has she gone?
She climbed that mountain,
and went back to her home.
What the hell's going on?
You're out of your mind.
Get down from there!
- Get her down.
- Yes, sir.
- Hand that over!
- Get down!
Give him back! That's my baby!
- That's my baby! That's Akio!
- Come with us!
Give him back to me!
Akio! Akio! Akio!
Give me back my baby! Akio!
Akio! Akio! Give me back my Akio!
Give me back my baby!
Akio! Give me back my baby!
Give him back! That's my baby!
Give him back to me!
Help me! Help me!
Doctor! Doctor!
The patient... the patient's...
It's the Scorpion!
The Scorpion...
The Scorpion's going to kill me!
I'm telling you, her terror is abnormal.
She keeps saying that
the Scorpion's going to kill her.
She's imagining things. The woman
Katsu Samejima's terrified of is dead.
Has anything out of the
ordinary happened to her?
No, nothing out of the ordinary
A new prisoner joined her ward,
but that's about it.
- A newcomer?
- Yes.
- The key to Cell 24.
- Yes, sir.
After you.
May I see her alone? There's something
I'd like to discuss in depth with her.
I see. Then please, be my guest.
The... alarm...
I killed the Scorpion!
10 days later, the Scorpion served
out her term, and was released.
Nobody ever knew what became of her.
I cannot die before I fulfill my fate.
So I live on, driven only by my hate.
A woman, a woman,
a woman's life is her song...
Her song of vengeance.
SCORPION - BEAST STABLE
THE END