So, Jon, when did your interest
in Comrade Detective begin?
Oh, when I was doing my
documentary on Stanley Kubrick.
It's called Stanley Kubrick's Boxes.
I actually found a copy
of Comrade Detective
in one of his boxes.
- Come on. No way.
- Yeah, yeah.
Kubrick had a copy.
There's one mention of Comrade Detective
in his diaries, from March 13, 1991.
He wrote, "We watched episode three
of Comrade Detective over dinner."
So, Stanley Kubrick was a fan?
A fan and a student. Yeah.
Wow. That's crazy.
- Should we keep watching?
- Absolutely.
The Father, the Son
and the Holy Ghost.
The Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost.
The Father, the Son
and the Holy Ghost.
The Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Bucharest PD!
Put your hands on your
head, turn around, slowly.
Turn around! Turn around!
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come...
- The guy's got a knife.
- ... thy will be done...
Drop it, motherfucker. Drop it!
... on Earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses...
- Put it down!
- ... as we forgive those
- who trespass against us.
- Don't be a hero.
- And God said...
- He's gonna do it!
- I don't believe it!
- ... let there be blood!
Holy shit!
- Look at this.
- Oh, geez. What the... ?
Look at the...
What the... ?
♪ And I hold them like a jewel ♪
♪ And they are colors ♪
♪ With an ancient fame ♪
♪ Of a brave nation. ♪
Hey there. He's here.
Come... come have a
drink with me, partner.
Constantine!
Give my partner a drink!
You been here all night?
And I'll be here all day.
Now, come on, goat fucker, have a drink.
Nikita would have a drink.
Where is Nikita?
Hmm?
Nikita!
Nikita...
Captain Covaci officially
reopened Nikita's case.
We have a chance to bring
the killer to justice,
but we won't find him at the
bottom of a bottle, Gregor.
I miss him, Joseph.
Yeah, me, too.
But he's dead, and there's no afterlife.
So we'll never see him again.
But he can live on in our good deeds.
You're right.
Don't you ever do that again.
Goat fucker.
In the name of the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit, amen.
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
It has been one week
since my last confession.
I have committed multiple murders.
Do you accept Jesus
Christ as your savior?
I do.
Good. Now say five Our
Fathers and two Hail Marys.
I will do more than that.
I will build you a
church so big and awesome
that all who enter will
be forced to their knees.
Then Romania will know
the true power of the Lord.
You are a broken vessel,
but I believe you have
been sent by the Almighty.
Bless you, my son.
Eh, he paid his rent on time,
he wasn't loud, kept to himself.
What is all this crap?
Thanks, lady, but we got it from here.
- Okay. Thanks.
- Oh, watch it. I'm spoken for.
What kind of freak lives like this?
I mean, look at this shit.
Check it out.
Bibles. In English.
What do you think?
I think we got some religious
nut who's smuggling in Bibles.
When he got caught, he killed
himself to avoid jail time.
Open and shut.
Open and shut. Hmm.
Hey, are you hungry?
Yeah.
Let's get lunch.
Hmm. Excuse me.
Carry the one...
Okay, very funny.
All right, well,
I just got to send them
in. I'll just take my lunch.
Great, here come these
two fucking assholes.
Oh, I heard you guys
closed a case before lunch.
Congratulations.
Yeah, Marku Miklos.
Religious nut. Slit
his throat this morning.
See?
That's how it's done, fuck-o.
The report said he has a stash
of English-language Bibles.
Nothing about that
seemed strange to you?
So the guy's into creepy Christian shit.
What's strange about that, huh?
Well, in case you
forgot, Nikita was killed
by a man with ties to an
international smuggling ring.
The guy was acting alone, fellas.
Go bark up another tree.
Yeah, some loner sneaking
in Bibles eventually
gets curious and gets hooked
on the same shit he's pushing.
Happens all the time.
Yeah, yeah, no, I'm sure you're right.
- Of course I'm right.
- Yeah.
Hey!
- Stop, please!
- You call yourself a detective,
you ginger piece of shit?
- Let go! Let go!
- We questioned his landlady.
He had no friends, kept to
himself, just him and his religion.
The case is closed!
End of story!
- Stop, please!
- Give us the file.
You like jerking off
with your left hand?
No! Give him the fucking file!
- Aah, give him the file!
- Fucker.
Ah, worked at a neighborhood bakery.
Did you question his coworkers?
Fuck you.
Enjoy your soup.
Motherfucker.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
I'm Detective Baciu and
this is Detective Anghel.
We're looking for
information on Marku Miklos.
Marku Miklos.
Yes.
I was saddened to hear of his passing.
Still, I wasn't surprised.
No? And why's that?
He was a strange young man.
Always praying.
If it rained, he prayed.
If he was late, he prayed.
If he couldn't find his keys, he...
He prayed, right.
And you don't share his
interest in the Christian occult?
Comrades...
I'm just a baker.
And Marku, he was a troubled boy.
He spoke constantly of his faith.
And why exactly didn't
you inform on him?
How about a slice of bread?
Hmm.
Marku spoke often about
transubstantiation.
Are you gents familiar with the term?
Yeah. Transubstantiation.
In countries that are slaves
to the Christian faith,
they eat bread during
ritualized worship.
They believe that the bread
literally turns into the body of Christ.
Correct.
Think about that.
One second, you're chewing on my bread,
and the next moment, that
very same bread is transformed
into the flesh of Jesus Christ.
An absurd superstition.
Let's hope so,
or the two of you would've
just eaten the flesh of a man.
Well, that guy's a fucking weirdo.
Let's pull his file.
His name's Anton Streza.
Arrested eight years ago
for burglary and assault.
Did six years in prison.
Once he was released,
got a job at the bakery.
Kept a low profile ever since.
Gregor.
Look who the arresting officer was.
Detective Nikita Ionescu.
Could six years in prison
drive a man to murder?
Well, it certainly wouldn't
result in friendship.
We should take a closer
look at this Streza.
What's this guy's game?
Farooota, mika,
shooooo,
maliki maka.
Idiot.
The body of Christ. The body of Christ.
The body of Christ.
For thine is the kingdom,
and the power, and the glory,
for ever and ever.
Aah... !
Gregor. Hey, wake up.
What?
He's on the move.
♪ Three colors I know in the world ♪
♪ And I hold them like a jewel ♪
♪ They are colors with an ancient fame ♪
♪ Reminders of our brave nation ♪
♪ Red is the fire that
permeates my heart ♪
♪ Which is full of longing ♪
♪ For holy liberty... ♪
♪ Shall be our future ♪
♪ Always in eternal blossom ♪
♪ And unwithered radiance... ♪
Is he hurt?
Hello, comrade.
You don't think we know where you live?
We got your file, asshole.
Oh...
Gideon Bible, straight from the USA.
Some heavy shit for a baker.
Congratulations, pal,
you're under arrest.
All right, bread boy, what are these?
They're books.
Books that hold the Word of God.
We know what Bibles are, Streza.
It's my favorite work of fiction.
We found these same
Bibles on Marku Miklos.
Where are you getting them?
We prayed for them...
and God answered our prayers.
Hmm.
Marku Miklos committed suicide.
Doesn't that mean he's destined
to spending eternity in hell?
God has a tremendous
capacity for forgiveness,
unless you're a nonbeliever, Detective.
Then you go straight to hell.
How convenient.
So, people smart enough to know
there's no such thing as God,
we're the ones who should be worried.
You cannot prove there is no God.
That's because you
can't prove a negative.
Absence of evidence is
not evidence of absence.
All I know is God is good.
Is he?
Then explain war, rape.
Explain death and suffering.
Explain the horrors
man has had to endure
since the beginning of time.
God works in mysterious ways.
And that's all I'm going to say.
That crazy fuck's not
gonna give us anything.
How do you suppose someone
even gets wrapped up
in all this bullshit?
The universe is complex.
Religion offers simple-minded people
easily digestible answers.
It takes a great deal
of study to understand
how we rotate around
the sun, or to comprehend
the gravitational pull of our orbit.
It's much easier to just be told that...
God brings the sun out in the morning
and puts it away at night.
You make it sound so innocent,
like children who
believe in fairy tales.
Yeah, but don't forget,
every fairy tale has a monster.
What the fuck is she doing here?
Hello, Detectives.
As acting interim ambassador
to the United States,
I'm demanding the
release of Father Streza.
Father Streza?
Yes. He is a priest merely exercising
his fundamental human right
of practicing religion.
Okay, health care is a
fundamental human right.
Believing in an imaginary
God is a sign of insanity.
I have here a letter
signed by world leaders
calling for his release.
England, Canada, Australia, France...
Wales?
You gotta be fucking kidding me
with these bullshit countries.
I'm just doing my job.
And you've done it. Now you can go.
This isn't over, Detectives.
Great, now we got a ticking clock.
They're going to apply
international pressure.
How we gonna get this priest to talk?
You know what, Joseph?
You've been working too hard.
Go home to your family.
What are you planning?
I'm gonna set a herring
to catch a whale.
Good night.
Good night, Roy.
Good night, madam.
Uh...
What are you doing here?
You hungry?
I missed you.
I missed you, my love.
Ooh!
Mmm.
This bean soup with ham hock is so good.
I told you, it's the best in the city.
Bean soup is a delicacy.
When I go home, I'm really
going to miss the food
in this country.
I've never eaten so well.
You miss the United States?
I do.
I mean, I don't miss the poverty
or the crime or the...
racial inequality.
I certainly don't miss AIDS.
Everyone in the U.S. seems to have AIDS.
But America is still the
greatest country in the world.
Hmm.
What? It's true.
I mean, Romania has
some nice things, too.
Like, the literacy rate is amazing.
Everyone is so good-looking
and has such a youthful spirit.
But...
I miss my home.
I miss my country.
I think you're just lonely.
Yes.
Maybe I am.
Why aren't you with someone, Jane?
Why aren't you?
Because life is too short.
Hmm.
You're trouble.
Hmm?
Unfortunately, I'm a good American girl
and I don't sleep with
strange, Eastern European men
on the first date.
You want to bet?
Andrei? Andrei?
What?
Where's your sister?
She made me promise not to tell.
Well, that's a promise
you have to break.
It's your duty to inform
on your sister, Andrei.
And do the right thing.
♪ Are you ready for the sex girls? ♪
♪ The fine, fine, super
special, real sex girls ♪
♪ Are you ready for the best girls? ♪
♪ The knees-showin', knees-
showin' big-breast girls. ♪
I... I... I was just listening
for a second, that's all.
I... I didn't mean... I...
Listen, it's okay,
Flavia, I'm not angry.
You're not?
No.
You're almost a grown woman,
and so I'm gonna speak
to you like an adult.
Flavia, do you know what a whore is?
It's... it's a woman who
sleeps with men for money.
Exactly.
And do you think
that there are little girls
out there that dream of one day
growing up to become whores?
No, Papa, of course not.
No, of course not.
And yet the world is full of them.
The West wants to turn
us all into whores.
And they're devious in their ways.
But this is just music, Papa.
No, Flavia, it's propaganda.
It's propaganda designed
to break down your defenses,
little by little, and they
call it "art" or "music"
or "film" or "literature,"
but make no mistake
what it really is.
What is it really?
A tool for brainwashing.
Every time you listen
to one of these songs,
you are being indoctrinated.
Well, you didn't have to
break the radio, Flavia.
You know, there's a Bartók
concerto on tomorrow.
I've seen terrible things, Flavia.
It's why I'm so protective of you.
I love you, Papa.
I love you, too.
Mmm.
That's one more thing that
I'll miss about this country.
Romanians make love like no one else.
Listen, Jane...
Father Streza happens to
have information that I need.
Can you get him to talk to me?
Gregor, don't ruin the moment.
This man might have killed my partner.
I understand if you have
religious convictions,
but I need your help.
Okay.
Look, I'll be honest.
Some of us in the West don't
actually believe in religion.
We just pretend to in order to
convince a bunch of half-wits
to vote for us.
So, you'll help me then?
I'm a capitalist, Gregor.
If you want something,
you're going to have to work for it.
Really hard.
This is madness.
This is madness. You trust her?
No, but she trusts me.
You slept with her?
Yeah.
Well, detectives, looks
like you're in luck.
Father Streza has agreed
to give you information
in return for his immediate release.
We're authorized to release him
if he does, in fact, give us real info.
Where are you getting your Bibles?
They're the words of God,
and God is everywhere.
I want answers.
We all want answers.
But until you accept Jesus
Christ as your savior,
you're like a blind man
fumbling around in the dark.
So shed some light for me, Father.
Where were you and Marku
getting your Bibles?
There's a man intent on helping
me spread the word of God.
To you, he's a smuggler.
To me, he's an angel,
sent from heaven above.
And does this angel have a name?
He calls himself...
James Brown.
James Brown?
Hmm.
How do we find him?
You don't.
He has people who are devoted to him.
People like Marku
Miklos who keep him safe.
Who would rather slit their
own throats than give him up.
He is the rock on which
I will build my church.
He's coming for you, detectives.
He's coming for both of you.
How the fuck do we find him?
I told you, you can't.
He's a ghost. A holy ghost!
Okay, that's all you get.
Father Streza has been
more than forthcoming.
This is bullshit.
He gave us an alias.
That's all he knows.
And this interview is over.
Like hell it is.
Look, we had a deal,
and Father Streza has
lived up to his end.
Understood?
So, let me make this clear.
Release him now or I will use
the full power of my office
to make sure that the two of you
end up building canals in Constanta.
Got it?
Good.
You're free to go, Father.
These men won't bother you anymore.
May God bless you, comrades.
Hey, Father.
You know why Jesus
wasn't born in the West?
Enlighten me, Detective.
Because they couldn't find
three wise men or a virgin.
That's enough.
I will pray for you, Detective.
Nice work, Jane.
Do you think he bought it?
♪ My love ♪
♪ Tell me what it's all about ♪
♪ You've got something ♪
♪ That I can't live without ♪
♪ Happiness ♪
♪ Is so hard to find ♪
♪ Hey, baby ♪
♪ Tell me what is on your mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I can't wait ♪
♪ Baby, I can't wait ♪
♪ Till you call me on the telephone ♪
♪ I can't wait ♪
♪ Baby, I can't wait ♪
♪ Till we're all alone ♪
♪ I can't wait ♪
♪ You know I love you... ♪
Turn that fucking shit off!
♪ Even when you don't try... ♪
Put your hands on your head!
Comrades, I told you.
What did you tell us?
I told you James Brown
was coming for you.
He's coming for all of us!
Go, go. I'm okay.
♪ You'll never have to say good-bye. ♪
Freeze!
Take off the mask!
Now!
I said take off...
Joseph!
Joseph.
No!
Daddy.
How bad is it?
He's in a coma.
They don't know if he'll recover.
Pardon me, Detective.
There's a phone call for you.
Show me.
I'm warning you.
It's not pretty.
Just play it.
Play it again.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -