That poof is back from abroad.
Want a beer'!
Piss off.
The beer...
Feels really weird.
Like a dream or something.
There was a train. It was crazy.
Boys, coffee's ready.
I was, like, inside it
and there was this bridge...
I was inside the train and...
Then it, like, sank to the bottom.
I just can't explain it.
Then don't explain it.
I've poured your coffee.
It's getting cold.
Want a punch?
Hands straight. Straight!
Keep 'em up. Good.
Straight. Follow through.
That's the way.
Swipe. Good.
Good. That's it.
Double. Double.
Quit the fucking prancing.
If the wind could give me wings
I'd leave the darkening earth
I'd soar into the night sky -
up among the brightening stars
If I were young, guess what I'd do.
But you're not.
You're just as old as you feel.
Fuck that!
If it's her, I'm not in.
- Me neither.
Hi.
Well?
- Come out.
Fuck.
Where?
-just come out.
Did he try to barge in?
- Fuck that.
He's snooping for Raakel,
asking where I am.
I know Raakel well enough.
That Veera woman rang the other day.
And?
I told her you'd gone,
said you were already inside.
Forty, forty-one, forty-two...
Forty-three, forty-four...
Forty-six, forty-seven...
Fifty.
Fifty-one, fifty-two...
Fifty-three.
Fifty-four, fifty-five...
Two hundred and sixty-three.
Add 14 and you get 277.
Days and nights.
277 days.
That's it.
My whole sentence.
It's nothing.
No point counting it then.
What the fuck?
Windows, days.
What's it going to change?
Nothing.
Go get some beer.
And go to the shop
while you're at it.
Imagine all this burning.
What?
- The whole fucking lot.
Light it here and it'd all go up.
There'd be huge flames
flickering at your neck.
Your neck? -It would've
travelled right round the world.
Right.
Right. Goodbye!
- Thanks!
Crack open a beer.
They're my brother's.
Your brother can give you a beer if
he's got you running around after him.
Give us a sip.
Lick that up.
- Fuck off.
He came home last night.
- Who did'!
That fucking poof from your house.
- Okay. So what'!
What was that?
- What?
Why don't you air the room?
- What took you so long?
Catch.
- Bring it.
Listen.
- Yes?
Lend me a fifty.
Fucking listen.
- Haven't got any.
No, really.
Fetch me a towel.
The guys are going to
a cottage in Pusula.
Swimming and everything.
Empty the water.
Listen.
We can't leave him alone now.
Monday he's going... inside.
He might do something to himself.
Why don't you stay with him?
He never talks to me.
-Or me.
Can't you be a brother to him?
just once?
Fuck it.
- Don't say that.
Then give me a hundred.
How often do I ever get out?
I'll leave you some money,
eat at the gas station or something.
You can go to Pusula tomorrow,
or wherever it is you're going.
Simo. Is that Raakel?
You're fucking fat.
Jesus. Humans are humans
but only when they're young
are they night animals.
One of them's got a towel
wrapped round her head.
This one's an older wanderer
with an exceptionally large head.
I wonder whether she's carrying
all her earthly belongings up there
gold or diamonds.
Or maybe it's just grown.
We don't have access
to someone else's head now...
Do we?
Where's she going?
- She's got a new man.
I don't believe you.
She doesn't need you to believe.
Should go get a beer.
- Let's go.
We'd better go then.
- Well let's go then.
They won't serve you.
- I could wait.
What, outside?
- Yeah.
Try this.
I look religious, right?
-Like a fucking Mormon. Give it here.
Give yourself a parting.
Not like that.
Spike it up.
Great.
Now you look like a sparrow.
That's it.
So, where are we going?
The amusement park?
I understand you.
THE WATCHTOWER
RELIGION AND POLITICS
lie...
D'you think I look
like that blond guy?
What fucking blond guy'!
- You know.
In Deer/mater.
Stayed in town playing,
shooting and that.
Walk on ahead and I'll watch.
They're pretty good-looking.
Nah, broads, all of them.
Two pints. Cold.
They'll be whatever
temperature they are.
Remember,
there are two kinds of women.
Some don't give a fuck
about anything -
and some are always trying to save you.
Mine is the latter type.
You mean Veera?
The one that's always ringing us?
She's always smiling.
When she's upset,
then she really smiles.
And she's always upset.
Screw another woman, she gets upset.
Give her a slap, she gets upset.
And always that same
woeful grin on her face.
Have you, like, hit a woman?
You fucking bet I have.
What did she say?
She enjoyed it.
Women enjoy getting slapped.
You can hit women,
but don't hit men unless you have to.
And how old are you?
- He's old enough.
You'll have ID then?
- Yeah. I'll take 'em both, okay'!
Another time.
You can all fuck yourselves!
Quit gawping at yourself.
Your girlfriend'll probably
turn up there too
wherever it is you're going.
Don't you get it? I'm already there.
Left my fucking cigarettes back there.
Red Smarts. Mum's?
Yeah. From her handbag.
She coughs all the fucking time.
She'll end with cancer soon.
You watch her health like a dog.
Hey, Simo.
You're a good guy.
You're a good guy. I mean it.
You know the only thing in the world
you should be afraid of'!
It's hope.
Understand this. Hope.
If you're free of hope,
you're free of everything.
There's nobody stronger
than someone who's lost all hope.
I don't hope much. Normally.
We're going to see all this shit
blown to the wind, into space.
Not a stone unturned.
Burnt to nothing,
just as they predicted.
For billions of years this piece
of shit has been spinning around
first just steam and mud.
You know all this, right?
Then came jellyfish, fish, lizards,
amoebas, all with the same thought:
move forward whatever the cost
and eat everything in their path.
That's why they developed teeth
so they could dodge bigger animals
and chase after the smaller ones.
This is healthy, remember that.
But then something happened,
and it all went to shit.
Humans appeared on earth.
Humans are the only animals
that live in the future.
I won't eat this meat today,
I'll eat it tomorrow.
I won't drink today,
I'll drink at Christmas.
I'll screw my girl in 12 years' time
when I'm ready to be a dad.
I won't live today,
I'll live tomorrow.
But Simo, you see,
there is no tomorrow.
No tomorrow.
Not for humans.
The final act will start soon.
Humans will disappear from the stage.
There is no tomorrow.
When humans are extinct,
there'll be a kingdom of scorpions.
It says so in the scriptures.
Scorpions are the only animals
that can survive radioactive fallout.
Scorpions will eat human corpses.
Gouge out little Simo's eyes
guts bleeding out
in front of the shopping centre.
And when they've had enough,
they stab themselves to death.
It's true, they can.
Ready to kill
themselves at any moment.
Humans understand all right.
They watch their own demise
on TV every night.
Who can commit such a skilful suicide?
You needed a piss, right'!
We could join a brigade
or something.
We could save ourselves.
What are you on about?
- We could save ourselves.
Now fuck off.
Got a bit of a situation here.
And what kind of situation is that?
Is this fucking necessary?
You're back then?
Oh, it's you.
You're fucking drunk.
I'm not drunk.
Simo.
Simo, you see...
Why do you always have to...?
Little, little...
Simo, little Simo.
Mummy's little Simo.
Little Simo. Mummy's big...
Big, little. Little, big.
Little Simo.
Mummy's big...
I see.
Get yourself a glass
and you can have a taste.
Viva España!
- Simo!
'Viva' what?
You know.
All the way from here to Rhodes.
Don't be so childish.
Me? You, more like it!
Fuck, she lies to everyone!
Everybody knows
you're not in fucking Rhodes!
Raakel knows, Jusa laughs at you
and Raakel laughs at you.
You can't afford a fucking holiday!
You just hide here, pissed.
Fuck, you've...
you think you've tricked us all.
I am what I am.
Pretty childish.
It was just a few grams.
It was my thing, my fuck-up.
And I'll do the time.
It was supposed to be a shared thing.
We could have done it together.
Nothing we can do about it now.
Sorry.
He's a detective, this pretty boy.
Sorry, sorry...
Take a rest. For a little while.
Upstairs.
- Oh right.
What's that supposed to mean?
Am I going by myself?
Veera...
Do you like cats?
- Dunno.
I'm sure you do.
You're just embarrassed to say so.
It's difficult at your age.
It's the same thing
right through our culture.
Globalisation requires aggression.
Or what do you think?
Maybe.
You're a good kid, but you're evasive.
Doesn't matter.
Rebellion will become
marginalized and criminalized -
or aestheticised.
D'you understand?
No.
I mean, when you draw an erect penis
on a clean concrete wall
the criminal and
the aesthetic worlds combine.
What penis?
That dick.
Over there, next to the stairwell
I didn't draw it.
Feel like a drink?
Sometimes.
I mean now.
I'm thirsty.
- I can get you something.
Your mum lied,
said you'd already gone... inside.
And you just bedded another bloke.
You look pretty rough.
Thanks, you too.
We won't get through this unless
we sort it. -I'll get through this.
What do you want?
- What do I want?
I want you to get down.
Right here. Trousers down.
What?
So you won't then?
- You won't let me fuck you?
Which way?
- On all fours.
You not coming?
- Soon.
Turn this way.
Arse this way.
What?
Spread your legs.
Wider.
Okay.
You can get up now.
Beautiful, isn't it?
The mystics try to tell us that
everything in reality is okay.
There's nothing twisted about reality.
The only twisted things
are in our minds.
Events don’t justify
negative emotions.
Life is easy and joyous.
It only mistreats
delusions, ambitions
greed, desires.
Negative things exist in us humans -
but not in reality.
If humans disappeared
from this planet, life would carry on.
Nature would flourish
in all its beauty and aggression.
These negative emotions exist in us,
not in reality.
You're probably wondering
why it's so messy in here.
No, I'm not.
Are you afraid of me?
There are two things in this world:
love and fear.
In this world,
there's only one bad thing -
and that's fear.
And there's only one good thing -
and that's love.
Some people call it freedom, joy
God or whatever.
There isn't a single bad thing -
that can't be opened
without revealing fear.
There's always fear.
And when you unravel that fear
you find ignorance.
There's a line in the Bible that says:
'He will find himself
who first loses himself.'
Losing yourself means
understanding who you really are -
so you don't live
as though you're dreaming.
He who speaks doesn't know, and he who
knows doesn't speak. You say something.
We“...
What's your vision of the future?
Vision...?
I mean, when you close your eyes...
So close your eyes.
What do you see?
- Scorpions.
Scorpions?
- Yes.
That's what I see.
Scorpions.
They're the only creature
that can survive radioactive fallout.
It was written, you know.
What are they doing?
The scorpions.
When humans die out
they'll live in our houses
screwing each other.
And once they get pissed off,
they kill themselves with their tails.
Scorpions.
Apocalyptic visions, eh?
So I suppose I shouldn't even bother?
- I should be going.
No, don't.
I want to show you something.
I've got this idea -
of photographing
youth with a garland.
Just the way it is.
Even when it's ugly, it has a garland.
Naked or clothed
angry, crying.
Vomiting, shitting.
In the kitchen, on the toilet,
watching TV, shooting up.
D'you see?
And I've got this old helmet
found it in the woods.
So I decided to photograph
youth with a helmet.
Like a soldier.
That's what they turn you into.
Let me just...
There we go.
I'll just move you a little.
Against the white... Good.
Good.
Take off your shirt.
Fucking hell.
Fucking poof.
Let's not start that old stuff again.
just let me...
it can't be all that silly. Let me...
Stay there.
It can't be that silly. Let me...
I warned you.
Jesus. A morning like this.
Like after a sauna, isn't it.
For the soul, I mean.
Oh yes.
There's this old woman
wandering the streets at night.
She's got a towel
wrapped round her head.
And beneath that towel,
she has an exceptionally large head.
I wonder what she's carrying around?
Gold, diamonds, share deeds
all wrapped up inside that towel.
What if she's just very wise?
We don't have access
to someone else's head now, do we?
So... Where are you going?
To Pusula, a friend's place...
To Pusula.
You're running away,
now we're talking man to man.
Running away.
I've got to go.
- Running away from mummy.
Saw it straight away.
I can tell.
You've done your bad deeds,
looking for glory.
A man's deeds, and now you're running.
Don't you ever do that again.
If you had any sense,
you'd run back to mummy.
But you don't.
Where's your shirt?
- Fuck.
What's the matter?
- I'm cold.
Simo...
Leave him.
- But something's not right.
I'll make some coffee
and fry you an egg.
I'll add some sausage.
It'll be more filling.
You're not ill, are you?
- Don't!
Good God. There's police outside.
Is it because of that man?
The one Simo knew?
I didn't know him.
- Has he died?
Yes.
- Topped himself?
The scorpions.
- What fucking scorpions?
What you said yesterday...
They'll come and eat human corpses.
You said.
Have I been talking about scorpions?
- Well, that they're coming
and everything will change.
So nothing really matters.
Humans don't matter.
Humans will die out.
What the hell?
Because the scorpions are coming.
And the end is coming
and if you still hope,
you can never be free.
I don't get it.
Simo...