KIM YOUNG-HO
CHOI CHUL-HO
CHOO SO-YOUNG
YOON IN-JO
PARK MIN-GYU
WRITTEN AND DIRECTED
BY JUNG YOUNG-BAE
ONE YEAR LATER
Everything will feel unfamiliar
since his memories aren't back.
He may experience migraines
or dizziness for a while.
Take time with
rehab and therapy.
Then his conditions
will definitely improve.
What the heck?
MOTHER
Okay, Mother.
I love you, okay?
I'm busy. I'm hanging up.
I'll do it myself.
Since your arm hasn't healed,
I'll help you.
I'll be preparing dinner
Wash up first, okay?
- Welcome.
- Why are we meeting here?
You want kudzu tea, right?
One kudzu tea, please!
- What's with the name Arirang?
- Hey.
This is the only place
without CCTV
Get a new cell phone.
It's hard to get in touch with
you because of your phone.
When I catch this culprit...
I'll get a new one
and even get you one too.
Forget it. I'm busy,
so I have to go now.
Are you on night duty again?
Here's your kudzu tea.
Mn Lee, who's this guy?
He's Lee Night Duty.
Wow, your name is Night Duty?
Man, you silly boy.
- Hey, is it really accurate?
- Yes.
Are you sure we can trust it?
Go on your night duty.
You silly boy.
Honey, are you okay? Honey?
Go to sleep. You must be tired.
It's nice to have you back.
I DON'T NEED ANYTHING ELSE
DON'T BLOCK THE SUN
PRODUCED BY YOO SANG-WOO
It's okay.
Most plays have an emphasis
on our psychological state.
THE DRAMA DEPARTMENT
IS LOOKING FOR A NEW TA.
Due to this aspect
of Greek plays
Psychoanalytic terms such as
the Oedipus or Electra complex
are used to explain
psychological states.
Don't you think the Greeks
considered the gods
not as special
or superior beings...
but as beings similar to humans?
The gods in Greek mythology
are unpredictable...
What brings you here?
I wanted to have lunch with you.
President Yoo Sang-woo was
released from the hospital.
Already?
He was released
much earlier than I expected.
He must have recovered quickly.
That's fortunate.
But his memories
haven't come back yet.
Is that so?
That's unfortunate. I hope
his memories come back soon.
Are you okay?
Doctor.
When I arrived here
after the accident...
How was I?
You were in critical condition.
You had many fractures and
your face was severely damaged.
There wasn't much
information. It was barely...
It's a miracle you survived,
Mn Yoo Sang-woo!
I don't think
I'll need it anymore.
Thank you.
- Hang in there, Mn Yoo.
- Yes, Sin
- Make it neat.
- Okay.
It's already been three years
since we took that.
Do you remember then?
Do you want to see these?
This is Beach Saka.
This is where...
I remember Russian tourists
asked you to sing for them.
This is where the monkeys were.
I was going to feed them.
But the king monkey
stole the food.
I remember that.
You still don't remember?
Lift it up.
Try a little harden
Hold it there.
How was it?
I was surprised.
Goodness!
Keep pulling until the end.
Keep it there. That's it.
Pull it again,
and hold it at the end.
There you go.
Two, three.
Eat steamed ribs in the fridge
instead of eating ramen.
I'll be back before dinner.
Let me know
if you need anything.
- Okay.
- I'll be off.
No!
Honey, I'm home!
President Yoo!
- What is this?
- It's your jacket.
I see, thank you.
Do you know where it is?
- I'll find it.
- Do you want me to go with you?
You must have gained weight.
You used to wear it.
I guess the hospital
is comfortable.
I'm sorry for
asking you to do this.
Well, it's okay.
I'll take this jacket back.
BUSINESS LICENSE
You have another phone
under your company's name.
Do you still want to
open up a new account?
Yes.
- Welcome.
- A strawberry smoothie, please.
One strawberry smoothie?
That's 4,900 won.
- Is it for here?
- Yes.
I received 10,000 won.
Darn it, what are you doing?
Call me back now.
How could you do this? Are
you settling with the deposit?
Since you saw the photos,
you need to call me back.
Let me know how much
longer I must wait.
I'm too angry to work today.
Don't disappear again like this.
You made a promise.
I have my ways
of finding you, got it?
President Yoo.
The rehearsal's ready to go.
You can come down now.
I'll be right down.
Excuse me, President.
Don't treat me like a stranger.
You can treat me
like you used to.
I'll get used to it
as time passes.
Sang-woo!
You came back to work.
You look even
healthier than before.
Mi-hyun!
What's the secret?
How do you keep his body so fit?
Professor Seo.
Hello.
Professor Seo,
it's time for your meeting.
Tell them to wait.
It was really difficult
to get the time slot.
- I had to beg them.
- I told you to wait.
Okay, I'll go there first
and wait for you.
Sang-woo, you should
come since you're back.
You can live as if
you've been born again.
Everyone has memories
they'd rather forget.
For example...
anyway-
Some memories
are better forgotten.
I could probably write
a dissertation on your case.
It's not easy to find
a case like yours.
Well, okay.
There are things
he should be careful with.
I don't want to put
too much pressure on him.
- I'm okay.
- Honey.
You promised. You can't say
you can't remember later
That's enough.
What? He said he'd do it.
Sang-woo, do you want
to go for a smoke?
You have to give me
the goods before I can pay you!
What on earth!
What, call the police?
You really don't remember?
Really?
I'm jealous that
you can start oven
Mi-hyun.
What kind of person was I?
What kind of person were you?
What kind of person
was Yoo Sang-woo?
He's someone who forgot
what he wanted to lose.
Do you want me to tell you
what kind of person you were?
We all pretend we don't
know what we know.
You aren't any different.
I'm going home.
Honey, come in and have lunch.
What are you doing?
Honey, are you okay?
- You're sweating so much.
- No!
I had a nightmare.
- Would you like some water?
- No.
I'll go wash my face.
If we analyze it further...
we fear that we're no
longer worthy of love
someone who's worth being loved.
The attempt to hide
or ignore the fear
can lead to obsession.
Obsession makes
self-growth impossible.
You must have been surprised
that I asked you to meet me.
No, I was going to
call you anyway.
Aren't you surprised that
I chose a place like this?
Actually, I have
something to ask you.
What is it?
I feel confused
about everything.
I want to know the truth.
But I can't remember a thing.
So...
Do you want to ask
about Yoon-hee?
Want to ask me about Yoon-hee?
I heard I neglected my wife.
You neglect Yoon-hee?
Not the other way around?
You haven't heard
about another man?
I'm talking about Kim Hyun-min.
Were Yoon-hee and Hyun-min
seeing each other?
I don't know exactly.
But everyone suspected it.
Including you.
Do you know I'm also part of
the memories you've lost?
You had a hard time
because of Yoon-hee.
Even when you were
lying in bed...
"or having sex with hen"
you said you didn't know
who she was anymore.
You said she didn't feel
like she was your woman.
Mi-hyun.
I'm not sure what you're
thinking, but please stop.
What I'm thinking?
What were you thinking
when you were with me?
Is everything over just because
your memories are gone?
What were you thinking
when you were with me?
Is everything over just because
your memories are gone?
You still don't remember?
Hold on.
Drink this.
Thank you.
Darn it, I finally found you.
Wow, this tracking
system is great.
Long time no see.
Do you know me?
You lost your memories?
Wow, I thought that only
happened on TV shows.
That's what I thought.
So you wanted to start anew
after losing your memories.
I shouldn't have sent
those photos to you.
I thought you were avoiding me
so you wouldn't have to pay!
This world is full of scumbags.
I'm getting more upset
the more I think about it!
Anyway, we met.
On top of amnesia,
you were in an explosion?
Okay, fine.
You didn't request
anything special.
You asked me to find out
what your wife's been up to.
You wanted photos of when
she's with Kim Hyun-min.
What's the big deal
with having an affair?
Is there anyone who's
completely honest these days?
- You also had an affair.
- Pardon me?
Forget about that.
I have more photos.
Wait, here.
They're on my phone.
Why is it always out of battery?
Anyway, I have them.
Also, this is my business card.
I'll get going now.
And...
the remaining balance.
Pay it all at once.
If you avoid me again,
I'm going to get you.
You come here often these days.
Where did you go
after taking time off?
I had to meet someone.
- Who?
- Just a friend.
Why don't you stop?
Wait, I'm almost there.
I said stop.
- Wait, wait a minute.
- Goodness.
I said stop it!
LEE MIN-SIK
You probably don't know
how much I love you
and how happy I am right now.
Honey.
I'm sorry but I have a headache.
He was severely injured.
He had burns and fractures.
It's a miracle he survived.
Why did the car explode?
Was it really his car?
It crashed into the guardrail,
so the engine exploded!
But I found something strange.
You said the case got closed
as a drunk driving case.
But it was still very strange.
- Here you go.
- Detective agencies...
can't make money with
average cases these days.
Is it a fraud case this time?
It could be adultery.
An affair?
- It suits you really well.
- Hey.
Affair cases bring in
the most money.
If you hadn't helped Yoon-gu,
you'd have his position.
That's in the past.
Yoon-gu is my friend, you brat!
But it's still unfair.
Yoon-gu is about to get promoted.
But you're spying on lovers.
Be quiet!
If you care about me so much,
why do you look down on my work?
It's because I miss you at work.
Stop talking nonsense.
Just give me the information
Goodness, I can't!
I almost got in trouble for
tracking down Sang-woo.
But Yoon-gu helped me
while swearing at me.
Didn't I say he's my friend?
My friend, you brat!
My friend!
I'll get in serious
trouble this time!
It won't cause any trouble.
You drive me nuts.
- Hey.
- What?
Are you excluded from
promotion this time?
Employee without promotion.
They need people like me.
You're talking nonsense.
I'm leaving!
Did you meet
Sang-woo in private?
You're funny.
You might think you
can cover up the past
because Sang-woo
lost his memories.
- But you're mistaken.
- What you're doing...
is considered a crime.
You should take care of
your lover instead.
Where is he now?
Don't contact Sang-woo
from now on.
- Why should I listen to you?
- Really?
Do whatever you want to, then.
But you'll regret it.
You ruined my life.
You ruined everything for me.
Only if you hadn't introduced me
to Professor Park...
I can't wait to find out
what you'll do.
Follow me.
Come in, come in.
Goodness,
it's a little messy in here.
Sit down, sit down.
Wow.
What would you like to drink?
Coffee or green tea?
No, I'm okay.
That book doesn't reveal
the character's name.
It just goes on and
on about the girl...
Who's the one
writing the letters?
The main character of
the novel, I mean.
Werther.
- What?
- That's the main character.
Werther! The main character!
I didn't catch that.
Right, it's Werther.
Wait, you're here
for the photos.
Here you go.
Take a look at them.
Yes, Mother.
I will get it this month.
Who's going to make a loan
out to me? I'll get it soon.
Yes, yes. I already ate.
I won't cause trouble.
I'm working right now, so I'll
call you later. Don't worry.
Mom, I love...
Hello?
Why does she always
hang up on me?
Here you go.
Shouldn't you know
everything to remember?
Where have you been?
I was so worried!
I was just getting
some fresh air.
- I'll look for it.
- The target is on the move.
- B3, A2 regions are clean
- Clean
B2 and B3, be on the lookout.
- Yes, Sin
- We're moving now
- It's clean
- It's clear here.
- There's nothing here.
- Okay.
- It's clean
It's clean There's nothing here.
Move now! Move! Hurry!
- Yes, Sin
- Hurry!
- Hey, what is that?
- I'm a bean
- What did you find out?
- I'm not your assistant.
What did you say?
We met up yesterday, too.
You need a warrant to view
someone's phone records.
You read the newspaper,
don't you?
The law regarding
personal information...
You idiot!
- Wait, wait!
- Why you!
Darn it! You silly brat!
That's why I'm asking
you, Detective Lee!
- But...
- I'm asking you a favor!
Kim Hyun-min has been
reported missing.
I don't care about that.
I need his phone records.
Adultery cases are
all about evidence.
Follow the target around
and get some evidence.
Take some pictures and
you'll get paid, right?
This is a detective agency
run by a former detective.
Don't you know how
important differentiation is?
You should have worked
that hard as a detective.
If you do that for affair cases,
you won't last long!
Wait, wait. Yes, Sir?
I got it, I'll be right there.
- Wait a minute!
- You aren't going anywhere!
- Give me that!
- Wait just a little.
- What are you doing?
- Go!
- Run!
- Detective Lee!
- Good luck!
- Yes, Sir!
He's such a cute brat.
SPEEDING TICKET
KIM HYUN-MIN
Excuse me, Sin
Yes?
- Which apartment do you live in?
- Apartment 208.
Excuse me.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
Do you know anything about
the man living next door?
No, I don't know
anything in particular.
Have you ever had
a conversation with him?
We just say hello
when we see each other.
When was the last time
you saw him?
Well, maybe two days ago.
Three days ago?
Maybe a week ago?
- How was he then?
- He looked sick.
He had lost a lot of weight,
and he seemed tired.
I thought maybe he had
come back from a trip.
But why did he look so down?
Are you sure it was him?
I heard something while
I was taking out the trash.
- So, did you see him?
- Well...
you don't always
have to see to know.
- We're close neighbors...
- You didn't see him! Darn it.
Should you make a face?
You scared me!
What on earth? Goodness.
Why do you ask
about the guy next door?
Did he do something wrong?
Good bye!
Yes, Professor.
I gave you everything.
I told you there were
additional expenses...
Of course I trust you.
Excuse me!
A while ago,
an old lady came to visit.
I can't do it for you
if you don't pay in advance.
- Yes.
- Then she left right away.
- Okay?
- Why did you ask me?
I want to know the reason!
My tears are falling
My heart yearns for you
There's no one else
in my life but you
I will love only you
Let's not lose hope.
Even if tomorrow is
my last day...
Even if my spear pierces
my mother's heart...
let's not fight.
This is the revenge
I take against my mother.
- Honey!
- What brings you here?
I came to say hello to
your colleagues on my way home.
Is that so?
The audition isn't over yet.
Mrs. Lee?
- I haven't seen you in a while.
- Hello.
You get prettier
every time I see you.
Thank you.
- Is the audition over?
- We're taking a break.
Mr Producer,
they're looking for you.
That's great. There's a place
I want to take you.
Shoulders 19.5.
DETECTIVE AGENCY
Waist 36.
MISSED CALLS
Hip 40.
Thigh 25.
SPEEDING TICKET
ON MARCH 3
Honey, where are you?
What are you doing?
You scared me!
I feel fine for a while,
but then my chest hurts.
It's like my heart is
being torn out by a knife.
Scene, fate cannot
ever be changed.
Fate refers to the tragic
reality we cannot change.
Come in.
Hello.
Who are you?
I'm from Gangnam Police.
I have a few questions
to ask you.
You know Kim Hyun-min, right?
He was a student here.
Yes, he was an assistant at
this department but not anymore.
When did he quit, exactly?
I think it was about
three months ago.
He didn't exactly quit.
He just stopped coming.
Could you find out
the exact date?
Wait one moment.
It was December 5th,
the day before the final exam.
How was he as a student?
He was a good student.
He was smart and hard-working.
He was working hard
on his dissertation.
Has Hyun-min ever
contacted you after he left?
No, he hasn't.
Do you know any of his
friends or acquaintances?
Well, I'm not sure.
Which police station...
Okay, I got it.
This is Lee Sang-wook from
the violent crimes department.
Who's on night duty for traffic?
Okay, thank you.
Hello, Kang-seok?
Are you on night duty?
I'm on night duty, too.
Yes.
How is your baby?
Of course.
It's about December 3rd
of last year, on Tuesday.
Kim Hyun-min. Could you
send me the original photo?
Okay, thank you.
Who knew affair cases
were so complicated?
Aren't you working
too hard these days?
You should extend your break.
You haven't fully recovered yet.
I wish you wouldn't
be so impatient.
You can take your time at home.
Do you want me to...
stay like this without
remembering anything?
Never mind.
It's just a thought
I've been having.
If my memories come back,
I might get more confused.
I wish you wouldn't
struggle so hard.
Whether you want to
remember or forget
just let it happen naturally.
No.
As I told you before,
Hyun-min went missing.
But your wife continues
to visit his apartment.
Okay.
I don't understand.
I thought I gave her a hard time.
You of all people
shouldn't say that.
It's nothing. My business is
only to get paid.
- Are you married?
- No.
No woman wants to marry a guy
who has a single mother.
Also, this job makes
me scared of marriage.
Loss of memory and an explosion.
Kim Hyun-min disappeared.
But Yoon-hee keeps visiting
Hyun-min's apartment...
despite his disappearance.
What if the guy is
in the apartment?
Sang-woo, Mi-hyun
and Professor Park.
The ones who are highly educated
are dirtier than most!
Something definitely
smells fishy here.
Let's see, Hyun-min,
Sang-woo and Professor Park.
Hyun-min, Professor Park
and Sang-woo.
- You can't stay here.
- Wait...
- Just for a few minutes.
- Do what you need to do.
Thank you.
Goodness.
Sang-woo,
I'm telling you as a man.
We don't know what will happen.
We should choose a location
to get definite proof, okay?
Wow, you're quite big.
Do you work out?
When a bowl cracks, blocking
the crack won't stop the flow.
If you want,
you can end it here.
What's the point of
revealing the dirty truth?
If you can't decide,
let's just go back.
I need to talk to her about it.
If it's a misunderstanding...
Even if it isn't, I want
to save my marriage.
I should confront hen
That's a good idea.
I also have something to check.
Why are you
so interested in this case?
Isn't that...
Darn it, I told him to wait.
Please leave a message
after the beep...
- Honey, why are you...
- What is this?
- Let's go outside and talk.
- Move aside!
Where is he?
Where's that scum, Hyun-min?
How long did you think
you'd be able to hide it?
Were you afraid
I would remember?
Is that why you kept
coming back to his house?
Where is he?
Where is Kim Hyun-min?
I was hoping
you wouldn't find out.
Wouldn't find out what?
What?
He isn't here.
Hyun-min isn't here anymore.
You...
You killed him.
That night,
with your bare hands...
That night, Hyun-min got drunk
and came to our house.
Hyun-min, why are you here?
Why didn't you pick up my calls?
I kept calling you!
Hyun-min, stop it.
I told you it's oven
Who says?
I'm still in love with you!
You're very drunk.
Go home.
Let me go!
Where's your husband?
Where's your husband, Sang-woo?
Hyun-min, please leave.
- Move!
- Hyun-min, please!
- Come out now!
- Don't do this.
- Come out!
- Hyun-min, please leave.
Please.
Hyun-min!
Hyun-min, please don't do this.
No.
Honey...
He's dead...
Then, I got a call that
you were in an accident.
This can't be.
To protect you,
I planned everything perfectly.
This can't be!
I pretended Hyun-min is
still alive for your alibi.
I...
I killed Hyun-min?
Why? Why?
Why didn't you tell me before?
You might not remember,
but I'm still your wife.
I thought your loss of memory
was our only chance.
If I sacrifice myself,
you wouldn't know a thing.
Darn it.
It ran out of battery again!
Hey.
Sang-woo is acting strange.
I didn't know who to call.
Can you come over here?
Yes.
Please pick up, you brat.
Please leave a message
after the beep.
Kang Yoon-gu.
It's their loss!
Fine, let's see
how far it will go.
CONVERSATION OF DREAMS
Please leave a message
after the beep...
THE WORST SCUM
Who are you?
Where did you put the dead body?
- The dead body?
- Where did you put it?
Then, are you...
I said it's going to be okay.
I told you things will be okay.
I told you I'd help you
fill in the lost memories.
Why are you so curious?
You should have left
everything up to me.
I was going to
make it all pretty.
Who am I?
Who you are is not important.
You just need
to be Yoo Sang-woo.
You still don't know?
No.
Honey!
No!
No.
What have you done?
You ruined everything.
This is so upsetting.
No, it's okay.
It's okay. I can start over.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Honey!
Doctor Kim, you have an eye
transplant surgery at Room 7.
Please come
to the operation room.
Dear Sang-woo,
I heard you're in the hospital.
I'm sorry for not
being able to protect you.
Thank you for still being alive.
YOO SANG-WOO
Ae-kyung, it's time to eat!
Honey,
does that CCTV still work?
Don't do that.
You could hurt the baby.
Min-soo, good boy.
CONFESSION