Of all the words my father wrote,
and there were many,
I remember these most:
"Nothing in human progress
is achieved with unanimous consent.
Those enlightened before others"
must pursue that light
in spite of others.
There was a time
the New World didn't exist.
The sun set in the west,
where no man ventured.
And beyond that...
infinity!
Look.
Now...
half of the hull has gone.
Good.
And now?
Now, I only see the mast.
Close your eyes.
And don't cheat.
I'm watching.
Open them when I tell you.
Once I asked my father
where he wanted to go.
He replied:
"I want to travel over the seas.
I want to get behind the weather."
Now.
It's gone.
What does it tell you?
It's round,
like this.
Round.
Come on, lad.
Good morning, Father.
Diego!
Kiss your brother, Diego.
I have something for you.
You'll be heard
at Salamanca University.
In a week!
That's what it says.
How did you manage it?
With some difficulty.
I promised them
you weren't a total fool.
Marco Polo said he found Earthly
Paradise off the coast of China.
Do you believe this?
I believe in Paradise and Hell.
And I do believe both can be earthly.
Now...
let's go through this again.
Why do you wish to sail west?
To open a new route to Asia.
Asia is the richest Kingdom.
The land of spices and gold.
There are two ways of reaching it...
By sea...
Sailing around the African continent,
which takes a year,
or by land. But the Turks
have closed the route to Christians.
There is a third way...
by sailing west across the sea.
The distance is unknown...
It's said to be infinite.
Superstition!
I believe the Indies
are no more than 750 leagues
west of the Canary Islands.
How can you be so certain?
The calculations of Toscanelli...
Marin de Tyr...
Esdras...
Esdras is a Jew.
So was Christ!
- 2 minutes...
and already you're a bad man.
For telling the truth?
- Yes.
They're burning people for less.
The man you're to confront
has no emotions.
Learn to control your passion.
Passion is something
one can't control.
You need their blessing.
If they say no...
you would have to give up.
I will not give up.
Is it ambition?
We've been told lies for so long...
The world is flat like this table...
Monsters guard
the edge of the world...
I will not be told what
and what not to be afraid of!
I want to find out for myself.
I just hope your passion
will be contagious, my son.
Look, father!
Fernando!
Do you repent your sins
in the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit?
Burnings in the square...
They agreed to see me in Salamanca.
If they accept
I could be gone for years.
I know.
I haven't given you a real life.
Uh...that's true, I have a child
by a man who won't marry me...
Are you going to argue?
I'd love to argue with you more
often, but you're never here.
Unfortunately, that is precisely
where our opinions differ.
You're familiar with Aristotle?
Eratosthenes? Ptolemeus?
I am, Your Eminence.
So you can't ignore their
calculations that the circumference
of the Earth is approximately
22,000 leagues or more...
making the ocean uncrossable.
But you...
may have found new evidence
proving these great men mistaken!
You are aware of Marin de Tyr?
We are.
Then you are also aware that
his theories contradict Ptolemeus...
De Tyr believes the ocean to be
only 750 leagues.
Toscanelli...
and the French Cardinal D'Ailly,
both think De Tyr
is accurate in his calculations.
Therefore the ocean can be crossed.
Silence!
Gentlemen, are we here to examine
this man's proposal, or not?
Let's suppose the moment...
Marin de Tyr is right.
In your opinion,
how long would it take?
Seven weeks.
Six, during the summer.
De Tyr is wrong.
He's contradicted by the finest...
geographers.
Your voyage, Señor Colombus,
would take a year.
Suppose you cross the ocean
and reach Asia...
What would Spain do there?
Trade, Your Excellency.
According to Marco Polo,
the Kingdom of China
...is one of the richest
lands in the worlds
The meanest buildings
are roofed in gold.
It's your only interest?
Gold?
No.
I'll bring these people to God
and make them subjects
of Castille and Aragon.
From a Realm,
Spain will become an Empire!
If God intended our proximity to Asia
do you believe he'd have waited
for you to show it?
He chose a carpenter's son
to reveal Himself to the world.
So you consider yourself
the Chosen One?
Asia can be found to the west...
and I will prove it!
The Treasurer of Spain honours us.
The State has an interest
in his proposition, Your Eminence.
With all due respect,
the judgement is ours.
Why not?
And if he were right?
I've always found
such independent minds dangerous.
If he had wings
he'd return from the skies
and say heaven was empty.
I'd deplore the loss
of such an opportunity for Spain.
Especially over a point of geography.
It's not geography.
It's about reality.
This man is a mercenary.
States often use mercenaries.
If it is to the benefit,
the stability of Spain...No?
It should be as much your concern
as it is mine.
You would use your
influence to assist this heretic?
Well...
You know, your Eminence, the
fascinating thing about power...
is that what can be given...
so easily can be taken away.
And therefore nothing could justify
Your Majesties' participation
in a venture that relies on
feeble assumptions,
and which any man of knowledge
would take to be impractical...
if not impossible.
They didn't listen.
They don't want to listen.
Don't give in. You must wait.
- Wait?
After seven years,
how much longer can I wait?
If God intends you to...
Damn God!
- Christopher!
Damn all of you! You sit concocting
theories based on what?
You never leave your gardens.
Go out!
Well then, tell me something
I can accept.
These are full of assumptions!
Just lies!
All of it lies!
Father?
Don't disturb a man
doing penance.
What can you do?
Nothing.
That's the point, Fernando.
Fernando!
Señor Colombus?
I've looked all over Sevilla for you.
Never expected to find you
in a monastery.
I'm Pinzon.
Martin Alonzo Pinzon.
I'm a ship owner from Palos.
Is he a spy?
What is it?
Are you a Trappist?
Vow of silence?
Penance?
Just my luck.
I'll do the talking for us.
Just nod, agreed?
As with my wife.
I know the commission
turned you down, right?
What do you expect?
You're a foreigner.
And I want to help you.
Why do I believe in you?
I'm a seaman, too.
We don't like to be told
where to go or not to go.
I don't look much, but I have friends,
important friends.
A banker, for example.
He finances me.
He's name is Santangel.
Heard of him?
He'll get you in to see the Queen.
You know why?
She owes him money.
That's for it.
You, me, the Queen, the world...
Everybody owes something.
What do you say?
Where can I meet him?
- Here.
Right there.
May I ask a question?
Yes.
Why do you want to help me?
Faith.
Hope.
Charity.
But greater than all these...
is banking.
Wait, Señores!
The Moors built Granada centuries ago.
We've taken it back.
A tragic victory.
We're losing a great culture.
But I suppose there's a price
for every victory.
Isn't there Señor Colombus?
Don Luis de Santangel
to see Don Gabriel Sanchez.
Luis!
Señor Columbus, Señor Pinzon.
Rise...
Come forward.
I should not be listening to you
since my Council said not to.
But Santangel says you're
a man of honour...
And Sanchez says
you're not completely mad.
No more than she who said...
she would take Granada from the Moors.
They believe the ocean is...
uncrossable,
Señor Colombus.
What did they say about Granada?
That it was impregnable.
I can't ignore my Council's verdict.
Surely you can do what you want.
How little you know.
Why should I believe in you,
Señor Colombus?
May I speak freely?
You are not inclined
to speak otherwise.
I know what I see.
I see someone who doesn't
accept the world as it is.
Who's not afraid.
I see a woman who thinks...
- A woman?
Forgive me...
but you're the only Queen I know.
That makes us equal,
you're the only navigator I know.
How old are you, Señor Colombus?
Thirty-nine, Your Majesty.
And you?
I'm forty...
You will be informed of our decision.
I thought you were younger than I.
The cost would be ruinous.
No more than the cost
of two state banquets.
Two banquets,
for new lands and spices...
and gold.
What are you saying, Sanchez?
That if he's right
we have everything to gain.
And if he's wrong...
we've so little to lose.
Tell me what he says.
He demands to be made a Knight,
with the right to wear
the Golden Spurs.
And that he will receive the title
Don Christopher Colombus,
which will be extended
to his descendants.
What else?
He'll be named
Admiral of the Ocean Seas.
Viceroy of the West Indies...
Governor of all islands
or lands discovered,
or as will be discovered by him.
The highest titles of nobility,
Your Excellency.
To an immigrant sheltered by monks!
Furthermore...
he'll receive one tenth
of wealth or monies,
precious gems,
pearls, metals, spices
and other lucrative sources
acquired under his jurisdiction.
You worry too much, Francisco.
He'll have to lower his demands.
Believe me...
He will.
I won't!
We have considered your proposal
carefully. It is excessive.
The responsibility is excessive.
Consider the contract...
- No.
No?
And I thought he was an idealist.
Idealism and ambition
are not incompatible.
I've fought too hard.
Now you expect me to take all the risks
while you take the profit.
- No...
I'm not a servant...
- Señor Colombus,
you are in no position...
to bargain with me.
I'm not bargaining.
Then you are too ambitious.
And where you never ambitious?
Is ambition a virtue among nobles
but a fault for the rest of us?
If you won't accept we can
simply find someone who will.
If you can do that, Excellency...
I'll become a monk!
Your Majesty.
He'll become a monk...
It would be a pity, wouldn't it?
Call him back.
She said yes.
If I ever come back, I swear...
I don't want you to swear anything.
I don't want you to wait for me.
That's something
you can't decide for me.
Forgive me Father, I have sinned.
I am listening, my son.
Father...
I have betrayed my family.
I betrayed my men,
and I betrayed you.
I lied.
The journey is longer than I said.
How long?
I'm not sure...
How could anyone know.
It could be twice the distance.
You must tell them.
You must tell your men.
- They wouldn't follow me.
You know I'm right.
You must trust me.
You must speak to them.
If you don't, I will.
You made an oath.
May God forgive you.
I believed in you.
Give me absolution.
Absolution, Father.
Ego te absolvo a pecatis tuis.
Enter.
Mendez...
Sit down.
Wine?
What is it, Mendez?
Speak!
They wonder how you know our
position with no sight of land?
What do you think, Mendez?
I know you navigate by the stars
like the Moors...
but I don't know how?
Take this quadrant.
Find the North Star.
Steady yourself!
Keep the plumbline vertical.
And don't move.
A mistake of one degree
and we'll be off 600 leagues.
What do you read?
28.
- That's it!
28th parallel.
And we'll follow it
until we reach land.
How do you know that
we'll find land of 28th parallel?
I don't.
Mark 26, Sir.
Mark 27, Sir.
Mark 28!
Mark 29!
629!
629, Sir.
I heard.
Captain, I don't understand.
I think I do.
We should've seen land.
We've been at sea nine weeks,
Alonzo. Can't be that far.
Can't be that near.
I don't like the smell
of this sea around here.
Smells like a whore!
'Course it does.
That's why sailors go to sea.
And why is that one at sea?
Nobody knows.
He never says a word.
Captain Pinzon requests
permission to board.
You mislead me.
You lied to me.
We are way past 750 leagues.
Six days ago, yes.
- You must be mad!
Keep your voice down!
There'll be a mutiny!
- You think I don't know?
We're lost!
Land is there. I know it.
You don't know anything.
Listen, these are my ships
and we are turning back.
And then what? Half of the water
has gone, the rest is putrid!
I shouldn't have listened to you...
You...
Listen, Pinzon! Pinzon.
All we can do...
is go forward.
The land is there...
The land is close.
You tell them that.
You must tell them.
God doesn't want us
to cross this ocean.
This voyage is cursed.
We set sail for greed.
God has abandoned us.
The voyage is cursed.
There are signs.
Juanito has the voice of an angel.
His mouth is blessed, but what
comes out of yours is cursed.
Listen...
We're all afraid at first.
But those who overcome fear
will rightly earn their reward.
I don't know if it's God's will
that we should cross this ocean.
But I am certain it is you
who puts fear into our hearts.
We can't be lost if we keep faith
in God and in ourselves.
In time...
they will talk of the
courage of the first
men to cross this ocean, and return.
And then you will be
able to say to them,
I was on the Pinta...
I was on the Nina...
and the Santa Maria...
This jacket to he who sights land.
And 10,000 maravedis a year for life!
I wanna get a man aloft day and night!
Alonzo...
don't let the wind escape us.
You lucky bastard!
Mendez...
Mendez!
Land...
25 fathoms!
24 fathoms!
There...
Land ho!
Drop anchor!
Don Christopher...
Excellencia...
By the...
By the Grace of God...
In the name of their
Gracious Majesties
of Castilla and Aragon...
By all the powers vested in me...
I claim this island and name it...
San Salvador.
Don Christopher...
Muskets!
- No!
October 21st, 1492.
I think We have returned to Eden.
Surely this is how the world was
in the beginning of time.
If the natives are to be
converted to our ways
then it will be by persuasion
and not by force.
I believe no man will ever see
this land again as we do...
for the first time.
We come in peace and with honour.
They are not savages,
neither will we be.
Treat them as you would
your own wives and children.
Respect their beliefs.
Pillage will be punished by
the whip. Rape, by the sword.
You?
Utapan.
Utapan?
Columbus.
Co...Colum...
Co...lombus.
Where did you find this?
Cuba!
Thanks...
I've got a river of gold to piss.
Here!
Is it gold?
No, no.
No good, no.
Utapan!
Alonzo! Alonzo!
Help him!
Do something!
Pray for him.
With Alonzo's death, I realise how
vulnerable we are in these islands.
How much we have to learn.
On every island...
the natives welcome us
with great generosity and trust.
Because of our appearance
we have been mistaken for gods
and are treated accordingly.
Despite the Indians' compliance
we have not found gold in quantity,
except for the few artefacts they
gave us as a sign of submission.
You will speak first.
Tell him we thank him
for his hospitality.
He knows.
Tell him some of my men
are staying here
to build a fort.
I want them to be well treated.
Tell him...
we'll come back.
Many of us.
He said, how many?
As many as the leaves on that tree.
And many more will follow.
Why?
To bring the word of God.
He says he has a God.
And also to bring medicine.
He says...
...he has medicine.
Tell him...
we admire his people.
He knows you like his women and gold.
Pinzon is ill...
eaten up by a fever
that refuses to leave his body.
We must return to Spain.
39 men have volunteered to stay
behind to build a fort.
I name it...
La Navidad.
After 7 months,
I haven't seen a civilisation
that compares
with Marco Polo's descriptions.
No cities, no bridges.
No temples roofed with gold.
The mainland still escapes me.
But I know it's there.
My ships are not filled with the
spices and gold I was hoping for.
But this land intoxicates
my senses and my soul.
And all I can think of
is to return to this untamed land.
This unexplored Eden.
This is a chance for a new beginning.
Majestates conjuncta Hispania.
Reges Ferdinandus et Isabella
executores voluntas Dei sunt
et cum vobis Regnum Domini
per terras novas ultra mares crescatur
et in eas Crux Cristi
maneat semper.
It won't be easy
to get rid of him now.
On the contrary...
It seems he is preparing
his own cross.
Let the palate enjoy
the flavour of the tobacco.
Try it.
You say this is an Indian vice?
I don't see the pleasure
that would make it a sin.
The Indians have no such word, Moxica.
Have they such thoughts?
They come and go naked
as God created them.
God? Which God?
Nature is their God.
It's as if God and Nature were one.
They see him in a leaf...
in a stone...
in a shell.
The islands...
are covered with trees.
Forgive me, Don Cristobal...
What about gold?
It's not the purest metal I've seen.
Is there more?
We are more than gratified, Cristobal.
Excellente.
You fence well.
- For a commoner?
So...
Your second expedition, hm?
17 ships...
and 1500 men?
Thanks to you.
This is Don Francisco de Bobadilla.
He can be valuable to you.
He's very well acquainted
with our laws.
I heard you'd be appointing Governors.
Will you consider my application?
Forgive me, Don Francisco.
The positions are taken.
May I ask by whom?
By two very competent men.
I trust their men of quality.
Francisco is qualified
for high administration.
Well...
we do lack notaries.
You should contact my administration.
Francisco is a judge.
Good...
we also need judges.
Except, there are no crimes as such.
I see I was mistaken.
He has no need for my services.
Sanchez.
You have a special talent
for making enemies.
Why do I have so many already?
Don't you think to rise so high in so
short a time is dangerous occupation?
Beatrix...
I can arrange for the Queen
to take the boys into her service.
It's a great honour, Beatrix.
- We couldn't hope for anything better.
- Anything better?
- Better than being with their mother?
- It's not what I meant.
What do you mean?
- I'll be gone...
for several years.
I have powerful enemies at the court.
The boys bear my name
and bear my titles.
This way they'll be untouchable.
And you'll be free to see them
whenever you please.
- You don't know what you're asking.
- I do.
I wish I could give you another life.
I am sorry.
Don't say that, because you're not.
You lead the life you chose
for yourself...
and I chose you.
You might have given us a choice.
I'm a map maker!
And now you're Lieutenant-General
of the West Indies, Bartolome!
He's just out of seminary
and can't use a sword.
Never touched a sword!
You have time to learn.
What are you complaining about?
You can live the way we dream of.
I don't share your dreams.
Do you refuse to help me?
To help your brother?
Are you going to desert me?
You bastard!
You always had your own way.
I have always supported you.
- I know.
I went to Portugal...
- I know!
I'm the eldest!
- How could we forget?
You've said it enough.
Let me show you something.
Excellency...
It's about my son...
See...
Now, you tell me, who can I trust?
We're brothers. A bloodline.
I need you. Both of you.
Admiral!
The horses are here.
This pair's magnificent!
Send them Back!
- What?
They're like mules!
I hope you did better with men!
Who did we take on today?
30 blacksmiths. 28 halberdiers.
20 carpenters.
100 farmers.
20 miners.
And Doctor Chanca, the royal surgeon.
Then we can count on royal health.
Fire!
Fire again!
Where are they?
Drummers, sound the advance!
Almirante!
Juanito.
Is this your New World, Almirante?
We will teach these animals savagery.
Three heads for every life taken.
No mercy before God!
Vamonos!
No Moxica!
We'll be no revenge.
These were our cousins, our
friends, our countrymen.
But you say no revenge?
We will wash this in blood and now!
If you want to keep your head
do as I say.
I lost friends, too.
39 brave men who trusted me.
You want war?
Fine.
We are 1000.
They outnumber us by 10.
Who will you kill?
Which tribe?
We don't need to know.
- Moxica...
Try to remember
who you are talking to.
We came here to stay.
Not to start a crusade.
So, we will swallow our anger.
And in the name of those who died,
we will accomplish what we came for.
They're here.
There.
Guarionex!
Ricardo!
Arquebuses!
Preparen!
Ask him.
What happened to my men?
Warriors come from the sea.
Caribes. Guarionex says...
All fled to the hills.
When they came back
all the Spaniards...had gone.
God's mercy on them.
The monkey's lying.
You talk too much.
Here they are.
We should kill them.
No...You'll do it my way.
Tell him we will not harm his people.
Even though we have
the power to do it.
I'm prepared to believe him.
We will work with them
and we want peace.
Ask if he understands.
He understands.
Will he help?
He says you know the answer.
Moxica...
I need your horses.
My horse does no work.
- We all have to work, Moxica.
- Not my horse.
Forgive me, Moxica.
But it was your horse
that I was talking about.
Thank you, Moxica.
Now...
Heave!
My dear sons...
In unbearable heat, we are building
the first city of the New World.
I brought the plans
of a Florentine architect,
Leonardo...da Vinci.
God willing,
we will build his ideal city.
We are adapting to the Indian diet.
Meat is only a memory for us.
But in a week, the mill
will be ready to produce of flour.
Soon, we'll be eating bread.
Never again I'll never
underestimate it again.
Nor the simple comforts of home.
You are always in my thoughts.
As ever, your Father.
You want her?
Then you can have her.
To the New World, my friend.
To the Governor...
of the mosquitoes.
She's a good cook.
What meat is it?
Iguana.
What's wrong?
It's Indian dish.
I'm not an Indian.
You know Christopher,
I think Giacomo is right.
We can't live on corn and pepper.
For the plantation,
we need black slaves.
Everything rots
before it can be harvested.
Have you noticed?
The horses and pigs multiply.
They keep mounting each other...
Must be the heat.
I must confess that the heat
has a similar effect on me.
You're both right.
But the fort must be finished
before the rains.
We must rely on our strengths.
What do you mean?
Every able man must work.
All of us.
Including nobility.
They're exempt, Christopher.
Well...Now they won't be.
Next.
Name?
Colpa.
What's he saying?
He's found none.
Why? Ask him why!
Stop him! Bring him back!
Hasn't found any.
He's lying. Tell him...
to put his hand on the table.
Like this.
Tell them...
I know they are hiding
the gold from us.
And tell them...
this is how we treat
thieves and liars.
Don Adrian, you cannot do this thing.
I can't?
I can.
Your act of brutality
has created chaos.
All the tribes are now
joining forces against us.
All of that because of your
criminal savagery.
Savagery...
is what monkeys understand.
You should have done the same
a long time ago, Don Cristobal.
Your ways...don't work.
You'll be put in detention,
deprived of privileges,
until you are sent to Spain
for judgement.
Have anything to say?
For four years now...
we've been here.
We stayed here four years
because we believed your promises.
But we find neither gold
nor your earthly paradise.
You and your brothers...
have failed.
Señor...Colombo!
Don Giacomo, come at once!
- What's happening?
In the mine!
Get Don Christopher!
Cut him down!
Cut the ropes!
Moxica's right.
Your ways don't work.
We have to find them.
Did you hear me?
You have to find them!
You see what they did?
You did the same to your God.
You know them?
Goohooni. Goohooni.
Charge!
Stop!
Fire!
Moxica.
You know...
what will be said about this
in Spain...
don't you?
You are nothing.
Your bastards
will never inherit your titles.
No...
We...
We are everything.
We are immortal.
Bastard!
Don Christopher...
I wish to return to Spain.
I have no desire to remain...
in this Godless place.
They are criminals.
They have a debt towards Spain.
Moxica paid. They will pay, too.
I don't understand you,
Don Christopher.
You treat Christians equally
with heathen savages.
And what do you offer in return?
A New World, Buyl.
No one wants one.
Only you.
Not only me.
Look at them.
They could go back to their families.
But they stay.
They want something new.
A new world.
I'll be leave...
on the next ship.
Leave if you please but...
your departure won't help me
make this place more Godly.
Perhaps hope only exists
in the journey, Giacomo.
At beginning everything's possible.
Every expectation, every dream.
No one expected this to be easy.
This isn't how I imagined
it to be, Christopher.
Marchena was right, Bartolome.
Paradise and Hell both can be earthly.
We carry them wherever we go.
Utopan!
Speak to me!
You never learned
to speak my language.
Your Majesty, here are the true facts
concerning the island of Hispaniola.
The activity of your servant Columbus,
Admiral of the Oceans
and Governor of the
the truth he now presides
over a state of chaos,
of degradation and of madness.
From beginning He had shown he was
incapable of managing the islands
he appointed his brothers
very important positions,
injuring the pride and dignity
of nobles.
He promised to build a city.
Isabel, after Your Majesty.
A group of mud huts
in the wrong place,
swept away by the rains and mud.
He promised gold,
not finding the amounts he promised.
He has since commanded
the Indians to pay a tax...
a monthly tribute of gold.
Most being unable to, we find,
have been punished
or massacred.
Columbus forced nobility
to hard labour,
treating them equally with Indians.
He reduced them into his slaves.
When Adrian de Moxica
protested against this,
he was executed.
Is this true, Brother Buyl?
Yes, Your Excellency.
These all true. All of it.
I saw it. With my own eyes.
Well...
He promised a Paradise.
He failed.
He must be replaced.
Immediately.
And who would you think of
for such a task?
I am thinking of a man.
A man devoted to Your Majesties.
A man extremely motivated.
Excellency, I'm sorry.
Don Francisco de Bobadilla.
Yes...I remember.
My letters of appointment.
I am the new Viceroy of the Indies.
Congratulations.
Then I can search for the mainland?
The mainland was discovered weeks ago.
By another Italian.
Amerigo Vespucci, Excellency.
How far?
I'm no seaman, but I heard
it's no more than a week at sea.
I hope not too disappointed.
How could I be?
The mainland has been found
exactly as I said it would.
I'm afraid this isn't the worst news.
Diego?
Father.
Fernando.
Oh, my God!
A man?
How did this happen?
Diego.
Don't worry.
We're going to get you out.
Santangel's going to the Queen.
- Good.
Good.
I'll go back when they free me.
This time with me.
In your present state
it is madness, Father.
You needn't come with us.
Diego.
Rise, please.
Now...
I do look older than you.
I have looked for a reason why
I should allow you to go back.
And though I tried
I could not find one.
Help me find one.
All my life I have dreamed
of reaching the continent.
I thought my dreams...
grandiose.
But reality was beyond
my expectations.
Far beyond.
And now...
I want to explore that land.
Before I die.
I allow you...
to undertake another voyage.
Thank you.
But without your brothers.
You can't go to Santo Domingo
or the other colonies.
The New World...
is a disaster.
And the old one...
an achievement?
I know...
I shouldn't tolerate his impertinence.
Then why?
Because he's not afraid of me.
Sanchez!
You're a dreamer.
Look out there.
What do you see?
I see towers.
I see palaces, I see steeples.
I see civilisation.
And I see spires that reach...
to the sky!
All created by people like me.
No matter how long you live,
one thing will never change
between us.
I did it.
You didn't.
You're so beautiful.
I can't believe another man
has never taken you from me.
They tried...
but I didn't let them.
They took everything.
Not everything.
You think I care?
I'm a free man again.
Riches don't make a man rich,
they only make him busier.
God!
How much I've missed you.
By the Grace of God
and Your Beneficient Majesty,
a new continent has now
been found and claimed
in the name of the Spanish
Crown, in the year 1492.
As Your Majesty is aware,
the University of Salamanca
has always defended the theory
of the existence
of unknown territories to the west.
The surest route to the continent
is now firmly established.
West by south-west for 750 leagues
to Santo Domingo.
From there...
west-north-west from San Juan
to the north,
reaching the island of Hispaniola
on the Cape of San Raphael.
Then onto the mainland
at Cape Gracias A Dios.
Spain, by Your Majesty's grace,
has confirmed for all humanity,
the existence of a New World.
Terra Incognita.
It was discovered by a mariner
commissioned by Your Majesty.
His name...
Amerigo Vespucci.
Sanchez...
What a tragedy.
What a waste of a life.
A waste?
If your name or mine
is ever remembered...
it will only be because of his.
Diego is at court
with Santangel hoping
to get your privileges restored.
But how is he?
He wants to start a pearl trade
in Santo Domingo.
He has received many letters
from your men.
He sent some of them.
This one's from Mendez.
- Mendez?
What does he say?
He asks to visit you.
He left his address.
He never had one.
Except aboard my ships.
I want you to tell me
everything you remember, Father.
I wouldn't know where to start.
Tell me the first thing
that comes to mind.
I remember...
In 1502, Columbus made a final trip
to the New World with Fernando.
They reached Panama where the Indians
told them of the Pacific Ocean.
His son's biography gave Columbus
his rightful place in history.
In 1992, one of his descendants is
Honorary Admiral of the Spanish Navy.
There is more imagination in life
than in dreams...