You have 10 minutes left.
Jesus, My Father!
About the topic related to
"The 95 Theses" in Question 2...
Is the answer Martin Luther in B?
Yes. That was the answer.
It was quite hard.
But I made it somehow.
It was hard for you, I suppose.
I'm in awe of this school.
It's okay for you to look around.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you.
Maria...
Today was kind of a shocking day
I'm a bad girl.
Maria...
Please be quiet...
I'm...
I'm coming...
I came.
Sacred Honesty Girls' School
Entrance Ceremony, Heisei 26 (2014)
Maria... I somehow got
admitted to this school!
The top-ranking scorers
from all over Japan...
vie for admission to this
coveted girls' school...
making the entrance exam
very hard for everyone!
Ms. Yuzuki Muto!
Yes?
Wait...
Excuse me...
Excuse me!
I don't know what's going on but
you shouldn't do things like this!
I'm okay Ms. Yuzuki Muto.
This is our club's activity
Your club?
Welcome to the Torture Club!
What is that?
This is the place where we study and practice
torture as our extra-curricular activity
Our goal is to facilitate torture battles,
which take place between two club members.
And I'm Yuri Kobashi,
the president of the club.
This is Maika Shinzaki,
a first year student.
Waite minute!
Why am I involved
with the Torture Club?
That's right.
This is the answer sheet
from your entrance exam.
We secretly mixed a torture qualification
test into the entrance exam...
in order to assess the torture
skills of the applicants.
What?
According to these results, you are clearly
very talented at torturing people.
No way!
Admitted
Outstanding Torture Skills
I just intuited the answers and didn't think it
through at all because it was too hard for me.
The torture test is only effective
when you follow your intuition.
But...
I can't torture people!
It hurts!
Help me!
You can't fight it.
The Torture Club is the club with the longest
tradition and it's fully recognized by the school.
If a student commits a crime, they will bear
the torture here and reflect on their conduct.
The Torture Club has the responsibility
of keeping order at our school.
But I didn't do anything wrong!
Then why am I...
Wait!
You...
You really didn't do anything bad at all?
To what extent do you think violent conduct
can be excused in order to achieve a goal?
Umm...
On the entrance exam day...
...my underwear disappeared.
Did you steal it?
No...
I didn't.
Lying is a major crime.
On the entrance exam day...
Were you in the changing room?
No... I wasn't.
There wasn't anybody else there, Yuzuki.
Who stole my underwear?
It wasn't me!
People are more vulnerable to tickling
than they tend to think.
You will suffer breathing
difficulties and pass out.
Sorry!
The one who stole your underwear was me!
The Pear of Agony
This is a torture device which is used against
a person who has done something corrupt.
If I put this into a vagina and unfurl it,
the vagina will be destroyed.
Why did you steal it?
I don't know.
I'm going to stretch the hole.
Are you sure?
Pee?
You can pee in that position.
I'm begging you.
Please let me use the toilet.
Pathetic.
All right. Let's go to the toilet together...
I can't do this!
What are you going to do?
- What have you done?
- I don't know!
Shit! Yuzuki, why don't you confess?
I don't know! I mean that
underwear was very...
Okay then!
Just release me already!
Yes...
What? You tightened it...
Yuzuki!
Yuzuki Muto.
You are very talented.
Joining the Torture Club is your destiny
No way...
I can't torture anyone!
Sorry!
Maria, I'm in big trouble!
To: Yuzuki
1 Attached File
I can spread this anytime.
Sorry! The one who stole
your underwear was me!
Ms. Yuzuki Muto, you left
something in your club room.
Please come to Club Room G right away
The school life I had dreamed
turned out to actually be...
Nothing but torture!
The Torture Club
- Hello.
Too late! Have you brought
your application?
The purpose of the Torture Club
is to train a torturer or spy
Someone who could get the job done if
they were dispatched to a war zone.
We are strengthening minds through torture.
I'm sorry President.
I'm not sure about becoming
a torturer or spy...
The enemies!
They use various kinds of torture in order
to obtain confidential information.
You need strong endurance
against all kinds of torture.
Endurance...
Bear it.
Yuzuki.
Yes...
Your skin is showing.
What...
Embarrassed?
I'm embarrassed...
Embarrassing the victim to the fullest is one
of the most important tasks of a torturer.
First, reveal the embarrassing
things about the victim.
Strip the victim of all dignity
I'm so embarrassed it hurts.
Aoi, I can't take it anymore...
Yuzuki.
This is your limit at the moment.
If something like this already makes you scream,
the problem is clearly the weakness of your mind.
The most important thing is that you
learn to protect your mind.
Protect my mind...
Well...
If they put pressure on your weak mind, you'll
even end up confessing things you didn't do.
You can't become a torturer or spy
who deals with national intelligence.
President...
I can't become something like a spy...
First!
Strengthening your mind.
That's the required quality for a torturer.
Now, torture Maika!
Is she okay?
Maika is still a first-year student but she's been with
us since she was in elementary school. No worries.
I'm going to pull.
Judas' Cradle.
One of the harshest tortures.
Aoi... That's...
That's right.
If I let go of this rope, the tip will
go directly between her legs.
That's... What if she gets stabbed...
I'll be okay because my
endurance is high enough.
Enough...
You can't do that, Aoi!
Maika, are you going to give up?
No, no, not yet...
It's inside! I said it's inside!
No, Aoi!
You can't do that!
Too weak.
Yuri, show her an ideal example.
You leave me no choice.
There are two kinds of people. Those who are good at
torturing and those who are good at being tortured.
And you are...
Isn't it obvious?
I'm like you. I torture.
Like me...
Follow me to death from now on.
Is it really okay?
1!
Sorry...
2!
Sorry
Don't say sorry!
Sorry...
Sorry
I said like this!
Hit her now!
Thank you very much.
Aoi, that's...
Yuzuki.
Throw away your embarrassment!
Maria.
The Torture Club is very strict.
How can I keep going?
Of course, because of my seniors...
Excuse me, is it true that you're
doing the same club activity as Aoi?
Well... Yes.
She's so cool, isn't she?
Yes, she is.
Yuzuki...
I'll definitely kill you.
Yuzuki! Endure it!
- It hurts!
- It doesn't!
It doesn't hurt! It hurts!
President... President...
No, I just...
I beg you! Don't tell her!
I won't do that kind of thing...
If I got busted, I...
Maika, you like the president...
Yuzuki! What are you doing?
Are you some kind of spy?
You should have a strong mind
to be able to keep on torturing.
Therefore, having romantic feelings is
prohibited, because it weakens our minds.
Torture is different from simple S&M, which
is practiced in the pursuit of pleasure.
If something goes wrong,
you can get seriously hurt.
I see.
So...
If it comes out that I have
a crush on the president...
I can't participate in the
club activities anymore.
But how can you keep containing that feeling?
I'm strengthening my mind through torture
in order to contain my feelings.
So, let's do it together, Yuzuki.
Yes.
Of course, your feelings for Aoi
are quite strong as well.
You knew?
As a member of the club
I have certain skills.
Giving up already?
No. Not yet.
Will I be able to do it too?
What's wrong?
Hold it. I know you can do it.
Aoi.
- I...
- Yuzuki.
Stop whining.
You can't stay childish and weak forever.
Aoi...
I...
Can I become strong?
You definitely will.
You can still take more.
Aoi!
It hurts! It hurts!
That's enough. We've finished.
My Father in the sky My prayer is...
I can see you have anxieties because of
the Torture Review. Your mind is weak.
Please forgive me.
Mother.
You need a strong body and mind
in order to torture someone.
To train those things, you need to hurt
the person you least wish to hurt.
Hurt the person I least wish to hurt...
First of all, you have to know
who that person is.
What should I do about my feelings for Aoi?
I don't think I can become strong.
From: Yuri
A training camp is scheduled at
Aoi's house during summer break.
A training camp?
Aoi's family is traditionally
a torture family
A torture family?
Yes.
I heard their family tradition started
during the Middle Ages in Europe.
The reason why her expertise is on the torturing side
is because she has to follow the family tradition.
I heard she is even prohibited
to be on the victim side.
I see.
It seems there are some
torture devices at her house.
Yuzuki, you don't know what kind
of things will happen to you.
Wait. Stop, Maika.
Well, Aoi. Please explain.
Today's goal is to teach the Funaki
family's traditional torturing skills...
to Yuzuki and Maika and strengthen
their minds significantly
What do you think is the most
undesired thing for a girl?
What is that?
Honey? Don't they like that?
The most undesired thing
for girls in general.
It's bugs.
Bugs...
A special kind of insect
inhabits this garden.
They are following the smell of honey
Wait a minute, please.
This is the traditional Funaki family
torture called Bug Attack.
Bugs! Bugs!
Actually I have impressive
memories about Bug Attack.
I was once covered with honey and left
alone for a whole night after I broke a rule.
I once lost my mind because of the unpleasant
feeling of their bites all over my body
It's going inside!
I can't do this!
I'm going to give you the
punishment for running away
Hurry up. Follow me.
Do you know what that is?
An Iron Maiden.
The inside is covered
with needles in a circle.
Transgressors are tortured by putting them
inside and poking them with the needles.
Get in.
Aoi... I will die.
No! Aoi!
No!
I didn't think you'd pass out.
Look.
It's made of rubber.
The Iron Maiden is an execution device
made to put the fear into whoever sees it.
Meaning that seeing it alone
is already a kind of torture.
When I was young, I would get
locked up in this after breaking rules.
I wanted to let you know too, Yuzuki.
If I were you,
I would've been traumatized.
When I was young,
I cried just coming near here.
Was it scary for you too?
Everyone has something unknown inside.
You are the same.
You just haven't gotten wise about
your hidden talent for torturing yet.
But...
Aoi...
I'm just weak. That's all.
Yuzuki...
When are you going to stop
saying things like that?
But...
Aoi!
I...
Sorry! There's a bug on your breast...
What? A bug? Where?
Hurry and get it off me!
Hurry!
Maybe it moved somewhere.
It's still there.
Yuzuki...
It's okay now.
You got bitten by the bugs.
Sorry about that.
Aoi has been trying hard because
the Torture Review is coming up soon.
Maybe she overdid it.
I'm just doing a precisely
calculated strength training.
That is Yuzuki's...
You want her to enlighten herself
about her talent for torturing people?
Yes. That's it.
Hey Yuzuki.
Yes?
Do you want to torture me?
What?
Do you want to torture and hurt me?
No way! Aoi!
I don't want to hurt you.
I see.
Yuzuki.
I'm going to be the one
being tortured this time.
Aoi?!
I can't do it!
You are not allowed to be tortured...
ls it really okay?
Hurry up.
Yes.
Calm down.
Tighten it more as I told you.
Yes.
- Are you okay?
- You don't have to ask.
Yes.
Next. Hurry up.
Sorry
Harder!
Yes.
Yuzuki, stop holding back!
Yuzuki.
You need determination!
Aoi...
Aoi!
Let's return to the separate lesson.
Yes.
Aoi...
Is your injury okay?
Yuzuki?
I have brought medicine.
Sorry
I...
I'm reflecting on what you
said to me today
Everyone has something unknown inside.
That's right. You're...
You've been lying to yourself
because of the rules of your family
Aoi.
I can help you.
Wrong.
The reason why I allowed myself to be tortured today was
just that I wanted to enlighten you about your talent.
Aoi...
- I'm...
- Doesn't matter what I do.
The training camp is over.
Check it after using it.
Sorry
Keep going forward.
Don't lose to your mind.
- Aoi
Maria.
I'm...
Strong...
I'm going to be strong.
I'm going to be strong!
Dear God, please forgive my sinful mind.
One!
Two!
Yuzuki.
What are you doing...
Please be quiet.
You'll be busted.
You've hidden your own masochistic nature.
It's wrong to keep hiding your own nature.
You taught me that.
Why are you doing this?
I'm going to strip away your dignity
What will people think if a senior member of a club
is being harassed like this on a bus by her junior?
Yuzuki, please stop.
Are you embarrassed?
Stop it, Yuzuki.
Yes.
Good morning, everyone.
This summer has been very hot, as usual.
I'm happy that every student has
come back with renewed energy...
Aoi.
It's cruel.
This is where I saw you for the first time.
You were spanking yourself in here.
Stop.
Why were you doing something
like that at school?
I didn't do anything like that.
Aoi...
Lying is a major crime.
You can't punish yourself for your own crime.
I'm going to punish you.
You've been hiding your masochistic nature.
You've felt guilty about it!
You have been prohibited
to show your real self!
Nobody tried to understand you.
But...
I can understand you!
Aoi!
I'm sorry
I have...
hidden my masochistic self.
I have hidden my prohibited masochistic self.
Aoi... Aoi...
Forgive me.
I think it's okay
Stop...
It's not 'Stop', is it?
Say Stop it, please.
Stop it, please.
Aoi.
You're just one helpless masochistic woman.
You're this wet?
Aoi... I'm coming!
Do you know why this is happening?
Having a romantic relationship
is prohibited in the Torture Club.
You know that.
Transgressors should be punished.
Why did you have a romantic relationship?
Nothing good will come out,
even if you shut your mouth.
Aoi.
What should we do?
Please stop.
It must be hard to swallow that someone
you love becomes sexually incapable.
Please torture me.
Okay Let's do it then.
President.
- I can't do this anymore...
- Maika.
We must have faith.
Yes...
Pull!
Aoi.
You love Yuzuki, right?
Look
Stop...
It's not 'Stop', is it?
Say "Stop it, please".
How could you possibly forget
that you were under surveillance?
Fucking ridiculous!
Stop it please.
Can I stop?
Aoi.
You're just one helpless masochistic woman.
Why did you break the rule?
Why don't you answer?
Maika, pull!
Yuri...
- I...
- Maika!
Why did you break it?
Why did you break it?!
Why...
Why did you hide your masochistic nature?
The romantic relationship between Yuzuki Muto
and Aoi Funaki was punished...
with extremely severe torture. As a result,
Aoi Funaki is in serious condition.
Am I right, President?
Yes.
I had a conversation with
Aoi Funaki yesterday
She said she would quit the club and asked
me to end this commotion with her exit.
What...
- It was my responsibility too.
- You!
Are you trying to destroy our Torture Club?!
Come forward. Yuzuki Muto!
Yes!
This...
Aoi Funaki asked me to deliver this to you.
You better not go there.
In the history of our club...
there have been quite a few members who quit due to
the punishment for having a romantic relationship.
You still don't get what she's trying to do.
This was in front of the door.
I'm outside.
- Yuzuki
Can I tell you something?
There must have been...
a deep emotional conflict in you
since I met you for the first time.
The reason why I stayed in the club...
wasn't because I didn't want you
to know that I stole your underwear.
I wanted to be with you.
Yuzuki.
I love you.
I love you as you are.
If you are not with me, I...
I...
don't love you.
Aoi...
Yuzuki.
Be strong.
Aoi...
Yuzuki...
I'm coming!
Half A Year Later
Torture Club
Torture Club Review
Oh my God.
Jesus Christ.
Still want more?
Look at that face.
Torture without any hesitation.
She's a torturer.
I can't do it anymore!
I give up.
What an impressive torture!
You have tortured exactly the right spots.
You can retire with peace of mind, President.
Yes.
Now, bring it here.
This is...
The Funaki family gave us this.
They wanted to put it here since
they are going to move.
Move?
Be Strong
You can say something
to her for the last time.
But...
I don't even have her phone
number at the moment.
I have it.
Yuzuki Muto.
I'm going to test for the last time
whether you've become a real torturer.
Get Aoi Funaki's number from me!
I'm strong.
Wait a second.
You're going to use that?
That's an execution device!
I might die!
Hello?
Aoi...
Yuzuki?
I didn't know you were going to move.
Yuzuki.
Don't worry about me.
I'm already thinking about where to start.
I'm going to start something totally
different from scratch in university
What's wrong?
Aoi.
I can't forgive you like this.
Yuzuki...
I...
want to torture you.
Why?
Because you lied when you
said you didn't love me.
Lying is a major crime.
I'm going to wait for you
at the Torture Club.
What are you going to do after
your graduation, President?
Well...
Get married and become a posh wife...
What?!
I'm kidding!
I'm going to take the test
to become a public servant,
And learn more about
torture through my career.
In other words, an elite career.
I've tried hard to achieve that goal.
I want you to stay here at the Torture Club.
I'm going to keep supporting
the club with Yuzuki.
Great job.
You're not a child anymore.
President.
- I...
- Maika.
Don't say anything more.
I know. It's not that hard
to know your feelings.
Maika.
There are struggles in my life too.
But if you want to live as a torturer,
you can't say anything weak like that.
I know.
The world of torture is quite strict...
Aoi.
Yuzuki.
Thank you very much.
I should be thanking you.
Make it tighter.
Yes.
You've become so good
I don't have to do anything.
You were lying...
Weren't you?
Aoi...
I admit it.
Please do me a favor.
What is it?
I want you to torture me too.
Why?
Because I'm lying as well.
About what?
Actually...
I want to be with you.
I want you to be with me...
In the world of torture.
I got it.
Yuzuki...
Take off your clothes.
Yes.
Aoi.
Tighter, please.
Yuzuki.
Tighter.
Tighter, please.
Yuzuki.
Do you confess?
Yes.
Yuzuki.
Aoi.
Stay strong.
Yes.
Yuzuki is...
going to be the best in the world of torture.
Even if I...
change my career...
I want you to stay strong.
Yes.
I'm going to stay strong.
Noriko Kijima
as Yuzuki Muto
Haruna Yoshizumi
as Aoi Funaki
Yuki Mamiya
Mika Yano
Kanako Mochida
Nami Motoyama
Reiko Hayama
Shungiku Uchida
Executive Producer:
Shinichiro Inoue
Producers: Ujikatsu Omori
Hidehisa Chiwata / Yuuichi Shibahara
Based on the manga series Chotto Kawaii
Iron Maiden by Makoto Fukami
Line Producer: Akio Motojima
Director of Photography: Masafumi Seki
Sound Recordist:
Mikisuke Shimadzu
Production Design: Shuji Yamashita
Set Decoration: Kosuke Nishibuchi
Hair Stylist: Naomi Oikawa
Costume Design: Masae Miyamoto
Sound Effects: Yoshio Nakamura
Editor: Masayuki Narumi
Casting: Yuya Kusuma
Assistant Director: Naoyoshi Kawamatsu
Written and Directed by
Kota Yoshida