Under power of the State,
I am hereby authorized to put you...
Lee Ray Oliver,
to death by lethal injection.
Is there anything
you'd like to say?
Fuck you!
Fuck every last one of you!
Cover that up, please.
Let's get the bag open.
Thank you.
- Where am I?
- You're in the County Morgue, Lee Ray.
I'm not dead.
The injections you got were all
saltwater except the anaesthetic.
- What the fuck is going on?
- You're getting an opportunity...
to be part of a medical
research project.
If you agree to participate
in the experiment...
I'll take you toe tag here put
it on that body over there.
He'll be cremated,
you'll go on with these gentlemen.
If you don't agree the doctor will
inject you with sodium pentathol...
and the execution will proceed
right now in this room.
What kind of experiment?
It's a behaviour
modifying drug trial.
- Who the fuck are you?
- I'm a neuropharmacologist.
I'm involved in the research
and development of new drugs.
- I like drugs!
- The drug we're going to give you...
is not a narcotic. It won't
give you narcotic sensations.
And there may be side effects.
Some severe, possibly fatal.
- You want me to be a guinea pig?
- No, you'll be a test subject.
You have 1 minute
to make your decision.
Fuck you, Warden!
Proceed.
This is your last chance to do
something good in your life.
A chance to give something
back to society.
Fuck society! What the fuck
has society ever done for me?
Doctor!
Just wait!
Wherever we're going I hope it
smells better that it did in there.
Let's go.
You greedy fuck!
So now you see how it goes.
Every time I say fuck...
he does that!
Because you, Warden...
have a lot of fucking nerve!
You thought you're gonna
get another one, didn't you?
But I said fucking, not fuck.
- Please, stop!
- Didn't I pay you well...
to let my men go after
Lee Ray in prison?
When Lee Ray offered him instead,
did I complain? No.
I didn't give a flying fuck!
I found out the State was gonna
execute him. So I am satisfied.
But now you tell me that
Lee Ray is actually alive...
and that you will find
out where he is...
if I pay you?
I'm sorry,
I'll do it for free. It's fair!
You'll find him, and we'll kill him.
Third time's the charm, right?
Yes, Mr. Vertov. Third time's the...
Don't fuck up!
You'll start off by taking
one pill every six hours.
Wait a fucking minute!
Wait a minute.
What's this pill gonna do?
My name is Dr. Copeland. I designed
the medication you'll be taking.
It's called Anagress. It works by
altering the brain's chemistry...
by suppressing your violent tendencies.
And with you aggression reduced...
you'll begin to experience feelings
of good will and compassion...
a sense of right and wrong,
even remorse over past mistakes.
- Good fucking luck.
- This is the first time Anagress...
has been tried on humans. We don't
know what the side effects are.
Hopefully they're minor:
Dry mouth, dizziness, nausea...
but there is a chance they
could be more severe.
Like what?
Liver failure, brain seizures...
...a stroke...
- Whatever.
Years ago, they might have
given you a lobotomy...
carved out a piece of your brain
like a rotten part of an apple.
But today we're more civilized.
We do it biochemically.
I rather have a bottle in front
of me than a frontal lobotomy!
How long is your little
experiment gonna last?
It's never over.
You and the other 19 test subjects...
will be observed indefinitely.
That' one pill every six hours.
Open wide.
Let's go.
Open back up.
Smart man.
- Hey, Michael! How you doing?
- Good. I'm doing good.
Excellent.
Is that Austin?
He scored two goals
in the first half.
- He's getting real tall.
- They grow up so fast, don't they?
Ah, jeez!
I just came to see
how the team was doing.
We're doing good.
- It's not the same, but...
- No. Nothing is.
Yes!
The guy seems a real teddy bear.
Two days and not a peep.
I want blood,
urine and saliva samples.
I have a PET scan and
SPECT scheduled.
Add a cerebral spinal
fluid analysis.
Yes, doctor.
Mr. Oliver...
we're going to remove
your last restraint.
I want you to relax.
I just died and live
to talk about it.
It doesn't get more
relaxed than this.
Is it all right
if I smoke in here?
We have a security breach.
I repeat,
we have a security breach.
Go!
We got him!
- The man is a fucking animal.
- He's perfect!
Hey, Aiku!
- Shit!
- Zone 8 activated.
- Aiku!
- Hello.
- There you are!
I've been looking for you everywhere.
You've changed the code again.
I'm sorry. We agreed you were
gonna call before you came by.
It's my weekend.
You knew I was coming by.
- I forgot. I'm sorry.
- How unusual!
Hello, Aiku!
How are you?
- What happened? You look terrible!
- It was a rough day at the office.
You look terrific, by the way.
I got a call from Jenny. She said
you showed up at the soccer match.
- That was fast!
- She was worried about you.
And I'm worried about you too.
I just wanted do feel
what it was like to...
be there again.
- I hurt too, you know.
- I know.
- That's why I've gotta go.
- I know that too.
Come on. Time to go to mom's house.
Next time I call before I come.
- All right.
- Come on!
You never told me your
ex was so beautiful.
- How long have you been here?
- Not long.
I was just in the pool
and I saw her drive up.
It wouldn't be a brilliant idea for me
to be towelling off in the living room.
I went upstairs and
hid in your closet.
How's your jaw?
The truth?
- I'm gonna make you feel better.
- Make me forget everything.
Can you do that for me?
I can try.
- What the hell is going on?
- Take the pill first.
Where's my hair?
Where's my tattoos?
Erased. Like your past.
In the next few weeks we'll be
making changes on your outside...
while the medication
changes you on the inside.
After what you guys did to me, you
guys should be taking these pills!
OK, but you first.
Attaboy.
The guy is pretty good.
Beat my high score.
Seratonine metabolate levels?
Barely registering.
The guy is a textbook sociopath.
Is it true he stabbed an inmate
in the eye with a screwdriver?
Yes. He goes for the head.
- Increase game difficulty.
- Ok.
Let's crank it up to mach 5.
- How'd he do with his MMPI?
- Just what you'd expect from...
a guy with antisocial
personality disorder...
...with psychotic tendencies.
- And that's just for starters.
Your fucking thing is rigged!
You can't hit a thing!
Fuck!
This fucking thing is rigged!
Get the fuck...
thing is rigged!
This thing is fucked up!
It's a broken machine!
Get the fuck outta here!
Fix your fucking machine!
There goes 10 grand.
Take it out of my paycheck.
Nikolai Vertov. 27 years old.
Do you ever feel bad
about taking his life?
- Bad? I feel really bad.
- You do? Tell me.
If I'd known the motherfucker was
the nephew of a Russian mobster...
I never would've robbed him, let
alone put a bullet through his head.
Manoel Jose Gutierrez.
- You ever been in prison, Doc?
- Let's not get distracted.
I didn't think so. It's probably
not what you're exactly used to.
The Russian mobster took a contract
out on me for killing his nephew.
Gutierrez here tried to
cash in on that contract.
I just defended myself.
- You felt justified in...
- I felt fucking justified!
I don't give a fuck if you believe
me or not! That's what happened.
I got the jump on him,
he's dead, I'm alive.
Gary David Caputo.
We got a minor bump.
He's alive.
- Just a little worse for wear.
- Tell me what happened with him.
Just wrong place, wrong time.
It's not my problem.
You threatened to kill his brother
for testifying at the trial.
- Is that true?
- Are we done? This is getting boring.
You were 12 years old
when your mother died?
- You know exactly how old I was!
- These files have discrepancies.
I just wanna make sure I get it right.
A former boyfriend killed her...
and you witnessed the murder.
Is that true?
Just give me the drugs
and let's get on with it.
You never said anything about
answering any of these questions!
- Just answer the question.
- I'll answer whatever I want!
And don't you go talking to
me like that. I'm not your kid!
If you don't answer the question,
you're of no use to me.
I'll transfer you back to the
custody of the warden right now.
You are only alive because of me.
Why don't you answer the questions,
so I can help you?
I was 10...
not 12.
I was 10.
Thank you.
Yes, I saw her
thrashing around.
I saw the whole
goddamn thing.
And then the fuck who killed
her took a piss in front of me.
Then he turned around and said:
"When you got to go...
you got to go".
You wanna hear about what my
uncle John used to do with me?
He had a little hobby
that he called golf.
He used to beat me with his
driver every Tuesday night.
Write that down. Why don't you
write a fucking book about it?
- All right, that's enough for today.
- It is e-fucking-nough!
I'm everything you hate
in the world, huh, Doc?
He's more at ease.
Much less agitated.
Five of the rhesus monkeys showed
results after only three doses.
- When is his next PET scan?
- "Mañana".
Let's do it now.
- Hey, Doc!
- How ya doin'?
I'm actually doing really good!
It's strange. I feel... different.
Everything seems clearer,
I feel less wound up.
Good.
- Shit... it really works.
- We just got to do...
Come here!
Everybody, get away!
Nobody move! Back up!
I'm gonna stick this
pen in his eye!
Put the fucking guns down!
- Get away!
- Put it down!
- So what he says!
- Put the gun down!
- Help me outta here, Doc.
- I will!
Put'em down!
Put the guns down!
Get away! Put the guns down!
Put it down!
I swear to fucking Christ
it's going in his eye!
Tell him to put the gun down.
- Do as he says.
- Get outta here!
Tell me how to get outta here!
We'll take it from here.
Get the fuck... jeez...
You're just as fucked
up as I am, Doc.
You got a fancy suit...
You're just as fucked up as I am.
You're just as fucked up.
Get off of me!
Jesus, are you okay.
Increase the dosage.
8 milligrams three times a day.
That's more than 3 times
the previous.
Just do it.
Hart-Mercer Pharmaceuticals...
dedicated to making the world
a happier, healthier place.
Now and in years ahead,
we will continue our...
You are too involved.
There's a reason why they...
don't want a primary researcher
conducting his own clinical trial.
The man is out of control. Unsuitable.
We'll find another one.
We have to give him more time.
I'm increasing the dosage.
If you don't like it, you can hand
my resignation in to the board.
Be careful. If one threatens to
resign one time too many...
they get taken up on it.
And now, ladies and gentlemen, Senior
V.P. Of Research and Development...
Dr. Arlo Penner.
Thank you.
Not too long ago, the acronym
SSRI was virtually unheard of.
Now, of course, Selective
Seratonin Reuptake Inhibitors...
help millions of people
lead better lives.
Today, as we speak...
a new class of pharmaceuticals
is being developed...
that has the potential to
change society as we know it.
As you're probably aware,
the reason why Hart-Mercer stock...
remains strong within this
volatile market sector...
is largely because of Dynax.
And I'm pleased to be able
to announce to you that...
Dynax has once again
been named...
as this year's most
prescribed anti-depressant.
So, on behalf of...
the board of directors and the
shareholders of Hart-Mercer...
I wanna thank you,
Dr. Michael Copeland...
for your groundbreaking work
which continues to this day.
- Congratulations, doctor.
- Thanks.
- You look surprised to see me.
- Maybe a little.
Did you forget that
I'm a shareholder?
Made us both rich.
As you keep climbing the ladder,
don't forget to count the rungs.
Remember when all we wanted
was that one bedroom house?
With our very own washer and dryer.
- And I was gonna open up a center...
- Stop. You're making me feel old.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Congratulations, doctor.
- Thanks.
Barbara, this is Eden Ross.
She's a post-doc. Part of the team.
- Nice to meet you.
- My pleasure.
When I was an undergrad...
I read your paper on the educational
deficits effect on family violence.
- It was really brilliant.
- Thanks.
Now I officially do feel old.
Next time invent a pill for that. Bye.
- Nice seeing ya.
- Bye.
- So am I gonna see you tonight?
- I hope so.
Are you buying a car?
- Tuesday! Must be beef stew.
- I wouldn't be too sure.
I'm sorry, Lee Ray.
It's all right. It's cool.
No sweat.
I'll get something to clean it up.
- He didn't hit me.
- I could've made that accident...
more natural.
- This is very good, gentlemen.
- I did a decent Yago, senior year.
- Who the hell is Yago?
- We've got his MAO level.
Lambda K three is point one four.
This is your last chance to do
something good in your life.
OK. I'll be right there.
- Who was it?
- Security.
I'll go with you.
Come on, man, just chill.
It's all right.
No, it's not.
- I'm gonna be sick again.
- Take a deep breath.
What's going on?
- I can see his face.
- Whose face?
Gary Caputo's.
Wrong time, wrong place.
He was just standing on the
stairs with a bag of groceries.
I should've just ran by, passed him
and just gotten the hell outta there.
It's OK.
He was in a coma
for seven months.
He had to learn to do
everything all over again.
When I was in prison,
I used to joke about him.
I used to brag about how
I made the guy into a vegetable.
What's important is you know
that what you did is wrong.
The treatment is working.
- It's working.
- Why can't I sleep?
I wanna put my head on my pillow...
close my eyes and not
see his face anymore.
It's gonna be OK.
We'll give him Somnubel.
5 milligrams.
Brock, that's two tablets
whenever he can't sleep.
Ladies and gentlemen...
we've got remorse.
How can we be sure
he's not faking again?
All of his biomarkers back it up.
Ever since week 5 his serotonin
and MAO levels have improved...
limbic and amygdale activity...
as well as BFS measures
have responded in kind.
I think we're ready for Phase 2.
Are you sure? The board
and I both believe that is...
absolutely your call.
But we all know the risks involved
in moving forward too quickly.
It's going to work. I think that
we've uncreated a monster.
- Lot more cell phones!
- Tell me about it.
- This thing is tight.
- You'll get used to it.
The only way that truly gauge...
the effects of Anagress is to
observe you in the real world.
A controlled environment
can only tell us so much.
I haven't been on the
outside in a long time.
- What if I fall on my ass?
- You get back up.
This is it?
- I thought you were made of money.
- Beats your last address.
That's fine, guys.
- Thanks.
- Let's do it again.
- What's your name?
- Joe Monroe.
And what have you been
doing for the last 5 years?
Working in Cincinnati, Ohio,
in a packaging plant.
- Loading boxes in a warehouse.
- Good.
Here's 300 bucks and an
ID to get you started.
- And then what?
- Another 300 next week.
You're on your own.
It's nice.
- There's nothing in the fridge!
- Guess you'd better go to the store.
Something wrong?
No, just looking at the view.
All right.
I'll let you get settled.
He hasn't stabbed anybody in
the eye yet. So, that's a start.
Eden, I want a seratonin
metabolite analysis.
Attaboy!
- Tracking okay?
- We're on.
Oh, man, he's oh for eight.
What we'll do if no
one will hire him?
The question is, what he'll do?
He's into current events now?
- He's checking out the classifieds.
- Impressive!
Yeah, Sully. Sully from inside.
He told me to call you.
250 is all I can spare,
you understand?
Why? 'Cause I gotta
buy groceries.
Sully, yes.
All right. Good.
I'll see you there.
- You guys hiring?
- You see a Help Wanted sign?
You in the blue shirt.
Come here.
- What?
- Think I can help you.
You can fill out this application.
- What d'ya wanna know?
- The usual.
I know everything about cars.
Foreign, American, everything.
All you need to know is how to drive
them 10 feet without crashing them.
I could do that.
I'm gonna have to get back to you
for the numbers for references.
Don't worry. Put any number. I'm
the one who makes the phone calls.
Give these away to people who get the
hot wax. You getting the hot wax?
- No, sir.
- He's filling out the application.
It's looking really good.
- Are you a hard worker?
- Very hard.
- Take drugs?
- No. Vitamins, but that's it.
You bullshitting me? I don't
want drug addicts working for me.
I don't take drugs.
Honest. No drugs.
I'll start you at 5,75 an hour,
plus tips.
Go grab a rag and talk to Alfonso.
Tell him Ralph sent you.
- I'll be back at one.
- Thank you.
Here. Better go before
he changes his mind.
- Thanks a lot. I appreciate it.
- Sure.
You Sully's friend?
Do I know you?
I'm Sully's friend.
You got what I want?
You sound like someone
I knew. I think he's dead.
- Some son-of-a-bitch he was.
- I guess he can be me then.
- What's he doing?
- Looking for us.
I'd say that Lee Ray just took
the hidden out of hidden camera.
Nightmares again?
Can't give you any more.
Doc said two pills a night, max.
Did you ever try these things?
Nah. Soon as I hit
the bed, I'm out.
My daddy used to say that...
an honest man's pillow
is his peace of mind.
Wanna play cards? It's gonna take 20
minutes for these things to kick in.
I'm not supposed to do anything
that could affect your environment.
Winning a hand of cards is
really gonna affect my life!
Come on, I've got this
kick-ass root beer here.
You won't let me have any alcohol,
so I sprang for the good stuff.
All right,
but then I'm out the door.
Cheers.
How long have you been
working with theses guys?
Three years this month.
I used to be a cop in Detroit...
but this is much better.
I'm not even supposed to
talk to you. I gotta go.
- Get some sleep.
- No, take it with you.
- It's fine.
- Thanks, man.
What are you wearing?
Really?
Is that all?
I think you are a
very naughty girl.
Shit!
Come on, Brock.
I see your goddamn walkie.
The Blue Line for Davenport
now boarding on Track 4.
Dr. Copeland?
It's Norton. We've lost him.
The train is bound to Davenport.
We got him on GPS.
This piece of shit has been playing
a big con on us all along.
That's not possible.
What the hell's he
doing in Davenport?
Shit. That's where
Gary Caputo lives.
The guy Lee Ray shot
in the stairwell?
And his brother that testified
against Lee Ray lives there too.
Bill's not here!
Gary?
Bill's not here.
I'm not looking for Bill.
I came here to see you.
I like this commercial.
Who are you?
My name is Joe.
- I don't know anyone named Joe.
- I'm a new friend.
I wanna tell you something.
Long time ago,
somebody hurt you.
Really bad.
They hurt you really bad.
And they want me to tell you they
were really sorry for what they did.
They're really sorry
for hurting you.
It's okay.
No, it's not.
Here. I got you something.
I got you some stuff. Here.
I don't know what you like
so I got you what I like.
I'm not supposed to
eat too much candy.
- Look at this.
- But I do.
Listen to me,
anything that you want...
if you wanna go see a movie,
go to the park...
whatever you want,
you tell me.
I'll see you again soon.
Was that guy in here?
- He's my friend.
- What do you mean?
- He's gonna take me to a movie.
- What? What's his name?
- I forget.
- You fucking forget everything!
Where do I know that guy?
You gotta sign the check again.
Here!
- What do I write?
- Jesus Christ...
do we have to go over this
every goddamn month?
Write Pay to the Order of William
Caputo and then you sign it.
I should blow your fucking brains
out. You and Dimi Vertov.
He sent you, didn't he? You're lucky
I'm gonna give you another chance.
Leave me alone.
You tell him to leave me alone.
You understand? I'm a different
person now. It's over.
Turn the fuck over.
You count to 500.
If I see a fucking eyebrow
twitch, you're dead!
Don't move, asshole!
Move a muscle,
you'll be nothing but a bloodstain.
Ya think we weren't
gonna catch up with you?
- What the hell were you thinking?
- I needed to see Gary.
To apologize.
I was coming back.
- Brock is okay?
- Brock is unemployed.
It wasn't his fault.
I had to go see Gary.
I can't sleep.
I had to see Gary.
- I was coming back.
- Here's his train ticket, Doc.
Round trip.
- You were really coming back?
- What else am I gonna go?
You gotta give him his job back.
It wasn't his fault!
- I bet you want him back.
- If anyone figures out who you are...
if anyone knows you're alive, the deal
is off and it's back to the warden.
You understand that,
don't you?
Can I have a pill, please?
Couldn't be!
Was this the guy who that in here?
They showed that commercial again.
And you missed it.
The man had a return ticket,
for God's sakes!
What he did today was
an act of contrition.
12 weeks ago,
he had no remorse...
and now he's risking
his life to apologize!
- The man is a murderer.
- He was a murderer.
You put a guard in his room,
it'll influence his behaviour.
You can't do it!
If anything were happen,
we're responsible.
Hart-Mercer Pharmaceuticals!
I'll give you one more chance...
then we move on to a different test
subject. Period. End of discussion.
Arlo...
is there something I should know
about the other test subjects?
I've told you.
Any knowledge of their status...
could influence your interaction
with your own subject.
Yes, but I heard a rumour
from one of the post-docs.
Some of the test subjects
have died of liver failure.
If it's true, I should know.
Has your subject shown
signs of liver damage?
No, he hasn't.
The most significant side effects
are insomnia, dry mouth...
persistent feelings of
guilt and remorse.
Nothing here about
liver complications.
You don't need to concern
yourself with the other subjects.
You have enough on
you hands as it is.
You shouldn't spend so much
time listening to post-docs.
Especially the
attractive ones.
You don't like relish much,
do you?
Trying to eat more vegetables.
- So what's Cincinnati like?
- They got a baseball team.
I guess you don't miss it much.
I just wanted to start from scratch.
Me too.
It's a beautiful thing, isn't it?
- What's that?
- Starting from scratch.
I hear you.
Ralph says you're doing really good.
He says you caught on quick.
It's not too much to catch on to.
You want some dessert or...
They got a really good
ice cream sandwich.
- Come on, I owe you!
- You don't owe me anything.
I owe you.
Fairly smooth.
- What are you reading?
- Introduction to Geology.
- It's a real page-turner.
- You go to school?
Community College, nights.
It's my second semester.
- Keeps me busy.
- I knew you had brains.
If had brains,
would I be working here?
Come on!
You ever been inside?
Inside what?
Come on.
Do you do this very often?
I don't know.
For some reason
I find it to be relaxing.
- It is.
- For a couple of minutes...
I feel I can think.
I guess I can see that.
Only thing is, you have to
haul ass before Ralph sees you.
You get a thing?
Teresa...
what are you thinking?
Guess.
Jump!
- Did he see us?
- I almost tripped over my foot.
- Haven't seen him.
- He looks different now.
He doesn't have them scars.
He was in here 2 days ago.
It's on the receipt.
We get a lot of people
in here every day.
You should check the neighbourhood.
Maybe he lives around here.
Thanks.
Hop in. I'll give you
a ride to your place.
Looks like the doc's
breaking the cardinal rule:
Never get attached
to you lab rat.
Thanks, Doc.
Let's go.
- Thanks for the lift.
- Sure. Put on your belt.
Check those books out?
I stole them. Had to pop a couple
librarians to make me getaway.
- Nice.
- This is a sweet ride.
I drove one of these
on the car wash.
I only drive like 10 feet but...
You got a family, Doc?
That's none of your business.
I was just curious. I was just
wondering if you had a family.
It's inappropriate for you to
ask me personal questions.
But it's okay for you to
know everything about me.
I see how it works. Just curious.
What? Come on. I wanna know.
My wife and I have split up.
- And we had a son.
- Is he living with her?
No, he was killed.
- Accident? Was he sick or...
- Murder.
He was 8 years old.
We were driving home from the
park after shooting hoops...
like we did on every Saturday when
I could get away from work...
and a car cut us off.
I laid on the horn, changed lanes.
He cut me off again and I lost it.
I flipped him the bird and start
screaming and the next thing I know...
the guy shoots at me with a gun.
The windshield shatters.
I pull over, turn...
Tommy's slumped over
covered in blood.
He looked at me and said:
"It's gonna be okay, daddy.
I'm gonna be okay."
- And then he died.
- I'm sorry, Doc.
If that guy had been on Anagress,
maybe my son'd be alive today.
If I had been on
Anagress maybe...
You can just drop me off here.
I'll walk the rest of the way.
Thanks for the lift.
There you go.
- I have a date tomorrow night.
- Really?
- Good for you. That's great.
- This thing around my ankle...
- It stays where it is.
- Come on! What if I get lucky?
You're gonna have to figure out
a way to keep your pants on.
- Come on, Doc!
- Sorry, pal. I can't help you.
I'm not gonna run, I swear!
I like the way things are right now.
- I'm not gonna run.
- I know, I believe you but...
I got rules to follow too.
Borrow the car?
Have a good time.
- Thanks for the ride.
- Sure.
Be well, Joe.
They didn't change a thing.
- Can you tell me what's going on?
- What do you mean?
I haven't had dinner with
you since... I can remember...
even when we
were still together...
Friday's? I thought it was
in the off-limits category.
We only came here because...
Tommy liked it so much.
What can I tell you? I'm jonesing
for a number 3 with hickory sauce.
I'm surprised they
let us back in here.
- I don't think they recognized us.
- How could they forget?
The flames almost
touched the ceiling.
How could they forget...
how you tried to douse the
flames with your milkshake?
Who was the genius who left
his menu on a smoking toaster?
It's a stupid place
to put a toaster!
And let's face it:
We both panicked.
Only Tommy stayed calm. Just
unplugged it and got the manager.
That's the first time I've heard
you say his name since...
I brought the papers
for the lake house.
We got a pretty good price.
It will be divided fifty-fifty...
as per our very amicable
divorce agreement.
Right here.
I've cashed in my stock options.
Really?
Hart-Mercer not seem like a good
investment all of a sudden?
No, but I'm buying an old
school building downtown.
It's a major fixer-upper but my
accountant says that real state...
is less risky than biotech
these days, so...
True.
I'm gonna open up that youth
center I was always talking about.
- At least, I'm gonna try anyway.
- You'll do it.
Barbara, that's great.
I thing that's really great.
You know that colleague
you introduce me to?
She's very pretty.
Reminds me a bit of me
when I was that age.
You were prettier.
And a bit smarter.
You look nice.
- Whatever.
Come on.
- You know this guy?
- Can't say I do, mister.
- Ugly son-of-a-bitch, ain't he?
- Look closer.
He's different now. No scars.
He changed his face,
but's still him.
You do know him, don't you? He
just drove out of here with that girl.
Why are you looking for him?
Do he owe you money?
- Then what'd he do?
- For starters...
he shot my brother in the head.
This is really cool!
I can't believe you've never been
to an amusement park before.
When I was a kid,
a sandbox was a big deal.
Want a beer?
- No.
- Sure?
I'm 10 months sober.
Really?
Can't picture you a big drinker.
Drinking wasn't really my thing.
I dated this guy,
and he was a dealer.
I ended up doing speed with him
'til it got out of control.
I was down to 95 pounds
by the time I hit rehab.
Too much information
at once, huh?
At least you got out.
- You got yourself a second chance.
- I had to.
I see it like this...
keep one eye in the past
and one eye in the future...
you end up cross-eyed.
So I'm thinking about right now.
And right now...
- I'm happy. I'm having fun.
- Me too.
I got an idea. Come on.
I still think we should go in.
Give him some space. He's gotta
come out the same way he went in.
Lee Ray!
- You're very aggressive out there.
- It's better than crashing real cars.
That's true.
You wanna try the merry-go-round?
I'm a merry-go-round freak.
Really?
- Sure.
- Doesn't make you dizzy.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
I'll be right back.
- You don't mind I go on...
- No. I'll be right back.
Get out of the way!
You there! Stop!
Did I miss anything?
Nothing much. It was a tight
race but I won by a nose.
- What took you so long?
- Long line. Ready?
So...
you want me to drop you off?
I'll walk home from you apartment.
Make sure you get home safe.
- What?
- Wanna make sure I get home safe?
I was gonna invite
you in, anyway.
You got a nice apartment.
Welcome to my palace, darling.
The maid's quarters are downstairs.
And it's the butler's day off.
Hope you don't mind.
You probably wanted to
stay at the park longer.
I'm sorry. I hope I didn't
mess things up.
Don't worry about it.
Can't be a kid forever.
Joe...
I've trusted a lot
of people in my life.
I was wondering if...
I can trust you.
There's something
I should tell you though.
- Great. I've heard that before.
- No, it's not that.
I'm on this medicine...
these pills...
that make you...
calm or something.
What happens when you
don't take them?
You wouldn't wanna know me.
Whatever it is they're doing,
it's working.
- I should probably go.
- What's wrong?
Nothing. I just wanna have
something to look forward to.
Right.
A guy who didn't want to jump
my bones on the first date.
I can trust you.
- I had a great time tonight.
- Me too.
- Something to look forward to.
- I'm gonna regret having said that.
I'll see you tomorrow?
- I thought he was gonna get lucky.
- Tough break.
Just in time.
He's overdue for his Anagress.
Shit!
There's nowhere to park.
Drive around the block
We'll find another one.
Got ya, motherfucker!
Drop the gun!
Dammit!
Shit!
What's up with this asshole?
My God!
Shit!
Tell me you're not
gonna get that.
Hello?
OK. I'll be right there.
- Let's go.
- No, you can't.
- Why?
- It might be dangerous.
If you're not gonna
let me go with you...
I'm not gonna stay here by myself.
- He ditched it in the trash bin.
- I just can't believe that he...
Don't you see how he played you?
He's a sociopath.
You should've known better.
Those bastards can fool...
polygraph machines. What made
you think he couldn't fool you?
I don't know.
He's in a black pickup with flame
decals. Make sure he doesn't go far.
- You're authorized to terminate.
- What's that supposed to mean?
You know the protocol. If the
subject commits a violent crime...
during Phase 2,
there's no alternative.
He's already dead in
the eyes of the law.
And that justifies us hunting
him down and killing him?
Goddamn right, it does.
We'll do an autopsy and figure out
what happened with the Anagress.
Go to the lab.
Make the necessary adjustments.
You'll be back on
track in no time.
Come on! Get up!
Right here.
You can get rid of all those scars.
You still got the same evil eyes.
So, what'd you do?
Pay off the doctor?
The warden?
Where'd a low-life like you get
the money to fake an execution?
- I'm sorry about Gary...
- That just wraps everything up.
Right, Gary?
- Fuckhead here says he's sorry.
- He's my friend.
- He's your friend, huh?
- We're going to the movies.
You're going to the
movies together?
Is that right?
You're good friends?
Tell my brother what
a good friend you are!
- I'm sorry...
- Shut up!
Shut the fuck up with sorry!
I saw you snickering
with that lawyer.
You didn't have an ounce of remorse.
Tell my brother what
you did to him.
Gary...
your friend wants to tell you
exactly what he did to you.
He gave me candy.
Tell him.
I didn't tell you the truth about
someone else hurting you.
I did it.
Tell him what you did!
I shot you in the head.
I shot you.
- I'm really sorry, Gary.
- Shut up!
Fucking sorry. I could've had
a life if it wasn't for you.
Instead I had to take care of
my fucking brother all the time!
- If I could trade places with him...
- Shut up!
Look at me.
- Fuck you!
- He's my friend!
Don't!
Go! Go!
Get off!
Get the fuck off me, Gary!
Get those monitors packed up.
- Copeland.
- Doctor, I need my medicine.
- Where are you?
- Did Norton make it?
You shot him in the heart. Of course
he didn't make it. He's dead!
- I didn't shoot him!
- Don't lie to me!
I'm not lying!
Bill Caputo shot him.
He recognized me when
I went to see Gary!
He just kidnapped me
and tried to kill me!
- Why the hell should I believe you?
- Do you think I'd kill Norton?
After all this,
do you thing I'd do that?
They must've seen his car.
Caputo took me in his truck.
Your guys must have seen it.
Have them check it out.
You gotta believe.
Just come and get me.
- Come and give me my medicine.
- Where are you?
Where's the fire?
Maybe we better find out.
Shit!
- I need help.
- You want the Emergency Room.
- I need Anagress.
- Never heard of it.
Do you have a prescription?
Give me something to mellow
me out! What do you got?
Don't hurt me, man!
Come here.
Where are you going?
Teresa?
I need your help.
Are you there? I need your help.
I'm in trouble. Please, let me in.
Teresa, please, come to the door.
God! Teresa?
- Let me in. I'm in trouble...
- Ralph called.
He said somebody came to see him.
They said you were a killer.
That your name is Lee Ray.
Is that true?
- Is it true?
- I was...
Please, don't do this to me.
I was Lee Ray.
I'm a different person now.
I'm not who I was.
I can't be who I was.
Please, they're coming after me.
Don't do this to me.
- It's the cops, isn't it?
- No, they're not the cops.
Jesus! If you don't let me in,
they're gonna kill me.
Teresa, please!
Open up!
- We're here for Joe Monroe.
- Who?
Go!
I got here as fast as I could.
What happened?
- It's all gone to shit.
- What do you mean?
I keep on asking myself...
am I arrogant or
I was just stupid?
I had such hopes for Anagress...
I need my pills. Now!
- What's going on?
- Everything is gonna be fine.
It's not gonna be fine until
I get my pill. You got them?
- Get them!
- Not until she leaves.
- She's not going anywhere.
- I know you didn't kill Norton.
That was Bill Caputo's truck,
just like you said.
And I know what kind
of person you are.
And you gonna let her go 'cause
she has nothing to do with this.
Barbara, go.
Do not call the police
or I'll be in trouble.
Just go. It's gonna be fine, Joe.
I want everything
back the way it was.
- Please, give me my pills.
- The pills are in my office.
This isn't enough. What am I
supposed to do when this runs out?
- Eden Ross.
- Hi, it's me.
- I need you to do something for me.
- Now you need my help?
Please, this is important.
Take all the Anagress we
have and bring it to my house.
- Can you do that?
- Okay.
And don't tell anyone.
Was that him?
What'd he want?
He wants me to bring the lab
supply of Anagress to his house.
Well done.
It's my job.
- She'll be here in half an hour.
- Thanks.
What's happening?
Did you hear anything?
- Where is he?
- What?
Eden said you asked her to
bring Anagress to your house.
I tried to warn you. Post-docs,
they always put their careers first.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
He called one hour ago...
but wouldn't say where he was.
Just wanted his pills.
He didn't kill Norton.
Bill Caputo did.
It was Bill Caputo's truck
they saw driving away.
Joe Monroe doesn't have to die.
The Anagress works.
All we have to do is get him
back on the medication.
- Anagress doesn't work.
- Anagress does work.
Doesn't work!
All the subjects who
took Anagress are dead.
Their livers shut
down after six weeks.
- He's fine.
- He was on a placebo.
He was part of the control group.
He was getting
nothing but sugar pills.
If he was taking the actual
medicine, he'd be dead right now.
But...
that's not possible.
You knew there was a chance
he'd be in the control group.
Yes, but his biomarkers,
his seratonin levels... scientifically...
Never underestimate the
power of the placebo effect.
People have cured themselves from
every disease known to science.
Eradicated tumours, for Chrissakes!
But eventually the
placebo effect dies.
I need a drink.
Anybody want a drink?
- Hello?
- Michael, is he still in the house?
No, he's outside.
He crapped all over the floor.
I think he's got worms.
- I'm keeping him outside.
- Does he still have a gun?
No, but the vet
should check him out.
- He'll be ready when you get here.
- I'm calling the police.
I got to go now.
- I'm expecting a work call.
- OK. Bye.
That was Barbara.
I call her whenever the dog is sick.
You know how she is.
Are you still seeing her?
I always liked Barbara.
No, we just share
custody of the dog.
You sure you don't want a drink?
'Cause I need one.
Maybe I'll have a drink.
Shit!
You can get yourself
killed for doing this.
Nobody is gonna get killed.
Gonna get you to the airport.
Put you on the next flight out.
- I don't have enough pills.
- You don't need any pills.
- What are you talking about?
- You don't need them.
They were nothing but sugar.
- What?
- They didn't do a damn thing.
Son-of-a-bitch!
When we start a drug trial, half the
subjects are picked at random...
to get the actual drug, the other half
are given a phoney pill: The placebo.
You were in
the control group.
That's bullshit!
No. I never lied to you and
I'm not lying to you now.
- He's headed for the lake.
- We got him.
You know what to do.
You knew this the whole time?
It would've affected
how I treated you.
I just found out tonight, I swear.
You knew theses
things weren't real?
They were real to you,
and that's what matters.
You okay?
You gotta get outta here.
Get to the airport anyway you can.
Here's some money.
Disappear. Go.
- That was you, Doc.
- What?
You're the reason why I got better.
It wasn't any drug.
You changed yourself.
Now hurry! Go!
Go!
You gotta go.
- What do you think of it so far?
- It's okay.
Let's have a look outside.
Beautiful!
- Wayne, this is Michael.
- How you doing, Wayne?
- Good.
- You wanna meet the other guys?
Come on.
All right, Rhonda,
time to play a real master.
I want you to meet Wayne!