Kristal Film presents a Joe D'Amato film
Images in a Convent
Written by Tom Salima
Film Editors Vincenzo Vanni
Roberto Savoca
Music by Nico Fidenco,
directed by G. Dell'Orso
Director of Photography
Aristide Massaccesi
Executive Producer
Oscar Santaniello
Directed by Joe D'Amato
This Film is based on ''La religieuse'' by
Denis Diderot
Where is the fruit, Ceso?
Your Eminence will be here soon
I am sorry Sister Marta, it has happened
again
It was him.
Nonsense, I don't want to hear those
superstitions
do you understand?
Yes.
Go now, they are coming.
My apologies, your Eminence
we try not to let news from the outside
reach us.
Mother Superior, these are noble words.
I am aware what I ask is not easy.
The father of the countess Isabella
was a pious and righteous man
Just before passing away
he asked me to protect Isabella from her
uncle, Don Ascanio.
I heard he is a heartless person.
He is worse than that. He is vicious and
corrupt
and unfortunately Isabella is very close
to him.
Your Eminence thinks her uncle
will try to influence her negatively?
I brought her here because I think we
can still save her soul.
I am at your service, Your Eminence.
I know goodness guides your actions.
Thank you Mother. Isabella is a proud
and lofty woman
my hope is that she will decide to take
her vows
obviously with your help.
Against her will? With no authentic
call?
This would offend God, Your Eminence.
Not necessarily, Sister Angela.
This will protect her from Don Ascanio's
attempts to abduct her.
When things calm down, we would
release her from her vows
if she wishes.
My obedience is to the church of God,
Your Eminence
but you are asking me to obey the
church of the world.
Unfortunately in my position I am
required to deal with this.
I have no doubts the peacefulness of
this place
will work the miracle.
Now I have to rush to Milan.
As you wish, Your Eminence
please tell your coachman to avoid the
forest
it is dangerous to travel across,
especially at night.
Welcome to Santa Fiora, My name is
Sister Giulia
and she is Sister Consolata.
And I am Isabella, countess of Lignate.
What do you want? Are you my
servants?
No, we are to help you as sisters.
The Mother Superior wants you to wear
this.
Do you really think I will wear this?
It is not good for my skin.
Two underskirts, four shirts and
two pairs of socks and 1, 2, 3 ...
Mother, Isabella is here
Sister Giulia, Sister Veronica you may
leave now.
Welcome to Santa Fiora, Isabella. In this
peaceful place ...
Cover up, I said cover up.
I won't judge your insolence, daughter
it is my duty to forgive and to
understand.
You are here to find peace in the
serenity of this convent
Is this the reason you are keeping me
prisoner?
You are here because of your father's
will
and the church recommendation
aren't those good reasons for
obedience?
Why don't you admit that I am here
because of Cardinal Dell'Aio's plot.
Daughter, how dare you to speak like
that of a pious person?
I warn you Mother.
My uncle will not tolerate such an abuse
and he will do everything to take me
away from here.
I will not ask you to take the vows,
Isabella
becoming a nun is a struggle against
nature
The sacrifices are inhumane and are
worthy
only if done with humility, love and
charity of the heart.
This is something you cannot possibly
achieve.
It would mean to sacrifice your pride.
What do you know about love
about the kisses of a man that loves
you
of the arms of a man that hold you?
I have tried all these and I will not forget
them.
And how would I forget?
With your useless prayers?
Daughter, you are cursing, I am not
going to listen to you
go back to your cell, that's an order.
Ascanio.
Sister Marta, please forgive me
I cannot forgive your lust, come with me
What you have done is terrible.
I repent, I repent with all my soul,
forgive me.
Oh no.
Calm down, sisters. Please don't panic.
It is nothing, stay calm. Stay calm
I am sure there is nothing to worry
about.
Calm down sisters, please.
Where is Sister Marta?
In her cell.
Let's call her, Sister Veronica.
Yes.
I am ashamed, Lord, but I did not intend
to do that
something that I can't explain happened
inside me.
Something I couldn't resist, please
forgive me.
Sister Marta, where were you?
In the chapel, what's happening?
I don't know, something serious has
happened.
Oh lord! Is he dead?
I don't know.
He is breathing, go back with the
others.
Careful.
Sister, are we in danger?
No, don't worry.
Blessed Virgin, thank you. What was
that noise?
There is a young man injured in the
garden
Sister Angela is taking care of him.
Mother, our Rule forbids us to host a
man under our roof.
I know, Sister Marta.
But we also have the duty of charity
and we are bound to respect the right of
asylum.
The convent is too far from a village
who else would rescue that poor man?
You are right, Mother. Isn't it strange
what has happened?
Oh no, unfortunately it is not the first
time
brigands assault those who travel
across the forest.
Still, I don't understand what brought
the young man this far
there is only our convent in these hills.
Maybe he was lost, who knows?
Go now, and do as I ordered.
Mother, you asked for me?
Yes, Sister Veronica, ask Ceso to come
and see me.
Also, we have to bring some food to
that man
I want you to do that.
At your service, Mother.
I am old enough not to be led into
temptation.
Sister Veronica, I will not tolerate such
language.
I am sorry Mother.
They say he is very handsome and
gentle
and that he fought against the brigands
like a lion
maybe the brigands are still around.
Why do you want to scare me?
No, I want you to be ready.
What would you do if those sons of
Satan appeared here?
I would be dead scared, what else?
No, I meant, what if they would rape
you?
I'd rather die.
I'd rather be a martyr.
Oh Virgin Mary, what are you saying?
Take it.
Thanks.
Do you want some, Sister Marta?
It's so kind of you to bring this to me.
No thank you.
I told you that I have learned to repress
all pleasures of the flesh.
I know, you even refused a necklace
that would be envied by any woman, sit
here next to me.
Your friendship is the best present for
me.
You deserve more, Sister Marta.
When I get out of here and you'll see.
I'll convince the cardinal that this
convent
would have no better Superior than you.
Do you want me to commit the sin of
pride?
Oh no, I just want to be your friend.
You have to get rid of that
the Rule forbids us to keep profane
images in our cell.
There is nothing wrong with it.
He is Don Ascanio, my dear uncle
He can not help if he doesn't know that I
am here.
I was thinking of that young man
tell me what do you know about him?
Only what I've said. His name is Guido
Bencio
he is an artist or something like that.
Sister Marta, please do your best so I
can meet him
speak to him.
No, that's impossible.
I would do everything for you
but Mother Superior gave strict orders
I am sorry.
In this case, let's make something up,
an excuse
I absolutely have to speak to him.
Magnificent, celestial
they should canonize you for the way
you cook.
Shut up! You are not an atheist, are
you?
Quite the opposite
I would be more devoted than you
but I am scared of the idea of paradise
it is probably an extremely boring
place.
Oh Jesus
I can always change my mind.
Maybe it is not by chance that I ended
up here
you could treat my soul as you treat my
body.
No doubt, Sir.
There is only one problem; I would have
to stay close to you
if only I could get a room in the
convent.
This is impossible, that's the Rule.
Maybe I can convince the Mother
Superior, who knows?
She is an extraordinary woman
and she is inflexible with her principles.
You can say that.
She hasn't come to see me, tell her I
want to speak to her.
Believe me Isabella, this is not the right
thing.
Isabella, don't at impulsively.
By pretending to follow the Mother
Superior
you would get what you want.
You speak better than a woman of the
world
considering that you are a nun.
Careful Isabella, do not forget what I
wear.
Sorry Sister Marta, believe me
if I stay here any longer I will go crazy.
All right. I will help you.
But what tells you we can trust that
man.
You said that he is a gentleman.
This is what I think, but looks can be
deceiving.
We are not going to have another
opportunity like this.
Please, let me speak to him.
No Isabella, I won't leave you alone with
that man
I will speak to him, I promise
but I have to wait for the right moment
if Mother Superior finds out
we will be in trouble. Isabella, I am
doing this only for you.
You asked to speak to me, Sir.
I wanted to see you again.
Speak, I don't have much time.
I am dying. No, not because of my
injury.
Your hands worked a miracle. I am
dying of loneliness.
Sister Veronica told me of your request
what you ask is impossible.
Impossible is a cruel word and you are
not cruel, I am sure.
Do you know why I asked for a room in
the convent?
We will do our best to treat you here as
well.
It is not that, it is to be next to you.
Sir, I will not tolerate your language any
further.
No, please, do not get me wrong,
danger lurks out there
and I am the only one who can protect
the convent.
Our fate is in God's will.
There is no wealth here to attract
criminals
other than a few silver candlesticks in
the chapel.
You have more than that, Mother. Your
virtues, for example.
What do you mean?
I mean, I am a man, and you, under the
vest, you are a woman.
Sir
No, be honest, why did you asked the
gardener to leave?
You wanted us to remain alone?
How dare you?
Mother
Are you Ok?
Please don't leave me, I need you ...
I need to feel your body
Leave me, please
No, do not resist
I need to feel your body against mine.
Leave me
Do not say what you are not feeling in
your heart.
Calm down, I won't hurt you.
Mother, Sister Marta.
Help me.
Leave her, are you crazy, come Mother
let's get out of here.
Sister Marta, is that you?
Isabella!
I understand your surprise.
I know whom you were waiting for.
I bet the Superior doesn't imagine
what is happening in this bed
is that right Sister Lacinia?
Think what would happen if she found
out?
No, please, please, don't tell her
I won't do it again, I swear
What do I are of your repentance? I will
not say anything.
Thank you, you have my eternal
gratitude.
Sister Lacinia, you have to prove me it
to me.
Anything, ask me anything.
I want you to bring a message to that
man.
That's impossible.
It is impossible for me but not for you,
they keep an eye on me.
I was hoping that Sister Marta would
help me, but she won't.
So you'll do it. You have to, otherwise I
will speak.
Sister Lacinia.
Sister Marta, I don't ...
No, don't say anything, I know why you
are here
does it still hurt?
Yes, it is all burning.
A purifying burn, Sister that will keep
hellfire away.
Thank you Sister Marta
when you touch me the pain vanishes.
That's because I love you, sister.
Because you are the sweetest
and I want to rescue you from desire
and sin.
Sister Consolata, wake up, the devil is
here, in the convent.
Mother, hurry up.
Sister Veronica, what's happened?
Speak.
Sacrilegious, Mother, in the church,
hurry up.
What's happened?
Hurry up, look, over there, by the altar,
look.
No, no, look here he is again, look.
Lord help us.
Oh God.
Lord.
Sister Marta, is terrible,
we are all victims of a nightmare or God
has abandoned us.
That was not a hallucination, Mother. .
We have all seen those Sacrilegious
images
I have to face the facts, Sister Marta.
I don't know what we did wrong
but we have to get rid of this curse.
What you want to do, Mother?
I will call Padre Arnaldo, the exorcist.
Please go to the Abbey and ask for him.
With his help, God willing
we will restore calm and serenity in the
convent.
I will speak to the cardinal
I will give back the authority he gave
me
and I will refer you, Sister Marta, as
worthy to succeed in this ...
What are you saying, Mother? I am not
worthy.
Please, obey, you will leave at dawn.
But be careful, Sister Marta
I would not forgive myself if something
were to happen to you.
Thank you Mother.
I will walk through the hills to avoid any
nasty experience.
You can leave, Sister Marta. I am going
to pray.
Countess Isabella is waiting for you.
Here.
Tell her I will be there in one hour.
I will wait for everyone to be asleep.
Remember, second aisle, first door to
the left.
First door, thank you sister. One
moment
You see? It looks like the unknown god
is spying on us.
Do you also know the legend?
The convent was built on top of pagan
temple ruins
and this angered him
and lots of things have happened over
the centuries:
fires, pestilences, plunder.
I am an artist, I make sculptures and I
came over here to see him.
I had heard it was a masterpiece
but it is more than that. It seems alive,
cruel
with a terrifying strength. Look at its icy
eyes.
Leave me please.
Can it be the devil?
You gave an idea, my old friend, the
devil.
They will be so scared nobody will try to
stop me.
Yes.
So, how did it go, tell me.
He will come in one hour.
How is he?
He is handsome like an angel.
No, it is not what I asked.
Did you tell him what I want from him?
Yes, of course and he will help.
Was he honest? I mean, is he really a
gentleman?
How stupid, how can you tell if he is a
gentleman or not?
There was something, though ...
What? Tell me.
The way he looks at you
there is an evil gleam in his eyes, false
it scares you, like the eyes of the
unknown god.
If he does not help, it will be the end for
me.
Please, no, no.
Don't be stupid.
For me? Oh, it is wonderful but I can't.
Why? I want to prove to you
that I am your friend and I am not as
proud as you think.
Thank you, I have never seen
something so beautiful
but I cannot accept
the Rule forbids us to own anything, it
would be a sin.
It would be if you were already a nun
but you are not, like me.
When I get out of here, you will come
with me. Think Giulia.
In my palace, as my lady and my friend.
You would have beautiful dresses
jewelry like this one. Men will court you.
No, please.
Do not lie, I know that you want it.
Listen to me, you will do something for
me, for both of us.
At your service countess. Or sister if
you prefer.
My name is Guido Bencio, but you
should know that
since you asked for my help.
It seems like they are holding you
prisoner. You don't talk?
I understand, you don't trust me.
It is normal, you don't know me, but I
myself have to trust you.
It is a great risk, a kidnapping and a
sacrilege
means ending up on the gallows...
and I do are about my neck,
unless the stakes are worth the risk.
Let me see. Is this my price?
I have to admit it is a beautiful piece of
jewelry
but it is not enough.
There is another gem that could
convince me to take a risk:
your beauty.
You have to give if you want to receive
and you have a lot to offer.
You can't.
Finally I hear your voice. They told me
you were a tiger
but you tremble like a lamb.
No please.
Free us from temptation,
deliver us from evil.
Let's go.
I am Isabella di Lignate.
You?
Yes, and I am not the whore you think I
am
ready to rub myself against the first
man.
That's too bad, although I doubt this is
true.
And now that we have introduced
ourselves
could you explain what this game is
about?
I wanted to be sure that I could trust
you.
So?
You are a dirty, insolent man.
More, I am a sinner and a heartless
man.
Are you on sale?
Yes, it is only a matter of price.
Someone is coming.
Hurry up.
You know where to look for me.
The devil, Lord save us.
Go back to your cell
not a word about what's happened or
you will regret it.
The same for you.
Jesus, why do I have to see such things
at my old age.
How can you not believe in the
unknown god's curse.
Shut up, Sister Veronica. You are
cursing?
Hurry up, Sister Marta
I hope that pious man will purge the
devil out.
Praise the Lord.
Amen.
What is that nun doing in the forest?
I don't' know.
Is she taking a walk?
What is she doing then?
Maybe she is going to the village.
What should we do?
Maybe the man that ran away told them
about us
and she is bringing the money to the
village.
Don't move sister, don't scream or I'll
kill you.
Is she dead?
No, let's move her out of the path and
search her.
She is heavy.
Of course, nuns eat every day, not like
us.
They eat well.
Here is fine, let's see what she has.
There is nothing here, no money.
Nice tits.
Let's see what she has in here
she is like any other woman
not bad.
Look at her legs
Tell me, have you ever screwed a nun?
When I was with the Squinter we
screwed the whole convent.
Let's look how she is down there.
She is a virgin.
Really?
She is a virgin, a virgin.
She must be a recent nun.
We really have to fuck her, or it will be
bad for our reputation.
You are right.
You fucked the whole convent so I go
first...
Leave me.
Stop.
Stop or it will hurt.
Be quiet, hold her.
Hold her, let me do it.
Be quiet, don't scream.
Be quiet, here, take this.
Be quiet, we are not killing you,
take this
a bit more, like that
Come here.
Leave me, leave me.
Don't let her go, follow her.
I can't.
Let her go, she is going crazy.
Follow her, go.
Sister, you are saying that those
infernal apparitions
started with the arrival of the young
lady.
Yes, maybe they were called up by her
tormented soul.
If she was already
holding a sin in her heart
it was your duty to punish her
immediately.
Unfortunately, father, it is hard to realize
how weak charity and piety can be
sometimes.
That's why Satan wins.
We have to be strong in front of sin.
I am the only one to blame for all this.
Do you think this is enough?
Mother Superior, your faith is a wall of
pride
You, with your foolish actions
you have allowed lust and sin to enter
this house of God
There is no doubt the devil is here in the
convent.
Even if there was any doubt
did you ask yourself why I was already
on my way to the convent?
That's true, Sister Marta never reached
the village to call you.
I had a feeling, it was the devil
challenging me, but I will win.
God be with you.
Shut up, Mother, you offended Him with
your actions
I believe the devil is using Isabella .
and he is also using the man
whom you imprudently offered asylum
Have you Mother, how can I say?
Fornicated with that man?
Sister, my sister
I feel guilty for what has happened to
you, forgive me
Maybe God was kind with you
granting you this madness
and letting you forget the men's cruelty.
For me, for all of us, it will be worse
we will have to pay for our sin day by
day
and maybe all our prayers would not be
enough.
Listen to me, whoever you are, I am not
scared of you.
I don't want others to pay for me
I am the one who is challenging you
take me if you can, unknown God.
I will exorcize the whole convent
everybody has to remain in the cells
until I am done.
As you wish father, we will pray.
No prayers. That will be worse since
God is angry with you.
But father, we have to pray to ask for
forgiveness.
Do what I ordered, no discussion, now
you can leave.
Amen.
I trust in you God, to defeat the prince
of hell
here I am, beast, with God's help you
will soon be defeated.
So they believe that?
Trust me, the devil does not exist.
If he did he would not be worst than
men
The devil was fabricated by man
like religion or laws, to put a leash on
human nature.
You are not worried about your soul.
No, I have only one rule, take what you
like when you like.
Never put off till tomorrow the sin you
can do today.
Strange, you say you don't believe in
the devil
but you at like you have the devil in
you.
What? Don't tell me that a smart girl like
you
believes those things...
It's a question of name, definition, but
evil exists.
Here I am, Satan.
You will go back to hell defeated.
Who can win over the power of God's
army.
Because I am the Lord of the Universe,
evil will not prevail.
I am ordering you to return to hell, leave
the house of God.
It is exiting, but it is too risky, my
darling.
I've already slept with two nuns
to kidnap a third, a noble one, will be
too much
Governments like to hang a freethinker.
But tell me, have you decided...
To remain in the convent?
Absolutely not, I never had a all
although I was expecting something, a
feeling
but it has not happened.
What is it Signor Bencio?
Is it because you are not satisfied with
my offer?
I want you Isabella.
Help me.
You are so beautiful.
Come here.
Ceso, the cardinal will be here soon.
Where is the fruit?
It has happened again, it was him.
Ceso, when will you stop with those
superstitions?