CONVERSATION PIECE
Exquisite.
No other word for it.
Yes, without doubt.
- I'm sorry, let me move these...
- Really, it's not necessary.
Actually, I'd like to see the veranda.
Please, be my guest.
I'm afraid it's a bit untidy.
- I'll accompany you.
- Don't worry, I'll manage.
- Well, Professor?
- It really is exquisite, but...
- I can't.
- It's a reasonable price, Professor.
Last year at Sotheby's, you paid...
£3,000 Sterling, not a penny more.
Come now, Professor,
I made a bid of £3,500 myself.
- I can show you the receipt, if you like.
- No, please. I'll take your word.
I am quite surprised though.
In any case, my congratulations.
Still, you must admit,
prices have risen considerably
since last year.
Only yesterday,
I received a request for...
Anyone here?
Excuse me.
- May I ask a favor?
- Certainly, madam.
We'll leave it here
and you can think about it.
I've already thought about it.
The price is too high and...
it's not the right moment.
The taxes...
The apartment needs some work.
Bring it away.
I don't want the responsibility.
Don't worry yourself,
but would you do us a favor?
We have to look at some
paintings in a villa on Via Cassia,
and these days one can't just
leave it in the car.
Could we leave it here
and collect it this evening?
If you don't, I'll send it back myself.
I won't be buying it.
I'm still hoping
you'll change your mind.
We'll see ourselves out, Professor.
We know the way.
- I hope to see you soon.
- Thank you and good day.
Goodbye.
- It'd be a shame to let this one go.
- I won't be changing my mind.
- Goodbye.
So they finally left!
Yes, just this minute.
Good.
Not to be rude, but...
are you the owner of the painting?
- What? Goodness no!
- No?
Are you sure it's worth all that money?
What a slimy pair!
Are they stolen art dealers?
Stolen art!
They're from the Blanchard Gallery in Paris.
But...
Weren't you with them?
No, I only met them in the elevator.
- So to what do I owe this pleasure?
- Your housekeeper told me
that the apartment above is empty.
I want to rent it.
- Rent it?
- Yes.
It's not for rent.
I've no space here,
I intend to use it as a library.
Now, Professor, I've had a good look
in the hallways and storage areas.
You've got plenty of space down here.
And what's more:
You wouldn't have any problem
if you got some modern bookcases.
Thank you for the advice,
but I'd rather...
My husband,
who has never read a book in his life,
and I'm sure of that,
fills every single room with books.
Complete foolishness, if you ask me.
He had some bookcases made,
and not those horrible metallic ones,
but made out of cherry-wood,
and they can hold a lot of books.
I don't want new bookcases,
and the apartment's not for rent.
At least let me see it.
- See what?
- The apartment.
I might not like it,
and that'd be the end of it.
It'll only take a few minutes
and you needn't budge.
Your housemaid can show me.
Her name's Erminia, isn't it?
Erminia!
She told me she's been working
for you for twenty five years.
You're a lucky man.
Erminia.
Erminia!
- The Professor has very kindly...
- The keys to the upstairs apartment.
Straight away, Professor.
Not to be rude,
but you really are wasting your time.
Yes, I understand.
I'd just like to have a look.
I've been looking at
those windows up there for years.
I often park in Piazza Campitelli
when I come into town.
Parking has become nearly impossible.
It's another reasons why I'm looking
for a place in the center.
I live ten miles from Rome now.
- Well?
- Oh, darling.
- My daughter, Lietta.
- Hi.
For that matter, excuse me,
I'm Bianca Brumonti.
- Your coat, Professor.
- What have you been doing all this time?
Let's go up.
- Keep quiet. It's complicated.
- Okay.
- Nice up here.
- Remind me to ask Stefano
if he knows of the Blanchard Gallery.
I think they're thieves.
The Blanchard Gallery, it's as famous
as Christie's or Sotheby's.
But they'd probably rob you blind as well!
I won't open the windows,
they're barred up.
As I already said, I'm in a hurry.
Lietta, help me.
- Really, madam, I just said...
- Don't worry, I'll close them again.
It's just to get an idea.
Besides, it's so musty in here.
Perfect! You're a genius, Bianca.
It's stupendous!
Don't get excited.
He won't give it to us.
- What do you mean?
- He's keeping it for the mice and bats.
- He just wants more money.
- Think so?
Actually, that's not the case.
Mom, come and see.
Why can't we have it
if it's for rent?
From the very start
I told your mother it wasn't for rent.
Your mother insisted on seeing it.
He's not my son. Thank heavens!
They say he's his parents' son.
Bianca, get your ass down here fast!
Come on, you'll enjoy yourself.
Why is Konrad here?
Pardon me.
I can't see him.
I saw him.
Why did he stay down there?
I don't know.
He said he couldn't come with me
because he had to meet you.
Meet me?
I was there when he said
he'd come to collect you.
Oh, I must have misunderstood him.
Sorry about this.
Let me, you'll get all dirty.
I told you I'd close up.
A tow truck is bringing your car away.
- Couldn't you have stopped them?
- You never let me have the keys.
You ungrateful...
Can I see this luxury brothel?
Don't be an idiot.
Lietta, Stefano, see if you can
catch up with that tow truck.
Miss, is Mr. Blanchard there?
Yes, it's me.
Blanchard, is my doorman still there?
The one who brought the painting.
That's a shame,
because now one of your men
will have to come here.
I've changed my mind. I'll buy it.
Sold?
How? When?
Micheli, the lawyer.
- Come in, Micheli.
- Sorry for disturbing you.
Not at all.
Please, take a seat.
What are you doing there?
Here I am.
Yesterday evening I had a call from
Marquise Brumonti, whom you know.
I met her but I don't know her.
She's of no interest to me.
I hope that's not why you're here.
Careful, Professor,
don't say anything you'll regret.
Tell me you like it
or I'll have a stroke.
We bought it.
Where should I put it?
- Are they with you?
- We won him over!
As I was saying, yesterday evening
I had a call from Marquise Brumonti
- with a proposal of considerable...
- A proposal?
Yes, and as your lawyer it's my duty to
hear all serious proposals,
- as well as advise you on any...
- Micheli, don't beat around the bush.
It's our fault.
Listen, Professor, I know how you feel.
I know mom can be invasive,
but you simply can't say no.
Just for one year.
You'd let us have it for free
if you knew what it meant to us.
Perhaps Mrs. Brumonti didn't tell you,
she only wants the apartment
for one year.
Since you weren't planning to turn it
into a library before spring,
- I thought it would be an idea...
- No.
No. I'm sorry.
Rome is full of luxury houses
that would suit people like you.
But mom always invents excuses
not to see them.
From what the Marquise told me,
her daughter, the young lady here,
is engaged to...
Stefano and I are just dating.
Mom agreed that I can live here
with Konrad and Stefano.
Who is this Konrad?
He was with us yesterday, Professor.
The apartment is for him.
You're extraordinarily frank,
young lady.
And I'll answer you frankly.
I'm in no hurry to transfer
my library upstairs.
I'm an old man.
Neurotic, perhaps even hysterical.
I get disturbed by strange noises
and strange people.
I shy away from any sort of formality.
That's why I don't want
to rent the apartment.
You're neither old nor hysterical.
You're interesting, and you know it.
Maybe you're a little crazy,
like all interesting people.
But at least your craziness
is for things like this painting.
Don't tell me you no longer like it.
- He called Blanchard when we were there.
- Yes, I forgot.
Mom was right, that dealer's a thief.
He asked us for much less.
- You weren't meant to tell him!
- Why not?
The Professor should know he's a crook.
Those two tried to rip him off
because he's a collector.
We're even, Professor.
This is our three-month deposit.
Well, Professor,
shall we make these young people happy?
A one year contract.
What's going on?
Oh God!
Please God, help me.
Help me, God. Help me!
What's going on?
Are you mad?
The ceiling's falling down.
Domenico, Domenico!
Is anyone down there?
- Good evening, Professor.
- Good evening, Erminia.
What happened here?
I nearly went out of my mind.
You should take a look
in the kitchen too.
It's a good thing you dined out,
I couldn't even boil an egg in there.
It's soaked.
It's better since they
shut the water off.
I've never seen such madness.
It was like the war.
As though we were being bombed again.
I called Micheli, the lawyer,
but he wasn't in.
They wouldn't answer the door.
I wanted to call the police,
but Domenico said not to.
He told me to wait for you.
Would you stop chattering!
Bring me the keys to upstairs.
And a flashlight.
- It's in ruins!
- Call Micheli, the lawyer.
Who's there?
Mauro, is that you?
My house is full of rubble.
Water's running down the walls!
After what you've done it's a wonder
the building's still standing.
This madness is unforgivable!
So is your entering here,
silently, like a thief.
I could shoot you.
I am glad to still be alive
to hear your justification for this.
I do what I want in my house.
You said work could start,
even if the contract hasn't been signed.
The redecoration of one bathroom
is the only thing in the contract.
A contract which now I will not sign.
I do, however,
intend to claim for damages.
Excuse me, but that rental contract
is nothing but a piece of paper.
- The sales contract will be in my name.
- Sales contract?
It simply proves that
the painting was a sales deposit.
It's a one year rental contract,
and it's non-renewable!
- Can I make a phone call?
- A phone call?
So you can clear this matter up with
Mrs. Brumonti in my presence.
As you wish.
There's no way that Mrs. Brumonti
can support your claim.
- Did you call Micheli?
- The lawyer wasn't at home,
but I left a message for him
to call you immediately.
Thank you.
Could I have a whiskey?
Straight, please.
- I don't have any spirits.
- Not even...
I do it all the time.
I call the house in London
instead of Paris.
You can add this call
to your claim for damages.
Do you really have no whiskey,
or don't you want to give me any?
- There's wine, if you want some.
- I'm glad you're not a teetotaler.
Some red wine, please.
So, it's you!
Well, you ugly bitch,
what's this latest trick?
No bullshit, or I'll get really mad.
What's this trick about?
The fucking apartment, my dear.
The apartment, you whore!
I'll clear this up.
Actually, here's someone else
to clear it up with.
Hello, how dare you ring me like this,
you ungrateful shit!
- I'll tear you...
- Madam, it's the Professor.
May I talk? Yes, but...
- Hello?
- Pass me Konrad!
- Please, madam...
- And quit your lies!
Look here, I don't tell lies!
- My lawyer will be in touch with you.
- Wait, Professor, I'm sorry.
Please, Professor,
it was a misunderstanding.
I'll come straight to Rome
and clear this up.
It's all that bastard's fault.
I can explain everything.
Shame I won't hear your explanation.
You thought I'd be good for another year,
but you were wrong.
From this moment it's over,
Madam Marquise of Shit!
Bitch!
- Is that all right?
- Dreadful, thanks.
Goodnight, Erminia.
Well, now this is over too.
I don't like to interfere
in other people's business.
And besides, I haven't quite understood...
You understand, Professor,
the richer they are
the worse they are.
Do you know what it's like
to be vulgar on the inside?
Goodness, what happened in here?
This is nothing.
You should see the rest of the apartment.
Sue them and you'll get
millions in damages.
Trust me, millions.
When did this record come out?
I was sent it from New York,
it has just been released.
It has Mozart's wonderful aria,
"Vorrei spiegarvi, oh Dio!"
I've wanted to hear it for some time.
May I?
I never get around to going to concerts.
However, records...
It's better like that.
I love Mozart.
I have to make a call, excuse me.
I was expecting a friend upstairs and...
It's Konrad, who's there?
What about Mauro?
No, tell him not to come.
I might pass by.
Okay.
Just one minute.
Jane?
Who else would it be?
Still going to St. Moritz tomorrow?
Try to manage.
If you go, I'll go too.
I'm all by myself.
Arthur Devis.
No, nothing.
Listen, I'll call you later. Bye.
That's by Arthur Devis, isn't it?
It's definitely by an 18th century
English painter.
Some friends of mine
have an Arthur Devis.
A landscape with figures.
I've studied it well.
Yes.
It might well be.
In the center of my friends' painting,
not at the side,
there's the same monument.
What's more, this was painted...
- around the middle of the 18th century.
- I'll bring you a photo of it.
- Are you interested in art?
- No, not really.
But I know that painting intimately.
It's beside the telephone.
Who's that, Marcello?
Who's there?
Who else?
If she's there.
What are you doing later?
No, I've had enough scams for today.
I'll tell you tomorrow. Bye.
It's a strange house.
I don't like it,
but it has enchanted me.
Don't get up. I know the way.
It's a shame things ended like this.
I would have enjoyed chatting
with you now and again.
- Goodnight, Professor.
- Goodnight.
You should unplug the telephone
if you want some peace.
Sooner or later,
Mrs. Brumonti will call.
She's a real ball-breaker.
I don't want to talk to your lawyer.
These things don't interest me.
You're right, so what?
I didn't take
the overnight flight from Paris,
full with Arabs, to tell you
they were wrong to knock down a wall.
You call this knocking down a wall?
My dear, Professor,
your behavior is disgraceful.
I had my reasons for not telling him
the truth about the contract.
You had no right to interfere!
But since you did,
it must have been for a reason.
Perhaps you are protecting
Mr. Huebel's interests.
What do you mean?
I'm not protecting anyone's interests.
And certainly not Mr. Huebel's,
whom I don't even know!
You don't know him?
Well, I'll tell you.
He's my gigolo, my kept lover.
Want to know how much
I spend on him a month?
How awful to be reduced to this.
Mom!
- When did you arrive?
- Poor brainless idiot!
Now you can put
everything back as it was.
But I...
- only did what you asked.
- Everything as it was before.
I want to talk to you.
- Where's Konrad?
- I haven't seen him.
We called into number 74 yesterday,
but it was quite late.
Mauro said Konrad was going to St. Moritz
for a few days, while you were in Paris.
- Didn't you tell him you were coming?
- No.
I decided in a hurry,
I jumped on the first plane.
- Why?
- Don't you know?
That idiot told him
I hadn't bought the apartment,
so now I'll have to buy it.
The Professor will never sell it,
isn't that right, Professor?
What advice can I give you?
Your mother's hysterics
have nothing to do with me.
I've no interest in people
who can't control their own actions.
Any opinion of mine would be...
as futile as the drama
you're trying to involve me in.
I'm simply not interested!
Lf, as you say...
the lawyers have
already signed the contract,
and you put everything back as it was,
at your expense,
then you can keep the apartment.
But if you don't want it
I will reimburse you for the painting,
immediately.
You decide,
and then leave me in peace.
Okay, we made a mistake,
but you seemed so understanding...
Don't make another mistake.
I promise we won't mention
our family problems again.
Now you can tell Stefano
what you want done upstairs,
but don't forget about
the second bathroom,
and that it should be twice the size
of the one that's...
Why are you laughing, Professor?
It's as if we spoke
two different languages.
- We can never understand one another.
- And that's funny?
Tragically so.
I must be completely out of touch.
I want to show you
the new plans for the apartment.
The walls marked in yellow
are those we want to knock down.
Let's see, so...
- Can I make a call?
- Yes, over there.
This here...
This here is all right.
This too.
No, you can't do this.
Doesn't it work?
- It's unplugged.
- What?
- The telephone.
- It's been like that since yesterday.
No wonder you're out of touch.
- I'm not complaining.
- But it surprises you.
Jane, how are you?
I thought you were going to St. Moritz.
Who wanted to go with you?
Jane, are you kidding me!
Everyone knows Konrad's a whore.
Stefano, he didn't go.
I really hate him,
as soon as I see him...
Darling,
whose bed did you fall out of?
- Where were you yesterday evening?
- I was here.
- Listening to music.
- Here?
Why didn't you tell me?
Mom's back, did you know?
- You fought, didn't you?
- No, I've left her.
She's hysterical.
She took a night flight.
I was at my friends' place
and got a photograph.
Take a look.
Interesting.
We'll continue this later.
Very interesting.
It's hard to see well in a photo.
It's not just the landscape.
It's also the technique.
The trees are different...
Sorry!
From other painters of that period.
I'm impressed.
Did you study art history?
I studied it at university for a while.
Why did you quit?
Those were difficult years.
It was '68.
I became part of the student movement
and got into trouble.
So I came here.
And got mixed up with these people.
There's no doubt about it.
Congratulations.
Why didn't I think of it?
Of all my paintings that one has the
most complete documentation. Come.
Konrad is here.
He said you didn't fight.
- He didn't tell me anything.
- Why would he tell you?
Mom, we'll talk later.
I told mom you're not offended,
so now she's offended.
- Call her, what'll it cost you?
- I've finished with her!
- But you said you didn't fight.
- I'm still finished with her!
- So she'll buy you the apartment.
- Tempting, but I'm not interested.
Sure!
Listen, be nice and...
Do something,
I don't want to see her like this.
- Professor?
- What?
- Professor, you talk to him...
- No, thank you.
I need some air. Clear air.
You won't find it with Jane.
Lietta told me that...
Mind your own business!
Where are you going?
To see Bobby in Fiumicino.
Great, I'm coming too.
Maybe we can go sailing.
He's a friend who ordered a yacht.
It was meant to be delivered in June,
instead, he only got it now.
Konrad, you're a genius.
- Let's get going. So you're staying here?
- To do what?
Take care of the house.
Besides, if mom needs someone?
Listen, can't you call her?
And it's better if the Professor
talks to the engineer.
- That way there'll be no more mistakes.
- If you're coming, get a move on.
Keep the photo, and just ask if
you want to see the painting.
- Let's go, Lietta.
- First, a quick call.
No, I'll call from the bar downstairs.
I'm starving.
- I'm not waiting, I'm already late.
- But I've cramps.
Professor, could I have a bit of bread?
Konrad, I'll be there in a second.
- Erminia?
- Get a move on, Lietta!
Come this way.
- What can I offer you?
- Stefano, Konrad, come and see!
- The Professor has hidden treasure.
- Stefano, bring your car too.
- I might stay in Fiumicino.
- Are you really leaving Bianca?
Listen, I want to be free.
I have things planned.
In Fiumicino?
Asshole!
- Want a drop, Stefano?
- Yes, please.
- Some glasses, please?
- At once.
This salami is quite spicy.
I'm certain you'll like it.
I'm sure I will, thanks.
Can I have some cheese too?
Need some help?
- Erminia, get the door, please.
- I'll go. You stay here.
Professor, do me a favor.
Send them away!
- Can I have a taste?
- No, it's not ready yet.
A little patience, Stefano.
Erminia isn't used to all this confusion.
Neither is he, he doesn't even
like hearing my footsteps.
You're a son of a bitch.
He didn't want to rent it,
but I persuaded him to.
He didn't want it,
but we're doing work on it.
I could have persuaded him to sell it.
But you thought you'd be clever
and you ruined everything!
You're suspicious, pathetic and mean!
I'm ashamed of everything I've done for you!
You make me ashamed of myself.
I'll never forgive you, never!
- Where are you going? Come back!
- Let go of me!
I don't care about your apartments,
but don't make fun of me by
pretending to give me presents.
You're hurting me.
Let me go, you're crazy!
Let me go!
- Shout, what are you waiting for?
- Yes!
Professor, I've decided that
you're coming to Fiumicino too.
We'll come back this evening
and have dinner together.
We'll eat Erminia's stew
and decide about the work upstairs.
- Mom!
- That sounds great to me.
- I'm sure Erminia is a wonderful cook.
- She's fantastic!
Stew and what else?
- Stew and artichokes.
- Perfect.
- So, shall we go?
- Go where, darling?
To see Bobby's yacht in Fiumicino.
The Professor's coming too.
With this breeze today
the sea will be lovely.
The sea is always wonderful.
Its colors.
Its voices, the sounds it makes.
I've never understood
how the Greek artists
were able to concentrate
and create such marvelous forms
with such a spectacular,
fascinating spectacle before their eyes.
- Just the thought of it bewitches me.
- So you're coming with us?
- Not a chance.
- Why not?
Don't insist.
The Professor doesn't want distractions.
He likes to be alone.
You know that.
People say it's better to be alone,
but it's not true.
He does live alone though.
The truth, Professor:
What's the secret in your life?
I think you...
were once a really handsome man.
You still are.
I find you very interesting.
How come...
Why do you live your life like this?
Living amongst other men...
forces one to think about men,
instead of their works of art.
You become involved with them,
you suffer because of them.
Somebody once wrote:
"Crows fly in flocks,
the eagle soars alone."
- Well, you wanted to know.
- Let's get going, crows!
See you for dinner
this evening, Professor,
- See you later.
- Goodbye.
But in the Bible it's written:
"Woe to him who is alone when he falleth,
for he hath not another to help him up."
Konrad, the Bible!
- Thank you, Professor.
- See you this evening.
Erminia?
- Tidy this up.
- Yes, at once.
They haven't arrived yet.
Maybe it's a misunderstanding.
They would have rung
if they thought they'd be late.
They're so refined and well-educated.
They're not as refined as you think.
They're empty, stupid.
More than anything else, useless.
I'm going to eat.
I'm not waiting another minute.
As you wish, Professor.
- Good morning, Professor.
- Good morning.
- These are the samples.
- Yes, the samples.
I haven't heard from them
in over twenty days.
- We're wasting time with all these...
- It's your decision.
The house is yours.
You can do whatever you want.
I could decide about the walls,
but these...
- I need a decision, Professor.
- Immediately?
- Yes.
- All right then.
Let me take a look.
For the kitchen...
- I'd say this would go well.
- Yes, that's a nice color.
Yes, this color for the walls.
Professor?
Professor? Open up,
we have something for you.
We won't even come in.
Just open the door.
Just for a second. It's a surprise.
We can't tell you what it is.
Professor, be nice and open up.
- It's a surprise.
- Never mind them, Professor.
See you in the morning.
Goodnight.
I'll open up at once.
Hi, Professor,
we brought you a present.
- It's wonderful upstairs.
- You worked a miracle, Professor.
We'll look better tomorrow.
Pity there aren't two more beds.
Professor?
- Do you still have my blanket?
- Blanket?
- Yes, it's where you left it.
- I'll get it.
This is Simone.
It's all he can say,
and he never quits.
That's why we got him.
I've never had a pet in the house.
Animals should live freely
in their natural environment.
If it annoys you, send it up to me,
I'll deal with him.
I've a score to settle.
It was in Konrad's cabin on the yacht,
and it drove him mad.
- You really should have come with us.
- You must be kidding, Lietta.
You were actually very lucky.
You'll have to keep it tonight.
In the morning...
Listen, young man,
I want a word with you.
I don't want a repeat
of the last time.
You were meant to discuss the plans
with me over a month ago.
Hey, come and see!
- I found the skeletons. He's a pirate.
- What are you talking about?
- Very nice.
- Very nice? It's ingenious!
- Was it here, or did you have it made?
- It was already here.
It helped a lot of people during the war.
There's nothing interesting to see.
It's just a room.
Let's go, Stefano.
My mother was Italian,
she was living here when war broke out.
She had it made
to hide political refugees,
Partisans, Jews.
I know very little about her
when she lived here.
She died before the war ended.
I was in America
and came here with the Army.
I've lived here since then.
We're going, Professor.
We're very tired.
Are you coming, Konrad?
I'll get my blanket.
I'm disappointed.
I was sure you'd like Simone.
Perhaps I will in time.
Okay, I'm ready.
Now I can sleep over your head again.
- But nobody must know! Understand?
- No.
- Bye. Goodnight, Professor.
- Goodnight.
Bianca thinks he left for Vienna.
A holiday after sharing a cabin
with her for a month.
Shut up, Stefano!
- Goodnight, Professor.
- Goodnight, Lietta.
Stefano.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Professor.
Who's there? Stop!
Good God!
What happened?
I'll call the police.
No, don't call anyone.
Mind your own business.
- Help me get out of here.
- All right.
I'll bring you downstairs.
No, don't move.
Try to stay calm.
- Where am I?
- In my house.
You fainted twice. I brought you down.
You're better now. I'll be right back.
I'll kill the bastards!
You'd better lie down.
Do you know who attacked you?
I...
No. Why?
Because it seemed...
I didn't even see them.
They surprised me.
I saw one of them.
I'd recognize him again.
- You asked me...
- What?
You insisted I didn't call the police.
I thought you knew who they were.
That it was part of a dispute.
- I wanted to be sure before calling.
- Wait, don't!
It's my duty to help you.
To call the police.
You don't have any duty.
And I don't want anything
to do with the police.
Besides they'll never find those bastards.
They won't even look for them.
They've enough death and madness
to deal with every day.
Murders, robberies, rapes,
strikes, demonstrations.
What do they care about my split lip?
Four lines of a report, and that's it.
A load of shit.
No, the police don't give a damn.
But there'd be some asshole reporter
who would recognize my name.
"Young man involved in love affair."
Yes, that's what they'd write.
"With Bianca Brumonti,
wife of well-known Fascist."
Understand how it would finish up?
It's better like this.
- And the blood?
- The blood?
- There must be blood upstairs.
- Don't worry, we'll clean it tomorrow.
I already told you,
nobody must know anything!
- Let me go.
- I'll sort it out, you stay here.
I'll clean it. You stay here.
Don't move.
- Can I at least call a doctor?
- Christ!
We must. What if you get worse?
No, nobody must know.
All right.
- Professor?
- Yes.
Can I stay here tonight?
I'm afraid to go back upstairs.
- Of course, you can stay here.
- Thank you.
I'll be back soon.
It's so humiliating to get beaten up.
At least you have your pride
if they kill you.
Like this, people will just laugh.
"Have you heard?
They finally taught
that asshole a lesson."
- Oh God!
- Do you want a sedative?
No. I never take them.
Professor, open up!
Why did you lock me in?
No. It's because Erminia rises early
to do the cleaning.
Sorry. My nerves are shot.
Leave it open. I feel trapped.
Don't close it.
Apart from everything else,
you must think I'm a coward too.
Have you ever been afraid?
Yes.
Yes, I've been afraid.
I was afraid during the war.
But there are worse fears to have.
For example, when I quit working.
The fear of not knowing
how to start a new life.
- What was your job?
- I was a scientist.
Strange, I thought you were
a science Professor when we first met.
- Once.
- Once?
The price of progress is destruction.
I began to realize that
modern science can't be neutral.
In its attempt to be useful
science has turned technology's
power to liberate into a kind of slavery.
And that the use of science...
in today's social reality...
So you're already here, filthy beast.
- So they're with the Professor?
- No.
Must have come yesterday evening.
Shut up. Annoying, isn't it?
- May I use the phone?
- I'll bring it out.
I'm sorry, we should have one soon.
Excuse me, Professor?
I came to get the telephone.
The lady from upstairs is waiting for it.
Did you sleep here all night, Professor?
No, I...
I woke up early and came in
to do some work,
- and I fell asleep.
- I'll get your breakfast ready.
Yes. But bring it in here, please.
- The telephone is in the drawing room.
- Thank you.
In my opinion, it's starving.
Erminia, may I have a coffee?
Good morning, Erminia.
I'm looking for Mrs. Brumonti.
I have a message for her
from Mr. Stefano.
Luigi, is that you?
I'm in the drawing room.
Good morning, madam.
Mr. Stefano is waiting downstairs.
Tell him I'll be right down.
Meanwhile he should
buy some food for the blackbird.
That's a funny looking blackbird.
Here they are. They've arrived!
Daniele, come quickly!
Hurry up!
- Sir, give me your bag.
- Luisa, look at you!
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Daniele, how are you?
- Fine, thank you, madam.
- Give me the bag, miss.
- Thank you.
Sorry, "madam".
Finally, our little American
boy has arrived.
He looks like you.
- Help us with these bags.
- At once.
Say something.
Come on, say hello to Luisa
Don't you like my house.
Smile for your mother.
He's shy, madam.
Leave it on the table.
Mrs. Brumonti requested a coffee.
May I give her one?
Certainly.
I slept 16 hours straight.
Why didn't you wake me?
You needed sleep.
Besides, if you had left
someone would have seen you.
When I awoke this morning
Mrs. Brumonti was here.
- Did she ask about me?
- No.
She came to use the phone.
Then she brought Erminia upstairs
to help her do something.
They were moving things all day.
- Does Erminia know I'm here?
- No.
She didn't realize anything.
The bird's on the balcony, Professor.
I covered the cage with a sheet.
Leave it in the kitchen.
It should be kept warm.
Why not give it to the doorman?
He likes it.
- I will return it to them.
- As you wish.
- Is there anything else?
- No, thank you.
- Goodnight, Erminia.
- Goodnight, Professor.
I have to tell you something, Professor.
I lied last night.
I know who attacked me, and why.
- I never doubted that.
- Ask me whatever you like.
I don't want to ask anything.
I'm not curious.
It'll hardly be noticeable.
Noticeable enough.
You can't wait
for me to go, can you?
In a way.
Okay.
Thank you for helping me.
I understand that you don't
want to get involved.
That has nothing to do with it.
I'm used to living alone, so...
another person in the house disturbs me,
prevents me from working.
I'll make a few calls
and might be able to leave tonight.
As you wish.
What I told you about myself,
my studies.
Well, that was the truth.
And now to get myself out of one mess,
I've landed myself in a worse one.
I wasn't always like this.
Once...
Shit!
I don't give a damn about
all the things I once believed in.
I didn't sleep all day.
I kept waking up.
I heard footsteps.
I imagined...
I thought about telling you about me.
- And to ask you for advice.
- I don't have any advice for you.
A man of your age and intelligence
should know what to do.
A clean break.
Sure! It's that simple.
If Erminia's in bed
I'll get you something to eat.
Then I'm going to bed myself.
Make all the calls you want to.
Close that door when you leave.
I'll tidy up tomorrow.
I want to tell you everything.
Tell me if it's my fault.
Believe me, only you can help me.
Hey, we woke him up.
"If you see a fair form,
"chase it,
and if possible embrace it!
"Be it a girl or a boy, don't be bashful,
be brash, be fresh.
"Life is short! So enjoy whatever contact
your flesh might at the moment crave,
"There is no sex life in the grave."
- What are you saying?
- You taught it to me.
Don't you remember?
They say it's Auden's last poem.
You know everything,
have you ever heard of it?
We brought your patient
some suitcases.
He's finally leaving for Munich.
- Clean breaks are never possible.
- What does that mean?
The Professor knows.
Not good enough,
I want to know too.
The Professor thinks
I should change my life.
The Professor expects too much.
- And what would you know?
- What would I know?
Stefano is envious,
the only bad Cardinal Sin.
One day you can tell me
why I'd be jealous of Konrad.
Yes, I'll tell you one day.
Poor Professor, still half-asleep.
We'll soon go.
See, this is just a game.
There's no harm in it, honestly.
You were once young.
- Weren't you like us?
- No.
Absolutely not.
Shame, you missed out!
But you must have had fun.
You were rich and handsome,
what did you do?
- What did I do?
- Yes.
I studied and travelled.
I fought in a war and I got married.
But it didn't work out.
And when I finally looked around,
I found myself in the middle
of people I no longer understood.
Come on, Professor,
We're not that different.
No, he's right.
Don't forget, society is what it is.
- It's the fault of...
- No, Konrad. Don't start!
I want to know all about
the Professor's private life.
- His past, present...
- Present.
- Presently I'm old.
- Professor, don't talk like that.
You have to believe that
you're still an attractive man.
I think you are.
- And if I wanted to kiss you?
- I wouldn't envy you.
If I were in your place,
I'd see before me...
the face of a man who...
hasn't been young for a long time.
- Quit it, you idiot.
- I'm serious.
I like him.
If he asked me, I'd marry him.
I won't ask.
I see myself as a
tragic character from a play.
The old man who is deceived
and made fun of.
King Lear is the only
true love story for me.
A father and his daughters.
You managed to avoid that problem.
No children, no tragedy.
The Professor would be
an extraordinary father.
Know what I'll do?
If one of these idiots gets me pregnant,
I won't get rid of it,
I'll keep it and give it to you.
I don't have much time left,
I'd need an older child,
- to tell them the few things I know.
- Konrad!
Why not adopt Konrad?
He's intelligent and beautiful.
Distinguished looking.
And if he stops getting
into trouble over money...
Konrad, let him adopt you.
Mind you, Professor,
he doesn't come cheap.
Tonight alone would have cost you
five million lire.
Poor Konrad, a gambling debt
from some backroom club.
That's why they smashed his face up.
We'll pay the debt off with money
from the building work upstairs.
Whether Bianca knows or not,
she's always the one who pays.
A gambling debt.
That wouldn't be so bad,
but it's not just that.
You see...
I'd better go if I want to be
in Munich tomorrow evening.
Your jacket's there, Stefano.
- We'll walk you to the car, Konrad.
- Thanks.
- Be quick though.
- Did he agree to adopt you?
Not yet, but I'm working on him.
It won't be easy.
Professor, tell your son
not to drive too fast.
You risk losing him
before adopting him.
And I risk losing my car.
Would you come to my funeral, Professor?
You'd be the only respectable person
in the whole funeral cortège.
All the whores of Rome
dressed in black.
- A catwalk of widows.
- Followed by a crowd of dealers,
- junkies and lesbians.
- And a delegation of queers.
- Excuse me, Professor?
- Yes.
- What is it, Domenico?
- These two men would like a word.
I don't have any appointments.
- They're police.
- Police?
Yes.
May we have a word, Professor?
I'm Inspector Bernai,
from the Campitelli Precinct.
We need some information,
if that's not a problem?
- I was about to go out...
- It'll only take a minute.
Does a Mr. Konrad Huebel
live in your house?
No.
- So you don't know Mr. Huebel?
- You asked if he lives in my house,
- and I told you no.
- Yes, but do you know him?
Yes, I've met him.
He was a guest of my upstairs tenants.
We'd appreciate it if you could call
into the precinct when it's convenient.
- But if I don't know...
- The commissioner will explain better.
Huebel claims to have spent the night
of 2nd February in your house,
and all the following day.
I'll go with you to the precinct.
- It's simply awful.
- Please, Mom.
- It makes me vomit!
- We need some color behind the sofa.
- Very expensive for some color!
- We paid the market valuation.
- Stefano's right.
- A classical painting would be perfect.
I'll go down to the Professor
and ask him for one of his.
Sure, keep annoying him.
Professor, what a surprise!
Did you come to take Erminia back?
Sorry, Professor, we've shamefully
taken advantage of her recently.
Erminia, there are things to do
downstairs if you've finished here.
You hate it, don't you?
You'll get used to it.
I let the kids choose everything
since they're going to live here.
Don't you think a classical painting
here would...
Did you know that Konrad
was stopped at the border?
- Stopped?
- By the police.
But when? Where?
Konrad's in Munich.
They took him to the airport
the day after our cruise.
He left by car last night,
but that's not important.
It is important because it's not true.
What's going on, Mom?
The Professor says Konrad left by car.
It's true. We didn't tell you
because you worry when he drives.
- Did he have an accident?
- He's been arrested.
I didn't say that.
They stopped him because...
they had some suspicions.
He gave my name as an alibi.
He told them he stayed
in my house for two days.
- It's all very disagreeable.
- Is it true he left last night?
Yes, he delayed leaving
to sort some things out.
But why all these secrets?
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Once again the whole lot of you
have treated me dreadfully!
You too, Professor!
I did no such thing.
I simply allowed him to be my guest.
How nice of you, Professor!
You wouldn't happen to be
another victim of Konrad's charm?
- What does that mean?
- Exactly what I said.
Mom, quit it!
Just because Konrad stayed here two days
and didn't tell you, it's no reason to...
Shut up, you idiot!
She's only clever when she's making up
excuses to stay out all night.
Didn't you hear?
They arrested him.
Why?
What did he do when he was here?
- Can't you see how worried I am?
- No, you're jealous.
You want to know his every movement.
Give him some space.
Everyone needs a day off.
- Quit it!
- Professor,
- why was Konrad staying with you?
- It's not my place to tell you.
I didn't even tell the police,
something which wasn't easy.
I'm not used to concealing things.
They may still search both apartments.
They're looking for drugs.
I hadn't realized
that the police possess
a long list, let's call it,
regarding Konrad Huebel.
We already knew that, he told us.
Konrad has a record because he
was in the Berlin student movement.
- Such nonsense!
- You're unfair.
You know he was arrested.
He was committed to the cause.
Sure, he was only at the barricades
to get close to a little bitch,
whose father just happened to be
one of the richest men in Berlin.
Konrad's able to do anything
to get what he wants,
- it doesn't matter what the cause is.
- You love putting him down.
I might be infatuated with Konrad,
but I know who he is
and what he gets up to.
Know why he didn't
get off the yacht in Cannes?
If he sets foot in France
they'll throw him straight in jail!
I'm horrified, appalled.
What kind of people are you?
You entrust your daughter to someone
for whom you have absolutely no respect?
I've never entrusted her to him!
They live together, in this house.
Mom exaggerates, Konrad isn't so bad.
It's not fair to judge him from this.
I'm not judging anyone.
Konrad could be a saint for all I know,
unfairly accused.
What disgusts me is that you consider
him to be an immoral good-for-nothing,
yet you entrust him with your daughter
and force him onto your friends!
My friends are all vaccinated,
don't you worry, Professor.
And Lietta's not in any danger.
That's not what I saw in my house,
but let's not get into that.
- It's my duty to warn you, in case...
- In case I'm deluded?
No, I'm not deluded!
That would be the
only possible justification.
We have nothing else to say to one another.
The lady told me that you had agreed
for me to help her sometimes.
You may help them if you wish.
I don't ever want to see them again.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I had no idea.
You weren't very nice to grandpa.
He's so happy to have you here.
He's usually all alone.
It's not nice being alone
when you're old and sick.
Alone?
He's not alone.
He has a cook and a maid,
and even a cat.
I don't even have a cat.
Erminia, go upstairs at once.
- Tell those people to be quiet!
- Yes, Professor.
- Hello?
- Is that you, Professor?
- Yes.
- I hope we didn't disturb you.
You've disturbed me plenty.
- Will you turn that music down, please?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Professor?
- Yes?
- You know we have a telephone now?
Obviously, since you called me.
I'll give you our number: 676013.
- 676013.
- You can call if you need anything.
Did you write it down?
Yes, I did.
Hello?
Sorry for bothering you, Professor,
but you didn't answer my letter?
- Letter?
- Yes.
- I didn't receive any letter.
- Didn't you see it?
I slipped it under your door earlier.
- Very well.
- I'd like it if you answered it.
Something told me you wouldn't have
answered, so I came down myself.
It's an invitation.
Konrad's back and we wanted
to throw a big house-warming party.
Then we changed our minds,
it's just us and a few friends.
We'll just listen to some music,
dance and chat.
- Do you want to come?
- Thank you, but I have...
You know Konrad had nothing to do
with that business before?
- Yes, I know.
- You said some dreadful things to us.
- You really upset me.
- I know I lost my temper.
- I shouldn't have.
- You were right to.
But it's true that mom doesn't know
that much about Konrad's life,
neither do we.
Poor Konrad!
He'd do anything for some money,
gambling, getting into trouble.
The one time he won a lot
he spent it all on a present for mom.
You know, he was so proud to know
an important person like you.
Perhaps once he had ambitions
we don't know about.
Anyway, it'd make everyone very happy
if you came upstairs for a minute.
Just for a minute.
No.
Because of that infamous evening?
Try to forget about it.
I'm the one who mustn't forget.
It won't happen again, I promise.
- Will you come up?
- No, I...
I'm working.
If you like, you can come here
for dinner tomorrow evening.
At nine o'clock.
Is this wine from your land?
Where exactly?
Tuscany, near Arezzo.
It's good.
Come now, Professor,
we're nearly finished, then we'll go.
You're not in good form.
I bet you didn't want to invite us.
- Lietta forced you to.
- No, it's not true.
No, it was my idea.
So, how come you've hardly said a word?
We're all a bit down.
It's all these troubles
that are in the news.
It's the same everywhere.
Today I was at home for breakfast
for the first time in a while.
It was a mistake.
Father's workers have been
on strike for over a week,
and he wasn't speaking to my brother.
He just sat there in silence
at the head of the table,
like you, Professor.
But you don't have any striking workers,
or a son...
who pretends to be a Marxist.
You only have happy, calm,
characters surrounding you,
without any problems.
Do you like all of them?
I have my favorites,
and my infidelities.
For a long time I favored
the Sitwell Family.
I even brought them into my bedroom,
but we experienced some difficulties.
I quarreled with the eldest daughter.
The tall one in the corner.
And who will you fight with
in your new family?
Which family? This one?
I'll fight with all of you.
I already have!
But we made up again.
We're here now, aren't we?
The elderly are strange creatures.
Didn't you know?
Argumentative and intolerant.
Sometimes they're frightened by
the Ioneliness they wished for,
other times they defend it
when it's threatened.
It was during one
of these brief crises...
that I invited you here this evening.
But by the time we came
the crisis had already passed.
You really should try to change.
Really, Professor,
your solitude is over.
We really like it here,
and you'll have us at this table a lot.
- And mom will complete our little family.
- So I'm part of this family too?
- Mom!
- Please, Professor, don't get up.
Of course you're part of it.
We just formed it:
Father, mother and we're the children.
You look beautiful, Mom.
- Our family is somewhat incestuous.
- You're such a fool!
- Apologies for being late, Professor.
- That's all right.
- Erminia, would you mind...
- Thank you, but I already ate.
But I wouldn't say no
to that wonderful dessert.
I'm very happy
that you could come too.
You were right to find a new father,
- seen as your old one has left.
- He's left?
I brought him to the airport.
You know, airports these days
look a lot like cemeteries.
- Why did you bring him to the airport?
- I'm still asking myself that.
It was a nightmare evening.
I think your father
is going a little mad.
If you say so.
My husband invited his friends,
the Gasparris, to dinner.
And since he had some
urgent business to attend to
he begged me to meet and entertain
the Gasparris until dinnertime.
I was making them comfortable
when my husband rushed in.
He was in a state,
shouting that he had to leave immediately.
What's more, I had to drive him to
the airport as he had to talk to me.
A great evening!
What about the Gasparris?
- They weren't happy.
- So I'd imagine.
I almost sent them here.
That would have been fantastic!
- Where did father go to?
- Madrid.
He told Gasparri
the political situation is very serious,
and that he had
to leave on a secret mission.
They seemed to believe him.
Instead, I think your father
remembered at the last moment
that hunting season opens tomorrow
at Villaverde in Madrid.
He went last year as well.
- Who did he talk to before dinner?
- I don't know, darling.
A man I'd never seen before.
My husband told Gasparri
that he's someone who works...
in the government press office.
Shall we retire to
the drawing room for coffee?
But my story isn't finished, I warn you!
Excuse me, Bianca,
but was it a Mr. Ghisberti?
I already told you, I don't know!
Thank you, I'll serve.
- Who wants coffee?
- Mom never has coffee in the evening.
But I'll have a drop
with cream this evening.
- Would you like me to serve?
- If you please.
- Thank you.
- Professor?
Thank you, without cream.
- Konrad?
- I'll get my own.
- Stefano?
- No, thanks.
Now that we're relaxed,
I'll tell you the rest of my story.
Pay attention, Konrad,
it should particularly interest you.
Having gotten rid of the Gasparris,
we rushed to the airport.
And what did my husband want to tell me?
"I expect...",
and these are his exact words.
"I expect you to leave Konrad
and never see him again!"
- Papa? Since when has he...
- Exactly, since when?
He was in such a state
I didn't want to go against him.
I've never seen him like that before.
His passion has returned.
He's jealous.
Oh please, he was perfectly clear:
He doesn't mind if I take another lover,
but he wants me to get rid of Konrad.
He was saying some ridiculous things.
He told me to send him away
immediately, otherwise...
Finally I lost my patience and said:
"If that's how you want things,
I prefer to get a divorce."
- So that's what we're doing.
- So you can marry Konrad?
No!
Besides, Konrad has never
asked me to marry him.
Isn't that right, dear?
- I'm asking you now.
- Thank you,
but the answer is no.
You marry to have a family,
and divorce to be free.
- Free to remarry.
- No, free.
- Simply free.
- Don't talk crap.
- What do you mean?
- You know well.
- Lietta, what's he on?
- Come on, why won't you marry me?
- Enough. Shut it.
- Konrad.
- Shall I say?
- Don't worry, I'll tell them.
I won't marry you because
you're twelve years younger than me.
And because you're not marriage material.
Am I not? Why's that?
You're not being entertaining.
I'm not trying to be. Answer me.
He's drunk,
he's been drinking all evening.
I'm not drunk.
And I don't want her to marry me.
It would be absurd. I know what I am.
I know what you are too,
and I won't let you make fun of me.
- No one's making fun of you.
- I'm sorry, I wasn't referring to you.
Now then, darling...
tell me why, according to the rules
of your respectable society,
I'm not good marriage material?
- Enough of this foolishness.
- What is it?
- Did something happen to you?
- It's not because of my origins.
It's because of my life, isn't it?
A kept lover. Illegal dealings.
That's what matters.
Yes, my dear, that's what matters.
It matters because I wasn't successful.
Because I'm still just
a rich woman's lapdog,
to be brought where
other dogs are strictly forbidden.
Of course the others don't mind when he
steals food, or makes a mess, or bites.
Don't say these things,
you know they're not true!
Don't encourage him, Bianca,
he just wants to attack our
corrupt capitalist bourgeois society.
You're talking about
a society that doesn't exist anymore,
and if it does exist
all you do is profit from it.
It does exist.
It exists,
and it's more dangerous
now than ever,
- because it's disguised.
- Not you too, Professor!
I'm not a reactionary, you know that.
No, I don't.
You too are in disguise!
Every intellectual I've met
says they're left-wing,
a claim which luckily is never
substantiated in their lives or art.
The intellectuals of my generation
tried hard to find a balance
between politics and morals.
An impossible task.
At least they committed their lives to it,
but he's never tackled any
political or moral problems.
Who's he to hate a society
that lets him live like a lord?
- Even if he did sneak in the service door.
- It's true.
With an old shirt and
a jacket I'd had since I was young.
I remember the first house,
it was wonderful,
and the lady of the house's bed.
She wasn't beautiful like you.
To me she seemed marvelous.
I had a lump in my throat
and tears in my eyes,
like a prospector who sees gold
for the first time in a stream.
That was what I wanted,
and I've done everything to keep it.
The methods that disgust you so much,
well, I learned them there.
They're the same methods
that are used in your world.
They just have different names
because the stakes are higher.
They have fine names,
and are spoken of with respect,
instead of making you sick.
You think you live amongst gallant men,
but often these same men are criminals.
If I told you that your husband
escaped because his associates' plan
to get rid of a dozen communists
and some government ministers
and carry out a coup d'état
has been discovered,
- you'd be appalled.
- I wouldn't be appalled,
I'd say you've gone crazy!
My husband's an industrialist,
naturally he's right-wing.
But where are the left-wing industrialists?
Maybe some of them claim to be.
My husband is right-wing,
and he openly acknowledges it.
And why shouldn't he?
But that doesn't mean he's part
of a criminal organization!
Yes he is! Ask Stefano.
He knows the truth.
You're mad!
This little lapdog was also a pointer.
So that's your game!
That's how you manage
to stay out of trouble.
When everyone else is flushing
their cocaine down the toilet
you're the only one
who doesn't have to worry.
You're stopped at the border
and let go the next day.
- Your lies and defamation protect you.
- Enough!
It's not a lie, I denounced them!
And I'm happy I did it.
And you tolerate this
in your house, Professor?
- What do you want?
- Bastard!
Konrad!
- Get away!
- Stefano, no!
- Don't!
- Stop this!
I won't allow this!
Stop!
Even the damned in hell
don't accuse each other
- like you two do.
- One minute!
Konrad gave his side of the story,
now it's my turn.
Professor, you've already met
the people he's involved with,
they're scum, petty criminals
who beat him up over some drugs.
That's his world,
and it's all he knows.
Konrad, answer him!
Bastard!
I said stop!
You're fighting like rabid dogs!
I thought you loved each other,
that you were friends.
True friends. Inseparable.
That we loved each other?
Friends?
Sure, we're together every day,
we talk, laugh, eat and fuck together!
But when the fun is over
these friends disappear.
- Everyone for themselves.
- It's true. Everyone for themselves.
Anyway, people like you
always land on their feet.
Well,
I'll say goodbye and be on my way,
since that's what you want.
Isn't that what you want, Professor?
You said some very grave things.
I told the truth,
and I won't apologize for that.
Thanks for dinner, Professor,
but take my advice:
Stay out of the fray,
you have until now.
Stay here, with your beautiful
portraits of dead people.
They're the only ones safe
from the violence of Fascist clowns.
I hope you will suffer.
I hope it'll soon pass.
You people always
land on your feet as well.
It's not so easy at my age,
but I'll do my best.
Where will you go now?
- I'm coming with you.
- No.
I always tried to give him the best.
Nice clothes, trips,
they're part of life too.
Even if I did make some mistakes,
I did something for him.
I really loved him.
- What's wrong?
- Leave me alone!
You insulted him, fine!
You chased him away like
a servant who's caught stealing, fine!
But you, Professor,
you shouldn't have
turned your back on him.
You shouldn't have.
Not you. Not you as well!
Come now, nobody here is to blame.
If you want, I'll run after him.
I'll beg on my knees for his forgiveness.
I hope Konrad won't forgive anyone.
Myself included.
When Mrs. Brumonti first came here
and asked to rent the apartment,
I said no.
I was afraid of being near
people I didn't know.
People who might disturb me.
Instead, all this has been much worse
than I could ever have imagined.
If ever there existed
impossible tenants,
I think I found them.
But then I started thinking,
as Lietta had said,
that they could have been my family.
A family that turned out well or badly,
but completely different to me.
And since I love this wretched family
I want to do something for it,
just as it, without realizing,
did something for me.
There's a book by a certain writer
in my bedroom,
and I read it continually.
It talks about a tenant who moves
into the apartment above the writer's.
He hears him moving about.
Walking, doing things.
Sometimes, all of a sudden,
he disappears.
And for a long time
there's nothing but silence.
But just as suddenly, he returns.
His absences become rarer,
and his presence more constant.
It's death.
The knowledge of being near
the end of his life
appeared to the writer in one of its
innumerable, deceitful forms.
Your presence upstairs...
meant the opposite to me.
I don't think I was deceived.
You woke me up again,
roughly,
from a very deep sleep.
A sleep that was deaf and numb...
like death.
There's a letter for you.
Erminia! Hurry to see
if Konrad is upstairs.
Quick, go!
Dear Professor,
I wish I were mistaken,
but I don't think
we will see each other again.
Your son, Konrad.
- Oh God!
- Professor, don't touch him.
Wait for the police.
Breathe out slowly.
That's it.
Very good.
We'll be finished in a second.
Professor? You have visitors.
I gave back the keys to Erminia.
My lawyer will be talking to yours.
They'll sort out all payments
for what happened upstairs.
I'll let you know
what the inquiry finds.
I'd like to...
I only wish I had some doubts.
Unfortunately...
Konrad's suicide was his way
of having the final word.
In a horrible and cruel way
he wanted to punish us forever.
But there's something Konrad
hadn't yet realized:
That we will forget him.
And we will forget him.
He was too young to have learned
yet another horrible thing...
that even pain is fleeting,
like everything else.
Goodbye, Professor.
Don't believe mom.
Believe me,
he didn't kill himself.
They killed him.
You were the only one
to have faith in him.
Don't lose that faith
just because he's dead.