COUSIN ANGELICA
Chorus: "The Lord is my Shepherd"
That's because he rides in the back
seat. It won't happen up front.
Let him get some fresh air,
he'll get over it.
The cologne will freshen
you up, Luisito.
Mom, I don't want to go to granny's.
I want to stay with you two.
You said the same thing last summer.
And then you had a great time.
Don't you remember?
This year you've grown up
and won't cry ¿right?
I always want to be with you two.
It's not possible, son. We'll come
for you very soon.
A month flies by. Don't be silly.
Come on, Luisa. It's getting late.
You'll have a wonderful time.
Remember last year. You didn't
want to return to Madrid.
That's right, my boy. You'll have a
splendid time with those witches.
Feeling better?
Come on, get in.
No. Not the green one.
- Good morning. Doña Pilar Fuentes?
- Yes, this is the house.
Tell her it's her nephew Luis.
Come in. Come in.
Come this way.
Madam is expecting you.
Madam, your nephew Luis.
Luis...
- Is that you, Luis?
- Yes, aunt. How are you?
So many years...
- So many years...
- You look fine.
Yes, I'm fine.
Old... but fine.
And you? How are you?
- I'm also fine.
- Really?
Let me look at you.
A miracle.
Without a miracle, I couldn't
have seen you again.
Sit down, sit down.
- Do you still play the piano?
- No.
These won't obey anymore.
Aunt, I would have preferred to bury
my mother without troubling anyone.
But mother spoke of a family vault
and I need your permission.
What permission? She had every right.
Poor thing. Carrying her in the car
as if she was a piece of furniture...
It's just a change of
venue for her remains.
She died 20 years ago.
It's not my mother,
just what remains of her.
It's a...
I know.
Now come with me.
I'll fix your room.
I'm staying at the hotel, don't bother.
What do you mean at the hotel?
By no means.
- I'll fix your room.
- I'm fine at the hotel...
I don't want to trouble you.
What trouble? On the contrary,
you'll keep me company.
A hotel, for heaven's sake!
With this beautiful room here.
By the way...
Have you already seen Angélica?
- Angélica?
- Yes, Angélica. Your cousin.
Look at this room!
The camphor really smells! Truth is,
I overdo it with the camphor.
And how is Angélica doing?
See? You'll feel like a king here.
The camphor smell will go away fast.
Angélica? Angélica lives downstairs.
The apartment was vacant
and they bought it.
Just one thing...
Anselmo will take care of
the burial procedure.
I'm really grateful to you but
I prefer to stay at the hotel.
Let's see...
Do you recognize me now?
No. I'm sorry, I don't recognize you.
Let's see now...
The Salesian school!
Father Florentino?
London Eyes!
- London Eyes?
- Sure, that's it.
Sagun. Felipe Sagun.
We used to sit together.
He was quite a character.
I'm sorry... but with that attire...
Care to explain what
"London Eyes" means?
It's a movie that the priests
used to show us at school.
These eyes would appear
in the walls, in the sky...
everywhere.
- It was really frightening, right?
- That's right.
Inquisitive blue eyes...
Cruel eyes...
Well, we can bury your mother
whenever you like.
No problem.
- Tomorrow at 11?
- No... I can't in the morning.
I have a union meeting.
It's all right, Anselmo.
I can take care of it.
No way. What's the family for?
Could it be in the afternoon,
around four?
Sure. At four o'clock, then.
So, where do you live now? Madrid?
No, in Barcelona.
- Isn't this the Roman music?
- Yes, sure.
- So, how's it going with you?
- Fine, very good.
Are you married?
Got any children?
None, I'm single.
Come on, let's get on with it.
You, Mr. Cayetano.
And the boy: Luis Hernandez.
Ready.
Now!
Remember, absolutely still. As if
you were made out of marble.
This is for Luisito.
Fine.
Aunt is coming!
Luisito, this letter is for you.
Who opened it?
Grandmother opened it.
You won't get upset about it, right?
- Did you get anything out?
- Can't do it.
- How about with a magnet?
- I don't have one.
Madrid, July 5, 1936.
Dear son; we got your letter and we're
very happy to know you're all right.
At the end of the month, we'll go get
you so we can spend August together...
by the sea. So, in a few days,
we'll all be together, son.
We really look forward to seeing you.
You shouldn't say all those things
that you're saying, son.
I'm sure everyone is making
an effort so that you...
can have a good time and be happy.
You also have to make a small effort.
You have to be obedient and behave.
Until very soon, son.
Loads of kisses from your loving mother.
- This too?
- We have to see how it hangs.
Bend down.
Be careful.
Be careful with the sleeve.
Hurry up! Shut it all up!
Come on!
What's going on?
Let's pray the Rosary.
In the name of the Father...
Mother, what's going on?
The power's out.
Must be the utility.
A disaster's coming.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee;
blessed art thou among women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
- Mother, I'm scared.
- Don't be afraid, darling.
What should we do?
- Should I open the door?
- No, Miguel. Don't do it.
I'll go.
Things are getting complicated.
- Heard any news?
- No. Did you hear any news?
Did you hear the shots?
I believe it's the U.G.T.
And the army? What are they doing?
What are they waiting for?
I don't know.
The radio!
Silence!
Not a single station.
A disaster. That's what's
in store for us.
Attention! Attention!
Our city has become part
of the Salvation Movement!
- General mobilization has been decreed.
- Our side!
I'm so glad!
Open up the windows!
Let the sunshine in!
We have to celebrate.
Bring some cognac!
Luisito...
Now your father and his ilk will know
what's coming to them.
Angélica, serve your cousin
another drink.
- No, thanks.
- Come on, we have to celebrate.
Of course.
- Ice?
- No, thanks.
Aunt Pilar is looking well.
She'll end up much better
than my father.
She has deteriorated after she
stopped playing the piano.
Isn't that so, Anselmo?
Aunt Pilar? She's living the good life.
Every day, from home to church
and from church to home.
Listen, Luis, tell me something.
All this boom they're talking about.
This book avalanche.
Are the books selling or not?
We can't complain. We've sold
quite a few this year.
The impression I get is
that nobody reads.
I used to... Well, I've never
been a great reader.
But now it's impossible.
You need time to read.
And I'll tell you something else.
I prefer a magazine... or the TV.
Everything's already chewed and
digested. It enters through your eyes.
Who has time to read nowadays?
You like to read, don't you?
Depends. But yes, I like to read.
Poetry most of all.
"I dreamt that you were walking
me along a white path
"in the midst of a green field,
towards the blue hills
towards the blue hilltops,
on a calm morning. "
Did you write it?
It's pretty, mom, go on.
Don't know if I'll remember it.
Let's see.
"A calm morning... "
"I felt your hand in mine,
your friendly hand.
"The girl's voice in my ear...
"like a new bell...
like a virgin bell from a spring morn. "
But... how old were you
when you wrote that?
You must have been... 10 or 11.
What do you know? We have
a poet in the family.
No. I didn't write that.
I copied it from Antonio Machado.
Who did you say you got it from?
Antonio Machado, dad.
Oh, Machado. Right... Machado.
Madam, whenever you're ready.
- Ready for dinner?
- Whenever you say.
Let's go.
Luis... You probably want
to wash your hands, right?
OK. Thanks.
This way.
I'm really glad to have met you.
Your family here is a bit like...
You don't mind me saying it, do you?
- No.
- The black sheep in the family.
Crazy. Over thirty years have passed and
some people still remember the war.
Ask my daughter what she knows about
the war. Nothing, absolutely nothing.
It's natural, time erases everything.
We'd be in trouble if it wasn't so.
It's funny...
Me coming here...
all these forgotten things...
I'm seeing you on July 18, 1936...
shutting windows, nervous...
Me in 1936?
I was a little kid, and I was
in Burgos with my parents.
Are you serious?
- Here's a clean towel.
- I'm starving.
Your cousin is a five-star cook!
How are you, Angélica?
Fine... fine.
Glad to see you again.
So am I.
And your father? Didn't
he want to come?
No.
Of course.
May the Lord be with you.
Let's pray.
Forgive, O Lord, your
servant Luisa's sins.
So that she can find her place
among your chosen ones.
- In the name of Christ, our Lord.
- Amen.
Poor darling!
Luis, let's go.
But how could you confuse
Anselmo with my father?
Look.
Convince yourself. What did my father
and Anselmo have in common?
Obviously, nothing at all.
Like I told you, I have
some confusing ideas.
Let's see. How old were you in 1936?
In 1936 I was... 9 years old.
How could you be 9 years old?
Of course I was. I'll show you.
Look at me.
Who's this?
This is aunt Pilar when she was young.
This is my grandmother.
And this is my mother.
Your grandmother.
- Proust's cupcake.
- Whose cupcake?
Piles of papers have been written
about Proust's cupcake.
Proust, a writer, once dunked
a cupcake into a cup of tea...
suddenly, his mouth was filled with the
flavor of geraniums and orange blossoms.
- His grandfather's garden.
- You can come to the table.
The chocolate is ready.
It's true. Those things happen.
A fragrance... I don't know...
some music.
And in some new places you get
the feeling you've been there before.
I went on a school outing, and when
I reached the place I already knew it.
I had dreamt about it.
- It's good, isn't it?
- Excellent.
- I have to go, mom.
- Go, go.
Good bye, son. Behave.
Don't cause any trouble.
Pilar, take good care of him.
Don't worry. He'll behave really well.
Right, Luisito?
We'll take care of it. Any trouble and
he'll be going to mass every day.
A kiss.
Mom, I don't want to stay here.
I want to go with you two.
A month flies by, son. You'll have
a great time, I've already told you.
Goodbye, Angélica.
Bye, beautiful.
- Goodbye, mother.
- Goodbye, darling.
Good Lord.
I'm sure you don't
go to mass in Madrid.
I thought so.
Why must this happen to us, Lord?
Why? Why?
Come on, Luisito. We have to
put away your clothes.
A month flies by, Luisito.
You'll have a good time here.
Better than in Madrid, you'll see.
Luisito...
What's wrong?
Are you going to cry?
Come on, don't be silly.
You're already a man!
Come on!
- Aunt.
- What?
My father would never come in
when he used to come here, right?
No.
All right. I'm finished.
Come on, Luisito.
Let's go pick some berries.
Coming or what?
Luis!
Where are you?
Warm!
Warm! Warm!
Cold! Cold, cold!
Cold!
Angélica!
Angélica, wait for me.
You're dumb and dull.
You behave like a child.
Can I have a berry?
- Do you know what they were saying?
- No. What?
That if Pilar had married your father,
everything would be different now.
But why?
Because she met your father before your
mother did. Your mother stole him away.
- Didn't they tell you anything?
- Not to me.
My grandmother says that Pilar
could have changed your father.
And that your mother is a fool.
My mother's no fool.
If your father had married Pilar,
you would be her son now.
- What has your father done?
- Nothing!
He must have done something.
Something very bad. Grandma says that
when the Nationals reach Madrid,
he'll be shot.
My father?
You said the same thing last summer.
All that crying. And then
you had a great time.
Don't you remember?
This year you're older.
You're not going to cry, right?
I want to be with you two.
It's not possible, son. We'll come
for you very soon.
A month flies by. Don't be silly.
Come on, Luisa. It's getting late.
You'll have a wonderful time.
Remember last year. You didn't
want to return to Madrid.
That's right, my boy. You'll have a
splendid time with those witches.
Feeling better?
Come on, get in.
Chorus: "Mary, Mother of God".
Come in.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, aunt.
- Did you sleep well?
- Splendidly, but, why did you bother?
I was going to get up.
No... you didn't miss
your bed, did you?
Not at all. On the contrary,
it's much better than at the hotel.
It's a spring mattress, of course.
There's wool in here.
Look, I've fixed you these toasts...
- but if you want something else...
- No, this is fine.
Yes? Try it. Try the coffee.
Very tasty.
Luis... Luis.
I'll leave you alone.
I know I'm a bore.
Anything else to wash and iron?
No. But don't trouble
yourself, aunt. Really.
The mortified nun was there.
"The world perished,
and its concupiscence".
There was a washbasin here.
They must have thrown it away.
- Good morning.
- Did you sleep well?
- Very well, thanks.
- Goodbye, son.
- Goodbye, aunt.
Slept a while, didn't you?
Hi. Yes, I had a long sleep.
- Hi, Luis.
- Hi, Angélica.
You look busy.
Anselmo wants to know if you'd like
to come to the country on Sunday.
- To the country?
- Come on, come with us!
All right, fine.
This is the only classroom
still with the old kind of desks.
They've been replaced
elsewhere.
So you're one of the old timers,
when I attended here.
Well, I couldn't say.
I've been here for 16 years.
But there was a very old teacher,
Father Florentino.
Father Florentino?
- A tall, strong man?
- I knew him as a sick person.
In bed.
A very old man, as I'm saying.
The chapel.
- Yes, sir. - May I?
- Of course.
- This hasn't changed much.
- I couldn't say.
When I was a child,
the janitor's name was Adrian.
Adrian? I haven't met him.
- Do they still ring the bell?
- Yes, yes. Always.
- The auditorium.
- No, the cinema.
No, no.
The auditorium.
In my time,
this was the cinema.
- Please, go on with your chores.
- Thank you.
London eyes.
The London Tower. The Thames.
A lonely alley.
Wet cobblestones.
A blackened brick wall.
Just like in a horror movie.
And all of a sudden...
those inquisitive,
disturbing eyes.
Footsteps.
Footsteps getting closer.
And those beings,
chasing someone...
No, no... The worm...
The worm...
The worm.
Oh, no. Oh, no!
No! The worm!
No, I don't want to!
I don't want to! No, no!
I don't want to!
She's taking me! She's taking me!
She's taking me! No!
I don't want to, I don't want to!
- Luisito! - No! She's taking me!
- What's wrong? - She's taking me!
- Whos' taking you? - The nun!
- The nun?
The mortified nun!
There she is! Right there!
You're having a nightmare!
Wake up! Wake up!
It was just a nightmare.
I'm aunt Pilar.
You were dreaming.
Come on, calm down.
Come on, go to sleep.
I'll fix your bed.
Poor darling...
You really got scared.
Never mind,
I'll change the sheets.
It won't stop like that.
- Raise your chin.
- Leave me alone, you brute.
- What side was it?
- The left side.
Then you must raise
your right arm.
Just like that.
Did it stop?
It will stop even faster
if you lie down.
Come on, lie down.
But keep your chin up.
I didn't mean to hurt you, I swear.
You did it on purpose.
No. Really, I didn't mean to.
Did it stop?
Angélica...
- What?
I wanted to tell you something...
Go ahead, say it,
I won't bite.
No... It's nothing.
- How about this, huh?
- What a silence.
You get to breathe
some real air, here.
- Sugar?
- Yes, one, please.
You see, when they told me,
I didn't doubt for a second.
One's fed up of the traffic,
the pollution...
your nerves bursting
with every day's stress...
You need some peace.
Don't think
this is just an investment.
A group of friends -
all great people, right?
We didn't think it twice.
Let's go buy!
Hey, listen. Where would you
place the swimming pool?
The swimming pool?
I don't know.
Let me explain.
Come, please.
- Anselmo, leave Luis alone.
- Let me show you.
Our plot goes up to there.
Up to the bunker. See it?
- Yes.
- And from here up to there.
You see?
- Yes, of course.
I want to build the house over there,
and the swimming pool over here.
What do you think?
- What about the water?
- Water? All the water you want!
- Sure, 150 feet deep...
Huh, your cousin and her jokes!
Ignore her.
Great water.
Warranted by a dowser.
You know, one of those
guys with a divining rod.
- Yes...
- Those guys never fail.
Twenty thousand liters.
Not bad, huh?
Take my advice, Luis,
a great investment.
You see, as we're
selling those lots over there...
house and pool
come out almost for free.
Listen, should you want to buy,
of course you'll get a special price.
But dad, why would he come all the way
from Barcelona just for weekends?
So what? An investment
is always an investment, right?
Right. Well, excuse me,
but there's a lady waiting for me.
- You never take naps?
- Ah... no, I usually don't.
Well, you don't know what
you're missing. See ya.
- Good nap.
- Angélica, here. Here!
- He's crazy about his plot.
- What about you?
I'm happy too, but...
Turn around, my child.
Anselmo only sees
the advantages of living here.
But I see a lot of inconveniences,
no services, no malls...
no schools for Angélica...
But of course,
the house isn't even built yet.
- I'll need a motorcycle.
- A motorcycle?
How about that?
- Enough! - But...
- You're a bore!
- She acts like a savage!
- She's a wonderful child.
Dad... may I turn on the radio?
Yeah, no too loud.
After all, this family thing
is not a bad invention.
Really? Ask me about it.
Aren't you happy just like that,
free, no worries,
no responsibilities...?
Free, yes. But alone.
Instead, you look after your daughter,
your husband...
My husband...
What's wrong with Anselmo?
Is it something important?
I guess he's grown tired of me.
That's all.
D'you mean to say
he's cheating on you?
I'm not sure.
I guess he is.
Truth is,
I don't really care too much.
What are you doing?
- Come on, Luis, throw it!
- I don't know how...
Of course you do!
It's so easy! Watch this!
Throw it!
See? Come on, let's play!
Hurry up, Luis!
Come play!
Here!
Let's see, let's see...
As you know, Luis,
I'm an old family friend.
A united family,
exemplary.
Therefore I don't want you
to see me as a priest...
but as a friend.
- Right?
- Yes.
Good.
In that case...
from friend to friend...
or better yet,
from man to man...
Because you're already a man,
Luisito. A man...
who can realize
the consequences of his actions.
So tell me: what have you and
your cousin Angélica done?
Nothing.
We haven't done anything.
Come on, come on.
Don't you trust me?
I only mean to help you.
Oh, I see.
You love your cousin Angélica
just like you love your parents...
your aunt, your grandmother...
And maybe, because of that love...
you've kissed her.
Is that right?
Just a simple kiss,
but quite disturbing it was.
After that disturbance,
and maybe without even noticing it...
you've had some small chat
with an older boy.
A dishonest chat,
of course...
Am I right?
No!
You liar! And what was this
doing in your room?
Mother of God! Mother of God!
That child is a bent twig!
He needs some spiritual exercises!
- Where are you going?
- Come. I guess it was here.
- What are you doing?
- It will just be a second, wait.
- But what are you doing?
- It must be here, somewhere.
What are you looking for?
There it is!
See?
Angélica... Luis...
1938.
- Your mother and I.
- Really?
Do you have a pencil
and a piece of paper?
I don't know if a ball-pen will do.
See?
- So you were sweethearts?
- Sweethearts, at twelve!
So what?
I go out with boys.
- How did my mother look like?
- I don't know.
- Was she taller than me?
- Yes, I guess she was.
I'm not sure.
- She was not as thin as you are.
- She had larger breasts?
Me, I have nothing. Nothing
up front and nothing behind!
- Boys always say that.
- She walked differently.
Like this?
- Luis!
- What do you want?
Come,
I'll show you something.
- Let's see if you can guess what it is.
- I don't know.
It starts with a "b".
I'm wearing it...
I don't know.
You're so dumb!
Take a look.
My mother says
I have to wear it now.
Let me see it again!
Show me!
Just for a second.
Angélica! Luisito!
I'm coming!
- How are you?
- Hi, how are you?
As usual.
Hello, mother.
Miguel!
What happened to you, my son?
Nothing, some shrapnel.
Back to the front in a few days.
Oh Lord!
- And the war, how is it going?
- It couldn't be better!
- Madrid is about to fall!
- Well...
- They don't tell us nothing here.
- Like a saint. And your hand?
Just the same, mom, just the same.
And now... the other one.
The doctor has great confidence
on these soakings, but... I don't know.
Does it hurt a lot?
I rejoice in offering
my sufferings to the Lord.
Let's hope He will accept them.
And that He touches
your father's heart.
Daughter of mine!
- I bet you we won't find it.
- Anselmo, we'll be right back!
After all these years,
she can't have kept it.
She keeps everything.
Aunt Pilar is a magpie.
Magpies steal shiny objects
so they can find their nests, but...
I think we won't find anything.
- Nothing to lose by trying.
- Ok.
- I even believe I saw them once.
D'you know what she keeps?
- What?
Those old soda bottles,
the ones with those small balls?
She's got a full pack.
"Everything is useful... "
"It's a sin to trash things!"
Have you seen her apartment?
I call it The Museum.
Some rooms are
just like in those times.
- Really? - Sure, you don't notice
because you see them every day.
They must be somewhere
around here...
I had an idea
that this was a lot larger...
What a mess, huh?
Look at this... Come, come!
Look at this mess.
It's preposterous!
I know!
They're in the trunk!
This used to be in my room.
The washbasin?
Yes...
Luis, come. Come!
Help me with this stuff.
Isn't this funny...
Hey!
Just like I said.
HISTORY OF SPAIN
How hard it was to write
without blotting...
You'd be so very careful,
and all of a sudden, poof!
And when the pen got snagged?
Everything was perfect...
and out of the blue, zap!
A mess! Blots everywhere!
But today, with ballpoints...
"The city where you live"
"I live in a city and my parish church
is San Lorenzo...
"My house is in front of a park
where we can play very well.
"The city has several churches
and a very important cathedral.
"I live with my grandmother
and aunts...
"because my parents aren't here. "
Good! You've got your textbooks
and your notebooks!
Happy now?
- Yes, thanks a lot.
I'll have a great time reading them.
Really.
- Where are you going, Luis?
- Wait, I want to see something.
Some crazy idea!
You'll smash your head!
- It's all right. Come. Come!
- You're crazy!
- Come, come!
- I can't go out there!
- It's very easy!
- It's not easy!
- No danger at all!
Sure, not for you!
See how easy it was?
Very good!
Nobody will believe this.
- Sit down. - On the roof?
- Sure, come here.
Now I know for sure you're crazy.
This is so childish.
Somebody will see us.
Those are the bells of the Clarisas.
Luis!
Luis! Are you there?
Come down at once!
What were you doing on the roof?
Angélica, where is she?
Angélica! Angélica!
Come here at once!
Keep on with that!
Parra, come here!
Enough!
Go to your desk.
Read this.
Only the underlined parts.
"... among all the innocent victims
sacrificed to the fury of the reds...
"the death of the child
José Angel Cerneda is maybe...
"the one that causes the
greatest and deepest indignation.
"The eleven year old child
José Angel Cerneda...
"was playing in his school's playground,
and was torn apart by the shrapnel...
of one of the bombs
of the criminal air raid. "
Go back to your seat.
A village in the rearguard.
Just like the one we live in.
A school,
just like the one we're in.
A boy,
just like you.
The boy is eleven.
He's playing in the playground.
Happy, blissful, joyful,
totally unaware...
that life can be lost in a second.
In the sky, a deep hum is heard.
The boy doesn't worry.
He even rises his inquisitive eyes...
He's so used to seeing
airplanes fly by!
The boy's name is José Angel Cerneda...
He's eleven years old.
And I wonder:
Is he in God's Grace?
Or has he lived in Sin?
José Angel sees,
in the blue yonder of the sky...
the tiny silhouettes of the aircraft.
How long has it been
since his last confession?
How has he lived
Does he fear God,
and has he avoided Sin?
Or, on the contrary,
at the last moment...
he's fallen into Temptation?
The roar of the aircraft's engines
is now awful!
All of a sudden, the earth shakes!
It trembles with the explosions!
The bombs spread fire,
destruction, death!
One of them
reaches José Angel Cerneda.
Eleven years old. When he was
playing in the school's playground.
Tears his flesh apart, disintegrates
his body. Takes away his life.
Just like that poor unlucky child,
you don't think about death.
However, death may come tomorrow,
tonight, within an hour...
Even right now!
Look into your souls, and if
you are in Sin, may God help you!
Because Sin would condemn you
to Hell for all the eternity.
Eternity.
What do we mean by "eternity"?
Look a the blackboard.
Try reading that number.
A one followed by zeros.
Suppose they are years.
Or better, centuries.
Or, even better, millenniums.
Well, when all those millennia
have passed...
it won't be more than
a millisecond of eternity.
"Mine are the heavens,
and mine is the earth...
"Mine are the nations, the just
are mine but not the sinners...
"The angels are mine,
and the Mother of God...
"And all things are mine,
and God is mine and for me...
"Because Christ is mine
and all for me. "
"What do you ask then,
and seek, my soul?
"Yours is all of this,
and all for you.
"Do not engage yourself
in something less,
"nor pay heed to the crumbs
which fall from your Father's table.
"Go forth and exult in your Glory!
"Hide yourself in It and rejoice,
"and you will obtain
the deepest desires of your heart.
"... greatest love of God... "
My leg! My leg!
- Hi! - Hi! Is Maruja in?
- No, today is Thursday.
But of course!
I just need some flour.
- Well, come in.
- Thanks!
Don't mind me.
Get on with your business.
- No, I wasn't doing anything.
- Where could the flour be?
I don't know where they keep it.
It's not here, either.
Here it says...
- That's right. Fool of me!
- And there is some, too.
Yes! Thank you.
Oh! I'm sorry.
- What's the matter with you?
- With me?
Nothing. Why?
You look nervous.
Nervous?
How else could I be?
Anselmo?
Wouldn't it be better
to face the situation?
What for?
To get a divorce?
Why, yes. Why not?
Take this. My daughter asked me
to give it back to you.
Oh, Luis! Luis!
I'm so lonely, Luis!
Luis! I'm all alone!
Come on.
Calm down.
You know you can count on me
for whatever you need.
Forgive me.
I've got no right...
to bother you with my problems.
- Angélica!
I must get out of here.
What am I doing here?
Nothing.
I'll never see you again.
I know.
No aunt, I'll be back next summer.
You'll see.
Sure, man. But let us know first,
we might be on vacation.
- Right.
- I'll miss you so much.
Son!
- So will I.
But I must go back to work.
Luis. Luis, give me a hug!
Anything you need,
I'm at your service.
I travel quite a lot to Barcelona.
I'll call you.
Well, I'm planning to move
to a new apartment...
I'll let you know when I've moved.
- That will be fine.
Farewell, Angélica.
- Farewell, Luis.
- Goodbye, Luis.
- Goodbye.
Luis...
Tell your father...
No, nothing...
- Goodbye.
- Leaving already? - Yes.
- A kiss.
Don't forget to write.
- Wait.
Can I go for a ride? - Do you know
how to ride a bike? - Sure.
- It belongs to that boy.
- Ask him if I can.
- Manolo! Manolo!
- What?
- Can he go for a ride?
- Sure.
- Wanna come?
- Why not?
And what if you father
doesn't want me there?
He will. You'll see.
- How big is Madrid?
- Huh, very big!
I bet I'll like it.
But my mother will be very lonely.
I bet she'll cry.
We'll send her a letter.
Are you happy?
They're going to stop us!
- Why? - Because of the war.
Hold on!
Hey, you, there!
Kids! Where are you going?
- Keep moving.
- Hey!
I'm thirsty. Can I have a drink?
- Still a long ride ahead?
- Quite long.
Hey, you.
Come here at once.
Come on!
Why did you leave the road?
- Because... because...
- We've not done anything wrong.
Ok, come with me.
Come on.
Angélica! Angélica, my child!
Look at yourself!
- Thanks a lot, much appreciated.
- It's nothing. They're just kids.
- Sure, just kids' mischief.
- Bye. - Thank you.
- Anselmo, don't, please!
- You stay out of this!
Leave him,
he must learn his lesson!
Take off your sweater.
Get on your knees.