Previously on "The Whispers"...
- My wish came true.
- What did you wish for?
For Drill make you and daddy
love each other again.
Here's what we know about the entity.
It travels electrically,
through power cables,
so it can be identified
by a heat signature.
He uses kids, but not just any kids.
He chooses them carefully.
They all have access.
His whole planet was dying.
He needed to send a signal
back to the others.
Mr. President, we
learned how to kill Drill.
He can posses the body of a child.
Once he does, he can be destroyed.
He never goes outside.
- He's always on the computer.
- Well, that's what kids do today.
- They play on the computer.
- Maybe we should take his away, then.
Let's just sign him up
for some sports or...
He's not you. He doesn't like sports.
Well, we don't always get
to do what we want, do we?
And you know what? It's about
time Nicholas learned that.
Seriously? He is a 10-year-old boy.
Why don't you take him to the park?
I... I see other kids
playing there all the time.
Yeah, the other kids pick on him.
Who is that?
Who's there?
Stop it! Go away!
Just go away! Leave me alone!
Stop it! Stop it!
- Nicholas? Nicholas?
- What's wrong?
Nicholas, are you all right?
Baby?
I heard a voice... Like a ghost.
What are you talking about?
He says he wants to be my friend.
A ghost?
Maybe if he made some real friends,
he wouldn't have to invent imaginary ones.
Come here, baby. You're okay.
Okay.
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
How long are we gonna live like this?
Until we know we're safe.
How will we know when that is?
- I mean, if Drill can posses a child...
- Lena.
We know how close he is with Minx.
What if...
What if he chooses her?
That's... that's why we have monitors,
sensors all over the house, okay?
If he tries to go near Minx
or any of us, we'll know.
How will knowing stop it from happening?
He finally got to sleep.
Just took three stories
and a children's aspirin.
Said he had a headache again.
He had one last night, too.
Everything he's been through,
to only have a headache?
Pretty tough kid.
Pretty tough mom, too.
No!
Minx?!
No, Drill! Leave me alone!
You stay away from her!
It's okay, daddy. He's gone now.
Okay. What did he want?
He said that he'd forgive us
for everything we've done if...
If I help him make a new friend.
Okay, what... what... what friend, honey?
Did he... did he say who it is?
No. You said not to talk to him anymore.
- Good.
- So I didn't.
- It's okay, baby. You did good.
We're just trying to figure out
what Drill is up to.
I don't know. But whatever
it is, it's gonna happen soon.
How do you know?
Because he said he needed to
play with his new friend now
because... He's running out of time.
Time for what?
We don't know.
Well, if Drill's looking for a new friend,
- that means he needs access to someone.
- Or something.
But what? A-a new energy source?
Well, we know he tried to call his friends,
and we destroyed any possibility of that.
So what would he want to do next?
It doesn't matter what Drill
wants. It's what we want.
It's this thing out of lives for good.
Now, the only way we're gonna do that
is to stop reacting to Drill.
- We need to get a step ahead of him.
- Okay, but how?
The same way we would if we were tracking
any other killer... we profile Drill.
What are his habits?
How does he choose his victims?
And what happens when you find him?
We all know what
it's gonna take to kill Drill.
Are we really willing to go that far?
Dad?
Yeah?
I... I don't feel very good.
Is it your head again, sweetheart?
No, it's all over.
I got it, Claire.
I'll take him to the doctor.
You guys find the bastard
that's been hurting our kids.
- Okay. How the hell do we do that?
- We know he feeds on energy.
We know he travels through power lines.
So there has to be some kind
of evidence of that, right?
Trail of breadcrumbs
telling us where he's been,
hopefully where he's going next.
Ah, there you are. Good afternoon.
Agents, what can I do for you?
We're wondering if
you've noticed any anomalies
in energy consumption over
the last few weeks...
spikes, dips, anything out of the ordinary.
Guess it depends on what you
mean by "out of the ordinary."
What are those?
Brownouts.
They're not uncommon in the summer heat,
when, uh, people crank their A.C.,
but it's been pretty cool lately, so...
Can you pull up the addresses?
Yeah, sure. Over here.
There you go.
There's a school, playground...
Harbor Point nuclear power plant.
Bureau office where
we interviewed the kids.
Wes' house.
My house.
Capitol University Hospital, last night.
This is him, Claire.
That one, from this morning...
what's this spot?
Don't know. It's restricted.
One of those government buildings.
Usually NSA, D.O.D.
Uh-huh.
We need to know what's there.
Okay, Claire. I... I'll make a few calls.
Mr. Lawrence.
Talk to me, Theo.
Okay, so, we looked
at the four thermal images
that you brought to us.
The first image is from 10 days ago,
directly after he consumed
the energy from the meltdown.
Now, the most recent image is from today.
Now, these images might
look similar to the naked eye,
but they're not.
From one image to the other,
the I.R. Energy is changing.
Theo? Layman's terms, please.
Uh, your alien has dissipated.
It's literally getting less powerful.
That's not possible.
It's continually eating...
lights, power lines, et cetera.
Maybe it's different where he's from.
But in this planet, in this atmosphere,
he's basically chewing celery.
I don't understand.
It takes more energy to chew celery
than the celery can provide,
so a human being
eating nothing but celery...
will starve to death.
Hey, Nicholas.
Can we ask you a couple of questions?
I guess.
When you were born,
did the whole hospital get stretch marks?
Just leave me alone, okay?
Please!
Okay, let him go.
Did you see that? Let's get out of here.
What did you say your name was?
Thank you for saving me, Drill.
Okay.
How can I help save you?
The location you asked about...
there's a good reason
why it's ghosted on the map.
- DSN.
- The deep space network.
It's a system of transmission equipment
used to track, receive, and send
messages to orbiting spacecraft.
We destroyed the rock, so Drill,
he must be looking for another
way to send out the signal.
While he still can.
When he told Minx that he was
"running out of time,"
this is what he meant.
Now, according to my team,
Drill is getting weaker
every minute of every day.
Now, if we can keep him away from DSN
or, more importantly,
keep him from feeding,
them maybe we don't have to kill him,
'cause maybe he'll just die off.
Wes...
I think I know how we do it.
Wes?
Lena, what's...
What's going on?
Honey, I think I forgot
my sweater upstairs.
Would you go check for me?
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
What's this?
I'm scared.
If this thing can possess a child...
I can't lose her.
Not to something like that.
If Drill really wants Minx,
there's not a place he can't find her.
It doesn't matter if he knows where she is
if he can't get to her.
We're taking a cruise from
Baltimore to the Caribbean.
If Drill travels through
power lines, then...
you're taking her where there aren't any.
It's a good plan.
It's not a good plan.
It's a great plan.
I don't want you to leave... either of you.
Well, we're not leaving.
We're just taking a vacation.
Okay.
I couldn't find it, mommy.
That's okay, sweetie.
Come say goodbye to daddy.
Hey. Come here.
Now, listen to me.
You be a good girl for your mother, okay?
Okay.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay.
Take care. I love you.
Bye, daddy. I love you, too.
See you soon. Bye.
Mwah.
Okay, off we go.
It started as a headache.
Now he's saying he's hurting everywhere.
Feels tired, weak.
This is a hospital, Sean.
Why not just bring him to his pediatrician?
I wasn't sure if his unique circumstance
was the thing that might
be causing any of this,
so I thought if anybody
understood, it was you.
I know what you're thinking
about those kids from last night.
But Henry's not like that.
He's a good boy, Maria.
You think he wouldn't
do whatever Drill asked
to save your life or his mother's?
We're all good, Sean,
until we have something to lose.
Have you lost your mind?
Black out an entire city?
Not the whole city, sir.
Just the parts that...
Do you have any idea of
the panic it would cause?
Oh, we do, sir. And by all means,
we are open to any ideas
you have to capture
the alien loose in our nation's capitol.
Watching the grid,
we can identify his signature.
The next time he shows himself,
we shut the power down
grid by grid, block by block.
We drive him, funnel him
right where we want him.
A secure, abandoned building by the water.
A safe zone with no people, no electricity.
- Yeah, and then what?
- We starve him out.
With no energy to feed on,
no way to leave the area...
and how long will that take?
We can't truly predict...
wait, you want to bring
Washington to its knees,
and you can't even tell me
how long it's gonna take?
Sir, I don't care how long it takes
because if we don't do something today,
Drill could bring this country
to its knees by tomorrow.
The DSN is secure.
Even if Drill can access
the electrical system,
operating the satellites
requires security codes
that change daily.
There's no way he can access...
he accessed a secure nuclear
facility while were outside,
waiting for him to get there.
He will find a way, sir.
He always does.
I... fine, fine. I'll come in early.
But tell Bishop he owes me, all right?
That's three times this month.
And it's always me that gets the call.
Why is that?
I do have a life, you know.
No, I'm not trying to
make more of this than it is.
Just a schedule's a schedule, right?
Yeah, well, tell that to Bishop.
Tell him I can't do it tonight.
How's my boy?
I'm worried about him.
Maria's still examining him.
Still?
I thought you'd be home by now.
Yeah. Hopefully soon. Why? What's wrong?
We're blacking out the city, Sean.
But to help make sure
that Drill doesn't find out,
we can't tell the public, so...
You know it's gonna be
a madhouse out there.
Yeah. Get home as soon as possible.
Okay, I don't want the two of you
out on the streets when this hits.
Okay.
The school was shut down three years ago,
so we got complete control of the campus.
- Neighbors?
- Compliant so far.
We've evacuated nearly all of them.
What do you got?
All right.
These give us what
the thermal cameras are showing,
and this one's tapped
into the city power grid.
Mr. Secretary, can you hear me?
Loud and clear, Wes.
Everything is in position.
We're just waiting for eyes on the target.
Any sign?
Not yet.
Where are you, you son of a bitch?
Is that him?
It's the same energy draw
as the brownouts you isolated before.
Looks like a park in Columbia Heights.
What do you think?
You better be damn sure, Mr. Lawrence,
before I blind this city.
We're sure, Mr. president.
Then shut it down.
What is it, mommy?
It looks like we're delayed an hour.
Okay, honey. Why don't
we go sit over there?
Drill?
Where are you?
I brought what you wanted.
Look who's back.
I'm supposed to meet my friend.
Sorry. Your friend ain't coming this time.
How do you know?
'Cause he told me.
What?
It was pretty cool.
He said he couldn't stay here
and that you have to follow
the lights to find him.
He also told me you're all right,
and we should give you a chance to show it.
Thank you.
Good luck, Nicholas.
We're getting the first
crime reports in now
from the blacked-out areas, Agent Bennigan.
Well, that's to be expected, sir.
Question is, how long do
you stand around at the dance
till you realize you've been stood up?
Maybe you should tell me, sir.
My dates always showed.
Come on. Where are you?
We're monitoring the situation as best can.
Obviously, the conditions
are just horrendous
for anyone in Baltimore today.
Because of these power outages, traffic...
Almost home.
Shouldn't be too much longer, okay?
Did the doctor tell you
what's wrong with me?
Uh, we had to leave
before the test came back,
but I'm sure it's probably nothing
to worry about right now, okay, little man?
But what if it's not nothing?
What if it's Drill punishing me
'cause I won't play with him anymore?
Drill's not gonna hurt you, Henry.
In fact, mom is out there right now,
making sure that he can't hurt
you or anyone else ever again.
Okay.
What?
He's here.
- 8th and Jefferson?
- 8th and Jefferson.
Are you sure it's him?
There's nothing on the grid
at their location.
If Henry says it's there,
I say we go for it.
If we black out that grid,
they'll be stuck right in the middle of it.
Claire, we're gonna be fine.
Just do it.
Take out grid 8.
Of course. No, stay in the car.
W... What's going on?
Hey.
We're gonna be fine. Okay?
It worked. There he is.
Look at all those brownouts.
It's like he's starting to panic.
He must be trying to find a way out.
Well, let's give him one.
Funnel him straight to us.
Take out 5, 6, and 7.
Let's go! Back up!
You did it!
We did it. On our way now.
First star on the right?
And straight on till morning.
I'll be damned. It's working.
How close is he?
Almost home.
Where is this son of a bitch?
He's inside the school.
He's here.
Go dark now.
- It worked?
- It seems so.
Without any power source,
he can't move, right?
That's the idea.
I think we can assume he's not
gonna be too happy about this.
I need some help here.
You okay?
Henry?
H... Henry? Henry?
Henry? Son?
Dad?
Okay, don't move.
I'm gonna get you out of here, okay?
We can't go, mommy.
Honey, we've been through this.
I don't want to leave daddy here.
He's gonna come meet us as soon as he can.
Honey, here. Come.
Look, I don't like the idea
of being away from your dad
any more than you do.
But...
Drill doesn't care about us.
He's after you.
And we need to keep you as
far away from him as possible.
Breaking news...
the nation's capitol has been taken down
by a mysterious blackout.
What's happening?
I don't know.
We need to find your dad.
Have you heard from Lena?
Yeah, she said she'd call me when she gets
far enough out to sea.
Hopefully, you'll be able
to tell her this is all over,
she and Minx can come home.
Sean and Henry would like
that news, too, right?
I like him... Sean.
He's... he's a good man.
Yeah.
Yeah, he is.
It's funny.
I think I had to lose him...
really lose him...
to understand exactly what
it was I needed to save.
I feel the same way...
About Lena.
I guess I just forgot who she really was.
There's something there.
What?
There. You see?
Wes, there's a kid inside.
How?
Drill. He must have lured him.
He knew what was happening.
He took a hostage.
Sir, we need to get the kid out.
No, what we need to do
is hold our position.
I can get to him before anything happens.
For all we know, that kid
may be part of a trap.
I will not allow you or any
of my men to take that risk.
- I need you to stay here, Claire.
- Wes, I'm going with you.
Claire.
What the hell are you doing?
I ordered you to stand down.
I'm sorry, Mr. Secretary.
I'm disobeying those orders.
Wes, this is insubordination.
Yes, it is, sir.
Taxi!
Oh, come on, Wes.
Excuse me.
Can you get us into D.C.?
Sorry, lady. The city's closed.
Look, I'll pay you whatever you want.
I'd love to take your money,
but I'm telling you there's no way in.
You guys need a ride?
I just dropped my sister off.
I'm heading back home.
Uh, he said the city's closed.
I know the city inside and out.
I can find a way.
If we're gonna find that kid...
we need to split up.
Okay. Keep your coms on.
As soon as anything feels off...
I'll call in.
Okay.
Wait. Wait!
Claire, what's happening?
I saw him.
He was here.
We're not here to hurt you.
I just want to talk to you.
- I'm following the kid.
- Where are you?
Uh, somewhere on
the second floor, the West side.
Okay, I'm coming.
Drill.
He's here.
He can't move.
Be careful.
How is he doing that? How is he moving?
He must have consumed what little energy
was in that thermal monitor.
He can't go far.
Wes.
See, Drill?
I told you I could get them here.
Henry?
Be honest. Talk to me. Hey.
Dad, my head still hurts.
Okay. Hold on.
We'll get you out of here, pal.
You just stay right there.
Put your head right back there.
Hey!
What are you doing out here?
My son, he's stuck.
Well, let's get him out.
On 3.
1, 2...
Thank you.
Henry? Come on, son.
Okay.
Come on.
Stop.
Says he doesn't want you coming any closer.
Okay. Just tell us what your name is.
Nicholas.
Nicholas...
We have to get out of here.
Not until you let Drill out.
He's hovering right above him.
This is not happening!
You're not getting out of here!
Wes, he's moving closer.
Okay, stop. Just... Just talk to us.
Your husband...
uh, he's not a fan of cruises?
Excuse me?
Your wedding ring.
Oh.
Uh, he had to stay behind to work.
What's he do?
Why us?
You could get your energy from
other stars, other planets.
Why come here?
He says their future is dying.
And they need a new one.
But how can we give that to them?
He says you don't need
to worry about that now.
I don't want to do this any more.
I want to go home.
Okay, Nicholas. Listen to me.
Listen to me.
Everything is gonna be okay...
If you just do exactly
what I tell you to do.
What is he saying, Nicholas?
He says you never tell
the children the truth,
that things aren't gonna be okay.
We're just trying to protect them.
He says you don't even listen
to us... not like he does.
You're too busy playing
your own games with each other,
too busy to really love us.
But Drill loves us.
Nicholas, I need you to listen to me now.
Drill says you're good at tricking kids.
No. No, that's not true.
I am just trying to help you, Nicholas.
He says you can't even help your own son...
that he's the one who
gave Henry his hearing back,
and that he can make Henry love him again
when he tells him what you did,
what the two of you did.
You stay away from Henry!
Drill, my head feels funny.
We need to stop this.
Wes?
No! What are you doing?!
He's starting the possession, Wes.
It's... it's so hot.
Aah! It's so hot! It's burning!
Please make it stop! Drill,
you say you love them, but you don't.
You wouldn't do this to someone that
- you love.
- I'm burning! I'm burning!
Sir, you need to turn the grid back in.
- He's gonna take the kid.
- I can't do that, Wes.
Do you understand what that means?
Burning! It means we end this.
Ow! Please, make him stop! Drill, stop it!
Mr. President, I know you're seeing this!
This is not who we are.
We can't do it this way.
Sir, we may not get another shot.
This is our chance to destroy the enemy.
- Yes, at what cost?
- "At what cost?"
We make these decisions every day, Wes.
As difficult as this sacrifice is,
it's ultimately a small price,
when you consider...
if you think this comes at
a small price, you're wrong.
- Wes, we can't let this happen.
- I know.
Mr. president, before
you were commander in chief,
you were a father. You are a father.
And Nicholas, he has a father...
a father who you will
have to face and explain why
you allowed his son to die.
For that father, there will be no solace.
So for that, I assure you
this is no small price.
Let Drill go. Please.
Please! Please stop!
We will find another way.
Open up the grid.
Mr. President, I have to advise you...
that's an order.
Okay, okay. Okay, okay.
Okay. Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
This is not over.
You hear me?
I will hunt you down.
I will destroy you.
Mark my words, you will never win!
Are you okay?
I can't thank you enough.
Oh, I'm not gonna take your money.
- Please.
- No, y... You needed a helping hand.
That's all I offered.
Oh.
I was worried you were gonna be
some crazy killer or something.
I'm sorry.
- Well, I'm happy to allay your fears.
- Thank you.
Bye-bye. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
Okay.
Made it home, buddy.
Go turn some lights on.
- Hey, dad?
- Yeah?
I never got a chance to thank
the man who helped us.
I told him we'd call in the morning.
It just goes to show you, when you need it,
people will come to the rescue.
Come on.
You think I made the wrong call?
May I be frank, sir?
I'd expect nothing less.
I don't think you made the wrong call.
I know you made the wrong call.
And now that he knows we're after him,
there's no telling what he might do.
And that, sir... That is on you.
I'll be home soon.
Okay.
They're home safe.
Good.
How's Nicholas?
They think he's gonna be fine.
You need to take that.
Yeah.
Goodnight, Wes.
Goodnight, Claire.
- Wes?
- Hi, honey.
Oh, thank God. I was so worried.
You girls far out?
No. No, Minx and I, we changed our minds.
We're home.
Lena, I...
Okay.
Come home.
Okay, bye.
Ice cream sundaes coming up.
Sean.
Minx?
Hey, what are you doing out here?
Minx? Minx?
Lena?
No. No.
Baby? Baby?
Okay. It's okay.
Hey, hey, it's okay.
It's okay.
It's gonna be okay. All right. Okay.
I'm sorry.