Is that him?
Yes.
Oliver!
God be with you, Oliver.
And you too, John.
This is Henry Ireton, a good friend.
Good day to you, sir. Mr. Ireton.
I've just been taking
a last look at my land.
We had heard you were leaving, Mr.
Cromwell. We came from London directly.
You could have saved yourself
the effort, Mr. Ireton.
If we could discuss
it, Oliver, I'm sure-
There is nothing to discuss, John.
Well, come back to my house.
You've got a long journey back.
You must forgive the manner
of our table, Mr. Pym.
Our best crockery is
packed for the voyage.
Bridget, fetch the bread. Yes, Mother.
We had hoped to persuade your husband
to change his mind about
going to America, ma'am.
I should have thought you would know
Oliver better than that, Mr. Pym.
It was not an easy decision, John.
This is my country, my land.
God has been good to me here.
Then, sir, why are you leaving?
I have a family, Mr. Ireton.
I owe it to my sons to
make a better life for them.
England is no longer a
country for a young man.
I recall you often spoke out
strongly in Parliament for the rights
and privileges of the common people.
Ah.
That was a long time ago, Mr. Ireton.
I had a vision then.
A great nation.
Prosperous, God-fearing,
good laws, strong,
respected throughout the world.
That was the England I dreamed of.
Well, sir, you are a squire
now, a man of property.
Perhaps you no longer
care for the common people.
Perhaps I've been misinformed, sir.
I thought, as a Puritan, you
would see it as your God-given duty
to do the Lord's work in this
land, regardless of sacrifice.
Mr. Ireton, I was fighting for
the liberty of the common people
when you were in knee breeches.
Then why are you leaving?
I am leaving because this country
crawls with greed and corruption.
It is governed by
adventurers and profiteers
who think more of their
pockets than their principles.
I am leaving, sir, because we have a
king who taxes the rich beyond its means
and steals land from
the poor to maintain
his lavish court and his Catholic wife.
Now, when Parliament objected
against these injustices
he closed his Parliament down.
And our man dare not speak his
mind for fear of imprisonment.
Oh, yes.
All my life I believed it was God's
work to fight against such tyranny.
But God has turned his back upon
this nation, and we are leaving it.
And what if Parliament should
be recalled, Mr. Cromwell?
And why should a king do
that? He needs money, Oliver.
What? To build another palace? No.
To fight a war.
A war, John?
A war against whom?
The Scots have assembled
and army on our border.
They may invade us at any moment.
The king needs money to raise an army.
Ah.
By the king's own decree, Parliament
has not sat these past 12 years.
And now the king needs money.
Once Parliament has assembled,
it will lie within our power to change
the whole structure of
government in this country.
John, how many times did we sit
in Parliament in the old days
and how many resolutions did we pass?
And how many times did
this king overrule us?
Oh, the king can have
his war with Scotland.
We will be in America. There
will be a war, Mr. Cromwell,
but it will not be with Scotland. Henry.
With whom, Mr. Ireton?
Henry, we have argued
this matter many times.
I'm convinced of it.
A war against whom, Mr.
Ireton? Against the king, sir.
The king?
You mean a civil war? In England?
You know not the ways of this nation, Mr.
Ireton. Such things do not happen here.
And in my opinion, it is long overdue.
I will not have such talk in my house.
It is common enough
talk these days, I fear.
Then it is treasonable talk! And
I will not have it in my house!
I mark the time when you were much against
the king and never feared to say so.
In truth, there is much in
this king that does offend me.
Yet, with all, I would not take up arms against
him, and I would oppose any move to do so.
In such a cause, our swords
will be in God's hands.
It's an odd thing, Mr. Ireton. Every man
who wages war believes God is on his side.
I warrant God should often wonder
who is on his. Good evening, sir.
Well, if I did give you
offence, sir, I beg your pardon.
You're a young man, Mr. Ireton. It's fitting
a young man should want to change the world.
Not the world, sir. Only England.
With a civil war.
Good evening, Mrs. Cromwell.
Good evening, Mr. Ireton.
I'll get your cloak, Mr. Ireton.
I hope you'll forgive him.
Goodbye, John.
God be with you, Oliver.
You've no right to do
this. Leave them animals be.
This is the common land.
Any man who raises a hand against
the king's men will be arrested.
You have no right to do
this. This land is ours.
Well, now it belongs to
the Earl of Manchester.
By whose authority?
By the authority of the king.
Then I say the king is a thief!
You're under arrest. Take him away!
Bastards! Look at him,
now. What's he done?
He's done nothing. Release that man!
Who the devil are you?
This man works for me.
Whatever he has done, I will
take full responsibility.
He has spoken treason against the king.
Will you take responsibility for that?
The rights to pasture
belong to the common people.
By what authority, Lord
Manchester, do you take that away?
By the authority of His
Majesty's commissioners,
granting me and my friends full rights to
this land for the purpose of improvement.
Such a contract cannot be legal. It is
in violation of the law of this land.
As a magistrate, you should know
the king is the law of this land.
On the contrary, my Lord Manchester. It
is the king's duty to maintain the law.
This is common land. It
belongs to the people.
This is my land, and
you are trespassing.
It's only out of respect for your rank I don't
have you arrested for obstructing the law.
Captain Lundsford! My lord?
See that no unauthorized
person enters this area.
Yes, my lord. Remove these people.
Good morrow to you, squire.
Good morrow, Mrs. Cromwell.
Squire, have you news of my husband?
It's in God's hands, Mrs. Carter.
And in the king's. Aye.
PRIEST: Let us pray.
Almighty God, look down upon this
thy house and we, thy humble servants.
Grant us the spirit of thy grace
through Jesus Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
Who has done this?
Answer me. Who has done
this? An edict, squire,
from the archbishop himself
and by order of the king.
By order of the king.
Is the Church of England
not a Protestant church?
Would the king turn the house
of God into a Roman temple?
Mr. Cromwell, I beseech you.
Does the king think that God
can be bought with gold,
trinkets and gilded rubbish?
I know only that I have been instructed.
Has this king forgotten the Reformation?
Mr. Cromwell-
Away with it.
Popish idolatry!
Did the Lord not say unto Moses:
"Thou shalt not make unto
thyself any graven image
nor bow down to them"?
Has this king forgotten
the Spanish Inquisition?
Is the Roman Catholic Church
to have a seat in Westminster?
Oh, my God.
My God. Oh, my God!
Goddamn this king.
King's guard, attention!
Here we are, my lord.
That'll do, damn it.
I'm not a damned cripple.
Me sticks, where are me
sticks? Come over here, boy.
Here they are, my lord.
Give me the damned things.
And who the devil are you? Edward Hyde.
Let's in to His Majesty. Where is he?
He's at prayers, my lord. Aye.
He might do well to pray and
all. We're gonna need some help.
First the Irish and now the Scots.
You doesn't turn your
back on either of them.
Let us give thanks to our mighty God,
that he has seen fit to bless this table
with the fruits of his bounty. In the
name of our Lord, Jesus Christ, amen.
Amen.
I did remark, madam, with some distress
that His Highness, Prince Charles,
was absent from prayers this morning.
He was with me, my lord.
He did pray with you? In your chapel?
Yes, my lord. I am most displeased.
It is not fitting that
a future king of England
should make his devotions
in a Catholic chapel.
Your private beliefs are respected.
But this is a Protestant country
and as head of both church and state, it is
my God-given duty to see that it so remains.
His Highness found the whole business
so boring, my lord, that he fell asleep.
Didn't you, Charles? Yes, madam.
I believe you will find your
church as solid as ever, my lord.
Nevertheless, you will kindly
see that it does not happen again.
Yes, my lord.
Your Majesty, the Earl of
Strafford awaits your pleasure.
My good Lord Strafford,
welcome back to England.
Thank you, my lord.
Your Majesty. Your Royal Highness.
Most noble sovereign.
A chair for his lordship.
Thank you, my lord.
I'm sorry to see you in pain.
It is the agues from the bogs of
Ireland, my lord. Godforsaken place.
Saving your presence, my lord bishop.
We would not have summoned you, Lord
Strafford, had the situation here
not been of a greatest urgency.
You've doubtless heard that the Scottish
rebels are marching on Newcastle?
Aye, my lord.
You will whip these
barbarians to their senses.
But what of Ireland, my lord? We'll
deal with Ireland in good time.
You'll march an army on
Scotland. Army. What army?
Most of your army lies rotting
beneath the bogs of Ireland.
What's left of it is hard-pressed
to keep law and order.
Then we will raise a second army.
I fear Your Majesty may find
that easier said than done.
What? I guarantee I could raise
3000 men under arms inside a month!
But could you guarantee
their loyalty, my lord?
Is there an Englishman living
who wouldn't draw a sword
against his king's enemies?
There would be many
Englishmen, my Lord Strafford,
who would more readily draw
swords against the king.
My God, who is this jackanapes that mouths
such treason in your presence, my lord?
You've been away a long time, Strafford.
Much here has changed.
Aye, I can see it has.
I fear Sir Edward but speaks the truth.
To put an effective army in the field against
the Scots will cost almost a million pounds.
The Crown does not
have a million pounds.
Are we just going to sit
here then and do nothing?
Then I will summon Parliament and
instruct them to provide money.
Parliament?!
The king of England go cap in hand
to the common people, like a-?
A beggar. Aye! A beggar?
I have no choice. I say take the money.
You, my lord, are absolved before God
and before man from any such action.
For in extreme necessity, the king is
acquitted from all rule of government
and can do all that his power permits.
Power? Where is the power
of a king without an army?
I'll warrant you, I'll raise an army.
We'll reduce this kingdom
to submission in one summer!
Do you mean, sir, that I should
declare war on my own people?
Aye!
Before they declare war on you.
Well, sons, there it is.
Parliament House.
Upon that place rests all
the hopes of this nation
for a settlement of its ills in peace.
Do you think it could
come to war, Father?
Well, Oliver, when men run out of words,
they reach for their swords.
Let's hope we can keep them talking.
The king demands
money to raise an army.
This House demands
redress for grievances.
Grievances which the past 12 years have
laid heavy upon the nation. I say that-
Might I be heard? I say, therefore,
this House is resolved that we'll vote...
Welcome back to Parliament.
...no money for the king!
Order! Order!
Neither will we take up arms against
our Scottish brethren, unless...
Unless this Parliament
is allowed to function
as the true voice of
the people of England.
And not as a gathering
of lackeys to the king.
Sir Edward Hyde, Your Majesty.
Well, Sir Edward? Your Majesty.
I believe the House will
grant a loan to the Crown.
But only on certain conditions.
Conditions? What do
you mean, conditions?
What are these conditions, Sir Edward?
In essence, sire,
that the Crown relinquishes
all authority over Parliament.
And who put forward this proposal?
John Pym, Henry Ireton, John Hampden.
The Puritans.
They were well supported, my lord.
And they call themselves Englishmen?
My God, it's enough to make
a man deny his birthright.
Yet, withal, they still be Englishmen.
They make a mockery of the Crown!
They abuse the privilege of free
speech with sedition and treason.
You're too loud, Lord Strafford.
It is most unpleasant to the ear.
So it has come to this, my lord.
That you now bargain for your
Crown. What would you have me do?
Arrest every man who
opposes me? Hang them?
Would you rather make a
gift of the Crown of England
to the rabble in the street?
It lies beyond my power to arrest
a citizen without proper charges.
Charges are immaterial.
Such an act would subvert the
fundamental laws of this land, madam.
Such an act might save the
Crown of England, my lord.
I've governed this country
justly and fairly these 12 years
without reference to any Parliament.
You may be assured, I do not intend
now to be schooled in my high office
by illiterate farm hands, cobblers
and basket weavers.
My Lord Strafford, you will
rid us of these troublemakers:
Pym, Ireton, all of them.
I'll arrest every one of
them, my lord. As you will.
I shall need a warrant.
That is imperative.
And what will the charges be, my lord?
You're an experienced officer
of the Crown, Strafford.
You do not need to be instructed by me.
Mr. Speaker.
May I have permission
to address the House?
By all means, sir. Gentlemen.
A matter has come to my notice,
which is of deep concern to me
and will, I am sure, be to every
single member of this House.
The Earl of Strafford has, this
day, put his hand to a warrant
for the arrest and impeachment of myself
and four other honourable
members of this House
upon a charge of high treason.
Though Strafford's hand
be upon this warrant,
I see in this business, not the hand
of Strafford, but that of the king.
My lords!
I beseech you, do not
condemn this king too hastily.
For I am persuaded he has been
ill-advised upon this course.
Is not a king to be judged by
those from whom he seeks counsel?
He is not!
It is not the function of this House
to sit in judgement upon this king.
The fault lies with those very people
from whom the king has sought counsel.
I therefore move that this House demands
the arrest and impeachment
of the Earl of Strafford
upon a charge of high treason
against the people of this nation.
Silence! Order!
The motion has been proposed.
Let it be put now to the question.
Is the motion agreed? MEN: No!
In favour of the motion?
Aye! Aye! Aye!
The ayes have it.
I think my Lord Strafford's condition
will soon be far happier than mine.
Do you see, madam?
Do you see now what you've made me do?
Gentlemen, His Majesty.
Pray be seated.
Your coming is nothing if not timely.
My Lord Strafford's head
has but barely fallen.
Now, gentlemen, it is for you to speak.
Your Majesty, you see here the
leaders of all parties of the House.
And though we be divided on many
issues, we are of one accord.
In that we place above all
else, our allegiance and loyalty
to our most gracious sovereign.
For which reason we are deeply anxious
for a settlement of the
differences between us.
I share your sentiment, Sir Edward.
The issue be this, my lord.
Parliament is persuaded that without
the right to govern this nation
by the will of the people
and with God's guidance,
we be not a Parliament at all.
And that unless some constitutional
reformation be brought about,
we would as well go back to our
homes and our farms as pursue this
mockery of a government one more day.
In short, Mr. Pym, you're asking me
to relinquish my sovereign
power over Parliament.
It does amount to that, Your Majesty.
I do swear that I hold
this England and its laws
dearer to my heart than any here.
But gentlemen, if you were to reduce
me to a figurehead, a puppet king
manipulated by Parliament, how
then would I serve my country?
What manner of king would I be?
I am persuaded, Your Majesty,
that England must move forward to a
more enlightened form of government
based upon a true
representation of a free people.
Such an institution is
known as democracy, sir.
A democracy, Mr...? Cromwell, sir.
Democracy, Mr. Cromwell,
was a Greek drollery
based on the foolish notion that
there are extraordinary possibilities
in very ordinary people.
It is the ordinary people, my lord, who
would most readily lay down their lives
in defence of your realm.
It is simply that being ordinary,
they would prefer to
be asked and not told.
You know, as I do, that even as we sit
here, the Scots rebels are invading this land
and not an English sword is raised against them.
I beg you, therefore, let us bury our differences
in defence of both
our church and kingdom.
The Scots invade our land
and all is urgency and alarm.
In the past 12 months our Irish
colonists have been slaughtered,
our churches desecrated,
our clergy persecuted.
The Crown has been oddly reluctant
to defend our church and
kingdom over there, sir.
By my guard, I would as soon
take up arms against Rome
than against the Scots.
Would you have me declare war
on the entire Catholic
world, Mr. Cromwell?
It is your duty to
defend our church, sir.
We are speaking now of a
matter of international policy.
Is Your Majesty sure that it's not
a matter of domestic expediency?
Come, sir! I would remind you, sir,
that you are addressing your king.
Mr. Cromwell, you are impertinent.
Such issues are beyond
good manners, sir.
Catholicism is more than a
religion, it is a political power.
Therefore, I am led to believe
there will be no peace in Ireland
until the Catholic Church is crushed.
Your Majesty.
These gentlemen
are from the Parliament.
Your Majesty, Parliament
has drawn up this document
in which are set out
our main grievances.
It is our belief that
the demands made here
are only those that are just and lawful
and in the best interests
of both Crown and kingdom.
I shall examine these proposals
most carefully, Mr. Pym.
Gentlemen.
It is not too late, my lord.
You have the power still.
And with God's help, the
strength to use that power.
Oh, my dearest Charles.
I married you as a king and as a man.
I beseech you, do not
disappoint me in either aspect.
"This House has time and again
expressed its wholehearted
loyalty to the Crown.
Yet...
doth Parliament await
in vain for a gesture... "
The king is coming with a warrant to
arrest you, John Hampden, Henry Ireton,
Sir Arthur Haselrig and Oliver
Cromwell under charge of high treason.
I suggest you leave immediately.
"- that if the issues that
divide the king from his country
be not soon resolved, then these
issues may soon divide the nation. "
The king is coming with
a warrant for our arrest.
What? We must leave at once.
Oliver, your name is on it.
Come!
My lords! My lords!
Gentlemen! The king comes.
He comes with 100 men-at-arms.
The doors! The doors! Bolt the doors!
Stand aside, gentlemen,
if you please. MAN: Halt!
Open in the name of the king!
Mr. Speaker.
Gentlemen, you must pardon this
infringement of your privilege
but I will not detain you long.
Mr. Speaker, I must make
bold with your chair.
I have here a warrant for the
arrest of five members of this House.
John Pym, Henry Ireton, John Hampden,
Oliver Cromwell and Sir Arthur Haselrig
upon a charge of treason.
I see that the birds have flown.
Mr. Speaker, where are these gentlemen?
May it please Your Majesty,
I have neither eyes to
see nor tongue to speak
except as this House gives me leave.
Well, sir, I have eyes. I
see that one of them is here.
Captain.
Take him!
Any action against a member of
this House is a breach of privilege.
I move this House
declares as public enemies
any who lay hands upon its members.
And I further move...
I further move that any such
action against this House
be considered a crime against the people
and treason against this nation.
So be it.
Mr. Speaker, you will inform
the members of this House
that their presence is no
longer required by the nation.
This Parliament is, by my
authority, terminated, dissolved.
Your Majesty!
Are you aware that by your
action in this House today
you may have pushed this nation
to the brink of civil war?
Now do we see
in what contempt this king
holds this House and this nation?
It be either your king
or your Parliament.
Honourable members,
the decision is yours.
But I beseech you, in the
name of God, think well on it.
Fairfax.
Gentlemen.
I move that this House demand
the control of the militia
and that this country be put in
an immediate posture of defence.
Mr. Speaker.
My lords.
Honourable members. This nation
is now in a state of civil war.
And let us pray that God in
his mercy will give us strength
in this terrible and most unhappy hour.
Morning, William.
Give you good day,
squire. Why the coffin?
If it be God's will I die, squire, then
I would have a decent Christian burial.
Let's hope it doesn't come to that,
William. I need you in the farm.
Hello, Father. Father.
Morning. Where's your sword, Richard?
I have no sword, Father.
You must get one and wear it.
It's a mark of your rank, captain.
Yes. MAN: God bless thee!
Hallelujah, hallelujah, brethren.
It is the Lord's work we do this day!
The Lord's work- This
is no place for you, Hugh,
though you be welcome.
I've consulted God on
this matter, Mr. Cromwell.
I asked him, "Lord,
whose side are you on?"
And he answered me, saying, "On
the side of truth and justice. "
So here I am.
Company, forward!
MEN SINGING: Lift up your
heads ye gates of brass
Ye bars of iron yield
And let the king of glory
Pass the crosses in the field
That banner brighter
Than the star that
leaves A trail of light
Greetings, Uncle.
'Tis a fair day for a
fight. Where be the enemy?
My lords, I present my nephew.
His Highness, Prince Rupert,
Count Palatine of the Rhine.
My lords, I give you
greetings. LORDS: Your Highness.
And good Cousin Charles,
most noble Prince of Wales.
How fare you, young sir? I
am well, thank you, cousin.
So let us to action. For
I do swear by this sword
that within a week we will have severed
every round head from its shoulders!
Well said, Your Highness.
Let the standard be raised.
Get those guns moving!
Thou shalt proclaim his life
Though granted...
Halt!
Where the devil are we?
Edgehill, my lord, over there.
Morning, Robert. Morning, Edward.
Damn me, they've got
a lot of fellows there.
Where's Cromwell?
Approaching now, my lord.
Morning, Cromwell. Morning, my lord.
Your men fit, colonel?
My men are ready, my lord.
You seem damned eager to get
into this business, Cromwell.
We all enter this reluctantly,
but the die is cast.
Is that not so, Lord
Essex? You are right.
Well, to your position. Let no
man move except upon my signal.
And may God look
kindly upon us this day.
Amen to that.
Missed my breakfast. Damned
tricky things, stomachs.
God be with you, men.
God bless you.
God be with you. Take
care of yourself, William.
The Lord'll take care of
me, squire. Have faith, John.
I have, squire. Come on,
lads. Look to your muskets.
Have your muskets at
the ready. Come on, now.
Father. May God take
care of you, Richard
and be with you, Oliver.
And with you too, Father.
"O Lord, defend our cause
against the face of the enemy.
Save us from the violence
of the enemy. O Lord of hope,
fight for us that we may glorify thee. "
O Lord, God of mercy.
Put thy strength in our hands this day.
Give not the battle to the
strong, but to the righteous.
And be thou, O merciful God,
our saviour and mighty deliverer.
Defend me from them
that rise up against me.
In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.
Amen.
Amen. Amen.
Father, look. It's Lord Essex.
Come, cousin.
Let's take a good look at
these Roundheads. Your Majesty.
God's teeth, have we not
parleyed enough these past months?
Well, Essex, are you prepared?
We are. Shall we begin at 10?
Make it 9, my lord.
I'm positively starving.
Then in God's name, let's to it.
It is agreed then, 9:00. And
by my faith, which I have not,
I swear that within the hour, this
field will be strewn with English dead.
If this be so, they will have
been killed by Englishmen.
For we have not seen fit to import
foreign mercenaries into our ranks.
I will mark you well for that
insult, sir. Be on your guard!
Colours to the rear!
The Lord is our
strength. Praise the Lord!
What in the name of
God are we waiting for?
Ireton!
I thought we came here to do battle.
We're waiting for the appointed time.
The appointed time?
Colonel Hampden, commence firing! Fire!
What the devil is that fool doing?
Artillery, commence firing!
Fire!
O Lord, thou knowest how
busy I must be this day.
If I forget thee, do not thou forget me.
Fire!
You'd better send Fairfax in. Mm.
Bugler, sound the charge.
Troop at the gallop.
Advance!
Signal Astley to advance.
Bugler, sound the advance.
The sport begins.
Tallyho!
Troops rear left. At a gallop, charge!
Give fire!
Advance!
Fire!
Advance pike!
Charge pike!
Fire! Second rank forward!
At the gallop!
It's getting too damned
close for my liking.
Sound general retreat.
My lord, why in the name of
Christ did you sound the retreat?
Colonel, you've countermined my orders
once today. You'll do as you're told, sir.
Hold your ground, in the name of God!
Hold your ground!
Well, Uncle, did you ever see a
quarry so swiftly put to flight?
The king will forever keep this
field and this day's service
in grateful remembrance.
Come nightfall, we shall bury our dead.
And then, by God, we
shall bury this army.
With such pitiful men in our ranks, it
were better this war were never fought.
Not a drop of English blood
soiled this English land.
It's a bad officer who
blames his men, Cromwell.
I blame them not, my lord,
for they are simple men.
But what match are farmer's
boys against gentlemen's sons?
The battle is not yet lost, Cromwell.
This battle were lost
before it began, my lord.
And in like manner, so will this war.
In the morning, I'm
returning to Cambridge.
If you desert the field,
I'll have you arrested.
This war will not be won
with untrained ploughmen,
apprentices, old, decaying serving men.
We need men with fire in their bowels
who fear the Lord, but not the enemy!
As God is my witness, I am resolved
that this battle will be won.
Therefore, it's my intention
to return to Cambridge,
and raise an army of handpicked men,
the like of which this
nation has never seen!
With or without your
permission, my Lord Manchester.
Bristol will not be permitted to fall.
It is our only seaport in the west,
and if General Goring is
incapable of holding it,
then I will dispatch someone who can.
I've a mind to see Bristol, my
lord. It is a fair city, I hear.
Then I shall place Bristol in your command,
nephew. Now, my lord general, should our forces-
Your Majesty. Yes, what is it?
News of Cromwell's army, Your Majesty.
Come forward. At last, Old
Ironsides ventures forth.
Well, speak, man.
They're about six miles
away, Your Majesty.
Just south of Naseby.
By my reckoning, there be
about 1000 horse and 2000 afoot.
And what news of Manchester's army?
I saw no other army, Your Majesty.
Was not Cromwell to join
Manchester's forces at Naseby?
That was our intelligence, Your Majesty.
Then Manchester be still in Lincoln.
So Cromwell comes with his
army of 3000 to our 7000.
By your leave, Uncle. Your Highness.
General Astley, sound the alert.
I want every man in full
battle order at once.
By God, we have him!
Manchester!
Where in the name of Christ is he?
Know you not we are at war?
In God's name I do swear we
fight this war single-handed.
Oliver.
What bloody treachery is this?
We came to meet Manchester and
instead we find the king's army.
Well, I shall take on the king.
And after that if needs must,
I'll take on Manchester as well!
Before you stands the enemy,
his three to every one of us.
And where, in God's name, is Manchester?
My Lord Manchester will rue the
day he has not joined us here.
And now to your positions.
These tactics we have practiced
often enough these past six months
now let us put them to the test.
For upon this field of Naseby, we'll
turn the tide of this unhappy war.
God be with you all.
Is this wise, Oliver?
We're heavily outnumbered.
Was not Gideon outnumbered
by the Amalekites?
It is not numbers that
count, but speed and surprise.
Let no man move, except upon
the word of his commander!
Though we be outnumbered,
we shall win this battle!
I promise you!
So now put your faith in
God and keep your powder dry.
Halt!
Attack order. Double line abreast.
Forward. MAN: Forward!
The man must be mad.
Prepare to attack.
Prepare to attack!
Our swords are in God's hand.
And our faith is in the Lord.
Charge!
Fire!
Forward!
Colonel!
Regroup! Regroup!
After them!
Advance!
To the rear!
Forward!
Come on, lads!
At the gallop!
Your Majesty, may I
suggest that we withdraw?
No.
Who goes there?
RICHARD: Captain Cromwell, 3rd Cavalry.
Richard.
Thanks be to God.
Where is Oliver?
The outrageous incompetence
and inefficiency
of the high command
have tried my patience
and that of my hard-pressed
army long enough.
By my faith, I swear it would be
better that those gallant generals
Essex and Manchester, took
up swords with the king.
For then might we be assured of victory.
Hear, hear.
For by their reluctance to pursue
this war with the intensity it demands,
they have proved treacherous both
to our cause and to this nation.
Hear, hear.
If we beat the king 99 times,
he will still be our
king and we his subjects.
If he beats us but once,
we shall all be hanged.
If that is so, then why
in the bowels of Christ
did we take up arms against
him in the first place?
Gentlemen,
honest men have served us faithfully
and many have died
that this House may sit in freedom
and this nation live in liberty.
In the name of God, I beseech you,
do not desert them now.
Unless Parliament supports
this war to the full,
I am bound to say, in all conscience,
that I will lay down my sword
and let this House make
its peace with the king,
be that peace ever so base.
Then, it is for this House to decide.
I move that this House demands
the immediate resignation
of the high command
upon the grounds that
they be no longer competent
to command the armed
forces of this Parliament.
Order. Order. Order!
The motion has been proposed.
Let it now be put to the question.
Those against Cromwell's
motion. MEN: No!
Those in favour of the motion. MEN: Aye!
The ayes have it. The motion be carried.
I move...
I move that Colonel
Cromwell be appointed
commander in chief of the army.
Yeah!
Bristol. We must dispatch aid to
Bristol with all possible speed,
for as long as Rupert holds
Bristol, this war be not lost.
General Digby, if you can
detach your forces in this area
and approach Bristol
from the east-
To do that, my lord, would be to
expose this city to immediate attack.
Then we move the Marquis
of Huntly's army southward.
The marquis, my lord, surrendered
to Cromwell's forces yesterday.
Cromwell. I hear nothing
but Cromwell, Cromwell.
My lord, it is but a game we play here,
a game with wooden
armies and paper flags.
'Tis but a block of wood
you hold in your hand.
My lords, all I ask for is a little
time. Time, my lord, costs us heavily.
If we can hold on here
in Oxford for six weeks,
the Scots have promised
an army of 20,000 men.
Her Majesty is in communication
with my cousin, the king of France,
and I have good reason to
hope for support from Ireland.
An army from Ireland, Your Majesty?
I would as soon join
forces with Cromwell himself
as take up arms with the Catholics!
I am the king and defender of my people
and I maintain the right to seek
relief from no matter what quarter.
As king, my lord, it is your God-given
duty to defend the faith of this nation.
I do what I think to be right, sir.
Catholics as allies! It is unthinkable!
My God, if it has come to this,
let us rather sue for an honourable
peace than fight a dishonourable war.
I will not countenance defeat.
Rather than abandon my
kingdom to Parliament,
I would come to terms
with the devil himself.
Since you came to the
throne, Your Majesty,
your armies have persistently
persecuted our Church in Ireland.
And yet, now that your need is
great, you turn to us for help.
The king's actions in
Ireland, Your Excellency,
will seem as nothing should
these Puritans come to power.
It is not only the Crown of England
that is in peril, Excellency.
All institutions of established order
throughout the countries
of Europe are threatened.
An Irish army of 20,000
men, even 15,000,
would forestall such a threat
and bring this wretched
war to a speedy end.
I am instructed to say that His Holiness
would permit an Irish force to
take up arms in this country.
But there are certain conditions.
First, the Catholic Church in
Ireland must be completely restored
and permitted to practice freely
without interference or oppression.
Secondly, all Protestant
churches in Ireland must be closed
and all Protestant bishops and
ministers removed from office.
Oh, there are one or two other minor
conditions of little consequence.
What you demand, Excellency,
would be a betrayal
of my coronation oath as
head of the English Church.
You have a duty, Charles, to the Crown.
For without that, you
will be head of nothing!
May I tell His Holiness that you
will agree to these conditions?
You have something to
say to me, Sir Edward?
Your Majesty, His Highness Prince
Rupert attends in the council chamber.
Rupert? Here in Oxford? Yes, my lord.
I fear Bristol has fallen.
Your Excellency will
excuse me. Your Majesty.
My lords, His Majesty.
Do you not rise, sir,
when your king approaches?
Rise, sir! Or to your knees in shame.
You did give me your most solemn promise
that you would hold
Bristol for four months.
Yet you have not held it for four weeks!
You promised mountains,
yet you perform molehills.
You make a knave of your king.
My lord,
we were besieged on all sides.
Our men are foot-weary from battle,
ailing with plague and sickness.
Yet you contrived to
escape with your life.
I have brought you an army, my lord.
An army 2000 strong, ready and
willing to fight on for their king!
In exchange for all the corn and stores
you held in Bristol and 200 cannon.
That was the price of your freedom, sir.
I did what I considered to be right!
You deserted your command, sir.
I made a military decision.
A decision that may
have cost us this war.
Your action in this matter is
of such affliction to me, sir,
that it is the greatest trial
that has yet befallen me.
My conclusion is
to desire you to seek subsistence
elsewhere, not in my kingdom.
Most gracious lord,
I do not crave forgiveness,
for by all as I hold most dear,
I do solemnly swear that
I acted only in good faith!
The matter is at an
end. I will hear no more.
My lord!
My lord, I beseech you.
In God's name, allow that I may die
with honour. Condemn me not to live.
Captain Lundsford.
Do not put upon these shoulders the
terrible shame of exile and dishonour.
I beg you, take my
life, most noble lord.
Good Uncle,
for pity's sake!
His Highness is to be
kept under close guard
until such time as he is deported.
Very well, Your Majesty.
Father, Mother says I'm to
go with her tonight to France.
Is that your wish, Father? Yes.
My duty is to stay here with
you and fight beside you.
Your place now is at your
mother's side, Charles.
You will help her raise
money, perhaps an army.
Should I meet my death, and
you are safely in France,
then England will still
have, in you, a lawful king.
You will go with your mother.
I love this land.
And when this great
responsibility becomes yours
then I pray that with God's help,
you will reign more
happily than I have done.
Now go, with God's speed
and your father's blessing.
Oh, Charles.
I love you.
Your Majesty, it is my most solemn
duty to place you under arrest.
By whose command, sir? By the
command of Parliament, sir.
I know of no authority in
England above that of the king.
It is upon that issue
that this war was fought.
Whither am I to be
taken? To London, sir.
You must grant me a little time
to- We leave for London at once.
And my children, what of them? We
will take care of your children.
His Majesty will have
all the time he requires.
As for your children, sir,
you may take them with you.
I thank you, sir.
PEOPLE SINGING: Him serve with fear
His praise foretell
Come ye before him
And rejoice
The Lord ye know
Is God indeed
Without our aid
He did us mak e
We are his flock
General, John Pym is dead.
And for his sheep
He doth us tak e
When did it happen? This morning.
What is it? John Pym is dead.
Parliament is discussing
peace terms with the king.
Does the army have no say in this?
The army has been ordered to disband.
In God's name, did we fight this war
that the politicians should
take over behind our backs?!
If Parliament has decided
the army will disband,
then the army will disband.
I say we take the army
and march on Parliament.
The sword will not rule this land.
We fought to institute
a parliamentary system
and overthrow the very
tyranny which you now propose.
And who is talking to
the king? Parliament?
I doubt it. I warrant I know
who is doing all the talking.
I have these past three days been in
consultation with His Majesty the king.
And I am pleased to inform the House
that the king is now prepared
to discuss peace terms
provided that the army stand down.
I have given this House's assurance
that his wishes will be complied with.
Further, in recognition
of the very great debt
this House owes its
commander, General Cromwell,
it is proposed to award him a
pension of 3000 pounds a year
together with certain estates
in the county of Cambridge.
It is further proposed that
the sum of 2000 pounds-
Such low treachery is not worthy
even of you, my Lord Manchester.
Am I to believe my ears?
Did this nation win a bloody civil war
in order the king should
dictate the terms of peace?
I have already discussed the matter
at great length with His Majesty-
You have discussed it? It is a
matter for this House to discuss.
Hear, hear!
The king will not come to terms,
sir, until the army stand down.
Hear, hear.
And the army will not stand down
until the king comes to terms.
So if the king will
not talk to this House,
then let the king talk to the army.
Out of the question. The
king would never agree.
Parliament is behind us, sir, and on
this occasion, we have the majority.
Sir Thomas Fairfax.
He's bringing in the
army! SPEAKER: Order! Order!
Order, I say!
Order! Silence! Order!
Order!
Silence!
I believe, my Lord Manchester,
that now I have the majority.
This is dictatorship. It
will mean a new civil war.
Order!
Honourable members,
I swear before my God that
you give me no alternative.
When those liberties for
which this army and this nation
have fought so hard are
most solemnly guaranteed
then this army will stand down.
And upon that, you have
my most sacred promise.
And who have we here? It is I, my lord.
You were supposed to have run,
Sir Edward, not let me catch you.
I'm afraid I'm getting a little
too old for such games, my lord.
Cromwell is here to see you. Oh.
You must play on your own now, children.
Your father has other games to play.
Prince Henry, you will be good
enough to give me back my hat.
Sir.
Gentlemen, His Majesty.
We came to present our terms, my lord.
If Your Majesty will be so kind
as to study these proposals.
Has Parliament approved this
treaty? Parliament no longer truly
represents the people of
this nation, Sir Edward.
And you, Mr. Cromwell,
do you truly represent
the people of this nation?
I represent the army, sir,
and the army is the heart
and conscience of the people.
So having failed to come
to terms with Parliament,
you would now negotiate with the king.
I am not bound to negotiate with anyone.
With 50,000 men under my command
I could impose a government
on this nation overnight.
One is given to wondering, Mr.
Cromwell, why you do not do that.
I am deeply convinced, my lord,
it be the duty of Parliament
to frame a constitutional
government, and not the army.
Then I do not see that you
have any need of me at all.
On the contrary, sir.
An England without a
king is unthinkable.
But withal, a king
that can command respect
a monarch who governs, not from fear,
but by the affection of a free people.
Such a king could reunite
this great nation of ours
and make the name of England
the noblest in all Christendom.
Should you adorn that
inheritance, my lord,
all Englishmen would be
proud to call you king.
Mr. Cromwell, I do confess
that I did greatly misjudge you,
for I did mark you as an ambitious man.
To these ends, my lord, I am ambitious.
Then you have my respect, sir.
Thank you, my lord.
We shall return in the morning, sir. I
shall require a little longer to study
this document. Perhaps a week.
As Your Majesty pleases.
I sincerely hope that our future
relations may be equally amiable, sir.
That is my hope also, my lord.
A cunning fellow.
I believe him to be a
sincere man, my lord.
Indeed.
If these proposals be acceptable,
there never was a Crown so
nearly lost, so easily recovered.
Whatever these proposals
may be, Sir Edward,
they are not acceptable to the king.
Cromwell has
betrayed us! CROWD: Aye!
We have given our blood and our lives
in this war to put down this king!
If Cromwell comes to terms with him now,
what price our freedom then?
Get back, will you?!
I have served General Cromwell
faithfully all my life,
and I reckoned him to be a man who
feared God and did honour his word!
But in this business he has shown
himself to be a man of no honour!
Aye!
We fought this war to remove this king,
not to put him back on the throne!
Aye! I say, let us march on London,
let us take Parliament,
and then let the king
try to negotiate with us!
Make way for Cromwell.
Traitors! Mutineers!
I don't have to tell you, any of
you, you could all be hanged for this.
We are not serfs,
general, nor mercenaries.
We fought for the Lord in our cause,
and now we have a right to speak.
You have no rights to
preach revolt and mutiny.
As for you, John Carter, I did expect
a greater degree of loyalty from you.
I am still loyal to what I fought
for, sir. Can the same be said of you?
I have not betrayed my God,
country, Parliament or my conscience.
Where was your conscience this day,
when you parleyed with the king?
I tell you, all of you,
I do most honestly believe that
we have taught this king a lesson.
And he will prove most honourable.
Upon that I would stake my life.
Traitor! Traitor!
This is a military camp,
sir, not a debating chamber.
Under military law, any man
inciting mutiny can be hanged.
Colonel Harrison. Yes, General.
These three men will draw lots.
One of them will be hanged.
Captain Lancing, get a
length of rope. Yes, sir.
You, man. Yes, sir.
Pick up some straws.
General, there is a Sir
Edward Hyde to see you.
Sir Edward, has the king
considered our terms?
The king, sir, has not
even read your terms.
Nor, will I venture, has he
any intention of so doing.
He has, this day, drawn up a secret
treaty with Manchester and Essex
to raise a Scottish army
against the Parliamentary forces.
He has already consented to
a Catholic army from Ireland.
While you negotiate
a settlement with him,
he is planning a second civil war.
I do confess that I have these many
years given my allegiance to a man
not worthy of the
title, king of England.
Colonel Harrison!
I will have this king's head..
Aye, and the Crown upon it.
This obstinate king, this man of blood,
whose heart God has hardened,
can no longer be trusted.
For in prodigious treason, he has
revealed himself to be a traitor.
A man of no honour.
A man unfitted to bear
the title, king of England.
Hear, hear.
I demand, therefore,
in the name of the army
and the people of this nation
that Charles I, king of England,
be brought hence to stand trial
for his life on a charge of treason.
Oyez, oyez, oyez.
All manner of persons
having anything to do with this court,
come forward and give your attendance.
Every man to keep silence
upon pain of imprisonment.
God save the king.
Let the prisoner be brought in.
The clerk of arraigns
will read the charges.
"Charles Stuart, king of England,
you stand before this court
charged with high treason.
In that being admitted king of
England, and therein trusted with power
to govern according to the laws,
you did out of wickedness and design
erect and uphold in yourself an
unlimited and tyrannical power.
To rule at your will and overthrow
the rights and liberties of the people.
And that you did traitorously
and maliciously levy a cruel war
against Parliament and the people.
And are therefore guilty of all the
treasons, rapings, burnings, spoils,
desolations, damages and mischiefs to
the nation committed in the said war.
Thus, on behalf of
the people of England,
this court impeaches you as a tyrant,
traitor, murderer and public enemy
to the Commonwealth of England. "
God save the king!
Silence!
Sir, you have heard
the charges against you.
The court expects an answer.
First, I would know by what
authority, I mean lawful authority,
I am brought here and carried from
place to place, and I know not what.
And by what authority you
presume to sit in judgement on me.
Remember, I am your lawful king.
Think well upon it.
I have a trust committed to me
by God, by old and lawful descent.
Therefore, let me know by what
authority I am brought here,
and I shall answer.
It is not for the prisoner
to question the court.
I am no ordinary prisoner, sir.
An answer, sir, the
court demands an answer.
Then I refuse an answer.
Sir, you are before a court of justice.
Well, sir...
I see that I am before a power.
The court will keep silent.
Mr. Solicitor General, are
your witnesses prepared?
They are, my lord. Then
let them be brought forth.
Call Sir Edward Hyde.
And you saw the king and his
wife alone in their chambers
with this Catholic Archbishop Rinuccini?
I did.
And what did you assume was
the purpose of this meeting?
You are obliged to answer, Sir Edward.
To raise an Irish army, my lord.
To fight against the
Parliamentary forces?
And at this time, was
the king in communication
with any other foreign power?
Yes. Yes, with the king of
France and with the Dutch.
For the same purpose? Yes.
To raise a foreign army
to invade this country,
and to perpetuate the war against
the people of this kingdom.
Sir Edward?
Yes.
To the block with him!
Sir, throughout the three
days of this hearing,
this court has patiently
awaited your pleasure
to hear what you have to say in
answer to the charges against you.
Yet you have declined to speak.
I am most willing, sir, to
answer before Parliament,
but not before this assembly
whose authority I refuse to acknowledge.
Sir, what answers you may offer
the commons can be given here.
For this court does sit in the
name of the House of Commons.
Sir, if, as you have said, you do
love the liberty of the subject,
you will grant me, your king,
a hearing before Parliament,
which is the lords
and commons assembled.
Sir, I submit you seek only
to delay the course of justice.
By your favour, sir, I
seek only those rights
which, as your king, I would
grant to any one of my subjects.
Silence!
Sir, this court requires to
know if you have anything to say
before judgement is passed upon you.
I have nothing to say to you.
Then this court will
retire to judgement.
What ails thee? Art thou mad?
Have we come thus far that
you would betray us now?
There is nothing in the Constitution
of this land that entitles us
to bring a king to trial. Is he
not answerable to his subjects?
The trial is clearly
illegal, and I will have-
Is not the king
answerable to his subjects?
The king, sir, is
answerable only to God.
Then, by God, when he dies, he
shall have much to answer for.
We have gone too far in this matter.
This commission has no authority-
Our authority lies
with the Parliament, sir.
Parliament is
the law in this land.
If the charges against
this king be not proven,
what terrible retribution may
he not bring down upon our heads?
In the name of God!
What are we all? Men?
Cowering and quivering
like downtrodden serfs.
The king is not England,
and England is not the king!
It is not the survival of the
king that is at issue here.
It is the survival of England.
And this king, by his
dishonesties, by his treasons,
and by his secret treaties
with foreign powers,
has shown himself to be ill-fitted
to govern this great nation!
As God is my witness, Oliver,
I desire not the king's death,
but the settlement of
this nation in peace.
Do you think I don't desire that?
Go back to my farm and my family?
Very well. Go again to this king.
Offer him once more our terms.
Though God knows, he should be
well acquainted with them by now.
Tell him he may sit upon his throne,
but that this country will
be governed by Parliament,
and Parliament will be
elected by the people.
Now, Sir Thomas, if you can
achieve this where we have failed,
this trial will end.
Here is a warrant demanding
the death of the king
upon the charge of high
treason against this nation.
It will require all your
signatures. Sir Thomas.
I have come thus far with you,
Oliver, in our great cause...
but I will not sign this warrant.
Oliver, I cannot. Is
he guilty or not guilty?
He is the king. Is he guilty?
Yes. Sign it.
Charles Stuart, king of England...
you have been found
guilty of high treason
against the good people of this nation
represented in Parliament,
by whose authority
this court does sit
in judgement upon you.
Upon this charge, it is
the sentence of this court
that you be taken hence to an...
appointed place
and put to death by the severing
of the head from the body.
And that is the sentence
of the whole court.
Remove the prisoner. MAN: Silence.
Will you hear me a word, sir?
No, sir, you are not to
be heard after sentence.
By your favour, sir.
I know as much law as any man
here. I have the right to be heard.
No, sir. Guard! Remove your prisoner!
I demand to be heard!
I am your lawful king!
Blood for the traitor!
General. Sir Thomas.
I have been this past
night to the commissioners.
They have instructed
me to lay before you
this warrant for 40,000 pounds
in return for the king's life.
How little you know me that you
think you can buy my principles.
You insult me with that cheap bribe.
Will you not think on it?
I have thought on it. And well.
By my God, I have thought on it.
"Then the soldiers of the
governor took Jesus into the common hall.
And they stripped him and
put on him a scarlet robe.
And when they had platted a crown
of thorns, they put it upon his head.
And they bowed the knee
before him and mocked him
saying, 'Hail, king of the
Jews!' And they spit-"
Your Majesty. Is it time?
No, Your Majesty. Her Royal
Highness, the Princess Elizabeth,
and his Royal Highness, Prince Henry.
Elizabeth, sweetheart.
Don't grieve for me. Henry.
Now, both of you...
mark what I say.
They will cut off thy
father's head. Shh, there now.
Henry, pay careful
attention to what I say.
You must not let them make you king,
not while your brother
Charles is still alive.
I would be torn to pieces
first. That's my son.
Today, your brother will be king.
Elizabeth, now.
It's a glorious death to which I go.
Tell your mother...
that my love for her
was the same to the last.
And remember me in your prayers.
The king's escort,
Your Majesty. Thank you.
God bless you both.
What kind of morning is it, colonel?
Indeed it is somewhat
chilly, Your Majesty.
Then I was wise to
put on a second shirt.
For if I trembled with the cold, my
enemies would say it was from fear.
I would not expose
myself to such a reproach.
Please keep them. Oh, Your Majesty.
I do not fear death, Sir Thomas.
It is not at all terrible to me.
I thank my God I have prepared for it.
Are we to ride to Westminster, or walk?
My orders are that
we walk, Your Majesty.
Admirable. The morning
air will do me good.
The king's coming.
He's coming now. The king's
coming! Hey, you. Stop him!
Gentlemen, the king comes.
Traitor! MAN 2: Execute him!
Execute him!
And a true, urgent sword in our
hand. God bless, Your Majesty.
God bless you.
Escort, halt!
Well, gentlemen, are you afraid to
kill your king with an open face?
I will not delay you long,
but will say only this to you:
As God is my witness, I have forgiven
those that have brought me here
and pray that my death be
not laid to their charge.
For I do endeavour, even to the last,
to maintain the peace of my kingdom.
I go now
from a corruptible to
an incorruptible crown.
To everlasting peace.
Will that suffice?
Permit me, sir, that I may pray
a while before the blow is struck.
Then when I put out my hands so:
That will be the sign.
Lord, let us now, thy servant,
depart in peace according to thy word.
For mine eyes have seen thy salvation which
thou has prepared before the face of all people.
Glory be to the Father and to
the Son and to the Holy Ghost.
As it was in the beginning
is now and ever shall be.
Behold the head of a traitor!
We did not assassinate.
Nor was this thing done in a corner,
it was done in the face of God
and of all men.
The office of king is now
abolished. Long live Parliament.
Long live the Republic. MEN:
Aye, long live the Republic.
Richard, I want to go back to Cambridge.
Will you come with me,
son? If you wish, Father.
It will be peace and quiet there now.
God knows, my soul
craves a little peace.
You must not think on it, Oliver.
'Tis over now. The war, everything.
'Tis over and done.
Oliver, you're home now.
There's nothing more to think on.
Save that we two may grow
old together in peace.
Peace.
Father.
Henry Ireton is at the house
with some men from Parliament.
I'll be along shortly.
Tom.
Arthur.
Henry.
Well, you all seem solemn enough.
It is a solemn business
that brings us here, Oliver.
Well, speak of it.
The country needs a head of
state, Oliver. It must be governed.
Is it not governed by Parliament?
There must be a figurehead.
It is our tradition. The
country needs a king, Oliver.
God knows, you've said
so many times yourself.
The country will be ruled by Parliament.
Now, in the name of Christ,
how often must I say that?
And who will control Parliament?
The people, the people, the people!
It's not practical. It won't work.
It will work and it must work.
We are here, on behalf of
Parliament, to offer you the Crown.
To offer...
Me, king of England?
King Oliver I of England.
Elizabeth, tell me, do
you see before you a king?
This tired, sickening
man, this country oaf,
crude in speech and manner?
This rough fellow,
does he display the bearing of a king?
You are the one man who
can govern this country.
In the name of God,
did we cut the head off this
king only to steal his Crown?
This hollow golden ring,
this worthless trinket.
Give it to a whore for
the price of her bed!
If you would find a head to fit
it, let it adorn some court jester
or some strolling player that
he may play your king, but not I.
Power must be absolute,
or it be no power at all.
It was not for power that we did this
thing. Have you not understood that yet?
Now, Ireton, mark me, and mark me well.
That you be hard-set upon ambitious
courses has not escaped me,
and if you seek to use
me towards such ends,
though I love you like a brother,
I swear, I will destroy you.
Every freeborn Englishman, be
he the lowest of the lowest,
is entitled to a voice in
the governing of this country.
But there is no vote for the
poor, for the underprivileged,
no vote for all those who took up arms
to put down the very autocracy that
this Parliament now imposes upon us.
You did not vote this
Parliament into office.
This gaggle of buffoons, these villains!
Much has been said in this House
about the so-called inequity
of certain members being financially
involved in national projects.
Members have ascribed to this state
of affairs dark and sinister motives.
I say if we in Parliament cannot
gain from ruling the country,
there's really very little
point in our being here at all.
No member of this House should
be permitted to profit from his office.
Hear! Hear!
If this House knew its duty to the
nation, it would terminate its sitting
and let a new Parliament be elected.
Order! Gentlemen,
I move that this House
be given power to remain in office a
further three years without re-election.
In my opinion, a committee of inquiry
should be set up to investigate
the financial involvement
of certain members.
Order!
Mr. Speaker. May I have your
permission to address this assembly?
By all means, sir.
My lords, honourable members,
I have always desired, above
my life, a free Parliament
sitting by the authority of
the good people of this nation.
A Parliament open and
visible, to be seen by all men.
It is six years since I handed over
to you this great responsibility
in the hope that you would
make good and wholesome laws
which the people of this
nation expected of you.
I must confess to some
abatement of my hopes
for what has happened in my absence.
Instead of uniting the
good people of this nation
with righteousness and peace,
which would have been a glorious
and Christian thing to have done,
what do I find?
Anarchy, corruption,
division and dissatisfaction.
I say that the enemies of this nation
have flourished under your protection.
You were from the beginning
a provisional government
not truly representative of the people.
For have the people elected you?
Has this House gone once to the
people it purports to represent?
No, it has not! And after six years
of misgovernment, what do we find?
Sir Thomas Fairfax moves a bill
to give this House a further lease
of its worthless and dishonourable life!
Gentlemen, an immovable
Parliament is more obnoxious
than an immovable king!
You are drunkards, tricksters,
villains, whoremasters,
godless, self-seeking,
ambitious tricksters.
You are no more capable of
conducting the affairs of this nation
than you are of running a brothel!
You are scum, sir, and not
truly elected scum at that.
This is no Parliament. I shall
put an end to your sitting.
I hereby declare this
Parliament dissolved!
Colonel Harrison! Yes,
sir. Troops forward!
Rubbish.
Remove them! Come on, get them out.
This is dictatorship, sir! Dictatorship!
Dictator! Dictatorship!
This is illegal! Come, sir.
I refuse to quit this
chair. By your leave, sir.
Away with this bauble!
I seem to recall that
we cut off a king's head
for such as this.
You are a traitor, sir. It is the likes
of you who have turned my hand to this.
I have sought the Lord's guidance
night and day in this matter.
It is not idly done, for this
nation will be justly governed.
I will give this nation
back its self-respect.
We will walk in this world
with our heads held high.
I will liberate man's souls
from the darkness of ignorance.
I will build schools
and universities for all.
This will become the
golden age of learning.
I will bring the law within
the reach of every common man.
There'll be work and bread for all.
This nation will prosper
because it is a godly nation
and because we walk hand
in hand with the Lord.
I swear by the name of the living God
that I will see this nation
properly governed
if I have to do it myself.
Dear God, give me the
strength to do it...
alone.
Oliver Cromwell ruled the
nation as lord protector for five years.
In that short time, he raised
England to be a great power,
feared and respected
throughout the world.
Under his hand were laid the foundations
of a truly democratic nation.
In 1658, he died.
Three years later, Charles,
prince of Wales, was crowned king
and a monarch sat once more
upon the throne of England.
But an England never
to be the same again.