Long ago...
...the Medicine Game was given to the people
of the Haudenosaunee...
...to entertain the Creator.
Ooh.
Holy stick work!
Somebody better mail that guy's helmet
back from Syracuse.
Outlet pass and Coventry Academy is pulling
off another dominating coast-to-coast play.
Another goal for Coventry Academy!
All-Star middie Clay Watson
just obliterated a Sunaquot defender.
- Chewy, take him out!
- How did you miss that?
- Are you all right?
- I can't move it.
Let's bring it in.
And at halftime, the defending champs
lead the overmatched Sunaquot, eight to three.
It's game one of the season
and it's time for this team to tap out.
If anyone's still listening, please enjoy
this commercial-free intermission...
...as we still have no sponsors, here on
the Bryan Sports Broadcasting Network...
...the number one and only radio show
covering upstate prep school lacrosse...
...and streaming live on BSBN.com.
All right, guys, bunch up.
Listen, they are a very good team.
But we can be too.
We have got to bring our minds
together as one.
- Chewy, you gotta move your feet.
- I do move my feet. They move theirs faster.
Reed, you can stop some shots
if you take a step toward the shooter.
- Cut down the angle.
- I was protecting my backside.
This ain't dodgeball, moron.
Your job is to try and get hit.
And your job is to pass the ball, Jimmy.
Owen was wide open
when you got your ass handed to you.
Oh, whipped.
Owen. Sammy. Enough.
Starters, get ready for the second half.
We'd be better off scrimmaging
our middle-school team.
But I'm not gonna let today go to waste.
In the second half,
I want you all using your weak hands.
But don't you let up. Not for one second.
Remember who we are.
Scared to go back?
- I'm hurt.
- Your feelings or your shoulder?
- A kiss would fix both.
- Ha.
Ah!
- Toby, you're in.
- Me?
At attack.
- Against Coventry?
Okay...
Number 17 is a real firecracker.
Keep it up! Give him that shaft! Get him, Nadie!
This guy is frustrating the Coventry
offense with relentless position defense.
Uh-Oh.
Number 17 is blindsided by an illegal hit.
You gotta be kidding me, man!
Here we go! It's a fight, folks!
A rumble on the rez.
Watson, Dawes, enough!
Come on, boy. Want a taste, Wonder Bread?
- Back! Get back.
- Jimmy!
Jimmy, sideline!
Keep your helmet on!
Geronimo!
Get off of him! Chewy, on the bench!
- Get off of him!
- Enough!
Keep your helmets on.
Sam my, stop it.
Nadie.
- Come on.
- No! Ow!
Stay there!
They're not worth it anyways!
Hey, seems as though you got me shaking
Hey, you make me cry
You start me up
And then you leave
You're changing right in front of me
- Whoo!
- Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
Winning some wampum, ladies?
Oh, my God! Ah!
Three Tom Hot Toddies.
I want to get that jackpot back.
Don't shoot, Chief.
Oh! Five dollar free play!
Ah. Impressive stacks, ladies.
Hey. Got a fortune for me, Chiefy?
Of course. Chiefy always has fortunes
for beautiful Indian maidens.
- There you go.
- I hope he has one for me too.
Mr. Geyer.
Ladies, if you don't mind,
I'd like to borrow Chiefy for a minute.
That's impressive design work, Joe.
But how far have you gotten
with the casino expansion rights?
Almost there. I'm meeting
with my primary opposition this evening.
Hmm.
Joe, I came to you with this deal because you
were a closer when you worked for me.
And I can guarantee a full partnership
if you pull this off.
But there are a lot of other poor Indian tribes
out there with wasted land.
Yes, but we Sunaquot are poorer
and more wasted than most.
I want to help your people,
but I can't wait forever.
Ah. Look, tell your people
whatever it is they want to hear...
...and get my deal done.
Nadie, you need to get that leg elevated.
This is your fault.
Why did you enter the game?
Because nobody else would go in, Daddy.
And I was kicking ass out there,
you saw me play.
And I heard the doctor.
And if you don't heal properly,
you may never play again.
I've got a meeting at the Pow Wow.
You stay with her, this pain medication
can have some side effects.
Oh, no funny business, you two.
Right, because I can't wait to hook up with
the guy that got my ankle broken in two places.
I told you, it's not my fault.
Nobody made you go in the game.
Okay, nobody had to, Jimmy.
We needed a player and you were hurt,
so I stepped up.
Ow! Okay, I said leave me alone!
Now we know the side effects.
Good day for a Pow Wow.
How you doing, man?
Hey, Rollingstone. What's up, my man?
It's Rollingwind.
I've told you like 10 times before.
Yeah, I meant that.
Julie? Julie Gifford?
What are you doing here?
- I teach high school.
- Since when?
Like two weeks ago.
What are you doing here?
I run the casino.
So how you been?
I'm good. I'm really good.
The casino, huh?
Figures. Joe Money
pimping out his people.
Wow, really?
You do know that my casino profits
paid for your brand-new school buildings.
So if I'm a pimp,
what does that make you?
Ah!
- Grandma!
Ah...
Julie!
Of all the teachers in New York,
you just had to hire my ex-girlfriend?
Dr. Gifford is more than a teacher.
Doctor?
Julie wrote the only book there is
about the Sunaquot culture.
You should take one.
It's very enlightening.
And she was the only applicant
we could afford to pay.
Which is a perfect reason
you should deed more land to the casino.
You know my position, son.
We have no more land.
Dad, land is all we have.
And land is all we need.
Come on, let's just enjoy the celebration.
Celebration? What celebration?
Nobody came to the Pow Wow.
Drive downtown
and see the men begging for work.
And then tell me
that the land is all our people need.
Our people.
We haven't been your people
for quite some time, son.
Well, I'm here now, and I have a plan.
But I'm running out of time.
It'd be nice to have your support
at the tribal council.
Not just as an elected official,
but as my father.
Oh!
How'd she get her pajamas on?
I didn't look, Mr. Logan. I swear.
Our partner, Geyer Enterprises, projects
that our annual share of gaming revenue...
...will exceed 10 million dollars.
And in five years, we'd be able to build
a hospital, along with the school.
But can we trust his vision?
Have you seen his casino?
We have seen the new school buildings...
...and have decided that Abooksigun may build
on the land between the casino and the river.
What? This is not acceptable.
Your blood cloud your vision, Hagawa?
We are not finished.
Abooksigun, you may expand the casino...
...under the condition
that you first re-examine your spirit...
...and prove yourself worthy
in the manner of your father's choosing.
You play redskin to the whites,
then white to your people.
It's just for show.
To show what exactly?
Hey, Grandma.
You have forced me
into a very difficult position, Mother.
For the good of our people.
Yes.
Hey, Lady Bug, how is the leg?
- It still hurts a little.
- Keep it elevated.
- So the swelling goes down.
- I am.
I have decided the manner
of your spirit quest.
You will return to the Creator's game.
Return? You mean, like, play?
No, you don't play.
Our coach quit
and I'm not a suitable replacement.
Well, neither am I.
I have a business to run.
Which will not expand as you wish,
unless you do as I require.
Dad, you know why I don't play anymore.
I do, and they call it
the "medicine game" for a reason.
Let it heal you.
Our next game is tomorrow,
the season ends on Memorial Day.
I'm only half Sunaquot,
shouldn't that mean only half a season?
Restore pride to our people,
and their game.
That is your first obligation.
- There's more?
- To re-examine your spirit.
Yeah, can you give me some
defined deliverables on that?
No, but I know who can.
Is it within my power to assign
him a spiritual advisor?
It is most certainly.
Good, then I assign you.
So, what? You're my babysitter now?
- That's howl roll, baby.
- Heh, heh.
Great.
I like the ones who, I like the ones who
I like the ones
I like the ones who like to show me things
Oh, man.
Gentlemen.
Look at this.
You're late.
Doesn't your fancy car have a clock?
- Yeah, it has GPS navigation too.
- Ugh.
I had to make a pit stop.
Man, you have a nice car here.
You two brothers or cousins?
- Yeah.
Okay, then.
All right, you two play attack,
you three middie...
...you three defense,
and I guess that makes you goalie.
I'm your new coach.
Watch the cutters.
Go!
That was quick.
The new suit on the sideline
hasn't made a big difference for the Sunaquot.
Come on, guys.
Who's got point?
Reed, be aggressive!
Play your position.
Yeah, no, I know.
Yeah, it's a convertible.
You've got to hit him, Chewy!
Chewy, can you hit him?
Like you're any better, pretty boy
Why don't you step up?
Uh-huh. I'll be there after this game.
Yeah, I'll sign the check.
Just stall them, all right?
Hey. Unless you're Googling halftime speeches
that don't totally suck...
...I suggest you put that down and coach.
- Stay in the game, man!
- Fine.
All right, guys, they're in a zone.
Run Z82 and work it around the wings.
Joe, they have no idea what that means.
Yeah, but it sounds good.
Jimmy! Whoo! Over here! Yo! Yo! I'm open.
Ball hog! Owen was wide open.
- Get out.
- Z82? It's not even a real play.
Sounds like a radio station.
You, you're in,
as long as you don't hog the ball too.
Good luck with that.
Hey, who's the dorky white kid?
It's Toby, Dr. Gifford's son.
- Julie has a son?
- Oh!
Yeah, and he just got crushed.
Welcome to the club, kid.
So how did your meeting
go with our opposition?
How much land
are you able to deliver, Joe?
The council approved construction
on the land here...
...where the current casino is,
up to the river here.
Great. We will break ground next week.
Actually, that's where we had to make
one concession.
We can't go until the end of May.
But that's two months.
I know. Uh, it's an ancient tribal law.
What law? I thought you were my insider.
I am. Uh... It's, uh, called
It means "No disturb land in spring."
Your people didn't farm in the spring?
No, not really.
They were more hunter-gatherer,
scavenger types.
Like bears,
with a little bit of vulture mixed in.
My clan name means Vulture Bear.
I need a start date, Joe.
N ow.
The day after Memorial Day.
You're sure? There are no other
ancient tribal traditions I need worry about?
No.
This is from last night's reading.
"Loving that Land O' Lakes Maiden,"
by an Onondaga poet, Eric Gansworth.
She is the first lesson in love for many
Indian boys, all tanned hide and feathers
Features straight out of Hollywood
But she lights the spark for those red boys
And probably for some
Black and white and brown ones as well
For anyone who learns her tricks, really
And they're not that hard to master
So, what's this poem about?
That smoking-hot Indian lady
on the butter package.
Yes, Reed, that's clearly stated
in the title, but what else?
That smoking-hot Indian lady is a stereotype
we Native American women have to overcome.
We don't spread easy like butter,
we can be tough and strong.
Jimmy, your thoughts?
I think nobody cares about poetry.
I do. Actually I happen to love poetry.
Well, in that case...
Ooh.
Nadie, my wounded lady
Will you marry me?
I'm strong, tough
And man enough to churn your butter nightly
- Chewy.
- Mm.
- Oh!
- Ow.
Nice shot.
Now Maug has got another one.
Grandma, I'm not late today. Sis.
Wow.
All right, bring it in.
So that was pretty pathetic yesterday.
No focus, no fitness,
and zero team work.
We're gonna start over
with the fundamentals.
Passing and catching, line drills. Go.
Can't. No balls.
Maug's got them.
Okay. Who's Maug?
Protector of the forest.
Six-foot-10,
300 pounds of pure muscle.
Catch a deer
with his bare hands, eat it raw.
What you're saying is we're calling practice
on account of Sasquatch?
- Yeah, pretty much.
- Yeah.
Works for me.
- How about you go buy us some more balls?
- Yeah.
How about you man up, Jimmy,
and go into the woods and get them yourself?
Ooh.
How about you call me Silverfoot.
How about you make me?
Today's lesson:
If you're afraid to go into the forest,
you've got no balls.
Oh!
Come on, Jimmy.
We ain't got no balls.
You're the one walking away.
Look at him, with his face buried
in that Crackberry all day.
So tell me then,
how's your fitness, coach?
You want to go? We can go.
Everybody. On the line.
Oh, come on.
Ready?
Maybe you could coach baseball.
Strike three. You're out.
Dude, Italian leather boots.
I'll show up if I have to,
but I can't coach these guys.
There's no weak warriors, Abooksigun,
only weak leaders.
And in this case, weak and slow.
There was a time
when you beat the sun, Abooksigun.
Crooked Arrow.
I hear you have returned
to the Creator's game.
Yeah, I'm sure you've heard why.
I also heard you're are O and 2.
Yeah, I don't know what to do.
These kids have had sticks
in their cradles.
But they're a joke right now.
Do you remember the story
of the eagle and the arrow?
No.
The eagle once ruled our skies.
And then, one day,
he was struck down by the arrow.
As he lay dying,
the eagle could not understand why.
The shaft of the arrow had been feathered
by one of his own plumes.
We often give our enemies
the means to our own defeat.
Look inside.
Ask your heart.
The truth may sleep, but it never dies.
It was only an oral language
until Hiawatha transcribed...
...the Haudenosaunee constitution
onto a wampum belt. Later, Ben Franklin...
...copied your version
of three equal branches of government.
Go.
His famous quote, "if a bunch
of ignorant savages can govern fairly...
...then we should be able to do the same"...
-...is the foundation of American democracy.
- What you want me to do?
Nadie?
- Hm?
- What's going on?
Uh, nothing.
Time for practice.
This is my classroom,
and we will stay until I say otherwise.
So you like your new school so much,
you want to keep the kids late?
Even if it means denying them the opportunity
to participate in a traditional cultural heritage?
Oh, well, maybe I can make it up
to them with afield trip...
...to go visit Chief Wampum
and his bar-dancing waitresses.
Speaking of which, we're hiring,
if you can dance.
- And she can, she was a cheerleader.
- Ooh.
And valedictorian,
which your coach can't even spell.
Well, I guess I'll just sit out here
where it's warm and sunny...
...with a trunk load of surprises
for the lacrosse team.
- Yo, are you serious?
- What? That's us. We gotta get our buddy.
- All right, fine.
- Whoo!
But we have a history test on Friday.
So I was thinking about what
happened when we raced.
- When I smoked your ass?
Ha-ha-ha.
I wasn't properly equipped.
Yeah, right.
We've been giving our enemies
the means to defeat us.
But not anymore.
- Reebok, best on the market.
- Oh!
- That's awesome.
- No way.
Little bang stick, 10K.
Look at this.
Look at the bag in it, man.
And that's not all.
Thank you, Marilyn.
Marilyn stayed up all night
making these.
- Oh, Jackpots.
Whoo-hoo!
Gotta look good to be good, right?
That did not look good for the Jackpots.
Despite a makeover, the Sunaquot goalie
stood planted like a tree in the crease...
...insuring the loss to Sulgrave.
Today's broadcast was brought to you
by our very first sponsor...
...the Lucky Indian Casino,
where the Big Game-
Ten dollar free play at Lucky Indian Casino.
- Joe Logan?
- Yeah, that's my name, just use it at the door.
- You played for Coventry in '98, right?
Yeah, that was a long time ago.
No, I played here, at Sulgrave.
Senior year you destroyed us.
Yeah, if you say so.
He's being humble.
This guy right here, the best I've ever seen.
You went to Syracuse, right?
They called you Logan the Legend.
But whatever happened
in that championship game?
Sorry, man, we gotta go.
Here's another coupon.
Congrats on the win.
Okay, sure.
Good luck!
Logan! Logan! Logan!
Heh. What you doing?
Hey! She walks.
I was just looking for this.
I've been doing a lot of driving lately and,
you know, trying to keep it fresh.
- Chumbawamba
- H a-h a-h a.
Come on, these guys were awesome
for the one song.
Ooh. Can I look?
Uh, ahem. No, not tonight.
Okay, total strangers
know my brother better than I do.
Logan the Legend?
I actually prefer Joey Hustle.
- Whatever, they're equally lame.
- Heh.
What was she like?
Strong, like you.
Then how could she die so young.
There was no hospital at the reservation.
But I can fix that now, if Dad will let me.
Oh, my God, is that Dr. Gifford with you?
Yeah, we dated at Coventry.
No way.
Yeah way.
I wouldn't bring it up to her though.
- Okay.
- Let's have some tunes.
Tunes.
Yeah, that's what we used to say in the '90s.
I get knocked down, but I get up again
Are we really gonna listen to that?
- Oh, yeah.
All right, guys, take your pads off.
Don't need them today.
What? No practice?
Nope. No practice.
Whoo
Yeah
- We're running.
- Ugh.
- Up there, to Defiance Rock.
How about you drag your old butt up there
and then you can tell us all about it.
I'll make you a deal.
You give me four balls,
I'll rip all four corners with Reed in goal.
If I miss, I go alone.
If I hit them all, we all run.
- Take it.
- Take that.
I gotta see this.
Reed, you better save this, man.
He can't shoot.
- Come on, Reed.
- Ooh.
- What's that?
Lucky.
Can't you stop an old man?
Reed, you should have stopped that one.
Right here, gramps, come on.
- Come on, Reed.
Oh!
What the--?
- We're running.
- That was cheating.
- Why didn't you tell him to hit the bar?
- Why did you take that bet?
Come on, come on, coach!
Come on, Reed, get bent.
Guys, wait up
And this one's for the fall
And this one's for the earth we never had
What's with the stick?
Maug, he's here. He's everywhere, watching.
You do know that predators go
for the slowest in the herd, right?
Take a right at the dead tree.
How old does my butt look now, Jimbo?
Go!
- Whoo!
- You almost beat the sun.
Man, there's a reason
the white man invented cable cars.
Guard your tongue in youth.
And in age you may mature a thought
that will be of service to your people.
How long does it take you to make one?
I don't make them, the Creator does.
This hickory tree is older than you.
I carve away all but the heart,
leaving only power and strength.
Your opponent does not want
to be clubbed by one.
This was my great grandfather's.
Over 200 years old.
And strong as the day it was made.
But metal sticks have offset heads.
With that you'd have to cradle all the time.
Don't worry, the offset head will fit on this.
The ball lives in the offset head,
but the spirit lives in the stick.
I may be old, but I'm not out of touch
I watch ESPNU on my iPad.
What's this?
That's the Crooked Arrow,
my Sunaquot name.
I have made sticks and arrows
for generations.
Each one is different,
and none are perfect.
No arrow flies straight.
There's nothing wrong
with a crooked arrow.
As long as it follows its own path,
it will find its way.
Sticks up.
Creator gave the game to the people
of the Haudenosaunee Nation.
They played and it pleased the Creator.
Now go play the game for our ancestors
who are no longer here to entertain the Creator.
You put a lot of work into these.
How much do I owe you?
You want to repay me?
Return lacrosse to our people.
Welcome back to the rez, lacrosse fans.
Not that this game will qualify as lacrosse
against the beleaguered Jacked--
Pots.
- Hey, Chad.
- Hello, Nadie.
Yeah, we're not the Jacked Pots any more.
Whoo! Crooked Arrows! Yahoo!
And Chad?
How about you show us some respect
on our land, okay?
Two. We're up by two. B line get in there.
We're late in the third...
...and the newly minted Crooked Arrows
have put in a surprising effort.
Come on. Come on, Jimmy.
Head up, head up, head up. Come on.
Nice pick.
Yes!
Nice! All right, all right.
- That's not all right. That's not-- Jimmy!
- Whoo!
Hey! Hey, Silverfoot, knock it off.
Keep showboating.
Keep dancing, twinkle toes. Keep smiling.
Yeah, you're smiling now.
You won't be smiling later.
Let's see some sweat, jock straps.
I'm not running a ballet here, Silvertoes,
this isn't "Dance of the Sugar Plums."
You want to be a ballerina,
plié off to Broadway.
You want to play lacrosse,
respect your team.
What did you guys say?
Hey, hey! Guys, guys, break it up, okay?
Come on.
No secrets now, we're a team.
We all speak the same language.
- Keep them running till I get back.
- Okay. Ready?
Keeping office hours, Dr. Gifford?
I need Jimmy when you're through with him.
We've got a problem with him graduating.
He's failing English.
You know, I always thought
you'd be a teacher.
Location is a bit of a surprise.
Your people made quite an impression
on me, coach.
Did you know that Jimmy
doesn't understand a word of Sunaquot?
A lot of kids don't learn it these days.
Well, I think they should.
And why would that matter to you?
We're reconnecting with our heritage.
Really?
Okay, what do you have in mind?
"Motion, reverse, zone, V-cut, crease"
and "hit me I'm open"?
The Unishees use Sunaquot on the field.
I think it could give the team a big advantage.
Well, yes, Julie, I will have
dinner with you this evening.
Joe, when you can ask me
in your native tongue...
...l'd be glad to help
for the sake of my students.
Including the ones who just puked.
AH this time I thought I was wasting
But you've gone and saved me
And now I can breathe again
You're bringing me back to life
You're supposed to meet with Dr. Gifford
today about your test.
Why do you care?
Because if you flunk out, you can't play.
You know, Jimmy,
I'm trying to do something special here.
Provide our people with a little hope.
But to do that, I need to win games.
And to do that, I need you.
Why bother?
To honor our people,
make lacrosse matter again.
Look, together we can turn things
around here in a big way.
But for that to happen,
I need you to be a leader, a team player.
I need a captain, Jimmy.
I'm already captain.
Prove it.
You can start by passing the ball.
Hey. He was a ball hog at your age.
Still a show boater.
All right, guys.
I've translated the plays into Sunaquot.
And like the Navajo code talkers
in World War ll...
...we'll confuse the hell out of our enemies.
You two help with pronunciation, please.
Really?
What you have here for V-cut, vagi--
Uh, actually kind of means like a woman's--
You know?
- What?
- Let me see.
Oh, my God, Joe, he's right.
I got this from a very good source.
Well, something got lost in translation,
like maybe tact.
Just fix it, Sammy, okay?
Hello?
You must be Sasquatch.
Maug.-
I'm Joe, the new coach.
Hardly.
I guess you've been watching.
Crooked Arrow says you can play.
You can see that we could use
some help on defense.
No, I'm busy.
Well, you could help us win.
Be a part of the team.
Feel the pride.
Meet some girls.
Hit rich boys as hard as you want?
- Did I get it right?
- No. It's not a trapezoid.
Yes, it is.
Hi. Sorry to interrupt, but I'd like
to introduce you to your new classmate.
This is Maug.
I made him get dressed for class.
- Why?
Ha-ha-ha.
Well, welcome, Maug.
He's amazing.
Is it true you can catch a deer,
kill it with your bare hands and eat it raw?
Chill, bro, I'm vegan.
Crooked Arrows
showing some aggression, finally!
Another turnover caused by Maug!
This new guy is a hammer.
Come on, guys, set it up! Let's run it.
Come on, Jimmy.
And the Crooked Arrows
are on offense again!
Drop in, drop in.
Find the pass.
Jimmy Silverfoot sets it up.
Passes it to Sammy or is that Owen?
Fakes low, fires high, and goal!
It's tie score late in the fourth.
Uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh. Watch the feet.
Hey, hey, hey, act like we've been
here before, boys. Come on, let's go.
Amazing improvement
since Joe Logan took over.
Time out, sir, time out.
Dooley is in a battle, and the
Crooked Arrows are on target for their first win.
Toby, you're in.
Me?
Ah! Yes!
Come on, just be aggressive, buddy.
Whoo!
All right, guys, come on in. A minute left.
Okay, Lyle, take a breather.
Toby, you're in at middie.
- What?
Sticks up.
Come on, guys, it's tied.
We can win this.
Come on, boys! Let's do this.
Crooked Arrows on three. One, two, three!
Crooked Arrows! Whoo! Whoo!
You're on wing, Toby.
Toby, on the wing. On the wing.
Now coming off the bench for the
Crooked Arrows, number 12, Toby Gifford.
Watch the double team.
Hey, here! Over here! Here!
Look Toby! Look Toby! Look Toby!
Come on, Toby.
And he drops it.
Come on!
Hudson to Thomas.
Reed, clear crease!
Clear crease, Reed!
And it's in!
Dooley pulls out a stunning victory
after a crushing Crooked Arrows turnover.
What a game!
The Arrows are still winless
for the season.
How come their white boys can play?
- Lay off, Jimmy.
- Why was he even out there?
He's out there
because he's a member of this team.
We win and lose together
and nobody played perfectly.
But, hey, you guys played a great game, okay?
We'll get the next one.
So tonight,
steak dinner on me, all right?
I'm getting two steaks.
- How about a lap dance?
- You don't have a lap, honey.
Ooh.
- Thanks, Marilyn.
- You're welcome.
The hawk feather has long been
a sign of service for our people.
Warriors could earn feathers
on the field of battle.
Soto Jimmy, for winning
three face-offs and notching two assists.
To the Unishees, great speed, great effort.
And one goal apiece.
To Chewy, for tough position defense.
And to Maug, for creating four turnovers.
And to Nadie, for our motion offense.
I plan to make this a tradition
after every game.
So give ourselves a hand.
Hey.
Listen, I know you're in a tough spot here.
I've been there.
The only poor Sunaquot kid
at a fancy prep school.
You didn't suck.
You know how you get over it?
Take the next shot you have.
And I'll make sure
you get another chance, okay?
Thanks, coach.
Hey, Mom.
Was that a little bit of Sunaquot
on the field today, coach?
I told you, we're working cultural identity
into the game plan.
Uh-huh. A little bit of a loose translation,
don't you think?
Yeah, well, kids kind of made it their own.
Which is why I will be working some proper
Sunaquot into my lesson plan this week.
See you later.
Night.
You have been given knowledge and tools.
But now, you must commit yourselves
to the Creator's game.
To the ancient game that began long ago...
...when the birds
first played against the animals.
However, you must first accept who you are.
Within each one of us
resides an animal spirit.
You must go on a vision quest
to discover your animal spirit.
Actually, sweating kind of makes me
break out, so can I--? Ow!
When the animals of the sky played
the first game against the animals of the land...
...the Creator gave a gift
to every creature.
Tell me your vision.
The deer.
A spirit of speed and agility.
Tell me your vision.
The bear.
Great strength.
The wolf.
Became ferocious and wild.
The turtle
Was able to withstand any blow.
The hawk.
The birds were gifted
with flight and swift movement.
The raven.
And even the smallest animal...
The squirrel.
...would prove his worth to the Creator.
This is good. In one team you represent
both the animals and the birds.
It is said that our loved ones
return as birds to watch over us.
So for you, Abooksigun, the eagle.
May your mother's wings lift you up.
All right, everybody, we're gonna
do a friendship dance now.
So, ladies, grab a man.
So things are looking up around here.
What do you think?
Will we be ready to build
at the end of the season?
Ah, that's yet to be seen.
You don't answer to only me
in this quest, Joe.
But to your ancestors.
Grandma Skye tells me you come a long ways,
but there's more to your journey.
Step up, step up, Reed!
Poor goalie play has plagued them again
thanks to Reed "The Colander" Armstrong.
I've never been very good
with nicknames.
Anyway, along pass across the field.
Hit him!
Time out, sir.
Marston Hall climbs within one, 14-13.
Reed, come on, I've seen kittens
more aggressive than you.
No, no, no, Joe, wait. Look.
Reed, you better man up
and clear the freaking crease.
Okay, you hold onto this lead, or I swear...
...I will shove those feathers
so far up your asses, you'll fly.
Okay, me first.
- Sticks up.
- Come on, boys.
I mean, I like your hair and your body is tight,
but you play goalie like a wussy.
And that is so un-hot. We straight?
Yeah, we're straight.
Reed, buddy!
I got this, coach, okay?
All right.
Ten seconds left,
Marston on a break, looking to tie.
Baird breaks free, right wing.
Watch the cutter!
Too far! Too far, Reed!
Ah!
It's over! The Crooked Arrows win.
Yes!
The Crooked Arrows get their first win
of the season...
...with Reed coming out of the crease
to make the play.
Now that's bringing it home, son.
Just when you think you're not
getting through to these kids.
Don't you take credit for that.
You didn't do that. Booty did that.
Pfft. What?
Whoo!
- Ha, ha!
I get knocked down, but I get up again
You're never gonna keep me down
Reed, for making 10 saves.
The Crooked Arrows are flying true
of late, hitting only bull's-eyes.
Taking rematch wins against
St. Giles, Locke and Sulgrave.
Sweeping Dooley and blowing out
the lowly Bernard Forest twice.
They're flying out there.
The fleet-footed Unishee brothers, Owen
and Sammy, must read each other's minds...
...their passes are so perfect.
Two months ago, no one could have imagined
Joe Logan would take the lowest ranking team...
...in the New York Prep League
on a path towards the playoffs.
I get knocked down, but I get up again
You're never gonna keep me down
Another turnover.
- Move like the wind! Run!
- Yeah, Chewy!
- And yes!
- Whoo!
Chewy, great steal.
Another win for the Crooked Arrows.
Silverfoot scores!
The Arrows run a tight-motion offense.
This team is hot,
and I don't just mean their assistant coach.
The Sunaquot team is moving up
the ranks at a breakneck pace.
An unprecedented turnaround.
It's a Maug attack!
They weren't ready for that, were they?
Hello.
Whoo!
After six straight wins, the Crooked
Arrows are getting state-wide attention.
I get knocked down, but I get up again
You're never gonna keep me down
Yeah, good.
Ha-ha-ha. No.
Joe Logan has his boys believing.
They're passionate and driven,
but they'll have to ambush...
...undefeated Coventry on the road
in order to make the playoffs.
And that's a very tall order,
even for Logan the Legend.
Two hundred thousand square feet,
500 rooms, 3000 slots, 150 tables.
A 1000-seat performance theater...
...36-hole PGA golf course,
and the first Native Adventures theme park.
Mr. Geyer, this is 10 times bigger
than what we discussed.
Because with your plan,
your people merely survive.
But with mine, they actually get rich.
You, chief among them.
We're talking $100 million a year.
This is not what I agreed to
with the council.
Once the money starts to flow,
they'll forget all about it.
No, no, we had a deal. We had a deal.
And I changed it.
Trust me.
You will be a hero to your people.
Once we break ground tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Day after Memorial Day.
Welcome to Coventry Academy
and The Bowl.
This is the unquestioned seat
of prep lacrosse glory.
No love lost today. The last time these two
teams met, Coventry annihilated the Sunaquot...
...and the game ended in a brawl.
A lot has changed since then
for the Crooked Arrows.
But they still need a win if they're
going to make it to the postseason.
And it's going to take a monumental effort
to overcome the storied men in blue.
Gentlemen, you ever wonder why there's
no '98 championship banner here?
Logan the Legend choked.
Let's make sure that happens again.
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
For getting blood on your only uniform.
Down! Set!
Watson wins the draw. Off to Dawes.
And it looks like practice out there.
Fancy stick work, a lot of hot-dogging.
Coventry goes up one-zip.
The high-flying Arrows
have quickly fallen back to earth.
Hey, Arrows, how's that for stick work?
Coventry seals up another
undefeated season...
...and enters the playoffs as the number one
seed with a dominant 12-5 victory.
Coventry is stuffing the Arrows
back in the quiver.
They'll miss the playoffs again this year.
Yo, did you hear?
Marston lost and now we get a bye.
Nice. Who we got here?
You know, now that your season is over,
you can finally get with a winner.
Marston lost?
Marston lost!
Guys, Bernard upset Marston.
- Who cares?
- You do, we beat Bernard twice.
That means we're in the playoffs.
Whoo!
We're in the playoffs!
- Whoa.
- Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, what's u p?
Check this out.
Coach, what's going on?
How is this possible?
Geyer needed a start date.
The season ended today,
so I gave him one.
But it didn't end today.
What? You just thought we
wouldn't make it to the playoffs?
No, not two months ago.
Two months ago?
The council was clear. I was clear.
And you have not met
all my requirements, son.
Look, this team couldn't win
a game before I took over.
It's been a great season.
Pride has been restored, like you wanted.
I've done everything that you've asked of me.
Why can't you just be happy for once?
The lacrosse field
was not part of the plan.
I know, but the plan changed.
And...
...we don't need a lacrosse field
for the rest of the season.
Last-seeded teams don't play home games.
I can still coach, it's a win-win.
For you, but what happened
to honoring our people?
You're not our coach,
you're a liar and a hypocrite.
Let's go.
Nadie...
Abooksigun led our team to a winning record
and reawakened our traditions within them.
Our people were very inspired
by his efforts.
Because we fear losing the casino
if we delay...
...we declare that Abooksigun
has fulfilled his obligation...
...and may proceed
using the new land he requested.
That field is as old as our people.
The return of his spirit
was to be decided by me.
It was a difficult decision,
but the council has spoken.
I'm sorry that it happened this way, Dad.
But it's time to move forward
and this is good for everybody.
You are my son, and I love you.
But the future of our people
rests in your hands.
And I fear that your spirit
is not strong enough to protect us.
Hey, Wampum, spot me a fortune feather,
will you? I'm down big here.
Yeah? Me too.
More troubles you than what I know.
I think I may have feathered the arrow
for our enemy.
Yet the eagle still flies.
There is still time.
But remember, a wise warrior forces his enemy
to fight at a time and place of his choosing.
Don't try to pin me down
I'm a contradiction
Love, hate, get it straight
Half devil, half divine
What?
I'm here to talk to you.
Great, talk all you want.
Believe
I get what I want, not just what I-
You want to know howl lost
the state championship?
See number 12? That's Emmitt...
...the current coach of Coventry,
and he's pointing at me, number 17.
There were 15 seconds left and the call...
...was for me to come off a screen,
work to the crease.
I could have hit that shot in my sleep.
But I was the guy who choked
and lost the championship.
See? Everyone is devastated by my miss.
But I'm just heading to the showers.
You missed on purpose.
I was tired of winning for them.
Felt like I was being used.
For three years,
Coventry cheered every score.
They loved me
when I was helping them win...
...but the rest of the school day
I was invisible.
Julie was the only one
who could see me for more...
...than just a poor kid
who could play lacrosse.
And to her, the Sunaquot were more...
...than some Indians on a reservation,
you know?
Losing wasn't the problem.
I dishonored the game.
And I've done it again.
Okay, then fix it.
Why do you think I'm here?
Let me be your assistant, coach.
Mm. Tsk.
Now coached
by young Nadie Logan and her father...
...the Crooked Arrows
take down Montross and win in round one.
But where is Joey Hustle?
Shake it for the war chief all night long
Rattlebone
Sweet medicine
To each his own
Billy, hey, can I see that?
We've got a change.
Mr. Geyer wants this done ASAP.
Whatever, your money, boss.
Yes, it is.
One earth below
Hm?
- Ha-ha-ha.
Good job, Chewy!
Despite Joe Logan's absence...
...the Arrows are displaying
a vast arsenal of motion-offense plays...
...inspired by native box lacrosse.
Not to be denied a date with destiny,
the Crooked Arrows have ripped through...
...the best lacrosse teams in New York,
including the Dooley Devils.
Can you believe it?
The Sunaquot are heading to the state finals
and guess who they'll face.
You know who,
they who shall not be named.
Can the Arrows pull off one more miracle?
Doubtful, but I for one sure do hope so.
- Toby, get up here.
- Toby.
- Get up here.
- Get water, man.
Oh!
Wow.
Sprinkler systems are in order.
We've got the same grass
they use at Yankee Stadium.
Oh.
- Wait, you know I can't stand the Yankees.
Eh...
Well done, Abooksigun.
It's as it should be.
We got our coach back.
Hey, coach!
Thanks, sis.
All right, let's get to it.
Let's go, boys, let's go.
Louie, look over here.
MAN 2;
All right.
We're gonna miss the game.
Not if you two hurry up
and get the new name up.
There you go.
Welcome back to The Bowl on this
beautiful day for championship lacrosse.
This title game features familiar foes
and a battle of tradition.
The Sunaquot, representing the creators
of the ancient game.
And Coventry Academy,
the modern juggernaut that has perfected it.
Good afternoon, everyone,
on a beautiful day here in upstate New York.
I'm Sean McDonough,
delighted to have you with us.
What brings ESPN to a state
high school lacrosse championship game?
Well, America's fastest-growing sport
has spawned an amazing story...
...about a Native American team
called the Crooked Arrows.
After a miserable 0-5 start to their season...
...they changed coaches
and brought in Joe Logan.
These young men were on an unlikely
winning streak that lasted until the final day...
...of their regular season,
when they lost to undefeated Coventry.
In a surprising twist of fate, the Arrows
have marched through the playoffs...
...to set up another meeting.
It's therefore no surprise that the lacrosse elite
have turned out to witness this epic showdown.
Among those in attendance...
...professional lacrosse stars
Paul Rabil, Zack Greer and Brody Merrill.
And at the end of the field,
some of the sport's legendary coaches...
...including John Desko of Syracuse
and Virginia's Dom Starga.
Amidst all this excitement,
will Big Blue win another championship?
Or is this the day David slays Goliath?
Stay tuned, the game starts in just a moment.
Hey, isn't that your boss?
Hey, Joe!
Mr. Geyer.
Big game, huh?
Saw you made some unplanned renovations.
But I was wondering why my crew
and my equipment are sitting idle.
Well, you know when you asked if there
were any other ancient tribal traditions...
-...that might get in your way?
- Yes.
Well, this game is one I forgot about...
...so we'll be keeping that land
for our lacrosse field.
- Joe, we have a deal.
- No, we had a deal. You changed it.
I just changed it back.
There are a lot of other rich developers
out there looking for wasted land.
I'll sue.
In what court?
We're a sovereign nation.
Your laws don't apply on our land.
I have a game to coach.
One, two, three, Crooked Arrows! Whoo!
Hey, let them have the face-off.
No way, I can take this punk.
Silverfoot, trust me, okay?
Face-off man is gonna clamp
and put it between his legs to the middie.
Maug is gonna leave his man
and cover the other wing. Go!
Whoo!
Arrows won't work
against body armor and machine guns.
All it takes is one good shot.
Down!
Trust me, Jimmy.
Set!
Watson wins the opening draw,
a set play as he dishes and dashes.
Yes, nice hit, Maug!
Look at the point man, he's open!
Sammy, nice finish!
The Crooked Arrows strike first,
quieting this capacity crowd in blue.
When did the Indians
start playing lacrosse anyway?
Way to start off the game.
Give me a second line, let's go!
Like I said, one good shot.
I remember when I scored my first goal.
Put a body on him, Chewy!
Get in front of him, Chewy, come on!
That's what I'm talking about.
Just like we drew it up, baby.
- Just like we drew it up.
- Whoo!
All right, guys, come on.
We'll get it back.
And after getting punched
in the nose, the empire strikes back!
Come on, take it away top side!
Who's hot? Slide! Slide!
Two to one, we got them
right where we want them.
Great shot by Watson. Two to one Coventry.
And when they get a lead,
they rarely give it back.
Slide!
Goal!
- Come on, guys, regroup! Regroup!
- Fast break!
Coventry Academy
putting on a clinic here at The Bowl.
It's just too much for the Arrows
on both ends of the field.
No letup, blue line, no letup!
Good hustle!
No mercy!
It's getting contentious down on the field.
Get in the hole.
Come on, way to be, way to be.
And another turnover!
- Yes!
- Whoo!
Run Skada! Run Skada!
And Dawes just got away with an
obvious hold and the Arrows come up short.
- That's a hold, ref!
- Good no call, good no call.
Come on, ref! What do you need?
You're missing a good game!
Come on!
Nice job, way to not get caught.
Way not to get caught.
Hey, that's a hold. That's a hold, ref!
Quit your whining, 26.
You know whose field you're on!
Hey, hey, hey!
You gotta make that call.
Down 7-4 at half.
The Arrows are not going to get help from
anyone if they want back in this title game.
Joe Logan is going to have to impart
more than just strategy during halftime.
You know what you're gonna say?
Not really.
Okay, guys, great first half.
Yeah? Check the scoreboard.
- Tell that to the ref.
- Ref who?
Hey, quiet. Hey, quiet!
Yeah, I hear you.
All right, yeah, they're bigger
than you, faster than you.
And they have better facilities
and they have more championships.
And, yes, they have a better
coach than you.
But you know what?
None of that matters, okay?
This game is not about them,
this game is not about us.
And it's not about the scoreboard.
In the ancient game,
they didn't keep score.
They played to honor the Creator,
and so will we.
We'll play to honor our ancestors
who were buried with their sticks.
We will play to honor our grandchildren
who will be given sticks when they're born.
This game has been in our blood
for a thousand years, gentlemen.
Today, win or lose,
we return lacrosse to our people.
Whoo! Whoo!
Let's go, boys!
Welcome back to The Bowl, where
the second half is about to get under way.
We got this, man.
Hey, no letups, we play four quarters.
Hey, no letups, no letups.
Wait a minute, wait a minute, there's some
kind of a commotion at the end of the field.
It appears to be a large group of Native
Americans carrying some sort of tribal flags.
Despite the sudden invasion,
the Coventry supporters...
...are making room
for these new lacrosse fans.
This place has gone totally Native!
Whoo!
Where'd they come from?
Smoke signals.
All the Haudenosaunee Nations
in one spot.
I guess this is a home game now, huh?
Always was, son.
Go get them.
You ready to bleed again?
This is our game.
You just picked up the sticks we made.
Yes, thattaboy, Jimmy!
Finally got one.
I'm open! Over here! Ball!
He's open! He's open!
Patience!
Like predators, the Arrows are calmly
circling the Coventry goal.
A pass too tall even for Maug.
Save it, Jimmy, save it!
Holy stick work!
- All right, we have numbers. Push it!
- Hustle, hustle, get there, Dawes.
We're a man down, we're a man down.
Yes!
Yeah!
Yeah, get up, Twinkle Toes.
Way not to give up on it, Jimmy!
Good hustle.
Look Sammy, look Sammy, look Sammy!
Yeah.
Oh, my God, you gotta be kidding me!
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Whatever the reason...
Well, done, Silverfoot! Well done!
...the Arrows are playing with
a renewed sense of purpose.
Getting right back in the game.
They don't have Coventry's depth,
but they simply will not quit.
Reed!
Chewy, that's it!
Are you kidding me?
Get on the bench. Get on the bench!
With their second-half surge,
the Arrows are right on Coventry's heels...
...but can they ever draw even?
Now, Watson, now!
A rough, but perfectly legal hit.
- Yeah!
And number 10 Grayhouse is out of the game.
Toby! You're in.
All right, they're gonna double-team Jimmy
and lay off you, all right? Be ready.
Oh, my God, Toby, Toby, Toby...
Captain.
Thank you.
Two-six, get him, Silverfoot! Pick him up.
Sticks up, off your hip!
Move! You gotta rotate!
Two-six, two-six!
Double, double, six, double!
Jimmy!
- Look Toby, look Toby!
Jimmy! Jimmy! Jimmy!
Who's got him?
Yes!
Goal, point blank! Gifford with his first
of the season, first of his life.
Tie score late in the fourth.
Nice shot, Squirrel!
Give me that scout report.
He's not even on here, who is that kid?
Yeah, Toby!
Watson, get your carcass over here
right now.
Joe Logan is coaching the game
of his life here, folks, and we're all tied up at 12.
Have you forgotten who we are?
Because they could care less and they're
kicking your privileged tails all over the field.
Wake up and finish the job
or I'll find someone who will.
- On three, one two, three!
- Huh!
You've worked your whole life for this.
Now is the time!
You know who it's going to,
don't let 26 get the ball.
Brutal illegal hit by Dawes
and that's a call they can't miss.
He wasn't even in possession of the ball,
which makes it doubly egregious.
What did I do? I barely touched him.
I didn't do nothing.
The Arrows have been racked
by injuries today.
This is a fatal blow if Jimmy Silverfoot
is sidelined, leaving the team a man short.
Take it easy. Take it easy, Jimmy. Medic.
Ah!
You got us this far,
we'll do the rest, all right?
I'm going in.
What? No, you only have one good leg.
Yeah, and no one else
has one good leg right now.
What are you doing with that cheap shot?
Deal with it and play the game.
- Now we're a man down.
- So are they. They're putting in a girl.
Turn around!
Twenty seconds left, all right?
Finish the possession, we take it in overtime...
-...and seal the deal, all right?
- Remember, you're just a decoy, okay?
Okay.
Not okay. I'm finishing this.
Why, because you're better than me
with a broken arm?
It's just dislocated, I can still play.
Not with a sling you can't.
Look, Jimmy, you can't--
Her leg is my fault.
Last time I didn't go in, she got hurt.
I can't let that happen again.
If one of those guys hits that ankle,
she'll never play again.
You got two years left, this is my last game.
Let me play, coach.
Ugh. Fine. But if you break your other arm,
I'm not helping you with your pajamas.
- I don't wear pajamas.
Ha-ha-ha.
Okay, guys, we're gonna run Z82.
Maug, move up to middie and set the pick.
Toby, top of the crease
and screen the goalie.
And Sammy, this is your shot, so hit it.
- I always do.
- Okay, sticks up, guys.
- Let's go, boys!
- Here we go!
- Crooked Arrows on three, one, two, three.
- Crooked Arrows! Whoo!
Hey, hey, hey! Wait.
You're just a decoy, okay?
Okay.
And here we go!
The Crooked Arrows have a man advantage
with gutsy Jimmy Silverfoot at middie.
V-2-6, 2-6, left shoulder,
left shoulder 2-6.
Okay, okay, okay.
Now, Maug, now!
- Here we go, here we go.
The Arrows work the ball around,
looking for an opening. Seconds ticking away.
Aah!
- Jimmy!
Ten seconds.
Aah!
- Oh, my God.
Watch Sam my! Watch Sam my!
And it's a loose ball!
Aah!
Shoot it!
Shot! Shot!
Aah!
Unbelievable!
SportsCenter, you've got your lead story!
The Crooked Arrows are state champs!
All right, all right! Come on, get up! Get up.
Get off. Get off.
Coventry and Coach Emmitt
are taking the loss with great dignity.
Silverfoot, you all right?
Never been better.
Nice shot, ball hog.
What? Oh. Heh.
- Hey, decoy.
- Hey.
Hey, since I'm really hurt this time,
maybe I can get a kiss, coach.
Ah!
That's one good shot.
- Thanks, good game.
- Good luck next year.
Let's go, let's go!
How about that?
I have come to learn the stubborn ways
of my children.
You, your time is coming.
And you have found your spirit,
Abooksigun.
It was you.
Yo, Coach Joe!
Here. You earned this.
- Hey.
- Hey. So...
Is that a yes?
Come on.
When the first game between
the animals ended, the Creator was pleased.
And he gave the Medicine Game
to the people of the Haudenosaunee.
That we may all come together
as one and heal each other.
Yeah, yeah
Check the highlight tape
Put your beats with lyrics till I actuate
Grinding past the physical limits
Of which I violate
My mental place is in the Garden State
Spilling my body weight
Then hydrate until my pupils dilate
I make you go for broke
Pulling out the only fund
I don't blow my nose
Cleaner than a smoking gun
My friends dope a ton
Stay above the choking lung
Pushing up, hands stringing sticks
With a broken thumb
I keep it casual
Always check the manual
Always improvise
Already memorized the manual
My gains are gradual
But always moving up
Trading stocks with fake money
Learning how to chase the fast buck
I'm a fast buck
You better match up
Swim move, then I'm burning by you
Like a fat Dutch
Paint the corners when I shoot with braces flow
Whipping my stick they said it was miracle
I'm getting goosebumps
On me when I'm lyrical
Killing beats one at a time
Like they were cereal
I've moved around a lot
Lived on many different blocks
From partners of the street
To waking up to smoking shots
Well, I'm gonna stop it now
Check the flow
I'm Coventry
Rapping with a couple Crooked Arrows
Let's wrap.
I've got to remember
That all I need is right inside of me
I look at this world around me
The tallest tree was once just a seed
Over and over, what I find
Is when I see it in my mind
It's only just a matter of time
Keep your eyes on winning
'Cause if you try you'll never really lose
I'm John Desko and I'm a Crooked Arrow.
I'm Brody Merrill and I'm a Crooked Arrow.
I'm Gary Gait and I'm a Crooked Arrow.
I'm Lars Tiffany and I'm a Crooked Arrow.
- I'm a Crooked Arrow.
Dream big
Yeah
Each day
That you wake up
Is a chance for you to start
Something new
It's there for the taking
But that first step is always up to you
Over and over, what I find
Is when I see it in my mind
It's only just a matter of time
Keep your eyes on winning
'Cause if you try you'll never really lose
Yeah, this life's for living
There's no limit to the things that we can do
Keep your eyes on winning
'Cause if you try you'll never really lose
Yeah, this life's for living
There's no limit to the things that we can do
Dream big
Yeah
O
Keep your eyes on winning
'Cause if you try you'll never really lose
Yeah, this life's for living
There's no limit to the things that we can do
Dream big
Yeah, this life's for living
There's no limit to the things that we can do
It's only just a matter of time