-=This movie is an adaptation of a novel
about an actual case that happened at
a school for the deaf in 2005.=-
=Today's weather is cloudy to overcast.=
=There will be rainfall and snow
in the central areas.=
=In the early morning, there will be
thick fog in areas near the mountains.=
=Thick fog will also be seen on the
west coast and the mountainous region.=
=Today's temperature will be similar to yesterday's.=
=Seoul is at -2 degrees Celsius.
Dae Jeon is at -2 degrees Celsius.
Gwang Ju is at -1 degree  Celsius.=
=Mu Jin is at -1 degree Celsius.=
=You haven't arrived yet?=
The fog is too heavy.
I don't even know where I am right now.
=You will be reaching soon.=
=Mu Jin is naturally a place with thick fog.=
=What's Song In doing now?=
- Sleeping.
=She has been crying aloud for you
and only fell asleep a while ago.=
Did she cry a lot?
=It happens to all kids who are
separated from their parents.=
=Don't worry too much.
Just focus on your job.=
=It wasn't easy to get this job, so
make sure you hold on to it. Understand?=
-=Crucible=-
How long will I need to wait?
Because of thick fog in the early morning,
you still have to wait a while more.
Excuse me. May I know if there are any
public buses to Ja Ae School from here?
Ja Ae School?
Are you referring to that school for the deaf?
That place is a bit remote,
so there is no direct public bus.
A taxi will cost you at least 50 000 Won.
You are leaving just like this?
I'm running against time now.
Let's talk tomorrow.
If you can, leave your car here for repair.
Ajussi, what's the matter with you?
(Ajussi - older man, uncle)
How could you just suddenly reverse
without checking your mirrors?
What are you talking about?
I did not even move my car.
Ajussi, are you bullying me because I'm a woman?
You have picked the wrong person this time.
Boss, may I borrow your spray?
I'm speechless. Exactly which car get bumped into?
Miss, I haven't even started my car.
Hey you this person, I predict that
you will get into trouble one of these days.
Boss, come and take a look.
This person is pretty drunk.
What should I do?
Why?
Are you having a drink too many again last night?
I'm really sorry.
I will help you to get insurance compensation.
Looks like you are afraid of cold.
Yesterday I went out for a drink with my colleagues.
When I came out, the windows were all smashed.
You look like that fellow that ran away
after smashing the windows.
But it seems that I have made a mistake.
That...How much longer?
People in my profession tends to
make a few enemies.
Our job is quite similar to the policemen's.
We target those people who cause
troubles after drinking and use violence
on their wives and children.
I'm asking you when we are reaching.
You are already an adult
but why are you so impatient?
Anyway, why are you going to Ja Ae School?
I will be teaching the children.
Really? Are you a teacher?
So you know sign language, right?
What's the meaning?
I think I know why you have so many enemies.
Contact me after you have estimated
the compensation amount.
Don't try to do something different.
I am in extremely good terms
with the policemen of this city.
Hello.
This is the Headmaster Office.
Ask the Admin Head to
come over for a while.
So you are a student of Prof. Gim?
Yes. He's my professor in the university.
Prof. Gim painted this portrait for me.
I see.
I'm fully confident of the
calibre of Prof. Gim's students.
I was in the same class with Prof. Gim
till third year of high school.
If he didn't choose to specialize in fine arts,
most likely we would be studying in the same university.
You don't have to be so polite.
I have to.
You are going to be our teacher soon.
Of course, I need to be polite to you.
Admin Head.
This is our new art teacher from Seoul,
recommended by Prof. Gim.
I'm Gang In Ho. Looking forward to working with you.
Is this the first time you see an identical twin?
I'm sorry.
It's all right. I believe most people
who see us for the first time will
have the same reaction as you.
You must be very tired after
traveling such long distance.
Take a good rest this weekend
and start work next week.
The admin head will make arrangements
for you for the other matters.
Hyeong, how should we handle that matter?
Admin Head, this is a school.
Headmaster, how should we proceed with it?
Didn't I mention that
he's recommended by Prof. Gim?
Are you playing with me?
You are from Seoul,
but why are you so dumb?
Originally, you need to give a big note.
But since you are recommended by
Prof. Gim, 5 small notes will do.
- Are you asking money from me?
- Then, do you think this teacher's position comes free?
You are really...Remember, no cheque.
School Development Fund.
I heard everyone must contribute to it.
=So, how much do they need?=
50 million Won.
=Not 5 million Won but 50 million Won!=
I heard it was already a discount since
I was recommended by my professor.
=Oh my god! How could I get so much money?=
Nice drawing.
You have an aptitude for drawing.
The lesson has started for some time.
Why are you only here now?
I'm talking to you.
Are you saying Min Su?
That child's younger brother lost his life
in a train accident a few days ago.
That child definitely is not
in the right state of mind now.
His only brother died.
How can he not be depressed?
Not only Min Su. I feel that the
rest of the children are a bit strange too.
What is so strange about?
It's not easy to explain clearly in a few words.
Mr. Gang, this is your first time
teaching in such a school, right?
You cannot treat the children here
like any normal children.
When one has a disability,
one will feel incomplete.
I have been in contact with these
children for more than 10 years.
But until now, they are still
not opening their minds to me.
Jeon Min Su.
His father is mentally retarded.
His mother's whereabouts is unknown.
Jin Yu Ri.
With an intellectual disability grade 3
and a mental age of 8 years old.
Have to watch her as she has a huge appetite.
Gim Yeon Do.
She's is an orphan...
I just knock off from work.
=Have you taken your dinner?=
I have eaten a little.
Song In? Have you feed her?
=I just feed her a few spoons.=
Why did you feed her so little?
=She said she doesn't like to eat rice
and has been asking for pizza.=
If she wants to eat, just buy it for her.
How much can that cost?
=Don't worry. I won't starve your daughter.
When you reach home, remember
to check your bank account.=
You got the money?
=When you withdraw the money,
you must get the new coins from them.=
Anyone inside?
By any chance, did something happen?
What are you doing here?
Just now, there were some
strange sounds coming from inside.
But that doesn't mean you
can go into a ladies' toilet.
What if a child passes by and saw it?
Looks like you are new and don't know
the situation here well. The children often made
strange sounds when they are bored.
Furthermore, because they are deaf,
they yell even louder.
I'm going to lock up the main gate.
You better get going.
Recently, the investigation has given me headaches.
That bunch of kids always cause troubles for me as well.
Our kids have been a pain
in the neck to Officer Jang, right?
Can't really say it's a pain in the neck.
Teaching good morals to the children
is also part of policeman's duty.
The key is that the kids should listen.
I told them many times not to
leave their rooms at night.
No use saying to them.
They can't hear it.
You are right.
It's all right. Come in.
Development fund is not against any law.
Isn't it, Officer Jang?
Of course. If I earn enough,
I will also contribute to the
school development fund.
I heard you are from Seoul.
Are you adapting well?
This Mu Jin City, except for year in year out fog,
there isn't really many things here.
It's okay. I'm good.
That, how about a drink with me
when you have the time?
Although this city looks pretty dilapidated,
there are still enjoyment places for men.
The little fishes here are not bad.
Min Su, it's impolite to look at teacher
using that eye expression.
Stand up!
Stand straight. Didn't I teach you before
that you should still show courtesy
when you are being beaten?
Get up, Min Su.
Hello.
Mr. Pak, what happened?
Please wait a moment.
This kid secretly left the dormitory at night.
And even brought along two other girls with him.
I was so worried that I didn't sleep at all last night.
This kid's younger brother also
died because of this reason.
Mr. Pak, the Headmaster is looking for you.
Min Su, can't you understand my feelings?
Open your mind to me and enjoy
each other company.
Isn't it better that way?
What are you doing? Quick, get in.
Get in! Hey, you!
Come down quickly.
What do you plan to do?
What if you fell out of the window?
What's the matter?
Sorry. I have frightened you.
I did this because I was worried.
What are you doing?
I am educating the children.
Hey auntie, who are you?
Who allows you to educate them in this way?
I am the dormitory superintendent, Yun Ja Ae.
I am in charge of after-school education.
This is not something you should interfere with.
You are dunking the child's head into
the washing machine and you asked
me to ignore it? Are you crazy?
I heard there's a new teacher from Seoul.
So it's a fellow who cannot differentiate
between urine and shit.
Are you looking down on me because
you think I come from backwater?
In Seoul, I have a number of friends
who are prosecutors and lawyers.
If you dare to do it again,
I will make sure you are thrown into jail.
Heed my advice.
Yeon Do.
Hello.
Which ajussi?
Oh, that ajussi.
What's the matter? I thought the
repairing fees had long been settled.
Are you saying beating up disabled children?
This is not a discrimination,
it's completely an atrocity.
The child is in such a bad state.
Ajussi, what have you being doing?
Please call her parents first.
This child is an orphan.
I have heard it from the Admin Head.
Miss Yun Ja Ae's teaching method is bad.
Mr. Gang, it is understandable for you
to be angry when your students
are met with such encounters.
I had already issued a
harsh warning to Miss Yun Ja Ae.
So could you be magnanimous
and forgive her this time?
Miss Yun Ja Ae had already reflected on it.
She also want to personally
apologize to student Yeon Do.
But it seems that Yeon Do didn't go back
to her bedroom last night.
Nothing happens to the child, right?
We are worried over her.
Actually, her condition is quite bad.
So I admitted her into hospital.
Is that so? Is it very serious?
No, it's not. They said she
can be discharged tomorrow.
You don't have to be too worried.
We will handle the discharge procedure.
But which hospital is she in?
-=As Yeon Do is not feeling well,
she is unable to come today.=-
How about...
-=You draw me and I draw you.=-
-=Why? You are unwilling?=-
-=I have bruises and wounds.=-
-=Don't worry. I will draw you beautifully.=-
Ajussi, where are you now?
Can you come over right now?
=I am getting off from work now.
I will rush over to the hospital.=
It may be inconvenient to discuss it in hospital.
Let's meet outside.
- Okay, I know.
- Okay.
What's the matter?
Yeon Do, she...
was almost violated.
Furthermore, the Headmaster was the perpetrator.
He forced himself on her but
I think he wasn't successful.
Because the child was too young.
It's too ridiculous!
Who said that?
Did you have a drink too many?
How many glasses did you drink?
Yeon Do wrote this for me last night.
- Was it really the Headmaster?
- Yes.
Yeon Do wasn't the only one
who was violated.
There were a few perpetrators.
A teacher by the name Pak Bo Hyeon
had even sexually abused boys.
Can't you understand my feelings?
- Was the Headmaster the only person who did those acts?
- Headmaster, and also Admin Head as well as Mr. Pak Bo Hyeon.
Then,
we have to made a police report.
The Police was the one who sent the children
who reported the case back to the school.
They took revenge on those children
by violently beating them up.
That dormitory superintendent, Yun Ja Ae,
who beat up Yeon Do,
is found to be the adopted daughter
of the founder of Ja Ae School.
In other words, she is the
Headmaster's younger sister.
Is there a girl named Gim Yeon Do in the patient list?
And even more ridiculous is
that Yun Ja Ae and the Headmaster are lovers.
When she snipped off Yeon Do's hair, she told her this.
If she dared to seduce the Headmaster,
she will be killed.
Ajussi.
Wait a moment.
-=Mu Jin Human Rights Center.=-
We understand that you were violated by
the Headmaster of Ja Ae School last Thursday.
Could you give an account of what happened?
That day, after school,
I went to my bedroom to change my clothes.
Then, I went to play on the field.
My playmate Yu Ri said that
she needs to go to toilet.
As she was not back after a long time,
I decided to go back to school to look for her.
Then, I saw the Headmaster and he
seems to asking me to come over.
He brought me to the Headmaster Office.
The TV was on.
I saw pictures of naked man and woman.
After the Headmaster came in,
he removed my pants.
Anyone inside?
Anyone calling?
It's drizzling outside the windows now.
The sound of raindrops that fall on the leaves,
is like whispering to us that
the cold winter has ended.
My listener friends, why not open the
windows and listen to the sound of raindrops?
The first song that I'm playing is one that is
suitable to be heard in a raining day.
Let's listen to "A Thornbush" by Jo Sung Mo.
Everything is fine now.
Yeon Do said she had seen it too.
If you dare to tell this to others,
I will kill you.
Looks like you are new and don't know
the situation here well.
The children often made
strange sounds when they are bored.
- Father!
- You're here, mom.
Why did you take so long to open the door?
What are you doing?
Don't tell me because you are
teaching the deaf children,
so you become deaf as well.
Why didn't you tell me before coming over?
I'm coming to my son's house.
Do I still need to make an appointment?
This place is not a hotel.
But how can you bring a sick child over here?
You...Have you forgotten?
Today is Song In's mother's death memorial day.
How's the school?
Just like that.
What's wrong? Are you being disregarded?
You just have to tolerate a bit.
In the first place, country folks are a bit xenophobic.
What's that?
I heard that your school's
headmaster loves cymbidium.
Prof. Gim has mentioned before
that your school's headmaster is a
person with wide connections.
I heard that a few teachers that were before you
were transferred to Seoul after
getting into the headmaster's good books.
Mom, do you know what those people really are?
- Mom, let me tell you. Those people...
- Do you think I would think
people who sell teaching positions are good people?
Do you know where I got those money?
Those money came from the
deposit money for the house.
Did you return the house?
Is that how the remittance came about?
Then what was your initial thinking?
I can't possibly go and steal money, right?
You never remit any money to us.
How on the earth can I get
that large sum of money?
I understand but why did you return the house?
You really...You are still acting like
you are the head of this family.
During the times you were wondering
aimlessly for the sake of drawing.
Have you forgotten it was Song In's mother
and I who raised Song In and provided for
your living expenses?
Before Song In's mother died,
she was still worrying over Song In and you!
Father, are you quarreling with grandmother?
Don't say anymore.
You just focus on teaching the students,
don't be a busybody, and do a good job
in your own area of work.
Song In, are you all right?
Mom. Quickly.
Here's the medicine.
- Song In.
- Come, breathe in.
- One more time. Good.
- Good.
I have found a house near to where we lived previously.
Although it's a bit small,
it's good enough for Song In and me to live in.
In Ho, don't bother about other things.
Just think of Song In, please?
We are putting up a formal application
to dismiss Chairman of Ja Ae School,
and to punish the people who
sexually abused the children.
I'm very sorry. May I interrupt for a while?
Those sexual abuses...
were they done during lesson times?
In other words, was it something
that happened during class?
Looking at this video clip, it's clear that
- the children were abused after school.
- So, it was after school.
If it's after school, then it's not under our administration.
What?
Since Mr. Gim committed those acts after school,
why should it be under our administration?
Such things should come under City Hall.
The Headmaster, the Admin Head and also a teacher
sexually abused students in the school.
Don't tell me this is not under
the Education Department?
Let me put in another way.
Ja Ae School is indeed come under our control.
But Ja Ae Hostel...
is a school dormitory and should come under
the City Hall Social Welfare Department.
After school, the children are
managed by the school dormitory.
Therefore, you should go to the City Hall.
I already went to the City Hall.
The people over at the City Hall said since the
sexual abuses happened in the school compound,
we should seek advice from the Education Department...
I have told you that after school incidents
are not under our administration.
Ajumma.
(ajumma - addressing a middle aged woman)
The children encountered such things in the school
and all of you kept saying that it's not under you.
Tell me exactly who is in charge?
Don't tell me it's under the Blue House?
Or how about the White House?
Of course is City Hall.
Why aren't you investigating?
The children was sexually abused in school.
Furthermore, these acts were done by
the Headmaster. Shouldn't that be investigated?
Of course we should investigate.
Then why aren't you investigating?
Miss Seo, that Headmaster is an elder of Mu Jin Church.
He's a devoted Christian and
also a reputable person in this region.
That's why I brought you the DVD and
written records of the children's statements.
Here are all these evidences.
Why are you not taking any action?
How can we just based on what were said
by the deaf children and arrest that person?
Moreover, that person just received
a certification of commendation from
the Governor a few days ago.
Furthermore, as there are problems
concerning human rights recently,
we also cannot anyhow arrest people.
Miss Seo, you should know better
than me regarding the last point.
They had done such things to the children.
Why are you bullshitting on human rights?
If all of you going to continue like this,
I will take the issue straight to the Prosecutor Office.
If you really do that, I'm really grateful to you.
Don't jump into conclusions thinking
we don't want to investigate.
Without orders from the Prosecutor,
we also cannot take any actions.
I'm also not happy. I think I should consider
grooming my son to be a prosecutor.
Hello.
=Miss Seo, I'm Yeong Hun. Seoul Television Station
has contacted us, saying they are interested
to do a coverage on this case.=
- Really?
-= Yes. They are on their way here.
You come back quickly.=
I understand. I'll be there right away.
Come here. Come here.
Brat.
Min Su, get up.
Why are lying there? Quickly get up.
Where are Yeon Do and Yu Ri?
Aren't you friends with them?
Don't mumble. Speak up. Quickly speak up.
This is so frustrating.
I'm asking you to speak up! You dumb!
You are always mumbling.
How will I understand them?
This kid is really...
Mr. Pak, you are getting old.
Looks like the children are
no longer afraid of you.
Mr. Pak.
This is the Headmaster Office.
Find a quieter place.
-=They will really receive punishment?=-
-=Yes, I promise you.=-
Why did your younger brother go to
the railway track early in the morning?
Can you tell us what happened to
your younger brother before he died?
When Mr. Pak Bo Hyeon knocked off from work,
he asked us to follow him home.
Although I don't wish to,
I can't reject because he will beat me up.
Why? You want to go first?
You're too noisy.
I already said not to make noise.
I cannot concentrate.
Didn't I say to you before that
making noise is not a courtesy act?
I did not allow you to make noise.
I asked you to wait quietly for your turn.
You didn't hear that?
Come over! You this brat!
I'm not sure how long it was.
Min Su!
He took off my undergarment.
And then came on top of me...
Can't you resist or escape?
If I resist, I will be beaten the whole night.
Did that sort of thing happened before?
In the teacher's house and
also the dormitory's bathroom.
=My younger brother was weak.
After undergoing that sort of thing,=
=he was under great pain and cannot really walk.=
Officer Jang, what are you doing?
You have the right to engage a lawyer
and also the right to remain silent
with evidences against you.
Did you arrest me because of
what you saw on TV?
They fabricated it.
That wasn't me.
Do you believe I'm that type of person?
I'm an elder with Mu Jin Church
and a devoted Christian.
Officer Jang, you also knew this thing.
Let me go. Do you know who you are arresting?
I'm a friend of your superintendent.
What's your name?
- I'm not done with you.
- Hyeong, you don't have to worry.
Nothing will happen to you.
God will bless you.
Don't worry. I will definitely let off the
people who tarnish my brother's reputation.
- What bad luck today.
- Officer Jang.
Hyeong.
Let go of me.
Officer Jang, you really don't believe in me?
How could you treat us like this?
We have given you so many gifts.
This has caused a big commotion at the
Mu Jin Prosecutor Office today.
If we don't handle this properly,
not only I will be finished,
but also my superiors.
I'm not going to repeat. Please stop grumbling.
Listen carefully to what I have to say.
Make use of all your connections.
Search for a lawyer who started
his career as a judge.
He must be at least a judge of ministerial grade.
It's even better if his birth place is Mu Jin.
Don't keep doing useless things such as
screaming aloud that you are maligned.
You can do that during your prayers.
Before such a lawyer is found, you should act
ignorant and be well-behaved just like those
children who were sexually abused by you.
Understand?
Dear residents of Mu Jin, Elder Lee Gang Bok
and Elder Lee Gang Seok have over
the last 10 over years,
worked hard day and night, and contributed
selflessly to our Mu Jin Church and Mu Jin City.
They believe and serve Jesus,
and care for those pitiful disabled children.
They devoted their whole life to charity.
Yet these dishonest people maligned our elders.
We absolutely cannot forgive them.
It's a blessing in disguise.
I'm begging all residents.
The children cannot hear all these.
Both Elders spent all their time and
effort on our church and Mu Jin City.
Yeong Hun sunbae. Have you checked out
the background of their lawyer?
That lawyer is called Hwang U Sik.
He's a famous and talented lawyer in Mu Jin.
He graduated from Mu Jin High School
and was the best law graduate from Seoul University.
He was once a ministerial grade judge.
He opened a law firm just recently.
It seems that this is his first law case.
- "Jeon Gwan Ye U".
- What is "Jeon Gwan Ye U"?
(Jeon Gwan Ye U - privileges of former post)
There's an informal arrangement for a retired
judge with this ministerial grade to receive
special treatment for their first case in private practice.
Why are these two people so identical,
both in appearance and character?
I lived in disgrace over the last few days.
I reflected on why God is making me
go through this type of suffering.
My father, Mr. Lee Jun Beon.
Because he pitied those deaf and mute,
he used all his savings to build this Ja Ae School.
It's already more than 50 years. Since childhood,
my brother and I never forgotten
a saying from our father.
"Treat these pitiful lambs well."
We cannot hear.
Please find us an interpreter.
Silence.
Your Honor.
They cannot hear you asking them to be silent.
In court, if you speak without permission,
you will be ordered to leave the courtroom.
I am Seo Yak Jin who works at Mu Jin Human Rights Center.
This is a court case involving the hearing-impaired.
To assist these disabled people,
please arrange for a sign language interpreter.
Seo Yak Jin, please retire from the courtroom.
Objection.
Police guards, what are you doing there?
Quick, take her away.
Objection. I object to it.
Your Honor, objection.
Did I say the wrong thing?
Starting from now, even if it's a whisper,
I will also follow the law strictly
and take action on you.
Defendant, please continue.
Jesus will protect you.
Amen.
What? Rape.
You, this despicable person. In your eyes,
you can only see those dirty things?
Ajumma, what are you doing?
Where did this wretch girl pop up from?
Who are you exactly?
I'm Lee Gang Seok's wife.
What are you trying to do?
- You this wretch!
- Don't be like this.
How dare you sue my husband?
You thought that we can be easily bullied?
- Ajumma.
- I won't let you have your way, you wretch!
- Let go of me.
- You this devil.
Let go of me!
If your husband has done those things,
even if you kneel and beg for forgiveness
for a long time, he will still not be forgiven.
She still dare to behave so crazily towards me.
Ajussi, you are really different.
She spitted on your face and you just
calmly asked her why she did that.
Can I stay in your office this period of time?
-=Why?=-
Don't tell me you ran away from home.
Fired?
These people think that they could
just dismiss people as they wish.
Ajussi, you don't have to worry.
I will make sure they are punished by the law
and you can get back your job.
I really envy you.
You live such a simple life.
They really look down upon people.
My life is also not as smooth sailing as you thought.
I was only concerned with the latest fashion
and never go for a proper date.
Always getting zeros in school.
Cannot find any job.
And with this meagre salary from my current job...
Ajussi.
Have you regretted...
participating in such a thing?
Mom, you are really amazing.
You know that I receive my salary today.
I have remitted to you in the morning.
Visit the bank to check it out.
Yes, everything is well.
No. You come over. I'm very busy.
A lot of work in school.
After this busy period,
I will find time to come home.
I swear
by Almighty God that the evidence I
shall give will be the truth,
the whole truth and nothing but the truth.
If I withhold any truths,
I will be punished by the law.
Witness O Jae Sik.
Defendant lawyer, you can start examination.
Mr. O Jae Sik.
What is your area of work in Ja Ae School?
I'm the security guard and also do night-duty.
How long have you been working in this area?
About 5 years.
So in the last 5 years,
you are by the side of the
Headmaster and Admin Head.
What is your opinion of them?
They are both good people.
- And they also take good care of me.
- Your Honor, objection.
These questions are unrelated to the case.
Objection sustained.
Please only raise questions related to this case.
Do you patrol around the school every night?
Yes. I patrol every 3 hours at night.
Right. So over the last 5 years,
did you see any instances where the Headmaster
and the Admin Head called the children individually
into the Headmaster Office and Admin Head Office
respectively after school?
I didn't see any such instances.
Sign language interpreter,
please let them know clearly
that if they continue to noisy,
I will ask them to leave the courtroom.
You mentioned before that on the day when
Gim Yeon Do was nearly violated,
you met Gang In Ho
in front of the toilet, right?
Yes.
What did he say to you?
He said he heard a child's voice
coming from inside the toilet.
So what did you do?
He asked me to check it out.
So I pushed open the toilet's door,
and stepped in to check.
Was there anyone inside?
No one.
Okay. I'm done with my questioning.
Prosecutor, it's your turn to cross examine.
Witness, where did you work
before this current job?
I previously worked as a security guard
at Mu Jin Primary School.
Why did you decide to transfer to this special school?
From what I know, you earn a lower salary at this
special school compared with the previous one.
That was because...
Because when you're in Mu Jin Primary School,
you were caught stealing school's properties.
It is still on police records. Is it true?
You were dismissed by the school
and was unemployed for 3 years.
- Your Honor. The Prosecutor is asking
questions not related to this case.
- No, it's related.
Because there exists some kind of promise
between the school and its staff.
That's why such immoral thing is connived.
People are kept completely in the dark
and it was not uncovered till now.
It's even possible that this is the
key to solving this whole case.
Objection overruled. Please continue.
How did you get the job in this school?
It definitely not easy getting in
relying on your curriculum vitae.
I was introduced by an associate.
That's right. Because you were
introduced by an associate.
Also you gave money in the name of the school
development fund. Finally you got this post and
started work in the school.
But what if this case causes the school to close down.
You will lose everything and become homeless.
Was that the truth?
I'm done with my questions.
Witness, are you the doctor that came
with the staff of Human Rights Center?
Yes.
What's the outcome of the examination?
There are symptoms of
inflammation in her genitalia.
Her hymen was already torn.
Is sexual abuse the only way in
which a young girl's hymen is torn?
No. Cycling or
masturbation may tore it too.
As a gynecologist,
- you must have examined
many patients who are sexually abused.
- Yes.
Normally, what's the condition of such patients?
The genitalia tear will be more serious.
Furthermore, they will feel humiliated
and almost out of their mind.
So when you were examining Jin Yu Ri,
what was her condition?
She was munching biscuits.
She was extremely calm even to an extent
that I thought she wasn't violated.
She also didn't have any bruises or wounds.
In other words, you don't think
she had been violated, right?
Yes.
I'm done with my questions.
This doctor is the general secretary
of Mu Jin Girls' High School Alumni.
That woman is the Chairman.
Your Honor.
What is this?
This is the preliminary analysis report
for Jin Yu Ri written by the witness.
Am I holding the actual
preliminary analysis report?
In other words, you had
written 2 analysis reports, right?
That was because...
You just have to answer Yes or No.
Then let us take a look at the first analysis report.
The patient's genital injury and
the tearing of her hymen
were not caused by recent
sexual intercourse.
But in the subsequent analysis report,
you said that
sexual intercourse was highly unlikely the cause.
Instead, you wrote that it was
caused by other reasons.
This is different from the first report.
What's the reason for judging that
it wasn't due to sexual intercourse
in the second report?
- What's the reason for changing the analysis report?
- At that time, I...
didn't know that it will have
implications on such a serious matter.
Don't tell me that a doctor's analysis report
will differ according to how serious the matter is.
In the first analysis report,
you wrote that it wasn't due to
recent sexual intercourse.
Then, it means that you believe she
had sexual intercourse in the past. Am I right?
Witness, why did you change your testimony?
Is it really because of the seriousness of this case?
No, it is not.
I felt that the damage to her hymen
was not something that happened recently.
Instead, it had happened at least 5 years ago.
If it's 5 years ago,
the victim was only 9 years old.
It's really too young for her to have intercourse.
Therefore...
I like to ask
Is it really possibly for her to be involved in
intercourse with an adult man?
Even if it's possible,
without the consent and coordination by the female,
this sort of thing couldn't happen, isn't it?
Silence.
-=Min Su, you have no appetite?
Do you want me to order other food for you?=-
-=Yeon Do, you are not hungry?=-
-=When I was young, I came to the beach
before with my father and mother.=-
-=That was before I was deaf...=-
-=At that time, I heard the sound of
wave crashing into the shore.=-
-=But now it's very quiet.=-
-=The best and most beautiful things in the world=-
-=cannot be seen or even touched.=-
-=They must be felt with the heart.=-
-=This is a quote by Helen Keller,=-
-=and it's my favorite quote.=-
What did she say?
She said it would be good if I were her father.
She said it would be good if you were her mother.
Hey, she's already talking like an adult.
Until now, I don't even had a proper love relationship.
How can she match us together?
Ajussi, don't dream. There's not a hope for you.
Why?
Why don't you answer me?
Quickly answer me.
I am the one who has been
taken advantage of, not you.
Who said you had been taken advantage of?
You said it yourself.
First, the examination of the defendants.
Looking at the child who is sitting here.
What's your feelings?
With things being in this state.
In any case, she was victimized by you all.
I am always curious
who was the one who spread these absurd rumors?
- But it looks like I could vaguely
remember the child's face...
- Defendant.
You mean you cannot remember clearly
that child that sued you for sexually abuse?
Although I saw her a few times...
The Headmaster is not wrong.
That child is also intellectually disabled.
So I also remembered caressing her head a few times.
Defendant Pak Bo Hyeon, how about you?
She belongs to my class.
I have no reason not to know her.
I have always love and treasure these children.
Among them,
Who was the one who removed
your clothes and made you painful?
All 3 of them.
How many times?
Many times. Many, many times.
Do you still remember when it first started?
It started when I was in Primary 3.
Admin Head would always give me money
every time he did that thing to me.
Every time he would give me 1000 Won to buy biscuits.
Admin Head removed my pants.
It's too painful. I said no and pushed him away.
Because I was too scared, I tried to escape.
However, Admin Head grabbed hold of me
and pinned me on the table.
He also tied up my hands and legs.
They were all lies.
Your Honor, she's a lunatic!
Don't believe in her words.
They were all lies.
- How dare you say such lies!
- Silence.
Did someone incite you to say all these?
- Exactly who incited you to say such lies?
- Silence!
Settlement? The children were sexually abused.
Why should there be a settlement?
Yes, according to the Prosecutor.
Children who are 13 years old and above
and suffered from sexually abuse.
If they agree to a settlement,
their testimony will all become invalid.
If one really met with such a thing,
will one agrees to settle outside court?
Yeon Do's parents are gone.
Nothing much can be done.
But Min Su and Yu Ri's parents
are mentally retarded.
They are really a pack of beasts.
Bullying those children with no parents.
Once Yu Ri and Min Su agree to the settlement,
then what's left will only be
the Headmaster's sexually abuse case on Yeon Do.
Professor.
I'm really very sorry to ask
to see you so abruptly.
No, it's okay. I should have visited you.
I roughly heard about the case from Lawyer Hwang.
I was the one who recommended you to that school.
So I am sandwiched in the middle
and my position is a bit awkward.
I am sorry.
You don't have to feel apologetic to me.
But if this case continues to drag,
you also won't get any benefits out of it.
This is the money that you
donated to the school previously.
And we added a bit more to it.
I hope to settle the case with Yeon Do.
Appreciate if Mr. Gang could help out.
If you are willing to help us,
we will be responsible for the expenses
to send Yeon Do to university.
We will also send her abroad to further study.
Of course, you should continue to draw.
I feel it's a pity if you have to
give up your future in this area.
I have already made arrangements
for you to join a school in Seoul.
You just have to work hard for
another 1 to 2 terms over there.
I have already settled it with the school.
They would convert you to permanent staff.
I'm sorry, Professor.
I have some other things on.
I'm leaving first.
Mr. Gang.
You should give a thought to
your daughter who's still young.
I heard your daughter is quite sick.
The negotiation for settlement
had been completed.
It seems that Yu Ri's father
was convinced by his relatives.
You know it very well.
Yu Ri's father is mentally retarded. So...
-=Yeon Do, are you confident to
articulate your statement clearly?=-
What are you doing here?
You said that you were very busy at school
and so you couldn't return home.
Is this place your school?
Are you thinking that people
might not believe in your words,
that's why you chose not to tell me?
Think of yourself first.
Take good care of your family.
It's no use saying the right things.
I have to go in.
To you,
is this child more important than
your daughter Song In?
I was present when the child
met with that sort of thing.
But I was helpless.
If I were to give up now,
I'm not confident to be a good father to Song In.
Gim Yeon Do.
You said that the Headmaster violated you.
Was that the truth?
Yes.
Are you usually in good terms
with the Headmaster?
No.
Then how would you know that
the person who violated you was the Headmaster?
Because I met him a few times in school.
Furthermore, that person dragged me
into the Headmaster Office that night.
In that case, between the 2 persons over there,
which one is the Headmaster?
Objection.
He cannot request the victim
to confirm the identity of a suspect
whom had already been confirmed.
This is a very important question.
She said that she was violated by the Headmaster.
To the victim, it's just an encounter.
However, if we look from the perspective of
the Headmaster and his younger twin brother.
It's possible that the real culprit wasn't
the Headmaster but his younger brother.
Then Headmaster Lee Gang Seok
would no longer be a suspect.
Objection overruled. Please continue.
Between the two, who's the one who harm you?
Your Honor, Yeon Do requests to
take a closer look at them.
Agree.
Prisoner with serial number 4022
is indeed the defendant, Headmaster Lee Gang Seok.
But,
How did you recognize him?
Does Lee Gang Seok have any special features?
Headmaster and Admin Head
both do not know sign language.
But on the night when Headmaster
did that to me in the toilet,
and every time when he did bad things on Yu Ri,
he would always made one hand sign.
What's the hand sign?
If you dare to tell others, I will kill you.
I performed this hand sign to both of them.
Only one of them understood this
and his facial expression changed.
Hence, this person must be the Headmaster.
Yeon Do, according to your testimony,
after dinner,
on your way home after buying a bowl of noodles,
you noticed that Yu Ri had disappeared, right?
After that, you saw the Headmaster
sexually abusing Yu Ri in the Headmaster Office.
Was that the truth?
Yes.
In this hearing,
on your way to the dormitory,
you heard faint music coming
from the Headmaster Office.
So you changed your direction and
walked towards it to find out more, right?
Yes.
Your Honor.
This is it.
Faint music.
Everyone knows that Yeon Do is deaf.
But yet she could hear music.
This deaf child, upon hearing music, walked towards it.
When she reached the source of the music,
she saw the Headmaster raping her friend.
Your Honor.
This testimony is so absurd!
- To come up with such absurd testimony...
- She said she didn't lie.
She really heard very faint music.
It's a song from Jo Sung Mo.
Witness, you have impaired hearing,
but you can still hear music, right?
Yes.
Yeon Do.
From now onwards, we are running a test
to check whether you can hear music.
If you hear music, please raise your hand.
Begin.
I recognized the witness's account.
Forensic Branch, please submit a report to the court
as regards to Yeon Do's suspect identification.
The next hearing is this Friday.
Prosecutor and Defendant Lawyer,
if you have new witnesses,
please reapply to court.
What did all those adults do to these little children?
When you are done with it,
return home quickly.
Miss Seo.
Why are you here?
Looks like you have guessed correctly.
Correct. That is the...
contract.
When Min Su's grandmother saw the money,
she immediately signed the contract.
Really funny.
No matter how poor or how illiterate you are,
it's your own grandchildren
who met with such a thing.
Just because of money,
they agreed to settle outside court.
Well, of course.
It's not something that I cannot comprehend.
She has a son but he lies on
the hospital bed all day long.
Her daughter-in-law eloped.
Moreover, her grandchildren
are deaf and mute.
Even I feel that
God is a bit too much.
-=Teacher, when I'm giving my testimony,
can I have this in front of me?=-
-=I also want to give a good
performance just like Yeon Do.
But I'm not confident of myself.=-
-=So I have written them down here.=-
-=When Mr. Pak Bo Hyeon did that sort of thing
to my younger brother and me.=-
Min Su!
-=Originally, you need to give a testimony.=-
-=But you cannot do it anymore.=-
-=Why?=-
-=Your grandmother=-
-=has forgiven Mr. Pak Bo Hyeon.=-
-=Those people begged your
grandmother to forgive them.=-
-=Your grandmother is a kind person, so...=-
-=He killed my younger brother! He killed him!=-
-=When he saw my brother and me,
he would beat us and remove our pants.=-
Min Su!
-=Who said to forgive him?
I have not forgiven him!=-
-=He didn't apologize to my brother and me.=-
-=How could he be forgiven?=-
-=You promised that you would make sure
those people are punished.=-
-=Teacher, didn't you make that promise?=-
I am sorry, Min Su.
I am sorry.
Yeon Do.
Why?
-=I have something to tell you.=-
-=What is it?=-
-=That time, I forgot to say=-
-=that when I was dragged into the Headmaster Office,
the picture that was showing on the television...=-
-=That movie with nude man and woman.=-
-=Although I'm not certain, that man...=-
Will there really be that type of thing?
Even if there is,
it will not be left here.
The Headmaster was arrested suddenly that day.
He didn't have the time to destroy it.
He could ask someone else to do it.
Who could he find? His wife?
His wife trusts him so much.
Could he let her know that he's a pervert?
Could he get his lover Yun Ja Ae to do it?
That's right. If Yun Ja Ae knew about it,
she would throw him into the washing machine.
It's so nauseating.
The date on the video cassette tape
is consistent with the one in Yeon Do's testimony.
You mentioned previously that
for child above 13 years old,
the case is closed after
settlement with the family.
The date was 14 March.
It means that Yu Ri hasn't reached
the age of 13 yet. In other words...
In other words,
if he sexually abused a child less than 13 years old,
he could still be sentenced
even if there exists settlement.
Moreover, with such clear-cut evidence,
Even if the defendant has "Jeon Gwan Ye U",
it would also be useless.
The final trial is just a few days away.
Will there still be a retrial?
Even if there is a retrial,
we cannot show this evidence in court.
Then what should we do?
Do not worry.
I will go and find the judge personally,
and present this evidence.
The 3 defendants.
Despite being teachers of the deaf school,
they sexually abused the young students.
It's an unpardonable criminal behavior.
And violated the social responsibility
of protecting disabled children.
Making these victims the targets
of their sexual pleasure,
sexually harassed them,
or violated them.
They should be punished severely.
But,
the defendants have made great contributions
to the development of the city,
and have no previous criminal records.
Furthermore, the families of victim Jun Yu Ri
and victim Jeon Min Su
had already reached a settlement
with the defendants.
For the sake that the defendants
had taken care of their children before,
they had written a plea for the defendants.
With consideration of all the above,
the following sentences are meted out.
Defendant Pak Bo Hyeon.
Sentenced to 8 months of imprisonment
and 2 years on probation.
Defendant Lee Gang Bok.
Sentenced to 6 months of imprisonment
and 1 year on probation.
Defendant Lee Gang Seok.
Sentenced to 6 months of imprisonment
and 1 year on probation.
Prosector.
After the end of this trial,
carry out the procedures on
the release of the defendants.
You have really worked hard.
It's not really hard work.
I'm only doing justice to you.
Doing justice.
Justice always triumph.
This is so well said.
I am sorry.
I didn't fulfill my promise.
Take a look at the children before going.
That judge.
I should go and express my gratitude to him.
You don't have to go personally.
Jeon Gwan Ye U. This is expected.
When I met him in classmate
gathering in the future,
I will treat him to drinks.
By the way,
how did you manage to bribe the Prosecutor?
That person has no promotion opportunities,
or any other options.
He's always roaming on the fringe.
In other words,
he can no longer carry on in this circle.
I told him that I will give him a job in my law firm.
He was exuberant hearing it.
What's wrong? Are you hungry?
Min Su has gone to look for Pak Bo Hyeon.
He said he wanted revenge.
I'm going over there now.
Please hurry over.
Ajussi, are you still on the phone?
Oh it's you, Min Su.
Are you thinking of me?
You are even drenched.
Let's go for a bath together.
Min Su! Min Su! Min Su!
Anyone inside?
Min Su! Min Su!
Go to hell!
Min Su!
I treated you so well in the past.
How can you do this to me?
You this brat.
How dare you try to stab me!
I'm going to beat you to death!
Min Su!
You brat, how can you do this to me?
We are from Mu Jin Police Station.
Listen up, everyone.
By gathering here,
you have violated Demonstration
Act, Article 6, Item 1 on illegal gathering.
All of you are
illegally occupying the roads.
And jeopardizing the lives of the kind residents.
I hope you will disperse immediately.
Your demonstration now
is not allowed and is an illegal demonstration.
Please disperse immediately.
I going to make the announcement again.
Now, everyone of you
is illegally occupying the roads.
If you don't disperse immediately,
we will charge you under the
Demonstration Act and Traffic Regulation.
That's right.
They cannot hear me.
What is going on? Hurry to open fire.
Let go of me!
This child...
Neither can he hear nor can he speak.
This child
is called Min Su.
He's a child who cannot hear
and cannot speak.
Everyone! This child's name
is called Min Su.
Neither can he hear
nor can he speak.
Everyone, please.
This child
is called Min Su.
Neither can he hear nor can he speak.
Everyone, this child is called Min Su.
This child...
-=One year later=-
Ajussi, how are you?
It seems like I haven't contacted you for a long time.
Many things happened during this period.
There are good ones
and bad ones.
Let me tell you the bad thing first.
We are still unsuccessful with the appeal.
The main problem is still because of
the settlements that the families entered in.
The good thing is that many people
have come forward to help the children.
Because of them, the children who quitted
from Ja Ae School have a place to live in.
There are also people who provided free food.
Yu Ri is undergoing psychological treatment.
She is healthier now.
She is also more jovial these days.
And she will even teach me sign language.
Yeon Do said that she wants to be
an art teacher when she grows up.
She said she wanted to me like you
helping sick children.
Once during dinner time,
I asked Yeon Do and Yu Ri,
what's the greatest difference before
and after this incident?
The children said,
"We now know that we are no difference from others."
"We are treasured by people too."
Watching these children growing up gradually,
it comes to my mind that
the reason why we are fighting so hard,
is not to change the world
but instead not to let the world change us.
The weather has become colder.
Winter is cold
because it wants us to appreciate
the warmth from our surrounding people.
It's so precious!
Although we are not by your side,
I hope you can feel
the warmth given out by the children and me.
I will pray for you.
-=Till 2011, a few of the perpetrators
have gone back to school.
The case had completed ended.=-
-=But to expose the truth,
they are still continue with the fight...=-