Subtitles by DramaFever
[Episode 13]
Seriously, it came out again.
See, you threw out this hair clip
for no reason and it's all bent now!
Seriously...
Hand it over.
Come over here.
Did it work?
But... about that story of the Little
Mermaid you mentioned yesterday.
Does it really end like that?
To my knowledge, the Little Mermaid
doesn't disappear into sea foam bubbles.
The Prince can't remember,
so what can you do?
How would you have
liked it to end then?
Me?
Hey, hurry up!
The boat came in!
People must be waiting. Let's go.
About that Little Mermaid
story earlier...
I remembered how it ended.
How... does it end?
'The moment the Little Mermaid
turns into sea foam bubbles...'
'The Prince's memory...'
returned.'
Shouldn't fairytales
usually end like that?
A happy ending.
People don't know fairytales very well.
Soo In, when did you get here?
- Just now.
- Let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
I'm sorry to have made
you worry over nothing.
Not at all. Let's go.
That's right. It isn't over yet.
Snap out of it, Park Soo In.
- This way.
- Yes.
President Jo!
Let's have dinner together.
I have something to
tell you as well.
Let's eat.
- Did you find what you lost?
- Yes, I did.
What was it that you
were in such a hurry?
This is all because of that
hair clip you bought her.
Spend money if you're going
to buy a present for your girlfriend.
How countrified.
Go on, eat.
What?
Is it the first time you've seen
someone wrap eel in lettuce?
It's delicious wrapped
in sesame leaf as well.
President Jo. I told you that
I had something to tell you.
Joon Hyun and I are getting engaged.
I felt like you should know
ahead of time.
We're planning a quiet occasion
without letting the press know.
Yes well... that's
something to celebrate.
Congratulations.
Did I... do something wrong
by bringing up the engagement party?
I'm sorry for deciding that
on my own without consulting you.
No, it's okay. Let's go.
You're going to go home, right?
No, I'll go to the practice studio.
I'd like for you to rest at home today.
I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
You don't have to be like that
in front of me.
Do whatever you want.
Don't hold it in.
Joon Hyun and I are getting engaged.
Found it!
We found this at the crime scene.
Is this yours?
- Tae Song.
- Where are you right now?
I'm on my way to hand my cellphone
to a repair shop...
Never mind. I'll go myself.
It'll take some time to recover
the videos.
I'll contact you.
He isn't here.
[Happy Call Electronics]
Customer, were you happy
with your service?
We'll contact you when the phone
you gave us is repaired. Thank you.
He gave them a cellphone to repair?
But this is his cellphone.
No way...
- You're here?
- You're here.
These are the locations for
our engagement party.
Why don't you choose.
I think this one is run down
despite it being popular...
What? He already picked it up?
Jang Joon Hyun picked up
his cellphone in person.
Are you all right?
Why didn't I think of
that cellphone earlier?
It's all over if he looks
at that cellphone!
It'll have pictures of them
together and everything!
What do we do now?
What are we going to do?
Calm down.
Your engagement's coming up soon.
I'll take care of the cellphone.
You trust me, don't you?
[Lee Hwa Soon: LA Address]
Hello?
Is this Hwa Soon?
It's me, Yang Joo Hee.
Right, it's been a while.
Did you hear? That Joon Hyun
and Soo In are getting engaged?
Goodness, you didn't know?
These are all the albums
Shine Star produced.
Should I call it a
kind of honorary hall?
Wow.
Choose one.
See if there's a record that
could be your role model.
What if you put out a ballad?
What?
There's no rule saying
you have to stick to trot.
Think about it.
There are a lot of options.
Joon Hyun.
Yes, Soo In.
Our engagement party
invitations came today.
Who would you invite from Shine Star?
I was going to ask my mom first.
Choon Hee.
Our engagement party is on Monday.
You can come, right?
We shouldn't do that.
How about you sing a celebratory song?
We can quiet down the rumors
between the three of us that way.
- Soo In.
- I have an event that day.
I'm sorry.
About what?
Asking you to sing
a celebratory song.
Are you happy?
What reason would I have...
not to be?
That's enough then.
I gave out all the invitations.
I promised to give them
a call the day before...
- Soo In?
- Yeah?
Don't misunderstand what
I'm going to say and just listen.
There's something I need to confirm...
before the engagement party.
So about that...
Couldn't we postpone
the engagement party?
- Joon Hyun.
- No, it's that...
- It's not because of something else...
- Is there another woman?
Huh?
Tell me the truth.
It's not like that.
That's enough then.
Joon Hyun. After a sudden accident
and losing your memory...
I understand that you're probably
really confused lately.
Let's try a little harder, okay?
And...
Thanks.
You saved me at the concert hall.
I won't ever forget that.
I wanted to make sure
that I told you these words.
What's all this?
Son!
Oh, my son! Have you been well?
Mom. Why did you come here?
What do you mean? Should I not come
even if my son's getting engaged?
Yang Joo... I mean,
Soo In's mother called me.
My impressive son.
How long has it been, Hwa Soon?
You haven't changed.
I always look the same.
But you've seemed to age.
- We're both getting older.
- 'We'?
Oh dear, there are people asking me
if I'm in my twenties in the States.
Mother, we're seeing each other
after quite a while.
- Do you remember me?
- Oh yes, Soo In.
It's the first time seeing each other
since you were young, right?
- How pretty you've grown up to be.
- Thank you.
But who's going to pay for the house?
- House?
- The house the kids will live in.
Shouldn't you have
prepared one if you're
getting Joon Hyun
as a son-in-law?
[Soo In]
Are you happy?
Jang Joon Hyun and Park Soo In
are getting engaged today.
What? Jang Joon Hyun
and Park Soo In?
Per your instructions, I also
looked into Yang Joo Hee.
Is that right?
You have to go back to your owner now.
Right. You at least have to stay
by Jang Joon Hyun's side.
I'll miss you.
It was here.
I'll make sure to find
your guitar for you. Choon Hee.
Goodness, President Jo.
What brings you?
Were you responsible
for the scandal
between Choi Choon Hee
and the politician?
Excuse me?
Choi Choon Hee is a singer
I told you to train.
But you fed her to the wolves
like that, Director Yang?
What was your reason for that?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't know what
you've heard...
Did you know Choon Hee
is Sung Joo's daughter?
I have a debt to Oh Sung Joo.
I'll take care of Choi Choon Hee
until her father returns.
I'm warning you, Director Yang.
If you mess with Choi Choon Hee
one more time...
I won't stand for it.
President Jo just came by.
He claims to know everything
about Choi Choon Hee.
It's okay.
If this gets out, then let's take
care of Choi Choon Hee for good.
Jang Joon Hyun?
Someone asked me to deliver this to you.
Who... dropped this off?
A woman dropped by not too long ago
and asked me to give this to you.
- A woman?
- Yes.
Choi Choon Hee?
Choi Choon Hee!
Are you awake now?
Choi Choon Hee.
What about Choi Choon Hee?
She's asleep.
She'll wake up soon.
She'll be fine once she's stabilized.
Neither of you have to worry.
I want to say that I love you
Just riding on this wish
Afraid that you might leave
- Choi Choon Hee.
- Hmm?
Afraid that you might leave
- Choi Choon Hee.
- Hmm?
Sorry.
Are you okay?
Huh?
I was a bit late, wasn't I?
It's yours, Choi Choon Hee.
- Over there.
- Joon Hyun!
Joon Hyun!
Goodness, my son!
Son, what happened?
I heard you were in an accident!
- Don't worry, I'm fine.
- Are you really okay?
Yeah. But how did you know
that I was here?
I tried calling and
the nurse picked up.
But Joon Hyun, who were you
in such a rush to see?
Huh?
A friend who lives far away came by
and left without a word.
I went looking for that friend, and...
But now the engagement party is ruined
because of me. What will you do?
Is that the issue right now?
We can reschedule
the engagement party.
You should be getting better right now.
Still, what a relief.
Someone was complaining because they
didn't know you were in an accident...
What a relief. Oh, my son.
In any case, nothing good
can come from Yang Joo Hee's family.
Like that accident on stage
and today's accident, too...
What's going on?
Figures, in Sung Joo's accident too...
There was an accident in the past?
No, my son. It was nothing at all.
Now that our son-in-law is well,
we should continue with the engagement.
You saved me at the concert.
I won't ever forget that.
Even if this gets out, let's take care
of Choi Choon Hee for good next time.
Are you awake now?
You're looking for the man
that came in with you, right?
- Singer Jang Joon Hyun.
- Was he really hurt?
- Did he look okay?
- He went back home earlier.
It's a relief that
both of you are fine.
Ah, yes.
That guy has no loyalty.
How can he just leave?
But it's a relief to
hear that he's fine.
[Missed Call]
You must be giving it
to your girlfriend.
Who is it?
It's President Jo!
Here, a present for the Little Miss.
Wow, it's candy! Looks delicious!
What? You don't like candy?
That's not it...
This is a bribe.
- Huh?
- I'm a fair person.
I'm going to keep a firm boundary
with you and Joon Hyun.
I won't stand for it
if you cross it.
Ah, so there was that problem!
That's right. How about this then?
You eat this candy and also
eat the ones from that man!
That's fair then.
It's fair not to receive anything
from anyone
but isn't it also fair to accept
gifts from both people?
- Isn't that right?
- Oh!
All right, here.
What's this?
I have to hand it to these adults.
You shouldn't joke around
with food!
I really thought it was candy!
The real candy's here!
- Is it good?
- Yes.
This is for your sister.
Chocolate.
Wow, chocolate!
I really like chocolate!
No, you can't eat this, Byul.
There's a bitter alcohol in here
that only adults can eat.
- Liquor?
- Yeah.
Your sister is probably having
a hard day today.
Tell her to eat these and
have sweet dreams tonight.
Got it?
I think I know what you mean.
What?
This competition has
gone on, but it feels
like the other competitor
has withdrawn.
Jang Joon Hyun didn't get engaged.
- What?
- They're rescheduling it.
In any case...
You should probably
pull it more towards you, huh?
So what I'm thinking, is to give you
a proper chance to act as my father.
Huh?
Ji Sook, I'm sorry.
Because of my momentary passion,
I couldn't look at you.
I'll just keep watch over you
from a distance.
Tae Song!
- Hi, Pil Nyeo.
- Have you been well?
Look how much better you look
after being away for some time.
It must make a difference. I feel
great and my skin feels good, too.
Oh. Then you two went
on a trip together?
So you've officially
become a couple then?
We've officially become a couple!
Ji Sook!
No, it's good.
Let's eat together.
Why are you eating alone?
Should we order one more?
- I'm... done. Done.
- You still have a lot left.
You can't.
- Goodbye.
- I'm leaving!
They're embarrassed.
Hi.
I'm your top fan.
- Hello.
- You're prettiest when you smile
so why does your face look like it's
carrying all the burdens of the world?
Should we hold a fan meeting
to boost your spirits?
- A fan meeting?
- Yes.
Hi.
What? Are you worried because
it'll be expensive?
Afraid I might ask you to pay?
Of course not, of course not at all.
I'm just kidding.
Over here.
President Jo.
What are you doing here?
- I planned this with my father.
- Father...
He's your father?
- President Jo Hee Moon...
- Father.
Goodness, oh my!
There were so many things
I was curious about!
I heard that you told Jang Joon Hyun
to train me.
But how did you know who I was?
I was the one who trained your mother.
It was the first job I had
when I established Shine Star.
Then the person who gave up
singing was... my mother?
That's right.
Your mother was a great singer.
But you knew about this too, President?
What? No, I just found out.
But Father, Choon Hee must take after
her mother's excellent singing talent.
That's right. I sometimes
see Choon Hee's
mother in Choon Hee's
performances.
How about you make your mother's dreams
come true, Choi Choon Hee?
Mom, I want to become
an impressive singer like you.
You're going to help me
concentrate on singing, right?
I miss you.
Who is it?
Is this Choi Choon Hee's...
Why are you at our house?
Hey, Choi Choon Hee.
Next time that happens,
don't get involved.
If you have to get involved...
then call me.
Boo!
Why I ought to just...
I feel better. Don't
you think of the
person waiting at home
who made you food?
- Hey, I'm sorry.
- Let's go.
Agreed.
What brings you here?
You dropped off my guitar
and left, didn't you?
What was that?
You entrusted that to me
when you were my manager.
I entrusted that to you?
I definitely gave that to the new...
What?
So what I'm saying is that
it's a one of a kind so I wouldn't
have entrusted that to you.
I don't know your situation.
Anyhow, what happened
to your engagement party?
We're going to reschedule it.
Good for you.
How could you have run out like that?
What if something even worse happened?
You don't even have a pretty face.
You'll probably look good
if you get a scar.
Did you come all the
way here to say that?
That's not it...
Ah, it's hot!
What's going on?
- Why doesn't the rotation work?
- It's broken.
During the summer?
You're really something.
[Six times for a big one!
four times for a small one!]
I'm leaving.
You called me yesterday, didn't you?
- Yeah.
- How did you know my number?
I asked Tae Song.
Why did you call?
That's because...
I wanted to say thanks.
Thanks... for yesterday.
I'm leaving.
Thanks, Choi Choon Hee.
For saving me... and
for finding my guitar.
What are you talking about?
It's not like we did anything!
Who's Park Soo In to bark out orders?
She wants us to do
a homeless persons' event?
Don't you think it's
too much, Chul Man?
Those people don't know
how to be grateful.
Forget all those people
who don't have a conscience!
Choon Hee. What do you think?
I want to do it.
I'll think of Dad,
and if he likes my
song, then I think
I'll be strengthened.
Okay, good.
Chul Man, should we do
a dance this time, too?
Of course. How could we not do one?
- Isn't that right, Ji Sook?
- You really are amazing, Chul Man.
You're Choon Hee's manager
and her backup dancer.
Do they call that 'a multi-player'?
Goodness, look at me.
Don't worry about the
chorus, Choon Hee.
Tae Song, let's make sure
to practice and get it right this time.
We have to match our lips.
Like this and that,
they have to be in sync...
Oh my endorphins.
Thank you, everyone.
- Tae Song.
- Huh?
Pil Nyeo.
Goodness.
P...Pil Nyeo...
Pil Nyeo! Pil Nyeo!
Good good! Your voice
just came through from behind you.
Now that you have your sound down.
The 'feel' is very important in trot.
'Feel.' Listen.
It was like this from the start.
I liked you
from the moment I first met you.
Like a cold, I get feverish
and that's how I knew it was love.
The wind is blowing
on my heart topped with
desert and sand.
As the rain droplets fell,
a flower bloomed.
I want to live happily with you
like a happy pigeon.
- Hello.
I'm trusting you all today!
Let's get together!
We're... we're really doing this, okay?
Let's do our best and be serious.
Start! Choi Choon Hee!
Choi Choon Hee! Fighting!
- Fighting!
- I'm really nervous.
Hello. I'm singer Choi Choon Hee.
I'll be singing 'My Way'
for you all today.
How noisy! It's hard enough
living as  it is!
- We can't even eat in peace?
- That's right! Let us eat!
Mister, you're very tired, aren't you?
I really had a hard time
making a living, too.
But the thing about music...
is that it's a great strength.
So if you give me just three minutes...
I want to be a small source
of strength for you all today.
Could I sing just one song for you?
Thank you.
Then I'll be singing 'My Way' for you!
I thought that I came a long way.
I look back and you aren't there.
- Not there!
I really thought it would
rain hard.
But there wasn't any.
- Wasn't any!
At first I wasn't afraid...
But that scaredy cat changed
after some time.
Everyone can fall at least once.
But you can't get yourself down now.
Until the day I collapse
going down my path
I'm going to stand up and
face it one more time.
Everyone can fall at least once
But you can't get yourself down now.
Until the day I collapse
going down my path
I'm going to stand up and
face it one more time.
My way!
Choi Choon Hee!
- Choi Choon Hee!
- No, don't do that.
[Dongbu Hospital]
- Is this Choi Myung Sik?
- Yes, it is.
Yes.
You postponed your
surgery before.
What date should I reschedule it for?
About that...
I don't think I can get surgery.
I'm sorry.
You can't afford not
to get surgery at this time.
Choi Myung Sik!
Joon Hyun. This came for you.
Wow, it was...
What's this? Jang Joon Hyun,
has your memory returned?
Wow, this is good news!
This is good! I'm so happy for you!
- This is good news!
- Can you laugh right now?
Get on your knees.
I'm sorry.
I deserve to die.
You deserve to die?
For what?
For having handed me over
to the police?
Or not telling me about Choon Hee?
What do you think is the graver sin?
The second?
Forget it. There's something
you need to do for me.
What's that?
Keep it a secret that my memory's
returned for the time being.
Huh?
If Director Yang finds out, who know
what will happen to Choon Hee.
You can keep this secret, right?
- I got it.
- I'll kill you if you betray me again.
I... thought you'd be better
if I did that...
Joon Hyun, is it okay
to overwork yourself
like this when you
were just discharged?
- Soo In.
- Hmm?
Just a minute.
There's something that
I've been wanting to ask you.
W...what's that?
That day... the day of the accident...
Why were you up on that stage?
That wasn't your stage, but
Choi Choon Hee's concert.
That... I went to cheer Choon Hee on.
She's my junior, after all.
I went because I should at least
be looking after her.
I see.
But the thing is... I keep having
these weird thoughts.
That someone was targeting
someone else...
and that I was hit for their sakes.
By any chance...
was that person was
targeting Choi Choon Hee.
J...Joon Hyun, I don't even want
to think about that day.
Do you know how surprised I was
when you were hurt?
I seriously thought that
something terrible happened to you.
All that's important to me
is that you're safe, Joon Hyun.
If someone targeted Choi Choon Hee...
then that's a relief.
But someone I love.
If they were targeting you, then I
probably couldn't stand aside.
I'd hunt them down to the end.
Come in.
Come in. What brings you here?
I came to see you, of course.
Is that right?
Should I call Soo In over, too?
We could all have dinner later.
More importantly, I have something
to tell you, Director Yang.
Go ahead.
There's something that's been
on my mind.
About the accident last time...
I went to the office at the concert
because I'm superstitious.
But it just so happened that
the CCTV cameras weren't on then.
I lost my cellphone there too.
And so?
I'm thinking... that I need
to look more into it.
Aren't you overdoing it when
your body isn't up to it yet?
I'll look into that problem myself
from now on.
- You...
- No.
I'm the type who gets impatient
when I'm curious.
I'm planning to hunt it down
myself to the end.
But the thing is...
Why... are you telling me
all this right now?
What do you mean?
We'll be a family soon, and family
shares everything with each other.
Am I wrong, Director Yang?
Of course... you aren't wrong.
Mom, Joon Hyun is acting weird.
I'll say. He keeps
asking about that day.
He went to you, too?
Did his memory return
and he's pretending it didn't?
Wait a minute.
Let's think of an order.
What's the priority.
When will our little Byul....
She's here.
Hey.
- Ow!
- I heard you hit my sister!
You! You called your older
sister like a coward?
You little punk!
So fearless!
Do you want to be hit?
You little punks! So fearless!
Mister!
Who is it? You won't let go?
Let go!
You let go first.
Mister, don't butt in
and be on your way.
How annoying.
Pick up the gum you spat out right now.
What is he saying?
This man, seriously...
He doesn't know what
to be afraid of.
Hey, who are you?
Who are you to talk like that?
I'm...
Music's god... Jang Joon Hyun.
- Oh my god!
- Ah! Joon Hyun!
You're really Jang Joon Hyun?
What do I do? Hit me!
It hurts! This isn't a dream!
Kids.
I'm part of Byul's family, but you
seem to be giving her a hard time.
No, no. What do you mean?
I'm seeing this cutie
for the first time!
My little sister is really
good friends with her!
- Isn't that right?
- Then...
You're going to get along
from now on, right?
Hurry up and answer.
Yes.
- Should I give you an autograph?
- Yes, yes!
- Should I take a picture with you?
- Yes!
All right!
- Does it taste good?
- It does.
Byul, about today...
I know. It's a secret
to my sister, right?
Secret? Okay.
Okay.
- Bang!
- Bang, bang!
- Bang, bang, bang!
Choi Myung Sik? It's been a while
since I've seen him, too.
Anyone home?
Father!
Father, are you okay?
Here, here, here.
It's fine. It's hot, it's hot.
Be careful.
You haven't eaten until now?
That's what I'm saying.
I said we should eat anywhere, but...
For me, if I don't have the ox
bone broth you've cooked overnight
to have this soondae soup...
Then no matter what I eat,
it feels like I haven't eaten.
Check, please!
- Yes.
- Sit down.
Coming!
- For two, yes?
- Yes.
Fourteen thousand Won.
Goodbye!
Father, are you awake now?
In order to resolve my debts...
I went to loan sharks and
took out a private loan.
But then I was nearly beaten
to death by them.
When I opened my eyes,
I was in the hospital.
I also have colon cancer.
I found out... that I only have
six months to live.
I don't have the money
to pay for treatment, either.
But I wanted to leave something
to my children before I went...
So I started cleaning.
But this pitiful life...
is still breathing.
When I was in grade school...
I came back from school
to find out that my father had died.
I shouldn't have gone
to school that day.
I should have stayed by his side
for one more hour...
You hAve no idea how
long I regretted that.
Father.
Choon Hee's having a really hard time
because of various scandals.
I'm going to go back to Choon Hee.
But before I do, couldn't you
take care of her for now?
Even if it's just for an hour more.
Yes.
- President.
- Yes.
Hello.
I heard you had a concert
at a homeless persons' event.
Yes, I went to help volunteer
but they were so good to me.
It had a positive response,
so the company is going to help out.
Oh really? That's really great news.
And... at the concert...
I think I discovered
an extremely important fact.
Congratulating people
when they're happy,
comforting those
when they're sad...
and a song that doesn't differentiate
between age groups is trot.
I really must be made for trot.
I'm happiest when I sing trot.
So about the ballad album
that you mentioned last time...
Understood.
We'll pretend that never came up.
As expected!
Thank you!
Choi Choon Hee? Yes it was her who was
hospitalized with Jang Joon Hyun.
Has Joon Hyun's memories returned?
Or has he just fallen
for Choi Choon Hee again?
How do we make sure?
Just do as I tell you.
I'll cook it for you.
Go and get changed.
Okay.
Choon Hee.
The strings on my ukelele are fixed.
Did you fix them?
No.
Huh? The fan turns now.
Joon Hyun, I love it.
You bought this for me, right?
It says 'Angel' here.
It wasn't?
What's with your expression, Joon Hyun?
- I'm disappointed in you, Soo In.
- Huh?
I wanted to give it to you properly.
I wanted to see your
surprised expression.
So are you angry, Joon Hyun?
I'm sorry. What do I do?
I'm just kidding.
Why do I have such good taste?
It suits you perfectly.
Seriously.
Good thing you came!
Fix my ukelele strings for me!
- The rotation's broken.
- In this heat?
Watch out!
I'll drink it well.
I'm back.
Subtitles by DramaFever