Sync by Hana.Bean
www.VNItfriend.COM
www.Addic7ed.com
Taylor have you had breakfast?
- No I'm not hungry.
- Not acceptable!
Gotta go figure out what.
The latest public relations
crisis is today.
Who are you calling a brat?
Private!
What you do online isn't exactly private.
Oh! I almost forgot.
It's your birthday!
Mmm! Don't forget
to get me a present!
I'm gonna tie a string around my finger.
Good.
Eric!
Don't you dare miss your bus again!
It wasn't my fault last time!
Hey did you see my bag?
I need my bag.
What you need is a brain.
You can't hit me on my birthday!
Why does everybody think
I should have a party?
Turning 17 doesn't mean anything.
You're crazy. A party means
presents money bling.
If your dad left 3 months ago
you wouldn't want a party.
I don't care about that.
We should do what you did
for your 11th birthday party.
We just got our nails done.
The smell was so bad we all got sick.
I'm pretty sure Julie bryson threw up.
Did you hear Julie's pregnant?
What? How would you know?
She moved to Florida.
Clicksters. Hello!
Oh yeah of course.
...You were upset.
What did you say in health
that got Lindsay so pissed off?
Nothing! I just said it's
better to wait until you're 18.
Before you go all the way.
She's been doing it since 9th grade.
You basically called her a slut.
- Yeah!
- I did not!
It was a class discussion.
I wasn't talking about her.
My brother wears shoes like that.
He's 10.
- Don't you love High School?
- So great.
Best years of our lives.
- Wonderful.
- Amazing.
Uh definition of "contrarian"?
Me. Definition
of "lazy": You.
Do your own homework.
Look at you!
Taylor you're a "brainiac".
You should know.
Let's have it.
Oh the definition of "lust".
When I look at him my throat swells up.
You do know that Scott
is just a dumb jock right?
- No he's not!
- Ok!
If you were on clicksters.
You could send him a hot metre quiz.
And find out if he likes you.
Stop!
That is so 6th grade.
Even if I wanted to I couldn't.
My mom stands over
my shoulder the whole time.
She has computer-
monitoring software.
She goes on all the sites I've been on.
There's no way.
See you later.
- Bye.- Bye.
Her mom is so backwards.
She can't even have Internet on her phone.
Ah! How does
she live?
On this day in history the
great bard William Shakespeare.
Took his first breath in 1564.
The very first motion picture
was shown in 1896.
Theodore Roosevelt delivered
his man in the arena speech.
In 1910.
Also on this day in history.
Just a little closer to home
Taylor hillridge was born.
Happy Birthday Taylor.
Happy Birthday.
Thanks.
Today's my dad's birthday too.
Cool.
All right class.
If you would open your books
to unit 11 page 773.
We'll look at a turbulent time.
I swear when he touched my shoulder.
There was like electricity.
Oh please.
No I'm serious!
I felt a tingle.
You think he'd ask me to the spring fling?
- No!
- Why?
Scott ozsik is not the romantic type.
He's a basketball player
on the same team as Charlie.
Ok he's not like Charlie.
He is exactly like Charlie.
And I would know
because I hung out with them.
Yeah once.
Yeah. Charlie hooked
up with me.
He got what he wanted And he never spoke
to me ever again.
I know. I'm sorry.
I know how much that sucked.
He's not like Charlie.
He is exactly like Charlie.
And it's stupid for you to lose your head.
Over something silly like this.
Remember it was your dad who left you guys.
For a 25-year-old girl.
If that doesn't tell you
how scummy guys are...
Hey leave my dad out of it ok?
It's so late.
Thank you.
My own computer?
Aw lucky!
Wait hang on.
No there has to be a catch like uh...
I can only use it in the kitchen
I can't use it
after 1:00.
Or you have to share it with me.
No stop.
There's no catch.
It's all yours private.
You can use it wherever
you want if you follow my rules.
No inappropriate sites and no
giving out personal information.
I know the rules but you're
trusting me? Are you feeling ok?
You're funny. I know you think
I'm overprotective.
But the word is "responsible".
Try "suffocating".
I'll let that one slide.
You wanna be a journalist.
And I want you to write
to your heart's content.
Thank you thank you thank you thank you!
I'm gonna go hook it up.
I'll come help!
You touch you die.
Do you know if your father
called Taylor today?
Don't think so.
She told him she didn't want to
speak to him ever again so...
Ok.
What is my favourite body part?
I have to answer these
questions on my profile?
Just say "eyes".
Everybody says "eyes".
- I said "butt".
- You can get away with it.
Everybody knows you are
all talk and no action.
I'm putting "eyes".
- Shut up!
- Ah!
Hang on. What kind of
underwear am I wearing now?
Oh my God!
Just say "pink".
Everybody says "pink".
I said "black".
- You don't own black underwear!
- Black?
Seriously what's the point of
answering these questions.
If they're all untrue?
Fine! Tell everybody about
your virginal white undies.
They're not all white!
You're not gonna get
cute guys talking to you.
You'd be surprised how many guys
ask me about my black underwear.
- What?
- Now do you get it?
- Ok all right.
- It makes sense?
- But I'm not putting "black".
- Or "white".
I'll put "blue".
I'll put "blue". That's good.
What was that?
It just beeped.
Friend request.
Click there.
Ok... Oh!
- Ooh!
- It's Scott.
Ok now when you post your answer.
He'll be picturing you in your underwear.
I'm friends with Scott!
Hello?
Yeah thanks for calling.
Listen I'm looking over the numbers.
And what you gave me on line 56...
Hey!
Lindsay commented on our photo.
Oh Lindsay!
Hang on.
Oh that's not very nice.
I don't even know which one
I'm supposed to be.
Lardo or dogface.
I guess I'll be dogface.
What if I wanna be dogface?
Well fine.
Then I'm lardo.
I could always lose a little bit of weight.
You however will always look like a dog.
Thanks.
Maybe it was a freudian slip.
You know maybe you don't like history.
So you accidently dropped your book.
Get it?
I don't know.
I like history.
Oh me too.
Oh!
It's my favourite.
Caleb's kind of a weird dude huh?
Yeah a little bit.
So I saw you're on clicksters now.
I like it better
than facebook. A lot more raw.
Yeah I noticed.
So maybe I'll talk to you on there tonight?
Uh yeah. You mean like
instant message or something?
There's actually a chat
room just for the school.
I hang out there sometimes when I'm bored.
People talk trash.
It's kind of funny so...
Ha! Ok I'll look for it.
- Cool.
- Ok.
Oh what? Now I'm a loser?
That's true.
What?
Is that clicksters?
Can you make me an account?
- No!
- Please just don't... why?
- No! Get out of my room you little worm!
Go! - Aw! I hate you!
It has been decided.
I am officially lardo.
Thanks to the queen
of mountain High School.
Why does she call herself
lindsayluv online?
It's a contradiction.
Does she have bionic hearing or what?
Oh! Sorry!
Taylor hey.
Um I was actually reading
your page last night and...
- Oh!
- You're a really good writer.
Oh! Well
thank you.
But I do think you
need a few more pictures.
Maybe a bikini shot or something.
Ok I'll think about it.
- See you later.
- Bye.
A bikini shot? Come on!
- He was joking!
- You are so naive!
I can think of at least 2 girls.
He's hooked up with in the past month.
If you count just kissing
then I can think of 3 girls.
Whatever he's popular!
Wait hang on. Don't turn.
Drop me off first.
Why? We always go
to the mall on Friday.
I wanna go home and see
if Scott goes online.
Ok you're now officially pathetic.
I think it's cute.
Let her be in love.
It's not love!
I'm sorry but waiting for a guy to type:
"hey baby.
Send me a bikini shot"
Is not love!
Then what is?
Sleeping with a guy.
The 2nd time you guys go out.
And then wondering why he never
talks to you again?
Get out.
What?
- You can't be serious?
- Out.
Samantha gets so intense.
Yeah I know.
It's fine.
She'll be all right tomorrow.
Besides it was totally worth it.
Scott talked to me for like half an hour.
He sent me 13 messages.
Wow! You think
he likes you?
I don't know.
Probably not.
I know he talks to a lot of girls.
Oh hang on.
Maybe this is him.
Huh! No it's a friend request.
From some guy named James.
Whoa Cheyenne this guy's
like totally gorgeous.
Says he's 17 and he goes to ridgeway.
Oh my cousin goes there.
Whoa listen to this.
"read your poem about hiking Mount Maynor.
Was there last summer and felt like the wind was talking to me too"
"heard its voice in my soul
just like you said.
"made me wonder if talking to you
"would be the same kind of thing."
So he has a brain.
Yeah and a soul!
Should I write him back?
Um if you don't I will.
Eric it's your turn.
What you learn today?
Stuff.
Like?
Dad's in California.
You talked to him?
Yeah he called me.
Maybe he called me.
What is it?
Look! Somebody figured
out my password.
And they hacked my profile!
- How do you know? - Look what they wrote.
Look at the status!
"I'm a naughty bad girl.
Someone should spank me."
Someone has a sick sense of humour.
You gotta change your password.
No one should look at this.
It's too late.
- You ok?
- No!
Who do you think changed your status?
Who knew your password?
I don't know! I don't know!
I made Samantha and Cheyenne
look away when I set it up.
I looked around this website.
It's inappropriate for someone your age.
There are no boundaries.
You need to shut down
your profile.- Come on!
Look at you!
You're in tears after one day!
Just shut it down.
It's not worth it.
Honey it's not worth it.
Hello?
Hey.
Hey are you still in a "pissy" mood?
Shut up and come over.
You can put what happened
in your status right?
And then you change your password.
Not to something easy like your birthday.
It wasn't my birthday before.
Or like anything anyone could've guessed.
God all those things
people were saying about me.
How am I gonna face going
to school on Monday?
Don't be a wuss.
You can't take that stuff seriously.
Besides nobody's even gonna
remember it by Monday.
Hey one good thing
happened on clicksters today.
I talked to this guy named James.
What? You should've seen
what he wrote me.
It was like really smart and funny.
Oh! Let's not
talk about boys.
We can rent a movie you can sleep over.
Ok fine.
Hello!
Good morning.
What's going on?
Eric.
Tell her.
Me and my friend Cooper were the ones
that Changed the status on your profile.
What?
- You used the old Cat's name for your password.
- I'm gonna kill you!
Taylor come back here.
- I can't believe he did that to me!
- Taylor!
Look it I am really upset with him too.
I've grounded him for a month.
But I'm really upset with you too.
- What did I do? - I looked to see
if you took down your profile.
I never said I'd do that.
Well on your page you posted a
comment And called someone a bitch.
Whoa! Now you're
spying on me?
When you put something online
it's no longer private.
Everyone can see it and you know my rule.
You can't use the Internet to be
insulting or call anyone names.
- What about what they called me?
- I know it's terrible.
But that's no excuse to be ugly
to someone online or anywhere.
Fine. I'm sorry.
I won't do it again.
- To make sure you won't do it again I'm
taking away your laptop. - Oh come on.
Going on the Internet Means
responsibility and consequences.
You'll get it back in 3 days.
Wonderful.
Eric!
Taylor behave yourself!
I can't believe your own
brother did that to you.
It's disgusting. It's gross.
I'm never going to forgive him.
"I'm not going to your graduation.
"I'm not going to your wedding.
"I might go to your funeral."
Damn! Tayhill actually
came to school today.
I owe you 5 bucks.
What's your problem?
Oh I don't have a problem.
You do little miss
I'd-never-go-all-the-way.
Such a hypocrite.
How many guys did you
hook up with this weekend?
Ten? Twenty?
- You should have
a drive-thru.
You said everyone was
gonna forget it by Monday.
- Ok people have been posting really stupid
stuff On your page all weekend. - What?
They're saying you sleep around.
Why didn't you tell me?
Well Samantha didn't want
to freak you out and...
I honestly thought it would
die down by now.
I have to see. Give me your phone.
I have to see what's going on.
You don't have to see it right now.
Yeah I have to see it right now.
If everyone's seen it then Scott has seen it.
Please can I use your phone?
No I'm not gonna give you my phone.
I saw what people were
saying about you online.
I don't know why they have to do that.
It sucks.
How would you know?
You serious?
You've been called
a slut and a whore? Really?
I guess you've never been on my page.
There's fairy...
Fruit homo.
Too gay to live.
Yeah but I mean it's not
really the same thing.
I mean you really are gay.
What they're saying about me isn't true.
You really don't get how messed up it is.
I sit behind you
in algebra. You smell weird.
That's what skanks smell like.
What like puke?
Jealous much?
She's smarter than you.
"then why doesn't she know
she's a loser?"
And then James wrote: "haters suck.
The girl is more cool than you."
He defended me.
He is a gentleman.
Ah I'm gonna write him
back And say thank you.
Ask him if he knows my cousin.
You all finished?
Then back to your room.
- You're gonna keep me
a prisoner for a month?- Yeah she is.
Taylor!
Honey you really need to go to your room.
Dad would've never let you ground
me For something this stupid!
I get my laptop back tomorrow right?
Yeah. You gonna take
your profile down?
Are you saying I have no choice?
No I'm saying I'm trusting
you to make the right choice.
Well who says that's the right choice?
You know everyone at
my school is on that site.
I was just having fun.
It was Eric who messed it all up for me.
You know I wish
you wouldn't fake-trust me.
I wish you would just actually do it.
It's the seedy underbelly.
Oh my God!
- I know! Look at her!
- Ah!
I'm not gonna let it bother me.
You know I don't care what they think.
That's what James told her.
I let her borrow my phone.
Look what he said.
"even though we've never met
I feel like I know you.
"you make me melt."
Is this guy for real?
I can't believe
I'm actually encouraging this.
Yeah why are you encouraging this?
For you to see the difference Between
a guy that is genuinely nice.
And a guy that just wants
to hook up with you.
You don't like Scott anymore?
Like that was ever gonna happen.
Why not?
Thirteen messages.
That's a lot of messages.
But Scott was this fantasy guy.
That might like me if I was different.
But James likes me for who I am.
Now I just need my computer back.
So I can write him back.
- That sounds like love.
- It might be.
Oh I need ketchup.
Hang on.
- Oh! Sorry.
- Sorry.
I was just going to get ketchup.
Oh me too.
I was actually gonna come
look for you after lunch.
- You were? - Yeah I heard
somebody hacked your profile.
It happened to me once.
Sucked really bad.
My brother did it.
That's what's even worse.
- Oh man your brother? Really?
- Yeah.
Should I have a chat with him?
Straighten him out?
Please yes.
No but seriously I was gonna come find you.
I wanted to see if you wanna go To
the spring fling dance with me.
You're asking me to the dance?
If you're already going with
someone That's totally cool.
Oh no! I mean yes!
I mean no I'm not going with anyone.
And yes I will go with you.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Ok cool.
Why don't you send me a message
give me your number.
Ok sure. Ok.
Why did you tell him
you weren't going with anyone?
The 3 of us were gonna go together.
Why can't you be happy for her?
I'd be happy for you if
someone you liked asked you.
A minute ago you liked James.
I don't know if I would like him in real life.
I've never met him.
- Ketchup?
- Oh yeah. Thank you.
Ketchup?
You wanna know about Scott?
Charlie told him about
some stuff he and I did.
And you know what Scott did?
He laughed.
You're gonna get hurt Taylor.
I mean just 'cause you got
dumped Doesn't mean I will.
Thanks.
Guess what!
Guess what guess what!
Get out of the car!
Your father called?
Uh no.
Sorry bad question.
Why are you so excited?
Scott ozsik asked me to the spring fling.
That's wonderful sweetheart.
So can I have my laptop back now?
Ok fine.
What are you guys doing here?
Cheyenne made me drive her.
You haven't seen it yet?
- No. What?
- Your wall.
No I just got my computer back.
What did Lindsay post more stuff?
Um not Lindsay.
That James guy you thought was so nice.
He's saying he slept with you...
That you gave him an std.
No big surprises she's nasty!
Can smell clap on her
bet you big money has herpes too.
No wonder she reeks.
She's always made me want to throw up.
She's a loser.
I sit behind you in
algebra. You smell weird.
- The clap.
- Skanky whore.
Gross! Don't breathe
around her.
You'll get infected.
I don't get it
God why would he say that he slept
with me Or got an std from me?
I never even met him!
I'm so sorry.
I knew it.
I told my cousin to look at James's profile.
And see if she recognized him.
She says there's no such guy at ridgeway.
Maybe she's just never met him.
There's 300 people there.
She'd recognize him if he went there.
What so he's fake?
Well he's full of crap so yeah he's fake.
I bet you 100 bucks someone
just put up that fake profile.
Oh Lindsay!
Yeah Lindsay would totally
do something like that.
Oh God! All the stuff
that I told him.
I told him my dad cheated on my mom!
Like all kinds of personal stuff.
What if he posts it?
Almost dinner.
Time to go soon girls ok?
Thanks.
No. No I'm not
gonna tell her.
No I just got my laptop back.
Wanna try?
No I might look slutty.
Is that why you're wearing
all those baggy clothes?
Did you see what people were
saying about me last night?
You're not even in the
neighbourhood of being a slut.
And your status says
that you never slept with James.
I don't understand what I did wrong.
Should've brought the disinfectant.
Don't wanna use these sinks
after the skank patrol.
Sick.
Calling me a skank now too?
Yeah I know.
It sucks.
I've never been called a name at school.
You know what they say.
Sticks and stones may break your bones...
Don't make a joke about this.
Don't you dare!
Just stop following me ok?
She blames me for what Lindsay said?
I'll go talk to her.
Scott hey.
Hey what's up?
Uh nothing.
Look I know that a lot of people
Are saying stuff about me online.
This stuff's totally not true.
And I guess I just want to make
sure... - It's not a big deal.
Well it kind of is...
It's really gross stuff and...
Look I haven't slept with
anybody or anything and...
I'll see you in history.
You can come in you know.
Just let me ask you one thing.
Are you still my friend?
Yeah I guess.
What does that mean? My friend
everywhere except school?
Look I don't know what you expect.
None of this is my fault.
Samantha's standing by me.
Why can't you?
Why can't you not flirt
with people you don't know?
You didn't have to talk to that James guy.
You think all this is my fault?
You called Lindsay a bitch online.
Of course she was gonna come after you.
I made spaghetti for dinner
if you'd like some.
Hello.
Hi kris? This is Darren
mortenson Cheyenne's father.
Oh hi Darren.
How have you been?
Kris I don't know...
Are you aware of what's
been happening with Taylor?
Show me your clicksters page now!
Why didn't you shut this down
when I asked you to?
And why would you subject yourself to this?
Shut it down Taylor.
You have no choice anymore.
Oh look mom!
A new comment!
I'm so popular!
No this one's from lindsayluv.
She's my favourite.
Yeah she says that James told her
I took all my clothes off for 5 bucks.
Did you change your mind
about going to school?
You said I could have one day to stay home.
I just don't want you To get in the
habit of avoiding your problems.
Sometimes the best thing is to face
things head on Don't you think?
Maybe you should just walk into your school
With your head high and tell those kids.
They shouldn't believe everything
they see On the Internet.
That's gonna be a big help.
I'm gonna stop by your school
and tell your principal.
Great.
Hi you've reached Brett.
I can't get to the phone right now.
Please leave a message.
Hey dad.
It's me Taylor.
I know you probably didn't pick up Because
you think I'm still mad at you but um...
Ok I take back what I said About
never wanting to speak to you again.
Uh... You...
I just feel so alone right now And I
don't know if you care or not but um...
Just call me back.
You're preaching to the choir.
I know bullying over
the Internet is a problem.
It's given me a headache.
I still can't figure out
what to do about it.
Well why wouldn't you treat a
cyberbully like any other bully?
Well I can't control the Internet Or what
students do on their own computers at home.
And this kind of bullying.
Well it happens using anonymous user names.
You can't tell who's who
and who started what.
But the kids know who's who.
They can tell you.
Well maybe but unless
I can get the school board.
To give me some guidelines That
allows me to compel them to do so...
Well you must have some kind of policy.
A vague one created by insurance companies
To protect the school from liability.
Half the time I don't know
where I stand legally.
I keep asking the school board
to give me some policies.
That has some teeth that I can use
To bite down on these kids but...
Hey.
Look I promised my mom I wouldn't
go on clicksters on my computer.
Can I use yours?
Sure.
Now they're saying I missed
school because I'm pregnant.
And I'm some kind of prostitute.
- Nobody believes that stuff.
- Maybe Cheyenne was right. I was asking for it.
Cheyenne's stupid.
No I told all that personal stuff To James.
Ha! I didn't
even know him.
Taylor this is really hard...
You know Scott reads that stuff.
I mean what if he believes it?
What if he thinks I'm pregnant?
Wait that's what you're
worried about right now? Scott?
Yeah! Yeah I'm
worried about Scott.
Who cares what he thinks Taylor?
Where has Scott been?
Nowhere!
You even said yourself
he's been ignoring you!
Now all of a sudden
you care what he thinks?
Hey stop yelling at me!
I can't take it if you're against me too.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry Taylor.
None of this should've happened.
Maybe we should forget school today.
You wanna ditch?
I'll ditch with you?
No I wanna talk to Scott.
Of course.
Look you should just get Scott
to give you a ride home too.
Because I'm done trying to be your friend.
Have a nice life Taylor.
Hey Scott.
Hey.
Hey I know I haven't
talked to you in a while.
Um I was just wondering.
If we were still going
to the dance tonight?
Um listen Taylor.
My mom pissed me off last night And
said I have to go with marnie fox.
Her mom's best friends with my mom and...
Yeah.
So you're taking marnie?
I'm sorry. It's not
exactly my choice but...
I don't know what else to do.
Ok.
Just...
Oh! She's crying.
She must've seen the video.
Everyone's seen it.
500 views last time I checked.
You guys have all seen it right?
Isn't it hysterical?
What video?
Just wait till you see it.
I'm Taylor hillridge.
Wanna have a good time?
5 bucks all it takes!
You smell like a bit of a sewer.
You ever take shower?
How about 2 bucks...
Or $1? 50 cents?
How about I pay you to show me a good time?
Ew! Gross!
I act like I'm the most Holy
And pure thing at school.
But I'm really The dirtiest little whore.
I'm the real Taylor hillridge.
And I don't know why
everybody hates me so much!
But maybe I do.
Because now I hate me too.
And right now
I really don't see the reason for trying...
...Or for talking.
Or for breathing.
I'm just done.
So that's it I guess.
Bye.
Pick up the phone Taylor.
Pick up the phone Taylor!
Taylor?
This is kris.
It's Samantha. Something's
wrong with Taylor.
She posted a video online.
Now she's not answering the phone.
And I'm really freaking out.
Slow down.
I can't understand you.
I think she's trying to kill herself.
Oh my God!
Taylor?
Where's Taylor?
How should I know?
I'm grounded.
Taylor?
Taylor? Taylor!
I can't get the cap off!
No!
Give it to me!
Taylor?
Taylor let go!
What did you do?
Sit down sit down
sit down. Back up.
It's ok.
I got you.
Baby it's ok.
Please.
I wanna die. No!
I wanna die!
You're awake. You ok?
Yeah. I feel funny.
I'm sleepy.
That's the sedative.
It's starting to wear off.
Hey Sammi.
I'm ok.
I don't understand how this happened.
Did she tell you she was so depressed?
Uh I don't know. Maybe.
Did this happen because
this James kid turned on her?
Do you know who he is?
Taylor found out that he wasn't real.
What does that mean?
Someone posed as James to torture her?
Um look I gotta go.
My mom's gonna be worried.
Just have Taylor call me whenever.
I've talked to Taylor and
I'd like to keep her overnight.
Make sure she's stable.
You can take her home in the morning But
you'll have to keep a sharp eye on her.
I'm keeping her out of
school for the next week.
And I'm taking a week off of work.
Good. If she starts talking about
Harming herself again call me.
This is an appointment card For her
next one-one-one session with me.
And this is a teen support group I run.
It's twice a week.
We talk about assertiveness
bullying other things.
I think it might help her.
And finally a prescription
for a mild tranquilizer.
One tablet every 6 hours
for the next few days.
Or until you feel her mood has evened out.
It'll make her want to sleep
but that's a good thing.
I'm doing such a great job on my own.
Taylor mentioned you were divorced.
I'm sure that's a factor
But being bullied online.
That can push a kid over the edge.
It's like a group assault very traumatic.
Anyone with a computer can see it.
It's always there 24/7.
Makes the victim feel even more trapped.
Unable to escape from it.
I almost lost her.
Check in on Taylor every 10 minutes.
And call me if she wakes up.
Ok.
Eric I'm serious.
I didn't un-ground you So that you
could play video games all day.
Keep an eye on your sister.
I don't want it to happen to her either.
Thank you.
I'll be back in an hour.
Oh and your dad might call.
He left a message on Taylor's cell.
Just don't say anything.
I haven't figured out
what I'm gonna tell him.
Ok.
Where you going?
I'm gonna find out who that James is.
You're such an ass Scott.
Such an ass.
Thank you for letting me come over.
I'm really sorry Taylor's
having such a hard time.
You know the way they're
all ganging up on her.
It's pretty rough stuff.
It's gone.
James's profile it was here yesterday.
And now it's deleted.
I should've printed it out
when I had the chance.
Does Taylor hate me?
Of course not Cheyenne.
Do you think that this
James person could be a fake?
Well his profile says that he
goes to ridgeway and he doesn't.
Do you have any idea who
could've created this profile?
Can I help you?
Uh Mr. Fordyce.
Lindsay's father?
Yes I am.
What's this about?
Our daughters go to school together.
And I was wondering if I could
speak to you and your wife.
About some things that have been happening.
My wife passed away a few years ago.
So you'll have to deal with me.
I heard my name.
I'm Taylor's mother
and I was just wondering.
If you created a fake profile online.
- What? No!
- Lindsay go back inside.
You and your friends have been
harassing my daughter for weeks.
My daughter tried to commit suicide
Because your daughter was bullying her.
You should know you're
speaking with an attorney.
Before you slander my daughter.
It's not slander.
It's fact.
I have posts from lindsayluv
your daughter mocking Taylor.
If my daughter expressed
her opinion about anything...
Demeaning insulting opinions.
That's her right at least
according to the constitution.
Excuse me? You're going
to defend her?
It's called freedom of speech.
It's the first amendment.
You might want to give it a read.
Why are you staring at me?
Mom said I have to call her
when you wake up.
No you don't have to call her.
But you do have to get me
that water over there.
Were you really gonna do it?
I would've been mad if you did.
No you would've loved being an only child.
No I wouldn't!
If you hadn't put that video up
I could've been the one finding you all...
Dead in the bathroom you know?
God I bet they're saying
all kinds of things about me.
Eric go get the laptop. I have
to see what they're saying.
Fine I'll get it.
No it's fine.
I got it I got it.
Do you really think that's a good idea?
I don't know why you're making me do this.
This isn't a punishment Taylor.
It's a support group a place to help you
talk about What you've been through.
- I don't want to talk about it.
- Then don't talk about it. Just go and listen.
We can't pretend that this didn't happen!
It happened and you need help!
And there's nothing wrong
with asking for help!
It's really hard to see you
in this much pain.
And I am scared that
you're gonna try this again!
You've put so much into your life.
Your life is so precious.
Please.
Fine. Ok I'm going.
Before we had to stop unfortunately.
We interrupted your story Kate.
Then we're gonna talk...
Oh Taylor!
Glad you could make it.
Come sit down.
Uh...
Ok.
Awkward.
I printed out what
these kids are saying to her.
They're calling her terrible
names and saying she has stds.
Has she been physically threatened?
I can do something about that.
They're calling her dirty And saying
she's sleeping with boys for money.
Isn't that harassment?
If they said it to her face yes.
But online there's no law
against that in this state.
Other States have laws that are particular
To the Internet but not this one.
How can that be?
I'm trying to get help.
I've gone to the school school board And door
after door keeps getting slammed in my face.
It's not that I don't want to help you.
But unless a law is broken...
I can only enforce the laws
I can't write them.
In elementary school it was like:
"hey there goes jelly donut"
you know stuff like that.
And it sucked right?
But at least I could go home
to get some peace.
Now it's like I can't even post
pictures on my own profile
'cause people are gonna be telling me.
How fat or disgusting I am.
This stuff follows me home.
I hate that.
But the worst is when people
resend stuff you said to them.
There was this guy I liked.
I thought he liked me.
He really didn't.
But I told him personal stuff and...
And he sent it to a bunch of people.
And now at school
there's this bunch of guys.
And they act out the stuff
I said right in front of me.
They call it
the gay-boy show.
No wait.
That's not the worst.
You were right.
The worst is when it goes home with you.
And they pile on and pile on.
And you think: "I don't even
know who that person is.
"how can he say that
he despises that I exist?"
Caleb I'm really sorry.
You told me people were picking on you And I
didn't say anything and I'm really sorry.
You should post crap about those guys too.
You know that's what I'd do.
It's not about getting mad.
It's getting even.
Well that's one option.
Become the bully yourself.
Right? How many of you
have ever decided to get even.
Posted mean comments online About
someone you felt was being mean to you.
No one else?
You never called someone a name online.
Or said they were stupid or ugly?
I called Lindsay fordyce a bitch.
Thank you.
Scott!
Hey.
You must be feeling really
happy with yourself.
Is your ego all puffed up and feeling good?
Excuse me?
I'm Taylor's best friend.
I was sitting there when you
invited her to the spring fling.
So you're gonna blame me Because she
had some sort of mondo meltdown?
Like you even care about her!
Wait. Wait.
So is she doing ok?
- Give me a break Scott!
- I'm serious. I wanna know.
I actually really did like her.
- Right.
- You don't give a crap do you?
You just think I'm an ass which...
...Is probably true.
So why don't you tell me huh?
What's it like to be so perfect That you
don't have to feel bad about anything.
- Yeah I got your message.
- Oh that's good.
I saved the one where you said you started
To call like 50 times on my birthday.
I should've just called.
You know I care
about you a lot.- Yeah.
Yeah I know you care.
I do really.
Well I'll see you in a few weeks then.
Ok honey.
Ok. Hey dad wait.
Thanks for calling.
I'm really glad I did.
Bye.
Here's your pill.
Do I have to take it?
You don't want it?
I don't know. They make me so sleepy.
I kind of want to wake up.
Dr. Rilke said you can stop
when you feel better.
You've been so nice to me.
I never used to think you were nice.
What?
I don't know.
I guess I just always thought.
You were so strict and
overprotective and mean.
And here I thought you adored me.
Well that too.
You're in a funny mood.
I don't know. I just
felt so alone you know?
When all those people started saying
stuff about me I felt like such a freak.
Like I was the only one.
Like there had to be something
wrong with me For them to do that.
But today I found out this
happens to a lot of people.
Like these really normal people.
I don't know.
I wish I'd known that.
I wish I'd known you weren't against me.
Oh Taylor!
I should've talked to you.
I don't know why I didn't.
I'm sorry.
I should've talked to you.
I made it hard to talk to me.
I was so busy telling you what to do
That I wasn't listening to how you felt.
I'm sorry you thought
that I was against you.
I would never be against you.
I know.
- I love you so much.
- I love you too.
I'm glad I'm not dead.
Me too.
Was that my phone?
Oh it's in my purse.
Oh it's Samantha.
Ok.
Thanks.
Hey!
Come inside.
I can't.
Why not?
Because you're gonna hate me
after I tell you this.
You're scaring me.
I don't know how to tell you
this So I'm just gonna say it.
I'm the one who created
the James profile...
I pretended to be him.
I talked to you.
Told everybody you gave him an std.
I know you're lying.
You wouldn't do that.
I did.
I really wish I hadn't but I did.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry Taylor.
Samantha?
What is it?
What's going on?
I did something really bad mom.
And worse...
Now everybody knows.
Yeah I mean I guess I'm feeling better
But I haven't been going to school.
And I know I'll eventually have
to go back and face everyone.
And that scares me.
Hey if I can do it you can do it.
But I feel like I can't go
back until I go online.
And I don't know if I can handle that.
I think it's gonna be bad.
It's ok.
Hon...
It is gonna get better ok?
I'm fine.
Thank you.
Ok.
This seems like a good time to
talk about how to handle it.
When you run into unpleasant
comments about you online.
You mean besides getting
even going all bully on them?
Which only adds fuel to the
fire makes everything worse.
I don't know what to do When I read that stuff.
I just fall apart.
It's fine to fall apart For a little while.
It's fine to acknowledge that it hurts.
But there are things that
you can do that you should do.
- Like print out everything?
- Yes.
You see something negative
about you print it out.
Save the evidence.
What else?
Block 'em. You know
block the sender.
You know you don't wanna see What
crap they're saying about you.
Took me for damn ever to figure that out.
God I never thought of that.
Now there's one more thing you can do.
Probably the most important thing.
Anyone?
Speak up man.
Tell someone.
- Exactly.
- Tell who? Your mom?
My mom kind of knew although
I did kind of hide it from her.
Sure start with your parents
but don't stop there.
Your favourite teacher
your principal. I don't know.
You can report it to The bully's
Internet service provider.
Sometimes they'll shut down
the bully's account.
You're kidding.
Cyberbullies keep going.
Because they think no one
will do anything about it.
But if you call attention to it.
There's a chance you can stop it
from spiralling out of control.
- But you can't totally stop it.
- Don't know unless you try.
Don't hide behind your fear.
Do what it takes to stand up for yourself.
And for each other.
I've looked into it and most
States have passed laws.
Against harassment on the Internet.
Remember Tina meier?
Her daughter committed suicide.
I remember that.
How tragic. Tragic.
After that Missouri passed a law.
I mean do we have to wait
for somebody to die first?
Couldn't you introduce a bill?
I don't want to try to
legislate the Internet.
I don't go online myself if I can help it.
My staff does that for me.
But these kids are
on the Internet all the time.
And they're vulnerable to these bullies
That are hiding behind anonymous usernames.
But no one's making them
go online are they?
- Excuse me? - They do have
delete buttons on computers.
I thought that too until
I almost lost my daughter.
You can't keep these kids off
the Internet. It's their world.
If you can't understand that.
Maybe somebody on your staff could help me.
- I can't allocate
man-hours to that.
In a middle of a budget wrangle.
Why don't you try me again next session?
Thanks so much for coming in.
Take the fries off...
You good?
I hope you don't think it's
weird that I came here.
I don't know if it is or not.
Why are you here? Because
if it's about the dance...
No it's not about the dance.
I'm sorry anyway
for ditching you like that.
It's ok. Thanks.
Look I'm here because...
I just wanna know if...
Did you see the video that I posted?
Well yeah.
Everyone saw it.
Yeah I just wanna make sure you know that.
That was not because...
- Because of me?
- Yeah.
I mean yeah I thought that at first.
And it was like too much.
It freaked me out.
Oh my God! It was not
because of you.
I know. Even my mom was like:
"dude check your ego.
"there's a lot more
going on here."
Yeah. There was
a lot going on.
All that crap coming down on you online.
Yeah it was really bad.
I see that kind of thing
happen all the time.
And I never say anything.
And then I saw it happen to you
and it made me feel sick but...
But...
I still didn't say anything.
And I really wanted to. I just...
I don't know.
I'm really sorry
that it got so bad for you.
That's really nice to hear.
Thank you.
Yeah well it's wrong.
What Lindsay and her stupid
friends were doing to you.
It's not right that they get away with it.
Yeah.
There you are.
I was worried about you.
You ok?
I don't want us to give up
on trying to get a law passed.
Well we can always try
and find a new senator.
No I wanna try something else.
Dr. Rilke says we have
to call attention to it.
So I wanna call attention to it.
Are you sure that's what you wanna do?
Someone's gotta do something about this.
Yeah Jay P will do.
Uh-huh
St email it to me.
Ok thanks.
Sorry. I spend
more time chasing photos.
Than I do writing the story.
Ok. So where were we?
We were talking about how
um kids are getting hurt.
And adults can't see it
because it's happening online.
And the government isn't doing anything.
So we need public pressure.
I won't argue that.
But as far as your story goes
well it's not news.
I doubt my editor will let me run with it.
Although...
You said your friend Samantha
made a fake identity.
And posted things about you
that weren't true?
Yeah.
Now that could be an interesting angle.
I do an interview with
the bully and the bullied.
Think she'd talk to me?
Uh no. Why would she?
Lots of people don't wanna
talk to me but lots do.
Why don't you give me her number?
I'll give her a call invite her down.
She might just go for it.
Uh I don't think she'd wanna talk about it.
Um here's her mother's number.
Um her name is Karen caldone.
Samantha may be leaving for school.
Why did you do that?
I'm sorry. I should
have asked you first.
You know she's gonna think
I'm after her and I'm not.
Honey it's not a bad idea for Samantha.
To face the consequences of her actions.
Yeah but not like this.
Her mother said Samantha agreed to do it.
They'll be here in half an hour.
Go on in.
Hey.
Samantha you can sit by Taylor.
We want you sitting together So we can
take a few shots while we talk ok?
All right Samantha.
Taylor told me a pretty wild story.
That you her best friend.
Tricked her into believing
you were someone else online.
And then as that alternate person.
You spread rumours about her
in an online community.
Is that true?
Yes.
She didn't think you'd wanna admit it.
Yeah. Why are
you doing this?
I hate what I did but...
I'm not gonna pretend I didn't do it.
Well why?
You pretended just fine before.
It sounds like you're
still pretty upset at her.
She has every right to still be mad.
What I did was horrible.
And I've never been more
sorry in my entire life.
Well why do it then?
I had reasons that made sense at the time.
I thought I was protecting her from a guy.
I was hurt angry...
I don't know jealous.
But the reasons didn't matter
once I'd realized I'd hurt her.
So what was going on through your mind.
When you were doing it the cyberbullying?
It's hard to picture myself like that.
You know I'd always thought of bullies.
As people at school who pick on you.
But when you do it online You don't
even realize that you're doing it.
You can't see the other people.
And... and you can
do or say anything.
And it doesn't seem to matter.
It doesn't feel real.
But it's real when you're
the one getting bullied.
I know because everyone's turned on me now.
And Taylor I am so sorry That I
ever made you feel anything...
Wait...
Lindsay and them they're after you now?
I didn't know that.
It doesn't matter.
I deserve it.
No you don't.
Taylor?
I hope this can be the first
step For you and Samantha to...
Mom please let's just go.
Hey Samantha wait.
Thanks for doing this.
They... they wouldn't have run
the story unless you did it too.
It's fine.
If it's happening to you now.
They have support groups
for that kind of thing.
And it's actually really been helping me.
Thanks.
I'll think about it.
I think that went really well don't you?
I'm ready to go back to school.
Thank you.
I wish I could go in.
Go to class with you
go to lunch with you...
I'm gonna be fine.
All this group has been saying Is how I
can't let them have power over me anymore.
So that's what I'm gonna do.
- When did you
get all grown-up?
Oh my God!
Are you serious?
I better go.
Bye.
Hey.
I didn't know you'd be coming back today.
Yeah I didn't either.
Maybe we can sit together.
You really want to?
I don't know if we can ever
be friends in the same way.
But I'm willing to try.
I've really missed you.
Well let's go in then.
Hey over here!
Oh look it's the psycho twins.
Just ignore her.
No I'm not gonna ignore it anymore.
Hey Lindsay?
I know you think you're being funny.
But you should know
your words actually hurt.
And I think you should stop
attacking people online.
Get her linds.
No she's right.
You guys should stop.
You're making everyone
around you miserable.
Aw the twins are
sticking up for each other.
How cute.
Yeah because that's what friends do.
Stop attacking people on cliquesters.
You're making it so no one
wants to go on there anymore.
Yeah you seem to me
just like any other bully.
Spreading hate wherever you go.
- Oh!
- Yeah man.
I've gotta say the way that
you guys need to hurt people.
Maybe you need to talk
to someone and get some help.
Get out of my face losers.
Get out of here!
Ok I've dreamed about something like that.
Only a hundred times.
Hope it was good for you Taylor
'cause it was awesome for me.
Yeah.
Well you finally stood up.
I'm sorry I took
so long. I just...
You know things got so intense and...
It's ok. I know.
I'm sorry.
Well I am starving.
Let's go get some food.
- Hey.
- I'm sorry.
It's ok.
So you said something this time.
You were inspiring.
I was impressed.
Really? 'Cause I think
I'm still shaking.
I'm really glad you're back.
Me too.
So could I maybe sit
and eat lunch with you?
Maybe I can be the one
who gets the ketchup.
Yeah I think I'd like that.
This is kris.
Hi. Terry dunley
down at the paper.
I just wanted to tell you That I called sen.
Evans to get a comment from him.
About shooting you down on
sponsoring the cyberbully bill.
- Oh really?
- Oh yes.
And he said you misunderstood him.
He said his staff is already
working on a proposal.
To make a new law.
That will make it illegal To harass
minors online in this state.
And he's talking to the school
board To get their input.
That's terrific.
Sync by Hana.Bean
www.VNItfriend.COM
www.Addic7ed.com