- Randolph?
- Yes?
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Where are you going?
- Nowhere.
Indians?
- Don't you do anything till I get down!
- All right.
- Bonjour, jeune homme.
- Oh, sure.
Can I have a lump of sugar?
"Can I have a lump of sugar?", I said.
A lump of sugar? Certainly.
- You're not Swiss.
- Here's a trick.
- Are you German?
- I put the sugar on my hand.
Now, you put your hand
underneath here and, wait now...
I'm going to send the sugar
right through my hand.
- Are you English or something?
- Here we go.
You could be Polish. Are you?
I'm American.
- That makes two of us.
- You don't sound American.
- That's because I live in Europe.
- In Europe? Why? What happened?
- I chose to. I like it.
- You like it? Europe?
- You won't do your teeth any good.
- I haven't got any.
- Are you a dental surgeon?
- No, I'm not.
- See?
- My word.
I've got seven left. Mother counted
last night and one came out.
She said she'd slap me
if any more came out. I can't help it.
The climate here makes them come out.
These hotels. Do you like hotels?
- Are you staying here?
- I've just come to see my aunt.
- You're not going to help your teeth.
- I gotta get me some candy, then.
American candy is the only kind to eat.
You like her?
- Like whom?
- I thought you were German. Your aunt.
- Well, she's my aunt. Yes, I like her.
- I bet you don't.
Randolph, you try that and I'll fix you.
- How do you like that?
- She's right. How do you know her?
I don't know her.
She's my sister.
- What are you doing?
- I'm going up the Alps. This way.
That's the way you come down.
- He's American.
- You better be quiet.
Your brother and I
have made acquaintance.
- You're not taking that pole to Italy?
- Yes, I'm taking it.
- You'd better leave it somewhere.
- Italy? Are you thinking of the Simplon?
- What mountain are we thinking of?
- Thinking of?
Why, going over. Right down to Italy.
- I wanna go to America!
- Italy's a beautiful place.
- Do they have candy?
- You've had enough. Mother agrees.
I haven't had any for 100 weeks!
It's a beautiful view.
You can just see the Dents du Midi.
- Show her your trick.
- It's not a very good one.
- Would you care to sit down?
- I like just hanging round.
- He's American.
- A real American?
- You seem more like a German.
- That's what I said.
I've met Germans who sound American,
but not the other way round.
- We're from New York State.
- Where I want to be.
- You haven't told me your name.
- Randolph C Miller. I'll tell you hers, too.
- I'd like to know it.
- Daisy Miller, but that ain't on her cards.
- Pity you don't have one.
- It's really Annie P Miller.
My father is Ezra B Miller. He's not
in Europe. He's in a better place.
- I'm sorry.
- He's in Schenectady. He's very rich.
I'm gonna climb that tree.
He doesn't like Europe.
He doesn't like me, either.
He hasn't got any boys here. Well, one,
but he goes round with a teacher.
- Your brother has no teacher?
- Mother thought of getting one.
An American lady.
Mrs Sanders, from Boston.
But Randolph didn't want a teacher
travelling round with us.
He said he wouldn't have lessons
in the cars.
We met an English lady in the cars,
a Miss Featherstone?
She asked why
I didn't give Randolph "instruction".
- He could instruct me. He's very smart.
- He seems to be.
Can you find people in Italy
to do that kind of thing?
You can find people in Italy
to do almost any kind of thing.
- He's going to college. Have you been?
- Yes, in Geneva.
Miss Featherstone asked
if we didn't all live in hotels in America.
I'd never been in so many
hotels until I came to Europe.
- Europe's nothing but hotels.
- There are a number.
- I think Europe is perfectly sweet.
- I'm glad...
I'm not disappointed.
I'd heard so much about it.
So many friends have been.
Whenever I put on a Paris dress
I feel I'm in Europe.
- Are you waiting for someone?
- I'm taking my aunt for a cure.
They always made me wish
I was in Europe. The dresses.
- What does she suffer from?
- Pardon?
- Your aunt.
- Anything her doctors suggest.
But I don't know where the society
keeps itself here. Do you?
- Well, I...
- I haven't seen anything of it.
- Are you taking the cure?
- I hope I don't need it.
I'm fond of society.
I've always had plenty of it.
Not only in Schenectady,
but in New York, there's lots there.
Last winter, I had 17 dinners given me,
three by gentlemen.
I've more friends there. More gentleman
friends. More young lady friends, too.
- I've had a lot of gentlemen's society.
- I see.
- Have you been to the castle?
- Chillon?
- Pardon?
- The Château de Chillon.
- Have you been?
- Yes. And you?
No. I want to go, dreadfully.
I wouldn't leave without seeing it.
You can drive, or take the steamer.
That's what Eugenio says, our courier.
He makes all our arrangements.
He's the most fastidious man I ever saw,
but he's a splendid courier.
We were going there last week,
but Mother got dyspepsia.
- You could take her to the baths.
- I could ask...
Randolph says
it's too old to be interesting.
Mother's afraid to leave him alone
and Eugenio won't stay with him.
But it will be too bad
if we don't go there.
Can't you find someone
to stay with Randolph?
- You could.
- I'd rather go to Chillon.
- With me?
- And your mother.
I don't think Mother would go...for you.
She's not much bent on going, anyway.
Maybe she'll stay here with Randolph
and we can go.
- We? You and I?
- Oh, Eugenio.
I knew he'd be looking for me
any minute.
Mademoiselle, it is time
to go into the village.
- He's found a clock at an amazing price.
- I'm sure.
- Mademoiselle has seen her brother?
- He doesn't want to come.
- I'm going to that old castle.
- To Chillon?
- Mademoiselle has arranged it?
- You won't back out?
- I won't be happy till we go.
- You're really American?
You shall meet my aunt.
She will tell you all about me.
Oh, well. Maybe we'll go someday.
- You scared Eugenio!
- The carriage is waiting.
- Randolph, we're going into town.
- I don't want to!
What are you gonna do,
jump around on that pole?
They're horribly common,
my dear Frederick.
One does one's duty
by just ignoring them. Milk?
Please. So you just ignore them?
I can't not. I wouldn't if I hadn't to.
Sugar?
No, thank you. The little girl's very pretty.
Of course she's very pretty.
But she's of the last crudity.
- I see what you mean.
- She has that charming look they have.
- And she dresses to perfection.
- Yes...
No, you don't know.
Can't think where they get their taste.
After all, she's not a Comanche Indian.
Frederick, she's a young lady who has
an intimacy with her mama's courier.
- Does she? An intimacy?
- There's no other name for it.
The skinny little mother is just as bad.
They treat the courier as a friend,
as a gentleman and a scholar.
Very likely they've never seen a man
with such good manners.
So like a gentleman.
Probably corresponds to
the young lady's idea of a count.
Sits with them in the garden
of an evening.
I think he smokes in their faces.
I'm not a courier,
yet she was very charming to me.
You might have mentioned
you had made her acquaintance.
- We talked in the garden.
- Pray, what did you say?
That I should introduce her
to my admirable aunt.
Who is a thousand times obliged to you.
- To guarantee my respectability.
- Who is to guarantee hers?
That's cruel. She's very innocent.
- You don't say that as if you believed it.
- How does one say it?
- If you believed it, you wouldn't say it.
- She's uneducated, yes.
But she's wonderfully pretty and nice
and I'm taking her to Chillon.
You two are going off there together?
I should think that proved
just the contrary.
How long had you known her
when this project was formed?
- You've been in Vevey 24 hours.
- I'd known her half an hour.
Then she's just as I supposed.
- What do you suppose?
- That she's a horror.
Won't you meet her
and see for yourself?
Is she really going alone with you
to that castle?
She fully intends to.
Then I must decline
the honour of her acquaintance.
I am not too old, thank heaven,
to be honestly shocked.
Don't they all do these things,
the girls in New York?
I'd like to see my granddaughters
do them, or anyone else that's proper.
- You mean you really think that...?
- Think what, sir?
That she's the sort of girl
who expects a man to carry her off?
Frederick, I think you had better not
meddle with little American girls
Who are, as you mildly put it,
uneducated.
You've lived too long out of the country.
You'll make a mistake.
- You're too innocent.
- My dear Aunt, I'm not too innocent.
Too guilty, then.
- There you are. I was wondering.
- I've just finished dinner.
- With your aunt?
- Yes.
- This is the stupidest evening.
- Have you been alone?
I've been walking round with Mother.
- She's gone to bed?
- No, she doesn't sleep hardly at all.
She doesn't know how she lives.
She's gone to try and put Randolph
to bed. He doesn't like to go to bed.
- Let's hope she persuades him.
- He doesn't like her to talk to him.
She's going to try to get Eugenio
to talk to him.
But he can't seem to make
an impression on Randolph.
- How's your aunt?
- Not very well.
The chambermaid said
she's very proper, wears white puffs,
dines alone
and every two days has a headache.
- How observant!
- It's a lovely description.
- I'd like her. She'd be very exclusive.
- Yes, she is that.
I'm dying to be exclusive myself.
I guess we are. We don't speak
to anyone or they don't speak to us.
- I'd be glad to meet your aunt.
- She'd like to, but those headaches...
- She doesn't have one every day.
- She tells me she does.
She doesn't want to know me.
Why didn't you say so?
But she doesn't know anyone.
It's her wretched health.
You needn't be afraid.
Why should she want to know me?
Gracious. She is exclusive.
- To tell you the truth...
- Here comes Mother.
- Bet she didn't get Randolph to bed.
- Are you sure it's her?
I guess I know my own mother.
She's got my shawl on.
She doesn't see you.
Or feels guilty about your shawl.
I said she could wear it. She
won't come here because she sees you.
- I'd better leave.
- No, come on.
She doesn't approve
of my walking with you.
Mother doesn't like
any of my gentlemen friends.
She's downright timid. But I do introduce
gentlemen, almost always.
- Or I wouldn't think I'm natural.
- You'd better know my name.
It's Frederick Forsyth Winterbourne.
Oh, my, I can't say all that.
Mother.
Mr Frederick Forsyth Winterbourne.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
- I don't know why you wear this.
- I do.
- Is Randolph in bed?
- No, he wants to talk to the waiter.
- I was telling Mr Winterbourne.
- I've met your son.
- I don't see how he lives.
- It isn't as bad as it was at Dover.
He sat up all night in the lobby.
Wouldn't budge.
- I gave up.
- Does he sleep in the day?
- Not much.
- He should make it up.
- He just can't.
- He's real tiresome.
I wouldn't think you'd talk
against your own brother.
- He is tiresome.
- He's only ten.
He wouldn't even go to that castle.
Your daughter has allowed me
the honour of being her guide.
- I suppose you'll go in the cars.
- Or on the boat.
I don't know.
I've never been up to that castle.
- You ought to go.
- Yes, but it seems we never could.
- It would be a pity...
- Daisy wants to go everywhere.
A lady here, I don't know her name,
says we don't want to see castles here.
- I don't see...
- There are so many in Italy.
We only want to see the principal ones.
- We saw several in England.
- Yes, but Chillon is worth seeing.
If Daisy is up to it. It seems there isn't
anything she wouldn't undertake.
You're sure you won't join us?
- You'd better go alone.
- Mr Winterbourne!
- Don't you want to take me on a boat?
- Annie Miller!
- Do let her go.
- I wouldn't think she'd want to.
I'm sure Mr Winterbourne
wants to take me.
I'll row you to Chillon.
You haven't spoken to me
for half an hour.
I've been talking with your mother.
- I want you to take me out in a boat.
- If you'll do me the honour.
- I do like formality.
- It's a formal offer.
- I got you to say something.
- You're teasing me.
- I don't think so.
- Then let me give you a row.
- I love how he says it.
- It would be lovelier to do it.
It would be. I can't wait.
Why wait for anything?
- You should find out the time.
- It's eleven o'clock.
- I'm going on a boat.
- At this hour, mademoiselle?
- With Mr Winterbourne.
- Tell her she can't.
I think you'd better not, mademoiselle.
Eugenio doesn't think anything's proper.
Nevertheless, I'm at your service.
- Is mademoiselle going alone?
- No, with this gentleman.
I meant alone with the gentleman.
As mademoiselle pleases.
- I hoped you'd make a fuss.
- Then I'll make one.
- I just want a little fuss.
- Monsieur Randolph has retired.
Then we can go in now.
- I hope you're disappointed.
- I'm puzzled.
I hope it won't keep you awake.
Bang!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Been there long?
- Long enough.
- Want to come down?
- No.
- Goodnight, then.
- Goodnight.
We're gonna make it!
We're gonna make it! Come on!
Come on! Wait! Wait!
We made it! I told you we would.
"A mass of towers
on a block of boulders."
- Victor Hugo.
- It's much nicer than the carriage.
I have a passion for steamboats.
There's always a lovely breeze
and lots of people.
Why are you so solemn?
As if we're going to a funeral.
- I was grinning from ear to ear.
- Your ears are very close.
- Should I dance a hornpipe on the deck?
- I'll carry your hat around!
- I was never better pleased.
- I like to make you say those things.
- You're funny.
- Am I?
Come on, let's be the first ones off.
It was built maybe in the ninth cycle.
But it was maked bigger and also
rebuilt from the 11th to the 13th cycles.
- Centuries.
- Cycles.
- Yes, cycles.
- What's up here?
- Excuse me.
I'm sure you know all that.
The point was, the castle wasn't
all constructed at the same time.
No. Between the 9th and 13th cycles.
- Centuries.
- Yes, cycles.
A lot of people were imprisoned here,
including Bonnivard.
- Was he here long?
- Four years.
- Is that how long you've been here?
- Longer than that.
I went to school in Geneva,
then to college there.
What is this awful hole?
It's an oubliette. From oublier, to forget.
They would put a man in there
and throw away the key.
- Do you have brothers or sisters?
- No.
Oubliette.
- Look at that beautiful tower!
- Watch your head.
- What are these holes for?
- I've never been told.
The castle completely dominated
the pass through the Alps.
Why don't you like America?
It's an impression you give.
- I like America very much.
- "Oubliette" sounds funny.
- Look out here!
- Be careful!
- It's all right, come on.
- It's very rotten. As it gets older, it...
Yes, it is. It's very rotten.
- Why are you rushing?
- I don't know why I'm rushing.
- What's through here? Look!
- What? Watch your head there.
- It's beautiful. Hello.
- Hello.
- I wonder what's through there.
- Wait for me.
- There's steps here.
- Come on!
Miss Miller!
Amen!
- Don't stray, you're liable to fall.
- Into the oubliette. Don't forget me.
Oh, dear.
Bonnivard was chained to that fifth pillar.
My goodness.
Lord Byron carved his name on it.
Wrote that poem about him.
- What did he do?
- Byron?
- Bonnivard.
- It was during the Reformation.
He wanted Geneva to be free
from the Duke of Savoy,
Who ambushed him
and brought him here.
The Bernese stormed the castle
four years later and set him free.
"There are seven pillars of Gothic mould
In Chillon's dungeons deep and old
"There are seven columns,
massy and grey
"Dim with a dull imprison'd ray
A sunbeam which has lost its...
"...way."
I never saw a man that knew so much!
- You're teasing me again.
- No, it's lovely.
I wish you'd go round with us.
We might learn something.
- I wish that I could.
- Don't you wanna teach Randolph?
I do, unfortunately,
have other occupations. There's...
I don't believe a speck of it.
You're not in business.
But I do have engagements. I have to
be back in Geneva in a day or so.
- I don't believe it. I'm cold now.
- Wait for me.
You see the design
of this fireplace here?
You're not really
going back to Geneva?
Yes. I have to be there tomorrow.
Mr Winterbourne, I think you're horrible.
Don't say a thing like that!
I've a good mind to go back alone.
- Wait, there's so much more to see.
- I think you're horrid!
Who is she, this charmer
Waiting for you in Geneva?
You're completely mistaken.
Doesn't she give you
more than two days off at a time?
- I have studies to complete.
- Doesn't she give you a vacation?
Please stop teasing.
If you stay an extra day
she'll come after you.
Stay till Friday, so I can see her.
Please stop.
We were having such a good time.
Miss Miller?
- You think I'm teasing?
- Aren't you?
All right, I'll stop. If you promise
to come to Rome while we're there.
My aunt's taking an apartment there.
She's asked me to come and see her.
I want you to come just for me.
All right. At any rate,
I will certainly come.
- Shall we go back?
- I don't want to take the boat now.
Well, there'll be a carriage.
...the little abomination's picked up
half a dozen fortune hunters.
Close those windows,
I'm getting another headache.
I wish these Italians wouldn't put
so much garlic in their music.
- You were saying?
- What about?
- The fortune hunters. And Miss Miller.
- Yes.
The fortune hunters
are of the inferior sort.
She rackets about with them alone
in a way that makes much talk.
She takes them to such houses
as her nose is allowed into.
When she comes to such a party
as she can come to,
she brings one particular
Italian gentleman
Who has a good deal of manner,
with whom she seems very intimate.
As to what happens further
between them,
you must apply elsewhere
for information.
- Where is the mother?
- I haven't the least idea.
I really know nothing about them
whatever.
- How are my three cousins?
- Splendid.
Alexander's moved up the block
from the 42nd Street house.
Anthony is still out on Riverside Drive.
- Has Andrew been to see you?
- No. I heard he was in Hamburg.
He seems prodigiously busy.
He is in every city that I am not.
Are you coming to Mrs Walker's tea?
I find it difficult to take tea. Even more
difficult to take Mrs Walker.
- I think I might go.
- If you must.
I only hope you won't run into
those dreadful people.
Perhaps I won't go
to see them right away.
But after Vevey,
I think I might call on them.
If after what I tell you
you still care to, you are welcome.
Men may know everyone and
they are welcome to the privilege.
They may be ignorant,
but they are not bad.
Whether or not being vulgar is being bad
is a question for the metaphysicians.
They're bad enough to blush for.
- Who is the portrait for?
- And that's enough. My sons.
I'm presenting each one with a copy.
It's ludicrously expensive.
I can never bring myself to bargain.
I prefer to be robbed.
You know how a Roman distinguishes
between his pleasures and his sins?
Pleasures are what he enjoys
and sins are what he confesses.
I don't think the Romans
have a monopoly on that.
- How was Geneva?
- Pleasant. You stayed here?
Yes, but the boys are there.
I wish you'd look them up.
- I was fairly busy with my studies.
- Did you see Olga?
On occasion.
- Pity she never married.
- Is it?
But there are some
singular stories about her.
- Mr and Mrs Johnson.
- Pardon me, I have to be a hostess.
But I'm not through with you.
Hello, Mr and Mrs Johnson.
I am so pleased that you could come.
- Madame Miller.
- I want you to meet the Sinclairs.
- Hello. Hello, Miss Miller!
- I'm ever so happy to see you!
I'm so happy to see you.
Here's your mother at last.
- I know you.
- And I know you.
- How are you, Randolph?
- Well, I declare!
- I told you I'd come.
- I didn't believe it.
- You could have come to see me.
- I only arrived today.
- I don't believe a word of it.
- Mrs Miller...
You have the most beautiful house
in Rome.
You should know.
I hear you've been in all of them.
We got a bigger place.
More gold on the walls.
- I knew you'd say something.
- It is bigger, too.
- I hope you've been well.
- Not very.
She's got dyspepsia. I've got it, too.
Father's got it bad. I've got it worse.
- Too much sugar.
- I suffer from the liver.
This climate is less bracing
than Schenectady.
I haven't found anyone like Dr Davis
and I don't believe I will.
He has so much to do, but there's
nothing he wouldn't do for me.
There was nothing he wouldn't try
for my dyspepsia.
He was just going to try something new
when we left.
Mr Miller wanted Daisy to see Europe.
But I don't know if I can get on
much longer without Dr Davis.
In Schenectady he's at the very top.
It affects my sleep.
- But you are enjoying Rome?
- I must say I'm disappointed.
We'd heard so much about it.
We expected something different.
I'm sure you'll grow very fond of it.
- I hate it worse every day.
- Like the infant Hannibal.
- I ain't like any infant.
- You never were.
- We've seen places ahead of Rome.
- For example?
I think Zurich's real lovely and
we didn't hear half so much about it.
The best place is the City of Richmond.
He means the ship. Randolph had
a good time on the crossing.
But it was going the wrong way.
It'll turn around and
go the right way some time.
- Daisy seems happy.
- Yes.
It's on account of the splendid society.
- She's made many acquaintances.
- I've heard.
She goes round more than I do.
They've taken her right in.
She knows a great many gentlemen.
She thinks there's nothing like Rome.
- I've been saying how mean you were.
- Mean?
At Vevey, you wouldn't stay
when I asked. He went to Geneva.
Have I come to Rome
to be riddled by your silver shafts?
Just listen! Did you ever hear
anything so quaint?
- Quaint?
- Mrs Walker...
We've got to go.
Eugenio will raise something fierce.
- I'm coming to your party.
- Delighted to hear it.
I want to ask a favour,
permission to bring a friend.
- I'd be happy to see your friends.
- They're not mine.
- An intimate friend. Mr Giovanelli.
- I'd be happy to have him come.
He's the handsomest man in the world
except for Mr Winterbourne.
He wants to know some Americans.
- He's tremendously clever.
- I look forward to meeting him.
Mother, Eugenio's really gonna
raise something.
- We'd better go back.
- You go. I'm gonna walk round a little.
- With Mr Giovanelli.
- On the Pincio.
- Alone? It's not safe.
- There are lots of people there.
- That's why it's not safe.
- You're sure to catch a Roman fever.
- Give her that medicine.
- Mrs Walker, you're too perfect.
- I'm meeting a friend.
- Mr Giovanelli.
- Is it Mr Giovanelli?
- The beautiful Mr Giovanelli.
My dear girl, don't prowl off at this hour
to meet a beautiful Italian.
- He speaks first-rate English.
- What a fuss.
I don't want to do anything that affects
my health or my character.
If Mr Winterbourne were as polite as
he pretends, he'd offer to walk me there.
- I wonder if I might have the pleasure.
- How gracious of you!
Goodbye, Eugenio, I'm taking a walk.
This is the most beautiful spot in Rome.
More beautiful than Central Park.
Why haven't you been to see me?
- I just stepped off the train.
- You must've stayed on after it stopped.
- You had time to see Mrs Walker.
- I knew Mrs Walker...
You knew her in Geneva. She told me.
You knew me at Vevey.
So you should have come.
I heard you hadn't been
lacking in company.
Eugenio says we have
the best hotel rooms in Rome.
We're staying all winter
if we don't die of the fever.
I thought it would be
awfully quiet and pokey.
I was sure we'd be going round
with one of those old men
Who explain about pictures.
But we only had a week of that.
I know ever so many people.
The society is very select.
There are English, Germans, Italians.
I think I like the English best.
I never saw anything so hospitable.
There's something every day.
There's not much dancing, but I never
thought dancing was everything.
I was always fond of conversation.
And Mrs Walker's rooms
are too small for anything else!
One more.
Shall we buy some candy
for poor old Randolph?
- All right.
- Quanto è?
- I want that one.
- Due, prego.
- Sì, sì.
- Grazie.
- I'll walk you back.
- I'm meeting Mr Giovanelli.
- Must you?
- He's waiting here somewhere.
- I'm not helping you find him.
- I'll find him.
You're not leaving me.
Are you afraid you'll get lost
with your lollipop?
- Now, see here...
- There he is. Leaning against that tree.
- Did you ever see anything so cool?
- You mean to speak to that thing?
- I'm not going to communicate by signs.
- I intend to come with you.
- You sound too imperious.
- I wanted to express my meaning.
I've never allowed a gentleman
to dictate to me.
You should listen to a gentleman
sometimes, the right one.
I do nothing but listen to gentlemen.
Tell me if Mr Giovanelli's the right one.
Miss Miller! Here!
No, he's not the right one.
What have you done today,
aside from getting dressed?
- The most amusing lady I never meet.
- Ever meet.
- You are American, no?
- Yes.
- He never lives there.
- You don't like?
Not at all. I've simply been
studying at Geneva.
- I like America.
- You've been?
- Please?
- To America?
- No, never. Ever?
- Never.
I go there one day.
I don't like Italians so much.
- I do.
- Because you are...gentile?
- Nice.
- Thank you.
- Mr Winterbourne!
Mr Winterbourne? Mrs Walker just there.
She ask you come.
- Excuse me.
- Women follow wherever he goes.
Good afternoon. What brings you here?
That girl mustn't be allowed
to do this sort of thing.
Walking with two men.
Fifty people have noticed her.
- It's a shame to make a fuss.
- Or to let her ruin herself.
- She's innocent.
- She's reckless.
Goodness knows how far it may go.
Did you ever see
anything so imbecile as the mother?
Allowing her daughter to...
After you left I couldn't sit still,
thinking about it.
What do you plan to do with us now?
If she will ride with me,
it will seem as though it's arranged.
The world will see she's not running wild.
Ask her to step over here.
I don't think it's a happy idea,
but you're free to try.
Hello again. I'm enchanted to be able to
introduce Mr Giovanelli. This is he.
This is Mrs Walker,
who so sweetly asked you to her party.
- I am most honoured.
- That is the loveliest carriage rug ever.
Do get in and let me put it over you.
No, thank you.
I like watching you drive with it.
Do get in and drive about with me.
- It's so fascinating just as I am.
- Maybe. But it's not the custom here.
- If I didn't walk, I'd expire.
- Walk with your mother.
My mother never walked
ten steps in her life.
I'm not five years old.
You're old enough to be reasonable,
Miss Miller, and to be talked about.
- What do you mean?
- Come in here and I will tell you.
I don't think I want to know.
You should know. Or do you prefer
being thought a reckless girl?
Gracious me!
Does Mr Winterbourne think
I should get in the carriage?
I think you should.
I never heard anything so stiff!
If this is improper, I'm improper.
You should give me up.
Goodbye. Have a lovely ride.
- Get in.
- I feel I should accompany her.
If you don't get in,
I shall never speak to you again.
All right. Just a moment.
- Here he comes at last.
- I'm sorry, she insists I ride with her.
Forgive me.
- That wasn't very clever of you.
- I don't wish to be clever, only honest.
Your honesty's only put her off.
If she means to compromise herself,
the sooner one knows, the better.
- She meant no harm.
- That's what I thought a month ago.
- What's she done?
- Everything that's not done here.
Sitting in corners
With mysterious Italians.
Dancing all evening with one partner.
Receiving callers late at night.
Her mother melts away.
- Her brother sits up till two.
- He must be edified by what he sees.
A smile goes around the hotel servants
when a gentleman asks for Miss Miller.
We shouldn't pay attention to servants.
Her only fault is to think Giovanelli
a gentleman, when he's a poor imitation.
- There you are.
- He's some third-rate artist.
- But how can she know?
- She's naturally indelicate.
- How long had you known her?
- Two days.
That remark about your going to Geneva!
Taste never has been
the Miller family's strongest point.
On the other hand, Mrs Walker...
...perhaps you and I
have lived too long at Geneva.
- I think you should stop.
- Stop?
Encouraging the girl.
Flirting with her yourself.
Giving her any further opportunity
to expose herself. Let her alone.
I can't do anything
as enlightened as that.
- I like her very much.
- So don't help her to make a scandal.
There'd be nothing scandalous
in my attentions.
I've said what I had to.
If you wish to rejoin her...
- ...you have a chance.
- I believe I will.
As you wish.
- Madame Miller.
- Finally.
- Excuse me.
- I wouldn't miss this.
No, I've come all alone, you see.
It's the first time I've ever been
to a party alone, especially in Italy.
I wanted to bring Randolph,
but Daisy pushed me off by myself.
- Doesn't she intend...
- I'm not used to being alone.
- ...to favour us with her company?
- Daisy dressed before dinner.
A friend is there,
the gentleman she was bringing.
Mr Giovanelli. I've had the pleasure.
They got going at the piano,
seems they couldn't stop.
Mr Giovanelli does sing splendidly.
I guess they'll come before very long.
I'm sorry she's coming in that way.
Charles, she's trying to take
revenge on me. I won't speak to her.
No use putting on that dress
just to sit around with Mr Giovanelli.
Miss Miller.
I'm afraid you thought
I was never coming. This is for you.
Mr Giovanelli sings beautifully.
I want you to ask him to sing.
- Mr Giovanelli.
- How do you do?
- I'm sorry we are late.
- He knows such charming songs.
I made him go over them.
Is there anyone here I know?
I think everyone knows you.
- You are hungry?
- Yes. Mother!
- Did you get Randolph to bed?
- The singing kept him awake.
I do hope this is the finale.
I still don't know who asked him to sing.
- Daisy Miller.
- She's too busy chattering.
She's worked her way over
to your old college chum.
- These rooms are too small to dance...
- I can't dance a step.
Your legs must be stiff
from being in that carriage so long.
They were quite restless there.
- They wanted to walk beside you.
- We paired off. That was better.
My other friend stuck by me. He seems
more in control of his limbs than you are.
Fancy Mrs Walker wanting me
to get in her carriage,
supposedly just to be proper.
People do have different ideas.
We'd talked about that walk for days.
He'd never dare ask a young Italian lady
to walk about the streets with him.
Then where would he ask her to walk?
Pincio's not the streets, anyway.
Young Italian ladies
must have a pokey time of it.
I'm not changing my habits for them.
- You have the habits of a flirt.
- I'm a terrible flirt.
What nice girl isn't?
Now you'll say I'm not nice.
- You're a very nice girl, but I wish...
- What?
- I wish you'd flirt only with me.
- Thank you very much.
I wouldn't flirt with you. You're too stiff.
- You say that too often.
- lf it makes you angry, I'll say it again.
- Anger makes me even stiffer.
- I'd like to see that.
Stop flirting with your friend at the piano.
They don't understand it here.
- Really?
- Not in young, unmarried women.
It seems to me more proper
than in old, married ones.
Flirting is an American custom.
It doesn't exist here.
When you go about with him,
without your mother...
Poor Mother.
You may be flirting, but he is not.
He means something else.
At least he isn't preaching. And neither
of us is flirting. We're too good friends.
- We're real intimate friends.
- I see.
If you're in love,
it's quite another affair.
Mr Giovanelli at least... He never says
such very unpleasant things to me.
Do you want tea? ln the other room.
You didn't offer me any tea.
- I offered you some good advice.
- I prefer weak tea.
I'm glad you sang.
I just love that song.
I don't care what he does to me
as long as it brings me relief.
The climate in Rome is less bracing
than Schenectady.
Especially in winter.
That's where we live, Schenectady.
I haven't found anyone like Dr Davis
and I don't believe I will.
Schenectady thinks everything
of Dr Davis.
There's nothing he wouldn't do for me.
- Your friend hasn't moved all evening.
- Really?
- Why don't you break in?
- She's a disgrace.
Mrs Walker, thank you for
a serata absolutely delizioso.
I'm so glad you managed to come.
So nice of you.
So nice of you. So nice to see you.
Mother's probably tired.
Here she is.
Mother, I know you're exhausted.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
- Such a beautiful party.
- Thank you so much. Goodnight.
Goodnight. We had ever so nice a time.
I'm sorry we...
We had a beautiful time.
Though I let Daisy
come to parties without me,
I certainly don't want her
to leave them without me.
- Buonanotte.
- Goodnight.
That was very cruel.
She never enters
my drawing room again.
That's why you've been so pensive, eh?
- Have I been pensive?
- Preoccupied, anyway.
- You were supposed to come by for me.
- I thought we were to meet here.
- Your mind's on other things.
- I don't know what.
- Miss Baker or what's her name?
- Miss Miller.
- Her intrigue with that...barber's block.
- With so much publicity?
- That's their folly.
- I don't think there's any intrigue.
They say
she's quite carried away by him.
They're certainly as thick as thieves.
- He's very handsome.
- Do you think so?
It's easy to see how it is.
She thinks him the finest gentleman.
He's better even than the courier.
The courier probably introduced them.
Expects a commission
if the fellow succeeds in marrying her.
- She has no thought of marrying him.
- I'm not sure she's capable of thought.
I certainly see no evidence of it.
She romps on from day to day,
from hour to hour,
as they did in the Golden Age.
I can imagine nothing more vulgar.
No, I'm sure that's more than
Giovanelli expects. The little Roman.
She will be telling you at any moment
that she is engaged.
Depend on it.
He's perfectly respectable.
A lawyer, I think.
Though he doesn't move
in the best circles.
She must seem wonderfully interesting.
But he can't really hope to pull it off.
That's too impossible a piece of luck.
He hasn't even a title.
- If he were a marchese, even a count...
- Or indeed anyone at all.
Wouldn't it be funny
if they were perfectly innocent
and had no idea
the impression they're creating?
No, it wouldn't be funny.
- If it isn't Mr Winterbourne!
- Good afternoon!
- Am I interrupting?
- Not at all.
Mr Giovanelli's learning
an American song. Come in.
Sit down. I want you to hear this.
- Mr Giovanelli will now sing...
- No, is not possible.
- Is possible. Hurry, Mr Winterbourne.
- Is Randolph out?
Eugenio's taken him and Mother
to buy shoes.
Randolph's coming out of his shoes.
Mr Winterbourne, will you sit down?
- We're waiting.
- No, you sing your song.
The most difficult song I never hear.
Ever hear. Come on, we're waiting.
Mr Winterbourne is getting impatient.
- Please, you ask her to sing.
- I'd enjoy that.
You think so? First, we're going to hear
Mr Giovanelli.
- Then maybe I'll sing.
- She is always winning.
- I have no doubt.
- Ready? Here we go.
Bravo! Encore!
No, I think he has heard me.
I play for you now.
- Would you like that?
- Very much.
All right.
- Here's Mother.
- Good afternoon, Mrs Miller.
- Is Randolph here?
- I thought he was with you.
He just ran right out of the store.
Eugenio's looking for him.
I thought maybe he came home.
That boy will be the death of me.
Is there something I can do?
Allow me. Please.
- So many bits and pieces.
- He has the best manners.
- Excuse me.
- Mr Giovanelli's gonna sing for you both.
She's always teasing poor Mr Giovanelli.
I don't know how he stands it.
- But they're always together.
- They're very intimate.
It's as if they couldn't live
without each other.
- But I guess I have the joke on Daisy.
- The joke?
- That she must be engaged.
- How does your daughter take the joke?
- She says she ain't.
- I see.
- She might as well be.
- I'm afraid I must be going.
Mr Giovanelli has promised to tell me.
I'd want to write Mr Miller about it.
Perhaps you'll say
goodbye to Daisy for me.
If you see Randolph,
please tell him to come home right away.
- Of course. Good day.
- Good day.
- Randolph! Where's Eugenio?
- Looking for me.
Mr Winterbourne.
- I should think you'd be lonesome.
- Lonesome?
- Can't you get anyone to walk with you?
- I'm not as lucky as your companion.
- You think I go out too much with him.
- Everyone does.
They're only pretending to be shocked.
They don't care a straw what I do.
You'll find they do.
And they'll show it unpleasantly.
They're not inviting you places.
Haven't you noticed anything?
I noticed you and that you are
as stiff as a ramrod.
You'll find I'm not half as stiff as some.
Try going to see them.
- What will they do?
- Give you the cold shoulder.
- You know what that means?
- What Mrs Walker did?
I wouldn't think
you'd let people be so unkind.
- I'd think you'd wanna say something.
- I do.
- Do you?
- I want to say...
Yes?
Your mother says
she believes you're engaged.
I guess she does.
- Does Randolph believe it?
- He doesn't believe anything.
But since you've mentioned it,
I am engaged.
- You don't believe it.
- Yes, I do.
- For you.
- Grazie.
- You would walk with us?
- No, thank you.
No, you don't believe it.
But if you possibly do, I'm not.
She wants me to come to Geneva.
Her brats are at school there. Freddie?
You didn't say ten words at dinner.
- What's the matter?
- I don't know.
- I saw her today.
- Where?
- At the Doria Palace.
- Was she alone?
No. With that Italian who always
has a stack of flowers in his buttonhole.
- She's certainly pretty.
- Yes. She's a mystery.
- What?
- I can't decide if she's reckless or...
- Innocent?
- Yes, I suppose.
No one can say you aren't gallant.
I hear she's about at all hours with him
and not always in refined surroundings.
Maybe she's just an American girl
and that's that.
What do you say we both
go back to Geneva this summer?
Whatever it is I've missed about her,
it's too late now.
She's carried away with Giovanelli.
I don't think you've missed a thing.
- I'd like to walk the rest of the way.
- Are you sure?
Yes. It's such a lovely evening.
I feel like some air.
See you at the opera next week.
Cheer up. It'll be a grand summer.
He looks at us like those old lions
must have looked at the Christians.
Let's hope he isn't hungry.
He eats me first and you for dessert.
Why, that was Mr Winterbourne.
He sees me and he cuts me dead.
- How long have you been here?
- I guess all evening.
I see.
I never saw anything so quaint.
You won't think an attack of malaria
is very quaint.
This is just the way people catch it.
I'm surprised a Roman could be so rash.
- For myself I have no fear.
- I'm speaking for this young lady.
I assured Miss Miller
it was an indiscretion.
- I'm never sick and don't mean to be.
- But when was mademoiselle ever...
I'm as healthy as a horse. I was bound to
see the Colosseum by moonlight.
We've had the most beautiful time.
If there's any danger,
Eugenio's got some pills.
- I advise you to go home and take one.
- What he says is very good.
I go to see if the couriers are there.
The Colosseum
is one thing I can rave about.
There ain't no Colosseum
in Schenectady yet.
Why are you always so stiff?
Did you believe I was engaged
the other day?
It doesn't matter now
what I believed the other day.
What do you believe now?
I believe it makes very little difference
whether you're engaged or not.
Quick. If we are home by midnight,
we are quite safe.
Don't forget Eugenio's pills.
I don't care if I have
the Roman fever or not.
It's just too terrible.
I heard she spent the entire night
with that man, alone. Just imagine.
- It was after midnight when she got in.
- I blame the mother.
- I blame them both.
- Freddie. Freddie!
- Where have you been all week?
- I went to the seashore.
I'm going to Geneva. I just came by
to say goodbye to my aunt.
And Mrs Walker, I hope.
She's over there. Will you?
- Yes, alarmingly ill, I hear.
- Is she in hospital?
No, her mother's taking care of her,
but she's seen several doctors.
- I must say I'm not surprised.
- Charles.
What do you hear about Daisy Miller?
That's right, you haven't heard.
The silly girl's caught the Roman fever.
They say she's very ill.
Freddie! Where are you going? Freddie.
It's going around at night that way,
that's what made her so sick.
She's always going around at night.
I wouldn't think she'd want to.
It's so blasted dark over here, you can't
see anything unless the moon's up.
It's not like that in America.
Ain't that right, Eugenio?
It's so dark over here.
- Randolph, aren't you in bed yet?
- I'm going.
Thank you very much.
- Mrs Miller.
- Why, Mr Winterbourne.
Excuse my coming so late.
I only just heard. How is she?
The doctor says he can't tell.
I do wish Dr Davis were here.
- Is there anything I can do?
- No, thank you. It's just this fever.
I wish Randolph would go to bed.
But he's been very helpful.
In his way.
That Italian doctor says it's a very
bad case. Her fever's been so high.
I'm sure she'll be better soon. It always
gets very high before it drops.
Daisy spoke of you the other day,
quite pleasantly.
Half the time she doesn't know what
she's saying, but this time I think she did.
She told me to tell you
she never was engaged to that
Mr Giovanelli who was always round.
I'm sure I'm very glad. He hasn't been
near us since she was taken ill.
I thought he was such a gentleman
but I don't call that very polite.
I hear he was afraid I didn't approve of
his being with her so much, evenings.
You'd think he knows I'm a lady
and wouldn't raise a fuss.
He underestimates you.
Anyway, she wants you to know
she's not engaged.
She said to me three times,
"Mind you tell Mr Winterbourne."
And she told me to ask if you remember
going to that castle in Switzerland.
I said I wouldn't give any such message.
Only, if she's not engaged,
I guess I'm glad to know it, too.
Amen.
She was the most beautiful young lady
I never see. And...
...the most amiable.
And she was the most innocent.
- The most innocent?
- Yes. The most innocent.
Why the devil
did you take her to that place?
- For myself I had no fear. She...
- Yes?
She did what she liked.
If she had lived,
I would have got nothing.
She never would have married me,
I'm sure.
- She never would have married you?
- No. I hoped so, but no.
I'm convinced. I'm sure.
Time to go, I guess.
It's on my conscience, you see.
I'm afraid I did her an injustice.
Did you? How?
She sent me a message
before she died.
I didn't understand it at the time,
but I've understood it since.
I think she would have...
appreciated my esteem.
Is that some modest way of saying
you think she would have reciprocated
your affection, had you shown it?
You were right, you know.
That remark you made last summer.
I was booked to make a mistake.
I've lived too long in foreign parts.