Our numbers have grown
beyond wildest expectation.
And winter will soon be upon us.
Resources of the Senate
are drained by these conflicts.
There is one among us
who could fund endeavor
from his own purse.
It would take considerable
coin and effort
to raise such a force.
And in return you will
be offered a command,
under Cossinius and Furius, of course.
I begin to question turning from
the calm of the ocean breeze,
and the safety of my city's
walls in Sinuessa en Valle.
Their terms are agreeable.
Father.
Spartacus, this one carried a message.
You planned this.
It speaks of hope that
word finds them safe
within the villa.
Sole command and charge
to bring Spartacus
to deserved end is now yours.
There isn't a villa in all the land
that could hold such numbers.
No, there is not.
Only a city could hold us now.
Come on, keep it up!
Not as easy as butchering
a horse, is it?
Their kick is considerably more gentle.
Diotimus.
Spartacus summons you.
The southern coast?
It will force Crassus' army
to march much greater
distance to meet us,
sapping strength and supplies.
But will we not stand
as drained at journey's end?
The comfort of city walls
will see us revived.
A thing denied Crassus.
Diotimus.
I would have your counsel.
Apologies...
I am absent knowledge
concerning strategies of war.
Yet you are well versed in other needs.
You spoke of a city protected by walls
and caressed by ocean's breeze.
Ah...Sinuessa en Valle.
Uh, home to me for many years...
Then you know of its defenses.
You would take the city?
Mmm, that path rests upon your words.
There are two gates.
The main one faces
the hills to the west.
Open for trade during light of day,
secured as sun retires.
And the other?
Set against cliffs,
running up to the canyons
of Melia Ridge.
Impassable during winter months,
which are already upon its peak.
I would not find
ourselves trapped there.
Nor I.
How stands the main gate?
Formidable, once sealed.
Could a few men from
within see it opened,
beneath cover of night?
It is well defended,
and you would be absent means.
The Aedile feared weapons
could be turned upon the guards,
ordered all of note
locked within a storeroom near the gate.
We must give up sword upon entering?
Let us turn toward more
favorable prospect.
Hold a moment...
I had dealings with
a man during my travels,
who claimed the city his own.
Attius, a blacksmith by trade.
I know of him.
My dominus often spoke
of his distaste for the man.
Can we lay trust in the Roman?
He stands Roman only by name.
Weigh his purse with enough coin
and he would call Thrace
or Gaul his mother.
I would have you with me to break word.
I would join you.
Break camp and follow.
Remain unseen until called to purpose.
What of your brands?
If you are searched at the gate,
effort will be short lived.
A point well made.
My fucking dominus holds
sway with the Aedile.
Speak the name of Laurus
towards meeting of trade,
stand chance of avoiding entanglement.
The next you greet him,
it will be Laurus who kneels...
and calls you master.
Step forward!
That will do.
Give up weapons.
Any weapons?
Step forward!
State business within Sinuessa en Valle.
We come for grain.
And all the pleasures
your city has to offer...
Ah...you insult me.
By so light a palm.
Well...allow
weighted apology...
I would have your brace,
and the jewels upon it.
It is most treasured
possession at this time.
I would not part with it.
Then turn from fucking gate.
Guards!
As you wish.
Oh, please inform Laurus that...
his guests will not be able
to keep intended meeting, hmmm.
Wait.
Ah, give over weapons.
And grace ear of the man that
Decimus saw you well treated.
Gratitude.
I shall see you well rewarded this day.
I understand your plight, Ulpianus,
but you must understand my husband's.
The Cilicians yet plague our waters
and Spartacus now assaults
transport upon land.
The cost
of grain --
-- soars beyond reason.
If I raise the price of my bread
any further to cover loss,
I-I fear the crowd
will turn upon me.
A matter to be taken up with my husband.
I would not ask if profit
were my only concern, Laeta.
My wife is with child.
I will broach subject with him.
Gratitude.
Hold sentiment until it is deserved.
I do not expect him to be moved.
Three denarii!
Yeah, fresh this morning!
This is the one you spoke of?
It is, Aedile.
I warned you shackle would
not stand warning enough
after Diotimus slipped from grasp.
Words now heeded.
See it done.
And in grim wake,
post notice to quell
further unpleasantness.
This way!
Stand up!
Come on.
Ennius.
Forward.
Why are you not at the horreum?
I was delayed by young Ulpianus.
He has implored me to broach --
Now is place nor time.
Come on, get on with it!
By permission of honored Aedile,
I present yet another beloved slave
fallen to treacherous thought
and whisper of rebellion.
And who would not fall to such
beneath heel of a toad?
He was discovered
secreting scraps of food
intended for journey
far from these walls.
Laurus cannot be faulted
for a dog turned to madness.
Show an animal kindness
and it will give loyalty
until the heavens fall.
A journey that would lead to kinship
Show it nothing but the lash
with like mind of untold
mischief towards the Republic...
and wonder not why it bears teeth.
Shackles alone no longer
offer fair deterrent.
Let us add to them with
warning of weighted stone
and the promise of death
for any who dare follow in such regard.
Stop, and listen!
Make him suffer!
Finish that fucker!
Must make attempt to end this.
It would but pair our fate with his.
I will not stand idle
while the man's life
holds in the balance--
Spartacus!
He will see your fucking
Republic to blood and shit!
Spartacus!
Spartacus --
See rebellious tongue
forever stilled!
Spartacus!
Die!
With Spartacus that you will
all gonna have to lie!
Come on!
Throw!
This is your time for retribution!
Die!
Throw more!
Yeah!
Die!
Come on, throw!
You draw attention.
I but end suffering.
As I would for all so afflicted
by festering disease of Rome.
Procure a cornicen for each centuria.
I would not have command
obscured during battle.
And see tesserarius tripled in number.
Watch must be alert
should Spartacus attack
under cover of darkness.
I will not be caught unawares
as Cossinius and Furius.
Another message from Senator Metellus.
The man threatens to bury
us beneath a storm of parchment.
The Senate grows anxious
for our troops to move
from Field of Mars
in pursuit of Spartacus.
They are not alone in such thought.
Mmm, there are yet needs to be attended.
How stand we on account of arma?
Sabinus and I have procured
what was requested.
You will be well pleased.
Let us weigh the worth of your labor,
set achievement to scale.
You have exceeded expectation.
He will recognize value
of all your efforts.
And who most deserves
highest command beneath him.
Vulcan himself could not have forged
more glorious arma towards noble cause.
It's a rare thing...
for such blasphemy
to be proven in execution of skill.
I stand humbled
by the praise of Crassus.
A straighten back, and see words follow
towards honest price.
Ninety denarii.
My-my finest
offering.
And cost of less divine spectacle?
One hundred and twenty denarii
per soldier, fully equipped.
As agreed upon by your noble son.
A fair price.
Apologies, Dominus.
He has arrived.
Your terms are agreeable.
Tiberius will conclude our business.
Yes, of course,
gratitude --
Did I not tell you?
There now stands nothing
between you and deserved title.
Am I to be kept waiting
entire fucking day?
If that is my husband's wish.
Huh.
Well, one he shall not see granted.
Caesar!
Your men forget themselves.
You are the one that has lost mind.
Leave us.
Hmm.
She never did care for me.
Have you ever given her reason?
My apologies for not worshipping
her as Juno upon cloud.
I would fall to my own wife,
too long from my arms.
Cornelia has been sent
word of your delay.
Delay?
Is that what you term setting upon me
as I return through city gate,
in advance of bath or fresh robe
to erase hard journey?
I term it necessity.
Your victories abroad are well known.
As is your insolence
in waging battle against the allies
of Mithridates absent
proconsuls' permission.
The province would have been lost
if I had waited on word
from those sodden fools.
Ah, as I would've lost advantage
of lone voice upon ear,
if I had waited to break word with you.
Speak plainly.
I grow tired of mystery.
Ah, then let us part veil.
You hold revered name
of the Julian clan.
Sired from the bloodline of Venus.
Divine mother of Aeneas,
forbearer of Romulus,
exalted founder
of Rome --
I require no lesson
in my fucking heritage.
Then perhaps one in mine.
I am descendant from no god.
Nor man of lofty note.
I'm tolerated within the Senate
solely for the wealth I have amassed
through labor and dealings
those with "proper"
lineage deem beneath them.
And you believe this singular
cause why they hate you, hmm?
Your campaign against Mithridates
and um other adventures.
Costly, were they not?
I know you stand in considerable debt.
A dangerous place
for a man to find himself,
when he's made enemies
of the "sodden fools"
who would see him to ruin.
Ah, I shall see it repaid.
By what means?
You possess name absent wealth.
And you possess wealth absent name.
Imagine what could be wrested
from highest perch,
were Crassus and Caesar
to align themselves.
My name has remained constant
since falling from my mother's womb.
You have been heavy with
gold for equal years.
Why now suggest the pairing?
Opportunity to seize
laurels and the gratitude
of the Republic presents itself.
And with it, first stone upon the road
to greater glories.
What would you have me aid you in,
to see such a day hastened?
Bring end to slave rebellion.
And death of Spartacus.
Attius.
I would have words, you fucking goat.
Jupiter fuck me!
Have you lost wit coming
here, you mad shit?
You are branded an enemy of Rome.
I was told you hold
no love for the Republic.
Tell me you have not brought
the Bringer of Fucking Piss
and Shit to my very door?
Your legend precedes you.
I bring but opportunity.
One that you may profit greatly from,
if you are of a mind.
It would have to be very considerable,
to outweigh risk of association
dragging me to depths.
A river shall flow in its wake,
if we find ourselves lighted
upon favorable shore.
What would such a journey require?
Your skill, towards
the fashioning of swords.
Swords?
Hmm.
The fucking Aedile denies
me the crafting of weapons,
blame laid on fear of your rebellion.
All that is struck now are fucking
tools and shackles,
to keep the slaves of those
privileged fucks in hand.
The Aedile will not be of concern.
How many would you need?
Two will see our needs met.
You give coin enough for many
times what you ask.
The balance towards your discretion.
And what purpose will silent
tongue not speak of?
Do we have agreement?
Two swords, and an end to involvement.
Return as sun falls.
I would linger,
and recall joyous times
with trusted friend.
I hold concern for the Roman.
Let us hope the weight of coin
anchors him to purpose.
And what if current unwars him?
We shall see him dashed upon rocks.
Rejoin Agron.
Make preparations.
When moon is at its highest,
we shall see gate raised.
And fucking city fall to deserved fate.
Attius.
My appetite swells.
Where would I find holdings of grain
within Sinuessa's walls?
The finest quality.
From the fields of Sicilia.
I have mind towards large acquisition.
Ah, I'll seal that for you.
Apologies.
My husband concludes business...
No pressing concern
until moon greets night.
You stand well supplied.
Shipment received this day from Sicilia,
with another to arrive upon the kalends.
Although most of that
has already been purchased by Crassus.
Marcus Crassus?
He favors our stores above all others.
And one of the few that
can yet afford cost,
ever rising in light of events
concerning the rebel Spartacus.
Have heard of the distress
he has caused the Republic,
in my travels.
What brings you to Sinuessa en Valle?
Slaves.
I find myself with ever
expanding family of them,
and would ensure they
are well provided for.
You have thought toward
housing them in the city?
It has crossed mind.
If you wish to see them
any form of comfort,
I would strike from such.
Pleasure doing business with you.
I witnessed a slave stoned
in the marketplace.
A common occurrence?
No.
Yet I fear it will become so,
if this matter of rebellion
is not soon concluded.
Let us pray, then.
For the proper end to it.
He at last frees himself.
You were at the stoning
this morning, were you not?
I was present at unfortunate spectacle.
And ended it prematurely.
Gratitude.
The crowd pressed towards frenzy.
I would not see more blood
spilled absent cause.
Nor I.
Absent cause.
Bring knife to bear upon beard.
Hmm.
Why do you pause in the face of command?
She but obeys a higher one.
The dominus orders
you to remain unshorn.
Toward what purpose?
His thoughts are his own in such regard.
And what are yours?
I do not understand.
It is a simple question.
What are your thoughts?
Towards what subject?
The one that stands before you.
How do you gauge Caesar?
I do not know him,
and can form no opinion of worth.
Demand any question,
and he shall break answer to aid you.
You are taken with wife?
Your eyes stand as my wife's.
Mmm.
As does taste upon lips.
I would be reminded
of her in shadow's touch.
Eyes shut towards difference...
and warmed by longing remembrance...
Kore.
Remove yourself.
Yes, Dominus.
You send gift of wine and warm embrace,
only to snatch
away --
She was not sent for your
fucking pleasure.
Apologies.
I did not know the girl held meaning.
You've been away too long
from civilized company.
See yourself to robe,
and thoughts towards
more pressing matters.
You present yourself
with breasts and ass
formed with morning dew.
Is it wonder that a man strong of desire
would not be tempted
to taste such ripe offering?
Take lesson and remove
yourself from fucking sight.
Yes, Domina.
We have not yet procured enough horses.
I will not have cavalry found
lacking in moment of need.
What has happened?
Nothing of concern, apologies.
Break words, and find comfort
in how they are received.
I was attending Caesar as commanded...
Caesar?
Gaius Julius Caesar?
He laid hands upon me.
If your father had not appeared, I...
Where is he?
The man we hunt...
was a champion at the arena,
to rival any in the Republic.
Yet only a gladiator,
regardless of skill.
How has he bested our legions?
Spartacus knows of war,
and the waging of it from
his days in Thrace.
If rumor is true,
he fought among the auxiliary
beneath the fool Glaber
before his fall of Vesuvius.
Then he's familiar with our tactics.
And has used such knowledge
to the regret of those
that have pressed him.
Hmmm.
He believes he knows
what a "proper" Roman soldier will do.
A thing that could
be turned toward advantage.
Would that my own blood
stood now so sharp of mind.
Ah, years and the taste of battle
will hone your pup's teeth.
Of that I have little doubt.
Yet to bring Spartacus to ground
I must have a wolf at my side.
Hmm.
And let us turn gleaming fang
towards moon of full purpose,
and see blood and gore matted upon fur.
Curfew!
Inside please.
Make your way indoors!
Curfew!
Move, move.
Move along!
Off the streets!
You move along!
Clear these streets!
Messalina!
She has a habit of running wild.
Here.
You stay close to your mother.
Gratitude.
You inside.
You there.
I laid eyes upon you
in the square this morning,
did I not?
As I upon you.
Word has reached ear you spoke my name
upon entering gate, claiming business.
I fear you have been misled.
You have nothing I find of worth.
Then why are you within these walls?
Remove hand.
What is your purpose here?
Put question to honored
husband, and have reply.
He trades with the Aedile?
He does.
The mistake is mine, then.
See yourself from the streets
before nightfall,
to avoid further misunderstanding.
Come along!
Apologies.
I assure you, not all
in the city stand as him.
What he spoke of, removing
myself from the streets...?
Is it not troublesome?
I made attempt to dissuade my husband,
but he thought it best
to have streets cleared
of all but city guard,
until the rebellion has been quelled.
You have a place
to call your own this night?
Yes.
I have my eye towards such.
Move inside!
All streets are to be cleared!
Curfew is in affect!
A little more securer this time!
The streets cleared by guards?
By command of the Aedile.
Did you know of this?
Fuck yourself.
News greets me with shared ear.
Trust these will service need.
They will.
Yet there is more
we must ask of you now.
I thought as much.
Two hundred denarii a piece,
and you may lay hidden
here until sun crests
and curfew is lifted.
It is not sleep we seek.
What deformity of mind
do you think I suffer from,
that I would give further
aid to enemies of Rome?
You hold no love for the Republic.
Sentiment often belched from wine
served tongue in years passed.
Words of a drunken fool,
jealous of... priviledged wealth.
We find ourselves heavy with Roman coin.
What cost would sober intent?
Five thousand denarii would
see me far from this city,
and shores of fucking Republic.
A bargain well struck.
Call me Roman no more, then!
How many more swords do you need?
Those that join us are well armed.
Join you?
You move to take the fucking city?!
We move to liberate it.
The gate stands only in our path.
We would to slit throats in the night
and see it raised.
Unexpected curfew presents difficulty
in reaching it unnoticed.
City guard would raise
clamor well in advance --
I cannot aid you in this.
It would mean my life.
You have forged weapons
for Spartacus himself.
If we are discovered with
your craft clutched in hand,
then they will send you
to the afterlife all the same.
Fuck the gods.
What would you have of me?
Gently.
I should not have content
fall to ruin by rough use.
Go fetch the rest.
See that they are careful.
You would see me weighted
with unnecessary comforts.
Have I grown that heavy?
These are yours?
I would not be found wanting,
if campaign stretches
beyond expectation.
You wish to join me,
in pursuit of Spartacus?
I wish no such thing.
Yet I will not be removed from your arms
for months threatening years.
Publius and I shall travel
with you and Tiberius.
You know women are forbidden
within encampment.
Yet they are not banned
from followers' camp,
unless rules have shifted
absent knowledge.
I would not have my family
bedded among slaves and whores.
Is it not better solution
than having them stricken from embrace?
Desire much appreciated.
Yet I could not stay mind
from thought of your safety,
placed so near the enemy.
I would have you remain here,
far from the threat of death
war so often promises.
Is that sole reason?
Father.
All has been attended.
Your army stands ready
to march upon first light.
News well received.
I would have word.
There yet lingers issue
of what title I shall hold.
I am possessed of leanings
towards the matter.
Morning sun shall
see them fall to place.
Have these returned
from where they sprang.
I would have house in order
before we take leave from it.
I thought honored position all but mine.
Now I fear he favors another.
Then you stand as your mother,
bound by blood and inconsiderate worth.
It is a thing of rare beauty.
Is it not?
Yes, Dominus.
You will carry it when
you face Spartacus?
I shall carry my father's sword.
It is not as well bred
or considered as this...
yet it holds deeper meaning.
Caesar will carry it then?
As your word and will?
I should not have placed
you within his reach.
He is a man of base needs.
Then why honor him with title,
that above your son?
Apologies, I overstep.
You speak your heart.
I know your concern for the boy.
He no longer stands as such.
But in the eyes of his father.
Would my wife could
voice such simple wisdom.
I saw the gathering of trunks.
She goes with you?
It was her intent.
Yet I would find
no comfort in her presence.
As I would in yours...
Is such a thing possible?
I will be forced to place
you within followers' camp.
But yes, it is possible.
If you so desire it.
Yes, Dominus.
I do not pose question as master,
but as a man.
And would have answer as one.
Yes.
It is something I desire, Marcus.
Fuck my ass...
Quickly!
We must gather more men and swords!
Spartacus is here!
He has had ample time.
What's become of him?
There's but one way to know.
Let us see it done well.
The moon nears its peak.
Yet fucking gate stands firmly rooted.
They will see it raised.
Or fall in attempt.
Ready the others.
When gate trembles,
death follows upon heel.
Spartacus is within our walls!
Move, come with me.
See gate protected!
You, open the storeroom!
Quickly!
Reward will surely find hands for this.
Of that I have no fucking doubt.
Attius!
Raise the alarm --
Call for more men!
Hide yourself, I will find
you when it is over!
See gate opened!
Clear the way!
Move!
Arm yourselves!
Forward towards the front gate!
Diotimus.
Where is Laurus?
I am here, slave.
You would turn against your
dominus and join rebellion?
Fucking animals...
Diotimus.
The villa is taken.
See yourselves free.
Move.
My dominus... He is dead?
Then I shall follow
him to the afterlife...
and piss upon his shadow...
Ulpianus!
We flee to Melia Ridge,
if they have not already sealed escape.
Have you seen my husband...?
I have not, we must go.
I will follow once I find him.
May the gods protect you.
The Aedile.
Have you seen the Aedile?
You.
You aid Spartacus?
No.
I stand the man himself.
Caesar.
I had thought to find Crassus himself,
the tone so matching.
I am proud reflection of my father.
Tiberius?
Jupiter's fucking cock,
you were but a child
since I last laid eyes.
Apologies.
I am for my own home before we march,
I did not wish to stain
it with such business.
Years abroad led you
to strange pleasures,
worthy of the beast you appear.
And your father...
he's not spoken to you of this?
He finds himself preoccupied
with more pressing concerns.
Well, I'm certain
he will share confidence.
When he deems you deserving.
You think I am not?
Sleep well, young master.
And dream of future glories.
Under my command.
Sanus.
Please, let my wife live!
The city is taken.
See the Romans that yet live to chains.
Chains?
You let them live?
They pose no threat.
Nor fucking use.
Would they show mercy
if we were beneath heel?
Still, cunt!
Spartacus!
The Aedile bars himself in the horreum,
spilling pitch and threatens
to put light to bear.
Come.
I will not lend aid
to you and your animals.
If grain is put to fire,
even I will not have voice
to calm my "animals."
You will do this,
or see your people that
yet live fall from this world.
Please.
Stay still!
You will not have my city's heart!
Kill them!
Fuck the Roman man!
Make attempt on gate
and I will for all to torch,
you fucking cunts!
I can take him... Agron!
Lower spear.
Laeta... Kill them all!
Go to him.
And pray your words hold meaning.
Don't listen to his words!
He's the reason we suffered!
I thought you dead.
You would place our fate
in her fucking hands.
I place it in what I believe in.
I yet live, among a clutch of others.
How many?
Too few.
And we will be fewer still,
if you do not stop this.
You would give them
all we have worked for?
I would see no more death this night.
Open gate, let us see sun
crest upon another day.
I will not bow to fucking slaves!
Turn thought from them,
and towards your people.
If you do this,
you will condemn them
all to the afterlife.
Your wife among them...
Oh, no!
He would have opened the gate!
I know he would of.
He would have opened the gate for me.
I could not place faith in it.
We have had our fill of blood
and vengeance this night.
No Roman that yet draws breath
shall suffer further harm.
The city is ours!
The city is free!
Once again the Romans fall!
Victory!
To see one loved robbed
of life is a heavy thing.
One done lightly by Romans
many times to me.
It is no balm,
but know that I carry
the full weight of your loss.
Place her in chains.
War often carries with
it great sacrifice.
None more keenly felt
than threat of those
one holds closest to heart
struck from this world.
I would not have
my son fall to such a fate
because he was not ready for command.
Nor would I deny him opportunity,
to prove himself
a man in his father's eyes.
You stand as my word and my will.
You honor me, father.
As I shall honor the name of Crassus.
Ride with Caesar
and men of your choosing.
Seek out Mummius and what
remains of Cossinius' legion.
Find Spartacus and send
word of his movement,
but do not tempt engagement
until I have arrived with proper force.
You fill the air with lofty promise,
only to command I bow to a fucking boy?!
He is my son!
And shall be treated
with mirrored respect!
I have spread coin towards your
election as Military Tribune.
Formal title Tiberius
is yet too young to hold.
Wear my token to pass
unmolested through encampment,
until appearance is shorn
to Roman likeness.
I would prefer fancy sword
and expected position.
Stay upon path I have set,
and see greater glories
bestowed at journey's end.
Hmm?
Sound horn!
We advance south on Spartacus
and those who follow him in rebellion!
Let our shadow fall upon them...
and every man, woman, and child
so touched by it struck from this world
by the might and glory of Rome!