Halt. Look down.
Keep walking.
Inquiry Prison of the Ministry for State Security.
Address him as Captain.
Come in.
Sit down.
Hands under your thighs,
palms down.
What do you have to tell us?
I haven't done anything.
I don't know anything.
You've done nothing,
know nothing.
So you think we just
arrest innocent citizens on a whim?
No, not...
If you think our humane system
is capable of something like that,
...that'd be reason enough
to arrest you.
We want to jog your memory,
Prisoner 227:
Your friend and neighbor
fled the Republic on September 28th.
And we have reason to believe
he was helped.
I don't know anything about it.
He never told me, he wanted to leave.
I first heard about it at work.
Describe what you did
on the 28th of September.
- That's already on record.
- Once more please.
I took my kids to the park for a walk,
...ran into an old classmate
there, Max Kirchner,
...went to his place and
listened to music into the evening.
He has a phone. You can call him.
He'll corroborate everything.
I can gladly give you the number.
The enemy of our State is arrogant.
Remember that.
We have to be patient with him, some 40 hours of patience.
I'll fast forward some.
I want to sleep.
Please let me sleep.
Hands under your thighs.
Please explain again
what you did on September 28th.
Please, just an hour, just a little...
just a little sleep...
Tell me again what you did on this day.
Why did you have to keep him
awake for so long?
I mean, that's inhumane.
An innocent prisoner becomes angrier
every hour he is kept there,
...because of the injustice done to him.
He screams and rants.
A guilty one becomes quieter,
says nothing...
...or starts to cry.
He knows that he rightly sits there.
If you want to know
whether someone is guilty or not,
...the best way is to keep asking
until they no longer can.
...classmate Max Kirchner.
We went to his place
...and listened to music into the evening.
He has a phone.
You can call him.
He'll corroborate everything.
Anyone notice anything
about this statement?
He says pretty much
the same thing.
He says exactly the same thing,
word for word.
Those who tell the truth
can paraphrase whenever.
Do that as well.
A liar has particular sentences to fall back on
during states of increased stress.
227 is lying. We have 2 important indications,
and can increase the intensity.
If you don't tell me the name of the escapee's helper,
your wife will be arrested tonight...
..and your kids put into
a state reformatory.
Is that what you want?
What's the helper's name?
Who was it?
- Glaesker.
- Come again, louder.
Glaesker. Werner Glaesker.
Werner...Glaesker.
Quiet.
Quiet!
Listen.
Can anyone tell me
what that is?
The preserved scent for the dogs.
It's to be removed after every interrogation,
and never left behind.
With interrogation, you are working
with enemies of Socialism.
Don't forget that.
Have a nice day.
That was good!
That was really good.
How was it,
...when we sat here together 20 years ago?
Ya know, they proposed me
for a professor job.
See, grades don't matter in the real world,
even though mine weren't too bad.
What's on your agenda?
Why do you always think
I have a hidden agenda?
- I just wanted to invite you to the theater.
- The theater?
I heard that Minister Bruno Hempf
is going to be there tonight.
I ought to attend
as head of the Culture Department.
It starts at 7.
We should get going.
The Lives of Others
Minister Bruno Hempf,
1 o'clock.
He worked for the Ministry,
before he was called into the Central committee.
Cleaned house in those
days with the theater scene.
Georg Dreyman, the poet.
He's the kind of arrogant guy
I always warn my students about.
Arrogant, but loyal.
If everyone were like him,
I'd be jobless.
He's our only unsuspicious author
and is still read in the West.
For him, the GDR is the best
country in the world.
See for yourself.
Dear child, what's wrong?
A new vision?
Say something, Martha! Please!
Your Arthur...
...no longer lives.
Arthur? Isn't it possible
you're wrong this time?
No sisters, believe me.
He has fallen into death.
The powerful wheel has ground him up.
I see it,
...and would rather see any other horror.
Why am I not spared from this vision?
Elena, go home.
And, did you like it?
Dreyman's good, huh?
I would have him monitored.
Monitored? That teaching is
corrupting your instincts, Wiesler.
I'd even be the point man.
I told you he's cleaner than clean.
Even Hempf came to his premiere.
If you monitor someone like that,
you bite the hand that feeds.
I'm going downstairs for a sec.
"Faces of Love"
I'm hearing a lot about your work.
They say, "our culture is in good hands".
Your name is mentioned
often in the party.
We're "the shield and
sword of the party", Minister
We're conscious of that every moment.
What do you think of him?
Georg Dreyman?
Maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe he's not...not as clean as it seems.
Grubitz, that's why guys like you
and me are at the top.
The standard Stasi schmuck would've said:
he's one of our country's best, loyal, all this garbage
...but we see more.
You could make it up the ladder, Grubitz.
There's something fishy about him.
I feel it in my gut, and it doesn't lie.
Next week Thursday is a party at Dreyman's.
A few shady people are coming,
Hauser and those vermin.
Try and organize something by then,
...something small and discreet,
procedures A and B.
Just his apartment, nothing flashy.
He has powerful friends.
No one can find out about this
until we've found something.
And when you find something against him,
you've got a fat friend in the Central committee.
Know what I mean?
Minister, have a good evening.
Why's he still watching?
What's he even doing here?
I think, he fancies you.
I insist on proposing the toast tonight
to our community of culture.
A famous Socialist once said:
"The poet is the engineer of the soul."
And Georg Dreyman is one of the most
important engineers in our country.
- Charming comrades.
- Paul! Stop that.
And of course Christa-Maria Sieland.
She is the most beautiful pearl of the GDR.
I won't accept any objections to that.
So, please raise your glasses and toast
to Christa-Maria Sieland. May you live long!
- The fact, someone like that can even address you...
- Please, stay here.
And now another lively number.
May I?
- How did you like my little speech?
- Thank you very much.
I liked your play as well.
Really, it was good.
"Engineer of the soul".
That was Stalin you quoted.
Oh yeah?
Well, I like to provoke
every now and then, Hauser.
But on the other hand,
I know how far I can take that.
In that way, I'm more like
our dear Dreyman.
He knows that the party needs the artist,
but the artist the party even more.
If you guys want to talk politics,
I need to find someone else to dance with.
- I'm ready.
- Too late, too late.
I've been following the developments
of our theater for a while.
- Didn't you follow them professionally before?
- Paul!
It's fine Herr Dreyman.
We've known each other for a long time.
Herr Schweiber.
You did a fine job tonight as well.
Dreyman, I'm glad you're
working with such directors now.
There were other times though...
You mean Jerska?
I think you sentenced him too harshly.
Of course. His statement
crossed the line. No question.
But...
...put yourself in his position for a minute,
you as a man of your word.
He can't take back his signature
from this declaration.
Comrade Hempf, the man could
work at any theater in the West.
But he doesn't want to leave,
because he firmly believes in Socialism and this country.
- His career ban is absolute...
- Who said anything about a career ban?
That doesn't exist here.
You ought to choose your words more carefully.
Comrade Hempf, I'll tell you this now:
My plays aren't so good,
that someone like Schweiber could direct them.
I need Jerska.
- And I think you sentenced him too hard...
- See here. I don't think so.
But that's what we all love about your plays.
The love of man, good people,
...believing that someone can change.
Dreyman...
...no matter how often
you write that in your plays,
...people don't change.
So how's he doing anyway?
He was hoping that his career b...
...that he'd be allowed to work again soon.
- Can he hope?
- Of course. As long as he's alive, and even longer.
As you know Dreyman,
"Hope is the last thing to die".
The Tech. Team will be ready
tomorrow morning for the wiretapping.
It's important that everything's done by Thursday.
It's all up to you.
Can you manage that?
Good night.
Need to go.
Otherwise, I'll get in trouble.
- By who?
- My girlfriend.
20 minutes.
Yes?
Frau Meineke, one word to anyone...
...and your Marscha loses
her acceptance to medical school.
Is that understood?
Yeah.
Send Frau Meineke a thank-you gift
for her secrecy.
Thursday already.
Time goes by too fast.
It's better so.
- How're you doing?
- Not too bad.
It's not always this noisy.
I know, just on Thursdays.
Yeah.
- We missed you at the premiere.
- Schweiber have a good epiphany?
- What was good, he stole from you.
- That's how my ideas stay alive.
Don't think me evil, but I can't stand
the sight of these fat, spiffed up people at such a premiere.
That doesn't sound like me, does it?
But maybe it does after all.
Maybe that wasn't the real me back then
...friendly and kind to people
off the concentrated feed of success,
...for which I'm indebted
to the big shots for their mercy.
But I'll stop complaining.
In my next life I want to be a writer,
a happy writer who can write all the time.
Like you.
What does a director have
if he's not allowed to direct?
Nothing more than a projectionist without films,
a miller without flour. He has nothing left.
Nothing left...
Albert, the Minister was at
the premiere too. Minister Hempf.
I talked to him about your ban.
It's looking good.
He gave me some hope,
was very literal, very specific.
Really?
That's nice.
Jerska, the wine connoisseur.
And how's our sacred drinker doing? Is he coming?
I forgot to ask him.
You're vigorous and strong.
And I need you.
- Don't bring this destructive cycle into your life.
- Albert's my friend.
- And you're mine too.
- Looks like something for a 50th birthday party.
I'm turning 40 though, aren't I?
Don't forget. You promised to wear
a tie for your birthday.
I would, but I don't have one.
No more excuse.
- A tie?
- You did say, you didn't want any books.
Or can't you tie one after all,
you old working poet?
Ya think, I can't tie a tie?
I was born with a tie.
You forget, I had to break free
of this chain of the middle class.
Then chain yourself to it just once more for me.
Tying a tie.
A minor detail.
Frau Meineke,
come here for a second.
Can you tie a tie?
You can't imagine
how grateful I am.
- Something wrong?
- No, I'm fine.
Done?
Wonderful! It's perfect.
Couldn't be better.
But this has to be our secret.
You can keep a secret, can't you?
Yes.
Gosh! I really didn't
think you could do it.
You don't beat around the bush
when it comes to what you can do.
You just didn't know
I can do almost anything.
Our first guest.
Our dear good neighbors
locked the door downstairs.
- Can you go?
- On my way.
Master? Our present.
I specifically said, no books. Thank you.
Want something to drink?
- Sure. A seltzer.
- Vodka for me.
I'll get it.
What the hell.
Why's Albert sitting by himself?
He doesn't want to talk to us.
He just turned us away.
I brought you something too.
- Did you really come here to read?
- It's Brecht anyway.
I feel like an impostor
amongst all these people.
Impostor? Come on Albert.
You're losing grip on reality.
You know we admire you.
Every one admires you.
Yeah, for something I did
10 years ago...
...and probably could never do again.
Ah. My favorite director.
Wait a sec, I need to talk to you.
Man, explain to me exactly
how you got this job.
Your talent, naturally. Of course!
But what else did you do? Hm?
Every one knows,
you're with the Stasi, you washout.
- That's an unbelievable allegation.
- Don't forget that...
- Paul!
- What?
Schweiber, excuse my friend.
He's had too much to drink.
What's with you?
You know he's with the Stasi.
No, Paul.
I don't know that.
You're such a miserable idealist,
you're almost some big shot.
Who do you think messed up Jerska so bad?
People like that.
Narks, traitors and conformers.
You have to pick a side sometime,
otherwise you're not a person.
If you want to do something about it, then call me.
Otherwise we don't need to see each other anymore.
- Your friends don't have much taste, do they?
- That's really unfair.
The back scratcher, for example.
It's wonderful.
That's a salad fork.
Never the less.
Wonderful.
Check this out.
I'll write my next play with this.
You don't have any taste either.
For some things I do.
- From Jerska.
- Probably gave you a book.
"The Sonata of Good Men"
11:04 pm: "Lazlo" and CMS unwrapped gifts.
Afterwards prob. sexual intercourse.
You're late.
Excuse me, Captain. I got stuck at a red light,
can easily lose 4 minutes there.
You know how it is.
Already at it, eh? I don't believe it.
These artists! They've got it going on.
Ya know colleague, that's why I
monitor artists instead of priests or peacekeepers.
See you tomorrow at 11am.
Albert Jerska, the "Engerling" file.
Wiesler. Systematic as usual.
Take your jacket off.
Let's get some lunch.
"Volleyball game at 7pm tonight."
You haven't been here for a while.
The officer's table is over here.
Socialism has to start somewhere.
To your question about the limo
that brought Frau Sieland home the other night...
It's Minister Hempf's car.
Wiesler, we're not allowed to record senior comrades.
I deleted the citation from your report.
Next time there's something like this,
report it to me personally, not written.
We're helping our Committee member
get rid of his rival.
In light of this new information,
I don't need to say what that means for my career.
And for yours.
If we do find something.
Is that why we enlisted?
Remember what we swore?
- To be "the shield and sword of the party".
- And what's the party other than its members?
If they've got a lot of influence,
all the better.
I've got a new one.
So, Honecker comes into his office
in the morning
...opens the window, looks at the sun,
and says...
...uh, what's wrong?
Oh excuse me.
That was...I'm just...I...
No, please colleague. We can still
laugh about our state officials. Don't worry.
I probably know it already anyway.
Come on. Tell it.
Well, Honecker,
I mean, the General Secretary
...sees the sun and says:
"Good morning, dear sun."
And the sun answered:
"Good morning, dear Erich."
At noon Erich sees it again
and says: "Good day, dear sun."
And the sun said: "Good day, dear Erich."
After work Honecker goes back to the window
and says: "Good evening, dear sun."
But the sun doesn't answer.
So he says again:
"Good evening, dear sun. What's wrong?"
And the sun answers:
"Oh kiss my ass, I'm in the West now."
Name?
Rank?
Department?
Me?
Stiegler.
2nd Lieut. Axel Stiegler.
Department M.
Don't think I need to say what that
means for your career, what you just did.
Please...Lieutenant Colonel...I just...
You just mocked our party.
That was political agitation.
Surely just the tip of the iceberg.
I'm going to report this
to the Minister's office.
I was just kidding!
Pretty good, huh?
Your's was good too.
But I've got a better one.
What's the difference between
Erich Honecker and a telephone?
Nothing.
Hang up and try again.
- Hey I gotta go home. See ya!
- Night.
Cold?
Christa, Christa. You forgot about
our date on Thursday.
Or did your poet have
2 birthdays in a row?
Come on.
Get in.
You don't know
what's good for you.
Don't worry.
I'll take good care of you.
Don't tell me
you don't need it too.
Just say the word
and I'll let you go right now.
I'm already busy.
Where do you think
I'm taking you to?
I'm taking you him.
You'll get there faster.
Time for some bitter truth.
Yeah?
These idiots.
See you next Thursday.
Drive.
Christa?
Hold me tight.
Evening Captain.
You're 5 minutes late, again.
Good evening. 11th floor.
On the right.
I'm already up here.
- How did you get in the building?
- A few other guys from the Ministry live here.
I don't think I've ever been here before.
I don't think so either.
Was that good?
- Please, stay here a little longer.
- I can't.
I have another customer at 1:30.
I work by appointments.
1:30. You won't make it in time.
Yeah I will.
Don't worry.
Next time, book a longer time.
Bye.
Georg, did you heard about Hauser?
No. What about him?
His lecture tour in the West was cancelled.
He didn't get a travel permit.
Are you surprised?
If he's going to act so arrogant,
he ought to expect something like this to happen.
Would you allow him to travel,
if you were in their shoes?
"'Lazlo' supports Hauser's travel abroad ban."
- Have you seen my yellow volume of Brecht?
- What?
My Brecht volume.
Don't know where it is.
Weird. I can't find it.
"On that day in blue-mooned September,
quiet under a young plum tree,"
"I held her there, that silent pale love,
in my arms like a graceful dream."
"And above us in the summer sky,
was a cloud I saw for a time."
"On top it was white and tremendous.
And as I looked up, there was not but one sign."
- Yes?
- Georg? This is Wallner.
What is it?
Georg, it's about Jerska.
He's dead.
He hung himself last night.
Georg?
I'm gonna hang up, OK?
I'm thinking about what
Lenin said about Beethoven's "Appassionata".
"I can't listen to it,
otherwise I won't be able to finish the revolution."
Can someone who's
listened to this music
...really listened
...still be a bad person?
Do you really work for the Stasi?
Do you know what that is? The Stasi?
Yes. My dad says they're
bad men who lock people up.
I see.
What's the name of your...?
My what?
Your ball.
What's your ball's name?
You're weird.
Balls don't have names.
Everything is happening, Minister.
State-of-the-art technology
...under every light switch,
even in the john.
- The foyer is being monitored per procedure C...
- You said, you'd find something.
Find something already.
I wouldn't want my worst enemy
to disappoint me.
Get out of here.
Nowack, you're going to monitor Christa-Maria.
Report every minute she's not
with me. Understood?
We banned Hauser's travel permit.
Maybe that'll get something going.
Those two are pretty close.
How's it going between
CMS and the Minister?
They're meeting tomorrow night,
if I understand their rhythm.
Good. The both of us have a lot
to gain from their love story.
Or a lot to lose.
Don't forget that.
In the past,
I was scared of only 2 things:
Being alone and not being able to write.
Since Albert's death,
I don't care about writing.
Or other people.
Now I'm just afraid of being without you.
Don't be scared of losing me tonight.
- I'm just going out for an hour.
- Where?
I'm meeting up with a classmate.
Really Christa?
- Really?
- What are you getting at?
I know.
I know where you want to go.
And I'm asking you, don't go.
You don't need him.
I know about the pills, too.
And how little you trust your art.
At least trust me.
Christa-Maria...
You are a great artist.
I know it.
And your audience knows it too.
You don't need him.
Stay here.
Don't go to him.
No, I don't need him,
don't need this scandalous system.
What about you?
You don't need it either,
even less than I do.
But you're in bed with him too.
Why?
Because they can destroy you too,
despite your talent you haven't doubted yet.
Because they decide
who can act and direct.
You don't want to end up like Jerska.
And I don't want that either.
And that's why I'm going.
You're right about many things.
I want to do things differently.
But I'm asking you.
I'm begging you. Don't go.
So boss. On time?
Lemme guess
what they're up to.
Come on. I'll take over.
I can't be held responsible
for you doing overtime because of me.
"Don't go through this door."
Where's she off to?
Meeting an old schoolmate.
You can read the detailed report tomorrow.
I'll take care of it.
Good night.
What're you staring at?
Seltzer.
No, uh. Vodka.
2 shots.
Another shot.
Bring me a cognac, please.
Ma'am?
Please let me be.
I want to be alone.
Frau Sieland.
Do we know each other?
You don't know me,
but I know you.
A lot of people love you...
...because you are how you are.
- Acting isn't real.
- With you it is.
I've seen you on stage.
You were more yourself then, than...
...than how you are now.
So, you know how I am?
I am your audience.
- I have to go.
- Where are you going?
I'm meeting an old schoolmate. I...
You see? You weren't
yourself at all just then.
No?
No.
You know this Christa-Maria Sieland well.
What do you think?
Would she hurt someone who completely loves her?
Would she sell herself for the art?
Sell herself for art?
But she has the art already.
That'd be terrible business.
You are a great artist.
Don't you know that?
And you are a good person.
"As I took over, 'Lazlo' and CMS were arguing
about whether CMS should meet her schoolmate."
"Finally she went.
'Lazlo' seemed unhappy about this."
"After about 20 minutes,
CMS returned to 'Lazlo'..."
"...to his and my surprise."
"He seemed quite happy.
Heavy intimacy ensued."
"She said, she'd never leave again."
"He said repeatedly: "I have the strength now.
I will do something."
"Here it is assumed,
he will write a new play."
"'Lazlo's' play production has been plagued
with difficulty over the last few weeks.
"What her comment means is uncertain:"
"Perhaps she wants to take care
of 'Lazlo's' household now more than before."
"The rest of the night was peaceful."
Captain...
I was just, uh...
Good report.
Really?
I didn't know he was doing so badly.
Me either.
"From someone who's crossed over":
The State's head office for Statistics on Hans Beimler St.
...counts everything, knows everything:
how many shoes I buy per year: 2.3,
...how many books I read in a year: 3.2,
...and how many students graduate
every year with an 4.0 GPA: 6,347.
But there is one number not registered,
...perhaps because such a figure
hurts even the bureaucrats: suicides.
If you called the Beimler St. office and asked,
"How many people between the Elbe
and Oder rivers,"
"...between the Baltic Sea and
Ore Mnts. were driven to death from desperation?"
Then our oracle of numbers remains silent,
...and probably writes down
your full name
...for the State Security,
...those grey men who take care
of our country's security and happiness.
Since 1977 our country has ceased
counting cases of suicide.
"Murdering oneself".
That's what they call it.
This act has nothing to do with murder.
It knows no bloodlust.
It knows no passion.
It only knows dying,
the dying of hope.
9 years ago, when we stopped counting suicides,
only one European country had a higher suicide rate:
Hungary.
After them was us,
the country of the living breathing Socialism.
One of these uncounted is Albert Jerska,
...the great director.
Today, I'd like to talk about him.
I'm trying to get some stats on...
how much more effective our
State's security works, as is generally believed.
Stupid me, I practiced my lecture for the tour here.
Since then I've taken quite a taste in music.
Should we meet at my place?
"3pm, Ehrenmal Pankow"
Is this safe enough?
My own personal bodyguard.
I call him Rolf. That's probably his name too.
I call him Rolf.
That's probably his name too.
Shoot.
Here.
You want to publish this?
In the West. With your help.
Will you help me?
Have you told Christa about this?
No.
Good, I'll help you
...under the condition you
continue to keep it a secret.
What?
Georg, it's for her protection.
This is something for "der Spiegel" magazine.
I'm good friends with one of the directors,
Gregor Hessenstein. You know him?
- Not personally.
- You need to meet him.
But publishing under your name
is out of the question.
Unless an intensive
48 hour interrogation sounds appealing.
Man, it's cold.
So, to my place after all?
There are no Stasis watching me.
May I remind you, I'm a personal friend of
Margot Honecker and a National Prize winner.
2nd class winner.
I'm telling you guys, my place's clean.
Well, if we could somehow be sure...
I had an idea how we could check your apartment.
You guys know my uncle Frank visits every Saturday
from West Berlin with his slick, gold Mercedes.
For Herr Hauser,
this seems pretty risky.
Yeah, Georg's right.
Just dismantling the back seat and
hiding your nephew underneath.
I don't know,
I just don't know.
Believe me fellas,
they won't look under there.
Quick glance under the axle,
knock on the exhaust pipe and that's it, I'm over, Paul too.
They certainly aren't the brightest on the border.
You guys have that all wrong.
- Which border crossing are you taking?
- Heinrich-Heine Street.
Always Heinrich-Heine Street.
The guys know me there, me and my gold Benz.
I'm good friends with the border patrol.
Believe me, I'll call in 2 hours
with a bottle of Schultheiss in hand
...and give you guys the good message:
Paul is over.
What's up with Paul's Stasi-guy?
Rolf, Rolfy...
He thinks Pauly's at home.
Alright, I gotta go.
Otherwise the boy's gonna suffocate in the car.
Then he'd really be in trouble, wouldn't he?
Want another beer?
Checkpoint Heinrich-Heine Street.
Subscriber?
Whatever.
Just this once, friend.
- Dreyman.
- OK, as promised, "Paul is over".
No checks? Nothing?
Naw, nothing out of the ordinary.
Those guys aren't that bad.
- So, he's over.
- Thank you for doing this for us.
Don't mention it.
It wasn't all that dangerous.
Yeah, I guess not.
- Yeah good, then thank you. See ya.
- Later.
What do we say,
if someone asks what we're doing together?
We'll say...
We'll say you're helping me
write a play.
For the 40th anniversary of the GDR.
Yeah.
That's sort of right.
Who would've thought
our State's security is so inapt.
Who'd of thought such idiots even exist!
Just wait.
"7:32pm: No further noteworthy incidents."
Hi captain.
Listen to this for a sec.
For those in the West, we know why the rate
was the highest in '67.
But in 1977, you need to explain that,
clarify the social conditions.
It ought to still be a literary piece,
not a journalistic inflammatory pamphlet.
The article is great the way it is.
I just want to make sure
that it'll be properly understood on our end.
It's going to create a stir either way.
- That's Hauser.
- Of course that's Hauser.
Then he's not in the Wes...
They're writing a play together.
For the 40th anniversary.
Well, it doesn't sound like a play to me.
What does it sound like to you?
I dunno, but not a play.
You think quite a bit, 1st sergeant Leier.
Are you an intellectual?
Me? No. That's not me.
Then don't act like one.
I chose you for this assignment
for your technical skills, not for asking questions.
Let your superiors do the thinking.
Sorry captain, I'll just...uh...
Have a good day, uh great day.
Good work. I mean...Good luck with the work.
I can probably rewrite this.
I'll send you then
what we have on the subjects.
Two weeks. Can you handle that?
Then I can possibly get it
into the first March issue, maybe even the cover.
That's Christa.
Georg?
Christa, this is Gregor Hessenstein.
- Christa Sieland.
- Yes, I know.
So what're you guys conspiring to do?
Hauser and I wanted to write a play
together for the Republic's 40th anniversary.
Written by 2 people?
"Der Spiegel" might do a report on it. Maybe.
- And who's playing the main lead?
- We actually wanted to ask you that.
Christa, which role would you rather have,
Lenin or his dear old mother?
You can choose.
Well I can see I'm not wanted here.
I'm gonna take a nap.
I commend your caution.
The less people that know about this project, the better.
The Stasi aren't people you want to trifle with.
With that in mind,
I brought you something.
I would've preferred the torte.
-I already have a typewriter.
- One that's been documented by the Stasi.
If this text is written with your typewriter
and intercepted at the border,
...then you'll be thrown into
Hohenschoenhausen the next day.
And that wouldn't be too swell.
Paul can attest that, huh?
Unfortunately all I have in this mini format is red.
That bother you?
Writing the article in red?
Shouldn't be a problem.
You have a place to hide
the typewriter after using it?
- I'm sure I'll come up with something.
- Don't treat this lightly.
I don't want the next article to be:
"Where's Georg Dreyman gone to?".
No one other than us knows
this typewriter even exists.
Is the apartment really secure?
Yeah.
This apartment is the last place in the GDR,
where I can say what I want unpunished.
Good. Then let's drink to that.
The bottle is real.
Cheers to you, for showing all of Germany
the true face of the GDR.
Cheers! This is better than the Russian stuff.
Here's to a great success.
I need to see Comrade Grubitz.
It's urgent.
I'm sorry, but the earliest available
time is tomorrow at 2:30...
If our informant's exposed,
then we'll get rid of the congregation, close the whole church.
It's as simple as that.
He ought to call the Pope
and complain to him.
Now that's enough.
I've had enough of this nonsense.
Wiesler, glad you're here.
Gotta show you something.
"Terms of Imprisonment for Political/Ideological Dissidents
of the Art Scene, according to Personality Profiles"
Pretty academic, huh?
Check this out.
Disseration advised by Professor Anton Grubitz.
How do ya like that?
I gave them a B. They shouldn't think that
earning their doctorate is easy with me,
...but this is really great work.
Did you know for example
there are only 5 kinds of artists?
For example, Dreyman.
He's type 4: Hysterical Anthropocentric.
Can't be alone, always has to talk,
have friends around.
You wouldn't want to put someone
like this on trial. He'd flourish there.
Everything has to be done by the book, outside the public eye.
We're done with him quicker that way.
Complete isolation without telling him
how long he'll be there.
No contact with anyone,
not even with the guards.
Best way to deal with him:
no persecution, maltreatment or scandals.
Nothing he could write about later.
After 10 months, we let him go.
To his surprise.
Doesn't give us any more trouble.
You know what the best part is?
Most of these Type 4s we dealt with
don't write any more,
...or paint, or whatever it is artists do.
And that's without us pressuring them.
It's just...
...so to speak
...their fate.
What did you want?
Any developments from Dreyman?
I wanted to talk to you about that.
I think it's time...
Time for what?
...that we make the operation smaller.
I don't think day and night shifts
are required for such an uncertain case.
Uncertain, huh?
So, you don't think we'll find
anything for the Minister?
Maybe if the operation were
smaller and more mobile,
...if we could find out some things about "Lazlo"
outside of his apartment.
Should I give Udo the case?
I'd rather take it myself.
Why?
Might still find something.
I need to be able to...
...come and go as I please
during the day, at night.
Maybe he's doing something
outside his apartment.
Something about this bothers me.
You're not telling me something.
Fine, I'll pull Udo out.
I could actually use him in this church case.
File the request with me
in writing,
...and give "lack of suspicious facts"
as your reasoning.
And Wiesler?
A piece of advice:
We're not in school anymore.
With projects, it's not about grades here,
...but success.
...on Hans Beimler St.
counts everything, knows everything:
how many shoes I buy per year: 2.3,
...how many books I read in a year: 3.2,
...and how many students graduate
every year with an 4.0 GPA: 6,347...
"5:00pm: 'Lazlo' read the first act of the
anniversary play to Hauser and Wallner."
"Dentist office"
- We're not writing a play, Christa.
- You don't have to tell me.
- But I want to. It's a piece about...
- You don't have to.
Maybe I'm as undependable
as your friends say.
I'm on your side.
No matter what.
Strain in the German/German relationship.
"Der Spiegel" published a story today
from an unnamed East German writer about suicide in the GDR.
It was prompted by a number of suicides
of East-Berlin artists,
...the latest, the theater director Albert Jerska.
Jerska took his life on Jan. 5th
of this year after a 7-year career ban.
Since 1977, the GDR has stopped publishing
its number of suicide cases.
In that year, Hungary is the only European
country with a higher number.
Yes General, we have...
Yes, we have...
General, we have an informant at "der Spiegel"
who's obtained a copy of the original article.
- Obtained?! Way to control things.
Who wrote that shit?
He didn't know who the author was either.
Because of the typewriter's font, we can...
- You can't do anything.
Give me names.
General, I will as soon as I find something.
- I hope so.
Otherwise, I'll kill you myself.
Andrea, where's the writing expert?
In conclusion, the typewriter can only be
a domestic portable typewriter.
More than likely, it is a Colibri.
If the original had been in black,
I could say for sure.
- And who has a typewriter like that?
- It's hardly used in our Republic.
What's that mean? What's Hauser use, for example?
The journalist Paul
uses the Valentino model.
- But this model has...
- Yeah, yeah. And Wallner?
Uses a domestic Optimal Elite.
- Georg Dreyman?
- He writes the first draft by hand
...and the final draft on a Wanderer Torpedo.
He's never written on anything else.
How big would this Colibri typewriter be?
It's one of the smallest produced.
19.5 x 9 x 19.5 cm
So, not hard to smuggle in as a book?
Thank you. You can go.
Goodbye, comrade.
GDR: The Secret Suicide Statistics
Andrea, put me through to Captain Wiesler.
"4:00pm: The group is exhausted
from lots of writing."
- Yes?
- Wiesler, have you heard about this suicide article?
In "der Spiegel", yeah.
From where?
Hauser called Dreyman and told him about it.
- Wiesler, this is extremely important
for my career and your's:
Did he mention anything suspicious?
Or do you have any ideas?
I don't believe he mentioned anything.
No he didn't.
On the 27th, a "Spiegel" editor using a fake name
crossed the border at Checkpoint Bornholmer St.
...and stayed here for 4 hours,
Gregor Hessenstein.
The 6th division followed him
to Prenzlauer Berg, then lost him.
Did he have any contact with Dreyman?
- Wouldn't I have reported that?
- Yeah, of course.
This text has "Poet" written all over it.
I'd be surprised if I'm wrong.
Well, keep your ears open.
Shit.
Get in.
If an employee deceives you,
they're severely punished?
Yes, yes they are.
A woman too? Or no?
Of course.
Shouldn't someone who serves
a bigger man cooperate?
You could say that.
Or maybe you should.
This is where Christa-Maria Sieland gets
her illegal antipsychotic drugs.
Thought you ought to know,
it's in your division.
Whether you break her neck or not,
I'll leave that up to you.
Either way, I don't ever want to see
her on a German stage again.
Now get out of here.
Shut the door!
Frau Sieland, come with us
to clear up this issue.
Come on.
Well...
Comrade Sieland, looks like the end of your career.
That's too bad. You were good.
Quite good.
A little too short, wasn't it?
Have a seat.
So what's a non-working actress do?
Please.
Isn't there anything I could do for you?
- For the State Security?
- It's a little too late for that.
I know almost all our artists.
I could find out a lot for you.
I believe you
but that won't help you.
Maybe there's something else
I could do for you
...something that wouldn't be
unpleasant for either of us.
Unfortunately you've...
how should I put this?
Made a powerful man your enemy.
That's why I'm more restricted than usual.
Is there anything that can save me?
I'm sorry. No.
There is one thing...
...since you hang around
a lot of writers and artists.
You don't happen to know anything about
an article that was in last week's "Spiegel"?
An article about suicide?
State Security. Open the door.
Open up!
The light in the study is on.
Break the door down
before he destroys the evidence.
Crowbar.
I don't think that's necessary.
- What's wrong comrades?
- We have orders to search your apartment.
Here's the warrant.
- What're you looking for?
- Security matter.
Bols and Muehler: bedroom, corridors
Reske: kitchen, bathroom, hallways.
Heiser and Thomas: living room, study.
Go.
What did you burn?
Bad texts.
This is Western literature, no?
That book was a present from Margot Honecker.
- What's the situation?
- Everything's going to plan.
Nothing. Just some Western books and newspapers.
- No sign of the target.
- Were you thorough?
Yes sir. How should we proceed?
- Lieut. Colonel?
- Get your men out.
Here is the address of the Ministry.
If something's been damaged, you can request compensation.
I'm sure everything's fine.
Yes?
Wiesler, I'll be expecting you at
Hohenschoenhausen tomorrow at nine.
Well, I'll say what we're all thinking.
It was Christa-Maria.
The Stasi nabbed her,
she ratted you out.
It wasn't her.
How do you know?
You said yourself,
she wasn't with you last night.
She knows the hiding place.
Yeah, she knows.
If you're right,
and the search does trace back to her,
...then she's our guardian angel.
Meeting Lieut. Colonel Grubitz.
Captain Wiesler.
Interrogation room #76
Yeah?
Come in.
Sit down.
And?
What was that about?
"What was that about?"
You're asking me?!
What do you suspect Dreyman to be?
He's the writer of the "Spiegel" article.
Who says?
Come on.
I dunno how you could've
done such sloppy work and missed this,
...but I know you're different than that,
particularly as an interrogator.
So I'm giving you one last chance.
Bring me Prisoner 662. Immediately.
Are you still on the right side?
- Yes.
- Then don't mess it up this time.
Should I restrain the prisoner?
She's not a prisoner, she's an informant now.
You can go.
So you're the officer in charge?
Then take charge of me.
10 hours left.
9.5 actually...
...before Herr Roessing tells the audience,
you're unable to be present due to an illness.
And that will be the last time
the theater world talks about you.
Is that what you want?
Tell us where the evidence is.
There is no evidence.
There is no typewriter.
I made that up.
I hope not.
Then we'll have to keep you here.
Perjury carries with it the penalty
of at least 2 years in prison.
Dreyman is going to prison either way.
Your statement took care of that
...along with the evidence we've
already found in the apartment.
At least save yourself.
You wouldn't believe how many people are here
because of futile heroism.
Think about your audience.
"Think about your audience."
He's gotta be joking.
Think about what the State's done for you
...your entire life.
Now you can do something for the State.
It would thank you.
Tell me where the typewriter is.
Dreyman will never know.
I'll let you go right now.
We won't go until you are there with him.
You know how to act surprised.
And tonight you'll be back on stage...
...in your element
...in front of your audience.
Tell me where the documents are.
Where are they?
In the apartment.
Under the door threshold,
between the living room and hallway.
You can remove it.
You mean here?
Mark the correct spot.
You look a bit worn out.
Don't forget, you're an informant now.
With that come responsibilities like
conspiring, secrecy, but also privileges.
Serhabla.
Call Wiesler for me.
Captain Wiesler has already left, Lieut. Colonel.
I see.
Very good.
You're dismissed.
What's a knight do,
when he's thrown off his horse?
He gets back on.
Go in and sleep it off.
What happened has nothing
to do with your home situation.
No, but with the entire country.
Christa?
Don't come near me. I was at Karschner's
and there wasn't any water. I need a shower.
- You left pretty fast.
- Well, the "Lazlo" case is still going on.
- They're both in the apartment?
- Yeah.
Today's report.
The last report for the "Lazlo" file.
Why didn't you call me?
What?
I was in the countryside.
Hand the nail brush.
The Stasi were here,
they searched the apartment.
Who was here?
State Security, open the door!
Stay here.
Hello Comrade Dreyman.
Lieut. Colonel. Grubitz from the State Security.
Just wanted to make sure
last night's job was neatly carried out.
The study? We'll go in there.
Look through every book,
page by page.
Well what do we have here?
This threshold doesn't look
too kosher to me.
Could this be a secret compartment?
Leave her.
She's not a suspect.
That actress.
I was too weak.
I can never make right what I've done.
Nothing needs to be made right.
Understand? Nothing.
I have the typewrit...
Forgive me, forgive me...
Take your men back to headquarters.
The mission is over.
Comrade Dreyman, I called the search off.
We received bad information
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Don't delude yourself, Wiesler.
Your career is over...
...even if you were smart enough
to cover your tracks.
At most you'll be stuck in some cellar hole
opening mail until you're retired.
That's in 20 years.
20 years.
That's a long time.
"Gorbatschow voted General Secretary
of Central Committee"
4 years and 7 months later
The Wall is open.
The border patrol's opened the gate.
The elation is overwhelming.
Thousands are storming through.
It's unbelievable
That's right listeners.
Nov. 9th, 1989 is a historical turning point...
2 Years Later
Dear child, what's wrong?
Your Arthur no longer lives.
Arthur? Isn't it possible you're wrong this time?
I saw him just this morning.
No sisters, believe me.
He has fallen.
The faithful men stand around him
as you do me,
...because of the high sun,
only 7 narrow shadows are cast on his noble, dead body.
The powerful wheel has ground him up.
I see it
...and would rather see any other horror.
Why am I not spared from this vision?
Elena, Go home
and mourn.
I'll finish your shift.
Too many memories, huh?
Same here.
I needed to leave too.
But what about you?
Haven't written since the fall of the Wall.
That's bad.
After all, our country
invested in you.
But I basically get you, Dreyman.
What's there to write about
in this Federal Republic?
Nothing to believe in any more,
to rebel against.
It was nice in our little Republic.
People understand that now.
- One thing I have to ask you.
- Anything, dear Dreyman. Anything.
Why wasn't I ever bugged?
You monitored everyone.
Why not me?
You were completely monitored.
We knew everything about you.
I was completely monitored?
Completely bugged.
The whole program.
That's impossible.
When you have a chance,
look behind the light switches.
Knew everything...
We even knew that you couldn't really
give our little Christa what she needed.
To think,
people like you lead my country...
Research Facility and Memorial
Normannen St.
Wait just a moment.
Your file is in one or more folders.
I ordered the folder chronologically.
Older ones, on top. Newer ones, on bottom
Hat's off to you.
Operational record "Lazlo" opened
against Georg Dreyman, codename "Lazlo".
Suspicious evidence given by
Minister Bruno Hempf.
"Lazlo" daily receives the "Frankfurter Allgemeine" newspaper
from a courier without official permission.
Suggest leaving the courier and "Lazlo" alone,
so as not to raise suspicions to surveillance.
"Lazlo" and CMS unwrapped gifts.
Afterwards prob. sexual intercourse.
Paul Hauser's uncle
visits from West Berlin.
They tell him about the play Hauser and "Lazlo"
want to write for the Republic's 40th anniversary.
We're expecting detailed information about
the planned anniversary play: content, etc.
Contents of the first act:
Lenin is in constant danger.
Despite increasing pressure from the outside,
he sticks by his revolutionary plans.
Lenin is very exhausted.
HGW
HGW XX/7
I, Christa-Maria Sieland
...bind myself by my own free will,
to work unofficially with the State Security.
This decision is based
on my conviction that I...
Georg Dreyman is the author of the
"Spiegel" article, "From someone who's crossed over".
Accomplices are
journalist Paul Hauser, Karl Warn...
Based on evidence from Minister Hempf, Christa-Maria Sieland
was incarcerated on Mar. 10th for substance abuse
...and brought back to town
on March 11th at 1:50 pm,
...having confessed the hiding place
of "Lazlo's" documents
...and accepted the duties
as an informant, codename "Martha".
1:50 pm?
Then how did she...?
After an unsuccessful search on Mar. 11th
and the car accident killing informant "Martha"
...the operational record
of "Lazlo" was discontinued.
Sidenote: Promotion suspension
for HGW goes into effect today.
Duties transferred to Dept. M.
With that, it is recommended not
to entrust him with any further assignments.
10:50 am: Started control post
in front of "Lazlo's" apartment
3:10 pm: "Martha" goes straight home
from Hohenschoenhausen to him.
Search of the apartment
with results report follows.
End of the "Lazlo" file.
HGW, 3:15pm.
Who is HGW XX/7?
Stop here.
To Uferland St.
2 Years Later
Georg Dreyman
The Sonata of Good Men
Dedicated to HGW XX/7,
for my gratitude.
29.80.
Want it gift-wrapped?
No, it's for me.