Goodness!
Hello.
Congratulations on opening your office.
How did you...
How did you know about this?
Isn't it the opening day of Lawyer Lee Seoyeong's law firm?
Yes, it is.
Please have a seat and have some tea and rice cakes.
It's alright, Yeonhui.
It's alright. I won't stay long.
I'm going to the bathroom.
What do you think you're doing?
You said we weren't enemies.
I came to congratulate the opening of my ex-wife's office.
Isn't that cool of me?
- Kang Ujae.
- Seoyeong!
I mean, Lawyer Lee.
We have a visitor. A client.
Excuse me.
You're busy already, Lawyer Lee.
I'll leave you then.
Uin Co.
Oh Bongsu, CEO
Our company's working together with the Ilsan county office.
We're planning an event to give legal advice to the elderly.
I'd like to ask you to help.
I see.
We'll pay for the costs of your consultation fee.
How did you know about my firm?
I came to this building for work and happened to see your office.
Good bye.
Good bye and thank you.
We're going to be successful.
A client on the opening day!
How did Ujae know?
You went to the training institute get together.
Rumors spread quickly in our field so Ujae must have heard about it.
Hello.
CEO Ko...
I know I wasn't invited but I wanted to congratulate you.
How did you know?
We pick up a lot of rumors when we go to court.
I heard you attended the training institute get together too.
Thank you.
Hey, Mr. Yu.
Hi.
Wrap up 10 eggs for me.
My daughter in law's making omelet rice for me and we're out of eggs.
You even run errands for her now.
Wait just a minute.
Pack 3 steamed buns too.
My daughter in law likes them.
WINNERS, donates $100,000 to community welfare
"Migyeong, surgical resident at Hanjin University Hospital."
I don't want to marry Migyeong anymore.
Dad, when it comes to men and women,
there are a lot of reasons why people decide not to marry.
Dad.
Migyeong...
You said she's an orphan.
Is she Ujae's sister?
Is that why you broke up?
How did you find out?
Does Seoyeong know too?
She doesn't know about it.
How did you find out?
What about Hojeong?
She knew, didn't she?
Yes.
How could this happen?
Dad, it's all in the past now.
Yes...
Yes.
That's why...
Don't tell me that you're sorry.
Okay.
Alright.
I won't...
How did you find out?
Did Hojeong tell you?
Father, you went to buy eggs.
Why are you so late?
Did you meet up with Sangu?
Yes. Here.
Father, what took so long?
The fried rice got cold.
I heated it up again.
Oh, the thing is...
I think I have the flu.
You two eat without me.
I need to get some rest.
Come inside.
Kang Ujae's mother's interview was in the paper.
Oh, no.
Why is that bad things keep happening?
Father must be so distressed.
I think he blames himself for everything.
Tell him it isn't his fault.
Words won't comfort him.
Oh, no.
I should make him some porridge.
Your throat will hurt if you're consulting people all day.
You'll get so tired as well.
I've worked 12 hours at a supermarket opening to coax customers in the past.
Why does the person in charge want to go with you?
They want to brief me and let me travel in comfort.
That's good.
Good morning.
Goodness...
It's so early.
What do you think you're doing?
Let's go, Lawyer Lee Seoyeong.
Aren't you going to Ilsan to give legal advice to the elderly?
I'm the person in charge.
You're the one in charge?
Yes.
A company called Uin asked for my services.
Why are you in charge, Ujae?
They're our vendor.
I guess you've figured it out.
I asked them to hire you.
Why?
Why ask your vendor to do that?
Why pretend to be the one in charge?
Let's talk about it on the way.
The elders are waiting. Let's go.
Do you think I'll go with you?
You signed a contract to give legal advice.
They made reservations.
Everyone's waiting for you.
That company holds community events once a year.
I decided to butt in.
I'm not using a group of elderly people for my own benefit.
Really?
I have business with you.
I had to do this so you'd at least show me your face.
Then I'll go in my car.
We have to go together so we can discuss the event.
Kang Ujae...
I'll wait for you downstairs.
I don't believe this.
I think he's great.
Aren't you going?
It's for business.
I'm going.
We got paid. I have to go.
Cafe mocha.
I don't feel like anything sweet at the moment.
Then Americano.
Ujae, why are you doing this?
Don't get the wrong idea.
I'm not going to ask you to get back together with me.
But it isn't fair.
I didn't get to explain myself.
I never got to tell you how I feel.
Why do you have to explain?
Are you insisting on hearing an explanation from me?
I said I want to explain.
I want to explain myself,
not listen to you.
I have to tell you.
You know my personality.
If I want to do something, I have to do it.
So I used a trick.
I won't interfere with your work or take up your time.
Get in.
They're all over 65 years old.
It's 30 minutes per person for 8 hours.
That's 16 people.
Alright.
This is a report of the consultation content.
Read it before we get there.
You wanted to explain yourself.
Go on.
You're on your way to work.
I don't want to be rude and talk about personal affairs.
I don't want to talk about it with you afterwards.
I won't force you to give me time.
Don't worry about that.
Then when are you going to explain yourself?
I'll make time to do it.
Don't worry.
Free legal consultation for the elderly
- Hello.
- Yes, hello.
Manager Heo, this is Lawyer Lee Seoyeong.
Lawyer Lee, he's in charge of this event.
Hello, I'm Lee Seoyeong.
I'm Heo Byeongu.
He'll take care of the event.
You just have to give advice to those who've registered.
Please come this way.
Yes, Secretary Kim.
I'll be there soon.
He was supposed to brief me before the meeting.
And he left without telling me?
The vice president just got back.
Alright.
Tell him to come to my office after the meeting.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Something came up.
Sit down.
Let's begin the meeting.
Ms. Bang said you could take the day off today.
It's okay. I have to do something.
- Still...
- It's alright. I'm fine.
If your son got locked up for gambling repeatedly,
he can't just be released.
He needs to go to court.
Do we need to hire a lawyer then?
If you can afford it.
Otherwise, there are also public defenders,
lawyers provided by the government.
Legal fees... You don't need to pay them.
Really?
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Good bye.
Good bye.
Great work.
There's just one more to go.
Could you call me a taxi to arrive at 5 o'clock?
Sure.
Sir, please come over here.
Welcome.
Hello.
- We're finished now.
- Please.
- Come next time.
- It won't take long.
Ma'am.
Lawyer!
You need to make a reservation.
We're done for the day.
Here. I have money.
I brought money with me.
Manager Heo.
Yes?
It's alright. Please let her in.
My grandson is 18 years old.
He's in prison right now.
What did he do wrong?
He ran over someone.
Excuse me?
He's one of the top 5 students in his grade.
He drank and took the car out.
He ran over 2 people.
I think I read about it in the papers.
Yes.
It was on the news and in the papers.
Anyway, he's due for trial now but the brat won't open his mouth.
He won't speak? Why not?
If I knew, I wouldn't be here.
It's $1,000.
I saved up to pay for his university fees.
Lawyer...
Please take on his case.
He needs to explain himself.
He needs to speak up in order to reduce his penalty.
Did you raise him yourself?
He doesn't have any parents?
He does but they're just parents on paper.
You're late.
Isn't she finished yet?
We finished but one elderly lady showed up without notice.
Lawyer Lee agreed to see her.
Really?
What's his name?
You must've had a hard day.
Here.
It's okay. I got paid for it.
My throat does hurt a little.
Does it hurt a lot?
Let's go to the pharmacy.
I'm asking you to not talk to me.
Alright.
I won't talk to you until you open your eyes again. Rest.
I want to treat my lawyer.
I heard you just ate rice rolls for lunch.
I don't want to eat. Let's go.
I went to Ilsan, went back to Seoul for a meeting.
I took care of work and came back.
I missed lunch.
I was too nervous for breakfast.
I'm starting to feel dizzy.
What do you want to have?
Two of whatever takes the least time to make.
Two of whatever takes the longest to make.
Two of the quickest menu.
Wild herb bibimbap can be prepared almost immediately.
- We'll have two of that.
- Yes.
I've gotten tamer, haven't I?
I thought a lot about it.
A person's past makes who they are in the present.
Ujae.
I'm talking about myself.
Listen just until the food arrives.
For me...
My father is too charismatic.
I lived in an environment where his judgment was law.
My parents didn't converse.
I didn't converse with them either.
i never spoke to anyone about my feelings.
I never asked what I should do.
I never asked for advice or spoke honestly.
I guess I ended up being just like my father.
I judged and thought about things from only my perspective.
I pushed people.
When I found out about your father...
It was so typical of me...
I thought only from my perspective.
I didn't think that there would be a story.
I thought the Lee Seoyeong I knew had done something unforgivable.
The Lee Seoyeong I thought I knew...
I didn't even know who you really were.
I thought of you only from within the boundaries I'd created.
I saw you only from my perspective.
I didn't think of why you couldn't tell me.
I felt betrayed that you didn't trust me.
I judged you from my standards.
Are you repenting now?
I thought you wanted to explain.
Yes.
I thought about when Seongjae's story came out in the open.
Seongjae's my father's son.
I wanted to hide that from you too.
I didn't want my father to look easy.
Aren't you eating?
You said you're hungry.
If I finish eating you might get up.
Then I don't have time to talk.
Talk after you finish.
It's alright.
Eat. Listen as you eat.
Eat first. I'll wait until you're done eating.
Will you do that for me?
How many minutes do I get?
Just 5 minutes.
Eat slowly.
I won't take responsibility if you choke.
I won't choke. This is delicious.
Where did I leave off?
You don't have to keep going.
I've heard enough.
Really? That's all for today then.
Someone told me this.
I'm really good at forcing people into doing things.
I have a way of giving people no other choice.
I want to try to fix that.
Where should I drop you off?
At the office.
Okay!
Sorry we're closed...
I came to tell you something.
I'm glad you're still here.
How did you know I'd be here?
How did you know?
Don't ever come here again.
I didn't get the chance to introduce myself properly last time...
Father.
I'm sorry I didn't speak up despite knowing who you were.
And thank you for helping me to understand Seoyeong.
The two of you...
I heard you broke up.
I broke up to help her feel at peace.
I had no choice but to let her go.
You know what she's like.
I thought about things after listening to you.
I understood why she did that.
Also why she couldn't keep living with me.
I realized how she must have felt living with me.
I understood how nervous she must have been.
So I couldn't force her into staying with me.
I see.
Seoyeong...
She's difficult.
She's a fool.
She's twisted.
I made her that way.
Children should live through the comfort of their parents.
She had to take the burden of her mother and Sangu too.
She hung in there on those frail legs of hers.
How could she be normal?
How much tenacity could she have?
How skilled could she become?
She's human too.
She's human.
Yes.
She hung in there on nothing but her pride.
But...
Then she found that you and I were involved.
She must have felt so humiliated.
She wouldn't have been able to look at your face.
I'm sorry...
To you and to your parents too...
I'm so sorry.
I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't come to hear that.
It's also my fault that we ended up this way.
You know that.
You know I'm forceful.
Seoyeong and I failed in our marriage but this isn't the end for us.
Seoyeong's birthday
Still...
She was a good person, right?
Who?
Seoyeong?
There was nothing to criticize.
But that's how it is.
That's the thing about con men.
They make their victims fully trust them.
Are you saying Seoyeong is a con artist?
Con artists begin by lying to their victims.
By the way...
Are you really going to donate $100,000 every year on Seongjae's birthday?
I have to. It's in the papers.
I can't lie to the entire nation.
Make time for me tonight.
I don't want to make time to listen to your excuses.
I have something else to do.
It isn't easy to overcome differences in status.
Dr. Kang Migyeong.
Why damage the glass?
The glass is innocent.
You lied.
Of course people feel betrayed.
You'll own this hospital one day.
So this glass belongs to you too?
Professor, why are you so mean to me?
What did I do?
You're eccentric when it comes to me. You are.
I admit it.
Why?
Why do you do that?
- Responsibility...
Stop talking about doctors' responsibilities.
Responsibility as a doctor!
That comes after personal responsibility.
Excuse me?
The Kang Migyeong I knew wasn't like this.
What?
Do you know me?
The first time I met you was at this hospital.
Are you sure about that?
Seoyeong's birthday
2013 K-POP Super Concert
Pack Seoyeong's things from the closet.
Remove her books, desk and everything else from the study.
Yes, Executive Yun.
Can we meet up today?
Today?
What time?
Spend an enjoyable time with your husband.
Kang Gibeom
What is it?
Make some time for me this evening.
Come with me to a concert.
What are you talking about?
I have an appointment this evening.
Go with Gangsun.
Alright then.
What did you expect?
He's supposed to be acting on this.
He's vanished into thin air!
If he got fired from the home shopping network,
where is he eating and sleeping?
Does he really want a divorce?
Yes, Jiseon. What is it?
Gangsun, come with me to a concert tonight.
Sorry. It's my son in law's birthday tomorrow.
I'm out grocery shopping.
Go with Seongjae. Bye.
How can I go to a concert when my husband is missing?
You don't go out often.
You don't meet many people.
Loneliness is your friend.
Yes.
That's what my life's like.
I can't trust anyone.
I can't depend on anyone.
I wanted to meet you and ask you for a favor.
A favor?
Just for one day...
Will you join me in doing the things I wanted to do?
What are the things you wanted to do?
Excuse me.
- Here, take this one.
- Okay.
Didn't you go to the bathroom?
You have no idea, do you?
Cola and popcorn was made for the movies.
Here, it's sweet flavored.
Women like that.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Aren't you from my music academy?
Don't talk to me.
Excuse me?
Your husband could get the wrong idea.
I didn't bring him with me.
Did you come with a friend?
I came alone.
Alone?
You came alone too.
Why are you so shocked to hear that I came alone?
I gave you the tickets to come with your husband.
Why didn't you come with your wife then?
I can't come here with "Mrs. No."
Excuse me?
My wife always says no whenever I ask her to do something.
So she's Mrs. No.
Then my husband's name should be Mr. No.
I'm sorry.
I've been rehearsing since morning.
I haven't eaten all day.
You showed me a movie so I'll treat you to a meal.
What would you like?
Can we...
Can we eat at my place?
Your place?
I'm a regular here.
Are you shocked?
This is all I can afford.
Why do you think that I'd be shocked?
Because you've never been to a place like this.
"Do people eat standing up?"
Do magicians learn to read people's minds too?
How do you know everything?
Me?
It was the same last time with the tarot cards.
You're like a fortune teller.
That's the fun of magic.
Shocking and surprising people gives us pleasure.
It's a pleasurable lie.
A pleasurable lie.
Lies...
They can be pleasurable too.
Oh, my...
Wow, that's amazing.
Here, eat up.
When you're lonely, you should pig out.
How did you know that I was lonely?
That's right. I'm a hermit.
All human are lonely.
You said I'm a hermit.
You're breaking out of that.
Me?
When?
Today's the first time you've been to a concert by yourself.
I told you it's a charm that will help you break free.
Was it really a lucky charm?
Did you know that I'd come alone?
You didn't.
You hid thinking that I'd come with my husband.
For the first time, you're not eating with family or a friend.
You're eating with someone else and chatting with them right now.
Then is the sunshine really entering my life?
For sure.
I wanted to make seaweed soup for you.
You made my favorite dishes.
You've had poor bowels since you were born.
So don't eat cold foods in the summer, alright?
I won't.
The CEO's wife raised you well.
I thought a lot about what you said to me last time.
Everything you said is right.
I fooled myself.
As you said, I was always by your side...
So I...
I fooled myself thinking I was your mom.
I'll leave.
The actions I did for you may not be what you want.
I didn't think about that.
I grew up at an orphanage not knowing who my parents were.
I was so hungry.
I felt so empty.
So...
I wanted you to take over your dad's company.
I wanted you to live in comfort and have an abundant life.
"Why take up acting and live such a hard life?"
That's what I thought.
That's why I did that.
Even now, all I want is for you to be happy.
Now, I'm going to try and live a happy life too.
Eat up.
You try the seaweed in sesame oil like this.
Fry the seaweed in the sesame oil.
Then pour water.
Hot, boiling water.
- Into the pot.
- Pour it like this.
Boil the water, pour it.
Then?
Then it's easy.
Season it, add garlic.
It's really easy.
You need to boil it and let it simmer for a long time.
Simmer for a long time.
Father, does simmer mean I have to reduce the heat and boil for a long time?
That's right.
But father
why is Sangu's registered birthday different to his real birthday?
Seoyeong was really ill.
Seoyeong was sick?
Sangu was okay. Seoyeong had pneumonia and went into the incubator.
The doctor said she could die.
Goodness. What happened?
What do you think?
Fortunately, she survived.
Why did you register Sangu's birthday later then?
Did you register the same birthdays because they were twins?
I thought Seoyeong would die if we registered Sangu first.
So we postponed his birthday.
It's a relief that Seoyeong recovered quickly.
I felt like i had earned the entire world.
Thank you.
Are we having seaweed soup for breakfast today?
No, I made dried pollack soup.
Then why does it smell like seaweed soup?
They must have made it next door.
Why does it smell?
We didn't open the windows.
Are you having dinner at your in laws place?
Yes.
Go there, cut a cake and light candles.
Have a good birthday party.
We will, father.
Has she gone to work already?
Borrow up to $12,000 on the spot!
How much longer is he going to do this?
It's his son in law's birthday!
Oh! He doesn't know that it's Sangu's birthday.
It's Sangu's birthday today.
They're coming over for dinner so you'd better be here!
He has to come for his son in law's first birthday with us.
It's your first birthday with us.
I'm really sorry.
I can't tell you the reason
but I'm at a turning point in my life right now.
Try to understand, Sangu.
I don't mind.
But what is it?
Never!
You don't need to worry at all!
And...
Here.
What's this?
For the first time in my life,
I earned that money doing what I want to do.
It's your birthday gift.
Father...
Don't tell Hojeong about it.
Use it as emergency money.
Don't worry. I made seaweed soup for myself this morning.
It's your birthday today.
What are your plans??
I hope you're not just going to work.
I'm not that hopeless.
Alright then.
Seoyeong!
Happy Birthday.
You too, Sangu. Happy Birthday.
Seoyeong, is it your birthday?
I guess so.
You guess so?
Lee Seoyeong.
Birthdays are so important.
How can you speak that way?
The chance of an egg and sperm fertilizing is 300 million to 1.
Was he always like that.
Yes, he was.
I popped over to say bye before gong to Europe tomorrow.
My first love's birthday stops me from leaving.
What are you going to do for your birthday?
I'm going to hang out with Yeonhui.
Yeonhui, are any potential clients booked to come here today?
None.
Then get up, both of you.
Pull down the shutters and follow me. Do it!
What?
What are you doing, Yeonhui?
Yes, sir!
- Get up.
- Come on.
Let's go.
Get changed in the fitting room.
Why should I wear this?
On a special day,
you have to get dressed up to show yourself some respect.
Exactly.
Whose clothes are they?
They're from my friend's new collection.
You can keep it after you wear it.
Wow! Try it on.
Hurry up.
It's so pretty.
I have to go out right now.
Tell the finance team to bring the papers over quickly.
Yes, sir.
Lee Seoyeong
Why isn't he here?
Mom, we're here.
Yes, hi.
Welcome. It's cold outside, isn't it?
Have you been well, mother?
Sure. Thanks for asking.
Father's going to be...
I know. Sangu told me.
Told you what?
He said he can't come for dinner as he has something important to do.
He came to see me at the hospital earlier today.
What?
They're your favorite dishes.
Here. Have some of this.
Thank you.
Mother, why aren't you eating?
Mom, is is because dad didn't come?
It's okay. He met Sangu earlier.
I know!
He went to see his son in law.
What about me?
How could he do this to me?
Mom, what's wrong?
Your dad left home.
Dinner was enough.
I haven't been to a place like this before.
That's why we came here.
You have to try everything that other people do.
Exactly.
I'm sorry.
Were you shocked?
I have a special friend.
It's her first time at a club.
Really?
Who is it?
There's so much Seoyeong hasn't done.
It's her birthday today.
So I dragged her here.
Raise your glass.
Go on.
Lee Seoyeong...
Happy Birthday.
Happy Birthday!
Thanks for today.
I had a good time.
I accompanied the ice princess into the human world.
Have a good business trip.
Wait a minute.
What is it?
I want to give you a present for your birthday.
A photo?
Forget it.
I don't take photos of just anyone, you know.
Stand over there in front of the tree, okay?
It's nice here. Hurry up.
Come on, Lee Seoyeong.
Smile more.
Make your arms natural.
You look like a log.
Like this?
Lean against the wall.
Subtitles by KBS World
♫ Are you looking at me? ♫
♫ Are you looking at my heart? ♫
♫ I keep holding it in over and over but it hurts like crazy. ♫
♫ I've tossed it aside and erased it again, ♫
♫ But I've returned to the same place. ♫
♫ Come back and hold me, just like that time  ♫