Did you see him wave? There he is!
Will you help me up?
lnstead of getting sicker,
he just stayed the same
He didn't get sicker
He didn't get better
They were kind-hearted and thought
he was going out on his own steam
The doc must've come over,
or someone gave him something
Probably some kind of medicine
or something
l could have just took it
and put it in a ditch
Like they do to a horse
They shoot him right away
Buster, fetch!
Whoa Easy
Whoa, pup
Sally
Whoa, pup Sally Sally
Whoa, pup
Whoa, whoa
You seem jumpy today
l'm sick of these stinking birds
- What's the matter?
- You don't wanna know about it
Just as things were about to blow,
this flying circus came in
After six months on this patch,
l needed a breath of fresh air
They were screaming and yelling
and bopping each other
The big one pushed the little one
and said, ''l started You start ''
The little one started in
lf they couldn't think of a good one
to come back with, they'd stop
The little one said, ''l didn't do this ''
The big one said, '' Yes, you did ''
They couldn't sort it out
l wanna give them a hand for this
The devil just sitting there laughing
He's glad when people does bad
Then he sends them
to the snake house
He sits there laughing
while you're tied up and snakes
are eating your eyes out
They go down your throat
and eat all your systems up
You're confusing me, you know
You're driving me crazy
l don't know if l'm coming or going
You never did
l think the devil was on the farm
- What's going on?
- What's the matter?
You know what l mean
Why do you let him
touch you like that?
What are you talking about?
How do brothers and sisters act
where you come from?
Did you ever have a sister?
Well, then, who are you to judge?
Did you say anything to him?
l've never seen him
act like this before
- He must think we're awful
- What do you care?
You're in love with him
- Are you leaving?
- Yeah
What for?
l've got business to take care of
They're giving me a lift
- Just like that, huh?
- Guess so
He'd seen how it all was
She loves the farmer
He taught me keys on the pianos
and notes
He taught me
about the parts of our globe
Hey! l missed you so much
- Did you miss me?
- Yeah, a lot
Hey, you look just the same
We've been reading about you
- What do you mean?
- h, about Chicago
Did you come all the way
by motorcycle?
l'm sorry
You didn't do nothing to me
l didn't know what l had with you
l think about it
The things l said to you
How l pushed you into this
l got nobody to blame but myself
Well, l got to get going
Before it gets too late
Smoke them out! Swat them out!
That way! Let's go Come on!
What's this? What are you doing?
- What do you care?
- What are you doing?
Are you crazy?!
Let it burn!
Get tractors, blankets!
What are we gonna do?
We gotta get out of here
He knows
What did you want from me?
Wait
You're a liar!
Shall l pull it out?
l'll tell you the whole story later
We can't do anything about it now
You know, you're skinning me alive,
but l'll give you the old van for the boat
Nobody's perfect There was never
a perfect person around
You just got half devil
and half angel in you
She promised herself
she'd lead a good life from now on
She blamed it all on herself
lt's good l like it
She didn't care
if she was happy or not
She just wanted to make up
for what she did wrong
l have a three-pound cop
The sun looks ghostly when there's
a mist on the river and it's quiet
l never known it before
You could see people on the shore,
but not what they were doing
They were probably
calling for help or something,
or they were trying to bury
somebody or something
We seen trees
with leaves shaking
lt looks like shadows of guys
coming at you and stuff
We heard owls squawking away,
''ooming'' away
We didn't know where we were
going or what we were gonna do
l've never been on a boat before
That was the first time
Have you seen her? Where?
Some sights l saw were so spooky
they gave me goose-pimples
l felt like cold hands touching
the back of my neck,
and it could be the dead
coming for me or something
l remember this guy
His name was Black Jack He died
He only had one leg, and he died
And l think that was Black Jack,
making those noises
He's there!
Check out those trees!
Keep down!
- Just stay here
- Wait a minute
- Go around back that way
- Don't let him get back to the river
l'm gonna go this way
You go over there
Hey, Linder!
You want that, too, don't you?
You'll make lots of friends
You'll be all right
Turn around and go inside
ranges, oranges
Come on
Don't worry about that stuff l got
a new boyfriend He's in the army
Maybe the other got killed Anyway,
he said l'm pretty Maybe l am
Look at this
Hey, what did you do
at that school anyway?
lnto the alley Hurry up
l don't wait two hours for nobody
Maybe he don't have a watch
Yeah, if l believe that,
he'll tell me another
His name was Edward
He was nice
l liked him l don't know
He said he was gonna buy me a fur
l always wanted a fur
- Where are you going?
- For a walk
l don't know where, but
Go beat the heck out of some tree
Take it out on them
You coming with me, or what?
This girl didn't know where she was
going or what she was gonna do
She didn't have no money on her
Maybe she'd meet up
with a character
l was hoping things would work out
for her She was a good friend