REFRESH PRODUCTION
Presents
In co-production with
Produced with financial support of:
Cast
First time on film
A film by Pjer Zalica
DAYS AND HOURS
Screenplay
Executive Producer
Production Manager
Film Manager
Make Up
Costume Designer
Set Designer
Music
Director of Photography
Producer
Director
Hey, Fuke.
- Hey there.
What brings you here?!
I came to see my aunt and uncle.
What's up?
Nothing much.
I'm just going downtown.
See ya...
- Yeah, bye...
Idriz!
Where are you?!
- I hear you. I'm coming.
This is as fast as I can!
Sure! If you hear me,
why don't you answer?
Who is it?
It's me, Fuke.
Who?
- It's me, uncle. Fuke!
Who's there?
What is it that you want?
- Idriz, who is it?
Uncle Idriz, it's Fuke.
Fuad, Zineta's son.
It's you, Fuke.
Hello, my child.
- Hello, uncle.
I thought I knew that voice.
Come in, please.
What's up?
Am I interrupting something?
- Of course not.
I was just arranging some old boxes.
I thought about you this morning,
I wondered how come you never
come by. - As if I sensed that!
I know, I took ages to come by
and look at that boiler.
Something always comes up.
I know, my son.
You always have things to do.
There's something wrong
with hot water.
It sort of works,
and then it doesn't.
It could be really bad,
deep inside the system.
Don't worry, we'll sort it out
in no time.
We'll open it up, if necessary.
Right. Come on it.
I'm glad you came.
Sure.
I tried to get you on the phone
a few times.
I think there's something
wrong with the lines.
Really? We've been here
all the time.
Who are you talking to?
Fuke's here.
Really?
Look at him.
- Hello, auntie! - Hello.
Working too hard?
Nothing special.
Just airing the house.
Fuke's here to fix the boiler.
- That's nice.
We can have a chat, too.
I was just saying, I tried
to reach you a few times,
but I just couldn't get through.
As if it's busy all the time.
I probably unplugged the phone
when I was dusting it.
I'm sure that was it.
Please, come in.
Wait. Not those slippers.
Let me get you another pair
These are nice and soft.
Real leather.
Okay, thanks.
- Look at that!
And I searched for them
all over the place.
You don't need new slippers.
My dear, if I'd known
you were coming,
I would've cleaned up
the bathroom a bit.
Sure! It's already
tidy as a pharmacy.
You can speak all you want,
my dear uncle.
She is sort of careful,
but as soon as I leave
she's all over smoked meat
and cheese cream.
She knows she's got high blood
pressure, but she just can't help it,
she loves the heavy stuff!
I keep telling her:
'Mom, don't eat that,
you know it's bad for you.'
And she goes:'I won't, don't worry!'
As soon as I'm out the door,
she does it again.
What can you do about it,
up there?
I know, my child.
When your late father was alive,
he and I wondered
how your mother Zineta and Sabira
were so much alike,
as if they're sisters.
Like it or not,
they'll get their way!
Just look at her. Cleaning
the bathroom for you,
as if it could be any cleaner.
She's always been like that,
just like her mother.
But since this thing happened,
almost seven years now
since Emin, God rest his soul,
honest to God, it's twice as bad!
That's what she does all the time,
cleaning, washing, sweeping
and weeping!
She keeps cleaning and airing
rugs and carpets!
No words can describe
what she does!
I can imagine!
Just don't pay attention.
I know it's hard, but try not to.
I keep trying! But she always
frightens me with one of her...
The other day, every time
I laid eyes on her,
she was putting cream
on her hands.
I finally worked out that
she burnt her fingers
with toilet bleach, trying to make
the tub shiny white.
That could be nasty.
How bad was it?
It's okay, just the tips
of her fingers.
I keep telling her,
don't play with chemicals,
you'll burn down the house and
me in it, and she goes:
'People have always used
acid for cleaning.'
It's these bad times,
they keep giving us
really bad imported stuff.
It's all Chinese chemistry!
Chinese chemistry?
- Sure it is.
I don't know.
There, everything's ready.
Shall we have coffee now, or
you want to look at boiler first?
I want to look at that boiler first.
Who was that on the phone?
- It wasn't them.
I didn't think so,
that's not what I asked.
Zineta called, to check
if you arrived alright.
She says be careful and
don't pick up anything heavy,
you don't want to mess up
your back again.
She just has to find something
to worry about.
No, you won't!
Sabira!
Sabira-hanum!
Hello, Begzada-hanum.
- Hello, Sabira.
Why are you standing there?
- Cause your gate is locked.
And I'm in a bit of a hurry anyway.
Idriz must have been
doing something again.
Wait, I'll go get the key.
Don't, I'm not coming in.
I just came to give you
this piece of cornbread.
Real corn, bright as gold!
It's real cornflower.
Seval and Larisa went to Visoko
and her father went to the mill
to grind it. - Really?
This is your plate. That's why
I brought it!
I thought the pattern
looked familiar.
A visitor? Do tell who it is.
Fuke has come
to look at the boiler.
Great, you'll have hot water again.
- God willing, yes.
How's work?
Okay, most of the time.
The salary's not much,
but when you look at others,
this is just fine.
Just look at all those people
with no work at all.
You're right.
And you were so lucky in the war.
There was very little damage.
- Almost nothing.
And we were one of the first
to start the privatization.
Do Sheila and Aida
ever come to visit?
Watch out, don't let
the water burst out.
It won't.
It's not from the pipes.
It's just what's left
inside the boiler.
Whatever. Just make sure
it doesn't burst!
I'm careful with it.
Remember the mandolin your
late father brought for me
from that seminar in Opatija?
In Zivogosce, you mean?
No, in Opatija. Of course
it wasn't Zivogosce.
Right. He did go to Opatija,
just before the Olympics,
his company sent him.
- That's it.
I got it mixed up for a second.
I found the mandolin.
It's still there?
- Yes, it is.
You'd be surprised,
it still works just fine.
I remember those days,
you sure knew how to play it.
My playing days are long gone.
- Right.
So, what about Sheila and Aida?
What's up with them, where are they?
- They're here.
They went to Tuzla for the weekend,
to see Sheila's brother.
It's Aida's birthday tomorrow.
I forgot all about it.
- May 7th.
Coming on 10, my child.
Doesn't time fly?
- Unbelievable, isn't it?
I saw Aida last week
and I just thought,
hasn't she grown up.
Now that you say that she's
turning 10,
of course she's grown up.
Yes, a big girl.
They're not coming here for
her birthday. That's strange.
They can't. Work is so strict
these days!
I know, I heard someone
bought them.
And you can't mess with
these foreigners.
But it's no good when a woman
is too ambitious,
it's just not right,
and that's that!
When I saw Aida
I could hardly recognize her.
You should see her when
she comes to visit!
Heaven forbid to enter the house
with your shoes on.
She goes: 'Grandpa,
you can't wear same slippers
in the house and in the garden.'
- Really?
That child knows every
single thing in this house,
as if she was born here.
- She was born here.
Yes, but...
See, she knows
where everything is,
every little thing,
as if she lives here.
Uncle...
there's something
I just have to tell you.
Maybe it just seems to me,
but Aida has the same walk
as her late father.
She tiptoes.
It's just like seeing Emin.
You're right.
The image is there...
You say it warms up,
but there's no hot water.
Right!
There was warm water
until two days ago.
It was really nice and warm.
But even that's gone cold now.
I think it could be the heater!
- I think so too.
We'll see when I open it.
Is this 'Gorenje'?
Yes, Slovenian. From Velenje.
It's almost 17 years old!
I think I have a spare heater
in the garage,
but I'm not sure if it's 'Gorenje'.
Are you done with the coffee?
- Ages ago.
You burnt up four cigarettes
in half an hour!
Here's some juice, my child.
I made it a bit sweeter,
'cause you're working.
Thanks.
You must be tired.
No, I'm fine.
- The juice will do you good.
I'll have to go home
and get the heater.
Idriz said right away
that it was the heater.
Are you done painting the walls?
Yes.
And?
Not bad.
She didn't get the color
right again?
The color was right but
the base was real lime,
a total mess for two days.
Zineta likes lime,
and that's that.
She may like it, but
nobody does that any more.
The painter told her himself.
He only agreed to do it as
a special favor to her.
Nothing beats your cakes.
Just enough syrup, not too much,
not too little.
It could have been
just a bit airier.
No, it couldn't!
It could have,
just a little.
I was just telling uncle,
I saw Aida the other day.
All grown up, isn't she?
For your information,
Aida is turning ten tomorrow!
He knows, I told him.
Please play that tape,
when she sings in the choir.
We can't watch that again.
Fuke should see it.
He's never seen it before.
You can't see her well.
There she is, in the middle,
second row.
Next to the blonde girl.
I can see her.
- There she is.
They sure sing well.
Just like one voice.
As if it's not a choir.
- She is grandma's life.
Strange that they didn't call
when they arrived.
They haven't called, that means
they've arrived.
Does she have a mobile?
Want me to call her?
No, don't bother.
There... the end.
Why aren't you eating your cake?
- I will.
I can't just now.
Are you having that
chest pain again?
I'm fine. Never mind that,
let me talk to the man in peace.
- As you wish.
And don't spill the residue,
I need it.
I saw you brought them
into the house again!
So what? They're harmless.
They're in a tin box.
It's cold at night,
they'll die anyway.
Who?
Earthworms, that's who!
Why did you need that
funny little guitar?
Dear God.
Give us the good news now.
What you mean?
I mean, what's up with...
you know...
They say it's not good to ask
about that...
Love, I mean.
- Oh, that...
You just had to ask,
didn't you?
Let me be. You and Zineta
find out everything.
I never get to hear about it.
I feel like an idiot.
And?
Well, Samra is back...
so... you know...
it is...
It is what, my child?
We are... sort of...
dating again.
That's what I want to hear!
- To be honest,
if there was anything,
you'd be the first to know!
Is it serious?
- Well, yes.
We sort of talked about it
the other day, you know,
getting married and stuff.
And all of a sudden she goes:
'I would really like
to live in Rovinj! '
Where?
- In Rovinj.
On the Slovenian coast!
- Rovinj what?
I don't know. They used to go
there for holidays,
so she sort of likes the area,
and the climate,
the sea and clean air
and stuff like that.
That's far. Almost all the way
to Italy! - I know.
I said so too. I sure don't
want to live up there!
And yet...
I was just thinking, I mean...
if that's the only way...
Please be careful!
You're smart, but do
keep an eye on everything!
She mentioned this Rovinj once,
she sure will again.
I know, auntie, I know...
Then Rijeka, then Pula,
then hop, hop, hop...
All the way up...
Idriz?
- Yes?
Let me get you your medicines.
- No, I'll get them.
Remember where you stopped.
Sabira?
- Yes?
Sabira!
- What?
Where are my pink pills?
In the white box, next to your
shaver. I put them there.
In the white box,
next to the shaver...
Why did you have to take them
out of the box?
It was made that way on purpose.
His heart's gone to Tuzla.
I see that uncle is really
bothered by something.
Bothered and buried alive.
Sheila knows
you want them to come.
What can she do?
She's got so much to do,
she wouldn't manage
even if she had twice the time.
She sets things up
so that she's left no time
to think about things.
- I know, but still...
And this one...
He's killing himself.
You know that Idriz won't let
anyone touch Emin's room.
And Aida keeps going there,
it's her blood,
she keeps finding stuff
and asking us questions.
She's a big girl. Of course
she wants to know.
She should know. It's better
that we tell her about it,
rather than asking other people.
Sheila sort of keeps to herself,
she doesn't want to say no to us,
but I know her heart's on fire,
I can see it,
no one needs to tell me.
Her eyes tell me everything.
I know her inside out.
She brought a child to this world
with our loss.
I wish we could
take everything apart
and just put it back again.
Take what apart?
Emin's room, to fix it.
For Aida,
so it can be her own room,
it's time.
I don't know.
It will soon be seven years
since Emin was killed.
On Thursday.
- Yes.
Seven years,
like seven minutes.
I went to his grave a while ago.
I'll go again on Thursday.
My son, my son...
Auntie, don't...
What can you do now?
I won't, honest, I won't...
If only I could
disappear,
just fly far, far away.
Dear God, it's all up to you!
God's will...
That's all we can say.
God's will and the enemy's hand!
Yeah...
Did Zineta buy that gas stove?
I'll look for the heater right away
and I'll let you know if it matches.
If it doesn't,
I'll see where I could find
an original one.
Thanks, my child. Don't take
too much trouble.
No trouble, let's just fix it.
Take some cake to Zineta.
She'll enjoy it.
Thanks.
I was just telling uncle,
I'll let you know as soon as
I find the heater.
Thank you, my dear.
I hope it's not too much trouble.
You've got enough work as it is,
all the time.
Don't worry. We'll sort it out.
Bye now.
Good bye. Do come to visit.
- I'll see you out.
Let me take that.
Can you manage?
- Sure.
Go back inside.
- Never mind.
Drive carefully.
- I will, don't worry.
That doesn't seem to work.
Look at this! It works one minute,
the next it doesn't.
It sounds like a dead battery.
It sounds like there's no
electrical supply.
What can I do in this darkness?
Do you have a flashlight
in the house? - Yes.
Yes, but it doesn't work.
Wait, I'll go and ask Ekrem.
It's all because of
the wheat flower!
Where did you buy it?
At Djulaga's store?
That's strange. That must be
his new supply.
I didn't have the chance,
Idriz asked him while
I was in the kitchen!
Don't say,
summer holidays in Rovinj?
I told him. A smart man would know,
a hint would do.
What?
Of course he's smart enough.
He is smart enough.
Here.
Sorry for the trouble.
- No trouble at all.
These stairs are so steep.
What's up, Fuke?
- It just won't start.
Try it once.
It sounds like a dead battery.
- I think so too. - Me too.
And if we push it a bit?
It's easy to push downhill,
but what if we have to push it
uphill again?
I have charger cables, you know,
that electric thing you just plug in.
How long does it take to charge?
Roughly?
An hour and a half approximately.
An hour should do it.
Go on, plug it in and see
what happens.
Okay.
See how well they
make them now!
It's serious business now.
Aren't they cheap?
That's really cheap.
Around here you can't get them
for less than a hundred.
Any colors other than brown?
Not at the moment.
In a few days.
You've shown me all I need to see.
Light and good quality.
Aren't they soft as cotton?
I'll tell Sheila to stop by
as soon as she comes back.
I haven't seen her in a while.
Are there any leather slippers,
the ones from the last time?
I'll ask. I'm not sure though,
they are really in demand.
Put it over there.
Here! - Let me do it.
I saw Buba earlier.
Great car, congratulations.
That's what we could afford.
- Where does she go?
To school.
She is attending evening
classes for computer training.
Three times a week,
after work.
That's great. I wanted to
do it too.
So did I, but you just
can't find the time.
Work and then
the computer thing.
How about coffee?
We just finished a pot.
A juice will be fine.
- A vitamin drink.
Good evening.
What's up, my dear, honest friend?
All's well, no complaints!
Hello, Muhamed!
- Hi, Fuke. What's up?
We're charging the battery.
I couldn't start the car.
Don't say?
- Yeah, well.
Whose jump-cable is this?
It's mine, of course.
It's really good.
Decent people are in bed now,
and I have to teach kids
how to play table tennis.
Just look at the racket.
I thought I could give you
a quick beating
but this time you're saved
by a car battery!
11:8. Alright.
Acrobat the mighty flyer,
never mind, he trips the wire!
Brick, trick, kick,
Hamed's gone to the nick!
This doesn't count!
Go fetch the ball, Hame.
The ball!
Okay, champ!
- It's not okay, come on!
Acrobat the mighty flyer,
never mind, he trips the wire!
Idriz?
- Yes?
Where on earth have you been?
You went to see the man of
and you disappeared.
I've been with Fuke.
His car wouldn't start.
Is it okay now?
No. He went to Ekrem's
to charge the battery.
He's got one of those
charger things.
Dear God!
Is he coming back here?
I told him to ring us
when they come back.
Where are you going?
The news starts in a minute.
I've had enough, they just keep
spitting at one another.
You had a good team there.
You remember it?
- Of course I do!
Nobody in the world had
a kick like 'Krila'!
Remember when he whacked
the fat guy,
when the ambulance came?
- Down by the school.
Just think about that.
His mom was so worried,
she had to put an ice-bag
on her head.
His mum still says that
he could never go to college
because 'Krila' hit him so bad
that his concentration was
you know... all messed up.
- My foot!
'Krila' was in my class
in primary school.
Even then he could hardly get by.
He was always stealing stuff.
He was only good in crafts!
- You're right.
It's got a really powerful beam.
Dad!
Good evening, Almir!
- Good evening.
What's up?
- Nothing special.
Dad, can I play video games?
You've spent the entire morning
in front of the computer,
your head will just burst.
- Please.
Drop that, go home, straight to bed!
I'll ask mom.
Let me show you.
I've expanded the business.
I have two guys from Mostar,
refugees in Sweden for 6 years,
went to hairdressing school there,
and the customers really like them.
That means real business.
- You bet.
Sit down, try out this chair.
How come Sheila never comes
to see Idriz?
She does. She's just very busy.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
I don't want to interfere,
but everything and everyone's
as close as it can be.
Here you see everything.
Even stuff that shouldn't be seen.
What do you mean?
People see behind the gates,
even Idriz's gate.
Not that I would ever look.
It's the architecture.
So?
I saw Idriz yelling at Sheila.
The entire neighborhood saw it.
There, that's it.
Shit, I had to tell you.
When was that?
Maybe even 6 months ago.
Good that you told me.
Good that you came here.
Why did he yell?
- How would I know.
There was a situation,
I was just walking past,
saw the scene and
it just stuck with me.
It's just for your information,
so you know.
Did you hear that Samra's back?
- Samra who?
You know, the one and only.
Your Samra! - Yes.
- Hey, I had no idea.
Yes, that's recent.
She was a refugee in New York,
she got the passport
and now... she's back.
So, are you, you know...
sort of something...
Yes, sort of something...
again.
Well, congratulations, then.
I'm glad for you.
Never mind that.
People congratulated me once
before, and things went all wrong.
The war turned things all wrong.
It turned things upside down.
We'll see. Let things
come into place a bit.
Tell me honestly, whatever it is,
would you ever
go to live in Rovinj?
To Rovinj?
To live there?
Would you? Yes or no,
just tell me, no matter what!
I don't know. You got me there.
Fucking Rovinj. No idea.
That's it! That's
the issue of my problem.
Did you shake the tablecloth
properly? - Yes.
I don't want any crumbs
sticking to it.
I think it should go in the wash.
I called.
Who?
- Aida, in Tuzla.
Didn't I ask you not to call?
I didn't mean to,
my hand just flew.
What does Aida say?
She was out playing with kids,
I didn't talk to her,
she'll call tomorrow.
I spoke to Sheila.
Yes?
It's done, let's try it!
- I'm coming.
Did you check the fuel?
- What fuel?
Maybe he's out of fuel.
What fuel!? It's not that.
It's more of an
electrical problem!
Fuel!
Try now!
Don't push it any more.
See, it just won't work.
This time it sounded like
something else, not the battery.
Maybe it's the alternator?
- It's the battery.
Never mind, take the cable,
connect it to the battery
and leave it overnight.
I don't think you have
any other choice.
Let's push it, whatever happens.
That's fine, but how do we...
No problem.
If we're going to push it,
you just stand in the street
and watch the traffic.
Drive carefully, make sure
you control it. Go on.
Clutch, clutch, clutch!
Watch out!
Not a chance.
It's dead.
I told you.
Push, push, all together!
If you can't push, just step aside,
don't make a mess for nothing.
Go on, Tarzan!
- Get lost!
Come on, Ekrem!
Straight, Idriz, straight.
Come on... now... hop in...
Never mind the shoes,
take it straight to the bathroom!
Here I am again.
I just won't leave.
That's alright.
That car is really a nuisance.
It's just old.
It needs maintenance
all the time.
It'll be fine, my child.
This could have happened
on the road somewhere.
Great, you made me a pie.
The garlic smells great.
The oven's not that good.
I thought about stuffed peppers,
but I know how much you like
potato pie, so I took a chance.
Take it, it's calling you.
Okay then, I'll take a cab
and go home,
and come back early
in the morning to get the car.
The cab will be a rip-off.
Why don't you sleep here?
There's an empty room.
Tomorrow is Sunday,
you don't work.
I don't know, mum's on her own.
Nothing can happen to her.
I spoke to her a minute ago.
She must be worried.
- No, she isn't.
Did you tell her I couldn't
start the car?
I told her all and
she says you shouldn't drive
until the car's been fixed properly.
That's what she said.
What are you doing?
- Cleaning the fish tank.
At this hour?
What else? I work days,
and at night I wait.
Wait for what?
- Nothing.
I left you a piece of pizza,
if you're hungry.
They are doing overtime too?
Who?
The computers.
Is that supposed to be funny?
In good time!
Here it is, from Sweden.
Zejnil sent it to Idriz,
but it's too big for him,
it'll just fit you well.
Thanks.
This fabric is so soft.
- I told you.
I'll pack it for you tomorrow
before you go.
No. Why should I take it with me?
- Of course you will.
It'll just collect dust here.
How come you came up
with Sweden?
Did he go to sleep?
Yes. A minute ago.
I'll throw that computer away!
Sure you will!
What will I practice with?
What's up with Fuke?
- He's upset about the car,
he has to dish out the money
for a new battery!
Why doesn't Samra buy him one,
I'm sure she has enough
stashed on the side.
Great that she's back. I was so
surprised when he told me.
She's back
only to go away again.
What do you mean?
I heard she had a miscarriage,
with the same guy she ran away with.
She's here only to sell
the shop in the old town.
Money in her pocket and Samra's off!
How can you know that?
She came to my agency.
To see if she could extend her
return ticket... to New York.
Don't tell me you're on her side?
- I'm not on anybody's side,
I just know Fuke loves her.
It's not easy for him.
If only...
B&H ARMY OFFENSIVE
ENDS IN A BLOODBATH
Fuke?
Uncle.
Here's an apple,
if you feel like it.
Thanks.
Look... It fits you nicely.
Just look at this.
It's really the one...
It looks smaller now.
You've grown...
One string is missing.
I tried to find it,
but nobody in this neighborhood
has a mandolin.
There's a music shop in the center,
they should have it.
I didn't mean to fix it for real,
it's just for fun.
It's fine without the string,
it has been for years.
Let me see.
You can put any wire off a roll.
What roll?
Any roll. From any engine.
My nails can't handle this.
Uncle.
- Yes?
You should really look after
yourself a bit more.
I do look after myself.
I mean, you should...
get it out of your mind.
You can't tell your mind
what to do...
I mean... you could talk to Sheila.
She neglected my child.
How can that be, uncle?
- Just like that.
If she wants to marry again,
nobody can stop her,
nobody can stop anybody!
At least...
...for Aida's sake.
He walked her to the house,
the entire neighborhood saw them.
There can be no such infidelity
in my house!
I know how you feel, I know it all...
but tell me: What Sheila can do?
She can't spend entire life
mourning and living with memories.
She can't marry another,
she never left Emin!
Get it?
She's still married to him.
She never left my son.
That's not right.
Do you want me to call her?
To talk to her?
Whatever, I don't care what you do.
You took my happiness away,
But my heart knows no other love,
Sorrow is the only thing I feel,
And this endless pain is all I have.
I'll love nobody else
in a hundred lives,
I cry, but tears don't come
to my eyes,
My pain has no end, I cry,
but my tears are dry.
Sheila, it's Fuke.
We don't need any more firewood.
It's spring.
We need the force, mother.
The force.
Pick up some eggs on the way.
How can I jog with eggs?
- Slowly.
No eggs, no cakes.
Good morning, grandma.
- Good morning to you too.
It's fully charged,
but you can't say
if the situation is okay
with the electrics.
It must be something...
- I'll just set it on fire.
When did you fill it up?
I filled it up... last month.
Sabira said it must be the fuel.
No more for me.
Have another one,
while it's still hot.
Just a drop.
Some more for you?
- Okay, just a bit.
What's that? Somebody
left a car running outside?
Fuke left his car running,
to charge the battery.
Someone could steal it.
- No way,
not here.
I guess not.
Yes?
Is Ekrem there?
- Yes, come in, he's here.
Depends on who's wants to know!
Good morning.
- Good morning to you too.
Buba, come in...
- Thanks, I'm in a hurry.
Hey, what's up?
- Hey, Fuke.
I see the car's okay.
- Yes, finally.
Sorry to be rude.
Ekrem, what on earth are you doing?
What am I doing?
Don't make me tell you in front
of all these people.
Didn't we agree to go shopping?
We'll go, don't make a fuss
for nothing. What's the problem?
It's 10.30 already and you're
not even dressed... nothing?
How can you be so irresponsible?
What do you mean 'nothing'?
I'm dressed!
You're not coming with me
dressed like that!
In that tracksuit, you look like
a Montenegrin mobster!
You always have something
against Montenegrins!
They're people too.
Right, Fuke?
Sure they are.
And you just had to
agree with him.
Have a quick cup and then go.
Okay then, with milk,
I've got heartburn.
What kind of behavior was that?
- Why? I didn't... I just...
He left it running like that?
It will only get stolen.
Who would steal it?
- Fuke is such a sucker.
Samra, it's me.
I was just messing about
with the car.
Let me tell you...
I mean... I wanted to
tell you something... It's...
It doesn't matter where you live,
what matters is who you live with!
That's what I think.
Who... right, who you live WITH!
Right.
No, I haven't gone nuts...
Why would I...
What's up with you?
Go on now.
There, as if you haven't
been away at all.
You let them go?
Why not?
They would have just died.
They can't live on
coffee residue forever.
They better go while the earth
is still damp.
My dear Begzada,
summer draughts are coming
any day now, no transition time.
Right.
Thanks.
It's the same cake from yesterday.
What are you doing now?
I just want to give him
two fresh pieces.
These went dry in the night.
How could they go dry?
It's not the middle of the summer,
nights are not that warm.
On the contrary, the atmosphere
is sort of fresh in the evening.
Where did this plate come from?
I've almost forgotten all about it.
Begzada gave it to me a minute ago.
- My God...
This must be the new fashion,
sending candy to each other!
Does it really matter?
Should I return the bowl to Begzada?
Not until I'm done.
You'll just mix up the plates again.
I'll look for the heater right away
and I'll let you know if it matches.
If it doesn't, I'll see
with guys at work
where I could find an original one.
Thank you, my child.
Don't take too much trouble.
No trouble at all.
Let's fix it finally.
Take this cake to Zineta, please.
She'll enjoy it.
Thanks.
I was just telling uncle,
I'll call you as soon as I've found
the heater for your boiler.
Thank you. Don't let us
trouble you too much.
You have so much to do anyway,
all the time.
Don't worry. It'll be fine.
There. Bye now.
Bye. And do come to visit.
And please, be very, very careful
about that Rovinj thing!
Don't worry, I will.
Good bye.
Idriz!
- Yes?
Is Fuke gone?
Yes. Didn't you see him leave?
I forgot to give him the pajamas.
I packed it and tried not to
forget it and look at this now.
You'll give it to him
next time he comes.
Now I feel bad about this.
He'll be back as soon
as he finds the heater.
You're making a draft again.
- I just wanted to air it a bit.
Air or no air, it's just a draft!
What is it? Did the window rip
the curtain again?
No, it's fine.
I think someone
tried on Emin's uniform.
Fuke. Who else?
Idriz!
Who's that?
How do I know? I can't see
through walls.
Maybe Fuke remembered
the pajamas.
Open the door and you'll know.
It's great that you came back,
she's killing me with the pajamas.
Aida's here.
There's grandpa.
Grandpa's... everything.
Did you see this?
- Does it work?
Of course it does.
Fuke sorted out the...
This is Izudin. My boss.
He drove us from Tuzla.
- Hello.
Please, come in.
Yes, please do.
What do we do now?
Will this be okay?
Yes, it will.
Let grandpa take that.
Look at this idiot.
They wouldn't park here
only if I put a sign that
it's mined!
My God, Sheila is here.
Give us the instrument, dad.
Sing that song
that gives me pain
I can't stand this kind of music.
- Fine.
My love for you
seems to be in vain
In this world
you're all I have
The peace of my soul
only you can save
Days fly so fast,
alone you should not be
Nights fly so fast,
waiting is too long for me
Let us not cause each other pain,
or our lives will have gone in vain.
Is this a company car or his own?
Not you too. Just let me be.
- Why?
Don't leave it too thin.
- Okay.
Sing that song
that gives me pain
My love for you
seems to be in vain
Hard and cruel and cold,
this world will live on
but you and I, my love,
we will be gone
we will be gone.
Days fly so fast,
alone you should not be
Nights fly so fast,
waiting is too long for me
Let us not cause each other pain,
or our lives will have gone in vain.
Where did this come from?
I thought someone
might come by.
Would you like one?
- No, thanks, I'm driving.
Let me ask you something.
You should know.
Is Rovinj in Croatia now,
or in Slovenia?
In Croatia. It's always been
in Croatia. - Thanks.
Is it the battery?
It's not the battery.
The whole system collapsed!