Hello, Michele.
Roberto.
- Come in.
- Give it to me please.
Some water please, Rita.
How's Elsa?
Fine. And Giovanna?
Fine.
Listen, Roberto.
I know your choices
were imposed by necessity
and maybe our tempers
got the better of us.
And so...
perhaps we should reconsider
our relationship.
- Here's the water.
- Thank you.
I certainly didn't expect
to hear this.
Life's full of surprises.
Of course,
now the situation's a bit different.
And the new organization...
you know that Morelli's
changing the structure completely.
We're aiming
for compactness
and we have to be united
and firm on everything.
You should see yourself.
You're terrified.
Don't hide behind Morelli.
It's you.
It's you who's acting
like a piece of shit and you know it.
I'm in deep shit,
but you really are
a piece of shit
and I don't even know
why the fuck I came!
Now I recognize it.
I recognize
the old dick-head.
- You had me fooled for a second.
- Now you've pissed me off!
Michele?
Michele.
Wait, Luciano.
Careful.
Watch out for the door.
Let's put this in the middle.
Then we'll see.
Excuse me, wait a second.
Can I go through?
Luciano, go back!
Let's find a place
for it right now.
Elsa, it'll never fit.
There's no room.
Should we sell this one too?
Will you please make
up your minds?
- Yes.
- Okay. Let me through.
Luciano, go back again.
Alice called earlier.
She told me to give you a kiss.
She doesn't call me, does she?
You could call her.
Maybe with earplugs we'd be able
to sleep. What do you think?
Remember that house
at Santarém?
We got there late at night,
then the next morning
we took a boat
and the boatman said,
"You're staying there.
This house will fall
apart soon." Remember?
I wonder if it's still standing
or if it's just rubble.
Brazil. What a wonderful trip.
Elsa...
we'll make this place nice,
you'll see.
Why is this taking
longer than yesterday?
This room's bigger.
Well, we don't have
anything else to do.
The longer it takes,
the better.
But the money's
the same, Luciano.
- Sorry, but l...
- He's not talking about that.
Luciano never talks about money,
don't worry. Seriously.
This kitchen's kind of small.
And dark, too.
Why the hell didn't they make
an opening in this wall?
We could put a table there.
It'd be nicer, wouldn't it?
You know, Mr. Oliveri,
that's a great idea.
Eh, Luciano?
What's to stop us?
- What do you want to do?
- We're deciding whether to make a hole.
It might be
a load-bearing wall.
- You think so?
- Load-bearing.
- It's about 10cm thick.
- No more than that.
- What if there are pipes?
- Going where, Luciano?
The bathroom's
on the other side.
Well, maybe we should
ask the owner.
For a permit?
Well, in that case...
Most of the time,
if they're improvements...
It isn't load-bearing.
This part's still
at an intermediate stage
and here there's just a sinopia.
Who knows if the central
part was finished?
I wonder what the face is like.
Girls, I'm too curious.
Don't know about you,
but I'm staying late.
Then I'll stay too.
I just have to make a phone call.
Lucky you.
I don't even have to bother.
Sandra, I can't stay
this evening.
Okay. Next time.
There'll soon
be another chance.
Actually, I think
I'll have to stop coming.
What are you
talking about, Elsa?
Are you kidding?
It's a difficult situation.
I'll explain some other time.
- Good evening.
- Good evening to you.
Almost finished?
We need another day.
- I know it's a nuisance.
- No, not at all.
What floor are you working on?
The third.
Will you excuse me?
- Oh, the third one.
- Goodbye.
- Good evening, ma'am.
- Good evening.
- Wait, let me help you.
- Thank you.
- Hi, how are you? Tired?
- So-so.
- What about you?
- Fine.
Vito and Luciano are
real professionals.
You're too nice!
- Good evening.
Whose idea was it?
It won't stay like this,
it needs more work.
Well, we can put a shelf here.
There you go!
I knew the lady would like it!
Fortunately.
For example, I've never done
wallpapering or plastering.
Thanks.
Anyway... thank you...
this counts as skills
down at the job center.
What do you mean?
I'm registered
at the employment agency, right?
But while I'm waiting for work,
I do the job center courses.
They help us not to give up
or get depressed.
Every once in a while,
they even find you a job.
There are lots of us.
It's like going to school.
There are the troublemakers, the ones
who come once and never come back.
They lie to their wives
and go to the beach instead.
There are also managers,
but they do separate courses.
Everyone has their own skills.
How can you do anything else?
Well, we all have
other skills too.
Somehow you learn
what they are.
You could be a welder,
but you might be good at cooking too,
so you find work in a restaurant.
If I could cook like you, ma'am,
I'd have found a job ages ago.
This pasta is wonderful.
My compliments. Very good.
- Don't overdo it. Is it really good?
- Yes. Delicious.
See you tomorrow then?
Okay, Mr. Oliveri. Thanks.
Sorry, sir.
This is a bit embarrassing.
Could you advance us 100 euros?
Of course, Vito.
I'll be right back.
Thank you.
Elsa,
do you have 100 euros for Vito?
He asked me for an advance.
Yes, sure, in my purse there.
- Here you go.
- Thanks, sir.
- Good night.
- Good night to both of you.
Let me do it.
Listen, Michele,
I was thinking.
Since you aren't getting
many interviews
and everything's
at a standstill...
We decided that
I'd take care of moving,
of the house,
doing work here.
- I know, that's what we said.
- So?
Maybe in the meantime,
these courses for managers
that Vito mentioned,
might be a good way for you
to meet other people,
- talk to them.
- We just had dinner with two people
and talked to them, didn't we?
We're all in the same boat,
aren't we?
No, I'm sorry. No.
Sure, they're nice and kind,
whatever you want,
but they used to be
your ex-employees.
It doesn't make much difference
for them to be cooks or laborers,
but it does for you, damn it!
You don't go out anymore.
You don't see anybody anymore.
How do you see it then?
You suggest I go and take a course
for unemployed managers?
Is that how you see it?
I've had another job offer,
as secretary
in a naval brokers' office
from 6:00 p.m. to 10:30 p.m.
They pay well and I can still keep
the call center job.
And what about
your restoring work?
How can you even think
I can keep that on?!
When a fax or email arrives,
all you have to do is
advise whoever's on duty.
If they ask you
to take it to them, do it,
otherwise put it
with the incoming mail.
Then there's the telephone.
If it rings at this hour, 90% of the time
you'll have to speak English.
But you don't have problem, right?
No problem at all.
I'm available to help
you with anything.
I'm just pregnant, not sick.
Call whenever you want, okay?
For example, this is a draft
of the Hong Kong contract.
We have to notify Salviati
right away.
He's the agent on duty
in the evening.
- Why don't you call him?
- Me?
Yes. Dial extension 3-2-5.
- 3-2-5.
- Perfect.
- Salviati?
- Salviati.
I'm making a hot drink.
Would you like something?
- Yes, a coffee, thanks.
- One for me too, thanks.
Oh, I apologize,
I didn't hear you answer.
- This is not Cristina.
- No, I'm her substitute,
- but I start tomorrow.
- Oh, yes! Because of the baby.
- Well, good luck then.
- Thanks, good luck to you too.
- Talk to you later.
- Okay.
- Yes?
- Salviati speaking.
- How may I help you?
- Did you need anything when you called?
Oh yes,
the draft of the Hong Kong
contract has arrived.
Yes, good. I'll check it later.
- Keep it there, please.
- Of course. That's fine, sir.
How stupid of me.
- Here. How many sugars?
- One.
- You answer. It'll be Salviati.
- Me?
Again?
- Yes?
- It's me again.
You didn't tell me your name.
- Elsa.
- Thank you, Elsa.
You're welcome.
Good evening.
Thanks.
...an estimate since
the job will last more.
- Hi. Good evening, Vito.
- Good evening, ma'am.
I'm sorry it's so late.
We're almost done.
How did it go?
I'm dead tired,
but go ahead.
I'm going to bed.
Remember the retired man,
the one with the dog? The nice one?
- He's asked us to do his kitchen over.
- Really?
He thinks we're professionals.
Really? Poor guy!
- Not because of you, Vito.
- Because of me.
So?
So let's add another half-day, sir.
- Four, five hours, not more.
- Yeah.
- That should be enough.
- So how much should we ask for then?
I'm no good at this.
Don't worry, I'll do it.
It's far.
The office is at the port.
Yes?
Careful, Luciano.
Sir, did Luciano tell
you the news?
- What news?
- He's going to be a grandfather.
Congratulations, Luciano!
Yes. Too bad there's no father.
Luciano, come on.
As my wife would say,
that's not necessarily a disadvantage.
You need to introduce me
to your wife.
- Sure.
- Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
How are things going?
Pretty well, I'd say.
We put everything
in the middle, like you said,
and we're putting
the shelf in the hall.
Yes, but no more
than two days though.
Sure, unless you want us
to give the bathroom a coat of paint.
It wouldn't hurt.
- I can't spend any more money.
- We'll meet you halfway...
Since we're already at it.
Believe me. Let's go take
a look at the bathroom.
- Seriously.
- Let's take a look at it.
It will only be
one more day at the most.
Certainly with a nice coat of paint...
Look at the mold.
- It's not load-bearing, is it?
- Luciano.
Bye, see you later.
How much time do we have?
I have to be
at the office by 6:00.
We can go for a stroll
in the town center.
No. I'm going to
take you somewhere.
- Feel like it?
- Yes.
You can give it
to me next time.
I want you to read it right away.
I only have half a page left.
Done.
It's wonderful.
Thanks.
It's been so long
since I last came here.
I didn't remember
how beautiful it was.
Nadia came
to the bistro yesterday.
Why don't you call her?
She's your friend. She cares about you.
I know, but right now
everything exhausts me.
How's Dad?
Pretty good.
He's doing odd jobs
with Vito and Luciano.
- His former employees?
- Yes.
They paint, put up shelves.
I don't know how he feels.
They called him for an interview,
a cookie factory.
Let's hope it goes well.
And how are you?
So-so.
What about you?
Everything okay with Riki?
Yes.
When you finish the book,
will you give it to Dad?
Yes. Except by the time I finish it,
it'll be Easter.
Goodbye.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, ma'am.
- Can I help you?
- I'd like some ricotta.
How much?
- There's two of us.
- 200g?
Sure.
By the way,
are you Mr. Oliveri?
Yes.
Mr. Terzetti was very pleased
with the work
you did at his house.
I'm glad.
Are you expensive?
I wouldn't say so.
I need to repaper my living room
and put up shelves,
but my budget's limited.
How much will it cost?
If you want,
I'll come and make an estimate.
I live on the same floor
as Terzetti.
Would you like anything else?
I need some bread.
Thank you.
- May I come in?
- Yes.
Here's the pizza and the beer.
Thank you.
Please give it to me.
Yes, put it there.
Don't go away.
Please stay.
Are you hungry?
Did you order one for you as well?
I've already eaten, thanks.
Really? When?
At 7:00 like kids do?
It's 9:30 now.
I'll cut a slice for you.
- No, thanks, really.
- A sip of beer then.
All right.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Sit down.
Thanks.
Those are our ships
going around the world.
Lucky them!
- Do you like traveling?
- Yes, a lot.
I don't like it at all.
- No? Really?
- Yes.
You never travel?
All the time.
I'm always going around the world
chasing something...
often ships.
Where are you from?
I was born in Cagliari.
I won't tell you the rest,
it would bore you.
I've lived in too many
different places.
And then you ended up here.
Better than many places.
So I chase
and you run away,
but, in the end, here we are.
Does it look like
I'm running away?
No, it seemed like it.
Anyway, you look nice.
You think so?
This isn't one
of the best periods of my life.
No no no. What's wrong?
Oh, God.
What now?
Hi. What time is it?
Almost midnight.
The car broke down.
I left it in the middle of the road.
Fuck. What was the problem?
I don't know.
It started making noises
and then
the engine stopped.
- I had to take a taxi.
- Why didn't you call me?
What would you have done?
Alice's book is great.
The stories are lovely.
Why don't you tell her so?
What did you do today?
Nothing.
We could do it in two days.
The lady said she'd like it
all done for next Saturday.
Yes, but I don't want
to do it wrong.
I've never done it before.
Does it take longer with wallpaper?
The living room is
more or less the size of Terzetti's.
- Listen, I have to tell you something.
- Tell me.
Luciano didn't come today
because he was hired
at the shipyards,
the Voltri shipyards.
- A job?
- Finally.
- Good for him.
- At least he has a secure job.
Well then,
it's just the two of us.
I wanted to tell you
that they hired me too.
I start Monday.
I'm really sorry, Michele.
- Seriously.
- It's better this way, better for you.
No problem at all, Vito.
So how is it going?
- Fine.
- How nice!
- Would you like a coffee?
- Why not?
I'll have it ready soon.
- Thanks, ma'am.
- You're welcome.
What the fuck am I doing?
Here they are!
You didn't need to come
all the way here.
Next time you can make a transfer
with the bank, as usual.
Okay. Goodbye.
- How are you?
- It's Michele, Dad.
I know you're Michele.
So how are you?
So-so.
Some issues at work.
I'm not doing
that great either.
By now it's the others
who tell me when I'm well.
I have to trust them.
I don't know what
I'm doing anymore, Dad.
It isn't just work.
Everything has become
so difficult and exhausting.
Elsa looks at me
but doesn't see me.
I'm like a ghost.
- Elsa?
- Yes, Elsa.
There she is, see her?
The almost white one,
with the long tail.
Do you see her?
That's Elsa.
Now she's coming to the center
and you can see her better.
Look.
The apartment needs tidying.
It's a big mess.
I ironed your shirt.
Come on get up, please.
It's late.
Michele!
Go there by taxi.
Is the car ready?
It's fucked. They wanted
1,600 euros to fix it, so I just left it.
Perfect.
- What's that?
- What do you think it is? It's the doorbell.
It's the first time I've heard it!
- Are you expecting someone?
- No.
- Yes?
- Good morning, I'm Bianca Carminati.
I'm looking for Mr. Oliveri.
He's my husband.
Isn't he feeling well?
Why? Yes.
He was working in my apartment,
but he disappeared two days ago.
The place is a mess, and my
granddaughter's communion is on Sunday.
I even have relatives
coming from Asiago!
Excuse me,
where is your husband?
Here, this is
the advance you gave me,
and this is for your trouble.
You'd better look
for someone else.
What are you doing?
You're dumping me like garbage?
What can I do in two days?
You're very rude.
I'll report you!
Don't you have
anything to tell me?
All right. Good luck
with your interview then.
Yes?
Hello?
# 10 seconds ago #
# I closed a contract
with Hong Kong. #
Congratulations!
I've been working on it
for eight months.
Eight months is a long time.
We must celebrate.
- Shall we go drink to that?
- But I haven't finished.
That's enough for tonight.
I give you permission.
Let's have a toast
and then I'll take you home.
Okay?
Okay.
- Where's your coat?
- Here.
- My coat's there.
- Yes.
I shouldn't?
- Hello.
What's that?
It squashes bottles.
- What for?
- To save space.
Didn't you go
to the interview this morning?
No.
- Are you going to keep on doing this?
- Why?
- Michele, this isn't right.
- What?
Nothing.
Even the bathtub's disgusting.
- You were the last to use it.
- I really don't think so.
You don't believe
anything I say anymore!
If I say that's what it is,
you'd better fucking believe it!
Will you stop yelling at me?
I'm out all day,
I come home dead tired. Do l...
Do you want me
to welcome you with applause?
- Asshole!
- Sure, you're the one who works.
You now support the family.
It's you now!
Have you looked at yourself?
You don't give a damn about anything!
The house is disgusting!
You don't make the slightest effort!
You don't even
go to interviews anymore!
Can I decide if it's worthwhile
going to an interview?
All you can do is lie
on the fucking couch and sleep!
- You're ridiculous.
- What do you think you are?
Can't you see
what you've become?
You're like an amoeba, spineless.
Do you want to hit me
like you did with Alice?
Fuck off.
Do you want me to hit you?
- Is that what you want?
- Let me go!
Nobody's forcing us
to stay together!
Couples separate for a lot less.
I feel your relief
when you leave the house.
And I stay here jerking off
like when I was 15!
But I don't think of you.
If I did, I'd lose my hard-on!
Good morning.
- Passable night?
- Yes, fine.
If you need the bathroom,
you'd better wait a minute.
Anyhow, I left you a clean towel.
Is Alice asleep?
Yes, she came home at 2:00.
She said we should've called her,
but I think we did the right thing not to.
Riki, thanks for not asking too many
questions. I appreciate the discretion.
I never liked poking
my nose in other people's shit.
I bought croissants,
but you'll need to make the coffee.
I have to go.
Okay, thanks.
Have a nice day.
If you happen to come this way again,
you're welcome.
- Bye.
Hi, Dad.
Is breakfast included?
Sure, bed and breakfast.
Not much fun
to come home dead tired
and find your asshole
of a father on the couch.
Did you fight?
Yes. Where are the cups?
Is it serious, Dad?
Yes.
Sit down,
I'll get the cups.
Where were you, in Sardinia?
No, in Corsica, near Ajaccio.
- Beautiful.
- Yes, it is.
Now tell me,
does he bring them every morning?
More or less. Why?
No, nothing.
He's nice.
Who would have thought, huh?
Nadia, hi. Forgive me.
I didn't call you.
I disappeared again,
but I'd be really glad
to see you.
Will you call me
when you can?
Bye.
Yes? Good morning.
Good morning, ma'am.
Your husband?
He isn't in.
- Did he find a job?
- No no no.
I'm sorry.
I'll come back tomorrow.
- For a second, I thought that...
- I wish.
You see, ma'am,
I've lived here for 10 years.
My washing machine's broken
and your husband is
the only person
I could ask a favor of.
If you want, I can do it.
No, don't worry about it.
Could I have the... back?
What? Oh, this? Sure.
Thank you.
- Goodbye, ma'am.
- Goodbye.
Dad, leave it!
Oh, I see.
- How pretty you are.
- Thanks.
I'm going to the accountant
this afternoon.
We have to make
some decisions.
They say we should invest
because of taxation problems.
I don't envy you.
Dad...
why don't you give us a hand?
I've never been
a genius at accounting.
Neither have we.
- Will you drive?
- Mm-hmm.
- Michele. Hi.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Hi, Adele.
- Hi.
Minestrone tonight too?
- I think so.
- Can't you smell it?
- Is he cooking some fried stuff tonight?
- I hope not.
- I need a hand.
- Here.
Dad, I'm sorry,
but we need to set the table.
It's a mess, right?
It's gratifying.
In this chaos,
I almost feel like a genius.
We really suck at this, huh?
I think you've had
some bad advice.
Why?
Before investing
without a reason,
you could do simpler things.
Anyway, I've made a little
financial plan for you.
I'm leaving it here for you.
We can discuss it later.
Of course, with pleasure.
Would you like to come
to the accountant's with us?
Yes, but not today.
Just one?
Now we'll see him again.
Where is he going?
- Hello?
- Did you call him?
Nicola...
Gagliano!
That was the name
of my second mate on the Victoria.
Nicola Gagliano.
That's fine. If that's okay,
I'll give them a call.
Yes, don't worry.
You too, thanks.
Goodbye for now.
Mr. Rinaldi called.
He wants you to call
him back. It's urgent.
Rinaldi, what a fucking bore!
Okay, I'll call him,
then if you like
we can go for a drink.
I can't this evening.
I have to go somewhere.
I'll take you if you like.
No, thanks. Really.
All right,
see you tomorrow then.
Tomorrow is Saturday.
You're right.
You're free to go then.
Thanks.
Have a nice evening.
Good evening.
Banchi Square.
We thought the color
had faded completely,
but actually
it's been left in sinopia.
It's as if he had to stop
at a certain point.
Maybe his illness.
Elsa, you're back!
- Professor.
- Good evening, Elsa.
Look! Isn't it marvelous?
Congratulations.
Wonderful intuition.
The brushwork
and the colors,
even the angel's face
has a lot in common
with his female figures.
But I think it's really the landscape
- that eliminates all doubt.
- It's the light, isn't it?
It's the light of your Boniforte.
Good job.
Elsa, we're going to have a drink,
and we've convinced
the professor to join us.
What are you doing?
I'd like to stay
for a moment.
- Are you going
to the usual bar?
- Come on, will you join us?
Will you lock up?
You have the keys, anyway.
- Yes.
- Enjoy this moment. You deserve it.
I'm really ashamed
of what happened yesterday.
Me too.
I thought things could go back
to the way they were,
but it's not true.
I realized it's a mistake to look back.
I don't even know
how we got where we are.
I thought nothing
could separate us.
It's not true.
I can't lose you, Elsa.
When I look ahead lately,
I only see endless strain,
an unbelievable strain.
We have to take it from here.
I'll come up with something.
I'll start from scratch...
I don't care...
but not without you.
Without you,
I'm going nowhere.
You arrived right
when I was thinking
that the only thing I wanted
was to have you here.
It is you, right?
It's me, Elsa.
Unfortunately, it's really me.
Me too.