Legend has it that it was written by the Dark Ones.
Necronomicon ex Mortis,
roughly translated, "Book of the Dead".
The book served as a passageway to the evil worlds beyond..
It was written long ago.
When the seas ran red with blood.
It was this blood that was used to ink the book.
In the year 1300 AD, the book disappeared.
So what's this place like?
Well it's a little run-down... but, uh, it's right up in the mountains.
Are you sure it's deserted?
Oh yeah... I think so.
So what do you think kid?
I love it Ash.
I feel funny about being here.
What if the people who own this place come home?
They're not gonna come back.
Even if they do we'll tell them the car
broke down or something like that.
With your car, they'd believe it.
Hey, what do you say we have
some champagne hey baby?
Sure.
After all, I'm a man and you're a woman,
at least last time I checked....
Hey! There's a... There's a tape recorder here.
See what's on it.
This is Professor Raymond Knowby,
Department of Ancient History, log entry number two.
I believe I have made a significant find in the Castle of Candar.
Having journeyed there with my wife Henrietta,
My daughter Annie and associate professor Ed Gecki
It was in the rear chamber of the castle
that we stumbled upon something remarkable.
Morturom Demonto, the "Book of the Dead".
My wife and I brought the book to this cabin where
I could study it undisturbed.
It was here that I began the translations.
The book speaks of a spiritual presence.,
A thing of evil that roams
the forests and the dark bowers of man's domain..
It is through the recitation of the book's passages...
that this dark spirit is given
license to possess the living.
Included here are the phonetic pronunciations of those passages.
"Cunda astratta montose
eargrets gutt
nos veratoos canda amantos canda".
It's gone. The sun's driven it away.
Yeah. For now.
Gotta blow out of here for now...
Join us.
Gotta, I gotta get a grip on myself..
How'd the expedition go?
Great. I found the pages of the Book of the Dead.
Yeah, I got your telegram. Thanks.
So what condition are they in?
Take a look.
They haven't aged a day in 3000 years.
Maybe longer.
When do we begin the translations?
Tonight. Is everything all set with my father?
Well, it should be but I haven't spoken with him in a week.
There's no phone in the cabin.
We'll take my car, it'll take us about
an hour to get there.
Annie you hinted in your telegram that your father was onto
something in the first part of his translations.
What has he found in the Book of the Dead?
Probably nothing. But just possibly, a doorway to another world?
Dance with me.
Hello lover.
Even now we have your darling Linda's soul.
She suffers in torment.
You're going down. Chainsaw.
Please Ash... please don't hurt me.
You swore- you swore that we'd always be together.
I love you.
Yah! Your lover is mine
and now she burns in hell
Oh yeah, alright... OK.
I'm fine... I'm fine.
I don't think so. We just cut up our girlfriend with a chainsaw.
Does that sound fine?
You bastards! You dirty bastards!
Give me back my hand!
Give me back my haaaaand!!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Is this the road to the Knowby cabin?
That's right. And you ain't going there.
And why not?
There must be another way in.
There's gotta be another road or something.
Sure ain't no road.
Why the hell do you want to go up there for anyway?
None of your business.
Hey! I just remembered.
Why, yeah... that's right. There is a trail.
You could uh, follow Bobby Joe and me.
Sounds alright to me.
But it'll cost ya.
How much?
Forty fi...
Hundred bucks.
Tell ya what, you take my bags and you got a deal.
Sure.
Ah. Ah. That's right. Who's laughing now?
Who's laughing now?
Jesus H. Christ... thought all she was talking about
were those two Goddamn little bags.
Here's your new home.
Son of a....
Gotcha didn't I you little sucker?!
Old double barrel here...
blow your butts to kingdom come. See if we don't...
You little bastard!
You gonna be alright honey?
I-I don't know. I-I think so.
You just sit still for a minute.
You know this son of a bitch?
No we thought her father was going to be here.
That's why we decided
Oh my God! Where are my parents?
What the hell did you do to them?
Annie, come here.
We'll throw him in there.
Crazy buck's gone blood seeking.
Wait.
I made a mistake.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
Damn right. Blackmail son of a bitch.
I hope you rot down there.
Oh shit!
I know it hurts baby, but everything's gonna be fine.
Now in about 5 minutes
I'm gonna go fetch the sheriff and bring him
Checked all the other rooms.
Folks aren't here. Maybe they never came.
But these are my father's things.
It's only been a few hours since I've translated
and spoken aloud the first of the demon resurrection
passages from the Book of the Dead.
Shhh... Listen up. This is my father's voice.
And now I fear that my wife has
become host to a Candarian Demon.
May God forgive me for what I have unleashed unto this earth.
Last night Henrietta tried to...
kill me.
It's now October 1st, 4:33 PM.
Henrietta is dead. I could not bring
myself to dismember her corpse.
But I dragged her down the steps...
and I buried her. I buried her in the cellar.
God help me,
I buried her in the earthen floor of the fruit cellar.
What the hell was that?
Somebody's down there with him.
No, can't be.
Let's get out of here.
Someone's in my fruit cellar.
Someone with a fresh soul!
Let me out! There's something down here! Ah!
Let him out!
It's a trick, I know it!
Let him out!!
Move it! Open those chains up!
Come to me.
Ah! Help! Help! Help me!
Come to sweet Henrietta. Ha ha ha.
Hurry!
Help! Help me please!
I'll swallow your soul.
Do something!
There's something out there.
That...
that witch in the cellar is only part of it.
It lives...
out in those woods, in the dark...
something...
something that's come back from the dead.
Plee! Please let's just get the hell out of here!
We're going baby. We're going to get on that trail
Nobody's going out that door, not till daylight.
Now you listen to me
Remember that song Annie?
I used to sing it to you when you were a baby.
Mother?
Unlock these chains. Quickly!
No.
You were born September 2nd, 1962.
I remember it well because it was snowing. so strange
it would be snowing in September.
That thing in the cellar is not my mother.
We are the things that were and shall be again.
Steps of the Book.
We want what is yours.
Life! Dead by dawn. Dead by dawn.
Dead by dawn. Dead by dawn.
Dead by dawn.
Let me out.
Thirsty son-of-a-bitch.
Where you going? Help us you filthy coward!
We live, we live still!
That's funny.
What?
That trail we came in here on?
It just ain't there no more.
Like, like the woods just swallowed her up.
It's so quiet.
Maybe something trying to force its way into our world.
Hell no. You're the curious one.
Hey. I'll go with you.
Shit. I told you there weren't nothing in here no how.
Holy Mother o' Mercy.
Father?
Annie.
There is a dark spirit here that wants to destroy you.
Your salvation lies there.
In the pages of the book.
Recite the passages.
Dispel the evil. Save my soul. And your own lives!
Jake. You're holding my hand too tight.
Baby, I ain't holding your hand.
Hey? Where's Bobby Joe?
Hey? Where the hell is she?
We gotta go out there and find her.
If she went out in those woods, you can forget about her.
What's wrong?
Felt like someone just walked over my grave.
What's that picture?
What is that?
In 1300 AD they called this man the, ah, hero from the sky.
He was prophesied to have destroyed the Evil.
Didn't do a very good job...  Can you find it?
Here it is, two passages.
Recitation of this first passage..
will make this dark spirit manifest itself in the flesh.
Why the hell would we want to do that?
Recitation of this second passage creates
a kind of rift in time and space.
And the physical manifestation of this
dark spirit can be forced back into the rift.
At least that's the best translation that I can
That's right. I'm running the show now.
We're going to go out there in
them woods and look for Bobby Joe.
Once we find her we're getting the hell out of here.
No you idiot! You'll kill us all.
She's dead by now.
Don't you understand?
With these pages, at least we have a chance.
Bunch of mumbo jumbo bullshit.
These pages don't mean squat.
Besides, now you ain't got no choice.
Now move!
Move.
Look. You're nuts.
I'll blow your fucken head off.
Hey. No trail. Where to now?
You'll get us all killed!
Shut up!
Leave him alone!
Get outta here...
Where are you, girl?
You're next. Annie!
I'm sorry!
Get me another room.
Get the axe.
We'll kill it when it comes back.
But first, pull this damn thing out of me!
I can't breathe, I can't breathe. Hurry!
I'm trying! I'm trying!
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Check outside the windows.
Check the windows, he's probably right out...
Ahhh! Help me!
Oh God! Ahhhhh!
No! No wait!
Listen to me! I'm alright now.
That thing is gone!
Damn it! I said I was alright!
Are you listening to me?
You hear what I'm saying?
I'm alright!
I'm alright.
OK, maybe you are. But for how long?
If we're going to beat this thing, we need those pages.
Then let's head down into that cellar and carve ourselves a witch.
Groovy.
Those pages are down there somewhere.
"Nos veratos alamemnon conda."
Let's go.
I'll swallow your soul. I'll swallow your soul.
Hey! I'll swallow your soul! I'll swallow your soul!
Swallow this.
I only completed the first of the passages
and that was to make the Evil a thing of the flesh!
Finish it!
There's still the second passage.
The one
the one to open the rift and send the Evil back!
Well start reciting it! Now!
Don't look Annie! Finish the passages!
Get rid of it!
No!!!
We've won. We've won. Victory is ours.
You did it kid.
By God... No!!!! For God's sake!
How do you stop it?
Slay the beast. It is a deadite!
Run! Back to the castle!
Hail he who has come from the skies
to deliver us from the terrors of the deadites!
Hail! Hail! Hail!
No! No!! No!!! No!!!!!!