If you are gonna help me
with haley´s record,
you could maybe
move into the house with me.
It´s a
business arrangement?
Of course.
Mouth: with me tonight is my new
color announcer, gigi silveri.
You really expect us
to practice in this dump?
Whitey: not only practice.
Till further notice,
you´re gonna
play all your games in here.
If you tell whitey
i have a heart condition,
i´m off the team.
If I don´t tell whitey,
you´re off the planet.
Brooke:
it was you, wasn´t it?
The dress I designed --
the one you made --
it got me
into rogue vogue.
Your clothes are good,
but if you´re afraid to go --
oh, no, i´m gonna go,
and i´m gonna win.
Nathan:
did you think about it --
having a baby
to stay together?
Let me see the pills.
I cannot believe
you still don´t believe me.
Here.
Take them.
I don´t need them anymore.
Your future as a basketball
player is totally secure.
Your future as my husband --
not so much.
You know, I thought about you
every day I was gone,
and you´re even prettier
than I remembered.
Keith Scott?
Put your hands behind your head.
What the hell is this?
You´re under arrest for the
attempted murder of Dan Scott.
♫ I don´t want to be anything ♫
♫ other than what i´ve been
trying to be lately ♫
♫ all I have to do
is think of me ♫
♫ and I have peace of mind ♫
♫ I don´t want to be anything ♫
♫ other than what i´ve been
trying to be lately ♫
♫ all I have to do
is think of me ♫
♫ and I have peace of mind ♫
♫ i´m tired
of looking ´round rooms ♫
♫ wondering what I gotta do ♫
♫ or who i´m supposed to be ♫
♫ I don´t want to be anything ♫
♫ other than me ♫
You´re next. Haley?
You´re next.
So, have you
given any thought
to which college
you´d like to attend?
Yeah, actually.
I´ve been looking at Stanford.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, you´re serious.
[ Clears throat ]
Well, Stanford may not be
too realistic for you, faily.
Haley.
What?
I think you just called me
"faily." My name´s Haley.
My mistake. I must have
thought that was your name
because you failed
every class.
I didn´t fail anything.
No? what about
your marriage?
Well [scoffs] that
is none of your business.
Then there was the hcm test.
You failed that, too.
No, I didn´t.
Oh, that´s right.
You failed
the friendship test
by letting Lucas play basketball
with a serious heart condition.
Such a shame.
[ Monitor beeping ]
Clear!
[ Flatline ]
Oh, he´s 86´ed, yo.
Just say,
"he´s dead," Tim.
You´re next.
Woman: Haley? Haley.
[ Gasps ]
You´re next.
So, have you
given any thought
to which college
you´d like to attend?
S-s-Stanford.
That´s a great school
for you.
[ Sighs ]
Are you okay? ´Cause you seem
a little sketchy.
Me? no, no.
Actually, i´m fine.
I just love sleeping
in jail cells.
You understand
that we have you on tape
buying a bottle of liquor
the day of the fire.
I-i-i´ve seen it.
It was stimulating.
Yeah.
We also know
that you bought a gun.
Oh, my god.
Was Dan shot?
Oh, wait. No, no, no.
It was a fire. Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
It´s gonna be fine.
You need to get to school.
I´ll call you
if I hear something.
Come on, mom. It´s Keith.
This is important.
Your future
is important.
Don´t you have a meeting with
your guidance counselor today
to talk about colleges?
Oh, you wouldn´t
want to miss that.
Keith didn´t go to college,
and look where he ended up.
What the hell is wrong with you?
He´s your brother.
Exactly. someone should have
told him that
before he tried
to light me on fire.
Keith had nothing
to do with that.
How would you know?
Were you there?
Lucas, go to school.
Don´t waste your breath
on him.
You wasted
more than that.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now, come on.
You don´t want to get hurt
before the big game tomorrow.
There´s gonna be
scouts there.
Oh, but then they´re there
to see Nathan, not you.
Well, got to run. Don´t want to
be late for the Keith show.
In today´s episode,
Keith Scott learns
if you play with fire,
you´re gonna get burned.
♫ duh duh da ♫
Sorry.
why am I here again?
I mean,
not that i´m not grateful
for the "get out of jail free"
card, but what´s the catch?
You´re here
so I can help you decide
which college
is best for you.
I doubt i´ll even go to college,
so you´re wasting your breath.
And you´re
wasting my time.
Why do you think
your brother
would accuse you
of trying to kill him?
Maybe he´s still mad at me
for sleeping with his wife.
Woman: is your wife gonna factor
into the college you pick?
That´s not really your business,
is it?
Anyway, colleges come to me.
I don´t go to them.
Then why´d you come back
to Tree Hill?
´Cause I live here.
Woman: and do you want
to stay close to home?
Probably.
I mean, I can´t really afford
to go to college out of state.
Man: well, you´re not going
anywhere until we sort this out.
Okay, okay.
Stop, all right?
I want to
talk to my brother.
I know he´s out there.
Come on, Danny!
Come on in!
Danny!
Ahh.
You ready to confess?
Yeah, okay. Okay.
I confess.
I bought
a bottle of liquor.
I was just so thirsty.
I´m sorry, Dan.
Can you forgive me?
You think this is funny?
Stop smiling,
you son of a bitch!
Hey, there´s no need to bring
mom into this, Danny.
Okay, that´s enough.
Wipe that dumb smile
off your face.
That´s enough.
Ugh!
Help. police.
Well, I guess I just don´t
really get the point of college.
The point
is to find something you love
and hopefully
make a career of it.
What makes you happy?
I don´t know.
Music, I guess.
But everyone loves your stuff.
You know that, right?
I just think this would be
a great opportunity for you.
Okay. we´ll talk later, then.
Musicians
can be so neurotic.
No, that was Brooke.
She´s got this
fashion-show thing coming up,
so she calls me every second
she has a new idea,
which is pretty much
every second.
I didn´t think i´d hear from her
again now that her and Lucas
have stopped this whole
nonexclusive crap.
Nonexclusive meaning?
Basically,
friends with benefits.
Friends with benefits?
Isn´t that
just sleeping around?
No. it´s like
being friends
with someone
you get to have sex with,
but you can still hook up
with other people, too.
Okay. so, you´re right.
It´s the same.
And what about you?
Do you have
any beneficial friends?
No.
I dated this guy Nathan
for a while,
but we were more benefits
than we were friends.
But we´re just friends --
no benefits -- now.
And then...
There was this other guy, but --
but he was more than that.
Were you in love
with him?
That´s the hard part.
Sex is easy.
But if you find someone
you´re in love with
who´s also your friend,
wouldn´t that be
the greatest benefit?
Well, that´s the fairy tale,
i guess.
Well, there´s nothing wrong
with fairy tales.
Everyone ends up
happily ever after.
When I was little,
my parents took us to California
so my sister
could look at colleges,
and Stanford
was just one of our stops,
and I was only 8,
but I just fell in love.
I´d never seen anything like it
growing up in Tree Hill --
all those different people
in one place,
and I just
thought to myself,
"wow, this must be
what the world is like.
This is where
i want to be."
And ever since then,
i´ve just wanted to go there.
Where does your husband
want to go?
Haley: hey, uh, this came
to the apartment for you.
I guess they think
you still live there.
Thanks.
2,798 miles --
that´s how far apart
our dream schools are.
Yeah.
Nathan, I said some things
the other night --
I said
some things, too.
I´m sorry.
Me too.
I guess we can add this
to the list of things
we should have talked about.
We can
talk about it now.
I didn´t realize
I was supposed to figure out
my entire future today.
You should at least
be thinking about it.
Trust me,
i´ve been thinking about it
ever since
i could shoot a basketball.
Look, mayor Scott,
the arrest was a favor,
but without anything solid,
i can´t hold him.
In fact, the only charges
i could bring
would be against you
for assaulting your brother.
Can I fire you?
No.
It´s good seeing you,
Danny.
Oh, uh,
could this visit take the place
of Christmas this year?
[ Sighs ]
Haley: Stanford is, like,
my dream school.
It´s where i´ve wanted to go
since I played pretend s.A.T.S.
Man, I forgot
how much of a nerd you were.
Oh, whatever, Rambo.
Rambo was cool!
Ha!
Oh, I don´t feel like
i´m picking a college
as much as I feel like
i´m picking a future.
Yeah, but didn´t you
kind of pick a future
when you married Nathan?
Watch it, mister.
Hey, by the way, you´re, um,
like, feeling all right
and everything, right?
Yeah, i´m fine. Why?
I just had this dream
that you had a heart attack.
And you´re buying
your medicine
and you don´t need to borrow
any money or anything, right?
Yes, i´m fine,
but thank you.
What´s up, boyfriend?
Faily?
And i´m never telling you
anything again ever.
Speaking of, though, what is the
deal with these meetings today?
College is like
a million years away.
Or 3,000 miles. Bye.
Okay, I don´t get it.
She just realized
that she and Nathan
want to go to college across
the country from each other.
They just
figured that out?
Isn´t that the sort of thing
couples talk about?
Yes. so...
What are your plans
after high school?
Hmm. well, I always figured
i´d marry a millionaire
and he´d whisk me away to his
private island in the Bahamas.
Where are you on that,
anyway?
How´s the fashion institute´s
basketball team?
Is there a good fashion program
at, like, basketball school?
Mouth,
you´re totally screwed.
Principal Turner
wants to see you.
I don´t think
i did anything wrong.
I mean,
did he say what he wants?
No, because
he didn´t actually send me.
I just need your help.
But I had an appointment
with the guidance counselor.
Why would you let some burnout
in a dead-end job
tell you
where to go to college?
I mean, college obviously
didn´t work for her.
Rachel,
that burnout´s my mom.
See? I can joke, too.
But seriously,
i need to get back.
Just catch the counselor on her
lunch hour at the soup kitchen.
I need your help.
Marvin McFadden?
Keith.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, i´m fine.
The Tree Hill jail
isn´t exactly attica.
You didn´t
have to wait for me.
We can´t let Dan
get away with this.
We should probably sue him or
call the news or maybe even --
go out?
The ravens are playing
tomorrow night,
and I was thinking that maybe
we should go together.
You´re asking me out
on a date?
Keith, Dan is trying
to convict you of murder.
I didn´t kill anyone.
Dan is just
trying to rattle me.
Besides, nothing would make me
happier than taking you out.
And nothing would make Dan
angrier than seeing me happy.
Well, okay, then.
I´d love to.
But, for the record, i´ll be
doing it for the first reason.
Okay.
The second reason
will just be a bonus.
So, you´re interested
in fashion design?
Yes, but i´m interested
in a lot of things.
Such as?
I´m student council
president,
captain of the cheerleaders,
founder of dwnoti,
and girlfriend of ravens´ star
shooting guard Lucas Scott.
And what are your plans
after high school?
After high school,
i have cheer practice.
5, 6, 7, 8.
Cross front, cross back,
turn around, and pop!
And pop!
Back it up.
Whoa! stop!
Halt! Cut!
Why is everybody
here early?
You´re like an hour late.
I don´t think so.
Unlike you, i´ve never
thought there was a 13:00.
Brooke, Rachel said you wanted
us here an hour early.
And where did you two
think I was this whole time?
Late, as usual.
Brooke, the classic´s
next month,
and we don´t
have a routine yet.
I figured since mouth
helped you out last year,
we could maybe come up with one
and surprise you,
so...surprise.
The only way
i´d be surprised right now
is if you were
actually wearing underwear.
I guess no surprises,
then.
Okay. I am the captain
of this squad.
It is my job to come up with
a routine for the tournament.
The tournament´s the same
weekend as rogue vogue.
You´ll be
in New York City.
That´s why you submitted
my fashion designs.
Surprise.
But i´m really hoping
to still play basketball....
I guess i´m not ready
to give it up.
Keith:
you know, in jail,
a shot like that would make you
somebody´s girlfriend.
Yeah, well, you´d know.
I was worried about you.
Are you okay?
Yeah, i´m fine.
Anyway, you´re a kid, Lucas.
You should worry
about kid stuff.
Oh, you mean like school,
money, mom,
college scholarships,
scouts?
Wow, it´s tough being a kid
these days.
Since when do you
worry about scouts?
Since I realized if I get
a basketball scholarship,
my mom
won´t have to worry.
She likes
to worry about you.
I don´t want her to.
College is expensive.
We´ll manage.
We always have.
What?
you said we.
I, um...
Asked your mom out on a date.
I hope that´s okay
with you.
I think it´s great.
What did she say?
Funny.
I guess you had to
ask the question.
My track record with your mom
is about as bad as the ravens´.
Aah!
So, do me a favor --
win tomorrow night.
I was gonna say "score,"
but I didn´t think that
was appropriate.
Oh, hi. Come on in.
Have you seen my friend mouth?
He looks just like you, only he
has a skank attached to his hip.
I´m sorry, Brooke.
I was trying to help all
the cheerleaders, including you.
Well, for the record,
when you´re helping Rachel,
you are not helping me.
I don´t think
she tried to set you up.
She said she had no idea
it was the same weekend
when she submitted
your designs.
And you believed her?
Mouth, she is lying, okay?
If you weren´t so busy trying
to see through her shirt,
you would see through
her b.S. -- She´s using you.
How?
I don´t know.
I am not a conniving bitch.
But I know that
if she´s being nice to you,
it is for a reason,
and not a good one.
If you want a new friend,
hang out with the raisin girl.
Her name is gigi.
Yes, gigi -- good.
Rachel -- bad.
So, I should stick with
my own kind.
I´m not saying that.
I just know how someone like her
sees someone like you.
Someone like me?
I get it. A hot girl would never
hang out with someone like me
unless
she wanted something.
No, mouth, wait.
Why? do you have no furniture
for me to move?
Woman: your parents
aren´t around?
No, but that´s not unusual
for Tree Hill.
We should have milk cartons
with missing parents on them.
It must be difficult
being alone.
I´m not alone.
I hate being alone.
I have my roommate
and my squad,
my friends,
my Peyton, my Lucas.
Lucas: hey. I didn´t know
what to get you,
so I got a little bit
of everything.
Is there a kick in the head
in there? That´s what I deserve.
[ Scoffs ]
what´s wrong?
Mouth came over earlier, and
i went all "mean girls" on him.
Wait a second.
You were mean to mouth?
Yeah, you know what?
There might be a kick
in the head here somewhere.
He´s gotten all buddy-buddy
with that escort wannabe Rachel,
who I found out only entered me
in rogue vogue
because it´s the same weekend
as the classic.
So do them both.
I can´t.
I need you to help me decide.
This is my last year to take
my squad to the classic and win,
but rogue vogue could be my only
chance at showing my designs.
You know what I would do
if I was you?
Hmm?
do them both.
You are not helping.
Okay, they´re
in different states,
but they´re during
different times of the weekend.
And I would still have to
be in two places at once.
I´m not supergirl.
I can´t --
I could fly.
Oh, my god.
This could totally work.
I could win two trophies
and keep one on my dresser
and shove the other one
up rachel´s --
hello, Peyton.
Oops, I mean Haley.
It´s hard to keep all of
nathan´s girlfriends straight.
You know, i´ll probably
call the next one you.
So, what are you
doing here?
Oh, just some official
mayor business.
Wouldn´t want
to bore you.
Oh, thanks.
How´s my new song doing,
anyway?
What are you
talking about?
The song
you´re recording.
Nathan´s paying Chris Keller
to work with you,
and since i´m paying
nathan´s allowance
for being such a good
little boy, it´s kind of mine.
Oh...
You didn´t know where
the money was coming from.
Don´t you and Nathan
talk about anything?
Yeah, mostly we talk about how
happy he is to be away from you.
You know, that´s not exactly
the thank you I was expecting
after dropping thousands
of dollars on your career.
I´ll see you in class.
Nathan...
Did you pay Chris
to help me with my music?
Good morning
to you, too.
I just ran into your dad.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Why didn´t you
tell me, Nathan?
I want us to be honest with
each other about everything.
So, what, every time I want
to do something nice for you,
I have to ask first?
It was very nice, but you, like,
totally went behind my back,
and it felt like something
Dan would do.
Do I have to change the locks
at school now?
I´m the mayor.
I have the keys to the city.
Besides, is that any way
to talk to your new teacher?
Principal Turner
asked me
to speak to your
political-science class.
You´re kidding.
I need to get away from my dad,
and basketball´s the way out.
The plan´s always been
high school and then Duke,
then the NBA.
Who came up
with this plan?
My dad.
Whoa, where are you going?
Are you just gonna skip class?
I´ve heard you speak, dad.
Waste of time.
Well, I mean, my birth mom´s
really the only one
that´s around right now,
and she didn´t go.
What did she do
after high school?
Drugs.
Well, you didn´t go to college,
and you´re doing just fine.
I´m a freelance writer
who lives paycheck to paycheck.
I´ve done okay,
but I could have done better.
You don´t want
to go to college?
Does that surprise you?
Actually, it does.
I´d just assumed you´d go.
Why?
Because you can.
I never understood people
who had the chance to go
and chose not to.
Well, I don´t
understand people
that waste four years
in school
when they could be out
living life.
What´s the hurry?
From what I hear,
college is fun.
I can see you majoring in art
or music or business.
Really? you see all that without
tarot cards or a ouija board?
What else do you see?
I see you being late
for cheerleading.
I guess
you really are psychic.
All right.
Well, how ´bout this?
Do you by any chance
see a name for this album?
Hopefully something better
than "this album."
I don´t know.
It´s kind of growing on me.
Okay. have fun.
Don´t benefit any friends,
and do good cheering.
Go, ravens.
I´m starting
to doubt my powers,
´cause I never would have
seen you as a cheerleader.
My mom
was a cheerleader.
I just want my mom to stop
worrying and enjoy life.
She deserves that much.
So, tonight´s
the big night.
Are you excited?
I mean, Keith is, like,
the most popular kid in school.
Don´t make fun of me.
I´m too nervous.
All right. Now...
How do I look?
Like my mom.
I´m serious.
You look great, ma.
You looked great
the last time you asked me
and the time
before that.
And what about
the time before that?
Oh, so-so.
Shouldn´t dating
get easier?
[ Doorbell rings ]
Oh, um...Okay.
Do you want me to have
a little talk with him --
make sure his intentions
are honorable?
I got it from here.
All right.
Um...Good luck at the game.
You will be joining us
for dinner afterwards?
I´ll be there.
Okay.
This is getting
pretty serious --
bringing him home
to meet the fam?
Enough!
Keith, you look...
You look...Too.
I, uh,
have a confession.
I was pretty nervous
about tonight.
Oh, yeah, me too.
I actually changed my shirt
three times.
I was gonna
change again,
and I realized
i only have three shirts.
Well, I like that one.
Thanks.
This is yours?
This is the car
i´ve always dreamed about,
which makes it perfect
for tonight.
What made you
finally decide to buy it?
Lately i´ve been less about
talking and more about doing.
Woman: so, why don´t you
like to talk about college?
´Cause it
freaks me out, okay?
I, uh --
i like high school.
I´m good at high school.
You know, I know who my friends
are and who my enemy is.
I´ve got this place down.
Rachel.
Question -- what do rogue vogue
and the classic have in common?
Answer? Brooke Davis.
Nice try, but i´m doing both.
How are you
gonna do that?
It´s called
"you´re an idiot."
One´s on Saturday,
one´s on Sunday,
and there´s a flight
smack-dab in the middle,
so you´re gonna
have to try harder
next time
you practice bitchcraft.
Won´t you just be
the busiest girl in ho business?
And you´ll
be taking a backseat,
but I guess
you´re used to that.
Keith: this gym´s
nearly as old as you are.
Yeah,
but I look better.
Hey, whitey.
Gonna win one
for us tonight?
Well, it depends. Are you
gonna stick around and watch?
Yeah, i´ll be here.
I bet you will.
Good to
have you home, Keith.
All I need now is a win
to make this night perfect.
Woman: your basketball career
could end just like that.
You need to think about
your education, too.
You don´t get it.
Without basketball,
i´m not gonna have an education.
I´m not gonna get into college
based on my grades.
Basketball´s all i´ve got.
This place
is disgusting.
I can actually see the germs
in the air.
Yeah, me too.
Nathan, good news.
What, i´m adopted?
David shea is here.
What?
If you want to play
for any basketball powerhouse
on the east coast, that´s
the scout you want to impress.
Seems all those phone calls
i made on your behalf paid off.
This has nothing
to do with you.
If he´s here,
it´s because of me.
You can´t own this one.
[ Buzzer sounds ]
All right, let´s bring it in!
Come on! Move it!
Move, move, move!
This is gigi silveri.
Now that the ravens
have stripped out of
their street clothes
and put on tight shorts
that caress their firm buttocks,
we´re ready
to get under way.
Mouth?
That was...Good.
All right, here´s the deal.
You want to go back
to playing in a gym that doesn´t
smell like moldy cheese?
Well, go out there
and win a game for a change!
All right, on 3.
1, 2, 3!
Win!
win! win!
Nathan! not tonight.
You have a seat.
What? why?
I understand you skipped
political science this morning.
Coach, my dad was there.
He knew I was skipping.
I didn´t.
You know the policy.
You miss school, you miss
the game -- no exceptions.
Dustin, you´re in.
No, no, coach.
There´s a big-time scout here.
I have to play tonight.
Nathan,
sit down --
now!
I don´t expect it to.
But if it can help me
get into a good college
and help my mom
at the same time,
i´m gonna throw everything
i have into it.
Defense! defense!
Defense!
♫ dapper Dan
just lost his mind ♫
♫ hey, now ♫
♫ oh, no ♫
♫ what will he do? ♫
Piece of advice for you,
gramps --
most coaches
play their leading scorers.
It kind of helps them,
you know, win.
Wow. the mayor´s
talking to me.
What an honor.
♫ oh, no ♫
♫ what are we gonna do now? ♫
♫ oh, no,
what are we gonna do? ♫
[ Buzzer sounds ]
And there´s the end
of the first half.
The ravens trail
in a close one, 37-34.
We´ll be back
in a few minutes
with the start
of the second half.
Can I talk to you,
coach?
Not if it´s about your brother,
Ferris Bueller.
The only reason Nathan skipped
class was because of Dan,
and the only way
to get him away from Dan
is to let the scouts
see him play.
It´s not your place
to defend him.
Yes, it is. You made me
co-captain, didn´t you?
Well, he´s my teammate,
and the team needs him.
I appreciate your concern
for your teammate,
but rules are rules,
and you´re gonna have to find
a way to win without him.
Funny
running into you here.
Am i
in the right bathroom?
Mouth, i´m really, really,
really sorry.
Okay?
i didn´t mean to hurt you.
I just meant
a guy like you is...
One of
my very best friends,
and I was just
trying to protect you
from one of
my very unbest friends.
It´s okay, Brooke.
Can I make it up to you?
Hang out after the game?
I never thought i´d be
propositioned in a men´s room --
and like it, anyway.
Is that a yes?
Well...
i kind of have plans.
With Rachel.
I´d invite you, but --
it´s okay.
Be careful, mouth.
Dude, mouth,
nice work.
David shea.
Mayor Dan Scott,
nathan´s father.
Oh, I was looking forward
to seeing your son play.
Who wasn´t?
Listen, David,
the truth is,
coach durham
has a personal issue with me.
Unfortunately,
he´s punishing Nathan for it.
It´s sad, really.
Well, Lucas
is playing well.
Oh,
that´s even sadder.
Keith: were you
talking about Lucas?
´Cause i´m, uh, Keith,
lucas´ uncle.
He´s having
quite a night.
Yeah. he´s
a really good kid,
and he´s got
great grades, too.
That´s nice to hear.
Well, uh,
i´ve got to get back inside.
It´s nice
to meet you two.
You too.
Ohh.
You both
could do better.
God knows
i´ve done worse.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, Keith...
I wouldn´t leave town
if I were you.
I´m not going anywhere, Danny.
I wouldn´t dream of it.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Haley:
i-i feel like I can´t win.
I mean,
do I go on without him?
Do I beg him to come with me,
follow him wherever he goes?
I don´t think you ever realize
how much you love something
until you have to give it up.
What is that boy on?
Or not on.
Announcer: okay, time winding
down in the fourth quarter.
The ravens need a basket.
Lucas Scott
drives into the Lane.
He puts the shot up and scores,
and the ravens are down by 1 --
11 seconds left in the game.
Move, move, move, move!
All right, now,
i want you guys
to take a good look
around you.
Take a good, hard look,
because once in a while,
you have to ask yourself
how you got to this place --
0-2 playing in
this crummy sweatbox of a gym.
Well, i´ll tell you
how you got there.
You got there by playing
selfishly and losing.
But for
the next 9 seconds,
if you change the first thing,
you´ll change the second.
All right, let´s go.
1, 2, 3...
Ravens!
ravens! ravens!
Woman:
did your father go to Duke?
No.
But i´m better than him.
Lucas.
The dead spot -- Fleming
has no left, all right?
He´ll go to his right, so if you
force him to the dead spot,
you´ll be able
to pick his pocket.
♫ too much ♫
♫ hope ♫
♫ too soon ♫
♫ love ♫
♫ to see ♫
♫ it through ♫
♫ faith ♫
♫ look back ♫
♫ hope ♫
♫ at your life ♫
♫ love ♫
♫ with some kind ♫
♫ of pride ♫
♫ faith ♫
♫ too much ♫
♫ hope ♫
♫ too soon ♫
♫ love ♫
♫ to see ♫
♫ it through ♫
♫ faith ♫
♫ look back ♫
♫ at your life ♫
Lucas: I never would have
joined the basketball team
if it wasn´t for
my uncle Keith.
He wanted me
to be a part of something,
to feel like I belong.
♫ if I ever ♫
♫ let you
do-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-o-wn ♫
♫ would you ever feel... ♫
Woman: it sounds like
he really cares about you.
Yeah, he´s like
a father to me.
♫ faith ♫
Mmm.
You keep playing like that
and you might have a chance
with the captain
of the cheerleaders.
Really?
she say something?
Yeah. she said this.
Wow.
You coming over
tonight?
I don´t know. I´m gonna have
dinner with Keith and my mom.
So, how ´bout
after that?
You don´t want to hang around
and be a third wheel.
What if they
want to get freaky?
That´s my mom -- not a visual
i want to have in my head.
So, how ´bout you come over,
and i´ll give you a better one?
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Have fun
with your family.
You okay?
Yeah.
I´m just worried
about Lucas.
I´m sorry
you didn´t get to play today.
I know you wanted
to impress that scout.
Why? you don´t think
he was impressed
with my
bench-sitting skills?
[ Sighs ]
Haley...i´m sorry.
It´s just...If I tell you
not to go to Stanford,
i´m telling you not
to follow your dreams -- again.
If I tell you to go, i´m saying
i don´t want to be with you.
So, what do you
want me to say?
Say you love me.
Of course I love you.
Shea: Scott!
Dave shea.
You played
a great game today.
Lucas: thanks.
I had a lot of help.
You know, you should meet
my brother, though.
Uh...hey, Nathan!
How you doing?
All right.
Good to meet you.
The truth is, I don´t really
like to think about college...
´Cause that means
high school´s over.
After graduation, everyone will
probably go play basketball
or sing
or start record labels.
And i´ll have to
start all over...
Alone.
I´m sure i´ll be fine.
But, like I said,
i don´t like to think about it.
♫ I could hold you in my arms ♫
Lucas: at the end of the day,
I just want to be with
my family and friends.
I want to play basketball,
and I want to go to college.
That´s not too much to ask,
is it?
It´s just hard
because the game´s
the only thing
that ever mattered to me...
Till Haley came along.
♫ I could hold you forever ♫
Coach...
I wanted to talk to you
about not playing me tonight.
I´m not having
this conversation again.
It was
the right thing to do.
Well, that was a good tip
you gave to Lucas.
It may have
won us the game.
Tonight you put the team
ahead of yourself.
That´s what
a true leader does,
and that´s something
your father never learned.
And don´t worry
about that scout.
I´ll see he comes back.
You´ll get your shot.
Thanks, coach, but, uh...
I was hoping maybe you could
call somebody at Stanford.
All right,
i´ll make a call.
It´s just hard
because before I was married,
I thought Stanford
was my future.
But all those different faces
i remember,
all those different people...
None of them are Nathan.
♫ and I could hold you
in my arms ♫
Hey.
Hi.
how was the game?
Yeah, it was okay.
It wasn´t exciting watching
the ravens get their first win?
I was there.
Well, why didn´t you
come say hi?
Oh, I just wanted
to watch you do your thing.
Oh.
you were great.
Yeah, I can go pom-to-pom
with the cheeriest.
I´m serious, Peyton.
You´re smart, you´re funny,
you´re beautiful,
and what I can see, there´s
nothing that you´re not good at.
You want something?
Except taking compliments,
apparently.
No, i´m sorry.
I just --
i´m not used to it.
As I watched you tonight,
i thought to myself,
"this girl has so much
to offer the world.
If only
she could see it."
Are you sure
you´re okay?
Yeah, i´m fine.
I, um...
I came up with
a possible album title
and took a shot
at the cover art.
What do you think?
"Friends with benefit."
I love it.
So, I think
i want to study art and music...
And maybe business.
Any suggestions?
♫ I could hold on ♫
♫ forever ♫
♫ and I could hold you
in my arms ♫
♫ ohh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♫
♫ I could hold on ♫
♫ forever ♫
I hope
you got your pants on.
Go home, Danny.
This isn´t your life.