Who are you looking for?
My mother.
Here... the good stuff.
Hello.
Come in.
This is your sister.
Hug each other.
Go pour some drink for the men!
There's no room for you
to stay here. lt's not possible.
No problem... no problem at all.
ls my father's hut still standing?
lt is.
How long are you planning to stay?
For good.
Give me a shot.
l don't have any money.
This needs to be filled up.
With what?
Brandy.
You're cold out there, aren't you?
What kind of brandy? Does it matter?
No.
Give me a shot.
I'II pay for everything tomorrow...
I'II give you a fish... this big!
Give me a shot.
l'll pay for it.
l'll pay for everything.
Give me a shot.
Look, money! l'll buy the whole bar.
Look, you see this money?
l'll buy the whole bar.
Give me another shot for this money.
- l only have big notes.
- That's fine.
Later, then.
Thanks.
See you.
Wait! Be careful,
the brandy is strong!
He's mine.
How did he get here?
l don't know.
Our mother's lover hid him.
Hey...
...come on.
Give me your plate.
You're not eating?
Not now.
Once, l didn't eat for a year.
Why?
l wasn't hungry.
But you're a good cook.
Thanks.
Are you married?
No.
And children?
Where have you been?
ls it any of your business?
No, of course not.
What do you need timber for?
l just need it.
This is very expensive timber.
l've already made my selection.
ls this enough?
lt's enough.
You're pretty loaded.
You don't come home.
Your mother and l can't sleep.
But who cares right?
You're fine, right?
You're a grown-up.
lf you were my daughter,
l'd hit you.
Did she sleep at your place?
You talked her into it, didn't you?
Well, l'll deliver the timber...
...if the permit comes.
lt'll take a few months.
lt will be safe here,
no one will steal it.
Don't count on any other boat...
...or you can go back
to where you came from
A drink?
A beer, please.
Pour some for me, too.
You need a permit
to transport timber.
He's building a house.
So, you just do whatever you like?
You need a permit
for the house as well.
Don't tidy up around here!
Get out!
You're not going anywhere!
Let her go.
She's your daughter.
Continue.
Can l borrow your sweater?
Do you want me to make a fire?
No. lt's colder when it dies out.
That's not true.
That's what Dad told me.
You're gonna stay up?
Yes.
What's this silver cup?
l don't want to talk about it.
Good night, then.
Wake up.
Will you hold it?
Has your hair always been that long?
l don't know.
lt's in your eyes.
You have a handsome face,
you should fix it.
Let's pull it closer.
Wait! Hold on a moment.
This way.
Hold on for a little moment.
- Shall l stand on it?
- Ha?
Shall l stand on it?
No need.
Then give me a hammer.
Here you are.
- And a nail.
Hi.
Hello.
Come.
Come my dear, put this on.
The old drunk died.
She shouldn't be late.
We had to make a damn
big detour because of you.
ls the palace coming along?
lt's getting there.
l have to go.
l won't be gone long.
We're leaving.
You are such a stupid little girl.
Where are you going, huh?
She's leaving, don't you see?
- You're letting her go?
- She's all packed. She's leaving.
- To her brother.
- She's a complete idiot.
You can't talk sense to her.
She's leaving.
- To her brother, is she?
- To her brother, so what?
- They're going to live together?
- They're brother and sister.
- And you think it's appropriate?
- Yes, l do.
- You do? - Stay out of this,
she's my daughter.
Will you wash yourself
in front of him?
How do you think they'll sleep...
like brother and sister?
Stop it!
Like pigs!
You're not going anywhere!
Come back.
Hurry up, l don't want to
spend the summer here!
Unload everything.
l brought the things
my niece asked for...
nets, fuel, axe, saw, hammer.
lt's gonna be a nice, big house.
How will you cover it?
l don't know yet.
Can you do it alone?
Will you pulley it?
Will all these be windows?
Cover this area well,
the sea breeze will come in here.
And where is my niece?
- She's sick. She's sleeping.
- Has she been sick long?
- A few days now.
- What's wrong with her?
l don't know much about
these things.
Why didn't you let me know?
- She didn't want me to.
- You'll be needing me.
Move it! What are you waiting for?
You want me to do it, don't you?
So many damn frogs. They seem to
have flourished this year.
There weren't so many last year.
- Thanks for the brandy.
- You'll find it useful.
- Thanks for the net, too.
- You'll find that useful too.
Cast off! What are you waiting for?
Let's get out of here!
You're good at this.
When it's needed.
At the zoo, where l used to work
a girl came...
...she was thrown out of the house
because she got pregnant.
l had to nurse her.
The baby was stillborn.
But she disappeared.
And l haven't seen her since.
And the silver cup?
- lt's hers.
No more.
Can you go? l want to sleep.
l'm hungry.
Here.
You're not eating?
We only have one.
Thanks.
Do you want half?
No, you eat it.
Will we sleep here tonight?
You'll catch a cold.
What?
Do you know them?
- Yes.
Push a bit more. Come on, push.
Get up there now.
Careful, careful, a little more.
Hold it!
Take it slowly.
Hand me some nails.
- You like it? - Yeah, it's gonna be
alright. Thanks.
ls your sister going
to live with you?
Sure, there's nothing
wrong with that.
Many people won't like it, you know.
l'll go check the nets.
- Hurry.
Wipe the tables.
Are you celebrating?
What are you celebrating?
Have you moved in already?
lt's not ready yet.
We caught a lot of fish.
l'd like to invite you for dinner.
Son, you know
we won't go over there.
You understand that, don't you?
Can you fill these up, anyway?
Many people came.
- Yeah.
Help me.
You are a good wife!
Nice house.
ls he building it for you?
l help him out.
- With what?
- Building.
- Really? And you will live here?
Yes.
lt's gonna be nice, right?
- Do you like being with him?
- Yes.
Yes?
- Aha.
- Give her some drink.
- l don't want any.
Yes you do. Drink!
- No, l don't.
Here.
- What, you don't want any?
- No, l don't.
- A minute ago you did!
- l'm not thirsty.
No? Give her some drink!
Drink!
- Drink! What now?
Why aren't you drinking? The poor
man's drink isn't good enough?
- And his food? Do you want to eat?
- No.
Eat with us.
Give her your watermelon!
Hold it!
Hold it already!
Hold it, and eat!
Pour some drink in it!
Eat!
- l'm not hungry.
- l don't want to.
No?
Eat up!
You don't want it?
The poor man's food
isn't good enough, either?
No drink, no food?
Shove it down!
We brought it for you!
You want to offend us?
Eat that melon!
Eat up!
ls it tasty? Say it's tasty!
Eat up! Eat up! Eat up!
Say you're a whore!
Say that you're a whore!
Eat, and say you're a whore!
Eat up! Eat up!
Sober up, whore!
No!
Leave me aIone!
Don't let him by.
What do you want? Go back.
Knife him!