DESERT FLOWER
Waris!
Old Man!
Mom says, we have to move on.
Her name is Fattuma. - You can't
call a sheep like Allah's daughter.
Says who?
Waris,
I don't want anything to separate us.
I'll never leave you alone!
Promise!
LONDON, YEARS LATER
I have nowhere else to go!
I can't go back to Somalia!
Aren't you ashamed?
Showing this white man your body.
Our tradition is of no concern to them.
If you change what you are,
then you are betraying your parents,
your people and your heritage.
Does your mother know what you are
about to do? Shame on you!
Mommy, I am bleeding down there.
Good, it means
you are a woman now!
It's terribly painful.
All pain will pass.
Waris, this is Galool Mohammed.
Come closer my dear, come closer.
Do you like my watch?
You will marry him
to be his fourth wife.
I arranged the wedding for tomorrow.
Mom, I will not marry him!
Galool Mohammed paid a lot for you.
You can't say no.
Where are you going?
, To grandmother.
Mogadishu! It's far away!
I come with you!
No! They need you here, little brother!
Don't worry!
In the city I earn lots of money
and then I come back to get you!
Mommy.
Mogadishu?
Yes. Hurry up.
Shut up!
Mommy!
I said shut up!
Where is the mosque?
Over there.
Mother, see what comes of
living with goats and sheep!
We can't afford to keep her.
She has to go back home!
A girl who dares the long journey
through the desert has a good reason.
She blamed our family!
- Enough! Go back to work!
A miracle you survived!
It was Allah's will.
You have the same lips as your mother.
I always called her Afyareh.
Grandma, why have we never seen you?
Because your mother ran away
through the desert to marry your father.
A man we did not approve
because he was nothing but a nomad.
I wonder if it made her happy.
All that pain must be worth something.