Previously on "Designated Survivor"...
America's favorite
vice presidential candidate
and the CIA's most wanted mercenary
know each other.
I'm working a lead that could
prove damning to Peter MacLeish.
Congresswoman Hookstraten
just called for an extended recess.
She's delaying MacLeish's hearing.
Someone inside the U.S. government
handed over the
blueprints to Majid Nassar
for the Capitol bombing.
There's a traitor among us.
Special Agent Hannah Wells
seemed to be a bit obsessed with me.
I just hope she isn't trying
to convince the speaker
of any conspiracy theory.
I found the evidence I was looking for.
I'll explain everything when I get there.
My God, are you okay?
Can you hear me?
Look, you've been in an accident,
but help is on the way.
Just try and sit still, okay?
And don't move your neck.
You're gonna be fine.
Madam Speaker, I know
you're waiting for someone,
but the entire country is waiting for us.
We can't delay this vote any longer.
Peter MacLeish is a hero.
Who my witness claims
to have damning evidence against.
We owe it to our constituents
to find out what that is.
Damn it. Pick up.
It's me.
I lost her.
Aah!
Tom, what is this?
It's a blueprint.
A blueprint?
A guide for how to blow
up the Capitol building.
- Where did it come from?
- Us.
The Department of Defense.
Apparently after 9/11,
the Pentagon did a threat assessment
on all key government buildings
to show us where our weaknesses were.
A-And so you're thinking what?
I think someone inside our government
gave that blueprint to Al-Sakar
to blow up the Capitol.
Who else knows about this?
Just you and Mike.
Tom, you need to call in someone
from Homeland Security or the FBI.
No, no, we can't call anyone
until we know exactly what this is.
You're scaring me right now.
You remember the first night
we were here in the Rose Garden?
You asked me if I thought
we were a target.
I said I didn't know.
But now...
...I think you need to take the kids
and leave until we know it's safe.
Take them where?
Where's "safe"?
- I don't know.
- But that's my point.
How do we run if we don't
know who we're running from?
Mike's bringing in
the man who wrote the file, Dr. Enright.
Maybe he's got some answers for us.
But until then,
we cannot trust anyone.
Okay, time's up.
If you don't join us inside immediately,
I will tell the public
that you blocked Peter
MacLeish's appointment
so you would be next in
line for the presidency.
Reconvene the committee.
Hannah?!
- What happened?
- You can't let them find me.
Oh, my God, you're bleeding!
You need help!
Chuck, you can't call anyone.
I have to get you to the hospital.
You need a-a doctor.
You... Hannah?
Hannah!
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Now that the House Judiciary Committee
has given the nominee the green light,
the full House will convene
for a late-night vote
that many expect will
make Peter MacLeish
the next Vice President
of the United States.
Congratulations.
Ooh. To Peter MacLeish.
- To the new Vice President.
- Hear, hear.
What's up, Spring Break?
Oh, come on.
You know, if you had
60 news-hungry journalists
clamoring for information
about Nassar's murder,
you'd be thirsty, too.
Eh, maybe the MacLeish confirmation
will keep them off your
back for a news cycle.
Yeah.
The only thing that's
gonna keep them off my back
is an answer,
which, as I remind you, we don't have.
Yeah.
Rumor is MacLeish
is bringing a bunch of his
House staffers with him.
You guys know any of them?
Yeah, I used to play
soccer every Tuesday night
with his Coms director.
That guy's sharp as a marble.
I once shared a summer
house in Dewey Beach
with his legislative assistants.
I mean, we were only 19,
but they seemed on top of it.
19?
Yes, and I will need plenty more of these
before you get any of those stories.
All right, I'm gonna go meet the
speech writers on New Street.
You guys are welcomto join.
Nah, we're good where we are, Seth.
- Thank you.
- All right. See you tomorrow.
- Have a good night.
- Get home safe.
...will be his wife, Beth,
and their two daughters.
Can you believe
everything that's happened?
It's been a roller coaster, for sure.
You know, I have to admit,
when I first got here,
I thought that you were
gonna do everything you could
to get me out of the White House,
not be the reason I'm still here.
Well, I have to admit,
when you first got here,
I didn't think you could handle it.
Yeah, you called me a minor leaguer.
Yeah, well, I was wrong.
If anything, I'm learning from you.
Mr. President, Dr. Alan Enright.
Dr. Enright, please.
I need you to verify for
me that this is your work.
I think you know that it is.
I think that's why I'm here, Mr. President,
but I had nothing to do with
what happened at the Capitol.
I wrote this file to
prevent what happened,
not to cause it.
Even if that's true, you had to realize
that someone used your work
to plan and carry out the bombing.
They followed it to the letter.
Why didn't you come forward?
I close my eyes.
I can see the building fall.
The cast iron melting,
the marble crumble.
Whoever did this,
we're talking about a conspiracy
of unparalleled proportions.
I was scared, Mr. President.
Okay.
Doctor, I'm gonna need you to give me
every single name
that had access to this file.
I put an ORCON
classification on this file,
which means the number of
people who saw it is limited.
And then I sent it to
the DOD security team.
They all died in the Capitol.
I also sent it to the head of NORCOM.
You sent the file to General Grady?
I wrote this file two
years and six months ago.
General Grady was not
the head of NORCOM then.
Who was?
The general you fired.
Harris Cochrane.
...Met MacLeish properly
with the House Judiciary Committee.
Peter MacLeish has been named
the Miracle on the Potomac,
and this return to the capital
will hopefully redefine
the public's association with...
With a final tally of 424-9,
Congressman MacLeish
was confirmed by the
House of Representatives
in a historic vote late last night.
Meanwhile, organizers
are working double time
to prepare for...
Hi.
Hey.
Uh, hey.
You okay?
How you feeling?
Better.
Yeah, thanks to you.
Easy.
Hey, Chuck. Did you glue my wound?
Yeah.
Where did you learn to do that?
YouTube.
House confirmed him.
They're swearing him in this afternoon.
Peter MacLeish's confirmation
received no opposition from
the newly appointed...
Whoever made sure MacLeish survived
wanted him as VP for a reason,
so we have less than eight hours
- to make sure that doesn't happen.
- Okay, look,
I know this isn't what
you're gonna want to hear,
but...
...Someone tried to kill you,
Atwood's in prison,
Foerstel has me on suspension.
- Maybe it's time we...
- What?
- Quit?
- Hannah.
You almost died last night.
I literally had to scrub
your blood off of my hands.
What else do they need to do to us?
Chuck, why did you join the FBI?
To help people.
I joined to piss my father off.
He's a top surgeon in Chicago,
and he wanted me
to follow in his footsteps.
Practically held me at gunpoint
and took me to Johns Hopkins.
So I went.
And, uh, halfway
through grad school,
I walked out, jumped on a train,
went to D.C., and signed up for the FBI.
I wanted to help, too.
I just wanted to do it in my own way.
It's not their job to stop.
It's our job to stop them.
And I'm scared, too.
But if we quit, they win, and then...
everyone who lost someone that day...
they'll never know peace.
Nice try.
You've never been scared in your life.
Fine. I'm in. What's the next step?
- Get back in touch with Hookstraten?
- No.
I told her I had evidence on MacLeish,
- and someone tries to kill me.
- Right.
And they took all my evidence.
The evidence I got from the
woman who's been calling me.
No, I already told you
I can't trace the call from her again,
and even if I could,
I'm shut out of my office.
Then you'd better get creative
'cause it's the only lead we got.
- Did anyone see you bring him in?
- No, sir.
I kept him off Waves and brought
him in through the East Wing.
It was still early, so it wasn't a problem.
Okay, good.
Thank you, Mike.
It's different in here when it's quiet.
On the contrary.
This is what this room is usually like.
More calm than storm.
General, I need you to look at this.
Mike?
This looks like a re-enactment
of the Capitol bombing.
Well, it's not.
General, this is file 12-80C,
a threat assessment
created by the Pentagon
2 1/2 years before the bombing.
Mr. President, I have
never seen this before.
I find that highly unlikely.
This file was given an
ORCON classification.
I can count on my hand
the number of people that have seen it.
Your name is the only one on the list
that survived the bombing.
This was sent to me,
but I never had
the opportunity to read it.
That file was reclassified
by the Secretary of Defense
and recalled electronically
from my computer
before I could access it.
And you expect me to believe
that you just remembered that?
A file taken from my hand
by the Secretary of Defense
at a moment's notice?
A lieutenant general being told
he's not cleared to read something?
Never happened before, not to me.
What would be the circumstances
that would cause the Secretary of Defense
- to reclassify a document like that?
- I don't know,
but it's not something
he could do unilaterally.
He must've been given orders.
By who?
There's a chain of command.
Only one place the Sec
Def gets his orders from.
The White House.
General, you'll be detained
- until we can verify your story.
- I understand.
Mr. President.
You have a serious problem.
And while you may not ask for my help,
it's here if you want it, sir.
- Hey, Emily.
- Hey.
So, I was thinking,
now that MacLeish is confirmed,
we should start scheduling
committee hearings right away
to push the president's
cabinet nominees through.
That's a great idea.
We should get some Leg Affairs
folks to start prepping.
I'll get on it.
Hey, listen. About last night...
You mean when you kissed me?
You don't have to be weird about it.
Well, what if I want
to be weird about it?
Anyway, there's an Elvis impersonator
later tonight at the Nine Thirty club.
You want to go?
How did you know I like Elvis?
Well, opposition research
comes in handy sometimes.
Seth told you?
Seth told me.
I'm in.
All right.
The president wants to see me.
I didn't get a message.
Well, then it can't be
anything too important.
Yeah.
What I'm about to tell you
has to stay in this room.
- Do you understand?
- Of course.
Yesterday I received a
highly classified DOD file
detailing how to blow up the Capitol.
I believe it's what Al-Sakar used
to plan and carry out the attack.
I also think the file was given to them
by someone in Richmond's administration.
That's why I had to bring you in on this.
Not only do I trust you implicitly,
you weren't here when the
file was being circulated.
Who was?
This is what I managed
to put together so far.
- Aaron's on this list.
- I know.
I had to put down everyone's name
who had security clearance
that would allow them
to know the file even existed.
Emily, I think there's a
traitor in the White House,
and I need you to help
me find out who it is.
Yeah, Shelly.
Nassar's been dead for six days.
When can we expect an answer?
As I said before, Shelly,
I still don't have any
information about this.
Come on, guys, who's gonna ask me
about the swearing-in ceremony?
Over here. Seth. Seth.
Natalie.
About the decision
to hold the swearing-in
at the Capitol site...
How exactly was that reached?
Thank you, Natalie.
So, since Thomas Jefferson's
inauguration in 1800,
swearing-in ceremonies have
been held at the Capitol,
and the president felt
it was both symbolic and necessary
to continue with that tradition, all right?
That's actually all I have right now.
I am gonna be calling you back in,
in a few hours.
Thank you.
Have OP send us an updated list
of who they've invited to the swearing-in.
Seth.
A word?
Thanks, guys. I'll catch up to you.
Lisa. Hey.
You didn't call on me once.
Oh, sorry. I didn't see you.
I couldn't have been more clear
if I had one of those light sticks
they use to direct airplanes.
Now, if this is about you
holding a grudge about
the Leo Kirkman story...
Look, there's limited time.
You know, I can't get
to everyone's question,
but if you have
something that's pressing,
you can always send me an e-mail
or reach out to one of the
deputies in my office.
Seth.
Okay, I get it.
I betrayed your trust.
And I'm sorry.
But it's my job to ask questions
and your job to answer them.
The president can forgive me.
Why can't you?
Emily.
Hey. I was looking all over for you.
I thought you were gonna sit in on that
legislative affairs meeting with me.
Oh, sorry.
I got tied up.
So, what did the president
want to see you about?
Nothing.
Uh, he just... he wanted
me to take another look
at Bruce Rangell for HUD Secretary.
That one's obviously important
for him, so... Yeah.
- Hey, so, tonight,
pick you up here... -45?
Um...
Look, I think I'm gonna
be pretty swamped here,
so I'm gonna have to take a rain check.
I'm sorry.
Okay. All right.
Rain check.
Em... Emily, listen, you... you don't...
You don't regret last night, do you?
No, I just can't do it tonight.
Okay.
Okay, signaling system 7... SS-7.
Lets every cellphone
tower talk to each other
so your phone works
anywhere in the world.
How does that help us?
If I can get in,
we can connect the dots from your cell
back to the one that mystery
woman called you from.
Got it. I'm in.
- Good job, Chuck.
- Don't thank me yet.
I still got to backtrack the
number that called your cell.
- Damn it.
- What?
Network picked up the intrusion.
It's a race to see what happens first...
I track your mystery caller's phone,
or they track us.
Come on. Come on.
Got it.
Looks like the call to your cell
- came from a burner phone.
- Purchased from where?
A convenience store in Dupont Circle.
- Speaker Hookstraten's here, sir.
- Thank you, Wyatt.
You wanted to speak
with me, Mr. President?
Yes, Madam Speaker.
I was told that you had
information on Congressman MacLeish
that you wanted to
share with the committee.
I'm sorry, but I need
to know what that was.
Six weeks ago, an FBI
agent approached me.
She wanted access to the
blueprints of the Capitol.
Yesterday, she told me
she had evidence against Peter MacLeish.
And then she never showed up.
She... What was the agent's name?
Hannah Wells.
Congressman MacLeish told me...
What did he say, exactly?
He thought that
she was obsessed with him,
that her investigation had
somehow turned personal.
Did she come across that way to you?
No, sir, not at all.
Do you know where she is now?
Well, strangely, I haven't
heard from her since.
Okay, thank you.
Kimble...
why does she want the blueprints
for the Capitol Building?
She requested them
as part of the investigation
into the bombing.
Right.
Of course, right.
Thank you.
Is everything all right, sir?
I'm not sure yet.
I'll let you know as soon as I can.
Then your detail will bring you back
to One Observatory Circle.
Home, sweet home.
I'm sorry for the interruption.
- Mr. President.
- Not at all.
We're just going through
some of the final details.
It's gonna be a great event, Peter.
Mike, can I borrow you
for a second, please?
Excuse me.
I need to speak with an FBI
agent named Hannah Wells.
- Сan you find her for me?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Hannah Wells?
Why does the president want
to know about Hannah Wells?
He's interested in some information
she claims to have on Peter MacLeish.
Why? What kind of information
did she say she had?
She didn't.
That's, um...
That's what I'm trying to figure out.
Do you know where I could find her?
I wish I did.
She totaled her car yesterday
at 15th and "K"
and fled the scene.
I've checked every local hospital,
even tried pinging her phone.
You're saying an FBI agent
just up and disappeared?
Yes.
I mean, who knows what kind of mess
Jason Atwood's got her mixed up in,
but you want to know
more about Agent Wells?
Here's her file.
See for yourself.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
Hi. I'm Agent Wells.
I called earlier about looking
at your surveillance footage.
Yes, of course.
Uh, it's in the back.
Bob, can you take the register?
- No problem.
- Right this way.
- Thanks for doing this.
- Yeah.
Can you pull up some
footage from January 26th,
around 3:32 p.m.?
That's when the phone was initiated.
Stop.
Do you have any exterior cameras?
Yeah, in the parking lot.
Okay, I need you to pull that up.
Freeze.
And zoom in.
This is Chuck.
Hey, Chuck, I need you
to run a plate for me.
At the swearing-in,
the invocation will be delivered
by a Colonel William Sizemore.
He was the congressman's Army pastor,
and he'll be sworn in using
Beth MacLeish's Bible,
which is being brought in
from the family home in Oregon.
Yeah, Lisa.
Thank you.
I've just learned from a source
that a suspect is in custody
in connection with the
murder of Majid Nassar.
What is the White House's response
and... And when can we expect
to learn more about the suspect's identity.
Lisa, let me interrupt you right there,
as it would be inappropriate
for the White House to comment
on an ongoing investigation.
Now, that being said,
this is obviously a matter
of extreme importance...
How long
has the White House known?
When can we find out their name?
Are you worried about
the public's confidence
- in the president?
- What else is the White House hiding?
I would direct any
remaining questions you have
to the Army criminal investigators, okay?
That's all I have for right now, guys.
I'll see you at the Capitol
for the swearing-in.
You can't just walk away from this.
We deserve answers.
The public deserves answers!
Don't get many West Wingers here,
especially senior aides to POTUS.
It's a special assignment.
Now, all phone calls from the White House
- are catalogued, correct?
- Yes, ma'am,
every letter, call, correspondence...
All preserved for history.
Perfect.
I'm trying to find who,
from the White House,
contacted the Secretary of Defense
on June 23, 2015,
between 8:00 and 8:33 a.m.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Just give me a sec.
Here you go.
There was a call logged
to the Office of
the Secretary of Defense...
8:23 a.m., 23, June 2015.
Who made the call?
White House Chief of
Staff Charles Langdon.
Do we have an update on Agent Wells?
She was in a car accident
yesterday at 15th and "K."
And according to witnesses,
she abandoned the scene.
FBI hasn't been able to track her down.
Wait a second.
She was in a car accident on her way
to provide information
on Congressman MacLeish?
That's a bit of a coincidence.
Director Foerstel
gave me a look at her file.
Merits of accommodation aside,
Agent Wells has been going
through a difficult time.
According to Atwood's own notes,
he felt her judgment might
be compromised.
- Why?
- She was in a relationship
with someone that died at the Capitol,
Senator Scott Wheeler.
All I know is that she
went to Hookstraten
looking for the blueprints
for the Capitol Building
weeks before we knew about the file,
so she's either crazy,
like everybody says
or she knows something.
We got to keep looking for her.
Yes, sir.
FBI! Stop right there!
Turn around.
I know you.
You're Charles Langdon.
You were Richmond's Chief of Staff.
- Everything thinks you're dead.
- You've got to get out of here.
They could have followed you.
You're the one calling me about MacLeish?
You don't know how hard it
is to stay hidden from them.
It was a woman's voice.
They're never gonna
stop searching for me.
Who's "they"? Who is behind this?
Why do they keep MacLeish alive?
It's... It's bigger than you think.
Don't trust anyone.
Get down!
Aah!
Oh!
This is Russink.
Hey, Chuck.
I got a security key card here.
It's, uh, got a logo on it.
It's an "M" with a circle around it.
"M"? Um...
Could be Metway
Security out of Virginia...
Super high-end private
security and monitoring firm.
They offer me a job every year or two.
All right, I'm gonna give you
the serial number on the back.
Run it for me. See what this unlocks.
- Okay. You ready?
- Yeah, shoot.
Zulu-Tango-3-2-6-7-Echo.
Hannah?
Hannah, you still there?
Call me when you got something.
All right, so this reporter, Lisa Jordan...
She knows we have someone in custody.
She just doesn't know that it's Atwood?
That's right. She knows
we've arrested someone.
- She just doesn't know who it is.
- Then, she has nothing.
She knows we're hiding something.
Mr. President, we agreed
not to tell the press anything
until we have all the facts.
Well, we have them now.
The FBI just handed in their report,
and it concludes that Jason Atwood
did, indeed, kill Majid Nassar.
That's incredible.
I asked Ms. Jordan to stay on
as a White House correspondent
to keep us honest.
She kept up her end of the bargain.
We need to do the same.
Tell her we'll give her an exclusive
on the man that we have in custody,
but she's gonna have
to wait till tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
Sir, I'm sorry about Atwood.
I know you didn't want it to be true.
None of us did.
Oh, sir, I was thinking if, uh...
if... if you're having second thoughts
on Bruce Rangell
for Secretary of Housing,
I could always pull up
more information on him
to look over.
I'm not having second
thoughts on Rangell.
What would make you think that?
I-I'm sorry.
I-I must have been, um...
I must have been thinking
about something else.
The motorcade leaves for
the Capitol in 30 minutes.
- Thank you.
- Sir.
Ritter.
Agent Ritter, it's John Foerstel.
What can I do for you?
You asked me to keep the White House
in the loop on Hannah Wells.
I just got a disturbing phone call
out of Virginia.
Agent Wells shot someone?
Yes, sir, at a farm in Fredericksburg.
The FBI's still working
to identify the body,
but witnesses claim
they saw someone fitting
Agent Wells' description
engaged in a shootout
before fleeing the scene.
What the hell is going on?
The Feds are throwing a net over D.C.,
and their EOC is monitoring
every camera and feed
within a 30-mile radius.
I'll make sure our people
are on the lookout for her, as well.
- What... you think she's a threat?
- I don't know, sir.
But I can't logically explain her actions
over the past 24 hours.
We should consider that
both MacLeish and Foerstel
might be right about her.
And I'd rather we overreact and be wrong
than underestimate her
and live to regret it.
Okay, thanks, Mike.
Hey, Chuck.
Hannah, I've been monitoring
the police scanners...
Metro Police, the Bureau...
They're all looking for you.
I don't know how much
longer I can help you.
Look, I understand.
Were you able to find out
anything about the key card?
Yeah. It gives you access
to room 7 on the 8th floor
of the PLC Building on Louisiana.
Louisiana?
Chuck, room 7...
does it face east or west?
East. Why?
You can see the steps.
Hannah, what are you thinking?
Proximity to the Capitol,
direct line of sight to the platform.
Chuck, they're gonna kill Kirkman.
It'll be okay.
I just wish we had more time
to figure everything out
before we did something so permanent.
Tom, if you feel that way,
then we should not go through with this.
We don't have a choice.
The only evidence we
have is circumstantial.
We could be wrong.
The country can't afford another setback.
Peter.
Everyone's waiting. It's time to leave.
What's wrong?
We were supposed to be in
the car 10 minutes ago.
I don't know if I can go through with this.
- Honey, of course you can.
- No.
I think we need to rethink this thing.
It is perfectly normal to have cold feet,
but this is a great day for all of us.
It is exactly what
we've been working for.
Yeah.
But at what cost?
At any cost necessary.
Peter, you were chosen
to survive for a reason.
You've been given
a tremendous responsibility
to restore this nation
to the empire it once
was and can be again.
Our friends placed their faith in you.
What would they think if
they saw you like this?
You are on the cusp, Peter.
This isn't the time for weakness.
Now tell me you agree.
Tell me you agree, Peter.
Okay.
Good.
Now let's go.
Lisa.
Excuse me, Cody.
Hey.
I took your question to the president.
Let me guess... No comment.
If it was up to me,
honestly, yeah, no comment.
We've been way too reactive around here,
and that's gonna change,
but the president appreciates you,
and we've decided to grant you
the exclusive on the
Nassar investigation.
Really?
- When?
- Soon.
For now, let's let America celebrate.
I'll be in touch.
8th floor... all clear.
Clear.
- President Kirkman!
- Mr. Kirkman!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States.
I wanted to take a moment
before we get started
and congratulate you on
becoming vice president.
Our country's got
a long road to recovery,
but this is another big step.
Thank you, sir. I won't let you down.
Great to see you.
Emily Rhodes.
Ms. Rhodes, it's Amanda
at the switchboard.
- Yes.
- You asked me to look deeper
into Charles Langdon's
phone records June 23.
Uh, as it turns out,
he wasn't in his office that day.
I'm sorry?
I double-checked his schedule.
Uh, Mr. Langdon was on an
overseas trip to Geneva.
Then who made the call to the Pentagon?
His deputy, Aaron Shore.
Thank you.
Mr. President, it's time.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please be seated.
Good afternoon.
When I see how many of you
have chosen to brave the elements
to mark this momentous occasion,
I can only tell you how inspired I am.
Today, I stand...
...on the site of one of
America's greatest tragedies
and offer the promise
of America's rebirth.
The night I was sworn in
as President of the United States,
this nation,
our nation,
was in the grips of chaos.
But now, as I look out on the Mall,
I don't see a people that were scared.
I don't see a people
that were frightened.
- Excuse me.
- I see that we are strong...
Excuse me.
...and that we are proud
and that we are, once again, united.
God bless all of you
and these United States of America.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is my profound honor to introduce
Congressman Peter MacLeish,
our next vice president.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, sir.
Congressman MacLeish,
if you'll place your hand on the Bible
and repeat after me.
"I, Peter Lewis MacLeish..."
I, Peter Lewis MacLeish...
"...do solemnly swear
to support and defend
the Constitution of the United States..."
...do solemnly swear
to support and defend
the Constitution of the United States...
"...against all enemies,
foreign and domestic..."
...against all enemies,
foreign and domestic...
Excuse me. Excuse me.
...that I bear true faith
and allegiance to the same...
Excuse me. Move!
...without any mental reservation
or purpose of evasion."
...and that I take
this obligation freely,
without any mental reservation
or purpose of evasion,
and that I will well and faithfully
discharge the duties of the office
on which I am about to enter.
"So help me God."
So help me God.
I have a suspect in my line
of sight. I need a team.
Congratulations, Mr. Vice President.
Gun! Gun!
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --