Mom!
What happened?
Alley! Alley! Alley!
Oh, my God!
God, Alley!
Oh, God. God.
I warned you, Marco.
I fuckin' warned you.
I told you
not to sell him drugs.
It was the summer of '58.
The year the Dodgers
left Brooklyn.
The summer
Dion and the Belmonts...
were blasting
out of every car radio...
and the summer
that I first fell in love.
It was the summer
Marco Vendetti...
came home from prison...
and the streets of Sunset Park
ran red with blood.
My brother Leon started a gang
called the Deuces...
after our brother Alley died.
Our job
was to protect the block.
-Leon.
-Hey, Fritzy.
-You need anything?
-I'll let you know, kid.
But it was a local mob guy
named Fritzy...
who really ran
the neighborhood.
He pretended to be
everybody's best friend.
Get yourself an ice cream.
But he was only in it
for himself.
Scooch. Center field.
On the corner of Sixth Street
and Second, the Deuces ruled.
Hey, Pops.
Grandson gettin' better?
He's good.
-Hey, what?
-Aw, it's horrible.
We hung out at a candy store
called Willie's...
where we ran bootleg cigarettes,
illegal fireworks...
and did a little bookmaking
on the side.
Hey, we had to make a livin'.
Aw, come on. They're playin'
like little girls here.
What, did he throw it
underhand?
Oh, Scooch. We're havin' fun.
Ah, the Dodgers lost again.
The usual, Scooch.
I told 'em. They ain't gonna
win in Los Angeles.
They shouldn't have left
Brooklyn.
Come on, I never seen 'em cry.
The last game,
they wept like a baby.
How are you?
Go on. Fuck the Dodgers.
Fuck Pee Wee, fuck Jackie,
and fuck the fuckin' Duke.
Don't say that, Tommy! Don't
say, "Fuck the fuckin' Duke."
Hey, listen. Everybody knows
he signed your friggin' glove.
Get over it. They left.
I ain't rootin' for 'em
no more.
'cause you're
a fair-weather fan.
Oh, come on, now.
Let's go outside.
Let's go outside now.
I'll see ya later.
What's this?
Bridesmaid's dress.
Pink taffeta.
You like it, huh?
You know what I like you in.
Who's gettin' married?
My cousin Antoinelle,
out in Bayridge.
You're comin', right?
Another cousin gettin' hitched?
How many more are there?
People do get married, Leon.
It is somethin' people do,
you know.
Willie, is it suddenly
gettin' hot in here or what?
Oh, so what do you
want to do tonight?
-You know this fuckin' kid?
-Who?
-This kid.
-Who's he?
Hey, asshole.
You know whose turf this is?
This is Deuces turf.
You fuckin' listenin' to me?
Ah, me deaf! Ah, me deaf!
-Shut the fuck up!
-I'm deaf!
-Leon.
-What?
Come here. There's a fight.
Fuck! Fuck!
What are you doin'?
This kid
was disrespectin' our turf.
I think he's one of them
Garfield boys or somethin'.
This ain't a Garfield boy.
He don't hang with no peewees.
This is Betty Ann's little
brother--her deaf brother.
Nate. Big guy. Go home.
You hit one person a year,
it's a deaf kid.
Well, how the fuck
am I supposed to know?
His mother should hang a sign
around his neck or some shit.
Father Aldo, we're up here.
Father. Thanks, bud.
You missed a spot.
Hey, Father. You wanna
come up here and help me?
That's your penance.
I hear Marco Vendetti
is comin' home soon.
I thought you should know.
Give me your word
nothing's gonna get outta hand.
Give me some more
of that polish, Scooch.
You know the first thing I'm
gonna do when I get outta here?
I'm gonna get me
a nice cold beer...
a slice of sicilian,
a nice piece of ass...
and find that rat motherfucker
who sent me here.
I'm gonna slice his
motherfucking throat...
from ear to ear.
Mark the son of a bitch.
Not bad, huh?
-It's not bad.
-It looks all right.
Who put this on the window?
Carnival. Not bad.
It's gonna be a good spot.
-A good spot, yeah.
-Make us some money.
-Make us some money, yeah.
-Philly Babes.
Get away from here.
-Where's Leon?
-What's it to ya?
He told Mikey Festo
he was gonna break his head...
if he rented out
the store over here.
-So?
-Let me ask you somethin'.
Since when
did he become the landlord?
Since yesterday.
You didn't read the paper?
Tell your brother
we're movin' in over here.
You or any of your guys...
try to stop any of my guys,
and you're dead.
Over my dead body are you gonna
move junk into this building.
Whoa.
Who said anything about junk?
We're talkin' about
a little numbers action...
some broads, Mario Lanza
on the jukebox. Relax.
Don't tell me to relax,
you son of a bitch.
Watch your mouth,
you little prick.
Come on.
Go hang out
with the other girls.
There ya go, ya punks.
They're runnin'.
Squeal, pig!
How do you like them apples,
fat ass?
You boys all right?
Do I look like
I'm all right, you moron?
Get me outta here.
Help me get this guy
outta here.
Hey, Bobby.
Let's get outta here.
Beautiful.
It smells good in here, mom.
It's comin' from next door.
Well, what are we
supposed to eat?
I started to make
the cacciatore.
You know, it was
my Alley's favorite.
The onion made me cry.
What about makin'
my favorite, ma?
It's a dish called food.
I'm fuckin' starving.
Watch that mouth!
What you talk like that
to me for?
-Hey, ma. What's goin' on?
-Nothin'. No dinner.
If you would take the money
we give you...
and spend it on food
instead of fuckin' booze...
we would have
some fuckin' supper!
No! You gotta buy food!
Hey! You're talkin'
to your mother like that!
Get outside.
Now!
I can't take it anymore.
Don't worry, ma.
I'm gonna go to the corner.
I'll get somethin' to eat.
What?
What's the matter
with you, huh?
There's been a truce
on this block for three years.
Did I tell you to break it?
They were disrespectin' you.
What am I supposed to do?
Droppin' bricks off the roof?
What are you, fuckin' crazy?
Cinder blocks--they're bigger.
Oh, it's just a game to you,
huh, Bobby?
I gotta answer to Fritzy
for this.
One of those guys might die.
What's Fritzy
got to do with this?
Nobody moves in Sunset Park
without his OK. You know that.
So you're just gonna let 'em
move in?
You lost your fuckin' balls
or somethin'?
You don't run the Deuces,
I do.
And I don't back down
from nothin'.
There will be no junk
on this block, ever.
Now, we're gonna do it my way.
If I ever hear you talk to
our mother again like that...
I swear to God, I will crack
your fuckin' head open.
Hey, I'm here to see Fritzy.
Thanks.
Get this kid
somethin' to drink.
What do you want,
a soda or somethin'?
No, thanks.
You know...
bricks don't fall
out of the sky...
in this neighborhood
unless I'm throwin' 'em.
You understand?
Yeah, Fritzy.
Now, Philly Babes
is one thing...
but his car?
That really got me angry.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
I'm gettin' calls
from Mikey Festo.
Who are you
to strong-arm anyone?
There's no disrespect to you,
Fritzy.
He's gonna rent the store
to Philly and his crew.
They're gonna deal junk
out of there.
If I ever hear that word out of
your mouth again in my club...
that'll be your last word.
This ain't your block.
We all know what happened
to your brother Sal.
-I'm sorry for your...
-Alley.
What?
His name was Alfonse Michael.
We called him Alley Boy.
Alley Boy.
We're all sorry
for your loss...
but he was a little junkie,
wasn't he?
Wasn't he?
Yes or no.
Look...
Mikey Festo
doesn't own that store.
I do...
and I'm gonna do
whatever I want with it.
So mind your own business.
Wear your jacket,
sing your songs...
do whatever the fuck it is
that you kids do.
Just stay out of my way.
Alley Boy.
You movin' in?
That's smart.
You're a clever boy.
Where'd you live before?
President Street.
Yeah? Always there?
Before that, I crawled out
from between my mother's legs.
You got any more questions?
What, are you just gonna
stand there...
or are you gonna help me?
That's Vipers territory.
I'm a Deuce.
-Douche?
-That's--that's funny.
Come on.
It's just a line in the street.
Not to me. I'm sorry.
You're a real Prince Charming,
you know?
Give me that.
Here.
It's heavy.
Thanks.
Hey, Bobby, come here.
I'm talkin'.
Get up here, now.
Hey, Annie.
She's nice, right?
The little fox
with the ponytail?
They ain't foxes.
They're the Velvets.
Do you know
who I was just talkin' to?
Yeah. That's Annie--
Annie the ice cube.
What do you know about her?
She's Jimmy Pockets' sister.
That says it all.
What? They're related?
See, I told you we should have
killed that bastard.
You stay away from her.
We got enough trouble.
Hey, I just saw you
out the window.
What the hell you talkin'
to that Deuce for, huh?
None of your business.
Look, everything in my house
is my business.
Could you give me a hand
with these boxes?
They're kinda heavy, you know.
You're such a helpful brother,
Jimmy.
Hey, I let you live
in my house, right?
You wanna live on the streets,
that's fine with me.
I catch you talkin'
to that Deuce again...
you're outta here.
Take that crazy mother of yours
with ya.
She's your mother, too, Jimmy.
Come on.
Ma, come on. Ma,
what are you doin'? Please.
I'm sorry, OK?
A pepperoni pie. Table 4a.
-You're terrible.
-I am terrible.
I'm starvin', though, too.
I don't know.
She's hot.
She couldn't be
as hot as this pizza.
What do you got,
the red line to hell in there?
Is it the same one again?
-Hi.
-How are you?
That's terrible!
She looks like...
-Do I have dough on my face?
-No, you're good.
Oh, my God.
You can't go crazy, right?
You again?
Are you here
to take our orders?
Yeah, what do you want?
I want you to take it
on the arches.
What?
Get outta sight. Scram.
You know, disappear?
So listen, um...Annie.
How'd you know my name?
I know a lot of things.
So, anyway,
I was wondering...
What were you wondering,
wonder boy?
Are you going to the feast
on Friday night?
Who's asking?
Well, I mean, I'm probably
gonna be there, so...
-Where's our pizza?
-I don't know.
Have they cooked it?
I mean, I'm dying.
You're still here?
Why is he still here?
All right.
Hey, I think he's cute.
He's all right.
So how'd you do?
She likes me.
I'm here to see Marco Vendetti.
Right over there.
-What the fuck happened to you?
-The Deuces.
The punks ambushed me when
I was checkin' out the club.
I'm lookin' over my shoulder
everywhere I go now...
paranoid as a fuck.
I got a limp that's gonna be
with me the rest of my life.
There goes your dancing career.
-Yeah, that's funny.
-No, it's not.
You're an embarrassment.
If you weren't my cousin,
I'd break your other arm.
I'm sorry.
You'd better get that club,
Philly.
I got big plans for that spot.
It'll be ready. I promise.
All right. Don't mess this up.
Get me a sit-down with Fritzy.
Tell him Marco wants to see him.
Why?
Just shut up and do what I say.
Look at you.
You're fuckin' pathetic.
Come on, Vendetti.
Time's up.
Tell the Vipers to crush
them fuckin' Deuces, all right?
We gotta answer for this.
Yeah, nice to see you, too.
You know what I'd do to her,
Dommy?
You'd boff her, Jack?
Yeah. You know how good, Dommy?
Really good, Jack.
-Where do these girls live?
-France.
France. Where's that?
I think you take the "F" train.
The "F" train.
Oh, good God.
They got Elvis.
Goddamn, what's next?
Yeah, I got more peachfuzz
on my balls...
than he's got on his head.
I wouldn't shave my head
if they attacked my bedroom.
Looks like my gym teacher.
-Hey, how's it goin'?
-Got any deliveries?
Well, gimme a box.
-Dad, get me a pretzel.
-Oh, shut up.
You're like your mother.
Always got your hand out.
Money don't grow on trees.
How much?
-Twenty cents.
-Daddy, please.
When I tell you to shut up,
you shut up.
Leave him alone.
Hey, do yourself a favor and
mind your own fucking business.
This is my kid.
I do with him what I want.
That's because of you.
Leon, stop! It's OK!
It didn't hurt!
Don't touch him again.
He's a good boy.
Get outta here.
-Bunch of punks.
-Get outta here!
You want a pretzel?
Come here.
A little mustard
on the pretzel?
All right.
You go home to your mother.
Thanks, Leon.
Oh, my God.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Guys!
Holy shit. There must be
fifteen of 'em over there.
I never knew
they had so many guys.
All right. Fuck this shit!
Unh! You crazy?
Come on!
Get outta here!
Get off the street!
I guess
we're goin' to war, huh?
Well, that's what happens when
you all do somethin' stupid.
Well, maybe
it's for Marco's homecoming.
Look, it don't make
any fuckin' difference.
You gotta listen to what
I'm tellin' you--no fightin'.
Yeah, just chicken out, right?
Aw, come on.
What do I look like, Leon?
I say we beat
their fuckin' brains out.
What, are you deaf?
What did I just say?
Leon, they challenged us.
Why are you goin' soft on me?
Watch it, Bobby.
All right. You know what?
You guys wanna be pansies,
that's fine...
but I'm gonna have
no part of it.
I need a little time to think.
Go to the feast.
Just stay cool.
That's all I'm askin'.
Hey, I hear the Vipers
are gunnin' for you.
Yeah, so what else is new?
You want my guys ready? I mean,
in case you come up short.
I'm just here for the babes,
Freddie.
Oh, right. The babes.
Well, look...
we're there for you
if you need us, OK?
The word is you'll need us.
They got an army, you know?
-See ya, chief.
-Yeah, see ya.
You got some change?
Thanks.
Place your bets.
Hey, feelin' lucky?
Oh, fancy meeting you here.
So, what number
you gonna put your money on?
Fifteen.
You must be feeling lucky.
That's 100-to-1 shot.
I always go for the long shot.
Hi, handsome.
You sure you don't wanna go
to the feast, Leon, huh?
I been to that feast
twenty times already.
What am I gonna win,
another kewpie doll?
I got me a kewpie doll.
Come here.
You like me, don't you?
Well, I feel sorry for ya.
There's a difference.
Yeah, that's why you were
up all night screamin' my name.
I must have been
havin' a nightmare.
Talk about a nightmare, livin'
in that house with your brother.
You don't know the half of it.
You know, he labels the milk
so no one else can drink it...
and then he spends
the whole day in the bathroom...
shootin' skag
and drinkin' beer...
and then he thinks
drinkin' a glass of milk...
is gonna keep him healthy?
He's crazier than my mother.
You think that's crazy,
you should see my house.
Hello, Jack.
Hey, where you goin'?
Hey, Jackie.
Hey, don't touch me.
Please don't touch me.
Please stop. Please.
We just wanna talk to you.
Hey, put 'em up!
Put his arm out! Come on!
Oh! We got a winner, huh?
Which one you want,
little lady?
Uh, that one.
-This one?
-Yeah.
-There you go.
-Thanks.
They jumped Little Jack!
-Hey, somebody get the guys!
-Somebody get some help!
Jack, you OK?
Hey, Bobby. Bobby, man,
they jumped Little Jack.
They jumped him, man.
-Take it easy.
-He's all right.
The Vipers jumped me
in the park.
Oh, I'm gonna kill 'em!
All right. Cool it. Cool it.
We gotta get Leon.
Hey, Scooch, you know where
Betsy's baby-sittin'?
Go tell Leon it's going down
in the park. Go!
Bobby, man,
you want my guys now?
Yeah, all you can bring.
All right, man. You can
count on us. We'll be there.
Let's get these motherfuckers!
-They jumped Little Jack.
-Call an ambulance.
-Guys, come on!
-No more fightin', Bobby!
I'm sorry.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I'll get it. I'll get it.
-Leon.
-What's wrong?
The Vipers jumped Little Jack.
Come on, hurry up.
-Where?
-The park.
Hey, where's Freddie?
He's dead if he don't show.
No way, Moof, not us.
-Let's do it.
-Let's fuckin' do it.
You gotta be kiddin' me.
Little Bobby.
Where's your brother?
Don't worry, he'll be here,
you fuckin' grease monkey.
He ain't comin', fuck-putz.
What do you got, huh?
Look at him. He's a punk.
Come on!
Motherfucker!
Get him off me!
It's over.
It's fuckin' over.
Gotta run!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Bobby, are you all right?
Can you get up?
Give me a minute.
Is he gonna be OK?
Come on! We still got
more coming! Let's go!
Bobby, what happened, man?
It started already?
What are you talkin' about?
It's already over.
Man, you guys
are somethin' else.
Where the hell were you?
The Bulls! Scatter!
Let's scatter!
Alley?
Alley Boy?
It's Leon, ma. It's Leon.
Go get him.
It's OK, ma.
It's OK.
Oh, God.
God, that hurts.
Stop fidgeting, wonder boy.
Stop being such a baby.
There we go.
Is that Christmas music I hear?
What the hell?
It's, like, 115 degrees.
My mom has a thing for
Christmas music, that's all.
Don't pay no attention to it.
What has Leon told you
about me, anyway?
What'd he say?
-Nothin'.
-Nothin'?
I bet he told you
I was a slut, right?
No, nothin' like that.
He just said you were cool.
That's the trouble with guys.
They lie.
Big fat fuckin' lyin' mouths.
We wish you a merry Christmas
Hey, you want to see something?
What?
Come with me.
Where you goin'?
Just follow me.
You know, you don't have
to be embarrassed.
Embarrassed about what?
About your mother.
Mine's no prize.
You shouldn't say that...
'cause she's your mother.
You always gotta
take care of her.
Yeah, but it's gotta go
both ways, too.
She doesn't give a shit
about me.
What was your brother like?
He was kind of a dreamy kid,
you know?
He started out,
he just had a little habit.
But then he got strung out.
Leon went to Marco and Jimmy...
and said,
"Stop givin' my brother junk."
But they kept--
they kept giving it to him...
so he beat the hell
out of 'em...
and then one day, they--they--
they gave him a hot shot.
They killed him.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know that.
Now you do.
Hey, Bobby, you know what?
What?
I love my bear.
-Yeah?
-Yeah, I do.
Leon, listen to me.
Little Jack
was in the hospital all night.
Put an end to this
before somebody gets killed.
What do you want me to do,
Father?
You were fightin', too.
I want you to talk to the boys.
They listen to you.
I want you to make peace.
I don't know. I think you're
talkin' to the wrong guy.
Look out for the whale, man!
Deuces rule!
-Hey, Little Jack.
-My boys.
-Welcome back.
-Look who it is.
-How'd it go?
-Hey, we threw 'em a bing.
We ain't gonna be seein'
no Vipers for a while, trust me.
How you feelin'?
A lot better than I look,
I hope.
Hey, thanks for stickin' up
for me last night.
Don't mention it.
-We're Deuces, right?
-Right.
Hey, Jack, go put your feet up.
Hey, it's hot out here.
Best-looking guy out here.
Hey, who's that broad
from last night?
That's Annie,
Jimmy Pockets' sister.
What's he doing over there
with the enemy?
What do you think he's doing?
Hey, Marco. Welcome home.
What's the matter?
You know how long
I been waitin' here?
I don't know. Fifteen minutes?
I've been waitin' three years
and fifteen minutes.
Get the fuck in the car.
Right.
Here's your beer.
You take care of them Deuces?
Yeah, we fought 'em.
You gonna tell me what happened,
or I gotta read your mind?
It went down just like you said.
We were destroying them,
and then out of nowhere...
Leon shows up,
and then it gets bad.
You're tellin' me one guy
took on our whole crew?
Yeah. He went crazy.
Shut up. Goddamn, do I gotta
do everything myself?
-Where is he?
-How should I know?
Ask Father Aldo.
He's gonna make him a saint.
Jesus don't listen
to no snitches.
From now on,
I want you to tell me...
every fuckin' move he makes,
you understand me?
It's good to see you, Marco.
Oh, there he is.
The cavalry
and his lovely tomato.
-Great last night, Leon.
-Like the old days.
Hey, guys, don't egg him on,
all right?
-How you feelin'?
-Like a million dollars.
Leon, you gotta teach me
how to fight like you.
What are you talkin' about,
Scooch?
You're gonna be the new
center fielder for the Dodgers.
You're takin'
Duke Snider's spot.
Come on.
Come here!
Don't go.
-He's callin' me.
-What are you, a dog?
-No.
-Then let him come here.
What if he has something
important to tell me?
Well, you can let him
tell you here.
-Bobby!
-What?
Bobby, what's wrong with you?
Go on to your brother,
puppy dog.
I'll be right back.
Don't go nowhere.
What'd I do this time?
I wanted to tell you you did
the right thing last night.
I did?
Yeah, they jumped Little Jack.
What were you supposed to do?
-You mean you're not mad?
-I ain't mad.
You didn't shoot anybody.
I'm fuckin' thrilled.
All right.
Can I enjoy my day now?
Oh, hey, welcome home, Marco.
I fixed up the house
like you said.
-Good.
-Ohh. The neck, man. The neck.
Don't worry. They'll be swimmin'
in their own blood in no time.
Hey, get the drapes.
Hey, welcome home, daddy-o.
How you doin'?
-Good. How'd you get that?
-Fuckin' Deuces.
How's my good friend Leon
doing?
Dead,
when I get my hands on him.
You know how I can get to him?
Yeah, you remember
that little kid Scooch?
-What the fuck's a Scooch?
-That drunk asshole Gino's kid.
Leon's like a father
to that little mutt.
-Good shot.
-Good to see you.
Come here.
Do me a favor.
Get me a bicycle.
-What for?
-Just do what I say.
What are we gonna
tell everybody, huh?
Tell 'em I fell off a ladder
in church.
Well, at least your eye
matches your suit.
You really want to go
to this thing?
Yeah, Leon, come on.
All right. Let's go.
Hey, Scooch. Nice bike.
-Yeah, you like the bike?
-Yeah.
Yeah, it looks good on you.
-Scooch, get over here.
-Stay right there.
Why don't you come over here
and get him?
Well, come on, then. Let's see
what happens, motherfucker.
Stop! What are you doin'?
I'm gonna cut you a thousand
times, you know that?
One for every day you left me
in that fuckin' cage.
You come by my block again,
and I'll fucking kill you!
This ain't your block no more.
Just get off me!
It's good to see you, Leon.
Why didn't you say good-bye
to me at the pool?
-You was busy.
-No, I wasn't.
Well, if you wasn't busy,
then why didn't you come...
and say good-bye to me?
Can we talk about this outside,
please?
I'll see you later.
Are you ever gonna grow up,
or are you just gonna spend...
the rest of your life
in Leon's shadow?
Hey, I ain't
in no one's shadow.
Really?
Look, let's get
something straight.
If you want to be with me,
then be with me.
I want to be with you.
Well, you sure don't
act like it, you know?
Stop bein' ashamed of me,
especially in front of Leon.
You gotta take my hand.
You gotta put your arm
around my shoulder, you know?
Boyfriend-girlfriend stuff.
Well, let's make it real.
-You mean it?
-I'm serious as a heart attack.
You really want me
to be your girl?
Yeah. Right now.
What would you do
if I was your girl?
Well...
I would hug you...
and I would kiss you...
and then I would climb
the empire state building...
and tell the whole world
that you were my girl.
I would say, "Everybody,
Annie is my girl now!"
Marco.
My cousin Philly
said you had something...
you wanted to talk to me about.
Heroin.
I got an unlimited supply.
What are you, fuckin' stupid?
You know
I don't deal that stuff.
You don't have to. I'll do
all the dirty work myself.
What's in it for me?
You front me the cash,
I'll triple your money.
I'll think about it...
but if this comes back to me
in any way, I don't know you.
That's why we're not having
this conversation.
There's just one more thing.
There's these Deuces.
This fuckin' kid Leon.
I want your permission
to take him out.
Whoa, whoa. Slow down.
You just got out of jail.
Besides, I don't want him
to get killed on my block...
you understand?
It's bad for business.
You don't know who I am,
do you, mister?
I don't care who you are,
sonny.
The lady said
she didn't want to go.
It's lucky for you
you're not packin' a gun.
You could've at least said
something to her at the pool.
Like what? Congratulations?
Welcome to the family?
She ain't a Viper, Leon.
She didn't even go
to Marco's welcome home party.
As a matter of fact, she took
care of me after the rumble.
She took care of me good.
She's Jimmy Pockets' sister.
End of story.
It's not the end of the story!
Her family killed your brother.
You remember that?
Yeah, well you can't fuckin'
stop me from seein' her!
Oh, yeah?
What are you gonna do?
I'll do whatever the fuck
I want to do!
-You're not my father, Leon!
-You want out, Bobby?
-What are you talkin' about?
-You want out of the gang?
'Cause that's what
you're askin' for.
Leon, I am always behind you.
You want me to cut
Jimmy Pockets...
into a million pieces?
I'll do it.
You want me to kill
fuckin' Marco? I'll do it.
But Annie's my girl now...
and you're just gonna
have to accept that.
Listen up.
Some things are gonna change
around here.
No more nickel-and-dime
bullshit on the corner.
Anybody wants to get high
in Brooklyn...
they're gonna come
to the avenue first.
We're gonna need runners,
lookouts, baggers--
I'm the fuckin' taste-tester.
Ain't nobody gonna stop us now.
No crooks, no cops,
and no motherfuckin' Deuces.
Am I wrong, Willy?
I mean, tell me.
The kid's ridin' a Trojan horse.
I don't trust her.
Love.
Somethin' I just can't explain.
You just gotta let it--
let it take its course.
It's his life. Salud.
You all right?
Punk.
I gotta go out there.
Don't be stupid.
Listen, man,
we gotta do something.
I mean, if they smell
blood, weakness...
they're gonna hit us harder.
And if it's not the Vipers,
it's gonna be somebody else.
We gotta show ourselves.
That's my opinion.
It's your gang.
What do you want to do?
I don't know.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
What is Bobby doing?
Hey, you just gotta
give him some space...
learn to trust him.
I don't trust her.
There's something
about the ocean.
What about it?
I don't know.
It relaxes me.
It makes me feel
like I belong here.
You do--with me.
Hmm. I think the move
is to get out of here.
-We just got here.
-No, I mean Brooklyn.
I've been thinking about it
a lot, you know...
especially after
what happened to the block.
Where you gonna go?
I don't know.
Someplace nice...
where it don't snow.
Where you can lie on the beach
like this all year-round...
where the air don't stink.
Like Miami, maybe.
How do you know the air
don't stink in Miami?
'Cause I seen pictures.
How can you tell
what a place smells like...
by looking at pictures?
You can just tell, that's all.
I'd go to Los Angeles.
Why Los Angeles?
See the Dodgers.
I wonder
what those guys are doing.
Pee Wee, Koufax, the Duke.
I wonder if they miss Brooklyn.
I won't miss it.
I'm getting the hell
out of Brooklyn.
Well, you're not going anywhere
without me.
You serious?
You'd come with me?
Today, if you want.
Leon would never let you go.
-Stop it! Put him down!
-What are you doing?
-Shut up!
-Let him--let him fucking go!
Stop!
Where's your brother now,
Bobby, huh?
Leave him alone,
you pieces of shit!
You know what they do to
tough guys like you in the can?
Pass you around
like a dirty magazine.
Makes the pages all sticky.
Let me go!
Jimmy, make 'em stop!
Handle your fucking sister.
Take your fucking hands
off her!
Shut up!
You know, Bobby, your brother
screwed this whore...
in a pay toilet
on President Street.
Told you not to hang out with
that Deuce, you fucking whore!
Hey, stab him, Marco!
Have a nice day, Bobby.
Let me go!
Go lay down
next to your boyfriend.
Bobby, are you all right?
Tell Leon I'm coming.
He better get out of my way.
Thanks, Marco.
Can I ask you a question?
Of course.
-You with me?
-You know I am, Marco.
Then what the fuck's
your sister doing...
hanging out with a Deuce?
I knew you were gonna
ask that question.
It's--it's all part of my plan.
Remember you said
keep an eye out on Leon?
Well, what better way?
Just don't let me down, Jimmy,
all right?
Come on, punk.
We know you sold the drugs
to Alley.
I'm not the one you want.
I'll give you everything
on Marco Vendetti.
He's the one you want.
Nice girl.
Mind your business.
How many people
in this building you think...
are looking at your
naked girlfriend right now?
She's got a good body, though.
Not bad.
Were you ever with her?
Who, Annie?
Nobody could get near her.
Look, Bob, she's your girl.
Do what you want with her.
Just be careful.
I will.
Promise.
I'm always here for you.
You're my brother.
What happened to you?
I had a run-in with Marco
at the beach.
I was gonna tell you earlier,
but I was embarrassed.
He said he's coming for you.
Come here.
It's not bad.
Promise me
if anything happens to me...
you'll get ma out of here.
I love you, Bobby.
I love you, too.
I miss him, you know.
I miss him, too.
Hey, Marco, this is that guy
Maurice I was telling you about.
Hey, how you doing?
Nice to meet you.
Sit down.
Did you bring the stuff?
Yeah, I got it.
Got my money?
What happened to him?
It's there.
-Who's the tester?
-Me.
How'd I know?
Tell me what you think.
What the fuck are you doing?
Sit down. Sniff it.
That's some really good stuff.
It's the best stuff in Brooklyn.
I guarantee it.
Yeah, it's good, right?
You can step on that thing
ten times...
it'll still take you
out to deep space.
-Deep space.
-Goes a long way.
So, we done here?
Yeah. Yeah, we're done.
I'll be back in two weeks
with the rest of the wake.
All right?
You boys have a good afternoon.
And as for you, James,
take it easy.
Stow it.
Come on, get the fuck up
and help me.
Put the money under the sink.
There's a loose floorboard
under the litter box.
Come on, let's go.
There we go.
Shut the fucking thing.
Jingle bells
Hey, ma? Ma, you in there?
You in there?
Can you see this?
Will you just lay off her?
-You are such a loser.
-Oh, I'm a loser?
Yeah, you're a loser.
You've always been a loser.
You think I'm
some small-time jerk-off?
-Yeah, I do.
-Well, you're wrong, all right?
I'm with Fritzy now.
-Who's Fritzy?
Fritzy owns the neighborhood,
all right?
He gave Marco and Philly
forty large in a paper sack.
You're looking at a gangster.
Tree.
You never thought
I'd amount to nothing, did you?
So, what do they do
with the money...
they put it in the bank?
Nah, they don't trust no banks.
He's got it in a very
secret place in his house.
It's shh-shh!
Here, Jimmy, have another beer.
Where's Leon?
I gotta talk to him.
My mother's afraid
to leave the house.
Saw him at the apartment
with Betsy.
Jesus,
what are you talking about?
We got a rumble going on,
he's at home getting laid?
He must be taking pussy lessons
from Little Jack.
Screw you, Moof.
Why don't you
leave him the fuck alone?
Look, when we started
this gang, all right...
we made a vow to Leon
to protect the neighborhood...
and we're not.
I don't know about you...
but I'm willing to kill
for what's ours.
We're all family here.
You gotta talk to him, Bobby.
This stuff with Marco's
getting out of control.
Come on, Leon.
I'm not in the mood.
I'll make you feel better.
What's the matter with you?
My head's all filled up.
I'm sorry. It's not you.
Fine. You want to be alone?
I'll leave.
I didn't say that.
Where you going?
Home.
I'll walk you.
-I can walk myself.
-I'll walk you.
I mean, I don't know what's
gotten into you lately, Leon.
When you are ready
to fool around, call me, OK?
Can I talk to you for a second?
l, uh, got a little confession
to make.
The whole time that I was away,
I was thinking about you.
-I gotta go, Marco, come on--
-Listen to me.
I changed in there, I did.
You know?
I just--I just wanted
something sweet in my life.
That's all.
Someone like you.
Marco, I am with Leon, OK?
-Let go of me!
-You like that?
What are you doing?
You know...
I think I know...
a way we can get out of here.
I have a plan.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
Take Marco for all his money.
-You serious?
-I'm serious.
He's got all this money
stashed somewhere.
He thinks
no one will ever find it.
But I...
know where it is.
I need your help.
Will you help me, Bobby?
Yeah, of course.
What happened to you?
Baby.
What happened?
Who did this to you? Who?
What did he do to you?
What did he fucking do to you?
Oh, fuck! What did he do?
I am gonna fucking kill him.
He is fucking dead!
What's going on?
Is everything all right?
Get out of the way!
Get out of--
-No, Leon, stop!
-God damn it!
Oh, my God.
Baby, what happened?
Oh, sweetie.
That's four bad hands
in a row.
Hey, Vinnie, you dealing
from the bottom of the deck?
You vampires ever take a break?
I'm trying to concentrate
over here.
Oh, shut up, stupid, all right?
I'm down over here.
Ain't my dealing, Babes.
You just got shit luck.
What the fuck, are you crazy?
-Where's Marco, huh?
-I don't know!
-Where is he?
-I don't fucking know!
Yeah, well, tell him
he's fucking dead.
Boat yard, midnight.
You tell him
to fucking be there.
-Who is it?
-It's Joey.
How you doing, Miss Esther?
Is Leon home?
Leon didn't come home
last night.
Really?
What do you want?
Fritzy wants you.
Now.
Don't worry, ma.
I'll be home soon.
I thought we talked.
-You said you understood me.
-I do.
-You do?
-Yeah.
By aiming a moving car
like a guided missile...
through the front
of Philly Babes' joint?
Well, that don't
tell me that you do.
Look, Fritzy,
this is between me and Marco.
Marco's with me now...
so there's gonna be
no more of this bullshit.
It's time for you two fuckers
to grow up.
No more Vipers,
no more Deuces...
no more aces, no more
fucking kings and queens.
I can't do that. I'm sorry.
Get Marco in here.
Get him in here.
Look, Marco, come in.
Come here.
Now, I want you two guys
to shake hands.
You're gonna be neighbors
from now on.
So shake and
get the fuck out of here.
Find out if one of those fucks
outside...
can make me
a decent manhattan.
Hey, did you hear what I said?
Shake his hand now.
How's my sweet
little Betsy doing?
Take it fucking easy!
Not in the club, asshole!
Not in the fucking club.
What's wrong with you?
Why don't you kill
all the kids?
-Get him out of here.
-Huh, Fritzy? Kill 'em all.
How do you sleep at night,
you fuck?
I'll take care of him.
Will you tell her
to turn down the music?
It's driving me crazy!
Back off.
-Ma, I said turn off the music!
-You get off her!
I swear to God, I'll slit
your throat, you piece of shit.
You never raise your hands
to her, never!
-You're fucking nuts.
-Get the fuck out of here!
You're both nuts! And you,
you didn't hear Santa Claus.
It was that fat Irish bastard
upstairs.
-It was Santa.
-Santa don't exist, ma!
-You're fucking nuts!
Shut up and
get the fuck out of here!
It was Santa, it was Santa!
Don't you listen to him.
Of course there's a Santa, ma.
He just don't come to Brooklyn
no more.
Where the fuck have you been?
I've been looking
all over the place for you.
Word is you went crazy
at Fritzy's place.
Don't worry about that.
I need all the guys.
Round 'em all up.
What's going on?
It's going down tonight.
Do you want me to talk to
some of the Ocean Side boys...
see if I can't get
a couple of .22s?
-No.
-Are you sure?
I said no.
Get all the guys down here now.
Go, Bobby.
Hurry up.
What's up, Marco?
What happened with Fritzy?
He give the OK?
The saint crucified himself.
Round up the guys. The rat
goes down here right now.
I've been waiting three years
for this.
You got it.
What's the matter?
Bobby, I can't take it anymore.
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
I know. Me, too.
So let's do the job tonight.
I can't tonight.
We gotta fight the Vipers
tonight.
The guys need me.
All right.
Well, you make
your decision, OK?
You think real hard, because
I am getting out of here.
I've gotta--I've gotta
get the fuck out of Brooklyn!
Do you understand?
I can't take it anymore!
I gotta get my mother
out of here!
What are you doing here?
I don't know, l--
I saw all the guys. l--
You should be at home, in bed.
I don't want to wake up
tomorrow morning...
and find out
that you're dead, Leon.
I can't do this right now,
Betsy.
I need some time.
You don't have to do this
for me.
I've got a bad feeling, Leon.
I'm scared.
I love you.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you, OK?
If you love me,
then you'll understand.
Now go.
Go on.
Will you call me later? Huh?
Go.
So I went to see
Tommy Esposito.
He looked at me
like I was crazy.
Said it was a suicide mission.
Yeah, yeah,
and I went over to see...
Sally Black
and the Blue Knights...
and he laughed at me.
He said the word on the street
is we're a dead gang.
Freddie better show
with his guys, so help me God.
Maybe somebody ought to buy
the dumb Polack a watch, eh?
He ain't gonna be late.
He knows this is serious.
Where's Bobby?
He'll be here.
What time is it?
It's 11:00.
Wait here for me.
Pipe it.
Hey, Philly, man, what the fuck
happened to your car?
I thought
you just got it fixed.
Another wise-ass.
You all right?
You're sweatin', man.
You're with us now.
Now, hurry to the boat yard.
All right. All right, Babes.
All right, all right.
Come on.
All right, guys, come on.
You heard him.
To the boat yard!
Listen, I gotta go warn Leon.
Go hide the money
and meet me at the boat yard.
Fuck.
Motherfucker!
Mother!
You punk! You dick!
You scumbag!
Jimmy Pockets,
you rotten piece of shit!
Piece of shit! Motherfucker!
Piece--Come on!
Motherfucker. Motherfucker.
Piece of shit!
Mother!
Jimmy Pockets, you rat!
You rat! You motherfucker!
Guys, relax. It's Scooch.
I wanna fight with you guys
tonight.
Scooch, why don't you
get outta here?
Come on. I can do it.
No, you can't.
You're too little. Now go.
-I can help you.
-No! Now go.
Well, if it ain't
the sharp and shiny Deuces...
ready for some action.
Freddie, thanks for showin' up.
We're here. We're with you,
right, fellas?
-When are these pricks coming?
-Midnight.
I'm ready to slice
some Viper skin.
-Hey, Bobby, where you been?
-Hey, Bobby, what's goin' on?
-Hey, Freddie, how's it goin'?
-Good, man.
Yo! What the fuck?
This motherfucker
made a deal with Philly!
Are you sure?
I'm tellin' you,
he tried to fuckin' set us up!
You boys
runnin' with Philly, huh?
-Motherfuck!
-Get outta here!
Heads up. Marco's here.
Fuck!
You like fuckin' my sister?
Come on!
Jimmy Pockets,
you motherfucker!
You fuckin' dick motherfucker!
You were there for me tonight.
I'll always remember that.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good night, Leon.
Good night, pal.
Hey, Leon, Fritzy warned you.
You shoulda listened, kid.
Mom!
Oh, my God.
My God! No!
Today we say good-bye
to Leon Anthony.
May he never be forgotten...
neither in God's eyes
nor our own.
Amen.
There were a lot of funerals
in Sunset Park that week--
Marco, Jimmy Pockets...
and of course my brother Leon.
It seemed the war between
the Deuces and Vipers...
was finally over.
Love you.
Unfortunately, my mother
paid the highest price.
She lost two sons.
We decided
it was best for her...
to go live with my uncle
on Long Island.
She'll be better off with
someone to take care of her.
I'm gonna come visit you
out there, Bobby.
Maybe we'll go look
at a Dodgers game or somethin'.
Yeah, we'll do that.
I hear there's a lot of
nice-lookin' broads out there.
Maybe you could
send us a couple, huh?
Hey, don't forget about us
out there.
Deuces forever, right?
That's right.
Take care, Bobby.
All right, Bobby.
See you later.
That day was the last time...
we were all together
as the Deuces.
Eventually street gangs...
disappeared
from the neighborhood.
Life in Sunset Park
would never be the same.
Listen...
give this to Father Aldo.
He'll know what to do with it.
Go on.
Here.
I want you to use it.
The Duke signed it.
Thanks.
Take care of the block,
all right, kid?
You're gonna come back, right?
Of course I'm gonna come back.
You be good.
Don't cry.
Annie and l, we were going out
to Los Angeles...
to start a new life together...
and we were takin' her mother
with us.
Oh, yeah. There was one more
thing I forgot to mention.
What do you feel like eating?
Lasagna.
With who?
Let's go to Ricardo's.
Excellent.
There was no way I was gonna
let my brother die in vain.
Like Leon said, "There will be
no junk on this block, ever."