Good morning Tanya.
-Hello.
I'm Connor Mead.
You look ravishing.!
Oh well, thank you.
Stand here please.
Oh wow!!!
Let's get started. Get rid of the green screen.
Let's cosy up this key light.
- Excuse me. What are you doing?
And also keep the set on cue just
in case. Can I have the um...
Apples.
- This is my wardrobe.
Just the one. Ode and ode to Billy Tell.
I just want to let you know
that I'm a huge fan.
Oh, likewise.
I'm not 12 years old and tonedeaf. I
don't like your music but I really...
...dig your look.
Hey can we come in here and
strengthen up these eyebrows a touch?
Stay right there. Just stay right there.
So uh... this is it?
This is the picture?
I'm half naked with an apple on my head.
Yes, you are.
This is the cover of Vanity Fair
from the great Connor Mead?
Oh not quite.
I'd like to introduce you to Keiko
Tatsumi, she's a Japanese archery...
...champion, she's gonna be
helping us out today.
You have nothing to fear.
She's placed 6th in Beijing.
Are you joking?
Is he joking?
Somebody tell me his joking.
Don't move.
Keiko, on my count.
She didn't even move.
Just listen to my music.
I am more than my look.
I am.
Sweetie, you are already gorgeous.
Why do you need to be
good at two things, huh?
Connor.
Now?
I'm juggling three of your parties
on i-chat.
She knock?
- Sorry.
We need to make sure you're on
the road by two.
Why?
Your brother's wedding in Newport.
That's today?
Gonna have some dinner tonight cause
your Uncle Wayne ordered steak.
Oh God, I got to get up there.
And I have Kiki, Charlece and Nadja
on your i-hand. They keep calling.
Nadja. Remind me who Nadja is again.
Nadja was dinner Friday night.
Right. Very pretty girl. Didn't say much.
She's Romanian, barely speaks English.
Oh, that explains it.
Scan these to Mark right away and I am
a touch busy so if you could take...
...the other calls for me
I'd appreciate it.
Nope. No way. I'm not breaking up
with girls for you Connor. That's...
...where I draw the line.
I believe in karma.
OK.
Conference it.
Conference them?
Oh no, you wouldn't.
Oh yes, I would.
They're conferenced. Click here
to disconnect.
Hullo ladies, it's Connor Mead.
- Hullo.
Is there anyone else on the line?
Listen, I'm sincerely pressed for time
right now, so I'm gonna... I'm gonna...
...have to do this in bulk.
It's not gonna work out for us.
What?
- Wait, wait, tell me you're not...
...breaking up with me on a conference
call. I thought things were going great.
You are women hatred. Dominic hates woman.
No, no, no, I love woman. I mean women.
I love all women. That's the problem here.
No, the problem is you date a girl
for two weeks, get her to fall in...
...love with you.
You take the love and you horde
it like a remiser.
...anyone who's trying to
have fun anymore.
I like to have fun.
Then don't listen to these ladies.
They're crazy.
Connor, we can still hear you when
you cover the camera you know.
Oh, right.
- You are amazingly retarded.
Ladies, sounds like you have an
awful lot to discuss, OK? So I'm gonna...
...jump off, but feel free to
keep talking, OK?
Kiki, Nadja, Charlece, I had an amazing
time with each one of you.
I wish you all the best.
You really are as bad as they say.
Oh, Nadia, I am just a little bit worse.
Of course you'd never treat
me that way, right?
No, I just did that for you.
Leaving my plate for the main course.
You're the biggest jerk ever.
But you're so famous for it.
No really, why am I doing this?
That usually has something
to do with your father.
Oh please, I've never even met my father.
Well, come to papa.
OK, here we go.
So we'll have gone like plaque words.
So at 15:29, I will say you may...
...kiss the bride.
Oh, we should practice that, shouldn't we?
Oh God.
Paulie.
Connor. Go around.
He came.
What's wrong?
He can't be that bad, right?
No.
Jenny, Susan...
- It's alright.
Hey.
You made it.
- Yeah.
Wow, you look great.
Man, look what we did to
Uncle Wayne's karate dojo.
I psyched you came. I didn't think you
were going to make through rehearsal.
Yeah, now listen I wanted to get here
early, make sure you had time to...
You know the one about marriage, love,
looking her in the eye and falling...
...in love...
I definitely thought about it.
You did?
- Yeah, I did.
Listen, if you're having second thoughts.
Here's the key to my Jag.
You give me the way, I'll bog.
Oh my God, you're serious?
Damn right I'm serious,
I'd do anything for you.
Who's got your back, huh?
Me. It's you and me against
the world, right?
Why is he giving him keys?
I think he's giving you a car.
Wow, let me just go check on that.
Connor, we talked about this.
I want to get married. I love Sandra.
You say that now.
- Are you OK guys? Because we're still...
...you know rehearsing.
Jenny Perotti.
- Connor Mead.
I'll be damned.
It's probably true.
The bride's unsupervised.
- I'm on it.
Hey, we're gonna talk about this, huh?
Been talking about what?
Options.
- Options.
Listen to me Connor, this is the biggest
weekend in Sandy's life. If you...
...do anything to detract her from her
wedding, I will sneak into your...
...room in the middle of the night and
cut off your favourite appendage.
Our first party sounds nice.
I can make it look like an accident
honey. Don't push me.
Just try to be supportive. Normal.
Just not a train wreck for once.
I'll be on my best behaviour.
That's what worries me.
What? I'll be supportive. Whatever.
Really?
- Yes.
Come on.
See, I knew there wouldn't be any
maintenance on you two, huh?
Connor, you remember Sandra?
- Yes, I do. How are you Sandra?
You know it's not too late to
get out of court.
He's joking.
And you know the bridesmaids.
Deena, Donna, how are you? And...
- Denice.
Nice to meet you Denice.
- Me too, how are you?
My groom's men.
Guys, this is my brother Connor.
We've heard the stories man.
- An honour to be serving with you.
And with you.
It's nice to meet you. Damn it, I blew it.
Sorry to break up the moments guys, but
kind of need you right here where...
...I can keep my eyes on you.
Are we ready?
Yes, right, Sarge.
Sarge, what are you married by a cop?
Sergeant Major Volkom, United States
Marine Core. I am not a cop.
...game right after the war.
The war called Korea. Perhaps
you've heard of it slick.
Lost more men than Nam. Didn't get
a wall. We didn't get our movie...
...We got a sitcom with hell and all,
which was all non-stop laughing...
...unless you were the one
watching his friends die.
The war's over dad. It was a tie.
You know what we should probably try and
keep going on schedule.
Bowing the kiss at 1530 hours on my mark.
Groom will take brides left forearm.
Rotating 180 degrees orientating...
...north by north west.
And I will annouce you as
husband and wife.
Vow in which... vow in which you will
live happily ever after.
I'm surrounded by huggers.
I look cool.
Hey, Uncle Wayne.
The world's a lot less strong
without you buddy.
Oh no, oh no, no decorations in here, no.
No, no, and yes.
No... No!
What?
Something wrong?
You got over 30 scented
candles in my room.
Oh, the wedding scent is lavender.
The wedding scent? And people
wonder why I'm not married.
Not really.
And seriously, my Uncle Wayne is
rolling over his grave right now.
Oh come on, Wayne liked a good party.
Party yes, but Wayne no.
Back in the days, that man used this
place for a mind numbing, clothing...
...optional weekend of orgies.
You and Dean Martin slept in that
bathroom, he drank from the day and...
...sang the Canadian national anthem...
Now that, that was a party.
Not this.
You know people are taking that
back to where they're not eating...
See that's what I said.
The whole asshole in you is just
to get women to sleep with you.
Deep down you're a big sweetheart.
Oh, look who's got me pegged.
There's the side calender to cover
up the accidental display of affection...
...for Paul.
Hey.
I'm not covering anything up.
And I'd be more than happy to take
off the rest of my clothes to prove that.
And there's the cheap sexual innuendo.
Don't worry, your secrets safe with me.
I won't tell anyone you have feelings.
OK, didn't work still nervous.
Ooh, Sandy, what the him?
Dan, married.
Kids?
What? They're not really married
unless they have kids.
Heard, understood, acknowledge.
Sandy, come on.
Try and save some liquor for
the rest of the guys.
Bye.
- Miss you soon my real pledge.
Slow down, slow down.
Hey, you keep those coming all night.
Thank you. And now we're off.
Excuse me Mr. Mead, I just want to
tell you I'm a huge fan of your work.
Thank you.
So you're gonna photograph
the bride's wedding?
No, no, I'm not a wedding photographer.
Right, but it's your brother.
Right.
He's not good at taking pictures
of people with their clothes on.
Look who's funny.
It's not his specialty.
Turn your phone off.
Connor Mead.
No, I would not like to cut my cord.
Look, just tell him to go screw himself.
Yeah, I said go tell him to screw himself.
...Got to go, got to go.
Sit down sweetie.
Oh my God.
- What?
What is this?
- A salad.
No, no, no, no, the salad I ordered had fix.
This is a disaster.
My friends didn't come over here to
be met with some lacklustre salad...
...where are the figs?
Excuse me, where are the figs?
Sweetie...
- OK, I want some figs.
Sweetie, sweetie, hi.
Hi, hi.
- Hi.
OK, you're right, you did order figs.
But everyone seems to be loving the...
...salad, right? Anybody missing figs?
- No, no.
Sorry.
There she is. Alright. She's back.
- I'm sorry everyone, I just...
It's my wedding and I'm not
usually a bitch.
There it is.
I just want everything to stay up... I
mean I only planned on getting married...
...four or five times tops.
Oh sweet.
Which reminds me Connor, Sandy and
I wanted to know if you would make...
...a toast tomorrow?
What?
Yeah, we'd like that.
I know it's not really your thing but
it's kind of a tradition for the best...
...man to give a toast.
You could keep it short.
Shoot the bomb, whatever you want.
Are you kidding?
Yes.
No, no. No, you're the only family I
got here so I thought you could say...
...something.
I don't think this is the best idea
you've ever had Paul.
Hey, I'm with Jenny on this one.
I'm sure you could describe a cousin.
No. No, no, no, you're my brother, you're
funny, you're articulate, you're...
...smart.
True, true, and true.
I'm flattered really.
If you're not gonna take pictures,
it's the least you can do.
Who the hell is this guy?
Who's that?
Jeff.
I'm not toasting anyone tomorrow, OK?
I can't toast this.
Come on.
This always happens. All scotch, no carbs.
Is there a bread basket or... you know
what let's talk about something else.
So, when do you catch your flight?
Paulie, you know where I come
out in all of this buddy.
To me marriage is an archaic oppresive
institution, it should have been...
...abolished years ago.
It's magical comfort food for the
weak and the uneducated.
Yeah, it makes you feel all warm and
relevant but in the end love leaves...
...you weak, dependant and fat.
Yeah, that might not make the best toast.
Are you saying I'm fat?
No.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, sweetie...
...he's being funny, I think.
Better hold your next words
real close paco.
Believe me, for Paul's sake, I wish
I could believe in all this crap...
...I do.
I also wish I could believe in
the Easter bunny.
The missle shield and strippers
with a heart of gold.
Unfortunately, I am condemned to see
the world as it really is and love...
...love is a myth.
Oh good, I was afraid you were going
to make a really long cynical speech.
Truth hurts baby.
Why don't you go?
Yeah, why don't I do that?
I'm going to take my salad with me.
Some figs would be nice.
This is gonna be tougher than I thought.
You got that right kid.
Uncle Wayne.
You're dead.
Please.
Don't waste your life like I did.
What are you talking about?
You had a great life man. You're a legend.
The money, the parties, the women.
The music stops, you lick a few slacks,
none of that stuff matters with...
...the few links.
Well, there was this one party, New
Year '68 Philippines, me, Stevie...
...McQueen, 17 stewardess' and a
pile of blow the size of a toaster...
...now that was a good night.
Sounds like a great night.
I got a few laughs, I chase some tail,
but trust me Dutch, you don't want...
...to end up like me.
What are you talking about?
No, no, no, I've seen it for the sandman
kid. I've been watching you.
And you are definitely turning
out like me.
Frankly who could blame you. But
tonight, tonight things are gonna change.
Tonight you're gonna be
visited by three ghosts.
You've got to be kidding me.
And you're gonna be forced to feel
things you haven't felt in a long time.
Things like feelings for example.
And remember not matter how much
it hurts, it's all for your own good.
And the stuff that's not for your own
good, it's or my entertainment.
Look, Uncle Wayne...
Where did he go?
I don't believe this happened.
Uh-oh.
Melanie.
Melanie where are you?
I need you up here.
You are my assistant and
I need assistance.
Blue label and give it weed brother.
Call me.
You feel so real.
Well, I am honey.
A hundred percent.
I'm not sure what you heard about me,
but I usually like drink first.
You and I thought you were.
Vonda Volkom, mother of the bride.
Connor Mead. Brother of the groom.
Please sit, Vonda Volkom.
Thank you.
Yes ma'am. Champagne for the lady.
Lovely.
So how long have you been divorced?
I beg your pardon.
I mean you're ravishing.
No married woman your age
keeps her form this fine.
I've been divorced eight years now.
Sarge and I aren't just talking just yet.
It's juvenile and sad.
- Honey you stop right there. It's not...
...your fault.
Again marriage is a corrupt
and hateful institution.
I've given all of this at another table.
I want to ask you something.
When did casual sex become a crime?
Really. I mean nowadays being single
means what? You've lost your way...
...or something is missing?
...every night I swim in a lake of sex.
And they fall asleep in each
others arms spooning.
Connor, spooning is nice.
Yeah, but not as nice as fucking.
You know what the owner of
this place once told me.
He said keep it light Dutch.
Keep it light.
I never understood why he
called me Dutch but...
That's nice.
I like that.
Listen darling, before we take this to
the next level, are we off limits?
I mean technically we're not
family until tomorrow.
I am extremely flattered.
But yes, we are definitely off limits.
That's a shame. I bet you know your
way around the bedroom.
You always talk to women like this?
Yes.
Does it work?
Well, while I can't be of service
to you, I am sure that she can.
Blonde, 6 o'clock.
Blue dress, legs up to her chin.
That's the one.
She's been eye the whole
time we've been talking.
It's been a plesure talking to you.
Likewise.
You are truly an inspiration.
Hi.
- Just for a second.
Oh, you remember that guy I was
telling you about, Brad.
No, no, no, I told you I do not want to
be set up again. I've been through it...
...too many times. Please don't make me.
That's Brad.
OK, this is the last time.
How are my teeth?
Clear.
Just play it cool. No big deal.
Brad. Here's Jenny.
Right, hot single doctor.
Hi.
Sandra has been talking
about you non-stop.
Yeah, I already know what kind of car
you drive, where you went to med school...
...how many dogs you have...
So glad this is not...
Brad loves to run travel inns too.
Do you want to go anywhere else?
Yeah, I thought you'd never ask.
Bye.
- You guys have a good time, you crazy...
...toots.
Hey Connor.
- Hey.
How you been?
Well, I'm at a wedding.
I'm seeing ghosts in the john.
I've been better.
What were you and Sandra's
mom talking so intensely?
Casual sex.
What's your stand on casual
sex bridesmaid?
On top.
I mean I'm for it.
Speaking of which, I think
I owe you an apology.
I've enjoyed the company of all the
other bridesmaids except you.
I mean you must feel terribly left out.
I do hope there's some way
to rectify this injustice.
Well, you know what I always say
to think globally, act locally.
Listen, before I commence launch codes.
Are you the one my brother slept with
because I don't like to cross sword.
Wait, what?
Your brother slept with one
of the bridesmaids?
Oh I guess it wasn't you.
Alright, from now on, I don't cross
swords... listen, forget I even brought...
...it up anyway, why don't you scamper
up to my room, boil some water...
...get the chicken claw out of my
suitcase, do some light stretching and...
...I'll be up in five.
Chicken claw, OK.
- Chicken claw.
And that's how it's done.
Does it work on guys?
Probably.
Excuse me, do you mind if we
take these seats?
No please.
Hullo there, friend.
Connor Mead, brother of the groom.
This is Brad.
Hi, nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
Must be the wedding sex they
flew in for Jenny here.
And you must be the wedding sex
they brought in for everyone else.
Look, he's getting his little
joust splashed.
He's gotten it ever since he was
a little kid. Adorable.
Oh, honey if I was jealous, why am I at
this very moment heading upstairs...
...at my hattrick of bridesmaids.
Maybe because you're terrified of being
left alone with your empty hollow...
...soul for even a minute.
Ooh, you've got a live one here Brad.
Look, maybe I'd better go.
- No, Brad, you're staying.
Running along Connor, there's a bridesmaid
waiting to be partially satisfied.
Absolutely.
Brad's pleasure. I hope you enjoy pillow
fights, talking about our feelings...
...and sharing massages with
your clothes on.
Jenny.
Connor.
That's more like it.
How is my little sex button mixture of
gin and long haired blue eyed happy...
...meal of a bridesmaid?
Hi Connor.
Have you missed me?
Who are you?
You don't remember?
Allison Vandermeersh?
Connor, it's me.
Remember it's me. Oh, I could die now.
I'm just kidding. I'm totally kidding.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm like a ghost now.
Yeah, yeah, the ghost of past.
It tickles.
Connor.
Don't want to go.
We could do this all day dude.
You're not real.
You can't be. You're just repressed
memory activated by all the booze...
...and the trauma... but you are not real.
Alright well, then miss you.
See you next fall.
Isn't it real enough for you?
What? Be cool.
What are you gonna do?
I am going to take you back to all of
your past girlfriends and hopefully...
...you and I can figure out how you got
your head so far up your own ass.
Ready?
Ta-da.
Alright, what the hell is going on?
We're still at your Uncle Wayne's only
now we're in 1982 which is of course...
...the summer of your first relationship.
Connor.
Oh, how cute you were. I want
to squeeze you.
Oh, we knew who she was of course.
Jenny Perotti.
I win.
126 for you, 120 for me.
I beat you by 6.
- No way.
It's your birthday. I let you win,
it's your gift.
Then what's that?
Can they see us?
No, we're ghosts.
Do you like it?
Yeah, it's great.
You're the best Jenny.
Really? What else do you think of me?
I don't know.
You see how young we start.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, line it up
buddy. Get in there.
This doesn't even look like you.
You look like a girl.
What Connor?
Let's wait for your part.
I'm gonna keep it forever.
I don't think I said that.
Did you edit this?
I'm gonna keep it forever.
Are you sure it wasn't my brother?
He always said fruity stuff like that.
I'm gonna keep it forever.
Forever... forever.
OK, I get it.
I said it.
I'm gonna keep it forever.
Not as dumb as he looks folks.
Mom and dad.
This was the summer before
their car accident.
Look how happy they were.
Uncle Wayne, Paul and Jenny
were all you had left.
She knew you before you became you.
Alright.
Alright, what's next?
New school, really?
You remember this, right?
Pretty sure I intentionally
brought it down.
I'm sure that we don't have
time for this, do we?
So as you and Jenny got older, you
tried to make that super top transition...
...from being best friends to maybe
being boyfriend girlfriend.
This dance is so lame.
- Totally.
I don't why but there's something creepy
about the whole white glove thing.
Nice move.
Who's going groove Franklin Middle School.
I'm gonna slow it down... guys grab that
special girl and head on out...
...to the dance floor.
Ask her to dance buddy. She's
asking for it. Ask her.
So...
Jenny.
Oh my God, Jenny. Neil just told Suzie
that Pete Hastings wants to floor...
...dance with you.
Pete Hastings is totally gorge.
No, Pete Hastings is now bald and
doing civil war reenactments on the...
...weekends.
Yeah, and he's gonna want to make out.
Yeah, and he's a ninth grader
so that means tongue.
Oh my God, I can't believe
how lucky you are. Pete Hastings.
OK, I guess.
- Yes.
That dude used to get boners in
the gym shower. Don't sweat it.
Well, at least he didn't choke.
Hey, I didn't choke, alright?
I could close if I wanted to.
I was being a gentleman.
I can't breathe.
You know what, you don't want to
hit that anyway little man.
Hey kid, what's with the water works?
Jenny.
Pregnant.
No.
Crabs?
Took her to the coat check room, found
out she had a tin pinned up her chest?
Don't worry, happens to all of us.
Wait, what?
Nothing, nothing. So what happened?
Jenny kissed Pete Hastings tonight.
Her first kiss.
Now everything is ruined and I don't
even know if we're gonna get married...
:::anymore:
Trust me kid. You dodged a bullet. You
don't want to be anybody's first kiss...
...or their last.
Say what you will, that man
was a visionary.
You know he invented the word Milf.
What am I gonna do? I've
never felt this way before.
I feel like somebody has punched me
straight in the stomach and I feel...
...like I'm gonna throw up.
I hate girls.
That's sissy talk.
Never talk like that in the
Stabbing Wagon.
Uncle Wayne, where are your seatbelts?
Again with the sissy talk.
He never wore seatbelts. Never.
Look, kid I'm sorry I raised my voice
at you. Being a parent ain't exactly...
...my chosen profession, you know.
I mean I can't teach you algebra or
camping or even ethics.
But when it comes to dames,
I've got a gift.
Really?
Because I will do anything you say.
I never want to feel like this again.
Ever.
OK, Dutch. Never again. Hang on.
Are we in a bar?
Think of it like classroom.
Hi ya Tommy. Two jacks up please.
Dutch, try that old saddle up for size.
Rule number one, don't look at 'em.
Dames, they're like horses.
They spook easy.
Cheers Dutch.
Rule number two, never sorry
to be wingman.
Sorry.
...if you're actually out chasing tail
tonight, I'd turn your gaff into a funny.
Girls, they love to laugh.
Especially at men.
Makes them feel more powerful which
in turn makes them feel more comfortable.
Which in turn makes them crawl into
massive errors ofjudgement like...
...having sex in with a complete
stranger in a bathroom.
But I'm not even supposed to
talk to strangers.
That's good, that's good. No talking
is good. No phone numbers...
...no last names. Hey no first names
if you could swing it.
Will somebody please call the...
Quiet, the prophet speaks.
See kid, an ugly broad, you might as well
take her behind the shed and one...
...broom behind the ear,
that dog won't hunt.
But any dude with ajohnson,
because cool come from the inside.
God, I miss that man.
See, here's a couple of tips.
When you first meet a girl, you give
her two compliments above the neck...
...you tell her she's got nice lips, nice
eyes, nice hair, intelligent, her...
...moral ethics, whatever crap
comes to your mind.
Then, just when she begins to think
that you're another vanilla nice guy...
...she can tool around all night
without getting naked, you insult her...
...foot the power of dynamic, and you
let her know you're here to play.
Jenny said she doesn't like games.
Forget about that broad.
But I thought I was supposed to
get her back.
That's why you got to forget about her.
If you have feelings for her then
your killing your game.
If there's one thing that you learnt
tonight, it's this the power of a...
...relationship lies with whoever
cares less.
One day you're gonna wake up with
some chick spooning, you know...
...thinking about love and at that
moment, you have got to get up, you do...
...not walk, you do not get your
shoes, you run the hell out of there...
...because maybe not the next day or
next week but sometime in the future...
...you're gonna get crushed again.
Now you don't want to feel
that way, do you?
OK, so let's get down to brass text here.
Say I wanted to pick up on that ice
cold blonde at 8 o'clock.
8 o'clock?
How did you even see her?
We'll deal with reflective surfaces
another time.
Should I get a handful of daisies and go
hi do you want to go to a disco with me?
Uh, no.
- No.
No, cause I might as well say I'm
a fag, let's be friends.
So what could be a smart play?
Have some fun with it. What do you think?
Maybe you could talk to the
girl next door.
Maybe make her feel jealous.
Hand of God kid. I never felt like you
were my son until now.
Oh man, I don't know why we didn't have
this conversation years ago huh?
That enough for one night! Let's have a break?
What about the wain?
You gotta put smaller bag!
Come on.
I gonna get won't be right!
Please...
This celebration is going down!
Here we go!
Watch this move!
I gotta said I remember the ladies
been fit more glad for us!
And that does is how is does!
Let's hold some.
But you just strugle out!
You well!
Just because she not in fact...
doesn't mean i'm not!
I gotta gift!
Oh well, darling, what take you so long?
Alright and you not in the same.
Come on!
Look a the day make...
Oh I know is smell good!
Jenny?
You didn't see two years
ruin the head in master!
Oh hey, Carl is here!
Oh yeah, I got the new poison!
I heard this uncle Hold scholl
in Vegas in last three years!
Really, I heard it was in bangkok!
Nice move buddy!
- Yeah, he been all part...
...about your uncle invite to actually work.
My god...
He don't wanna talk to you!
You look like...
Hope of them!
Look at me, is me, is me!
Oh my god!
We did it! That 39 minute!
And that was be best
to be my young life!
You'll happy with work!
You didn't got the girl you really love!
But you did get every girl in highschool
starting with me in very nice...
Remember that? First time?
I was in that...
Is over!
Connor Mead first sex partner!
That like feel, I feel Mead Armstrong!
Is really the only thing I could wait
you know, you know...
...to brought idea... are you?
You know him and moon,
me and you is like you the first!
You know like Jenny was your first love!
But you have to brought love in
your hair before you sorry that
Everywoman is beautiful in someway!
I like to figure it how,
I gotta see it! I gotta film it!
Force it!
And actual and yeah...
Jenny perotti
Connor Mead. Hey!
Good gorgeous!
Thank you darling!
Ladies, you gonna have to excuse me...
I must buy a drink a girl who blew
me up for hasting in me
I so please you!
Excuse us for a second.
Maybe that ajoke!
Jenny Perotti!
Yeah...
What did you doing in all the woman?
I work for his breath.
You know the famous target!
You had the target for?
I give you your first kiss.
You sure did!
So what did you, what did you doing?
And I'm a doctor, well, first in all the day!
Her press god that impressive!
Yeah, I means second shoe...
I bank in a hundred fifteen k a years,
is totally love my job!
Hey, those, those 30 Martiny
must all the thirty pound on me!
I can't believe you just said that!
You know what?
You just told me you sorry
and you suppose be in way guy
You told me to cheat now.
- Get out!
You gonna try that in sadness...
You damn right, you get to trying this...
Is gorgeous!
Getting invite you have a
drink and see how you been...
How you been?
Damn!
Son of the bitch!
Hey, Jen!
We're leaving!
But you can wait.
I'm going!
You got it, just give me your number!
No, I don't!
- Yes, you do doc!
Alright, I have matter can do I need
to see you about my last...
...that you have to help...
Come on, let all go out or have
fun or I have a little dinner!
Have a little sex!
Ok, ok, just have sex!
How about this here?
Guys, this just not why you girls...
There is good, there is good!
Yeah! I love that!
You know what...
I'm pretty hunger right now,
Yeah, no one condition...
you gotta about new out...
You are cookie great pilot!
Well, I have to calling caps?
No...
Where should get up great is 150k a years.
I do...
Alright, some deprecating
steak really work.
Why you not putting in my back place.
I'm generally concern that you
might be seem there a voice.
Good night.
Hold on a sec. I means I been care you job...
No, we just met today.
What did you talking about?
No, until i arrive!
Until night that came out here!
You down with this!
But...
You cannot come up!
I wanna see the one weird things!
See you!
Got a wound here.
Only things is dude!
Don't worry, is actually not my benefit.
This is not at all!
What next?
Wow!
What is the romantic...
Wait me with that action sequenze,
will you?
Thank you so much, everything is great!
Oh here we go!
Oh, that is amazing!
What did you doing?
Oh, I gotta get home, something in the
earlier morning I have to take care of
Yeah, me too!
Jenny, I don't tell stay over...
- Wait Connor, listen...
There two type of woman in this world
woman you shake and evil
I glad to be in some of kind
So, you got 3 second to get back in
this bed where you belong
and tell you actually wanna be.
Or you right out my apartment
and never call me again!
One...
Three.
See Connor is truly fall in love with Jenny.
Is the creepy rather end...
This is the moment
they realize you stupid!
So, you did what you do best.
Well, I don't wanna screw this...
Hello?
Oh!
No, this is Dr. Perotti.
Ok, I'll be there 15...
Ok, good!
Now is stop before you
fishery you came Connor Mead.
Come on, I buy you a drink!
Social in factthat be easier to do some work!
Hey, Connor
We're playing sex somewhere in Manchester!
And self fended here...
You slept with my sister.
- You slept with my sister.
I shock about that!
Away to set the paul...
We did it for two day.
Connor, we at 48 second.
We have sex on your car.
Let me know when you call me again!
Never call me again,
everytime you start with me
you call me Jenny!
How much woman I going out?
- All...
Wow!
- This is somekind of weird!
We miss you Connor!
Connor, stay with us!
Step off.
Get off.
Oh god!
That complicated our guest reputation by...
All knew you guest are now...
I try to enter that sir!
Move five man and 4 personality...
Oh my God, I like Gunny Luncher!
Daddy, you not showing up foragain, are you?
Oh god!
Oh not good!
No good!
I need something hold you up.
Is not work!
Ok, Sarjan...
Oh, this is Volkom!
Try to keep up some
And now you know the weeding party is...
Watch out of the flower...
Would you like to dance?
Thank you, but I just watch...
Oh, nice spray.
Where you learn for this?
I just spend sometime in Columbia!
Are you the drug...
Wow!
Well, se your ridiculars with good ask...
Is we gonna know that?
What's going on?
Oh god!
Did you see what happen?
Here we go!
No!
Look, I will fix this.
In any consulation,
I hate very well in good!
You had piece!
Look, is plyer in my mouth. At my opinion.
Is some valuable
Is my wedding cake, you stupid bitch!
And is also a dinner cake...
Release! Release!
I'm fine. I'm fine!
I'm a lady, i am perfesional.
And I fine.
Let's get, let's get out of here.
Let's see we can stabilize there,
I got the cake in charge here.
Let's see some happy face.
Big happy. Big happy.
Where did you think you going?
Oh no!
Connor is ruining the weeding!
He is also ruin operation sex experience
What?
No one call me to go by perm they call
by dark and who talking self inside!
Dude, that guys in my gift and unbelievable
To next round
Wait!
No!
Oh shut up!
You never told us that!
- That something great
Look like them are
cross them down gred...
Hey, guys!
Woman!
Said this is them.
Yeah, someway is doing this...
- Are you kidding me?
Calling me to cleaning this mess!
You know what, I'm sorry!
Is just a cake!
Is not being open the town.
I'm not gonna talking about this!
I'm talking about us!
You know, hard place that hard.
You actually appologist, are you?
Alright, we no need production...
You know what probably
some small way actually before...
Is always attractive asshole!
Thank you very much!
- You know what I means...
Guys i thought I could fix!
Probably is something
i could do with my dad!
Probably?
- Yeah, after you left
I make without myself to did very
fully function adjust this man...
...no more work in progress!
- Woman...
- Basically woman!
And had that tattoo in my ass!
What did you doing?
- What?
What are I'm doing? What?
You know I drop the ball before.
I have change, I swear, now I have!
And easier things...
now different way that night...
I love you, I think now we have,
you the one I was suppose to be with.
Connor, just stop it!
I hear what you saying and I think
I know you actually but...
I know you, tomorrow morning
you wake up, you won't be there.
Ok, give me a chance, really.
Really, I don't wanna be alone in the night!
Ok!
Please stay, seriously!
And I got gold in my bedroom!
Hello, Connor!
Dude!
What is the girl to do
in late of this way?
Yeah, all this way.
God!
Stop!
What did you think you doing?
Oh!
Oh man! God I happy to see you!
Really, do you not learnd anything in last ghost?
You think ghost girl friends present.
I meant that sense!
Oh, damn you about it!
This is sad that doing on your
consistant woman ruining your life!
So do I am, just working in the weekend!
No...
I was just one timing calling and I wanna buy...
I have no choice!
Hey, I'm sorry man!
If I know, I know you alot!
What is that for?
Because tonight, I'm the boss!
You ready?
What are you doing?
I like fly off something...
Is a present who here... we here on ready.
Mel!
Hey, looking what the fun
having not that your gone!
Charlece, you spend every Christmas
alone after next games!
Is it defence is a really hot service.
Alright, is not that bad.
Thank you Polly.
Hey, behave your mother in law!
You just know my good...
You don't know that guys is race me!
I was two in the pend died...
College seven!
And they are suppose to be kitty...
...she busy taking care...
He talk me in read...
He taught me how ride a bike...
He be the quite by any kids who teach me.
And he always said, Polly,
you and me againts the world
My voice is I did opportunity to be,
you know is kids Connor do.
I know seem like a... joke you got
and then trust they all fear point...
But like guys you and family I got!
And this is one things family does
it is believe...
I guess all in the best with each other!
I love as long as i go and change
cause is is my big bro!
They call my brother!
Is been a while!
Of cause that didn't means anything to you!
Because lost doesn't take this jake
Is just matter come
through weekend in educated
Fatherjust cross the ever come to
feeling something Connor Mead
I still don't wanna doing.
I'll be scrumbing and charging here!
Oh like when to meet so
deplicated really call man...
I was drunk...
Oh, you think that better then me and
the Conner is doing the Journey!
He got back girl in twisties
until the pencil,
she can't even appreaciated
that behind that kick in Andy...
Wow!
Jenny, she just...
Jenny?
Jesus, is she ok?
What do you think?
Jenny?
Of course, sensitive Brad rescues!
Wait the second, you actually
try to prepare in wedding cake!
Maybe! The little!
You tell me this guys is gay!
He's not, just me.
Really?
You wanna talk about it?
That your doesn't means in wedding sex
everything you seen is privillage
No, i just... is been like a dedecate since Connor and I...
You know...
When i see him again,
I just pay back to where was before
You attenting to say the doctor is never
break up we just going the mission
When actually drown the hope in patient.
That you screw up!
The terminal cases!
We get the point Brad!
This just embarassing, you know?
I think you only look at somebody.
When you find somebody else
that you care about more!
Oh this is nightmare!
I bring in the gather!
Is very cute...
No, really not!
Come on! Let's go!
Let's see how this play are!
Ok, you the boss!
Really?
I just can't...
How many all of us?
Other things that really?
Is seem like you wanna fall in love with them.
And one weeks gather that we did!
Just disappear!
Kiki, don't cry!
At least kinda brought us together, right?
Hey, Clarissa go Charlece test the
winning out how we gonna bite sound
All we got the relationship,
and friendship right?
Here we go, so exciting have feel way...
Martiny?
- This is your apartment?
Looking good!
- Mel!
I got Apple, bubble gum or Tandorri.
I know is sound close with
anyone to be you taste...
Cheer!
You brought them together?
- Come on!
Can't decide that Richard!
Honest is worthy!
He's like a thin man!
He was brully out the heart!
And ladies!
Know this!
That what ever calling laser had tonight!
When the sun come up in the morning!
He will be all alone!
Is all you gonna bet!
Is not your great!
What are this woman hate me?
No... I don't hate them.
Woman love to be screw!
They just don't like to be screw!
I know is noice!
Maybe I have a few woman in my time
A few woman?
That please!
Don't calling...
How is it?
Wheather trick?
- No trick...
This all the ladies here that had
been shit with you in your life!
And this, is the Tissue
they use to dry the tears
And this the chocolate they eats...
No, you don't send chocolate!
Becauise is straight to the head!
Right, and this all the condom you use!
No... get off!
Guys, you not gonna believe
what just happen to me!
Is about the cake?
No, this is not about the cake!
This is about the practice paused
that information that you...
...so kind this should would
denice all you tonight
Come on, i don't want that a years ago.
This seem to be some
debate about the time line!
No, there is no...
We were going out,
we were together in cheat of this
That you right, that you right, that importants...
...important that I hurt you, listen, baby...
Listen, not baby me!
You have sex with her and
then you didn't even tell me...
I not know about you!
Nothing, there is nothing else
hey, I'm so sorry sweety...
I never meant to hurt you!
Cool, right there...
He saw it, he need it, case close!
- Case close!
Because one appologist make
everything all better right? Connor?
No, Jenny, make it ok!
Is that Paul still clearly love her!
You the expert on love?
You don't even believe in it!
Here I'm gonna said, I can tell
that you two love each other...
Then you must really love each other!
You know I do, honey!
I love you so much!
You did! That girl been like a male patient
the past 12 hours!
How did she even trust her anymore?
You talk about my brother,
you talk about me?
And that good something else...
This always down...
A fact that you let her
let my seem to god!
I'm seriously!
If you ruin that marriage anyone
that bridgemate house left with...
You been have to go bar,
you got a husband!
Get out Connor!
Connor.
I want you to leave.
You better end this thing up now.
You're-
- Connor! Leave!
God! You've been nothing but make
this weekend rust for everyone.
Paulie!
Hey come on. Hey Paul.
Hey man, look. I'm sorry.
- They were right.
I never should've invited you.
You know, for years, I keep trying
to convince myself there's something-
redeemable in you.
I'm done here. There isn't.
I was just trying to get you back
in there, Ok? Instead-
It's you and me against the world,
right?
You don't wanna be here.
And nobody wants you here.
Please go.
Just please.
Sandy!
I know I've got one more ghost
sleep on my contract.
But right now I'll leave the premises.
So if you want me, come on.
Of course, I wouldn't mind seeing
my future ghost.
Because that was the ghost that
I'm really looking forward to.
But whatever.
Whoa!
Are you my future girlfriend?
Would you like to be?
Oh no, I getting married?
Ok, this girl look-
As a matter of fact,
this may be alright.
Brad? No.
No...
No!
And now if anyone here know any reason
why these two should not be wed?
I do.
- You better speak now or-
You're suppose to be with me.
No, she's always suppose to
be with me.
No! Don't you risk this walk!
No! I'm here! I'm here!
Paulie.
No wedding ring.
He didn't get married?
Why?
What did I do?
You don't say much, do you?
Looks like we're all here.
Let's begin.
Before we gather here today to
lay the rest of Connor Mead.
Connor Mead was a great man and
great friend of the church.
Is that the only person at my funeral?
That's the way it works, Dutch.
Guys like us...
We don't get a big funeral.
I didn't expect big...
Uncle Wayne but this is-
this is ridiculous.
Yeah, I don't know how to solve this
for you, Dutch.
Nobody's really gonna miss you.
Before the burial, would you like to
say a few words about him?
Connor Mead was a lot of things
to a lot of people.
Not all those things
but to me he was a great brother.
I guess it's just me
against the world now.
No, it's not, Paul.
No it's not.
Look, hey.
It won't have to happen like this.
It's not gonna happen.
There's nothing you can do
about it, Dutch.
You made your bet and you gotta bear
whatever calls into it.
That's what I keep trying to tell you.
What can I say?
Life, you know, is like a-
quick cup of coffee.
You end with a cup and love someone
and love with all you got.
You never drink it alone.
No, I wouldn't-
Sorry, kid. Party's over.
Ladies, let's take it away.
I'm alive!
Are you there? Young man.
Well what day is it?
It isn't Christmas?
No, it's Saturday, you moron.
That's the day of my brother's wedding.
Alright. I'll just have to think-
Yes! We're now ready for this hop.
Hey... Paul.
Hey.
Did I miss the wedding?
No. You got your wish.
Sandra call it off.
- What?
Why?
- What are you saying?
The day I took up Donna?
Yeah.
- No...
No, you can split it up.
Alright. The two of you are meant to
spend the rest of your life together.
You're gonna be miserable without her.
Trust me.
You know, you can be a real
sarcastic prick sometimes.
I'm not being sarcastic, Ok?
So who was taking her?
Sir is taking her and the bridesmaid
to the airport.
It's over.
No!
Sandra!
What are you doing?
No seatbelt!
Sandra!
Hey!
Sandra you better get to a side.
Is that Connor?
Sandra!
Oh shit!
Whoa!
You better kill us right there.
Sandra!
- Get away.
I'm trying to stop your daughter.
Over my dead body, papo.
Alright? Relax.
I was real sorry, sir.
You've just come too far.
Did he just walked us-
Will you listen to me?
Hey, first off.
I'm sorry about destroying
your wedding cake.
Going second base with your mother.
Knocking your dad unconscious
and tried it there.
And basically-
brighten up your wedding.
Sorry.
But the thing is that I am begging you,
begging you, don't run away, alright?
You and Paul have something so rare
that's just so powerful.
Don't you get out now.
Chicken out? He cheated.
You'll get over it.
It was years ago.
Alright. With one of that
slutty friend of yours.
Yeah that's true.
A friend who you've never
even mad at.
And you know why?
Because you're the one he care.
You loved Paul so much you forget
at the second you're hurt.
And that's what scares you.
You have no idea how I feel. No idea!
- Yes, I do.
I've been in your shoes.
You know what did scare the hell
out of me too?
What if she hurts me?
You know, what if she love me?
What if she died?
Lt'll be the end of me.
So I cut it short.
Before she ever got it.
And you know what?
That was the biggest mistake
I have ever made.
And you're making the same mistake
right now...
and I'd be God dead
if I'm just gonna sit by and watch.
You're in the risk club.
Risk it.
I didn't.
Look at me.
I'm the only ghost of a man.
It doesn't mean that you're not
gonna get hurt.
I can guarantee you this.
Any pain that you feel,
will never ever compare to the regret
that comes from walking away from love.
So is that what love's about?
Trust me.
Pain...
beats regret everyday in a week and twice
on Sunday.
Don't run away.
Don't do it.
I don't think I'm saying this but-
You wanna get married?
I do.
- You do.
Yes!
Oh baby.
Flowers. Check.
Cake, check.
Dinner, check.
Photographer.
I know a pretty good photographer.
It was cold and dark.
We've been taking fire for hours.
Took an incoming mortar yet.
All I end up with jacketless and
insight and fell out.
In my head is bloody guts in my hand.
Feel warm and mushy and squishy.
And I pushed him right back with body
cavity and wisdom to live with my tears.
And that is what true love is.
To love.
- To love.
I guess now is a good time for me
to make the best man's toast.
I've never gotten one of this before. So-
So bear it with me.
Someone once told me that the power
of all relationships lies with...
whoever cares less
and he was right.
That's-
and nobody proves that better
than my kid brother Paul.
Buddy you give love...
to everyone.
And you require none in return.
And this day on,
I wanna be more like you.
I want you to be proud of me again.
Yeah.
And here's to my new sister.
All I can really say here all that
I know for sure.
As to mom and dad.
They who loved you.
I'm glad you become our family.
This is to Paul and Sandra.
Look here. Look right here. Ok.
How old are you?
Oh what's the matter?
Don't bite your hand.
Alright. I'm done.
We're really worried about you.
Let me remind you as man's heart
resident.
You're serving duties
for the single ladies here tonight.
That is very tempting.
Yes, it is. But-
I'm out.
Ladies, thank you but
no thank you.
Hey, I think it will all work
if you eventually give in.
Hey!
Hey.
Congratulations.
You do... pull off the wedding.
We pulled off the big wedding.
Of course I would've broken it
and you'd fix it.
I do.
Ok, I have to know.
What happened to you last night?
It was just yesterday you were
just usual and awful self.
And then today you became
the guy I used to know.
Well I always thought
deep down you actually were.
I honestly don't know what the hell
happen to me last night.
You know. But I do know that I'm seeing
things more clearly today than-
anytime that I can remember.
How good I feel about you.
That's something that has never changed.
I wish I could believe.
We've just been through this before.
It's like-
And all I know is that it's not just
another line...
from the me and family playbook.
Look at that.
You keep it.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm missing the days actually.
L-
I can't believe it.
Give me one more chance.
I'll do better.
More than all the things.
The rulings, I'm all in.
Your moustache verticle is on.
No. Not a chance.
I promise you this.
When you wake up in the morning,
I'll be there. Everyday.
What?
What is it?
Nothing.
I just recognize this song.
Oh yeah.
May I have this dance?
Finally.
He hates this. You too are now.
That's how it should.
What do you say? Let's get naked.
Dry. I love it.
You know, I've interviewed before
a new secretary.
How good is your dictation?
Again"dick-tation"
I'm actually at this party.
Looks like it's just you and me,
sweetie.
I love those squirshy.
I'm only 16.
We're ghost, baby.
We're ageless.
...Subs By aBDu...