DIARY OF A LOST GIRL
after the novel
by Margarete Böhme
Script: Rudolf Leonhardt
Direction: G. W. Pabst
So you've had your way
with this housekeeper too!
Why is Elisabeth leaving.
- today of all days?
PHARMACY
Oh why does Elisabeth
have to go away?
l'll tell you about it this
evening - little Thymian!
- big Thymian!
My confirmation gift!
But... l'm no countess!
That doesn't matter -
l'M Count Osdorff!
This evening at half-past 10
in the pharmacy
This is Meta,
my new housekeeper!
Good night, Herr Pharmacist!
l'm all alone!
l want to be here for you!
l'll tell you what happened
with Elisabeth!
- l'll tell you everything!
And she doesn't want to
say who the father is.
You have to marry her.
Yes, if the pharmacy weren't
so heavily mortgaged - !
Of course, Thymian
must be asked, too.
l can't marry him:
l don't even love him - !
Don't lay a finger on the
innocent child, - you - !
The family -
- has decided -
Ww. Bolke: Midwife
RULES OF ATTENDANCE:...
Forbidden...
Dear Father,
Dear Osdorff,
l am so unhappy.
Your nephew still doesn't
want to obey, Herr Count.
l've tried everything with you,
every school and every trade:
you've failed at all of them!
Now l've had enough! See
how far you get on your own.
In  the reformatory one lived
according to the house-rules.
And so the housekeeper
became the lady of the house.
Thymian's Room
NURSERY
Count Osdorff resolved
to help Thymian.
Dear Osdorff:
l am so unhappy.
What did l actually do that l
am treated so strictly and cruelly?
...because Meta has father
wrapped around her finger.
l beg you to go to him. Perhaps then
l'll be able to go home again.
Yours,
Thymian
-...l'm afraid to write to Father:
Meta is so mean... -
l heard that your uncle
has thrown you out -
- go now to Thymian.
You belong together:
the outcast and
the lost-girl.
Go to her -
Tell her something nice - !
Here the pharmacy won't be
auctioned off to you just yet.
now that l possess
the mortgages.
Even the strictest discipline
cannot repress
the girls' desire
to look pretty.
PUNISH ERIKA
Count Nikolaus Osdorff
The Count claims to come
on behalf of your father.
No-one at home wants to know
anything more about you:
Meta has married
your father.
Steal the key,
and l'll help you further.
l'll wait for you tonight
in front of your house!
l know where we can stay.
No: l want to go to my child.
l'll write down for you
where l can be found.
Bar ''FOR TWO ANGELS''
Dessauer Str. 17
I'd like to see my child,
Little Erika Henning -
She happens to be dead -
He just took her away.
Where you headed, Iuv?
- to Erika!
Erika and Count Osdorff are
received with open arms
by the proprietress
of the establishment.
And what's more,
he leaves his regards!
Oh, be reasonable,
little one:
you don't even have
a shirt on your back!
If your friend helps you,
you'll be outta this whole mess!
Me?! l'm penniless, and my uncle
won't give me anything more!
l want to go to work!
What are you able to do,
my poor little thing?
Be so kind as to place
this advert in the paper.
Dance Lessons. Thymian Henning
Dessauer Str. 17
Dance Lessons by the beautiful
Thymian Henning
Little child,
how did you end up here...?
...l tell you, you'll
bitterly regret this!
That's Dr. Vitalis -
he always wants to save us -
- but in the end he joins us.
You look like you're
at a funeral, dear friend:
try and be a li'l happy!
Today's your birthday?
l know how l'll help:
we'll do a lottery for you.
Once a year the pharmacist
takes his wife out on the town.
So here you have the
seamy side of the big city.
And what can you
win with the lot?
Yes, Thymian, now you
are a lost-girl -
- just as we're all lost!
Three years have passed
since the painful meeting
between father and daughter.
Thymian still leads
the same life.
After a brief, trying illness,
my beloved husband,
the pharmacist
Karl Friedrich Henning
passed away yesterday,
on the 17th of June, 1929.
INHERITANCE NOTICES
Thymian Henning, as legal
heir to Herr Henning's estate,
is requested to attend
the reading of the will,
which will take place
in the house of the deceased.
Money will enter the house -
over a short course -
by way of a dark lady!
Why, you're rich!
Yes, l could start
another life -
For another life -
you need a new identity!
He should marry her!
Countess Thymian Osdorff:
there's an identity!
You insist on exercising
your right
to take over the pharmacy....
...and drive your friend's poor
widow out of her home?
Countess, Herr Meinert has
redeemed the mortgage
of 45.000 marks that you
inherited from your mother...
and thus becomes the sole
owner of the pharmacy.
Here is the money.
Filthy slut!
The money!
Where's all the money? -
l gave it to my little sister,
so she doesn't end up like me.
And me? Am l to
blame in the end?
I, his uncle, bear
most of the blame.
l should never have
repudiated that helpless lad!
May l attempt to repay you
with the debt l owe him?
We're now in Swinemünde.
Uncle Osdorff is so kind to me.
My former life often seems
like an ugly, terrible dream.
Cousin Osdorff - !
My niece -
Countess Osdorff:
Little Thymian, you don't
recognize me any more?
Dear Countess, l hope you'll
let me take care of you.
I'd like -
for us to leave!
We beg you, dear Countess,
to work with us
in our society for saving
wayward young girls.
Countess Thymian Osdorff
is invited to the board meeting
and to examine our institution
on 19 August 1929.
Our youngest member -
Countess Osdorff.
Today we have an
especially difficult case.
A young girl has once again
been entrusted to us....
...who has struck down our
every educational measure
by repeatedly
running away.
How we've worried
about her -
Fabulous!! My dear,
try the soup they make here!
Yet she constantly turns away
from the blessings of our home -
l know this house
and its "blessings" -
Your ignorance
won't help her -
l want to try, for l was
once what she is.
A little more love and no-one
would be lost in this world!