Is this our new house?
No, this isn't our new house, bud, this
belongs to one of Mommy's yoga clients.
Yeah, we couldn't
afford this house,
- but we're happy to stay here.
-  Tim... Tim...
This is like a nice
hotel house.
-  Are you gonna be a D-O-U-C-H-E?
-  - No, no, no.
Okay, good.
It's gonna be a really super
fun vacation for our family.
-  Oh!
- - Yeah!
-  Are you excited?
- - Yeah.
All right, Jude, it's time.
He's going first, for sure.
Okay, thank you.
- All right.
Guys, swimming pool.
- Good, right?
- Yeah, it's great.
- I'm really glad we're doing this.
- Me too.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- It's gonna be fun.
- We'll build a fire.
What do you think, buddy?
Good.
- Fun.
- Yeah.
For me now, okay? Perfect.
Oh, yeah. That's called Child's Pose.
You can put your head down right there.
That's a resting pose. Yeah.
It's like a really, really
sweet resting pose.
Okay, and then you're gonna
come up on your hands.
Up. Stay there.
Now we're gonna pretend...
We're gonna come up a little bit,
come up where you just were.
Right here. Okay, now we're
gonna pretend we're a cow.
- We're gonna go like this.
- Okay.
- We go like this.
- A cow.
A cow. And we're gonna
kind of arch our...
Yeah, that's perfect, buddy.
And then we're gonna pretend
we're a cat and go like this.
Left leg,
which is your left leg?
This one.
This one? This one's your right leg.
This one's your left leg.
Okay, you're gonna fold
this one in right here,
and now you're gonna bend over your left
leg and touch your toes with your fingers.
Can you do that one?
You're gonna straighten
your legs,
and you're gonna touch your toes like this.
Can you do it like that?
Yeah.
- Wow, you sure can, and then you're
gonna fold your head right over there.
God bless you, God bless you.
Gesundheit.
We're gonna go like this, and you're gonna put
your head down for a second, like, down here.
-  How does that feel?
- - Good.
It feels good?
Do you feel like a nice stretch in here?
Here, you want some of this?
Hey, Lee, look what I
found on the hill.
So I was just digging around here, I
wanted to see where that sprinkler went,
and I started kicking
around and I found this.
- Can I touch it?
- Yes.
And then this bone, Lee,
was, like, back in the hill.
That's a bone? Let me see that.
I wanna touch that.
I feel like we gotta
know whatever...
I mean, are you trying
to think like "pow pow"?
- Mom?
- -Yes.
I think at some point, somebody put this...
And if we go deep in here...
Oh, God. No, no, no.
And I feel like we should
probably find out what it is.
Why?
See, now you know what happens to my brain, because
now my brain thinks there's like 20 bodies...
There could be.
- There absolutely could be.
- -It's my skin.
All right. Okay.
Great. So if I find it myself
then I'll call, for sure.
It's ridiculous. Absolutely.
Okay, thank you.
Yeah, goodbye. Thank you.
That was a joke.
Uh, the L.A.P.D. just said that it's not
their job to dig out somebody else's trash,
and to call
if we find the body,
but in the meantime, there's
nothing they could do.
And she had a tone with me, like
I was doing something wrong.
Good.
And I told her about the gun and
I told her about the bone, so...
So, what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna dig out the body.
- Or I'm gonna at least get closer to that.
- No, I think we're gonna leave it.
Lee, we can't leave it.
Tim, I was just putting down Jude and
he was like, "Where's the bone?"
Fine, we don't tell Jude.
I'm fine with that.
I told Jude, and he said, "What was
it?" And I said it was just pretend.
- It was probably a bone from a coyote.
- So let's find out if it's pretend.
Why?
'Cause there might be
a dead body on our hill.
It's not our hill.
Fine, of the hill
of this person.
Of my client,
of my livelihood, my job,
And I can't have them come home after
shooting a movie in Budapest and say,
"Oh, guess what. And by the
way, while you're out of town,"
"my husband decided to, like,
excavate your hillside,"
"and we found remains of a body,
and we think it's conn..."
I mean, what? Connected to what?
Where is it gonna go?
Well, obviously, I don't know the end of the
mystery at the beginning of the mystery.
Right, if there's a mystery.
I mean, my guess is that it's an animal
bone and it just happened to be...
- Some other animal shot it?
- Yeah.
- Come on, Lee. Come on.
- You come on.
Let's not make this a crazy drama.
Let's just enjoy this place.
Okay.
- That was just way too easy.
- I was thinking.
No, you said, "Okay."
And then I did see you think like,
"Okay, I'm gonna appease my wife"
- "and then I'm gonna keep digging." -No.
I won't dig.
- No more digging?
- No more digging.
Let's go enjoy this place.
And if you want
a little bit more of a stretch,
you could push
your foot up to the ceiling.
Nice.
Tell me if this is too much.
Ready? Ooh-hoo!
All right, good.
We made up a new game.
- Oh!
- Great!
You're gonna arch
your back and look up.
Then we're gonna
round our backs
and kind of, like, tighten
right in here, right in here.
No, don't get me! Don't get me, buddy!
Don't get me!
What? Aah! Full wipe-out!
It's cheesy to say, but really,
and people say this all the time, but they
really were, like, glowing when they came back,
- and they seemed...
- Yeah.
Maybe this is just how I feel about
Ken, but he seemed a lot nicer.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
You know, like, they really...
It's something that it's like...
I think you owe it to
yourself to do it, you know?
- Mmm.
Yeah, I mean, honestly...
I mean, I've always wanted
to go to India, like...
- literally forever.
- So do it, fucking do it.
You know, once you have kids, it's
like you can't, I just can't...
That kid came into your life,
it wasn't the other way around.
He came in to your home. Take
your kid with you, you know?
Don't let that limit you,
you know?
Ugh, yeah.
- No, it's not...
- When we have kids,
we're not, you know,
it's not gonna limit us.
- No.
- -Mm-hmm.
What time was it
when you looked at your phone?
It was uh... 5:30.
I have to get home
and make the sweet pea dinner.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Have a fantastic time.
- Thank you so much for this beautiful
session today. -You guys practice.
You don't have
regular milk, do you?
Um, we have raw milk.
Do you have
regular milk, though?
Um, today we have goat's milk, uh, coconut
milk, almond milk, cashew milk, um, soy milk,
and then there's hemp and flax milk
actually in the dry goods section.
So no just regular milk?
Not today.
I can't believe the poopies
go in the ground.
- That's where dogs and cats go poopie,
in the ground. -Jude, Jude, Jude...
Let's have dinner. It's not nice to talk
about poopies at the dinner table, okay?
- Okay.
- But guess what.
- But I love you.
- And your daddy needs to do the
taxes this weekend... -Yeah.
Because I'm gonna have a nervous breakdown if I
eat dinner on this table like this one more time.
You got it. Hey, Jude, can I ask
you a question about the taxes?
Uh, did you take
a poopie today?
I didn't.
What?
- Tim, I'm not joking.
- Okay, yeah.
We love you so much.
You're such a good boy.
- Aw.
- All right.
- See? You make me the bad guy.
- How do I...
Because you have to do this.
And them I'm getting...
I'm turning into this.
Okay, how about this?
You can go play. You can do whatever
you want, buddy boy. Is that okay?
- I'll do the taxes. I'm sorry.
- No, but see?
You see what happens?
And then I'm...
And then I'm the bad guy.
Come here. Come here.
- Just do it. This weekend.
I know. -Okay.
I don't wanna take
your mom and your step-dad's
money in this moment.
And I don't think there's anything wrong with that
'cause we're talking about a three-year-old boy.
Mm-hmm.
If this conversation was
about college and it was...
- college or no college, then...
- They say, they say...
They say, they say that preschool now is
more important in getting into college
- than, like, high school.
- Stop it. I don't...
- It is! They say development
is... -Who the fuck is "they"?
The experts, whatever.
All the stuff that I read.
Yeah, and then we read another thing about
preschools where, uh, the one that was all dirt
and they play in the dirt
all the time
- and they raise those turtles.
- Yeah, I read that article.
And you spend $12,000 for three months and
you need to pay for every extra activity.
And there's...
Yeah, but, here's the thing,
you wouldn't be paying for it.
That's the thing. That's the
thing that I'm talking about.
How about our son goes to school
in the neighborhood he lives in?
Yeah, how about
that school is a six?
How about he's in preschool?
It's not a good preschool.
Let them run around and figure
out problems on their own.
And so if one kid
bites another kid,
- well then, the biter hangs out
with the bitee... -Oh, stop. Stop.
And they have to figure out what they did wrong, and
they talk it out for $10,000 over three months.
You're making me mad. I'm reading this.
You're making me mad.
- Do you want some of this?
- No.
- "Love and Foreplay Aren't
Blind." -Yeah, right.
My favorite chapter.
What does that even mean?
Hi, Mom, it's me. Can you give
me a call when you get this?
I, uh, was thinking about coming
down for the weekend with Jude.
And maybe asking if you'd babysit for
me so I can have a night out to myself.
I just... Tim's got a lot to
of stuff to do this weekend
and I just need a break
to be honest with you.
I love you. Call me back. Bye.
You're on the hook
for next time.
Okay. Have fun.
- Don't have too much fun.
- I won't.
Okay, say hi to everybody.
Yes, I will.
- Love you guys.
- We love you, Daddy.
- Bye.
- -Bye.
Okay, bud, you're ready to
go see Grandma and Pop-pop?
Yeah.
Don't forget the taxes.
I won't.
Why don't I come to you? Because I
haven't seen the kids in so long.
That would be so nice, and then
we'll just do it from there.
Cool?
All right, get ready, baby. We are
gonna have a fun Saturday night.
- Mama?
- -Yeah?
Why isn't Daddy here?
Because Daddy had to stay home and do
some things that Mommy wanted him to do.
Because Daddy
has some responsibilities.
Oh, what is a responsibility?
- What's a responsibility?
- Yeah.
Sometimes mommies want daddies to
pitch in and help out and do things,
and those are called
responsibilities.
And if you don't do them,
then Mommy comes after you
and goes, "Rawr! Why didn't you do
everything I wanted you to do?"
- You don't like when Mommy
gets like that. -No.
No. I don't like it
either, actually.
So Daddy is at home
doing his homework.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Yeah!
- Hey, man.
- -Hey, man.
- How are you?
- -Good.
Can you believe it?
This is very strange.
Very unusual for people like me
to be at a place like this.
- It's the best, right?
- Yeah. Thanks for having me.
Yeah, you got it.
I'm just griling out, man.
Check it out.
Explore the place.
This is all ours tonight.
There's a pool, there's a hill.
Yeah?
I think I am gonna walk around.
This whole place is hers?
Everything.
Hey, would you grab some buns?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm gonna pee in each of the
bathrooms, is that okay?
So then the lesson is, "Hopefully
you get a really lucky,"
and your grandmother marries a
man who's got a lot of money,
and then therefore you get
to go to private school,
"but your parents couldn't
have sent you there."
Yeah.
And so then you're essentially
alienated from your own surroundings.
Right.
Yeah, I mean, there's
pros and cons to both.
I think the optimistic choice is
sending them to public school
because we teach
at public school.
That's right. That's right.
If we don't believe that you can
send your kids to public school.
- Then what am I doing?
- That's right. What are we...
Yeah, what are we doing?
Yeah, what is that lesson then?
I teach there,
but my kid doesn't go.
- Very cynical.
- Yes.
I'm very cynical.
Mind you, I teach gym.
We would start constructing the
fire when there was still light.
- That's right.
- So we, you know,
we could do it right,
the tepee.
No, I'm good, thanks.
Here you go, Paul.
When we told her, you know...
So we were with the cat and it's
like, "We don't believe in anything."
We don't believe
you're going to cat heaven."
So it's like we're just telling her, like,
"We appreciate that you were alive."
- Oh, jeez. -Like it's just so...
It's devastating.
You know what, though, having someone come
over and put the cat out of its misery,
way better
than taking an animal in.
'Cause the last thing they'll remember
is all this panic and fear in the car.
- You shouldn't take them in.
- No.
I think you have to put
them down at the house.
I think it's funny
'cause it's just like...
Cremation versus burial is such a
no-brainer when I think about it.
It's like crem...
Everyone should be cremated.
Why is it a no-brainer?
Because there's too many people
on the earth, there's no space.
- Oh, you mean practically?
- Yeah.
So no one got it. All right.
150!
That was a nice toss, though.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
- Okay.
- -Perfect.
350 to 280 to 120. One hundred!
420 to 180 to 130.
Hey, uh...
Sorry, um...
Did I get the wrong house?
I'm looking for a Tim guy.
Oh, yeah, Tim's in the kitchen.
Hey, man!
Whoa!
Look at this guy!
- What's up, homie?
- Yes, man!
- You made it.
- Look at this guy.
Look at this beautiful face.
And the fucking bod!
- Hey, man.
- -I'm so glad you came, man.
- Good, I'm so glad to be here,
- I miss you.
What are you guys doing,
dick-sucking-cock fest over here?
- What's happening?
- No. Hey, let's get a beer.
- What's going on?
- -You fucking made it, man!
The Weight Watchers points just on the
hamburger bun is like 12-13 points.
No hamburger.
Ray, you want one of these?
So they were literally I'd say about
three feet apart from each other.
Any more people
coming to the...
I found this, which I
don't know what that is.
And then I found that, man.
What the fuck?
Grab it. Yeah.
Wow.
- That was in the...
- That was in the... Yeah.
I mean, that was probably a foot and a half in the
ground and that's on the hill, but check it out.
I mean, the land is crazy.
- That's beautiful, look at that.
- That's pretty awesome, man.
Tim, you want a peanut butter
and boysenberry sandwich?
Well, what do we... Let's go down
there and let's dig this shit up.
I did. Well, I got
this out there,
Well, let's keep digging.
- Why don't we keep digging?
- Yeah.
I think we're gonna
just sort of hang here.
- I'm in.
- Yeah.
Let's do this.
Let's hold it down. You
guys, let's hang here...
Come on. Let's go.
Okay, that's you.
All right.
Come on, it's gonna be fun.
Yeah?
This is great.
What are you doing?
Watch your steps right here, guys.
That's it, down there.
So this is where
I found the bone, guys.
And then right here I dug a little
bit deeper, if you see that hole,
this is where the gun was.
So, Adam, you wanna jump up there?
You mind taking the lead?
Paul, you wanna get in there?
Yeah, awesome.
Actually, leave that light.
Yeah, and then if we
just get in here...
- Ray, you wanna... You and
me can work this. -Yeah.
Uh, and Phil, just, you know, I mean,
like, whatever you want, buddy.
You can't just dig up someone's yard.
I think it's illegal.
Holy shit!
Dudes, a license plate.
Nevada. 5752673.
- Wow.
- That's like, wow!
It's just gar...
There's garbage in the ground.
If you dig far enough
you'll find a landfill.
Stop, Phil. Stop, man. This
is really fucking exciting.
- That's a great find, dude.
- Thanks, man.
I think this is a good area.
- So that was right here? -Yeah,
let's stick around here then.
Look, if you don't wanna dig,
how about some hookers?
No, no, I, uh... That's sort of
an illogical jump you just made.
You went from digging
in the yard to hookers?
That seems sort of irrational.
I was having a great time.
You wanna play 500?
Yeah, we could play 500.
Guys, stop fighting, stop it.
Let's just enjoy...
I'm not fighting. I'm
actually being inquisi...
I'm really asking
a real question.
Let's just enjoy the moment. There
could be a dead body right beneath us.
You know, it's pretty
fucking exciting, Phil.
- It could be any...
- Well, I mean, you know,
if Phil doesn't
wanna dig, that's cool.
I'm not gonna judge him
He doesn't have to dig.
But I'm just saying,
is there an alternative
to digging? Do you have
another alternative?
Because I'm game.
I'm open to ideas.
- Go to a bar or something?
- What the fuck is that?
It was right there.
- You just found it?
- Yeah.
Hold on, let me see that.
Are you kidding me, dude?
It was right there.
This is too weird for me, man.
Wow, this is for real.
Admit it, Phil.
It's strange. That's strange.
Let me see that. Look at that.
- All right. -That's some
real  Quest for Fire...
- We gotta go deep. We
gotta go all the way out.
- ...2001 shit, right there.
For a cadaver, they're
worth a lot of money.
I know.
No. I mean, I know that,
I think, from like...
I'm gonna get a beer.
Yes, please.
But I do know that for a fact
because I think back in the '60s...
- Holy shit.
- You okay?
Phil, are you all right?
I think I'll be
all right long-term.
Aah!
- You're sure? -No, I'll be all right.
I'll be all right.
I think we should call it
a night, don't you think?
So it's on. It's happening?
What's happening, brother?
It's on. Billy T's coming.
He's bringing these two broads.
Tango is coming here?
Yeah, he's bringing some fucking tarts.
I don't know...
It's gonna be awesome.
Who's Billy T?
Tango. Tango. Yeah.
He's coming now.
He's coming now. Right now.
Timmy, we should, uh...
We should talk this out, right?
Tango is coming, man.
It's gonna be beautiful.
Yeah, I, uh...
We should probably check
before the evening changes.
Don't break that.
Jude loves it.
Are you, are you okay? Do you need me?
You need me here?
I don't know. Not unless you wanna come.
I mean, if you wanna stay, stay.
No, I'm gonna go. I just want
you to know I'm here for you.
- Yeah, I'm good.
- Okay.
- You're okay? -I'm gonna go.
Yeah, no, it's good.
I'm gonna put you in.
Put your legs in.
Really nice to meet you.
There we go. There we go.
- Hey!
- Hello!
Hey, come on!
- Hey, what's up, man?
- -Yeah!
- What's going on?
- -Tango!
We're doing it? We're doing it?
What's up, man?
- It's good to see you, bro.
- It's good to see you.
Hello. Hi. That was
the ride of my life.
I think we should
do it for America.
Tango?
Girls, want a hit or something?
Hi. Thank you so much
for having us over.
- Hey, thanks for coming.
- That's so nice.
Cougars are getting younger.
Like, when I was...
Like, MILFs were like...
- Now the MILFs are like 28, right?
- -Yeah.
And the cougars are like...
Can we go in the house,
is that okay?
- Is it cool if we go in the house?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna make the girls
squirt tonight.
Easy, easy.
- Check you out. -Use
a condom, at least.
- What do you think of the other one?
You like the other one? -Beautiful.
Yeah. I mean, I'd do anything but
we gotta give him first dibs.
- No. You guys fuckin'...
Are you kidding me?
You... Fuck you, fuck you.
- Come on, man.
You know what his wife said?
You're crazy, man.
Who do you want, man?
No, but I want you to be happy.
What the fuck is this, man?
Peanut butter and jelly?
It's kind of nice to just hang out.
And I actually miss seeing you, man.
You don't want
a little side action?
- I miss you too.
- Yeah.
Hey, man,
you got some coke on your...
- Speak of the devil.
- Yeah.
It's crazy having a kid.
It fucking changes...
I've been wanting to talk to you about this. I
have these conversations with you in my head.
No sleep. No sleep.
No sleep.
That's part of it.
I couldn't do it.
No sleep, man.
- Yeah, the sleeples...
- How do you, how do you sleep?
Yeah, yeah.
I can't do it.
I gotta sleep, man.
Also, there's a person...
I mean, I'm not...
I can't do that. I can't...
I gotta sleep, man.
The lack of sleep
fucks with you, man, but...
You know, there's, like, this human
being just looking up to me to be...
- Yeah.
- Jesus!
- Is your wife cool?
Is she cool? I mean, does she let you hang out? Does
she let you have some time and be free and be cool?
Can you hang out?
She's great, you know,
all bullshit aside.
- You're not trapped?
- No.
- No, you know... -I can't
fucking handle that, man.
You know, I can't fucking...
I can't handle being trapped,
man, you know what I mean?
- Whoo!
- I did it, I did it, I did it!
Just give me one good thing.
Ray-ray!
Oh!
Whoa!
What are you doing?
Uh...
Just digging for something.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
For something?
What kind of something?
- What's that?
- What?
I just found uh, some stuff earlier.
I found like a bone and...
Yeah.
You're amazing. Look at you.
What are you, Fred Astaire?
You're gonna tap dance for
me, you fucking poopie?
You gonna fucking... Get in the pool and
fucking do a tap dance, motherfucker.
It's not... This isn't my house, so
I'm not moving it all out I'm just...
- This isn't?
- No.
My wife and I are staying
here for a few weeks.
- Sweet.
- Yeah.
- That's a good deal.
- It's a great deal.
Yeah.
I wanna help you find the body.
Well, there's a shovel
right there.
Great, that's all
I needed to hear.
Chica! Chica! Chica!
Yeah, where is that chica?
I don't know.
Get that chica over here.
- Hey, hey, hey. Hey!
- Hey.
- Yeah, that's nice.
- You're bringing it, huh?
I could do this.
I got it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where are you going?
- Oh, it's colder than I thought!
- Hey, man!
Don't try and have sex with me.
Oh, I didn't know
it was time to show off.
Oh, that wasn't funny.
Where's chica?
Hey, give me that...
Hey.
I gotta show this to Ray.
He's gonna lose his shit.
- What did you find?
- Ray, I found a shoe, buddy!
- A what?
- -Ray! Ray!
Ray! Ray.
Ray, I found a shoe.
Hey, man, that's awesome.
Dude, I found a shoe.
It was right by the gun, so...
- That's great. Let me check it out, man.
- Yeah, man.
- It's unbelievable.
- That's awesome, bro.
Yeah, that was prob...
Oh, no, no, no! No.
Oh, man, Ray.
- What do you got there?
You got a joint? -Yeah.
You threw the shoe
in the pool, man.
Oh, man.
- How's it doing?
- Yeah, it's good.
- Smoting... Smoking up marijuana...
- Smoting?
I think if there's any clue that says that
there's somebody out there, Ray, it's this.
Smoke the dutchie often,
if you know what I mean.
Who would just throw this...
It's fucking nuts.
I can't even understand
what you're saying anymore.
All right,
I'm gonna hit the sack.
All right, guys.
All right,
good night, everybody.
It's like you got Jekyll
and then you got Hyde.
And then you got Jekyll,
and then you get Hyde.
Stay as long as you want.
Enjoy the night.
- You know what I mean? You punk rock?
- I don't wanna look at it.
Oh, shit.
- I'm gonna fucking...
- I will whip this at you!
- Okay, okay, okay.
- This is a crossroads.
- -Mm-hmm.
- This is a very important...
- It's not a crossroads.
The kid's three years old.
- But, darling...
- -It's not the crossroads of his life.
- Right.
- -Yes.
You think the best education he could
possibly get is in a public school?
No, actually, I don't. But sometimes
I think it's a compromise.
What? No. It doesn't
have to be a compromise.
- It is. Marriage is a compromise.
- Why?
- Well, life's a compromise.
- Yes, but...
- Life's a compromise. -Can we
stop talking in platitudes?
- Life's a compromise.
- Please? Look.
We think it's important for him to have
the best education that he can have
- and I know you do too.
- Mm-hmm.
And so now you're under
the cover of your marriage.
- And Tim does too.
- I...
Tim is prejudiced because he works
in the public school system
and that's the difference.
That's kind of harsh.
I don't think he's prejudiced.
- He just believes in the pu...
- It's not harsh, it's the truth.
I feel like the voices
are getting really...
- Mama!
- I'm sorry, buddy. Yeah?
- I'm sorry.
Oh, wait. I think I know
what I need to do.
I know what I need to do.
I think I have 15 blueberries
and you have 14.
No, I have 15 too.
- You do?
- Yeah.
Look, I have 16.
We're getting a lot
of anti-oxidants.
Okay.
-  Knock, knock.
- - Who's there?
- Orange.
- Orange who?
- Knock, knock.
- Who's there?
- Banana.
- Banana who?
- Knock, knock.
- Who's there?
- Banana.
- Banana who?
Didn't you glad I didn't say...
Orange?
I'm just waiting
to get my life back.
What does that mean?
When did it come back?
When do you go from being...
I mean, you know, it's the
great joy of my life to be...
- I did it. -I know you did.
Thank you, buddy.
To be mom.
But when am I mom and...
All right, you wanna step in?
I'm gonna do this one.
All right, step in.
I'm asking you when did you feel
like you got back to yourself?
When I divorced your father.
I knew you were gonna say that.
Can you zip these up?
No, I'm not
recommending divorce.
No, I thought you were gonna say, "I'm not
kidding." I'm like, I know you're not.
Can you zip these up for me?
You know how to do that part.
But there was something truthful
about my having my own life again.
Doing pretty good
for an old man.
- I feel like an old man.
It's hard to have
a separate life.
- You do, though?
- Yeah, I feel like I do.
But I think it's the hardest
thing, somehow, getting married.
It's like, well am I a couple or
am I still the person, you know?
It's really...
It's key to remain the person that
brought something to a relationship.
And being in love,
man, we being in love.
What is that? Getting what you want or
is it giving somebody what they want?
Sacrificing, if you
want to call it that.
Two, three.
- Cheese!
Okay, you wanna come down?
Uh...
Here, you want me
to give you a push?
Okay, I'll give you
a little push.
Whoa, oh, whoa!
Can I take a picture of you
with Grandma and Pop-pop?
No? I gotta take a picture
for Daddy.
All right.
- Hey, neighbor.
- Oh, hey.
- Sorry, I should have called.
- No. Stop. How are you?
I'm good, I just brought
something up for Lee.
Oh, she and the boy
are gone for the weekend.
- Oh, they are?
- Yeah. Oh, okay.
Wanna get a cup of coffee or something?
You wanna come in?
Uh, I don't wanna be
any trouble.
Better than not doing anything.
Here you go, my friend.
That's all I get?
- That's all that's left?
- Yeah, that's all that...
- I mean, it's yours if you
want it, but... -Nah.
Sorry about that, it's my friend's.
I don't do cocaine, actually.
- I don't either.
- Yeah, I'm a weed guy.
You know, if you need a little bit of help
digging your swimming pool down there,
I got a brother-in-law
that does that business.
Oh, no, the... Last night.
No, we were just
goofing around, just...
- Yeah?
- Yeah. I uh...
I'd found... I'd been doing a
little gardening for Julia
and I found some stuff and,
you know, it was interesting.
Doing some Indiana Jones
stuff, I guess.
Well, a lot of weird shit
happened around here.
Man, you said it.
That's the stuff
I like to get into.
Oh, really?
Yeah, it's fun.
Well, sometimes
not so much fun.
You want all those spirits to come
up here and join your family?
Well, that's interesting.
That was kind of the debate.
'Cause Lee said not
to mess with it.
- Yeah. -She said it was kind
of none of my business.
But my thought is like,
there's something in me,
and I don't know if you
can relate to this,
but there's something, if there's something down
there, part of me has got to know what it is.
Well, I know what it is, but there ain't
no way I'm gonna go digging down there.
- Right? Have all that shit
come back on my family.
You don't wanna find anything
down there, believe me.
Yeah, I know.
The Chicano Hall of Fame
is down there.
Okay. Thanks for stopping by.
And I keep thinking the older I
get the more I'm gonna know,
and I don't, I'm just getting older and
fatter, and, like, more broken down.
And that's true.
You know when you talk to like
an old man, or at least for me,
you know, they'll say like, "It's weird
when we talk because I feel your age,"
and then I look
in the mirror and I'm not.
- That's starting to happen.
- Oh, really?
With... I'm like... This is... I was with two
16-year-old boys and we were, like, goofing around,
Why were you with
two 16-year-old boys?
- It was a work thing. I'm a teacher.
- Oh, okay.
But we were, like, having fun, and,
like, laughing and doing bits.
We were doing like, "Ooh, kill 'em, kill
'em." and they're like, "You don't..."
And we were like, all laughing.
And I saw the reflection of
this, like, of the car in the
and I was so old,
and they were so...
And I had that thought
of like, wow!
But I didn't feel different
when we were having fun.
And that made me feel like,
I am gonna die.
- Hey!
- Yeah?
I found something!
Ooh!
Holy shit.
I just found a bag of bones.
Oh, my God.
So somebody had bones...
Chopped them up, put them
in a bag, put them in here.
Yeah, here.
It's an awesome find.
This is so cool. It's like, the
most weird Easter egg hunt.
- Oh, God.
- Good job, good find.
Thank you.
Mom?
Okay, give me a kiss. Mwah.
- All right, you're gonna play with
Grandma and Grandpa, okay? -Okay.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Have fun!
Bye, Grandma.
Hi.
- Hey. Are you Lee?
- I am.
Oh, good.
I'm so glad I found you.
- The GPS took me... -I know. It always goes
up Deerpath and then you can't get through.
I know, I'm sorry.
So am I.
Where are you going?
- Big Brackwood. I'll tell you
how to get there. -Oh, awesome.
Was that your house?
No, no. I mean, I wish.
Well, I don't know if I wish.
I mean, it was my mom's house.
- It's really nice.
- It is really nice.
My house is not very nice.
No.
No. We live on the east side.
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah, Atwater Village.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
I know where that is.
Yeah, we don't even live in a house.
We live in a duplex.
That's still nice. You can
pretend to have a house.
Yeah, I know, right?
Sort of. I think we thought we were
gonna move out of it and get a house
several years ago,
but it hasn't panned out yet.
I kind of like
driving around over here
because I can sort of pretend that I
live in one of these giant houses.
Right?
But I always wonder if I would be happier if I
lived in one of these, instead of an apartment?
I think I read this study, or my
husband told me about this study,
because we talk about
this stuff a lot,
that they did for Harvard or something
where they said you actually,
people with money actually are
happier, live marginally happier,
and then it kind of plateaus and
they're as unhappy as everybody else,
but they are
a little bit happier.
Where are my two
favorite munchkins?
- Hi.
- How are you doing, darling?
- Hi, Lee. Good.
- So good to see you.
- Hey, guys, you remember Lee?
Oh, my God, you're all wet.
I can't even hug you.
High-five. Two hands.
You remember Auntie Lee?
On the side. In the hole.
You've got soul.
- Hi, how are you?
- Good. Good to see you.
- Good to see you too.
- Oh, this is Lucy.
- Hi, I'm Lucy. Nice to meet you.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- It's amazing.
- Wow.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Cheers, you guys.
- -Cheers.
I have been counting the
minutes to this reunion.
You wanna cheers me or no?
- Yeah, cheers.
- Okay.
You, if you would give
that to me, I would win too.
- Okay.
- I win!
- How is he doing?
- He's so good.
I wanna eat him every day.
You could have bought him.
You know he needs some time
with Grandma and Pop-pop,
and Mommy needs some time too.
- How old is he now?
- Three.
- Oh.
- Yeah, it goes fast.
- Yeah, it's been a long time.
- Yeah.
I mean, part of me wishes we could have
someone, you know, full-time, live-in...
You could do it. I mean,
we just found her, you know?
Um, she knew
somebody from work, so...
Do you mind if I ask
how much you pay her?
- Very little.
- Yeah.
But lives in the guest house
it's kind of a big draw.
There's kind of a deal.
She's like an actress,
and she is auditioning.
We're kind of flexible.
It's not...
It's an interesting...
I think she's great. I think she fits
in really well. The kids love her.
Here's the, here's the thing.
Tell me how you feel about this.
We are gonna go to Costa Rica
on a family vacation.
It was gonna be us
and the kids.
- It's still gonna be us and the kids.
- I'm excited about it.
But suddenly, Bob thinks
that Lucy should come.
- No. Okay, here's what happened.
- For the whole time.
Here's what happened.
Squitch says...
- What do you think about
Costa Rica, right? -Uh-huh.
We penciled in Costa Rica,
starting on the 10th,
because that was the week that
seemed like it was gonna be open.
Everybody agreed to the 10th.
- My schedule doesn't work like your
schedule works. -The 10th is good.
I know what it is three,
four months in advance.
I started planning... Well, it does.
It can.
It can, it can
if you want it to.
- It can't. It can't.
- It can if you want it to.
- Okay, sure, if I wanna call the client...
- If you communicate...
and say, "We're gonna drop the account.
Sorry, we're not ready",
"and I'm going to Costa Rica."
If you communicate and you talk to me when
you find out that it's not a good date,
you tell me then,
so I can change things.
So I have a project,
that went over,
and we've got a lot of options.
One of the options is, we can
postpone the trip and we can go...
Why don't you have just like a nice
night and have some, like, you time
- and, like, read a, read a book...
- What does that mean?
I feel so shitty. I don't even
know what I'm saying to you.
You're saying
you don't wanna go out.
- I'm saying I can't, I can't.
- I know, I know.
I was really
looking forward to tonight.
Like, on a level that I can't
even describe to you, but...
You sure you can't do it?
You can't push it?
I know, and I'm supposed to
just let you off the hook,
but I'm being so selfish and
just pushing for my needs.
I was so excited to see you and
I wanted to be able to do it,
but I haven't done anything
for like two months.
Maybe you need to get out.
- Hey.
- What do you say we call it?
- Call it?
Yeah. I'll buy you some dinner
as a thank you.
- Yeah.
- You in?
My clothes are
pretty dirty, though.
I'll find you
some clean clothes.
- Okay.
- Good.
I want...
Whoa.
- What's up, Timmy?
- Hey, Phil, my boy.
- How are you?
- Good. -How was the
rest of the night?
- Great, and Tango came
by, it was fun. -Yeah?
What you up to?
What are you doing?
Just, uh, I was just in the neighborhood,
heading to soccer practice.
- You're dressed like Ray.
- -Hey, Tim?
These don't fit.
I don't wanna go
in the closet, but...
Let's get you
something else to wear.
Okay.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
- Thank you.
- -Yeah.
Take anything you want.
- Just whatever? Uh...
- Honestly.
Yeah, just grab anything
and I'll meet you downstairs.
- Anything?
- Anything.
Thank you.
- Tim.
- What's up, man?
Listen, I got to uh...
Just talk to me for a second.
Phil, I want to clean off that table
so I won't have to do it later.
Listen, I wanna talk to you because
you're not yourself right now,
you're like in this
other head space,
and, uh, I just wanna
talk to you about, like...
I feel like we should jut go out for
dinner, like, just drop these guys.
I have plans, man. I'm
going out with my friend.
- No, but it would be fun It would
be just you and me. -Yeah.
And we can kind of shed this because I feel
like you're, whoo, you know what I mean?
You're just in this other place
and I just wanna bring you back.
What do you think is going on here?
What are you implying, Phil?
- I don't know what's going on. -I made a
friend and I'm going out to eat with her.
Yeah, I'm not involved with this.
As a matter of fact, when...
I'm friends with your wife.
I know your kid.
Phil, Phil. You're a good dude.
But I've known you for two years.
- Relax. I'm fine. I'm a man.
Okay? -I'm just saying...
I'm just saying, for when I'm out with your
wife and, you know, when we're on double dates,
I don't wanna be
an accomplice to this.
There's not... Okay, stop.
Your... That coat looks ridiculous,
it doesn't even button properly.
And the hat, you know, it's
practically the summer.
You're gonna be boiling.
By the time we actually
got the divorce itself,
it was over, so...
Were you devastated?
Oh, I was, I was a fucking mess.
I was, you know,
sobbing into the sink
every morning.
You know, like,
it was, it was just terrible.
But, um, since then it's been,
you know, revelatory, you know.
And life is someplace
where I never found it before.
You know, you live a whole... You grow up with your
parents, and you have roommates, and you do all this stuff
and all of a sudden you're, you're
exactly what you wanna be, sort of.
- Now.
- Now. Really, it's uh...
It's pretty amazing, you know?
No compromises.
Nothing that really requires
anything but your own desires.
The thing is, you just gotta
figure out what they are.
When you decide
what you're interested in
and it's, if you're not
seeking, then there's no part,
and you are in a moment of your
life where you are seeking.
- Mm-hmm. -So something
like taking ayahuasca,
which would be
really scary for me right now,
is really exciting
and really scary.
Because if it shifts everything up for
you, well, this is the time to do it.
Well, I'm not set in anything right now.
You're like set in your thing.
I think what is, is everything
that excites me is what he's doing
and not how I'm reacting to it, and
not how it's affecting my brain.
It feels like what's happening to
me and what's happening to my wife
kind of doesn't matter.
- Mm-hmm. -And there's a bit of
a loss that happens between us
because our thing,
our connection, our love,
and I know it's wrong and I know we always like... We
have, like, rules of, like, make sure we always connect,
it's just so much more exciting
to put everything into that kid,
in their love, in their
development, in their thought,
and, you know,
you lose yourself in that.
All right?
Hi. Can I just sit at the bar?
- Yeah, please.
- Thank you.
- How you doing?
- Good, good, thank you.
Want a drink?
Do you need help?
Oh, no, thank you. Um, I'll
have a martini with a twist.
Wait, I haven't seen this in so
long, I eat here all the time.
What are you gonna get?
- I was thinking about...
- Uh...
- Do you guys have burgers?
- Yeah, we do.
I don't see it on the menu.
Awesome.
- Here you go.
- Perfect.
You have beautiful eyes.
Thank you. I'm just
gonna scoot over here.
What color are they?
Um, I think they're hazel. I think that's
what it says on my driver's license.
Hey.
Uh-oh.
Brian, what are you doing, man?
- I'm just coming... She was
telling me about... -You good?
No, I'm good. Yeah.
What, are these chips?
Why did you get chips?
- I'm enjoying some chips.
Do you want some? -Yeah.
Eat some chips.
Did you eat enough tonight?
- No?
- A little. I, uh...
Maybe one too many
to drink, huh?
I don't think so.
Mmm, leave some.
What are you doing?
I'm just texting my husband.
- Wait, those are haz... You're married?
- Mm-hmm.
Since when?
Since 2004.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Let's go, bud. Come
on outside, let's go.
Excuse me.
- Nice meeting you.
- Nice to meet you too.
She's really not interested.
Come on, let's go.
Brian, it's time to leave.
It's time to leave.
No. Please, please. Seriously.
- Really? -It's time to leave.
Let's go.
Come on, out the door.
Brian, I'm serious. Relax.
No, no, man, I'm serious.
Listen, dude.
- Why are you doing this?
- Because...
- Oh, fuck!
- Oh, my God.
- You!
- -Fuck you.
- Would you just go home?
- -No.
Fuck!
Fucking loser.
- You okay, dude?
- Honey, will you just
- get him a cab or something?
- Yeah.
I apologize. Sorry.
Here you go.
Thank you. Okay. I feel like this is
gonna hurt a little bit. Can I see it?
- Can you take this away?
- It's gonna be fine.
- Can you just take it for a second?
- Sure.
Okay. Oh, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Okay.
This is like a total...
It's fine, honestly.
It's really not a big deal.
- And you're gonna need stitches.
- No, I'm not.
Oh, yes. Yes, you are.
No, you really are.
No, I'm not.
I'm not going to a hospital.
I hate hospitals.
I fucking hate them.
- Ow. Okay.
- Oops, sorry, sorry.
Yeah, you're gonna need
some stitches.
You know what we'll do, I have a friend, she's
a medical student. We'll go to her place.
Yeah, I don't care who does
it but you really need to...
Alicia, she's great. She's...
- Okay.
No, don't.
I feel good.
I feel great about it too.
I'm a little hungover,
so I'm just gonna get the...
- You're hungover? Perfect.
- Get the shakes out.
What were you doing?
Just, I don't know, I don't remember much.
I was at somebody's house or something.
But do you want me to walk you
through it as I'm doing it,
- or just do it?
- -No, just do it.
Okay, it's gonna take
a couple of deep breaths.
Should we do that together?
- Yeah, okay.
Okay.
- How many times have you done this?
- -Plenty.
Plenty?
Well, like on cadavers or something?
No, no. I got it. I'm just
not usually in my bathroom.
- Don't make it a thing.
- No, no. It's not a thing.
This is gonna be really easy.
It's just your face.
What have you
been getting up to?
- My mom was here until a
couple of days ago. -Your mom?
Hold still, please.
Right, this cotton's
itching on my face.
Why did your mom come?
Are your parents still together?
No, no. Are yours?
No.
You know, it's funny.
I actually feel like...
This weird thing with my friends when
their parents are together, like...
- You can't relate.
- Yeah, I guess.
It's almost like I feel like they're
inherently more naive than me or something.
Not like in a judgy way,
just like...
If it hasn't happened
to your parents, you don't...
You don't really understand that
it can happen to you or something.
Mmm.
Just not like
taking it for granted.
- Can you please hold still?
- -I'm trying.
- But...
- -Okay, get comfortable.
It's in your fucking face
right now, so if you want...
- I'm getting comfortable, but this...
- I want a break anyway, okay.
The toilet is more uncomfortable
than that needle.
- Okay, okay.
- Okay, I'm good.
- You ready to start again?
- Yeah, I'm ready.
- Okay.
- -Okay.
I'm so grateful for this, by the way.
Did I tell you that already?
- Yeah, you did.
- Okay, good.
You might not be
when you see it.
- Really? Can you please make it look good?
- Please just stay still.
I need one of those sexy scars.
- So you have to come back and see
me in seven to ten days... -Okay.
- ...so I can take out the stitches.
- Okay.
Lee, how are you?
Good. Hungry.
Hungry?
Yeah, I'm starving.
- You have anything?
- -No.
We'll go get something.
-  Can't find your...
- - One week.
- It was nice to meet you.
- You too.
Sorry I didn't have any food.
Okay.
All right.
Fingers crossed.
Hah!
No, don't shoot!
No!
Shit! Shit!
How do you like your steak?
Medium well.
Medium well. Medium well.
So I go on in what turns out
to be a bit of a boys' trip.
I was thinking it was
the last thing I need,
but I end up on this
big boy's trip and...
Meaning that you were going to
get all drunk and everything.
- We would get all drunk and get into all
sorts of trouble. -This is really good.
Is it? It's not overcooked?
It's perfect.
I think I have an easier time with
spiritual desire than earthly desire.
Is that possible?
- Yeah, of course.
- That I'm more comfortable...
- With earthly desire, with
spiritual desire... -No.
Yeah, of course. Well, you would be
because that's what we aspire to.
The earthly desires lead to
spiritual desires hopefully.
- You can start... -But I think
I'm trying to bypass it.
- Do you? -Yeah, I think I
try to not experience...
I think you should
experience them.
Like, I think my appetite
is so ravenous.
Mm-hmm.
- Why?
- I love that.
Oh. I think it is that maybe I think
it might, like, overwhelm the system.
Your appetite is so ravenous. Well, it was
certainly the way you attacked that steak.
Well, it was a big steak.
Boy, she is a beautiful girl.
You gonna smack that hippy ass?
Hey, what are you doing here?
Hey, dude, she's fine,
fine as wine.
Get out of here. Come here.
Hey, get out of town.
- Get out of here.
- -Hey! Get high.
- Where are you going? Come on.
- Oh, no.
Okay, hey, I'm gonna go...
Max, one sec, come back.
I might crash out
on that hammock.
Find me in a couple of hours.
The hammock's perfect.
- Max.
- Yes.
- Please do not tell me
you're leaving. -Yeah.
This has been nice.
We are having a blast.
Hey, Tim, what's going on?
Hey! Hey!
I'll just have one beer
and I'll get out of your hair.
- Hey, I'm gonna get rid of him.
- You look great in that dress.
- What? -I'm gonna
get rid of him.
- It's not about him. -Then
we can keep hanging.
- It's not even about him.
- I know.
That felt like
an accusation of sorts.
No, why are you here? Where's Tim?
What's he doing?
Um... Hopefully,
he's doing our taxes.
I don't know what he's doing.
Probably has some guys over.
Eating pizza, drinking beers.
We're house-sitting in this amazing house.
He may be swimming in the pool.
Well, hey,
if you're really gonna go,
do you mind if I get
the dress back?
But she looks great in it.
- I know, you look beautiful, I
just need it back. -Thank you.
Can I just wear it for
one more night?
No, obviously, you know,
my wife will be here.
That would be tough to explain.
I don't... Honestly, I don't even wanna
deal with it, you know what I mean?
Oh, yeah.
Like, I'm really
nervous right now.
Like, just talking on the subject,
and I don't even know you.
- I have that effect on people.
- And I'll never see you again.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Oh, you're so sure?
- I've already committed to that.
Ray, why did you do that?
I was just trying to help you out, man.
Did I embarrass you?
It's a fucking dick move, man.
Sorry, was it? You're showing
off in front of the broad?
I wasn't showing off. We were having fun.
It was kind of a dick move, dude.
It's, like, funny when Tango was here.
It wasn't funny right now.
Sometimes you gotta know when to not
do the fucking, you know, Ray Show.
- That's very liberating.
- What?
Well, we're never gonna see
each other again.
- It is, right?
- Yeah, I love that.
Mm-hmm.
That I can embrace.
Good night.
Goodbye, Mrs. Ray.
What's that from?
How much do I have to pay you to
please leave my fucking house?
A lot of money.
I love you, man.
I just wanna hang out, dude.
I just wanna hang out, come on.
Come on, bro.
Oh, my-fucking-God.
What's wrong? What, are you uptight?
What do you got over there, taxes?
- You gotta decide whether...
- Shut up, Ray!
Shut up? No!
I'm not gonna shut up!
You shut up! Fuck you, man!
You want me outta here,
I'll get the fuck outta here.
Fuck you.
I think I know people
that are happy.
The qualifier of insanely
is the one that's a little
tricky, you know what I mean?
- Just everyday happy.
- Hmm?
Just everyday happy,
forget the "insanely" bit.
Be consistently happy.
Mm-hmm.
You've thought about it, undoubtedly.
Or dealing with it, unable to.
Um...
Thank you
for a really good night.
Sorry about your...
Thank you.
- You wanna take this with you?
- No.
Oh!
Huh.
Oh, fuck me.
Oh.
Oh, care... Care...
The tide's coming in.
- Hey!
- I know.
Sorry. Come here.
Do you wanna see something?
- Yeah. -I mean, I know I
don't know you, but...
You gotta...
Have you seen Saturn?
Okay, wait, wait. Did you
ever look through...
Just don't touch it
because it's lined up,
and just look through the, just look
through there and see what you can see.
Can you see?
- Oh, my God!
- -Right?
- Yeah.
- And you can see the rings.
I know.
Which one is it?
I know, you can't even see, but then you
just look through there and there it is.
I mean, this is like...
Isn't it just
the most perfect...
I think we should get
a telescope.
Oh, that could be neat.
- Right?
- Yeah.
I might wanna try
ayahuasca together.
Really?
I think we should go
pick up our child.
Me too. But can we get breakfast
first, just the two of us?
Oh, yeah, let's get breakfast first.
Let me just text my mom.
He'll be okay
with Grandma and Pop-pop.
He'll be great.
They'll spoil him.
Did you guys miss me at all or
did you guys just had a blast?
No, we did. I missed you.
- I missed you too.
- Oh, yeah.
I'm not the same
without you guys.
- Yeah, me neither. I've discovered.
- Good.
Can we be bad parents and
let Jude watch cartoons?
Climb back in bed.
I think I'm gonna open a
bottle of wine at about noon.
I love you.
I love you too.