DISTANT
Mahmut, it's Mom.
I called earlier,
but you were out.
Take care.
Are you looking for someone?
- Does Mahmut Ozdemir live here?
- Yes, he lives here.
I'm a relative of his
from back home.
- Did you ring the bell?
- There's no answer.
Sometimes the bell shorts out.
- Do you think he went out?
- I didn't see him leave.
Good morning, Kamil.
Could you accept
a package for me?
Sometimes they won't
let me sign for it.
- Please try anyway.
- Of course.
- Kamil.
- Yes?
Go buy the things
on the list.
Right now?
Yes, I've got
some cooking to do.
- All right.
- Hurry up.
Yusuf?
Sorry, I completely forgot
you were coming.
That's okay.
No problem.
What's the news?
Back home, everybody's the same.
Do you still work
at the factory?
The economic crisis
put the factory out of business.
My father was dismissed,
then me.
There's no work at all now.
How many people lost their job?
1,000.
That's a whole town
full of people.
It sure is.
What will you do on the ship?
I'll work as a cabin boy
or a steward.
I'll do whatever job
they've got for me.
Sailors make a lot of money,
money in U.S. dollars.
And you see the world.
There's no economic crisis
at sea.
The dollars make up
for the inflation.
It may not be that easy.
You'll be away on long journeys.
Can you can take
that kind of loneliness?
Have you thought about that?
You know I like to travel.
But the main thing
is to earn money.
That's why I'm here.
I also want to travel!
You've been everywhere,
so why not me?
Every place
ends up looking the same.
How many days
before you find a job?
I don't know exactly.
You said about a week
on the phone.
I guess it'll take a week or so.
Yeah, about a week.
At night, be careful
of the mouse glue strip.
If you step on it,
you'll be stuck there all night.
And don't use the toilet
in the bathroom.
Use the other one.
The one by the entrance?
Yes, and we only smoke
in the kitchen.
- Okay, then, good night.
- Good night.
Come this way.
Hello.
Is this where the freighters
come in?
They dock here,
but the offices are in Karakiiy.
They dock here?
Yes, they do,
but the offices are in Karakiiy.
So I can't get a job
directly on board?
No.
Go to the shipping agents
on Monday.
I'll come.
You set it up.
The thing is,
I'm coming with someone.
No, he is someone
from my hometown.
Will any girls be coming?
Great, okay.
We'll be there.
See you tomorrow.
Hi.
Welcome back.
God, it's cold.
It's so late.
I was getting worried.
God, the snow is bad.
How could you go out
in this weather?
My socks are soaked.
Can I dry them on the radiator?
Yes, you can.
How'd the job hunting go?
Well, I went down to the port.
I'll dry my shoes too.
All right.
It seems you don't find jobs
at the port.
I was told to go to Karakiiy
on Monday.
I walked around Eminonu.
I'd better put on a new pair
of socks.
Money doesn't make you happy
anymore.
And I think you're looking
for your past here.
You're rambling.
Maybe,
but have you already forgotten
our climb
to the summit of Reshko
to get a better shot
of the White Valley?
You used to say then
you'd make films like Tarkovsky.
So why are you trying
to forget those days?
- Photography is finished, man.
- No, it's not.
The mountains too.
Maybe it's you who's done for.
You're announcing your death
before it's happened.
You don't have the right
to bury your ideals
or make everything commercial.
Hey, Arif, where are the chicks?
They all backed out.
What do you mean?
We've reserved the whole Sunday.
Where are they?
Not here.
At the cinema or wherever.
Fuck it.
You're weaseling
out of it again.
Photography or women,
which do you prefer?
I prefer photography.
Come on.
Photography is dead.
This fits here normally,
but it's too loose.
Tell your mother
to wrap some tape here.
Hello.
There's a package.
Shall I get it now?
Please.
If you want, I'll wait for it.
Okay.
For the love of God.
We can't find anything
once we've put it down.
Here it is.
- Thanks.
- Good evening.
Good evening to you too.
There's also a problem
with the dust bag.
Let's go to your house to show
your mother how to attach it.
- I think I'd better go to bed.
- Okay.
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
Could you close the door?
Hi, Mom,
what are you up to?
Is your tooth ache better?
Why don't you let
that old tooth-puller, Nuri,
take care of it?
'Cause Mahmut's sleeping.
I am sure Nuri gives credit.
I'll pay it once I earn it.
Tell him.
What are you ashamed of?
Yeah, so I've been around.
I was told to go
to Karakiiy on Monday.
What did Dad do?
There's no chance the factory
will take him back.
He should stop kidding himself.
They always say that.
Anyway, I've got to hang up.
Stop putting off that tooth,
Mom, okay?
I'll call you again.
Good night.
Can I take the magazine
over there?
I'll turn on the light
for a second.
It's late.
Let's turn that off.
- Good night.
Do you know where
the sailors coffeehouse is?
Behind that hilltop.
May I sit here?
At your age,
I thought the same, but listen:
I've worked on the ships
for months now,
and I have nothing.
I never could send
any money home.
l am broke just like Tarzan.
Listen to me.
There's no work
and no money on the ships.
Forget it
while you're still ahead.
It's an empty dream.
Hi.
Come on in, Yusuf.
It's snowing like crazy.
Where were you 'til now?
I was trying to find a job,
you know.
So what happened?
Well, some said
they would call me.
Others told me to come back
or that they'd think about it.
What are you doing?
What can I do?
Surfing around...
ls there a problem with the job?
No, there's no problem.
It looks like they want someone
to act as a guarantor.
No guarantor, no job.
That's easy enough.
You can take care of that.
But I don't know anybody
in Istanbul.
I don't know what to do.
There was something here.
I just can't seem to...
The God-damned thing
has 50 channels,
but there's only shit.
What a rip-off.
Look at that.
I want to call home.
Can I use the phone?
All right.
The phone in the back room.
Okay, go use it.
He refused to give us
any credit?
What a bastard!
When I get back,
I'll punch him real good.
I'll punch out his teeth
one by one.
Anyway, forget about it.
I'll send you some money
as soon as I get a job.
Mahmut's going to Anatolia
to take pictures,
and he says I should
go with him.
If he gives me money,
I'll send it to you.
Then you throw that money
in that bastard's face.
Okay, take care.
That fucking mouse.
"Our agency has no current need
for ship personnel."
Hello.
I'm looking for a job on a ship.
There are no jobs.
All right.
Thanks anyway.
So it's Canada?
Orhan got a very good offer.
We don't want
to miss this opportunity.
When are you leaving?
In two or three weeks.
By New Year, we'll be in a new
country starting a new life.
It's hard.
It's not so hard when you don't
have that much to leave behind.
We spent a lot of money
on doctors.
That's one reason
to sell the house.
We can settle that.
But I keep thinking
about that baby matter.
How can they be sure it happened
because of the abortion you got?
They just say the abortion
is the most probable reason.
I was three months pregnant
if you remember.
I remember.
But we were about
to get divorced.
That's why I didn't want it.
I'm not blaming you.
Really, don't worry about it.
You should see a doctor
in Canada.
I still doubt that one abortion
can cause infertility.
We didn't believe it either
at first.
We went to different doctors.
But that's the way it is.
I've resigned myself, actually,
but it's hard for Orhan.
He really likes children.
I told him we could separate.
He doesn't want to.
It's empty.
Have one of these
sailor cigarettes.
How can you smoke that shit?
There's still sun coming.
Raise it a little.
It seems okay.
Don't you see that?
Now, there it is.
Raise that light a little.
Leave it.
Didn't you see me
do that before?
Why did we stop?
Open that window.
God, what a place to photograph.
It's best to shoot from the top.
Sheep in front
and the lake behind.
Shall I set up the camera now?
Shall I?
Mahmut?
Fuck it.
Why bother?
I'll set it up right now.
Forget it.
Kamil, put it down on the rug.
I'll take it from there.
Mahmut, this is your sister.
Mom is sick.
We're rushing to emergency.
Call me back.
Mahmut, where the hell are you?
Mom's been hospitalized.
She'll be operated on tomorrow.
I'm staying with her.
My kid's suffering
and so is my work.
You could at least come
and help.
How can you refuse
to get a mobile?
You're so irresponsible.
- God, I'm tired.
- Take this.
Isn't it too much?
In that case, give some back.
If you take more photos,
I'd like to come along again.
What's wrong, Mom?
Can't you sleep?
It hurts.
Right here.
Maybe it's just gas.
Do you think
I should walk a bit?
All right, let's give it a try.
Take the serum too.
Come on, now.
Hold the serum up.
Higher, higher.
Or else blood comes.
Easy, now.
It hurts more when I lie down.
Sickness comes
when you least expect it.
And you smoke so much!
I don't understand
why you smoke so much.
I can't stop, Mom.
I've tried...
Yes, you can.
First cut down,
and then give it up altogether.
Just a bit more, sweetie.
I can't find anything
in this house.
I'm closing the door
to keep the noise down.
Yusuf, are you there?
It's Mahmut.
If you're home,
pick up the phone.
Hey, Mahmut.
Where were you?
I've called you all day.
Well you know, I went to...
How's your mom doing?
We brought her home.
She's resting.
Listen...
I've got something going on
at my place tonight.
Can you get lost
until ten or so?
Sure, I'll go to Beyoglu
or around there.
I've got this thing to do.
I got it.
Son of a bitch.
Look at that.
Little prick.
Filthy son of a bitch!
- Is she gone?
- ls who gone?
You know.
Did you smoke
in the living room?
No, I didn't.
Come on, stop lying.
It reeked here when I came in.
And there were ashes
on the floor.
Remember that day
when we smoked together?
I thought you smoked here too.
Listen to me!
When I turn my back,
you take advantage of it.
I often told you to flush
the toilet, for in stance.
No, you didn't.
Do I have to tell you this?
At your age,
haven't you learned yet?
When you're a guest,
you have to be a little careful.
I'm not home for a day,
and you shit everywhere.
I've got lots of worries,
and now I
have to clean your shit?
Listen...
No more smoking
in the kitchen, either.
I've quit.
Okay.
What do you think?
I bought it for my niece.
Isn't it great?
What happened with the ship job?
Nothing definite yet.
I'm waiting for some final word.
When will you know for sure?
I don't know.
I keep running after jobs.
They all say they'll let me know
in a few days.
Will you go back home
if you don't find a job?
No way.
So what the hell will you do?
If I return to the village now,
I'll never get out.
And there's no work
at the factory.
So what are your plans?
Shut the fucking thing off.
I'm asking you something here.
Could you get me a job
at the tile factory?
Sure, they're just waiting
for you.
Don't you think the recession
has hit here too?
Maybe they need a guard
or something like that.
A guard?
Two days alone here,
and look what happened.
You have no credentials.
What work could you do
if they did hire you?
Plant beans,
work as a steward, or what?
Come on, Mahmut.
Don't be so hard on me.
I just want you to ask them.
I'd do the same for you.
I've never asked them
for anything.
This town has changed you.
Listen kid, ever heard of pride?
You can't just throw it
on a garbage heap.
What would you lose by trying?
You don't know shit.
You're running off at the mouth.
You think it's that easy?
I've taken photographs
for them for ten years.
And I didn't even get a discount
for the tiles on the balcony.
You come in from the country
and look for someone with pull.
You don't worry
about learning any skills.
You start looking for a cousin,
an M.P. or whoever.
You want it all on a platter.
I did everything by myself here.
I came to Istanbul
without a cent.
You hop on a bus
without thinking ahead,
and you become a burden.
That fucking mouse
doesn't leave the kitchen.
We get caught,
but the fucker doesn't.
Shut it off!
Do you have
any Sezen Aksu music?
No.
Who's that "Bak"
on all those CDs over there?
What are you looking for?
A watch.
Have you seen it?
What kind?
A silver pocket watch.
No, I haven't seen it.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
If I had, I would tell you.
Why wouldn't I?
Where did you keep it?
In the middle drawer of my desk.
When did you put it there?
Just a month ago.
I used it as a prop
on my last shoot.
I swear, I haven't seen it.
Maybe you put it
somewhere else...
or gave it to a friend.
Forget about it.
It's not that important.
Of course it's important.
Just drop it, okay?
Fuck it.
Hello?
Mahmut, hi, it's me, Nazan.
Hi, Nazan, how are you?
We're leaving tomorrow,
and I wanted to say good-bye.
Tomorrow?
That's so soon.
Yeah, on the 9:00 plane.
We may never
see each other again.
I wanted to thank you again
for signing the paper.
Forget about it.
It was nothing.
Can you hold for a second?
Okay, we can talk now.
When I left that day,
I had a terrible feeling.
I don't want to leave
feeling like this.
I was somewhat distant towards
you because of my emotions.
But after all these years,
there's no need for that.
It doesn't matter.
Forget it.
Nazan, listen...
I think Orhan's coming.
I have to hang up.
All right.
What were you going to say?
I'll tell you some other time.
Take care.
Okay.
Bye.
I swear I never saw it.
Okay, enough!
I didn't even know
where it was.
Stop chewing on it!
I don't want to hear
about it anymore.
God, what a character.
Leave it.
The janitor will take care of it
tomorrow.
It'll be squeaking like this
all night.
What can we do?
Can you handle it?
Yes, I can.
But how can I get it unstuck?
No need to.
Put the whole thing
in a plastic bag.
Close it and throw it out
in the trash.
Alive like that?
What else can we do?
For Ebru.