Kazakhstan...October 4th, 1957...
A Soviet Vostok rocket thrusts its way
through the clouds...
...towards Earth orbit...
There, it delivers Sputnik...
a tiny man-made satellite...
...and the Age of Space was born.
A Soviet triumph that amazed the world...
...and stunned the Americans.
Two months later, came a Sputnik
6 times as heavy...
...with a passenger...
a dog named Laika.
Hey...dog-face...!
Show us ya snatch!
I'm hanging around that same old scene...
My girlfriend Betsy, she's just fourteen...
There's nothing better for me to do...
I'm living on dog food...So what?
Dog food is so good for you...
It makes you strong and clever too...
Dog food is a current craze
Eat some every day...
...hit me on the head...
...I think I've got brain damage.
...And when do the tickets go on sale?
Tomorrow!
And who are the tickets for?
David Bowie!
Oi! You!...
Hey...dick'ead...I'm talkin' to ya!
Hey...you...prick-face!...
Me?
Yeah...you!
Are you from the planet 'Poofter'?...
Or the planet 'Stupider'?
Think carefully before answering, Sammy.
I'll knock your fuckin' block off!
Didn't you hear me?
I asked you a question,
prick-face!
I said...
'Poofter'.
Or just stupid!
Eh?!
What's the matter with ya?
That hurt!
Someone kill 'im!
I'm talkin' to YOU...
ya little poofter!
Why don't you fuck off!?
No one asked YOU...
plain-face!
Easy!
Coward or somethin'?
What's the matter with ya?
Come on...get up!
I said what's the fuckin' matter
with ya...Get up!
Fuckin' bitch!
Let's get the fuck outta here!
You fuckin' moll!
Fuckin' moll!
Look at me fuckin' head!
I got a fuckin' bleeder there!
Let's hear it for Frankie Teardrop!
Frankie's gonna make it!
You!
Frankie Teardrop is gone!
Let's hear it for Frankie Teardrop!
4...
3...
2...
1...
Ladies and gentlemen...
...the stories you are about to hear
are true!
Only the names have been changed
to protect the innocent.
Now...live across Australia...
Welcome to 'Countdown'...
with a look at today's Bowie fever...
also a new Irish band...
...Irish band in stereo...
OK thanks, Gavin...I've gotta say...
I've just seen the David Bowie concert
in Melbourne...
Have you seen...
...Thunderbirds are gold...
'The Boys Next Door'...
...do you want to hear more?
They want to hear more.
Oops...sorry...!
See ya!
Have you still got the phone?
You wouldn't know, anyway.
Not another one!
Fuckin' bloody thing!
Stupid fuckwit!
5...4...3...2..1...
Good morning, Sammy!
Did ya have a good kip
on the stairs there?
Yes, little fella...it's food!
It's been a long time since you've seen
anything like this, hasn't it?
You weed!
Better watch out, Sammy...
You'll get healthy eating
all THAT crap!
You're right!
Brains...
That's TV, Sammy...
That's what you watch
when you got no brain...
...like you and me.
The physical contour of the RTL2 interests me
much less than the success of the whole operation.
Haven't you got your glasses with you,
little fella?
You're blind as a bat, aren't ya?
Careful you don't
get any sun on you, sonny...
You'll shrivel up and die!
Sammy?...Sammy No-brains...
I remember you...
Didn't I just see you a moment ago
in the kitchen?
What's this you've got here?
It's a THING.
Hmm...
It's a girl, Sammy.
Never seen one of THEM before...
have ya?!
Hello little fella...
Where are YOU from?
It's NOT a girl!
I've seen girls before...
and they don't look like that.
Want a bite
of my fairy-toast?
Check!...1-2-3...1-2...
Might explode, out come dark,
facing off into space...
Dogs out there, floatin' 'round,
it's rattling the human race...
Dogs in space...
Planet opens, out come dark,
facing off into space...
Underneath the eye of God,
angels in the shape of dogs...
Dogs in space...
Warming coat, coats of gleam,
threw up stars, charged and still...
We are tough from an open can,
dark flash in, can this be real?
Dogs in space...
Inconsiderate arseholes!
Lock the door!
Lock the door?
It's falling open...
Just got to put my lipstick on!
What for?
You've got enough on already.
No...there's not enough.
- It looks fine!   - Are you sure?
- Come on, hurry up.
You want a tug?
No...!
Hey, Jen...you want some love?
Yeah.
Good old Jenny!
Someone's been fucking using this
for making skag.
Tim.
There you are, Jen...
Oh...thanks.
Hiya, Luchio...
Been building any bridges lately?
Ah...Come on, guys...
Stop giving me a hard time!
What have you got here?
Constructional engineering.
How do you understand
all those wiggly things?
Easy...I've  done it before...
See what the government
has done?
Look at what the mad man is doing?
Totally ignored Land Rights.
Causing mass unemployment.
Poverty.  Infringement
of people's personal rights.
Spent a mega-fortune on defence.
And now he's cutting back
on social welfare.
Oh, no...Chuck's here!
How's it going...
you hippy bastards?!
One bloody thing only...
Fascist dictatorship...
and a police state!
How are you going, punk rock?
That's 2 things!
Hello Barry...how's it going?
Fightin' the fuckin' revolution, mate.
Have a bong.
- Feels beautiful!...So fluffy!
- Thank you.
- 'bye
- 'bye!
Women and blacks are the load.
- Hi Anna.
- Hi Anthony.
How's work?
Oh, you know...a bit depressing.
My favorite patient died today.
- Oh, really?!
- Yeah.
I used to work in a nursing-home.
- A while ago.
- Did you?
It's really sad actually, the way
they're put away like that...
Some of them are so cluey.
Yeah...I know what you mean...
- I met some amazing characters.
- Fuck off Sam, I'm trying to talk.
There was this old guy in there...
He was a vaudeville actor
from Hollywood.
He was ancient!
Fuck!
Stop it!
There was this one guy...
He was an old vaudeville actor
from Hollywood...
Yeah?
He was really ancient.
He must have been
well over 80.
He came out here
in the thirties...
He knew people like Douglas Fairbanks
...and Charlie Chaplin.
He's an amazing character.
Leave me alone!
Come here!
Find many beer-bottle tops?
Stop it!
Yeah...he knew people
like Charlie Chaplin and Douglas Fairbanks.
Say 'three'!
Three!
Say Meryl Streep.
Fuck off!
You only care about yourself.
I do not!
I've written a song
about you, Clare.
Oh yeah...
What's it called?
'Brick Woman'
Oh...thanks a lot!
He was incredible...
- ...he'd just ramble...
- Why's it called that?
Coz you're a BRICK!
Anyway, I used to get round
into the wards...
Hi guys...what's happening?
Show it to me!
Come on Charles!
I remember when I had a girlfriend...
Boy, those were the days, eh, Luch...
More sex than you could
poke a stick at...Sorry Jenny.
Did someone here say 'Ballarat'?
- You guys can really fuck.
- No you can't!
Twenty-one year old Frankie...
He's married, he's got a wife and kid...
Everybody is...
...acting so deranged.
Where is this party, anyway?
My God...we've landed!
Tim!
It's better than taking acid!
Righto, kids...open the door!
Bloody fuckin' bastards!
Come on!
God, I hate parties...
Piece o' poo!
We've just been involved
in a serious accident.
Nearly cost us all out lives.
Get me a drink, Billy...
I'm thirsty!
Hey, Jeff...
Jeff!...
Say...'clitoris'!
What?!
Say 'clitoris'!
Go on! It's easy!
'Clit...or...is'!
Anna!
Hell!...Anna...Got a cigarette?
Am I gonna get a drink?
I want a beer!
How does it feel?
What?
How does 'what' feel?
Being in love.
THAT thing?!
Really frightening.
What have you got there, Sammy?
My corelian wig.
Yum!
Get some crumpets.
One 'Submarine' sandwich...
...and a chocolate 'Paddle Pop'...
Sammy...what else have you got?
Do you want anything else?
Oh, and a big brown of these.
And a chocolate 'Smokey'...
We want these.
Thanks, Anna.
That's alright.
Look at all the crumpets!
Oh...what is this here?
Remember these...
A Winfield Blue...
and a packet of Peter Stuyvesant.
And I'm Freddie!
And 6 chocolate 'Freddos'...
Do you want anything?
How much is that?
Yum!
Hot brick!
I got dropped from the agency, today.
What agency?
The agency I work for!
No more of this...
No more peanut butter!
No more chocolate 'Smarties'.
Oh, Anna...this Communion dress
is just beautiful!
I had one just like that,
when I was at 'Holy Family'.
'Holy Family'?!...
I was at 'Holy Family'.
Oh, bullshit, Sammy!...
You were not!
I was!
Okay, then...
What's your Confirmation Name?
There's Anna...
...lookin' stoned.
We ARE NOT!
We haven't even GOT one!
Oh...watch out!
Get your OWN cigarettes, Sammy!
I always buy them...!
This is very important!
Is it, really?!
...the astronauts in the very special Skylab......
...join concerns of people everywhere.
...and the Skylab III crew...
we wish to extend to people around the world...
..a message of peace, goodwill,
and human understanding.
I can't believe it!
Fuckin' thing!
Oh...Luchio...
Hi...This is Anne...
- Luchio...Anne...
- Hi Luchio... - Hi...
I don't wanna hear about her!
Wouldn't you?...
Even when she had an amazing body!
I don't want to hear about it!
We must have made love,
about...7...8 times.
I don't want to hear about it!
Luchio...there are millions
of girls out there...
...All you have to do is
go out there and get them!
Listen, arsehole!...
I've got 6 engineering exams
to study for, in 5 weeks...
...and I don't want YOU
fuckin' me around!
Rompicolioni!
Dingo!
What are you doing?!...
We were watching that!
You were asleep!
Doesn't mean we weren't watching it.
Can you believe that, Tim?
Leave him alone...
You're sick!
My vein hurts.
Timmy...
Oh...shit!
The door!
Tim...get the door!
Has to be Chuck!
Oh, no...not Chuck!
- Chuck...Chuckie...
- Chuck you old bastard!
Okay, shithead...
once is enough!
My God...did I say that?!
Luchio here?
Luchio...um...
The name rings a bell.
Well, is he or isn't he?
Luchio!
Is this him, Leanne?
Hang on...
Give me a look...
Luchio!
We're in for some fun now.
Hey...do you want us to go in there
and rough him up a bit?
No...no worries...
I'll see you later.
Jesus!...What a dump!
Pleased to see me?
See ya, Leanne!...
See ya!
Oh!...Fuck!
You nearly spitted on me...
...fucking arsehole!
Oh...honey...
Come back!
- Fuck off!
- Don't leave me!
Get the bloody phone!
I AM getting it!
I don't think so...
I'll just ask.
Come back!
Hello...she was here a few times
earlier in the week...
...but she went off
on a school camp.
She's not there?
Well, I don't know
where she'd be, then.
No....I'm sure she's quite capable
of looking after herself.
Yep, she's a big girl, now!
- Yep...OK....bye bye.
- All she does is talk.
Phone!...Shut up!
She was crying.
I don't need YOU or my mother
to tell me what to do.
Love 'll get you like a case of anthrax...
And that's something I don't want to catch
And that's something I don't want to catch...
What's with the 'dress-up'?
I have an interview
to become an air-hostess.
Air-hostess!
Airline food!
Love airline food...
Bring me back some!
Is that all you can
ever think about?
I think of lots of things...
Yeah? Like what?!
Like...um...
I'll use the axe!
Now I've got to go
to the interview..all wet!...
THANKS a lot!
I'm sorry.
What are you wearing THEM for?
How else am I supposed to wash 'em?
You're disgusting!
Coming tonight?
No!...
Who wants to hear YOU sing?
Bring your eye-liner!
Please.
Come on...let's DO something!
Where did Mitch get to?
Hang around, and you'll see
Mitch's first one-night stand!
Let's score!
I love that theme.
Great pad, Anna...
How much is the rent?
50 a week...great isn't it?
This hair looks great...
You'll love it.
Watch out...Chuck's here.
Come on David...
Let's get a fuckin' move on!
He's in a bad mood!
We're busy...we're takin' stock!
Better get that thing working, Tim.
- Yeah...try it. Try it!
- Shut up!
What about ME,
you bastards.
How are the synthesisers, Timmy?
It's gonna be fantastic.
Can I have a bottle of ephedrine.
Yes...it's all there...
- You get 'em?
- Yeah.
Chuck's leaving...
Come on!
It's wonderful!
Looks great...
Just love it!
- You're a fantastic hairdresser, Anna.
- Come back here!
Leanne...come on up!
Boo!
'Called Sue'...
I'll be right down.
Bloody hippy!
- Hi Sue....sorry!
- Bloody sex-maniac!
Fixed it, Tim?
- Shut up, Chuck!
- Hi, Tim.
- This is Sue.
- Hi Sue!  - Hi!
Tim...can I borrow
your Dingo record?
Can you borrow it?!
You've still got it
from last time!
-You're right, Tim...
- I've given up trying to steal it back!
What 've you done with my sticks?
Great!
Nice!
That should do it!
Prepare yourself, Moocho...
He's playin' that record again.
Sam...where are my sticks?
Thanks for nothin',
you bastard!
Alright...let's drive!
...true love...working it out...
True love's what it's all about...
True love...beautiful...
Hey!...
What's on at the monkey's place?
Hey...Anna!...
Got any underwear, Anna?
Have you got my lipstick?
Who's playing, Anna?
The Champions!
Somebody get the fucking phone!
Just leave me alone.
Yeah...you'd like that,
wouldn't ya?!
I hate ya...hate, hate, hate!
Fuck that...
I've got pure adrenalin!
Cigarette?
Still guilts?
It's about Tim...
I've got this friend...
with a real synthesiser.
Well, Chuck...
Time to buy us a beer.
Reckon it might be,
you old bastard.
Come down to the bar with me,
and I'll buy YOU one.
This stuff's made
from an electronics kit!
You could get something
so much better.
He's not a fuckin' muso...
He can't even play.
It'd be really good to have someone...
who knows something about music.
I've been contemplating suicide...
But it really doesn't suit my style...
So I think I'll just act bored instead...
Who contain the blood I could've shed?
She makes me feel so weary...
My heart is really on its knees...
But I keep a poker face so well...
That even mother couldn't tell...
Oh, fuck it!
Come on girls...
give it a push!
Come on girls...push, Anna!
Why don't you, 'round the door?
Come on...let's go...
Are you a cowgirl?!
Whoo...cowgirl!...whoo whoo!
Fuckin' bitches!...
Fuck off!
Oh...you're beautiful!
Could you buy me a drink, Annie?
You were going to give me some pot.
Anna!
Buy us a beer!
I missed you!
You know you only said that yourself!
I do so love you!
Liar!
I do! I love your big nose!
Big nose!
Filthy cowgirl moll!
It's not finished yet.
Hi, Anna!
- It's alright?
- Yeah.
- Kate!
- Yeah?
- Got any 'speed' on you?
- Yeah!
What's the matter with HER?
Alright, guys...what's happening?
What's that doing?
Excuse me...
Could I have a tequila and orange...
Are you sure it's in here?
There...it's in there!
Thanks...That'll do.
Pure adrenalin...
George got it from a chemist place.
Oh...shit!
Oh my God...
I don't think you should
swallow this in future.
Yeah.
Can't you get that
bloody thing working, Tim?
Leave him alone, Davis!
It's supposed to be a synthesiser,
you know.
Shut up, will you...
It's gonna work.
Come on, Tim...
Get it together!
Hello there...dogs in space.
Long ago when I was not much younger
than a day...
Daddy used to take me there
to watch him as he played...
Golf course do you remember
of course you do...
Golf course when I was young
I did not envy you...
Now the days have turned to years
and I'll become a man...
I bought myself a set of clubs
and I tried the best I can.
Here comes the early morning light
revealing you...
Golf course without you there's
not much a man can do...
Golf course do you remember?...
Of course you do...
Golf course when I was young
I did not envy you...
A world's a scene in my head
telling me how to play...
I'm alive, so alive, well,
what more can I say?
Ask me what I get it done
than where the future lies...
I tap my clubs and smile and say
I'll stay here 'til I die.
Here comes the early morning light
revealing you...
Golf course when I was young remember,
I did not envy you.
Golf course do you remember?
Of course you do!
Golf course a hundred percent....
I'll not envy you...
I can fix it...
Just give us a second.
Okay...here's your beers...
Let's get out of here...right?
Boz...I'll buy you a drink.
Big fucking deal!
Do you forgive me?
Sam!...
Listen...can you score for us?
Can you sing?!
Thank you very much.
I've been contemplating suicide...
but it really doesn't suit my style...
so I think I'll just act bored instead...
Fakes and phonies...
That's all they fucking-well are!
How do you know
if you've had a good time?
Well, how d'ya know?
How DO ya know?!
When ya throw ya knickers
up against the wall...
...and they STICK there!
You wanted to front that girl...
didn't ya?!
Tim...
We've all decided
to get a new keyboard...
...kind of.
It doesn't matter.
I was gonna leave, anyway.
Are you coming, Sammy... or what?
Hey...wait for ME!
and the sound of her name
sends a permanent shiver
down my SPINE.
I keep her photograph against my heart...
for in my life she played a starring part.
All alcohol and cigarettes...
I've got no room for cheap regrets...
Will you do it for me?
Just hold onto it.
You will have a long flight...
And then you should come clean.
Once upon a time,
there was a green monster...
And he ate a whole train
full of obnoxious people.
Of course he got
a very bad case of indigestion...
...that lasted for many weeks.
And so he eventually decided
that he needed some medicine.
He strolled, on his many legs,
to the nearest pharmacist, and said...
"I have indigestion and nausea..."
"What from?" asked the chemist.
"Oh...just all the obnoxious people
in this world."
...said the dragon.
And the chemist, after carefully
considering the monster's problem...
...gave him some milk of magnesia.
In 2 days, the monster
was feeling better again...
So he ate another train
full of the same sort of people.
He felt worse than before...
...and after weeks of suffering...
...went back to the chemist...
"Please help me, Mr Chemist!"
he said
"All of THOSE people in this world,
make me terribly sick."
The pharmacist replied...
"You must get over this terrible objection
to the people of this world..."
"I'll give you some
milk of magnesia, anyway."
The green monster
was much fatter now...
...yet, as he had eaten 2 trains...
recovered in a few days.
He was lying
by the railway tracks...
...when a train stopped,
right in front of him.
He looked up with his big brown eyes...
...watching the people...
Even man's sleep was monitored
by a cap with sensors...
...as each astronaut bedded down
vertically in a sort of sleeping bag...
...in his individual sleep compartment...
...or should I say...stateroom!
Why on the one-way?...
Look at notice...
Look at the sign,
you bastard...look!
Only one-way...
Only one-way! You...
You want a go, mate?...
Come on!...
Effin' wog!
Morning!
Leanne!
It depends, really...
It can be over in 5 minutes.
And then...it can last for hours.
Especially if it's stirred.
And sometimes
you can almost fall asleep.
The worst part of it
is standing up after...
...and have it all running
down your leg!
Yeah...yuk!
Get up!
What sort of time do you call this?
We've been up since 5 o'clock!
- Hi, Al!
- Come on!
Jesus Christ!...
-...What sort of dump...
- Tony...wake up! You've got some visitors.
What sort of shit-cunt
sort of street is this anyway?!
Lucky I didn't bring the '250' down here...
I've brought the 'F100'...
It was all I could do
to get it down the street.
- It wouldn't do me, I tell ya.
- Come on...wake up!
I've got a truckload
of chainsaws down there...
I'd better not leave them there
without me being there.
I'll go down and get 'em
out of the truck.
I'll bring them into the kitchen.
Okay?
Weren't you supposed
to be at work today?
I don't feel like going.
Well, how would YOU
like to try it?
You just don't give a shit about anyone
except yourself...DO you?
Let's go back to the comfortable environment
of life in space.
No circus acrobat
or elite swimmer, can match this.
Well, you take this little beauty, mate...
It purrs like a kitten full of cream...
It's so simple to use...
your granny could use it...
And this chain brake...
That's what your professionals
dream of...right?
I tell you what...
It's got an 80cc motor...
...that puts out enough power...
...to really get
you environmentalists worried!
Sam!
Down there to the left...
just right in front of the telly.
Oh God...a hippy!...
...Yeah?
I'm Barbara...I rang you.
I'm from the Socialist Youth Alliance.
Oh, yeah!
Yeah...
The 'Rock Against Unemployment' concert.
Have a seat.
Where shall I start?
Well, that's Nick...he's in the band...
plays guitar...
Hi Nick!
Excellent!
- Hey Nick...which one's Don Bradman?
- Well as you're probably already aware...
...all the welfare schemes
put into operation by the sacked Labor government...
...have been ruthlessly slashed
by the present fascist Fraser dictatorship.
It eats into the living tissue
of the working classes...
...like a tumour.
"Power to the workers"...yeah...
I've got cancer.
It's a refusal to even acknowledge
the institutionalised bureaucracy...
...that perpetrates these social conditions...
...Right?!
So...we're organising a benefit concert...
...for bands such as yourselves...
...whose music epitomises an anarchist
and...
Anarchistic?
Anarchistic...
Got a cigarette?
...reaction to the present
totalitarian society...
..and attempts to break down
the crushing monopolies of the multinationals.
No future...right?!
Right.
How much money we gonna get?
How much money do we get?
Has your band got insurance?
"Countdown"!
And now...live through Australia...
"Countdown"...
Now let's talk to the great Bowie!
Get out of the way!
Hi...I'm Barbara.
G'day...I'm Jenny... this is Colin...Al...
Emmy and Lizzy.
Do you people realise the present capitalist crisis,
we now find ourselves in?
I mean...we're in a situation today...
...totally and completely...
This'll go through a red-gum sleeper,
like a knife through a piece of fuckin' butter.
Do you realise that?
If this gets stuck...say in a log...
All you do, is whack on the chain brake...
And it slips straight out, like that!
Fuckin' incredible!
Where's Eno?
Did he get thrown out
of his band, too?
Shut up, Tim!
I'll give you a demonstration...
Now we missed it all!
Fuckin' idiot!
That's a dumb thing...
We're trying to listen to the TV.
We were watching that.
You wouldn't 've said that
if it was a guitar, you know.
YOU could operate that.
Look...it's like driving a car...
I drive a V8...
I wouldn't drive anything else.
Not like these whelps in here...
They're putting
the whole movement back years.
After 1975 and 'Gang of Four'...
Hiya 'Chainsaw Baby'!
How'dya like a nice big axe
to play with, eh?
It was originally designed
by the Swedish...
...to operate under
all weather conditions.
Here's our bundle...
Haven't paid in 3 months...
There's Guy Fawkes.
Won't be long before you're
spewing out one of them, will it?
I hate babies!
One day you can grow up
and take on louts like him...
Won't that be fun?!
Let's say hello to Uncle Sammy No-brain!
It's the only part of the whole machine
that's not made in Sweden.
But you've got to remember...
Put the plastic cover
back on the top.
Otherwise you could
put your hand back...
...and burn the back of it
on the cylinder-head.
Otherwise it's a...
fucking amazing machine, that!
It's a fucking amazing machine.
Don't forget to get the batteries.
Hello, welcome to the store...
How can WE help YOU?!
There's better be some egg-flip here!
There's only one left,
and that's mine!
I'll tell Tim...but I don't think
he'll be very pleased.
- Tim...no egg-flip left.
- What?!
No bloody egg-flip left...man...
what's the world coming to!
I've been called a lot of things
in my time...
....but I'm not responsible
for shortages.
I like these...
Can I get a whole-grain sandwich?
Can I get some 'Coco-Pops'?
Davis...you're really stupid!...
Big...little...
Well at least we're in bread.
Hello, Mum.
Hello, Sam!
The time, Mum.
I had to book it, Sam.
No drinks?
Sorry...I'll go and get something.
No...don't bother.
I brought you some clean clothes.
Are you still with that girl?
Does SHE cook?
Father Francis said to say hello.
You can ALWAYS stay at home,
you know.
I'm on my own now.
Luch...
There's something
I've been meaning to tell you...
I'm pregnant.
Well, I know it's not yours...
But it's gonna need a father...
Enjoy that?
I have to go now...
- Take care.
- I will.
See you, Mum.
Bang!
But, Leanne...
Bloody arsehole!
Leanne, I'm not the father!
Thanks for nothin', creep-face!
Aw...Leanne!
- Hi, Leanne.
- Piss off!
Anna...
Anna...Is that you?
Fucking arsehole!
Why don't you go after her,
if that's what you want?!
Hey Tim...this egg-flip
tastes like cold sick!
Yeah...great, isn't it?
Sammy No-brain!
I wouldn't kiss you, if you were
the last bloke on earth!
Oh yes...you don't have to,
you know.
Bloody egg-flips are shit!
- What day is it Mully?
- I'm not Mully...
Get out of the way...
You weed!
What gives me the shits, is the Fraser
government's attitude to land rights.
After what he did to Whitlam!
One of my closest friends
has an aboriginal girlfriend, right...
A really beautiful person...
But so fucking angst!
Are you a Malist or a Trot?
Smile, guys!
...stop jumping up and down...
...so I can see who you are.
I'm not jumping.
What's your name?
Guthrie.
Are you someone I know?
We met last night
at the Waldorf-Ritz.
Oh yes, you were with Mrs Matthews,
talking to God.
Or were you?
I'm the forgotten man.
But surely you'd allow Maoists back.
HOW much money did you...?
It's arseholes like you
who perpetuate the state of male domination...
How many other societies
do YOU know of...
...where the main form of male abuse
is to grope for the female genitals.
Women are the slaves of slaves...
and the outcasts of outcasts...
...Bonded into marital prostitution...
...in YOUR male-dominated society.
Are we gettin' through to you,
shit-head?
...you and your wife bloody fill us up
with toxins from our industrialised society...
Now this is the only thing
that can break 'em down.
I used to be in a band.
I quit, though.
I'm getting too famous.
- Chlorophyl?
- Yeah...chlorophyl.
Liquid sunshine!
You look at any society
in the world today...
...and on the bottom rung of the ladder,
you'll find women and blacks...
Do you understand that...
you stupid cunt!?
Cheers, Bub.
Bloody punk-rockers!
What the hell...
That's why I use benzie.
Hey...it's the fuckin' Trots, mate...
Split us!...
Split the black movement...
Split the women's movement...
Split the primates!
Split the fuckin' apathy!
Still smoking that?
There's not much left...
I can't believe you're living
in this place...
These men are preying on the naivet
and inexperience of young girls!
It's pure sexual exploitation!
Barny, mate!...Merci beaucoup!...
as they say in fuckin' Europe.
You have beautiful hair!
Are you involved with anybody
at the moment?
Get out of it...you stupid creep!
What YOU need...is a good fuck!
I had some 'magic mushrooms', once.
And I was feeding my dog...
...And all these blue and red sparks
started shooting up between my fingers.
And all these little rain-clouds
around my head...
...and sort of rained on it!
Fan...tas...tic.
It's ME...I'm on fire!
Do you want a tug?
Oi...you!...
What?
Suck my brother's fucking dick!
What's YOUR 'glue'...a 'friar'?
Are you alright?
Tequila!
Hey Tim!
It's the cops!
One thing I hate
more than fucking blokes...
...is fucking dykes!
Do you think you could turn
the music down?...
...because the neighbours
have been complaining.
And keep your little friend up there, quiet...
...Because we don't want
to have to come back, again!
Tequila...TEQUILA!
Fuckin' arseholes!
Ya fake arseholes!
Take hold of it...!
Shove it up ya fake A!
Yeah...ya fuckin' fakes!
Hey...how can you hate...
someone your pint size...
If Chuck touches me once more...
I'll scream!
Have you got
any cough mixture?
I'll need that for my throat.
Yeah...sorry.
What are you doing?
What exam's that for?
When is it?
About a week.
You're kidding!
Piss off!...The lot of ya!
Fuckin' idiots!
Fuckheads!
Come on, you fuck!...
Help me with this.
Hurry up!
Oh God...
Who's he fucking now?!
Hey, Luchio, ya bastard...
Plug this in!
NASA has also just confirmed
that the American space station 'Skylab'
will re-enter the earth's atmosphere
at approximately 6am this morning.
It would break up in the stratosphere
about 100 miles due east of Melbourne
scattering burning debris
in a wide fan-shaped trail
across the southern states of Australia.
And that's the end
of this evening's news bulletin.
We cross now to London to pick up
the final day of play at Lords,
in the Australia v England
World Series Test Cricket.
You know, 3XY are offering $1000...
...to the first person to bring
a piece of 'Skylab' into the studio.
A thousand dollars!
I wonder how much heroin THAT'd buy!
We wish to apologise for the cancellation
of the scheduled live telecast from London...
You've gotta be kidding!
We now bring you instead, our late movie...
"His Girl Friday".
Beauty!...ANYTHING'S better
than the cricket!
- Oh, what would YOU know?
- Shut up!
Fucking arsehole!
I've seen this movie...
It's really great!
- Forgive me?
- NO!
I'm bored!
Tim's goin' to have some fun...
say hello to the sex-maniacs!
Hello, sex-maniacs!
Davis...you're really stupid.
Yeah...youse guys are idiots.
Shut up!
It's MY TV!
You're in front of the bloody picture!
- It's MY television.
- It IS NOT!
Bloody well is so!
It IS NOT, Sam!
Shut up!...
I'm tryin' to WATCH this!
- That's Linette's mum's television which she gave to us.
- I think it's MY television.
Bullshit! This is the one
my brother gave me...
THAT's the one
that Linette gave YOU.
That one with all the paint
and bullshit on it.
THAT's the one
your brother gave you.
This is mine...
...and now it's on fuckin' fire...
and I don't want it burnt!
Well, it's a bit fuckin' late now...
isn't it, Sam?!
You know, in all the years
I've known Sammy...
...I've never heard of him, ONCE...
...having a single coherent thought!
In the entire time!
My brother Ed is gonna kill you, Davis!
Oh, don't worry...
I don't want to know...
I want to see the movie!
...I seen in that film...
Anyone for coffee...or sex?!
What?...either or both?
I want coffee.
Piss off...or go to bed.
- I knew this guy...
- Oh, yeah.
He was a friend
of my mother's.
Got to know each other
really well.
It's amazing how much
we came to suit each other.
We'd think about things
in the same way.
There was perfect chemistry.
You could tell
what each other was thinking.
How old is he?
41.
Really?!
It's not just physical, you know.
He ended up having these terrible fights
with my mother...
He'd tell me about it afterwards.
He wanted to stay here and live...
become a resident...
...except his visa ran out.
My mother rang up Immigration,
and got him deported.
That's terrible.
The bitch.
We've been hit!
Help!
Women and children first!
Thanks a lot, guys!
Aah...shut up, ya arsehole!
Come on, Annie...let's go!
Watch it!...
I could get killed!
Want to go upstairs?
Oh...yeah...
That'd be nice.
Watch it!...
The neighbour's here!
For why? 4 o'clock in the morning!
Why for you do this?!
Move!
I'll see you tomorrow...
Alright?
Okay.
I'm gonna stay in Tim's room.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Goodnight.
Gee, Chuck...what's that?!
I dunno, Nick...
Must have been Skylab!
"Solar winds, Earth-view"...
Sounds far-fetched at the moment,
doesn't it?
But you know...
You may be seeing ads like this
in the not-too-distant future.
In fact, there's the equivalent
of a small bungalow
out there in space,
right now.
It's empty and available...
...with a beautiful view of Earth.
Skylab...a bungalow that has
already had 9 tenants...
The main purpose of Skylab
was to make space flight more useful
to man's endeavours on Earth.
I am fucking warning you...
Why you play music?
Oh...hello!
At least I didn't miss anything.
Bugger off!
What the fuck's THAT?
You're not USING anything...ARE you?!
Anything what?
Didn't think so.
One minute.
I wouldn't have to borrow any,
if you didn't steal all of mine!
And don't you dare play
that bloody Eno record!
What's this, Davis?
It's a sheep, Luchio.
Took a trip up the country last night,
and got you a little friend.
And if you don't like it...
you can always eat it!
I got it!
Hey...what is that?
I've never done this before,
you know.
Me neither!
Oh, bullshit!
It's true...
I'm a born-again virgin.
This is outrageous!
Would you believe this, Luchio?
Typical of a bunch of spoiled
middle-class brats.
Pathetic!
Have you seen some of the girls
they have in here?
They can't be more than 14!
What's that?
It's a sheep.
Don't you know anything?
It's not gonna fit.
Either I'm too big,
or you're too small.
Would you mind if I use
some Vaseline?
G'day, Tones...
Well you must've really got up
your neighbour's nose this time...
He reckons you've got drugs
on the premises.
You wouldn't have anything
like that here...would ya?
No...not that I know of.
No, I didn't think so...well...
I think we'd better come in
and take a look around...
...just for the record...
you understand.
Hey, guys...there's a bloody sheep
in my room!
Well, think yourself lucky!
Well there doesn't seem
to be anything here.
Anyway, Bert...
You want to take a squiz-around,
out the back?
Yeah...'right.
Yeah, I know how you feel, Tones...
It's a bit bloody ridiculous.
I was at me girlfriend's place last week
...sharin' a joint!
And what happens?...
The blokes from the Richmond CID
decide to raid the place for drugs...
Well it's MY head
that's on the choppin' block!
If this doesn't get us $1000...
nothing will!
Skylab...
There's a bloody lamb in here!
Yeah...well, anyway...
It cost me a fortune in beers
to get out of that one...
...unscathed...so to speak.
...we'll have to start drinking,
till we have sex.
What's it look like out the back...
pretty clean?
It's no worries.
Yeah...that's what I thought.
Okay...thanks a lot, Tones!
Lucky we got you guys here...
Otherwise there'd be
nothin' for us to do!
- Seeya.
That's the stratosphere...
That's travelling through space.
The Skylab.
I think I'm gonna join
the Public Service.
Thank God!
Good luck, Luchio!
Thanks, mate!
Hey...look at what you do...
4 o'clock in the morning!
Not WHAT you do,
4 o'clock in the morning...
You play the music!
WHY you do this?
- Hi, Tones...
- Hi.
Could WE have a word?
Sure!
I've decided to go to Sydney.
Really?!
- Yeah.
- How long for?
I don't know...about 3 months,
or something.
Okay then...
If you want to go...
I suppose you should.
Hi!
Hi.
- How are YOU, this morning?
- I'm fine.
I still love you...Okay?
If Barry comes around
looking for me...
...tell him I don't live here
any more...okay?
I'm going rock-climbing.
- Goodbye.
- See you.
I'll tell you why they fuck
sixteen-year old girls!...
Thanks...see you later.
...because they're scared
anybody older...
...would tell them
what a lousy ROOT they are!
Bloody dykes!
Jen...
...are you coming or staying?
You don't HAVE to come,
you know...
You can stay with HER.
A high priority is also placed on a machine
that would allow an astronaut...
...to move freely about,
outside a spacecraft.
Using the Skylab's upper dome area,
to explore this kind of flying characteristic...
The astronaut uses...
Hello...come on everyone...
Where IS everyone?
Where ARE they?
Come on, ya bastards!
See ya!
It's just come in
from Thailand.
They got it through Customs
in a shoe.
What's the address...
Do you remember?
Sammy!...
Hello...it's photo time!
Oh, no...what a bore!
Jeffrey!
Are you in?
Hi, Jeffrey!
I want three 'tons'.
You want some?
It's great, isn't it?
Ready?
Oh baby, what a place to be...
In the service of the bourgeoisie...
Where can my believers be...
I wanna jump into the endless sea.
Oh oh, the endless sea...
I wanna jump into the endless sea...
Let it wash all over me.
Above us is a dirty sky...
Full of youths and liquors...
A little girl, a little guy...
This air can't get much thicker.
Oh oh, the endless sea...
Let it wash all over me.
And when you're tight for the rent...
You think you're gonna break...
But you know it's no damn good...
Just one more phony on the take...
You better go...
Oh buddy...
I really think that you better go...
Buddy...you better go!
I've passed!
I've bloody-well passed
the whole lot!
It's hard to believe it.
Hey, guys!...
What's happened?
The endless...sea.
Lord...hear our prayer...
Welcome our sister, Anna...
And help US to comfort each other,
with the assurance of our faith.
There's a corner to this room...
Where there's nothing left to remember...
There's time on the clocks on the wall...
But there's nothing left to remember...
A thought or two lingers on...
In memoriam the plaques on the wall
and time stands still...
Rooms for the memory,
rooms for the memory...
rooms for the memory.
It's a pretty nasty business, Tones...
When these gorillas come
and knock down your door...
...and drag all your personal effects
out into the middle of the road...
...But you haven't paid your rent
in 3 months...
So, legally, you haven't got a leg
to stand on, Tones.
The best we can do
is give you 24 hours...
...and then you'll have to find
somewhere else to live.
There's time on the clocks on the wall...
But time stands still, remember.
But there's nothing left at all...
A thought or two lingers on...
In memoriam the plaques on the wall
and time stands still.
Rooms for the memory,
rooms for the memory...
rooms for the memory.
There's a corner to this room...
A telephone, a chair, a memory...
But there's nothing left to this gloom...
When time stands still, remember.
A thought or two lingers on...
In memoriam the plaques on the wall
and time stands still...
Rooms for the memory,
rooms for the memory...
rooms for the memory.
Remember!
Rooms for the memory...
Subtitles by FatPlank for KG.