Come on, Jeanne?
Robert?
Hello
Come, sit.
Well
Why do you want both
writing fiction?
- You do not like?
- No.
Sorry, but I prefer
be quite honest.
Not good.
Forget it.
I want to write this story.
Listen, Jeanne, forget
stories, novels.
Their biographies are remarkable.
His investigations
history is accurate.
Your guides are written
with imagination.
But that is not writing,
this is journalism.
E?
So what?
I've had enough of that.
I want to write something else.
- When I was little...
- In former times.
Or change the subject.
This is a failure.
Why write about your childhood?
- She inspires me.
- It does not inspire, do not.
I'm not saying there's nothing there.
Are single images.
Heroin notes
but lacks depth and emotion.
Several details of the story
never become clear.
These details are important.
- I want very detailed descriptions.
- I know, Jeanne, I know.
But it is very cold.
You do not make sufficient use
their memories.
I have no memory.
I do not remember anything
before age 8.
Sorry, I did not know.
His mother and you...
never told me.
- I do not understand...
- No matter.
There are things and pictures.
Mom told me a lot.
The memory is not made of information,
but perceptions and emotions.
And that is precisely why
interests me.
I must write about it
and rediscover my childhood.
Something was lost in my life.
Sure.
Thanks for receiving me.
Jeanne?
You okay?
Yes..
- Nadia?
- A.
Three for me.
Nadia, in turn.
1000.
I will.
His 1000 plus 3.
I run.
- More 1000.
- I bet it all.
Come on, kids.
Take your designs and pens and go.
Jeanne?
Nadia, you're playing?
Wait, darling, I'm going.
I'm finished here.
- Is he interested?
- No.
Why?
Many descriptions, facts and details.
- What details?
- No matter.
Let me read it and tell you what I think.
No, not yet.
Why not start
with an autobiography?
I read "Tales of Jeanne" for them.
Mother, it was 30 years ago.
That his father
and his brother?
They were legal?
Do not worry, honey.
Nadia, you come from?
- You can have dinner with me?
- I do not like to see you play.
And I do not like your friends.
- Let's go somewhere else.
- No.
I'm tired.
You clear your hair?
It is more beautiful without it.
- Bye, my dear.
- Bye, Grandma.
I'll call you tonight.
Coming.
Robert is a fool.
Your book is great.
I canceled my meeting / dinner.
We will spend time together.
No, please, I hate it.
Stop.
It's just for us
children will love.
In this case...
Smile, honey.
Crap!
It has a boy in school
who is afraid of apples.
This is strange.
Enough. Eat.
- You are reading your books?
- Just taking a look.
I had more imagination
old, no?
That's backwards.
Find inspiration in the present.
- Mom said the same thing.
- So maybe not a good idea.
can talk. 'm Filming.
Are you sure?
Will enslave us.
Only 5 minutes.
Jeremie release his sister.
not fight.
Stop, do not like it.
Stop.
It seems so stupid.
What is this?
I'm tired or what?
The table was moved.
Parallel to the window.
As ever.
You changed the table.
Why have you changed the table?
The table has always been so.
No matter, as long as everything
return to its place.
Lea.
What are you doing?
What is this nonsense?
What are these words and these guys?
I see nothing.
It's just a movie.
You could laugh at least.
What is this?
For me?
No.
Did you like your movie?
Stop, do not like it.
I let you work,
therefore deserve a small reward.
I'll make a hot chocolate.
Hi
I could not wake her.
- The board did not return to the place?
- What place?
Do not start again.
I also have to say in how
things are placed in the kitchen, right?
Where's the honey?
I'm warning you
everything has to go back to your place.
I hope you have a good memory, because
I will not spend hours looking for things.
No one changed anything.
He got on the wrong foot?
You can check my dick?
I put it right
and I think he has changed.
Very funny.
Jeremie, put your hands on the table.
Coma.
Lea, feels right.
All you need in 27 days?
Who are these gestures?
Is someone in your presence?
Are you crazy?
Yes, of course.
I'm mad.
I'm a little lost
because of the table.
- Easy, Jeanne.
- No.
- This is hot.
- Sorry.
Give me that.
Do not do these guys.
I'm tired.
I'm tired, OK?
We comb the hair.
The birthday party was not bad.
Do not move,
or you can cut.
I wonder
how others live.
Everything seems strange.
And I do not like his mother.
It flattens my hair
and smells like eggs.
Raw eggs or fried?
A little like ham.
not agree, but I'm listening.
Let's do something.
I'll do something.
fictitious.
To obtain the license.
also will go to prison for killing him.
I'm losing time
customers and patience.
He is incompetent.
He's looking for me,
for us, and he will find.
What?
Nothing.
Go.
This trainee is a bag.
I swear I'll beat him.
Want a drink?
Bird.
Come to Mama.
Lea?
You scared my bird.
Put your pajamas.
Grandma is gonna come.
I made posters for the Day of Woody Allen.
- I do not know which to choose.
- Maybe this.
What are those squiggles?
What happened?
Not like most of the apartment?
No, that's fine.
You became obsessed
with this table.
I misplaced my necklace.
Jeanne?
Will you answer me?
I see changes everywhere.
The table and other things.
Everywhere.
Their eyes and faces.
Everything is changing.
Everything?
What do you mean?
I do not know where I am
and most do not recognize this apartment.
I recognize some things,
furniture...
But we are not ourselves.
And the pictures and videos...
...do not recognize anyone.
Not us.
It is a different family.
Outside things are normal,
but here...
Are you serious?
Do not recognize anyone
is a serious matter.
Maybe something with your head.
Maybe a brain injury
or a tumor. I do not know.
A tumor?
Stop saying those things.
I recognize you.
You said no.
I recognize many things.
This is not a tumor.
Maybe it's his eyes.
Go to the hospital.
See a doctor.
I'm afraid.
Maybe it's nothing serious
it has to be examined.
It's okay.
Tonight we will relax.
Let's not talk of literature.
- OK?
- No, no.
- Good night.
- Good night, Teo.
- How are you?
- Okay.
Children already dined.
- Jeanne is in our room.
- I know the way.
like a drink?
Why do not you call?
Not have time.
But stop, I get stressed
for you to worry.
Thank you.
No.
I will not insist further.
I do not understand but okay.
A pity.
There is food in the refrigerator,
and thanks for the shawl.
It is the story of a woman
witnessing a crime.
She hears a gun firing.
Everyone around you try
help her cope with the shock.
And very quickly, she is deaf.
I've heard enough.
is not what it is.
According to her,
is related to the firing of the gun.
But her husband, who was with her,
not remember anything.
As if his memory
had been cleaned.
She begins to suspect her husband's
and the people around you.
Why are behaving
in a strange way.
She oversees the.
We fear that she may be dead.
It is when we understand
she died at the beginning.
- It seems very interesting.
- This is a complete nonsense.
Forgot Italian
he learned in school?
I remember perfectly.
Okay.
Are you satisfied or talk some more.
Anyway, it is not
the film is.
Here.
is the story of a woman
he sees an accident...
It's a little tricky.
We will see you
and judge ourselves.
What are you doing, Jeanne?
Nothing.
I do not know.
Why are you crying?
What?
I'm not crying.
I do not understand.
I'm not sad.
Not even noticed.
You are hiding something, Jeanne?
In the book and the problem of the eyes,
you seem absent.
You do not pay attention.
Even the children have noticed.
They said that?
It is because of the book
or is it something else?
I want to know.
I do not know.
I do not know...
I do not know
I do not understand...
I'll try to be more attentive.
Come. Are 3 in the morning. I work.
- Are you crazy?
- Sorry.
- Be careful.
- Yes, sorry.
Unable...
...service is out.
- Here.
- Thank you.
never bother about the number itself
so it's normal to forget it.
You okay?
What happened?
She is shaken.
I had a lapse of memory
but now everything is fine.
Come on, children are alone.
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye.
- What are you doing?
- The same every day.
It will become a vegetarian?
Hurry.
Between.
Jeremie?
Lea?
Children?
We are in the room.
Jeremie?
What are you doing?
Mom.
I'm hot.
I'm going to change.
I'll put the cartoon.
Jeanne?
What?
See?
Yes, you are very red.
That's it?
What do you mean?
I do not understand.
What were you doing?
What is wrong?
- Sit down.
- I feel hot.
- What the doctor say?
- Nothing.
Well, something.
Cranial pressure rose.
Can be the cause.
- Why? What else could it be?
- Nothing. I do not know.
- He gave some treatment?
- Yes
There seems to be sure.
Let's call him.
- I want to know.
- Not now, please.
Tomorrow, OK?
- Still feeling hot?
- Yes
- Just how hot?
- Stop, is with cold hands.
- Do not feel so hot.
- Stop it.
Let's go out for a few days
after the day of Woody Allen.
Going to do well.
We can go to the Hotel Borgne.
You like it.
- Borgne?
- Yes
I've never been there.
- You're wrong, not me.
- Stop.
I saw you sing. I was
firefighter club karaoke.
It will not convince me
it was not you.
Were you there?
How do you know?
I mean, you remember that?
I miss you, Teo.
I miss you.
I'm not doing it on purpose.
Things will improve.
Relax.
Teo?
No.
Let me go, motherfucker!
Let go!
Sorry.
No, that was good.
This guy and that,
"Let me go, bitch!"
I loved it.
I had the courage to ask you
call me a piece of shit.
That would have been better.
Daddy, the movie ended.
Mommy will give you a bath.
I take a walk.
I need air.
No...
I need psychiatric help.
Jeanne did not say
has always been fragile.
Nor said
who suffered a serious accident.
What caused amnesia.
I do not know what all this means.
Can you tell me something more
about these changes?
What changed?
Everything.
The colors of things.
Others.
I.
And how do you see?
I...
I always had brown hair
and blue eyes, green.
How do you see your husband?
Well
It is not pretty.
Well, it's a little prettier.
I see a man with
light brown hair, short,
blue eyes and a small
scar on his forehead.
Broad shoulders and slightly bent.
Tall, with dark complexion.
There is nothing wrong
to see it differently.
No, I see it the same way.
But my husband had brown eyes
and a clear complexion.
Hair too dark, wavy.
He had a round body
a constitution and heavier.
This is the man with whom I lived.
He is not the same man.
Incredible, is not it?
This is difficult for you,
but try to understand without judging.
You can leave us alone?
- Yes
- Thank you.
Yes?
I'm listening.
Nothing.
I said everything.
These changes and gestures...
As if the gestures
were made by others.
Strange faces that have stopped coming.
As if they were
keeping a secret.
Moments with no connection to anything.
- Like a dream?
- Nothing like that.
Changes
in your daily life scare you?
Not much.
But it all seems staged,
as if I were manipulated
for my husband and children.
You said it also changed.
But since he came here this means
you think you have a problem.
There must be something more.
It's not just me.
Everything is so different.
When you say "different"
I hear "the others are lying. "
Think I'm lying?
- I meant the other.
- What else?
It's just a thought.
Do you feel manipulated and believes
that there is a hidden reality.
I do not know...
I'm telling you what I hear.
Often see
what we believe.
As those drawings
to hide a second drawing.
When we see the first,
no longer see the second.
I was not drawing.
I made sketches of the apartment to...
I'm not talking about it.
That was a metaphor.
I do not know.
When I think about it...
I do not know...
Someone should monitor it,
but with their consent.
I do not want to impose a treatment
to worsen things.
Since there
no neurological problem.
Monitor the situation
and do not hesitate to return.
- Thank you, doctor.
- Thank you.
I want to spend a few days
with my mother.
Previously, when he felt ill,
you looking for me, not her mother.
Can I get a ride?
Be careful
is driving too fast.
Subtitles
_rMonta_
Please do not use it against me.
Will you call me tomorrow?
Yes
Mom?
Darling.
Mom...
I feel bad.
- I want to go home.
- In 10 minutes.
Why not now?
- How long are you here?
- Listen, not now.
- In 10 minutes?
- Yes, 10 or 15.
Go drink something.
- 300.
- The bet is 300.
- Increase to 600.
- Pay.
- The bet is 600.
- Yes
Madame?
- You need something?
- No, thanks.
- Ace
- 1000.
Madame, it's your turn.
Madame wins.
Madame, the use of mirrors
is prohibited.
- Sir, it's your turn.
- 1000.
Lord, it's your turn.
Mom?
- Any problem?
- It's okay.
- I'm going.
- 5 minutes.
Hold on.
Go get my things.
Wait for me, I'm going.
Sorry.
Too small for you.
I can not breathe.
Still working
the novel?
He spoke with Robert again?
Jeanne?
You okay?
Yes
No answer.
And the romance?
Crap!
Stop asking about the novel!
- Just keeps asking about it.
- So why come?
Why did you come if you do not want to talk?
He would not talk to me
for weeks and months.
Who am I to you?
Make dinner yourself.
I'm not avoiding you.
I'm tired of these questions.
Robert gave me and started reading.
Should I return it?
How could you?
Here.
What a relief.
I could not finish it.
It's too bad.
It is unreadable.
Descriptions that never end.
Thank you for my picture.
I want to stop
write this novel.
Do not relive the past.
It is painful for both of us.
Jeanne?
You scare me.
What is wrong?
Nothing.
You misunderstood me.
I need to recover my memories.
I told him about his childhood
and that is enough.
No.
I'm missing something.
Or you're not telling me everything.
I?
Honey?
Jeanne?
What's going on?
No...
I can not continue like this...
What's going on?
You're pale.
Should I call a doctor?
The past is painful.
It is good to remind him.
Why are you doing this?
I think I'm crazy.
Are you nervous because of the novel.
Why not work as a writer?
I do not love my children.
I am a bad mother.
Never got used to them.
I make a great effort,
Teo so do not get it.
I feel trapped by it.
I'm afraid.
I'm doing what I can
but it is not good.
I do not know why.
I need to rediscover my childhood.
You think not, but you love them.
Ask not so much.
If you do not love them, then pretend.
How you?
I was not bad for you.
You will regret what he said.
I want to go to Sicily.
I want to travel.
I will not let you go
this state.
- Let me go.
- You're all I have.
I can not stand the fact
which is very far.
- You're all I have.
- Stop it!
Stop, I can not stand it.
I'll go and lie down, okay?
LECCE 1979
What are you doing, dear?
Who are they?
's Us.
This is you.
And this is me.
And who is that?
An Italian friend.
Nobody special.
I do not know why I kept that picture.
Not look this drawer for years.
Look, a theater ticket.
I do not know why...
This woman can not be Italian.
This is impossible.
She was here a while ago.
And it was you.
She is a foreigner.
And this is you, my mother.
Really?
What do you mean?
Of course I'm your mother.
But you always had that face.
Until a while ago.
I do not know who you are.
She is my mother.
I do not understand.
Hold on.
You leaving?
Forgive me.
Mom! Open the door,
Stop it, Mom.
Madame?
What are you doing
with your hair?
- Come, let's go home.
- I can not.
- I brought my stuff?
- I brought.
His mother is concerned
and looked for you everywhere.
- I left it with the neighbors.
- It is not my mother.
- Jeanne, this is absurd.
- Yeah?
Look.
Great.
His mother, you and a blonde.
What is the problem?
I'm going.
Jeanne, listen.
Jeanne, you are making things worse.
Go to the hospital
and you will calm down.
Let's go home
and spend a few days in bed.
At least the children
will see you.
Look what they did to you.
Look.
Stop!
Do not blackmail.
- I do not see it.
- What blackmail?
Are your children
and need you.
I do not recognize
my face at all, Teo.
Let me go for a few days.
Trust me.
You do not love me anymore?
I do not know.
Mom?
Sit at the table.
You okay?
Are you sure?
A little tired.
Can we talk?
- But I do not understand. I'll get...
- Wait.
I came because of this photo.
And for you.
Recognize?
No, do not recognize this picture.
What do you drink?
Coffee.
And a cream amaretto.
My name is Jeanne.
And yours?
I will make the cream, I hope you enjoy.
I came to France to see her.
Let me go.
I'm working.
You are bothering me.
Eat and go!
Why was upset about it?
What happened?
Nothing.
I do not feel well.
Who is that?
Nobody. A French.
I'm going home.
Hi
We know?
I do not know. What do you think?
No, not really.
Are you all right, miss?
Eat something, you're pale.
Is everything okay?
Okay.
Sorry, I'm back
to the hotel.
Okay.
The girl in the picture, who is?
What picture?
Come.
Calm down, lady.
Come, Teo, between.
I do not speak French.
My name is Gianni.
I work in coffee.
Sure.
I have nothing here
but I can ask anything you want.
I will not take, thank you.
I just wanted...
I was worried.
You looked completely lost.
This hotel is beautiful.
You are here as a tourist?
- Gianni, right?
- Yes
- The lady in the coffee sent you?
- My mother? No.
Why do you follow me?
I do not know.
I really do not know.
Sorry,
you should think...
I do not know what to follow.
Finally, I
the feeling that you, Teo.
Are you?
Not what you think.
Swear.
So what?
What is it?
Hold on.
Calmly.
- Calmly.
- I want you.
- What is it?
- Nothing. I do not know...
Your touch is weird.
Stop.
Stop!
You're weird.
Do not recognize.
Impossible.
I recognize your face
but do not recognize you.
Who are you?
You are not Teo.
- Who are you?
- What are you talking about?
Who is Teo?
'm Gianni.
Not come to this.
I'm going.
- Do not leave me!
- I am leaving!
We were both wrong.
Do not go!
Hold on!
Gianni, wait!
Do not go.
I'm not here by accident.
I'm looking for this woman.
I know her.
Often we are faced with tourists.
My mother was young at that time.
That does not mean we met.
Why she went home?
Because he felt bad.
It happens.
His mother...
I grew up with it.
For me she is my mother.
What are you saying?
Need to understand that.
Help me.
Come.
Sit.
Do you know anyone here?
Call your husband, your parents.
Can I call someone to pick her up.
I need to talk to his mother.
It is important to me.
My mother did not know you,
like me.
His family should take care of you.
- There is something...
- Do not insist!
You are wrong.
Go home.
Believe me. Enough.
Why to me...
You remind me of someone I knew.
- Who?
- No matter, she's dead.
It can be you.
Leave me alone.
Go back to the hotel.
Fabrizio, happy birthday!
How old are you?
You do not have 30 yet, right?
What did she do to you?
It is impossible.
You do not have another 5 years.
Forget it.
So why is
behaving like that?
Why Dad is so aggressive?
Enough! Come on down. Promise
we talk about that later.
Calm down.
No. I'm going to the hotel.
What do you mean?
Do not tell me it is.
Do not tell me is my sister.
Please Gianni.
Rosa Maria is dead. Forget it.
You'll spoil the party.
I do not care!
I'm going to see it.
- Gianni!
- No, let me go.
I do not know where it came from this face.
I do not know who I am.
You become a very beautiful woman.
You looks a lot like his father.
I recognized immediately.
I had no choice.
So much time has passed.
I called his mother, Nadia, in Paris.
She'll come pick you up.
My mother?
I can not help you, Rosa Maria.
Go.
Go and never come back.
I cried for a long time.
But he did not.
Do you understand?
You're not his daughter.
He never loved you.
What could I have done
by his brother Gianni?
Gianni, my brother?
Let me.
I feel bad.
I'm afraid.
- Rosa Maria, wait.
- Let me go.
What you told her.
Let me!
Care!
No one forced you
to take the place of Jeanne.
You wanted to be called Jeanne
like her.
I have no power
to change things.
After the accident
you did not recognize his parents.
Do not remember anything.
You clung to me.
And really became my daughter.
What difference does it make if your name
the Jeanne Rosa or Maria?
And my family?
Go away.
You'll be okay?
Come see us at breakfast.
Mom!
Not happy
see me again?
I prepared a feast for you.
Fortunately his mother kept me informed.
What did she say?
Nothing special.
You made a mistake.
- What are you feeling better.
- That's true.
I rested and did me good.
Let's go to your room?
I present to you.
- What are you looking at, Mom?
- Nothing. Let's go to the room.