Subtitles by NoTearSwoman
- Min Jae! - Min Jae!
- Min Jae! Where are you? - Min Jae!
Subtitles by NoTearSwoman
- Min Jae! - Min Jae!
- Min Jae! - Min Jae! Where are you?
- Min Jae! - Where are you?
- Min Jae! Where is he? - Oh, no.
Kid.
Do you want a candy?
Ta-da.
I'll give you all these if you come with me.
Where to?
Does he think he's the only one who employs people?
This mess is all Mr. Kwon's fault.
- Min Jae. Can you help us? - Have you seen a little boy?
Soo In.
What are you doing here?
Dad.
What's wrong?
Min Jae...
Min Jae's missing.
What? Min Jae's missing?
- Min Jae! - Min Jae!
Min Jae!
- Where are you, Min Jae? - Lady.
Did you see a little boy?
- No. - Oh dear.
- Min Jae! - Min Jae!
- Min Jae! - Where are you?
Min Jae! Yoon Min Jae!
Min Jae!
Min Jae. Yoon Min Jae!
- Dad! - Shoot.
Let's go.
Min Jae.
Here you are.
Who were those men?
- They said they'd give me a candy. - What?
Where did they go?
You silly boy.
You can't go off with just anyone.
Oh dear.
- Min Jae. - Soo In.
Are you okay?
Where did you go off to?
Why didn't you watch him?
If you brought him out here, keep him safe.
You shouldn't leave him alone in this busy place.
I'm sorry.
What if you'd lost him forever?
Dad, don't yell at Soo In.
What? Okay, I won't.
If this happens again, I will punish you properly, okay?
Okay.
What a scare.
Come on, Min Jae. Let's go home.
Come along.
We're home.
Listen.
You can't just go off with strangers.
If you want candy, tell Dad and I'll buy you some.
- Okay? - Yes.
Are you that happy?
Yes, I'm so happy.
You're so sweet. Now you can play.
- Okay. - Good boy.
Min Jae.
Why do you have that? Give it to me.
No. I will play with it.
That isn't Daddy's. Give it to me.
No. I want to play with it.
Do you? Okay, then. But promise...
to give it to me when I ask for it.
You can't lose it either, okay?
Okay, Dad.
You cheeky boy.
Are you okay?
Your dad's really scary when he's angry.
It was my fault.
It wasn't. Min Jae walked off on his own.
He's still little.
I should've watched him.
I was so scared earlier.
I thought we'd lost him.
It's fine now that we found him.
Yes, it's a huge relief.
The hairpin suits you really well. I made the perfect choice.
Does it look nice on me too?
Yes.
Don't you ever lose that hairpin.
It's a symbol of our friendship.
Let's be friends forever, okay?
Okay.
No one would beat up a man like that...
unless they were trying to kill him.
What if he never wakes up?
I don't think that would happen.
The old sayings are always right.
Make someone shed tears and you shed blood.
He paid for what he did.
You reap what you sow.
Now that they found the swindler Mr. Kwon,
will Dong Chul get his money back?
I wonder. Do you know anything, Soon Ok?
Did he say anything?
Only that they have to wait until the man wakes up.
I guess no one can take money from an unconscious man.
Is it true that they don't know if he will wake up?
Yes, apparently so.
He needs to wake up if we're to get the money or punish him.
What do you think happened to him?
Was he robbed?
He paid the price.
He took from others and made them shed bloody tears.
He's self-sufficient.
What? "Self-sufficient"?
You meant to say he reaped what he sowed, right?
Yes, he reaped what he sowed.
My tongue slipped.
Your tongue slips a bit too often.
What? Do you think I'm that ignorant?
What do you take me for?
You couldn't take a watch from a kid?
I apologize.
Do anything it takes to bring it to me tomorrow.
Mr. Jang.
Dong Chul's son has your watch...
which means he didn't give it to the police.
Perhaps he thinks it belongs to Mr. Kwon.
So what?
Instead of trying to take it back with force,
why not wait and see?
No one knows that we're involved in Mr. Kwon's beating.
Trying to get the watch back could turn things against us.
I think it would be better to decide what to do next...
depending on Mr. Kwon's condition.
Is he still unconscious?
Yes.
What if he wakes up and tells the police about us?
I have a plan in case that happens.
What plan?
I will tell you about it then.
You don't have to worry, sir.
It would've been nice if you were Snow White.
Don't you want to play the princess?
Did your teacher tell Se Young...
to play Snow White?
No, Se Young said she wanted the role.
Why didn't you do the same?
I'd have said I wanted to be the princess.
That way you get to wear the princess dress.
I'm jealous of Se Young. She gets to wear a dress.
I want to wear a pretty dress.
(Snow White)
The table's full of delicious-looking food.
Will it be okay to eat a little?
Oh, dear. I ate everything up.
What's your next line?
It's...
"I'll ask for forgiveness when the owner comes back."
- That's it. - Se Young.
I told you to memorize everything by today.
You're the main character and you still don't know your lines.
This won't do.
Soo In, you play Snow White.
Se Young, you have two days to memorize the queen's lines.
Miss!
Se Young, wait for me.
Hello, Se Young. You're back early.
What's wrong with her? Is she upset?
Se Young, have you still not memorized your lines yet?
There are too many lines.
Soo In seems to have memorized hers and yours as well.
I told you to memorize everything by today.
You're the main character and you still don't know your lines.
This won't do.
Soo In, you play Snow White.
Se Young, you have two days to memorize the queen's lines.
Se Young, look at this. Mommy had...
What's wrong?
I hate everything.
- Se Young. - I hate it all.
What's wrong? Why are you crying?
Why are you crying?
I lost it!
What do you mean?
My role. My teacher told Soo In to play Snow White.
What?
Why?
Because I couldn't remember my lines.
How could she do something like that?
What about this dress? You can't wear it?
I don't know!
Dong Chul, check the chairs too. Some are wonky.
Okay. Tell me if anything else needs fixing.
I think that's all. Right, Soon Ok?
Yes. Thank you.
Soon Ok, I heard that Soo In came first in her last test.
She never let go of 1st place since she started 4th grade.
Who does she take after?
Dong Chul, do you know that Soo In's her class captain?
What? Class captain?
See? Honestly, how could you care less about your own daughter?
Love Soo In and Jung In half as much as you love Min Jae.
I'm not that bad.
What would you be like if Min Jae came first and was class captain?
It's so obvious.
Mom, mom.
Hi, I'm back.
Hi there.
Why did you come here and not go home?
Do you have something to brag about?
You come here when you want to brag.
Did you come first in another test?
It's not that.
I'm playing the lead in the Snow White play.
What? What's that?
The fourth-graders put on a play at the school festival.
Wasn't Se Young going to be Snow White?
- The teacher changed our roles. - Really?
So you get the play the lead?
Our whole family should be there.
Will you come as well?
Yes, of course.
Good. No dad should skip a play when his daughter's the lead.
That's right. I should be there.
Really?
Of course. You're playing the main character.
I should be there.
- I'm home. - Welcome home.
Do you have good news?
I got to play Snow White in the school play.
Really? That's great news.
Do you want me to make you a dress?
- Can you? - Yes.
I was a bit worried about that.
I'm glad to play the lead but I didn't have a costume.
Don't worry, I'll make you one.
Thank you.
Are you still in bed? Get up.
- I don't want to. - Get up.
I'm upset that Soo In always comes first in every test...
and now she took your role.
This is so upsetting.
I told my parents to come and watch. This is such an embarrassment.
Why don't you go and talk to Soo In?
- About what? - What else?
Ask if you can swap back.
No. That hurts my pride.
Pride isn't the issue here.
We can't go back on the teacher's order.
She won't have a choice if Soo In says she can't do it.
You were so nice to Soo In.
I'm sure she'll say yes.
Go and talk to her.
- Hello. - Se Young.
Is Soo In at home?
Just a moment. Soo In.
Se Young.
You want to play Snow White?
Yes. It was my role to begin with.
Our teacher told us to change roles.
If you say you can't do it, she'll give us our old roles.
Do you not want to switch back?
So you get the play the lead?
Our whole family should be there.
Will you come as well?
Yes, of course.
Good. No dad should skip a play when his daughter's the lead.
That's right. I should be there.
- Really? - Of course.
You're playing the main character. I should be there.
Sorry.
You won't give up your role?
How could you do this to me?
I let you borrow all my books...
and my dad even got you a music box...
and you can't give this up for me?
Sorry.
You aren't my friend anymore.
Se Young.
Se Young. Se Young.
Yoon Soo In.
How could you do this to me?
Did you and Se Young fight?
No.
Then what?
I think she's a bit angry with me.
I see.
You two are close friends.
She'll get over it soon. Don't worry.
- I'm done. - Okay.
Thanks for making me the costume.
Don't thank me. It's nothing.
So...
Do you want to come and watch the play?
Can I come?
It's a bit embarrassing though.
Okay. I'll be there.
- I hope you will. - Okay.
How did it go? She said yes, didn't she?
No. She refused.
What? Did she really say no?
She really did.
It's nice and sturdy now.
Dong Chul's good with his hands.
Soon Ok, did you see Soo In's face?
What face?
The face she made when Dong Chul said he'd come and watch.
She doesn't say so, but she likes her dad.
You appreciate what I did, don't you?
- What did you do? - I put pressure...
on Dong Chul to watch Soo In's play with us.
We need to force them together if they're to get close. Right?
Right.
How is Mr. Kwon. Is he still unconscious?
Yes. He still hasn't woken up.
And the investigation?
It's still ongoing, but Mr. Kwon's still alive,
so the police aren't doing much at the moment.
They're actually...
having trouble because they can't reach Mr. Kwon's family.
They won't manage that soon because he never had a fixed address.
Keep me updated on Mr. Kwon's condition...
and the police.
I wonder why...
Mr. Kwon's still unconscious.
The longer he's unconscious the less likely it is for him to wake.
When he took off with all our money...
I expected he'd do pretty well.
He never had a fixed address and his family's scattered...
and the police can't reach them.
What do you think he'd been up to...
after he left?
He should've lived an honest life.
What a pity.
Soo In's such a horrible child.
Your dad got her a new music box when her brother broke the old one.
How could she turn down your request?
Your teacher too.
You have until the day of the play to memorize your lines.
How could she take your role just because you struggled?
This is so upsetting.
Your dad gives so much to that school.
How dare they. Right, honey?
Honey.
- What? - What are you thinking about?
Nothing. Were you talking to me?
Se Young lost her role to Soo In just because...
she couldn't remember her lines.
Soo In?
Did she memorize all the lines, then?
Why can't you do something she can?
She's been doing better than you in all the tests this year.
Honey.
Se Young, eat...
Did you have to upset her even further?
You want to play Snow White?
Yes. It was my role to begin with.
Our teacher told us to change roles.
If you say you can't do it, she'll give us our old roles.
Do you not want to switch back?
Sorry.
Prince. You saved me.
Thank you.
Princess, come with me and live in my kingdom.
I can't leave my friends behind.
Then they can all come and live with us.
The end. You're amazing, Soo In.
How did you memorize all this?
I couldn't even remember one line.
Soo In, our stepmother said...
she'd make your Snow White costume.
Yes. Why?
Can I try it on later?
Yes. You can have it when the play's done.
Can I?
(Snow White)
Oh dear. I ate everything up.
I'll ask for forgiveness when the owner comes back.
There are seven of everything.
7 chairs, 7 cups.
Even seven plates.
This is so fun.
Let's try this chair.
It's so small I can barely sit in it.
I'm sleepy.
I'll nap until the owner comes back.
Well done.
Seven dwarfs, come in.
- Okay. - Okay.
Soo In's really good.
I think she did much better than Se Young.
Do you all remember where to sit?
- Yes. - Dwarf One.
- Do you remember your line? - Yes.
You have to remember your lines and where you sit.
- Okay. - Soo In.
You did really well.
Shall we practice the scene?
Soo In, how are you so good? I'm so jealous.
I'm not that good.
You'll look like a real princess once you wear your dress.
You should have played Snow White from the start.
That's right. You're a much better princess.
- Soo In. - Hello.
- Are you going somewhere? - To the hanbok store.
I steamed some potatoes. Eat them when you want.
Okay. See you later.
Let's go, Min Jae.
I want to play with Soo In.
You can't. She has to study.
I can watch him.
He'll disturb your studies.
It's okay. Go on.
Do you like her that much?
Yes.
- See you. - I won't be long.
Okay.
Let's go.
Soo In, let's go to the seaside.
No, you'll catch a cold.
I'll wear something warm.
Can we go?
I said no.
I want to play by the sea.
Can we go, Soo In?
- Do you want to go that much? - Yes.
Slow down, you might trip up.
You need to walk faster.
Okay.
What? The police got in touch with Mr. Kwon's wife?
Yes.
Then they might find out that the watch isn't his.
What should we do?
What do you think? Get that watch back.
Get it!
- Soo In! - What?
I want to fly a kite.
A kite? We don't have one.
Let's build sandcastles.
There a kite that Dad made at home.
I want to fly a kite.
Then let's go and get it.
No. My legs hurt.
You go and get it.
I'll be right back. Wait for me here.
Don't go anywhere else. Stay here, okay?
Okay, I'll stay here and wait.
Get back quick. Be really quick.
Min Jae.
Se Young.
Why are you here?
I'm going to fly a kite with Soo In.
- Where is your sister? - Soo In?
She went home to get the kite.
You can fly it with us.
No. I don't want to.
Why didn't you watch him?
If you brought him out here, keep him safe.
You shouldn't leave him alone in this busy place.
I'm sorry.
- Min Jae. - What, Se Young?
Is Soo In really waiting for me there?
- Yes. - Really?
Yes, really. Now come with me.
Where is my sister?
She's over there.
You're lying! She isn't there!
I'm going back!
Min Jae! Stop!
Stop right there! Min Jae!
Soo In.
Where are you going? To fly a kite?
Yes. Min Jae wanted to.
That sounds like fun.
I used to play kite-fighting when I was a child.
I have to go. Min Jae's waiting alone.
Okay, hurry on. Bye.
Soo In! Soo In!
Where are you? Soo In!
Min Jae! Stop where you are!
Soo In! Soo In!
- Min Jae, come back here! - Soo In!
Come here.
Let go! Let me go!
Let go of me!
Come with me!
Let go!
Min Jae! Min Jae!
- Save me! - Min Jae!
Save me!
Se Young!
Min Jae! Min Jae!
Min Jae!
Min Jae! Min Jae, where are you?
Save me!
Min Jae!
Min Jae! Min Jae!
Soo In!
Save me!
- Save me! - Min Jae!
Min Jae!
- Soo In. - Min Jae! Min Jae!
- Min Jae. - Save me, Soo In.
- Min Jae! - Soo In, save me.
Min Jae!
Someone, help! My brother's in the water!
Save my brother!
Min Jae. Min Jae!
Mom, Mom. Min Jae...
fell into the sea.
- Min Jae! - Min Jae!
Yoon Min Jae!
Min Jae!
Young Sun! Young Sun!
Come here. Bring him back! Bring him back!
- Mr. Yoon Dong Chul. - What?
- Hello. - Hello.
Subtitles by NoTearSwoman