There's an accident on the course.
- How'd you do?
- Half a second slower than Hinsch.
I was half a second slower
than the last Cuban.
- Where'd you finish?
- Fourth.
That's not so bad.
He's still under morphine.
Trans World Airlines announces
the arrival of the flight
Starstream ASV0 from New York.
What?
Box three.
Hello?
Hey, how do you get... Hello?
This is Dave Chappellet.
I'm here at the airport.
Yeah.
All right. How do I get there?
Yeah. Who?
No, I never have.
Yeah, okay. I said okay.
No one told me about anybody else.
Excuse me.
No, I don't want a reservation.
I have a reservation.
Yes, it was made a month ago.
Glad you two got together.
- Hey, Mayo. How are you, buddy?
- D.K., how are you?
- Long time no see.
- How are you doing?
- Did you have a good trip?
- Will you talk to him, please?
Tell him we have a letter confirming it.
Nice to see you.
I think you're in room 44
or something like that.
We're paying with...
It got through American Express.
Don't tell me not to shout!
You know what that is?
Yeah.
Hey, where do you know Mayo from?
From Dartmouth.
I was one of the Olympic hopefuls.
I was hopeful, not them.
Mayo's okay.
Dartmouth.
- Chappellet? Johnny Creech.
- Yeah, I know.
You know Kipsmith?
- Hey, how's it going?
- Yeah, what do you say?
Hey, Stiles, you're sure
you want to ski today?
- Who's this?
- He's a German. I don't know who he is.
- Is this Bryan?
- Yeah.
- Not bad.
- Too much style.
Who's next? Chappellet?
- Okay.
- What do you have?
- 28.8.
That's what I have.
All right, here are the bibs.
Can I have the salt?
Eighty-eight?
Yeah, you'll be starting
in the sixth group.
It's the best we can get for you.
You should be higher, but that's
all we could do for you right now.
What's the point of even racing?
Same as always. You try to win.
Starting 88th,
I'll be in ruts up to my knees.
Probably.
The officials have made a decision
about the break you're going to take.
There'll be a five-minute pause after...
- How come you didn't race?
- I don't know.
But you had a start number.
Well, I'll tell you, D.K.
What is D.K. For?
What does that stand for?
My name.
- Is that really your name? D. K?
- Yeah, well, it's my initials.
Your initials.
Yeah, everybody's always called me that.
- What's the "D" for?
- Nothing.
- What is it, a name you don't like?
- I just don't use it, that's all.
- What is it? Douglas?
- Nope.
- How'd you do?
- Oh, I had a bad line.
Picked the wrong line
and I was too slow going into flat.
- Whereabouts did you come in?
- Way back.
So how come you didn't race?
- What did your friend Mayo tell you?
- Nothing.
What happened?
Well, they had me seeded about 150,
so I told them I didn't want to.
- You didn't want to?
- No.
You should have raced.
If I skied half as good
as I play cards, I'd be great.
Big ten showing, dealer set.
Good luck, Gabe.
All right, here are the bibs.
Creech, you're number 14.
- Want to try it again?
- That's pretty good.
Come on, okay?
Stick with me, boy. You'll wear silk.
Queen showing. Not bad.
Hey, Alec, you ever race here?
- Yeah.
- Make the top 10?
Yeah, I finished second.
I'm serious.
Bryan, you're number 98.
Gabriel, you're 44.
Kipsmith, 66.
Chappellet, you're number 79.
You did so well last week,
they decided to move you up.
Yeah.
What?
- Time for number one.
- L. Brown, 2:31.39.
On the course, number two.
Time run for team USA, 2:31.51 seconds.
Alec?
Right here.
Moving down. See you.
I just thought you might like to know.
Your boy finished fourth.
Is that right?
This new boy, this 79, he can win, too?
What's his name? David Chappellet.
You will consider him
for the FIS team, yes?
Well, we haven't...
We haven't selected a team yet.
We still have a couple days.
Creech, of course, that's obvious.
This Chappellet, is he...
Is it his first season?
No, he's raced in the United States.
It's his first season in Europe.
Dave. Dave, come over here, will you?
We wanted to congratulate you.
That was quite a showing you made.
Yeah, maybe next time
I'll get to start in the top 50.
Oh, we have to be going.
We'll see you in Kitzbühel.
Dave.
Come here.
Look, you're going
to be doing quite a bit of this.
I know you like to joke around,
but they don't.
But one thing they do know,
and that everyone knows,
you have to earn your starting spot.
- Now I'm going to fight for you. I will.
- I wasn't joking.
Look, you finished fourth in one race.
Don't expect to be given the world.
I don't expect to be given anything.
Good. Get in the bus.
Good afternoon, ladies and...
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
- This is Ron Engel.
- And Bruce Devore.
Here at the Hahnenkamm
in Kitzbühel, Austria,
to bring you the FIS World Skiing
Championships being run here this week.
Now, these championships are held
every other year with the Olympics
taking their place every fourth year.
Now, Bruce, you've been here before in
Kitzbühel, and it's truly a beautiful town.
The kind of town, really,
for which Europe is famous.
Many great, great old hotels,
and, of course, Kitzbühel is known
for its many ski champions.
Now on the downhill course today, you're
going to see the greatest skiers in the world.
Skiers from 17 countries.
Champions past, champions yet to be.
There's number one, Peter Haas.
He's the only member
of the German team in the top seeding.
And over here, number 13,
hidden a little bit there on the right,
there's Istel of France.
You know, Ron, the great
Austrian-French rivalry
which has served to define the sport
for the last 10 years
is essentially being carried on
by Jacques Boyriven.
He's had the best year by far
of anyone on the French team.
He's strong in all the events, but
downhill is his speciality. And here's...
Here's the great Austrian, Max Meier.
Meier's 31 years old,
and has been in international racing
for the past 17 years.
And over there on the right
is Johnny Creech,
upon whom the American hopes
are riding today.
He was fourth...
Fourth or fifth in the Lauberhorn,
which is the oldest
and perhaps the most important
of all the European races.
Or is Kitzbühel the oldest?
There's Chappellet of the United States.
Oh, I should mention a young man
seeded in the second group
on the basis of a stunning performance
when starting way back.
I think he was 79. Was it 79, Bruce?
Well, I think it was
in the Kandahar at Saint Anton.
He finished fourth just behind Boyriven.
There he is, number 23.
Oh, wait a minute.
I'm sorry, we've got the wrong...
There he is now.
We're on him now. Number 23,
Dave Chappellet from Idaho Springs...
Idaho Springs, Colorado.
Johnny Creech, 2:17, 2:18, 2:19, 2:20.
His time, 2:21.06.
That's a good time for Creech.
He's only sixth, but as you can see,
he's very popular over here.
Looks like Boyriven
is already celebrating a victory.
Well, that time of 2. 17.92
is going to be hard to beat.
Alec?
Yeah.
- Where's Chappellet?
- Right here.
- Tell him to uncork one.
- Okay.
Now here's David Chappellet
of the United States.
He's off. The American team's last real
chance in these FIS World Championships.
How does he look to you, Bruce?
He's new on the team, as you know,
but he's already made a sensational showing.
He's doing the upper part very well.
Chappellet. American.
His interval time is 1:08.
1:08. Now that's the fastest so far.
He's coming to the bumps now.
- Oh, he's having difficulties... He's...
- Here's the second...
The snow was cut to hell
by the time I started.
It was bad. It was really bad.
There were holes.
They were, I mean...
It would be hard on top
and soft underneath.
If I could have started
five places ahead, just five,
then I would've at least had good snow.
I wouldn't have lost
my balance in the ruts.
- I wouldn't have had to pull so hard...
- No.
What do you mean, "No"?
If I'd have started in the first 15,
I could've won it.
No.
You just weren't good enough, that's all.
You lost your strength,
and then the bumps took you out.
That's it. That's all there was to it.
You got to have your strength
right up to the end.
These guys aren't amateurs,
they're national heroes.
You're trying to beat them
out of their way of life.
You're just not strong enough.
Well, I'll take a Charles Atlas course this
summer and build myself up, all right?
Okay.
All right, that's it.
Chappellet, how do you feel? Tired?
Give me two more laps.
- What?
- Two more laps.
- Are you kidding?
- No, we got time.
- How do you feel, John?
- Cool.
Talk and move. Talk and move.
Europeans simply can't understand why
this country doesn't turn out
the world's greatest ski teams.
And I'm ashamed to tell them the truth.
We have the mountains,
we have the men, we have the muscle.
We don't have the money
in this richest nation in the world.
Every racer on
a well-equipped winning team
is a foreign sales representative
for U.S. Ski products.
These fine young competitors
that we are training
are roving ambassadors
for the American way of life.
Thanks a lot.
Hey, Dad.
David.
How you doing?
- So, how've you been?
- I got your postcard from France.
Oh, yeah?
Your cousin said to thank you
for the stamps.
Yeah, I was all over Europe.
Dad, I was in... I was in Austria,
I was in France, Switzerland, Germany.
I've just been training out in Oregon.
That's really great country.
- I'm on the U.S. Ski team, you know?
- Yeah.
They had your picture
on some paper in town.
- I see you still got the old Chev, huh?
- Well, it runs pretty good.
Hey, why don't you knock off for a while
and ride into town? I'll buy you a beer.
Keys are in it, if that's what you want.
So Long Ago, Bobby Greensboro
trying to grab you and a-groove you.
It's nine before four is what it is.
Do you know we have 88 degrees
right here in downtown Denver,
and a good chance of rain? So take care.
KZOK in Denver
Country music, country music
Mind some business, preferably your own.
Our business is playing top tunes,
and here's Hank Hopkins,
It was a Long Happy Day.
I better go.
I'm not talking to you.
Who's talking about talking?
Come on, get in.
You didn't tell me you were leaving.
Well, I'm back.
Come on, get in.
Come on.
I'll see you later, kids.
I'm going for a ride with Dave.
I... I've got a chance to go to Denver
this fall and study dental hygiene.
Of course, if I do that, it means
finding an apartment and everything.
And then Pam, she went...
You remember Pam Houser?
She's going to Yellowstone
to work as a waitress.
She wanted me to come with her.
And afterwards, we could travel.
I'd sort of like to see everything.
It's a... It's such a big decision to make.
- Well, what do you think I should do?
- I don't know.
You got any more of that gum?
Well, you're back early.
- What's happened to the water?
- Gone bad, isn't it?
- Want some coffee?
- Yeah.
Well, I guess you've been doing all right.
- Won some races.
- Yeah. I had a pretty good year.
- Win any money?
- Money?
No, see, we're thinking ahead
two years. For the Olympics.
The Olympics.
The Olympics ain't for money.
No, but for after. Afterwards.
- So that's how it works, huh?
- Yeah, it can,
because, you know, you put together
two good years and you win a couple...
Well, I just hope you don't end up
asking yourself the question
some folks ask me, "What's he do it for?"
Well, I'll be famous. I'll be a champion.
World's full of them.
I would never dream of
jeopardizing your amateur standing
with the Olympics, Mr Creech.
I want you to win
the Olympics using my skis.
- Hey, who's that?
- Huh?
- With Claire.
- Oh, that's... What's his name?
The guy that makes... Machet.
- No, no. I mean, who's she?
- Who knows?
It's either his secretary or his niece.
I'm going to wash up.
You speak French?
Dave.
- Did you meet Mr Machet?
- How do you do, Mr Chappellet?
- And Carole... No, I'm sorry, Miss...
- Miss Stahl.
- Delighted to meet you.
Please join us.
I've been hoping to meet you.
And you know Bobby, of course.
- Will you have tea?
- Good. Thanks.
One cup of tea, please.
That was a brilliant victory at Morzine.
- What skis did you use?
- Head skis.
You like Heads?
Yeah, they're okay.
Mr Machet has long been
a friend of American racers.
- He manufactures skis.
- The best in the world.
I would never dream of jeopardizing
your amateur standing,
but I want you to win
the Olympics using my skis
so that I can advertise my
gold medal at the Olympics.
Very few racers are good enough
to get the most out of my skis.
Mr Creech here
has consented to try a pair.
I would like you to try a pair, too,
with my compliments, of course.
- Hello.
- Did you come to buy something?
No.
Well, I'm happy you stopped.
Me, too.
- Would you like some?
- No, no. Yes.
Thank you.
Do you always buy
one of these at a time or...
- You like it?
- Oh, yeah. I don't know.
- You don't like it?
- Yeah, I do.
- I've been reading about you.
- You have?
- Yes.
- Really? Where?
Follow me.
Oh, here it is.
"The American, David Chappellet,
must have felt
"still more disappointed.
"In the final schuss, only Chappellet
was near Meier's top speed.
"He was at 132 kilometres an hour,
when deeper into the..."
- I don't know the word.
- Well, go on.
Okay. "...and fell. A sad sight
as he tried, having only one ski,
"to finish the race.
"It wasn't sad, but to win
is everything, to place nothing."
Do you live here?
No, I'm only here for the week.
I'm working.
Well, do you work for Machette...
Or Machet? Or...
Yes. What did you think?
Oh, no, I... Your uncle or... I don't know.
Hey, read it again, okay?
- I'll see you in a sec, all right?
- Well, take care of that, will you?
- Hello.
- Hey.
- Is this yours?
- Yes. You like it?
Here, hold this.
- You practising today?
- Yeah.
- How's it going?
- Good.
- Yeah?
- The snow's great.
- Is it?
- You bet.
I thought you'd never stop.
- Tired?
- A little.
My legs.
You see, it's right in here. When
you're forward, this takes all the action.
Put the brakes on.
I think it must be the most thrilling thing
in the whole world, don't you?
And you have to be terribly strong,
even for a man.
Well, there is a girls' team, too.
Oh, yes, of course. Where are they?
Well, they're not here.
They're in Grindelwald.
They don't really
do the same things, do they?
- Some of them do.
- Yes?
- Well, some of the things.
- Oh, what do you mean?
- Well, it's like you say, they...
- Actually, our girls have done...
Done better in the Olympics than the men.
I mean, really?
Well, isn't that interesting.
Tell me, why would a girl want to do it?
I mean, I wouldn't. First of all,
I just wouldn't have all that strength
in the mornings and...
And the morning is important, isn't it?
Well, a man in the morning...
I think a man must feel stronger
in the morning.
- I think you're right.
- He certainly looks stronger.
Well, you'd know more about that.
- You got a point, you know.
- I wonder.
Well, you know, I think... I think
girls look stronger and feel stronger.
Yes?
I've known some girls who look
stronger, but when you...
Yeah, we have some
very strong girls on the team.
And they have to get up very early.
I'd say a girl that feels strong looks
strong, wouldn't you say that, Tony?
- Or vice versa.
- Some do and some don't.
Yes, you're probably right.
Some of them must. Yes, of course. Yes.
Well...
Thank you.
Oh.
Excuse me.
You what?
Pardon me. Pardon me.
Are you David Chappellet?
Yeah.
Well, I'm doing a story on the team
and also on skiing.
And I'd like to find out
everything I can about it.
- I could never learn, could I?
- What?
I don't know, everything.
Like for example, do you go
as fast as you can all the time?
Yeah, I go as fast as I can.
I know that sounds a little foolish,
almost stupid.
But I don't know really what to ask.
- Do you have to give up a lot? I mean...
- What?
Do you mind my asking these questions?
- No, I don't mind.
- All right, what I mean is...
Well, do you practise...
Do you practise self-denial?
- Part of the time.
- Fascinating.
- Yeah? Really?
- Does it affect your strength?
- Do you like that?
- Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- The boss pays.
Thank you very much.
- Would you like a drink?
- No, thanks.
Look, if you have to get to bed,
I understand.
I know everything about self-denial.
No drinks, no late nights...
3:15.
Did you know how quick
your time was at the gate?
No, I was by
before I even thought about it.
- What?
- What are your plans for next year?
- What about the light conditions?
- It's fine. It didn't bother me.
- What are your plans for next season?
- I think I'd like to...
Could you have run any better?
I guess you can always run better.
- Tell me, how does it feel to have won?
- Feels great. What's your name?
So Chappellet's just made the fastest time.
What do you think of his time?
He still didn't beat the record, you know.
...your success?
Well, has it made any difference to you?
He's getting better all the time.
...my friends over here.
- No, no, I don't think so. We hoped.
- Jake!
You know, what are you gonna do?
All right, just tell the girls
we'll meet them 8:00 at the Tenne.
Okay. So long.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
It was a damn good race today.
Thought I was going to beat you.
Yeah, I had a good run.
Only missed one turn. Took it too wide.
Only one turn, huh?
Did you hear him?
"I only missed one turn, you know,
just one because I'm really good.
"And if I hadn't gone wide
on that other one...
"You know what?
I would have broken the record."
Probably would have.
He thinks he's the only guy
that ever won a downhill.
He's as jazzed with himself as Max Meier.
- That's not your style, is it, John?
- What?
Come on.
All right, he's good and he's fast
and he wins a couple of races.
And I'm the first one to admit
that a good racer turns everybody on.
But he is not for the team
and he never will be.
Well, it's not exactly a team sport, is it?
Maybe you're right.
- Alec?
- Right here.
It's getting icier by the minute.
- I'll tell him.
- He did 2:20.
- What?
- Meier's time.
Meier got 2:20.
Why should I feel bad? I had a good year.
I got myself seeded.
Creech?
Well, he wins sometimes, I win sometimes.
We're both Americans.
Good. I feel good. I do.
I said the garage was having
trouble getting parts for the car.
It would take them a day or two.
Machet wants to send a car for me,
but I said I was quite content.
Content?
Machet always take such good care of you?
Always. He's a very good boss.
- He give you this?
- No, somebody else did.
Before my time.
You got a thing with Machet?
Something going?
Not exactly. We never made love.
- What's wrong with him?
- Nothing. I just never wanted to.
How do you feel about the season, Eugene?
I think we had a damn good season.
For the first time, we've won
the respect of the Europeans.
You're damn right.
We've got two top racers.
Either one of them could win the Olympics.
When I stop saying it and start thinking it,
then we're all in a lot of trouble.
Look, we can't take a team to Europe
and expect them to compete
against the Meiers and the Boyrivens
by selling lapel buttons.
Okay, okay. You give us the money,
and I guarantee you I'll get you a gold
medal at the Olympics. Maybe two.
If we're going out on a limb
for this kind of a budget, gentlemen,
I propose we set up a watchdog committee.
Well, we've...
We've never been stronger,
I think I can say that.
Oh, we... We've never had as good a team.
I think we might very well
surprise some people.
Do you expect to win
any medals in the Olympics?
Which events?
Well, we'd like to win medals, of course.
I don't expect anything.
It's too fragile a sport.
- This is your third season in Europe?
- What do you feel your chances are?
- Do you notice any difference?
- Difference? In the FIS?
Well, hopefully, we will get
in better shape in the first three races,
then go on to take the Olympics.
That's my plan, at least.
- Well, how do you feel about...
- I think our chances are very good.
Well, I used to come to New York,
and I'd have my skis in a case
and my boots, and they'd say,
"What are they?" I'd say, "Skis."
"Skis?" they would say.
"Where are you jumping?"
Now they say, "I saw your picture
in Sports Illustrated."
Hello?
- Hello?
- Hello, David?
Hello.
Oh, I'm in Megève.
- I saw you arriving today on television.
- You did? Hey, I've missed you.
- I missed you, too.
- You have?
- Are you going to come down here?
- How long are you going to be there?
Till Thursday.
And after that we've got a week off.
- What?
- Till Thursday.
And after that we have a week off.
A whole week?
There's a lot of snow here.
- If you're coming down, I could stay on.
- I will try to, David.
- Thirty-three.
- Yes, sir.
Miss Stahl called twice.
Where's...
Hello, Mr Chappellet.
Nice to see you again. How are you?
- Welcome to Zurich.
- Carole isn't here, then?
No, she went home for Christmas.
She will be heartbroken.
Come on, sit down.
Tell me, did you ever try my skis?
Yeah, I was practising on them last week.
They're fine. They are a little stiff
for me, but they are okay, though.
Let me get my designer to come in here.
I'd like him to hear
exactly what you think.
Perhaps it could be remedied.
- Do you know when she will be back?
- Pardon?
Do you know when she'll be back?
Why, after Christmas.
- Are you alone in Zurich?
- Yeah.
You'll have lunch with me, huh?
No, no, I just stopped by to say hello.
Would you tell her that...
Yes, of course I will. But now lunch.
About the skis, you know, you say they...
They were too stiff.
Actually, we have tried that stiffness, and
we find it gives you much more stability,
especially for the downhill.
Oh, one night I was supposed
to go out to a dance.
This was the youngest chick I could find.
David!
Hello! What a surprise.
Yeah, I guess it is.
I waited for you in Megève.
But why, David? You knew
I had plans for Christmas, didn't you?
No, you didn't tell me that.
If I had known, I wouldn't have waited.
But I had to go home.
Every year it's the same thing.
Everybody was there.
- I didn't know.
- Oh, yeah?
I got a present for you. It's in the car.
Here.
- How long have you been in Wengen?
- One week. I'm here for holidays.
Did Machet tell you I came by the office?
Oh, yes.
You know, he's really counting
on you for the Olympics, David.
Yeah, me and a few others.
Oh, no, he really feels
you have a good chance.
Aren't you going to open it?
- You like them?
- Yeah, they're great.
You know, I had such
a terrific Christmas this year.
My brother was Santa Claus.
We had so many presents
because everybody bought
funny presents to one another.
It was great.
We didn't have too much snow,
but, really, it doesn't matter because
we put cotton in between the windows
to make it look like it had been snowing
a lot outside and it was really great.
We had a fabulous Christmas party...
Okay, that's it for today. Let's wrap it up.
Okay.
Whatever you can handle, all right?
Don't...
Beat you to the bottom.
Hey, what the hell is that?
Hey!
I'll see you.
D.K., make yourself scarce, would you?
Yeah. See you later.
That was quite a stunt you pulled.
It was a real gem.
Seven years. You know, in seven years
I have never had a hot dog like you.
You take my best racer and pile him
into a stone wall just for the fun of it.
I didn't pile him into anything.
- Creech can look out for himself.
- You'd take a chance like that?
The day before the Lauberhorn?
Two weeks before the Olympics?
No thought, Chappellet.
- He didn't have to race, did he?
- No, he didn't.
- I thought he knew better.
- Did you speak to him already?
- Him?
- Creech.
- No. No, I haven't.
- Are you going to?
Don't you worry about
what I'm going to say to Creech.
I'm going to tell him
just exactly what I'm saying to you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Besides, he knows.
He knows what he did. He knows how I feel.
Well, what did he do?
He bailed out on a course he'd been
running every year for five years.
So he fell over.
He can do that any time he races.
Nobody races unless I say so.
That's why I'm here.
That's why they made me the coach.
They did not send me over here
for the fun of it, Chappellet.
You know, it costs lots of money.
A lot of money.
That's why we have to train as a team.
That's why we have to race as a team.
We have to have a team, Chappellet.
A winning team.
And whether you like it or not,
I'm just as much a part
of that team as you are.
That's why they sent us here.
Some very important people.
The same people that bought you that
ticket to get you out of Idaho Springs.
What do they know about skiing?
The same people that's been
supporting you for the last three years.
People like me.
There's a whole world out there
that you know nothing about...
Well, you can't understand that, can you?
What's there to understand?
I'm here because I ski and I ski fast.
That's all there is to it.
That is it, huh? Yeah, you ski fast.
You race, but you're reckless.
You rack up a lot.
No consistency. That's what Creech has.
- It doesn't win a medal.
- It counts for a lot.
It comes from a certain
consideration for the sport.
A desire to learn.
That's something you never had.
You never had any real education, did you?
All you ever had was your skis.
And that's not enough.
Wengen is so remote
that it doesn't get as big crowds
as the Hahnenkamm or the Kandahar.
But there's more than ordinary interest
centred in the Lauberhorn this year
because it falls two weeks
before the Winter Olympics.
So it becomes
a very tough dress rehearsal.
The results here are bound
to have a significant effect
on the Games themselves.
There's Johnny Creech.
He is in the gate now.
You know, doing well today will certainly
give him confidence at the Olympics.
My leg. My leg.
Creech has fallen.
I hear it's not too bad.
About 50 pieces is all.
Yeah, not too bad.
- You'll get them next year.
- You mean four years from now?
I sure...
I sure wish...
How is it?
Isn't it
stupid?
I was telling Dave about
how we used to talk
about justice of sport.
The justice of sport, yes.
The sacrifice without end.
Well, what do you think your chances are?
I don't know. I don't know.
At the moment, I...
- Do you feel physically fit for the race?
- Yeah, I feel good.
Well, this is it. How do you feel?
This is it.
What are your plans after the Olympics?
The long section on top is grippy snow.
It's not blowing on top any more.
It's all blown away.
It's very well,
the conditions are really good today.
Yes, the course is fine.
Will your wife be watching the race today?
Sure, she will be there. All right.
Were you holding anything back
in the non-stop yesterday?
- Have you seen Johnny Creech?
- Yeah.
We are just a few moments now, ladies and
gentlemen, from the start of the downhill.
And this is the event in alpine skiing.
You can see the size of the crowd
already gathered.
At the gate, you see the great Austrian
racer, Max Meier, number five.
There is Istel, number 13.
Others are still arriving.
And now into the gate,
Boyriven of France, number three.
Okay.
- Alec!
- Right.
Boyriven is down.
Right.
Max Meier, the Austrian
who's probably won more races
than any man in history,
but never yet an Olympic gold medal.
He's off!
Here he comes around the hairpin.
Looks a little icy here. Look at this.
He is skiing a fantastic race!
Now here's Meier.
He has to break 2:21. He did it!
Max Meier of Austria with 2:20.91.
And a really great chance
for the gold medal.
Sure, I had some trouble.
In the bumps, you know.
So I don't... You know.
You don't do well,
especially when you can't see a thing.
This is Hinsch.
- Very icy here by the farmhouse.
- Right.
Meier almost went down.
Alec says the course
is holding up pretty good.
Except by the farmhouse,
the last three turns.
It's a little slippery, but it's not too bad.
- Who's ahead?
- Meier.
Chappellet, you can win.
And now here comes the French
second great hope, François Istel.
Can he beat Meier?
Here comes Istel. He'll have a good time.
Not good enough to beat Meier,
but could give France the silver medal.
Here it is, 2:21.56.
We are almost ready up here.
He is in the gate now.
Here is the great American racer
from Idaho Springs, Colorado.
Can he beat Meier's...
Can you hear me? 1:09.
His interval time is the fastest time yet.
I have it at 1.08.5.
Exceptionally fast race. He's taking
the high line and he's holding it.
He's really going fast.
He's coming to the shambles now.
He has 2:20.91 to beat.
That's 2:20.91.
There is no doubt about it,
Chappellet's really going all out.
Can he beat him? Can he beat Meier?
Here he comes.
It is going to be very close.
2. 17, 2. 18, 2. 19, 2.20.
He beat him!
What do you think of that, huh?
...to be the first American man
who ever won a gold medal?
- Good.
- Yes.
He did great. Just great!
That's it! That's great!
How was the course?
Did you have any trouble?
It's a good course. The main course...
Yes, we have. We're definitely in there.
We are at the top!
- I had great confidence in him all along.
- What are your plans now?
What? Pardon, what?
I'll go back to the States
and I don't know, just take a rest.
By the time I crossed the finish...
No, I didn't know Meier's time.
I just knew he was ahead.
- The time 1:08, is that what they said?
- Yes, they did.
...wouldn't do much
thinking about it before.
I was just thinking about getting down.
I knew we'd win.
- You didn't expect come up here.
- We waited so long for it to happen.
I was just thinking about getting down
as fast as I could.
You know, he just let me go.
Said it's up to me.
Do you feel it's one
of your strongest races?
I don't know.
I mean, I slowed down a little.
Hey, the German's got a good time.
We have a good time coming up.
The German's got the best time
at the halfway sign.
He had the best time at the half,
the German, didn't he?
- You've got a gold medal!
- You got a gold medal, huh?
Hey! That was... Great! Great!
Very fast race, very fast.
Did you think Chappellet would beat Meier?
Yes.
What are your plans now?
Oh, we're just going to go back
to States and take a good rest.
No, no... We were ready for it. No.
Meier. Yeah, Meier.
What?
We trained hard.
Yes, it was very fast, awfully fast.
What are your plans now?
- Just to slow down, I guess.
- I don't know, I don't know.