Therefore, I declare
you husband and wife.
Congratulations, Albert.
And you too, Anna.
You are a lucky couple.
Thanks to the Baron.
Not all masters give their
servants a beautiful wedding.
Nonsense, nonsense.
Albert has been part of
this family all his life.
Before him, his father
was already part of her.
And I do not know what the Baroness
would do without our little anarchy.
I hope you are very happy, dear.
If Albert is half as a
good husband as a butler,
You will not have cause for complaint.
A small gift.
Of the Baroness and a server.
You know, a good pipe is
the only rival of a woman.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
The coat of arms of the family.
The von Burgen crest for me?
Why not?
I'm sure it means a lot more to
you than to any of my family.
That's right, Lord.
And when I have a
child, I hope that...
Good...
Well, everything in its time, Lord.
Congratulations, Albert.
And you too, Anna.
Good...
I will prepare a snack
for the guests.
And today the servants...?
We will have a small dinner
on the ground floor, sir.
I see. I see. I trust you
to organize things, Albert.
Thank my Lord.
We just started with
the new fresh grapes.
And we were wondering if the
bride would step on them for us.
Young wine and a fertile bride.
Yupi!
Are you Karl Schneider?
Yes.
Go up and wait in the kitchen.
What wait in the kitchen?
It must be an error, Excellency.
The new driver, right?
Yes.
Someone told me to tell you.
Hears!
Hey, you owe me 5 cents.
It's okay.
Here you have.
Where is everybody?
At the wedding.
Yes. Everyone is at the wedding.
Glad to be here, right?
Yes. We have come alone
for the weekend.
I'm with the Countess.
We are from Paris.
Of course, you can see
that you are from Paris;
It shows to the league.
I feel so uncomfortable here.
These provincials are so...
Oh, I know.
They are just a bunch of servants.
Give them enough food and wine...
and they will be satisfied.
We are different.
Oh, you're very right.
Of course, I'm just a driver.
I travel, I see the world...
I try to instruct myself.
And see people.
Hey, tell me...
Do you have to stay with
the Countess every night?
Oh yeah!
I always have to be with
her in the same room.
Any free night?
Do not.
Well, Albert...
we should kiss the bride.
Oh, good news.
Oh, do not worry.
I am the new driver.
An unusual wedding.
Yes.
One does not distinguish the servants.
Have you known von
Burgen for a long time?
No, not much.
I met them through the Rothschilds.
The Rothschilds?
Do you work in banking?
No, cars.
Can I have a sandwich?
- No more missing.
- How is it going?
Countess!
Oh, I see they know each other.
- Thank you.
- I have not had that pleasure yet.
I'll leave you with the Countess.
I hope to see you again.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
Now I am the new driver.
But you can not work here.
I have the best references.
Even one that you wrote, Ma'am.
I dictated it to you.
You are a shameless man!
I thought that the Lady had
been entirely satisfied.
You can not work here.
You can not.
The Baroness is my friend.
If you do not leave right
away, I'll tell you...
Here comes the Baroness.
I'll tell him myself.
Karl Schneider. The new driver
At your complete disposal, Madam.
Oh, from the employment agency?
And before committing myself, Countess
De Marnac would like you to know...
Only, my dear Eloise, who
was my driver last winter.
He is an excellent driver.
The lady is very kind.
It seems that Albert is
somewhat lost today.
It is better to go to
the servants' quarters.
Countess.
Are you the cook?
Do I look like a cook?
Oh me...
I have not seen His Royal Highness before.
What?
And who are you?
The new driver.
I would like to have dinner.
Dine?
First of all, I'd
like some caviar.
And then, some onion soup.
Salad, of course.
The crab is my favorite.
And... and... a good slice
of undercooked roast beef.
And perhaps His Excellency would
like to be taken to his quarters?
No. I'm not fussy.
I will have dinner here.
The drivers are all the same.
Some useless lazy!
- Oh, Karl.
- Yes?
I am sorry. I did not have an
opportunity to talk to you.
Oh, I understand. It's okay.
Congratulations.
Oh thanks. Thank you.
Everything fixed, huh? Oh yeah.
- You have a place to sleep.
- Great.
Well, good night.
I do not have to wish you good night.
Goodnight.
Yes.
I must cross the threshold
with the bride in my arms.
Oh, Albert. Is beautiful.
We practically have two rooms.
Oh, Anna.
Now close your eyes.
And come here.
Do not look.
A radio!
Oh, Albert, you're so good to me.
No no. No no no no.
No, it's not nonsense.
It's true.
Albert, when I arrived here...
she was just a
scary kitchen helper.
All he could say was "yes,
sir" and "no, sir".
You remember?
Then you taught me to be a servant.
Then to be the maid
of the Baroness.
And now, you marry me.
Oh, Albert. I'm very grateful.
Forget about being grateful.
Be happy. That is all.
Always happy.
No, not that one.
Cast the jack.
Françoise, you're drunk.
I also!
Oh, Albert.
All the other maids envy me.
With that distinguished air
and your pretty sideburns.
Well, better worry about
your business, young lady...
or lose your handsome husband.
Oh, do not think you scare me.
You're just a stubborn old man.
Oh, but a sweet one.
Please, say you will always love me.
Always, my love.
Because...!
No no. For! Anna, please. No no.
Albert, not tonight.
Timbrazo Timbrazo Timbrazo.
They are not able to look at a
doorbell without pressing it.
Is not Françoise tonight
in charge of everything?
Yes, dear, but something
must have happened.
Oh, that's it.
It's already going.
But do not worry, dear.
My father was a butler...
and had nine children
between ringing and ringing.
But I do not want to go to bed.
You have already served enough for today.
I do not want to go to bed.
That will be it,
Françoise, for tonight.
I'm sorry Mr.
I will stay and serve the guests.
Cognac or pipermin?
Cognac, good man.
My mother also used to keep her
wedding ring in a showcase like that.
Forgive me for watching.
It made me feel nostalgic.
Do you live far away?
I lost it when I was a kid.
Oh, how sad.
He also used to do that.
It always kept it
bright and shiny.
Once when I was a kid,
I threw it playing and I broke it.
I cried. And my mother cried.
And I started saving
to buy a new one.
It was so small and
it took me so long...
that when I finally saved enough...
it was too late.
It means that...?
Instead I bought her
a wreath of flowers.
Oh poor.
I did not want to tell my
problems to a stranger.
Especially tonight, when
I should be so happy.
Oh, you must not think we're strangers.
Here you will feel at home.
I have been happier here than I
have been in my entire life.
I waited.
Let me fix it.
It is done.
A little kiss and I'll say good night.
It is the title of the
song that is playing.
Good evening, Eric.
It's Albert!
It is better to leave.
It's okay.
Anna.
Yes sir?
Anna, I'm going to get mad at you...
and you're going to
win a good reprimand.
How many times have I told
you not to call me "Lord"?
Oh, Albert.
For a moment I really thought
you were angry with me.
Oh darling.
It would not scare you for
anything in the world.
Hold me tight, Albert.
Do not let anything happen to
you, or to me, or to our home.
What an appetite!
Just a little bit, Sophie.
Wow!
Careful, Sophie.
You could fall and break that gossip.
You have flour in your thing.
Shake it, will you?
Domestic chores.
Driver - Take the Baroness to Vienna
at 10 o'clock - Take the cabriolet.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Do you mind taking the
wheel for a moment, Ma'am?
My ring has caught on his hair.
Oh yeah.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Oh, it's a woman's ring.
It was a woman's ring.
How long were you with the Countess?
Almost two years, Ma'am.
The Countess said that you
are a very discreet man.
The Lady can trust me to remember
everything and... forget everything.
Take me to 18 Louisa Strasse.
Yes ma'am.
Thank you very much.
The key to your wallet, Ma'am.
Thank you.
My coat, Lady.
Oh, no, no, no. You will freeze.
I'm always hot, ma'am.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Thanks, Karl.
Make Anna come up right away, please.
Yes ma'am.
The car broke down.
Hey, what kind of accident did you have?
Anyone who believes Your Honor.
Your Honor?
The boss. The Baron.
You can not be disrespectful
and stay here, Karl.
I have not been disrespectful
to you, right?
The very basis of our principles
is respect for those above.
I respect you and your wife
because you behave well...
Okay, Karl!
Let me talk to you expensive.
I've known this kind of thing since
I was about seven years old.
We have not had any accidents.
We stopped in a strange alley...
The Baroness said you
had an accident.
Well, do you want me to
respect her for that?
If we criticize them...
that is, those below
we stop being raised.
We have broken our code.
You know, as servants,
we do not make life;
It is made for us.
While we are capable, we
serve you the best we can.
But if we grow old or... get
sick, they take care of us.
And if they make a mistake,
we turn a blind eye, huh?
You do not have to listen
unless you want to stay here.
When they are wrong...
What right do we have to judge
whether it is right or wrong?
If a servant falls apart,
yes, I understand.
Down life is very simple.
But above, the rules are different.
And there is no relationship,
but a desire for service;
There are no feelings, but a
deep loyalty and protection.
Yes, I get it.
Fred Albert, I want to inform...
that the Baroness had
a mishap with the car.
That has delayed her a bit.
Well, I'm sure...
Hey, I trust you
to conform to us.
You know I like you.
To my wife too.
I like your wife.
You too.
You know, Albert...
I would like us to meet
and talk very seriously.
- Agree.
- Why...
I will respect the Baroness
if you want me to do it.
I'll even respect that kind of fool of
the Baroness, if that makes you happy.
You are just what we needed, Karl.
Someone to drink and laugh with.
In fact, sometimes
it's a bit boring.
Oh, Albert!
No, darling. I'm just saying it's not
like it used to be in the old days.
You would not believe it seeing him now,
but the Baron was a savage
when he was younger.
Oh, back then I was in
the Imperial Guard.
And every weekend, it
filled the officers' house.
And they all brought their girls.
Well, he behaved very badly, and
finally the Emperor intervened.
But while it lasted, it was
a wild and happy time.
Many tips, Albert, huh?
Tips?
Well, once we argue among ourselves.
He had gotten so drunk he wanted
to appear before the Emperor
with his uniform,
from the waist up,
and nothing, except his sword...
and his underpants, underneath.
I had to chase him on his
way to town with his pants.
And he gave me 100 crowns for them.
- Do not!
- Yes sir.
You young people do not know
what it was like before the war.
Oh, Karl. Too many cigarettes.
You must taste a good tobacco.
Like this.
You know?
I worked for an American.
Karl, there you have it: Americans.
Why a lot of money if you do
not know how to enjoy it?
I remember that the Baron had
here, once, the cream of Belais.
At 30.
Well, sir...
Sorry.
Well, I'll tell you later.
Come on, Albert.
You are very cruel.
No no. No way.
You are a newlywed.
These newly married women want
to know everything right away.
All!
Your Lordships again.
Yes.
No, Karl. You stay.
Take another coffee with Anna.
I will be back.
And do not forget, we still
have to talk seriously.
You can bet on it. Clear.
Come back soon, Albert.
You know? Sometimes I would
like to have a place like this.
Maybe one day.
No I do not.
Something in my blood...
makes it never stand still;
Something wild pulls me.
I get it.
I used to dream about places
where I would like to go.
Paris.
London.
America.
Have you never been away from here?
Not too far.
How fun it would be to show you
some of the places I've seen.
You would love Paris.
Maybe one day the Baroness will
take me to Paris with her.
And Monte Carlo.
There is a place on the hill where
you can dine in the moonlight.
You can see Corsica.
Geez, it's beautiful.
I do not understand why you
want to establish yourself.
If I were a man, I would like to
continue traveling and traveling.
He has his good things.
Sometimes it seems to me that
I have to leave a place.
Something happens...
My bags are made.
I'm on the move...
Alone.
It's getting cold, is not it?
Well, let's go inside.
It's been great to come and
chat with you tonight.
It makes me realize
what I've missed.
Albert always asks the new ones
to come and have coffee with him.
I'm thankful.
I have a friendly interest towards you.
I feel like you're my sister.
You do not care about
this feeling, right?
Do not.
Oh thanks.
Thank you.
Do not do it again or...
Or what?
I will tell my husband.
I will tell him myself.
Hi, Albert.
Hi.
I wanted to tell you...
That if there are no more orders tonight,
I would like to go to bed early.
To the bed? What nonsense!
Who do you think I
bring beer with?
Albert!
If you do not mind, I'll take
it and finish it in my room.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
What's wrong?
Is that...
I do not want him here.
Why? Karl is a good guy.
I know but...
Oh, no, dear. You are tired.
That is all.
Now go to bed while
I finish my beer.
But good.
Very shameless.
Come and sit in my room without...
without something like a "please"
or a "with your permission".
And you smell like onion. Phew!
But last night...
Well, what about last night?
I thought that...
Did you believe?
Hey, who do you think I am? A train
that departs according to the schedule?
Last night was last night.
And good?
I just wanted to bring you some dessert.
Dessert?
Food, food, food.
Do you ever think of something else?
You are like a walking refrigerator.
Do not insult me, please...
treating me like a pig
to get fat for the market.
Ah, Sophie...
There are better things in
life than eating, or drinking.
Things better than the
pleasures of the moment.
Or of the hour.
Sophie...
do you know what I said to
myself the first time I saw you?
I told myself "this is
a woman with a soul".
But Sophie...
you disappoint me.
Oh, oh, Sophie.
Ya, ya. I spoke too harshly.
But I'm very nervous.
It's the mixture of blood in my veins.
Sophie, if I told you
about my ancestors...
My father was...
You would not believe me if I told you.
Oh, I would.
Anyone would know that
you are a gentleman.
A gentleman?
My dear Sophie...
my father was a Grande from Spain.
And my mother...
How much he suffered!
Trying to hide your
secret with pride.
Without any of the sacred memories
of other women's marriage.
Without wedding ring.
Without wedding garland.
Only one son...
that he could not carry
his father's last name.
Sophie.
You should not keep your
money in the average.
But there he is sure.
I know but...
It ruins the shape of your leg.
Wow. Please, take it, Anna.
Buy it for you.
One day I took the
Baroness to the city.
No, Karl, I do not want it.
Despite how much I try to please
you, everything I do is wrong.
Did not I apologize for
kissing you that night?
Have not I behaved
well since then?
Almost always.
Are you not all happy with me?
Even Albert?
Is there someone you
have not been kind to?
Yes; Sophie.
You made him believe that you cared.
Sophie, well...
And I really care.
I feel towards Sophie as
if she were my mother.
Your mother?
Well, what else could I feel?
Because, Anna, do not you think...?
True?
Do not.
Good.
Poor Sophie.
He has worked so hard
all these years,
Sweating the fat drop in the kitchen.
Now that you are older and less
attractive, what do you have left?
A lot of money.
And what is that?
I'm sorry I talked about her.
We all make mistakes.
Look...
it goes this way, Anna.
Anna.
The Baroness wants to
see you right now.
We will go fishing tomorrow.
Very good, Albert.
And you, Karl,
You will go for the Baron's fishing rod
to the warehouse and take it upstairs.
All right.
What do I do with these, ma'am?
Those?
You can keep them if you like them.
Those water spots never came out.
Oh, thank you, ma'am.
Where did you get that brooch?
It's mine.
I'm sure it's mine
I just bought it.
What are you doing with him?
And good?
Because you do not answer?
Have you stolen it?
Oh, no, ma'am.
It can not be yours.
Oh, do not be ridiculous.
Of course it's mine.
Do not I know my own jewels?
To think that a girl like you,
raised in our own house,
I can be a vulgar thief.
Forgive me, lady.
I could not help but hear him.
Could not you avoid hearing what?
Call Anna a thief.
And what should I call it?
Duchess?
No ma'am.
The brooch that Anna
carries is not yours.
I gave it to him.
A wedding gift.
Did you give it to him?
I got it in a small house
on the Louisa Strasse.
Louisa Strasse?
The Lady, probably, does
not know that street.
His name is not very lucky.
I can give you the address,
if you're interested.
- Number...
- I'm not interested.
As the Lady wishes.
But I can assure you, Madam,
that the brooch is not yours.
I was wrong.
It is not mine.
I'm sorry, Anna.
Oh, please, Madam.
You can go.
I do not know how to thank you...
putting you on my side
in front of the Baroness.
Oh, it's nothing.
I could not see anyone unjustly
accused, even if it costs me the job.
Well, I think you were fantastic.
Was nothing.
I would do it for anyone.
Dear. At this time, tomorrow
night, we will be on the ship.
Rights to deep water
and big fish.
Oh, I do not like the idea of
smelling fish during the weekend.
Go, go, dear.
There are worse things than fish
to smell during the weekend.
That reminds me...
I have to take the new
pills for the liver...
my dyspeptic tablets and
something in case I get dizzy.
Nicky.
Are you going to stop imagining
that you have something wrong?
You have an iron health.
This always stops hiccups.
We better suspend that fishing trip.
But why?
Because you expect to get sick.
Who said he was sick?
I have not felt better in my life.
I'm just thinking about your happiness.
I am a lucky man,
especially in this day of intrigue and
scandal, of having a wife like you.
Scandal?
Yesterday I heard that old von
Rappan's wife had a lover!
And what did you expect?
He is 80 She 23.
And he has asthma.
Well, there are a lot of
remedies for asthma today.
It worries me much more, Nicky,
having a little scandal
in our own house.
A scandal in this house?
Impossible.
However, it concerns Albert.
Albert?
But if he just got married.
It is clear that he can not
be dissatisfied anymore.
It's not Albert...
but his wife.
And Karl, the new driver.
He has given him a jewel.
- Karl?
- Yes.
You mean that Karl and Anna...?
Karl?
Well, I'm happy for him.
Anna is a very pretty girl.
A charm.
You look like the
night we got married.
Nicky?
Remember what the doctor said.
You're right.
I must be careful.
- Goodnight.
Oh, Albert.
Yes ma'am?
Albert...
as the Baron is not going
to leave you under suspicion,
It could be a good idea for you...
Well, put the house in order.
Yes ma'am.
Some of the servants like...
Let me think...
Hans, Liezel...
And Karl.
You may want to
make some changes.
Use your own criteria.
Thank Mrs.
Something else, ma'am?
That is all.
Good evening, Albert.
What's up with everything?
Half of my team is not here.
No no no!
I knew he was not here!
Albert!
Where were you, Albert?
I was calling you.
I'm sorry Mr.
Did not I tell you to make
sure you brought my troll rod?
Is not he in his cabin, sir?
But hey, why did not anyone tell me!
Good good.
What are we waiting for?
I can not be here all day.
Well sir.
I have taken out your things, Lord.
My wool socks?
Yes, and his flannel briefs.
Well done, Albert.
Then I will disembark.
What? Land? For what?
Because I understood that you
would not need me, Lord.
The Baroness said...
Silly stuff! Of course it comes.
Eloise, what's that about
Albert not coming?
I do not...
I thought you did not need him.
And there is a lot to do at home.
It is not necessary?
Do you realize that we will be
out in the open for three days?
How do you think I could
live without Albert?
What happens?
Karl and Anna.
What? What?
Oh nothing.
Then very well.
Good, Captain. Clearance!
Goodbye, Albert.
Karl.
I have to tell you something.
What's up, Albert?
You know what happens.
And it's going to end.
You understand?
End up? What is going to end?
I'm a patient man, Karl...
but I've had enough
of your impudence.
Do you hear me?
Stay away from my house.
And do not talk to my wife.
Do not talk to Anna?
What will she say?
It does not matter.
You're going to leave her
alone once and for all.
What's going on here?
Why do not you disembark, Karl?
Albert wants to talk to me, Lord.
A few last minute instructions.
What a moment for that!
Go Go! Get off the boat.
Yes sir.
All right, Captain. Clearance!
Well sir.
See you later, Albert.
Are you sure Albert agreed?
After dinner. Clear.
Do not you remember that he made me come
back just as I was getting off the ship?
That's what we were talking about.
I wonder why he stayed.
He said he was not with them.
Well, I did not expect to do it.
That's why I wanted to be sure you
were going to have a good friend.
Albert is so considerate.
Hey, you do not have to tell
me what a good guy Albert is;
Not after how he has treated me.
Well, good old Albert!
I feel great.
So warm in here.
I wonder what makes me
feel so warm in here.
It could be wine, right?
Do not.
I thought it was
wine, to drink it.
Of that nothing.
Oh, his feet are wet.
Poor Albert.
Albert?
Clear.
Look at his pretty sideburns.
Come on. Come on.
They tickle, right?
What tickles?
The whiskers of Albert.
Oh, poor Albert.
Albert abandons you.
Hey, an old love mess.
And also family.
In your husband's lap.
What's happening to me?
Behaving like this!
I do not know what I was laughing at.
Excuse me.
Goodnight.
Do not.
I know where you like to be kissed.
What do you mean?
It is marked by a charming little moon.
It's like a drop of chocolate.
Did Albert never tell you
how beautiful it was?
Albert never looks at
the back of my neck.
Not even to see if it was clean?
Oh do not worry.
I'll turn it off right away.
What a disappointment.
Hala, that's it. Look.
Ea, ready.
The fire is already off.
I know. But...
Your room is ready
for when you like.
What are you talking about?
I have not asked for any room.
Oh, yes, Lord.
Everything as he said.
Wine and a fire.
And a nice surprise for the lady.
Anna, please.
But it was for you, Lord.
Do not you remember the money?
Oh, money, huh?
Is that what you want?
But, Lord, you...
What is happening, Lord?
This man made a mistake.
Which unfortunately
concerns this lady...
for which I have
the deepest respect.
Take.
The next time you want money,
try to earn it honestly.
Thank my Lord.
I do not give you any pity.
I could have died by your side,
with so many attentions.
Does it hurt a lot, Nicky?
It starts giving me pangs.
That's bad.
After all the plans I
made for this trip,
Who would have thought this would happen?
Well, what do you expect
from a fishing trip?
It's a miracle you did not
take the bait before.
Albert.
Are you sure the hook was new?
Yes sir. All were.
I carry you in my heart
I take you in thought.
You make me suffer a lot.
You do not know how good I am for you.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Why you do not believe me?
It was a mistake.
Believe you?
I do not believe anything about you.
I have never felt so
ashamed in my whole life.
I did not even think I
was that kind of girl.
Wait until Albert...!
I do not think Albert
said you would take me.
He did not say. He did not say.
You know he did not say it!
You also lied about that.
Shut up.
You will awaken the whole world.
What will they think?
You lied to me about Albert.
According to you, he
said he could go, right?
What am I going to do now?
What will I do when he finds out?
He does not need to know.
You do not have to tell him.
So you did it?
And now you want me to lie to you?
I've never lied to
Albert in all my life!
And now you want me to do it!
Listen, Anna.
I have to tell you the truth.
I have done everything you said.
All.
I cheated on you...
and I lied to you...
because I'm crazy about you.
I have done everything
in order to be with you.
But now I will go.
Nothing you can say
will be enough.
Do not you think to talk to me?
Well, I deserve it too.
Listen, Anna.
I have never had many opportunities;
I have never had anyone to
show me the right path.
I have had to fight alone in life.
Bad companies.
Never before have I been in
love with someone good...
like you.
I did not know how to treat you.
Well, now it's too late.
Goodbye, Anna.
Goodbye?
I leave.
I can not stay after
what I've done.
I'm so embarrassed that...
I could not look
you in the face again.
But... but your job.
I do not want you to lose it.
It does not matter.
I'll find another one.
And if not, well, nobody will care.
Do not worry about me.
I'm not worth it
Anna.
Before I leave...
You want...?
Could you...
kiss me goodbye?
Come on. Come on. Open the door!
Why does not someone do something?
I'll call Dr. Stirs.
Someone prepare my bed.
Albert.
Yes sir?
Are you sure the hook was new?
In all, Lord.
Hi, Albert.
How did you get back?
We rent a car.
What are you doing here?
I was going to wash the car.
Good morning, Anna.
You came back early, Albert.
Yes.
Karl gave you good morning, Anna.
- Good morning, Karl.
- Good Morning.
What time did you come back last night?
Oh I do not know.
It was not too late.
What time, Anna?
At that... nine o'clock, I think.
Look at that button.
What does that mean?
With this aspect!
I am sorry. I did not see it.
I'll fix it.
I will not tolerate such
neglected habits in this house.
I already had more than enough.
You can collect your payment.
Charge my...?
I am fired?
Yes!
For a loose button?
I will not talk about it.
Did the Baroness complain about me?
That has nothing to do with this.
I am responsible for the
servants of this house.
It is understood?
Yes, understood, Albert.
How was the music last night?
Music?
What do you mean?
There was a concert from Vienna.
Gypsy music.
On the radio.
I did not turn on the radio.
I thought you would.
There was not much more to do.
Anna.
Is it all you have to tell me?
Yes, Albert.
I'd better go see the Baroness.
Do not!
You're not going to see the
Baroness with that look.
You are not wearing
the cap or the apron.
What do you think the Baroness will say?
Sorry. I...
Go fix it right away.
You know what I expect from
a servant in this house.
A servant?
You already heard what I said.
Albert.
I was not sincere a moment ago.
And where have you been?
Where you come from?
Of the coffee.
He told me you asked
him to take me there.
We drank a lot of wine.
We stay until very late.
Yes, you drank a lot of wine...
and you allowed him
to make love to you.
I'm sorry, Albert.
More than I can tell you.
Stop lying about it!
Put on your clothes!
You have work to do.
Wait a minute.
I do not deserve you to
give me orders that way.
For the first time in
my life I discovered...
for the first time...
that there are more than two
kinds of feelings in the world.
It is my fault?
A way of making love that
makes you lose your head!
So you do not know
what you are doing.
Are you going to throw me out on the
street because I never felt that before?
Let's leave this conversation.
Enough now!
You learn something vile about a rat...
and you forget that you are my wife...
and that I love you.
And you bring him here.
It's okay.
You, honest man.
I will leave this conversation.
Create exactly what you want to believe.
But listen...
whatever happens,
it's partly your fault.
Partly.
You think you can make love
in the same cold way you
do everything else;
You think that's
all I should want.
Well, now I tell you
frankly and plainly.
It's nothing like that.
It was not my intention.
The only thing I want
in my home is you.
But if you are going to be so straight,
so perfect and so implacable,
then I can not have it.
And I thank heaven for having found
that there is something else;
Something that makes you feel so excited...
you do not know what
happened and you do not care.
Now, continue with yours
and believe what you want.
Do you realize that this is blackmail?
That is the word I was
trying to remember.
But in reality it is not, Madam.
The simple desire to stay longer in
the service of such a lovely lady.
I'm sorry to present the
matter to you in this way...
but that's what
happens to the servants.
Sometimes our duties
are not pleasant.
Are you sure you do not accept money?
Well... not at the moment.
All I want is to remain
at your service...
to carry out my plans.
Will the Lady order it to Albert?
Sophie.
I heard you I heard you!
Apparently I can not be absent for a single
night without everything falling apart.
Do you say it for me?
Did someone complain about
not having enough food?
I wanted to imply that I expect
discipline in this house.
Discipline? Ha!
You talk so much about
order in this house...
And why do not you put some
order in your own home?
What do you mean?
Ask your precious
Anna what I mean;
Ask her what is going on
between her and Karl.
Of course I can be wrong.
Maybe it was not Anna who returned
with Karl at five in the morning.
Do not. Stop!
Well, of course, if
you're not interested...
I'm not interested in anything you
have to tell me about my wife.
Anna is a good girl...
and a good wife.
And Karl is finished.
I've fired him.
Leave this house.
Really?
Does Karl leave us?
Yes. I said goodbye.
Like I'll fire
anyone so insolent.
Can you hear me?
Albert.
Yes ma'am?
Karl tells me you've fired him.
Yes ma'am.
I... I find Karl to my
complete satisfaction.
But Madam...
I want him to stay.
But...
After all, Karl is my driver.
And you do not have the power to fire him.
But Madam, I was always
responsible for the servants...
I do not want to talk about it anymore.
So you fired him, huh?
Orders, Albert?
Do not.
Well, if you think of any,
let me know, will you?
Go back to work!
There is so much to do
without having to flutter.
Queen Sophie.
A word from you and everyone jumps, huh?
What were you doing, hanging
out at home with Anna at dawn?
Ha! So you also jump.
Do you think someone else saw us?
Listen, Sophie, what a good time I spent.
On the way home from the
boat, nothing to do.
But she had to stop somewhere to
buy something to eat and drink.
We argued because I did not
think Albert liked it.
Well, in the end I gave up.
You talk about those discreet
and quiet girls, huh?
After drinking a few extra glasses,
The only thing that saved me was
that they closed the place.
He was happy to have brought
her safe and sound.
Wow!
You tell it very well.
Almost as well as you tell the story
from the cafeteria that you are
going to buy me in Vienna...
with my money!
Is that what you want.
My money.
"You should not work so hard, Sophie."
"What you should be opening
your own business..."
"with a man like
me to help you."
My savings.
Everything I have in these
35 years of hard work.
Since I was 9 years old.
And all this time you were
with that fresh maid.
Laughing at me.
Laughing both of me.
I should have imagined
that you did not love me.
Okay, I do not love you.
Satisfied?
Oh, Karl!
"Oh, Karl!" Do you hear?
Complaints, complaints, complaints.
If there's something I detest, it's
the women who are harassing me.
You should be very grateful.
I've spent a lot of time
and a lot of attention.
And how much has it cost you?
Nothing!
¿Costarme?
Yes, cost you.
With a face like that, you
should have paid, and a lot!
Goodbye, grandma.
No ma'am.
I could not, I could not do it.
There is no room in this
house for Karl and me.
Albert, please.
This house needs you
now more than ever.
I need you!
I can not fire him.
He forces me to keep him.
Obligated?
I do not get it.
Karl is blackmailing me.
Oh, Madam!
I should have told him.
Oh, that liar, that blackmailer!
What kind of history has
he invented about you?
He has not invented any history.
It is something that knows.
About you?
Ma'am, that's ridiculous.
Well, the police will clarify it with him.
Police?
Oh, no, no!
Albert, we can not do that!
Do not you realize?
What he knows about me is true.
I do not dare let him go.
You have to find another
way to fix this with Karl.
Sorry Mrs.
I was wrong to think about my pride.
There are other things to protect.
You must be careful.
A man like that is dangerous.
I told you, Ma'am.
I have always been responsible
for the servants of this house.
I am still responsible.
And now, if I may...
Albert.
About Anna...
She is young.
It's not made for a guy like Karl.
You must be patient with her.
Women sometimes do nonsense.
Only because of ignorance.
Yes.
Now I see it.
Between.
Well thats what you want?
I'm so miserable.
You have not talked to me;
You have not even looked at me.
Not since...
Not since you insulted me.
Oh, Karl! I did not mean that.
I can not stand it, if
you do not talk to me.
I do not care what you have done.
It's okay.
Do not you care what he has done?
What have I done?
I mean you and Anna.
You will not start with that again!
More suspicions, more
insults, more reproaches.
Please, Karl, let's not fight.
I can not live without you.
I will do anything.
If you let me stay here with you.
For a few days, I would be so happy.
Karl.
Karl, let's do what we said.
Buy a cafeteria.
With your money?
It's what you said before.
Throwing it in my face!
You think I'm going to give you
another chance to do it again.
I'm not a sentimental fool.
It's our money, Karl.
Look.
Here it is! All!
Do you know what is the
saddest thing of all this?
Just one day before,
I went all over Vienna...
looking for the right
coffee shop to buy it.
Wandering in the sun.
Did not you have the car?
Do you think I would use the Baron's
car for my personal affairs?
And I found a beauty.
Black marble tables.
Red plush furniture,
golden mirrors.
It was the most beautiful cafe in Vienna.
We could make a fortune.
Here it is, Karl.
Sophie, you offend me.
Thinking of money right now.
DOMESTIC HOUSES.
For hunting the boar
47 horses ready at dawn
Hunting lunch for 50 guests.
Hurry with those pigeons.
These lobsters are ready.
Better send them up.
Hey, what's up with that oven?
And Anna...
tell Otto to take three
bottles of Brandy Napoleon.
It does not have the necessary height.
It is four inches tall.
Why do you say that?
It's not high enough for this house.
I've been working in
this house for 20 years.
Hey, do you want to shut up, you parrots?!
44... 46... 48... 50.
Shut up!
56... 58...
60... 65... 100.
What time is the fastest
train to Paris?
Otto.
Three bottles of Napoleon Brandy.
What?
Three bottles of Napoleon
Brandy, up here.
Anna
I've been looking for
you all over the house.
Karl, let me go. I'm scared.
Oh, well, it's normal that you're scared.
You do not have to come down.
Look, charm.
I have not forgotten you.
I was just waiting for
my plans to be ready.
There is a train leaving
Vienna in one hour.
Think about it.
Karl! Karl, please!
I love Albert.
It's a bit late for you to
think about that, right?
Let's finish with this nonsense.
We are crazy for each other.
And you know.
Let's go somewhere...
before you have the
chance to tell him.
You love Me. You love Me!
No no. Karl.
All I want is my
husband and my job.
Let me go, please!
Listen out.
Are you going to do what
I say and come with me?
Or are you going to be
around until you get kicked?
Please, have a little mercy.
Piety? I tell you...
I love you.
Listen, Anna...
I have much money to spend.
We will spend like kings.
I'm going to make you happy.
It's Sophie's money.
And what else does it give you?
I'm going to spend it with you.
- Spending Sophie's money with me?
- Yes.
No, I will not go with you!
I will not go!
Oh, listen!
I will leave you here for
nothing in the world.
You are welcome!
Besides, how do you know Albert
wants you to stay here...
once you know what's ours?
And he will know because I will tell him!
- Oh no!
- Oh yeah!
And to each inhabitant of this house.
If Albert does not have
arrests to forgive you,
the others will make your life impossible.
You will not be able to
continue living here!
Let go of me, you filthy beast!
So you do not want to leave, huh?
All right, then
I'll tell Albert!
I'll tell him and he'll kick you out!
Come here! Come here!
Give me that!
Do not!
I'll see what happens.
Albert, I'm sorry.
The barrel slid and
hit the wine rack.
As a...
Albert!
Do not!
I'm sorry Mr.
But many of its best
bottles have been broken.
I lost my head.
The spilled wine is not
as important as this.
Yes sir. I am sorry.
Go back to work
and fix the mess.
I do not want to know anything
else about the matter.
Yes sir.
You, go back to work!
And help clean the cellar.
Leave this place clean.
Liebfrauenmilch!
Well, Karl.
I think I rushed.
Anna, it's better to go
up and change clothes.
And Franz...
you and Ernst go back to the kitchen.
We will finish this tomorrow.
No, Karl, do not go.
You are still nervous.
I'm sorry, I lost my composure.
It is not the way to fix things.
Better take something.
Clear.
Here is one that is not broken.
Intact, Karl.
But affected.
The wine is like that.
Easily alterable.
Like a woman.
And when she's upset, she
needs time to calm down.
Time for the grounds to
return to the bottom.
With some care, time and rest,
you will get well again.
But you must take care of the wine.
And of women.
Otto, stay in the care of wine.
And of the women...?
Good...
It is a work of men.
Take care of them.
A few glasses, Otto.
I'm sorry about what happened, Albert.
I imagine it's too late to
cry for the spilled wine.
It is done.
Let's have a drink, huh?
Oh no.
We will provide something special.
I will bring a bottle.
Hey, I do not want wine.
Blind?
Do not. I'm not blind
I'm just deaf
I do not hear.
Here we are.
Well, Karl.
For your future!
And no more spilled wine.
Well, Albert, I
accepted your apology.
I think now I should go.
Yes, Karl.
Ten minutes to collect
your stuff and get away!
Take my hands off!
Now we will do it without making a fuss!
I could have killed you if
the Baron does not stop me.
Oh, save my life so you
could fire me, huh?
Well, do not kid yourself, Albert.
If you want to get out
of here in 10 minutes,
You will have to work quickly.
Hears...
I will be here
as long as I want.
And you're going to have to put up with it.
Out of my sight or I can not
take your hands off you.
You're going to take my hands off me
because the people from
above will tell you.
If you say goodbye again,
I will turn you into a laughingstock again.
And those above will
do what I tell them.
No, Karl!
You will never be near the ones above.
You are done.
Leave the Baroness out of this.
And to Sophie, leave her alone.
I have everything I need from Sophie.
And my wife...
You're going to save them all, right?
Well, look.
When they're over, I'll
go for the Baroness's.
And she'll pay me until I want to.
Filthy pig!
So there's no other
option with you?
My wife can not protect herself from you?
Come on, let's go!
Stand up and fight, dirty rat!
I give you that opportunity.
But only one will come out on its own.
No, damn dog!
Albert!
Albert, stop!
You are killing him!
Call the Baron!
It is killing you!
Albert!
Take this!
Come on, get up!
Come on!
Quick! Quick!
It is killing you.
Albert!
For! Enough is enough!
I will take care of this.
Excuse me sir...
but this time I will do it.
He has something to tell you.
Some twisted idea.
Come on, let's go!
Say it!
Nothing, Lord.
Sophie, come here!
Give him back the money you
stole from this woman.
Come on!
And my wife.
There is something pending with her.
Come on. Tell her!
Say it! Come on.
Nothing.
Creepy!
Out of here!
You loaded my grinder.
Well done, Albert.
Thank my Lord.
Just a little cleaning.
Go back to work. Everybody!
As before. Hurry!
Very good, Albert.
Thank my Lord.
What did he say, Albert?
Nothing sweetheart.
Everything is well now.
Do not worry.
Yes sir.
Did not I tell you not to call me "Sir"?
Well, just one more, ma'am.
Oh, no, no, Olly.
I will not interview more drivers today.
Tomorrow afternoon at three.
And good?
The new chauffeur of the Lady.
I hope so.