Here.
Let's hug Eun Sung
and hug Mom too! I'll hug you both!
Eun Sung,
you're not hungry?
I'm hungry.
- Shall we go eat? - Yes! Let's!
There wasn't anything up?
What would happen?
Never mind. I don't mean anything by it.
Did you think I would be emotionally moved
if you wrote this statement of account?
Don't do that ever again.
Aren't you ashamed to face Eun Sung?
Everything's been taken care of now.
Father just went overboard.
Did it really get all resolved?
What's not to be fixed?
There's nothing I did wrong.
Kang Hye Soo, from now on, don't
decide anything by yourself.
I'm undoubtedly your husband
and Eun Sung's dad.
Our divorce hasn't been processed. Even if the deliberation period has passed, you know if we don't go to
court, it becomes invalid, right? (Korean court of law gives the couple appointed time to mull things over)
Eun Sung, instead of calling
me Ahjussi, call me Dad.
Look here.
What do you mean "look here"? I
told you to call me Ji Hoon.
Well. Rather than... Uh, Honey or Darling
since it's too corny, just call me Oppa.
From now on, please don't do anything
foolish. Just do only what I tell you to.
First. Let's combine our stuff.
Let's find a house first.
Look here.
Eun Sung, could you call me Dad?
Dad.
Eun Sung, say it again.
Aigoo. Aigoo my daughter.
Who did you say I was?
Dad.
There can't be a single word from the
board meeting leaked to the press.
Let's first silence the board members.
Organ selling or whatever. Not a
single word of that can be leaked out.
Understood, chairman.
Contact Attorney Oh and ask him
to come up with some solutions.
Yes, Chairman.
Managing Director Han Ji
Hoon resigned I heard?
It seemed he made some big mess. They say
he resigned before anyone took note.
- What kind of news is this immediately after promotion? - It
seems the elder son will now take charge of the spotlight.
Oh yeah Reporter Hong. You didn't forget
the appointment we made last time did you?
We need to have a meal together.
The Promise
Here here here. You've all worked hard. Let's head
to Hongdae (neighborhood in Seoul) for drinks.
You've all done good work.
Hello.
Will you see me for a bit?
Thank you for all this time.
I'm going to be working until the end of the
month. Then I'm won't be coming here anymore.
What did he say?
He said he's quitting.
Thanks to you, I believe our Promise
Restaurant was able to grow this much.
If there was any hard feelings you had towards
me, please be understanding and let them go.
I also know I did a lot
of unsightly things, too.
Uh... what are you saying..
All of a sudden...
Oh. You're here? Regional
Headquarter Manager?
Well I'll be closing up and leaving. If there are any
complaints that you'd like to address, please let me know.
I'll do my best to address them.
Hey. What happened? Tell all.
What's there to tell. Since I did wrong,
quitting is certainly the right thing to do.
What do you mean "sin"? Your mother
didn't even get surgery from Hye Soo.
Isn't it too much quitting over that?
You should've kept hanging
on and pressing hard.
It's ok. I'm actually
feeling quite relieved.
Relieved, you punk? W-w-what are we going to
do now? What're you going to be living off of?
I found a new place of
employment, so don't worry.
Already?
Hey Ho Joon. I'm going to marry Hye Soo.
-What - I mean
The marriage has already been done. I'm going
to move in with her and live together.
Look. Has your father
given you his permission?
Am I some kind of minor? I've already passed the
age to gain parental approval for marriage.
I'm deciding my own marriage. What's
that have to do with my father?
You... did you by chance, get kicked out?
You you punk. Why are
you speaking like that?
Hey. You! you... what am I going to do now?
I'm about to get the can...
Kang Hye Soo, are you ok?
Yeah. I'm ok. Don't worry.
If it's difficult. Let me know.
Yeah.
- Hello - Hello
Could you have a seat there for one moment?
I think we have to... temporarily
suspend the radiation treatments.
Not to mention your stamina, your
immunity has decreased tremendously.
Since there are too many side effects. I
think there'd be more to loose than gain.
If your body's not strong enough, it's
not possible to undergo treatment.
What happens if we stop treatment?
You said there's no other way
besides radiation therapy.
Next year, our child
will be entering school.
Will I be able to live until then?
Maybe it's because you're young. It's true that the
progression is most faster than I had thought.
But still don't loose hope,
and have a strong heart.
Has Miss Kang Hye Soo not arrived yet?
Miss Kang Hye Soo's treatments
have been suspended.
Yes? What are you talking about?
I'll start again...
- Hello - Hello, yes.
- Mr. Lee Sang Soo?
- Yes - Let's go inside.
Ah excuse me, doc.
What does it mean that my wife's
treatments have been stopped?
Has it become much worse?
Yes, it's because the patient's condition has worsened
considerably. The speed of progression is just so fast.
Is there no other way? We should still
treat it. You said it was getting worse.
Does it make sense that we sit
here twiddling our thumbs?
As of now there's no other way really.
There' s nothing i can guarantee.
Look here. How is that so. Anyone
can say that. Are you a doctor?!
You have to get her well no matter what. I'm a
slipshod husband, but you're also a slipshod doc too.
You have to tell her that she'll live no
matter what. That way she'll get better.
Please calm down.
I'm begging you doctor,
save her.
We have to save our Hye Soo.
I told you not to come to the hospital by
yourself. Why did you break your promise, huh?
You worked hard. Aren't you hungry?
Yeah I'm really hungry. Buy
me something delicious.
What would you like to eat? Tell me.
I'll buy you everything.
I want to eat chicken, pasta too, and..
Seolleongtang (beef stock stew) as well.
I also want to eat Korean table d'hote. The ones
with banchan (side dishes) that are this big!
You're not going to eat?
I will eat.
If you're not going to eat,
I'm going to eat it all.
Let's change hospitals.
Excuse me?
That lady just had a bad temper.
She seems like she has no skill.
I'm looking for another place, so
let's change for the time being.
I just want to go to the
place I usually went.
The doctor is skilled.
What do you mean skill?
She's totally a quack.
She says that I'm progressively
getting better. Don't worry.
I'm serious. Can't you tell
by the way I'm eating?
Here. Drink some water.
Okay.
Do you have somewhere you
want to go after we eat?
You're not going to work?
What do you mean work? I'm a golden
spoon (meaning he's wealthy).
I don't have to work.
Let's go see some houses later.
- House?-Did you not understand
what Jung Hoon was saying?
Other people will curse at you. Does it make sense
for a married woman to live at a friend's house?
I have my eye on a house we can live in.
Don't worry. I will go in
when they allow me to.
When should we have the wedding ceremony?
Do we have to do that first?
The order is all messed up.
So what if it's messed up?
Kang Hye Soo, will you marry me?
Is this a plee for help?
Yes. A plee for help.
Why? You don't like it?
Of course I don't like it.
Is this the first time doing a proposal?
I've received one before.
What kind of proposal is this?
I would still be indecisive
even if you did a proper one.
There are proposals where
they hang balloons
pop confetti, fire laser
beams, and scream "I LOVE YOU
Hye Soo!" and they sing you songs.
Isn't that what a proposal is?
What do you mean? It's so childish.
I'm not saying I would
receive something like that.
I'm just full of energy that's why.
I'm not saying I'll get hit by lightning
just to get something big out of it.
So, you don't like it?
I'll have to think about it.
Getting married isn't a joke.
You're very old fashioned. Do you
have to receive something so obvious?
Forget it! Act like the proposal
and everything else didn't happen.
I don't like it either.
This is delicious. Right?
Eat more.
Eat this too.
I'm eating.
This place is delicious right?
You said you eat well.
Here.
Hurry up and eat.
Madam. A guest is here for you.
Hello Madam.
I heard the surgery was a success.
Congratulations.
Get out.
This is matter regarding Ji Hoon's life.
Make a promise with me.
That kid looks like he will be investigated
by the police if he isn't careful.
What are you saying?
Who exposed it?
That kid exposed it himself.
So innocent.
Since this originated from you,
act like you know nothing.
If someone asks you,
say that Ji Hoon and that girl have
already been dating for a long time.
When you meet Ji Hoon, tell him
to proceed with the divorce.
Divorcing right now will
only raise suspicion.
They said to divorce once
the rumors died down.
According to the lawyer, that
is the only way right now.
Why are you making me say those things?
Say it yourself.
That kid is not in his
right mind right now.
He is so caught up with that child's
mother, he can't see anything.
He turned his back on his
father, and left the company.
What did you just say?
Did you not hear anything from him?
That wench is a total player.
The innocent kid is caught.
There is no reason for parents to be meddling in
the dating life of a child who's all grown up.
He must like her because she is likable.
-What?-Get out. I don't know anymore.
I have no debt to that household,
so don't request anything from me.
How dare you just barge in and
shamelessly ask me for a favor.
Why else do you think I came to you?
This is Ji Hoon's matter! He is your son!
How can you say, you don't know when
your son's life is about to be over!?
Do you have the right to
say something like that?
Are you a father?
Did you think that I wouldn't know
that you are doing all of
this because of your greed?
Stop acting like you're
thinking about your child.
Did you know that the girl was dying?
What?
You didn't undergo the surgery
already knowing this fact did you?
What do you mean?
Eun Sung!
Dad!
It's my dad!
You came.
- Thank you. Come to
Daddy.-Teacher, it's not that.
That's not it, Teacher.
Did you miss your Dad?
I missed you.
Where are we going?
Let's go Eun Sung.
We have to go to your house.
We're here.
Shall we go in? Come in.
Hurry in Mom.
Tada!
Wow, is this our house?
Do you like it? You have your own room.
-Where? Where?-Shall I show you?
It's over here.
Mom! This is my room!
-Look at this.-Wow!
When did you prepare all of this?
I was dying trying to quickly
decorate everything.
For the rest of the stuff, we can
clean it up as we live here.
This was the only house that looked good
enough that was close to Joo Yeon's house.
Live here even if you don't like it.
When Eun Sung grows, let's
move to a better place.
Why are you so quick to act?
Because I want to quickly live together.
Is it normal for a couple
to live separately?
Don't you want to see the master bedroom?
Why are you like this?
- What do you think about the bedsheets?
You don't like it?
Forget it.
Why? Have a seat or lay down.
Are you upset because I
picked what I wanted?
You're right. I am getting upset.
If you're upset, lets lie down.
Wait. One second. It tickles.
Eun Sung came!
Eun Sung, do something about this Ahjusshi.
Why? Do you not like the furniture?
Should I return them all?
Change it to what you like.
My taste will probably be better.
You're old fashioned.
I like it. Ahjusshi. Dad.
My daughter is the only
one who knows my heart.
The cats are going to live with us right?
-Of course!-Oh yeah!
Manager! Come talk to me.
Yes, sir!
What's going on? Tell me
everything there is to know.
What?
Why is the Executive Director quitting? Why
did he resign right after being promoted?
That rumor about trading
organs was true, wasn't it?
I said it wasn't! It was a
totally groundless rumor!
Then why would he resign?
Is it because of the sexual
harassment issue with Kang Hye Soo?
Ah, geesh! I said it wasn't that!
Why would he sexually harass Hye Soo?
When they can't live without each other?
What? He can't live without her?
That's what I said!
He's quitting because he truly likes her.
If he likes her, then why doesn't he just like
her? What does it have to do with quitting?
That's... a... little...
Did he get kicked out by his family?
Seung Joo!
Oh! What about Eun Sung?
You should've just left. What's up?
No, I was just passing
by and thought of her.
They're fish shaped bean pastries.
Give them to Eun Sung.
Thanks.
Executive Director quit because
he was caught, didn't he?
-Quit?-You didn't know?
He said he's quitting the restaurant.
They said he turned in his
resignation at headquarters.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Ah, what would happen?
You didn't even go through with the surgery. I
think he just resigned because they found out.
My big mouth.
But that guy seems like a decent person.
He must really like you.
I hope things work out.
I came to congratulate you and
wish the two of you well.
Receive all the love you
weren't able to from Hyung.
Thanks.
No need for thanks. I'll be going then.
Take care going!
How are the rumors?
Do you think they're dying down?
For now, it's being stated to the
board of directors that you objected
to their relationship and
that he said it out of anger.
Well done.
The media's quiet? There's
no one trying to contact us?
-Actually,...-What?
Is something going on?
There's someone called this Reporter Hong Jin Seok, whose been in contact with the public
relations office saying that he's trying to understand the progression of our company.
What? Who is that?
But, it's a reporter who has been friends
for quite a while with Han Jung Hoon.
That punk.
Contact that reporter immediately. I'll
meet him directly and take care of it.
Yes, sir.
-Father, you're home?-Come here!
What? What is it, Father?
I said to come here!
Father, I left something upstairs.
You've decided you want to die, didn't you?
What did I say to you?
Did I tell you that if this leaked out,
that I wouldn't leave you alone or not?
What did I do, Father?
Are you asking as if you don't know?
- You're going to fight me until the end?
Is that it?-Honey!
You stay out of this.
What do you have to say after
raising someone like this?
Pack up tomorrow and move to the US office.
I left orders before coming home.
- The American office? - Yeah!
If I leave you alone like this, there's
no mistake you'd ruin the company!
Go and live quietly, holding your breath.
If you cause trouble there as well,
that day will be the end of our
parent-child relationship.
Just know you won't receive
a cent of the inheritance.
It's so unfair, Father!
-Unfair?-Yes, it's unfair!
What do you find so unfair?
Punk.
Mom. Mom, it's really unfair. Seriously.
I really don't want to live, Mom!
It's so unfair I'm going to go crazy, Mom!
Please leave. I want to be alone.
Didn't you hear me say that
I want to be left alone?
Yes. Stay alone.
I'll let you stay alone forever.
If Jung Hoon goes, I am
going to follow him.
Stay here alone and live well.
Live for a long, long time.
This woman. Are you saying this
knowing what's going on at work?
That work has nothing to do with me.
Always your work. I've put up hearing
about that work my whole life.
Do you think it's because I'm stupid?
But still, I thought there
might be something at the end.
Since you're getting old,
when you got old, I thought you'd change.
I lived hoping for that one thing.
But, that was all my misunderstanding.
I regret so much having married you.
Do you know whose fault it is that
Jung Hoon turned out that way?
It's because he's never once seen
you and me cherishing each other.
So what if he's incompetent?
Can't you still comfort him?
Isn't that what family is?
Why else do you think I would do all this?
Never mind. It's the same story I've always
heard. I don't want to hear it any longer.
Everyone else is envious
that I'm a chairman's wife.
But who would know that my
life is most like dung?
Live well.
I'm leaving.
After you die,
I'll return then.
Pp
You should get one!
-Mother-in-law!-Oh, welcome.
A customer just left.
Why are you here again?
Did you eat lunch?
Huh? Lunch? No.
I'll buy you something delicious.
Ay! Okay, okay. Let's just eat.
Ow, ow, my legs! Ow, ow!
Try some.
Try some of the vegetables.
It's been a really long time since
we've eaten together, isn't it?
Now that I'm full, I feel like I can live.
I was aching so much today.
It's difficult, isn't it?
It's okay.
Everyone has to survive somehow.
But, your face keeps looking
more and more gaunt.
Why do you keep losing weight?
Actually,
-I have something to tell you.-What is it?
You see,
I...
am a little sick.
Yeah, that's what I said!
I was right, wasn't I?
So what did they say was wrong?
Is it a genetic disease?
No.
If it happens
that I leave suddenly,
I wanted to tell you ahead of time.
What are you saying?
They say that I can't live very long.
If I end up leaving,
please take care of my Eun Sung.
But asking you that favor
brings me the most peace.
Aren't I so shameless?
Right, Mother-in-law?
I heard all about it. How did this happen?
Who did you hear it from?
Your father. He came to see me.
As even more time passes
by, I'm in complete awe.
I can't believe you, nor that child.
Because I didn't want to believe it to be true. I didn't even
contact you and was completely out of it the entire day.
Is it all true? Is she really that sick?
I'm sorry, mom. You haven't even
recovered yet, [and] this is difficult.
So... you're going to stay with her?
Yeah.
Mom, I need some
encouragement from you now.
I even want to be comforted by a kitten.
That's how I feel.
So don't say obvious things that
I can't be helped or something.
Do you like her that much?
Couldn't you tell? You knew it all already.
How much time does she have left?
Why would you say that? You lived too!
You were dying, but you're survived.
She's going to live too! I'm going
to live with her for a long time.
I'm going to live with her
and die a day earlier.
I'm sorry, Ji Hoon.
I understand how you're feeling,
but I can't lose to you.
When a son says that he'd hold on to the
bristle-grass and jump into a fiery pit.
What kind of mother would like that?
Do you know what a difficult
and scary family that will be?
Have you really thought about it?
I feel sorry for that child [Hye Soo].
I know she's a good person, too.
But Ji Hoon...
Don't worry, Mom. It's not a fire pit.
I'm doing it because I want to.
Oh, Hye Soo.
Should have dinner together tonight?
I've been indebted to my friend,
so I wanted to treat her.
Let's cook and eat together
at my friend's house.
You're inviting me right now?
It's true. I am inviting you.
What do you want to eat? You
like kimchi stew and japchae.
And you don't like broccoli. I know
something about your food preference.
I studied a lot.
OK. I'll be there a little later.
Who are you talking to to be so beaming?
Uncle, I was coming to see you actually.
There's rumor your dad's
still without some sense.
I don't know what it is but your
family is so rich but hollow too.
Geez, even if I only get to eat vegetables and
drink water, living without stress is the best.
Goodbye.
Rest up.
Madame and Executive just left the country.
Chairman Seo.
Weather's nice too, should we go play golf?
Yes, if it works for Na Yoon too, the time.
Oh, I'll call you back.
Oh, Na Yoon. I was going to call
you anyway. It's good you came.
I had something to say to you.
Sit down. I have something
to say to you, too.
About Ji Hoon. Soon, he's going to
come back to the way things were.
I sent him away and told him to stay with
bated breath until the noises calm down.
And that woman [Hye Soo], you don't
ever need to worry about her.
Now all that's left is stuff that
will settle on its own soon.
Chairman. From now on, don't
associate me with Ji Hoon.
Whether it's Ji Hoon or that woman, I'm
not going to be concerned about them.
I don't want to ruin my life any
longer by hanging on so pointlessly.
I'm not that innocent or romantic.
I think I should end here so that I can
still have some redeemable memories.
♪ Chubby and charming body. ♪
♪ Putting on red clothes. ♪
♪ Spreading out my sweet
and sour fragrance. ♪
♪ Charming tomato ♪
♪ I will be juice. Gulp. ♪
♪ I will be ketchup. Squirt. I will dance.
Show off. Tomato. ♪
Chubby
Mom. - Hmm? Can I eat this?
Of course! You can eat any of it.
Are we having some party today?
Yea, a party.
What party?
With Ahjussi and Auntie, the four of us, let's have a party.
Mom's going to display my cooking skills first time in a while.
I'm thankful to ahjusshi; I'm thankful to aunt
[Joo Yeon]. I'm thankful to my Eun Sung too.
Mom wants to treat you guys.
Thankful to me for what?
Thankful because Eun Sung is Eun Sung.
Nah.
Mom, are you okay?
Yea, I'm alright.
Mom! Mom!
Eun Sung, don't come closer! Don't come!
Stay there. Stay right there!
Eun Sung, leave. Leave for a little bit.
Eun Sung, I'm sorry. Mom's sorry. Sorry.
- Smells good. - Eun Sung, sorry.
Oh, oh, Eun Sung. It's okay, it's okay.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Hye Soo.
I'm okay. Take Eun Sung out.
Take Eun Sung out of here.
Oh, ok…oh, Eun Sung, aigoo. Do you want to go out
with aunt for a little bit? Aigoo, it's okay.
It's okay. It's okay. What a
good girl you are, Eun Sung.
Mom is acting weird.
It's okay. Mom was a
little dizzy, that's why.
Why is she dizzy?
Motion sickness. Eun Sung knows
what motion sickness means, right?
I think your mom rode in the car for
a long time earlier today. Right?
Eun Sung, can you stay by
yourself for just a moment?
I'm going to go help Mom
and come right back.
No, I want to go with you.
It will really, really be just a moment.
Eun Sung, do you want to
play nail polish with me?
What color are you going
to choose for me today?
Hello.
Eun Sung, what's wrong? Hmm?
Would you go inside for me?
I think Hye Soo needs some help.
- Daddy.-Yeah, Eun Sung.
Don't cry, don't cry.
Eun Sung, should we go see the kitties?
Hye Soo.
Stay right there. And don't move.
♪ The words are harder to say than I feel ♪
♪ My heart doesn't smile like it used to ♪
♪ In these tears that are drying up ♪
♪ you are getting far away from me ♪
♪ If there is no use holding onto you ♪
What a mess. Were you that
happy your husband was coming?
♪ Please don't turn around and ask me ♪
I know, right?♪ Please don't
turn around and ask me ♪
♪ If you get tired, if things get
hard and that's how we drift apart ♪
I'll clean everything up.♪ If you get tired, if
things get hard and that's how we drift apart ♪
♪ I will let you go, but until
then please wait for me ♪
I wanted to watch you enjoy eating it all.
I'll eat it all.
I'll eat it all so don't worry.
You should have come a little later.
Just a little later.
Should I go back out then?
♪ If there is no use holding onto you ♪
♪ I will just follow you ♪
♪ Please don't turn around and ask me ♪
♪ If you get tired, if things get
hard and that's how we drift apart ♪
♪ I will let you go, but until
then please wait for me ♪
Oh, Joo Yeon!
Hello.
Our Eun Sung came, too!
Eun Sung, do you want to
go up and see the kitties?
Okay. Come right back.
It's been a long time after Hye Soo quit.
You're still beautiful as always.
Did you eat?
Not yet.
Not having eaten until this
hour, how hungry must you be?
Then, please give me something good to eat.
Eun Sung is probably hungry, too.
Eun Sung! Come down quickly
after seeing the kittens!
Ahjusshi said he's going to
buy us some delicious steak!
Steak?
Oh, sounds good! Steak!
I like it medium well done. So
that no blood is showing, okay?
Okay! You're just like me.
I don't like blood either.
Jet Black, Chubbie, and Cutie.
We'll be back after eating dinner.
Have a hot night!
I guess Eun Sung will be
back after eating dinner.
I saw.
It feels like it's going
to get hot already.
You're too much. Seriously.
Should I try some of this?
How is it?
Hey, mmmm.
You're not a chef for nothing.
-Really?-Yeah. Really.
Thanks.
No need for thanks.
I have something to say.
I said that I have something to say.
When I'm gone,
will you promise me that you'll
return to your rightful spot?
I'll work hard at being
your wife until then.
Kang Hye Soo,
Ah, and also about Eun Sung,
will you see her often and
be her daddy long legs?
Actually, that's what I'm most sorry about.
I would like you to be her daddy long legs.
Are you joking with me right now?
Who says you can leave? What are you leaving?
Why do you keep looking that direction?
Cancel everything you just said.
Cancel it!
I understand. I'll cancel it.
Cancel, cancel it.
I'm sorry but I'll go and rest.
I'm getting dizzy.
I'll get some sleep.
Finish eating before you go.
Okay, I will.
Continue to act so foolishly then.
Whether you leave or not,
do whatever you want.
I'm just eating it because
it will go to waste.
It tastes good.
Mother-in-law
Yes
Listen carefully to what I have to say.
You're not thinking that
you're dying, are you?
Unbelievable.
What you said earlier, I'm going
to pretend I didn't hear it.
After sending away my son like that,
I can't send my daughter-in-law
like that, too.
Make a firm resolution to live, okay?
You have to live.
Think of Eun Sung, and live
with every fiber in you.
Understand?!
Yes, Mother-in-law.
I'll live.
I will make sure to live.
Ji Hoon!
Why are you sitting there like that?
Hey, Ho Joon. Let me ask
you to do me a favor.
I'm going to propose. I
need you to help me.
Gosh! Propose? To whom? To Kang Hye Soo?
Who else would it be? Didn't
you know how to play guitar?
No, I can't play the guitar.
"A Love that can't be
Forgotten" Just maybe one song.
I'll do my best! I'll do my best.
A sofa is being delivered to
the house we're moving to.
Come and decide if you like it.
See you at 5:00.
Where are you going? On a date? A date?
No. He wanted me to look at some furniture.
Kang Hye Soo. Start enjoying yourself?
What's the big deal?
You can start taking now. There's
no reason not to, right?
Thanks. I'll be right back.
Take care! On your date!
Hye Soo, marry me
♪ Today lo...
Are you in your right mind?
Why? You don't like it?
How far are you?
I'm on my way.
Eun Sung, you hold the
flower bouquet there.
And Ji Hoon ahjusshi
will come out this way.
And then you run out
with the flower bouquet,
and give it to ahjusshi. Now kneel.
Then Ji Hoon ahjusshi will, cue!
What are you doing? Tell
her that you love her!
Cue!
Oh, I don't know.
Who's the one who wanted to do this?!
Ah, I can't do this.
Hey, you're the one who said to do this!
Geesh! Okay, then the proposal song.
Sing it.
Hey, sing it! Sing. Start.
It's so corny. I don't think we need to go
this far. Do we have to do it like this?
This is normal. Everyone does
it like this these days!
Never mind. Forget it. It's too childish.
Hey, now. Where did the one who
was making all that fuss go?
I wasn't the one singing from the start.
Daddy, then should I sing a song?
Yeah, let's have Eun Sung sing.
Oh, really? Then, rock it!! Now.
♪ Three bears were living in a house.
Daddy bear, Mommy bear,
♪ Baby bear.
♪ Daddy bear was big and fat.
♪ Mommy bear was slender.
Baby bear was so cute!
♪ They are all doing well.
Eun Sung, who taught you how to sing?
My mommy did.
♪ Three bears were living in a house.
♪ Daddy bear, Mommy bear, Baby bear.
♪ They're doing well.
♪ Three bears were living in a house.
♪ Daddy bear, Mommy bear, Baby bear.
♪ Daddy bear is big and fat...