Audrey!
Your diploma.
You worked very hard for that.
Very proud of you.
(TELEVISION PLAYING)
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Okay.
Let's go.
My perfect boyfriend
would have to be really sweet.
And cute.
He's got to look like...
Like Jesus, or Bob Marley.
And he has principles.
Like he would never listen to
that crappy K-dude rock...
-And he'd smell like
Jolly Ranchers.
-Jolly Ranchers?
Apple Jolly Ranchers.
(LAUGHS)
Hey, call me Calista.
Calista.
Come again?
I don't want to be Cindy
anymore.
Call me Calista. I'm changing
my name to Calista.
Calista.
Yeah. Isn't it sexy?
Calista Bliss...
It kind of sounds like
a porn star name.
Awesome.
I know.
(GIGGLES)
Licking morning visions that
feel like crushed velvet...
Desiring a shadow drink
with a peach aroma and
purple mist.
A delicious moment
for worshiping
calm language...
And being ice.
That's fantastic.
It's about my dad.
How is he?
Bad.
He feels really bad about
missing graduation, but,
it's all right. I didn't
expect him to make it.
I didn't expect him to be able
to handle that.
(DOG BARKING)
When I woke up this morning,
my right arm felt all numb.
Like it felt fuzzy
and I was...
Wigging out and sobbing and,
I thought it was it.
But I'm fine.
Calista...
Because I just slept on it
funny.
It's just...
It was really scary.
I just get...
I just get so scared
because one of these days...
You know, it's not,
I'm not just going to sleep
on it wrong.
You know, I'm just going
to succumb...
That's how it is.
(SOBBING)
Please always be there for me.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey.
Hi, Dad.
(LAUGHS)
Dad!
It's lopsided and belated...
But I thought it was
an occasion that deserved
a cake.
Well, it's awesome.
We'll have some when
I get home, okay.
Okay. Cool.
(TELEVISION PLAYING)
Goodnight.
Thank you, baby.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Can we please change
this music?
It's annoying me.
No. It's my turn to pick.
Come on,
find some groove tunes
so we could break it down!
Stop. I won't break it down.
You need me to give you
a ride home tonight?
(SOFT MOANING)
(MOANING)
You don't smoke.
Who?
Calista.
Cindy. She's Calista now.
Anyway, her doctor says that
she can't smoke. So,
she asked me to start and
see what it's like.
That's messed up.
The guru is having another
drum circle on Saturday.
I can't go.
The guru?
Why not?
A bunch of white guys
with dreadlocks and bongos?
You are very close-minded.
You know that?
-What are you afraid of?
-I'm not afraid of anything.
I just don't want to go.
Who?
Cindy can come.
Calista. She can come.
I just don't want to go.
You could give me a ride home
tomorrow if you want, though.
I just don't want to.
Okay.
I'm kidding.
Bye, Abraham.
I want to give you a ride home
tomorrow.
Really bad.
Audrey!
You get a lot of mail, girl.
Thanks, Dreamer.
Good night.
(TELEVISION PLAYING)
Kiss your mom for me, baby.
(SIGHS)
We love you, Mom.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hi there.
(LAUGHS)
Ooh, cake!
So, darling, what did you do
tonight?
Your dad came over to smoke
a joint with my aunt...
So I laid down and I listened
to them talk about movies.
How about you? Abraham?
Yeah.
Was it nice?
It was all right.
We're just friends
experimenting with sex.
And is that healthy?
Yeah.
And I wrote in to that
sex columnist
in the free paper.
And she says that it's fine,
as long as it's
mutually enjoyable.
And we're both open
with each other.
And it'll probably help us out
in our future sex lives.
I mean, I really care
about him. You know.
We're just not going steady
or anything.
Yeah, but, does he know that?
He's a total beatnik.
He's all into that free love,
blah, blah, blah.
(GIGGLES)
Free love.
This is good.
(LIGHTS OFF)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Audrey!
(BOY SHOUTING)
I saw him first.
I did. Your back was turned.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
What are you doing to my toes?
What's going on?
We have new neighbours.
One of them is a hottie.
Just put it anywhere
right now.
Hot, but it's a dry heat.
That's for sure.
Oh, thanks.
Henry Sinclair.
Herb Myerson.
You picked a real fine place
to settle down. Dreamland.
Dreamland. Wow. Cheers.
Calista over there thinks
you're a hottie.
Thanks.
(LAUGHS)
-So, what line of work
you're in?
-Underwater welding.
Is that so?
Yeah, I used to work
the oil fields in Texas.
Hello.
-Hey.
-This is my, my sweetheart,
Mary.
Henry.
Then my wife passed...
And Audrey, that's my baby
Audrey up on the porch.
We've been pacing out here
in the desert ever since.
That's a heart breaker
about your wife. I'm sorry.
Yeah. If Lissa were around,
you'd probably have a fresh
batch of brownies
on your porch
tomorrow morning.
Put some M&Ms in there
or something.
(LAUGHS)
Hope you can settle for
a couple of beers.
Yeah. Beer. Cheers.
(GIGGLES)
Pass it to me. I'm open.
Hey.
I don't want to wake anybody
up.
So, imaginary ball, you know.
That's sweet.
Hey, Dreamer, find anything
tonight?
Not yet. I'll let you know.
All right.
Aliens, that's what
he's looking for.
Does he ever find any?
Sometimes.
Have you ever seen
that episode
of Jerry Springer where...
That woman goes into labour
on air?
I... I think so.
Well, she used to live here.
Isn't that funny?
Well, it's not really funny.
It's actually kind of sad.
Or at least it's sad for
the baby because it,
it's doomed, right?
And it's kind of sad for us
because it kind of...
Reinforces that whole
trailer park trash
stereotype thing.
I'm sorry, I'm babbling.
I knew a guy who was
on "Cops" once.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah. I played little
league baseball
with a guy who got pulled over
in a stolen car on "Cops."
Wait. Was he wearing a shirt?
Was he wearing a shirt when
he got pulled over?
Oh, I...
I don't think he was.
Because he had stuffed
his weed down his shorts,
so you could see
the little baggy sticking out.
That's incredible.
The criminals are always
topless on that show.
That's perfect.
Yeah, they are.
His name is Mookie.
Mookie?
He's from Las Vegas.
He's apparently really good
at basketball.
Graduated last year and
he was going to play for UNLV.
That's nice.
Yeah, but, he blew out
his knee and lost his spot,
so he's been rehabbing
all year.
Now they have an opening.
So he's gonna go back and
train with them at the end
of the summer,
and see if it's healed up.
What else did you find out
about him?
Does he have a girlfriend?
I don't know.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey. What's up?
That's him.
He's dreamy.
Maybe he'll let you wear
his lettermen jacket.
You could take his picture,
put it up in your locker
and then all the girls
on the A-list will invite you
to their slumber parties.
I'm already on the A-list.
That's an excellent choice,
but cherry's better.
I think cherry is better
than lemon,
that's just my opinion.
Thanks.
Sorry, I was running.
I mean, that's why, this is
kind of wet.
That'll happen. Yeah.
That's cool.
Okay. Bye.
I'll see you later.
That's cool.
Shut up!
Have you picked your classes
yet?
Pretty much.
I'm going to do Tuesdays and
Thursdays,
Religions of Asia...
Hey, are you going to pledge
a fraternity?
Mondays, Wednesdays and
Fridays I have Britt...
Come on.
It's going to be so cool.
Could do keg stands and
date-rape sorority chicks.
You jealous?
It'd be so awesome, dude.
You're jealous.
I am not jealous.
Because you're going to still
be right there, you'll be
drooling on that counter.
And I'm going to be
at UNM
with worldly grad students
holding peyote rituals.
Or watching Star Trek.
Do you ever think about going
back to school?
Don't you have to read and
stuff in school?
Seriously.
I mean you're smart
and talented. Why not?
I guess I figure after I win
Miss America...
and get all
that scholarship money, so,
I guess I'll just go then.
I was just thinking.
You know what the most watched
television show in Venezuela
is?
No. What?
The Miss Venezuela Pageant.
I wish I lived in Venezuela.
Because I'd be Miss Venezuela.
And then everyone in
the country would know who
I was.
You'd get to star on one
of those Spanish soap operas.
I'd date, like,
a Brazilian soccer star.
And we'd be in the tabloids
every day.
And he'd have an aunt
who is a bruja.
And we'd visit her in
the rain forest and she'd give
me this
crazy herbal remedy to make me
all better.
I watch her play with fire,
and hold my breath...
As the fluttering sparks dance
on her skin...
like 1,000 baby fireflies...
Born one electric minute ...
And gone by summer's end.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Yeah.
She is. She looks like a,
like a Dallas Cowboy
cheerleader.
But not really.
She really likes you,
you know?
You guys should go on a date
or something.
What's she doing?
She read about this in
a music magazine.
Some kind of
experimental treatment for MS.
What?
Yeah, Calista got diagnosed
with multiple sclerosis
a couple years ago.
That's why she came here,
to relax her nerves.
And her aunt could hook her up
with some health insurance.
(BEES BUZZING)
What is she doing?
The bee venom helps her MS.
What do you like on your
pizza?
Anchovies.
Yeah.
Really?
I like sardines too,
but not on pizza,
just with a little mustard.
Me too. I like anchovies.
That means we're soul mates.
(LAUGHS)
I figure I do have
a realistic shot of winning
it all.
Because,
even if I'm not like
the hottest or the most
poised contestant,
when it comes time to ask me
the question,
I'll find a way to just talk
about
the health care situation
in the United States.
And then I'll relate it to
my disease.
So, the intelligent judges
will appreciate
that I have these
well-formulated personal ideas
on actual issues.
Then the dumb judges will vote
for me because
I'm the sick girl.
And, that's how it works.
Does it hurt?
Sometimes.
I mean, not all the time.
Not very often, but...
Yeah. Sometimes.
Don't forget about tomorrow,
okay?
Until tomorrow.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Have you guys ever had one
of those moments that are just
so cool
you think you don't
deserve it?
And God must be gracing you
with it because you must
be doomed,
but you just really
don't care?
Not in a long time.
I just had one on the back
of Mookie's motor-scooter.
He's wonderful, and gentle,
and honest...
and weird and all that stuff,
and I...
And I really like him.
I even pretended that
I liked anchovies.
Hairy.
Do you guys think it's
possible to fall in love after
one date?
Yes. I do. March...
March 28th, 1982.
Austin, Texas.
I picked up the
lovely Lissa Stevens in...
In his mom's
'68 green Mustang.
Not green. Sea foam Mustang.
She loved that car.
It was a great car.
Took her to see a, 8:00 p.m
showing of
Breakfast at Tiffany's
at the Paramount.
I waited until
old Holly Golightly
went looking for her cat
in the rain...
Before I reached over and
grabbed her hand.
That's got to be the sweetest
goddamn movie they ever made.
After we left the theatre,
it was raining cats and dogs.
-Lissa was jumping through
puddles...
-She was a puddle-dancer.
We sat in the car and let our
clothes dry.
I forgot my bowl, so we smoked
weed out of an old beer can
she found on the backseat.
It was perfect.
Just chilly and perfect.
We took that old long cut home
and listened to some tapes...
And I walked her right up into
her dorm room.
We almost kissed.
Remember this, girls,
the only thing better
than kissing on a first date
is almost kissing on
a first date.
Their courtship lasted
42 kisses.
And then they eloped.
Number 43 was in a makeshift
wedding chapel down
in Roswell.
I can still taste
that kiss.
Number 43.
To this very day.
All right, guys...
Don't stay up too late.
We've got a barbecue to go to
tomorrow.
Good night.
What do you want?
Meat or tofu?
How in the hell do you kill
a tofu?
You got me.
Medium-well, por favor.
I hear you want to be
Miss America, is that right?
-I pray for it every night.
Like I really pray.
-That's cool.
God, I'm almost 40 and
I still don't know what I want
to be when I grow up.
How about a travel agent?
No.
No?
A princess?
I don't think so.
A princess spy?
That's kind of interesting.
See, I used to want to be that
and then I decide I should
give it up
'cause I want to be
Miss America more.
Although princess spy,
kind with secret cameras
under the tiara, kind of hot.
So, what can you tell me about
my new hometown?
Well, unfortunately,
I don't get out much.
Ever, really. I get these...
Attacks when I try to leave.
I couldn't even attend
Audrey's graduation ceremony.
That's a shame.
So Herb's really, uh, likes
to do dad things, huh?
Yeah, he does.
But he's not my dad though,
he's my mom's boyfriend.
No, it's cool.
I mean it's for real.
They just haven't gotten
around to getting married.
I love him. He's a cool guy.
He's got this neat office,
it... It smells like Pez.
Oh, that's neat.
Shut up.
Cool I mean. Nice office.
His cool place...
Blue eye make-up...
A red bed...
An urge to fall into
the picture void...
Where it's always lazy
and summer...
Drunk on sugary juice...
I'll drive away on this
delicate trip ...
Like a woman .
I like it.
Thanks.
Cool place, that's Mookie's,
huh?
Yep.
The narrator isn't Calista,
is it?
No.
Yeah, I thought so.
(SIGHS)
They're having sex right now,
aren't they?
And it's a beautiful thing,
isn't it?
Come on.
Where are we going?
The fence.
The what?
The electric fence.
What's that?
I'll show you.
-People come out here
to be healed.
-What do you mean?
People with all sorts
of ailments come out here.
You know,
like arthritis and stuff.
And they grab onto the fence
for as long as possible
because the currents
will heal them.
I've never been here alone.
I mean, without Audrey.
Does it work?
Of course.
(SIGHS)
(BUZZ)
June-July issue of our
magazine.
I got a story in here.
About these kids that invented
this shrinking formula...
And then they form this
utopian society inside
Jerry Garcia's beard.
Pretty cool.
What are you doing?
My dad's famous hang-over
cure.
Is it good?
(VOMITS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey, do I have any puke
on my shirt?
No.
You don't have any puke
on your shirt.
Yeah, good,
because...
That would kind of suck.
Listen, can I ask your advice?
Calista showed me something
this morning...
I kind of want to do
something special for her.
Do you think you can help me
think of something
really special?
-Yeah. I'll think of
something.
-Cool. Thank you.
She really likes
barbeque sauce on her
French fries.
And don't forget
the berry blast,
that's her favourite dessert.
That's sweet.
She's gonna love that.
Thank you. You, you're sweet.
Yeah. Whatever.
You must have guys just
knocking down your door.
None, actually.
Really?
Seriously?
I have a boy toy.
What? You have a boy toy?
Yeah.
That dude?
Actually, that dude.
No, he's a sweetheart.
He just tends to be
a little bitch sometimes.
Listen, I was talking
to Calista the other day,
and she was telling me all
the stuff you do for her.
How she'd lie in bed all day
if it weren't for you.
And I just think
that's pretty amazing what
you do for her.
Yeah, well, she's my
best friend.
Yeah.
What's going to happen
when you go away?
I'm not going anywhere.
No, I mean when you go
to college or whatever.
I'm not going anywhere.
Calista says
you're like a genius,
so I just thought...
Well, I'm not a genius and
I don't need a degree
or anything.
I want to be a writer.
Emily Dickinson is one
of the greatest poets ever
and she never went to college.
She never left her room.
Okay.
Sorry.
Perched on the edge of nothing
and beyond...
I water the dream garden...
But wither in the bone
dry soil...
Invisible, I invent
a fairy tale...
And mend her angel wings...
Weaving until my fingers ache,
so she can fly...
Hamburger, no cheese,
extra ketchup. Okay?
Got an egg roll...
From the Chinese place next
to Wal-Mart,
for an appetizer...
McDonald's fries, and...
Drum roll... Berry blast.
Oh, my God, this is...
Hello!
Oh, and barbecue sauce.
They charged me 35 cents
extra,
but I said it doesn't matter.
(SIGHS)
How's it going?
I don't feel so great.
Oh, you mean their date?
That's one of the goddamned
most romantic things I've seen
in a long while.
Was that the wrong answer?
No.
That's the right answer.
I hope it's ready
in two weeks.
How about you?
How, how you been feeling?
I'm good.
I mean, I have bad days.
But I have more good days
than bad days for now.
I think you're brave.
I think you feel sorry for me.
No... I... I'm just...
It's just kind of scary,
you know.
It's like this story
I once read about this guy
who was playing a pick-up game
with Larry Bird...
And Larry Bird jammed
his finger.
And he asked the guy
to pull it out.
The guy was just afraid
to do it, you know,
'cause he like...
What if he messed up and...
Did more damage to one of
the best fingers to ever touch
a basketball.
So I guess I just don't know
how I'd react if...
You ask me to pull your finger
out for you.
Does that make any sense?
Yes.
(SNORING)
(MUSIC PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
(MARY SINGING)
That was great.
You are so good!
-Hey.
-Hey, I didn't know
you smoked.
Oh, I don't.
I mean, I smoke one or...
I don't know, six a day.
You have a really cool voice.
Oh, thanks. I mean
I don't know about that,
but...
Seriously. That last song you
were just singing...
I haven't heard
anything like that,
even on the radio.
Have you ever been in a band
or anything?
Or anything.
She's done it all, Audrey.
She played bass
in a real romper stomper
safety pin
and beer punk band.
And then after that...
After that,
she had a couple of
really big hits in Finland...
with a band called Horse.
You ever hear of them?
I don't know.
Yeah, he gets silly.
And then she broke about
a million hearts
with her folks songs and
her guitar.
You're sounding cheesy, dear.
Yeah. A million hearts.
A million and one.
Don't listen to him.
It's all true.
She was awesome.
She was like Joan Jet.
Well, how come she doesn't,
like, play out anymore?
Stage fright.
She could only play
if she got really loaded,
so, she says she'll only play
for me and Herb from now on.
That's kind of sad.
Yeah, it is, you know?
It's sort of like a girl
who writes really cool poems,
but won't even put it in
her friend's little magazine.
Getting a little scruffy?
I'm trying to grow a goatee.
It's nice.
Yeah, I don't think
Calista's too crazy about it.
Yeah?
I think it's nice.
Too bad I don't have
connection yet.
But, I don't really care,
because...
What about this?
Let's see.
Can I read some of your poems
sometime?
I don't know.
I, don't really like
to let people read them until
they're ready.
I don't get it.
How do you know they're
really ready unless
you let people read them?
I just know.
You should get this
for Calista.
She'll look hot in it.
Hey, by the way...
Emily Dickinson
went to Mount Holyoke College
one year.
Don't know if you knew that.
Yo, Audrey, mail call.
Dreamer, what am I going
to do?
Don't ask me.
I'm just the messenger.
Okay, baby.
Thanks.
Dad?
-I ran out of cigarettes.
-Okay. It's okay.
Just breathe.
It's okay.
I just thought I could get
some cigarettes from
the store.
Here, take these.
I'm taking you to a doctor.
There has to be a pill
you can take.
No doctors, baby.
-I've seen it on commercials.
-Just help me get my head
above water.
All right?
Of course.
Will you get me a wet rag?
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Oh, thank you.
Can you get me another,
please.
Thank you, baby.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey, Audrey.
Want something to drink?
Yeah. Water.
What's wrong?
Dad. I'm so tired of always
worrying about him.
For what?
I'm sorry.
For making you worry about me
all the time, too.
Calista, I love you and
I'm always gonna be there
for you.
I love you too.
So you're coming with me
to the hospital tomorrow then,
right?
Of course.
What are you guys talking
about?
Are you sure?
I got to get back to work.
It's Mookie's last chance
to test out the knee
before Vegas.
-I didn't realize it was
so soon.
-Two days.
Don't go.
What are you talking about?
You know I have to go.
I know. Then you're just gonna
have to spend every moment
with me until then.
All right. Let's go.
Don't worry about it. Bye.
Audrey?
I need a ride home.
Hey, Audrey...
You know there's fungus
among us.
What?
There's fungus...
Among us.
No. No.
Yes. Yes.
Audrey
Abraham.
I know what's going to happen.
I'm going to end up lying face
down on this bed...
Thinking sentence fragments
and drooling...
Just like last time.
It's all right.
This time it'll be smurfy.
Audrey, it's a pattern.
It's all a pattern.
All pattern, layer.
We're all connected.
That's all, but we are
connected...
But we're this pattern moving
through space.
We are time moving
through time,
that's all we are.
It's a pattern,
it's just a pattern.
It's like a coil on top
of itself...
Like a slinky.
And that's all we are.
We are this pattern moving
through space.
We are time moving
What time is it?
There is no time.
That's what I'm saying.
You know, you and I,
we are time, that's it.
Calista...
Calista is time. Everything
you know, that's time.
Plants are time, rocks
are time, animals are time.
Everyone you know is time.
You forgot.
I know. I screwed up.
She was really scared.
She had killer spasms today.
And when she found out
you weren't around,
she just kind of freaked.
And it got worse.
I didn't mean to.
I just got lost.
Mookie's leaving.
He's too good for Dreamland.
He's going to go somewhere
far, far away.
I just, I feel it
all unraveling, you know?
I know how it feels.
I don't.
You and Calista have always
been the unravelers.
I'm a raveler, you know?
You have raveled.
I just don't wanna face her.
I don't want to deal with
her all...
Unraveled?
Yeah.
What do I do?
Baby, you're asking advice
from a guy
who hasn't been out
of a trailer park
in two years.
I'm no good at raveling.
Will you miss me?
Of course I will miss you.
How much?
This much.
No, you won't.
-You're going to forget all
about me.
-What are you talking about?
One week away
from Dreamland...
You're just gonna
hook-up with some
basketball groupie
and forget all about
your sickly girlfriend.
I won't forget about you.
I'm sorry.
Don't sweat it.
Well, you know.
How'd it go?
I still tune out all that
medical mumble-jumbo...
So I guess I don't really know
for sure...
But, he had a nice smile.
Not too comforting
or anything, so,
I guess that's good, right?
I was selfish, I'm sorry.
I said don't sweat it, okay?
Thank you, Mookie
for stepping in.
Come on, Mookie, we only have
one more night.
Hey.
I like this spot.
How did you find it?
It's a really nice spot.
Have you been spying on me?
Maybe. Metaphysically, maybe.
I guess it's kind
of impossible to keep secrets
in Dreamland, huh?
You'd be surprised.
It is nice though, isn't it?
Isn't it cool?
Herb helped me build it.
Herb's awesome.
Yeah, he is.
He's gonna be my official Dad.
How about that?
He and Mom are getting married
tomorrow night.
Well, tonight, I guess,
when we get to Vegas.
For real?
They're going all out too.
We're staying at some place
called the American Motel.
Because I guess that's where
Mom was when she wrote
Herb's favourite song.
It's crazy, you know,
everything's kind of happening
all at once.
Sort of coming together.
What are you doing out here?
I, um, I like to take walks
when I can't sleep.
Just kind of found this place.
Why can't you sleep?
I'm, um, unraveling.
You come out here to write?
It's desire...
Graced by his subtle touch,
this...
It sucks!
What are you talking about?
That was great!
I wanna see what happens next.
No. It's, it's just a couple
more lines
about some misunderstood
sad girl and then it ends.
Okay.
Good, then let me read it.
I wanna read everything
you write.
Shit. I don't know where I am.
Audrey?
What are you doing here?
Nothing.
This is where
and I come sometimes.
He's gone.
I know.
Was he here?
Yeah.
What's going on?
I'm in love with him.
Is he in love with you?
Does he love you?
(SIGHS)
I don't know, but...
I hope he does.
Oh, Calista, listen to me,
okay, just...
I don't know anything
about anything, okay?
I just...
Well, I've, I've listened
to my Dad tell stories
about my Mom and...
And I've read books.
I just...
I really believe in love.
-Audrey.
-And no matter how
fleeting or tragic,
I just... I really,
really believe in it.
And I'm 18 years old
and I just want to surrender.
Well, you know what,
fuck your teen angst,
because I'm dying.
(SIGHS)
Happy birthday, Lissa.
Happy birthday, Mom.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Calista's gone.
I think she took my bike.
Going to Las Vegas!
You should have told me, man.
I would've got some more
weed and set up.
It's not that kind of trip.
It's serious.
Things have gotten
really serious.
What does that mean?
That means that
when we get back,
I think that you should stop
giving me rides home.
What?
Look, we always said that
we would quit it
if we found somebody
we really cared about.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Get out of the car.
Abraham...
Things are just really
messed up right now.
And I really need somebody
to help me get through this.
(SCOFFS)
Me?
Well, my mom's dead...
My Dad's drunk and
my best friend is forsaken.
Get out of the car.
Abraham...
Get out of the car!
I'm sorry.
Just get out!
I'm sorry!
(MOTORCYCLE ENGINE ROARING)
(HORN HONKING)
(HORN BLARING)
Can you take me to Vegas?
Audrey?
I'm sorry. I would have
called. I just fell asleep
and I didn't have change.
Not that you could find
a pay phone around here
or anything.
Well, what are you doing here?
That's your wedding ring.
Yeah.
That's so great.
Um, congratulations.
This is your wedding night
I'm interrupting.
I'm so sorry.
I'm looking for Mookie.
He went back.
He went back where?
To be with Calista.
(SIGHS)
You don't know.
There's been an accident.
Calista's been in an accident.
Come on, you'll stay with us
tonight. We'll go back
tomorrow. It's okay.
HENRY:
How is she?
What are they saying?
Is she going to be all right?
AUNT SADIE:
I don't know.
She's been hurt pretty bad.
She's going to be here for
at least a couple of weeks.
They're still running scans
in her neck and
she's in a lot of pain.
Goddamn.
Henry, Audrey's really got to
get down here.
Have you found her yet?
She's not going to be back
till tomorrow night.
Can you come down here then?
I have to get back
to the plant.
I can't leave her alone.
Come on, Henry, please?
No, I, I can't.
Why not?
Because I just, I can't.
-There's nobody else
I can call on, Henry.
-I'm sorry, okay?
Calista needs you now...
(PHONE BEEPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INDISTINCT)
Hey, baby.
Henry?
How you doing?
I'm so glad you're here.
Juanita dumped Mauricio.
Well, now, that sucks.
No, it doesn't. It's cool.
You know,
'cause she did it for him.
'Cause she knows that
he really loves Rosa.
You know, it was sad.
But it was really
beautiful too,
because she loves him so much.
What can I do for you, baby?
(SIGHS)
Give me the pill...
That's good stuff.
Easy. Open up. Easy.
Okay.
All right, just don't
move now.
Oh, shit. My bad.
There you go. It's all right.
I guess what I have to
look forward to...
Sad people wiping drool
off my chin.
You're going to...
You're going to be all right.
You'll recover.
You didn't.
You lost your lover
and you never recovered.
Baby, that's different.
I know.
Yours died...
And mine just stopped
loving me.
(SOBBING)
I was going after you.
That's what I was doing.
I know.
I was going to seduce you.
I was going to be
weepy and sexy,
and seduce you.
And I was even maybe going to
let you get me pregnant...
and I didn't care if that
made me ineligible for
Miss America.
I don't...
I don't want to lie to you.
I don't know what's going on.
It's like I'm handling
the ball on a fast break,
you know...
And all I got to do is
pull up and just take
a little jump shot and...
Hey, Mookie,
I'm just a little too doped up
right now for basketball talk.
Can you just be here?
Just be here.
Yeah.
Hey. Hi. Hi.
How is she?
She's all right.
I mean, you know,
she'll be okay.
Can I see her?
She doesn't want
to see you right now...
So, no, not now.
Has she been here
alone all night?
No. Henry came by.
-He was here for
a little while.
-My Dad was here?
What are you doing?
What is this?
Why don't you tell me, baby?
How can you ask me that?
What kind of question is that?
These big ones,
they mean that you got in.
Do you know that?
Yes, I know that.
Let's talk about it.
No.
You had no right to do this.
Okay, you're right.
I didn't, but now I know.
Look, smoke another fatty
and forget about it.
Hey, baby...
I really don't want to
hear this right now!
Well, you're going to hear it.
I'm proud of you.
I want to help you do
whatever you got to do.
I want you to leave me alone.
What?
Audrey!
Okay, come on,
let's hear it, Dad.
Let's hear the
I'm-your-father speech
you've been rehearsing
for three years.
How can you do this
to me right now?
Doing what? I'm
trying to help you figure out
what you want to do.
Maybe what I want to do
is just stay in
Dreamland forever,
nursing your hangovers and
peddling cigarettes
at the convenience store.
Maybe I want to drink this
beer and sit in the hot tub.
Maybe that's what I want.
You deserve so much
more than that, baby.
Maybe I should have
crashed a motorcycle
a long time ago.
(SOBBING)
You okay?
Uh...
What's the matter?
I couldn't sleep, so,
I was watching Baywatch.
These two kids,
they were drowning.
And David Hasselhoff could
only save one of them.
So then David Hasselhoff
had to go tell
the dead kid's dad
that his kid was dead.
And then, I don't know,
during this like,
huge emotional scene...
David Hasselhoff was like
sucking his stomach in
the whole time.
And, I don't know,
it really made me sad.
I must be losing it.
You know there's
a fine line between
losing it and getting it.
What's that supposed to mean?
-I don't know,
I just made it up.
-(LAUGHS)
Thanks for spending
the nights with me.
That's really, really
helped me feel better,
so, thank you.
Good.
I know Audrey
wants to come visit.
Maybe later, but, not now.
Okay.
How does that feel?
Does it hurt?
No. That feels wonderful.
We need to talk about us.
I want you to know that I...
That I really care about you.
And that I think you're
an amazing person.
You are too.
And that I will always
care about you.
You know? But you're leaving.
So I just don't...
I just don't know.
I think we should just
be friends, Mookie.
Yeah.
No, please don't stop.
Please don't stop.
It feels so good.
(DOOR OPENS)
Morning, baby.
What?
You. You look great.
Thanks. I feel good.
Not getting as many headaches
and, you know...
I didn't realize how shallow
my breathing had gotten.
The type of thing I stopped
noticing.
How about you?
I just want to see her.
She's getting better every
day, she really is.
She's not though.
I mean, she's going to
recover from this but she's
never going to be okay.
Her neurons are going
to keep getting attacked
and...
They're eventually just going
to break down.
And she's going to get weak
and tired and that's just the
way it is.
Well, you never know.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
CALISTA: Hey.
Calista?
Hi, um, I was just wondering
what you were doing
the day after tomorrow?
I don't... I don't know. Why?
I'm coming home.
I'm... That's great.
So if, you know, if you're
not doing anything...
I mean if you're around,
I just thought, you know,
you could just be there
when I get back.
Of course.
I've missed you.
Well, um, I'll see you in
a couple days, okay?
Okay.
Splendid. Goodnight, crazy.
Goodnight.
(PHONE BEEPS)
Hey.
Dreamer said you'd
be out here.
I was just leaving.
Come on.
I'll walk back with you.
Did Calista call you?
Did she tell you she's
coming back?
Uh, yeah.
I talked to her yesterday and
she said she's coming home.
Yeah.
Did she tell you she broke
up with me?
She broke up with you?
Yeah.
It's okay, we both knew
it wasn't going to work.
Why not?
You know why not.
I can't stop thinking
about you.
Calista is my best friend.
I know, but this isn't
about Calista, Audrey,
this is about you.
Why are you doing this?
Because I couldn't leave
without telling you how
I feel.
It doesn't matter anyway,
because you're leaving
and I'm going to be here.
You can't stay here forever
taking care of other people.
So what do you want
me to do?
Abandon them?
For what? So I can sit in
a classroom and talk
about poems?
They need me.
They love you more than
they need you.
You don't know anything.
I know you want more
than this.
Let me take care of you.
I'm so proud of you, baby.
I'm proud of you too.
Tell me all about it.
Well, I'm going to be
in customer relations in
the product distribution
division.
Hey, they gave me a company
car.
Yeah.
Smooth.
It's just going to keep
getting better and better,
you know that?
You'll be Miss America
one day. I know it.
You know, I don't know.
I don't know if I want
to be Miss America
anymore.
How about Miss Dreamland?
It's got a nice ring to it.
Hmm.
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
Hello.
That first night when
I was in the hospital...
I had this moment.
I had woken up in
the middle of the night...
And Mookie was there,
and he was asleep,
and I didn't...
I didn't believe it at first.
You know, and then I looked
at him, and he was just
so cute, and kind,
and, um...
Kind of like an angel.
And that's when I knew it.
What?
That it was over.
I mean, not like over, but
that it was over between us.
Like, I...
I didn't want him there.
Like I didn't want him at my
bedside dreaming about me.
Not like that.
Yeah, but that's weird, huh?
'Cause I always want
people dreaming about me.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Of course.
I tried to close my eyes
and make it go away,
like that feeling,
and I couldn't.
It just kept getting bigger.
And all those other things,
like those other feelings
of love,
they just kind of faded out.
And I wasn't afraid anymore.
You know what I mean?
I don't know.
But...
I know that you're beautiful.
And that I'll never, ever,
ever meet anyone else
like you
for the rest of my life.
I have candy.
Do you want some.
Sure.
All right.
Uh, pick one.
Not that one.
I love this one.
Check out the look on her
face.
She's lovely.
Yeah, she was always lovely,
but right here she looks like
she's going to take
on the world, huh?
Have you come to a decision?
Yeah.
I'm going.
Mmm-hmm.
All right. Packed and
ready to go.
Thanks.
You're all set.
I'm going to miss you.
I'll miss you too.
Really?
Yeah.
Yeah?
The blanket of smoke
and candy lies crumpled
on the bed...
Drenched in perfume,
unraveled by desire...
But strong as spider silk...
It falls away while
I stretch...
Brush the diamonds from
my eyes and wake up.
(INAUDIBLE)
(BUZZING)
That's beautiful.