Ferdinand Choupard is a minor
character in our story.
Nonetheless, he is where this
adventure begins,
as he wandered home
after an evening spent
playing cards
and sipping a marvellous
12-year-old malt whisky.
It was November 4th, 1911,
at 1 o'clock in the morning.
The streets were empty with
a chilly nip in the air.
Yet, at the same time,
exactly 953 metres from there,
the city was jumping.
On stage, Nicole Gambert,
or Nini-les-Gambettes,
kicked up a storm.
The enthusiastic audience
revelled in the show.
I love you.
Wonderful.
Great.
Every evening was a triumph.
From the gent over there.
And every evening for nearly a month,
Raymond Pointrenaud,
a former Prefect,
celebrated his promotion to Paris as
Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs.
Meanwhile, Ferdinand had barely
travelled the 280 metres
that separate La Concorde
from Place des Pyramides.
Don't be shy!
You've seen others!
Oh my God!
Ferdinand's visions were
in fact an optical illusion.
The frenzied lights came from the home
of Professor Marie-Joseph Esperandieu.
This eminent scientist and
expert on Ancient Egypt
had obtained a degree
in physics aged only 16.
His research culminated
35 years later
in a book with the evocative title,
Is There A Life After Death?
At the same moment,across the Seine,
the question seemed
to have been settled long ago.
Yet, on the first floor,
a life form that contravened
the laws of science
was about to give
the scientist his answer.
As the century's most
amazing experiment
took place before our eyes,
Inspector Albert Caponi
had his tightly shut.
Of course, had he seen the
pterodactyl fly by his window,
our story would have been
drastically different,
but for now no one could blame
the inspector for his somnolence.
His stoutness and perseverance
had previously earned him
a god many distinctions,
including the Medal of Merit
for solving
the mystery of the missing
persons of Dreux asylum.
He was decorated
on August 28th, 1907,
by the Prefect Raymond
Pointrenaud in person.
Raymond! What are you doing?
Let my little bird
land on your branches.
You devil! Nothing arouses
me more than poetry.
Really?
Yes!
As the night recedes,
the dew in the branch
prepares to fall
And the bird in the
nest to open its eyes...
Drive normally, can't you?
Godness me! Get out! Get out!
Hello!
Caponi speaking.
In the Seine?
Oh my God!
Oh my God! Help me find the words.
This young man's a scientist too,
but a humble assistant,
working at the Botanical Gardens.
His name's Zborowsky and he's 23.
Science isn't his only passion.
He has another,
more voracious one.
Dear... Miss Adele...
What if she's married?
Or even worse, widowed?
Yes, his second passion is unconditional
love for Miss Adele Blanc-Sec.
A passion she provoked
with these few words...
Who's it for?
For Zbo... bo...
bobo rowsky.
First name, perhaps?
Yes.
Which is?
Andrej, with a J, as in jaguar.
Oh, I'd love this one.
A jaguar.
Oh.
Thank you!
Andrej Zborowsky was
definitively lost to science.
As for Adele Blanc-Sec
and her sense of humour,
they had set off on a new adventure,
much less monstrous and much more exotic,
since her publisher
had sent her to Peru
to unravel the mystery
of the last Incas.
Something you should
know about Adele,
to really understand her...
She listens to her instincts,
not her publisher.
Aziz, how many hours'
ride to the rendezvous?
In this heat,
at least six, Miss Adele.
Very well. Let' s move out.
What's "move" in Arabic?
Yalla, Miss Adele.
Yalla
And "Move, you ass,
or you're dead"?
Stop!
Is this it?
I think so.
Very well.
You need to drink
a lot of water in this heat.
These are the two men
I told you about.
A cup of tea before the drop?
I look like I drink tea?
Is this the tomb room?
Not yet.
It's the embalming room,
where the mummies were prepared.
The bodies were gutted on the altar
and the entrails thrown in these pots.
Then, after a quick wash, they were
powdered, made up and dressed.
What was this for?
Made-to-measure suits.
The body goes here
and the machine
wraps it in 200
layers of bandages.
Not to mention the oil,
squirted between each layer.
What kind of oil is it?
No idea, but it worked a treat.
Found it!
Yes, this is it. Gents,
let's see your treasure.
Death...
is the only path...
that leads... to birth.
Your journey ends here,
darling.
To thank you for
your coperation,
we'll spare your life.
Get lost!
Fine Egyptian hospitality!
Yes, but he's not Egyptian.
Great...
A peculiarly inflammable
mix of oil and petroleum.
Enter with even a tiny match
and there'll be fireworks.
Let me know when your gentlemen's
club is open to women.
Excuse me.
Just as I thought.
Miss! After careful consideration,
we accept your application.
Allow me to save my
emotion for later.
That' s that bit done.
Hold on a sec...
Where'd you learn all this?
There are only two ways.
Be Egyptian or learn to read.
Amazing!
Allah is great!
I make a fortune.
Here he is...
C'mon, they're down there!
Even without the stone, it's very
heavy. How will we ever get it out?
In tombs like this,
there's a way in and a way out.
Find it.
Yes, Miss Adele.
Open it.
Hey, wait.
Opening a pharaoh's tomb is sacrilege.
You can hang for that.
What punishment for
taking his gold?
None.
Beware, you witch!
I won't leave without my gold.
I fear you're right.
Money can't buy happiness,
Aziz. Open it!
That' s your pharaoh?
No, a doctor.
Don't move.
If it's for a consultation, miss,
you may be a bit late.
However, I know a specialist
institute in Cairo,
where the doctors would be
delighted to examine you.
I'm fine, thank you. Except for the nausea
I feel in your presence, Prof. Dieuleveult.
Still the same caustic sense of humour,
my dear Adele. You'll need it.
Meanwhile,
tell me why a great reporter
like you is here looting tombs.
Not looting, borrowing.
Of course! You're taking him for
a walk to get some fresh air.
Patmosis is a professor of medicine,
Ramses II's personal doctor.
The greatest medical
expert in Ancient Egypt.
Fortunately, because...
I need his expertise.
Would that be to cure humankind?
No, just my sister. She's ill.
How very thoughtful and touching!
But has it crossed your mind that
your professor is... dead?
I'd noticed, thank you.
How will you resuscitate him?
May I?
Is There A Life After Death?
That old fool, Esperandieu?
He's barely able to
spin a chair round.
He'll be dead before he
revives this old mummy!
Mind your language!
Mummies hear everything we say
and detest disrespect.
You're scaring me!
After the Ice Monster,
here comes the Sand Zombie!
Watch out, he's a real grouch!
My dear Adele,
I confess I'm one of
your most avid readers,
but this is by far the silliest
story you've ever told.
Take her away!
Yes, sir!
Come along. Hurry!
The way out?
I checked
every wall. Nothing.
It must be in the middle.
The tomb's in the middle.
See? You found it.
Hurry up. Let' s go!
Damn rainwater!
You know the punishment
for tomb raiders?
Hanging.
For locals only.
Foreigners are given more
consideration
and a swift death.
More protocol,
but much less pain.
Miss! Miss!
A last wish perhaps?
It's not very god
for my health,
but I'd appreciate a cigarette.
Why not? One won't kill you!
Thank you.
It's magnificent.
Yes.
May I?
A gift, I suppose?
A memento, actually.
My father. On his death.
Oh
It's better this way. Whenever
I use it, I think of him.
Oh
I'd like to give you a souvenir.
Really?
Whenever you use it,
think of me.
Into my arms!
Forgive me the sudden intimacy.
Excuse me, my god man!
Cairo?
Thanks.
Put him on the table.
Calm down. Careful!
We'll take care of you.
Scissor.
Calm down, Professor. Oxygen!
We're nearly there.
I'll kill that woman!
Oxygen!
I'll kill her!
I'll kill her! Breathe in!
Blow out! Blow out!
Fifty!
Mr. Choupard,
how can I believe a man with
50% alcohol on his breath?
I swear it's true,
Commissioner.
Inspector.
Inspector, yes. The bird swooped
onto the car
and pecked it to pieces!
And Prefo Pectoral...was aboard.
Ex-Prefect.
And he had a scantily
clad woman next to him.
A scantily clad woman?
With Pointrenaud, founder of
Christian Aid? Nonsense!
I know, but I saw her!
Like you saw Joan of
Arc ablaze once more.
Sir...
We've identified the dead.
There were three passengers
in the vehicle.
Pointrenaud, his driver, and...
god Lord!
What did I tell you?
To the drunk tank!
I'm innocent!
It's the big bird that did it!
I was just going home.
Gentlemen, until we find out
more about this tragedy,
I'm relying on you to keep
this case confidential.
of course, sir.
not a word to the press.
no, sir.
The Prefect and the Showgirl!
Their Dance with Death!
Giant Bird Preys
on the Capital!
Get The Little Parisian today!
Giant Bird Preys on the Capital!
Monster Kills Prefect!
Police Clueless!
Read all about it!
There you are, sir.
Monster Kills Prefect!
Police Clueless!
A pterodactyl? How grotesque!
They'll do anything
to sell their rag.
Even Le Gaulois has run it.
They'll panic people, that' s all.
Probably. It's the talk of the town.
Send poor Pointrenaud's widow
our condolences.
Yes, Mr. President.
A Prefect with a showgirl, perhaps.
But a pterodactyl?In the 20th century!
you sent for me, sir?
Yes. Call the Interior.
god morning, sir.
This pterodactyl business sounds
serious. It could be anarchists
up to their tricks.
Look into it and
keep me informed.
Leave it to me, sir.
Call the Prefect.
Hello!
En...
Minister.
This pterodactyl
business is dragging on.
The President wants
results this week.
I'll take care of it, sir.
Call Police Headquarters.
Yes? Dugommier?
Who's on the pterodactyl case?
Captain Poissard.
Hardly surprising
it's going nowhere!
We need more energy.
A sleuth!
Give him 72 hours to
obtain results.
I'm on the job, sir.
Get me Cheval!
Hello!
We have to solve this fast.
you have 48 hours.
Consider it done, sir.
What a mess!
Caponi speaking.
Cheval here.
god morning, Commissioner.
I've put you on the
pterodactyl case.
Don't let me down.
Our reputation's at stake.
I'll do my best, sir.
you have 24 hours.
Thank you, sir.
Where'd an animal
like that come from?
Look...
It wasn't like that.
of course not, Andrej.
This egg's always
been in my care.
What happened?
Yesterday, an attendant
noticed broken glass.
He blamed it on
a careless visitor
and simply replaced the glass.
People are so clumsy!
It's more complicated
than that.
Look at the remains
of the shell.
Most are still connected to
the amniotic membrane,
as if the force that
cracked the egg
came from...
The inside?
Exactly.
But that would mean the egg...
Hatched, Zborowsky.
After 1 35 million
years' gestation,
it emerged from
its shell and flew away.
Through there!
In that case,
could it be related to
the pterodactyl in the press?
you'd have made an
excellent policeman.
Professor Menard?
Yes?
Inspector Caponi.
What can I do for you?
I'm in charge of
the petrodactyl case.
Pterodactyl.
That' s what I said.
Seeing the bone collection
in your museum,
I thought maybe you could help.
I'm strictly a Cretaceous man.
I'd suggest you see a
specialist in the Jurassic.
Look, I have 24 hours
to solve this.
I can't go visiting Jura.
Let me find you a specialist
in Paris in that case.
Most kind of you.
Say...
That egg... It'd make
a heck of an omelette.
Please follow me.
Yes, of course.
I'll keep you informed
of developments.
Please do.
godbye.
Come on...
Don't be scared. come on.
Look what I've got for you.
Smells god.
come on...
This is it, sir. Up there.
Excellent!
Fetch me a black coffee
and something to nibble on.
I can't think on an empty stomach.
you want more? Eat, my baby, eat!
That' s god, my baby.
Yes? What do you want?
Inspector Caponi.
I have some questions for you
about the ferodactyl.
Pterodactyl, sir.
I was told you're
a specialist.
Yes, that' s right. But this isn't a...
I was about to eat.
Perfect, that's our speciality.
Well, please come in then.
godness, it's dark in here.
I'm very sensitive to light.
Please, take a seat.
En.
Thanks, Jeannot. May I? I haven't
eaten in 2 days. Go ahead.
so, how can I be of help?
Tell me about the animal.
What it eats, where it sleeps..
We know very little
about its habits.
We do know it's a carnivore.
Quite right!
Nothing beats a
rare rib of beef!
What's that?
It's the toucan.
Please go on, Professor.
It has a wingspan of
about... six metres,
and can fly for hours on end,
looking for food...
to take back to the nest.
There's a nest of them?
no, I mean... There's only one.
En
But at the time,
when they had a mate,
finding food and
building a nest
were their main activities.
Mating took place once a year
and for reasons as yet unknown,
they only laid
one egg at a time.
Which explains their aggressive
nature, especially...
when it came to defending their
one...and only offspring.
Amazing!
Sir, the toucan's...
Help! Help! Jesus!
It's because of the egg.
It was too much for him.
The man's deranged!
Take him away!
sorry.
Need a porter?
I wouldn't say no.
Adele
Mr Xavier? How kind.
My only hope of seeing you,
my dear,
as you travel far and near,
is if lie in wait
for you here.
Very god!
Gently! It's fragile.
Yes, ma' am.
no 28, Rue du Four, please.
so? Peru?
Far! Very far.
And very high.
Indeed.
You made it up Machu Picchu?
Every morning.
very morning!
Is it indiscreet to ask
what treasure you bring us
in that fine box?
A pipe. An Andean pipe.
A pipe?
The large model.
A sacred pipe
I wrenched from the tomb
of the last Inca king.
No!
Yes! Fatal for the
uninitiated player,
so don't touch.
Definitely not.
Tell me, my god man,
is this a cab or a B&B?
I'd love to get
moving, lady,
but these damn nags
are blocking the road.
When will they
ban horses from Paris?
This is the 200th century!
Move! you moron,
or you are dad!
Oh, what happened?
Where we were just now?
What hocus-pocus
have you brought back now?
Miranda, mind your language
and help with the bags.
I just cleaned your room.
you bring back these old dirty
relics again.
I'll take care of this one personally.
What's all this mail?
The young man from
the Botanical Gardens.
A letter a day,
and two Monday to
make up for Sunday.
Reminds me of my youth in
Andalusia, in my mother's family.
There was a young picador,
strong as his bulls...
How is Agathe?
Fine. She's been very god.
But she eats less and less.
soon she'll be skin and bone.
We'll take god care of her.
Thank you, Miranda,
for your patience,
your time and your advice!
so, you
refuse to eat?
now you look so unhealthy.
You need some blusher.
you're as pretty as ever.
I hope Miranda didn't
bore you with Andalusia.
I was in Egypt.
I have a surprise for you.
Look!
Meet Patmosis,
personal physician of Ramses II,
the great pharaoh.
Medically, they
were so advanced.
Their preservation
techniques prove it.
Nobody's ever done better.
I'm sure with all his secrets,
he'll son have you
on your feet.
As son as I find the
man who can revive him.
Sir?
I'm very sorry,
Miss Blanc-Sec.
I was about to
slip you a note.
I'd no idea you were back.
I was about to go out.
I won't keep you.
I hope not.
Here...
Number them, so I
know where to begin.
forget the others. I mean,
you can read them later.
That one's the most important.
Ok,I will read them in bath.
In bath?
I always do.
Um.
Beautiful.
What?
I mean, your room is beautifully
decorated.
What's this pterodactyl?
Exactly. That' s what my...
Which prison has a death row?
La Sante.
Can I do something to help?
Drink to my health!
Esperandieu,
your lawyer to see you.
your client, sir.
Miss Blanc-Sec?
What are you doing here?
Professor, I found Patmosis' mummy.
That' s impossible.
True, but I did.
And don't ask me how.
Where is it now?
At home.
Waiting for you.
Oh.
But Adele...
I fear it will have
to wait some more.
I don't see how I
can get out of here.
Anyway, my mind is to busy
controlling the bird.
The pterodactyl?
Yes. I wanted to refine
my technique
while you were in Egypt.
I brought to life an egg
over 135 million years old.
Perfect! A 4,000000-year-old
mummy will be child's play.
Perhaps,
but the bird exhausts me.
Whenever I doze off, its killer
instinct takes over. I must stop it
My sister first,
then your giant insect.
That's fine by me,
but how will you get me out?
Trust your lawyer.
Sir?
I'm here to see my
client, Esperandieu.
Mr. Saint Hubert,
can we have a comment?
Don't crowd.
Hold back the reporters!
Gentlemen, calm down!
Let him speak!
I cut short my African trip
at the government' s behest.
They have invited me as an
expert to assist Mr Caponi
to dispatch this pterodactyl.
It's a great honour to put my talent
at the service of the nation.
Mr. Saint Hubert,
what approach will you use?
First, we'll track it down,
to study its
behaviour and habits.
How will you find it?
Quite simply,
by raising our sights.
Anything god today?
Pigeon.
You've saved my life.
Don't mention it.
Come out, wherever you are.
It's right here, Caponi.
I can sense it.
Wonderful.
it's pter...ptero...pterodactyl...
What is it exactly?
Mutton! That' s what it is.
Really?
Categorically. Trust me,
I know my droppings.
It's the best
way to track an animal.
We're making progress,
Caponi. Progress!
Wonderful.
In the bowl,
there's a badge.
you're Armand
Petit-Blanchard, head cook.
Armand what?
Petit-Blanchard, I said!
someone stole my badge
from my locker.
Hands off me!
Get out! That's enough now!
Right... I need a better plan.
sorry, no more pate.
Not to worry.
Hey! Caponi!
Yes?
Unless I'm mistaken,
it could find sheep in 3 places.
Montmartre in the north, the
colonial exhibition in the east,
or the Botanical Gardens.
That' s right.
Let' s go!
By the grace of god!
Thank you, my son.
Wow! Sister is coming.
Don't touch!
Hurry up, let' s go!
As Daddy would say,
a battle that seems lost
is the most exciting.
Up and at 'em!
Bang! Bang!
Bang!
The farmer's counted the
herd twice. None missing.
Fine! Let' s go!
My sheep!
I'm so sorry. It just went off.
Bertrand? Get a vet.
Cell 28. It's for his jab.
Ouch!
Sorry.
Professor? Wake up!
It's time to go.
Would you be so kind as
to come back later?
I really am very tired.
That takes the biscuit!
Six Poitou goats,
four Vanoise chamois,
fifteen Larzac ewes and...
nine, ten, twelve
mountain sheep from Jura.
Jura?
All present and correct!
god. On to the Botanical Gardens.
Get ready, Caponi!
We'll launch our assault
at first light.
Thank you!
You're relieved!
Fine by me.
god luck!
I hope you had a god sleep.
We have to go now.
What are you doing here?
It's not by choice.
Where's the Professor?
They transferred him last night.
Always do before the execution.
Execution?
The guillotine,
tomorrow at dawn.
It can't be...
Unfortunately, it can, unless...
he gets a pardon.
Pardon?
Yes.
Here... I pardon you.
go on, fetch! good boy, Nelson!
Mr. President,
Miss Blanc-Sec's here.
She has nothing on her.
What? nothing on her?
We searched her.
She's unarmed.
go on!
Come on, Nelson! god boy!
My dear Miss Blanc-Sec!
Mr. President.
You know I have a fond
memory of that interview...
When was it?
January 18th, 1906.
The day after you
were elected.
It was my first interview.
And the last time I
laughed so much.
Yes, I was appalling.
You were charming.
so, what can I do for you?
Well... As President, you often
criticise the death penalty.
I've pardoned 17 condemned
men in my first term.
Precisely.
Please, pardon one more.
Professor Esperandieu.
Due for execution tomorrow.
He's innocent.
I know his case.
We have 3 dead bodies,
including a Prefect.
He didn't kill them.
It was a prehistoric beast!
Only the Professor
can control it.
Without him,
how many bodies
will there be?
Miss,
we have put our
finest men on the case.
We even called in a big game
hunter from Africa
to dispatch the animal.
Nelson! Fetch your ball!
Esperandieu is a fine scholar.
His research keeps
science going forward.
By taking his life, you
condemn so many others.
I promise I'll think it over.
Thank you, sir.
What's wrong?
your ball's over there!
Fetch it, Nelson!
Come on! Look!
What's up? Seen a ghost?
See? your ball's over here.
come and fetch it!
Be a god boy! Hurry!
come! Nelson! come!
Oh,no! Mr. President!
god boy! Into my arms!
Get down!
President assaulted!
Sorry!
Don't move!
Get off him!
Take your paws
off me! Let me go!
Are you hurt, sir?
I am fine, go away!
I'm warning you,
I do jiu-jitsu.
Nelson!Nelson!
Let me go or I'll press charges!
Nelson!
Find Nelson!
Eyes open, Caponi!
Both are wide open, honestly.
Vigilance and patience are the
hunter's watchwords.
Tell me, Saint Hubert,could
I nip off for a minute
for some food?
Out of the question!
We are at war, my friend.
one day I hunted a tiger lying
low in a Bengali temple.
We went three days
without food.
Three days!
Yes.
Incredible!
How did you do it?
I started by consulting all
the books in the library,
which confirmed the animal's
sedentary nature.
so I got the idea to collect
the fragments of its egg
and put them in a quiet place.
Then I left out some
choice cuts of beef,
to keep them from hunger,
so it wouldn't decimate
our herd of Corsican sheep.
Zborowsky... You're a genius!
It's nothing really.
Just a little intuition.
With intuition like that,
you must sweep the ladies off
their feet, my young friend!
That depends on the lady.
Are there two L's in Addle?
no, two E's.
Two E's?
Adele. A-D-E-L-E. Blanc-Sec.
Like the wine. Dry white, you know.
Yes, I know dry whites.
Marvellous!
Go ahead.
From the beginning.
To cure my sister,
I went to Egypt, not Peru,
to find a doctor, Patmosis,
a charming but
mummified fellow.
Prof. Esperandieu
was supposed to wake him,
not the damn pterodactyl
he should've left alone,
given its attack on
the President and his pet.
The petero...
no, the pet's the dog.
I summoned up all my courage
and threw myself on the President.
A heroic but calculated gesture,
intended to secure a pardon for
the Professor to save my sister
I was arrested for
attacking him.
Do I look like a terrorist?
no.
so the bird dunked on Nelson.
Dunked?
Clear? Can I go home now?
Yes. However...
one tiny detail escapes me.
Which is?
Who is... Whose is...
Whose is the dog?
Right... do you have
to speak in Morse,
or we'll be all night?
I save the President and
that' s the thanks I get?
you louts!
Things didn't quite
go to plan, little sis.
I need a bath to
gather my wits.
sorry for bothering
you for nothing.
Truly. But aren't you happier here
eyeing the girls than in your tomb?
My god!
Yes?
Into my arms!
I read your letter.
Which one?
about the pterodactyl.
you're a genius, Andrej.
Let' s go. The taxi's
waiting downstairs.
Right away.
This way.
See? I wasn't telling you lies.
Incredible!
Be careful, Miss Adele.
Don't worry, I've
cracked tougher nuts.
Birdy, birdy...
It prefers meat.
Really?
Silly me.
Where are you from, my beauty?
I don't mean you!
In any case, you
have beautiful plumage.
In truth, if your voice is the
equal of your coat...
Fine. Clearly no ancestor
of the nightingale.
Watch out, it might
think you're a goat.
you smooth-talker.
no, I meant...
I'm usually called bird names.
Really?
My dove... My chickadee...
My feathery thing!
Actually...
You want my
feathers, don't you?
My feathery thing...
Feathers of little birdies...
Incredible!
There you go, that' s
god. Now we're friends,
I have a favour
to ask of you.
Surely you're not going to...
It'd be rude not to.
It's madness!
It can't be more
complicated than a camel.
It can.
Watch out! The tree!
Stop!
There we are.
you're unbelievable,
Miss Blanc-Sec.
now we've mastered the unbelievable,
let' s perform the impossible.
Here we are!
This way, my friends.
This is so exciting!
you haven't seen anything yet.
And don't blink,
or you'll miss it.
I prepared some snacks for you.
god thinking.
This is for you.
Thank you.
Champagne? I'll be tipsy again.
Which way?
At the window.
Thank you.
Look at the crowd.
We're just in time.
There he is!
An ugly little head he has.
I see why they'd chop it off.
Charlotte!
It was because of the egg.
It was too much for him.
They've put a bag on his head.
I don't understand. Why'd the executioner
fly off with a bag on his head?
There! There it is!
There! I'm here!
It's snatched a man. Fetch an ambulance.
Leave the rest to me.
I'll go right away.
you keep it, buster.
you've earned it.
Anyone there! Where are we?
Is this hell?
Here I am!
Adele?
Hello.
How can this be?
He saved your life. You brought
him to life, so it's only fair.
Yes.
What's going on? Who are these...
Esperandieu?
Menard!
By the saints! A miracle!
Menard, you old blackguard!
Esperandieu, well I never!
How on earth did
you get here?
That' s a very long story.
you can tell it later.
This winter,
over a hot chocolate.
We have a mummy to
wake and sister to save.
Just joking!
Yes, she's just joking.
Well, I'm not joking.
Tired after your trip?
Indeed I am. Very tired.
Want to go home?
Yes. I should be going home.
I'll take you.
Yes, take us home.
Sure, take him home.
godbye, ducky!
What's that...
Saint Hubert?
Esperandieu!
not now!
What's wrong?
Saint Hubert.
Get out!
Stupid hound!
you worthless nincompoop, who
allowed you to shoot at science?
I am Justin de Saint Hubert,
big game hunter...
Big game hunter?
I'm a hunter, too,
but I only shoot black sheep.
You seem a fine specimen.
Stop that! you've no right!
one!
no!
Two!
Three!
no!
Four! Five!
no! no! no!
Don't die now, please!
I'll do my best.
Let me help.
If you want to help,
look after the pterodactyl.
But the Professor's bleeding.
They're connected!
Don't ask how or why.
If we lose one, we lose both.
Don't let it happen.
Yes, of course!
Leave it to me.
Twenty-eight, Rue du Four.
What do I do now?
Place antique objects
in a circle around me.
The older the better.
Yes, that one.
I'm going to need to...
put this bandage on you.
I'll be right back.
There! What now?
now... I'll try to establish
contact with the mummy
to see if it agrees to
entrust the keys to me.
Excellent!
What keys?
After death, the
whole body shrinks
and locks itself in the mind
which never die.
I discovered the key to
communicate with the mind.
Wonderful!
It's going to work.
Maybe... some procoagulants...
in a nub... of butter?
Professor!
Please, stay with me. Please,
just a little longer!
Bless you.
Thanks.
sorry about the glass.
forget it. I have
to tidy up anyway.
What a shame he's gone. I'd have
liked to get to know him.
What have we here? I detect
a certain likeness.
She's my sister.
She doesn't look well.
Yes...
But...
Actually...
With the knowledge you possess,
perhaps you could try
to bring her back to life?
I have some modest talents,
but not that one.
What? You're not a doctor?
Absolutely not.
I'm a nuclear physicist.
I deal in figures, signs and
equations. nothing very extraordinary.
doctors don't leave
the pharaoh's side,
and are buried next to them,
right next door.
May I make some tea?
Be my guest.
Very kind of you.
Kindness is a highly prized
quality in our dynasty.
I admit that throughout
this adventure,
you have been very hospitable towards
me, and I'd like to thank you.
you could hear?
Everything.
And see? Like when I...
Don't blush. With this body,you
appreciate that of others more.
Thanks.
I suppose you want a doctor
to cure this poor child.
Yes. not only is
she my sister,
but also my friend,
my angel... My twin.
What happened to her?
A freak accident.
A camel?
Tennis.
Lend me your hatpin.
no way!
Thanks.
for nothing.
How do I look?
Like skewered kidneys.
Which I take to mean...
"Gracious!
Why did my parents give her beauty and
leave me only bitterness and jealousy?"
one game all. New balls.
We'd just turned twenty.
Agathe was so beautiful.
We'd discovered a new sport
and played whenever we could.
In order too avoid
any sense of rivalry,
we never had an actual match.
Our games were
strictly friendlies.
Then, in a moment of euphoria,
a moment of shared happiness,
tragedy struck.
Agathe!
Miss, are you okay?
Miss, wake up!
Move! Please!
Agathe! Move!
No, not that!
Sorry! Stay with me!
Go and fetch a doctor!
Agathe!Agathe!
Agathe!Agathe!Agathe!
She was born a
few minutes after me
but she departed well before me.It's
the only race I'd have loved to lose.
Indeed, a most
regrettable accident.
Believe me, I'm very
sorry I can't help you.
The Professor did a remarkable
job. His mental power
must have woken the
dead in a radius of 2 km.
But I'm not the right person.
Hold on a sec... 2 kilometres?
Yes, probably.
The waves ripple out like when
you throw a stone into water.
And Ramses' doctors
never left his side?
They never left the room, even when he
was mating. The Mummies of Ramses II.
Patmosis, you're a genius.
Let's go!
Excuse me, I'm looking for
the Ramses exhibition.
Yes, quite!
Stop importuning people.
You'll get us noticed.
After 5,000 years in a tomb,
can't I have some fun?
I couldn't resist.
It was rather amusing.
First things first.
Then you can die.
of laughing, if you wish.
Can you open it?
I'm no better
locksmith than doctor.
Perhaps you could serve some kind of
purpose, or I'll float you down the Seine.
The Nile, it ain't!
Don't get upset. Humour soothes
the savage breast.
That' s not humour!
Maybe it made
the pharaohs laugh,
but this is the 200th century!
That' s better.
This way, Mistress.
Patmosis!
Yes, Mistress.
Coming, Mistress!
This way, Mistress.
Cut it out!
you're very tense. Relax.
I'll give you a massage later.
you're a chiropractor now?
no, but I studied
molecular energy.
for now, stick
to opening dors.
Beautiful, eh? Reminds me
of when we painted.
All clear?
Look, what's that?
what?
Patmosis!
Leave it to me, Mistress.
Miss!
Waking people, no, but knocking
them out, no problem.
Thank you, Mistress.
Oh my god!
They're all jumbled up.
If Ramses saw this...
Wake him, so he can
rearrange them.
The faithful first, so they're
there when the Pharaoh wakes.
Poor dear, don't want
him feeling homesick.
And definitely not insulted, so
I suggest we respect protocol.
I'm in favour of protocol.
sorry to bother you,
are you a doctor?
Are you a surgeon?
I'm looking for a doctor.
no, you're not a doctor!
doctor anyone?
Great nap. What is that
ridiculous attire?
Native costume,
your Highness.
Allow me to introduce
Miss Adele Blanc-Sec, a scribe.
Hi.
The natives employ women
to write their texts?
Their civilization is
still rough and ready,
but she is very amicable
and waking us was
her god idea.
god idea? I feel I've
woken up a little early.
Sorry to wake you, your Highness, I had no
choice. It's a matter of life or death.
Life or death?
It comes and it goes.
I'd like my
sister's to come back.
Miss Adele woke me up in the
belief that I was a doctor.
you? A doctor?
I wouldn't let you
clip my nails.
She's looking for a doctor
to treat her sister,
and we thought that
in your great kindness,
you might let your personal
physician take a look at the child.
you woke me up for
such a trivial affair?
Hold on, Rammy! Five thousand years,
you've been snoring away.
I've had 5 years of grieving,
of suffering with my
sister who can't see me.
I'm a poor earth-dweller
with no divine protection.
I live everyday with the pain
and guilt that never goes away.
Because it was all my fault!
It was my hatpin!
What's this about a hat?
nothing, I'll tell you later.
nosibis, my faithful doctor...
See if you can give the
girl a little life back,
so she can enjoy
all this love for her.
Thank you...
your Highness.
Serene Majesty?
The doctors said if we took
it out,she'd most likely die.
you're insane!
I asked you to cure her,
not kill her,
you bag of bones!
Calm down, Adele.
Don't interfere.
What's that?
The Pharaoh's entrails.
Charming.
Is the kiss necessary?
not really,
more of a tradition.
It's better to do it now,
before she wakes up.
no kidding.
Well... Let' s go out
and see the sights.
Agathe!
Are you mad, hitting
the ball like that?
And I love you more
than the whole world.
It was a privilege
meeting you, Miss Adele.
Same here, Patmosis.
Apologize to your Pharaoh for me,
for being so rude.
And thank him for me.
I will... Mistress.
Who are you talking to?
Nobody, darling. Don't move. Everything
will be fine now, I promise.
This way, your Majesty.
What was that?
Sorry to importune you again.
Go ahead.
Which way to the Nile, please?
Why, of course!
They are very curious people.
Cruelly lacking in manners.
I agree, Your Highness.
But they have highly developed
artistic talents.
This courtyard, for example,
is magnificent.
Quite magnificent!
We should build
a pyramid here.
I'm sure it would be
a fine addition.
Meanwhile, Sire, perhaps
we should rejoin the others?
you are right,
Patmosis. Let' s go!
Curse of the Pharaohs
Strikes Paris!
Read all about it! Mummies
Vanish from the Louvre!
There you go, sir!
Curse of the Pharaohs
Strikes Paris!
What's this now
about mummies?
It's another anarchist plot.
Call the Interior.
Tuck in, my little Caponi!
Who's it for?
It was for Miss Adele.
She's taken a
few weeks' vacation.
Well.
Give them to someone else.
For me? That's so kind!
What's your name?
Zborowsky.
First name perhaps?
Yes. Andrej,
with a J, as in...
As in jaguar.
Cup of tea?
Yes.
Enjoy the trip.
Thank you.
Hurry, miss,
we're about to leave.
All right,
keep your hair on.
Blanc-Sec, Adele.
Thank you.
The woman in the green hat?
Leave it to us.
Hurry up!
It is Miss Blanc-Sec's luggage.
Welcome on board.
Hurry. Move fast
for the luggage!
Welcome on board.
Hurry up!
How are you? Welcome!
Take this.
Miss Blanc-Sec...
Yes?
These are yours?
Take god care of them.
Sorry!
god start to the holiday.
Sorry, it was an accident.
That's my bag!
Take god care of it.
Have a god trip, Miss Blanc-Sec.
Saint Hubert!
Caponi! Caponi!
A fine zebra!
I've lost Saint Hubert!
I just lost him! Go and find him!
You put up a god fight.
Please, I'm begging you.
no!
Smile!
No!
Nobody move!
I'm out of ammunition.
Take him away!
You look like a
fine specimen, too.
Sit tight.
I'll get reinforcements.
Fine, take your time.
Oh, no!