Take off these cuffs!
Think you can shut me up?
Fuck you! Remove the cuffs, fag!
I'll remember you, fags!
Easy.
Don't touch me. Raise your hands.
I can walk alone.
Fuck you, asshole!
Where are you taking me?
First, take off the handcuffs.
Take them off or I'm not coming in.
You think I'm stupid?
Take off the handcuffs!
Malik, can you hear me?
- Do you understand?
- I understand it's 6 years.
Now you're an adult.
You'll be in a prison.
You're among the adults.
Sign here.
- What's this?
- For legal aid.
- Money?
- Money for me.
So they pay me. Sign here.
Money for you?
Thank you.
Raise your arms.
Higher.
Palms out.
Shake your hair.
Open your mouth.
Stick out your tongue.
Turn.
The soles of your feet.
The other one.
Bend over.
Cough.
Money is not allowed here.
You'll get it when you leave.
Give him a uniform and shoes.
Rubbish. You can't wear them here.
- Do you have a family?
- No, sir.
- Somebody to send you money?
Friends or enemies in here?
No, sir.
You'll be in observation.
So we can evaluate you.
We'll see how you adapt.
Then you'll have a permanent cell.
- Are you a practicing believer?
- What?
Your religion.
Will you pray?
Any special diet?
Nothing special, sir.
Do you eat pork?
No. Yes..
How will you receive any money sent?
I don't know.
Want to work?
- What do you do besides
attacking policemen?
- I did nothing!
Vocational training?
Anything else?
Stand back, please.
Boss!
Are you new?
You're in the office.
Did you get something from outside?
- A mobile, drugs, pills?
- What the hell? I have nothing.
Do you get checks?
Do you have friends outside?
- What do you want?
- Your shoes. They're nice.
Can I keep them?
Take my slippers.
Fuck you.
Faggot!
Son of a bitch.
To your cells. Closing time.
Closing time.
Line up.
Cesar.
Call Cesar.
The guy on the right.
- What's that dirty Arab doing here?
- Could be for the Farraldo trial.
Luciani. Ward.
Luciani. Consultation.
So?
They've brought him
for the Farraldo trial.
His lawyer wants to negotiate.
Get a lesser sentence.
He will stay until the trial.
Jacky Marcaggi wants you to do him.
- When is the trial?
- On the 14.
In ten days? Not much time.
- Does he suspect anything?
- The usual.
Like any rat. He's asked for a
transfer to the Muslim section.
And if left alone,
we lose our chance.
Stays all day in the cell. Doesn't see
anyone. Never goes out. Doesn't eat.
He requested block B,
with the Muslims.
We have to get him
while he's in the cell.
- Hit and run?
- We can't risk one of our own.
Stay tuned. We'll find a
way. Any contact in block A?
Just the porter.
Open. Dinner!
- The door must always be open.
- Yes, I know.
- Nothing to eat?
- No, just bread.
- Bread, then.
The other.
Bon appétit.
- When is there mail?
- Tomorrow.
- How you doing?
- Okay.
Bread?
Bon appétit.
- What the fuck?
- I recognized you. We're neighbors.
- What's your name?
- Yours?
- Which block are you in?
- Do you know yours?
B.
Ask for the B.
It is for our brothers.
Come closer.
I said come closer.
You want hashish?
Yeah, hashish. Want some or not?
But.. I have no money.
- We'll manage.
- What do you mean?
I'll bribe a guard and you suck me.
- What?
- You suck me off.
- Fuck you, asshole!
Me, suck? Mother fucker! Fuck you!
Shut up! Faggot!
Are you okay?
I found it in the yard.
This way.
- How old are you?
- 19. Why?
- Don't look at me. Look at this guy.
- Look at me.
I heard you got 6 years.
It's a long time.
Think you can last
without protection?
I'll manage.
- What do you want?
- To protect you.
- Do you speak Arabic?
- Sure.
The guy in the shower yesterday..
You know him?
What did he want?
To talk.
I told you not to look at me.
I want you to go on with him.
Get close to him.
Become his friend.
Why?
Because you're going to kill him.
Let him go.
Come closer.
Closer. Near to him.
You can do it.
You're not alone.
We'll help.
But remember something.
Now that you know, either you
kill him, or I'll kill you.
Go on, now.
Understood?
Kill him and be quiet. Understood?
I can't kill anyone.
- Yes?
- Can I speak with the director?
There is a procedure.
First you have to ask for an interview.
The guard..
Can I talk to the guard now?
- Why?
- I need to.
I'll check.
I have a problem, sir.
We give the orders. What do you want?
Nothing? Shut up and do as you're told.
Reyeb is careful.
He won't accept easily.
Are you listening?
- Once again. Are you paying attention?
- Yes
It won't be easy.
You can't carry anything.
Talk to him.. naturally.
About your mothers, visits..
Normal talk.
You cut here.
You hit him on the balls.
You grab his shoulder.
You get up and do it. Understood?
Can you give me some hash?
I can't hear you.
Some hash.
Ok. I'll talk to the dealer.
Move away.
What?
Move away, I said.
Turn.
Raise your hands.
Guard!
Is it that one?
- El Djebena, move.
- Give us a minute.
Problems at work?
- What did he do?
- He hit a guy.
Did you hit a guy?
What did he do to you?
Nothing?
Nothing and you hit him?
You know what I think?
You did that to get caught.
Am I wrong?
You think we can't get to you
to do what we want?
Is that it?
Bitch!
Piece of shit!
Asshole!
Enough, Cesar!
Stop, Cesar! Enough!
He'll bleed a lot, so be careful.
Check the soles of your shoes.
Leave the blade in his hand.
Your turn. You're the girl.
Fast or it won't work.
Come on.
That's right. Fine.
Come in. Don't move.
Raise your hands.
I said hands up.
Sorry, but not everyone
is a friend here.
I decide.
Sit.
On the bed.
On the bed I said.
You want something?
Water? Coffee?
Coffee.
- Are you interested in this?
- What?
- Books.
- You want to read?
- I don't know.
Don't know what?
You can't read, right?
it's never too late.
There is a school in prison.
You can learn here.
Sugar?
The idea is to get out of here
a little smarter.
Here.
I've seen you in the yard.
Always alone.
Always wearing the same clothes.
Don't you have friends here? None?
I'm just passing by. I won't stay.
I can leave you some books.
You can learn to read.
Shut up!
Are you okay?
What are you doing?
Come.
From Cesar Luciani.
You are now under his protection.
I have seen your profile.
Almost empty.
Are you interested?
Why didn't you fill it out, then?
- I don't understand.
- Want to learn?
You wrote your name, so
you can write a little.
A little.
- When did you leave school?
- At age 11.
Can you write "In" and "out"?
Is your mother tongue French?
Did you talk in French
or Arabic to your parents?
- I wasn't raised by them.
- Did you speak French or Arabic first?
Both.
- Where was your school?
- A Youth Center.
There is a word with "a"
which is not pronounced "a".
The fourth.
- The fourth. What is the word?
- "Dans".
Go to the second word.
The second word..
"Canard".
This word has two syllables.
Ca..
..nard.
Repeat, separating the syllables.
Very good.
In the first syllable, "ca", is the "a"
at the beginning or the end?
Happy birthday, brother.
1 year
Stop it!
Have you no shame?
Who are the leaders?
- You know them?
- Who?
The Muslims.
These fucking Arabs! Dogs
at least screw in silence.
3.40 Euros.
How much is that?
In francs?
Money is money.
20 francs?
Pass the biscuits.
- Can you buy me something?
- You cheated me the last time.
- Not true.
- Ask him.
- What do you want?
- Soap, cereal and Coca-Cola.
- No Coke.
- Why?
Not with my card.
- But it's for me.
- Don't bust my balls!
Stop sponging.
Sponge your own people.
Or your friends out there.
It pisses me off that you're here.
He's not one of us.
Let him clean if you want. But he's
finished, so out he goes. Arab shit!
Have you finished? Out.
Fuck them!
Fuck you.
Arab shit!
How much you got left?
Two more..
3 years.
What about you?
"Rabia": Rage.
"Rabid": furious.
"Raccia"..
To caw.
Who cares?
"Radica": Root.
Electricity is like water
in a circuit.
Whatever the tube diameter
the flow is the same. Same here.
The current remains constant
1, 2 and 3.
You have to change "he" for "us".
Understand? "He ate before. "
"We ate earlier".
the "we" is fine, but " to eat"..
What is the participle?
We had eaten.
Okay. Now in the indefinite past.
- We.. ate.
- Do people talk this way?
It's complicated. I don't,
but they use it.
One day I saw an ad.
For a security guard.
I had no dog. I bought
a second-hand one.
In my ignorance, I bought a Rottweiler.
You know how they are?
His name was Tyson.
He came with a name: Tyson.
He was huge!
You see this?
That was his butt.
His poops were bigger than mine.
I went to work at a supermarket.
I left the dog inside and
went to smoke a cigarette.
When I tried to enter again,
it was impossible.
- He didn't recognize me.
- Your own dog?
He was mad. Tyson was a psychotic.
I went in and he pounced.
I panicked and pulled out the gun.
He grabbed me like that.
I sprayed him with gas. No effect.
I ran away scared. What to do?
I left him inside.
Three hours later the employees arrived.
I didn't know they used the back door.
The dog had a field day.
He mauled them all.
He was like Karim in Block B.
- What are you doing here?
- Returning books.
Out. You come with me.
- Why are you with him?
- He's a brother.
- He's a Corsican!
Dirty bastard!
- Pig!
- You call me pig?
Who is the pig?
Me a pig?
Let me go!
This is not right!
This isn't Corsica.
You are being disrespectful.
El Djebena!
Tell your boss I have to
introduce a new one.
- You bring the papers?
- They haven't arrived. I bring clothes.
- Make coffee.
- For everyone?
Did you see Ilbanez?
He'll come later with the new prisoner.
Luciani.
Vettori.
- Antarro.
- Santi.
- Ceccaldi.
- Profundi.
Mosconi.
Pilicci.
- Valpato.
- Corleoni.
El Djebena.
The Minister said that Corsicans will
serve their sentences closer to home.
The law will be published on Sunday.
This is due to the revaluation of
political prisoners sponsored by Sarkozy
Currently there are no comments
from the Corsican National Front.
Cesar!
Are you there?
Did you hear the news?
When are we leaving?
- When the bill is passed.
- Soon?
No idea.
Luciani. For Mr. Sampiero.
I can tell you who won't benefit.
Not you, you know that.
Neither Pilicci, Antarr nor Prof.
You fucked up bad.
"Fuck up" wasn't used back then.
Santi and Vettori are expecting
conditional freedom, so..
- Are you saying I'm going
to die alone here?
- Don't talk like that.
You're not alone.
You have strength outside.
And here?
Here!
Guard! I already pinned three.
This is disrespectful. Seriously.
Do you work for the Imam Moussab?
He helps to rehabilitate sick prisoners.
He got me a job.
I'm doing some work for him.
Some day I'll have a real job.
- Are you sick?
- That's why I got a pardon.
Are you leaving this place?
- Do you have AIDS?
- Of course not! Don't say that.
Are you crazy?
- What have you got?
- Cancer of the testicles.
- Cancer in the balls?
- Don't shout. Don't advertise it!
- Besides, I'm cured.
- Are you better then?
Thank God.
Does it hurt?
No.
Chemotherapy is what hurts.
You lose your hair.
You feel like you're 80.
You're always tired.
But thank God it's over.
I can even have kids.
- Here, for your balls, bro.
- It's welcome.
- What's your sign?
- Cancer.
Just kidding. I'm Aries.
See you, Cesar!
Take care, friend!
We won't forget you, Cesar!
Be strong, Volfoni!
See you in Bastia!
Got your phone?
Why don't you leave it with someone?
I speak Corsican.
I speak your language.
Did you understand me when
I was on the phone?
You were talking to a layer.
A what?
A lawyer?
- Who taught you?
- You.. and the others.
- Looking, listening.
- You mean spying?
I didn't spy on you.
I've learned by listening.
You were here. If you weren't spying,
what were you doing? Having fun?
If I had been having fun,
I wouldn't have told you.
Why are you tellimg me, then?
Because the others have gone?
Look at me, Arab. Because
the others are gone, right?
Yes
Does anyone else know?
It has a life of its own.
Come sit.
Get your ass here.
Keep it.
Keep it, but don't use it.
Not everyone is like Ilbanez.
If they find it, you're fucked.
Go on with the cleaning,
washing clothes..
Ilbanez will transfer you to the
adjacent cell.
I'll have them make you a porter.
You'll get paid, you can buy stuff
and go anywhere.
You'll be my eyes and ears.
- What about the others?
- Who, my friends?
Watch them as well.
Are you happy?
You look worried.
- I'm fine.
- Well, say so.
eyes and ears
- What did Cesar say?
- The lawyer will help your brother.
He doesn't give a shit about my brother.
My wife left him 10 messages.
He never answered.
As with Santi and Castelli.
No news. Nothing.
Play.
Did you masturbate?
Jordi, the Gypsy
I like porn movies in castles.
The girls are prettier, cleaner.
How many times did you come?
- When?
- Fuck off. Who cares? Give me that.
Remember with the driver?
With his dick pointing to her pussy.
He fucks her from behind
and stuffs her ass.
And she sucks off the blonde's husband!
Then she goes for a walk with her dog.
I'll give you the rest tomorrow.
Do you make a lot dealing?
No. Enough for shopping and my drugs.
To purchase..
Want to work with me?
I don't understand your game.
- It's not a game.
- You work for the Corsicans.
I work for me.
You don't know anybody in Block C.
You don't sell to just anyone.
What will you do after you get out?
- When you leave, what will you do?
- Don't know. Do you?
- Same as here, but big.
- Hash?
Yes, hash.
But in large quantities.
Marbella-Paris, 3 cars.
600 kilos per trip.
You don't believe me?
I was just trying to imagine 600 kilos.
Something like this.
You see nothing beyond.
Got it.
They died for no reason!
You killed them!
Do you still need me?
- Do you know my business?
- You told me to stay out.
- Come on..
I don't know. Things with the Italians.
Casinos in the south.
What's wrong?
- How long will you be in here?
- 3 years. Minus time for good behavior
You did half, right?
- You can get furloughs.
Did you request them?
- No, that's for my lawyer.
- Has he requested them?
- Why do you ask?
Ask for parole. I'll get you
priority treatment.
Meanwhile, you can get furloughs.
You go out for me, come back, I'll pay.
What do you say?
- What's the risk?
- No risk. The risk is in here.
As soon as the judge considers the
case, he'll ask for more information,
and answer in 5 or 6 months.
I mean an answer,
not necessarily positive.
Do you have a card with your number?
I'll telephone a lawyer,
the name's Sampiero.
Give him what he asks.
Do as he says.
Present the case as soon as he
prepares it. He'll pay you.
- What about the trial?
- Don't worry. He'll explain.
Who is he? Who are these guys?
Thugs?
You never told me about it. Do you know
I can get kicked out of here?
- It's not what I need.
- It's too late. You're in this.
From now on you're a model prisoner.
You're a porter.
Be the best one.
Study for your exams.
Antarro will keep the phone.
- He'll suspect something.
- I'll tell him you pissed me off.
Peace be with you. I was glad
to receive your letter.
In the first place to hear from you.
And also to see your progress.
You write like a professional and I'm
glad. At least I served some purpose.
Now I can tell you
it was not easy.
About your request,
I'll see what I can do.
I'll send a request to visit you.
Life here isn't easy.
I will avoid saying that it's better
over there, but honestly it's tough.
Djamila has a part-time job
and it's hell with the kid.
Imam Moussab's Center got
me a job as an operator.
I get paid shit, but I
keep quiet and hang on.
Keep your head up!
Your brother, Riyad.
For the girls, Martine,
and for the boys, Jean-Pierre.
- A question.
- What's your name?
- Ryad Mnaili.
You are Jean-Pierre. You already made
a mistake. Only two are allowed.
Be careful, put your hand
under his head.
Issam.. this is Malik.
He's your godfather.
It's a garage. The owner
agrees to hire you.
He'll meet you in your day off.
It's the guy who fixes the Imam's cars.
He's already hired other guys.
Do you know what you do for them?
Does it bother you?
I go out and they pay me. If it's risky
for you, just tell me.
Risky? Are you crazy? I'm
rehabilitated. Aren't we rehabilitated?
Outside of Paris there are radars.
Go slowly.
Suddenly.. the car breaks down.
It skids a bit. Where?
Near a gas station.
The guys get off and push.
Guess who shows up to help them?
Come on, guess.
- Who?
- Guess!
- I have no idea.
- The Customs guy, the Customs!
100 kilos.
They confiscated 100 kilos.
- What is the point then?
- You'll know. You know what I want.
This is a business.
Don't you smoke my hash every day?
Are they going to screw me for
your booty? For some smokes?
- Fuck you!
- Back to your cell.
- My dessert, sir!
- Get inside!
What does the accusation say?
In view of the case, I have no objection
to grant furloughs to Mr. El Djebena.
But he can't be out more than 12 hours,
and he has to go to the police station.
Thank you.
Do you have anything to add?
Let the prisoner in.
Hello, Mr. El Djebena.
I authorize a furlough. You'll leave
at 7 am and must return by 7 pm.
That's disgusting.
Do something.
The door.
- Have a good day.
- Good day, sir.
Roll up the window.
Your phone. That's my number.
So you can find me.
Want to meet Djamila?
She's alone.
Do you have a TV in your cell?
- For a day?
- Until 7.
- How is Cesar?
- He was fine yesterday.
You'll leave this someplace for us.
- What then?
- You return.
- Cesar says you don't ask questions.
- Cesar says you'll pay me.
Later, all right?
- What do we do?
- Wait until he returns.
What if something goes wrong?
Who cares?
In the middle of nowhere.
There, to the right. Here, here,
to the right. Get closer.
There's a car in front.
The messenger's an Arab!
Do I let him in?
What the fuck?
- Who are you?
- Malik El Djebena.
- Who sent you?
- Luciani.
Luciani is in jail!
Who are you?
I'm doing time with him.
- Are you in jail or out?
- One day leave.
- Do you work for those bums?
- Don't work for anyone. I work for me.
- Everything in there?
- Yes
- Can I go now?
- Have you forgotten something?
You don't know about the exchange?
Let's go.
Shut up.
Call Cesar..
You have to call Cesar.
Hello. It's me.
I have a problem.
I'm not alone.
I'm with Santi.
- Calle de Madrid. They're waiting.
- We gotta go. Can you go back alone?
- Any message for Cesar?
- I'll call him. Be sure to arrive on time.
Maybe we'll work together again.
- What?
- You know..
God!
- How much?
- 25 kilos.
Take this too.
5,000.
€ 5,000.. and 25 kilos of hash?
All in a day?
We have guys to keep it and sell.
We'll supply them.
We use convoys and buy from
the source. The Gypsy has contacts.
We need three large cars.
Paris-Marbella in one night.
The first car to explore.
The second carries the load.
The third car as an escort.
They stay in contact by phone all night.
Each car has an exit.
- Wait, I've never done this before.
- So what's the problem?
None.
You focus on the city, I do the prison.
I'll make deals with leaving prisoners.
Jordi knows a trucker
who delivers to jails.
We invest half the money. We divide
the rest by 3. You, me and the Gypsy.
Okay.
Put a part in my account.
The rest we'll see.
- What time is it?
- 6.45.
Let me tell you something.
Come out whenever you want!
- Be careful.
- You too.
El Djebena Malik.
35-114T.
- How was the test?
- Car repairs.
- Do you like mechanics?
- Yes, definitely.
I'm in rehab.
Bend over.
Cough.
- Sampiero said we could do it again.
- What do you think?
- It's legal.
- You see?
- Who did you see after Sampiero?
- The friend who got me the garage.
Any problems?
I'll make myself clear. Your
furloughs are mine. Period.
- Here I am still your "Arab"?
- Yes, you do the dirty work.
Put your names on the
top right and fold it.
You have one hour for French.
Then we continue with Economics.
- Do we write here?
- Yes, directly on the test sheet.
ECONOMICS
You!
I've heard about your mother.
Gentlemen, go back.
We'll do the Economics test.
- El Djebena.
- Good morning.
- And the batteries?
- Large ones.
- Malik.
- Sophie.
Am I crazy or do they multiply?
Soon the carpets will come out.
We used to control the court.
Good thing they're dumb.
If they'd stop thinking with
their balls, they'd evolve more.
You should get closer
to see what's going on.
I don't understand.
What don't you understand?
- Want me to get a beating?
- Why would they beat you?
- Are you crazy? To them I'm a Corsican.
- What? Their eyes are blinded by shit.
Sends some guards to mingle with them.
They will eat from your hand.
Good thinking.
Just another Arab
thinking with his balls.
YOU ONLY LIVE TWICE
Let me introduce you to some friends.
The man in Marbella.
- This is Khalid!
- Your brother.
This is Mishka!
This is Damien. And here is Olivier.
Say hello to Malik.
- What's your name?
- My name's Fernanda. And I love cocks.
Marbella!
There, in Block C. What are the
Muslims doing? Smuggling? Drugs?
- They do their own things.
- Really? You get nothing?
Don't you think it would be nice
to send a pair of strong guys?
- Press them a little bit.
- Why press them?
Why? To show them who's boss,
which hand they have to kiss.
Isn't it obvious?
Before you were 20. Now you're 5.
Can't you see the difference?
- What kind of difference?
- I can't do for 5 what I did for 20.
If you can do nothing what good are you?
Want a transfer? I'll speak to Marcaggi.
- No, it's all right.
- What's all right?
- I'll manage. I'll see what..
- You'll manage?
Use your head! Tomorrow you tell
me what you can do for me.
We have a problem, brother.
- Make a petition. What can I say?
- Maybe Luciani can do something.
I don't understand. I was his lapdog
and now you ask me to lick your ass?
Not for myself, for our brothers.
To stop being his slave and be yours?
If you want a favor, learn to ask.
- What do you want?
- What could I want here?
- Respect.
- Do I look Corsican?
- You think they trust you?
- I'll see what I can do.
Luciani.
- Now the meetings are here?
- It's cozy, warm, with a sea view.
- Sit down.
- I'm fine here.
- So, what do you want?
- I have a problem in Marseille.
A cousin of yours, Brahim Lattrache.
I want you to pass a message.
Tell him Luciani wants to talk
to him face to face, okay?
- I'll see. What about the guards?
- I'll take care of that.
Brahim Lattrache in Marseille.
See the guy in red? He'll go to the end,
turn around and start again.
The two that are running..
See the little guy with the hat?
He'll do some push-ups.
Check the game.
Look at the hoop.
- Missed. Fuck him!
- No, the other.
For me you see nothing?
Yes.. snow.
Ok. I'll move aside.
Fuck you..
Quick, quick!
Ok
Latif, the Egyptian. They let a car
pass and then ambushed Riyad.
He was caught with hash.
Now they want money.
Who are those guys?
What do you know?
Nothing. I know their boss is called
Latif, the Egyptian. From the south.
They use the same road.
They know the secrets.
What do we do?
Give them what they ask.
Boss!
- Any news of his friend?
- None. What should I do?
It's been 3 days..
Calm down! There are many people
here and we have hash.
If anyone knows the Egyptian
we'll know, don't worry.
And he's going to hurt when I find him!
- How are you doing with the beards?
- Getting along.
Talk to them.. and investigate.
- I need a favor.
- What is it?
- I need information about someone.
- Who? - A black, Latif, the Egyptian.
Latif? What can I do?
- Tell me who he knows here.
- His brother-in-law.
- What's the deal?
- Nothing. It's my business.
See him?
The one over there.
With the blue cap.
Are the other two with him?
- Seems that way.
- Will the Muslims help?
- They give us two guys. - No problem.
If we plan well, everything'll be fine.
Shut up!
Boss! His ankle.
He needs a doctor.
Lights!
Mohammed Gaziler?
You know the Egyptian?
- You know him?
- Yes
Sit down.
Ouassila is your mother?
Is her address on the visitors' list?
Look.
If you want to see her alive, tell Latif
I want my friend and my stuff, okay?
- Okay?
- Agreed.
Call.
- Where were you?
- At the registrar's office.
Everything Ok?
- Have you eaten?
- I have to see a guy.
It can wait.
Come for coffee.
Help yourself.
I want to talk to you. I've seen you in
the yard with this tall guy, the Gypsy.
What's the business?
Hash, pills?
- Hashish.
- A lot?
- Want a part?
- No. It's your business, your business.
- How does it come in?
- The visiting rooms, the kitchens.
- So you bought off some guards.
- No. A dealer. Frozen food.
- So that's how it works?
- For the moment, yes.
What if you get caught?
The hole.
And no furloughs.
What did I say last time? To be careful.
Not to risk your outings.
What do you do? Fight with some guys.
Lay down your law. What's your game?
You're valuable with furloughs, Djebena.
If not, what good are you?
Get out.
Get out!
Bastard!
I'll kill you..
You don't fear me any more?
If you get around,
it's because I made you a porter.
If you eat it's thanks to me. If you
dream, think, live.. it's thanks to me.
You say you have no guards.
Bullshit!
You have Luciani etched on your face!
You live for me, Djebena!
They look at you and they see me. Who
else would they see? Can you tell me?
Are you here?
Come here.
Enough already.
Come here I said.
I have something fun
to tell you.
You're going to Marseille.
Your next leave will be to Marseille.
From Brecourt to Marseille in a day?
There is a flight at 9 am
and a return flight at 3.
There you will see Brahim Lattrache.
Should I take anything?
No. You talk and listen.
Find out the cost of cutting
ties to the Italians.
Tell him I'm interested in negotiating
without Jacky Marciaggi and the others.
Sampiero will contact your friend
for payment and expenses.
Have you ever flown?
Good morning, Truette.
- Morning, El Djebena.
- Good morning, sir.
Open up, please.
- Look at the time, I arrived on time!
- Careful! Don't talk to me like that.
- How should I talk? I'm at risk here.
- Okay, okay. I understand.
This car is a piece of shit!
A lure for the police.
- You're becoming an idiot.
- Enough is enough. - Why enough?
Who made you the boss?
If you want to split, say so.
Keep that for Latif's trunk.
Get Latif out of your head.
I'll find him and I'll finish him.
You won't finish anyone. Wake up.
Business has stopped.
It's nothing personal.
That bastard has blocked everything.
We got back the hash,
but we can't move it.
They even fucked us up in the city.
I swear I'll finish him off.
Fuck them!
You look like a lawyer.
Boarding at 9:55,
gate 33, Terminal 2.
Bon voyage.
Come forward.
Raise your arms.
- Hands!
- Why?
Hands!
Move..
Is this necessary?
I'm not worried.
What does Luciani want?
He wants to know your price to quit the
deal with the Italians in the casino.
If you agree, he'll gurantee your
position with the slot machines.
How will he guarantee our work?
With his ration card?
No, with the Council.
Sampiero will guarantee your place
with Marcaggi and the Corsican Council.
- How long have you known Luciani?
- From prison.
Have you worked for him
all this time?
How was it? Did you arrive
and begin to work?
- Does he protect you?
- No. I work. He doesn't protect me.
- You're his Arab. He protects you.
- No. I work for them.
At what price?
Are you the mole?
Do you send messages?
- Do you suck him off?
- What the hell is this?
Why does an Arab work for the Corsicans?
Do you belly dance for them?
Are you his girl? I had a friend there.
He never came out.
His name was Reyeb.
Sound familiar?
Was it Luciani who killed him?
What do you know?
Animals coming!
Watch out!
There! Two more!
Kill it!
What are you about?
How did you know this?
What are you? What are you?
A prophet or what?
I killed Reyeb.
Fuck. You've come a long way.
- What's your name?
- Malik.
- I'll wash your shirt and pants.
- The pants aren't dirty.
- You sure?
Then give me the shirt.
Here's your shirt, son. I washed it,
but the blood stains won't come off.
Hey, prophet! Tell me. The Muslims
want to talk about Luciani. Is that it?
You speak with the Muslims,
the Corsicans, you come here..
You deal with everyone. That's
not good for your balls, you know?
Do you also talk to Lingherri?
Looks like someone is spying among the
Corsicans. Does your boss know?
- Are you sure?
- Sure.
- Do you know him well?
- I think so..
Well, tell this to Luciani.
I accept his offer with one condition.
Find the spy and clean the house.
I need a favor. I'm having
trouble with a guy in Paris.
His name is Latif, the Egyptian.
You know him?
What can I do for you?
Can you tell him we know each other?
That we work together?
We work together..
You think I can say that?
Let's eat before you go.
- Can I go to the beach?
- Whatever.
Hurry!
Has everything gone well?
- You'll see Latif and talk to him.
- Really? With that asshole?
- Lattrache will talk to him.
- What does he have to do with it?
His problem is the Corsicans and ours,
Latif. We'll help each other.
I proposed a deal. Let's be partners. We
share everything. Caches, cars, vendors.
- We occupy the market and control it.
- Know what you're asking, brother?
We'll settle all accounts when the time
comes. For now we leave it as it is.
I'm sick again.
The test results are not
good. I need more chemo.
Will you be okay?
Take care, brother.
You're 30 minutes late.
You know the rules.
- All day working with car doors..
- Spread your legs.
I'll let it go this time, but think
about your probation, moron.
Use your watch.
I don't care about Marcaggi's gratitude.
What I want is for him to move
his ass and fix this.
As we speak one of us is sleeping
with the Italians. I want to know who.
- Does he know?
- Yes
- So?
He's negotiating with him..
- He thinks of himself.
- Same as Lattrache.
- Do you know who he is?
- No.
Wait, Cesar. Jacky wants
you out of this.
Neither on one side nor the other.
Out!
- He says if you need anything..
- Okay, okay. Understood.
I have good news.
About creating a hotel company. I've
found someone. A Basque from Pamplona.
- Why do you say "good news"?
- You asked me to look for someone.
Wait. We are talking about
Jacky, Sardinia, casinos,
You tell me not to interfere and
suddenly you speak of good news.
- The ones before were not good?
- Yes.
- Why then "good news now"?
- I didn't say "now".
- I can tell you two good things.
- Yeah? Why did it take you so long?
Thanks, boss.
Pass the papers.
- You got the results?
- Which match?
Why do you make coffee?
Because you're still a servant?
You go out for me, you see Sampiero,
you see Lattrache.
You take care of my business..
The casinos, the Lingherris.
And when I ask for coffee, you make it.
- Don't you have anything to say?
- Which is the question?
Why do I do it, or how I feel?
I do it because you ask me to.
- Want to know how I feel?
- No, no. I'm not interested.
- Do you still need me?
- It's you who needs me.
Can I go?
You hear me?
When will I see Latif?
Listen. Give my whole part
to Imam Moussab. All of it.
No idea.
Try the mosque.
I want him to know the money
is from Malik El Djebena.
He'll know how to find me.
Do as I say. Leave me
a message afterwards.
Move that ass, nigger.
- How you doing?
- Okay.
Is the money at the mosque yours?
Is it dirty money?
Of course it's dirty!
But it's better in his hands
than in mine.
Do you think the Imam will accept it?
It depends on you, friends.
I understand what you do here and I
respect that, but you have no power.
The Corsicans control the guards.
You pray in pigsties, you sleep in
shitty places. You rise..
and they crush you again. Perhaps the
Imam knows how to use that money.
What do you want?
Just like you, Hassan.
A better life for me and my brothers.
You think I'm stupid or what?
You just want to use us. That's all.
So? As long as it's good for everyone.
Listen. If you ever talk to
the Imam again, you're dead.
You talk money to me.
It's between us, okay?
Is that why you gave him the money?
To talk to me?
- From a killer to a killer?
- Leave that shit.
Just kidding.
Christmas
Handmade. No gifts, no Christmas.
- I am the gift. 100% handmade.
- What a gift!
Want some?
Help yourself.
Is it made from wild boar?
Are you kidding?
Shall we stop?
Can we talk honestly?
Why?
I have to ask you a favor,
but not because you work for me,
but because I trust you.
Do you see the difference?
I'm not sure.
I saw Vettori. He has some information.
He knows that I'm dealing
with the Lingherris.
Form a team.
How are your guys?
- A team for what?
- To eliminate them.
- Eliminate the Lingherris?
- The Lingherris & Jacky Marcaggi.
Kill Marcaggi? Is that it?
Kill your boss?
Nobody must know. You, me,
Vettori and nobody else.
It will be in Paris.
Vettori will provide the stuff. He'll
help, but we must remain invisible.
Can you do that for me?
Any plans for when you get out?
When we have the casinos, we'll
need someone to manage them.
With Lattrache.
We'll do it. We'll do it.
I only have six months.
- Six more months and that's it.
- Maybe they're wrong.
Give me time.
What's the problem?
- Kill those guys?
- Speak softly.
We don't know them.
What do we care?
Think about when you get out.
I won't be here.
You can think of your future, I can't.
Malik.. there's Djamila.
There's my son.
- What'll I leave them? A fridge? A TV?
- What are you saying?
You'll take care of them.
That's what I ask you, brother.
You'll say we agree.
And we'll do it.
I talked to my outside friend.
We'll do it.
He's put together a first class team.
I'll talk to my people. Give me the
number. Vettori will call your friend.
Have you tried this?
I'll give you some.
Are you listening? It's bad.
Our guys are good for drugs.
Not for other stuff.
- You were the one who wanted
to do it.What now?
- I can't force them.
When the Corsicans took out the
guns they ran away. Like devils.
That bastard Vettori
treats us like shit.
There was a fight on the way.
Now Khalid wants to kill him.
- Find some other guys.
- Now?
- For a contract?
- Who cares?
You got a minute.
I lost my time and money
with this group of idiots and..
just look at him!
- Be careful what you say.
- I will deliver you from your misery!
- Hands off!
- Calm down!
Hush! We will do it our way.
- What?
- I'll try to explain. May I?
- Listen. We'll kill them.
- Promise.
We'll kill them,
but they can't know how.
- I'm going to hit you. Lower you head.
- What?
I'll hit you and you lower your head.
I get it. Can I go on?
Pick me up without the others.
You and I will deal with this.
Will you be able to do it?
Guard!
Are you ready to complete your
insertion and rehabilitation project?
- It's a support center for detainees.
- I know Imam Moussab's Center.
You requested two days.
It seems excessive.
I propose a practice module of one day.
From 7am to 7 pm.
- Is that all right?
- Yes, very good.
Muhammed, peace be upon him, reached
the top of the mountain and fell asleep.
The angel Gabriel appeared.
Do you know what he said?
He said, "Pray, pray, Muhammed.
Pray to God because He created you. "
"He created mankind from scratch.
Pray what He taught in his writings. "
Wonderful!
Wonderful, brother!
Prayer.
The door.
Have a good day, Djebena.
- What about the others?
- In the back.
The car comes out here.
A bodyguard and a driver. The guard
gets out first to open the door.
He wears a bulletproof vest.
We let them get out.
We hit the bodyguard first,
then the others.
Come on.
They're coming out.
Coming.
Black car.
Wait for them to come out.
I'll go for the bodyguard.
What's going on?
Come on, come on!
See them?
Yes, now I see them.
- Three cars in front.
- Follow them!
It's turning. What do we do?
They stopped!
- Go on. I'll kill them.
- How? It's an armored car.
I tell you it's armored. If they don't
come out, there's nothing we can do.
What's he doing?
Buying tobacco.
- I'll go.
- It won't work.
Macarggi here!
Down!
I can't hear!
I hear nothing!
This blood is not mine.
It's theirs.
We've fucked you up, pigs!
Are you Jacky Marcaggi?
Don't talk. I can't hear. Just signs.
Do you know this guy?
Your friend Luciani sent us to kill you.
I won't do it. He's all yours.
- Get revenge!
- I'll take care of him.
- Are you sleeping?
- No, no. I'm exhausted.
- Have you talked to Djamila?
- I'll sleep in the kids' room.
- You won't go back tonight?
- No, I'll go back tomorrow.
- They'll put you in a punishment cell.
- As the Corsicans kill each other.
Need anything?
I'm not doing chemo.
You're screwed.
Watch your sleeve.
You're rubbing it on the plate.
- Eat a little, Riyad.
- I'm eating.
- Want some more?
- No thanks.
- Any good?
- Yes, delicious.
El Djebena, Malik.
35114T.
40 days, 40 nights
Are you there?
Make sure you have everything
and sign here.
Garbage.
Your exit papers.
The door.
- Good luck, Djebena.
- Good day, sir.
How are you?
- It's cold.
- Very.
It's not a good time to come out.
- Have you come by bus?
- Yes
- When's the next one?
- Half an hour.
- Want to walk a little?
- If you like.
Do you know where you're going to live?
Come home. I'll sleep with the
child and you use his room.
- I don't want to disturb.
- You won't.
Okay.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326