Shochiku Films
Early Summer
Participant in the 1951 Arts Festival
Written by
Kogo Noda & Yasujiro Ozu
Produced by
Takeshi Yamamoto
Cinematography by
Yuharu Atsuta
Art Direction by
Tatsuo Hamada
Cast:
Setsuko Hara as Noriko Mamiya
Chishu Ryu as Koichi Mamiya
Chikage Awashima as Aya Tamura
Kuniko Miyake as Fumiko Mamiya,
Ichiro Sugai as Shukichi Mamiya
Chieko Higashiyama as Shige Mamiya,
Haruko Sugimura as Tami Yabe
Hiroshi Nihonyanagi
as Kenkichi Yabe
Shuji Sano as Sotaro Satake
Directed by
Yasujiro Ozu
- Breakfast, Grandpa
- Morning
- Come on
- I'll be right there
I told him
Take this with you
- Some pickles
- Thanks
Where's Isamu?
Isamu!
- Looks delicious
- Isamu!
Isamu!
- Have you washed your face?
- Yes
No, you haven't. Your face is still dirty
Hurry up, Isamu
- Done already?
- I washed my face!
If you don't believe me,
check the wet towel
All right
You sure?
- Here
- Thank you
- We've started
- Will you post this for me?
Chew your food well
- You're off early
- I've got a very sick patient
- I'll bring uncle back with me
- I appreciate it
- See you later
- Bye
Bye!
Hurry, Brother!
You only have seven minutes
Are you coming?
Where will we meet?
Noriko and I have decided
on a place
See you later
Thanks for breakfast!
Hurry up, Isamu
What kind of food does uncle like?
You don't have to cook anything
special, but he likes beans
- Me, too!
- Just be quiet and eat
You're slow, Isamu
Thanks for breakfast
- I'll be off
- Have a good day
- See you at 5:30
- All right. See you later
You'll be late for school
Don't forget father's post
Thanks. Bye for now
See you later
What are you doing?
- Bye!
- Have a good day
- You've got everything?
- Yes!
Bye!
- Morning
- Morning. Where's your brother?
- He caught the earlier train
- I see
- So there's a very sick patient?
- Yes, I was there till 11:00 last night
- I'm enjoying Les Thibault
- Where are you up to?
- Halfway through the fourth volume
- I see
Now your toes are all neat and clean
Here's a treat for you
Here. You love your grandpa?
Very much?
- Very much
- Really? Here
I love you
- Here
- I love you
That's enough
- I hate you
- Hey!
- I hate you very much!
- Stop it!
An order's come in
for our new product
- What about Asahi Processing?
- That's still pending
Know a good cafe?
Well, I'd recommend the Luna
in West Ginza
- It's a tiny place, though
- Luna?
Did you give that stuff
to the director?
Yes, why?
That's fine
Yes?
- Hello
- Ah, here comes the debt collector
- Are you busy?
- Very busy
It must mean the business
is going well
Thank you
What happened the other night?
It was very entertaining.
Mr Yada started singing again
What a shame
It made mother's heart act up again
Don't worry,
the old bag's not about to die yet
Did you hear?
Chako's getting married
I didn't know. To whom?
- Mr Tsumura. Don't you know him?
- Mr Tsumura?
He played basketball
for Waseda University
I don't know him. Is it a love match?
She's had a crush on him forever
You're a sad sight,
like two jealous old maids!
Here, I hope it doesn't bounce
- Thank you
- You're welcome
- I'm going out
- Where to?
Mr Robert's hotel.
If he calls, I'll be there at 2:00
Could you give me a lift?
- It's out of your way
- I'll continue home from there
- Will you come by later?
- I can't today
- All right. Bye
- Bye
SHIKIKAWA'S
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thank you
What's this?
- Some sort of seafood
- Squills
- Some more?
- I've had enough
- You certainly can drink, can't you?
- It tastes good
- Won't you have a bit more?
- Maybe just a drop
I'm not wasting it.
You don't need to drink just to keep up
- What's funny?
- That's so typical of him
- He's always like that
- Like what?
You have a habit of offering
something and then taking it back
She said she'd had enough
- You have no sense of etiquette
- What do you mean?
- Is the tempura good, sis?
- Really good
You're always bringing up etiquette
at every turn...
...expecting men to be kind to women
by law or something
But you're mistaken
Men and women should have respect
for each other
That's what etiquette really means
So you do know. That's good
- I didn't think he did
- Idiot!
- Noriko, do you want some rice?
- Yes, please
It's been deplorable since the war
Women have become so forward,
taking advantage of etiquette
That's not true.
We've just taken our natural place
- Men have been too forward till now
- Hear, hear!
That's why you can't get married
It's not "can't", it's "won't"!
I could any time, if I wanted to
Lies!
- Just don't marry a doctor
- Never!
What? You two are impossible
We should hurry
if you still want to go to Ginza
Really?
He's coming on the 9:45 train.
We have plenty of time
When was the last time uncle visited?
A year after the war ended.
The station was so crowded
That's right. I was still wearing
those wartime trousers
He's kept in good health
through it all
This rice tastes good
I remember that scroll
from the house in Yamato
What happened to the other one
that was shaped like a fan?
- The one shaped like a fan...
- Oh, I sold it
Really?
This one's really nice
Prices have gone up, times are hard
You're working on Sunday?
Yes. Shall I bring back
some treats for uncle?
But he can't chew anything hard
All right, then I'll be going
See you later
Bye!
Noriko, take this up to uncle
Is that all, sis?
Here's some tea for you, Uncle
How old are you now, Noriko?
Twenty-eight
- She's 28 now
- Is that right?
About time to get married
Some women don't want
to get married
You're not one of them, are you?
- Here's my share, 570 yen
- I have change
- Don't bother
- No, I insist. I've got some
- Here
- Thanks
We could've cooked that same meal
for a third of the price
- Not nearly as delicious, though
- But the whole family could’ve eaten
I almost forgot.
How much was the coffee in Ginza?
That's my treat
- No, how much?
- It was my treat
Are you sure? Thank you
- Auntie
- What?
What is it?
- Is Uncle deaf?
Not at all
But he can't hear me
Yes, he can
Idiot
Speak louder!
- Aren't you tired, Uncle?
- Maybe...
How old are you now?
Twenty-eight
Well, it's about time
you got married, isn't it?
Do you know any good men
in Yamato?
Someone rich...
...who can make me happy
and give me a very easy life?
What a lovely day!
- Good afternoon
- Afternoon
Taking a walk with grandma, Mitsuko?
Where are you off to?
The weather's too nice to stay in
- Is your father home?
- No, he's with your brother
At the conference?
I hope he's a help and not a hindrance
to your brother
Quite the opposite, I'm sure
Your dress is so pretty
- I hear you have a guest
- He's here with me
Is that so?
Isamu, give uncle some sweets
Here
Eh? He eats the paper too
He must be enjoying this
I hope he can hear the show
We got him a seat
right near the front
Takako's taking a long time
in her bath
- Why did she leave home?
- Well...
When I got home from downtown,
she was here crying
Then she asked me
to let her stay the night
- She had a fight with her husband
- But they're such a happy couple
Maybe too happy
Ah, Noriko's here
Thanks for the bath
- When did you get here?
- Not long ago
Why are you staring at me?
- You were too happy
- What?
- In your marriage
- Not at all
- What were you fighting about?
- Nothing at all
- It wasn't "nothing at all"!
- What happened?
- You know our dog?
- What dog?
My pet dog Chibi
It chewed his pipe
He left it lying around,
so of course the dog chewed it
It's a nice pipe from London
or somewhere
He blamed me, so I served him carrots
every day out of spite
- The dog hates carrots?
- Not the dog, my husband!
- A horse would have loved them
- Idiot!
Anyhow, he blew his top this morning
- Over something so trivial?
- It was really upsetting
You just have to be patient with him
- You're a married woman
- So what?
You have to put up with it.
Doesn't she?
It's only natural, isn't it?
All husbands are selfish like that
That's why we won't get married
That's right, isn't it?
What? You know nothing
about married life
- Married life?
- Only married people understand
Once you're hitched,
it's too late to understand
I'm going home
Yes, you should
It's for the best
He'll still be eating carrots
Then I'm staying
- Not going home?
- No
- Then spend the night here
- So you'll go?
- No
Make up your mind!
Takako, your husband's on the phone
Oh, really? Thank you
- Aya, shall I bring it up?
- What?
You know.
Should I ask Noriko about it?
- About what?
- This
Your heart?
She wants your brother
to examine her
- Do you think he'd see her?
- You?
Yes. I feel sick whenever
I drink a few tiny cups of sake
- Then stop drinking!
- In my business I have to drink
My heart starts racing
Someone recommended
moxa treatment...
...so I went to this place
in Yokohama
- I've heard this already
- I'm talking to Noriko not you
- I'll explain it to Noriko later. Right?
- Of course
I hope you will. Thank you
Oh, by the way,
your boss is upstairs
- Alone?
- He just got here
- I should go and say hello
- What?
I still have time
- Are you staying, Noriko?
- Are you going home?
Yes, I'm going.
Thanks for everything
Why? Sit down and relax
I can't.
He's waiting for me in Ginza
Who? Mr Carrot?
Yes. Sorry
Go on, then
You're going to Chako's wedding,
aren't you?
No, I'm not going
Excuse me
Oh, you're here?
Come and sit down
Hill Enterprises called
after you left
- And?
- I did as you said
Thank you
Have a drink
Oh, I'm glad you came.
I wanted to talk to you
- Are you...?
- Yes?
Why don't you get married?
It's about time
I have a good prospect
A man from my old university,
a little older than me
He lived in Calcutta for a long time
His name's Manabe. A good man
He's never been married.
I'm not sure if he's still a virgin
I have some photos of him
They're not that clear.
This is him
Have a look
This one, too
He's a better golfer than me,
and better looking
- Sorry but...
- What?
I have to go and meet someone
- Are you trying to escape?
- No, but my parents are at Kabuki
Really? Then take my car
- If you don't mind, it's to Shinbashi
- Fine
Thank you
Take these with you
Ask your folks their opinion
Come on, take them
All right, thank you
- Sorry to keep you waiting
- Thanks
Aren't you sleepy, Uncle?
Brother, you must be tired
No
Why don't you go to bed?
You have an early train tomorrow
I really enjoyed the play today
The young actors were so good
Really admirable
Really? I'll have to see it
I'm glad you liked it
- I'm off to bed
- All right
Come and see me in Yamato
I will,
after Noriko's been sorted out
You must come. Shige, as well
Yamato is the best place to live
Leave this house to the youngsters!
I agree.
Koichi's independent now
I'd love to visit you
Right, I'm going to bed
- 'Night all
- Goodnight
Goodnight
Mr Satake was talking to me
about marriage
Uncle was talking
about the same thing, too
Really? I'm suddenly very popular!
- So what did your boss say?
- I didn't have time to listen
- May I take this hot water?
- Of course
- A visitor for Dr Mamiya
- Who is it?
It's a Mrs Tamura from Tsukiji
All right, I'll see her
- Any test results yet?
- Not yet
That's odd
How do you do? I'm Dr Mamiya
Pleased to meet you. I'm Aya's mother
- Have a seat
- Thank you
Your sister Noriko is such
a good friend to my daughter
So, I hear you're concerned
about your heart
I wanted to ask you
to examine me, Doctor
If I can be of any help
I'm sure you can, but I'm sorry
to bother you when you're so busy
Not at all
Thank you
By the way,
congratulations about Noriko
Aya and I are very happy for her
- What do you mean?
- Mr Satake found a man for her
Is that right?
He seems like a fine man
He's the young director of a company
with a very good reputation
- And he's very smart
- I see
He's from a very old family
from Zentsuji in Shikoku
They keep up their manor
in the best traditional style
I see...
- Well, shall we begin?
- Yes
- This way
- Thank you for making time for me
I'm home
Welcome home. You're early today
- Is Noriko home yet?
- No
- She's at her friend's wedding
- Which one?
Chako. You don't know her
- The bath's ready
- Good
Your father's taking his now
That woman from Tsukiji
came in today
Oh, Aya's mother?
She's really something
Does she have a bad heart?
It's her nose, not her heart
How's the bath, Father?
Very nice. Just right
Good
Mr Satake's friend sounds
like a good match for Noriko
You know about that?
That woman from Tsukiji told me
- She said he's a company director
- Really?
He looks like a good man
- You've seen him?
- I saw his photograph
- Noriko's got a picture of him?
- Yes
Isamu, go to your room
- What's he like?
- It was a golfing picture, not very clear
Go to your room!
Sounds good
- I think so, too
- Shall I ask around about him?
Yes. I have the feeling that
he could be a good match
Go away, Isamu!
- He sounds promising
- I agree
...six, seven, eight, nine, ninety
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, one hundred!
That was 200
20 yen!
For that, I should get more
Isamu, give grandma
a little extra massage
Is Isamu going to massage me now?
Thank you
With this 20 yen,
I'll have saved 300 yen, Grandma
Very good.
But what are you saving for?
A model train track
But you already have some
I need more to make
a really long track. Right, Isamu?
I see
The bath was good. Just right
Father...
- Noriko has received a proposal
- Really?
- It seems very promising
- That's good to hear
- It's about time she got married
- She's 28 already
That's right.
I hope it's a good match
I think so.
I'll ask around about him
Yes, do that. And right away
- It's not fair to say that
- You don't think so?
- Any bride would be like that
- But I've never seen her like that
Yes, putting on airs, looking all prim
- Where was your honeymoon?
- Chuzenji
We went to Atami
It started raining that very day.
We couldn't go out for three days
It rained solidly every day. We didn't
know what to do with ourselves
Mari, why are you telling us this?
Just a documentary report
We asked a hotel employee
for a top
- A top?
- Yes, you know?
A spinning top painted with flags
- We passed the time playing with it
- Oh, really?
- My husband's very good at it...
- Really? Oh, really?
You shouldn’t flaunt it
in front of the single girls
How silly! We don't play
with spinning tops, do we?
We're not children, are we?
Single girls just don't understand,
do they?
- No, they don't
- You have to feel sorry for them
Takako! How can you say that?
- What is it?
- She has no right
Right, I'm leaving
Single people don't know
what real happiness is
They have no right to talk
Look who's talking, Mrs Carrot!
Single people have no say!
You always go on about happiness,
but it's just anticipation
Like before you go to the races,
planning which horse to bet on
Then dreaming about
how you’ll spend your winnings
You're wrong. You don't know
You don't know
- You too?
- Don't back down!
- I'm leaving, too
- Leave, you dreamers!
Shall we go to Kamakura,
to Noriko's?
Please do.
It's a beautiful season
How about Sunday after next?
Sounds good.
How about you, Aya?
I can go anytime,
because I'm not married. Right?
She's at it again!
I'm home!
Noriko?
- Shall I lock the door?
- Yes
- Finally home!
- Welcome
- How was Chako?
- She looked so lovely
The reception was magnificent
- Was she in Western dress?
- No, a kimono
Would you like to try a bit?
What is it?
Shortcake! It looks delicious
I went to the Ginza with some friends
They're coming to Kamakura
next Sunday
Really?
I'll cook something special
Please have some
- You don't want any?
- I've had enough
Thank you
My friends are funny.
We always split into two groups...
...the married and the single
- Aya got all worked up again
- How come?
Because the married ones
look down on us for being single
Why not get married, then?
- You're on their side?
- Of course
Oh, dear!
I'll think about it, then
You should. How about the man
Mr Satake suggested?
He sounds nice
Mr Satake speaks very highly of him
Oh! You scared me!
Were you awake all this time?
She doesn't seem against the idea
I know. I think it's a possibility
She may accept. Try and ask her
This cake tastes really good
Is it?
- I'll buy more next time
- Please do
Noriko can be stubborn
so be tactful
I know. Leave it to me
Tell her that her father approves,
but don't press her too much
Don't worry
Do your best, all right?
Hello?
- Hello?
- Who is it?
Hello. Long time no see
Ah, Aunt Tami. Come in
Very well. Thank you
Sorry I haven't seen you
for such a long time
Where's Koichi's wife?
She went shopping.
Please make your self comfortable
Here's something for you
from my hometown
I hope you like it.
It arrived this morning
You're always very kind
Oh, it's nothing
We had a strange visitor
this morning
Oh? Who was it?
I'd never seen him before
A man with parted hair,
glasses and a black bag
At first, I thought
he was from the tax office
- But I was wrong
- Who was he?
He was from one of those
reference agencies
He asked me questions
about Noriko
Did he really?
Then I realised that it must be
about her marriage
They're doing a background check
- I asked him who was interested
- Did you?
He just scratched his head
and tried to laugh it off
I got so annoyed, I told him
he'd never find a better girl
I gave him what for!
Oh, my!
Turns out, that horrible little man
knew quite a lot
He even knew that both our sons
were classmates...
Oh, hello
Welcome
Thank you for being so kind
to Kenkichi
And how are you?
I'm fine, thank you
Your son has become a fine doctor
Thank you, but all he does
since his wife died is read books
- It's been two years, hasn't it?
- Yes. How time flies
- What about your son Shoji?
- He won't be coming back
Some people have returned
recently from the south
I've given up hope
There you go
My wife still thinks
he's alive somewhere
I know how it is. You can't help it
Every day, she listens to
the Missing Persons Hour on the radio
It's funny how our memories work
I forget about recent things...
...yet I remember everything
about Shoji so vividly
He won't be coming home
PHYSICIAN
You were stationed
in Zentsuji, right?
That's right
Ever hear of a man called Manabe?
No. Who is he?
Never mind
- Sakaguchi was at Zentsuji
- Was he really?
He might know him.
He knows a lot of people
That's a stalemate position
- Was this here?
- No, it was there
There are so many kids
around here now
It's extra noisy on Sundays
My house is filled with them today
I can't stay in that position
Watch your legs! Careful!
There it goes!
More speed
Here it comes!
- Coming!
- Almost!
- Is this ready?
- Yes, take it in
What a crowd!
Lunch, everyone
Sandwiches for lunch!
Sandwiches!
Let's eat on the terrace
Don't step on the tracks!
Here, take this
Buy me some more track, Mum
You have enough
It belongs to my friends.
I only have eight pieces
- Buy me some more
- Why not use your pocket money?
It's not enough.
I want to make it longer. Right, Isamu?
- Buy me more, Mum
- I'll ask Father
Ask him, then
Tell him it's 32mm-gauge.
Don't forget!
- You're so crafty
- Shut up!
- Will you buy me some?
- No way
Hello?
- Welcome
- Hello
- Mari called to say she can't come
- Really?
- Has Takako come yet?
- No
Oh, what a crowd!
Just look at that!
Just go away!
- Hello
- Welcome. Please come in
How lovely
- A little something for your mother
- Thank you very much
The sky's so beautiful here
I can't even see the sky where I live!
- Where's your father?
- The museum with my mother
What did Mari say?
Her husband's going away on business.
She really wanted to come
I see...
How inconvenient.
If I were her, I'd have come
It's not that simple for her
She could have come.
She has a maid to help her
Maybe a wife has other worries
- We single women wouldn't know
- Right!
Help yourself
Kamakura is such a nice place
I wish I could live here
Noriko, phone call for you!
- From Oiso
- Is it?
Hello? Takako? What is it?
Really?
I see...
Takako just called. She's in Oiso
Oiso?
Her father's sick
That's not true. He's on a trip,
I read it in the newspaper
Is that so?
This party was her idea as well
I wonder why she didn't come
We've been dumped
Because we're fussy, right?
We were such close friends
in school
Now we're slowly drifting apart
Can't be helped.
That's how it is, it seems
I can't bear it
Shall we go to the beach later?
Yes, shall we?
- Have something to eat
- Let's eat
Pass me the juice
This may be the happiest time
for our family
We'll be sad when Noriko leaves us
to get married
You're right
What do you think
of Mr Satake's plan?
I hope it works out.
It's time she got married
How time flies
Koichi got married,
our grandchildren were born...
...and now Noriko's getting married
This may be the happiest time
of our lives
You think so?
But we'll still have happy times
We mustn't ask for too much
I've really enjoyed today
Look
Some child somewhere
must be crying
Remember how Koichi cried
when he lost his balloon?
Hello? Hello. Yes, it is
- It's from home
- Oh, thanks
Hello? Fumiko? It's me
I have to stay tonight
to keep watch on a patient
Is Noriko home? I see
Her prospects seem very good.
Sakaguchi told me
I'll tell you when I get home
All right. I understand
What? Oh, I see
Goodnight
- Is he staying over?
- Yes
How marvellous. It looks delicious
- How much was it?
- 900 yen
- 900 yen? That?
- Yes
For that? That's so expensive!
- Is it their usual price?
- Yes
I've lost my appetite
Come on, pass me the plates
I shouldn’t have asked you
The plates, the plates!
I feel terrible. I shouldn’t have
asked you to buy it
Will you pay for half of it?
Me? Forget it
- I will, I will!
- You're serious?
Here
- It's so expensive, though
- But this bakery is the best
It costs as much
as half a pound of wool
But it's a rare occasion, I suppose
- Good evening!
- Who is it?
It's Yabe
- Welcome
- Tonight your brother...
- He just called, he's staying overnight
- I see
- Please come in
- Thank you
Good evening
Here you are
- Thank you for stopping by
- Not at all
- Where are your parents?
- Gone to bed
Please
My timing was good.
You don't mind me having this?
Please do
- Are you celebrating something?
- Why?
Do you eat cake like this often?
Not that often
I wish I could
- May I?
- Please
It must've cost a lot
It was quite reasonable, right?
It was cheap, so don't worry
It's good
Noriko, I believe
congratulations are in order
Really?
So I've heard
Really? How wonderful.
What's the occasion?
I'm right, aren't I?
Maybe...
- And you too, I hear
- Me?
- Your mother said so
- That's just an idea in her head
I think you should remarry.
Shouldn't he?
Yes, it would be good
for little Mitsuko, too
- I heard the lady's really nice
- Mother's just getting all excited
Are you not going to eat that?
If not, I will
- I certainly am!
- Are you sure? Too bad
It's so good
Hide the cake
What is it?
Evening, Minoru
I'm home
Hi, Dad
Great!
Look, Mum! Great!
Welcome home
Isamu, dad bought us some track!
This is great!
Great!
Hands off and wait!
Dad's great! Let's see
What's this?
- Bread
- Shut up!
Idiot!
- Where's mother?
- In the bathroom?
Mother?
My belt...
The proposal for Noriko
seems very promising
That's very good
Sakaguchi says the man is
from a very good family in Zentsuji
- He is the second son
- Really?
He's in the social register
and seems to be a fine businessman
I see. How nice.
And how old is he?
He was born in the 43rd year
of the Meiji Era, so he's...42
- 42?
- That's about right
- Forties, huh?
- He's that much older than Noriko?
Age doesn't matter!
- But that's too old for Noriko
- That's right
So what age is good?
Noriko's not so young herself
She can't be too choosy
or she'll never get married
As long as he's respectable,
we shouldn’t be picky
I just feel sorry for her
Sorry for her? Why?
What do you mean?
With that kind of attitude,
you’ll spoil things for Noriko
- I wonder...
- Yes, you will
Aren't you asking for too much?
You always do this
- Yes, but...
- But what?
What does Noriko think?
- You said she'd accept
- Yes, but...
Didn't you tell me that?
- You said so
- But it was you who...
Idiot! Stop twisting things around!
Am I asking for too much?
What's wrong?
He scolded me
It's all right
We're all just concerned for Noriko
Don't worry about it
Liar! Liar!
I wanted train track, not that!
Stop that!
This stupid thing!
Why did you do that?
You do not kick food around!
Liar!
That's a bad thing to do!
- You understand?
- Let me go!
Isamu, come here!
I'm home!
Where are you going?
Have you been scolded?
- Where are you going?
- I don't know
I'm home
Did you scold them again?
You're in a bad mood
You shouldn’t scold them
when you're angry
- I feel sorry for them
- Why?
- They've grown scared of you
- Don't lecture me
I'm not lecturing you.
You're always...
Just mind your own business
Very well
- I'm home
- Welcome back
He's in a bad mood, isn't he?
Idiot! Idiot!
Isamu! Come on!
Where can they be?
Where, indeed?
They'll be getting hungry now
Yes, they will be. Poor things
Aren't they back yet?
Not yet.
Where could they have got to?
It's getting late
I'll go and have another look
- But, Father...
- No, I'm going
Good evening. Anybody in?
- Is that you, Noriko?
- Yes
Did our boys come here?
- No
- They didn't?
No. What's wrong?
They've been out all day
and still aren't back
Really? Where can they be?
What's up?
- Will you help her find the boys?
- All right
- Let's go
- Thank you
- Those sandals have got holes in
- They're fine
It's dark out, be careful!
Check the road
that goes towards Hase
And don't forget
to check the train station
And the back lanes, too!
- Your turn
- Is it?
Why did you get so angry with them?
Don't be too harsh on them.
Children are sensitive
You shouldn’t lose your temper
I know I shouldn’t
- It's not easy
- Right, it's not easy
Hello? Yes?
Ah, Mrs Mamiya? How are you?
Yes, he's here
- For me?
- Yes, your wife
Hello? It's me
Really? They're home?
That's good
I see. I'll be home soon
- They're home
- Thank goodness
They were starving
and just sitting in the train station
- Poor boys
- They're such a bother
- I'll be off
- Yes, you'd better
They take after me more and more
But only my bad side, unfortunately
That's just how it goes
- Don't forget our conversation
- What?
They want that position
at Akita Hospital filled right away
I'll ask him tomorrow
- See you
- All right
- Goodnight
- Let me know
I'm home
Mitsuko, my good little girl
You mustn't go outside
You're early. Are you hungry?
- There's fried rice
- Fine
- Mother?
- What?
- I have something to tell you
- What is it?
Come and sit down
What is it?
- I'm thinking of going to Akita
- Akita? On a business trip?
They've asked me to run the internal
medicine department at Akita Hospital
- They asked you?
- Yes
The offer came through Mr Mamiya
He told me I'd be called back
to Tokyo in a few years
What do you think?
I'd like to go.
But I can always go on my own
- You can't do that!
- Will you come with me then?
- How about it?
- Well...
It's far away
Not keen? I'd get a big raise
Can't you find a job like that
in Tokyo?
No, posts like that are only
in the provinces
Listen, Mother,
it's a great opportunity for me
I know that, but...
And I can do my research
on local problems there
They promised I could return
to Tokyo in three or four years
I don't know when I might get
another opportunity like this
What do you think, Mother?
I'll accept, all right?
You have a bad habit of going quiet
when you're angry, Mother
Yes?
- Hello
- Hello. What is it today?
- I was just in the neighbourhood
- Well, have a seat
- Where's Noriko?
- She's out
- Mr Manabe came by last night
- Did he say anything?
Not much
- What about Noriko?
- What about her?
- Marrying Mr Manabe
- She hasn't said anything yet
I see...
- Will you ask her about it?
- Me?
- I don't understand her
- What do you mean?
- Is she interested in men?
- What do you think?
Sometimes she seems to be,
and sometimes she doesn't
- Has she always been like that?
- Yes
- Has she ever been in love?
- I don't think so
But she used to have an album
of Katharine Hepburn photos this thick
Who's Hepburn?
- The American actress
- A woman?
- Yes
- Is she queer?
No way!
You can never know.
She's very strange, in any case
- Why don't you teach her?
- About what?
- Everything
- What do you mean, everything?
Don't try to be coy
Don't talk to me like that!
- That's rude!
- Sorry
Bring some tea
Or some coffee?
Nothing, thank you
Noriko's late
She might not be back today.
She's seeing her brother
That was mean of you.
You could’ve told me sooner
- How about going out for some sushi?
- All right
- What is your favourite sushi?
- Tuna
- Tuna? How about an open clam?
- Sure
- And a rice roll?
- No way
You're a strange one, too
Shoji and I often used to come here
when we were students
- Did you?
- We always sat at this table
- Really?
- That painting was there, too
Time flies, doesn't it?
It does
We quarrelled a lot,
but I loved my brother very much
I still have a letter from him
It came through the military post.
He'd enclosed a wheat stalk
At that time, I was reading
Wheat And Soldiers
- Could you let me have it?
- Of course. I'd like you to have it
Thank you. Oh, there he is
- Been waiting long?
- Not too long
- Shall we go? What shall we eat?
- I'll eat anything
It's your farewell dinner,
make him treat you
Of course.
But nothing too expensive
- Stingy!
- Expensive dishes aren't always good
Shall we go?
- Good evening
- Who is it?
- It's me
- Ah, Noriko?
Welcome. Please come in
Thanks
- Mitsuko's fast asleep
- Yes
You're packing?
I'm not making much headway, though
This is a little farewell gift
from my family
Oh, you shouldn’t have.
You're very kind
Thank you very much
Where's Kenkichi?
Still at his farewell party
even though he's off tomorrow
When will you join him?
As soon as I finish
cleaning this place up
It must be hard work
Thanks for all your kindness
over the years
- Is this your first trip to Akita?
- Yes
The furthest north I've been
is Utsunomiya
I see
You’ll be back in a few years
That's what Kenkichi says, too
- It's true
- I hope he's right
I wanted him to get remarried...
...and then we could live
the rest of our lives here
Actually...
I hope you won't be offended,
and please don't tell Kenkichi
- What is it?
- Well...
I know it's an impossible dream...
...but I just wish Kenkichi had
got married to someone like you
- That's what I thought
- Really?
I'm sorry.
It's just a wish in my heart
Please don't be angry with me
- Do you mean it?
- What?
Do you really feel
that way about me?
Forgive me, I didn't mean
to hurt your feelings
You wouldn’t mind
an old maid like me?
Then I accept
- Really?
- Yes
- You mean it?
Are you sure?
You really mean it?
How happy I am!
This is so wonderful
Thank you so much!
Thank goodness I mentioned it,
or this would never have happened
See? Sometimes it's good
that I talk so much
Oh, I am so happy!
I feel so relieved
Noriko, let's have some
red-bean buns
No, thank you. I ought to go now
Why?
Please wait a little.
Kenkichi will be home soon
But it's already so late
Very well
- Can I really believe it?
- Yes
- You promise? Are you sure?
How happy I am!
- Goodbye
- Goodnight
And thank you. Thank you
- Welcome back
- Thanks for last night
- When's your train tomorrow?
- It's the 8:45 to Aomori
- Well, goodnight
- Goodnight
I'm home
Did you see Noriko?
Did she say anything?
Nothing in particular
Listen, she said
she'd join our family
She promised she would
You see, I told her
what's been on my mind
It was good that I did.
I didn't think she'd accept
- What's this about?
- She'll join our family
- What for?
- What do you mean, "what for"?
She's agreed to marry you,
to become your wife
- My wife?
- Yes!
Isn't it wonderful?
I'm so happy for you
I'm absolutely overjoyed!
You must be happy too.
I'm really glad for you
- Then stop crying
- I can't help it
If you’re happy, then show it
You are happy, aren't you?
- Yes, I'm happy
- Then don't hold back. Show it!
What an odd boy you are!
Is Noriko back yet?
I heard her come in
a few minutes ago
- Father
- What is it?
- You too, Mother
- What?
Please come downstairs
- What is it?
- Please sit down
- Well?
- Noriko wants to marry Yabe
Kenkichi?
Yes. She says she promised
his mother just now
But he's leaving for Akita
tomorrow morning
That's why I decided
This is important. Have you given it
careful consideration?
He has a child, too
We've all been concerned
about you getting married
You must've known that
Why didn't you at least talk
to father and mother?
Have you thought this through?
You acted rashly
I don't know about father and mother,
but I don't like this match
But I...
When his mother talked to me,
I didn't feel a moment's hesitation
I suddenly felt that
I'd be happy with him
That's why I accepted
Are you sure
you won't be sorry later?
I don't think so
Are you positive
you won't regret this later?
- I'm sure
- You're sure? Absolutely sure?
I'm sure
Don't you feel chilly, dear?
Shall we go back to bed?
Let's go back to sleep
It was thoughtless of her
to decide on her own
She acts like she grew up
all by herself
What should we do?
Should we let her?
Why not? It's her own decision
Maybe something can still be done
What could we do now?
She's made up her mind
You know how she is
Yes?
There's a visitor for you
in reception
All right
- Thanks for seeing him off
- I'm glad that he got a seat
He couldn’t have stood
all the way to Akita
- He's lucky
- What brings you here?
- The station was too crowded to talk
- About what?
I couldn’t possibly ask you
with all those people around...
...but I kept thinking about it
after we parted
- What is this about?
- About last night
I still can't believe it.
It feels like it was a dream
Did your parents approve?
- Yes
- And your brother?
- Don't worry
- Really? They approved?
Wonderful, wonderful
But what does Kenkichi think?
Kenkichi?
He's overjoyed.
He didn't sleep a wink last night
We ate again
in the middle of the night
Really?
I'll live a nice long life,
thanks to you
I feel so relieved now
Well, I'll be going now.
I'm so happy!
- This is the way out
- Oh, is it?
Oh, I'm so happy!
Fumi, can you pull it from that end?
I wonder if she did the right thing,
deciding on her own
I wonder too
She didn't have to marry
someone with a child
You're right
Maybe she doesn't mind...
...but it's a pity there was nothing
we could do
I always thought...
...ever since she left school...
...every time I heard
people compliment her...
...I wondered what kind of family
she'd marry into
You know Mrs Shinoda
from Denen-Chofu?
Yes
Whenever I visited
her beautiful home...
...I dreamed Noriko would be a wife
in such a smart house one day
I'm sure
Now I think Mr Satake's man
might've been a better choice
I agree
I don't understand
young people nowadays
Are you going out?
To buy some seed
for the canaries
I'll see him out
- Do you want me to get anything else?
- No
See you later
So you've already decided?
It was all very sudden.
When's your wedding?
We’ll discuss it when he returns
from Akita in a few months
You've taken a big step
I didn't think you were the type
who could ever leave Tokyo
Why?
I imagined you'd live Western-style,
with a flower garden...
...listening to Chopin
And in your tiled kitchen, you'd have
a refrigerator filled with Coca-Cola
I thought you'd be a wife
in a house like that
And when I'd visit, you'd meet me
on a covered porch...
...wearing a white sweater,
playing with a Scottish terrier...
...and you'd greet me over a hedge,
"Hello, how are you?"
- Not at all
- I couldn’t imagine otherwise
Akita is farm country, right?
- Will you wear farmer's clothes?
- Of course
"A wright my luvva?
"Proper nice weather
we been havin', eh?"
Can you talk like that?
"Reckon I can a wright. Tis easy"
"Well, I be!
"You come up 'ere from the big city
and already talk our dialect
"You don't look local,
but you talk local"
"If I's gonna live in Akita
when me man an' I tie the knot...
..."then reckon I shud learn
the dialect"
You speak it so well!
A girl from Akita went to our school
So that's why!
Do you remember...
...before your brother Shoji
left for the front...
...we went hiking
with him and a friend?
Is he the man?
I don't remember if he was with us
Did you like him then?
I had no particular feelings for him
- When did it start?
- I don't know. It happened gradually
Really? I had no idea
Of course not.
I never imagined myself marrying him
So what happened?
- It was just by accident
- Accident?
Well, that's not entirely true.
How can I explain it?
It's like when you look
for something all over the place...
...and then you find it was
right in front of you all along
My mother always looks for her glasses
when they're on her nose
- That's how it was
- How so?
He was so close at hand,
I didn't realise he was the one
So you did love him
No, it wasn't like
I was in love with him
I'd known him well since childhood,
and I knew I could trust him
That means you love him
No, it's different. It's the feeling
of being totally at ease with him
Don't you understand?
If that’s not being in love, what is?
- No, it's not
- Yes, it is
You've fallen in love with him
- You're in love
- Am I?
Yes, you are.
Don't make me hit you!
- You better not. I know how you hit
- Right!
- Grab her, Mother!
- What's going on here?
- Aya, where's that thing?
- What thing?
The thing I brought up the other day.
It's about this big, and yellow
I was sure I'd left it here
somewhere
- Madam, you're wanted
- Oh, all right
- What's she looking for?
- I don't know
She's always like that.
She’ll be back, anyway
I wonder if she’s getting senile
I can't leave home to get married
with her like that
Wouldn't your husband
live here with you?
No way. No real man would live
with his wife's family
See? And she usually
comes back once more
Really?
I'm happy for you. You're lucky
you found a man you love
I'm sure our new life together
won't be easy
There will be a lot of difficulties
and inconveniences to deal with
I'll have to scrimp
and work really hard
- And what about your boss's plan?
- I declined this morning
What did he say?
He laughed that I was old-fashioned
for a modern girl
That's funny. He's upstairs right now
And Mr Manabe's with him
Why not take a peek
from the next room?
- No
- Come on, it'll be fun
- He's quite good-looking
- No
Come on. Why not?
It'll be all right
No, I'd rather not.
I don't need any more husbands
Don't worry. Come on
I may marry whoever's left.
Let's go!
- We shouldn’t
- It's fine!
- Let's not
- Come on!
I wonder if we should give her
our blessing
She's impossible
I just don't know
I feel sorry for her
Let's talk to her again
and make sure
Maybe we should
She said she's decided,
but she might have second thoughts
I'm back!
- I'm home. Sorry I'm late
- Welcome home
- I went to see Aya
- Did you?
Have you eaten?
I'll fix myself something.
Don't bother. I'll help myself
- There are some leftover croquettes
- Good. Thanks
Thanks for the food
Are you worried because
I'm marrying a man with a child?
- That's one reason
- Please don't be worried
- I'm not worried
- But mother feels sorry for you
I saw her crying in the kitchen
last night
But I love children
Father and mother don't see it
the same way as you do
Mitsuko will grow up, and what happens
when you have your own child...?
It’ll be fine.
I've given it a lot of thought
It’ll be all right
The situation's not that unusual.
I'm sure I can manage
- But...
- Don't you worry, Sister
- I'm confident I can do it
- Is that so? That's all right, then
Maybe I'm an optimist
Being without money doesn't worry me
like it does other people
I'm fine with it
- Are you sure?
- Yes
I'll stop worrying, then
Frankly,
I felt I couldn’t trust a man...
...who was still unattached
and drifting around at 40
I think a man with a child
is more trustworthy
- I admire you, Noriko
- Why?
I knew nothing about marriage
when I got married
But what will become of the family
when I leave home?
You needn't worry about that
Your father and mother
only want you to be happy
So don't worry
But it’ll be harder for you
without me
It’ll be fine. You and I can compete
from now on
- At what?
- Economising
- And I don't intend to lose
- Neither do I
You’ll have to stop eating shortcake
Of course! It's too expensive
But if we’re given some, I'll eat it
Come on, it's lovely down here!
I'm glad you came
Congratulations
Thank you for everything
over all these years
No, I should thank you
Shall we call Aya
and go out for dinner?
Well, thank you for asking,
but I really must be going
I see
Well, do stop by
if you ever come up to Tokyo
Thank you very much
And take good care
of your husband
Manabe will probably be
disappointed, but tough luck
If I were younger and single and
proposed to you, would you accept?
You'd turn me down too?
Hey, come and take
a good look at Tokyo
Tokyo's not so bad
Putting it back on?
- I can't decide
- Leave it off
Please look towards me
Keep still, Isamu
Madam, chin down a little, please
Ready, everyone?
- Thank you
Could you take one more picture
of my mother and father?
- Good idea
- Really? All right
Very well
You look wonderful together
- Don't make fun of us
- It's been years since the last time
- I'm finished
- Me, too
You've eaten everything up!
Where are you going, Isamu?
To poo
Thanks for the meal
Now you're marrying Yabe,
I wish I hadn't sent him to Akita
But knowing he was leaving
made me realise how I felt about him
Three or four years will pass
in no time
Yes, it’ll go quickly
We've lived in this house
for 16 years already
That's right
It was spring
and Noriko had just left primary school
That's right. She was just
a little older than Minoru is now
She used to wear a ribbon
in her hair...
...and she was always singing
She was so cute
Children grow up so quickly
- What will you do now, Koichi?
- I'm going to start a practice here
- Really?
- And what about your hospital post?
I'll keep working there
in the evenings
I see...
Well...we're parting ways,
but we’ll be together again
I wish we could live
together forever...
...but that's impossible
Father and Mother, you must visit us
now and then from Yamato
I'm sorry, it's all my doing
No, it's not your fault.
It was inevitable
Noriko, please take
good care of your health
I hear Akita's very cold
Yes, you must take care
and keep healthy
Then we’ll be sure
to get together again
Hey, look there
A bride is passing by
I wonder what sort of family
she's marrying into
I wonder how Noriko is
Our family’s been scattered
But you and I,
we've done quite well
We've experienced a lot
in our years together
We shouldn’t ask for too much
We've been so happy
THE END