I went through a period...
when sex had to be violent.
I was desperate to feel something real,.
Nothing felt real.
Every kiss felt like half
of what it should be.
You're just reaching for air.
♪ Just because
The whole world's gone dwanky ♪
♪ Doesn't mean
We fuckin' gonna go out like that, too ♪
♪ Fuck the system ♪
♪ We have our own system ♪
♪ We make our own rules ♪
♪ We don't answer to no one ♪
♪ That's right ♪
♪ We keep it gangsta ♪
♪ We keep it Zef ♪
♪ We keep it pumping
Off its motherfucking face ♪
♪ One time ♪
♪ Vuilgeboosted warrior styles ♪
♪ Yo, DJ Hi-Tek ♪
♪ Gooi roof, homeboy... ♪
We have to sing.
Help people by lifting their heads.
♪ Yeah, yeah..- ♪
It's not all real.
I thought you had to know
the right people...
get close to them.
The ones who could give you
what you need...
to get through the fence.
Oh! He flying!
He went away!
I wanted experience.
I told myself“...
any experience is better
than no experience.
I wanted to live...
sing my song.
You going for a swim, Melissa?
This is the Doctor.
Have a party for him every year.
Celebrate.
To the Doctor.
Eternity.
Don't be shy.
It's okay. It's a special thing.
It's a special thing.
- It's a special thing.
- Okay.
Do you like these people?
Why not? What have you got against them?
- I don't even know them.
- Well, get to know them.
You had to pick one.
There's one girl in a...
♪ Good Lord, now... ♪
What's your name?
♪ Oh, I've been changed ♪
♪ I said that ♪
♪ I... I... ♪
♪ Know I've been changed ♪
♪ Whoo, yeah..- ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Know I've been changed ♪
♪ Angels ♪
♪ Angels in Heaven ♪
♪ Done signed my name ♪
♪ Well... ♪
Let's go from the top again,
just 'cause I want your tongue
to be three times the size it should be.
Yes, sir.
His hands were in everything.
The money, the fame.
I Thought he could help me.-...
if I paid my dues.
You probably have a boyfriend, huh?
He told me I was pretty.
What's his name?
Just tell me a complete lie.
You could... you could
say anything you want to me.
That's the fun about me.
♪ I rolled and I tumbled ♪
♪ I cried the whole night long ♪
♪ Yes ♪
♪I roll and I tumble ♪
♪ I cried the whole night long... ♪
f lied to you.
And, people, you are the future!
You will decide what happens
to our world!
What happens to the birds of the air,
the fish in the sea,
the water that we drink.
You will decide what happens to our world.
You, people, you are the future!
And the future is now!
I think you should tell him...
about us.
We were together
before he even knew us.
Right.
- Are you looking?
- Yes!
Oh, yeah!
That's old. That's been there.
Oh, I was there this summer.
What about a job? You working this year?
I have a few different jobs, you know?
You looking around?
- Yeah, I'm trying.
- Yeah?
You worry about me, Daddy?
I just wanna know what you're doing.
Am I prying too much?
There is someone, but...
I'm not really sure what's gonna happen.
Oh! Okay-
But does he play out, like,
make money playing and stuff'?
- He does'?
- Mm-hmm.
So he's a working musician?
- All right, well, that's good to hear.
You think I could meet him?
Maybe someday.
Do you trust this man?
You know, we never hear from you.
Your mom and I wanna come up
and visit together sometime.
She really misses you.
We just want you to be happy.
Whatever you're doing.
I know.
Who am I?
I show apartments.
A dog walker.
I thought we could just roll and tumble.
Live from song to song.
Kiss to kiss.
What's that for'?
"X" marks the spot.
I love your soul.
Go, "Ah."
Ah...
Oh, no.
What's the matter?
Let me see.
Can you see my soul?
Is it still there?
What's so funny?
How well do you know this guy?
And how come he's letting you
stay at his place?
You shouldn't trust him.
Why not?
I just think you should be careful.
Ladies and gentlemen...
He said, "Trust me."
- We should make a record together.
- And I did.
I know you do the live music thing
and everything else,
but don't you wanna make some money?
Whatever I wanted,
he'd make it happen.
You've got talent.
You want one of those?
You wanna be me?
Where do you get a jacket like this?
Makes you walk different.
Get you a hundred jackets like that.
How long you lived here?
About two weeks.
I don't like it.
It's all for sale.
All of it...
honors, titles.
This, none of this exists.
What do you see?
Pool?
It's a stage show.
It's all just free fall.
You have too much pride.
I thought pride was a good thing.
People aren't proud enough.
Selfish!
Arrogant! Conceited!
If you know what's good for you,
you will stay as far away
from this man as you possibly can!
People changed around him.
They did things.
So did I.
He leaves us alone this way.
Because he wants to be free.
All his life, he's tried to get free.
He doesn't know how.
You aren't who you think you are.
He doesn't love you.
I like you this way.
I wanted to be free the way he was.
I went on seeing him.
I Let myself be smashed.
You can't?
Well, why can't you?
Do you trust me to stick
your finger in here?
He did everything.
He exhausted every poison.
He knew every form of love,
suffering, madness.
Learn all the rules when you're young,
'cause that makes Mom and Dad happy.
And then throw the fucking
lot of them out the window.
And they want you to!
They want you to!
So that he could reach the unknown.
He experimented.
They scare you with names.
Like wickedness.
You liked it; that I did what I liked.
I pulled you down in the car.
You realize that, um...
you know, it's like the sea.
Things come in and out.
We feel happy and ecstatic.
And then, you know, hours later,
you know, we feel
the deepest sorrows, or...
I didn't believe enough in love.
Afraid it would burn me up.
Be ready to suffer.
Don't be afraid.
I saw my husband.
I saw this boy across the room.
And I loved... I...
I just...
loved him the first moment I saw him.
And we had a life.
And it was beautiful,
and it was difficult.
And I thought I would be
with him for the rest of my life.
But he died.
I wanted to escape from every tie.
Every hold.
To have fife at any price.
Not to settle.
To go up...
Higher.-...
free.
♪ I rolled and Humbled,
I cried the whole night long ♪
♪ Woke up this mornin',
I must've bet my money wrong... ♪
♪ I got troubles so hard,
I can't stand the strain ♪
♪ I got troubles so hard..- ♪
♪ Some young lazy slut
Has charmed away my brains ♪
♪ The landscape is glowing... ♪
"Ooh"
The birds said...
we'd love each other forever,.
Love never fails.
- Ay!
Didn't seem like anything
could break us apart.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Father ♪
Thought we'd build each other up...
♪ Brother ♪
make music together.
♪ I believe ♪
♪ Let me tell you ♪
♪ Living just as fast as I can ♪
♪ Trying to understand ♪
♪ Brother... ♪
- What do you mean?
- Let's make a fucking record.
Huh'?
How long have you known Faye?
She's a receptionist for me.
How long?
I guess she came to work for me...
when she was 17.
16, maybe.
Let's us decide what's right now.
Cheers.
- What do you think of this world?
- It's its own.
- There's no possessions, right?
- No.
You know
I felt terrible about that.
Beer...
M'dear?
Why've you been a slut?
♪ Have troubles ♪
♪ Don't cry ♪
♪ Just remember ♪
♪ That he's standing nearby ♪
♪ And if ♪
♪ Disappointments come... ♪
That was the first time in my life
that I knew,.
♪ But don't you worry... ♪
Everything came from that hour.
♪ Don't cry... ♪
I wish that it could last forever.
They have a beauty in their life...
that makes me ugly,.
Ajay...
Everything okay?
Yes.
Don't leave.
- Help me. Help me.
- Let me put these down.
What can I get for you?
- I have a condition.
- Yes'?
Uh, I can't be left alone...
for more than five minutes.
Can I get you something else?
I'd like to hear you sing.
- Okay, I gotta...
- Elephant...
- I gotta check another table.
- Why'? Why?
- 'Cause my boss is watching.
- Which other table?
- You're gonna get me fired.
- Yep, that's the plan.
You...
What do you like to do'?
Well...
I was a teacher, but there's
not many jobs around here.
- What do you teach?
- Kindergarten.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
You like kids?
Yes, I do. It wouldn't be a very good job
- if I didn't like kids, would it'?
- No.
So you like physical things?
Yes.
I was shy.
This concert.
Who's on first?
This concert! It's insane.
No, I said, I do a better Mick Jagger
than I do Iggy Pop.
'Okay!
'Okay?
I misunderstood.
I don't know
how I didn't hear you.
You don't listen to me.
I'll listen to everything.
The record companies would sort of...
They did... they believed in artistry...
It's something they put in a
film to tweak the heartstrings
or to raise the adrenaline, you know.
Desperate to fuckin'...
drain the fuckin' chord and go, "Waah!"
And, "Fuck me!"
"Gimme!"
- Yeah.
You know, uh, "Love me."
You know, these things.
Lived very near Claridge's, and, uh...
- Nice. Swanky.
- The latest.
I lived on Upper Brook Street,
and I had...
After Dad left...
you thought you were a failure.
Mama...
you gave us so much.
Your hands are so beautiful.
You should be wearing gloves.
I wanted you
to have so much more.
I don't know where else we can go.
Remember, we have nothing.
Well, you need money for a lawyer.
The law's no help
for people who are ruined.
♪ Ahh ♪
You have everything.
Everything you want.
♪ My heart... ♪
She likes the cheerleaders.
You do?
Were you ever a cheerleader?
Scare me. Come closer.
Marry me.
No.
You gave Mother a new house.
You said I could get out
whenever I wanted,
keep all you'd given us.
You wanted me to be free.
Why do I owe you a Coke?
You said I couldn't climb the tree.
Don't have to.
What're you gonna do?
You're all the way up there.
How strong do you think you are?
One, two, three, go.
To the tree. Don't! You're running.
You're running. You're running.
I went along
like someone in a dream.
I knew I had to tell you.
Come clean.
I didn't know how.
Hove you, Hove you, Hove you...
Say it like you mean it.
Say it like you mean...
Do you lie to me?
I know you always wanna
know the truth, but...
but I don't.
Sometimes the truth
isn't the right thing to say.
- Mm-hmm.
- You can hurt someone more
' Saying it.
♪ Mm, hmm, hmm ♪
♪ Mm, mm... ♪
- This looks like a birthday card.
- Oh, isn't that pretty'?
"The life you live again.
Happy birthday.“
Do you ever think about leaving here?
I don't know.
Are you a good liar?
Do you love me?
Why do you ask that?
I like to hear it.
You don't like to say it.
I love you.
I'm so scared sometimes.
We're Wanderers, you and I.
Like birds.
So you're saying
you wanna produce it as well.
So I'm suddenly feeling
a little bit out in the cold here.
- You know what I'm saying?
- Well, you wanna help produce it'?
I just feel like you're...
you're going ahead
on this thing by yourself.
Well, just look at the facts.
Take it out of your hands.
Why do you think it
can't work as a country song?
- It can.
- Maybe you...
As a... as a country...
Take your finger outta your ear.
Put it back up your ass.
You think you're better
than me, don't you?
You look down on me.
I gave you everything, man.
You sit on your high horse
looking down on me.
Look at your fingernails, man.
Where's the dirt?
You think you can get here
without getting your hands dirty at least?
Look at my batting average.
Look at it. Look at yours.
Who's helping who here?
I wrote those songs.
I did the work.
How many people do you think
in this city alone are writing songs?
Huh?
Think your songs are that good?
Yeah, what is it, morals...
Taking credit for someone else's work.
I told you about that shit.
50-50. Equals.
Brothers.
- Get outta here.
- Come on.
- You got a weird way of showing it.
- What'?
- We partners? Are we brothers?
Why'd you put the copyrights to my songs
in your name and your name only?
Or did you think I didn't know about that?
No, maybe you thought,
"This guy's so stup..."
Don't put your hands on...
Don't put your hands on me.
Maybe you thought, "This guy's so stupid,
he doesn't want a lawyer,
he trusted me."
Should we make a scene? Huh?
I'll give you a record contract.
How's that make you feel?
That's what you want, right?
I love the pain.
It feels like life,.
Sometimes I admire what a hypocrite I am.
On!
Strange what you get used to.
You're skinny.
You ever think
about coming home?
Okay.
Feel like I just got out.
Place felt like it was on fire.
Come and help put it out.
- I did my best.
- Did you?
You sound like Dad.
It's hard at home with Mom.
'Cause...
you don't wanna be there.
I just feel like I keep...
sinking lower, and lower, and lower...
I think I'm just tired.
I wanted all that pain
to be for something.
I'm okay.
Ma, you're healthy, right?
You're a stone cold fox.
Turn it into something.
You've got... you got...
you got it in the bag.
I don't think that... I don't think
that takes care of everything, darling.
Have you seen your father?
- Have I seen him?
- Mm-hmm.
No.
I know, I gotta go.
I don't know.
I haven't done anything.
♪ Leave it there, leave it there ♪
♪ Leave it there.. ♪
Does Dad even look at you?
He's so... strange.
We've... waited so long
to be free of that man,
and now...
Do you think about forgiving him?
No, I don't.
- You pray for him?
- No, I don't.
Not anymore.
- Why?
- What's the point?
♪ The world from you withholds ♪
♪ All its silver and its gold ♪
♪ And you have to get along ♪
♪ With meager fare ♪
♪ Just remember, in his work ♪
♪ How he feeds the little birds ♪
♪ Take your burden ♪
♪ To the Lord ♪
♪ And leave it there ♪
♪ Take your burden ♪
♪ To the Lord ♪
♪ And leave it there ♪
I met him
on the street today, and he, um...
said that he wanted to sign me.
Wow.
I didn't know what to tell him.
Why not? I mean,
this is... that's a good...
That's a good opportunity for you.
I mean, you know how I feel
about him, but that...
that shouldn't affect your...
that shouldn't affect you.
You gotta do it.
Why are you crying?
Because I'm happy.
Your old girlfriend...
she asked you to go off with her.
Why didn't you?
Was it for me?
Do you ever
think of me when I'm not here?
- Sure.
- Well, what do you think?
Why wake up next to someone
you don't even know
if you don't even know yourself anymore?
What happens then?
Do you think she'll be happy...
living with ghosts, sadder?
- It's more complicated than that.
- No, it's not.
What's it feel like to be a girl?
Like I have special powers.
What don't I know?
How to feel.
How to be sick to your bones.
How to yearn.
Stay.
You're casting spells.
Does it work?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah'?
I don't even think
you know you're doing it.
I may.
Just going around
casting spells on people.
♪ What went wrong with our love ♪
♪ A love that was so strong ♪
♪ And as I still walk on ♪
♪ I think of ♪
♪ The things we've done together ♪
♪ While our hearts were young ♪
♪ I'm a-walkin' in the rain ♪
♪ Tears are fallin' and I feel the pain ♪
♪ Wishin' you were here by me ♪
♪ To end this misery ♪
- Are you happy?
♪ And I wonder... ♪
I think I might have
misunderstood happiness, you know?
I dream about it and stuff, and...
I sing about it sometimes, but...
I don't...
No.
♪ While our hearts were young ♪
♪ I'm a-walking in the rain... ♪
I mean, would you want more?
I could follow you around.
You'd give it all up?
I would.
If you'd ask me.
But you never do, you know?
♪ You're so smart ♪
♪ Going around ♪
♪ Breaking lovers' hearts ♪
♪ You'll be defeated ♪
♪ By your own weapon ♪
I dream about being in love and...
being free and safe.
You know?
Can you have, uh... you think...
have it all?
That's one thing I know.
You can't have it all.
- You gonna miss me?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Are you gonna miss me?
Do you want me to stay?
I can't ask you that.
Well, then I gotta go.
Foolish me.
Devil.
I need to talk to you.
I know.
I love him.
Of course you do.
Say it again.
Say what again?
I don't wanna do this anymore.
I want out.
Then go.
- ♪ I know places we can go, babe... ♪
- I'm low.
I'm like mud.
I don't deserve you.
♪ The high won't fade here, babe... ♪
The shame of it,.
♪ No, the high won't hurt here, babe ♪
Things changed.
♪ I know places we can go... ♪
You became suspicious.
♪ I know places we can go, babe ♪
♪ Where the highs won't
Bring you down, babe ♪
♪ No, the highs won't
Hurt you there, babe ♪
♪ Don't ask me when ♪
Stupid girl.
♪ Don't ask me how ♪
♪ But ask me where... ♪
How long have you known?
I don't know, um...
I was a receptionist there
before I met you.
You know, I...
He's after you.
I dreamed of having him help me
the same way he helped you.
You don't have to, uh...
you know, hide anything.
We don't have to have
any secrets between us.
Why is he after you
if he's not attracted to you?
Did you ever sleep with him?
Yes.
You did?
Once.
How come you never told me?
Tell me about the teacher.
Just tell me.
- Tell me what you did.
- I don't remember.
Try and remember.
- I can't
- Try and remember.
It was dark. I don't know.
He told us what to do.
Did you do it?
Yes.
You did what he told you to do?
I wanna live a good life.
Hmm? How many times?
We had...
a sort of a romance, I guess.
No, it was more than once.
It was several times.
Why'd you just do that?
Do what?
Change your story.
I was trying it out to see how you'd do.
I'm a beast.
Still not unhappy about it.
I don't seem to bring people
happiness anymore.
I wasted your love.
I was wrong.
Will you forgive me?
We broke up.
I tried to be kind.
It only made me colder.
What part of me do you want?
Take what you want from me.
Let me untie them.
Untie mine.
In our state
and even across our border.
We would express that generosity
not just in this moment or on this campus,
but as we have opportunity every day
throughout our community and our city,
around our state, even across our borders.
And we will be known as a generous people.
And we bless even as we have been blessed.
For we ask this in Your Son's name.
Amen.
Gives you life.
Eat it.
I've tasted it.
Tried it.
This is dipped in God.
They've never been where we've been.
Open your eyes.
Right here you know.
You won't die.
Here I reign.
Kins?'
Who sees us?
The world wants to be deceived.
Think you'll be able to drive?
- Taking that as a no.
- Our friend will pick us up.
All right. You need to move on.
We have a little fun right here.
Quite frankly, I don't know if you're
gonna come back. Careful with that.
You know that river?
This is a ticket around the world.
Last call...
Now leaving on track twelve.
Board!
Whoa!
What are you afraid of?
What do you wanna do'?
Are you afraid of me?
I was once like you.
I didn't know what I know now,.
To think what I once was...
what I am now.
- Ls this your dog?
- Yeah.
- Can I say hi?
- Yeah, of course.
- Hi there.
- Say hello.
What's your name?
Look at you.
Stuff like that.
You what? What?
- Like, uh, uh, house-sit.
- House-sit? Oh.
Hi.
Very tired with the weather.
So I decided to move here.
I don't know if I would
move here from Paris.
I wanted to experience it.
Just let me know when I can
come over and take him out or...
- Anything. If you need me to feed him.
- Tomorrow... if fine?
- Where are you from?
- From here.
Yeah, it's like the, um...
the skin, I like this idea of, um...
you know, losing your... your-your skin.
- And, like, the phoenix.
- Yeah.
You know, like...
- Starting over'?
- Start... starting over.
Dying and being reborn...
The light is so beautiful on your face.
You have one part of your face
in the shadows
and one part in the light.
- Are you scared?
- Mm-mm.
You kissed me in public.
You held my hand.
Stay.
Volunteer their time to make it so.
The very traditions
of the Bachelors of Austin
are the result of years of service
by dedicated individuals
and a solid and loyal membership.
This year, to help us usher in
and host a great social season,
I would especially like
to thank Layne Cricket
and his wife Susan for serving.-...
You get used to drifting.
Waiting.
They say follow the light.
So happy to meet you.
Where do you find it?
When you're young, it's not always
easy to know what is the light.
- I don't understand either.
- Except for you.
- It's different.
- Sweet of you to say.
I hear you have songs on the radio
and you're meant for better things.
It'd be awful to have these
good times and not have life itself.
I wanna meet you before you move on
- and leave us behind.
- Mm-hmm. No, thank you.
Uh, she was mixed up with a guy back East.
He was a very nice man, I understand.
Divorced, four kids, but...
I heard you just moved here.
Yeah, I've been back a couple of months.
Mind me asking why?
I was, uh, wondering.
I grew up there.
Oh, yeah?
No, I went... I went away to school.
Back East.
I think you've got a secret
you're not telling me.
What is that?
It's a chicken.
Hold on, you gotta...
You're beautiful.
♪ Rather die in your arms
than die lonesome... ♪
I hope I don't fall in love with you.
Nobody asked you to.
♪ The higher that I climb ♪
♪ The deeper I fall down... ♪
What's the matter?
I'm scared.
They play with sex.
They make it cheap,.
Maybe you need this world.
The falsehood, the show.
Maybe what stirs your blood
is having wild people around you.
You might have to be a sinner.
♪ Started crashing his head
against the locker ♪
♪ Started laughing hysterically ♪
♪ When suddenly ♪
♪ Johnny gets the feeling ♪
♪ He's being surrounded by ♪
♪ Horses, horses, horses, horses... ♪
♪ Can I take you down? ♪
♪ Come on outwith me... ♪
What if I don't become an artist?
Don't have one life,.
Don't have the other.
Running around, trying to be somebody.
Snatching at life.
I got some uranium!
I bought it off my mom.
The music's all about feeling free.
So you don't have
to do nothing to be free.
Why ain't I free'? Answer me that.
♪ Baby, baby ♪
♪ We just went out to have some fun ♪
♪ We can't go back 'cause now it's done ♪
♪ Baby, baby ♪
♪ Now I'm the one who has to pay ♪
♪ Since the night they took you away ♪
♪ You pushed this guy
And he pushed you back ♪
♪ You knocked him
into the amplifier stack ♪
♪ The bouncers came
And dragged you both... ♪
I feel like we are so...
connected.
And it's. ..
I can't really understand, it's like...
I forget everything,
but seeing you again...
♪ I rolled and I tumbled ♪
♪ I cried the whole night long... ♪
I never knew I had a soul.
♪ I cried the whole night long ♪
The word embarrassed me.
♪ I got up this morning ♪
♪ Feeling that something going on wrong ♪
I've always been afraid to be myself.
♪ Please let me be ♪
♪ Yes, love me... ♪
I thought there was no one there.
♪ Please let me be ♪
♪ if you don't like my peaches ♪
♪ Please don't shake my tree ♪
I don't believe anything
that you're saying.
Yes, you do.
You know, but even the...
the sound of your voice and...
that upsets me.
I forget what I am.
Whose I am.
You're so far off.
I'll die if you don't come soon.
I don't like to see the birds in the sky,
because I miss you.
Because you saw them with me.
Come.
Save me from my bad heart.
♪ It won't let up ♪
♪ And I see them coming in,
Oh, I hear them coming in ♪
♪ I couldn't hear them before,
But I hear them now ♪
♪ It's a radar scope ♪
♪ It's all silver ♪
♪ And all platinum lights ♪
♪ Moving in like black ships ♪
♪ They were moving in, streams of them ♪
♪ And he put up his hands and he said ♪
♪ It's me, it's me ♪
♪ HI give you my eyes ♪
♪ Oh, take me up, oh, please, take me up ♪
♪ I am helium raven waiting for you ♪
♪ Please take me up, don't leave me here ♪
♪ The son, the sign, the sign ♪
♪ The true prophet, the true prophet ♪
♪ A tortured woman, the true sign ♪
♪ The cross is just the true sign
Of a tortured woman ♪
♪ Standing there in the doorway ♪
♪ Dreaming of, dreaming of the prophet ♪
♪ They don't want their presidents ♪
♪ They don't want
Their children to be presidents ♪
♪ But prophets, prophets ♪
♪ They're dreaming of their children ♪
♪ As prophets ♪
♪ They're gonna come in,
Run through the fields ♪
♪ Dreaming of animation ♪
♪ She said, oh, please, please, please ♪
♪ I'm gonna shoot 'em up like light ♪
♪ Like Mohammad Boxer ♪
♪ Oh, please take me up ♪
♪ Up, up, up... ♪
♪ Ahh ♪
♪ To the belly of a ship ♪
♪ Let the ship slide open ♪
♪ And I'M go inside of it ♪
♪ Where we are not ♪
♪ Human ♪
Touch me.
♪ We are not human... ♪
Fallen so low.
I had to find my way out...
of you.
- ♪ Where there was a desert ♪
- To life.
♪ The sun shone down... ♪
All right, our second course
will be our salad course,
which will consist of a salad...
I revolted against goodness.
Thought it had deceived me.
Careful, Matthew.
Thought!
Could do better than others.
Didn't need what made life sweet for them.
Look at me.
I'm sor...
I'm sorry that you're not
as proud of me...
as you are...
with my sisters.
I'm not who I thought I was.
Am I a good person?
You made so many...
so many sacrifices for me.
So that I could have a chance
to do the things that you couldn't do...
Even want to be?
And I failed you.
Or just seem like one
so people will like me.
♪ Ow! ♪
♪ Ah! ♪
♪Ow! ♪
♪ Ah! Ah! ♪
♪ Ah! Ah! Ahh! ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ I'm inside your DNA ♪
♪ You can't make me go away ♪
♪ AH you do is fuck and eat,
That's what we do too ♪
♪ Tough for you 'cause you're our meat
But we don't make the rules ♪
♪ Not only will we drink your blood ♪
♪ We're gonna suck your head ♪
♪ There isn't much to think about ♪
♪ 'Cause soon you will be dead ♪
my family.
Is now the time to tell you that?
I guess not.
- Is this a joke?
- She's kidding, ma.
- Oh.
- Oh, it was a joke.
Not very funny.
Cheers.
Excuse me for a second.
You're unhappy-
I can see it.
Sorry about that.
What'd you do?
She's the wrong person for you.
I'm sorry?
It's wrong.
Come on, honey. It's okay.
I don't understand it, but...
- Can I walk with you?
- No.
I don't know how to change.
I want to,.
How do you?
Will you take me somewhere?
How do you get better?
Gotta sacrifice something.
How do you know
when you're lying to yourself?
When you give somebody your word...
does it mean anything?
You can just take it back,.
I told her that Fm gonna do my best.
Do my best not to say things I don't mean.
The world built
a fence around you.
How do you get through?
Connect?
There's something else.
Something that wants us to find it,.
You're the part
that I don't know...
that you don't know yourself.
I swear.
How long have
you been doing this?
My dream was to be a teacher,
but this is kind of something I just...
I fell into after my fiancé passed.
In memory for him, but...
like, this is not something
that people just choose to do,
so I'm trying... this is just
a means to an end for me.
It was
so much better when he was around.
But, you know...
God has a plan, and...
and I guess this is part of his plan.
You know, Shawn being gone
and me being in this situation
where I have no choice
but to do what I do, so...
Eventually, maybe he'll hear
my prayers and I'll be able to...
you know, move forward and do something...
valued with my life.
Something my dad
can be proud of, you know.
Make the money.
Don't let the money make you.
Create the illusion,
but don't let yourself
believe that illusion.
Only make him believe it.
Don't let yourself get caught up in it.
I sell a fantasy, not my body.
I sell an illusion.
I sell, you know...
a daydream to these guys.
And I try to keep the cookie jar closed.
Is that me?
The cookie jar closed.
You burn me.
Who are you?
I can't take this world straight.
Big candy store out there.
- I think I get a little insecure
- What do you like to drink?
And... you know,
I just... I look for comfort...
- in places I shouldn't.
- You like to get high?
I don't know...
It's kind of...
I'm weird,.
- I'm just...
- What's your fantasy?
What turns you on?
I think just
being wanted turns me on.
Tell me what scares you.
I'm really scared of spiders.
Um, but most things don't scare me.
I think I have a thick skin.
I think I'm pretty strong.
No, but what really scares you?
I don't know my family.
No one's ever been there for me but me,.
You like those girls, don't you?
They know what you are.
When I was a girl,
I loved everyone.
You killed my love.
What did I say?
Do?
Mom, I'm afraid of myself.
A hatred in me.
Everything I could do to get free...
goes through my mind.
Makes me evil.
I used to think I could never be wicked,.
Wicked before.
A long way out for me.
So much to seek to be consoled
as to understand,
to be loved as to love.
For it is in giving that we receive.
It is in pardoning...
Bang.
Bang, may the blessings
of all those that you love
and those who love you...
Mama.
Where am I now?
Where are we?
I knew how destroyed... I was.
Forgive me.
In that time, did she have
any medical history or medication?
About her mental health issues?
Had she ever had any Bang.
Or expressed any depression to you?
You got food all over you.
I just wanted to come...
come and sit next to you.
Things turned out a little different
than we thought they would, didn't they?
They like carrots and apples.
Every now and then,
I'll bring them one, but...
They're spoiled now.
These old guitars seem to have
a song ready-made for you.
They always have old songs...
loan... I can go on
for hours with one chord.
It's just one chord hammering.
♪ Glory of a good man ♪
♪ Come on and they carry him home... ♪
Can you see?
Yeah, she has a face... a face like yours.
I do... f don't know... I didn't know
why I was coming to this party.
Then I saw you,
and I thought, "That's why."
You got a boyfriend?
No.
I don't think so. Did we meet before?
- Did we?
- I've seen you before.
- Where?
- Lots of times.
But I mean, I'm...
I'm not doing anything wrong, am I?
- By talking to you?
- No.
There's something on your face.
Did you get it?
- Huh?
- Did you get it?
Mm-mm.
Gotta come closer.
I got it.
Thank you.
Here we go.
- Okay, start from the beginning.
- Okay.
Does it start right there,
or does it have an intro'?
Do you want it to...?
But slower.
It's a love story.
Excuse... excuse me.
Hey.
Hi.
Is this happening?
Who was that girl
I saw you with at the hotel?
Just a girl.
A woman.
Why you smiling?
I don't know.
Wow.
I don't have to tell you
that kind of thing.
Oh, I didn't realize there
was something not to tell.
She was your girlfriend?
Mm-hmm.
What happened?
I went out with her,
and I never called her again.
Did you love her?
I didn't realize it at the time.
Mm-hmm.
Don't smile.
Well...
- You ready?
- Okay.
You gotta try harder than that.
I wish I could
take back every wound.
Guess that blue bug is back.
Every doubt.
You found me,.
You held out your hand.
I took sex.
A gift.
I played with it.
I played with the flame of life.
I was married in 1980,
and I've been a widow since...
1994, but...
I still wear my ring
'cause he's still my husband.
You know, we didn't get divorced, so...
This is... this is my wedding ring,
and this I bought
for myself after he died.
It's what they gave runners
who didn't win a marathon
but finished the race.
Be an artist.
I never thought I would live long.
You know, I'd be an artist
and die young of tuberculosis or something
like Charlotte Bronté, but, uh...
What bad thing did you do?
Just...
got involved with...
this man who I thought
could help me and...
You made a mistake, you know?
Do you look at it...
You'll do fine.
I love you.
Thank you.
Is that your fella?
Fight for him.
Really love him.
Don't let him get away.
♪ Boots that tramped from track to track ♪
♪ Worn down to the sole ♪
♪ One road was paved in gold ♪
♪ One road was just a road ♪
♪ Mercy has a human heart. ♪
"For Mercy has a human heart;
Pity, a human face;
And Love, the human form divine:
And Peace, the human dress.
Then every man, of every slime,
That prays in his distress,
Prays to the human form...
Love, Mercy, Pity, Peace.
And all must love the human form,
In heathen, Turk, or Jew..."
♪ Mercy... ♪
- Want him on your shoulder?
- Mm-hmm.
It was like a new paradise.
Forgiveness.
Think I gotta go home.
Dad's sick.
Mom's gone crazy.
Brother's up to no good.
I won't stop loving you.
I don't think I can.
BV...
It's complicated.
There you are.
I gotta go back and start over.
Like a kid.
I didn't have the right heart in me,.
You're the only one I love.
Even after all we've been through.
Mercy was a word.
I never thought I needed it.
Or not as much as other people do.
You asked me if I wanted to come out, too.
I've never been out West before.
I'll come find you.
Gonna have to pick your feet up.
If you don't, we will have
somebody to replace you.
I'm-I'm just tired of this.
So let's get up there
and lend a hand.
You wanna go back to a simple life.
I want the same,.
Let nothing come between us.
Ever.
This.
Only this.
You should do it like this.
The drums should...
If we just build up so the third...
The third verse is a build.
Like, it's-It's on top.
- And then we go into "it hurts"...
♪ After he...♪
And then we stroke it back
and then it dies.
♪ Breaks your heart ♪
♪ Then you'll be sad ♪
♪ And your teardrops start ♪
♪ Then you'll know how ♪
♪ it hurts to be alone ♪
♪ Just because ♪
♪ You think that you're so smart ♪
♪ Going around ♪
♪ Breaking lovers' hearts ♪
♪ Now you're defeated ♪
♪ By your own weapon ♪
♪ it hurts to be alone ♪
♪ Baby, it hurts ♪
♪ To be alone ♪
That was cool, no?
Should we... Can we just-
We should listen to it,.
♪ I stepped in the water ♪
♪ And the wa-wa-wa-wa-wa-water was cold ♪
- ♪ You know the an... ♪
- ♪ Angels in Heaven... ♪
♪ Yes, they have ♪
♪ ...done signed my name ♪
♪ It chilled my body ♪
♪ But not my sou! ♪
♪ Angels in Heaven ♪
♪ Done signed my name ♪
♪ Good Lord, now ♪
♪ I... ♪
Come on, church!
♪ ...know I've been changed ♪
♪ I said that I... ♪
♪ I... ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ ...know I've been changed ♪
♪ I... ♪
♪ know I've been changed ♪
♪ Angels in Heaven done... ♪
- ♪ Wait a minute ♪
- ♪ ...signed my name ♪
♪ Somebody said
how can a brown cow ♪
♪ Eat green grass ♪
♪ And give you white milk? ♪
- ♪ Angels in... ♪
- ♪ Yes, sir ♪
♪ ...Heaven done... ♪
- Come on, Zion.
- ♪ ...signed my name ♪
♪ Name ♪
♪ The angels in Heaven done ♪
♪ Signed ♪
♪ My name ♪
♪ Yes, they did ♪
- ♪ Yes ♪