Who's there?!
What do you want?!
Some say
the world will end in fire.
Some say in ice...
From what I've tasted of desire,
I hold with those who favor fire.
But if I had to perish twice...
I think I know enough of hate,
To say that,
for destruction,
Ice,
is also great.
And would suffice.
You know,
I've got an english final.
I gotta focus.
Marry me.
No.
Change me.
Okey I will if you marry me,
It's called a compromise.
It's just called coercion.
It's not fair.
Marriage is just...
Is a piece of paper.
Where I am from,
it's the way one says, "I love you".
Where I come from,
at my age...
It's the way one says,
"I just got knocked up".
So, you're worried about
what people will think.
You know, it's two out of three
marriages end in divorce.
Well, I think you'll find
the...
Vampire, human divorce rate
is a little lower.
Just marry me.
I can't.
I have to be back at four.
Four o'clock on the dot.
That kid trying to brown nose me
now or something?
He has a name.
And now he's too punctual for you?
Okey...
You understand
why you're being punished, right?
- I know, I put you through hell.
- Yes, you did.
But I have other reasons,
for grounding you.
Like...
I just want you to get
some separation from him.
Dad, there is nothing
you can say.
Edward is in my life.
Yeah, I'm gathering that.
So, alright. How about this?
I'll make you a deal.
You're not grounded anymore,
if...
You use your
new found freedom...
to see some
of your other friends too,
Like...
Like Jacob.
He's going through
a really tough time right now,
His Dad's
really worried about him.
I remember
when that was you.
You needed a friend,
Jake was there.
Hey, it's Jake.
Leave a message.
Jacob hadn't talk to me
in weeks.
I wanted to fix it,
he just...
He wouldn't give me
the chance.
"I miss you too.
Doesn't change anything. "
You scared me.
You're going now
to the reservation.
How'd you --?
Alice...
Hey,
did you do this to my truck?
Bella, you have to understand.
Your safety is everything to me.
Jacob is not gonna hurt me!
Not intentionally,
but the wolves have no control...
Edward!
I have...
Until graduation,
to see him.
And I'll be one of you,
and he'll hate me forever.
I'm sorry.
- Hey.
- Just in time. Alright, check it out.
- Alright, let's see what you got.
- My fellow students.
- Cool.
- Right?
- Wow.
- Okey, right? -- Cute.
We are the future.
Anything is possible...
... If you just believe.
- Nice.
Blah, blah, blah...
- Perfect.
- And got your self a speech.
No, this will be my speech.
When I want everyone to throw
diplomas at my head.
So...
Thank you.
Ya gotta embrace the cliches,
Jess.
They have the bread and butter
of all valedictorians.
And that is why
you are not valedictorian.
And Jess doesn't need cliches.
Speech is gonna be epic.
Epic? It'll change lives.
I decided to throw a party.
After all, how many times
we gonna graduate high school?
A party? At your place?
- I've never seen your house.
- No one's ever seen their house.
A nother party, Alice?
- It'll be fun.
- Yeah.
That's what you said last time.
- Hey, Angela.
- Yes.
Do you need some help
with those?
I know you know what she saw.
Tell me.
It was nothing.
You looked worried.
Just that everyone would notice
how strange Alice is.
I think that ship sailed
long ago.
I wonder what's wrong.
There's someone missing
in Seattle, over a year ago.
Charlie is doing what he can,
but...
Do you know something
about this?
We've been tracking the situation
in Seattle for a while.
Unexplained disappearances,
killings...
If the situation gets anymore
conspicuous,
the Volturi will step in.
If they go to Seattle,
they can come here.
- They can see I'm still human.
- We won't get that far.
But we'll go to Seattle
if we have to.
I'll fax these down
the first thing.
Thank you.
- Hey.
- You're ready for dinner?
- Yeah.
It is still just...
you and I, alright?
No, I'm just dropping her off.
- See you later.
- Bye.
Oh...
Bella.
My parents wanted to
remind you about the...
Airline ticket
you got for your birthday.
What airline ticket?
A round trip ticket
to see Mom in Florida.
Wow, that was generous.
And it expires soon, they say
you might wanna use it this weekend.
Well, I can't just drop
everything and go.
It might be your last chance
to see her before you graduate.
Well. It might not be
a bad idea.
get out of the town
for a couple of days,
get some distance.
Yeah,
I wouldn't mind seeing Mom...
As long as you
use the companion ticket.
Wait, just two tickets?
Super,
That makes me really happy.
I did wanna see my Mom.
I wanted to know that her life
was full by satisfying
Aren't you gonna miss this?
Don't you just feel the vitamin D
soaking up in your pores?
Yeah, I'm gonna miss this.
You know, colleges in Florida
are a lot sunnier.
I'm just saying,
if you go to university of Alaska...
I'm never gonna see you.
They have a really great
science program.
You mean Edward program.
The way he watches you...
It's like he's willing to leap
in front of you,
and take a bullet
or something.
Is that a bad thing?
It's an intense thing.
You're different with him.
If he moves, you move.
Like magnets.
I don't know, we're just...
In love.
I get it.
I just want to make sure,
you're making
the right choices for you.
You know, cause you're the one
who's gonna have to live with him.
Alright, enough with the heavy.
- Mom.
- Congraduation.
I didn't want you
to spending you're money.
I didn't, come on.
Are these all our old trip T-shirts?
- Emm. -- Get out!
I saved'em all.
I thought they'd make a good quilt.
To keep you warm up in Alaska.
Remember this one?
Ensanada.
- The snake pit.
- Yep.
But this one is my favourite.
Here...
The three-headed lobster
in Maine.
- This is amazing.
- No, honey. I'm glad you've like it.
I just figured, you know,
when you get older, have kids,
We can add to it.
Maybe go visit...
the world's largest catsup bottle
or something.
- Thanks
- Oh...
I'm glad you like it.
I just thought, you should have
a little piece of me, up there in Alaska.
- Mom.
- Yeah.
- I miss you.
- Oh, honey. I miss you too.
You sure this is
where you saw her?
She's almost here.
On your left!
Wait!
She's in their territory.
She'll get away!
No she won't!
Emmett, no!
Did you regret going?
No.
It was really great to see my mom.
Just really hard saying goodbye.
- It doesn't have to be goodbye.
- Is that why you ask me to go?
You thought
I was gonna change my mind.
I'm always hoping for that.
What?
If I asked you to stay in the car,
would you?
Of course not.
Hey.
- Charlie said you left town.
- Yeah. To visit my Mom, why?
Just checking to see
if you're still human.
I'm coming here to warn you.
If your kind
come on our land again...
Wait, what?
- You didn't tell her?
- Just leave it alone, Jacob.
Tell me what?
Emmett and Paul
had a misunderstanding,
there is nothing
to worry about.
Listen to you.
Did you lie
to get her out of town, too?
You should leave.
Now.
She has a right to know.
She is the one
the red-head wants.
Victoria?
- Alices's vision.
- I was trying to protect you.
By lying to me.
Okey. We're gonna talk
about this, but...
You!
Why haven't you
called me back?
I had nothing to say.
- Well, I have tons. Hold on.
- Hey.
Bella.
- Edward, you have to trust me.
- I do trust you.
It's him I don't trust.
Lose the grin, Jacob.
We're just going for a ride.
Hold on tight.
Are you sure,
this is a good idea?
I'm a "vampire girl",
remember?
- Look who's back.
- Whatup, Bella?
- Quil, you too?
- Yep. Finally made the pack.
I'm glad you're here, Bella.
Maybe we can get a break from
Jake's obsessive inner monologue.
"I wish Bella would call".
- "I wish Bella wouldn't call".
- "Maybe I should call Bella".
"Maybe I should call Bella
and hang up".
Alright, you can shut up now.
Bella, this is Leah Clearwater.
Harry's daughter.
Hey.
I'm really sorry about your father.
If you're here to torture Jacob
some more, feel free to leave.
Fun, isn't she?
- Bella... Hi.
- Hey.
I was wondering when we'd see
your face around here again.
Yeah, same here.
Sam, we're good?
We're good. She won't be getting
through our line anytime soon.
So, when did Leah
joined the pack?
Around when her Dad died.
Her brother Seth, also phased.
He's only fifteen.
One of the youngest we've had.
Sam keeps him home studying,
but he's chomping at the bit.
Wish it was Leah
who'd stay home.
Come on,
don't be such a guy.
No, it's... It's not a chick thing.
It's... You know, a triangle thing.
We all have to live
the Leah, Sam, Emily pain-fest.
Wolf telepathy, remember?
So, Sam dumps Leah
for Emily?
It wasn't like that.
Sam hates himself for hurting Leah.
But, Emily was The One.
Yeah, I guess it's sort of
chooses you sometimes.
It's more than some crush, Bella.
Sam imprinted on Emily.
Do I want to know what that is?
Imprinting on someone
is like...
Like when you see her,
everything changes.
All of a sudden, it's not
gravity holding you to the planet.
It's her.
Nothing else matters.
You would do anything...
Be anything for her.
It sounds like
you know the feeling.
Have you...
imprinted on someone?
You'd know if I had.
I just have a direct line
to Sam's thoughts.
So for now, you're...
still you.
- And you're still you.
- Yeah.
Until graduation.
graduation?
You knew
this was gonna happen.
Not in a month!
I mean, not before you've...
you've even lived!
Or before I could...
For a second, just a second,
I thought...
But he's got his hooks in you
so deep.
- I decided this, not him.
- Bella, they're not even a live!
It makes me sick!
Better you really be dead
than one of them.
I can't believe you said that.
Edward was right,
I shouldn't have come.
Bella, come on.
Please.
I'm sorry.
You know...
Edward could at least
respect meal times.
I was just with Jake.
Oh...
Good.
I'll just give you two
some privacy then.
Hey.
Do you understand
how worried I've been?
I was perfectly safe.
I almost break the treaty
to make sure of it.
- I know, I smell like a dog. I'm sorry.
- No, no. Something's wrong.
- Edward, what's wrong?
- Someone's been in here.
Who was it?
Someone we know?
Just a stranger.
I didn't recognize his scent.
A nomad passing through?
A passer-by wouldn't have left
Bella's father alive.
His scent disappeared about five miles
south of Bella's house.
- Someone's orchestrating this.
- Victoria?
- I would've seen her deciding.
- It has to be the Volturi.
I don't think
it's the Volturi either.
I've been watching
Aro's decisions, too.
So we keep looking.
We also take shifts,
guarding Bella at her house.
- A nother protection detail?
- Rosalie.
No, she's right.
You can't protect me,
watch my dad...
and search for the intruder.
- And for Victoria.
- And keep yourselves fed.
I'm not leaving you here
defenseless.
Well, I'm not gonna
let you starve.
And I wouldn't be unprotected,
I have...
What?
Whoever it was,
he left his stink behind.
It'll be hard to miss
when we cross it again.
- We'll handle it from here.
- We don't need you to handle anything.
- Or anyone.
- I could care less what you need.
Alright, we're done here.
- No, you're done here.
- Stop!
I'm tired of this.
From now on I'm Switzerland, Okay?
Edward hated the idea,
but it wasn't about rivalry anymore.
It was about my safety,
and Charlie's.
In the days that followed
I got them to at least try to work together.
The wolves took over
so the Cullen's can hunt.
It wasn't exactly
an easy alliance.
Doesn't he own a shirt?
I'm good here,
you should go.
- I'm not gonna be going long.
- Don't rush. You need to hunt.
Maybe you rush a little bit.
- Hey, beautiful.
- Hi.
So, whaddaya wanna do today?
Bike, hike, hang?
Your call.
Or we're going to a party tonight.
You sure this is okay?
I really hate being a party crasher.
Technically,
you're a Council Meeting crasher.
See. The Council leaders,
Dad, Quil's grandpa, and Sue Clearwater.
She took over for Harry
when he died.
Okay, I should not be here.
You're okay.
I thought...
I mean, they thought it would be
good for you to hear the histories.
The histories? The tribe's histories?
Aren't they secret?
We all got a role to play.
And you're a part of this.
I mean, it's the first time Seth,
Leah and Quil are hearing them, too.
But you are the first outsider.
Ever.
If I haven't known that,
I wouldn't believe you.
- And would've dressed better.
- Jake.
- Hey.
- It's about time, you got here.
Paul's been hoovering the grub.
But, I saved you some burgers.
Good looking out, Bro.
Bella, this is Seth Clearwater,
Leah's brother.
- Newest member of the pack.
- Newest, bestest, brightest.
And slowest.
- Come on. Your dad's about to start.
- Alright.
The Quileutes have been a small tribe
from the beginning...
But we've always had magic in
our blood.
We were great spirit warriors...
Shape shifters,
that transform into the powerful wolf.
This enabled us to scare off
our enemies,
and protect our tribe.
One day our warriors
came across a creature...
It looked like a man,
but it was hard like stone,
and cold as ice...
Our warriors' sharp teeth,
finally tore it apart...
But only fire
would completely destroy it.
They lived in fear,
the Cold Man was not alone.
And they were right.
She took her vengeance out
on the village.
Our elder chief,
Taha Aki,
was the only spirit warrior left
to save the tribe,
after his son was killed.
Taha Aki's Third Wife could sees
that he would lose...
The Third Wife
was no magical being,
no special powers, but one...
Courage.
The Third Wife's sacrifice
distracted the Cold Woman,
long enough for Taha Aki
to destroy her.
She saved the tribe.
Over time,
our enemies have disappeared.
But one remains...
The Cold Ones.
Our magic awakens
when they near.
And we sense it now,
we feel the threat in our blood.
Something terrible is coming.
And we must all be ready.
All of us.
What did you do to me?
- I'm so...
- Yeah, I know...
We'll find you someone
to drink.
Just try not to get killed,
will you?
I'm gonna need numbers.
Seattle is in a state of terror...
Police are baffled by the
escalating murders and disappearances.
Theories range from a vicious new gang
to a wildly active serial killer...
- Reporting live, Dawn Chubai. CNN.
- It's getting worse.
We're going to have
to do something.
It takes more than one of our kind
to cause the damage they're reporting.
Quite a few more.
They're undisciplined, conspicuous...
It's a Newborns.
What, like new vampires?
In their first few months
after the change.
That's when we're at our most
uncontrollable,
vicious, insane with thirst.
Something to look forward to.
No one has trained these newborns,
but this isn't random.
Someone's creating an army.
Oh, now we definitely
going to Seattle.
An Army of vampires?
And they've been created
to fight someone.
We're the only clan
even close to Seattle.
Regardless,
of who are they were may,
if we don't put a stop to them,
the Volturi will.
I'm surprised
they've let it go on this long.
Maybe they're behind it.
In Italy,
I read Aro's mind...
He wants me and Alice
to join him...
He knows we'd never choose him
as long as our family is still alive.
An army
could solve that for him.
Hey.
Did you eat dinner yet?
Um... no...
I haven't.
This kid Riley Biers,
disappeared over a year ago.
And his poor parents been papering
Seattle with these things ever since.
You think
they should just give up?
I wouldn't.
If it were you...
Not ever.
I have to figure out
what to tell people...
Whu I won't be home
for Christmases.
Why I won't visit.
Why they'll never see me again.
After a few decades,
everyone you know will be dead.
Problem solved.
Why are you so against me
becoming like you?
I've told you.
Be honest with me.
There's more.
I know the consequences,
of this choice you're making.
I've lived through it,
and to let you suffer that.
You believe I have a soul...
I don't.
But to risk yours, just for the sake
of never having to lose you.
It's the most selfish thing
I'll ever do.
I thought, maybe you were afraid
that I'll be too different.
Unlike. I won't be, you know...
warm.
And won't smell the same.
You'll always be my Bella.
My Bella, just less fragile.
Gosh, it's so pretty here.
So, Alice is planning
a big graduation party.
Which you're invited to.
Yeah,
I figured that.
What?
I just wanted to do this
differently.
Smoother.
But now, I'm out of time.
To what?
You need to hear the truth,
Bella.
Understand all your options.
You need to know...
That I'm in love with you.
And I want you to choose me,
instead of him.
I thought you understood.
- I don't feel that way for you.
- I don't buy it.
What don't you buy?
That's how I feel.
You feel something else for me,
you just won't admit it.
So I'm not giving up.
I'm gonna fight for you.
Until your heart stops beating.
Well, then you're not gonna have
to fight for long.
You're rushing into it because
you're afraid you'll change your mind.
No, I'm not.
I know what I want.
You wouldn't have
to change for me, Bella.
Or say goodbye to anybody.
I can give you more than him.
I mean, he probably can't even
kiss you without hurting you.
Feel that?
Flesh and blood and warmth.
Edward!
If you ever touch her
against her will again!
- Don't do this!
- She's not sure what she wants!
- Well, let me give you a clue!
- Wait for her to say the words!
- Fine! And she will!
- Jacob. Just go, okay!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey...
Easy guys, easy.
Let's take it down a notch. Alright?
What's going on?
I kissed Bella.
And she broke her hand...
Punching my face.
Total misunderstanding.
It's just a sprain,
should heal fairly quickly.
Trying to walk and chew gum
at the same time again, Bella?
- I punched a werewolf in the face.
- Bad ass...
You're gonna be
one tough little newborn.
Tough enough to take you on.
Don't worry about it.
Okay, any Leads?
No sign of the intruder. But Victoria
continues to make appearances.
Go blather to someone else
about the joys of becoming a newborn.
Okay.
Rosalie...
I don't understand what I did,
to make you hate me so much.
I don't hate you.
I don't particularly like you,
but...
- Bella, I envy you.
- What?
- That's ridiculous.
- No, it's not.
You have a choice.
I didn't.
None of us did. But you do,
and you're choosing wrong.
I don't care how miserable
your human life is.
My life is not miserable.
It's not perfect,
but nobody's life is perfect.
Mine was.
Absolutely perfect.
Everything as I still wanted.
To be married,
with a nice house and a husband...
to kiss me when he came home.
A family of my own.
Royce King was
the most eligible bachelor in town.
I barely knew him.
But I was young.
I was in love with the idea of love.
On the last night of my life,
I left a friend's house late.
- I wasn't far from home.
- Here she is.
Hey, Rose!
Come over here!
Here, hold this.
Hey, come over here.
We've been waiting for you.
Here she is
Royce.
You're drunk.
Isn't she lovely, John?
I told you she was a looker.
It's hard to say
with all those clothes on.
What do you say, Rose?
Why don't we take off a few layers?
Stop it!...
I'll see you tomorrow.
Sober.
Hey, where do you think
you're going?
- Stop it! Just stop it! Let go! Stop it!
- Comeback! Hey, you'll do as I say!
They left me in the street,
thinking I was dead.
Believe me, I wanted to be.
Carlisle found me,
he smelled all the blood...
- Thought he was helping me.
- I'm sorry.
I got my revenge on them.
One at a time.
I saved Royce for last,
so he'd know I was coming.
I was a little theatrical back then.
Things got better
after I found Emmett.
But we'll always be this.
Frozen,
never moving forward.
That's what I miss the most,
the possibilities.
Sitting on a front porch
somewhere,
Emmett gray haired
by my side,
surrounded by
our grandchildren,
their laughter.
I understand,
that's what you want.
But there's nothing
I'll ever gonna want, more...
than Edward.
You're wrong again.
After you've been changed,
there's one thing you'll want more...
One thing you'll kill for...
Blood.
What did I say,
about low profile?
Something's coming...
Something...
Bigger than any of us alone.
And if you can't...
control yourselves...
We're all going to die.
What's done is done,
just...
clean up after yourselves.
They've already drawn
too much attention.
So has our "inaction".
Others may begin to question
the Volturi's effectiveness.
Let them.
Maybe we should consult
with Aro.
Aro's decisions
are being watched.
We must decide.
Then decide sister.
It's time.
Yes, it is.
Either we let them do
what they were created for...
Or we end them.
Decisions, decisions...
When we were five,
they asked us what we wanted to be
when we grew up...
Our answers were things like
astronaut, president...
Or in my case, a princess.
When we were ten,
they asked again,
and we answered,
rock star, cowboy,
or in my case,
a gold medalist.
But now that we've grown up,
they want a serious answer.
Well, how about this...
who the hell knows?
This isn't the time to make
hard and fast decisions,
this is the time
to make mistakes.
Take the wrong train
and get stuck somewhere.
Fall in love,
a lot.
Major in philosophy, because there's
no way to make a career out of that.
Change your mind, and change it again,
because nothing is permanent.
So, make as many mistakes
as you can.
That way, someday,
when they ask what we wanna be...
we won't have to guess.
We'll know.
You've made it!
- Hey.
- What'd you think of my speech?
Too easy-breezy, too self-helpful?
You may admit it.
- No, you pretty much nailed it.
- Yeah?
- It's like I was born to lead, right?
- Oh, great. I love this song, let's go.
- What are you doing here?
- You invited me, remember?
Was my right hook
too subtle for you?
That was me
uninviting you.
Look, Bella. I'm sorry...
about, you know...
The kiss and your hand...
I'd blame it on the whole
inner animal thing...
But it was really just... me.
Being an ass.
I'm really sorry.
I brought you something.
A graduation present.
I made it myself.
Oh...
You made this?
It's really pretty.
Thanks.
I'll be right back.
- Alice, what did you see?
- The decision's been made.
- What's going on?
- You're not going to Seattle?
No...
They're coming here.
- They'll be here in four days.
- This could turn into a blood bath.
- Who's behind it?
- I didn't see anyone I recognize.
Maybe one...
I know his face.
He's local, Riley Biers.
He didn't start this.
Whoever did
is staying out of the action.
They must be playing with
the blind spots in your vision.
Either way,
the army is coming...
and there aren't enough of us
to protect the town.
Hold up!
What damn army?
- Newborns. Our kind.
- What are they after?
They were passing around
Bella's scent. A red blouse.
They're after Bella?
- What the hell does this mean?
- It means an ugly fight.
With lives lost.
Alright...
- We're in.
- No.
You'll get yourselves killed,
noway.
- I wasn't asking for permission.
- Edward.
It means
more protection for you.
Jacob. Do you believe Sam
will agree to... an understanding?
As long as we get to kill
some vampires.
- Jasper?
- They'll give us the numbers.
And the newborns won't know
they even exist.
- That'll give us an edge.
- We'll need to coordinate.
- Carlisle, they'll gonna get hurt.
- We'll all need some training.
Fighting newborns requires
knowledge that Jasper has.
You're welcome to join us.
Alright.
Name the time and place.
Jake...
You don't know
what you're getting yourself in to.
Bella...
This is what we do.
You should be happy.
Look at us, working together.
You're the one who wanted us
to get along, remember?
Again!
It's a graduation present.
They don't trust us enough
to be in their human forms.
They came.
That's what matters.
Will you translate?
Hey, Jake.
Welcome.
Jasper has experience
with newborns.
He'll teach us
how to defeat them.
They want to know
how the "newborns" is differ from us.
They're a great deal
stronger than us,
because their own human blood
lingers in their tissues.
Our kind is never more
physically powerful...
than in our first several months
of this life.
Carlisle's right.
That's why
they are created.
A newborn army, doesn't need
thousands like a human army.
And no human army
could stand against them.
The two most important things
to remember are, first...
Never let them
get their arms around you.
They'll crush you instantly.
The second...
Never go
for the obvious kill.
They'll be expecting that.
And you will lose.
Emmett?
Don't hold back.
Not in my nature.
Never lose focus.
One more thing...
Never turn your back
on your enemy.
Some of you,
are gonna get hurt.
Some of you
could get killed, because of me.
It's gonna be a hundred times
worse than this, right?
We're done for the day.
Jasper...
Are you sure, there's nothing
I can do to help?
Your presence alone,
your scent will distract the newborns.
Their hunting instinct will take over,
drive them crazy.
Good. I'm glad.
Hey.
How do you know so much
about this?
I didn't have quite the same upbringing
as my adopted siblings.
Those bites are like mine.
Battle scars.
All the training the Confederate Army
gave me...
was useless against
the newborns.
Still,
I never lost a fight.
This has happened
during the civil war?
I was the youngest major
in the Texas cavalry.
All without having seen
any real battle.
Until...
Until I'm not a certain immortal.
Maria.
I was riding back
to Galveston...
after evacuating
a column of women and children.
When I saw her...
I immediately offered her my aid.
Lovely. And an officer.
You'd better do it, Maria.
I can never stop once I've started.
- What's your name, soldier?
- Major Jasper Whitlock, Ma'am.
I hope you survive.
You maybe of
a great use to me.
Maria was creating an army?
They were very common
in the South.
And cost a brutal battles
for territory.
Maria won them all.
She was smart, careful.
And she had me.
I was the second in command.
My abilities to control emotions
served her well.
I trained her newborns.
An endless occupation since she never
let them live beyond their first year.
It was my job
to dispose of them.
I could feel
everything they felt.
I thought what Maria and I had
was love.
But I was her puppet.
She pulled the strings.
I didn't know
there was another way...
Until I found Alice.
Now she'd seen me coming,
of course.
Kept me waiting long enough.
My apologies, Ma'am.
I don't know what I'd have become
without her.
You'll never have to be
that again.
What is it?
The intruder...
The newborn army.
They're all her puppets.
Victoria.
Alice would've seen
if she wanted to make an army.
Unless she's hiding
behind them,
and she's letting
someone else decide.
Welcome to the army.
I'm not just gonna hide,
while you're taking
all the risks for me?
If it's Victoria involved...
I need to keep you as far away
from the fight as possible.
Jasper said that
I could be of help.
We won't need your help.
With the wolves in this,
it's an easy win.
The rest of us,
aren't gonna have enough to do.
Okay, either it's so dangerous
that I have to hide...
Or it's so easy, that you're gonna be
side blind, which is it?
It's dangerous for you.
It's easy for us.
I think it's dangerous
for us to be apart.
How many times
we have to prove that?
I'll be worrying.
You'll be worried.
And we''ll both
feel more horrible.
Okay, you're right.
So, I'm coming with you.
No, we've got
to stay away together.
I can't make you choose
between me and your family, it's...
The only way I can protect you,
is to be with you.
You're not fighting?
What, you pull a muscle
or something?
- He's doing it for me. Okay?
- Whatever.
Just tell me the plan.
This field will give us
an advantage in battle.
We need to lure the newborns
with Bella's scent.
It needs to end here.
Edward and I
are going on a campsite.
Even if he carries me,
they'll still pick up our scents.
Your stench, however,
is revolting.
Dude, you really don't want
to start comparing stinks.
What he means, is that your scent
will mask mine if you carry me.
Done.
This is not a good idea.
Edward.
They won't want to get
anywhere near his... odor.
Okay, let's just try it.
- Eau de wolf, comin' up.
- Run.
You gonna ask me
to sit out the fight, too?
Or don't you care
about my safety?
Of course I care,
but you'd say no.
So I won't have a choice
anyways.
Since I let Sam be alpha male.
I got to live with the shots
he calls.
Since you let Sam be alpha?
I didn't want to be in a pack,
let alone be it's their leader.
Wow.
- Chief Jacob.
- Opted out.
But every choice has
it's consequences.
- Some more than others.
- Don't start.
Everybody makes choices,
you gonna have to accept mine.
You can love more than
one person at a time.
I've seen it,
with Sam, Emily, and Leah.
Well...
- I'm not a wolf, I can't imprint.
- It has nothing to do with imprinting.
It has to do with...
Feeling something for somebody.
And I know
you feel something for me.
I can sense
how I make you feel...
Physically.
I make you nervous.
Jake.
Don't worry.
I promised I wouldn't kiss you
again until you asked.
You're going to be keeping
that promise for a while, Chief.
All I picked up was wolf stench.
No Bella.
- This will work.
- Great.
- Okay, Alice. Don't be a stranger.
- Okay.
Your alibi for the battle
is all arranged.
Really?
I told your father that our whole
family's going camping this weekend.
So you and I are having
a sleep over at my house.
- Charlie is going fishing anyway.
- Charlie?
You guys run
for the same basis now?
Me, he likes.
Actually, you and Edward will have
the house to yourself tonight.
Like alone?
We're all going hunting,
powering up for the battle.
You're welcome.
- Hey. Do you want a sandwich?
- No, I'm good.
Well, the sister...
I like.
Alice.
Yeah, she's great.
Hey, Dad.
I was wondering...
Why didn't you get remarried,
after Mom?
I don't know...
Guess I still haven't met
the right gal.
- Why?
- I don't know.
I thought you just...
Maybe you gave up
on the whole institution of it.
Of marriage.
But do you think
there's any value in it?
Yeah.
Yeah, marriage has value.
When you're older.
Much older.
Like you're mother...
It seem to work out fine for her
the second time round.
- Later in life.
- Yeah, I guess.
I mean...
You definitely don't wanna
have to get married,
because you weren't...
careful.
What?
Look, you know
what I'm talking about.
There's...
Things, that you need
to think about it, if you...
If you gonna be...
physically intimate.
Okay. Don't...
until we've enough of "The Talk".
- Don't you just quit.
- It's just as embarrassing for me,
- as it is for you.
- I doubt that.
And don't bother, 'cause Mom
beat you too early ten years ago.
Well, you didn't have a boyfriend
ten years ago.
I'm sure things work
the same way.
Alright.
So...
You guys are...
taking precautions, and...
Okay, dad. Please just
don't worry about that.
Edward is... old school.
Old school, great.
What's that?
Like a code for something?
Oh my god.
Dad...
I'm a virgin!
Okay, go.
Glad we covered that.
Me too.
Virgin...
Liking Edward
a little bit more now.
What are you doing here outside?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It seems the only fair,
that I'd be represented as well.
It's really pretty.
Thanks.
There's a bed.
I thought you might need one
to sleep in.
I think an air mattress
would've sufficed.
- It is too much?
- No.
No, it's perfect.
I want to ask you something.
Anything.
Okay, marriage
is the condition for you,
to change me yourself, right?
Yes.
Okay. I want to negotiate my
own condition.
Anything you want,
It's yours.
Do you promise?
Yeah.
Bella... no.
You've said that you wanted me
to have every human experience.
Not the ones
that support risk killing you.
You won't.
And everyone says,
once I'm changed...
all I'm gonna want is
to slaughter the whole town.
That part doesn't last forever.
I want you.
While I'm still me.
While I still want you this way.
It's too dangerous.
Try...
Just try.
I'll go to some ridiculously
expensive college
and let you buy me a car.
I'll marry you, just try.
Stop trying to take
your clothes off.
- Do you want to do that part?
- Not tonight.
Okay.
I mean, you don't...
But, fine.
Believe me, I want to.
I just want to be married
to you first.
You really make me feel like
I'm some sort of like a villain trying...
steal your virtue
or something.
It's not my virtue
I'm concerned about.
Are you kidding?
It's just one rule,
I wanna leave unbroken.
It might be too late for my soul,
but I will protect yours.
- I know it's not a modern notion.
- It's not modern.
It's ancient.
I'm from a different era.
Things were...
a lot less complicated.
And if I met you back then,
I would've courted to you.
We'd have taken
chaperoned strolls,
or had iced tea
on the porch.
I may have stolen
a kiss or two.
But, only...
after asking
your father's permission.
I would've got down
on one knee.
And I would
presented you with a ring.
This was my mother's.
Isabella Swan. I promise
to love you, every moment forever.
And would you do me the extraordinary
honor of marrying me?
Yes.
You're not coming with us?
It will be a last minute decision.
I told you how it works.
The Cullens have powers.
Don't underestimate them,
Riley.
You'll have the numbers,
but they'll be able to...
anticipate your every move.
- According to your friend.
- Yes.
My dead friend.
Laurent found out about
the things they could do,
and they killed him.
But not before he told me.
Maybe he was wrong.
I mean...
This is supposed to be...
Cullen territory.
But we've been tearing it up
and I've never even seen them here.
You don't trust me.
With my life.
I'm just saying that...
I'm doing this for us.
So that we can feed,
without their retaliation.
I can't live in fear anymore,
waiting for them to attack.
I won't let them.
I'm going to
end the Cullen clan.
I swear.
I love you. So much.
You're going overboard.
If this is all I can contribute,
I want to be thorough.
The newborns will be frantic.
It's Okay. Don't make yourself
uncomfortable.
It doesn't bother me anymore.
Since when?
Since I spent 24 hours
thinking you were dead.
You're not wearing your ring.
Well, I didn't want to risk
losing it.
Or risk Jacob seeing it?
I think we should wait to tell him.
I mean, at least till after the fight.
- If you're having second thoughts...
- I'm not.
I just want him to have
a clear head.
Whose head is unclear?
Nobody's, I hope.
Alice says
there's a storm coming.
Yeah, I can feel it.
We should get going.
I'll see you
in a couple of hours.
Something up?
A bunch of vampires
trying to kill me.
Same old, same old.
Thank you.
You should get back
before the storm hits.
No, I'm staying.
You'll need my connection
to the pack,
to keep tabs
on what's going on.
- You're not going to fight?
- Seth will spell me in the morning.
He's not happy
about missing the action,
but it'll keep him
out of trouble.
Let's get you inside.
I should have chosen
a site lower down.
No, It's fine. I'm okay.
What can I do?
I can't sleep with all that
teeth chattering going on.
Forget it.
She may need her toes someday.
And let's face it...
I'm hotter than you.
Get your hand off me!
Get your hands off her!
Don't fight.
She gets sick, it's on you.
Why!
you're freezing, Bella
Relax,
You'll warm up soon.
Faster
if you took your clothes off.
- Jake.
- Survival one oh one.
Can you, at least attempt
to control your thoughts?
I really get under that
ice cold skin of yours, don't I?
What?
Are you doubting her feelings
for you?
Nice...
So picking through
my brain's okay,
but letting me into yours,
forget it.
Look...
- I know she's in love with you.
- Oh, good.
But she's in love with me, too.
She just won't admit it to herself.
I can't tell you
if you're right.
Then let me ask you something.
- If she chooses me...
- She won't.
If she did.
Would you try to kill me?
That's an intriguing idea.
But no.
I couldn't hurt her like that.
see, you'd just turn her into
a bloodsucking demon like you.
I don't want that.
I never wanted that.
- So stop her.
- I tried.
- I left.
- But you gave up too quickly.
If you'd stayed away
another six months,
I could've made her happy.
Trust me.
You have to consider...
that I might be better for her
than you are.
I have considered that.
I know you can protect her.
But you can give her a life,
a human life.
It's all I want for her.
But, I'm not...
I'm not going to force her
into anything, ever again.
The last time I tried,
it almost killed us both.
Yeah, that I remember.
When you thought
she was gone...
that you'd lost her...
How did you... cope?
There're no words.
But I wouldn't wash it
on anyone, Jacob.
This might sound odd,
but I'm glad you're here.
Pretty neat.
As much as I'd love to kill you,
I'm glad she's warm.
If we weren't
natural enemies...
and you weren't trying to steal
my reason for existing...
I might actually like you.
Well...
If you weren't planning on sucking
the life out of the girl I love,
I might...
No...
Not even then.
But she could still
change her mind, you know.
Then I'd let her go.
Fine. Hi, Seth.
Where's Jacob?
Did he already...
Not yet.
He's checking to see if the woods
are clear before he goes.
I'm really sorry
about last night.
I couldn't have been
easy on you.
It definitely won't make my list
of top ten favorite evenings.
You have a list?
All ten I spent with you.
Number one is when you said
you'd marry me.
Mrs. Cullen.
This is the twenty-first century,
I always wanna
hyphenate my name.
You're marrying him?
Jake...
You knew he was listening?
He deserves to know.
- Jake, stop!
- Bella, let him...
Don't!
Jake, stop!
- Jake, please!
- I'm done! I'm so done!
- What can I do?
- You can't do anything.
I can. By going out there
and killing something.
No! You're not thinking clearly,
don't do that!
Maybe I'll get my self killed
and make it simple for you.
No! Just, Jake...
Stay!
Why?
Give me one good reason.
Because I don't wanna lose you.
It's not good enough.
Because you're too important.
Still not good enough.
Jacob!
Kiss me!
I'm asking you to kiss me.
That should have been
our first kiss.
I gotta go.
I'll be back.
You saw.
No. But Jacob's thoughts
are very loud.
I don't know what happened.
You love him.
I love you more.
I know.
It's starting.
Jacob just got there.
He's good.
Someone's hurt?
She's close.
I can hear her thoughts.
Seth, go.
She knew we weren't there,
but she caught my scent.
She knew you'd be with me.
She found us.
She's not alone.
Riley...
Listen to me.
Victoria's just using you,
to distract me.
But she knows I'll kill you.
In fact, she'll be glad she doesn't
have to deal with you anymore.
Don't listen, Riley.
I told you
about their mind tricks.
I can read her mind,
so I know what she thinks of you.
He's lying.
She only created you and this army
to avenge her true mate, James.
It's the only thing
she cares about. Not you.
There's only you.
You know that.
Think about it.
You're from Forks,
you know the area.
That's the only reason
she chose you.
She doesn't love you.
Riley...
Don't let him do this to us.
You know I love you.
You're dead.
You won't get another chance
like this again.
You want her!
You want me to feel the pain
you felt when I killed James.
When I tore him to pieces.
When I turned him into ash.
When I turned him
into nothing.
Victoria!
- Something's wrong.
- Alice needs us to go.
And now.
- How long?
- A few minutes. Maybe ten.
The pack needs to leave.
The Volturi won't honor a truce
with the werewolves.
Leah, don't!
Jacob!
Jacob. Hold on, Carlisle
is gonna take care of you.
The bones on the right half
of his body are shattered.
- Bella.
- Jake, I'm right here.
- Jacob, you idiot. I had it.
- Leah.
I need to set the bones before
his accelerated healing kicks in.
- It's already starting.
- We need to get him out of here.
We're not gonna win a fight
with the Volturi.
- We'll take him back to Billy's.
- I'll be there as soon as I can.
Hang in there, Jake.
We got you.
They're coming.
Impressive.
I've never seen a coven escape
an assault of this magnitude intact.
We were lucky.
I doubt that.
It appears we missed
an entertaining fight.
Yes. It's not often
we're rendered unnecessary.
If you'd arrived a half hour ago,
you would've fulfilled your purpose.
Pity.
You missed one.
We offered her asylum
in exchange for her surrender.
That wasn't yours to offer.
Why did you come?
Who created you?
You don't need to do that.
She'll tell you
anything you want to know.
I know.
I don't know
Riley wouldn't tell us.
He said our thoughts
weren't safe.
Her name was Victoria.
Perhaps you knew her.
Edward. If the Volturi had
knowledge of Victoria,
they would've stopped her.
Isn't that right, Jane?
Of course.
Felix.
She didn't know
what she was doing.
We'll take responsibility for her.
Give her a chance.
The Volturi don't give
second chances.
Keep that in mind.
Caius will be interested to know
that she's still human.
The date is set.
Take care of that, Felix.
I'd like to go home.
- It's been going on for a while.
- Doc's rebreaking his bones.
Why'd he have to butt in?
I could've taken that tick...
Oh, give it a rest, Leah.
The worst is over.
He'll be alright.
I gave him some morphine,
but his body temperature
will burn it off soon.
I'll come back
to set up a drip.
Thank you.
He's asking for you.
Hey, Jake.
Hey.
I was worried about you.
You were worried about me?
Yeah.
I guessed Edward
would read my thoughts.
Was he hard on you?
He wasn't even mad at me.
Or you.
Well, damn.
He's better than I thought.
He's not playing a game.
Right.
Bella...
He's not as perfect
as you think.
I know who he is.
I must not talk about that.
I'd rather get all the rebreaking
done at once.
At least I know
I did everything I could.
Wasn't easy making you
admit your feelings for me.
I only fought them, because I know
they wouldn't change anything.
I'm exactly right for you,
Bella.
It would be as easy
as breathing with me.
You know I love you.
You know how much
I wish it was enough.
Should I come back?
I need some time.
But I'll always be waiting.
Untill my heart stops beating.
Maybe even then.
- August thirteenth?
- Yeah.
it's a month
before my birthday.
I don't need to be
another year older than you.
Alice said she can get
the wedding together by then.
I'm sure she can.
There's no rush.
I've chosen my life.
I want to start living it.
And so, you're gonna let Alice
plan the whole thing?
Yeah.
Dress, the reception,
the guest list...
I mean, who knows
who she's gonna invite?
Does it matter?
I just don't know
why you're doing this.
What? The wedding?
You're trying to make
everyone else happy.
But you're already
giving away too much.
You're wrong.
This wasn't a choice
between you and Jacob.
It was between who I should be
and who I am.
I've always felt out of step.
Like literally,
stumbling through my life.
I'm never felt normal.
Because I'm not normal.
I don't wanna be.
I've had to face death...
and loss and pain,
in your world.
But, I've also never felt
stronger...
more real, more...
my self.
Because it's my world, too.
It's where I belong.
So, it's not just about me.
No, sorry.
I've made a mess trying
to figure all this out, but...
I wanna do it right.
And I wanna tie my self
to you,
in every way
humanly possible.
Starting with a wedding.
Actually...
Something,
a little more difficult first.
And maybe even dangerous.
We have to tell Charlie.
It's highly dangerous.
It's a good thing
you're bulletproof.
I'm gonna need that ring.