Halt. Look down.
Keep walking.
Inquiry Prison of the Ministry for State Security.
Address him as Captain.
Come in.
Sit down.
Hands under your thighs,
palms down.
What do you have to tell us?
I haven't done anything.
I don't know anything.
You've done nothing,
know nothing.
So you think we just
arrest innocent citizens on a whim?
No, not...
If you think our humane system
is capable of something like that,
...that'd be reason enough
to arrest you.
We want to jog your memory,
Prisoner 227:
Your friend and neighbor
fled the Republic on September 28th .
And we have reason to believe
he was helped.
I don't know anything about it.
He never told me, he wanted to leave.
I first heard about it at work.
Describe what you did
on the 28th of September.
- That's already on record.
- Once more please.
I took my kids to the park for a walk,
...ran into an old classmate
there, Max Kirchner,
...went to his place and
listened to music into the evening.
He has a phone. You can call him.
He'll corroborate everything.
I can gladly give you the number.
The enemy of our State is arrogant.
Remember that.
We have to be patient with him, some 40 hours of patience.
I'll fast forward some.
I want to sleep.
Please let me sleep.
Hands under your thighs.
Please explain again
what you did on September 28th.
Please, just an hour, just a little...
just a little sleep...
Tell me again what you did on this day.
Why did you have to keep him
awake for so long?
I mean, that's inhumane.
An innocent prisoner becomes angrier
every hour he is kept there,
...because of the injustice done to him.
He screams and rants.
A guilty one becomes quieter,
says nothing...
...or starts to cry.
He knows that he rightly sits there.
If you want to know
whether someone is guilty or not,
...the best way is to keep asking
until they no longer can.
...classmate Max Kirchner.
We went to his place
...and listened to music into the evening.
He has a phone.
You can call him.
He'll corroborate everything.
Anyone notice anything
about this statement?
He says pretty much
the same thing.
He says exactly the same thing,
word for word.
Those who tell the truth
can paraphrase whenever.
Do that as well.
A liar has particular sentences to fall back on
during states of increased stress.
227 is lying. We have 2 important indications,
and can increase the intensity.
If you don't tell me the name of the escapee's helper,
your wife will be arrested tonight...
..and your kids put into
a state reformatory.
Is that what you want?
What's the helper's name?
Who was it?
- Glaesker.
- Come again, louder.
Glaesker. Werner Glaesker.
Werner...Glaesker.
Quiet.
Quiet!
Listen.
Can anyone tell me
what that is?
The preserved scent for the dogs.
It's to be removed after every interrogation,
and never left behind.
With interrogation, you are working
with enemies of Socialism.
Don't forget that.
Have a nice day.
That was good!
That was really good.
How was it,
...when we sat here together 20 years ago?
Ya know, they proposed me
for a professor job.
See, grades don't matter in the real world,
even though mine weren't too bad.
What's on your agenda?
Why do you always think
I have a hidden agenda?
- I just wanted to invite you to the theater.
- The theater?
I heard that Minister Bruno Hempf
is going to be there tonight.
I ought to attend
as head of the Culture Department.
It starts at 7.
We should get going.
The Lives of Others
Minister Bruno Hempf,
1 o'clock.
He worked for the Ministry,
before he was called into the Central committee.
Cleaned house in those
days with the theater scene.
Georg Dreyman, the poet.
He's the kind of arrogant guy
I always warn my students about.
Arrogant, but loyal.
If everyone were like him,
I'd be jobless.
He's our only unsuspicious author
and is still read in the West.
For him, the GDR is the best
country in the world.
See for yourself.
Dear child, what's wrong?
A new vision?
Say something, Martha! Please!
Your Arthur...
...no longer lives.
Arthur? Isn't it possible
you're wrong this time?
No sisters, believe me.
He has fallen into death.
The powerful wheel has ground him up.
I see it,
...and would rather see any other horror.
Why am I not spared from this vision?
Elena, go home.
And, did you like it?
Dreyman's good, huh?
I would have him monitored.
Monitored? That teaching is
corrupting your instincts, Wiesler.
I'd even be the point man.
I told you he's cleaner than clean.
Even Hempf came to his premiere.
If you monitor someone like that,
you bite the hand that feeds.
I'm going downstairs for a sec.
"Faces of Love"
I'm hearing a lot about your work.
They say, "our culture is in good hands".
Your name is mentioned
often in the party.
We're "the shield and
sword of the party", Minister
We're conscious of that every moment.
What do you think of him?
Georg Dreyman?
Maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe he's not...not as clean as it seems.
Grubitz, that's why guys like you
and me are at the top.
The standard Stasi schmuck would've said:
he's one of our country's best, loyal, all this garbage
...but we see more.
You could make it up the ladder, Grubitz.
There's something fishy about him.
I feel it in my gut, and it doesn't lie.
Next week Thursday is a party at Dreyman's.
A few shady people are coming,
Hauser and those vermin.
Try and organize something by then,
...something small and discreet,
procedures A and B.
Just his apartment, nothing flashy.
He has powerful friends.
No one can find out about this
until we've found something.
And when you find something against him,
you've got a fat friend in the Central committee.
Know what I mean?
Minister, have a good evening.
Why's he still watching?
What's he even doing here?
I think, he fancies you.
I insist on proposing the toast tonight
to our community of culture.
A famous Socialist once said:
"The poet is the engineer of the soul."
And Georg Dreyman is one of the most
important engineers in our country.
- Charming comrades.
- Paul! Stop that.
And of course Christa-Maria Sieland.
She is the most beautiful pearl of the GDR.
I won't accept any objections to that.
So, please raise your glasses and toast
to Christa-Maria Sieland. May you live long!
- The fact, someone like that can even address you...
- Please, stay here.
And now another lively number.
May I?
- How did you like my little speech?
- Thank you very much.
I liked your play as well.
Really, it was good.
"Engineer of the soul".
That was Stalin you quoted.
Oh yeah?
Well, I like to provoke
every now and then, Hauser.
But on the other hand,
I know how far I can take that.
In that way, I'm more like
our dear Dreyman.
He knows that the party needs the artist,
but the artist the party even more.
If you guys want to talk politics,
I need to find someone else to dance with.
- I'm ready.
- Too late, too late.
I've been following the developments
of our theater for a while.
- Didn't you follow them professionally before?
- Paul!
It's fine Herr Dreyman.
We've known each other for a long time.
Herr Schweiber.
You did a fine job tonight as well.
Dreyman, I'm glad you're
working with such directors now.
There were other times though...
You mean Jerska?
I think you sentenced him too harshly.
Of course. His statement
crossed the line. No question.
But...
...put yourself in his position for a minute,
you as a man of your word.
He can't take back his signature
from this declaration.
Comrade Hempf, the man could
work at any theater in the West.
But he doesn't want to leave,
because he firmly believes in Socialism and this country.
- His career ban is absolute...
- Who said anything about a career ban?
That doesn't exist here.
You ought to choose your words more carefully.
Comrade Hempf, I'll tell you this now:
My plays aren't so good,
that someone like Schweiber could direct them.
I need Jerska.
- And I think you sentenced him too hard...
- See here. I don't think so.
But that's what we all love about your plays.
The love of man, good people,
...believing that someone can change.
Dreyman...
...no matter how often
you write that in your plays,
...people don't change.
So how's he doing anyway?
He was hoping that his career b...
...that he'd be allowed to work again soon.
- Can he hope?
- Of course. As long as he's alive, and even longer.
As you know Dreyman,
"Hope is the last thing to die".
The Tech. Team will be ready
tomorrow morning for the wiretapping.
It's important that everything's done by Thursday.
It's all up to you.
Can you manage that?
Good night.
Need to go.
Otherwise, I'll get in trouble.
- By who?
- My girlfriend.
20 minutes.
Yes?
Frau Meineke, one word to anyone...
...and your Marscha loses
her acceptance to medical school.
Is that understood?
Yeah.
Send Frau Meineke a thank-you gift
for her secrecy.
Thursday already.
Time goes by too fast.
It's better so.
- How're you doing?
- Not too bad.
It's not always this noisy.
I know, just on Thursdays.
Yeah.
- We missed you at the premiere.
- Schweiber have a good epiphany?
- What was good, he stole from you.
- That's how my ideas stay alive.
Don't think me evil, but I can't stand
the sight of these fat, spiffed up people at such a premiere.
That doesn't sound like me, does it?
But maybe it does after all.
Maybe that wasn't the real me back then
...friendly and kind to people
off the concentrated feed of success,
...for which I'm indebted
to the big shots for their mercy.
But I'll stop complaining.
In my next life I want to be a writer,
a happy writer who can write all the time.
Like you.
What does a director have
if he's not allowed to direct?
Nothing more than a projectionist without films,
a miller without flour. He has nothing left.
Nothing left...
Albert, the Minister was at
the premiere too. Minister Hempf.
I talked to him about your ban.
It's looking good.
He gave me some hope,
was very literal, very specific.
Really?
That's nice.
Jerska, the wine connoisseur.
And how's our sacred drinker doing? Is he coming?
I forgot to ask him.
You're vigorous and strong.
And I need you.
- Don't bring this destructive cycle into your life.
- Albert's my friend.
- And you're mine too.
- Looks like something for a 50th birthday party.
I'm turning 40 though, aren't I?
Don't forget. You promised to wear
a tie for your birthday.
I would, but I don't have one.
No more excuse.
- A tie?
- You did say, you didn't want any books.
Or can't you tie one after all,
you old working poet?
Ya think, I can't tie a tie?
I was born with a tie.
You forget, I had to break free
of this chain of the middle class.
Then chain yourself to it just once more for me.
Tying a tie.
A minor detail.
Frau Meineke,
come here for a second.
Can you tie a tie?
You can't imagine
how grateful I am.
- Something wrong?
- No, I'm fine.
Done?
Wonderful! It's perfect.
Couldn't be better.
But this has to be our secret.
You can keep a secret, can't you?
Yes.
Gosh! I really didn't
think you could do it.
You don't beat around the bush
when it comes to what you can do.
You just didn't know
I can do almost anything.
Our first guest.
Our dear good neighbors
locked the door downstairs.
- Can you go?
- On my way.
Master? Our present.
I specifically said, no books. Thank you.
Want something to drink?
- Sure. A seltzer.
- Vodka for me.
I'll get it.
What the hell.
Why's Albert sitting by himself?
He doesn't want to talk to us.
He just turned us away.
I brought you something too.
- Did you really come here to read?
- It's Brecht anyway.
I feel like an impostor
amongst all these people.
Impostor? Come on Albert.
You're losing grip on reality.
You know we admire you.
Every one admires you.
Yeah, for something I did
10 years ago...
...and probably could never do again.
Ah. My favorite director.
Wait a sec, I need to talk to you.
Man, explain to me exactly
how you got this job.
Your talent, naturally. Of course!
But what else did you do? Hm?
Every one knows,
you're with the Stasi, you washout.
- That's an unbelievable allegation.
- Don't forget that...
- Paul!
- What?
Schweiber, excuse my friend.
He's had too much to drink.
What's with you?
You know he's with the Stasi.
No, Paul.
I don't know that.
You're such a miserable idealist,
you're almost some big shot.
Who do you think messed up Jerska so bad?
People like that.
Narks, traitors and conformers.
You have to pick a side sometime,
otherwise you're not a person.
If you want to do something about it, then call me.
Otherwise we don't need to see each other anymore.
- Your friends don't have much taste, do they?
- That's really unfair.
The back scratcher, for example.
It's wonderful.
That's a salad fork.
Never the less.
Wonderful.
Check this out.
I'll write my next play with this.
You don't have any taste either.
For some things I do.
- From Jerska.
- Probably gave you a book.
"The Sonata of Good Men"
11:04 pm: "Lazlo" and CMS unwrapped gifts.
Afterwards prob. sexual intercourse.
You're late.
Excuse me, Captain. I got stuck at a red light,
can easily lose 4 minutes there.
You know how it is.
Already at it, eh? I don't believe it.
These artists! They've got it going on.
Ya know colleague, that's why I
monitor artists instead of priests or peacekeepers.
See you tomorrow at 11am.
Albert Jerska, the "Engerling" file.
Wiesler. Systematic as usual.
Take your jacket off.
Let's get some lunch.
"Volleyball game at 7pm tonight."
You haven't been here for a while.
The officer's table is over here.
Socialism has to start somewhere.
To your question about the limo
that brought Frau Sieland home the other night...
It's Minister Hempf's car.
Wiesler, we're not allowed to record senior comrades.
I deleted the citation from your report.
Next time there's something like this,
report it to me personally, not written.
We're helping our Committee member
get rid of his rival.
In light of this new information,
I don't need to say what that means for my career.
And for yours.
If we do find something.
Is that why we enlisted?
Remember what we swore?
- To be "the shield and sword of the party".
- And what's the party other than its members?
If they've got a lot of influence,
all the better.
I've got a new one.
So, Honecker comes into his office
in the morning
...opens the window, looks at the sun,
and says...
...uh, what's wrong?
Oh excuse me.
That was...I'm just...I...
No, please colleague. We can still
laugh about our state officials. Don't worry.
I probably know it already anyway.
Come on. Tell it.
Well, Honecker,
I mean, the General Secretary
...sees the sun and says:
"Good morning, dear sun."
And the sun answered:
"Good morning, dear Erich."
At noon Erich sees it again
and says: "Good day, dear sun."
And the sun said: "Good day, dear Erich."
After work Honecker goes back to the window
and says: "Good evening, dear sun."
But the sun doesn't answer.
So he says again:
"Good evening, dear sun. What's wrong?"
And the sun answers:
"Oh kiss my ass, I'm in the West now."
Name?
Rank?
Department?
Me?
Stiegler.
2nd Lieut. Axel Stiegler.
Department M.
Don't think I need to say what that
means for your career, what you just did.
Please...Lieutenant Colonel...I just...
You just mocked our party.
That was political agitation.
Surely just the tip of the iceberg.
I'm going to report this
to the Minister's office.
I was just kidding!
Pretty good, huh?
Your's was good too.
But I've got a better one.
What's the difference between
Erich Honecker and a telephone?
Nothing.
Hang up and try again.
- Hey I gotta go home. See ya!
- Night.
Cold?
Christa, Christa. You forgot about
our date on Thursday.
Or did your poet have
2 birthdays in a row?
Come on.
Get in.
You don't know
what's good for you.
Don't worry.
I'll take good care of you.
Don't tell me
you don't need it too.
Just say the word
and I'll let you go right now.
I'm already busy.
Where do you think
I'm taking you to?
I'm taking you him.
You'll get there faster.
Time for some bitter truth.
Yeah?
These idiots.
See you next Thursday.
Drive.
Christa?
Hold me tight.
Evening Captain.
You're 5 minutes late, again.
Good evening. 11th floor.
On the right.
I'm already up here.
- How did you get in the building?
- A few other guys from the Ministry live here.
I don't think I've ever been here before.
I don't think so either.
Was that good?
- Please, stay here a little longer.
- I can't.
I have another customer at 1:30.
I work by appointments.
1:30. You won't make it in time.
Yeah I will.
Don't worry.
Next time, book a longer time.
Bye.
Georg, did you heard about Hauser?
No. What about him?
His lecture tour in the West was cancelled.
He didn't get a travel permit.
Are you surprised?
If he's going to act so arrogant,
he ought to expect something like this to happen.
Would you allow him to travel,
if you were in their shoes?
"'Lazlo' supports Hauser's travel abroad ban."
- Have you seen my yellow volume of Brecht?
- What?
My Brecht volume.
Don't know where it is.
Weird. I can't find it.
"On that day in blue-mooned September,
quiet under a young plum tree,"
"I held her there, that silent pale love,
in my arms like a graceful dream."
"And above us in the summer sky,
was a cloud I saw for a time."
"On top it was white and tremendous.
And as I looked up, there was not but one sign."
- Yes?
- Georg? This is Wallner.
What is it?
Georg, it's about Jerska.
He's dead.
He hung himself last night.
Georg?
I'm gonna hang up, ok?
I'm thinking about what
Lenin said about Beethoven's "Appassionata".
"I can't listen to it,
otherwise I won't be able to finish the revolution."
Can someone who's
listened to this music
...really listened
...still be a bad person?
Do you really work for the Stasi?
Do you know what that is? The Stasi?
Yes. My dad says they're
bad men who lock people up.
I see.
What's the name of your...?
My what?
Your ball.
What's your ball's name?
You're weird.
Balls don't have names.
Everything is happening, Minister.
State-of-the-art technology
...under every light switch,
even in the john.
- The foyer is being monitored per procedure C...
- You said, you'd find something.
Find something already.
I wouldn't want my worst enemy
to disappoint me.
Get out of here.
Nowack, you're going to monitor Christa-Maria.
Report every minute she's not
with me. Understood?
We banned Hauser's travel permit.
Maybe that'll get something going.
Those two are pretty close.
How's it going between
CMS and the Minister?
They're meeting tomorrow night,
if I understand their rhythm.
Good. The both of us have a lot
to gain from their love story.
Or a lot to lose.
Don't forget that.
In the past,
I was scared of only 2 things:
Being alone and not being able to write.
Since Albert's death,
I don't care about writing.
Or other people.
Now I'm just afraid of being without you.
Don't be scared of losing me tonight.
- I'm just going out for an hour.
- Where?
I'm meeting up with a classmate.
Really Christa?
- Really?
- What are you getting at?
I know.
I know where you want to go.
And I'm asking you, don't go.
You don't need him.
I know about the pills, too.
And how little you trust your art.
At least trust me.
Christa-Maria...
You are a great artist.
I know it.
And your audience knows it too.
You don't need him.
Stay here.
Don't go to him.
No, I don't need him,
don't need this scandalous system.
What about you?
You don't need it either,
even less than I do.
But you're in bed with him too.
Why?
Because they can destroy you too,
despite your talent you haven't doubted yet.
Because they decide
who can act and direct.
You don't want to end up like Jerska.
And I don't want that either.
And that's why I'm going.
You're right about many things.
I want to do things differently.
But I'm asking you.
I'm begging you. Don't go.
So boss. On time?
Lemme guess
what they're up to.
Come on. I'll take over.
I can't be held responsible
for you doing overtime because of me.
"Don't go through this door."
Where's she off to?
Meeting an old schoolmate.
You can read the detailed report tomorrow.
I'll take care of it.
Good night.
What're you staring at?
Seltzer.
No, uh. Vodka.
2 shots.
Another shot.
Bring me a cognac, please.
Ma'am?
Please let me be.
I want to be alone.
Frau Sieland.
Do we know each other?
You don't know me,
but I know you.
A lot of people love you...
...because you are how you are.
- Acting isn't real.
- With you it is.
I've seen you on stage.
You were more yourself then, than...
...than how you are now.
So, you know how I am?
I am your audience.
- I have to go.
- Where are you going?
I'm meeting an old schoolmate. I...
You see? You weren't
yourself at all just then.
No?
No.
You know this Christa-Maria Sieland well.
What do you think?
Would she hurt someone who completely loves her?
Would she sell herself for the art?
Sell herself for art?
But she has the art already.
That'd be terrible business.
You are a great artist.
Don't you know that?
And you are a good person.
"As I took over, 'Lazlo' and CMS were arguing
about whether CMS should meet her schoolmate(?)."
"Finally she went.
'Lazlo' seemed unhappy about this."
"After about 20 minutes,
CMS returned to 'Lazlo'..."
"...to his and my surprise."
"He seemed quite happy.
Heavy intimacy ensued."
"She said, she'd never leave again."
"He said repeatedly: "I have the strength now.
I will do something."
"Here it is assumed,
he will write a new play."
"'Lazlo's' play production has been plagued
with difficulty over the last few weeks.
"What her comment means is uncertain:"
"Perhaps she wants to take care
of 'Lazlo's' household now more than before."
"The rest of the night was peaceful."
Captain...
I was just, uh...
Good report.
Really?
I didn't know he was doing so badly.
Me either.
"From someone who's crossed over":
The State's head office for Statistics on Hans Beimler St.
...counts everything, knows everything:
how many shoes I buy per year: 2.3,
...how many books I read in a year: 3.2,
...and how many students graduate
every year with an 4.0 GPA: 6,347.
But there is one number not registered,
...perhaps because such a figure
hurts even the bureaucrats: suicides.
If you called the Beimler St. office and asked,
"How many people between the Elbe
and Oder rivers,"
"...between the Baltic Sea and
Ore Mnts. were driven to death from desperation?"
Then our oracle of numbers remains silent,
...and probably writes down
your full name
...for the State Security,
...those grey men who take care
of our country's security and happiness.
Since 1977 our country has ceased
counting cases of suicide.
"Murdering oneself".
That's what they call it.
This act has nothing to do with murder.
It knows no bloodlust.
It knows no passion.
It only knows dying,
the dying of hope.
9 years ago, when we stopped counting suicides,
only one European country had a higher suicide rate:
Hungary.
After them was us,
the country of the living breathing Socialism.
One of these uncounted is Albert Jerska,
...the great director.
Today, I'd like to talk about him.
- I'm trying to get some stats on...
- ...how much more effective our
State's security works, as is generally believed.
Stupid me, I practiced my lecture for the tour here.
Since then I've taken quite a taste in music.
Should we meet at my place?
"3pm, Ehrenmal Pankow"
Is this safe enough?
My own personal bodyguard.
I call him Rolf. That's probably his name too.