You speak so strangely, Geert.
There's a hidden reproach in your words,
and l sense why.
lt irks you that Crampas came
and offered us his help.
Us?
Yes, us. You and me.
Have you forgotten?
The major helped at your request.
Why shouldn't l drive with him
in his carriage, then?
Where l come from...
one says it is wrong...
to mistrust a gentleman.
A gentleman!
lsn't he one?
You yourself said how gallant he is...
a perfect cavalier.
Yes, he's gallant enough...
No doubt about it. But a gentleman?
My dear Effi,
a gentleman is something different.
Do you see anything noble about him?
l don't.
lt would seem we're of the same opinion.
Anyway...
as you remarked, it's my fault.
l won't say it was a faux pas.
That's not the appropriate expression.
lt was my fault.
And it won't happen again if l can prevent it.
But you, too...
should be on your guard,
if you'll take my advice.
He's an unscrupulous man.
He has his own ideas about young women.
l know him of old.
l shall heed your words...
but l must say...
l think you misjudge him.
l do not misjudge him.
Perhaps me, then.
Nor you, my dear Effi.
You're a delightful little woman...
but steadfastness is not your strong point.
NOT A DAY PASSED WlTHOUT
HER TAKlNG THE PRESCRlBED WALK.
Roswitha...
l'm going down to the square
where the merry-go-round is.
l'll wait for you there.
The first day, they met as arranged.
UsuaIIy, though, when Roswitha
reached the merry-go-round...
nobody was there...
and when she entered the haII
at home again...
Effi wouId come toward her and say.:
''Where have you been, Roswitha?
I got back ages ago.''
It went on Iike this for weeks.
''Forgive my sudden departure, lnnstetten.
lt all happened so quickly.
''l shall try to spin it out.
''lt's good to get away for a while.
''My regards to your charming wife
and my benefactress.
''Major Crampas.''
A good thing, too!
-What do you mean?
-That he's gone away.
He's always saying the same things.
When he comes back, at least
he'll have something new to talk about.
l must go away as well. To Berlin.
Perhaps l can bring back
something new, too.
My Effi always likes to hear something new.
She's bored in dear old Kessin.
l'll be away for about a week...
perhaps one day longer.
And don't be afraid.
lt won't come back.
You know what l mean...
that thing upstairs.
Effi smiIed to herseIf...
and in her smiIe was a hint of meIanchoIy.
She recaIIed the day
Crampas had Iast toId her...
Innstetten was enacting a comedy
with the ghost and her fear.
''The born schooImaster!''
But wasn't he right?
Wasn't the comedy justified?
ConfIicting thoughts, good and eviI,
went through her mind.
Three days Iater, Innstetten Ieft.
He said nothing about
his reasons for going to BerIin.
SHE GAVE UP HER WALKS
TO THE BEACH AND THE PLANTATlON
WHlLE CRAMPAS WAS lN STETTlN,
BUT SHE RESUMED THEM ON HlS RETURN.
NOT EVEN lNCLEMENT WEATHER
COULD DETER HER.
Either it was unrequited love,
or it might have been requited...
and the Chinaman couldn't bear
the thought that it was suddenly all over.
The Chinese are human beings as well.
They feel everything just as we do.
Everything.
-l need the leather varnish.
-l'll bring it out to you, Kruse.
Everything as we do.
There's a time and place for everything.
But that business with the Chinaman
is very strange.
lt's a load of nonsense.
And instead of attending
to what's important...
my wife talks about things like that.
When l need a clean shirt,
there's a button missing.
Then there's the black chicken!
lt doesn't even lay eggs.
And anyway...
how should it lay eggs?
lt doesn't even get out.
You men are worse than one thinks.
l ought to take the brush...
and paint your moustache.
Well...
l could accept that from you, Roswitha.
Roswitha!
l must remind you
that Kruse is a married man.
l know, ma'am.
One knows so many things
and behaves as if one didn't.
lf you're reckoning on her illness,
you'll be disappointed.
Sick people live longest of all.
How was it the first time with you?
ls it something you can tell me?
Yes, l can tell you.
lt was terrible...
and for that reason...
you can set your mind at rest
as far as Kruse is concerned.
When you've been through
what l've been through, you've had enough.
The next day, l always feel shattered.
And such terrible anxiety!
Tell me, then. How was it?
l know from at home, with women like you,
it's always the same story.
Yes...
in the end, it probably is always the same.
l don't want to pretend
my case was anything special.
Not in the least.
But when they accused me to my face...
and l suddenly had to admit:
''Yes, it's true.''
That was dreadful.
My mother wasn't too hard on me.
But my father, the village blacksmith,
was strict and terrible.
When he heard about it, he went for me
with an iron bar from the fire.
He wanted to kill me.
l had a younger sister...
who used to point at me and say,
''Shame on you!''
When the child was due,
l went into a nearby barn...
because l didn't dare show my face at home.
Strangers found me half dead.
They carried me into the house
and put me to bed.
On the third day...
they took my child away...
and when l asked later where it was...
they said it was in good hands.
Oh, ma'am...
may the Holy Virgin
protect you from such heartache!
The things you say!
l'm a married woman.
You shouldn't say things like that.
lt's out of place.
lt's unseemly.
Oh, ma'am....
Tell me...
how do you imagine a ministry?
A ministry?
That can mean two things.
lt may mean clever, distinguished men
who govern the country...
or it could be a building, a palazzo.
Would you like to live in such a palazzo?
l mean...
in such a ministry?
Heavens above, Geert!
They haven't made you a minister?
Gieshuebler said something of the kind.
And the prince is all-powerful.
He's done it at last...
and l'm only 18!
No, Effi, not a minister.
We haven't come that far yet.
To tell the truth...
we won't even live in a ministry...
but l'll be going to one every day.
And you'll be the wife of
a leading official and live in Berlin...
Soon, you'll hardly remember...
you once lived in Kessin...
with only Gieshuebler...
and the dunes...
and the plantation for company.
Thank God!
Get up, Effi! What's the matter?
What's the matter?
l thought you were happy here.
You say ''Thank God''
as if it had been an affliction here.
Was l the affliction?
Tell me!
How can you ask such a thing, Geert?
Oh, ma'am...
Kessin is...
all well and good...
but it's not Berlin.
Some days, you see no more
than half a dozen people.
And nothing but the dunes...
and the sea out there...
rushing and surging.
But that's all there is.
Yes, you're right, Roswitha.
lt rushes and surges...
but that's not life.
One has all kinds of foolish ideas.
You have to admit...
that matter with Kruse was not right.
Yes, my dear Gieshuebler,
but just for a moment.
l've come to say goodbye.
But, my dear lady, surely you'll be back.
l heard it was for just 3 or 4 days...
Yes, l should return.
ln a week at the latest,
l'm supposed to be back in Kessin.
But who knows if l shall return?
l don't have to tell you,
so many things can happen.
You want to say l'm too young...
but even young people die.
And if l lived to be a hundred,
l'd never forget you.
There were times when l felt lonely here.
Sometimes my heart was heavy,
more than you can imagine.
l haven't always done the right thing.
But whenever l saw you...
l felt better, a better person, too.
But, my dear lady....
And l want to thank you for that.
Goodbye, my dear friend!
Give my regards to your friend,
Miss Trippelli.
l have thought of her a lot recently
and of Prince Kotschukoff.
lt's a strange relationship.
Yet l can understand it.
Let me hear from you.
Or l shall write.
''I am Ieaving tomorrow by boat,
and this is a fareweII note.
''Innstetten expects me back in a few days,
but I shaII not return.
''You know why.
''It wouId have been better
if I had never seen this pIace.
''I beg you not to take this as a reproach.
''It was aII my fauIt.
''In view of your home Iife...
''your actions may be excusabIe,
but not mine.
''I bear a heavy burden of guiIt,
but perhaps there's a way out.
''Being transferred from here
seems Iike a sign...
''that I may stiII find mercy.
''Forget me.
''Your Effi.''
What a lovely place you have, Mama!
But what's wrong with your eyes?
ln the carriage, all we talked about...
was lnnstetten and our career.
Far too much.
There must be an end to it.
Your eyes are more important to me.
ln one respect, they're unchanged.
They have the same old kindness
when you look at me.
You're so impetuous. The same old Effi!
No, Mama.
Not the old Effi.
l wish l were.
Marriage changes a person.
lnnstetten is impatient for me to return.
To cut matters short,
l suggest we rent the apartment today...
and l'll go back tomorrow.
lt's so hard to leave you.
Which apartment will you take?
The one in Keithstrasse...
which we both liked
from the very beginning.
lt's probably not quite dried out yet...
but it's summer now,
which is some consolation.
lf l feel a twinge of rheumatism...
there's always Hohen-Cremmen.
Don't tempt providence!
Suddenly one has rheumatism
without knowing why.
Dr. Rummschuettel...
l don't know how to describe it.
lt keeps changing.
At the moment, it seems to have gone.
At first, l thought it was rheumatism...
but now l think it might be neuralgia.
Very likely, my dear lady.
Rest and warmth...
are the best thing.
And a little medicine...
nothing bad, will do the rest.
But no mental exertion...
no visits...
-no books.
-lt's Scott.
Oh, l've no objection to him.
Travel books are best.
l'll call again tomorrow.
The question of costs has to be considered.
Our expenses wiII increase anyway.
RummschuetteI wiII have to be paid
if he remains our doctor.
He's a very pIeasant oId gentIeman...
aIthough medicaIIy,
he's not considered top rank.
His detractors caII him a ''Iadies' doctor, ''
but there's an eIement of praise in that.
A NEW ERA lS DAWNlNG,
AND l'M NO LONGER AFRAlD.
l SHALL TRY TO BE BETTER
AND COMPL Y MORE WlTH YOUR WlSHES.
How are Gieshuebler and all the others?
Who are ''all the others''?
Crampas sends you his regards.
That's nice of him.
And Frau von Padden sends her respects.
She said you are a charming woman...
but l should take good care of you.
And when l replied...
you regarded me more
as a teacher than a husband...
she murmured...
almost absently:
''A little lamb...
''white as the driven snow....''
Then she broke off.
Has Johanna ever shown you
her Chinaman?
Which one?
Ours, of course.
Before she left our old home,
she detached him from the chair...
and put him in her purse.
When she changed a mark for me recently...
l saw it.
And...
she admitted it with embarrassment.
She told me...
that her sense of
being a stranger had gone...
and that she was very glad.
Kessin wasn't the right place for her...
with its spooky house and the people.
Some were too pious, others too pedestrian.
Since her move to Berlin,
she says she feels at home.
He's the best of husbands...
a bit too old and too good for her.
But now the worst is over.
That was the expression she used...
and it rather surprised me.
Why? lt may not be
the best of expressions, but....
There's something behind it...
which she wanted to allude to.
You think so?
Yes, Briest.
You think butter wouldn't melt in her mouth.
But you're wrong.
She likes to drift with the current...
and if the current is good, so is she.
Fighting and resistance
are not her strong points.
She recaIIed the day...
scarceIy two years before...
when the visitor had come...
and she had cIimbed
the steps beside the bench...
and an hour Iater she was betrothed.
Images of her Iife in Kessin
rose unbidden before her inward eye.
There was Crampas coming to greet her...
then Roswitha with the baby.
She took the chiId,
heId her up and kissed her.
''That was the first day,
when everything had begun.''
The nearby cIock began to strike...
and Effi counted the strokes.
''10.:00.
''This time tomorrow, I'II be in BerIin.
''It's our wedding anniversary.
''He'II say nice things,
an affectionate word perhaps...
''and I shaII sit and Iisten...
''with guiIt weighing on my souI.
''Yes, it is there...
''but does it weigh on my souI?
No, it doesn't...
''and that's what frightens me about myseIf.
''What weighs on me is something different.
''Fear, a mortaI dread...
''that aII wiII be discovered.
''And on top of the fear, I feeI ashamed.
''But I don't feeI true repentance.
Nor do I feeI true shame.
''I'm tormented by fear
and ashamed of the whoIe web of Iies.
''But I feeI no shame for my guiIt,
or not properIy and not enough...
''and that is what's destroying me.
''If women are Iike that, it's terribIe!
''And if they're not, as I hope,
things are iII with me.
''Then something's wrong with my souI.
I Iack the right sentiments.
''OId Niemeyer once said to me...
''when I was onIy a chiId...
''that it's important to have
the right sentiments.
''If one had them,
one wouId be spared the worst.
''If one didn't have them,
one Iived in constant danger...
''and what peopIe caII 'the deviI'
wouId have you in his power.
''MercifuI God, is that how I am?''
She Iaid her head on her arms
and wept bitterIy.
l thought you might not keep your word.
Really, Geert! That's the least l can do.
Don't say that. lt's not always easy.
Sometimes one can't. Just think back.
l was expecting you back in Kessin,
after you'd rented the apartment...
and who didn't come? Effi.
That was something different.
Our life in Berlin is just beginning, Effi.
ln April, when we moved in...
the season was coming to an end.
We hardly had time to pay our calls.
And Woellersdorf...
the only person we know better...
is a bachelor unfortunately.
From June onward, everything's dead.
The lowered shutters...
tell you everything.
''Everyone's gone''...
regardless whether it's true or not.
So...
what was left?
A chat with cousin Briest...
dinner at Hiller's...
That's not real Berlin life.
But now things will change.
l've noted the names of all top officials
who are active enough to entertain.
We shall entertain, too.
And when winter comes,
the whole ministry should be saying:
''The most charming woman in our circle...
''is the wife of lnnstetten.''
Oh, Geert, l hardly know you like this.
You're talking like a ladies' man.
lt's our wedding anniversary.
You must allow me that.
First and foremost, Crampas...
Major Crampas, quite the beau...
and something of a Barbarossa
to whom my wife...
understandably or not...
had taken a liking.
Let's say ''understandably''...
because l assume he was chairman
of the club and playing a role...
the lover or bon vivant.
Perhaps something even grander.
He may have been a tenor, too.
A second year passed...
and when a new foundation
was estabIished...
the empress chose
the ''privy counciIIor's wife''...
as a Iady-in-waiting.
At the court baII, the oId Kaiser
addressed appreciative words...
to the IoveIy young woman,
of whom he had heard so much.
Well then...
Schwalbach to begin with, let's say...
three weeks.
Then the same length of time in Ems.
During the cure in Ems,
your husband may join you.
ln other words...
three weeks' separation.
That's the best l can do for you, lnnstetten.
Tell me, Roswitha...
you're a Catholic.
Don't you ever go to confession?
No.
Why not?
l used to go.
But l didn't confess the important things.
Didn't you ever feel it a relief...
to be able to unburden your soul?
No, ma'am.
l was afraid...
when my father went for me
with the red-hot iron.
Yes...
l was scared to death...
but it wasn't more than that.
You have no fear of God?
No, ma'am.
lf you feared your father as much l did...
you wouldn't be so afraid of God.
l always thought God was good...
and would help a poor creature like me.
Let's see who gets up the stairs first.
lt's nothing, sir.
Annie fell on the stairs.
There, there!
Where were the letters?
Right at the bottom, sir.
Johanna, bring me a cup of coffee!
FRAU VON lNNSTETTEN
''Come to the dunes again this afternoon.
''We can taIk at Frau Adermann's pIace.
The house is isoIated enough.
''Stop worrying about everything.
We have our rights, too.
''Get that into your head,
and you wiII cease to be afraid.
''Life wouIdn't be worth Iiving if aII
the random ruIes had to be observed.
''The finest things Iie beyond them.
Learn to deIight in these things.''
MY DEAREST EFFl,
BE AT THE USUAL PLACE AGAlN TODAY.
I have asked you to come for two reasons.
To issue a chaIIenge on my behaIf...
and to act as my second in the dueI.
The first is not agreeabIe,
the second even Iess so.
And what is your answer?
You know l am at your service.
But before l know more,
forgive a naive question.
Does it have to be?
We're both too old...
you to take a pistol in the hand...
and l to assist you in the deed.
Don't misunderstand me.
That doesn't mean l'm saying no.
How could l refuse you anything?
But tell me what it's all about?
lt concerns a suitor of my wife...
who was also a friend of mine, or almost.
That's impossible!
lt's not only possible, it's a fact.
Read these!
Addressed to your wife?
l found them in her sewing table.
-And who wrote them?
-Major Crampas.
Then these things happened
when you were still in Kessin...
-six or more years ago?
-Yes.
It seems aImost, WuIIersdorf...
as if those 6 or 7 years
make you think differentIy.
There is a theory of Iimitations, of course...
but I'm not sure this is a case
where that theory can be appIied.
I don't know either.
But everything wouId seem
to turn on that question.
Are you serious?
AbsoIuteIy serious.
It's not a matter of jeu d'esprit...
or for sophistry.
What do you mean by that?
Tell me frankly. How do you see the matter?
You're in a terrible situation.
Your happiness is destroyed.
But if you kill the lover...
your happiness will be doubly destroyed.
The pain you have suffered...
will be compounded
by the pain you have caused.
lt all turns on the question,
do you have to do it?
Do you feel so injured, insulted, incensed...
that one of you must die, he or you?
ls that the position?
l don't know.
You have to know.
No, that's not how it is.
How is it then?
The thing is...
I'm desperateIy unhappy.
I've been injured and shamefuIIy deceived.
NevertheIess...
I harbour no feeIings of hatred.
I don't even thirst for revenge.
And if l ask myself why not...
all l can say is, the time that has passed.
People always talk about inexpiable guilt.
ln God's eyes, that is wrong,
and in man's eyes, too.
l would never have believed
that time could have such an effect.
What is more...
l love my wife.
Strange as it may seem, l still love her...
and however terrible l find these things...
I am so captivated by her good nature...
and her own serene charm...
that, in spite of myseIf,
in my heart of hearts...
I'm incIined to forgive her.
Can understand you entirely.
Might feel the same way myself.
But if that's how you feel, and you say:
''l love this woman so much
l can forgive everything''...
and if one considers
that this happened long, long ago...
like something on a distant star...
if that's the case, lnnstetten, l ask you...
does it have to be?
What's the good of it?
lt has to be done.
l've looked at it all ways.
One does not live alone.
One is part of a larger whole.
And we always have
to bear the whole in mind.
We are entirely dependent on it.
lf l lived in isolation,
l could drop the matter.
l would bear the burden assigned to me.
My happiness would be over, but...
so many have to live without happiness...
and l would have to as well, and l could.
One does not have to be happy.
Least of all, one has a right to be.
One wouldn't need to remove
from the world the person...
who has robbed us of our happiness.
One could also...
let him go free,
if one turned one's back on the world.
But...
in living together in society,
a certain something has evolved.
lt simply exists...
and we're accustomed
to judging everything by its rules.
Others...
and ourselves.
One cannot contravene them...
without society despising us.
We wouId come to despise ourseIves, too...
and uItimateIy bIow our brains out.
Forgive my holding forth like this
and merely saying...
what everyone has said
to himself a hundred times.
But then...
who can really say anything new?
I repeat...
it's not a matter of hatred
or personaI happiness.
That tyrannicaI sociaI eIement...
is not concerned with charm or Iove...
or the Iapse of time.
I have no choice.
I simpIy have to.
I'm not so sure, Innstetten.
You must decide, WuIIersdorf.
It's ten o'cIock now.
Six hours ago, I admit...
I stiII had a free hand.
There was stiII a way out.
But not any Ionger. I'm in a bIind aIIey.
I've onIy myseIf to bIame, you might say.
l should have been more on my guard,
kept everything to myself...
fought it out in my own heart.
But it all came too suddenly
for me to give myself the blame...
for not having kept my nerves under control.
l went to your place and wrote you a note...
and in doing so relinquished control.
From that moment...
someone else was half-aware
of my misfortune...
and, more importantly,
of the stain on my honour...
and with this discussion,
that person is now fully aware.
And since there is such a person...
there's no going back.
I wouIdn't say that.
I don't Iike using trite phrases...
but I know no better way of putting it.
l'll be as silent as the grave.
That's what people always say.
But there's no such thing as secrecy.
You may be the soul of discretion...
but you know about it...
and the fact that you express
your consent and understanding...
does not save me from you.
l am, and l remain...
from this moment on,
an object of your sympathy.
Every word you hear me say to my wife
is subject to your control.
lf my wife talks about being faithful...
or, as women do...
sits in judgement over others...
l shan't know where to look.
Or suppose l urge...
reconciliation in some
everyday affair of honour...
because no ill intent is involved.
A smile will cross your face...
or it will twitch, at least...
and in your heart you'll say,
''Good old lnnstetten...
''has a passion for analysing
the chemical content of all insults...
''but he never finds the precise amount
of poison they contain.
''He can swallow anything.''
Am l right, or not?
lt's a terrible thought, but you're right.
l'll stop asking, ''Does it have to be?''
The world is as it is.
Things don't work out as we want them to,
but as others want.
All that talk about divine punishment...
is nonsense, of course.
On the contrary...
our cult of honour is idolatry...
but we have to submit to it,
as long as the idol stands.
Crampas wishes
to speak with you, lnnstetten.
Grant him his wish.
He has only a few minutes to live.
Will you....
GUlLT DEMANDS EXPlATlON,
THERE lS A LOGlC TO THAT.
BUT THE lDEA OF A TlME LlMlTATlON
lS A TERRlBLE HALF-MEASURE.
-How is Annie?
-She's well, sir.
-She's not asleep if you--
-No, that'll only excite her.
-Who was here?
-Only the doctor.
''Arrived back this morning.
''Many experiences,
both painfuI and touching...
''above aII GieshuebIer,
the nicest hunchback I've ever met.
''He didn't speak much of you.
But your wife, your wife!
''He was inconsoIabIe.
''FinaIIy, he burst into tears.
The things that happen!
''There shouId be
more peopIe Iike GieshuebIer.
''Then the scene in the major's house!
DreadfuI!
''Enough said. One is on one's guard again.
''I'II see you tomorrow. Yours, W.''
Another thing, Johanna...
my wife will not be coming back.
You will find out why from others.
Annie should not be told.
Not yet, at least, poor child!
Break it to her gradually
that she has no mother.
l can't do it. Do it properly...
and make sure Roswitha
doesn't ruin everything!
Back in the kitchen...
she feIt a sense of pride
and superiority, aImost happiness.
Not onIy had her master confided in her...
he had toId her to make sure
Roswitha didn't ruin everything.
That was the main thing.
AIthough she had a good heart...
and feIt sympathy for her mistress...
what most moved her
was the sense of triumph...
at enjoying a certain
intimacy with her master.
WE ARE lNFORMED
THAT YESTERDAY MORNlNG
lN KESSlN, EASTERN POMERANlA,
A DUEL TOOK PLACE BETWEEN
COUNClLLOR VON l.
AND MAJOR VON CRAMPAS.
THE MAJOR WAS KlLLED.
A RELATlONSHlP HAD ALLEGEDL Y
EXlSTED BETWEEN HlM
AND THE PRlVY COUNClLLOR'S
BEAUTlFUL YOUNG WlFE.
The things these papers write!
Yes...
and people read it...
and say nasty things about my mistress.
And the poor major's dead, too.
-Should the master be dead instead?
-No, Johanna.
Our master should live.
Everyone should live.
But don't forget...
it all happened so long ago.
The letters are yellow with age.
-How can anyone dig up--
-That's how you see it, Roswitha.
''As for your future, my dear Effi,
you are on your own now.
''You may count on
some materiaI support from us.
''Live in BerIin,
where you'II be one of the many...
''who have deprived themseIves
of air and sunIight.
''It wiII be a IoneIy Iife if you don't
want to descend beIow your cIass.
''Your former worId wiII be cIosed to you.
''The saddest thing for aII of us...
''is that you wiII aIso be excIuded
from your parentaI home.
''We cannot offer you a refuge
in Hohen-Cremmen...
''for that wouId mean...
''cutting ourseIves off from the worId...
''which we are not prepared to do.
''Not because we couIdn't bear to bid
fareweII to what one caIIs 'society.'
''No, that's not the reason.
''But we have to make our position cIear...
''and show the worId
that we condemn your actions...
''the actions of our one and onIy daughter
whom we Iove so dearIy.''
After receiving her parent's
Ietter of refusaI...
and taking the train back to BerIin...
Effi did not at first
move into an apartment of her own.
She sought Iodgings in a boarding house
with reasonabIe success.
Do you remember how Gieshuebler came
and had to join us at table...
and said he'd never eaten
anything so delicious?
He was always so well-mannered.
ln fact, he was the only person
who knew anything about food.
The others said everything was nice.
Have you thought it over?
You've had it good all these years.
There was always enough.
We never had to think about saving.
But now l have to economize.
l am poor.
All l have is what l receive
from Hohen-Cremmen.
My parents are very good to me...
as far as their means allow...
but they're not wealthy.
What do you say?
May l move in next Saturday
with my suitcase?
Not in the evening.
ln the morning, so as to be here
when you arrange the household.
l'm more robust than you are, ma'am.
Don't say that, Roswitha. l can do it.
One can do anything if one has to.
And you needn't worry about me.
As if l could ever think:
''That's not good enough for Roswitha.''
For Roswitha, everything is good...
that she can share with you...
and most of all the sad things.
EVERYTHlNG WENT WELL
UNTlL CHRlSTMAS,
BUT CHRlSTMAS EVE
WAS A SAD OCCASlON,
AND AS NEW YEAR'S GREW NEAR,
EFFl BEGAN TO FEEL VERY MELANCHOLlC.
One day, coming from her
painting Iessons near the zoo...
she got on a horse-drawn tram
passing aIong Kurfuerstenstrasse.
It was very hot...
and the curtains, fIapping to and fro
and biIIowing in the breeze...
refreshed her.
She Ieaned back in the corner...
and Iooked at the sofas enameIIed
on a pane of gIass...
bIue, with bobs and tasseIs.
The tram was moving sIowIy...
when three schooIgirIs with satcheIs
and IittIe pointed hats jumped on.
Two of them were fair-haired and IiveIy.
The third was dark and serious.
It was Annie.
Effi started. The thought of
a meeting with her chiId...
which she had Iong desired...
now fiIIed her with mortaI fear.
What shouId she do?
She opened the door to the front pIatform,
where onIy the driver stood...
and asked him to Iet her get off at the front.
''Not aIIowed, miss, '' the driver said...
but she gave him a coin
and such a pIeading Iook...
that the good-hearted man
reIented and muttered.:
''ShouIdn't reaIIy,
but aII right, just this once.''
And he removed the grating,
and Effi jumped down.
She's half one and half the other.
ln her prettiness, her specialness...
she takes after her mother...
but she has her seriousness...
from her father.
All things considered,
she's probably more like the master.
Thank goodness!
Well, ma'am, that's the question.
Many would be more
in favour of the mother.
You think so, Roswitha?
l don't.
You can't pull the wool over my eyes...
and l think my mistress knows
the truth of the matter...
and what men really want.
Let's not talk about that, Roswitha!
Effi was oppressed by the notion...
of having run away from her own chiId.
''l'm delighted to be able
to tell you the good news.
''lt worked out as we hoped.
Your husband is a man of the world...
''and would not refuse a lady's request.
''At the same time,
l should not conceal the fact from you.
''His consent was evidently
not in accordance...
''with what he considered wise and proper.
''But let's not find fault
when we should be rejoicing.
''lt was agreed that your Annie
should visit you at lunch time.
''May your reunion
stand under a lucky star.''
One makes the bed one Iies on,
and I wish to change nothing in my Iife.
It is right as it is. It was my own doing.
But the situation with my chiId is too hard.
I wish to see her from time to time...
not furtiveIy or in secret...
but with the consent of aII those concerned.
Annie, darling, how glad l am.
Come and tell me about yourself!
How you've grown!
And that's the scar?
Roswitha told me about it.
You were always so wild when you played.
You take after your mother in that.
She was just the same.
How are things at school?
You look as if you were
always first in your class...
a model pupil...
who always has the best grades.
-What are you best at?
-l don't know.
Oh, you must know.
Everyone knows that.
What do you get the best marks in?
-ln religious instruction.
-There, you see. You do know.
That's good.
l wasn't so good at that...
but that may have been the teacher.
We only had an ordinand.
We had an ordinand, too.
Has he left now?
Why did he leave?
l don't know.
We have the preacher again now.
Whom you all like?
Yes. Two girls in the first class
want to convert.
l see.
That's good.
And how is Johanna?
Johanna brought me here.
l shouldn't keep her waiting too long.
You're very considerate,
and l suppose l should be glad.
lt's all a matter of apportioning things.
Now tell me how Rollo is.
Rollo's very well.
But Papa says he's getting lazy,
always lying in the sun.
l can believe it.
He was like that when you were very young.
Tell me, Annie...
-will you come and see me often?
-Certainly, if l may.
We could go for a stroll
in Prince Albert Gardens.
Certainly, if l may.
Or go to Schilling's and eat ice cream.
Pineapple and vanilla were your favourites.
Certainly, if l may.
l think it's time for you to go.
Johanna will be getting impatient.
Roswitha, go with Annie
as far as the church!
Johanna's waiting there.
Let's hope she hasn't caught cold.
Give my regards to Johanna.
Oh, God in heaven,
forgive me for what l've done!
l was a child.
No, l wasn't a child anymore.
l was old enough to know what l was doing.
l don't want to diminish my guilt.
But this is too much!
What is happening with the child...
is not You, God, punishing me. lt is he...
and he alone.
And l thought he had a noble heart!
l always felt small beside him.
But now l know it's he...
who is small and petty.
And because he's petty, he's cruel.
Everything that's petty is cruel.
He taught the child to behave like that.
He was always a schoolmaster.
That's what Crampas called him...
sarcastically perhaps, but he was right.
''Certainly, if l may''!
You don't have to ask if you ''may'' anymore.
l don't want either of you.
l hate you both...
even my own child.
Too much is too much!
He was ambitious...
and that was all.
Honour, honour, honour...
and then he shoots the poor man dead,
whom l didn't even love.
Nothing but stupidity...
and then blood...
and murder.
And l'm to blame.
Now he sends me my child...
because he can't refuse a minister's wife.
But before he sends her,
he trains her to answer like a parrot...
and teaches her to say, ''lf l may.''
What l did disgusts me...
but your virtuousness
disgusts me even more.
Be gone the pair of you!
l have to go on living...
but it won't be forever.
Ma'am!
When RummschuetteI was caIIed...
he was concerned about Effi's condition.
The hectic state
he had observed for some time...
seemed more pronounced than before.
''But it must be at Hohen-Cremmen.
''To regain her heaIth, your daughter
needs more than just a change of air.
''She's pining away. AII she has is Roswitha.
''LoyaI service is good,
but parentaI Iove is better.
''Forgive an oId man interfering in matters...
''that are no concern of a doctor.
''And yet, it is as a doctor
that I write to you...
''and make these demands
out of a sense of duty.
''I've seen so much of Iife....''
...l love her at least as much as you do.
Each in his own way.
But we're not here just to be
kind and understanding...
towards things that are
against laws and commandments...
and that society condemns...
and rightly condemns at present.
-One thing counts above all else.
-Of course one thing really counts.
But what is it?
The love of parents for their children.
Even if there's only one.
Then that's the end of...
catechism...
and morality...
and the claims of society?
lt's hard to get along without society.
Without one's child, too.
EFFl, COME TO US!
It was determined that Annie...
wouId inherit Hohen-Cremmen.
Effi's spirits revived, and her mother,
who was not averse...
to regarding the matter
as an interesting, but painfuI, incident...
vied with her husband in showering
Iove and attention on their daughter.
lTlS STRANGE,
BUT MANY THlNGS lN MY LlFE
MlGHT APTL Y BE DESCRlBED
WlTH THE WORD ''ALMOST.''
Pastor Niemeyer!
Effi! You're the same as ever!
No, no.
That all belongs to the past.
l just wanted to try it out once more.
How wonderful it was!
How stimulating the air!
lt was like flying up to heaven.
Shall l ever go there?
Tell me, dear friend. You should know.
-Please!
-Yes, Effi.
You will.
lMPERlAL OFFlCE OF THE lNTERlOR
DEAR lNNSTETTEN,
l HAVE THE PLEASURE OFlNFORMlNG YOU
THAT HlS MAJESTY HAS CONSENTED
TO YOUR APPOlNTMENT.
MY SlNCERE CONGRATULATlONS.
''l'm afraid, Roswitha,
because l'm all alone here.
''But who should accompany me?
Rollo? Yes.
''He bears me no grudge.
That's the good thing about animals.
''Those were my mistress's words.
l'll say no more.
''Please remember me to little Annie
and to Johanna as well.
''Your obedient servant...
''Roswitha Gellenhagen.''
We could learn something from her.
l think so, too.
That's why everything else
seems so questionable to you.
lt's been on my mind a long time,
and these simple words...
with their conscious...
or perhaps unconscious
hint of accusation...
have completely unsettled me.
lt's been tormenting me for some time.
l want to free myself of this whole business.
Nothing gives me pleasure anymore.
The more distinctions l gain,
the more meaningless it all seems.
l've messed up my life.
May was IoveIy. June even IoveIier.
Once Effi had overcome the heartache...
RoIIo's arrivaI aroused in her...
she was deIighted to have
the faithfuI creature with her again.
Roswitha was praised,
and Briest expressed to his wife...
his respect for Innstetten...
who was a perfect gentIeman, not petty...
and whose heart was in the right pIace.
''A pity that stupid affair had to happen!
''They were the perfect coupIe.''
What a glorious summer!
l should never have thought
a year ago that l could be so happy.
Just get well again!
Happiness will come.
Not past happiness, but a new one.
There are many types of happiness.
You'll see, we'll find something for you.
The summer passed...
and the nights with
shooting stars were over.
On these nights,
Effi had sat Iong at her window...
never tired of watching.
''I never was a very good Christian,
but perhaps we do come from up there...
''and when it's aII over here,
we'II return to our heavenIy home...
''to the stars up there, or beyond.
''I don't know, and I don't want to know.
''I simpIy feeI a Ionging....''
You wanted to tell me something.
Yes, because you spoke
of my being still very young.
Of course l'm young.
But that makes no difference.
ln happier days, lnnstetten
would read to me in the evening.
He had some fine books...
and in one of them there was the story...
of a man being called away
from a festive table.
On the following day, the man asked...
what had happened after he'd left.
He received the reply:
''Oh, all sorts of things...
''but you didn't really miss anything.''
You see, Mama,
those words stuck in my mind.
lt doesn't matter if one's called away
from the table earlier than others.
And since l mentioned
old times and lnnstetten...
l must tell you something else.
You're exciting yourself, Effi.
No. Getting something off one's mind...
doesn't excite one. lt's calming.
l wanted to tell you, Mama...
l shall die reconciled
with God and mankind...
with him, too.
Did you feel such bitterness
in your heart towards him?
ln a way...
forgive my saying this now...
you really brought
these sorrows on yourself.
Yes, sadly enough.
But when misfortune befell me...
and finally there was
that business with Annie...
then...
if l may use the absurd expression...
l simply turned the tables...
and convinced myself he was to blame...
because he was sober and calculating
and cruel, too, in the end.
l cursed him.
And now it weighs on your conscience?
Yes, and l want him to know...
that during the days l've been ill...
which have been almost
the loveliest days of my life...
l've come to see...
that he was right in everything.
ln the matter concerning
poor Major Crampas...
what else could he have done?
The thing with which he hurt me most...
was the way he raised...
my own child against me.
But as much as it grieves me...
as hard as it affects me...
he was right in that, too.
Let him know l died convinced of that.
lt will console him, give him new heart,
reconcile him perhaps.
For there was a lot of good in his nature...
and he was as fine a man
as anyone can be...
who doesn't know true love.
A smaII change had occurred
in the circuIar fIowerbed.
The sundiaI was gone,
and its pIace had been taken...
by a white marbIe sIab...
which bore onIy the words ''Effi Briest''...
with a cross beneath.
That was Effi's Iast request.
''I'd Iike to have
my oId name on my gravestone...
''I did no honour to my other name.''
And her request was granted.
Look, Briest...
Rollo's lying by the stone again.
lt has affected him more deeply than us.
He won't eat a thing.
Yes, Luise, these creatures!
That's what l always say...
we're not as remarkable as we think.
We talk about instinct...
and in the end, it's the best thing.
Not a day has passed,
since she was buried there...
-without these questions arising.
-What questions?
Whether we're not perhaps to blame?
Nonsense, Luise!
What do you mean?
Whether we shouldn't
have been stricter with her.
We most of all.
Niemeyer is useless really...
because he casts doubt on everything.
And then, Briest...
l'm sorry to have to say it,
your constant equivocation.
Finally, l ask myself...
since l don't wish to remain
blameless in this matter...
whether she wasn't perhaps too young?
Oh, Luise, don't go on.
That's much too vast a subject.
Subtitles: Peter + Waltraut Green