Today, the glory of ancient Egypt...
is ruins and dust.
And this greatest of the earth's
earliest civilizations...
...a thing of darkness
and mystery.
These mighty monuments
tell us of a people...
...who were rulers of the world.
Who created a civilization never surpassed
for beauty and splendor.
But the Egyptians were not only
builders of monuments.
They were human beings,
no different from ourselves.
This is the story of a man...
...who dwelled in the ancient
land of the Nile...
...thirty-three centuries ago.
I, Sinuhe the Egyptian...
...write this...
...in my place of exile,
on the shores of the Red Sea.
There is no more
desolate spot on earth.
Soon the jackals
and the vultures...
...will make a poor meal
of what is left of me.
No monument
will mark my resting place.
I will leave only this.
The story of my life.
I have lived fully and deeply.
I have tasted passion, crime...
...and even murder.
It is for you to judge me.
You must weigh the good
against the evil.
The passion
against the tenderness.
The crime against the charity.
The pleasure against the pain.
I began life
as I am ending it, alone.
I rode alone
on the bosom of the Nile...
...in a boat of reeds daubed with pitch
and tied with fowler's knots.
Thus the city of Thebes was accustomed
to dispose of its unwanted children.
I grew up on the waterfront
of the city...
...in the house
of my foster parents...
...who had saved me
from the river.
My foster father
lived there by choice...
...because he was, also by choice,
physician to the poor of the city.
From the rich he could have
commanded princely fees...
...for he alone in Thebes,
was master...
...of the ancient art
of opening skulls.
Have more of the good wine ready.
Afraid, Sinuhe?
Good.
You must never fear death.
In our craft death
is a familiar companion.
This time we cheat him.
Look...
...this tiny splinter of bone
pressing on the brain.
When I remove it...
...he will speak again.
Will walk, and live.
Why father? Why?
No one knows.
From the beginning
I kept to myself.
I used to wander alone
on the banks of the Nile...
...until the day came when I was ready
to enter the School of Life.
In the School of Life...
...were trained the chosen
young men of Egypt.
The future scientists
and philosophers...
...statesmen and generals.
All the learning of Egypt...
...lay in the keeping
of the Gods.
For ten years,
I served them in the school...
...that I might earn the right
to call myself a "physician."
I learned
to bend my body to them...
...but that was all.
My mind still asked the question:
Why?
Sinuhe...
...be careful, the priests!
Free wine!
To the health
of our classmate, Horemheb!
The best swordsman,
the finest horseman...
...the fastest runner,
and the strongest wrestler.
And the first one to tell about it!
Well, if you don't speak
well of yourself...
...no one will do it for you.
This I learned from the gods.
You drunk to what I am...
...now drink to what I will be.
For the day will come,
when I will carry the Golden Whip...
...and lead you all into battle.
Hey, you're not drinking, my friend.
- Wine!
- He's had enough.
Never enough for a friend.
Finish the night in some gutter
with his throat cut.
He's under my protection.
To your future.
- Look at our brilliant physician!
- The honor student!
He's got the reeling sickness!
Can I help you?
Just a second.
Don't throw things at my friend.
He's alive!
Who is he?
He's a stubborn arrogant fool,
but he is my best friend.
Then take him home.
A tavern wench can't give orders
to the son of a Falcon.
The son of a cheese-maker!
Take him home!
Good night physician.
Your friend is the fool, not you.
Why does no one ever answer me
when I ask "why"?
Come on, let's go.
How did she know your father
was a cheese-maker?
The Queen of Cities.
Thebes, of the hundred gates.
Capital of the world.
After my graduation
from the School of Life...
...I set myself up as physician
on the waterfront.
Far from my father's house...
...lest I steal
his patients from him.
But I found that not even
the poorest of patients...
...would come to the door
of so young a physician.
I had to go out into the streets
in search of them.
Too late for that one.
Come over here, into the shade.
Here, sit down.
I can help you.
Under certain conditions,
blindness can be cured with a needle.
Alas, no physician
can restore my eye.
My first master put it out
when I drank a jar of beer...
...and refilled it in a manner
which displeased him.
- Then what is the matter with you?
- Nothing...
...I'm as healthy
as the 40 sacred baboons.
My name is Kaptah...
...and I've decided
to be your servant.
Even if I needed one,
I couldn't afford it.
And if I could afford it,
I wouldn't employ a ragged beggar.
I may be ragged,
but I'm intelligent...
...I am handsome
and I can read.
Well, you're quite right, master,
I am a poor servant.
But then you're a poor physician
and deserve no better.
I shall obey your orders...
...you may beat me,
within reason...
...and in return,
I shall steal from you...
...also within reason.
Ohm then you admit
you're a thief?
We are all thieves.
Only the dishonest ones deny it.
I will improve your reputation.
People will say:
"He must be a good physician
if he can afford a servant".
With one eye? They will say:
"He must be a poor physician
not to have cured his own servant".
Well, I shall say that when
you first bought me I was totally blind...
...and that you restored
half my sight.
Master! Master!
Heave! Heave! Heave!
Master, come quickly!
Come quickly!
Look. This is your chance.
I told you I'd make
your reputation.
Come here everyone!
Come here and watch!
You shall see such wonders
as your eyes have never beheld.
The gods themselves have instructed
my master in his arts.
Known to him are the ancient spells
and potions of our ancestors.
Come here and watch!
- Someone bring water.
- Here's water.
Moisten the cloth,
and squeeze it between his lips.
I'll need fire to purify
my instruments.
Fire. Bring fire,
for the worker of wonders.
The fire won't be needed,
he's dead.
Observe! Observe the wisdom
and mercy of my master!
Lest this poor soul
be forced to hobble...
...for the rest
of his life on one foot...
...my master has granted him
the boon of death.
No one could have saved him.
Saved him?
For what?
So the young physician
is still asking "why"?
Master...
...that's a dangerous woman.
Dangerous?
The look in her eye,
the look of a calfless calf, for a ewe...
...for it's lamb.
Beware of such looks, master,
her mind is on breaking...
...a jar with you...
...on marriage.
I don't even know her name.
Her name was Merit.
She was a tavern maid.
And she could neither read,
nor write.
She loved me all her life.
But this I didn't learn
until it was too late.
People of Thebes!
Ask pity of the gods!
Pharaoh is dead!
They have been caterwauling all night!
The fools think they can bring
pharaoh back to life?
Why don't you take him home?
It's early morning.
What's wrong with him?
He was refused an appointment
in the palace guards...
...because of his birth.
You don't have to lower your voice.
I know what you're saying!
Yeah, I was refused!
Refused because of my birth!
Look at the ones they accepted!
Mincing perfumed idiots...
...who carry sunshades,
and twitter like birds!
How long till dawn?
An hour, perhaps.
Did you ever hunt lions?
No?
I saw a black mane male...
...drinking from a pool at sunset.
But if he never hunted lions...
He is under my protection,
I told you once before.
I need no protection.
I'll bring you back
the skin of a lion myself.
Suppose the lion brings back your skin,
what happens to me?
Find another master to rob,
richer than I am.
Sinuhe, please be careful.
To pay our score.
May it benefit, my lord.
Let's go before
she changes your mind!
You know
that's how I lost my eye.
Lion hunting.
Son of a cheese-maker.
Why didn't you run, you fool?
You were nearly killed!
Be quiet.
The god is coming.
What's he talking about?
He said "The god is coming".
Which god?
He is coming. Aton.
Aton?
Look!
He worships the face of the sun.
Thy dawning is beautiful...
...in the horizon of heaven.
Oh, living Aton,
beginning of life...
- What's the matter with him?
- He has the holy sickness.
At least I can prevent him
from biting his tongue.
Well, we can't leave him here.
Let's take him in the city.
Seize them!
What's wrong?
What have we done?
You'll find out in good time.
Put them in chains.
For two days, we were held
without knowledge...
...of the reason for our arrest.
Then we were taken under guard
to the Royal Palace.
Silence!
On your faces!
Our new pharaoh comes!
On your faces
before the Living God.
The one we called fool,
is pharaoh.
We'll lose our heads for this.
Princess, come back!
Mighty pharaoh! King of Upper
and Lower Egypt...
Princess!
Look, father!
Hush! Your father is busy.
But I want him
to see my new monkey.
Not now, child.
Sit down, princess.
Mighty pharaoh!
King of Upper and Lower Egypt!
- Son of the Sun...
- You have feet.
Stand on them.
You will please me much better
if you will all rise.
My heart is heavy because
of my father's death.
Let us finish our affairs
as quickly as possible.
The embassies
of Hati and Kush...
...come to pay respect
to the new pharaoh.
- There are gifts from...
- Later.
I wish to see the two prisoners
you spoke of.
Are they here?
Yes, Sire.
Come forward!
On your knees!
On your feet!
Why have these men
been held without trial?
Their crime is sacrilege, Sire.
They laid hands on the sacred
person of pharaoh.
Sinuhe, a physician,
the son of Senmut.
Horemheb,
the son of a cheese-maker.
Come forward.
For a cheese-maker
he has bold eyes.
The other one, the physician...
- Notice his features.
- You are the son of Senmut?
I've heard of his work
among the poor.
Come closer.
Sire, he must die!
He laid hands on you!
I know that.
It was to help me.
The law makes
no such distinction, Sire!
Have I the power
to change the law?
There is no limit
to pharaoh's power!
The law is changed.
I appoint you physician
to my household.
I am deeply grateful, Sire,
but I cannot accept this honor.
Why not?
I've sworn an oath
to serve the poor.
Because of your father?
For that,
and other reasons.
Senmut is not my real father.
My parents must have been
of the poor themselves...
...for as a baby I was cast adrift
on the Nile, in a reed boat.
And you never learned
who your parents were?
Perhaps they were fowlers.
The boat was tied
with fowler's knots.
"Fowler's knots"?
Did you say "fowler's knots"?
Yes!
Why do you ask, mother?
Curiosity, my son.
You may honor your vows Sinuhe,
and serve the poor.
But on condition you bind
yourself to come to the palace...
...whenever I or my family,
have need of you.
Thank you, Sire!
This other one is no healer,
this cheese-maker's son.
Yet, he too, profane pharaoh
with his touch.
Sire, may I speak?
Speak!
Horemheb saved your life
by slaying the lion.
What is Horemhed's desire?
To let my sword drink the blood
of pharaoh's enemies...
...as my arrow drank
the lion's blood.
This has been foretold
is my... destiny.
And is the destiny of Egypt...
...to be written in blood?
It has always been, Sire.
As long as there's war,
blood must flow.
What is your request?
An appointment, Sire.
As an officer in your guards.
You request is granted!
I wish he asked to be
our cheese-maker.
- Princess!
- I wish he would!
The sun is setting.
Forgive me all.
I will return to my meditations.
Come, my children.
My Lord, the princess Baketamon
commands your presence.
Follow me.
Not you.
This way, my lord.
Come in physician.
My mother wishes a word with you.
He won't hurt you.
Some more beer.
Come closer.
So, you never learned
who your parents were?
Surely you tried to find out?
Speak up!
I'm content with the parents
I have, your Majesty.
In what year
were you cast adrift?
In the same year
that pharaoh was born.
Or so I've been told.
Why does your Majesty...
You're not here to ask questions.
My mother wishes you
to examine her.
I know that I'm dying.
I want to know
how long it will take.
Don't be shy.
Once, I enjoyed the touch
of a man's hand.
How long ago!
Why do you stop, physician?
To admire the way a queen
can weave a mat of reeds?
Those are fowler's knots!
Didn't you know that my family
were bird catchers in the Lower Kingdom?
And I caught
an eagle in my net.
Pharaoh himself.
He loved me, Sinuhe,
because I was strong and lusty.
Because I was vulgar and unlearned
and told him the truth.
His other wives,
the high born delicate ones...
...with their narrow heads,
how they hated me.
So I swore that I would give him a son
to wear the Double Crown.
And I did.
But the gods
were perverse.
They gave me a son
as soft as a woman...
...and a daughter as hard as a man.
Baketamon here,
should be pharaoh.
Not her brother.
Well, what do you find?
- If your Majesty will forgive me...
- Tell her the truth.
If you want
to live much longer...
- ...you must give up the strong brew.
- What impenitence.
I was drinking beer
before you were born.
Your Majesty asked me
for the truth.
Now I give you
some advice, young man.
Never tell the truth
to an old woman.
Especially if she asks for it.
Go now, you weary me.
What did she want?
I'm not sure.
- Did she speak of me?
- No.
Some day, when I command
the armies, I...
You know, when I think of her,
my blood boils.
Tell me, my friend...
...do you have a potion
or something to cool my fever?
The wise men say that: "One evil spirit
can only be driven out by another."
You mean, another woman?
- Of course.
- A noble medicine.
I know just the place.
A woman from Babylon.
She gives a banquet every night.
She won't mind
two additional guests.
- No, I...
- Look...
...we've got to celebrate
our good fortune.
Don't worry, my friend.
You're always
under my protection.
Let's go outside.
We'll show you the garden.
Sinuhe, my friend...
...let's go out in the garden,
and pick a few flowers.
- No, I'll wait for you here.
- Alright, I'll pick a few for you.
Have you never looked
at a woman before?
Hundreds. And in the state
the gods created them.
I'm a physician.
Your name?
I'm called Sinuhe.
"He who is alone."
Is this is your house?
This is my house.
And I have guest every evening.
I dislike being alone.
Baraka!
The inscription
of the new pharaoh!
His gift.
- I must leave now.
- Why?
Because men bring you rich presents
for as little as a smile.
This is all I have.
I have never asked a man
for anything.
But I ask you to stay!
I can't.
Is it because
we women of Babylon...
...have such a bad reputation?
Or do you find me so ugly?
Do you?
You're beautiful.
Beyond all dreams.
Such flattery must come easily
to a man who's known...
..."hundreds of women."
No one before has ever seemed
to me so beautiful.
So strange.
When I look in your eyes, I...
I feel...
What do you feel, Sinuhe?
I feel the fever of Thebes
in my blood.
And I know that I was born to live
in the sunset of the world.
And that nothing matters...
nothing...
...but what I see in your eyes.
It's late, I...
I must be leaving.
If you go fulfilled with wine...
...and wild thoughts...
...you will surely get into trouble
with some designing woman.
Would you care?
No, I brought you here
only to show you the gate...
...in my garden wall.
Later...
...when all my guests
have gone...
...I will be here by my lotus pool.
Why do you tell me this?
Perhaps because I'm fond of gifts.
And the greatest gift
any man can bring to a woman is...
...his innocence...
...which he can give only once.
Wait.
Before you touch me,
I must give you a warning.
Warning?
There is a reason why the Goddess
of Love takes the form of a cat.
When I look at you,
I care nothing for cats or gods.
Look, Sinuhe...
...a cat's paws are soft...
...but they hide claws.
The cat takes pleasure
in tormenting its victim.
Not until the creature
is nearly dead...
...will it show pity,
and put an end to it.
What does this to do
with you and me?
You hadn't any experience...
...and I must be what I am.
Leave now...
...and do not return
to the gate in my wall...
...or you may regret it
all your life.
I don't even know your name.
In their foolishness...
...men give me the name
which means "beautiful."
Nefer!
Nefer! Nefer!
It's no business of mine
where he spends his time.
Well, if you don't
consider it your business...
...why are you
so angry with me?
Get out.
For a full week now
he's telling me...
...to send his patients
to other physician.
I've even had to return
the coppers I've excepted...
...for appointments with him.
This woman stole his mind.
He's as mad as a jackal
that prowls...
...around the graves
in time of drought.
And I'm as mad as he is.
It was you I warn him against!
Then why come to me now?
There are worse things
than marriage.
How could I be such a fool
even to dream of it?
He is physician
to pharaoh, and I'm...
Kaptah, what can I do?
Offer him more then she can.
Get out, you one-eyed
son of baboon!
Out! Get out!
Why do you wait, Sinuhe?
I've told you that tonight
I'm engaged.
I'm entertaining
a merchant from Syria.
If he touches you, I'll kill him.
Only foolish boys
speak in such terms.
I must confess, Sinuhe.
I find you appealing.
Very appealing.
You're not like the others.
You're young, and strong...
...and innocent.
But unfortunately,
I must protect myself.
Women like me who live alone...
...cannot afford to give in
to their weaknesses.
Or they end their days
begging in the streets.
I offer you my protection
for as long as you live.
Men have said that to me
so many times...
...in so many tongues.
Listen, Sinuhe...
...I live in Egypt...
...because I can never
return to Babylon.
When I was 12 years old,
I was sold as a slave...
...and passed from
one master to another.
Is there any difference
in your life now?
A very great difference.
For now,
no man is my master.
The Syrian merchant
who dines with me tonight...
...brings me a ruby
that once belonged to a queen.
But to give away a present
from pharaoh is sacrilege.
I ask for nothing.
I only want you to understand.
You must go now.
- My guest will be here at any moment.
- Send him away.
- I told you why I can't.
- Send him away!
You're hurting me!
I've given you the only thing
of value that I have.
Isn't that what you wanted?
What deceivers men are.
And you're the same
as all the rest.
You're not so poor
as you pretend, Sinuhe.
You have a house...
...and many fine
instruments of copper.
If I give them to you,
will you promise me...
I promise nothing.
If you wish
to give me a present...
...do so.
But ask nothing from me...
...as I ask nothing from you.
I'm an evil woman, Sinuhe.
From the very beginning
I warned you.
Keep your house
and your instruments...
...and go!
Your Highness shoots well,
for a woman.
A child's game.
- I see you won promotion.
- Why not?
A real soldier here
is like a falcon among sparrows.
I wish a word with you,
over here!
May I say, I long dreamed
of a word with you?
We won't discuss your dreams.
I wish to speak of your friend,
the physician.
Why are you so interested in him?
My brother has been asking for him.
He hasn't yet presented
himself at court.
Sinuhe has... left the city.
He's gone to... Memphis I think.
If you hope for further promotions,
don't lie to me.
I love my friend enough
to lie for him.
Even to a royal princess.
What do you want?
I want him saved from this creature
who has stolen his wits.
That's easy.
She's a Babylonian.
- Have her banished, or killed.
- He'll follow her into exile...
...or moan over a grave
the rest of his life.
No. He must be made to see
that she is worthless.
And how do you expect
to accomplish that?
By letting him find out
that she has betrayed him...
...with his best friend.
You shouldn't find that too difficult.
Such women like to be assaulted
as if they were fortresses.
Your Highness flatters me.
I value you in the same way
that you value yourself.
Give me that bracelet.
You want a reward...
...for helping a friend
you love so much?
I want it for the Babylonian.
Then you're afraid that
your manly charms won't be enough?
Not for her!
My friends are watching us.
They think
you're awarding me an honor.
Let them think what they will.
Some day you'll strip
your arms of honors for me.
Your ankles, and your neck.
Save your passions
to the Babylonian.
She'll appreciate them
more than I do.
Open up, let me in.
The hour is late.
I have orders to admit no one.
Your mistress is expecting me.
- I have a message from her.
- Those are my orders.
Horemheb.
Horemhed!
Nefer, let me in!
You must go.
He knows you're here.
I don't care, do you?
I sent him no message
to come tonight.
I took the liberty of sending one
in your name, do you mind?
So, that's it.
Go now!
Stupid fool!
I'll kill you!
You're crazy!
Listen, you fool!
It was our friendship
that brought me here.
Can't you see what she is?
The only reason I came here
it was to prove it to you.
Never call me friend again!
- Get out!
- Very well.
You'll deserve everything
you'll get from her.
You may go too.
This is my house,
and it is not a tavern.
Nefer, wait.
Look, here...
...I brought you what you asked.
The deed to my house...
...my instruments.
I never asked you for this trash!
It's all I have...
...and not entirely trash.
The house is small,
but it's fitted up for a physician's use.
The instruments are the finest.
They're worth as much
as precious jewels.
There...
...now you own
everything that was mine.
Sinuhe, please! I'm tired.
You always have some excuse.
- Nefer, I...
- Wait.
Since you won't listen
to my warnings...
...you force me to treat you
like my other friends.
What more
do you want from me?
For you I've disobeyed pharaoh...
...disgraced my family,
beggared myself.
And still you lie to me.
Lie?
How?
Why have you chosen
not to tell me...
...that your father
has a fine house on the waterfront?
I can't give you
what isn't my own.
Or that he has built and furnished
for his wife and himself...
...a splendid tomb
in the City of the Dead?
You're asking me to rob
my parents of immortality.
To let their bodies,
rot into nothingness...
...like the carcasses
of slaves and animals?
I ask for nothing.
But if you do
this one thing for me...
...I will show you
the finer perfection of love.
What are you doing here?
You haven't been to the tavern
for many days.
- I had to see you.
- The man you know, is dead!
Forget him!
I could never forget you.
Sinuhe, please listen to me,
I want to help you.
I am not without experience.
You learn a great deal
about life in a tavern.
Every night, I see the hunger
in men's eyes.
With a tavern maid
they don't trouble to hide it.
There are some who approach you
arrogantly, demanding...
...like your friend Horemheb.
That kind can never
be hurt by a woman.
Then there are those
too shy to ask...
...but the hunger
is in their eyes too.
They are the ones
who are unarmed.
Because they are afraid to approach
a woman who might make them happy...
...they fall an easy victim
to the other kind.
They think they are in love...
...because they have no way
of knowing what love is.
What are you trying to say?
What I shouldn't have to say...
...when you come home at this hour,
and find me waiting for you.
If you wish to help me, you can.
Here are the deeds
to my parents' house...
...to the tomb which they thought
would give them immortality.
Here it is her name,
the new owner.
Read it, Merit.
Nefer! Nefer! Nefer!
Sinuhe, you can't!
The deeds have to be witnessed.
Be the first to sign!
Go on! Sign!
If you can't write,
make your mark!
Gods have pity on you!
The house and tomb are yours.
From this hour
I am accused and disgraced...
...before gods and men.
It's a high price to pay.
Now prove to me
that it's not too high.
How should I prove it, Sinuhe?
By keeping your promise.
Promise?
What did I promise?
The perfection of love.
I did?
Sinuhe, as I have already told you...
...I find you very appealing.
Are you quite sure that
"perfection" is what you want?
Yes.
Then you shall have it.
I will end your misery.
Secum!
Show this man to the door.
Never admit him
to my house again.
Every philosopher knows...
...that we spend our lives
seeking perfection...
...and find it
only in an ending.
Ending?
Sooner or later,
even a cat tires of it's game.
Sinuhe!
No!
Baraka! Secum!
Sinuhe! Sinuhe!
Once again I came alone, and in darkness
to the house of my parents.
The house that
was no longer theirs.
How did they die?
As you should know, master...
...a physician can turn
his skill to taking life...
...as well as to saving it.
Your father left this for you.
Read it.
I can't.
Then listen.
"To Sinuhe, our son.
We are grieved for your sake,
because you have met with ill fortune.
Do not regret that you were required
to sell our tomb.
For all existence is vanity...
...we desire no life
in the hereafter.
Remember always that
we blessed you before we left.
For you who came to us
from the river...
...when we were already old...
...were the greatest joy
of our lives.
May your heart
be shielded from sorrow.
Such is the desire of your father...
...and your mother."
What do you want here
in the House of Death?
I've brought you the bodies
of a man and a woman...
...to be preserved by your art...
...so that they may enjoy
eternal life.
As you say,
we are artists here.
What can you pay for our services?
I have nothing.
Nothing? Throw this carrion
in the river.
Wait! I am willing to work here...
...to pay for the embalming...
- ...for as long as you say I must.
- Work here?
Only condemned criminals...
...and the accursed of the gods
seek work in the House of Death.
There is no man here
who is not better than I am.
Put him to work!
For 90 days I labored among
the accursed in the House of Death.
It was as if I had died myself.
And only my servant, Kaptah...
...knew what I had done,
or where I was.
What are you doing here?
Speak, or I'll bash your head in!
- Are you a god?
- God?
No god would dare
show his face here after dark.
You're a grave robber!
I didn't come here to steal.
What do you want then?
I brought my parents
here to bury them.
In the Valley of the Kings?
I hoped that
if I buried them here...
...they might share
the wealth of the pharaohs...
...in the other world.
Other world!
It's true that many pharaohs
planted here...
...but I have yet to see one of them
putting out any shoots.
And it's certainly
they don't see the gifts...
...because we get them first.
You don't believe in another life.
They did.
You're a strange one.
I'll help you dig.
I wish somehow
I could mark their graves.
Mark or unmarked,
it's all the same.
20 years
to build a pyramid...
...or 10 minutes to scrap
a hole in the sand.
Dead are dead,
no matter where we put them.
In the end,
the sand conquers all.
Every grain of sand...
...will outlive every man alive,
and every man that ever will be born.
Immortality?
I hold it in my hand.
Only the little grains of sand
will never die.
Listen!
A jackal.
A jackal with two legs.
One of my friends warning us
there is a stranger coming.
Here, in the shadow.
Sinuhe?
- That you?
- Yes.
This is as good a place
as any to meet a woman.
Sinuhe?
How did you find me?
Kaptah told me.
He told me what you've done.
How you labored 90 days
in the House of Death.
Keep away!
The smell of death is still on me.
How long since you've eaten?
I don't know.
I brought you some bread and wine.
Go back, Merit. Go back.
Leave me alone.
Not until you've eaten.
Sit here, Sinuhe.
To please me if nothing else.
Bread?
Some wine?
Thebes, city of lust and evil.
Men deserve injustice.
They deserve their cruel priests,
and evil gods...
...for we are vile!
No more than a crawling disease
on the face of the earth.
The grave is the only cure
for our vileness.
That is what I've learned.
I'll take you back to the city.
You can't go back.
Pharaoh's daughter died because
you couldn't be found to save her.
He's frantic with grief.
Sinuhe, he's...
He's sentenced you to death.
It means nothing.
Death never comes to him
who asks for it.
I know this too
in my new wisdom.
Do you call that wisdom?
To despise yourself
because of what one woman did to you?
Do you really think
all women are like that?
Can't you believe in a love
that asks for nothing?
My love!
Everything is arranged, master.
- I was able to buy passage for us!
- Buy it?
Took everything I had,
everything I'd stolen from you.
Come, we must hide below decks
before the other passengers arrive.
Merit...
...I don't know how to say this...
Take this with you.
It isn't real gold, but...
...I want you to have it.
It's the symbol
of the Sun God, Aton.
- Perhaps someday...
- No.
We'd only fool ourselves
to think so.
This is goodbye forever.
Forever?
You're young, Merit.
Your whole life is before you.
Mine will end somewhere
in the darkness of a foreign land.
I love you, Sinuhe.
Always remember that.
Hurry, master!
And so I left behind me
the land of my fathers.
And with it, I left my youth
which had promised so much...
...and whose only fruit
had been despair.
As the years passed...
...Kaptah and I traveled
to the ends of the earth.
In the beginning,
we lived as we could.
Friendless wanders that we were...
...we cheated and stole,
in order to live.
We knew heat, hunger, and cold...
...and slept under the stars.
Then, as time softened
my sorrow...
...I began to put to use the skills
I have learned in the School of Life...
...and in my father's house.
As we moved on,
my fame went before me...
...to distant lands, which had
never seen an Egyptian before...
...nor a trained physician.
The simplest cures
were thought to be miracles...
...and I became known
as a worker of magic.
As we traveled on to new lands
our wealth increased.
Everywhere we saw
injustice and misery.
But I hardened my heart.
I reserved my skills
for the rich and the powerful...
...who could pay.
For the children of poverty,
there was no cure.
Cry out when the pain is greatest.
No Hittite warrior
cries out in pain.
- There?
- Yes.
It's as I feared,
Lord Commander...
...your skull must be opened...
...and the evil
removed with a knife.
Is this an Egyptian plot?
To murder our commander
at the time...
At the time when you're planning
war on Egypt?
It was you that brought me here
from Babylon, my Lords.
I take no interest in your plans.
I have no country.
Egypt, least of all.
Shall I undertake your cure?
What chance
have I to survive?
One chance in five.
- If I die, my officers will kill you.
- I know that.
If I live...
...what will you demand?
Your sword of black metal.
Nothing more.
- Then you are a spy!
- Doesn't matter.
After the first skirmish our secret
will no longer be secret.
After the second Egypt
will no longer be Egypt.
Proceed, Egyptian.
Shave his head and wash it.
Tie him to this chair securely.
I'll prepare a drug
to dull his pain.
Master. Master.
It's you and not
the Hittite commander...
...who should have a hole
bored in your head.
Why do you even
ask for a sword?
You could have demanded
a fortune.
Because I think this new metal
of the Hittites...
...may change
the history of the world!
And because Horemheb
now commands the army in Egypt.
So you lied.
There is a key
to your heart after all.
Still love your native land.
Master, you will never
go back there.
No pharaoh ever forgives
his enemies.
Leave my instruments
in the flame.
Kaptah, we're going home.
Home.
But Egypt...
Egypt was a stricken land.
Torn by hatred and civil strife.
I fear the Hittites, master,
but I fear this more.
Better if we had never come!
Your name, Syrian?
I am Egyptian.
My name is Sinuhe.
Once physician to the pharaoh.
You must have been bitten
by a rabid ape when you were small.
You know, that if your name is
on that list of prescribed criminals...
Well, you know the Egyptians.
Seize them!
Take them to headquarters!
There must be some mistake!
Could you go over the list again?
What do you expect me to do?
Bring soldiers here from the Delta?
From the Cataracts?
Your duty is
to keep order in the city.
You should be able to do it
with the men you have!
You were told
to never return to Egypt.
Why did you come back?
It's said that "He who has drunk
of Nile water...
...can never quench his thirst
in other lands."
I know why you're here.
The priests of the old gods
hope to rid themselves of pharaoh.
They whisper that he is mad
and his skull should be opened.
It would be a simple matter
to let the knife slip.
So they brought back to Egypt
the one man...
...who is master
of the operation.
You.
Give me the sword
you took from my servant.
Give it to him.
This is why
I came back to Egypt!
- Draw your sword.
- Stand back.
And now?
Strike at me, hard.
Do you know
what you're asking my friend?
Strike!
Again, harder!
Where did you get this?
In the land of the Hittites.
Hundreds of forgers
are at work there night and day...
...making weapons of this new metal.
It is called "iron".
Come with me.
How beautiful our God
The new temple where
the pharaoh worships his One God.
Look!
I've seen the sorrow this One God
has brought upon Egypt.
It was the priests, not pharaoh,
who brought this sorrow on us.
It was they who blamed
the misfortunes of Egypt on pharaoh...
...and made the people believe that
thus the old gods show their anger.
If I had my way,
I'd hang every priest by his heels.
But our pharaoh believes in repaying
treachery with kindness.
Come.
Stay on your feet.
I apologize, Sire,
for interrupting your prayers.
I have urgent news.
Lord Commander
owes me no explanation.
I bring you someone
that you will remember.
Sinuhe, the physician.
Sinuhe? Yes.
He asks of you
grant him pardon, Sire.
And I, as commander of the army,
also urge you to be merciful.
It is I who should ask
your pardon, Sinuhe.
Once I raised my hand against you.
I would have killed you.
It delights me to see you.
Sinuhe just returned
from the land of the Hittites.
They're preparing
war against us.
They've succeeded
in making a new metal.
He brought this sword as proof.
It cuts through our Egyptian copper
like a knife through straw.
How could all this be true?
I've sent the Cross of Life
to the Hittite princes.
I promised them my friendship.
Akhenaten, my mad friend
do you think...
...they care
for your "Cross of Life"?
They want loot, slaves, power!
And with this...
...they'll get them.
Unless you let me strike first.
Destroy their cities,
their mines, and their forgers.
Are you asking me
to condone slaughter?
I am asking you to show our enemies,
the same mercy they'd show us.
No more, no less.
There's mercy in every man's heart.
If we can only reach it.
A man who's lived
in darkness all his life...
...doesn't understand the light
he calls evil, because it hurts his eyes.
Should we then, extinguish our lights
and crawl into the darkness, with him?
Such wisdom is already filled
the Nile with corpses.
Sire, again this morning rioting
broke out on the waterfront.
I had to send soldiers in
to stop it.
Don't you see, Sire...
...a war now
will unite our country.
Once again the Egyptians
will stand together...
...brothers
against a common foe.
He is right, my husband.
Even you?
So near to me then
is the darkness?
You should listen to Horemheb.
I can listen only to Aton.
I will write
to the Hittite princes...
...asking them to make
their intentions clear.
Thank you for coming.
Now, do you see
what I have to contend with?
Could he prevent you from doing
what you want with the army?
No. The men follow me, not him.
But he is pharaoh,
and I have sworn him oath of loyalty.
He'll write to the Hittites!
He might as well invite them
come take his throne.
Would it matter?
I've seen rulers,
great and small...
...old and young,
warlike and effeminate.
The people suffer and die
whatever the ruler calls himself.
Hittite, Egyptian, Cretan.
It's bad to believe
in too much, like pharaoh.
But it's worse to believe
in too little, my friend.
I believe in nothing.
While Egypt tore herself
in civil strife...
...I doubled my fortune,
as physician to the wealthy.
Send away the other patients.
I'm tired.
I will see no more today.
I think you will see this one, master.
You might find it rewarding.
- Oh, is the fee so high?
- Not high, but interesting.
Send her in.
He'll see you.
Come again tomorrow.
I'm very sorry,
there is nothing I can do.
Can you help me?
Tell me what ails you.
Give me your hand.
Open your robe.
I can save your life
but I can't restore your beauty.
The trouble has eaten
too far for that.
- Do you want to live, Nefer?
- Yes.
Yes, I want to live.
Come back tomorrow morning,
I will undertake your cure.
I cannot pay you.
Your collar was all I had left.
There will be
no fee for my services.
Here.
For 10 years I dreamed of this,
of meeting her again.
When I would be the master.
Of taking my revenge,
slowly... savoring it.
What do you feel now
that you have your chance?
Only pity.
Sorrow.
Because once,
she was so beautiful.
Well, a cat can't help
being what it is.
It's strange, Kaptah.
Revenge leaves you as empty
as fame and fortune.
Eat your fill of all of them...
...and you're still just as hungry.
- Master, what is it you want?
- I don't know.
But whatever it is, I've been searching
for it in the wrong places.
Master, it's dangerous to walk
in this quarter unescorted.
Sights, and sounds, and smells,
can make the past live again.
This is where I used to draw water
for my father.
It was a long time ago.
Look, Kaptah!
This is the tree that I learned to climb
when I could barely walk.
- Leave me alone!
- Come back here!
- Don't let him get away!
- Get his cross!
- It's my cross!
- I got him!
- What are you doing?
- Give me that cross!
- No!
Let him alone! Stop that!
Go on! Go on!
- Are you hurt?
- No.
- Where do you live?
- Over there.
- Thoth, my poor darling!
- I'm alright.
- You're bleeding!
- It's nothing.
Some of those other boys
didn't like my cross.
- I'll take you to a physician.
- May I help?
Sinuhe!
Yes, my Lord, you can.
This is the Lord Sinuhe, Thoth.
A very famous physician.
- I must get linen for a bandage.
- I'll get it.
Merit.
After all these years...
You've been
in my prayers, Sinuhe.
I'm grateful to your god...
...if it was he
who brought us together.
Won't you come in?
You knew this was
my father's house?
The house was cheap.
I needed a place of my own.
You, and your husband?
I am not married.
- I found the bandages, mother.
- Mother?
He's the child
of a friend, an orphan...
...but he doesn't know that.
He thinks I'm his mother.
- Sinuhe, please...
- I understand.
Your secret is safe
with this orphan.
Please come in.
Here are the bandages...
...and instruments,
if you have to use them.
When I grow up,
I'm going to be a physician too.
I hope you use these
with more credit than I did.
I bought them the same time
as I bought the house.
I see.
Sit down over there.
Now hold the bandage.
- This is going to hurt.
- I'm not afraid.
Have I been
in your prayers too?
Yes. I prayed that Aton
would teach you humility, and manners.
Now I know we've come home.
Only in Egypt,
does a woman's tongue...
...takes so sharp an edge.
Now, in two days
you can take off the bandage.
- But not before, do you understand?
- Why?
Oh, I mean,
what will happen, if I do?
Probably nothing.
I spoke sternly to you...
...because physicians should always
be firm with their patients.
You'll find out.
It increases their respect for you...
...and also
the size of your fees.
But I will be physician
to the poor.
But the rich have
more interesting ailments...
...and can better afford them.
No. I would work for the poor.
I'm hungry. Are you?
I could eat a hippopotamus.
Well, we're having fish.
- Hurry up, Mother!
- Yes, hurry!
- Be quiet, both of you.
- Come here.
Clean your instruments,
and put them away.
You think you see so much
with your one eye?
More than my master
does with two.
- Did you dare to tell him...
- Why should I tell him?
I like my life as it is,
without a woman...
...to pour hot water on my feet,
because I displeased her.
Questioning my accounts,
rationing my beer...
Hush!
Merit...
I didn't ask you to come here,
to pry into my life.
I didn't expect to...
Smoke!
Perhaps you think the smoke
has blinded me too.
What does the lord Sinuhe,
the great, rich, and cynical...
...lord Sinuhe,
want with a tavern maid?
You call me great and rich
but I have nothing.
I am the poorest of men
because I've wasted my life.
Everything I ever touched,
I destroyed.
My birthright, my parents...
Your life too, Merit.
But you've given me something.
Perhaps an answer
to the question...
...I've asked myself
ever since I was a boy.
Not your god,
because I don't believe in gods...
...but one thing I created,
which wasn't a waste.
If it's too late
to live for ourselves...
...perhaps we can begin
to live for our son.
Thoth, my boy.
Let me offer you
a priceless jewel of wisdom.
Never peer through windows
on matters which don't concern you.
That's how I happen
to have only one eye.
Did you intend to pass
without speaking to me?
I beg Your Highness pardon,
but pharaoh has sent for me.
I know.
It's been many years,
physician.
The look of innocence is gone.
If Your Highness will excuse me...
- You've heard the news?
The Hittites
have invaded Syria.
Their chariots are approaching
the Delta of the Nile.
- Then the war has begun.
- No!
My brother's refused to give Horemheb
permission to fight!
Then he must be mad.
- I've known that for a long time.
- Physician!
After you see my brother
come to my chamber.
- Your Majesty.
- Thank you for coming.
Sire.
My friend!
Sire, you must give Horemhed permission
to defend Egypt.
No! No!
Right or wrong,
I will not order death.
I can not plunge Egypt
into a bath of blood.
They say I'm mad.
Horemheb, the priests,
even my own sister.
Are they right, Sinuhe?
Am I mad?
You are mad, Sire.
But your madness is more beautiful
then the wisdom of other men.
Beautiful...
Yes, my vision of Aton
was beautiful.
I thought it would give peace
and happiness to all men.
I thought I could be his voice...
...and bring his message
to my people.
But I was wrong.
The vision has faded.
My voice was no more than
the whisper of wind in the desert.
Aton has abandoned me...
...to war...
...to madness...
...to the death.
If you love me, Sinuhe...
...lift the burden from my soul.
Give me peace.
A physician's task
is to prolong life, Sire...
...not to shorten it.
He should rest now.
Can you do anything for him?
I'm sorry, but his illness
is not of the body, Your Majesty.
What is it you want?
What pharaoh himself asked you for:
"to give him peace."
You have more courage
than I thought.
If Horemheb
were to learn of this...
My men are ready!
The loyal Lord Commander!
You too?
Look, Sinuhe...
...I love Akhnaton,
as I love my own right arm...
...but if my arm were gangrene,
I'd cut it off.
Just as Akhnaton
must be cut off from Egypt!
All Egypt knows that I'm right...
- ...and you know it!
- Yes.
Yes, in your place,
I'd tell myself the same thing.
Have you a potion that
will give him sleep, without pain?
I'm to kill him...
...when all around me
there is such a talent for violence?
Do this, and the gods
will bless you forever.
I see, you speak for the gods
and Horemheb for Egypt.
Tell me one thing,
who succeeds to the throne?
Who else but the commander
of the army that will save Egypt...
...and make it once more,
the greatest power in the world?
Yes.
Horemheb!
You, pharaoh?
- So that's the price for your treason.
- Call it treason if you like.
But there's only one thing
that can save Egypt now...
...and that's courage.
Courage to act.
Courage to conquer our enemies
and put their leaders in chains.
Akhnaton is in his chamber.
He is helpless.
Now is your chance to strike.
But you won't, will you?
Because no hand has ever been raised
openly against a pharaoh.
If you strike him down...
...then the way will be clear,
the precedent established...
...for someone else to strike down
the next pharaoh...
...whose name you hope
will be Horemheb.
So, this dirty thing
must be done by indirection...
...as it's always
been done in the past.
By a physician
pretending to heal him.
who's known to be his friend.
I'm sorry,
but I'm not that man.
Wait outside.
Don't go far away.
Your Highness wished to see me?
Are you going to do
what they want?
No.
You should agree.
Akhnaton must die.
For his own sake.
Now it's for his own sake.
Mekere, wants to kill him
for the gods...
...Horemheb for Egypt...
...and his sister
for his own sake.
Any hunter will show mercy
to a wounded animal.
Did they tell you how they plan
to dirty the throne?
They told me that Horemheb
was to be pharaoh.
And I'm to be his queen.
He is to come
to my chamber tonight...
...and tomorrow our marriage
will be proclaimed...
...in the temple of the old gods.
I see.
A good plan.
This marriage will make him
acceptable to the people.
But not to me, physician.
When I marry, it will be
to no cheese-maker's son.
Leave!
We haven't much time.
Horemheb's men
are in control of the city.
Tonight the priests will open
and restore the old gods...
...and make
a sacrifice of blood.
But together,
we can beat them.
Horemheb and
all the the evil priests.
Sinuhe, come here!
This is what you must do.
Pretend to fall in
with their plans.
Kill my brother,
and kill Horemheb too.
- Two murders.
- Then come to my chamber tonight...
...and I'll gladly open the doors
with my own hands.
Willingly share the throne
with you, as pharaoh.
Why should the people accept
a nameless physician as their pharaoh?
Because you are pharaoh.
You're my half brother.
The only man in Egypt
fit to be my husband...
...and rule by my side.
Why do you think
my mother and I sent for you...
...the day you first came
to the palace?
Before she died,
she told me everything...
...and left it to my judgment,
if you should ever hear the truth.
She was not the first to bare
my father, the pharaoh, a son.
A few weeks before,
one of his other wives...
...was delivered
of a boy child... You!
You were taken away
from your mother...
...and cast adrift on the river,
in a boat tied with fowler's knots.
Tied by my mother herself,
who was a fowler's daughter.
And the mother failed to notice
that her newborn had disappeared?
She was shown a dead girl baby,
and told it was hers.
Hundreds of babies
are cast adrift every year...
...and boats are often tied
with fowler's knots.
In the Lower Kingdom,
not in Thebes.
But there is stronger
evidence than that.
Get my chariot!
Come with me to the Valley of the Kings,
to my father's tomb.
See for yourself.
The Third Amenhotep...
...the great pharaoh....
...my father...
...and yours.
Look!
The finest artists
in Thebes made this.
His exact likeness.
Look at the nose,
the cheek bones...
...the forehead,
the line of the jaw.
You wanted further proof.
Look!
That's what my mother saw...
...when you stood before us
in the throne room.
What no one else, but she,
could recognize.
The face of her husband
as a young man.
The great pharaoh come
to life again... in you!
Now have you any doubts?
Leave me alone here.
You know that
I've shown you the truth.
Yes, now I'm sure
that it's true.
But would Horemheb
ever accept such proof?
Of course not. He's eaten up
with his own ambition.
He's gone much too far.
He couldn't turn back now,
even if he wanted to.
That's why he must be killed,
along with Akhnaton.
You hold Egypt
in your hand, my brother.
The power
of a god is yours...
...if only you have
the courage to seize it.
What's that?
What is it?
Horemheb has began
his holy war.
Every follower of pharaoh's god
has been marked for death.
- A massacre!
- Why should we care?
Let Horemheb prepare
the ground for us.
When my brother is dead,
and we rule...
...we'll be better off
without these fanatics.
Let them go!
Merit! Merit!
Master! Master!
- Where's your mother?
- We were separated.
Kaptah listen,
get the boy down to the docks.
Here, take this money
and these jewels.
Find a boat. Buy one.
Steal it if you have to!
And you?
I'll find Merit.
We'll come to you when we can.
But don't wait for us.
- Get the boy out of the city!
- Yes.
I want to go with you.
No. You must go
with Kaptah, my son.
Now hurry.
Hurry!
Stop them!
Is this yours?
I never saw it
before in my life.
You're lying!
I saw you throw it away!
Be sensible, captain.
Do I look like a follower
of the accursed Aton?
They're simple people,
honest people.
I am the biggest rogue
in all Egypt.
Is this your cross?
Captain, you have an honest
and intelligent face.
I always collaborate with the soldiers.
I a was soldier myself.
In fact, I gave my eye
for my country.
- Well if that's all...
- Kill him!
Kill me for a thousand crimes...
...but not for one
I never committed!
I hate the gods!
And the gods hate me.
Oh, take everything then.
Take that, jewelry, silver...
...everything I have.
You've made a beggar out of me.
I will starve to death
for as long as I live.
Let him go!
Come on!
What can you pay?
Give me your jewels!
Go aboard! Only those
who can pay can go aboard!
Give me your jewels!
Give me your gold!
Only those who can pay
can go aboard!
Come on, step up!
Kaptah, how can we pay?
You gave those soldiers everything.
Not quite everything.
Savings of a dishonest lifetime.
Come on! Come on!
- Please! Please!
- What can you pay?
Take this ruby.
The child won't take up much room.
All right, let him go.
Only those who can pay
can go aboard!
- Come along!
- There, sit here.
Well...
...I fear that at my age,
and all innocence...
...I'm becoming a father.
Thoth!
Kneel!
Aim! Shoot!
Merit!
Sinuhe!
No!
Merit! Merit!
Thoth?
He's with Kaptah.
With Kaptah he'll be safe.
Hold me, my love!
Merit!
Take the ones that are still alive
to the dungeon!
I want this temple torn down,
every stone of it!
- Yes, commander!
- Archers, follow me.
I'm sorry, my friend.
It had to be done.
It wasn't you that killed her,
but that madman in the palace.
He and his One God.
She believed in his god,
and she's dead.
- Is he still alive?
- Yes, he's at the palace.
Then go to the palace
and I'll meet you there before dawn.
How will you give it to him?
In a cup of wine...
- ...when you and I drink with him.
- I?
We're bound together
in this business, Horemheb.
As we we've always been bound,
since we were boys together.
Since what we do
is for the good of Egypt...
...you should be honored
to have a direct part in it.
Go and make sure he is awake.
Arrange for our audience.
Don't worry.
What's needed, will be in pharaoh's cup.
You finally came to your senses.
Why did you leave me there
in the street?
Where did you go?
To bury a dream.
It's dead now and forgotten.
For pharaoh...
...for Horemheb...
For me.
What do you mean?
Horemheb's no fool.
How can I persuade him to drink,
unless I drink as well?
- But you'll die!
- I'm a physician.
This oil will smother
the poison...
...until I can come back here
and swallow this emetic.
And if something goes wrong?
Then I'll die in any case.
Be careful my brother.
I'll be waiting for you.
Let's not pretend, my sister,
that our bargain...
...is for anything but power.
Perhaps you can't be blamed
for the evil in you.
It's not your fault
that you were warped and twisted...
...like a tree forced to flower forever,
and never bear fruit.
What you are,
you were made to be by others...
...but I made
the evil in myself...
...and I know it for evil.
You must go.
Sinuhe, open the door.
Sinuhe!
Why did you bar the door?
I couldn't be sure
that it would be you who came.
Is everything ready?
He's in the great hall
praying to his One God.
Which cup is his?
The one he will take.
Well, welcome, my friends.
We come to you as friends, Sire,
for we both love you.
I know.
We were just speaking of the time
the three of us first met on the desert.
Yes, it was at sunrise.
I hoped that day would be
a sunrise for the world.
But you killed a lion,
his blood spilled out on the sand.
Violence must be met
with violence.
Drink, Sire.
To our memories.
Does Sinuhe invite me to drink?
Yes.
Have I drunk... death, Sinuhe?
Yes, Sire.
So be it.
The fault is mine.
You gave me what I asked for,
but I was wrong to ask it.
I was weak.
I thought my god
had forsaken me...
...but he hadn't, Sinuhe.
Nor have you killed him,
as you believe.
Horemheb seeks to kill him
by tearing down his temples...
...but the house of god
is all creation.
Tear down the mountains,
empty the seas...
...strip the sky of stars...
...and still
you haven't touched god.
I see it clearly now.
I thought God
was the face of the Sun...
...and thus I made his image.
But God is more.
Much more.
The sun is just a symbol
of his warmth...
...of his creative power.
He is no idol,
no tangible thing...
...but the creator of all things.
The loving spirit
that lives in all our hearts.
I'm fortunate beyond other men...
...that he permitted me
to recognize him.
Stay close to me, Sinuhe friend.
I cannot see you well...
...but there is no pain.
I gave you no pain, Sire.
Nor does my death matter.
I was no more than a shadow
of things to come.
One voice that spoke for him.
But there will be other voices...
...clearer than mine.
For the hearts of men
will not be denied forever.
God is in us all...
...and one day...
...in his own good time,
he will speak out...
...in words that
cannot be misunderstood.
The others lied to me, Sinuhe...
...but I think
you really loved me.
God forgives everything, Sinuhe.
He forgives you.
Poor soul...
...he was mad to the end.
I will make sacrifice
to the gods on his behalf.
They won't refuse me now...
...for I am one of them.
I am Egypt!
Your cup, Sinuhe!
Drink with me.
Drink to the beginning
of a new Egypt!
Horemheb...
...don't drink it...
...or you won't be Egypt...
...or anything.
You dared!
Put on the crown
and go to the princess.
She will be greatly surprised,
for it isn't you she expects.
But you can prevail,
and make yourself divine.
You really dared!
You're the pharaoh
that Egypt wants.
But that isn't
why I spared you.
Don't thank me for your life.
Thank this poor sick fool here.
For it was he
who saved us both.
Saved me?
Are you mad too?
I am pharaoh!
Silence!
Pharaoh comes!
On your faces!
On your faces
before the Living God!
Sire!
The commanders
of the defeated armies...
...beg mercy of pharaoh.
I will deal with them later.
Let the physician come forward!
- On your knees!
- Let him stand!
What are the charges
against this man?
He has publicly spoken
against pharaoh.
He has belittled pharaoh's victories
in Syria and the land of the Hittites.
He has blasphemed
against the gods...
...and committed other acts
of treason, without number.
Once we stood together
before this throne...
...and you spoke up for my life.
Is there anyone here
who will speak up for this man?
You, my devoted wife?
No.
You will have to speak
for yourself, physician.
Not for myself, Sire...
...but for one whose memory
you've tried to wipe out.
Whose very name
you've sought to destroy.
For Akhenaten!
Do you flaunt
your treason in my face?
That name is forbidden!
Take care, physician...
- ...or I will...
- Will? Will? What you will?
You will go to war,
and win a battle?
You will conquer, and not know
that it is defeat?
You will raise Egypt to glory,
and watch her die?
We live in the twilight
of our world, Horemheb...
...and you will be it's sunset.
Nations rise, only to fall.
Kings build mighty monuments
only to have them crumble into dust.
Glory flees like a shadow.
All these things have
the seeds of death in them.
Only a thought can live.
Only a great truth
can grow and flourish...
...and a truth can not be killed.
It passes in secret,
from one man's heart to another.
It is given in a mother's milk
to her child.
Are you trying to tell me
that you'll fight against me?
Oh, you will win that too.
For if you fail to silence me,
you know what I'll do.
What will you do, physician?
I will go among the people...
...and try to answer the questions
that burden their hearts.
The questions that I've asked
myself all my life...
...wherever I wondered
in the world...
...and which were answered for me...
...by a dying man.
I will wear
the clothes of a slave...
...and kick the sandals
from my feet...
...and speak to the wives...
...as they fry their fish
before their mud huts by the river.
To the porters on the docks...
...to the smiths by their bellows...
...to the slaves
under their yokes...
...and I will say:
"A man cannot be judged
by the color of his skin...
...by his clothes,
his jewels, or his triumphs...
...but only by his heart.
A good man is better
than a bad man.
Justice is better than injustice.
He who uses mercy is superior
to him who uses violence...
...though the latter
call himself pharaoh...
...and make himself
Master of the Earth.
We have but one master.
The God who made us all.
Only his truth is immortal...
...and in his truth,
all men are equal.
No man is alone."
The sentence:
exile for life!
I have spent my life
in seeking knowledge.
This is all I know.
I have written this
for you, my son...
...wherever you are...
...and for your children,
and your children's children.
It's a poor legacy...
...but it's all I have.