This film is freely based on
memories of Uschi Obermaier.
In Paris that summer, the students wrote
"Power to the Imagination" on the walls.
In San Francisco,
they danced in the streets
and fought for what had become
their way of life.
And I was at home in Sendling,
a suburb of Munich.
I felt I was dying,
slow and never-ending.
The only thing that kept
me alive was the music.
Without that, I would have died.
Or worse,
I would have turned into my parents.
But music alone
wouldn't get me out of Sendling.
That much was clear to me.
What I needed was a man.
The wilder, the better.
My God, Uschi...
Hey, I stole a record from Steffen.
From London.
Have you girls lost your minds?
It's too loud!
Uschi, turn off that awful music!
Quiet in there!
Hey!
I work for a big magazine, "Twen."
Can I take some pictures of you?
Sure.
What's the matter?
What are these photographs?
How could you?
Why? They're cool.
I'm going to be a photo model.
What?
A photo model?
Are you crazy? That's not a job!
And then what?
What do you mean?
I'll be a model. Then I'll be famous.
You want to be famous?
Nonsense.
You think you're better
than everybody else? Well, you're not.
What's going on?
What has she done now?
Look at her. She looks like a slut.
Shut up!
She's your daughter.
Uschi, I want you to become respectable.
Do you understand?
want you to be a lady.
All this is good for nothing!
Carry on like this
and you'll be a nothing!
Now take off those clothes!
Are you crazy or what?
Does this look like a brothel?
Now clean this pigsty!
What will the neighbors think
when they see what I've raised?
Now clean up your damn junk!
Uschi...
What are you doing?
What are doing?
Where are you going, Uschi?
In California
they walk around nude.
Here they get upset
if you even smile. Look!
Typical.
Sabine, look.
Where are you going?
We don't care.
- Hello.
Where are you headed?
Commune 1, Berlin.
Are you musicians?
Everyone's a musician.
Really?
There's a musician inside all of us.
It's not about being able
to play scales correctly.
You see, everyone makes music.
Everyone is music.
Do you play music?
We're musicians.
We can't play scales,
we just live in the moment.
Yeah? We play music, too,
but we can play scales.
We've even made a recording.
We're "The Third Ear."
Here, try it.
- Hurry up, we're in the East!
- Hold on!
Ever tried this before?
Hair tonic?
You wait for the perfume
to evaporate and chug it.
- And that works?
- It'll blow your mind!
Hurry up! Don't talk.
- Damn, the police! Let's go!
- Let's get out of here!
Get rid of the hair tonic!
- You drive!
- Hurry up!
Get in!
Wake up.
- Don't forget your guitar.
- I'll get it later.
We'll leave the instruments in the van.
How do I look?
Good.
This is a stupid idea, Rainer, really.
This is nudism.
Stop complaining.
Nothing but nudism.
To be subversive,
you have to come up with something else.
Commune 1
polarized public opinion in Germany.
There'd never been anything like it.
Come in.
It was founded with the
intention of abolishing security,
property and the concept of privacy.
The communards rejected the work ethic
and preached fun and free love.
Here you could do as you pleased,
as long as it was done collectively.
This isn't about being subversive.
- Why so critical, Günther?
- I'm not critical, I'm decisive.
Mr. Langhans, you turned the courtroom
into a real circus.
Why such contempt for German justice?
No walls, no doors...
I could never live here. You?
I could.
The German system of justice
is the justice of the Third Reich,
and this trial has revealed that
in a big way.
What's your stance on the use of napalm
against the Viet Cong?
- What's yours?
- I have my opinion, and you?
Then why don't you
write it down and print it?
Mr. Langhans... do you plan to overthrow
West Germany?
We support a cultural revolution,
but we oppose all forms
of aggressive resistance.
We'll play our song
until the system sings along.
And dances along. Write that down.
We're fighting for the
eroticization of life, aren't we?
Does everyone sleep with
everyone around here?
We are standing on
the brink of a new age.
The old will be replaced by the new.
You've got to be blind not to see it.
Without a doubt.
And... what will this new age look like?
I'm not exactly sure,
but clearly it has long hair.
He means me.
Welcome. I'm Rainer.
Uschi.
I'm Sabine. Hi.
Nice of you to make it.
I saw you on the cover of "Twen."
What's it like being a musician?
It's such a responsibility.
Every string you pluck,
every chord you play...
You travel through a tiny universe,
a microcosm...
of a soundscape, with highs, lows...
Tape's running.
Nice rattles.
Nice hair.
I wish I were a musician.
Everyone's a musician.
Are you sure?
Yes.
What should I tell them at work?
Yes, breathe... breathe...
Slower...
No, more like this, please.
And now with more feeling, okay?
Yes.
That feels good. That's intense, yes.
Now slower. Slow. Slower.
Yes, circular movements.
Is she your girlfriend?
I don't own her.
Well, were you ever a couple?
For us there are no couples anymore,
only human beings.
What do you think about that?
Me? About couples?
I wouldn't mind having a boyfriend.
And you?
I think that we have to
change ourselves first...
before society can change.
If we don't change our own lives,
society won't change either.
Well, I have no idea about politics.
Uschi, we... us... free love, right?
I always felt something like that.
She felt something!
How revolutionary!
Aren't there any rooms here
where we can be alone?
That's how it all starts!
How will anything reach the outside
if we always keep the doors shut?
Are you afraid to
go without make-up?
Why are you such a square?
As a woman, you should help overthrow
the patriarchal system.
You're just jealous,
you old wallflower.
Just because Rainer digs you,
you think you're hot shit.
But that model crap
doesn't count here. Not at all.
Why are you here anyway?
For the experience.
I want to take part
in a peaceful renewal.
How did this
imperialist whore's piss get here?
What, you don't like Coke?
I should've known!
The model! No, I don't like Coke.
We have to help her understand
the mechanisms of exploitation.
Coca Cola is a
multinational company.
You're turning into
a capitalist stooge.
You know what? I say we exclude Uschi
from our discussions.
Her lying around is distracting us all.
As decoration,
at least she could sit upright.
Uschi belongs to our commune
like everyone else.
Exactly. Besides, yesterday I put
3 marks into the cash box.
We thank our patroness
with the political mind of an amoeba.
Don't let them get to you.
Any idea who the publisher
of this magazine is? Axel Springer!
Yeah, "Give Springer a real stinger."
I say we launch a real operation.
We should plant rhetorical bombs,
instead of sitting around talking.
I think that can be done.
What do you mean?
If you're serious about bombs,
I have connections.
The long-haired ones,
whose appearance is a provocation...
What were you thinking,
bringing that spring chick in here?
Günther, it's spring chicken. Chicken.
A little more precision, please.
Conrad, I think that deep down,
you are actually a little girl
who wants to be put to bed by Mommy.
With a doll.
But you don't have that here.
So you have to accept
that if it's dark, it's dark.
It's quite clear.
Try it out and you'll see.
Everyone's part of
the communal collective...
Damn it! It's not your fault.
Look at Günther. What do you notice?
Günther is anti-orgasmic.
That's his problem.
Okay, so this is the bomb.
And this is the timer.
It creates an electrical circuit,
and sets a detonator.
Then you have one hour to get away.
This is fucked up!
I only meant a metaphorical bomb!
Kajol! You're back!
Nice to see you again.
How was Hamburg?
Good.
No way. I don't believe it...
Hello.
Stop it. There's no point.
Leave me alone.
You've seen all there is to see.
Uschi! Don't shed your tears
for your lover!
Uschi! Out there you will find another...
Rainer!
Your woman is trying to overcome
her petty bourgeois conditioning.
I'd say she's failing miserably.
Uschi, what is it?
Stop it! You're hurting me!
That's a conditioned reaction,
not real feelings.
Look at it as a task I'm giving you,
for you to improve yourself.
Is that the extent of what you feel?
Come on. Don't mind her. Carry on.
Open the door! This is the police!
- Let's go, men!
- The cops!
Police! Don't move!
Do not resist
or we will use our guns!
Get up! Get dressed!
Everyone!
I'm not resisting.
Rise and shine!
- Let go of me.
- I'm not resisting.
If we all stay calm,
nothing will happen.
I'm not resisting.
Hold on, I'll get a bladder infection
if I don't get dressed.
- Let's go!
- Come on! Move it!
Stop!
Justice?! This is justice?!
You preach peaceful protest!
Why do you build bombs?
That was just a game.
Rainer, you see that?
Move it out!
POLICE DISCOVER BOMB
IN COMMUNE 1
ENOUGH TO DESTROY
A WHOLE BUILDING
WAS THE COMMUNE PLANNING
A BOMBING?
COMMUNARDS REMAIN IN CUSTODY
MODEL USCHI OBERMAIER RELEASED
Ho! Ho! Ho Chi Minh!
A thousand-year stench
lingers on the judges' bench!
Cut your hair!
Get a job! Go home, rich kids!
Look beyond the tips of your noses!
Go on over to the East, then!
A thousand-year stench
lingers on the judges' bench...
THE FEDS PLANTED THE BOMB!
COMMUNARDS DENY ALI L
KNOWLEDGE OF BOMB
Mr. Langhans!
Police line...
March! March!
What now?
This is only the beginning!
The state now knows...
They're afraid,
and they're showing it,
through these actions... naturally...
Keep moving!
Nazis! Nazis! Nazis!
Piss off!
The press conference has begun.
Hand me the "Stern."
Let me see that...
Ah! I should've known.
Even on the "Spiegel" cover.
You see, Rainer?
Our Under-Maier!
Bullshit. Look at this!
It's all Uschi. Typical!
The sex-crazed press!
Our agenda goes to the dogs.
No, to the chicks.
'Verbal precision.'Right, Rainer?
On the contrary!
We have to use this.
Yeah, right, let's do more of the same.
They won't be able to ignore us...
'Sex sells.'
That's bullshit, Rainer!
'Sex sells! 'What a load of crap!
Everywhere you look is
Under-Maier, but no content!
Hey, the Stones wrote us back!
Did they really invite us to London?
What is this all about?
Want to go back?
I'll be right out.
And? How was it? What's Mick like?
Must we discuss this now?
This won't get us anywhere.
I don't want to get anywhere.
I just want to have fun.
But all your screwing
merely satisfies your animal instincts.
I love my animal instincts.
Psychologically speaking,
your relationship to men
is a case of ideal sublimation
of childhood rejection
by an unreliable and egotistical father.
If you keep this up...
Sex is death. Clearly, it is.
Are you crazy? You don't even know
what it means to let yourself go
and to be aware of your partner
and enjoy them... like rock music.
Look at yourself!
What do you see? What's Uschi?
Nothing but a lust machine.
Press here beep, lust. That's it.
- Know what your problem is?
- What?
You're scared of fucking.
Now that's ugly. What a stupid argument.
Listen, Uschi! True freedom
can only come from abstention.
Fine, then I'll abstain from you.
Come on, Uschi. Let's talk.
Let go! I don't want to talk to you!
Then come on, hit me.
Come on, Uschi.
You really make me sick.
What you just said is nonsense, Rainer.
Conrad just hasn't found himself yet.
The problem is simply that
he never cleans the toilet,
and I hate that. Otherwise he's all right.
I don't believe it,
it's the Under-Maier!
I thought we'd gotten rid of you!
Hello.
Where've you been for so long?
I'm just picking up my things.
This isn't for me.
All this talk,
these endless discussions.
Who gave you the necklace?
That chain?
It's from Keith.
Uschi, let's go somewhere else.
You and me.
Rainer, it's pointless.
Don't you get it?
How nice! Mommy and Daddy
want to start a family!
I thought this was
a serious experiment,
not a matchmaking institute.
I've realized that there are many ways
to reach one's goal.
You all have a lot to learn.
You all have a long way to go.
That much is clear.
You've capitulated, Rainer.
You've simply capitulated.
Flown the white flag, Rainer.
That photo model, there...
Don't give me that look!
You've fucked him stupid!
We could've achieved something,
Rainer Langhans!
But you betrayed the revolution!
For that woman
I would've betrayed any revolution.
Each and every one.
You! Go to hell, Rainer Langhans!
Intellectuals shouldn't fight!
Stop it! Stop it, damn it!
Rainer Langhans!
OBERMAIER LEAVES
BERLIN'S COMMUNE 1
RADICAL MODEL
MOVES BACK TO MUNICH
THIS IS HOW
THE COMMUNARDS LIVED!
Okay, move, move...
Yes, look at that tummy.
Uschi, yes!
Check the exposure.
Eight.
Could you perhaps...
turn toward me a bit?
No, a little more shy, perhaps.
Like this?
Pretend that you're really
embarrassed by something...
Finished?
Who is that?
Bockhorn and Lurchi.
They're touring across Africa.
Two real freaks.
I just develop their film.
What are they doing there?
I don't know.
Traveling, exploring, going on adventures.
Bockhorn views his life as
nothing but an endless trip.
He's the King of St. Pauli.
He runs the hippest bar
and stages happenings.
He does what he wants.
Should I send him a photo of you?
No, thanks.
But you can send him by in person.
Oh, Lurchi! Look!
Look how cute!
What do you think of her?
Who's that?
Obermaier from Munich.
Uschi Obermaier.
Not bad, eh?
MUNICH 1973
Mick who?
Jagger.
He's coming here?
Keith is coming over, too.
Oh, my God!
Uschi!
You always borrow my things!
They're right here.
- Where's my top?
- Here it is.
- My hair!
- What?
I look like hell!
Uschi? Uschi? Hey, listen!
My name's Bockhorn.
I'm on my way back to Hamburg!
I'm in Africa now! Can you hear me?
The connection's really bad!
I'm throwing a midsummer's night party,
in your honor!
I've sent you plane tickets,
they should be arriving by mail.
Hello? Uschi?
How'd it go?
It worked. I got her on the phone.
How are you?
Hello.
Hi!
The watch is a metaphor
for a life running out of time.
Lurchi!
Hold Cheetah, will you?
Okay, people! The party's over.
Yes, ciao, ciao!
We'll have another one tomorrow,
but for today, it's over.
Come on! Out!
See you tomorrow, dear.
Yeah, see you then. That's it, Angel.
Ciao, ciao.
I'm Bockhorn.
So you're Bockhorn. I sure am curious.
So am I.
You've been to all those places?
Yeah, all of them.
And where will you go with me?
To the end of the world, if you want.
You don't even know me.
I know our destiny.
Will you shuffle?
You do it.
That's you.
I knew it. You're a witch.
That's me.
And this is us together.
And this is our future.
Travels...
riches...
children...
You can forget about that.
Now the last, most important card.
So what does that mean?
You know.
'Til death do us part.
You're kinda spooking me.
Kalle! A little more respect for Charlie!
Come on!
That way.
Make room for the King of St. Pauli.
And the new Queen.
Uschi, darling, have a seat.
Lurchi, let's get this started.
By the way, Uschi...
That gentleman there, the slugger,
he's our heavyweight boxer.
You're the hottest piece of ass
I've ever met.
I say that with all due respect
and humility in the face of beauty.
Really, Uschi, you're simply
the hottest broad in all of Germany,
if I may say so.
Respect, Bockhorn, a real...
Get your hands off me!
Hey, pimp! Leave the slugger alone,
he still has to fight!
Charlie, Charlie, Charlie...
Let's drink to Charlie!
To Charlie!
Listen, Angel,
you have a hot body and a sweet ass,
but I'm no pimp.
- Come on!
- I'm an artist.
What do you want with that bimbo?
She won't earn you one cent!
I'll let the whole gang screw me,
and you can watch.
Stop that before I get horny.
And no one wants to see that.
Yes, everyone does.
No, Angel. Knock it off.
Lurchi!
That old lady is going to make me happy.
Yeah? You think so?
Angel! Come here!
Don't call me Angel. I'm no Angel!
Fine, then come here, Witch!
No, you come here.
Slap some sense into her!
Alright, Lurchi. I'll take care of it.
He should put his old lady in her place!
Come on, you and I need to talk!
Uschi, this just won't do!
You're right about that.
If they see that you're out of line,
it won't help anybody at all!
Should I do what you want
so they think you're the greatest?
Bockhorn...
Forget it!
Cheetah! Go!
You stupid little ape!
Okay Obermaier,
time to change Cheetah's diapers.
Change them yourself!
Lazy bitch!
A fine mess I'm in!
Come here, Cheetah-baby!
Yes, yes... it's alright, Cheetah.
If you don't start developing
some motherly instincts...
I'm throwing you out.
If you want motherly instincts,
run to your mommy in Stuttgart.
He didn't, did he?
Look what your damned monkey did!
Hey, Cheetah!
I know, you were here first, right?
That evil woman
wants to come between us!
What are you doing?
Going to the airport.
Why?
My agent is waiting.
What agent?
My agent.
I forgot I've a meeting with Ponti.
I hear Ponti's drawn up the contract.
- You'll work with Jack Nicholson. -Really?
He's made them all famous.
Brigitte Bardot, Lollobrigida,
Claudia Cardinale...
- Hello?
He saw your film, "The Red Sun."
Yes, I'll send them in.
Mr. Ponti will see you now.
Finally! Beautiful! Miss Obermaier,
welcome to Rome.
Mamma mia, you are beautiful!
So beautiful.
Did you get to see Rome?
You like it?
Are they all like this in Germany?
I saw your film, "The Red Sun."
You're a natural actor.
What? Ten years?
I'm hosting dinner
with many important people tonight.
Antonioni will be there.
There's no way. Ten years, Alma, that's...
Ten years... I don't know.
Aren't you happy?
Let me see your laughter!
Antonioni's next film.
We'll work together.
See you tonight!
But Bockhorn and I wanted to...
What's going on?
You sure haven't made much progress.
What have you been doing all this time?
We took out the radiator.
I can see that.
What's your problem?
Uschi!
Bockhorn's busy right now.
Oh, Uschi! There you are. Look, Angel...
Go have a smoke,
then come back and knock.
what did you say?
Get out! Now!
Let her finish!
What's the monkey doing here?
The monkey stays. He's watching.
This just isn't worth it.
Get out!
Angel, I'll call you.
I mean,
you could've really learned something.
I simply don't understand you.
I build you a luxury bus...
- Luxury bus?!
- Yeah, luxury bus.
Show me the luxury here!
All you do is complain.
Any idea how much all this shit cost?
I don't care how much it cost!
Bockhorn, I'm not staying.
This just isn't my thing.
All these whores, sluts and players!
Do you think I want to rot here?
You promised to show me the world.
And what do I get?
I'll be gone soon enough.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
What's that mean?
Keith is taking me on tour.
If you do that...
Then what?
Is that all you can do?
Listen, Lurchi, get her back!
Drag her back inside the café!
Move your ass and get her back.
The monkey is gone!
Should I run after her?
Do something! Go out and get her!
Now?
Run out there and bring her inside!
Think of something, dammit!
I'm going out to get her now, okay?
Uschi! Uschi, wait!
Come with me, please!
Bockhorn said I can't let you go!
He'll kill me. Wait! Please!
No thanks, Dieter.
For me, this is pure medicine.
It gives me positive energy.
Dammit!
It's all Uschi's fault. She wears me out.
I've no energy left. I did all I could.
I got rid of the monkey...
For six months
I tried to turn her around.
I tied her to the bed,
I whipped her, raped her,
dragged her throughout the apartment.
Nothing.
I don't know what to do.
And I don't know what she wants.
No idea what she wants.
She's a cannibal, an evil witch.
She'll eat you alive.
But you know what, Rainer?
I love her. I love her!
Man, I've never loved a woman
like I love her.
But Dieter,
what do you love about Uschi?
I mean, what does she have
that makes you say, let's go forward?
I'm the one whose will...
That's the real essence of it, isn't it?
Everything. I love everything about her.
Where is Uschi now?
With the Stones, I think. Dammit!
Come with me, Rainer.
I want to show you something.
Know what those are?
Those are our scalps.
Only shock therapy can help.
How do you plan to shock her?
You have the world's greatest man,
you're a star yourself,
everyone envies you...
So? What if I want something else?
I want to see the world, be free,
not do the same old things.
Concert, limousine. Concert, limousine.
It's so boring!
You know what?
I think I miss Bockhorn.
Bockhorn? No way!
We were just talking about you.
How'd you get my number?
The bus is ready. I wanted to say bye.
What? But I wanted to come along!
I'm leaving without you.
Go jump in a lake!
But... hello? Hello!
What is it?
He's leaving without me.
- What are you going to do?
- I'm going to the airport.
Yea, yeah, I'm coming.
Hey guys, what do you want?
What? I don't have the money!
It's time you paid up!
You can't just leave me alone with them!
I'm going with you.
Do you have everything?
- My bag.
- I got it.
Café Adler doesn't exist anymore.
Every week another dead body
got carried out of there.
Bockhorn has huge debts.
They want the bus,
and everyone's looking for him.
We're heading out tomorrow.
Bockhorn and I are leaving.
He's taking me along. To India.
Oh, it's you.
Where did you come from?
Is Bockhorn here?
No, he's gone. He left already.
What?
Yeah, he's gone.
He really left without me?
Yeah. I'm sorry.
Hey, Lurch!
Lurchi, can you do me a favor?
Whiskey's no good for polishing.
I need the Polylux...
I must say I am happy to see you.
Wow...
Amazing...
I never thought it'd be this beautiful.
Voilà!
Unbelievable!
How beautiful!
- Just for you, Witch.
- A radio!
All for you.
Amazing. Really, you...
I don't know what to say.
Now you see what your
good-for-nothing man can do.
You're so beautiful.
What's going on around here?
They're all just jealous, the fools.
They want my money.
And the bus. But they won't get it.
They won't get us.
Stay in touch!
USCHI OBERMAIER AND THE PRINCE
What's that you're tearing up?
My contract with Ponti.
Not another road toll...
Get rid of it, Uschi!
Obermaier! Obermaier,
throw the dope away!
No way. It would be truly barbaric
to get rid of it.
Lot of good it'll do you
when you're rotting in jail.
And I know that this is
the worst border in the world.
Then we'll just put it in here.
Yeah, chill out.
Yeah, no worries. Just keep cool.
Hey, get your grimy fingers off of me!
I said,
get your grimy fingers off of me, okay?
Uschi, bring me the photo!
You're the best old lady ever! The best!
Unbelievable!
Bockhorn, this here is paradise.
Don't dream your life, live your dream.
USCHI OBERMAIER AND THE PRINCE
CONQUER THE WORLD
LIVING THE DREAM OF A GENERATION
INDIA, 1975
Uschi, come here, quick!
He wants to show us something!
You won't believe this!
That's the goddess Kali.
She looks just like you,
except that I still have my head.
Eh, Witch? King of St. Pauli!
I don't want to get married!
Why not? What is it?
What if they find out?
Find out what?
That you're no Prince,
and I'm no Princess.
But we are. Just look at us! We are!
Brass band... the works!
It's only symbolic!
A performance. Come on.
You're completely stoned!
Bockhorn sweet-talked
the Maharani into giving us
a full fairy-tale wedding.
But I realized that for him,
it was more than just a performance.
And though I loved Bockhorn
more than anything,
I never wanted to belong to
one man alone.
Look, it's Uschi!
Hey, kids! I have more in the bus.
I'll get more if...
I'm going to be a father! A father!
Bockhorn?
Bockhorn!
Why did you lock me in?
What is it? What happened?
Because you're my wife,
and we're having a baby!
That doesn't make me your prisoner!
It was to protect you!
Bockhorn?
Bockhorn...
It's alright. It's alright now.
You can be proud of yourself.
You did that like a nomad.
We'll make a new one, okay?
We won't have another child.
I'm not a mother.
Sleep.
Let's get out of here.
Off we go.
Hello? Can I ask you a few questions?
Miss Obermaier, would you answer
a few questions? Please!
We'd lost our child.
I felt fear for the first time.
Bockhorn always said to
look your fear in the eye
and the fear will disappear.
And so we drove on.
To the end of the world.
Following the endless summer.
Lurchi, go see if there's enough firewood,
and if everyone has enough to drink.
What a long trip it's been, eh, Witch?
But it's not over yet.
We'll do something new,
something different.
Yeah, something new and different.
Really different. No more strife.
I always thought I had to be
stronger than you.
But that's impossible.
You're the strongest old lady ever.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing. It's all good.
I'm going back down to the beach.
You coming?
Bockhorn, come here! Look who's here!
Bockhorn, Keith. Keith, Bockhorn.
He just happened to be here.
Oh, yeah? You don't really believe that?
You know what? You can have
whoever you want. You do anyway.
Bockhorn, that's not what this is about.
Lurchi, you old dumbass! Tommi, you stupid...
Stop, you're hurting yourself!
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Lurchi, give me the knife.
You're going to slit its throat?
No need for that.
You don't even know how.
- You're not riding with me...
- Why not?
You ride with the others. Get off!
I want to ride with you,
not with the others!
Come on! Please!
Viva Zapata!
Have you see Bockhorn?
He left that way on the motorcycle.
No! No! No! No! No!
Leave me alone!
In the course of a single night,
I lost the two most important men
in my life.
The freedom I'd always
dreamed about and lived,
suddenly seemed like a curse.
Suddenly it had turned into loneliness.
I could feel that he still loved me.
I thanked him for everything he gave me
during the life we shared.
I told him that I could've
been a little nicer to him,
instead of being an egotistical monster.
I regretted not telling him
more often how much I loved him.
But now he was just lying there,
and it was too late.
I asked myself
if I could've done anything differently.
And my answer was...
no.
Today, Uschi Obermaier
is a successful jewelry designer
living in a small villa
in Topanga Canyon,
between Santa Monica and Malibu.