Move it! We're late!
I can't figure out what you do
and we're late every time
Hello Nikolo!
Hello Maestro!
What kind of angels did you
paint this time Maestro?
C'mon and have a drink with us!
Our treat!
Down! Down, you wench!
So, you were working all night?
I know this kind of "work".
Hello, highest of Crete!
To our health!
I can buy three paintings at this price!
You won't go?
Everyone in Crete will be there,
but you won't go?
Throw it away! I won't go!
Yes, you will go!
I can't leave you alone.
You will go to the dance.
Nikolos will be with you.
He will have his eyes open.
Da Rimi is up to something.
Listen to your father.
Remember why we came here.
I do, but do you?
This time we won...
...but we lost many
Next time...who knows.
For the dead!
May they fare well!
He must leave. You will go with him.
From here on...
you will be his guardian.
Play!
He's in a dark mood again
Like the sky in this town: Black
Because life takes you where she wants
your job is to paint
That's what your father says,
and that's what I say too.
What are you doing here?
I escaped from Crete, and I'm looking
for my older brother.
My ship sails at dawn
What's new? Father?
What?
Da Rimi set us up.
At a wedding.
They poisoned the wine.
Everyone's dead.
It's not finished yet.
You have to sign it.
Dominikos Theotokopoulos
The Cretan temperament.
Lord, come to me, please
He is here, for me!
The Lord comes in the middle of the night...
...and your lights will be out,
foulish virgins.
He's our Lord...
and he is beautiful...
In our days, everyone thinks
he can talk to God
Finally, they won't be
needing us anymore
What kind of farce is this?
She is not well, that's obvious,
but she is not a witch.
You are still yound.
That's understandable.
But be careful Guevara.
People in high places
watch your every move.
Don't let them down.
He is here now.
He is everywhere.
Why don't you see him?
Why can't you see him?
What will happen to her?
Well, she...
...will be your first decision.
Beauty!
Is there art without beauty?
I don't like him.
- Are you going for a confession;
- Excuse me, I don't want to be late.
- Have you commited many sins?
- I haven't done anything bad!
Not yet.
But the biggest sin is
to obstruck his work
He doesn't belong to you.
He belongs to God.
You play with fire
senorita De Las Cuevas
- How dare you!
- Listen to me!
He pretends to know everything.
He needs someone to guide him.
And it cannot be you.
He needs to believe in something.
He believes in life!
In life!
Are you the Lord...
...that comes in the middle of the night?
Yes.
ꇎ.
We are waiting for your verdict.
To the Pyre!
Nino De Guevara
...welcome, Grand Inquisitor.
- What did you see?
- Nothing.
I shall see her.
Again.
My hand is asleep dad.
You have to help me.
The Inquisition arrested my husband,
the baker Karkadil
He is Greek,
he doesn't speak Spanish
Sweetheart!
Talk to me, talk to me!
Why don't you talk to me?
Why don't you ever talk to me?