subtitles by pranavhs
Why do you go
among the people, Majesty?
I tell you plainly,
you will be murdered.
Every Catholic in England
is a potential assassin!
Be warned
by the atrocities in France.
We know the Catholics
take their orders from Spain.
The Spanish speak
openly of Mary Stuart
as Queen of England
in waiting.
Their loyalty is to
the Pope in Rome!
How many Catholics
are there in England, sir?
Lmmense numbers,
Majesty.
Half the nation cling
to the old superstitions.
What would you have me do?
Hang half the people of England
or just imprison them?
We must act, Majesty.
Our inaction is perceived
as weakness.
If my people break the law,
they shall be punished.
Until that day,
they shall be protected.
Majesty, we have proven reason to fear
every Catholic in the...
Fear creates fear.
I am not ignorant
of the dangers, sir.
But I will not punish my people
for their beliefs.
Only for their deeds.
I am assured
that the people of England
love their Queen.
My constant endeavor
is to earn that love.
My Queen.
Our friends write
to give us hope.
Soon England's
true believers will rise up
against the bastard
usurper Elizabeth
and slit her throat.
That's enough!
Slit her throat? Please.
And when that bastard
usurper is dead,
my lady will be queen.
Your bishops are preaching
that God is showing
his displeasure
because the Queen
is still unmarried,
some rudely
suggesting infertile.
What nonsense.
Dangerous nonsense.
Mary Stuart has a son.
Why does everyone
torment me with Mary Stuart?
It's not her fault
she's next in line
to the throne.
Don't hide your face.
So long as you
have no issue.
If you were
to produce an heir,
there'd be no more talk
of Mary, Queen of Scots.
I've heard it's customary
to obtain a husband
before producing an heir.
We shall have to hunt
out a husband
for you soon, Bess.
Not too soon,
my lady.
There are husbands
to be had.
You don't want
to be married?
I'll want to be married
if I want the man...
Austria. France.
Turkey. Turkey has a sultan.
China has an emperor.
I confine myself
to the possible.
That's where you and I
differ, Walsingham.
I find the impossible
far more interesting.
What kind of man
would you want?
An honest man
with friendly eyes.
And good legs.
And sweet breath.
So you can kiss him
without choking.
There must be
any amount of princes
in the undiscovered lands
across the sea.
Find me an honest one
of those.
Since when do we discuss
private matters
in public spaces?
I ask Your Majesty's
forgiveness.
Have my doctors
confirm that the Queen
is still fertile.
The people need
to be reassured.
I care
for your safety.
The threats to your
person are real.
You know very well
if I fall,
you'll all come
tumbling down after me.
The sea wall at Dover
is cracking, Francis.
We have no money
to rebuild our defenses.
Turn your mind
to that threat.
May we have wisdom
not to fear shadows
in the night.
And courage when the day
of danger truly dawns.
My time has come,
Majesty.
Send me back to England
to begin God's work.
Your Majesty.
Guards!
Take hold of him!
A puddle in the way,
Majesty.
A puddle.
Puddle.
You'll have to see
the Lord Chamberlain, sir.
Which one is he?
He's over there.
You can't come in.
So how am I to see him
if you won't let me through?
You must wait for him
to come out.
And when will he
come out?
There's no way
of knowing that.
I had less trouble
than this boarding
a Spanish ship.
What if enemy ships
should sail up the Thames,
can the docks be closed?
Not closed, Majesty.
But the gun positions...
Spanish...
Ambassador.
King Eric of Sweden,
Majesty.
Not again.
Still madly in love with you.
Still mad, you mean.
Lvan, Tsar
of all the Russias.
Where's Bess?
Known as
"lvan the Terrible," Majesty.
Late.
I beg
Your Majesty's forgiveness.
Given.
Once.
The Archduke
Charles of Austria, Majesty.
The puddle man
is outside, Majesty.
My suitors.
Younger brother
to Maximilian II,
Holy Roman Emperor.
Cousin of Philip of Spain.
Wealthy.
He's rather handsome.
How old is he?
Young,
I believe, Majesty.
An Austrian alliance
would keep France quiet.
And put Philip on a leash.
I've become
almost enthusiastic.
Send for him.
Danke schön.
How much longer
do you think I can play
this game, Francis?
Virginity is an asset
that holds its value well.
Walter Raleigh, Majesty.
Your Majesty, this man
is a notorious pirate.
Spanish gold stolen
from Spanish ships,
attacked without provocation.
Well, sir, what do you want?
I have just returned
from the New World, Majesty.
I have claimed
the fertile coast
in your name
and called it Virginia
in honor
of our Virgin Queen.
Virginia?
And when I marry,
will you change
the name to Conjugia?
I ask your gracious
permission, Majesty,
to return to the New World
with your royal warrant
to found a colony
under the laws
and protections of England.
He wants money.
Who are they?
Natives of the
Americas, Majesty.
Have they no ruler
of their own?
None to match
England's Queen.
These gentlemen
are welcome.
See that they
are treated well.
I also come
bearing gifts
for Your Majesty.
These gifts, Majesty,
are the fruits of piracy,
the true property
of the realm of Spain.
Let's see, shall we?
What have you brought me?
Patata, Majesty.
You eat it.
Very nourishing.
Tobacco.
You breathe its smoke.
Very stimulating.
Gold.
Courtesy of a Spanish ship
that found itself unable
to complete its journey.
Forgive me, Majesty.
I find the air
has become stale.
I am sensitive
to the smell
of open sewers.
I cannot accept
the fruits of piracy,
Mr. Raleigh.
Philip of Spain is no friend
of England, Majesty.
The more gold I take from him,
the safer you will be.
Well, well.
A political pirate.
And Your Majesty's
most loyal subject.
Welcome home, Mr. Raleigh.
Lord Howard, the docks.
Master Raleigh.
You eat it...
You traitor!
Judas!
You're Walsingham's pawn!
Don't do this!
I didn't say anything!
You're a
Protestant traitor!
Don't do it! Don't!
Don't!
Hold his head!
You Judas! You Judas!
Stop!
You Judas!
The traitor's dead.
We must act!
Why do we not strike?
What are we waiting for?
You wait for my order.
Walsingham knows
too much already.
One traitor is dead.
Who can I trust now?
There's a visitor
waiting, sir.
William.
Hello, Francis.
You've always
been a fellow who
delighted in surprises.
You look well,
Francis.
Well, you look dreadful.
They're not feeding
you in Paris.
You can't learn
the secrets of the universe
on an empty stomach.
Then she my heart beguiled
Mary. William.
Supper is ready.
William.
Have you spoken
to the Queen?
I speak
with the Queen daily.
You work too hard.
You're a sick man.
William,
come over here
and sit by me.
William, if we are not
allowed to sin,
maybe we could
talk theology.
You have done enough.
No man could do more.
I can't leave
the court yet, Ursula.
She needs me.
Never listens to me.
Not a thought for his health.
So you talk to him,
he's your brother.
William, what do they say
in Paris about the Pope's
call for holy war?
Many welcome it.
Why must we talk
about war?
Tell us your nice
news, William.
Are you married yet?
Not yet.
Mary, would you leave
William alone, please?
Sweet, sit.
Grace?
Oh, Lord,
provider of all things,
we offer Thee
our humble thanks.
In the name
of the Holy Trinity, amen.
Amen.
More lines on my face.
Where do they come from?
Smile lines, my lady.
Smile lines?
When do I ever smile?
Now you have
smile lines, too.
The beauty of Your Majesty
is dazzling to my eyes.
I am overwhelmed.
I am conquered.
I die.
Only your love,
my stattlich Elizabeth,
can restore me into life.
Your Highness
does me great honor.
Oh, Elizabeth.
How blessed am I
to stand in your
fabled presence.
Ah, Elizabeth.
To speak your name
is to hear celestial music.
May that sweet sound
guide me through my life
to come, Elizabeth.
I have traveled here
to this illustrious court
in the hope that
our two great nations
might be
joined in love.
He interests me.
Talk to him.
Him, my lady?
Him.
I adore the natives
you brought. I don't suppose
you could get one for me.
They're not
dangerous, are they?
That depends
on what you propose
to do with them.
I'd dress him up
in mulberry
colored silk,
and have him walk
behind me,
carrying my cloak.
I have a secret,
my dear.
I pretend there's
a pane of glass,
eine Glasscheibe
between me and them.
They can see me,
but they cannot touch me.
You should try it.
Majesty, I am...
It is something,
after all,
to take a blank on the map
and build there
a shining city.
Which you will no doubt
name after yourself.
No doubt.
May I ask
a question in return?
Of course.
How am I to win
the Queen's favor?
Why should I tell you that?
I've little enough to offer,
but whatever I have to give,
ask, and it's yours.
Say what you mean to say
as plainly as possible.
All men flatter the Queen
in hope of advancement.
Pay her the compliment
of truth.
I don't even know
your name.
Elizabeth Throckmorton.
A second
Elizabeth?
Everyone calls me Bess.
Your most serene Majesty,
bright star of our firmament,
we present our humble masque
of the heavenly spheres.
His Highness is tired
after his long journey.
No man
can become tired
in the presence of
so lovely a queen.
His Highness, the Archduke
informs me that my charms
overwhelm him.
He will retire
to his private chambers
to rest.
I don't want him hurt
by your schemes.
So how should
we proceed?
Perhaps we should
all retire.
I suspect him of being
a professional charmer.
Am I right?
He is certainly
charming, my lady.
Well, there are
duller professions.
You like him, don't you?
He's a man
that lives in a world
far beyond the court.
It's refreshing.
Well.
We shall let him
come again.
Blue.
Can you imagine
what it is to cross an ocean?
For weeks, you see nothing
but the horizon,
perfect and empty.
You live in the grip of fear.
Fear of storms.
Fear of sickness on board.
Fear of the immensity.
So you must drive
that fear down deep
into your belly.
Study your charts.
Watch your compass.
Pray for a fair wind.
And hope,
pure,
naked,
fragile
hope.
Majesty, the Archduke
and court are waiting.
Let them wait.
Go on, Mr. Raleigh.
You were hoping.
At first,
it's no more than
a haze on the horizon.
So you watch.
You watch.
Then it's a smudge,
a shadow on the far water.
For a day.
For another day.
The stain slowly spreads
along the horizon taking form,
until on the third day,
you let yourself believe.
You dare to whisper
the word.
Land.
Life.
Resurrection.
The true adventure.
Coming out of
the vast unknown,
out of the immensity,
into new life.
That,
Your Majesty,
is the New World.
I like
your immensities.
Your ocean is an image
of eternity, I think.
Such great spaces
make us small.
Do we discover
the New World,
Mr. Raleigh,
or does the New World
discover us?
You speak like
a true explorer.
I like you,
Mr. Raleigh.
And I like you.
You know, of course,
that when I like a man,
I reward him.
I have heard that.
And what have you
to say about it?
Reward my mission,
Majesty, not me.
Is the mission
not the man?
Then you leave me free
to like you in return.
Go on.
I think it must be hard
for so great a queen
to know the simple pleasure
of being liked for herself.
Now you grow dull.
Come on!
Mine.
You have
the stronger horse.
Yours carries
the lighter load.
No.
The Queen does not
give way to others.
Whoa! Whoa!
Forgive me, Majesty.
My horse doesn't seem
to know his place yet.
Have you ever
known your place,
Mr. Raleigh?
Oh, come on!
It's from her.
Mary Stuart
is the heart and soul
of our enterprise.
Make sure she
and only she reads this.
We wait for her order.
The order
must be given clearly.
The jailer, madam.
My noble jailer.
Am I a danger to England
even when I pray?
As always, ma'am,
my concern
is for your safety.
I pray for
my cousin Elizabeth.
Do you think
she prays for me?
Is it true
that I've never known
the pleasure of being
liked for myself?
I hope you believe
I like you for yourself,
my lady.
Is anyone ever liked
simply for themselves?
I doubt it.
Are you?
Men like you
because you're pretty,
and because you have
the ear of the Queen.
No doubt.
Him, too.
He likes you because
he wants my favor.
You do realize that.
Yes, my lady.
And the other thing,
too, of course.
But then,
all men want that.
Male desire
confers no distinction.
Oh, I envy you, Bess.
You're free to have
what I cannot have.
You're my adventurer.
Thank you for coming.
You mustn't send
letters to the palace.
You know
what would happen
if I was caught.
I need your help.
More money?
No.
My father doesn't
want to hide
like this anymore.
Of course.
We both want to get
back into favor
with the court.
That's impossible.
You know that
you're Papists.
Why impossible?
Everyone at court
has a Papist somewhere
in their family.
Francis.
Just as you have.
Speak to the Queen.
You are her favorite.
My father and I
will embrace the new faith.
Cousin Bess.
No.
We have known
each other
all our lives.
I would do nothing
to harm you.
Why can't you help us?
They will kill us!
Oh. Do not tease me,
Mr. Raleigh.
There's nothing
I'd like to do more.
So why don't you?
All right, then. I will.
You see? You lie.
You don't want me
on your ship at all.
You're a liar.
Bess. Would you
like to go to sea?
I'm afraid
that's not possible.
Women bring bad luck
on board ship.
Do they?
Lock up a hundred men
in a space smaller
than this room
for months at a time.
Men have needs.
A beautiful woman
would drive us all mad.
Men have needs?
Let them stay on land
and see to their needs.
Mr. Raleigh
is eager to sail away
to his maiden colony.
We must persuade him
to stay a little longer.
Mustn't we, ladies?
Bess?
No!
Wait! What do you want?
Who are you?
Let me go, damn it!
Who the hell are you?
If you won't assist me,
perhaps your father will.
No.
Enough.
Yes?
You cannot
save England now.
The Enterprise
has begun.
Ambassador?
What do you know
of the Enterprise
of England?
The Enterprise?
Forgive me, Majesty,
I'm not familiar...
Two armies landing
on the coasts
of Sussex and Norfolk.
Mary Stuart is to be
set free and placed
on the English throne,
and I am to be
assassinated.
Does any of this
sound familiar?
I know nothing
of any invasion plans...
Well, I refer to
this plan as the
Enterprise of England,
it should more
accurately be called
la Empresa de Inglaterra
because it is
a Spanish plan.
The plan of my
one-time brother-in-law,
your king,
to attack my country.
Your country?
It is my country
that is under attack.
Your so-called piratas,
your pirates attack
our merchant ships daily.
And you...
You think we don't know
where the orders come from?
The whole world knows
these pirates sail up
the Thames,
all the way
to your royal bed.
You will leave
my presence, sir.
Go back to your rat hole.
Tell Philip I fear
neither him, nor his priests,
nor his armies.
Tell him if he wants to shake
his little fist at us,
we're ready to give him
such a bite,
he'll wish he'd kept his hands
in his pockets.
You see a leaf fall
and you think you know
which way the wind blows.
Well, there is
a wind coming, madam,
that will sweep away
your pride.
I, too, can command
the wind, sir!
I have a hurricane in me
that will strip Spain bare
if you dare to try me!
What are you staring at?
Lower your eyes.
I am the Queen!
You are not my equal, sir,
and you never will be!
The alignments of the planets
is most unusual this year.
Mars is due to take
the ascendant
three days
after the anniversary
of Your Majesty's birth.
And also on that day,
there is a full moon,
which governs
the fortune of all princes
of the female gender.
Princes of the
female gender.
I mean to say,
a prince who is
also a woman.
Yes, Dr. Dee,
I am following you.
What does it mean?
It means the rise
of a great empire, Majesty,
and the fall of another.
Convulsions.
Which empire is to rise
and which is to fall?
That I cannot say,
Majesty.
Astrology is,
as yet, more an art
than a science.
Nothing more, Dr. Dee?
No more specific calamities
we can guard against?
He means,
will I be assassinated?
Walsingham, would you
leave us for a moment?
And the private life
of this prince
of the female gender,
what do the stars
foretell there?
These are matters
of state, Majesty.
Surely the stars
foretell matters
of state, Dr. Dee.
For such a prediction
I must look
in a different chart.
Wonderful.
Such strength.
You will need
all your strength
in the days to come.
But you doubt yourself,
my child.
I have not seen
fear in your face
for such a long time.
Have I reason to fear?
Something has
weakened you.
There are
hard days coming.
But I am no prophet.
I see no more
than the shadows
of ghosts.
Visitor, sir.
Sorry to come
aboard your ship
without permission,
Mr. Raleigh.
Welcome aboard.
The Queen wishes
to see you.
She asks me
to assure you...
I need
no assurances, Bess.
I'm no courtier.
Never have been.
Then you should
say so in person.
This is
my life, Bess.
This is where
I belong.
It seems to be
a lonely life.
Sometimes.
But it's the life
I've chosen.
I understand.
You ask permission to go.
Yes, Majesty.
You plan to return
to your colony
for two, maybe three,
four years.
If Your Majesty grants me
your royal warrant.
That is a long time.
There's nothing
for me here.
At sea,
I know what I'm to do.
I know the risks.
Here...
No. You're wrong.
You're needed here.
As captain of my
personal guard.
Captain of your guard?
Kneel.
Majesty.
I said, kneel.
Sir Walter Raleigh.
Well, you may express
your gratitude.
This is too great an honor.
If it's so great an honor,
why are you staring
at your boots?
You know why.
Now you stare
at the wall.
Am I so hideous
you can't even look
me in the face?
Why do you speak
like a fool
when you are anything
but a fool?
Fool?
Yes, I am a vain
and foolish woman.
And you, you...
You come here
as if from another time.
And I've...
You have real adventures.
You go where the maps end.
And I'd...
I would follow you there
if I could. Believe me.
The storm clouds
are gathering.
You are needed here.
You cannot leave England.
"For he that will
save his life
will lose it.
"And he that will
lose his life for my sake
shall find it. "
Lord be with us
as the end approaches.
We will not fear the coming
of the shadow of death.
Sorry, I didn't mean
to disturb you.
I thought I prayed
in silence.
You did.
Excuse me, sir.
I must go to the Queen.
The man who was
hanged today...
He was your cousin.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
The last time
I saw him,
he needed my help.
I did nothing.
What could
you have done?
I don't know.
Now he's dead.
I keep seeing his face.
I keep seeing his eyes.
Believe me, there's nothing
that you could have done
that would have spared him.
I'm so afraid.
We're all human, Bess.
We do what we can.
Your laundress
was found to be carrying
letters in her washing.
Not her job, I think.
How am I to send
my intimate letters?
Through me.
And you will read them.
With respectful
admiration.
Am I to have
no privacy?
No.
You disappoint me, sir.
The Queen orders
these measures
for your protection.
The Queen?
I am a queen.
They call her
the Virgin Queen.
Why is that, sir?
Can it be that no man
will have her?
Let him
throw you round.
Be bold. Come on,
you can trust him.
And jump.
When I bend like this,
you take a leap
into the air.
The Volta.
I require all my ladies
to learn it.
You see
how fearless Bess is?
You like your ladies
to jump at your command.
Do you think
that wrong?
No. You are the Queen.
You are to be obeyed.
To tell you
the truth,
I'm very, very tired
of always being
in control.
Nonsense.
What?
You eat and
drink control.
Is that so?
Bess.
You should try a dance
with Sir Walter.
He's eager
to show us his skill.
No skill at all, Majesty.
I don't know the steps.
Come now.
You stand
like this,
with your hands here.
And when she jumps,
on the fifth step,
you lift her.
What could be simpler?
Take your position,
Sir Walter.
I am to be obeyed.
As Your Majesty
wishes.
Hold her firmly.
I don't want her dropped.
Play.
Six counts.
One, two, three,
and lift, down.
Leave us.
I want both of them
left alone.
Madam.
I must reply.
"If our forces
are in readiness,
"both within and without
the realm,
"then your Queen commands you
to set the gentlemen to work."
I think we have it.
Yes.
Let God's
work begin.
Where have you been?
I met up
with some old friends.
From Paris, no doubt.
We haven't
seen you for days.
Yes.
Now you're back.
Do you know,
I can still remember
the day you were born.
I was 11 years old.
And you,
this helpless bundle.
I looked at you
in your crib,
with your little,
wrinkled face,
and I loved you
from the first.
I've failed you,
haven't I?
Forgive me
if I haven't
loved you enough.
Did you imagine
I wouldn't know?
Your blessing,
Majesty. My little one.
Your blessing?
Walk on.
The Queen is at her prayers.
Go!
Elizabeth is a whore!
Mary Stuart is our
true queen!
Elizabeth!
Whore!
You bring news?
The Queen
has been attacked.
The assassin seized.
The Queen
unharmed.
Unharmed?
And you, ma'am,
are to be tried
for treason.
Me?
What has any of this
to do with me?
That's the trouble
with intrigues, isn't it?
With so many secrets,
you can never quite be sure
who's on whose side
till the game ends.
Walsingham has every
letter you've written.
Traitor.
Traitors!
Ready to die,
I see, Jesuit.
I have done what
I was sent to do.
Why was the gun
not loaded?
I need your help.
I, too,
have failed, brother.
What was the Jesuit
sent to do?
I told you everything I know.
So kill me.
There's a better world
waiting for me.
We'll all be judged
in the end, brother.
Even you.
William, you're
not a martyr.
You weren't even
much of a murderer.
I'm going to have you
taken to France.
No one will know.
You must never let me
hear of you again.
Francis.
Francis!
I've never seen her
so distressed.
She's been alone
in her room since morning.
She'll see no one.
Has she asked for me?
No.
But she needs you.
I know she does.
Go to her.
Please.
Are you here
to tell me I must
murder a queen?
I would
never presume to tell
my Queen what to do.
Only you know
where your duty lies.
Was it my father's duty
to murder my mother?
She was a queen
for a time.
Oh, I would be
loath to die
so bloody a death.
Since when were you
so afraid?
I'm always afraid.
Kill a queen,
and all queens are mortal.
We mortals have
many weaknesses.
We feel too much.
Hurt too much.
All too soon we die.
But we do have
the chance of love.
Do we?
I have given
England my life.
Must she also
have my soul?
Mary Stuart must die!
Must? Mary Stuart must die?
Where is it written?
Who says so?
Have I ordered it?
Majesty, this is
no time for mercy.
Don't preach at me,
old man!
Look at you.
You can hardly stand.
Go home to your wife
and your bed.
The law must
have its way.
By whose authority
do you condemn me?
God is my only judge.
The law
is for common men.
Not for princes.
The law, Your Majesty,
is for the protection
of your people.
Leave me.
Your Majesty.
You know
neither who you are
or what you do.
I know who I am.
And if I die,
it shall be
as I have lived.
As a queen,
trusting in the mercy
of God, my Father.
At which hour?
At 8:00.
Tomorrow morning.
It must be stopped!
I want it stopped!
I forgive you
with all my heart.
Forgive me, Majesty.
I have failed you.
How have you failed me?
What am I
to forgive you for?
Philip of Spain
is a God-fearing man
who cannot declare war
without a just cause.
I intercepted
every letter Mary Stuart
secretly dispatched,
but failed to see that Spain
knew I was reading them.
They waited for her
to write the words
that would, in my eyes,
confirm her treason.
Forgive me.
I am trapped
in my own web.
And I ordered
Mary's execution.
I murdered God's
anointed Queen.
And now God's most dutiful son
makes holy war to punish me.
We are at war.
Who knows when
we will meet again?
If we will meet again.
If England falls,
my last days will be
in a Spanish prison.
To die far from home.
That is the
loneliest death.
Never.
My thoughts
turn dark.
What do you do
in a storm
when you're facing
your death?
The closer
I come to death,
the more
I want to live,
the hungrier
I am for life.
Yes. To live
right to the end.
Why be afraid
of tomorrow when today
is all we have?
I wish...
I have never known
a woman like you.
In some other world,
in some other time,
could you have
loved me?
I know only
one world.
And in this world,
I have loved you.
There's something
you could do for me,
something I
have not known
for a very long time.
If you felt
so inclined.
But it's not to be
spoken of afterward.
It must be forgotten.
But just for now...
A kiss?
I die.
I've given
Drake the orders
to prepare the fleet
to defend the Channel.
How soon can you
join him?
We're waiting for supplies.
We can move as soon
as we're ready and armed.
Good.
Bess.
I have something
to tell you.
I ask for nothing.
Is that understood?
Your life is your own.
Nothing will change.
What is this?
I am...
You're with child.
No one knows.
My plans are made.
I shall ask the Queen
for permission
to leave court.
Where will you go?
To my
mother's house.
I'm a ward of the Queen.
I can't court a man
without her permission.
I can't marry
As for having a child,
your child...
All I know
is nothing's as it should be.
Please, listen.
You once said to me,
"Whatever I have to give,
ask and it's yours."
Do you remember?
Of course, I remember.
I ask that you
forget me.
Go to your ship.
Do your duty.
Forget me.
Bess!
We're summoned.
Coming.
This Spanish Armada
is at sea with an army
of 10,000 men?
And Philip's friend,
the Duke of Parma,
has 15,000 men
on the French coast.
They plan to cross
the Channel in barges
and sail into the Thames.
They don't have
enough barges yet.
We have a little time.
And our forces
defend the mouth of
the Thames at Tilbury with...
What? How...
Four thousand men?
Three thousand.
Possibly.
If the Spanish fleet
unites the barges,
their combined strength
will overwhelm us.
Then we shall
engage them at sea,
before they have
the chance to unite.
Your Majesty,
this vast Armada
will surely smash through
our naval defenses
and overrun
us on land.
We must prepare
for the worst.
I need air.
With this ring,
I thee wed.
With my body,
I thee worship.
And with all
my worldly goods,
I thee endow.
And with all
my worldly goods,
I thee endow.
In the name
of the Father
and of the Son,
and of the
Holy Ghost, amen.
Bess!
Bess Throckmorton!
Here, my lady.
Tell me,
is it true?
Are you with child?
Yes, my lady.
You traitress.
You dare to keep
secrets from me?
You ask my permission
before you rut!
Before you breed!
My bitches
wear my collars!
Do you hear me?
Majesty! Please,
dignity. Mercy.
This is no time
for mercy, Walsingham.
You go to your
traitor brother
and leave me
to my business.
Is it his?
Tell me. Say it.
Is the child his?
Is it his?
Yes.
My lady, it is
my husband's child.
You bitch!
Majesty.
This is not the Queen
I love and serve.
This man has seduced
a ward of the Queen.
And she has married
without royal consent.
These offenses
are punishable by law.
Arrest him!
Go!
You no longer have
the Queen's protection.
As you wish,
Majesty.
Get out.
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
The fall of an empire,
you told me.
Did you mean
the English empire?
Because, by God,
England will not fall
while I am Queen.
If that is
your prophecy, sir,
you prophesy again.
You want me to tell
Your Majesty
only what Your Majesty
chooses to hear.
I will not be a toy
of the fates!
Have I not faced
an assassin's bullet
and lived?
Just tell me
there's no certainty.
That any outcome
is possible.
The shadow of ghosts,
you said.
Please, just
give me hope.
The forces that shape
our world are greater
than all of us, Majesty.
How can I promise
that they'll conspire
in your favor,
even though
you are the Queen?
But this much
I know.
When the storm breaks,
each man acts in accordance
with his own nature.
Some are dumb
with terror.
Some flee. Some hide.
And some
spread their wings
like eagles and soar
on the wind.
You are a wise man,
Dr. Dee.
And you, madam,
are a very great lady.
Light the beacon!
My lords,
I can offer you
no words of comfort.
This Armada
that sails against us,
carries in its bowels
the Inquisition.
God forbid it succeeds,
for then there will be
no more liberty in England
of conscience or of thought.
We cannot be defeated.
The bells are to ring
from every tower.
Laborers are to
leave the fields,
and take up arms.
The harvest must wait.
All prisoners
are to be released.
England is their country, too.
And release Raleigh.
He is forgiven.
As I, too,
long to be forgiven.
Let the fleet know
we're on our way,
Mr. Calley!
Fire broadside
from the bow!
Run out the prime!
From the starboard bow,
number one gun!
On my mark!
Discharge! Two!
Three! Four!
Majesty, the enemy
has been engaged.
What news?
A brave action,
Your Majesty.
Two ships lost.
With what gain?
The enemy continue
to advance.
Tighten the buntlines
on the foresail!
Another four
ships lost.
We must continue
to engage and harass
the enemy.
We're outgunned,
Drake. Decisively.
We're losing too many ships.
We must fall back
and defend the coast.
If the wind
is with us, Walter,
we can attack them
with fire ships.
Six fire ships
into the Spanish formation,
that may force
them to scatter.
We can't get
anywhere near them.
We have to break
their formation.
That's our only chance.
The Spanish
are barely
a day away, Majesty.
We must withdraw
to safe ground.
I beg you to appreciate
the gravity of the situation.
There is very little time.
My loving people.
We see the sails
of the enemy approaching.
We hear the Spanish guns
over the water.
Soon now,
we will meet them
face to face.
I am resolved in the midst
and heat of the battle
to live or die
amongst you all!
While we stand together,
no invader shall pass.
Let them come
with the armies of hell!
They will not pass!
And when this day
of battle is ended,
we meet again in heaven
or on the field of victory.
Thomas! Get up!
Get up, man! Get up!
Help me!
Somebody, help me!
They've dropped anchor.
These Spanish monsters
can't handle
our English seas.
We have the wind
in our favor.
Do we go?
We go.
Godspeed, my friend.
Walter?
Don't forget to jump.
Calley!
Enough tar!
Clear the deck!
If that cannon's primed,
set the fuse!
Get everybody
off the ship, now!
Get off the ship!
Off the ship!
Go!
Get over there!
Come on, boys!
Get going!
The Spanish
continue to advance.
Just five of their ships
are burning.
Not enough.
Amen.
Francis?
I have served Your Majesty
in all things.
I know it.
You won't need me anymore.
You rest here,
old friend.
Elizabeth has a son.
You must be proud.
Very.
And fulfilled.
As any man can be.
Do you still dream
of your shining city
in the New World?
Always.
I'd like to give
your son my blessing.
I'd be honored.
I am called
the Virgin Queen.
Unmarried,
I have no master.
Childless,
I am mother to my people.
God give me strength
to bear this mighty freedom.
I am your Queen.
I am myself.