1
00:01:41,940 --> 00:01:43,150
Mom!

2
00:01:43,150 --> 00:01:45,140
There's no more Cocoa Krispies

3
00:01:45,140 --> 00:01:45,870
Mom.

4
00:01:45,870 --> 00:01:47,600
M...well...

5
00:01:47,600 --> 00:01:49,800
What'll I eat for breakfast?

6
00:01:51,150 --> 00:01:52,630
Well, I didn't finish them.

7
00:01:52,630 --> 00:01:54,870
You didn't throw out the empty box.

8
00:01:54,870 --> 00:01:56,770
How was I to know?

9
00:01:56,980 --> 00:01:59,030
And hello, by the way!

10
00:01:59,030 --> 00:02:00,930
Hello, Mommy dearest!

11
00:02:01,680 --> 00:02:03,250
Did you work all night again?

12
00:02:03,250 --> 00:02:04,750
Yes.

13
00:02:04,750 --> 00:02:06,100
Either you're insane

14
00:02:06,100 --> 00:02:08,050
or you can't stand sleeping with Dad.

15
00:02:08,050 --> 00:02:10,040
I'm not insane.

16
00:02:10,450 --> 00:02:12,640
I have an article
to finish for tomorrow, that's all.

17
00:02:13,810 --> 00:02:15,380
The Cocoa Krispies are for Stephane.

18
00:02:15,380 --> 00:02:16,590
You could eat

19
00:02:16,590 --> 00:02:18,320
the organic stuff I buy you.

20
00:02:21,620 --> 00:02:23,640
What made me do it?

21
00:02:25,910 --> 00:02:27,870
Well, actually...

22
00:02:28,560 --> 00:02:31,760
It wasn't really a conscious decision.

23
00:02:32,850 --> 00:02:35,540
It's the other way around...

24
00:02:35,540 --> 00:02:37,300
I keep deciding I'm going to quit.

25
00:02:39,310 --> 00:02:41,110
But...

26
00:02:43,060 --> 00:02:45,150
It's like smoking.

27
00:02:46,420 --> 00:02:48,390
It's hard to stop.

28
00:03:02,130 --> 00:03:05,290
1、2、3、4、5、6、7

29
00:03:07,190 --> 00:03:11,950
1、2、3、4、5、6、7

30
00:03:32,880 --> 00:03:37,650
So repetitive...

31
00:03:37,650 --> 00:03:40,750
So hard...

32
00:03:40,750 --> 00:03:42,810
and hostile.

33
00:04:00,560 --> 00:04:02,000
Stephane!

34
00:04:02,000 --> 00:04:04,880
I've told you
not to leave your shoes lying around!

35
00:04:04,880 --> 00:04:06,350
Stephane ?

36
00:04:08,980 --> 00:04:10,420
No, not first thing in the morning!

37
00:04:10,420 --> 00:04:12,210
I said not first thing in the morning!

38
00:04:12,210 --> 00:04:13,330
It's time to go to school.

39
00:04:13,330 --> 00:04:15,150
Hurry up.

40
00:04:15,150 --> 00:04:17,550
Give me a kiss.

41
00:04:17,550 --> 00:04:18,610
It's OK, we're not late.

42
00:04:18,610 --> 00:04:20,010
We are!

43
00:04:34,290 --> 00:04:35,660
What did the fridge do to you?

44
00:04:37,270 --> 00:04:40,060
I'm seeing what I need
for tonight's dinner party

45
00:04:40,240 --> 00:04:42,110
with your dear boss.

46
00:04:43,280 --> 00:04:44,650
- Good morning.
- Good morning.

47
00:04:45,490 --> 00:04:46,980
- Sleep well?
- Yes.

48
00:04:53,590 --> 00:04:55,050
Is Charles coming?

49
00:04:55,630 --> 00:04:57,300
Well?

50
00:04:57,870 --> 00:05:00,870
No, I specifically asked you to...

51
00:05:03,310 --> 00:05:04,650
- See ya.
- See ya.

52
00:05:05,140 --> 00:05:06,230
Bye, Mom.

53
00:05:07,600 --> 00:05:09,870
That's what we said, remember?

54
00:05:10,260 --> 00:05:11,830
Put your coat on.

55
00:05:11,830 --> 00:05:14,640
This is very important.

56
00:05:14,640 --> 00:05:15,830
If we don't do as I say,

57
00:05:15,830 --> 00:05:17,110
it won't work.

58
00:05:17,110 --> 00:05:18,470
Don't forget the wine.

59
00:05:18,830 --> 00:05:20,180
Pardon?

60
00:05:20,180 --> 00:05:22,000
Well, we...
- The wine!

61
00:05:22,000 --> 00:05:23,250
- I'll be there in 20 minutes.

62
00:05:23,250 --> 00:05:27,030
The wine for tonight.
Is...

63
00:05:27,030 --> 00:05:28,120
Hello?

64
00:05:31,380 --> 00:05:38,980
Elles

65
00:06:02,100 --> 00:06:04,790
You're listening to Classic Radio.>

66
00:07:00,400 --> 00:07:01,960
I can't...

67
00:07:04,850 --> 00:07:06,680
There's just no way.

68
00:07:19,790 --> 00:07:21,460
Nothing works.

69
00:07:34,870 --> 00:07:37,030
I brought you the latest issue.

70
00:07:37,200 --> 00:07:40,330
I did an interview on Tom Ford. Oh, sorry.

71
00:07:40,530 --> 00:07:41,680
I've already got it.

72
00:07:41,680 --> 00:07:43,650
OK, well, never mind.

73
00:07:43,790 --> 00:07:45,620
Mind if we go somewhere else?

74
00:07:45,620 --> 00:07:47,120
As you wish.

75
00:07:47,120 --> 00:07:48,380
Let's go over there.

76
00:07:56,690 --> 00:07:58,180
You have two phones?

77
00:07:58,930 --> 00:08:00,990
Yes, one for me, one for the clients.

78
00:08:26,710 --> 00:08:28,370
Can I call back to make an appointment?

79
00:08:28,370 --> 00:08:29,800
Go right ahead.

80
00:08:36,470 --> 00:08:37,400
Hello?

81
00:08:38,000 --> 00:08:39,260
Hi, this is Lola.

82
00:08:42,480 --> 00:08:44,010
You want to meet me?

83
00:08:45,750 --> 00:08:46,770
Um.

84
00:08:50,000 --> 00:08:52,200
You saw the photo?

85
00:08:53,300 --> 00:08:55,390
I have small breasts.

86
00:08:55,760 --> 00:08:56,790
Brunette.

87
00:09:00,790 --> 00:09:02,250
Yes, I do that.

88
00:09:03,380 --> 00:09:04,870
Without a condom.

89
00:09:06,740 --> 00:09:08,970
The usual escort rates, you know.

90
00:09:14,450 --> 00:09:16,650
See you tonight.

91
00:09:17,330 --> 00:09:18,390
You don't know him?

92
00:09:18,550 --> 00:09:19,310
You don't know him?

93
00:09:19,310 --> 00:09:20,080
No.

94
00:09:20,080 --> 00:09:21,430
but he sent me his photo on the net.

95
00:09:21,430 --> 00:09:22,950
He's not bad.

96
00:09:23,310 --> 00:09:25,340
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.

97
00:09:29,270 --> 00:09:31,150
What's without a condom?

98
00:09:31,150 --> 00:09:32,120
Fellatio.

99
00:09:35,410 --> 00:09:36,640
What is it?

100
00:09:37,110 --> 00:09:38,390
What?

101
00:09:38,390 --> 00:09:39,830
You're not afraid!

102
00:09:39,830 --> 00:09:41,140
No, I'm not.

103
00:09:41,140 --> 00:09:44,200
Most of the men just sleep
with their wives.

104
00:09:45,780 --> 00:09:48,410
It's almost more dangerous with Thomas.

105
00:09:53,300 --> 00:09:56,130
Thomas is your boyfriend, right?

106
00:09:56,880 --> 00:09:58,580
It's not too compllcated?

107
00:09:59,190 --> 00:10:01,280
You have to be organized.

108
00:10:02,260 --> 00:10:04,390
I'm very organized.

109
00:10:07,190 --> 00:10:08,470
I started when I reallzed

110
00:10:08,470 --> 00:10:09,940
if I worked nights.

111
00:10:09,940 --> 00:10:11,630
I'd never pass my exams

112
00:10:11,630 --> 00:10:12,980
What kind of job?

113
00:10:12,980 --> 00:10:15,440
Babysitting.

114
00:10:15,440 --> 00:10:17,240
And I worked in a fast food restaurant.

115
00:10:18,000 --> 00:10:19,600
It's horrible!

116
00:10:19,600 --> 00:10:22,300
Never again. It's exhausting.

117
00:10:22,670 --> 00:10:25,870
I still work there occasionally.

118
00:10:25,870 --> 00:10:27,830
It's a sort of cover,
but it's so horrible.

119
00:10:27,830 --> 00:10:29,020
cover?

120
00:10:29,490 --> 00:10:32,470
How could I explain to my parents

121
00:10:32,470 --> 00:10:34,990
- and my boyfriend the money?
- I see.

122
00:10:35,730 --> 00:10:37,820
It's like smoking.

123
00:10:39,060 --> 00:10:40,550
It's hard to stop.

124
00:10:41,040 --> 00:10:45,870
'Cause all of a sudden, I've got money.

125
00:10:45,870 --> 00:10:49,970
So, to go back
to the way life was before...

126
00:10:49,970 --> 00:10:53,800
with the crappy earnings you get
doing student jobs...

127
00:10:57,140 --> 00:10:59,730
And yet it's not...

128
00:11:00,340 --> 00:11:01,670
It's not easy.

129
00:11:02,670 --> 00:11:06,010
Well, it is
in that it doesn't take much time...

130
00:11:07,190 --> 00:11:09,980
and you get used to the money.

131
00:11:18,900 --> 00:11:20,750
Why do you buy this crap?

132
00:11:20,750 --> 00:11:22,810
You were less picky as a kid.

133
00:11:30,610 --> 00:11:32,370
Hello!

134
00:11:32,370 --> 00:11:33,360
Hello!

135
00:11:33,360 --> 00:11:34,920
So, Charlotte...

136
00:11:35,440 --> 00:11:37,330
how's life in Paris?

137
00:11:37,330 --> 00:11:38,800
It's OK.

138
00:11:38,800 --> 00:11:42,420
Your Mom told me
you're in a top school now.

139
00:11:42,420 --> 00:11:43,950
That's great...

140
00:11:43,950 --> 00:11:46,070
- Excuse me.
- I'm stuck.

141
00:11:46,070 --> 00:11:48,430
Come on, Snowy.

142
00:11:52,880 --> 00:11:55,210
Don't tell everyone things like that.

143
00:11:56,180 --> 00:11:58,700
I'm not in a top school yet.

144
00:12:14,640 --> 00:12:15,630
A clementine delight>

145
00:12:15,630 --> 00:12:19,440
is always what I recommend>
as a dessert...>

146
00:12:19,440 --> 00:12:20,880
No, thank you.

147
00:12:20,880 --> 00:12:22,190
Why aren't you eating?

148
00:12:22,190 --> 00:12:23,630
I'm not hungry.

149
00:12:23,630 --> 00:12:24,690
Isn't it good?

150
00:12:24,690 --> 00:12:25,880
Yes, it is.

151
00:12:35,090 --> 00:12:38,460
Put your slippers on.
You'd be more comfortable.

152
00:13:18,900 --> 00:13:20,160
Just a second!

153
00:13:25,300 --> 00:13:26,420
I'm Benoit, I'm the...

154
00:13:26,420 --> 00:13:30,550
I answered your ad on the net, you know...

155
00:13:30,550 --> 00:13:31,670
The other day...

156
00:13:34,130 --> 00:13:35,600
Goddammit!>

157
00:13:36,430 --> 00:13:38,400
Can I talk to you for a minute?

158
00:13:39,950 --> 00:13:41,230
Open the door.

159
00:13:41,230 --> 00:13:42,790
What do you want?

160
00:13:43,570 --> 00:13:46,100
I'm doing an article
on Paris students for "Elle".

161
00:13:46,100 --> 00:13:50,320
I wanted to hear your side of the story.

162
00:13:50,320 --> 00:13:51,470
Open the door.

163
00:13:51,470 --> 00:13:53,710
I'll pay whatever you like.

164
00:13:53,710 --> 00:13:55,790
I won't use your real name.

165
00:13:55,790 --> 00:13:58,190
I think it's a good deal for you.

166
00:14:10,740 --> 00:14:12,070
OK...

167
00:14:14,510 --> 00:14:18,920
Do you... do it just for the money?

168
00:14:21,590 --> 00:14:23,570
We need some vodka.

169
00:14:23,570 --> 00:14:26,370
I don't want any, I don't drink.

170
00:14:33,870 --> 00:14:34,930
Here you are.

171
00:14:35,600 --> 00:14:36,950
I don't drink.

172
00:14:36,950 --> 00:14:38,290
It'll do you good.

173
00:14:38,290 --> 00:14:39,880
I'm sorry, I don't drink.

174
00:14:41,170 --> 00:14:43,430
Shit, it disgusts her!

175
00:14:51,440 --> 00:14:52,560
Is this better?

176
00:14:52,560 --> 00:14:54,460
Thanks.

177
00:14:57,170 --> 00:14:58,730
No, drink it all.

178
00:14:59,570 --> 00:15:01,470
OK, down in one.

179
00:15:09,070 --> 00:15:10,710
You'll like it here.

180
00:15:10,710 --> 00:15:12,820
You'll see, the room is small,

181
00:15:12,820 --> 00:15:14,390
but very comfortable,

182
00:15:14,390 --> 00:15:16,910
very well-lit... I mean, it's bright...

183
00:15:16,910 --> 00:15:20,530
It's very quiet
and overlooks the courtyard.

184
00:15:20,530 --> 00:15:22,770
I don't need much cleaning done.

185
00:15:22,770 --> 00:15:25,740
I just need you to dust around the books.

186
00:15:37,490 --> 00:15:39,150
Can I see your breasts?

187
00:15:43,410 --> 00:15:44,600
Excuse me?

188
00:15:48,110 --> 00:15:51,240
You do realize
how much rooms cost in Paris...

189
00:16:24,340 --> 00:16:27,090
We can't find a room for you
just like that!

190
00:16:27,090 --> 00:16:28,750
There's a waiting list.

191
00:16:29,750 --> 00:16:31,040
What'll I do, then?

192
00:16:31,730 --> 00:16:33,290
I don't know anyone here.

193
00:16:33,680 --> 00:16:35,120
My suitcase was stolen.

194
00:16:35,120 --> 00:16:36,380
You must help me.

195
00:16:37,430 --> 00:16:39,060
Do you have a student card?

196
00:16:39,060 --> 00:16:41,220
I told you, it was in my case.

197
00:16:44,210 --> 00:16:45,700
Are you on a scholarship?

198
00:16:46,390 --> 00:16:47,910
I told you I'm not.

199
00:16:48,720 --> 00:16:50,260
I can't help you, then.

200
00:16:50,260 --> 00:16:52,950
Try the office for foreign students.

201
00:16:52,950 --> 00:16:54,280
But I just came from there.

202
00:16:54,830 --> 00:16:56,390
Try again.

203
00:16:58,740 --> 00:17:00,150
Is that it?

204
00:17:00,150 --> 00:17:01,270
That's it.

205
00:17:02,550 --> 00:17:03,480
Excuse me.

206
00:17:05,620 --> 00:17:06,810
Excuse me.

207
00:17:31,510 --> 00:17:33,100
Here's a phone card.

208
00:17:35,440 --> 00:17:37,770
It's cheaper for international calls.

209
00:17:38,420 --> 00:17:39,480
It's OK, thank you.

210
00:17:40,950 --> 00:17:43,440
Don't play the haughty princess,
I'm trying to help.

211
00:17:49,710 --> 00:17:52,180
Yes, Mom, the room's good,

212
00:17:52,180 --> 00:17:53,770
and the man's nice.

213
00:17:59,510 --> 00:18:01,740
I need you to add the goddam...

214
00:18:03,760 --> 00:18:05,560
roaming plan to my cellphone.

215
00:18:05,940 --> 00:18:08,340
So I can make international calls.

216
00:18:10,580 --> 00:18:12,020
I know you can't pay for everything,

217
00:18:12,020 --> 00:18:13,920
you're saving up...

218
00:18:17,070 --> 00:18:19,200
Yes, I am wearing warm clothes! Bye!

219
00:19:26,100 --> 00:19:28,220
This looks just like Poland.

220
00:19:29,010 --> 00:19:30,310
Villiers-Le-bel?

221
00:19:30,800 --> 00:19:32,180
You are really

222
00:19:32,180 --> 00:19:33,300
You are really

223
00:19:34,220 --> 00:19:35,760
really an asshole!

224
00:19:35,760 --> 00:19:36,960
really an asshole!

225
00:19:39,220 --> 00:19:41,710
Teach me an insult in Polish.

226
00:19:43,030 --> 00:19:44,020
Really?

227
00:19:44,020 --> 00:19:44,980
Yes, really.

228
00:19:49,200 --> 00:19:52,100
--No no, really

229
00:19:53,170 --> 00:19:57,870
really

230
00:19:57,870 --> 00:20:00,950
asshole!

231
00:20:00,950 --> 00:20:06,820
asshole!

232
00:20:07,090 --> 00:20:10,800
You are really an asshole!

233
00:20:10,800 --> 00:20:14,360
You are really an asshole!

234
00:20:16,050 --> 00:20:17,650
In Arabic.

235
00:20:17,650 --> 00:20:19,240
- Arabic?
- Yes.

236
00:20:20,530 --> 00:20:22,520
Say...

237
00:20:24,850 --> 00:20:26,770
I like you very much.

238
00:20:26,770 --> 00:20:28,750
I like you very muchا

239
00:20:28,750 --> 00:20:29,940
and you?

240
00:20:29,940 --> 00:20:31,540
and you?

241
00:20:31,540 --> 00:20:33,140
Do you love me?

242
00:20:33,140 --> 00:20:34,800
Do you love me?

243
00:20:34,800 --> 00:20:36,050
love me.

244
00:20:36,050 --> 00:20:37,140
love me

245
00:20:37,140 --> 00:20:38,350
Love me?

246
00:20:38,350 --> 00:20:40,220
Love me?

247
00:20:42,480 --> 00:20:43,860
Is that OK?

248
00:20:43,860 --> 00:20:46,220
- It's good.
- Good!

249
00:20:48,750 --> 00:20:50,240
Tell me...

250
00:20:51,570 --> 00:20:54,090
Are you doing all this to sleep with me?

251
00:20:54,160 --> 00:20:55,790
Yeah, sure.

252
00:20:59,570 --> 00:21:02,000
I bet all men want
to sleep with you, right?

253
00:21:03,670 --> 00:21:06,360
I only sleep with girls
who want to sleep with me.

254
00:21:23,030 --> 00:21:25,070
Do you have any Arab friends?

255
00:21:25,070 --> 00:21:26,010
No.

256
00:21:27,090 --> 00:21:30,080
But that's just how it is.
I'm not prejudiced.

257
00:21:39,380 --> 00:21:41,110
Typical French hypocrisy.

258
00:21:50,420 --> 00:21:51,940
Your shoes aren't bad.

259
00:21:52,910 --> 00:21:54,510
Are they expensive?

260
00:21:55,220 --> 00:21:56,480
Yes, very.

261
00:21:58,220 --> 00:22:01,630
What kind of man do you see?
What kind of clientele?

262
00:22:03,980 --> 00:22:05,650
Bored husbands.

263
00:22:06,480 --> 00:22:07,910
Are you happy?

264
00:22:14,100 --> 00:22:15,990
With my first client, we spent

265
00:22:15,990 --> 00:22:17,820
a lot of time in the kitchen.

266
00:22:20,720 --> 00:22:23,120
Because you cooked for him?

267
00:22:25,260 --> 00:22:26,320
Yes.

268
00:22:28,940 --> 00:22:32,440
He taught me to make
"coq au vin" with Riesling.

269
00:22:33,360 --> 00:22:34,520
OK...

270
00:22:36,880 --> 00:22:38,470
Was it good?

271
00:22:47,250 --> 00:22:48,510
I love you.

272
00:22:49,870 --> 00:22:51,130
No?

273
00:23:06,870 --> 00:23:07,920
You're mean.

274
00:23:09,010 --> 00:23:10,270
Mean!

275
00:23:10,640 --> 00:23:13,070
You're not nice to me.

276
00:23:14,060 --> 00:23:15,360
Right?

277
00:23:21,360 --> 00:23:22,890
Be nice.

278
00:23:23,660 --> 00:23:25,150
Be nice.

279
00:24:42,240 --> 00:24:46,050
It's a song>

280
00:24:46,050 --> 00:24:49,860
Which is just like us>

281
00:24:49,860 --> 00:24:53,640
You loved me>

282
00:24:53,640 --> 00:24:57,320
I loved you>

283
00:24:57,320 --> 00:25:01,060
We both lived>

284
00:25:01,060 --> 00:25:05,030
Together, you and me>

285
00:25:05,030 --> 00:25:08,740
You loved me>

286
00:25:08,740 --> 00:25:12,840
I loved you>

287
00:25:12,840 --> 00:25:20,230
But life separates>
Those who are in love>

288
00:25:20,230 --> 00:25:23,810
Ever so slowly>

289
00:25:23,810 --> 00:25:28,130
Without making a sound>

290
00:25:28,130 --> 00:25:35,750
And the sea erases>
On the sand>

291
00:25:35,750 --> 00:25:42,710
The footsteps of lovers>
Who are divided>

292
00:26:03,840 --> 00:26:05,730
I was really lucky.

293
00:26:05,730 --> 00:26:06,890
Lucky?

294
00:26:08,520 --> 00:26:11,820
After 1 month, I had a great apartment.

295
00:26:14,920 --> 00:26:17,910
Do men often ask you
to do things like that?

296
00:26:19,330 --> 00:26:20,770
Are you surprised?

297
00:26:22,600 --> 00:26:25,060
He couldn't do it with his wife.

298
00:26:25,060 --> 00:26:26,690
Typical!

299
00:26:34,440 --> 00:26:36,900
You don't find it humiliating?

300
00:26:38,210 --> 00:26:39,980
I don't.

301
00:26:44,000 --> 00:26:47,300
The way he looked at me
was actually exciting.

302
00:26:49,380 --> 00:26:51,410
Don't you like that?

303
00:26:53,920 --> 00:26:56,650
I don't think we're here to talk about me.

304
00:27:58,880 --> 00:28:00,320
Why did you phone me?

305
00:28:02,470 --> 00:28:04,940
We haven't spoken since Christmas.

306
00:28:10,050 --> 00:28:11,280
Really?

307
00:28:11,840 --> 00:28:13,370
When?

308
00:28:14,560 --> 00:28:16,120
In the hospital?

309
00:28:18,530 --> 00:28:21,200
I don't think I can go today.
I'm too busy.

310
00:28:26,370 --> 00:28:27,880
2 croissants?!

311
00:28:27,880 --> 00:28:29,540
He's diabetic.

312
00:28:40,480 --> 00:28:43,480
Gently...

313
00:28:56,710 --> 00:28:58,400
Faster.

314
00:29:03,110 --> 00:29:05,540
Stop.

315
00:29:14,820 --> 00:29:16,650
Faster.

316
00:29:27,240 --> 00:29:28,930
What's more...

317
00:29:31,460 --> 00:29:34,400
I feel like you can still smell it on me.

318
00:29:38,180 --> 00:29:41,170
I know, it... it must've been terrible.

319
00:29:42,050 --> 00:29:44,280
A terrible experience.

320
00:29:45,280 --> 00:29:46,750
You mean "that"?

321
00:29:48,230 --> 00:29:49,600
No, I...

322
00:29:49,600 --> 00:29:52,570
I'm talking about something worse
than a blow job.

323
00:29:53,190 --> 00:29:55,490
I'm sorry. What do you mean?

324
00:29:55,490 --> 00:29:57,020
You know what I mean.

325
00:29:57,920 --> 00:29:59,720
The smell of housing projects:

326
00:30:00,640 --> 00:30:02,050
I don't know, the...

327
00:30:02,050 --> 00:30:03,780
Acrylic sweaters...

328
00:30:05,090 --> 00:30:06,860
The cheap furniture...

329
00:30:08,770 --> 00:30:11,040
like everyone else,
but it makes no difference.

330
00:30:11,040 --> 00:30:13,340
You can read Flaubert or Proust

331
00:30:14,310 --> 00:30:16,870
I can see I'm not like you.

332
00:30:17,320 --> 00:30:19,650
I'm not...

333
00:30:22,400 --> 00:30:23,720
It's not against you.

334
00:30:23,720 --> 00:30:26,080
I don't take it badly.

335
00:30:31,720 --> 00:30:34,650
I wanted to go back to...

336
00:30:35,240 --> 00:30:36,970
to the first time...

337
00:30:37,380 --> 00:30:39,140
when you...

338
00:30:41,960 --> 00:30:47,010
You remembered the beauty spots on...

339
00:30:47,010 --> 00:30:48,880
on the man's stomach.

340
00:30:53,800 --> 00:30:57,860
When... I think back on it...

341
00:30:58,880 --> 00:31:00,720
I remember the beauty spots.

342
00:31:02,080 --> 00:31:07,280
They seemed so... so human...

343
00:31:07,910 --> 00:31:10,100
The first time must be difficult?

344
00:31:10,340 --> 00:31:12,810
I was stressed out.

345
00:31:13,570 --> 00:31:15,370
But it was so easy.

346
00:31:16,200 --> 00:31:17,930
I placed an ad.

347
00:31:18,720 --> 00:31:22,390
And in no time, I had 50 or 60 emails.

348
00:31:26,310 --> 00:31:30,240
Did you phone anyone to tell them
you were pleased?

349
00:31:30,240 --> 00:31:32,340
Could you share it with anyone?

350
00:31:32,710 --> 00:31:34,510
No, I didn't tell a soul.

351
00:31:38,050 --> 00:31:42,750
Doesn't that...
make you feel a bit lonely?

352
00:31:47,200 --> 00:31:49,040
No, not really...

353
00:31:53,600 --> 00:31:55,540
We're all alone, aren't we?

354
00:32:21,700 --> 00:32:24,640
of a... new generation.

355
00:32:26,150 --> 00:32:28,910
The obvious...

356
00:32:31,680 --> 00:32:33,450
consequences...

357
00:32:59,300 --> 00:33:00,460
Well?

358
00:33:01,350 --> 00:33:04,320
Yes, it's going well.

359
00:33:04,520 --> 00:33:06,350
I've written 10, 000 characters.

360
00:33:07,810 --> 00:33:09,840
We said 12, 000.

361
00:33:10,440 --> 00:33:11,770
8, 000?!

362
00:33:12,200 --> 00:33:14,470
No, listen... There are 2 girls.

363
00:33:14,470 --> 00:33:16,160
I think you'll love it.

364
00:33:16,290 --> 00:33:18,350
It's a great article. I've...

365
00:33:18,560 --> 00:33:19,910
If I cut it down to 8, 000,

366
00:33:19,910 --> 00:33:22,140
I don't know how long...

367
00:33:22,150 --> 00:33:25,640
We said 4 pages and a catchllne, so now...

368
00:33:26,560 --> 00:33:28,830
Tomorrow morning, as agreed.

369
00:33:29,600 --> 00:33:31,330
I know we have to go to press...

370
00:33:31,720 --> 00:33:33,800
OK, talk later.

371
00:33:33,800 --> 00:33:35,940
I know you're the boss.

372
00:33:35,940 --> 00:33:37,130
OK, bye for now.

373
00:33:39,590 --> 00:33:41,890
It's just straight sex.

374
00:33:42,690 --> 00:33:45,160
I do exactly the same with my boyfriend.

375
00:33:47,040 --> 00:33:49,670
But with the clients, I'm more in control.

376
00:33:52,260 --> 00:33:53,920
So, you decide everything?

377
00:33:53,920 --> 00:33:55,050
Yes.

378
00:33:56,770 --> 00:33:59,170
There are certain things I won't do.

379
00:33:59,170 --> 00:34:00,930
For example...

380
00:34:00,930 --> 00:34:02,060
sodomy.

381
00:34:02,630 --> 00:34:05,530
I don't feel like doing it with clients.

382
00:34:07,590 --> 00:34:09,920
They pay by the hour.

383
00:34:10,530 --> 00:34:12,590
When they arrive, they take a shower.

384
00:34:13,280 --> 00:34:15,380
That takes time. That's good.

385
00:34:15,910 --> 00:34:17,540
It's good they're clean.

386
00:34:18,150 --> 00:34:20,140
And...

387
00:34:21,480 --> 00:34:23,310
They like to say things, too.

388
00:34:25,280 --> 00:34:27,480
Do you like my big cock?

389
00:34:28,450 --> 00:34:30,550
You like this, little bitch?

390
00:34:32,230 --> 00:34:33,820
You think it's funny?

391
00:34:34,020 --> 00:34:35,610
Yeah!

392
00:34:38,370 --> 00:34:40,200
Does this make you wet?

393
00:34:40,770 --> 00:34:41,860
Me?

394
00:34:43,140 --> 00:34:45,480
It's what they say.

395
00:34:45,480 --> 00:34:47,030
Oh, OK! OK, sorry.

396
00:34:57,410 --> 00:35:00,070
Excuse me, which way is Room 216?

397
00:35:00,070 --> 00:35:02,160
- Straight ahead.
- OK, thanks.

398
00:35:27,720 --> 00:35:29,710
What do you want me to do?

399
00:35:32,520 --> 00:35:33,810
Whatever you like.

400
00:36:04,960 --> 00:36:06,330
Don't worry.

401
00:37:38,400 --> 00:37:40,000
It doesn't matter.

402
00:37:51,620 --> 00:37:53,140
Here...

403
00:38:21,480 --> 00:38:22,470
That's it.

404
00:38:22,470 --> 00:38:24,260
You're fine here.

405
00:38:24,260 --> 00:38:25,660
Oh, yes.

406
00:38:27,490 --> 00:38:30,920
It's nice and quiet.

407
00:38:30,920 --> 00:38:32,510
Yes, it's good.

408
00:38:36,610 --> 00:38:39,100
It's funny, the thing about getting old...

409
00:38:40,100 --> 00:38:44,400
Old people... I know I'm getting there.

410
00:38:46,660 --> 00:38:48,150
But...

411
00:38:50,370 --> 00:38:52,740
slowly...

412
00:38:55,400 --> 00:38:56,480
Know what I'd like?

413
00:38:56,480 --> 00:38:57,280
What?

414
00:38:57,280 --> 00:38:58,750
A foot massage.

415
00:38:58,950 --> 00:39:00,480
A foot massage?

416
00:39:00,480 --> 00:39:02,180
I was going to suggest it.

417
00:40:42,660 --> 00:40:44,920
Do you like him to touch your breasts?

418
00:40:59,110 --> 00:41:01,840
Do you prefer fellatio?

419
00:41:08,260 --> 00:41:11,560
Do you feel like you're dominating
or being dominated?

420
00:41:13,060 --> 00:41:15,120
What do you prefer? Being dominated?

421
00:41:26,630 --> 00:41:28,060
You won't answer?

422
00:41:33,440 --> 00:41:36,040
Do you have a feeling of power?

423
00:41:48,580 --> 00:41:50,570
I don't really understand.

424
00:42:00,450 --> 00:42:03,320
Often they go straight home afterwards.

425
00:42:07,010 --> 00:42:08,740
Actually, they talk.

426
00:42:10,080 --> 00:42:12,020
I didn't expect them to talk so much.

427
00:42:14,530 --> 00:42:16,070
The first time, I was scared.

428
00:42:16,070 --> 00:42:17,860
I thought...

429
00:42:18,720 --> 00:42:21,160
I was going to be screwed for hours!

430
00:42:24,130 --> 00:42:25,860
But in fact, no, they...

431
00:42:26,950 --> 00:42:28,970
They tell me about their lives.

432
00:42:30,560 --> 00:42:31,760
Their jobs.

433
00:42:33,030 --> 00:42:34,020
Their wives.

434
00:42:35,520 --> 00:42:36,820
I don't like that much.

435
00:42:40,260 --> 00:42:42,460
But mainly their work. Weird, huh?

436
00:42:43,430 --> 00:42:44,760
They love talking about that.

437
00:42:48,550 --> 00:42:51,610
I mean, I go to college, so...

438
00:42:55,620 --> 00:42:58,650
What are these men like?

439
00:43:00,900 --> 00:43:04,340
Do they have...a particular psychological profile?
Do they have problems?

440
00:43:05,000 --> 00:43:06,460
Not at all,

441
00:43:07,750 --> 00:43:09,180
they're... completely normal.

442
00:43:11,330 --> 00:43:13,390
It's not at all what people think.

443
00:43:14,560 --> 00:43:16,050
They're not losers!

444
00:43:17,190 --> 00:43:20,450
So, it's like... any other relationship?

445
00:43:23,620 --> 00:43:25,520
Well, not exactly...

446
00:43:27,720 --> 00:43:30,480
Most of them are old enough
to be my father.

447
00:43:56,040 --> 00:43:57,370
Shit!

448
00:50:00,130 --> 00:50:01,890
You didn't hear what I said.

449
00:50:11,590 --> 00:50:14,370
It must require a lot of organization.

450
00:50:14,370 --> 00:50:15,670
Yes, of course.

451
00:50:16,480 --> 00:50:19,210
I can't put it on my resume. Pity. Nope.

452
00:50:25,960 --> 00:50:29,410
How are your studies going? Your studies...

453
00:50:29,540 --> 00:50:31,370
My studies are going just fine.

454
00:50:32,870 --> 00:50:35,130
At the moment, I'm studying Mankiw.

455
00:50:37,860 --> 00:50:39,270
Mankiewicz?

456
00:50:39,270 --> 00:50:40,560
Mankiw!

457
00:50:47,010 --> 00:50:49,880
You have to chew
to get it to the other side.

458
00:50:50,400 --> 00:50:51,670
Like Mom!

459
00:50:53,920 --> 00:50:55,910
I have to...

460
00:50:58,370 --> 00:50:59,500
And so...

461
00:51:02,180 --> 00:51:04,520
Mankiw is a great economist.

462
00:51:04,520 --> 00:51:05,710
Heard of him?

463
00:51:07,430 --> 00:51:08,790
No.

464
00:51:23,270 --> 00:51:25,830
Do you think you'll tell your children?

465
00:51:26,560 --> 00:51:27,860
One day...

466
00:51:28,930 --> 00:51:30,060
You...

467
00:51:32,420 --> 00:51:34,500
What does that mean?

468
00:51:34,500 --> 00:51:35,430
Drunk.

469
00:51:42,240 --> 00:51:43,680
How about some music?

470
00:51:44,740 --> 00:51:47,430
Shit, she's spitting at me!

471
00:52:01,480 --> 00:52:02,820
What happened?

472
00:52:02,820 --> 00:52:03,970
- What?
- What happened?

473
00:52:03,970 --> 00:52:06,340
- Dunno.
- Me neither.

474
00:52:51,460 --> 00:52:53,020
See you soon.

475
00:53:13,030 --> 00:53:15,190
You're hurting me.

476
00:53:21,220 --> 00:53:22,370
Not now.

477
00:53:22,370 --> 00:53:23,460
Why not?

478
00:53:23,460 --> 00:53:24,950
Because.

479
00:53:29,190 --> 00:53:30,450
What?

480
00:54:02,400 --> 00:54:03,800
You seeing someone else?

481
00:54:06,180 --> 00:54:07,740
Don't be silly.

482
00:54:24,260 --> 00:54:25,570
Patrick, I can't reach you.

483
00:54:25,570 --> 00:54:27,000
Call me back.

484
00:54:27,430 --> 00:54:29,490
Florent hasn't been to school for 2 days.

485
00:54:47,460 --> 00:54:49,030
Patrick,

486
00:54:49,030 --> 00:54:50,210
why haven't you called back?

487
00:54:50,210 --> 00:54:51,460
It's about Florent.

488
00:54:51,460 --> 00:54:52,820
Call me back.

489
00:55:44,290 --> 00:55:45,380
Oh,

490
00:55:45,830 --> 00:55:47,320
it's you.

491
00:55:47,840 --> 00:55:50,020
I thought it was Florent.

492
00:55:50,020 --> 00:55:51,880
I don't know what he's up to.

493
00:55:53,440 --> 00:55:54,920
You told me to call

494
00:55:54,920 --> 00:55:57,940
if it happened again.

495
00:56:00,290 --> 00:56:02,620
Of course he's cutting class.

496
00:56:03,940 --> 00:56:05,300
Sorry. Hang on a sec.

497
00:56:12,070 --> 00:56:13,560
Sorry.

498
00:56:13,860 --> 00:56:15,450
OK.

499
00:56:19,710 --> 00:56:20,910
No.

500
00:56:27,080 --> 00:56:29,910
I'll call you back
as soon as I have any news.

501
00:56:31,110 --> 00:56:32,230
OK.

502
00:56:32,230 --> 00:56:34,590
No, "coq au vin" with Riesling.

503
00:56:35,680 --> 00:56:36,680
You're better than me.

504
00:56:36,680 --> 00:56:38,400
I can't choose.

505
00:56:39,010 --> 00:56:40,570
See you later.

506
00:56:51,560 --> 00:56:52,610
What?

507
00:56:54,210 --> 00:56:56,440
I have to go. I have to be clean.

508
00:56:58,440 --> 00:56:59,970
Am I OK?

509
00:56:59,970 --> 00:57:02,020
Does it show I had a screw?

510
00:57:02,020 --> 00:57:03,070
Sure.

511
00:57:03,070 --> 00:57:04,260
Seriously.

512
00:57:04,260 --> 00:57:05,440
No, it doesn't.

513
00:57:05,440 --> 00:57:07,000
- Really?
- Really.

514
00:57:07,140 --> 00:57:08,500
It's important.

515
00:57:36,840 --> 00:57:38,200
What're you doing?

516
00:57:39,110 --> 00:57:40,550
Taking your photo.

517
00:57:40,550 --> 00:57:41,540
No.

518
00:57:42,050 --> 00:57:43,110
Don't move.

519
00:57:44,000 --> 00:57:44,710
Stop it.

520
00:57:44,710 --> 00:57:46,440
No-one knows you. I can...

521
00:57:46,440 --> 00:57:48,100
I said, stop it!

522
00:57:48,260 --> 00:57:49,450
OK, Lola...

523
00:57:52,640 --> 00:57:54,010
Lola.

524
00:57:54,950 --> 00:57:56,440
It's not funny.

525
00:57:57,570 --> 00:57:58,660
Erase the photos if you like,

526
00:57:58,660 --> 00:58:00,590
but give me my phone back.

527
00:58:04,320 --> 00:58:05,650
Lola.

528
00:58:06,530 --> 00:58:07,760
Please...

529
00:58:15,870 --> 00:58:17,900
Give me that fucking phone!

530
00:58:18,280 --> 00:58:19,900
It really isn't funny.

531
00:58:20,230 --> 00:58:21,720
Open the goddam door!

532
00:58:27,490 --> 00:58:28,790
Open the fucking door!

533
01:01:48,350 --> 01:01:51,220
Florent? Is that you?

534
01:02:11,270 --> 01:02:13,290
What do you think you're doing?

535
01:02:13,640 --> 01:02:14,910
What've you done?

536
01:02:14,910 --> 01:02:16,110
Nothing serious.

537
01:02:16,550 --> 01:02:19,410
What are you doing all day long?

538
01:02:22,110 --> 01:02:23,620
I draw.

539
01:02:23,620 --> 01:02:25,980
So, you want to fall your exams?

540
01:02:26,750 --> 01:02:28,230
No,

541
01:02:28,230 --> 01:02:29,700
but I don't really care.

542
01:02:29,700 --> 01:02:32,900
Yes, but I do care.
And so does your father.

543
01:02:32,900 --> 01:02:34,230
I see.

544
01:02:34,660 --> 01:02:35,870
So you called Dad?

545
01:02:35,870 --> 01:02:37,360
What do you expect me to do?

546
01:02:39,040 --> 01:02:41,140
Start by solving your own problems.

547
01:02:46,950 --> 01:02:48,740
You're overstepping the line.

548
01:02:48,740 --> 01:02:50,330
Have you any idea how lucky you are?

549
01:02:51,170 --> 01:02:53,040
People fight to get ahead,

550
01:02:53,410 --> 01:02:54,430
and you do nothing.

551
01:02:54,430 --> 01:02:56,930
What are you talking about?

552
01:02:57,310 --> 01:02:59,490
You had to fight, did you?

553
01:02:59,490 --> 01:03:01,570
The world owes you everything.

554
01:03:01,570 --> 01:03:04,400
Your books just fall in your lap!

555
01:03:04,580 --> 01:03:06,150
Well, well...

556
01:03:06,150 --> 01:03:07,940
Vegetables grow in saucepans!

557
01:03:07,940 --> 01:03:09,000
The whole works...

558
01:03:18,310 --> 01:03:19,300
Sorry!

559
01:03:19,300 --> 01:03:20,660
You been smoking?

560
01:03:24,320 --> 01:03:26,240
You been smoking?

561
01:03:26,240 --> 01:03:28,070
Yes. You should give it a try.

562
01:03:28,990 --> 01:03:30,590
Let your hair down a bit.

563
01:03:30,590 --> 01:03:32,120
Not to be so neat.

564
01:03:35,780 --> 01:03:37,080
Mr Smart Aleck!

565
01:03:40,550 --> 01:03:41,710
Mom...

566
01:06:52,190 --> 01:06:54,190
Little bitch...

567
01:06:57,280 --> 01:06:59,050
likes to be screwed.

568
01:07:05,570 --> 01:07:06,830
Cry out.

569
01:07:13,310 --> 01:07:15,010
Louder.

570
01:07:16,990 --> 01:07:18,830
Louder...

571
01:07:19,200 --> 01:07:20,760
Louder.

572
01:07:21,990 --> 01:07:27,420
Louder or I'll stick something...
up your ass!

573
01:07:29,220 --> 01:07:33,020
Cry out.

574
01:07:33,280 --> 01:07:34,910
Louder.

575
01:07:35,170 --> 01:07:36,800
Stick it in me.

576
01:07:42,020 --> 01:07:42,370
Louder.

577
01:07:42,370 --> 01:07:44,600
- Stick it in me.
- Louder.

578
01:07:45,570 --> 01:07:46,690
No...

579
01:07:46,690 --> 01:07:48,180
- Beg me.
- No...

580
01:07:49,890 --> 01:07:52,550
"Stick it in me!"

581
01:07:52,550 --> 01:07:55,910
- No...

582
01:07:56,230 --> 01:07:58,520
Look.

583
01:09:48,070 --> 01:09:49,590
Mom!

584
01:09:51,330 --> 01:09:52,640
Mom!

585
01:09:52,640 --> 01:09:54,010
Coming!

586
01:09:59,010 --> 01:10:00,410
Mom!

587
01:10:00,870 --> 01:10:02,270
Darling!

588
01:10:02,270 --> 01:10:04,400
Dad bought me a new game.

589
01:10:10,400 --> 01:10:11,990
Is Florent home?

590
01:10:12,230 --> 01:10:13,490
Yes.

591
01:10:17,990 --> 01:10:19,080
Oh, you're heavy!

592
01:10:20,740 --> 01:10:22,050
You could've told me.

593
01:10:22,050 --> 01:10:25,440
I thought we said no more video games.

594
01:10:25,440 --> 01:10:27,840
You've time to play Scrabble with him?

595
01:10:27,840 --> 01:10:29,540
A new drill...

596
01:10:29,860 --> 01:10:31,750
When did you last drill a hole?

597
01:10:31,750 --> 01:10:32,940
It's the latest model.

598
01:10:46,080 --> 01:10:47,620
Let's stop this, OK?

599
01:10:47,620 --> 01:10:48,550
OK.

600
01:10:49,090 --> 01:10:50,220
It smells good.

601
01:10:53,120 --> 01:10:54,610
What did he say?

602
01:10:55,070 --> 01:10:56,320
Who?

603
01:10:56,320 --> 01:10:57,380
Florent.

604
01:10:59,970 --> 01:11:02,700
No explanation.

605
01:11:03,620 --> 01:11:05,310
Did the plumber come?

606
01:11:05,670 --> 01:11:06,720
Yes.

607
01:11:07,910 --> 01:11:09,510
I'll talk to him.

608
01:11:09,510 --> 01:11:10,910
I forgot the cheese.

609
01:11:12,550 --> 01:11:13,470
Give.

610
01:11:13,470 --> 01:11:15,170
It'll be too cold otherwise.

611
01:11:17,310 --> 01:11:20,480
It did this all day long.

612
01:11:20,930 --> 01:11:23,160
It's OK. Calm down.

613
01:11:23,940 --> 01:11:26,500
And promise me just for tonight

614
01:11:26,500 --> 01:11:28,670
you won't say your feminist stuff.

615
01:11:28,670 --> 01:11:30,910
I made a meal for your boss,

616
01:11:30,910 --> 01:11:32,130
I ran around all day.

617
01:11:32,130 --> 01:11:34,190
- Is that feminist?
- Just for tonight.

618
01:11:39,010 --> 01:11:40,390
It's not my fault

619
01:11:40,390 --> 01:11:41,910
if they make sexist remarks.

620
01:11:42,050 --> 01:11:43,450
You know what I mean.

621
01:11:44,190 --> 01:11:45,180
"Anne..."

622
01:11:45,790 --> 01:11:47,920
"You know Tom Ford? What's he like?"

623
01:11:48,990 --> 01:11:51,010
What they really want to know is

624
01:11:51,010 --> 01:11:54,910
if I have special rates at Celine
and elsewhere.

625
01:11:55,040 --> 01:11:57,810
"50% ? Oh, only 30%!"

626
01:11:58,020 --> 01:12:01,320
OK, but don't forget she's my boss's wife.

627
01:12:01,630 --> 01:12:04,600
You can put up with her for 2 hours.
Please...

628
01:12:05,950 --> 01:12:07,550
I'll talk to Florent.

629
01:12:07,550 --> 01:12:09,850
Take off the plastic. It won't look nice.

630
01:12:10,080 --> 01:12:11,170
Bye.

631
01:12:11,170 --> 01:12:13,250
- No!
- You're not going out!

632
01:12:13,250 --> 01:12:14,840
For once, you agree on something!

633
01:12:14,980 --> 01:12:16,670
What do you take us for?

634
01:12:16,670 --> 01:12:17,830
You're not going.

635
01:12:17,830 --> 01:12:19,490
Tell us what you're up to!

636
01:12:19,490 --> 01:12:20,800
He doesn't reallze...

637
01:12:20,800 --> 01:12:22,050
I do.

638
01:12:22,050 --> 01:12:22,980
I don't want to be like you.

639
01:12:22,980 --> 01:12:23,970
You're not 4 years old.

640
01:12:23,970 --> 01:12:25,440
Just listen.

641
01:12:25,510 --> 01:12:26,600
Well?

642
01:12:27,270 --> 01:12:28,900
What about your future?

643
01:12:28,900 --> 01:12:30,660
Just take a look at yourselves.

644
01:12:32,990 --> 01:12:34,650
OK, bye, Mother dear!

645
01:12:46,910 --> 01:12:48,540
I don't believe this!

646
01:12:51,710 --> 01:12:52,740
Stephane?

647
01:12:53,830 --> 01:12:55,120
Stephane?

648
01:12:56,030 --> 01:12:57,800
Get your pajamas on.

649
01:13:02,820 --> 01:13:04,280
I don't know.

650
01:13:05,510 --> 01:13:07,410
You'll have to explain it to me.

651
01:13:07,940 --> 01:13:08,960
Yes.

652
01:13:09,190 --> 01:13:10,620
I'll look. Just a second.

653
01:13:11,170 --> 01:13:13,570
I understand, but still...

654
01:14:47,680 --> 01:14:49,080
Bye, Mom.

655
01:14:53,600 --> 01:14:55,660
Sorry, I have to go to class.

656
01:15:04,000 --> 01:15:06,030
I'm not as stupid as you think.

657
01:15:06,850 --> 01:15:08,710
I never thought you were stupid.

658
01:15:16,320 --> 01:15:18,720
Explain what you're up to, dammit!

659
01:15:19,140 --> 01:15:20,570
What is all this?

660
01:15:22,180 --> 01:15:23,770
This!

661
01:15:25,510 --> 01:15:27,670
You didn't buy it with my money!

662
01:15:45,790 --> 01:15:46,850
What did you do?

663
01:15:46,850 --> 01:15:48,180
I cut myself.

664
01:15:50,950 --> 01:15:53,920
Where did Florent go?
Why did you let him leave?

665
01:15:55,010 --> 01:15:56,700
I don't know where he's gone.

666
01:15:57,060 --> 01:15:59,360
Do you want me to fight with him?

667
01:16:01,860 --> 01:16:02,790
Claude

668
01:16:02,790 --> 01:16:03,950
will be here in 1 hour.

669
01:16:05,120 --> 01:16:07,090
You could keep a closer eye on him.

670
01:16:08,510 --> 01:16:09,670
Screw you!

671
01:16:15,070 --> 01:16:16,870
I'm to keep a closer eye on things?

672
01:16:18,340 --> 01:16:20,130
Well, I sure did today.

673
01:16:21,950 --> 01:16:25,350
In this damn house,

674
01:16:25,350 --> 01:16:27,750
all the men watch porn
on their computers.

675
01:16:28,710 --> 01:16:30,640
Except Stephane.

676
01:16:32,870 --> 01:16:34,080
Think it's funny?

677
01:16:34,080 --> 01:16:35,330
He'll be at it soon

678
01:16:35,330 --> 01:16:36,630
once he's finished his war games!

679
01:16:38,910 --> 01:16:40,290
Since you started this article,

680
01:16:40,290 --> 01:16:41,850
you've been weird.

681
01:16:44,830 --> 01:16:46,360
We do what we can.

682
01:16:47,750 --> 01:16:48,970
Is that all you have to say?

683
01:16:50,240 --> 01:16:51,400
It's my fault.

684
01:16:52,900 --> 01:16:55,330
Why you go through my computer?

685
01:16:55,330 --> 01:16:56,350
Do I go through your computer?

686
01:16:56,350 --> 01:16:57,650
Why are you shouting?

687
01:17:00,190 --> 01:17:01,220
I'm not.

688
01:17:01,220 --> 01:17:03,430
Do you want me to keep
an eye on things or not?

689
01:17:03,430 --> 01:17:06,500
Going through my things! You're crazy!

690
01:17:06,500 --> 01:17:07,680
It's not the same.

691
01:17:07,680 --> 01:17:09,840
You decide whether it's the same, do you?

692
01:17:15,490 --> 01:17:19,950
It's driving you completely crazy,
this article on whores.

693
01:17:20,230 --> 01:17:22,130
Sure you don't need to see a shrink?

694
01:17:23,780 --> 01:17:25,840
I'm not so sure they're whores.

695
01:17:26,660 --> 01:17:27,970
No more than anyone else.

696
01:17:27,970 --> 01:17:29,150
A whore's a whore.

697
01:17:29,150 --> 01:17:30,450
You know a lot about it!

698
01:17:31,360 --> 01:17:33,250
This really isn't the moment.

699
01:17:33,250 --> 01:17:34,500
When is it the moment?

700
01:17:34,500 --> 01:17:35,790
Aren't you getting changed?

701
01:17:37,570 --> 01:17:38,630
Everyone sees whores.

702
01:17:38,630 --> 01:17:40,530
All women are whores, is that it?

703
01:17:46,820 --> 01:17:49,550
Why do you walk off
when we start talking?

704
01:17:50,690 --> 01:17:51,990
I'm here.

705
01:18:02,240 --> 01:18:03,500
Don't touch me!

706
01:18:07,520 --> 01:18:09,610
Aren't we a little bit responsible?

707
01:18:10,240 --> 01:18:11,800
Isn't it our fault somehow?

708
01:18:13,120 --> 01:18:14,650
Responsible for what?

709
01:18:16,190 --> 01:18:17,720
Stop it, Anne.

710
01:18:24,260 --> 01:18:27,690
What do you care about...
apart from your job?

711
01:18:32,130 --> 01:18:33,430
Right...

712
01:19:19,430 --> 01:19:20,760
You OK?

713
01:19:52,800 --> 01:19:54,700
Do you have a bathroom with a view?

714
01:19:55,070 --> 01:19:56,800
A bathroom with a view?

715
01:19:56,800 --> 01:19:58,030
Yes.

716
01:19:58,400 --> 01:20:00,700
I guess. I've never thought about it.

717
01:20:02,470 --> 01:20:03,710
Why?

718
01:20:03,710 --> 01:20:04,980
No reason.

719
01:20:07,270 --> 01:20:12,330
Anyway, what's the hardest
thing for you in all this?

720
01:20:14,750 --> 01:20:16,080
The lies.

721
01:20:19,300 --> 01:20:21,460
Having to lie all the time.

722
01:20:27,910 --> 01:20:29,300
- Well, goodbye.
- Goodbye.

723
01:20:31,750 --> 01:20:33,140
Can I...?

724
01:20:36,230 --> 01:20:37,220
Thank you.

725
01:20:37,220 --> 01:20:38,480
Don't mention it.

726
01:20:41,510 --> 01:20:43,130
Oh, my real name's Charlotte.

727
01:20:43,810 --> 01:20:44,640
Charlotte?

728
01:20:44,640 --> 01:20:46,800
Lola is just...

729
01:20:47,680 --> 01:20:48,960
Bye then.

730
01:20:48,960 --> 01:20:50,620
Thank you.

731
01:21:30,530 --> 01:21:31,830
It was delicious.

732
01:21:32,320 --> 01:21:33,520
They loved it.

733
01:21:37,700 --> 01:21:38,990
You look good.

734
01:21:40,000 --> 01:21:42,630
Are you sexy for my benefit?

735
01:21:48,290 --> 01:21:49,630
You have to get back.

736
01:21:49,630 --> 01:21:52,830
They're very busy, you know.
They're chatting.

737
01:21:52,830 --> 01:21:54,430
I'll finish this.

738
01:21:59,200 --> 01:22:00,670
Not too hot?

739
01:22:00,670 --> 01:22:01,920
No,

740
01:22:01,920 --> 01:22:03,150
it's perfect.

741
01:22:03,840 --> 01:22:05,630
So, when's your daughter getting married?

742
01:22:05,630 --> 01:22:06,790
Is the date set?

743
01:22:06,790 --> 01:22:08,670
Soon enough.

744
01:22:08,670 --> 01:22:09,630
They plan to.

745
01:22:09,630 --> 01:22:10,500
They plan to.

746
01:22:10,500 --> 01:22:11,710
No-one gets married now.

747
01:22:11,710 --> 01:22:12,710
They do!

748
01:22:12,710 --> 01:22:15,110
She's in London now.

749
01:22:15,110 --> 01:22:16,930
An English wedding, just think!

750
01:22:16,930 --> 01:22:17,630
People still get married.

751
01:22:17,630 --> 01:22:20,860
- He's English.

752
01:22:23,040 --> 01:22:25,120
She'll stay on in London.

753
01:22:25,120 --> 01:22:27,750
We'll see. That's up to her to decide.

754
01:22:28,900 --> 01:22:32,390
Will you have some more
of this Brane-Cantenac?

755
01:22:32,580 --> 01:22:37,910
- It's sublime.
- Yes, please.

756
01:22:38,370 --> 01:22:39,620
"Brane-Cantenac"...

757
01:22:39,620 --> 01:22:41,310
The beauty of French village names!

758
01:22:41,310 --> 01:22:42,750
"Brane-Cantenac"...

759
01:22:43,590 --> 01:22:46,370
Margaux... What magical words!

760
01:22:46,370 --> 01:22:47,490
Don't I get any?

761
01:22:47,490 --> 01:22:49,920
Sorry, I thought you had some left.

762
01:22:49,920 --> 01:22:52,260
I heard that...

763
01:22:52,260 --> 01:22:54,980
you or rather your company

764
01:22:54,980 --> 01:22:57,760
helped to finance the exhibition of...

765
01:22:57,760 --> 01:23:00,260
And we're proud of it.

766
01:23:00,260 --> 01:23:03,750
Well, bravo. Thank you. I mean...

767
01:23:03,910 --> 01:23:05,440
Anne will tell you...

768
01:23:05,440 --> 01:23:06,660
I wrote an article... How can I put it?

769
01:23:06,660 --> 01:23:08,390
About the artist... There's a visit soon.

770
01:23:08,390 --> 01:23:10,370
I've written several about
the artist, but the exhibition...

771
01:23:10,370 --> 01:23:12,030
Come to the private showing
in 10 days' time.

772
01:23:12,030 --> 01:23:14,180
Really? Which artist?

773
01:23:14,180 --> 01:23:17,150
The same one, but there's a party...

774
01:23:17,150 --> 01:23:19,230
I hope it's a success.

775
01:23:19,230 --> 01:23:20,640
I'd be delighted to come.

776
01:23:20,640 --> 01:23:23,510
Of course.

777
01:23:25,030 --> 01:23:28,870
Actually... What's interesting
about Lucian Freud...

778
01:23:28,870 --> 01:23:31,460
I was told an incredible story
about Lucian Freud.

779
01:23:31,460 --> 01:23:33,250
It's just a trivial story.

780
01:23:33,250 --> 01:23:45,890
He spent 2 days, stuck...

781
01:23:45,890 --> 01:23:48,830
- Yes, in London.
- Right.

782
01:23:48,830 --> 01:23:50,750
In a taxi.

783
01:23:50,750 --> 01:23:51,910
It's true.

784
01:23:51,910 --> 01:23:54,910
It's an amazing story.

785
01:23:54,910 --> 01:23:57,470
How did you hear that?

786
01:24:00,960 --> 01:24:04,960
"You loved me"

787
01:24:04,960 --> 01:24:08,290
"I loved you"

788
01:24:08,290 --> 01:24:12,190
Actually, they're not all quite...

789
01:24:12,190 --> 01:24:15,390
"Those who are in love"

790
01:24:15,390 --> 01:24:18,850
"Ever so slowly"

791
01:24:18,850 --> 01:24:23,110
"Without making a sound"

792
01:24:23,110 --> 01:24:30,400
"And the sea erases On the sand"

793
01:24:30,400 --> 01:24:37,120
"The footsteps of lovers Who are divided"

794
01:24:37,120 --> 01:24:40,960
"It's a song"

795
01:24:40,960 --> 01:24:44,740
"Which is just like us"

796
01:24:44,740 --> 01:24:47,970
"You loved me"

797
01:24:47,970 --> 01:24:50,110
"I loved you"

798
01:24:50,110 --> 01:24:52,000
Didn't we first see you

799
01:24:52,000 --> 01:24:53,350
at the Orsay Museum?

800
01:24:53,350 --> 01:24:55,200
I doubt that very much.

801
01:24:55,200 --> 01:25:00,330
Orsay is a place I never set foot in.

802
01:25:00,960 --> 01:25:04,760
"Of lovers who are divided"

803
01:25:05,630 --> 01:25:09,250
"But life separates"

804
01:25:09,250 --> 01:25:12,670
"Those who are in love"

805
01:25:12,670 --> 01:25:15,970
"Ever so slowly"

806
01:25:15,970 --> 01:25:19,130
"Without making a sound"

807
01:25:21,760 --> 01:25:22,820
I stay fully dressed

808
01:25:22,820 --> 01:25:23,680
On the beach,

809
01:25:23,680 --> 01:25:25,830
under a parasol.

810
01:25:25,830 --> 01:25:26,980
Handy for reading!

811
01:25:26,980 --> 01:25:28,570
Why do you go?

812
01:25:29,510 --> 01:25:31,520
Excellent question!

813
01:25:31,520 --> 01:25:34,750
I've stayed in touch with certain friends

814
01:25:34,750 --> 01:25:37,660
who love Brittany, who love...

815
01:25:37,660 --> 01:25:41,290
So, occasionally I go with them.

816
01:25:42,950 --> 01:25:44,380
Come with us this summer.

817
01:25:44,380 --> 01:25:46,780
Sure. Another good reason.

818
01:25:51,200 --> 01:25:52,390
Excuse me.

819
01:26:04,160 --> 01:26:05,570
It's nothing...

820
01:26:05,570 --> 01:26:07,870
She's been overdoing things lately.

821
01:26:07,870 --> 01:26:10,340
Her article is due. Do excuse her.

822
01:26:10,340 --> 01:26:12,930
Do you want some salad?

823
01:26:14,560 --> 01:26:16,230
Let's go straight on to dessert.

824
01:26:16,230 --> 01:26:17,980
It's ready. No, it's OK.

825
01:26:17,980 --> 01:26:20,000
If you insist.

826
01:26:20,000 --> 01:26:22,370
It's refreshing.

827
01:26:22,370 --> 01:26:24,100
With some cheese, then! But of course!

828
01:26:25,280 --> 01:26:26,580
Oh, to hell with it!

829
01:27:46,630 --> 01:27:48,990
You scared me. Where were you?

830
01:28:10,020 --> 01:28:11,180
What're you doing?

831
01:28:13,760 --> 01:28:14,990
I'm doing something for us.

832
01:28:27,840 --> 01:28:29,190
Get up.

833
01:28:29,190 --> 01:28:31,050
That's enough.

834
01:28:32,770 --> 01:28:34,100
Come on.

835
01:28:37,220 --> 01:28:38,110
I can't!

836
01:28:38,110 --> 01:28:39,670
Shit...

837
01:29:17,950 --> 01:29:19,270
'Morning, Mom.

838
01:29:19,270 --> 01:29:20,600
'Morning.

839
01:29:32,830 --> 01:29:34,430
Sleep well?

840
01:29:39,740 --> 01:29:41,080
Want one?

841
01:29:45,030 --> 01:29:46,050
Thank you.

842
01:29:49,790 --> 01:29:50,660
Thank you.

843
01:30:10,270 --> 01:30:11,740
I'd like a cookie, please.

844
01:30:22,530 --> 01:30:24,190
It's apple flavor.

845
01:30:24,610 --> 01:30:25,700
Want one?

846
01:30:30,080 --> 01:30:31,810
I doubt you'll like it.

847
01:31:03,590 --> 01:31:04,780
Thank you.

