- I miss you, Satinin'.
- I miss you.
- I waited up all night for you to call.
- We went on an all-night bivouac.
I just got back a while ago
and cleaned up.
They treating you right?
They don't treat you decent
I'm going to call that President myself.
They're treating me fine, Mama.
Some of the guys gave me some static.
When they see I'm like everybody else,
they cool down.
It's all over, Mama.
They're not gonna remember me
when I come back.
Of course they are, baby.
You just got to trust the Colonel.
I miss you, Elvis.
I miss you, Mama.
Mama, I gotta go now.
The drill sergeant wakes me up
about the time I used to go to bed.
You really got to go?
I guess not.
I ain't got a lot to say though, Mama.
You don't gotta say nothing, baby.
Just don't hang up.
Hey, Presley.
There's this rule that lets enlisted men
live off-base with their families
if they're nearby.
This house is going to do just fine.
They're gonna like it. We're gonna
line one up in Germany, right?
- I want 'em there, too.
- It'll be taken care of.
Good.
This general asked me
if I wanted to work for the USO.
- Entertain the troops.
- For free?
I got a call like that.
From the White House.
Would Elvis like to sing for
the President? "How much?" I asked.
Does the President work for free?
No, we stick to our principles.
Meanwhile, I piddle away my career.
Our career. I built it, I can keep it
going whether you're out there or not.
Your name's in the paper every week.
Magazines every month.
Your records are selling
as I parcel 'em out.
King Creole is doing well, and
I'm negotiating a couple more films.
You got no room to complain.
Hello.
Hi, Daddy.
What's wrong?
When?
Oh, my God. I'm on my way.
- What's wrong?
- Mama's in hospital. It's her liver.
- I gotta pack and get to Memphis.
- Now? You can't do that.
Why the hell not?
You think you'll get special allowance
because you're Elvis Presley?
- Quite the opposite, in fact.
- I'm going.
- Go AWOL, and they'll ruin you.
- Don't you give me that crap.
You say you're the great snowman,
go snow 'em.
You brag about being able to twist
everyone around your pinkie finger,
you work your magic, Colonel, and
do it now, or, by God, we're through.
Mama?
Mama.
Come on, let me see
that beautiful face of yours, baby.
It's gonna be all right.
Mama!
She's gone, Daddy.
Our Satinin' is gone forever.
Why would God take her away from us?
- [Elvis Presley: Loving You]
- Winter, summer, springtime too
Loving you
Makes no difference where I go
Or what I do
Doesn't she look beautiful?
She loved you guys very much.
Oh, Red.
I'm so sorry, man.
- I'm so sorry.
- I know.
Look, I'm out of the Marines now,
so I'm back if you need me, OK?
Thanks, man.
Look who I found out at the gate.
Oh, she loved you, Dixie.
We all loved her, Elvis.
I killed her.
All that worry about me traveling.
She wanted me to quit and kept asking me
over and over, and I wouldn't quit.
She's gone, man.
America's latest export to Europe
is not the Hula-Hoop or Coca-Cola
but the king of rock 'n'roll.
Elvis Presley has changed
his Hollywood limousine for a tank,
as he patrols in Germany
with the Third Armored Division.
America salutes you.
Elvis.
Just keep your hands
away from his mouth.
We're having a party tonight.
Some of my Army buddies are coming.
Currie Grant, Esposito
and Charlie Hodge.
Charlie Hodge.
Don't he just act like he knows it all?
- Thank you, Grandma.
- That ain't funny.
Where you been all night, Daddy?
Out with friends.
Friends my ass.
You were with that Stanley woman.
- I know what's going on. She's married.
- It ain't none of your nevermind.
It's been just three months.
- You're cheating on two people.
- Look, Elvis.
I loved your mama
as much as a man can love a woman.
But I'm tired of crying.
I'm a lonely man.
It's an insult to her memory.
You watch your mouth, son.
I know what you've been up to with
those French hooch dancers in Paris.
What would your mama say?
I'm the one who pays the bills.
Don't ever forget it.
How can we forget it
when you keep reminding us
every time you
don't get your way?
Thanks, babe.
- Elvis, you ever listen to opera?
- What?
Sure. Yeah, I love Caruso.
And what's the other guy?
The Lion. Titta Ruffo.
Listen to this.
- Yeah, I love this.
- You could sing this too, you know.
You got the register and the range.
You love gospel.
Not much difference.
Well, what do we have here?
This is Priscilla Beaulieu. This is
the girl I've been telling you about.
Hi. I'm Elvis Presley.
Hi.
Come and sit down next to me.
- So do you go to school?
- Yeah.
And what are you? Junior? Senior?
- Ninth.
- Ninth what?
- Grade.
- Ninth grade?
- Man, you're just a baby.
- Well, thanks a lot.
Well, the girl's got spunk.
- Do you have to go?
- It's way past my curfew.
My daddy's gonna kill me.
I'm sorry to hear that.
- Good night, Priscilla.
- Good night.
Good night, Currie.
See you on the base.
Did you see that face? Those eyes?
I've been looking for that woman
my whole life.
- She's really young.
- That's OK.
That just means I can raise her
to be the woman I want her to be.
God Almighty, man, she's as cute
as a bug, but she's just 14.
You could go to prison for life.
It might be worth it, Daddy.
Love me tender
Love me dear
Tell me you are mine
I'll be yours through all the years
Till the end of time
Love me tender
Love me true
All my dreams fulfill
For my darling I love you
And I always will♪
I'm so glad you came back.
I didn't know if you would.
- I didn't think you'd ask me.
- Oh, honey.
I want to be alone with you.
- Well, we are alone.
- No.
I meant really alone.
Would you come upstairs to my room?
Don't be afraid.
I would never do anything
to harm you, Priscilla. Ever.
I'll treat you like my sister.
Please.
- All right.
You go on up first, and I'll be up
in a minute. It'll look better.
Okay.
It was nice to talk to someone.
I miss that.
- Gets lonely here.
- Are you going home soon?
In six months, yeah.
But we won't quit then.
I feel like we're close.
How I just wish Mama'd
been there to meet you.
She would have liked you
as much as I do.
I wish I could have met her, too.
There's this photograph of her
when she was your age.
Oh, man.
You look an awful lot like she did.
Same eyes.
Beautiful cheekbones.
My father says if you expect
to see me again he's got to meet you.
I'll meet any man to keep you.
Slow down.
We've plenty of time, little one.
Sir, right now I'm driving a jeep
for the Third Armored Division.
I guess you're very anxious
to get home, huh?
Yes, sir. Only six more months now.
How do you like being stationed here?
We love it.
Couldn't be happier.
We're gonna be here three more years.
Let's get down to brass tacks, Elvis.
You got women coming at you from
every direction, all over the place.
Why do you want to date my daughter?
Well, sir, I happen to be
very fond of your daughter.
She's a lot more mature than her age,
and I like her company.
It hasn't been easy for me,
bein' away from home and all.
I guess you might say
I needed someone to talk to.
You don't have to worry, Captain,
Mrs Beaulieu,
I'll take good care of her.
No, please, I want to do it.
Please. I love you.
I've learned to love you.
But Daddy keeps reminding me
of your age.
I could get into a lot of trouble
for this, Cilla.
- Maybe when I go home...
- I don't want you to go.
I'm kinda mixed up about me and you.
I mean, maybe me being away
will help me to figure things out.
That's all the more reason
for us to do it.
At least I'll have that
to remember you by.
No.
Some day but not yet.
You're just too young.
Come on, it's time to go.
I promised your daddy.
Are you tired?
No, I'm OK.
I'm tired cos you and me stay up so late
and I have to be at school by seven.
How you doin' at school?
Finding it hard to stay awake
in some classes. Like in algebra.
I got a D.
If my dad finds out
he is going to kill me.
Here.
If you get tired, take these.
They'll help you stay awake.
No more than one,
or you'll be doing cartwheels.
- What are they?
- Don't worry, they're safe.
They give them to us on maneuvers.
Put them in your pocket.
Don't tell anybody.
Don't take them every day.
Only when you need energy.
I love the way you take care of me.
I don't want you moping
after I've left.
- I don't...
- Try and have a good time.
- And write me every chance you get.
- I'll write every day.
Get pink stationary and address them
to Joe, so I know it's from you.
I want you to stay
just the way you are.
Untouched.
As I left you.
I will.
And I don't want to see
that sad little face.
Now give me a smile.
I'll take that with me.
I want you to have this.
So everyone knows you belong to me.
Oh, God, Elvis.
This is it, baby.
Come on. Come on, baby.
Don't worry.
I'll call you as soon as I can.
Bye, Cilla.
Elvis.
Elvis!
I love you.
Has sobering Army life changed
your mind about rock 'n' roll?
Sobering Army life?
No. I was in tanks a long time.
And they rock and roll quite a lot.
You break any hearts in Germany?
No special one. There was a little gal
I was seeing quite often over there.
And there was some stories.
"The girl he left behind."
Yeah, but no big romance.
I got to be careful
how I answer that question.
Any plans, details
you can share with us?
I guess I got to cut some more records.
Then I'll take a train to Miami. I'm
doing a TV special with Frank Sinatra.
And I'm really looking forward to that.
I guess I have one new fan.
As well y'all know,
Frank was no big fan of rock 'n' roll
before I went in the Army.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
Hey, man.
Ten-hut.
- How you doin'?
- Boy, I missed you guys.
- Good to see you.
- Good to see you, too, Elvis.
- How's Bill Black?
- He's selling some records.
- Good for him. Steve, how are you?
- Good. And you?
- Real good.
- Good.
I got these demos for you.
There are some real rockin' hits.
- I got Stuck on You...
- Skip the rockin', I ain't into that.
We're gonna do opera.
Opera?
You're kidding, right?
[Elvis Presley: It's Now or Never]
It's now or never
Come hold me tight
Kiss me my darling
Be mine tonight
Tomorrow will be too late
It's now or never
My love won't wait
Come hold me tight
Kiss me my darling
Be mine tonight
Tomorrow will be too late
It's now or never
My love won't wait
My love won't wait♪
Colonel, I want to talk to you
about West Side Story.
Have a seat.
It's a big classy film,
and they want me for the lead.
I can act the hell out of it.
Have you seen the shooting schedule?
Six months.
We could make five films in that.
But it's a chance to do something
special, something really good.
Elvis, let me give you a lesson
in economics.
G.I. Blues. Your first movie back.
One of them blame musicals
you always gripe about.
A blockbuster. Made us millions.
Your second movie.
Flaming Star.
An ambitious drama. Well reviewed.
Made zilch. What does that tell you?
Why don't you tell me?
You're chomping at the bit.
Folks live sad lives.
Your job is to give them 90 minutes
to forget their pitiful circumstances,
not rub their faces
in some phoney, righteous misery.
What they want to see is some paradise
that they can never afford to visit,
lots of pretty girls and Elvis Presley
fighting and singing a half-dozen songs
that we can stick on a soundtrack album.
That's our bread and butter, son.
You stick with what sells.
You don't see the snow-cone man
switch from cherry juice to prune juice
just because he's got some blockage
in the poop chute.
Didn't everything work out like I said?
While you were away playing soldier?
Hasn't everything worked out
exactly like I said it would?
Yes, sir.
OK.
You are the money maker,
I am the money finder.
Let's do our jobs.
Yes, sir.
I take your bags.
I got another shot. I got another shot.
What you got on me here, Red, man?
- Twenty bucks you choke.
- Twenty bucks I choke you.
There she is. It's Priscilla.
Oh, baby. It's about time.
Where you been all my life?
I've been missing you.
- Let me take a look at you.
- You like?
I do, baby, you look beautiful.
You look so grown up, baby.
You look so beautiful.
Everybody, this is Priscilla.
I haven't seen her in two years.
This is Gene.
What a girl, she sure is one pretty.
Smith, away you stay.
God, I missed you so much.
I couldn't get you off my mind.
- Did you wait for me?
- I told you I would.
That means a lot to me.
Wait.
Wait, baby.
- This is getting out of control.
- Don't you want me?
Yes. But not yet.
I don't want to spoil you.
It's got to be the right time
and the right place.
- Time to go.
- What?
I told your daddy
we'd do this thing proper.
Otherwise he'd make you go home.
You're staying at the Barrises'.
They're good people.
How would you like to go to Vegas
with me tomorrow?
We could head out about midnight,
sleep all day, then hit the shows.
Smith.
- So, what did you think of the song?
- I liked it. It's really sweet.
I prefer the fast songs,
like Jail house Rock.
Why don't you do more songs like that?
I didn't ask you to tell me how to sing!
I just asked you if you liked it!
I get enough amateur opinions.
I don't need one from you.
I'm sorry, Satinin', come here.
Come here.
Come on.
I'm sorry. I just finished
that recording session,
and I'm real proud of it, that's all.
That was better than the hogwash
they give me to sing in them movies.
Stupid movies. Stupid songs.
Each one makes more money than the last,
so I don't even get to tour.
I'm sorry.
I'll make it up to you, I promise.
When we get to Vegas I'm going to get
you the best dresses money can buy.
Lamar. Red.
Charlie. Gene. Joe.
- Pretty slicky.
- Not bad, Elvis.
Won't it be strange,
being dressed alike?
Hell no.
You all look like an organization.
All right, go and get dressed.
Now, come on, now, guys. Go on.
Gene, I said get going.
You make that dress
look like a million bucks. Turn around.
Charlie, get tickets for Red Skelton.
See if you can get someone
to do Cilla's hair and makeup for her.
What's wrong with my hair and makeup?
There ain't nothing wrong with it.
This here's Vegas.
You just need more makeup on your eyes,
make 'em stand out.
I don't want you looking plain.
And I like makeup.
You look amazing, baby.
Why do you always have the TV on?
...that resulted in new pledges to
China by the United States.
It keeps me company.
...Mr. Eisenhower made to Taiwan...
But I'm here.
...provides shelter for his host.
A warm, candid vignette
of two world figures in a friendly...
Leave it on.
President Eisenhower's office
in Gettysburg
is becoming a must-stop for
distinguished visitors to the country.
Chen Cheng, Vice President
and Premier of China...
Can you believe it, baby?
Who'd ever thought we'd pull this off?
I don't want it to end.
I don't want to think about
you going away.
We'll have a good time.
We'll think about that
when the time comes.
Congratulations. You got three
of the top grossing films this year.
See what happens when you pay attention
to the Colonel?
Yeah.
But I also see that West Side Story
got ten Academy Awards.
Try to cash one of them at the bank.
But people remember who won, Colonel.
- You think people will forget you?
- If I keep making the movies I do.
They won't as long as I'm alive.
Elvis, I need to talk to you.
Yes, Grandma.
- It's been two days.
- She's tired. She's been sleeping.
- For two days?
- It's OK, Daddy.
- She's not used to the lifestyle.
- Lifestyle?
Priscilla? Honey, it's Grandma.
You all right?
Priscilla, hon?
- What'd you give that young 'un?
- We oughta call a doctor.
Oh, hell, no!
We're not calling any doctor.
Look, she's comin' to.
She's gonna be OK.
Elvis?
- What's wrong?
- Baby, you had us scared.
You been out for two days
on those Placidyls I gave you.
Two days?
But that's two days off of my trip.
What's today?
- Twenty-eighth.
- Elvis!
I leave in three days.
Baby, we still got plenty of time.
I promise I'll make it up to you.
One huckleberry, two huckleberry,
three huckleberry.
You know I love her.
Her daddy's concerned about
her being back for school.
What do I care about school?
Why don't you put her in a school here?
Son, she's gonna have to go back.
You had an agreement.
- Screw the agreement!
- You know better than that.
Presleys do not back out
on their word.
She's goin' back to Germany,
we're goin' to Graceland.
Look out! Oh, got it, oh...
Smith, get these folks out of here.
Me and Priscilla want some peace
and quiet. And take Honey with you.
Get the ball.
A cows purple,
Cilla and me one fix.
On that.
What is that?
A purple cow is vanilla ice-cream
and new grape soda. You'll like it.
No, I mean that way you're talking.
Well, that's our secret language.
We've been doin' it since we were kids.
You take the last word and put it up
first, and the first word up last.
Like... loves Cilla Elvis.
- Kind of childish.
- Yeah?
Why don't you try it?
Much Cilla loves Elvis very.
Oh, that's it. Now everyone will think
we've been talkin' nonsense,
and it'll just be our own
secret language.
Private code. It'll be our very own.
A secret for our world.
- You and me?
- Me and you.
Go I don't want to.
Neither me.
Cry I want to.
What's wrong?
I was just telling Mama how much she'd
have loved Priscilla. She would, Daddy.
Yeah, she would.
You gotta help me get her
back here permanent.
Help you?
Son, I think this here is a bad idea
all the way around.
They buried Jerry Lee Lewis
for these shenanigans.
You gotta help me find a way, Daddy.
It's important to me.
She's important to me.
- Aw, hell, she's a miserable as I am.
- Yeah, I know she is.
Maybe her daddy'd go for it
if we found a good Catholic school
for her here to finish her senior year.
And have her stay some place other
than Graceland.
That's a great idea, Daddy.
Catholic school.
Oh, man, I love them uniforms.
Wake up, Elvis. I'm home from school.
I got 'em making you breakfast.
Orange juice, home fries,
a pound of bacon, burnt,
and a Spanish omelet. Right?
Coffee. Coffee first.
Honey, do you really need
all these pills?
Placidyls, Seconals, Guinals,
Dexedrines, Quaaludes.
I know what I'm doin'.
Here.
This here explains
everything that I take.
Ingredients, side effects, everything.
Ain't nothin' I don't know about 'em.
And I'm not dependin' on 'em.
I use 'em like a doctor does.
You could use a few Dexies.
Help you lose some weight.
And don't slump.
And don't wrinkle your forehead.
That's a bad habit too.
- How's school, darlin'?
- It's good.
I need money for books. Getting a dollar
out of your daddy is like pulling teeth.
That's Daddy. He's pretty tight.
That's why I have him pay my bills.
I don't trust anybody else.
You gotta understand,
Daddy came up hard.
But I'll talk to him
about giving you an allowance.
I've gotta go to LA
to do this movie, Satinin'.
Who's in it with you?
Now don't be getting jealous.
It's just another Hollywood starlet.
Redhead, this time.
She was in that movie that made fun
of me going into the Army.
Bye Bye Birdie.
- What's her name?
- Ann-Margret.
And foot. And foot.
That's it. Now turn her in.
That's great. Great.
It'll be fabulous. Get some lunch.
- That sure was fun.
- Sure as hell was.
- You can move, baby.
- You can sing, baby.
This is one movie I might enjoy makin'.
She's like a female you.
Now Odetta's Tomorrow Is a Long Time
is a great song.
- You should record that.
- We tried but couldn't get the rights.
Elvis Presley? Why not?
They wouldn't accept the Colonel's deal.
Every song I record,
the songwriter's gotta give up
50 percent of his royalties.
- Colonel does a good job, doesn't he?
- No, that's outrageous!
Why?
- We give them a big hit all the time.
- You don't make enough money,
You have to go rob some poor songwriter?
No wonder you have no decent songs
for your films.
Oh, come on, Rusty,
why you being so hard on me?
I'm hard on you
because someone has to be.
Elvis, you are a great singer.
You deserve great songs.
For me?
- What's the occasion?
- You and me together.
Isn't that enough of an occasion?
Oh, yes, it is.
Open it.
All right.
- Bob Dylan.
- Yeah.
- You know who that is, right?
- Of course.
See, maybe if you change your contract,
you could record some of this new stuff.
- You know, maybe like the Beatles.
- I don't wanna hear about them.
ls baby jealous?
I hear they treat their fans like crap.
You think they should be treated
with love.
- That's right.
- Well, baby,
I think you should show me
some of that love.
Cos I'm your biggest fan.
Elvis! What prompts this rare pleasure?
I have Ann-Margret outside.
I want you to manage her.
Well...
...she's a wonderful talent. I could
certainly do something with her.
Of course, it'd take some time,
some work.
But I think I could do it
without neglecting your career.
- Neglect?
- Certainly.
I'd have to donate half my time to her.
At least at the start of things.
That much?
To do her justice, yeah.
Look, son,
you know where my loyalties lie.
I was just talking to the director
of this here masterpiece.
Have you seen how much
he's putting her in the film?
All them close-ups of her?
He's in love with the girl, I swear.
Don't he understand that this
is an Elvis Presley picture
and that all that extra shooting
puts us over schedule,
which means over budget? That's
stealin' money out of our pockets.
- I'm not worried about money.
- You shouldn't be.
That's not your job, it's mine.
How deep are you in
with this showgirl, Elvis?
That's a personal question, I know,
but you crossed the line
when you asked me to represent her.
Do you love her?
I like her. A lot.
Well, don't you have
some responsibilities
in Memphis you're forgetting?
You made some commitments there,
and I know you to be a man of your word.
I am. I am.
How would it look?
You toss aside this 16-year-old child
that you have moved into your home
with promises of marriage?
Could raise a mighty stink.
Maybe threaten your career.
She's not 16, she's 17 now.
Yeah.
I have to get back to set.
Elvis.
This Ann-Margret representation idea.
Think long and hard if it's something
you want me to do.
Oh, just forget about it.
I never thought I'd get
too serious with an actress.
They're always into their own careers.
And their men always come second.
I couldn't be second place to anybody
or anything.
Maybe you just haven't found
a woman who can handle both.
Baby, don't I make you feel
like you're number one?
That you do, Rusty. That you do.
Tell me,
how far you ever gone
on a motorcycle?
Gentlemen, start your engines.
I really wanna see you.
Now's not the time to come out.
There's a problem on the movie.
- What kind of problem?
- All hell's broken loose.
This crazy director's in love
with Ann-Margret.
He's given her all these close-ups
and wants her to sing with me.
You'd think it was her movie.
The Colonel almost crapped
cubes of blue marble.
How are you and her getting along?
She's OK. Typical Hollywood starlet.
I've been reading about you and her.
I told you about reading
those gossip rags.
- ls there anything to it?
- Hell, no.
I wanna come out there now.
No, not now. We're wrapping soon.
I'll be home in about two weeks.
You just keep your cute little ass there
and keep the home fires burnin'.
The flame is burning on low. Someone
better come on home and light the pilot.
You're beginning to sound like me.
I better watch it.
Look, I'll be home soon.
You get everything ready, OK?
Bye.
That is an outrageous lie!
I can't believe she'd say that!
- So it's true.
- No. We're not engaged.
But you're seeing her.
Those gossip rags were true.
Why doesn't she take her ass
back to Sweden where she belongs?
Look, damn it!
I didn't know things
were gonna get out of hand.
I want a woman who's gonna understand
that things like this might happen.
Are you gonna be that woman or not?
It's over, Cilla.
I swear to you, it's over.
Forgive me.
Please?
I'll go to LA,
get this thing straightened out.
Mrs Kennedy, Caroline,
Little John-John,
saluting the President's casket.
The caissons, followed by
a black-jacketed riderless horse.
A pair of boots strapped backwards
in the stirrups
signifies a fallen leader...
Elvis.
I heard the news in London.
It's so sad.
You have to know, I didn't tell
those reporters anything.
I didn't. I don't know
where they got the story.
That bastard Colonel Parker set me up.
It'd never have worked anyway.
You have your career, and I got mine.
I have commitments.
It was December 1956 when one artist had
nine concurrent hits in the top 100.
That artist was Elvis Presley.
His record was shattered this week
as the Beatles find themselves
with 14 hits in the top 100 and
Can't Buy Me Love at number one.
And here it is, Can't Buy Me...
Thanks. Oh, Red, go put that up.
You guys read that jive?
Hal Wallis says
he only puts me in pictures
so he can afford to make classy movies,
with Peter O'Toole and Richard Burton.
Double-dealing son of a bitch.
And the Colonel ain't no better.
Why don't they put me
in a classy production?
Those bastards are riding my career to
hell in a hand basket. Come on, Joe.
Red, I'd move if I were you.
- Where's Cilla?
- She's gettin' her hair done.
I'm bored out of my gourd.
Come on, let's go shopping.
Come on, Red.
I'll take this and let each fella
pick what he wants.
- Whatever you say.
- You don't have to do that, E.
Maybe we can get some burgers.
Your daddy told me...
- You tryin' to tell me what to do?
- No, E...
Then shut up. Go get yourself
some wheels, damn it.
Now.
We got 'em all...
Vernon's gonna be mad.
Lamar, this has big enough seats
even you could make out in the back.
How do you do, ma'am.
My name's Elvis Presley.
Oh, I know that! I'm Katie Day.
How do you do, Katie Day?
- Are you looking to buy a Caddy?
- In my dreams.
No, I'm just window shopping.
I used to do the same
when all I had was dreams.
Howard, I want you to take a pink
ribbon, put it around that car
and hand the keys to Katie Day here.
What? Oh!
- Thank you.
- Drive safely now.
- Take care now.
- I will.
- God bless you, baby.
- Oh, no, God bless you.
God bless you, Elvis!
Do you know how much money
you spent last month?
Over $500,000.
And more the month before.
You're gonna break us,
put us in the poorhouse.
- I can always earn more money.
- Why can't you just stop buying stuff?
Cos I like the look on folk's faces
when I buy 'em somethin', Daddy.
You remember when we were dirt poor.
How nice it would've been
if someone bought me a car.
I ain't sayin'
that it ain't a nice thing,
but you keep this up, and we're gonna be
livin' in a Tupelo shotgun shack again.
Elvis?
I gotta take a nap, Daddy.
Where are my sleeping pills?
You're nodding off already.
Do you need 'em?
- Nice shot.
- Yeah!
- Gene, honey, I wanna go home.
- When we're finished.
- Gene...
- Damn it! Turn that crap off!
I'm sick of this English Invasion jive.
Why don't you listen to the originals?
Like Muddy Waters?
Now there was a singer.
The hell with these Beetle Bugs
or Rolling Rocks. English critters!
Don't mind him,
it's just the pills talkin'.
That's OK, I'd be mad too if those
English guys put me out of business.
When was the last time
you had a hit, Elvis?
Nobody talks to me like that, you bitch!
- What the hell are you doin'?!
- Oh, God!
I think you broke her ankle, E.
Get her the best doctor you can find.
And buy her a car. A Cadillac, T-Bird.
Whatever you say, E.
Find my anti-depressants, Charlie.
I've been lookin' everywhere,
and I can't find 'em.
- None of you bastards hid 'em, did you?
- I'll see if I can find them.
- I'm worried about you, Son.
- Why?
What are you looking at me
like that for? I got a zit?
It's the pills, E.
We're concerned about your health.
I know what I'm doin'.
- I'm just tryin' to help you, Son.
- I don't need no advice from you.
You work for me, that's it. Understand?
- I'm your daddy.
- And I'm of age, old man.
I don't need a daddy anymore.
- So, Larry, what are you into?
- What do you mean?
You know, man,
what rocks your boat?
Like me, I'm into... Aw, hell, I don't
even know what I'm into anymore.
Music, obviously.
Karate. I picked that up in the Army.
Yep, I like karate.
You?
Jeez, let me see.
Well, I'm into hair, obviously.
But, you know, last few years I've been
thinking about the big questions,
like where do we come from?
Why are we here? Where are we going?
Oh, man, just keep talkin', man.
Keep talkin'.
- What do you mean three hours?
- Just like I said.
For a trim?
I swear to God, man,
no one knows how empty I feel.
I mean, no one knows anythin' about me,
man, least of all me.
And what is this emptiness?
I have no right to feel this way.
- What do you want?
- E, are you OK in there?
- Everything's fine.
- You've been in there four hours, man.
I said everything's fine, damn it!
Leave us alone!
- He shoots...
- That's it. Go, baby, go, go, go, go!
He's got it!
- He's gone, he's gone.
- Twenty, 15, ten...
- Elvis, what are you doin'?
- Listen to this.
This is how God works.
"I may be expressin' through you
beautiful symphonies of sound,
color and language,
that manifests itself as music.
And which so affect others
as to cause them to acclaim you
as one of the great ones of the day
and hail you as a wonderful preacher
and teacher."
Huh?
Don't you get it?
Ever since Mama died, I been trying
to figure these things out.
Why God took her away from me.
Why He gave me this success and fame.
Why out of all of the millions,
He picked me to be Elvis Presley.
These books are explaining things to me.
Why is there so much suffering
in the world?
Why am I not happy
when he gave me all this?
Don't we make you happy?
No, Lamar, you don't. None of this does,
that's the whole point.
You gotta read these books.
If it don't have Batman in it,
it ain't in my library.
- Or naked women.
- Amen.
Oh, the hell with the lot of you.
Cilla?
Wake up, wake up,
I wanna read you somethin'.
Oh, Baby, it's 2am.
All right, Larry.
I just want the damn truth, man.
I mean...
What the hell am I doin' wrong?
- Or maybe God doesn't love me.
- Come on!
Hey, you shut up or get out of the car!
All I wanna know is the truth.
To know and experience God.
But ever since we started,
I haven't had one experience.
Nothing. And I believe, man.
I really do believe. And I want it,
Larry. I want it so bad, man.
What the hell is wrong with me?
It isn't a prize, Elvis.
It's not something one earns.
Nobody knows when that moment
of revelation might come.
It could take your whole life.
For some, it never happens.
ls this thing gonna work or not?
We're runnin' out of highway.
That's funny.
It'll be up in just one sec.
Can we start that playback, please?
Cut! Cut!
Sorry about this.
Just get the damn thing workin',
will ya?
Man, that bites, huh?
Go on, guys.
What?
You're startin' to look
like a kettle of crap.
- That's none of your business.
- But it is my business.
No one's gonna pay
to see a burned-out Elvis.
Now, you've been late to the set.
More than once.
That's not like you at all.
Have you even read this piece of crap?
Do you know the lines I gotta say?
You wouldn't hurry up
to get here either.
It's not professional, son.
You signed on to do this,
you owe them your best.
I signed on to do this movie
cos you told me to.
- I need the money.
- You do.
You spend like a drunken sailor.
Now, that's none of my business,
but you show up on time, say the lines,
stupid or not, that is my business.
Yes, sir.
Now what's this about
some religious kick you're on?
How dare that son of a bitch?
He doesn't know the first thing
about my life.
It's not a kick, it's my life.
It's real.
And what happens in this house
is my own private business.
It's none of the Colonel's affair
or anybody else's.
My God, if I ever catch the traitor
in my own house!
- What are you looking for?
- My Dexies.
He's bitchin'
because he thinks I look beat.
- Where are they?
- You've already had a fistful...
Maybe they're in the can.
Elvis?
Honey. Honey, you're OK.
No, you don't wanna look at that, honey.
Come on. Vernon!
What's the matter with you boys?
What do you think your job is?
Someone has to be with him
24 hours a day.
I don't care if you have to go
into the donica with him.
Look at him. If they have to stop
the film because of this,
it's gonna fall on you boys' heads.
There's going to be some changes
around here.
First, all them religion books
is to be carted out of here and burned.
Some of you think
that maybe Elvis is Jesus Christ,
that he should wear robes and walk down
the street, saving the world.
- But that's not who he is.
- He's not trying to save the world.
He's trying to save himself.
Second, from now on,
everything goes through Joe,
who will be present
at all hair-cutting sessions,
which will be limited to one half-hour.
Elvis needs to concentrate on his work.
I don't want him reading any more books
or involved in things
that clutter up his mind.
We've gotta take care of business.
Now get the hell out of here.
Why are you doing this to yourself?
This religious kick, the drugs?
What is it you want?
You said that to me
the first time we met.
I remember.
Rich and famous.
You wanted to be a movie star.
Well, I got it for you,
so I'm asking you again.
What is it you want now?
I don't know.
Are you just bored, is that it?
There's that.
I get so lonely.
What about that little girl
you've got cooped up in there?
She make you happy?
- Sometimes.
- Well, son,
that's more than most folks ever get.
Why don't you latch on to her
before she wises up?
The whole scene
is starting to get unseemly.
You hear me?
She's legal now,
so what are you waiting for?
The right time.
If that's the case, I'd check my watch,
because if ever there was a time
to set things straight, it's now.
- Congratulations, Son.
- Thank you, Daddy.
- It wasn't how I imagined your wedding.
- I know what you're saying, Mum.
When the Colonel said he would take care
of it, I thought it would still be big.
Yeah, it got out of hand with him.
He didn't want it to be this big media
event and excluded half our friends.
Red went home furious.
I'm sorry, Mama.
Come on.
We'll be late for the press conference.
Come on, baby. Sorry, Mama.
Press conference?
That's a real low-key event, yeah.
The Colonel would sell tickets
to the honeymoon if we let him.
Cilla, my wife.
I love you.
They got me singin' to a dog.
At least it's a talkin' dog.
There's a bunch of fans out at the gate.
We best fly below the radar
so we get you to the airport pronto.
- Can you believe I'll be a daddy?
- We can.
We just can't believe
Priscilla's gonna be a mom.
Hit it, Joe!
Just a few more seconds, E.
We're passin' through a
mob of fans here at the gate.
Little Lisa Marie.
- Isn't she the most beautiful thing?
- I know.
Oh, she's a miracle.
I can't believe
I'm a part of this beautiful child.
She's so perfect.
Let's face it, Elvis. The movies
ain't doin' what they used to,
and the records,
they're not doin' much better.
It's the material you shove down
my throat. You can't polish a turd.
Now don't go pointing blame.
The way you go through money,
we can't just sit and wait
for good stuff to come along.
You bought a ranch, couple
dozen pickup trucks for your pals,
I don't know how many horses,
and now a house in Beverly Hills.
- You need the money, boy.
- All right, all right.
What's the deal?
Elvis, we need to
kick-start this career of yours.
We started big in TV,
and we can restart big in TV.
I done made this deal with Singer
sewing machines for a Christmas special.
No, now this is an
important opportunity, son.
And if I flop, we're done.
- You won't flop.
- Oh, come on, Colonel.
It's one thing to flop
in a film that's been done.
It's another to fall
on your face in front of...
- How many saw The Ed Sullivan Show?
- Fifty-two million.
Just meet the director.
He's a young hotshot that's done
a couple of rock 'n' roll shows.
You don't like him,
we get somebody else.
All right. I'll meet him.
Let's be frank. I don't think most kids
know who the hell you are anymore.
It's the '60s, man. You hear
what they're playin' on the radio?
The Mamas and the Papas,
The Stones, Marvin Gaye...
I know, I know. I listen to everything.
The Rascals, Aretha Franklin.
There's a song out right now, MacArthur
Park. Richard Harris sings it.
- Would you have sung that tune?
- Damn right. That there's a great song.
Jimmy Webb, he can flat-out write.
Here's what I have in mind.
We tape it over three days.
The first day is in front of a live
audience. Elvis' big comeback.
Now, I know you'll be nervous,
so we'll just get that out of the way.
The next two days,
we tape several staged numbers,
drawing on your own
personal and musical life.
- I like it.
- There is a problem, Elvis.
The Colonel and NBC want you
to sing just Christmas songs.
I think that's too limiting
and the exact opposite
of what you should be doin'.
What do you think?
I think let's do it.
It's gonna be great, Steve.
- All right, man.
- All right.
He's backstage, he'll be here.
What's goin' on, Elvis?
I'm sorry, Steve.
I can't do it, man. I can't go on.
- What?
- This whole thing was just a bad idea.
I haven't played in front of a live
audience in more than seven years, man.
I don't know if I can do it anymore.
And what if they don't like me?
Don't like you? Oh, my God.
Elvis, you created rock 'n' roll.
You were the king.
You step out there,
you're gonna be king again.
It's just like ridin' a bike.
Once you get out on stage,
it's gonna be like old times.
I just went out there.
Those are your fans, Elvis.
You can't let 'em down.
You have never let the fans down.
- That's true.
- And some of 'em are lookers.
I ain't gonna lie to you.
If nothin' else, just do it for me.
It'd be one of the few times I get to
play to your face instead of your ass.
Don't worry about a thing.
It's just a jam session.
You're just sittin' with the band.
- Come on, E!
- My boy, my boy.
- Oh, my, boys. Been a long time.
- Long time. Yes, siree.
- It's been a while.
- I forgot what you looked like.
Oh, did you now?
- All right, good night.
Well, what do I do now?
- Play us somethin'.
- Well, all right.
Oh, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Something wrong with my lip.
Remember that one, baby?
I done 29 pictures like that.
- And the finger, Elvis?
- The finger, that's right, the finger.
I was down in Florida, and the state
police decided to come and film my show.
I had to stand still, and all I could
move was this little finger here.
It got more applause than I did.
Hey, Elvis, sing me that song
about Lawdy Miss Clawdy.
Twelve years I've been
on stage with this man,
and this is the first word
he's ever said to me. First word.
And for that now I'm gonna take his
guitar. Come on, Scotty, give it up.
That's all I got to say.
Well lawdy, lawdy, lawdy Miss Clawdy
Well you sure look good to me
Well please don't excite me baby
I know it can't be me
Well I give you all my money gal
But you just don't treat me right
You like to ball every morning
Don't come home till late at night
I will tell, tell my mama
Lord I swear to God
What you've been doing to me
I'm gonna tell everybody that
I am in misery
I said bye
Bye bye baby
Girl I won't be calling no more
Goodbye to little darlin'
Down the road I go
Da-da-da da da da-da ♪
Thank you very much.
That was a beautiful thing, man.
Did you hear 'em?
My ears are still ringin'.
- Just like the old days.
- Old days? Just listen to us.
We're young. There's days ahead.
I'm gonna go down to Nashville.
- Still got that studio?
- Yeah.
We're gonna woodshed like we did before.
Come up with stuff and cut records.
- I love that idea.
- Once we're done, we'll tour again.
- I'm talkin' Europe, Japan, Australia.
- What about the Colonel?
I thought you never toured
because he was an illegal alien.
I don't know. Screw him.
We're gonna do it, brother.
We'll be waitin'.
Ready, willin' and half able.
Go on, D.J. I'll see you guys later.
Red! Come here, man.
Get the car ready.
We're done for tonight.
- Steve, that was great.
- Congratulations. You were great.
- Thank you, brother.
- Hey, look at that.
- New beginnings.
- Yeah. A new beginnin'.
Let me ask you, do you ever think
about gettin' rid of the entourage?
It's not an entourage.
One is my driver,
one takes care of appointments,
and there's bodyguards.
You think you need the bodyguards?
I get bothered every time
I go out so, yeah.
Really? No offense, but when
was the last time you went out alone?
Uh...
It's been a while. It's been a while.
I bet you, if we went out
to Sunset Strip right now,
you wouldn't get bothered at all.
- You think?
- I think.
I'll take you up on that bet. All right.
- Stairway's secure. Ready, E.
- I'm gonna go downstairs with Steve.
- I'll get the boys.
- No, just me and Steve. It's all right.
Come on. I'm gonna get changed.
Hey, how you doin'?
- Hey, how are you, man?
- Peace, man.
Hey, how you doin'?
It's 1968.
The times, they're a-changing, man.
You can change, too.
He's still dressed.
That's OK. I like to unwrap my presents.
What's wrong?
- I'm just goin' through some things.
- You worried about the TV show?
- Yeah.
- The hardest part's over, isn't it?
The audience loved you.
Only two days of taping,
just like making a movie.
Why don't we make our own movie?
We can't do this. It's too soon.
- Oh it's OK. The doctor says it's OK.
- It's not that, Cilla.
It's just...
I've never been able to make love
to a woman who's had a child.
What?
- I don't believe that.
- It's true.
Cos I'm a mama,
you can't make love to me?
I'm not your mama, Elvis.
Satinin', I love you.
And we'll be OK, I promise.
It's just...
I just need a little bit more time.
I got a lot goin' on right now.
I know you do, baby.
We have the amusement pier
and the bordello set.
Here we're gonna
build the road to nowhereville.
- Oh, man, I been on that road before.
- I hear that.
You two! Come here.
This is supposed to be
a Christmas special.
That's what we sold the sponsor.
Elvis feels we can not
have a proper Christmas special
unless we have at least one
Christmas song. Right, Elvis?
Yes, sir.
We're having somethin'
written for the finale.
- A Christmas song?
- Something special.
- Elvis insists on a Christmas song.
- I haven't heard that from Elvis.
I'm telling you that Elvis
wants a damn Christmas song.
Isn't that what you want, Elvis?
- Yes, sir.
- All right. Glad we got that settled.
Why do you put up with him
bullying you? Treatin' you like a child?
I've thought a lot about
that over the years.
I'd try to explain it to you,
but you just wouldn't understand.
- I think I do.
- How?
You know nothin' about
the world I come from.
Actually, I know a lot about you, Elvis.
It's my job.
You're not that poor kid from Tupelo
anymore. You live in the big house.
You could be your own boss man.
And you've certainly
outgrown that old carny.
I gave him my word.
Besides, before me there was
no such thing as a rock star.
He wrote the book on how to make one.
Anyone else I'll hire
will just have read it.
Well, maybe it's time
to write a new book.
Your own book.
I'm gonna get me a boss man
One who's gonna treat me right
I work hard in the day time
Rest easy at night
Big boss man
Can't you hear me when I call?
I said you ain't so big
You're just tall that's all...
- Cut, cut, cut!
- Was that all right?
- All right? Man, that was perfect.
- All right.
We're gonna go into the
Guitar Man sequence after that.
- I like it.
- That's great.
All right, all right.
What now?
What's this?
That's the demo for the finale.
Where'd you get it?
It's not a Christmas song.
It's one of them
hippie, communist,
American-hatin' protest songs.
Actually, it's more like a gospel style.
It's a new direction, Colonel.
I like it, and I'm doin' it.
What's going on here, Elvis?
Oh, just a few other new directions,
Colonel.
I'm gonna tour again.
Europe this time.
I don't care that you got
some birth certificate problem
or you're an illegal alien,
as some say.
And after Europe, I don't know.
Japan. Who knows?
Why are you being like this?
Cos I don't want to be bored anymore,
Colonel.
I don't want to sing
another song I don't believe in
or make another
movie I don't care about.
This TV thing has me excited
for the first time in years.
I'm havin' fun,
and I don't wanna lose that feeling.
A feeling? I'm not sending you out
on some cockamamie tour
just because of some feeling.
Then I'll find somebody who will.
Son, let me explain some things to you.
We have a contract...
You always told me a contract can be
re-negotiated. Broken, if need be.
Maybe it's time
we tore up this contract.
That's what you want?
After all my years of dedication
to you and your career? All my work?
- You ungrateful hillbilly!
- Watch your mouth!
- Get out of my office!
- I paid for this office!
- You're fired.
- You can't fire me. I quit!
I'm holdin' a press conference
to tell 'em you're fired.
Go ahead!
But if you wanna end
our business relationship,
you have to pay up what you owe me.
Fine. Write me a bill.
Oh, I was expecting something like this,
so I prepared some documents.
There's money I've advanced you.
Then there's bookings that I haven't
taken my full commission from.
Then there's expenses, future
monies to deal with, movie profits,
I get a percentage of the residuals
on them too, and the records.
Then there's other
items of mutual interest.
So you wanna be free of me, you're
going to have to pay for the privilege.
Where we gonna
get millions of dollars?
I'll talk to my agents.
They in cahoots with the Colonel.
I'll get us a lawyer,
figure something out.
Lawyer's steal faster
than a man with a gun.
We could lose everything, E.
What about your word?
You made a promise. He kept up his end.
Lately his end's been draggin',
and I been doin' all the heavy liftin'.
I'll figure somethin' out.
Please, I'm dyin' here.
- I can manage myself.
- But how is all I'm askin'.
You can't handle money.
I got the bills to prove that.
You don't even carry any money.
You don't know your phone number.
How you gonna manage yourself?
- I'll get somebody else.
- Who? Who, Elvis?
I was thinking about
our conversation yesterday,
and if you want to tour,
well, I'll set it up. We'll tour.
What about the movies?
Well, that's going to
be a harder nut to crack.
We're obligated to three films,
and the next has been set up.
It's called The Trouble With
Girls and How to Get Out of It.
Sounds like a winner.
What about this?
Oh, that. Trifle.
- So where we gonna tour?
- Las Vegas. I cut us a hell of a deal.
Mr Presley, we need you on the set.
Think about it, son. Vegas.
Guess what, Steve?
I'm touring Vegas.
Can I get a marker ready, please?
And we're ready.
Quiet on the set, please.
- You ready, Elvis?
- Yeah. Yeah.
If I Can Dream, scene 18. Mark it.
There must be lights
burning brighter somewhere
Got to be birds flying higher
in a sky more blue
If I can dream of a better land
Where all my brothers
walk hand in hand
Tell me why?
Oh why?
Oh why can't my dream come true?
There must be peace
and understanding sometime
Strong winds of promise
That will blow away
all the doubt and fear
If I can dream of a warmer sun
Where hope keeps shining on everyone
Tell me why?
Oh why?
Oh why won't that sun appear?
We're lost in a cloud
With too much rain
We're trapped in a world
That's troubled with pain
But as long as a man
has the strength to dream
He can redeem his soul and fly
Deep in my heart
there's a trembling question
Still I am sure that the answer
Answer's gonna come somehow
Out there in the dark
There's a beckoning candle
Oh, yeah
And while I can think
While I can walk
While I can stand
While I can talk
While I can dream
Please let my dream
Come true
Whoa
Right now
Let it come true right now