e u r o f i L e s
for
* T e A M.L o V E i N A *
e n J o y
Hello? ls that you, Emmanuelle?
Hello, Marie?
Yes, I'm leaving.
My flight is at 10.
Yes, I'll hurry up.
Sure, you can come if you like.
No, neither Christian
or anyone else. Come alone.
All right. See you then.
Bye bye.
You'll be fine at 5 o'clock.
-Yes, but when one is alone...
One is never alone in life.
It's like on a boat:
Worries, love seem unreal.
Everything is allowed!
-Yes, but nothing is possible.
Wrong.
Lots of people fuck on airplanes.
I'd never dare!
-One must always dare.
But if what you say is true,
aren't you afraid she'll...
No, I didn't marry her to
deprive her of anything...
Nor to put her in a cage...
But because she loves to make
love and she's great at it!
And you don't think some people
would try and take advantage?
I'm not jealous, I say.
Jealousy is outdated.
See this girl?
All science and innocence.
But it's no miracle.
They all had to learn.
And they do anything you want?
-Even more. For the right price.
That's what bothers me.
I don't like paying for it.
The idea makes me go limp.
It's hardly that simple.
I'm off to the airport.
See you at 5 at the embassy.
It's always the same faces.
Ex-adventurers, diplomats.
They are dying to see you.
I showed them your pictures.
Have you shown them my pictures?
-Of course.
I enjoy watching them
and showing them off.
Maybe even more so.
I'm proud of you.
Say, this photographer.
-What about him?
Have you made love with him?
Oh, Jean.
He never even touched me.
Strange. I thought an artist
always had to sleep with his model
before accomplishing a portrait.
If not before, then afterwards.
Poor fellow!
He must have suffered.
Not at all.
He was gay.
Wait a minute.
What is the matter, dear?
-Let's leave. It's horrible.
This boy with the chicken.
This beggar! I hate this country.
That's nothing, darling.
Welcome to Thailand.
Take it easy.
You'll see, you'll love the house.
I drive by here every day
on my way to the embassy.
I don't see it anymore.
Come on, baby.
This is Tim, Vine, our cooks.
No, not like that. Like this!
And this is Ap and Noi, the maids.
They are stunning. You chose them?
-Yes. John, the houseboy.
Our factotum.
Come see the house.
It is over 100 years old.
It belongs to a princess.
I had to court her for three
months before she let me rent it.
It's splendid.
Just splendid!
I never imagined anything like this.
Unbelievable.
Your little maids. Are they good
at making love with you?
I couldn't compare
any other woman to you!
You are just saying that
to please me.
Please me. Please me...
Please me...
Not at all.
I'm fitting out my house.
I'm very happy to be alone
with Jean.
You'll see in a few months' time.
Our only enemy here is boredom!
And our only ally to fight it:
making love.
You'll get around to it. Unless Jean
has suddenly become jealous?
No, it is a choice I made myself.
Jean would gladly push me
into his friends' arms.
I never tell my husband anything.
He's no worse off because of that.
True, Richard does looks very smug.
Hi, girls.
Allow me to present Emmanuelle.
Emmanuelle, you just missed out
on a great occasion.
A small naval vessel.
It's crew was splendid
and knew how to manoeuvre!
Why didn't you come?
You'd have had lots of success.
I spent the weekend at Pattaya
with my husband.
Jean took you away on purpose.
-No, I don't think so.
Your loss. Occasions like this one
are quite rare in Bangkok.
I haven't been home for two days.
Luckily my husband is very busy.
He works so hard at the embassy?
-Do you like your house?
Yes, it's beautiful.
Jean decorated it himself.
It's a splendid site.
-You know it?
Yes, Jean invited me over one
evening while you were in Paris.
In Paris? You must tell us
about all your affairs.
Don't worry, you can confide in me.
I'm quiet as a grave.
What do you want to know?
It may sound dumb, but I never
cheated on my husband in Paris.
Really. Wow. Well done.
Incredible.
Is she as good as she says?
-I'm afraid so.
Oh, it's you? You scared me.
I'm always a bit scary.
You are very lovely all over.
But I wouldn't be surprised
if you were a bit of a liar.
How come?
Have you never cheated
on your husband?
No, I have never cheated on him.
Cheating means hiding, lying.
Who is that girl?
She's called Bee.
She's not quite part of our group.
Have you never cheated
with a girl either?
Does it count with girls?
Try it with me some day.
You'll see if it doesn't count.
I'd like to talk with you.
May I come see you?
Do you know the address?
Yes. See you tomorrow afternoon.
My name is Marie-Ange.
Hello.
-Hello. I bet you are Jean.
Marie-Ange. My name is Marie-Ange.
I'm a friend of Emmanuelle's.
My wife hides such beautiful
friends from me.
Well. I'd like to become her friend.
She asked me to come see her.
She's in her room. Go on in.
See you around, I hope.
Oh, it's you. I hadn't heard you.
You're beautiful. Who took it?
A photographer.
One of Jean's friends.
Don't you have any more?
-Any more?
Photos, of you making love.
-Of course not. Silly you.
Do you know why I eat lollipops?
-Because you like them, I guess.
No, it excites the old geezers.
If only you had seen your husband.
But he isn't old!
-How old is he?
32.
-Well, there you go.
Were you asleep? At this hour?
-Yes. I was.
What an enormous bed!
How many can you fit in there?
These are twin beds
pushed together.
Don't listen to the girls bragging.
They don't do one tenth
of what they claim.
How is that?
-Well, the girls at the pool.
Come on, let's not stay here.
Your house is very cosy
and you have a great view.
It was very nice of you
to come see me.
Was there something special
you wanted?
Not at all. I just chose you.
-Chose me?
Excuse me.
Oh! French newspapers.
-Jean got them at the embassy.
I like your husband's looks.
You must give me a picture of him.
I like touching myself.
Great, isn't it?
Do you like doing it?
-No.
Don't you like it?
-Yes, but not now, not like this.
Don't tell me you're ashamed?
-Not at all. But I am surprised.
You are so young.
-I've done it since I was 12.
No one taught me.
My hands found out by themselves.
I think it's quite normal.
Don't you?
How did you start with men?
Jean deflowered me
the day after I met him.
We met at my parent's friends.
He arranged for privacy and asked
all sorts of questions. Like you.
The next day,
he invited me for a drive.
He stopped in the forest
of Fontainebleau.
He took me right there in the car.
It may not be comfortable,
but it's quite normal.
Eleven per cent of all girls
get deflowered in a car.
What does it change
to be married?
Nothing. Well, at first I found
it strange to make love at night.
Then Jean left...
He wasn't afraid
to leave you in Paris?
No, he always tells me I am free.
I may do what I want.
That scares me.
So what you said yesterday is true.
You never cheated on your husband?
No, I said
I never cheated on him in Paris.
I said
What have you done today, darling?
-Nothing.
Just like all my girlfriends
in Bangkok. What can you do here?
There are lots of things to do.
Tennis, golf, squash...
One can sail on the canals
or visit the pagodas.
One can make love.
-Even when you're not around?
You are not my possession, not my
beauty. You are beauty itself.
I love you.
If it's really love,
how far can it go?
It would be a poor love
if it lent itself to measuring.
Am I the woman you want?
-Even more than that.
And I want to become yet more
than that. How can I explain?
I feel that in love there must
be something more important.
Brighter than just technique.
I am certain that the answer lies
in physical love.
Maybe it's in your mind,
your mentality.
A different way of conceiving love?
-Not only love, everything.
I want to drink you.
It must have been Marie-Ange
who troubled me.
Why Marie-Ange?
-She's quite forward.
Will that little girl reveal
the mysteries of love to you?
Why not?
I certainly need to progress.
Find out things to become
a real woman, your woman.
Marie-Ange is innocent.
I mean, she is so pure.
Compared to her,
I feel very prejudiced.
You want to make love to her.
Don't worry, so do l!
No, that's not it.
Marie-Ange to me is...
Like a teacher. Like you.
She's very natural.
Why can you say: "She's got a pretty
nose." "l had a dream last night."?
But you can't say: "He has a big
cock. He fucked my ass tonight."
You can say that, you just did.
Look, hold it like this with
your wrist supple at all times.
You're lovely!
No, enough, I've had it.
I've lost the use of my legs.
Well you still have them,
and they look splendid.
I'm dead. Let's continue this
some other time.
My ugly duckling is all wet.
Apparently, I'm a free man!
You can do what you want,
as long as I may do the same.
This goes for all my husbands.
-I'm the first, and only one.
I'm talking about future ones.
-Did you hear that, Emmanuelle?
I dread being
even more free one day.
One husband will suffice for me.
-Look, your young friend claims you.
Excuse me.
This is Yves,
whom I mentioned to you.
Delighted to meet you.
Jean has told me so much about you.
I thought you might
discover Bangkok together.
He only knows the naughty places.
-How ghastly! I never go there!
Finally a virtuous man!
-He's just a hypocrite.
He's just a part
of a hypocritical class.
Good evening, I'll take
Emmanuelle away from you.
I've got a man for you.
-Who says I want one?
You must take a lover if you
want to become a real woman.
But I love my husband.
You're a virtuoso playing all alone.
Time for your first concert!
Promise you'll do what I ask.
It'll be fine.
Well, if that tickles your fancy.
-There he is.
Mario, the man I've found for you.
But that's an old geezer!
-Knowledge is always on the ball.
Forgive me for bailing out
of all this disgusting talk.
Is fucking your only topic? I'll go
back to my sorry life. Good night!!
She is angry.
May I present Emmanuelle.
Marie-Ange, good evening.
Gosh, what a looker your friend is.
I'll lend her to you, if you want.
-And if I want.
You have a great body.
You could say:
"Your dress becomes you."
I am not naked, you know.
The important thing is not that you
be naked, but that I see you naked.
Won't you smile for me?
Let's make up over a drink.
-Were we at ends, then?
Marie-Ange has told me
a lot about you.
Whatever might she have revealed?
She talked about your games
and common Lolita games.
She says you must become an adult.
Or do you prefer no to change?
No, not really.
-So, change.
Would you supper with me
one of these evenings?
You are not giving me any answer.
-Maybe... We'll see. Excuse me.
How did you like Mario?
Great, isn't he?
Not all that irresistible.
All cliche.
He loves listening to himself.
Why don't you present me to Bee?
-No way.
Ariane, I need you.
You need me.
You tease,
you're naked under your dress!
Have you had any sex
since squash? With whom?
I'm not telling.
-So, what do you want?
I want to meet Bee.
-You want that licentious girl?
You are like me.
Children who are alike, play alike.
No, I won't do it.
Fend for yourself!
I'd like to talk to you.
-Go on. I'm listening.
But not here, like this.
I'd like to see you again.
Impossible, I'll leave Bangkok
tomorrow evening.
Are you free tomorrow afternoon?
-No, I'm working.
Working? You must be the only one
around. What are you doing?
I am an archaeologist.
I'm called Bee.
I know, like the insect.
That's because you're working.
I never thought about that.
What are you doing?
-It fits you.
If you don't want it, you can
give it back to me tomorrow.
You're joking.
-No. See you tomorrow.
By the way, where do we meet?
At two o'clock, at the
Wat-Sa pontoon by the khlongs.
The what?
-The canals, you know.
Yes... I'll find it.
"Dear Emmanuelle."
"You disappeared quite suddenly.
I'll expect you at nine tonight."
"My car will fetch you. Mario."
Here. Help me. This way.
Sorry I have no time for you.
My schedule has been altered.
Fortuitous that we met last night.
I never go out, so to speak.
My boyfriend brought me along.
-The officer, he's your fellow.
Yes, he kept insisting. He had
to show off his brand-new uniform.
Why did you look at me
like that last night?
Because you are beautiful.
Do you want some?
Well now, you, Bee, busy insect,
tell me about yourself.
Too complicated.
I prefer you talk about me.
I think your are a girl who is
happy in her work and never bored.
How great that would be!
Are you married?
No.
-But you are in love.
I was. No more!
You know, I have no time.
See, men meet up in New York.
They ask: "How much do you make?"
Women ask: "Are you in
love, married?" Funny, no?
Not at all. I see you are judging
me. I don't know what to say.
So, say nothing!
And you, why did you look
at me like that, yesterday?
Because I immediately felt
you were different.
From all these women
I meet in Bangkok.
A world where doing nothing
becomes an art.
I feel like a convict
escaping from prison.
Are you bored?
-What?
Boredom...
Your life is boring in Bangkok?
Perhaps. I don't think so.
Anyway, not any more.
Are you going far?
-Two days travelling:
One day by jeep,
one day by horse.
I was delighted to see you.
I'm sorry I won't see you any more.
When will I see you again?
-Who knows?
I haven't even asked your name.
-Emmanuelle.
So, good bye, Emmanuelle.
I almost forgot.
-Please keep it.
No, thank you.
-Please do. It's my favourite.
Oh, really! No! No way!
Good bye, Emmanuelle, I like you.
You're a gorgeous doll.
We'll play some other time.
Whatever are you doing?
Whatever I like.
I am free, am I not?
If you say so.
This time she didn't come home.
-You must be happy.
You wanted your wife to be free:
"She's not my object,
not my beauty". So, here you go!
What you really wanted
was not for your wife to be free.
You wanted to use her as you
please, just like these girls.
Who is that? Let him in.
Do you speak French?
-Yes, sir.
Tell your master that he was
bested, well, too late. Too late.
We have to hurry, now, if we want
to be there before nightfall.
Is it still far?
-No. But we've lost some time.
Do you think so?
That's not what I meant.
Come on.
What'll I wear?
Here you go...
What a night yesterday.
Your wife, what a pair of knockers!
If I had a wife like yours,
I wouldn't live in the brothels.
I've got something to tell you.
I've said it a thousand times,
but only to my husband.
Yes, I think I love Jean
as deeply as anyone could.
Yes, that's what I thought.
He has always said that love was the
search of pleasure, always further.
With either a man or a woman.
But now, I feel differently.
When I saw the cascade,
I thought, "How beautiful."
I felt it wasn't beautiful
unless I could tell the one I love.
Listen, I like you.
That means
that I don't want to hurt you.
But I don't love you.
All right?
It's not that bad.
Let me tell you a story.
One day, at school,
I made a flawless dictation.
I was proud.
The teacher accused me of cribbing
off somebody. She never believed
me.
I was shattered.
For two whole days.
When my sorrow disappeared, I was
sad. Sad to be consoled so quickly.
Look here, the bachelor.
I want to talk to you.
Right now, I don't have much to say.
But do come in. For a nightcap.
I've just come home.
I think I've had
a bit too much to drink.
Gilbert is staying with Martine.
You know, the consul's daughter.
She doesn't want to be alone
at night. Actually, I don't either.
I'm glad to see you. Even though
you have a long face tonight.
Where is Emmanuelle?
-I don't know.
Furthermore, I don't give a damn.
Did you present her to Bee?
-Well, yes, if you like.
Is she with Bee?
She'll come back. They always do.
I'm not joking, Ariane!
-You've become a bit of a bore.
Well, that's not quite true.
In fact, you are becoming
the laughing stock around here.
Help me, will you?
I don't know what to do.
Emmanuelle has changed the game.
She is cheating.
-You know, you are ludicrous.
You are doing exactly
what you blame Emmanuelle for.
You are showing feelings!
Do you know what feelings are?
Instead of whining, you should
see to your wife's education.
If you can't, leave it
to competent people.
Like Mario.
He seems to be interested.
Ariane, you're a slut.
-Really?
So what are you waiting for?
You are a bitch!
Whatever are you wearing?
Now, I didn't mean it, darling.
No more playing the adult.
I don't know how to do it properly.
I've tried to get interested
in their thoughts...
But I can't... not anymore.
Relax, relax, it's all right.
In fact,
it is much better this way.
You would only have got hurt.
Passionate love is not for us.
It's much too sad, too humiliating
to demean oneself in front of them.
You must forget.
Take your revenge in other arms.
It's the only answer,
the only one she expects.
I'll help you, I'll help you.
Quickly! It's ten past now.
Will you ever be on time?!
-I'm always on time.
On time leaving, but not arriving.
Why don't you like me?
-I do, but you've disappointed me.
I know why. You're jealous.
-Jealous? Of Bee?
Poor darling,
you really don't get it, do you?
Your affair with Bee
is everything I abhor.
Violins, walks in moonlight,
not my thing.
I like surprising things. You know,
I slept with your husband.
I know, he told me. Was it good?
Unexpected. He almost raped me.
He raped you?
-Almost.
What is it?
-Help me, please. My bra.
I love your skin, so soft
and smooth like a pebble.
Let go of me!
-What's wrong?
We are late, you said so yourself.
We can play squash some other time.
But we can play at something else.
Let go.
Let me give you some advice.
-No.
You'll get it anyway.
You are going through life like
a baby waiting for her first cold.
You'll become some statue,
unless you pay with your person.
If you want to live and forget Bee,
you must learn. Go see Mario.
Why do you all go on
about this old man?
The old guys are a treasure chest
of erotic science.
Erotic science?
When you are young, you make love
naturally... as you eat or breathe.
When you're still making love
at Mario's age, it's poetry.
It's something you really want,
and reflect upon.
That's eroticism!
Go see Mario.
I don't like him. He's disgusting,
pompous! An ageing Don Juan.
You promised Marie-Ange to do
whatever she told you to.
How do you know about that?
She told me.
-I want to see Marie-Ange.
She is with her parents at the sea.
I promised that we would visit her.
Did you see her while I was gone?
-Yes, I did.
Why did you invite Mario?
He came for you the other night.
So I invited him to come back.
Did he accept?
-Of course. Perfect!
You fix me up
like a sacrificial lamb.
What about yourself?
-I didn't want to ruin the evening.
I'm going to Vientiane for two days.
You are ravishing.
You are beautiful.
That's the least I could do.
I am thrilled to have you here.
To the future law.
Before we drink
may I know this law?
This law proclaims that making
love without restraint is great.
Virginity is no virtue.
The couple is no limit.
One must expand one's boundaries
until there are none left.
So, to the future law.
Let's eat now.
Eating is also important.
Jean says there is one thing
more important.
Coming a lot.
I'm not scared.
Bravo. Down with all fears.
Fears of thinking,
of being happy.
All these fears make up
a false morality.
Conformity, refusal to live.
In fact: lying!
Come here!
You see these legs?
Take them!
I'm giving them to you.
You can't give it all
to the same person.
But what do you want?
What part of me do you want?
Let me go.
-What, let you go?
Or be satisfied with what I am.
Make love to me
and send me back to my husband.
Your husband is not there.
He entrusted me with you.
But why?
So you can break through a barrier.
Let you into the land of eroticism.
Eroticism, how do you perceive it?
Well. It's... how do I put it?
It's a cult of sensual pleasures?
-Not at all.
It is not an exercise of the senses,
but rather a movement of the soul.
It's an art, a school helping
to humanize sexual acts.
It's a refusal of subterfuge.
It's lucidity itself.
Well, if that's it,
it's not very tantalizing.
So eroticism is the opposite
of making love?
It is mostly through love.
It's an effort to break
with everyday life.
It's the victory of dreams
over nature.
I prefer thinking of love
simply as pleasure.
What counts is not making love,
but how to make it.
You mean the 32 positions!
-Absurd.
Asians talk technique
all the time.
But the body is necessary
to reach the important stage.
Take off the gag.
Scream your centennial claim!
Destroy established values.
Fill your head with sensations
that no one could give you.
Use the unusual,
the out of the ordinary!
The woman who gets pregnant in her
conjugal bed doesn't know eroticism!
Go beyond words and feelings.
The empty, scared head I am...
... will only be satisfied in death.
Why are you saying this?
I waited for her to fall asleep.
I left in the middle of the night.
I don't know how I managed
to get back to Bangkok.
Bee does not exist.
You dreamed her up.
Maybe everything I've lived for
for some time was only a dream.
It's because we are somewhere else.
Doomed to ludicrous activities.
Napoleon used half of his days
on St. Helena counting spoons.
One mustn't give in at any price.
One must always be curious. When
you say this, everybody agrees.
But when you talk sex,
it's a scandal.
I am a collector
because it's very respectable.
I collect situations.
Take me now.
You don't know me yet.
That would be too easy.
Let me guide you.
This moment is always identical.
But I will make it unforgettable.
Real love is always against nature.
Real love is erection, not orgasm.
The couple should be outlawed.
A third person introduced by force.
Wait for me here.
Thai-boxing. Have you ever seen it?
-No.
It's a savage sport. You will have
the privilege of witnessing it.
You'll live the fight
like no one else.
There's a prize for the victor.
Whom do you prefer?
I'm proud as the first day my
blood flowed. On my 12th birthday.
I hate morons, all those laughing
as if someone tickled them.
I am all woman.
Daytime is not for the likes of us.
What more do you want from me?
First of all,
that you take off your dress.
I'm tired.
You don't want me, do you, Mario?
-It's someone else I want.
Another Emmanuelle.
The one I don't know yet.
The one you don't even
know yourself.
One must find the unknown
through disorder of one's senses.
The couple should be outlawed...
A third person
introduced by force...
The couple should be outlawed.
A third person introduced by force.