These subtitles are only the English translation of
the Chinese subtitles displayed within the movie.
Subs are best synced if this subtitle dissapears at
the same time as the complete fade of the universal logo.
Leave me. Prepare for war!
Stop! I am not harmed!
We attack tonight!
I have too much to do for one lifetime.
Your Majesty...
Rise up.
I do not possess the secret of
immortality, my Lord...
...but I know where to find it.
General...
No man is to touch her.
She is mine.
This is a key.
You have served me well.
I will grant you anything you desire.
I want to spend my life with General Ming.
Of course.
Read
I feel your spell working.
I am now immortal.
Come, I want to show you something.
Become my queen
and I will let him live.
Do what he says! Save yourself!
You will never keep your word.
You are right.
Now, join General Ming in Hell.
What did you do to me?
I cursed you and your army.
Surround the Palace!
The Emperor is in trouble!
Don't worry. We'll find the entrance today.
Li Tung, what's for lunch?
Noodle soup.
Very good.
We found it! We found the door!
Ok, stay together.
The O'Connell's are in Shanghai.
Do they have the Eye of Shangri'La?
Our spy says they do.
Good.
Assemble the men.
Yes Sir!
Soldiers!
Soon all our training and sacrifice....
will bring great honor.
It's now time to wake
the Emperor from his tomb.
Only he can bring order out of this chaos.
Soldiers!
Our greatest battle begins!
I am your servant forever.
We shall see.
Hurry!
Welcome to the modern world, my Lord.
Why did you wake me?
I love this land.
Only you can lead us back to greatness.
What is in it for you?
I want to rule as your general.
The last general I trusted...
betrayed me!
I will not make that mistake.
I cannot conquer this world
until I am immortal.
General.
I understand, my Lord.
We must go find the Pool of Eternal Life.
This will point the way.
Clear a path to the Golden Tower.
Prove yourself to me.
Setup a crossfire!
Move it!
Please, I need your help!
These soldiers are evil!
Shoot! Kill them!
Shangri'La.
Mother.
My sweet daughter.
I beg you...
My father is dying.
They are my friends.
Where are you going General?
Our destiny awaits.
I was wrong to involve you in my revenge.
No, mother.
I would do anything for you.
You look tired. You should rest.
I'll stay.
Fate is about to deal it's final hand.
It is mine to defeat the Emperor.
I must ask for one more sacrifice.
Anything, mother.
Your immortality.
General Ming's daughter.
Her death will be mine.
Grab her!
Guard her with your life.
Arise!!
Today your world awoke..
In the grip of chaos and confusion.
I will restore order..
I will retake what is mine.
I will crush any idea of freedom.
I will show no mercy.
I will conquer without compassion.
I will lead you beyond the Great Wall.
Once you bathe you will be indestructible.
I command you to go forward...
and enforce my will on the entire world!
All hail Emporer!
Zi Juan.
Everyone wake up!
Follow General Ming!
Ready for attack!
Charge!
Ready up! Ready up! Ready up!
Archers. Ready!
Fire!
Formations march!
Attack!
Attack Emperor Han!
You are no longer Immortal.
Get in!
The O'Connells are going after the Emperor!
I dug you up...
And I'm gonna put you down.
Let go!
Never!
The Emperor is dead.
The Emperor is dead!
Subs created using the version
mtg.the.mummy.tomb.of.the.dragon.emperor.telesync.xvid-optic
by On-Line/EmanonMAi from Undernet. Original subs were
either a joke or incomplete so I took the time to make these. Visit
#123Warez and #MoviesToGo on irc.undernet.org