1943 Amazon Basin, Ecuador
Moipa!
Father!
Get Gimade!
Dayumae!
You went back for the stupid bird?
I went back to put Nemo in the earth...
so her spirit won't wander.
Now I follow my father's carvings.
Father! Father!
I was so afraid you were dead.
Where is Nemo?
Mincayani went back for the bird.
Dayumae went back for the
stupid bird. I say we eat him.
There is no food in this place.
If you die, I'll strangle her...
and put her in the earth with you.
Do you want me in the earth with you?
Mincayani, come here.
Take Dayumae into the forest.
Don't let her mother find her.
Are you leaving us?
I must jump the Great Boa,
Next full moon, we'll go back.
I'll never go back.
- No, Dayumae. They'll kill you.
- I'm dead if I stay.
- They'll eat your flesh.
- Then I'll join my father.
Watch out! Shoot!
Shoot!!
I've only one bullet!
There are others!
1956 Shell Mera, Ecuador
Mincayani,
we need wives to make our drink.
We say take them from the Aenomenani.
What do you say?
I say a jaguar ate this monkey.
Maybe the monkey ate himself.
He thinks the Aenomenani
sent a jaguar spirit.
I will spear this jaguar.
We need women, not jaguar.
We should hunt monkeys or wild pigs.
At least something we can eat.
A very big wood bee.
Mincayani's kissing the jaguar.
Dayumae is alive!
- Dayumae is alive.
- They've eaten her!
We must spear Moipa quickly.
Not the children!
Who has killed Moipa?
Show yourself. Let me see you.
A boy?
A boy has killed Moipa?
We'll take the women with us.
Moipa doesn't deserve to go into the earth.
He's a warrior just like us!
Let the Great Boa judge him, not Nampa!
This one will make my drink.
What do you say?
No. Don't take it.
No. No, don't take it.
Don't be afraid of us!
The creator God you call Waengongi...
Waengongi has sent us.
We’re just like you.
The creator God is our friend.
What's he talking about?
How does that one sound like a woman?
Even when drinking?
I'll go to them...
and see if Dayumae lives.
The foreigners are cannibals.
I'll go with my sister.
No, I'll go.
Go home to your second wife...
and stay away from my sister!
Enough!
Let's go hunting.
We're just like you.
Dayumae is my sister.
Can you show me where she is?
Can you take me in the wood bee?
I'll be very happy if you take me.
Take me to Dayumae.
Mincayani why are you so small,
and I am so fast?
The wood bee flies fast.
Did you see Dayumae?
No, I saw Mincayani and Kimo like ants.
Why don't you take me to Dayumae?
These foreigners understand nothing.
Gimade, where are you going?
I think you're a very tall woman.
You sing like a beautiful canary.
Why's he alone with my sister?
Where's Maengamo?
Where is she?
The foreigners attacked us. We ran!
But we saw you in the wood bee!
I wanted to see Dayumae...
but they already killed her.
Gimade, is this true?
We didn't see her. She must be dead.
Don't the foreigners always kill us?
Why should we spear each other?
I say we spear them now.
Mincayani, what do you say?
Nenkiwi says they've killed Dayumae!
What else does Nenkiwi say?
I say they ate her flesh.
They can't eat if they're dead.
Nenkiwi's right.
We must spear them!
All the foreigners are coming.
- They search for us?
- No. They searched for the others.
They'll never find them.
The river has hid them.
We've angered all the spirits.