Subtitles by DramaFever
[8:11 a.m., Kita Ward, Iwahara Fureai Park]
[Corpse Discovery Site]
Strangulation from behind.
The weapon is a thin rope.
No, actually it's a straw rope.
There are no gaps in the ligature marks
left on his neck.
The culprit strangled the victim without
stopping.
I see.
Without stopping...
You think he was a really big guy?
Can't you even figure that out, you
short-sighted mind? Get out of here already!
This is a sign of electric shock
by a stun gun.
The culprit gave the victim an electric shock to
stop his movement first, then strangled him.
This could be a woman's work.
Captain Yurine.
[Makimura Shinji]
- We're going to carry out the corpse.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Akagi-san, are you finished...?
Huh? Akagi-san?
Akagi-san?
Nothing at all.
- What are you missing?
- Both the corpse and the method are too clean.
I don't like this culprit.
[ST: Scientific Task Force]
The victim was identified by his
fingerprints.
Tadokoro Jun, 24 years old.
The time of the murder was between
11:00 p.m. and 1:00 a.m. yesterday.
Identified by his fingerprints means he
had a criminal record?
Seven years ago, Tadokoro
who was 17 at the time
picked a fight with Osaki Keisuke,
who was 21 years old at the time
after getting drunk and assaulted him.
Tadokoro neglected Osaki Keisuke, who
fell down after getting beaten.
Osaki Keisuke died from a brain contusion
the next day.
Because it was handled as a juvenile crime,
Tadokoro was never put on a criminal trial.
Also, since his parent was a teacher, they considered
it was possible for him to rehabilitate at home
and he was released from the juvenile
reformatory after about one year.
Only one year for killing someone!
Any possible grudges?
Parents of Osaki Keisuke, who died,
had alibis.
Osaki Shigeru, the father of Keisuke
has been in the Philippines, where he's
staying during his long-term business trip.
Fuyuki Yoshiko, the mother,
was at the food factory
where she works part-time,
at the time of the murder.
By the way, the parents got divorced
one year after Keisuke died.
- Um, the murder weapon was--
- A thin straw rope with a diameter of about 1 cm.
The fiber of straw rope was found
by the collar.
Just an ordinary straw rope. You can get
it at any home improvement stores.
It'll be difficult to
trace the distribution channel.
- Um, the culprit came from behind--
- He approached the victim from behind
and pressed the stun gun on the back
of the neck to give an electronic shock.
After the victim fell face-down, the culprit
sat astride and strangled him to death.
There were no pieces of evidence, body fluids,
and tissue slices left at the scene.
I wonder what the victim was doing at
the park in the middle of the night?
He says, some people do exercise in
the middle of the night
but, that park isn't suitable for exercising,
since there's no playground equipment.
Wasn't he just passing through?
If you go across this park, it'll be a shortcut
from the train station to the residential area.
What an acute insight!
Keep it up, since you'll be in charge
after I'm gone.
After you're gone?
Gee, I'm a little dumbfounded.
It's really hard for me to leave
the front line too
but I can't go against orders from
the higher-ups, you know?
This will be my last case in
the front line.
You got fired, didn't you?
Who do you think you're talking to?
I'm being transferred to the Personnel Division
of the Police Administration!
Wow, that's like the most elite division!
Did you know?
- Overly shocked. How come?
- Um...
Well, let's put my bright future
aside for now.
- About the culprit in this case--
- Lieutenant Kikuwaka!
When are you being transferred?
I have some handing over to do, so I'll
come and go for a little while--
Please leave the front line to us...
No, leave everything to me!
It'll be also my honor to take over the
position of liaison with the ST!
- Well, having said that--
- It'll be just fine!
I see. Well then, I'll leave it to you.
I've been asked!
If there are any problems--
I'll let you know immediately,
so you may rest assured.
Okay.
Tadokoro was the kind of man who assaulted
and killed someone after getting drunk.
It's only natural to make other enemies,
in my opinion.
- Let's start from that--
- Momoko-san, time out!
- Yes.
- Your remark just now sounded like Akagi-san.
Tadokoro-san is the victim,
not the assailant.
Please don't forget that.
Oh, no! Her enthusiasm is just
spinning her wheels!
That reminds us of Captain back in
the day, doesn't it?
It's totally bad to add Akagi-san's improper
remarks to my spinning wheel!
Please be careful.
I know.
- Captain!
- Yes.
Don't confuse me with that
good-for-nothing.
We're going to see the suspect,
number one.
Yes!
Why is she coming with us?
Rather than coming with us,
she's actually leading the way.
- Mom, I'll call you later.
- You always say that and never call back.
- It's about the condominium.
- I did buy the condominium
but never said I wouldn't get married.
I'm hanging up now.
Quit such a dangerous job at once! I'm so
worried that I can't sleep every night.
Mom, I'm on duty right now.
Hanging up now.
I'm sorry about that. Let's go.
- So you bought the condominium.
- The condominium.
- Please don't eavesdrop.
- Did you take out a loan?
- There's no way she can buy it in cash.
- I decided after taking thought for the future!
Everyone dies alone in the end, so I really shouldn't
expect to rely on someone, you know?
- She has her feet on the ground.
- No, you are greatly mistaken.
Now that life-time employment has
become an illusion
there's no guarantee she'll
sustain her current annual income.
Once the loan payment is delayed, you'll still owe
millions of yen even after selling the condominium.
I'll be alright, because I won't get fired.
You should be careful of dying
on duty as well.
What kind of human would make
remarks like that?
[5:15 p.m.
Fuyuki Keiko's apartment]
- Thank you for offering incense sticks.
- Not at all.
[Fuyuki Keiko]
I can't believe it's been seven years already.
Do you know about the incident this time?
The detective came to verify,
you know, my alibi.
- We're sorry.
- Not at all.
I guess I deserve it.
Since it's true that I still have a grudge
against the murderer.
Have you ever thought about
killing him yourself?
Akagi-san!
I can't do such a thing...
These are the letters from
all over the country.
After Keisuke died, they encouraged
me to 'hang in there'
though they didn't even know
what I looked like.
You just changed the subject.
Are you hiding something?
You're right.
I'll tell you what I really think, Detective.
Parents like me believe that surely there
will be a reckoning someday.
That God will surely give the murderer
punishment.
Without believing that there will be a reckoning,
parents can't continue on living.
I wonder who the person is?
The person who killed Tadokoro for us.
At this moment, the only people who seem to
hold grudges against Tadokoro-san are...
the former couple of Oosaki Shigeru-san and Fuyuki
Yoshiko-san, whose son was killed by Tadokoro-san.
But both of them have solid alibis.
Yeah?
The culprit knew that the victim would come, or
pass through the park in the middle of the night.
Do you think it would be someone
close to the victim?
Like a lover?
If this was discord between lovers, I'd expect
the ugly feelings to show in the method
but there's nothing remarkable
on the corpse.
Oh? Even Akagi-san understands discord
between man and woman.
But it's still impossible for me to understand the
mind of a good-for-nothing woman
who bought a condominium without
forethought out of fear of the future.
- Captain!
- Yes.
The Director is calling you.
[7:25 a.m., Adachi Ward, Hikawa-cho, Izumi Park]
[Second Corpse Discovery Site]
[Kobayashi Eita, The second victim]
- Another corpse of a man was discovered.
Same as Tadokoro, who was discovered yesterday
he was given an electric shock
and strangled from behind.
The stun gun and straw rope, the murder weapons,
were probably from the same manufacturers.
- You think these are serial murders?
- It's not definite yet.
I thought it was the ST's job to
assess that, is it not?
- You're right. We'll do our best.
- I don't need your best.
Just bring me the resolution of the case.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh...
It's about Lieutenant Kikukawa's
transfer...
Did you call me?
I heard you were leaving the front line.
Oh, was I supposed to bid
farewell to you?
Honestly I wasn't really involved with you
two, so I didn't think it was necessary.
Captain Yurine is worried.
Sorry? What is he worried about?
He's actually worried about Sergeant
Tsutsui Momoko after you're gone.
Oh, I see.
I already know that.
I'm planning to advise her plenty
later on, as a senior.
Then, it's all good.
We're going to miss you.
Once you leave the front line.
Well, to be honest I'm also sad
but I was relieved that the guys in ST
didn't seem to care at all.
Really, it's exactly the same method
of killing as Tadokoro.
The victim is Kobayashi Eita, 28 years old.
Lived in Nishi Arai, Adachi Ward.
His occupation was a part-timer at
the restaurant bar.
Same as Tadokoro, we haven't found his
wallet and cell phone
but the body was identified by its fingerprints.
Identified by the fingerprints again?
Kobayashi had a past of being charged four
years ago, with stalking and murdering
Niijima Yuna, who was
18 years old at the time.
Was the case against him dropped?
The parents of Niijima Yuna, had reported
Kobayashi's stalking to the police at the time
but there was only circumstantial evidence
and they couldn't indict him for the crime.
Was the culprit arrested later on?
No.
The crime scenes were both at
parks similar in size.
Taking away the items which can identify
the victim, is also the same.
More than anything, two people who made enemies
in the past were killed with the same method.
That's the biggest thing in common.
The common point is...
What are you doing, Captain?
I'm entering all the information here. This will
make it easier to write the investigation report.
- So you stopped using your notepad.
- Yes.
I see.
Okay, here we go.
The murder case of Tadokoro and
Kobayashi this time.
By the look of the clean condition of the corpse,
the killings were prepared carefully and done well.
The culprit is probably highly educated, established
in a profession, and has higher social status.
This person pays attention to the crime information
through mass media and such.
Married, probably.
And no criminal record.
No criminal record.
Would it be possible for someone who's totally
unrelated to commit the crime
for the sake of social justice?
In that case, there should be a social appeal,
like leaving a common mark.
I've just received a report.
Niijima Yasuhiro, the father of Niijima Yuna,
whom Kobayashi was stalking
testified that he was working alone at the
university at the estimated time of the crime.
The university?
Niijima is a professor of criminal psychology
at Seinan University.
Seriously?
We're in the same business?
At this point, there's no eyewitness testimony.
Niijima doesn't have an alibi.
How about his wife?
Around the time of the crime, she received the
phone calls at home from her friend and her parents
and had conversations with them.
That's been confirmed.
This is the professor in question.
It says, the internet course.
- [Professor Niijima Yasuhiro]
- It is normally thought that
the murderer has the motive
and the purpose.
And, the case in which the killing
itself is the purpose
and the murderer gets pleasure from
the killing, is called lust murder.
Professor Niijima also works here,
in addition to the university.
He must have a private office
or something.
Scholars of the human race like to claim
their territories, you know?
That's just a prejudice.
[1:40 p.m., Niijima's office]
- Akagi-san, you'll get yelled at
if you touch his things without permission.
Are you listening?
I apologize for the wait.
Thank you very much for making
time in your busy schedule.
Not at all. Please have a seat.
It is the duty of a citizen to cooperate
with a police investigation.
As someone who teaches criminal psychology
I wanted to be helpful,
even if just a little.
We appreciate your cooperation.
Now, did you get any eyewitness
information?
Not yet.
Did you find the murder weapon?
- No.
- We can't tell you such a thing.
Oh, I see.
But, there isn't much traffic in those areas
and as I recall, there weren't any security cameras
at the convenience store or the ATM machine nearby.
The culprit made them look like thefts by
taking away the victims' personal belongings
but far from it, I'd say these were
planned very carefully.
Are you saying that the culprit is not
a random attacker
but more likely to have clearly
targeted the victims?
Yes.
In the case of serial murders, I'm more
concerned about the motive.
Oh, I guess they haven't been necessarily
determined as serial murders yet.
Do you think Kobayashi was the murderer
who killed your daughter?
Come on, Akagi-san!
I don't know that.
Do you hold a grudge against the police,
who couldn't arrest the murderer?
What are you saying?
No, it's alright.
As a parent, there's no greater pain than
the murder of my own child.
However, holding a grudge against the police
won't bring my daughter back.
In the same way, even killing the murderer
a million times won't bring my daughter back.
How did you feel when you heard
Kobayashi was killed?
It's the fact that Kobayashi was
stalking my daughter.
And my daughter was killed.
But the police didn't think that Kobayashi
was the murderer.
From this point on,
it's a matter of my personal feelings.
I don't think it's necessary to
answer that question.
You said that it's no use to hold a grudge
against the police.
But it's only natural to hold a grudge
against the incompetent police
which couldn't arrest the murderer
of your daughter.
As someone who studies crimes, I understand
that not every criminal cases can be solved.
And it's not because the police
are incompetent.
But, there are some criminals beyond
the long arm of the law.
That's why I convinced myself that it's no use
to hold a grudge against the police.
Is it okay if we finish now? I have some
other work to do.
He sure is a professor of criminal
psychology, as expected.
Until I brought up his daughter as a topic,
he didn't say a word on her case.
Normally he would have been the first
to talk about his daughter.
Now that you mentioned it...
But, maybe he just didn't want to bring it up.
He's the kind of person who's always cool
and never influenced by his emotions.
He wouldn't have killed someone over a grudge.
But, grudges aren't the only motives
for murder.
Are you saying that Professor Niijima
is suspicious?
But, even though Professor Niijima may
have the motive to kill Kobayashi-san
he doesn't have a motive to
kill Tadokoro-san.
Oh, Momoko-san.
[2:34 p.m., Niijima Residence]
- What did you come here to do?
I came to question Niijima Haruna-san.
My questions will suffice.
Get out of here already!
We've visited your husband's office just now.
I see.
Haruna-san, what do you do for work?
I do translation work at home
just enough to earn a little bit
of extra money.
You were here the whole time last night?
Yes.
- What were you doing?
- Excuse me?
Your husband has been secluding
himself in his office.
What were you doing at home
by yourself?
I think you already know my
alibi last night, but
I just took a bath and watched TV after
having dinner by myself last night.
And at the time of the crime, I was talking to my
friend in the United States on my home phone.
That's why the call was made in
the middle of the night.
- And we'd like to verify one more--
- Can't the police arrest the murderer of Yuna yet?
We're sorry.
For Niijima Haruna-san, not only the murderer
of her daughter
but also the police, which haven't been able to
arrest that murderer, must be the subject of hatred.
She seems to be distracting herself
from grief with anger.
And taking her eyes off the past
she doesn't want to face.
I guess it's only natural for the parent
whose child has died.
On the contrary, Keisuke-kun's mother seemed
to be immersed in grief.
Stop babbling about nothing.
These are about the people involved in these
cases. They're not nothing!
Then, let me ask you. Did you just say
she was immersed in grief?
Can you really see someone else's mind?
I can at least feel it.
She can't throw away any of her
son's belongings
and his ashes haven't been placed
in a grave yet.
There's no need to feel, even a fool can see it.
You're less than a fool.
Those two have the strong motives.
Do the parents whose children were killed all
take their revenge?
That aside, it's also important to investigate
thoroughly when something catches your attention.
Everyone's anxious about the future, but
that's also why they embrace their lives.
But I think, for a mother whose child has died,
it was about the same as having no future.
Since they have their alibis, what about
the exchange of murders?
Why now? I've already thought about
that possibility a long time ago.
But, we can break their alibis if these
were exchanged murders!
You said that, by the look of the killing method,
the culprit could be a woman.
Is this kindergarten? Do I have to say
the same thing again and again?
Niijima Haruna is highly educated,
but too emotional.
And she doesn't fit the profiling of someone
who has higher social status.
It's impossible for Fuyuki Yoshiko to come
up with this plan.
Also, those two had no point of contact
whatsoever, like the hobby group
the supermarket they use, the acquaintances
before marriage, or their regular clinic.
There may be something we overlooked.
Don't let your emotions rule you.
Analyze calmly using your brain.
The crime scene, the corpse, and the evidences.
There's nothing uncertain in those.
There must be a meaning in the
uncertain feelings as well!
That'll just get in your way, you idiot!
Akagi-san! I think you've gone too far!
I'm not your puppet!
I'm acting on my own ideas
as a detective!
Wonderful. That's totally welcomed.
You're not even a member of the ST.
Just act on your own ideas as you please.
Sorry to disturb you!
Don't forget the loan payment.
Ugh....
Hey, hey, hey! What's the matter?
I'm expressing my anger! Can't you see
the steam coming out of my head?
Did Akagi twist you around his finger?
Are you getting ready for the transfer?
I envy your optimism.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Was I just rude to you?
No, I was going to give you advice as a senior
who's been angry at the ST
but I'm at a loss for words.
Yurine is really amazing, you know?
While being with those guys
- he's even worried about you.
- About me?
Don't you think he should have been worried
about my future after the sudden transfer first?
- It would be nice if there is a farewell party for me.
- Oh...
I'm kidding.
I don't care about that.
Solve these cases for me.
Yes.
The only thing I learned from being
involved with the ST was that
I'm no match for them,
no matter how hard I try.
A good-for-nothing like me could never
understand those guys at all.
But, I think we still can go along with it even
though it may be impossible to understand.
- Wow.
- What's the matter with you?
You're amazing!
That is absolutely right!
How didn't I notice such an important thing?
I'm off to make inquiries!
Was I able to say it without making
much of my seniority?
In both cases, the murder weapon and
the method are the same.
But, there's no evidence at all.
The first victim got the reduced sentence
for the past crime
because he was a minor and his parent
was a teacher.
The second victim was an assailant of stalking.
He was suspected of the murder of the stalking
victim, but acquitted for lack of sufficient evidence.
But, the public and the surviving family seem to
think that the stalker was the murderer.
The grudges, and revenge.
Momoko-san is concerned about the mothers
whose children were killed.
Huh, what a nerve!
You're just annoyed because she has
the same opinion as you.
I get goosebumps knowing that my close reasoning
coincides with her random guess, even by accident.
It's not a random guess. She's trying hard to think
about the victim's feelings in her own way.
In a criminal case,
the evidence means everything.
But as you know, it's human feelings that
causes criminal cases.
By being close to the human feeling, you may be able
to get closer to the culprit and the victim.
You also need to make an effort to understand
other people, as a police officer.
Anyway...
Where do you think the feeling of someone
who lost the loved one should go?
Sorry?
So this is geographic profiling, huh?
Right. Two murders took place
here and here.
By making each crime scene
a center point
you draw a circle with the radius of the distance
which you can travel within an hour on foot.
- And then?
- You designate the area where the circles overlap
as the living point.
But, not much to do with this little
information, you know?
Hey, what are you two doing together?
I was teaching her some profiling.
I thought I should study a little.
I see.
It's hard to find the common denominator
since we only have two cases.
If we have one or two more cases...
Oh, sorry. That wasn't a proper thing
to say, was it?
It's fine as long as you understand that.
Also, I've read in the autopsy
report just now.
Kobayashi, the second victim, lost consciousness
by an electric shock once
but woke up while being strangled,
and resisted.
The dirt between his fingernails.
The dried dirt doesn't penetrate like that,
from just falling down on the ground.
It's the evidence of him grabbing the dirt tightly
after falling down by an electric shock.
Why didn't you tell me if you had
already known?
It was quite obvious, you know?
- And also--
- Do you have some more?
If he was strangled to death
without stopping
the thickness of the ligature marks on his neck
shouldn't change depending on the area.
That means, this isn't by the same culprit,
and there may be more than one?
That's possible.
And whether it's the same culprit
or more than one
there's only one person who
fits the profiling.
[Interrogation Room, Number One]
- On that day
I was writing a paper in my office
at the university
because the deadline for presenting it at
an academic conference was approaching.
I don't detect any changes in the pitch
of his voice. He's not lying.
When a human tells a lie, his body naturally
gets slanted from the other party.
Niijima's body is facing right in the center.
If I could check on the pupils of his eyes, I
would be able to tell even more precisely.
Is there someone who can prove that?
I talked to my wife on my cell phone
other than that, there was
no one I talked to or saw on that day.
Do you often spend the night
at the university?
Yes, when I get busy.
His behavior does seem suspicious
if you nitpick.
He might have been able to write
a paper at home.
But he's not lying.
With the 'organized' type, the culprit often
anticipates the police interrogation.
His dignified manner may be
just an act.
Niijima Yasuhiro-san had an alibi?
There was more than one eyewitness
testimony.
It's a perfect alibi.
At the time of the crime
a few students who were spending the
night for the event during the summer break
saw Professor Niijima in his office
through the window.
Aoyama-san and Midori-san said that
Niijima-san wasn't lying.
That means, the investigation is back
where you started.
Yes, ma'am.
What are you going to do?
That's...
Some things may go out of sight if you
only see things logically.
The person who depends only on the
theory can never escape its spell.
I thought that the ST had been investigating
the case without abandoning every possibility.
I'll tell you my personal opinion.
A human can't commit murder so easily.
In the background of almost every murder
whether it is good or bad
there lies the earnest truth.
That's what I think.
Thank you, ma'am.
The dirt between his fingernails.
Slight differences in the killing method.
More than one culprit.
The exchange murders by the mothers.
But, the mothers don't fit the criminal profile
and in the first place--
In the first place, without the point of contact
between Fuyuki Yoshiko and Niijima Haruna
the exchange murders wouldn't take place.
That's right.
Let's investigate the mothers' surroundings
thoroughly all over again.
We need to look for the point of
contact between the two mothers.
That's the necessary condition for
this exchange of murders.
I'll continue on making inquiries.
Have you ever seen these two?
No, I haven't.
I see. Thank you anyway.
Thank you very much. Thanks.
Alright!
[5:45 p.m., Near Niijima Residence]
- Haruna-san used to be an active person
but she rarely goes out ever since
Yuna-chan's incident.
Um, have you noticed something strange
about the Niijimas lately?
- Come to think of it.
- Come to think of it?
Mr. Niijima has been coming home late.
Or actually he doesn't come home
sometimes.
He also seems to go out by himself
on his days off.
Haruna-san doesn't go out with him?
I haven't seen them together lately.
I used to see them together in a place like
the supermarket until just a little while ago.
I see.
[In 2007, my son died at 21 years old.
I'm the mother who can't accept it yet.]
This must be it.
According to the people who
know the Niijimas
things are getting worse between the couple
after Kobayashi was killed.
If they thought he was the murderer, I would
normally expect them to feel even a little better.
Things got worse between the couple.
Yes.
Tsutsui.
Your reasoning is correct.
Well done. This is your first step
to your success.
What?
And as for the point of contact between
Fuyuki Yoshiko and Niijima Haruna.
This is Fuyuki Yoshiko's blog.
There was someone posting comments in
there, with the handle name, 'Spring.'
I've checked out the comment made by the same
person in the other websites on the internet.
Judging from the time of the incident of losing
a child and the contents of the comment
I can assure you that this person
is Niijima Haruna.
What?
Fuyuki Yoshiko-san and Niijima Haruna-san
are connected now!
Thank you very much!
But, there's no clue written here,
which may lead to the crime.
This isn't strong enough.
Captain, interview those two mothers
tomorrow.
Yes!
This is the blog you've written, isn't it?
Yes.
You've posted about hatred and grudges against
the murderer, and grief for the loss of Keisuke-kun.
The last time you updated this blog was
on the day of the murder of Tadokoro-san,
who had killed Keisuke-kun.
- I heard about it on the news--
- And there was no need to write anymore?
I decided to live facing forward
from now on.
I've finally laid his ashes to rest, which I
couldn't do for a long time.
She's not lying.
Do you know Kobayashi Eita-san?
No.
That's a lie.
Is that true?
I'm sorry. Come to think of it, I think
I heard of him on the news.
That's not a lie.
Do you remember the name
Niijima Haruna-san?
No.
Not a lie.
Kobayashi Eita-san was murdered.
Haven't you known
Kobayashi Eita-san from before?
I don't know!
I've never known such a man!
That's... not a lie.
[Interrogation Room, Number Two]
Do you know the person who
writes this blog?
If I had known that person, I wouldn't be
able to write these kind of things.
And you don't post your comments anymore?
Even if I carry on like this, that won't
bring my daughter back.
Have you ever wished to take revenge
for your child?
- Yes, I have.
- Have you ever thought of killing Kobayashi?
- Did you kill Kobayashi?
No.
On the day before the stalker of
your daughter was killed
another person was murdered with
the same method.
Did you do it?
- What are you talking about?
- You've been jolted just now.
I wonder if there's someone who
wouldn't get jolted
after being brought up to a place like this
and treated as a suspect.
It's no use telling us lies.
Do you have any proof that I did it?
What do you think?
So they don't know each other?
If these were exchanged murders, they should
have known about the person they killed.
But Fuyuki Yoshiko-san didn't know anything
about Kobayashi Eita-san, except the name.
And of all things,
those two don't know each other.
That actually brought me
to an answer.
- Sorry?
- What do you mean by that?
There's only one mystery left.
The question is how.
Captain, even she brought an important
clue this time.
Why can't you become useful,
even a little?
I don't even know what's what.
Ahh!
You scared me!
Captain, thank you for trying to keep me
awake, but I'm not sleepy yet.
All gone!
All of my efforts...
were for nothing.
What's happening?
My memos.
My memos...
Oh, I see. Anything and everything
Yurine-kun was entering.
Don't put it simply like that!
Those were very important
memos for me!
Oh, why? I should have kept my usual
notepad as always!
The lost data.
The documents which cannot be
thrown away.
It's the paper (kami).
You're right.
God (kami-sama) is so cruel.
Stop making a bad joke.
Ugh...
Because of you... and Captain...
the mysteries... have been solved!
Ugh!
I don't need these anymore!
My head is going to burst!
Captain! All the mysteries have
been solved!
In regards to those two cases this time, we wanted
to ask your opinion as a criminal psychologist.
Let me start first.
If you were to kill someone,
how would you do it?
That's a very interesting question.
By the way, who are you?
Are you with the police?
- Yeah.
I have a PhD in criminal psychology
in the United States.
Oh, that's impressive.
And?
Let me see, if I were to do it...
The bones, the flesh, and the hair.
I would eliminate all the
body parts from this world first.
I agree.
How about the mental state of the criminal,
who strangles the opponent
after making him unconscious by giving
an electric shock?
I guess it's possible to use a strategy like that,
if the opponent surpasses you in strength.
What's the reason to strangle
from behind?
In cases of killing without seeing the victim's face,
or covering up the face of the dead body
I guess it's safe to consider that the
culprit had some sense of guilt.
Right.
Committing a crime must be easy
with your knowledge.
Isn't it the same with the police officers?
But police officers wouldn't commit a crime
so easily. Isn't that right?
By the way, did you figure out
who the culprit is?
The ones who executed the murders were
the mothers who wished to take revenge
for their children.
[Niijima Residence]
And the person who planned the
exchange murders was
you, Professor Niijima.
Well, well!
What are you saying so abruptly?
It's impossible for the mothers to commit
these crimes by themselves.
But with your brains, it can happen.
Just two mothers getting connected wouldn't
have started an act of revenge.
It didn't become reality until you
got involved.
And you must have left evidence
somewhere.
- Evidence?
- Something which proves you planned it.
My plan for the exchanged murders...
Where do you think it is?
This office must be considered a
part of your brains.
This place has your knowledge and everything
else you've earned in my life so far.
You must've hesitated to keep crime-related material
at home with your wife, after your daughter had died.
I'm certain that the evidence is in this room.
And in the most sacred place for you.
I'm sure you know this since you're a
professor of psychology
but, when a human lies, he averts his gaze or
the area around the mouth gets tightened.
And also, when someone hits the nail
on the head.
Evidence?
By the way, when a human lies, he tends to
cover up the face with hands
and that's why you've been holding that pen
with both hands all this time. Right?
But, it's too bad.
Unconsciously your eyes and the direction of
your body showed us where the hiding place was.
The most important thing for you.
The happiest time of your life.
The evidence is...
right here.
Bingo!
It's a copy of the letter.
Our Captain here doesn't trust
the computer data
which could be glanced by the hackers or
recovered even after being erased.
As a matter of fact, there are many
organizations which don't
store the important data on the server
or the network anymore.
Since there's a risk of getting it stolen.
Oh, but of course you must
already know that.
That's why you wrote a letter, which will
disappear completely when burned.
Your target will pass through Izumi Park, Hikawa-cho,
Adachi Ward, right after 12:00 a.m. on August 20.
The detailed instructions for the murder weapon
and even the disposal method are written here.
Your wife found Fuyuki Yoshiko's blog
on the internet.
We've already verified their accounts.
Two of them must have become close right
away, since they both had their children killed.
[I'll make him pay for it no matter what.]
What's the good of doing this?
Stop it!
Stop it already!
You must have tried to stop those mothers when
you learned they wished to take revenge.
But they didn't give up on their revenge.
That's why you planned two murders by
putting all your knowledge in full force
before your wife took action.
You chose exchanged murders so that
the mothers would have the impregnable alibis.
And Niijima Haruna killed Tadokoro Jun, even
without knowing what he looked like.
In order to make it look like
the same culprit's work
you prepared the clothes, the shoes and
the murder weapon for Fuyuki Yoshiko
and mapped out the plan for
the exchange murders.
And Fuyuki Yoshiko took revenge for
her son without hesitation.
After Kobayashi was killed, you dared
to treat your wife coldly
because you were afraid of the police
getting suspicious of you two.
So that you two don't look like the
parents succeeded in revenge.
Your neighbor was wondering why things were
getting worse between you two than before.
Even though the killing method was
written in that letter
that doesn't necessarily point out
who the culprit is.
- It's just a copy.
- Stop making a disgraceful excuse.
There's no evidence which proves who
actually committed the murders!
By now, our people are meeting with
your wife and Fuyuki Yoshiko-san.
For those mothers,
taking revenge was justice.
I'm sure that they won't be
able to keep lying.
No, they will choose not to keep lying.
Do you still have some business with me?
Excuse me.
This is Tsutsui. I found it.
Understood.
The original of that letter was found
in Fuyuki Yoshiko's apartment.
- Why?
- Fuyuki Yoshiko kept every single letter
which had been supporting her,
with great care.
If it was the letter that helped her take revenge
for her son, she would surely keep it as well.
It was you who investigated the surroundings and
behavior patterns of Tadokoro-san and Kobayashi-san
and also established the alibis.
Not only those mothers have never met
but they didn't know each
other's names or even the murder plan.
They just followed your instructions.
Was this copy of the letter the sign of
your revenge against the police
- which couldn't arrest your daughter's murderer?
- Captain, you're wrong.
This letter is nothing like a war trophy or
the sign of revenge.
This is the evidence to protect
the mothers.
To protect the mothers?
He dared to keep the evidence in order to prove
that he planned and led two murders
in the unlikely event that the mothers were
arrested by the police.
I guess it didn't matter whether I
kept this or not in the end.
Since my plan...
ended in complete failure.
Get a hold of yourself! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Who's going to pass judgment on that man,
if the law won't do it?
Who's going to end this hell for me?
She was already at her limit.
No matter how many times I stop my wife,
she'll surely kill Koboyashi someday.
Just because you couldn't stop your wife
why would you plan the murders after
knowing everything about crime?
There are limits in what the police and the
judiciary can do.
I had no choice but to save her
from suffering.
Don't be stupid! You just committed murder
using your knowledge.
To avenge your daughter's death and
archive your wife's revenge.
That's just self-satisfaction of the
murderer and a pathetic excuse.
How would you know the feelings of
parents whose child was killed?
We're in hell every single day and even
though we don't want the future anymore
we're forced to continue living while our
hearts are stabbed by the invisible knives.
Do you really think you can understand
how we feel?
He laughed.
When we passed each other in the corridor
of the police station, he laughed at us.
Lust murder? Don't talk rubbish!
We won't stand having our daughter
killed for pleasure!
What you're experiencing must be
as bitter as death.
It must be like living in hell.
But revenge creates only a
cycle of retaliation.
While being the victim's family,
you created another victim's family!
You're just a murderer.
I'm sorry, Keisuke!
I'm so sorry.
I don't regret what I've done.
The only regret I have is that I couldn't
save my daughter.
That's all.
Niijima Haruna and Fuyuki Yoshiko.
They both confessed.
Perhaps, the cause of the crime is much
more of a familiar thing than we think.
Hey! What's this?
Where are the others?
Oh, they went home.
You should have told me if you were coming
to say good-bye.
That's not it! What's wrong with them, even
though I went to the trouble of coming here?
[Don't look.]
What's this?
[Thank you very much for everything!]
[Yurine Tomohisa]
[Namu Shaka Muni Butsu.]
[Bon appetit.]
[Go away already!]
What the heck are these?
Don't you have something
I could use?
Hey! Akagi, what are you doing?
Hey!
- If you have no use, I'll use them.
- Give me back! Give me back! Give back!
- Tsutsui!
- Yes.
These guys are just hopeless.
This is what I get after taking care
of them for two years, you know?
That's a great weight off my mind.
I feel sorry that
you're going to have a hard time!
I'll be sure to suffer!
Kikukawa-san, thank you very much!
A criminal psychologist,
who became a monster.
There are limits in what the police and
the judiciary can do.
Someone who's closely related to the crime
should be more careful not to
commit a crime or to become a monster.
It's the same with the police officer.
I may become...
Akagi-san won't become a monster.
- Why can you say something like that?
- I'll make sure to stop you.
As for you, Captain... I will...
Subtitles by DramaFever