Who the hell is he?.
He's a friend I can vouch for him.
He's here to help.
He's from Consolidated Goldfields.
To talk about fund raising for our
schools programme.
We didn't ask for his hand-outs.
- Leave him be!. Let him be!.
I've waited a long time
for this opportunity, Doctor.
Likewise, sir.
A! W! B!
Good night, Doctor.
- Good night.
The departmental conference
is postponed, professor.
We know exactly what's going on
in the UK...
between you and
the ANC thugs professor.
Think carefully before going next time
or learn to sleep with your eyes open.
yes, I understand well.
Are you absolutely sure?.
We can't put it like that.
yes, it's important, but
it's a waste of time.