Watch and Download App at official site FastDrama.Co to support us
What about my daughter-in-law?
The girl...
that Ji Seok is married to is...
I'll contact you when we get back.
Watch your mouth until then.
What about her?
She's my...
(Tae Ran)
Go Ya's wedding went well.
I thought you should at least see some pictures.
What do you think you're doing?
Continue with what you were saying.
What about the girl that Ji Seok is married to?
I know what this is about.
Na Ra put you up to this.
She wanted you to find out about the girl...
that Ji Seok married.
Well, it's not that.
Go tell her.
Tell her that she's a great girl...
and makes Ji Seok very happy,
so you two can stay out of their lives.
- What? - Make sure...
you tell her that.
Sa Ra.
I mean, Ms. Oh!
What's going on?
Sa Ra, Ms. Oh!
This is driving me crazy.
She's my sister-in-law and my in-law. My gosh.
- That way. - I see.
Ji Seok, are you okay?
I'm fine.
You're sweating.
- Does your stomach hurt? - Yes, a bit.
This isn't good. Let's go see a doctor.
I'm fine. I can take it.
Let's go...
Ji Seok. My gosh.
Does it hurt a lot?
What do I do? Ji Seok.
Ji Seok got married today.
Seriously.
I can't believe I didn't know about this.
Darn it.
Goodness, why does she keep calling me?
Yes, what?
I called you so many times. Why didn't you pick up?
I didn't hear it. What is it?
Can you come out now?
Goodness.
The garden is a huge mess.
It's just like how that guy tore my heart out.
Ji Seok, why does it have to be you?
Darn him. He must be crazy.
I can't believe that guy.
- What? - Are you still angry...
- that you weren't invited? - What do you want?
- I'm not in the mood to talk. - Did you see the pictures?
The wedding went very well. I hope you feel better.
It ended well thanks to me.
If it wasn't for me, they wouldn't have gotten married.
- I was going to ruin it. - Don't say that.
Your daughter finally found her happiness.
The least you can do is to give her your blessings.
I'm not in a situation to bless her.
Do you even know who Go Ya is married to?
Why wouldn't I know?
He's from a rich family and has a good job.
He's also handsome.
What do kids these days call guys like him again?
Right, he's like a luxurious sedan.
He's not a beat-up car like you.
- What? How dare you say that? - Don't be so sour.
You saw how happy she is in those pictures.
She smiled so much all day today.
I never knew that she had...
such a great smile.
She could never smile because of what you've done,
but she finally got her smile back.
Just give her your blessings, will you?
You don't even know anything. Hey, Tae Ran.
The guy Go Ya married is Oh Na Ra's nephew.
You're the one who would be the angriest if you found out.
Goodness.
Anyway, what do I do now?
My sister-in-law is about to be my in-law.
What kind of a disrupted family is this?
My goodness.
You dropped this.
It's been a while.
Indeed.
- Are you eating here? - I'm leaving now.
I have someone waiting for me.
Sorry.
- Hello. - I'm late, right?
Couldn't you come a bit earlier?
Why?
Your ex-husband was here until a moment ago.
I know. I saw him outside.
Really?
Then did you see the woman he was with too?
- "Woman"? - He was with a woman.
He couldn't stop smiling.
- They must be together. - Hey.
What's the big deal?
I'm married to another man now.
He should get married too.
I'm sorry it took so long.
I ran into my ex-wife.
I see. What?
Your ex-wife?
Yes.
Are you okay?
You had a hard time getting over her.
I sometimes thought about...
what I should do...
if I ever run into her.
But it was hard to imagine.
Just by imagining it, I couldn't even breathe.
I understand.
I also can't breathe when I see my ex-husband with his new wife.
I feel betrayed because I trusted him.
But it wasn't as painful as I had expected.
Really? That's good.
I think it's because you're here with me.
- What? - Because I knew...
you were waiting for me outside,
I somehow felt at ease.
It's a good thing that you were with me...
when I ran into my ex-wife.
Let's go then.
I'm sorry we had to miss our flight.
Didn't you hear what the doctor said?
You might have collapsed if you had got on board.
I don't want to become a widow.
Stomach cramps aren't that serious.
And I'm okay now.
I feel better after getting a sedative at the emergency room.
Did something stressful happen at the wedding?
- What? - I mean,
that's what the doctor guessed.
I've been worried too.
You looked fine this morning,
but you started to look so troubled right before the wedding.
I did?
Did something happen?
What made you so stiff?
Of course I became stiff.
I've been right next to this beautiful lady all day.
- I'm being serious now. - I'm being serious too.
Let's find another flight tomorrow.
That's absurd. We're not going anywhere.
The doctor said you needed good rest.
I won't be able to rest next to you anyway.
My heart will beat too fast.
Do as I say.
You might feel some pain for the next few days,
and you might get more cramps.
We're staying here.
Are you saying we're spending our honeymoon here?
Why not? It's nice here.
We can see the sky and sea, and you're with me too.
I'm sorry. We'll go on another trip soon.
Let me make up for this time.
- Okay. - Let's go out on the beach.
No. You need some rest.
Come here.
All right.
Get some sleep, okay?
You know what?
I read somewhere that you look like the person...
you loved the most in your past life.
In my next life, I'll probably look like you.
I'll...
look like you then.
Guess what I'll do in three seconds.
3, 2, 1.
How did we miss each other so much?
We've always been so nearby
Go Bong.
Gosh!
Did we sleep together?
No. That's impossible.
You brat.
- What happened last night? - What do you mean?
Do you have to stay out the night before your sister's wedding?
Let me explain.
Explain what?
Where did you sleep last night?
At Yeon Hee's.
I can't believe her.
How could she let you sleep there...
when your sister is getting married the next day?
Well,
it turns out that the man she fell in love with...
is her brother-in-law's brother.
Does she want to get married to him?
She can't?
Of course not. That's absurd.
- Why? - Why?
It becomes too complicated.
It's not like he is the only man in the world.
She's right. Your sister won't be just your sister,
but she'll be your brother-in-law's wife too.
It doesn't end there.
It'll be the same...
on the man's side too.
It's making my head spin.
Tell her to break up with him before her parents collapse.
Mom, would that make you collapse too?
Why would I?
Before that happens,
I'd break my daughter's legs.
By the way, where have you been?
Me? I just wandered around a bit.
Were you feeing empty after Go Ya's wedding?
Why would I feel empty?
She got married to a nice man.
- What's that? - What?
It's nothing.
Then why are you hiding it?
- What is it? Show us. - Show us.
It's really nothing.
What?
What's with her? Is she afraid we'll take it away from her?
She probably did some shopping.
Exactly. It's not like...
she received flowers from a man or anything.
My goodness.
Go Ya.
Be happy.
It's beautiful here.
Do you know this poem?
"I wait for you..."
"not because I want to,"
"but because I have no choice but to do so."
"While waiting for you,"
"the pain makes me put on weight,"
"and the longing makes me grow taller."
You know it.
That's not the only thing I know.
Since I met you,
I've learned what it means to have no choice but to wait for someone.
The pain and longing has made me...
grow too, I think.
Love has got us through it all.
It will from now on too.
No matter what awaits us.
It's been a while.
Indeed.
Right.
He must have known Ji Seok was getting married.
Was he at the wedding?
Tae Ran?
Isn't she Tae Pyung's sister?
Tae Pyung, here are a few more pictures of Go Ya.
Pictures of Go Ya?
Why are you looking at my phone?
You.
Since when were you so close with your sister?
- What? - Why is your sister...
sending you Choi Go Ya's pictures?
Did you see them?
Give it to me. Let me see what she sent you.
- No. - Give it to me.
Fine. One second.
My goodness.
Hey, I pressed the wrong button and deleted everything.
How can you come up with such an obvious lie?
Did you whine to your sister...
and said you missed her?
- No. - Why didn't you...
ask her to send you Woo Yang Sook's pictures too?
That's nonsense. It's not like that.
I don't care about her.
Tae Ran just keeps on sending me these.
Darn it, I hate everything.
Seriously.
My gosh, this is driving me crazy.
(Tae Ran)
Hey! Stop sending me these!
Do you want to see me dead?
My goodness, what's with him?
Why would he act like that when I just sent those pictures...
because he whined about not getting invited?
- Aunt. - What brings you here?
Can I take some kimchi?
I moved out to a studio near my cafe.
- Take some. - Where are you going?
Upstairs. The newlyweds' room.
I want to come too.
Nonsense. They haven't even seen the room yet.
You can't come.
Take your kimchi, and go.
She's so cheap.
- Goodness, stop following me. - One second.
You can't come into the newlyweds' place.
My gosh, why is she so strong?
I know I asked him to bring someone to share the bed with,
but you brought someone like her.
I was feeling complicated enough,
but that guy made it even worse.
Mother, we've arrived well.
We'll lead a happy life.
And next time, let's come here together.
(Go Ya)
She doesn't even mean that.
Fine. At least she's not his daughter.
Who cares if she filed a suit against her dad?
It's not like she's his daughter.
Have some.
- Did you do it? - Why aren't they eating?
Okay.
Good.
It's been a difficult journey.
So make sure you two live happily ever after.
- Yes. - Yes.
And don't take each other for granted because you're family.
Always treat each other with respect.
Someone once said this.
"If you think of your wife as a business partner..."
"and not your wife,"
"you can treat her with more respect."
Yes, I'll remember that, Mother.
You too.
Yes, Mom.
So how was the honeymoon?
- Where did you go again? Pa... - Palau.
I heard Milky Way Bay is really beautiful there.
What?
Oh, yes. It was.
- Show us some pictures. - Yes, show us.
Well,
we were really out of it, so we couldn't take any pictures.
Of course.
I'm sure you didn't have any time to go sightseeing.
During a honeymoon trip, all you want to do is...
My goodness.
- Come on, Tae Ran. - Mom!
What? I'm just saying that those are the good times.
My gosh.
As you know, our family is very talkative.
- I love it. - I'm glad then.
They must be hungry.
- San Deul, come get the table. - Okay.
She made some braised ribs for you and Ji Seok.
Thank you, Mother.
- Is this little girl you? - Yes.
- Is this your high school picture? - You can't see this.
- Why not? - This was back when I was...
a bit fat. It's embarrassing.
Okay. I'll close my eyes. You can take that out.
Hey, you can't see that.
What? You look pretty.
You've never been ugly in your life, have you?
How many girls did you hit on with that line?
What do you think of me? I'm not that easy.
I'm very reserved.
Do reserved men say things like, "What's your religion?"
"What do you have to believe..."
"to be so pretty?"
I really wanted to know.
I wondered what you had to believe to be this pretty.
So why don't we...
It's so inappropriate to do that here.
Put those lips away.
- Go Ya. - Hey, Go Woon.
- Goodness. - Go Woon, what is it?
Come out, and have some fruit.
Oh, you can finish doing what you were doing.
My goodness.
We're leaving now.
Okay. I'll pack up some side dishes.
Why did you make so much food?
If I don't do this right, your mother-in-law...
will nitpick over the smallest things again.
She's really quick-tempered.
I'm afraid she'll give you a hard time.
- Don't worry. - I won't.
You aren't just going to let her bully you.
Be confident and stand up for yourself...
just as you did with me.
And if you have something to show off, do that.
You're good at that.
Letting everyone know about something you've done.
- Okay. - And...
if things get too hard, don't sit on it by yourself.
- Come talk to me. - Okay.
Don't forget to care for yourself while caring for others.
I'll visit often.
Okay. That's good news for me.
(Jang Ok Ja's Cooking Class)
- Goodness. - Are you insane?
Yes, you're driving me insane.
I can't believe I didn't know about Ji Seok's wedding.
You're unbelievable.
I was courteous enough to tell you...
that Ji Seok is getting married.
I'm his aunt.
I deserve to be at his wedding.
In your dreams.
You aren't welcome there.
You'll be nothing but a shame.
What did I do so wrong?
I have nothing to hide. I'm confident with myself.
What?
When is Ji Seok coming?
Why do you care?
I'm going to see him again.
Why can't we see each other? Who are you to tell him that?
When you see him,
I hope you tell him...
that you broke someone else's family.
- Sa Ra. - You're confident?
How can you feel so confident?
Do you feel confident about living with a guy like Tae Pyung...
after dumping a great guy like Jae Woong?
Do you not feel ashamed regarding the child...
that Tae Pyung's wife had at that time?
Do you not feel ashamed for breaking their family?
- Sa Ra. - If not those,
do you really feel confident in front of me,
who brought you up like your mom?
When I tried to stop you as you left me,
you told me this.
"Stop being so clingy."
Why are you so clingy now?
You should stop being so clingy about Ji Seok.
Unbelievable.
The person you have reached is not available.
- Please leave a message... - I can't believe this.
Ji Seok, it's me, your aunt.
I need to see you for a minute. Please.
I have something to tell you.
My gosh.
Darn it.
All right.
Mom, where is the cake?
Didn't you say you were going to get a cake?
I dropped and ruined it because of my sister.
- Was Aunt here? - Yes.
She threw a tantrum...
about not being invited to Ji Seok's wedding.
We're welcoming our new family member today.
Exactly. I can't stand her.
Please don't say anything...
in front of Go Ya.
I don't want her to know about Ji Seok's aunt.
And Ji Seok will feel bad if he finds out she was here.
They must be here.
Did you enjoy your honeymoon?
Yes. We had a lot of fun.
Ji Seok, didn't you eat well?
You look so thin.
I was so happy that I didn't need any food.
Gosh, you're making me cringe. Stop it.
Exactly.
What's with him?
What are you talking about? I think it's cute.
I heard your little brother...
is Eun Seok's student.
Yes. It surprised me too.
I had no idea you were Go Woon's teacher.
Neither did I.
Go Woon used to say his eldest sister's future husband...
would be the luckiest person in the world.
I didn't know it'd be my brother.
What are you talking about?
Ji Seok's wife is the one...
who would be the luckiest person in the world.
I'm not saying this because he is my son,
but your husband is an amazing man.
Yes. And I have you to thank for that.
You got my point.
Your mom must feel empty after her sweet daughter's wedding.
That's why I should be a nice son-in-law.
You're making me cringe again.
Hey. Where did my smart son go?
He sounds so silly now.
What do you mean?
It's nice to see him in love.
What? "That's why I should be a nice son-in-law."
I'm the one he should be nice to,
not his wife's mom.
That woman is so vulgar.
Mom, she is your in-law now.
Stay for dinner.
I ate too much already. I'm not that hungry.
I've seen Ji Seok and Go Ya now,
so I should get going.
- Already? - Yes.
Is something bothering you?
No. I'll get going then.
Welcome to our club.
Hello, sir.
Ask for Lady at the entrance.
(Lady)
(Trash)
- I miss you, Trash. - What?
Ask for Trash at the entrance.
(Lemon Balm Diet)
How did I end up here again?
(Slimedge Lemon Balm Diet)
He's not even calling me.
Is he cutting me off because we're in-laws now?
Just a second.
Are we far yet?
You can see now. Surprise.
What do you think? I chose everything in this room myself.
It's like you.
What do you mean?
I like it for no particular reason.
We're starting over here together.
It's finally starting to sink in that we're married.
I'm so happy...
to always have you by my side.
You must be tired after meeting so many people today.
Why don't you take a bath?
I have to go out for a while.
Is it something urgent?
There is something I have to take care of today.
Should I tell her or not?
If she finds out that her nephew is married to my daughter,
she'll faint.
But if she finds out that I've been keeping it from her,
it'll make her faint too.
Cake!
You startled me. What about it?
I'm sure Sa Ra was holding a cake...
when I saw her earlier.
It means...
Ji Seok is coming back from his honeymoon today.
Where are you going?
- I want to see Ji Seok. - Please don't do this.
You might collapse.
- Why? - What if...
you see Ji Seok's wife there?
What about her?
What's wrong?
Hold on.
- Hello. - This is Ji Seok.
Okay.
All right.
What is it?
Hold on.
I'll explain when I come back.
Honey.
Honey. Honey!
What's going on?
You jerk!
(Forever Enemies)
Why can't I see Ji Seok's wife?
I disappointed Mother on our first day here.
I'm looking for someone.
I'm being threatened.
Something doesn't feel right. I feel empty.
Ji Seok got married to Go Ya?
Please don't ask Ji Seok...
to give his kidney to your brother.
I want to be tested for the kidney transplant.