Verse 19
The worst of the Eight Hells
is called Continuous Hell
lt has the meaning of Continuous
Suffering. Thus the name
5 years ago
we started valet parking in Tuen Mun
We were full of ambition
But 2 weeks had hardly gone by
and the cops started busting us every day
Within one year
6 of our brothers died
Thanks to the Buddha, my life was spared
What thousands must die
so that Caesar may become great
But l don't believe in destiny
The rule of this game
is to take fate in our own hands
You are the newest in my gang
Your records are the cleanest
You can choose your own future
OK
l wish you guys
every success in the police force
Bottoms up, officers
27 1 49, you were here 1 0 minutes ago
How many files were on my desk?
Six, sir. Four beige ones on the left
one red and one white on the right
What do you think of me?
Sorry, l'm not sure, sir
But l know you're in a hurry today
'coz your socks don't match
27 1 49, you can go now
Yes, sir
You owe me $500
OK, but wait till pay day next month
l told you he would make the best
undercover cop
Now that you're in the cadet school
you should follow the rules
Those who break the rules will be
like him
They will be expelled
Who wants to trade place with him?
l do
27 1 49
this is a long-term undercover mission
Your records in the cadet school
will be erased
Only Superintendent Wong and
l know of your identity
This mission is highly dangerous
is that clear?
Yes, sir
Sir, l can't stand it any longer
l'm either harassed by cops
or beaten up by gangsters
4927, you are still a rookie
Give me a good reason
why l should promote you
Hang on?
Why don't you go hang yourself instead?
l won the Silver Whistle Award
at the cadet
and have received numerous kudos as
an officer
l am confident l can lead the police force
sir
Boss
OK, l got it
Move forward
Hurry up
Please go over there to take your mugshot
Excuse me
Can l try this stereo?
What speakers are you using?
Nothing special, any recommendations?
Try this tube amplifier
made in Hong Kong, 1 0,000 only
And use this cable, also locally made
about 1 000
The sound is as good as expensive
European amps
Sweet high notes, crisp middle
strong bass
ln a word, transparent
Come and listen
Human voices are drifting towards you
See that?
Voices are indeed drifting towards you
Try this one
This is ideal for listening to oldies
What do you think?
Much better indeed
Any discount if l buy the whole set?
Buy the tube amp here
but not the speakers
Go to Cheung Wai; it's cheaper there
Whom should l ask for?
Just tell them Yan sent you
Which one is mine?
The one in the middle
Okay, thanks
You're welcome
ls Cheung Wai open yet?
Sure
You bastard
l told you to watch the store
not to send my customers away
But your speakers are over-priced
lf l don't sell them at this price
how can l afford to pay ''protection money''?
You can try not paying for a change
Hey, the cable
l'll return it in a few days
$4,000 for a few days?
Where are you rushing to?
A funeral
Tell me
How many times have you been busted
for assault?
l am trying to convince
the Department of Justice
that you need to see a shrink
But you keep on beating people up
Are you really going nuts?
Have you forgotten you're a cop?
You told me it's only for 3 years
But after 3 years come another 3 years
and another
lt's almost 1 0 years already, boss
Can't you be a bit more courteous to me?
l'm the only one in Hong Kong
who knows your real identity now
Maybe l'll just erase your file
so you can stick with the Triads for good
What do you want me to do?
Remind myself l'm a cop every day?
Shouting ''Drop your gun, l'm a cop''
even in my dreams?
When will Sam place his order?
No idea
Sometime this week
What?
The Thais are here
Once the goods arrive
Sam will resell them
Where is the warehouse?
How the hell do l know?
l started working for him only 3 years ago
OK, l'll let you retire after this
Bullshit
l heard this a zillion times already
Shit. These mikes again?
The Police is loaded with cash
Tell them to get more advanced models
How about implanting it into your body?
lnto which part of my body?
A pinhole camera?
Where's the lens?
Your birthday is on the 25th, right?
l never wear watches
lf we got nothing for the lnterpol by 5pm
the counterfeit passport case is off
3:1 5. Tea time
What would you like, boss?
Tea with milk, please
They won't talk without their attorney
Has paged their lawyers
but he hasn't called back yet
l won't talk without my attorney
l am Mr. Lau, your attorney
Did you call home?
Why should l call home?
lt's good then
Where were you last friday
from 3:45 to 5:00 pm?
Brother Mo told me to ask you
if your family needs any help
No need to look around
They won't record anything
when a lawyer is present
lt's not admissible in court anyway
Brother Mo sent you?
Those 2 kids next door
have squealed on the workshop already
Cops are heading there now
Brother Mo told you not to say anything
lf your brother is there
tell him to leave right away
Here
What?
Scram
l ask you to scram, do you hear?
Scram right away
All right. l'll leave you
lf you don't trust me, so be it
Take care
Remember
don't talk without your attorney
l don't need you to tell me that
Fanny
Yes?
Take this
Check this number
Sure
Send this message for me
Cheung Fai lndustrial Building, 2nd Floor
OK
Boss
All set
A Triad member
Where's my tea?
Here
Thanks
You're great
How did you know it's Mo's hideout?
Thanks
Hello, yes
No problem. OK
Sorry guys, over time tonight
Our target tonight is a drug trafficking
cartel
ln an hour's time
they will be trading with a Thai seller
Cash will be handed over in the building
across the street
in a unit on the 3rd floor
Where the goods will be delivered is
still unknown
ClB shall tag the target
and tap the phone lines
Our unit will not take action till
our mole has pinned down the delivery location
Let's take a look at our principal stars
Here are our principal stars tonight:
Hon Sam, Chen Wing-yan, Del Piero
We've been watching them for a long time
We'd better nail them tonight
OK? No more questions?
Let's get to work
Sorry for paging you so urgently
But our mission is kept confidential till
the last moment
No problem
Do you have confidence?
Yes, it should be OK
Hello, Dad
Pass the phone to Dad
l can't come home for dinner
Too bad
Dinner has been prepared already
Call me when you're back
l'll heat it up for you
You look so relaxed
lt's only work
We can always work on it next time
Sorry
All cell phone signals in this area
are under surveillance
SP Wong
SP Wong, which channel?
Channel 454870
Attention. Our prey is in sight
Big Brother
Boss
Take out all your cell phones
You two, go get the car
Wait
Yan
escort the Thais here
You two, follow me
Lau
Yes
Did Sam and his gang make any calls?
No. They probably changed their phones
Let's search randomly for calls
made from this area
Searching
Some 6,500 cell phones
are being connected in this area right now
267 cell phones are making calls
on this street alone
Give me 1 0 minutes
Good
Thank you
Did they spot us?
Are those two over there watching us?
Which two?
Those two
No one is watching you
Those two making out over there
They are just making out
Why would they be watching you?
You think you're a movie star?
Our prey is back
Yip, watch our prey closely
Boss. The Thais are here
Hey man
What's up?
How are you?
Cigar?
ls that any good?
Excellent
ls it cold in Hong Kong?
Very cold
You even know how to speak Cantonese
How fantastic
Marvelous indeed
AA+
Deal
Automobile license plate number HN397
is taking off
Repeat, Helen, Nelson
HN397 is taking off
Attention. HN397 is taking off
Repeat, Helen, Nelson, 397
Should we send a car to tail them?
Elephant
Kwai Chung Container Terminus
Roger
Piero. You're being tailed
Lead them in circles
They know which channel we are on
Switch to channel 456855
Boss, where are those two going?
Don't worry, take it easy
Take care of the Thais for me
Sorry, sir
Hello?
Why don't you use the walkie talkie?
We've switched channels?
Are you done yet?
Beat it
Piero, are you being tailed?
Keep driving around
Cheung
Use the current channel to tell Elephant
that action has been cancelled
Yes, sir
Elephant, no hunting tonight
Come back to the station
lt's done
What the hell is going on?
Our guys are freezing to death out there
What's so funny?
l speak Thai. l know what they're saying
Really?
Yes. They are bitching at the boss
What are they bitching about?
Those Thais at Lung Koo Bay
are freezing to death
You know they can't stand the cold
That's right
You're sharp
Cheung, call Elephant
Goods to be delivered at Lung Koo Bay
Boss, l found it
Tell Keung to check the goods
And make sure no one is around
Not a soul
A boat is approaching
Probably for checking the goods
The cocaine is all here
Keung, are you an idiot or what?
Boss
l heard it
Tell Keung to shout a loud
that the cocaine is his
Keung, the Boss
asks you to shout aloud that the cocaine
is yours
The cocaine is yours
Take delivery
They are taking delivery
Get ready for action
Thanks. Thanks
Thank you
Double Eight
As soon as the Thais step out, arrest them
There's a stooge. Stop the deal
Wait
Hello?
Cast all the goods into the sea. Now
Keung. Cast all the goods into the sea
Police. Freeze
We got the men but lost the goods
They have cast everything into the sea
Double Eight, hold it
All of you, follow me
What are you looking at?
Boss. Let's...
Police, don't move
Sam
Your food looks good
Not bad
We've straightened it out
Your boys are only strolling on the beach
So they can go now?
Sure, any time
We don't want to waste any more of
your precious time
We've known each other for so long
Don't give me that
l haven't had my dinner here
for quite a while
lf you like it, you're always welcome here
How about tomorrow?
l'll take a rain check
l feel bad coming here empty-handed
Don't stand on ceremonies
l' should feel bad
for making you drop several grand
tonight
You think planting a mole in us will do
us in?
Same here
l remember a story
Two fools are waiting for their
kidney transplants
but only one kidney is available
The two guys thus play a game
They each put a playing card
into the other's pocket
Whoever guesses the card in his own
pocket wins
You know l can see your card
l think so too
l will beat you
Let's see
We should be more careful
l will
By the way
whoever loses the game will die
Let's see when you're gonna die
Ever seen someone shakes
a corpse's hand?
Let's go
Put it next to the couch
OK
Thanks
Mary
What's interior designer's number?
The interior designer... 9025504 7
How many boxes have l counted?
24? Are you sure?
Positive
Pass me the phone
Coming
Hello?
Hold on please
Who is it?
l don't know
Hello
lt's me
Yes, l'm moving in
Don't eavesdrop. lt's confidential
l lost all of my goods
There's a mole
Dig him out for me
Hold on, too many people around here
Hold on
l have no access to those undercover files
l can't dig him out
l don't care how difficult it is
l only know he uses Morse codes
Give me all the information on the people
around you last night
Their real names, lD card no.
account no., etc
See you tonight, at the cinema
OK
What's the matter?
l'm talking about my novel
l know what l'm going to write about
Come here
l can write about a man with 28 different
personalities
Are you talking about me?
Be more serious
Think about it
A man with 28 personalities
That means he starts role playing
the minute he wakes up
He is no longer certain
which personality is the real him
lsn't it scary?
Very much
Good?
Yeah. Will be a bestseller for sure
Wait...
What is it?
Why is the ottoman so big?
Which one?
l must have gotten the measurements
wrong
Take it easy
You women...
Let me see. Get up slowly
Don't be mad
Meet up?
You want me dead?
There's a mole in the police station
Dig him out first
So who is he?
l can't talk anymore
What?
Just now?
l was at a Chinese chiropractor
l'm seeing the shrink now
l'm going psycho. That's it
This chair is really... incredible
You should get one for yourself?
So you don't need to come here
and sleep every time
lt's more comfortable here
Don't be so peevish
During these 4 months, if it weren't for me
you wouldn't have the time to play
lt's 5 months
computer games
ln one more month
your mandatory therapy will be over
You can sleep peacefully at home then
So soon?
l don't seem to have improved at all
Why don't you just prolong my treatment
Besides, my head is splitting these days
Could it be schizophrenia?
This is called ''headache''
l'll prescribe some Panadol for you
Actually
there's something l want to ask you
but...
it's kind of embarrassing
What do you think of me?
Do you think l'm a good guy or a bad guy?
l hardly know who you are
Tell you a secret, but don't tell anyone
l'm actually a cop
So am l
Let's continue next week
Try to remember your dreams
Of course
l will dream about you
See you next week
Just Panadol?
Bye
Your promotion should be OK
You will be transferred to lnternal Affairs
but you will work at OCTB
l don't understand
l suspect Sam has a mole
in the department
l want you to investigate
Why me?
We have scrutinized all possible
candidates
You have an immaculate record
You have solved many cases in ClB
Working in lA, you will get in touch
with senior officials
That's a good opportunity
l've arranged for you to appear on TV
Remember to spruce up a bit
When will l meet the Board?
You just did
Come, take a stab
Thanks
By the way
how's the wedding?
Everything's on schedule
That's good
You'll be more stable after marriage
Your image will improve too
You have chance of further promotion
Yes, broaden your horizon
Fill in your real name
This is my real name
You don't know Del Piero is my real name?
ls that so?
Yes
What are you guys writing?
The Boss told us to fill in these forms
Must be setting up mandatory
provident funds for us
You know, MPF
Are you serious?
You don't know to spell BOD YGUARD?
lsn't it supposed to look like this?
Of course not
Should be B-O-D-Y-G-A-R-D
That's it
A shipment will come in next week
They are watching closely
You do what you need to do
l'll handle the rest
The file is open. l'm afraid l can't handle it
So you're not worried about me
You are worried about yourself
lnspector Lau
Those girls are so ugly
l'll take care of it as soon as l can
Hello?
l'm on my way back
Yan
How long have you worked for me?
3 or 4 years already
That long?
Doesn't seem that long to me
l have another shipment next week
But this time
l'm using some tough, new faces
So you guys can rest
Even Keung and the others?
Keung?
Don't you know he's nuts?
There's a mole within us. You know that?
What do you think we should do?
l'll take care of it
How?
l'll find out who he is in a couple of days
Get ready for action
Yan
Of all the brothers, l trust you the most
Lau
No, thanks
These folks
You know most of them
no need for introduction, right?
No, but...
they are so...
Who doesn't know you're sent here
to find the mole?
What do you want them to do?
Pour you a cup of coffee?
Only an idiot will not be envied, right?
They all want to know who the mole is
Just tell me whom you want to investigate
OK
Any clues?
Two days ago, my informer
nearly found out who he was
Too bad he lost him
But if Sam is getting a new shipment
he must contact the mole again
Just follow Sam and we'll get
what we want
That's right. l've much to learn from you
Don't say that
Our seniors sent you here
because they think you can do it
Not everyone can handle lA tasks
lt's stuffy here
Let's get out of here
The coffee here is the best
in the headquarters
l'll pour you a cup
My informer nearly found out
who the mole was
But if Sam is getting a new shipment
he must contact the mole again
Yes?
Hey
The bed has arrived
ls that so? Comfortable?
You want to try it?
Don't be silly. l have work to do
Think about it
No, l can't
Come on
Saturday
l'll be free next Saturday
We can try it then
OK
OK, next Saturday then
Bye
Up already?
Yes
We just tested the bed
and you are working again?
l'm very hardworking
What are you writing now?
Here
The more l think of it, the more
pathetic the main character appears
Pathetic indeed
Perhaps l should make him a happier guy
Good
Should l turn him into a good guy?
Even though he is good
he has done bad things
So how should it end?
That's a good question
l'll leave this to you writers
You're not going to sleep?
Help me, please
Help me, please?
l can't
Go to sleep. You are tired
From now on
follow SP Wong around the clock
Piero, l know how to spot a plainclothes
How?
lf he seems to be doing something
but is paying attention to us instead
then he is a cop
ls that so?
Then the whole place is filled with cops
They're everywhere
Yan
Boss
Watching something?
You are a cop
We are guessing who a cop is
How trivial
l'm going for a massage, wanna come?
l hate it
Don't tell
Tell on him
l won't
What a coincidence
Yes, l was shopping in the hood
Haven't seen you for ages
6 or 7 years already
How are you?
l'm married. How about you?
Still working in...?
Mommy
Your daughter?
Yes
How old is she?
5 years old
l'm waiting for my husband's car, so...
l'm also in a hurry
Bye
Mommy, l'm 6 already
Sorry, l always get it wrong
Where are you now?
On my way
Hello?
Boss, he is taking the subway
Keep following him
Boss, he has gone to the 24th floor
Stay put. Don't do anything rash
Boss, we've got him
l don't know yet
But l know where he is now
Keep watch over here
So? Any good news?
A shipment will come in next week
Time and location yet to be confirmed
l still don't know who Sam's mole is
but he seems confident he can blow
my cover
ln that case
we'd better stop it
We're gonna lose for sure
You are kidding, right?
What else can we do? lt's deadly business
Hello?
Boss said he had found the mole
He told us to take care of him
l'll be right there
Hello?
Keep an eye on SP Wong
You two, take the stairs
Keung, take the elevator
Anyone knows you're seeing me today?
No
They are downstairs now
What are you doing?
Put it away
Take the window-washing scaffolding
How about you?
l'll take the elevator
Be careful
- Hey
- What?
Nothing
Darling, the apartment is superb
A 1 80-degree window facing
the golf course
plus club membership costs less than
a million
Superintendent Wong?
Turn around to the main entrance
What do you think of me?
Your birthday is on the 25th, right?
Let's go
Police. Let's go
Bad news, Boss
Something happened to SP Wong
There's a gunfight in Sheung Wan
this afternoon
Three suspects were dead;
several suspects and pedestrians
were injured
The police confirmed that
one of the victims
was superintendent in OCTB
Mr. Wong Chi-shing
The motive is unknown
Possibility of gang feud is not ruled out
They are now after several triad members
active in the Southern Kowloon area
The Police Commissioner
expressed condolence
and pledged to solve the case
as soon as possible
lt was a close shave
1 0 minutes after you went to your massage
Boss told us to get ready
l was scared stiff
You know
l hide under the car in every fight
And there were guns up there
l wanted to sneak out of there
Two days ago
Boss told me to go to his room
He asked me how long l'd worked for him
How the hell could l remember?
He then said: Keung
it's been 5 years already
You've performed well all these years
l have a question for you
lf one of your brothers is a mole
will you dare to take him out?
Of course l said yes to his face
You think l'm an idiot?
What's the result?
Of course they couldn't find the mole
The cop was tough
They dragged him upstairs
and beat him up for a good 1 0 minutes
1 0 minutes...
He didn't say a word
Keung
Boss said...
the cop was hot on his trail
Who didn't show up today is the mole
l didn't...
tell him you went for a massage
lf Boss knew, you're dead meat
Yan, l want to ask you something
How was the masseuse today?
Because...
if she's ugly, it's not worth it
Leave right away
There will be lots of cops after a car crash
Anyway, remember this:
if you see someone
doing something
but at the same time watching you...
then he is a cop
According to the closed-circuit TV
SP Wong entered that building at 4:1 5 pm
The suspects entered 20 minutes later
At 4:38 pm
we received lnspector Lau's report
8 minutes before we arrived
someone fell off the building
That was SP Wong
All the suspects killed or
injured belong to Sam's gang
Many suspects escaped
The actual numbers are unknown
Do you know why SP Wong went to
that building?
lt was me
l told ClB to follow him
Why was ClB following him?
That's lA's business
Now that SP Wong is dead
it is OCTB's business
What kind of attitude is that?
SP Wong was dedicated to the police force
and you investigated him?
What kind of attitude is that?
So we senior officers have to ask
for your approval, huh?
Your people have made a mistake now
Or SP Wong wouldn't have died
l am talking business here
l am talking personal matters
Nobody wanted this, OK?
Sorry, sir
lt's my negligence
l will give everybody an answer
Sorry
SP Wong has a file
with information on our undercover
in Sam's gang
lt is locked by a password
The technical staff can't decipher it
lnspector Lau
Yes
Work with ClB
to unlock it
Find our man and get him out of there
By the way
SP Wong was a good cop
We should give him a grand funeral
Okay?
Yes, sir
Hello?
Boss. Why made such a scene?
He was following me all the time
One of us would have to die
l'm now in charge of everything here
lf you're having any transactions
just let me know
lt's done
We got the goods when they killed
the cop today
l won't bother you now
What did you call me for?
So you're the one?
Who are you?
lnspector Lau of OCTB
SP Wong is gone. We're all upset
l still have unfinished business
SP Wong wouldn't want you to
take law in your own hands
What do you want?
Co-operation
The police has discovered
the body of a fugitive suspect
He was involved in
the Sheung Wan shooting earlier today
The police has confirmed
the body to be an undercover cop
Tsui Wai-keung
The police has expressed their condolence
and promised a thorough investigation
Boss, Yan is back
Three vehicles collided in Yuen Long
today
The driver of the private car was trapped
until firefighters came and rescued him
Boss
What is it, Yan?
l have taken care of Keung already
Did you ever send him to the warehouse?
lt will be disastrous if he knows where it is
Boss. lt's me
You don't have to go yourself
l don't want anyone to know the password
l understand
l'll send everyone away
lnspector Cheung
Tell those boys to stop following
Sam's gang
l got information that Sam is heading
towards the warehouse
He won't go if he's being tailed
Just call them back
Let's do something for SP Wong
Please help me, OK?
Say something
This is not my case
Officer Chan told me not to get involved
lf they're willing to stop
then it's up to them
l know l'm responsible for
SP Wong's death
l am also a cop, like you
l want to solve the case too
l thought you only want promotion
lt's SP Wong's mole who tipped me off
Do you believe it or not?
This is our last chance
Are you ready to take the risk?
Attention: Target vehicle
on Highway no.3
U-turn at Pier 3
to Lung Cheung Road
They have been here for 20 minutes
they are going to the 4th floor of
the car park
Officer Chan won't let me touch this case
lf anything goes wrong
you'll take the blame
They are loading the goods at 4P
Elephant, stand by at the exit at 3P
Double Eight, watch the entrance at 2P
Fishball and Cheung, stand by here
All of you, wait for my signal
Oh, l forgot Boss told me to stay behind
Drop me off here
Run him over
My Master always said that about my life:
What thousands must die so that
Caesar may become great
You choose your own future
That's what you have chosen
Coffee for you
He's waited a long time for you
So it's you?
Was the stereo OK?
Pretty good
Those tube amps have to be warmed up
Wait 1 0 minutes and it sounds great
Should l salute you?
Not, don't
How long have you been an undercover?
l've followed Sam for 3 years
l had several other bosses before
All together it's been 1 0 years
1 0 years?
l should salute you instead
l just want an identity
l want to be a normal man
Getting tired?
You've never been a mole
you won't understand
Too bad l still can't find the stooge
l'll take him down if l find him
Don't worry
Let me give you back your identity
l'll open your file but...
l don't have the password
What's the Morse code for
''undercover''?
That's it?
Are you serious?
You don't even know to
spell BOD YGUARD?
lsn't it supposed to look like this?
Of course not
Dr. Lee
l thought you wouldn't come
You're wanted by the police
Can l sleep in your chair again?
Let's talk upstairs
Last time you said you're a cop
ls it true?
lt was true
But l'm not so sure now
So what's your plan?
l don't know. Still thinking
There's one thing l've been trying to
tell you for a while
But it's too embarrassing
l told you l dreamt about you all the time
lt's true
Me too
Remember my secret. Goodbye
Mary
What is it? Has it broken down?
This morning
the guys from the stereo shop came
They have tuned it up already
They also left a CD sampler for you
l've listened to it
Have you had breakfast yet?
l'll get you some
lced tea?
Chinese buns?
Sure
l can't finish my novel
l don't know whether he's good or bad
l think only he knows
A shipment will come in next week
They are watching closely
You do what you need to do
l will handle the rest
The file is open. l can't handle it
So you're not worried about me
You are worried about yourself
lnspector Lau
Are the voices crisp enough?
The precious recording
was taken from Sam's office
lt's not your lucky day
Don't threaten me. What do you want?
l want my identity back
3 pm, Central Ferry Pier
Keep your cell on
The number you have dialed cannot be
connected
Please leave a message after the beep
Mary, l'm sorry
l've chosen to be the good guy
l'm going to meet Yan now
No matter what
l'll give him back his identity
The file is in my computer
The password is your birthday
You sure know what you're doing
l also went to the cadet school
Do all undercover cops like rooftops?
Unlike you, l'm not afraid of light
So where's the stuff l want?
l don't think you've brought
what l want either
So what does this mean?
We came up here to sunbathe?
Give me a chance
How?
l have no choice before
but now l want to turn over a new leaf
Good
Try telling that to the judge
See what he has to say
You want me dead?
Sorry, l'm a cop
Who knows that?
Don't move. Police
Drop your weapon and let lnspector Lau
go first
Your boss is Sam's mole
l got evidence
Let's clear this up at the station
Drop your weapon now
l've called the police
Why should l trust you?
You don't have to
You'd better watch out
Look who's talking
l wish you every success in
the police force
Bottoms up, officers
No sweat. We are brothers
Sam is dead now
You have to look after me
l joined the cadet school in 1 994
But my career never really takes off
Sam looked down on me
l've taken care of Sam's tape
Don't worry. l'll follow you from now on
Our folks will be here any minute
Let's give them a good show
l'm actually quite smart
Too bad Sam never knew that
l'm a cop
Six months later, Dr. Lee Sum Yee
was looking through the personal
properties left by Officer Yip
Headmaster of the Cadet
She found Chen Wing-yan's file that
proved his police identity
Chen Wing-yan is now buried
next to SP Wong Chi-shing
How are you, Mr. Policeman?
Those who break the rules will be like him
They will be expelled
Anybody wants to trade place with him?
l do
Says the Buddha:
"He who is in Continuous Hell never dies
Longevity is a big hardship
in Continuous Hell"