[Episode 17]
Hyung, sign here.
I am more like an uncle.
What do you mean "hyung"?
Okey, Jo Ha Neul.
Sin Seok Ho...
Here! The contracts...
I will try to make your younger
brother to become a singer.
Aigoo, thank you.
But, it worries me that he hasn't even
graduated from elementary school yet.
Seong Hyeon.
I'm very late keeping my promise, aren't I?
Now it's my turn.
I will return the song which I stole.
I said I looked forward to taking you
to the airport. Let's go in my car.
I called a taxi. That's
too much to ask of you.
I should have contacted you in
advance and I came so late.
Let's say our farewell here.
Thanks to you I have literally
laid down ten years
I should take care of whatever
complication remains.
Thank you for taking such a huge step.
I also learned a lot.
Now I am in the same spot.
The taxi is waiting.
If you are in Australia later, contact me.
We'll have a drink.
- All right.
- Then.
I don't think I can forget this for a
very long, long, long, and long time.
Ha Neul was so cool!
How about Hyung Seok Ho?
CEO worked very hard for it.
Everyone, thank you so much.
It was very hard for me to keep my
tears away while playing the bass.
Hey, but where did CEO go? I bet
he's crying alone somewhere.
He said he wanted to say
good bye to Choi Joon Ha.
I enjoyed watching the performance.
It was good.
Yes, it was good.
You are saying as if it's
someone else's stage.
Why did you want to see me? Ah!
I will start looking into the
overseas study thing soon.
Before I leave,
I should also return it.
I gained confidence on
how I should live my life
while watching you and Choi Joon Ha.
I will obey your words,
and return "Don't Touch".
You may never be able to perform again.
Well, wouldn't it be hard for me to go on a
stage anyway? With this guilt inside me.
You have a bigger problem.
I looked into it,
and both of us may get arrested.
What will happen to the Entertainer Band?
I don't know.
What should I do?
CEO Sin, are you feeling sick?
Did you get diagnosed with something bad?
I lose some weight, but I don't
think it will affect my health.
Then, why would you propose
something like that?
I'm joking, but unless
you are terminally ill,
there's no way that you would.
Now's the end of hardship, and the
start of success for Entertainer Band.
So, why would you throw out?
What do you mean I'm throwing out?
I just want them to grow big under a
company with professional system.
Then Mango can just merge
under our Wild Company.
I may have to vacate my
position for a long time.
Wow, you keep saying weird stuff today.
What did you say? Turning yourself in?
You should have discussed it with me.
What were you thinking?
If I did discuss this with you, then what?
"Okay! That sounds good. Let's confess.
Is that what you would have said?
And the investigation? How
will it be conducted?
If they can contact composer Jang Min Soo's
family, they should be calling me in again.
They can't seem to reach
his younger sibling.
I guess the only thing
lacking is my confession.
And if they can prove the facts,
Will... you be going into the prison?
Prison term up to 1 year or a
fine under 10 million Won.
Let's prepare the fine. Ten million
Won isn't that hard to get.
Don't. I won't pay the fine.
Even if Ten million won falls
from the sky, I won't pay.
I should go to prison.
Do you think jail cell and
prison is your playground?
Min Joo,
How can Ten Million won
replace someone's life?
Even if I get released from prison after 1
year, can that replace a person's life?
I, will gladly receive any
punishment given to me.
Also, it's already decided
our Entertainer Band
will join Wild Company
I am sure you and Green
can manage well together,
but I thought it would be better for
the kids to be in a bigger company.
Let's worry about you before the kids.
After you are done with
the prison sentence,
how will you feed yourself?
You need to keep Mango alive. How
could you close the door on it?
Because I am not confident.
"You can cry"
Hyung, how was our performance?
I will be singing until I die,
but I don't think there will be anymore good
performances compared to the one that you and I had.
CEO wants to have lunch with everyone.
Let's go.
Okay, I will be right there.
It's delicious.
Tastes more delicious
since it's been awhile.
Oh, right!
You guys... ever heard of this
big company called Wild Company?
Well, that company is a very
big talent management company.
There are many singers, and actors.
Why are you talking about that company?
I think it's time for Entertainer
to move up to step 2.
We had a meeting
the general feeling towards our band
'Entertainer' seems to be incredibly fond.
So let's make Entertainer a bit wilder and work,
no longer with Mango, but with Wild Company.
Japan, China, South East Asia. Even
entering into the hallyu wave.
I like it the way it is, though.
If we all work hard too, we can
just become such a company.
That's right. Let's eat
diligently and do our best!
- Fighting!
No. You're saying this
because you don't know.
Mango is at the Level of a
neighborhood corner shop.
At an average sized company around 100
people are employed to work on one newbie.
But we're saying we like it this way.
I mean... if you open your mind a bit...
Let's try to think about
this cool-headedly.
At Wild Company, they have separate
people in charge for music,
dramas, CFs, overseas business.
They're methodically...
Why are you like this suddenly?
I...
Because going on being the head
of Entertainer's Company...
I don't have the right to do that.
No. For someone to have taken a
light promise from 11 years ago,
into an ideal stage. You're
saying has no right?
What the hell does not having the right?
I know right.
Be it me or Lee Joon Seok, we're
exactly the same kind of people.
But, how can you say something like that?
What does that guy have in common with you?
You see...
while doing this job,
no matter how drunk I'd be,
I'd call a substitute
driver or take a taxi.
I would never drive.
Director, why are you talking
about drunk driving now?
But that day...
the reason I took the wheel...
That day,
An unknown composer committed suicide.
Jackson's 'Don't touch'.
It wasn't Jinu's song but his.
I took it from him. That song.
I only gave cold-hearted words to
that pleading poor unknown composer.
That's why he killed himself that day.
And, while only thinking that I
had to go to the funeral home,
I grabbed the wheel and
got into an accident.
I got arrested.
And I couldn't protect Jackson.
Having done that, what right could I have
to work any longer with
such nice guys as you?
I'm turning myself in.
If they investigate I'll probably...
be taken into custody, won't I?
The police are looking for
the composer's family
and if they can find them, the
Investigation will be conducted.
That's why...
I can't be here with you. So...
Let's go to a better company.
And have Entertainer work
even more successfully.
Your pizza's here.
Yes, thank you. Here you go, Yeon Soo.
Take this and give it Chan Hee. It's about time
you pick him up from kindergartenm isn't it?
Let's go.
What are you doing? Get up.
What's up with your expression?
Am I emigrating or something?
You guys have to go to a big
company and earn lots of money
so that later on you can
give me an allowance.
Let's go. ♪ A small child
who has lost his way. ♪
♪ Where time stopped ♪
♪ the small child who lost his feelings ♪
♪ is walking together with you ♪
The person who died because of the low level gangster's moral
♪ The small child who has put his two hands together ♪
I made it worse by running away.
♪ prays you will return again ♪
♪ The small child is
separated by a big wall ♪
The case of Hyung Seong Hyeon ♪ The small
child is separated by a big wall ♪
was by deception and was different. ♪
You are holding my hands somewhere. ♪
What kind of person was the director before?
♪ you are holding my hand somewhere ♪
He's a really good person now.
When I was about to give up playing drums
because of my mom, ♪ Can time be restored? ♪
If it hadn't been for him, I probably wouldn't have had
the courage to go on. ♪ Can I go back to that ime? ♪
I would have still kept doing Aubrey Band.
I mean, whose life doesn't have some kind of dirt
if you dig up a bit? ♪ Can memory hold on to you? ♪
On the other side, the family of the
deceased composer... ♪ I am losing my way ♪
must have suffered as much as Ha Neul did.
♪ The days when we forget ♪
♪ the memories of when we
loved are too painful ♪
♪ I'm sorry. I still am waiting for you. ♪
You're very tired, aren't you?
I can look through it myself.
Seok Ho. After your parents,
I thought I was the one who
knew you the best, you know?
That's probably true.
Lately, seeing you changing,
- I don't think that's true anymore.
- Who's changing?
You're still cleaning after the
screw ups barely getting by.
Yes. This is Sin Seok Ho.
Yes. Yes.
Yes. I understand. I'm leaving right now.
- What is it?
- They got into contact
with the composer, Jang Min Soo's, family.
I'll be back.
- Let's go together.
- If you go you're only going to cry the whole time.
It's okay.
I'll go alone. And sort
out my thoughts a bit.
Please make sure the kids
aren't too shaken up.
Oh, you came. Sit down.
You're Jang Min Soo's brother, Jang Ji Soo.
Is that right?
Because of the copyright theft regarding Jang
Min Soo, Sin Seok Ho has turned himself in.
So I needed to verify the facts.
The song Jang Min Soo composed was
taken from him by Sin Seok Ho here.
And well... after that,
he even committed suicide. Is that correct?
I'm not sure.
You would have to say it precisely.
There's nothing I know precisely.
Excuse me. What do you mean...?
- Last year, you came to find me in my office and...
- My brother,
it is true that he passed away.
But the reason...
I don't know. There's
no suicide note either.
I'm busy trying to live my life, why did you make me
come all the way here over something so unpleasant?
But you came with that song.
I mean, you came to my office asking
me why I killed your brother.
Don't call me with another's
sad family history ever again.
I came because you said I had to come once.
If I come down here once,
my daily payment goes away.
Making a living is already difficult so please don't
call me out again for something so pointless.
Does that mean you're not going
to sue over the Jang Min Soo matter?
If that's the case...
I have nothing to sue anyone over. I...
don't know this person.
What's going on?
Excuse me for a second.
You said that you don't know me?
But you do.
You know what I did to your brother.
Do you really want to
go to prison that much?
- I don't want to go.
- Why would you get punished? I should be the one.
I came all the way from Sokcho.
I can't go back today anyway.
Buy me some alcohol at least.
I.. am the guy who killed Songwriter
Jang Min-Soo, your big brother
I even turned myself in, why
did you say you don't know?
You came to find me after listening to "Don't Touch".
You know everything, but why are you like this?
You should forever remember
what you did wrong,
since I will remember what I did wrong.
Things like other people's lives
I'm the man who stole the song that was his one
hope in life and made him leave this world.
I am not the guy you should be
sitting and drinking soju with.
Not only could he not raise me well,
even falling to malnutrition,
our father's poverty,
probably pushed him once.
A man doing music has no future,
the woman that left him was another push.
No. It wasn't like that. They were getting
married after releasing the song.
It was my brother's wish.
He broke up with that
woman over a year ago.
The day my brother died,
he said he was too tired and lonely,
and asked to have a drink
with me in that situation,
but I told him it's difficult for me working hard
to make a living and let's meet another time.
I pushed it back once more.
To a person on the edge of life and
death, you pushed him even further.
Who should be getting punished then?
Even so, nothing changes.
If you're done drinking, get up and go to the police
station again, and tell them what exactly happened.
- I made Songwriter Jang Min-Soo commit suicide...
- I told you to shut up!
After my brother passed away like
that, my father couldn't even get up.
Now, he is finally able to live on. If
my brother's incident breaks out again,
and he falls down again, he won't
be able to get back up this time.
Why is everyone so selfish!
Even if you go rot in the prison, do
you think I would feel much better?
And would our father feel much better?
Just to make yourself
feel comfortable, you...
Why did you tear open the healing wound?
Then what should I do?
Your brother cannot even come back to life,
Just... I just wanted to write his
name and return him his things.
I should get punished.
If I have to live the rest of my
life in prison, then I should.
The person is gone. The
person is dead, gone now.
Just live with that memory
for the rest of your live.
Live as though a thorn is stuck
painfully in your heart.
I live like that.
I drank well.
Excuse me!
I enjoyed that stage.
That dead man,
just like my brother,
cried a lot.
♪ It must hurt so much ♪
I enjoyed the stage. ♪
Everything is in flames ♪
♪ Just like my heart. ♪
♪ I understand everything now. The
tears I have been holding in ♪
♪ Even your moments which were difficult.
Which you desperately tried to hide. ♪
♪ You always stood by me. I won't let
go of the two hands holding me ♪
It's hot.
♪ It's okay if you can't bear it anymore ♪
I told you I will call you when Seok Ho comes.
Why did you come? ♪ I will hug you some time ♪
I have nothing holding in my hands, and I don't feel sleepy. ♪
It's okay to cry out loud. It's okay to cry even louder for you ♪
Why didn't you come back in? ♪ The
sad eyes are telling me that ♪
Yeah, perhaps I was like you. ♪ The
dreamlike love is telling me that ♪
You don't know where the
police station is, right?
♪ It's okay to cry harder ♪
He was going alone, and wouldn't tell me a
thing. ♪ It's okay to cry my heart out for you ♪
♪ The sad eyes are telling me that. The
dreamlike love is telling me that. ♪
- Is it Ha Neul?
- Where are you? Are you okay?
Our Ha Neul.
My little brother, lovely Ha Neul...
Where are you? Wait for me,
I am going right now, okay?
Ha Neul.
- Stop drinking, Hyung.
- You're here now?
Sit. Drink a cup.
You drank all of these?
Let's have a drink, Ha Neul.
Ahjumma, please give us
one more bottle of soju.
No, it's okay.
Hyung, you drank a lot.
Get up and let's go.
Ha Neul.
You're dying of curiosity, right?
Why am I like this, right?
Why is the man so drunk when he
is supposed to be in the prison.
Tell me about it tomorrow. Man Sik Hyung
said he will come to the office tomorrow.
Why did you call him over?
Okay, let's go to the second round.
If Hyung comes, he can come along.
Oh-oh.
Aicha.
Whoa, Jo Ha Neul is strong.
Strong. Look at your back muscles.
You're heavy. Don't move around.
Ha Neul.
Stop talking. Your alcohol
smell is really strong.
Seong Hyeon saved me.
He said he won't sue me. ♪ A smiling face even
though I'm sad. Sometimes I lie as well. ♪
He said he saw you and Seong Hyenn's stage
and liked it.♪ Everything changes ♪
Seong Hyeon,
Our Seong Hyeon ♪ You
know, because of you ♪
saved me.
♪ I feel like I have the whole world ♪
♪ Even if everything changes ♪
♪ I will only call your name ♪
Hey, you were groaning in your sleep
last night. Did you hurt your back?
No, did I not sleep well?
What happened to CEO? Is he
still in the police station?
He will be sleeping at home well.
You got a call from CEO?
He is not getting sued, right?
I don't know the details, but he was really
drunk last night, and I took him home.
Wait he is drunk?
This is the first time I
heard CEO drank alcohol.
- The other side they will not sue.
- What?
So we don't need to go to
that Wild place then?!
Of course.
Eat! Eat!
Ah...
I'm dying here.
How much did you drink?
I haven't drank in awhile. It's killing me.
Who did you drink with?
Anything going on with you?
What did the people from
police department say?
-Police department?-Police department?
-Hello.-Hi.
CEO, aren't you feeling sick? I knew it.
Drink some of this. It'll help you relax.
I already ate something. I am fine.
Why did you go to the police department?
Not now... later.
I will explain later. How are the kids?
They are at home.
Come to Wild Company by 6 o'clock evening.
I will also be there.
CEO!
Ah, I should go to sauna today.
-Aigoo...
Ah, really.
You should eat something
before sauna to sober up.
It really does help me sober up.
I don't really see anything good
with the composer incident.
The world is so cruel.
But, everything is solved, so why do the
kids have to move to another company?
The kids, they are too good
to be growing under me.
I think there's a traffic jam.
Gangnam is very heavy on
traffic at this hour.
It's okey. They should be arriving soon.
I will call and see how close they are.
Hey, where are you at?
We are still at the house.
What?
What were you guys doing
all this time at home?
Well, the thing is... Nobody wants to go
I am sorry, CEO. Seems
like the kids are nervous.
They must really like you, CEO Sin.
No, it's nothing like that.
I will, uh... arrange the meeting again.
I am sorry.
Everyone! Gather at the office immediately.
End of call
What are you guys, huh?
Ah, really...
CEO Choi is a very busy person. I worked hard to
get his time for a meeting, and you guys waste it?
What a bad first impression this is!
We don't need to meet him anymore, so
what good is the first impression?
What?
Right! Let's sit first, CEO. Sit. Sit
Everyone sit. Sit. Sit around quickly.
Hyung, here. CEO, here.
Ah...
I am not in a mood to joke around.
Let's calm down. I have
some major announcement.
Now is not the time to converse.
Why would you talk about your...
It's a story that will introduce
- develop - conclude Mango.
Everyone, prepare your hearts and listen.
You can cry.
-That's the title of the song.-Shhh!
CEO, you said you want to send
us off to a better environment.
I understood your intention. But,
that's same as throwing us out.
Hey, stop blabbering...
Firstly, listen to what I say.
Don't cut me off. I am serious.
Just because you think you
can't raise the child well...
Sending the child off to better parents to get
adopted... to grow up in a better environment...
From that child's perspective, he is
being thrown out, not being sent off.
What? Why are you talking about adoption
all of a sudden? Snap into your sense!
I can't tell whether they
are better parents or not!
I don't even know my birth parents,
and I haven't even met them,
so how will I know whether they are
better or worse than the new parents?
I grew up happily with good mother
and father in a good environment.
They supported me on things that I
liked, and I enrolled in Julliard.
I am an adopted child.
When I saw Yeon Soo, I
thought he was great.
On the other hand,
I kept wondering why my
real parents abandoned me.
When I was adopted, I cried
so much that my father
wanted me to smile endlessly, and
gave me the name "Lee Bang Geul".
I am not sure if this was a better
environment, but I am endlessly thinking
and imagining how it would been
to live with my birth parents
even if I were more poor and burdened.
You are telling us to
go to a better company?
What do you mean by better? How
would you measure that standard?
And, who will be deciding on that?
See? You guys need more tissue.
You can cry.
The song title really
does sound familiar now.
What is this. Nobody is crying?
I even announced my painful family history.
Well, it is very tearful...
Why aren't the tears coming out?
Don't say it. Do you guys think
that I am lying right now?
Hey, Noona! Don't you have to cry with me?
You were also adopted.
It's not really an adoption for me.
I am still listed under my
mom and dad's family tree.
They left to heaven, so Ha
Neul's parents raised me.
What?
What is this!
I was super nice to you because I thought
you were adopted into Ha Neul's family.
You were? To me?
Anyway, Kyle is right.
Are you really going to
abandon us like this?
Ha.. I am going crazy. I am not abandoning.
If I leave my position for a long time,
Entertainment Band may tumble down from its place.
How could you guys not understand
anything that I say as a group?
CEO Sin, you are the one not
understanding anything.
We understood everything,
but why don't you notice?
We will work very hard, and
become bigger than Wild.
That's right. We... don't
want to take fast steps.
Even if it's slow and takes long
time, we want to go all together.
With CEO Sin Seok Ho.
We should go on a MT(Field
trip) to cheer up!
I haven't been to any since university.
That sounds good!
Daddy, we are going somewhere together?
I hope we do.
CEO Sin, you should let us have this.
Everyone worked so hard to
climb over big mountains.
Everyone's going, right?
President Byeon, Man Sik
Hyung, and CEO Yeo.
What. You weren't going to let me come?
What are you guys doing? If you are not going to
Wild, you should go work hard and get some money!
Please, let's go!
Where should we go? Sea? Valley? Or...
South East Asia?!
Your back's feeling okey?
Go buy me some pain relieving patch.
It feels so heavy.
The stock price is dropping down very fast.
If this continues, there's a
possibility of delisting...
Get me meetings with
broadcasting station chiefs.
Well, CEO. The broadcasting station
boycott is not the main issue here.
The singers and talents that we represent are
preparing for a lawsuit to terminate their contracts.
What kind of crap talk is that?!
They state that the company has done a
great damage to their public image...
How is this place?
It looks good. Oh, you can even have BBQ.
I wonder where CEO would prefer.
I am fine with anywhere.
Ah! You were asking about CEO Sin.
Not at all. Both of you guys.
It reminds me. The pretty green umbrella that
doesn't really suit Seok Ho, is it from you, Green?
Ah, that? He was walking home in rain
without umbrella, so I gave it to him.
Isn't that too pretty for Seok Ho?
He should just have some
dark, big umbrella.
Yes. That would suit him.
Oh, I almost forgot about the meeting.
I'll be back soon.
Take care.
I don't even have car key, nor wallet.
I don't want to go back in again...
Where are you heading to?
Is there something wrong?
No, something just went into my eyes...
Don't you need to go to the office? Go in.
I have to attend a business.
You have no car keys, nor bag...
Where are you going?
Are your shoes comfortable? It's really great
for walking; your shoes and the weather.
Let's stop walking. My legs are hurting.
Why were you crying?
Last time, I cried like a baby in front
of you. It was embarrassing as a man.
I told you everything
about why I was upset.
Can't you also tell me?
If you can keep a secret.
I am not Kyle.
Where should I start?
If I start from 10 years ago, there won't be
enough time even if we stay up all night.
Where should I start?
This person named Sin Seok Ho...
You like CEO Sin.
It's funny, right?
You guys haven known each other for
10 years. Why haven't you confessed?
Because he might run away.
If I tell him "I like you", our
relationship will just become awkward.
Even staying as friends, It'll
feel ambiguous. That's why.
So, why are you crying now all of a sudden?
I learned that
Seok Ho, that bastard
likes some other woman.
Tears came out, because
I was a little shocked.
You'll keep the secret, right?
Of course. But, that... I
don't think it's love.
Love is something that you
can't hide for that long.
If it's someone that you really love,
you can't withstand without confessing.
I hate you.
You are too cruel.
It's direct (Baseball term
"fastball" is pronounced the same).
Love is direct (Baseball term
My age is a bit too much to throw fastball.
35 is also a good age to start a new love.
I am 34!
Aren't you the same as CEO Sin?
I lied, because I didn't
want to call him "Oppa".
If I knew that he's into young girls,
I should have just called him "Oppa".
You are cuter than Green.
You seem to know more than me.
Me? Not at all. I only know that
CEO Yeo Min Joo is a very cool woman.
Looks, career, and even her
background is so good that
she really needs courage to throw a
fastball. I know about this much.
Thanks for saying that.
Let's head back in now.
Your legs hurt, right? What can I do?
I'll just walk. While walking again,
I can rethink whether this
is friendship or love.
♪ Lend me your shoulder,
you must give me a hug ♪
By the way, it'll be the end if someone takes
picture of us walking together.♪ To Your Dream ♪
If that happens, I'll just tell them that it's a one-sided thing
from my end only. ♪ Come here. Tell me. Only let me know. ♪
No way! Your fans will chew
me out.♪ To Your Dream ♪
♪ I will forget the time upon me,
and I just want to be with you ♪
I am disappointed. You should have told me.
There's nothing wrong with being adopted.
When I was in the US, it was fine, but
Korea has a difference stance on it.
I didn't want people to look down on me.
That's why.
- You must have been feeling
sad back then-When?
Before I laid everything down and disappeared, I
said to you "Are you some director of an orphanage?"
Did I ask you to feed me?
I just wanted to do music,
but I got treated like an orphan.I must
have had guilty conscience back then.
I didn't even know what was going on, and I
said something about orphanage director...
You must have been upset.
My life is like a boomerang.
Importantly, where are we going for the field trip? If we can't
go to South East Asia, we should go to Jeju Island at least.
It is certain that both your birth
parents and adoption parents
are very kind. That is for sure.
How can you be this bright? Talking
about field trip all of a sudden?
I need to succeed, CEO. My adopted parents are still
angry. Because I quit Juliard, and in a band now.
- Let's become Hallyu. Starting with the
US.-I am so ready for the US market.
Hello. This is Sin Seok Ho. Yes.
Yes?
Yup, of course.
- Don't do it-They are asking
us for a commercial. Why not?
Going up on a stage is more important
to a band compared to a commercial.
Hey! Then actors should only act.
Why would they shoot commercials?
They sent in a proposal, and it suits our Yeon
Soo's image completely. How good is this?
He can get money, and prepare
to send Chan Hee to school.
But, why does it have to be...!
Jae Oh Group's "WithMe" condominium commercial is
a jackpot. Why is our Min Joo acting like this?
So, Why would you link Yeon Soo's goody
image with Jae Oh Group-like company?
Aren't your opinions getting too
personal, Miss Yeo Min Joo?
Ah, really!
Oppa Seong Hyeon has four more
songs in Choi Joon Ha's album.
CEO Yeo is asking to do
remake of those songs.
Will Choi Joon Ha agree to that?
He's the one who suggested it first.
I need to discuss this
with Hyung Seok Ho first.
I personally thought it'd be good if we
got my song and Hyung Man Sik's song
and worked them together
to make a new song.
Hi.
Hello.
Hey. Our Entertainer guys are
working hard late into the night!
- Seeing the president in such a good mood makes me feel like
something good has happened.-Are we going to the South East?
Man..! Shut it!
Hey, we got another commercial deal.
-Wow!-Wait, wait, wait! A beer ad?
Condominium commercial!
A commercial for apartments! Wow! You have to have
a great impression to get an ad for apartments!
As expected, our image really is appealing!
This commercial didn't come
to the Entertainer Band,
but to our Na Yeon Soo.
What?
Wow. Awesome.
Since people these days aren't able to take responsibility for young kids,
it's a world where unpleasant events are being talked about on the news.
Na Yeon Soo, who has raised his son alone
and is making his dream come true,
has gotten a proposition saying his image
was suitable for the WithMe Apartments.
Stop... With Me Apartments. JO group?
Ah, what is this! Hyung Yeon Soo, you're
not really dating President Yeo are you?
President Yeo supported you Hyung Yeon Soo!
Again with that.. again.
It's not like that. How could I with a
person like that... Don't be ridiculous.
For your information, President
Yeo said not to do it.
She said it would destroy his
image and was totally against it.
What do you think Yeon Soo?
I don't really... How could I go shoot a commercial
independently? Can't we just all film together?
Hyung you're perfect for it! The company's
promotions team are good at what they do.
Perhaps I really would do
well standing in the back.
Looks like no. Don't do it.
If it works out there will be residual
advertising fees, all in one big shot, huh?
Let's hurry go to MT first.
Let's shoot the advertisement
cleanly and go.
Gosh, really.
Green tomorrow go and
meet up with the team.
Never mind going to the office and clean up
at Mango then you can go meet with them.
Okay, CEO.
Did CEO Yeo make it for you?
Did she push you?
Hey stop.
Then give me one section of an apartment.
Now ready!
Action!
♪ Life could be a dream.
If I could take you up ♪
How is it? Do you... ♪
in paradise up above ♪
♪ If you would tell me I'm the only one ♪
want to live together? With Me...?♪ that you
love. Life could be a dream, sweetheart. ♪
Cut! Hey it's okay.
Let's think of the first time we dated.
Sweet! How sweet!
You know you can do that!
Okay makeup let's wipe his sweat!
Come on come on.
Sorry.
Think about her thump thump right?
No no that's the face when you
think about Chan Hee's mom.
I can't do that well... What should we do?
Then think about a favorite celebrity.
You know when you get to the top you could be
dating one of the top prettiest celebrities.
Now look cool and good right?
This is not a time to joke around.
Concentrate.
Okay we are going to get going!
Did you get bored and came to have a look?
I came to see how this
concept does not fit him.
Okay let's get this done for the last time.
Okay it's very sweet! Okay ready.
Good good. Action!
How is it? Us.
Do you want to live. With me?
♪ I opened my eyes in the
dark and I saw you smiling. ♪
Cut it was so good! Look at the camera!
Where were you looking?
- I am so sorry.
- That was so good.
- With me. With me.
- One
Two. Three. Four.
I don't think I can look at that.
Min Joo?
If you're going to say some
nonsense, put it away.
That article
is real right?
♪ In the gap between the teasing breezes,
this feeling which is spreading sleepily ♪
♪ The truth is, I'm not sure ♪
How is it? You want to live together?♪
I think that I am not awake yet ♪
With me...!
Do you want to live together, CEO?
Stop it!
Hyung, I like you so much!
I can do it very well too.
How is it? Us together.
Drive.
Okay.
Aloha. Aloha! ♪ Do you wanna
go straight to Hawaii? ♪
♪ Straight to Hawaii ♪
We're going to Gapyeong, but you
must think we're going to Hawaii.
Don't mess with me. My heart is to Hawaii.
Don't shatter my dream. Aloha!
Dad are you going now?
Chan Hee when Auntie Green
is coming we are going.
Where is Auntie Green?
I bet she went to the market to
make something yummy for Chan Hee.
She'll probably buy Hanwoo beef, right?
Let's put the items in the van and
hurry go pick up to the practice room.
Are the other people coming by themselves?
They're going to go straight
to there in Man Shik's car.
Okay. It must be fun.
You like it that much?
Yes, this is the first time going to the MT
even when I went to school I never been to MT.
It must be fun.
Until what grade did you attend school?
Second year 1st semester.
-Your major?-Veterinary Medicine.
I did some studying. From Busan
I was in a university in Seoul.
Veterinary Medicine...
It fits you well! You would
give a shot to a dog well.
My Professor said that it would be
perfect for me since I look like a dog.
I need to make a brief stop.
Where?
Of course it's sunglasses in a vacation!
What do you think of this, CEO?
-Pick yours out.-Me?
Are you going to scold me and
harshly criticize me all the while?
I'm okay.
Hurry and pick before you change your mind.
Can I buy an expensive one?
Pick a suitable one. A suitable one.
Because I'm pretty, anything
I pick will suit me.
That's true.
Pick one.
How is it?
It's good.
You came?
Hello!
Wow! This is good.
Did you put that in and say they were
going to eat a lot of whatever like that?
Well, I mean...
Jump!
It's good since it's cozy!
Ta-da!
Ginseng liquor?
It's a cousin of ginseng.
If you bring it, what are you like a
grandfather bringing 21 year old whiskey?
You're saying that without knowing
how good this is for men.
Then let's say Man Shik
is not drinking this.
But, I didn't say I wasn't going to drink it...
Well... Did I say that? What good would that be?
Really...! When there are kids here...
Good!
What did you pack, Noona?
Hanwoo beef and lobster.
Hanwoo and lobster? You're
the best, rich Noona!
Hey!
Do you want to live together, rich Noona?
Hey, you! Have you ever
been hit with a lobster?
It's big. Big.
But this big...
Your hip is going to get hurt.
You carried the heaviest one.
Thank you.
It's good!
Eat a lot.
Come on! Come on!
What was that, Hyung Man Shik?
It's because I'm not wearing soccer cleats.
Ah, hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
- Hurry and kick it over.-Fighting Aunt CEO!♪ A feeling
similar to childhood when I wanted to grow up quickly ♪
♪ A feeling similar to childhood
when I wanted to grow up quickly ♪
Nice!
Man Shik Hyung!
It's sad.
Is that so?
That's doing it in the spirit of twenty year
olds. You go all out and develop everywhere.
Since I feel sorry for him, I can't look.
Kick!
I'm going to vacate this
spot to go eat some lobster.
Aigoo...!
♪ The crying face even if it is sad ♪
Look at Kyle playing soccer with his mouth. I could
die from the loudness!♪ sometimes even lies. ♪
♪ Everything has changed ♪
Yeon Soo Hyung is good at sports.♪ 하나뿐인 널 훔쳐갈까
봐서 ♪ because I see the one person who stole me ♪
Yeah, he's good. You're not playing? ♪
Because I see the one person who stole me ♪
You still have the aftermath
of having to be back-carried.
Who's saying I need to be back-carried?
I usually walk well.
You walk well? Ha! Really! I should
have filmed a video on that.
Ah, it's hot.
Ho! My ball! My ball!
Are you okay?
Ya.
♪ Even when I look at your eyes my heart ♪
CEO when are you getting your license?
Why? Because you feel
sorry for Manager Jeong?
What are you talking about?
Of course CEO came here to work.
I am not adopted.
Here! Here! My ball! My ball!
♪ While sweeping aside ♪
Why are you putting your life on the
line over that?♪ my long hair, swish ♪
♪ Swish he told me ♪
-Be careful. -Catch it here catch it. -Oh!
Good job!
♪ That was enough, you've changed.
You who were my comfort ♪
♪ I'll return to you, all
that you did for me ♪
♪ Because I couldn't even thank you ♪
Why is our Ji Nu on search one?
Last year's "Don't Touch" is not my song.
Are you okay?
- Have you read this book before?
- Please take it away.
Please read the last page of this book.
Ktop I am not leaving them alone.
What do you want?
Come to my school once.
You said your school has no pretty girls.
No. But I think there is one.
3 weeks from now
Jae Yoon is going out.
Sorry I couldn't stay with
you guys until the end.
There is a new drummer coming in
today instead of Jae Yoon right?
Please take good care of me.