Hey!
Hey, Linda! Come here!
Come outside!
I wonder what Tokyo
looks like from up there.
I don't.
Why not?
I'd be scared.
Scared of what?
Of dying, I guess.
Falling into the void.
They say you fly when you die.
It's fucking cold!
Hey, check out this book
Alex gave me.
- It's like the Tibetan Bible.
- Alex, the junkie?
It's all about what happens
after you die. Look!
So you're gonna become
all Buddhist on me, huh?
No.
You know they're all the same,
the fucking Catholics, the Jews...
Just a bunch of sects
out to get their hands on your money.
Alex is gonna make you a junkie
and then he's gonna
make you a fucking Buddhist.
No! He's just a friend.
I'm not gonna become a Buddhist.
Alex is a fucking junkie.
He's not your friend.
- Come on!
- He's not your friend!
I gotta go.
Hey!
I'll see you later?
See you.
Lock the door.
Just lock the door.
Okay, good.
Why did she say I'm a junkie?
I know I'm not a junkie.
I know who I am.
She's my sister,
but sometimes
she doesn't know who I am.
There you go!
This is the good stuff.
Why else would Bruno
give this to me?
He probably wants a blow job.
That's disgusting!
Who do they think I am, anyway?
I know I'm not a junkie.
Easy...
This stuff doesn't taste good.
This drug tastes like shit.
Wow! It's already kicking in.
This is it. It started.
Oh God!
This is the best.
What if I faint?
I'm not gonna faint.
Just calm down.
I've done this before.
You love this.
Wow!
- Hello?
- Oscar... It's Victor.
Hey, I've been looking for you.
Can you bring me my stuff?
Can you come and get it?
No, I need you to bring it to me.
- Oh, okay. Where are you?
- I'm at The Void. I'm....
You know, I'm really sorry
about yesterday...
- I'll wait here.
- Actually, I'd rather...
Don't be long.
Hello?
Come on!
Oh fuck!
Wake up!
Get a hold of yourself!
Oh God! What's that?
Wake up!
Collect yourself.
The balcony.
Walk away from there!
Keep your eyes open.
My head is throbbing.
Oh, you look like shit!
Water.
Just fresh tap water,
from some natural place to here.
Nice, clean tap water will help.
That's perfect.
Back to normal.
Look at your pupils,
look at your eyes.
They look different.
Oh shit!
Is it the neighbours?
Did they hear me?
Did I scream?
Maybe I did.
Just calm down.
Alex!
Hold on.
- Hey, Oscar! You all right?
- What's going on, man?
Nothing much.
Doing pretty good.
I think I need a shower.
The balcony.
Don't go to the balcony.
Stay away from the balcony.
- Hey, have you read the book?
- The book?
- Yeah.
- Ah, the Book of the Dead?
Yeah.
I haven't actually finished reading
the whole thing, but it's pretty good.
- It's a wild book.
- I'm glad you like it.
Do you mind if I keep it,
so I can finish it?
- I don't mind.
- Thanks.
Thanks, thanks.
You Okay?
Yeah, well...
- I bumped into your sister.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
She was with that cunt, Mario.
I fucking hate that guy.
I can't believe she's
going out with him, you know?
If she ever gets pregnant,
I'll kill the baby.
I swear to God.
Hey, look, anyway... Do you mind
if we go and see her tonight?
- I'd really like to see her.
- Yeah, sure.
First, though,
we have to stop by The Void.
I have some stuff for Victor.
You wanna come?
- The Void?
- Yeah.
Well, I don't like that place,
but I'll follow you
and we go and see your sister?
- Oh yeah. Let's go.
- Great!
- Can I grab some water?
- Yeah, sure.
Water!
- You're not taking everything, are you?
- No, only his share.
- Man! That's a lot of gear!
- Yeah.
Shit!
That's fucking dangerous, you know?
You should let him come
and fucking pick it up himself.
No. He won't come by here anymore.
After what happened with his mother.
- What? He found out?
- Yeah.
- How did he find out?
- I don't wanna talk about it.
All right.
You don't mind if I take your water?
- No, bring it.
- All right.
The streets are really empty.
Is it a holiday today?
Hey, what's wrong with you?
- You tripping, man?
- Yeah.
You can tell?
Yeah, you look really fucked up.
I popped some tabs this morning
and just took a hit of DMT
before you came, actually.
Shit!
Looks like you had a good day.
Yeah, and the day
isn't over either.
Hey! Do you think Bruno
has anything stronger than DMT?
Come on, you're gonna
fry your brain, man!
You should finish the Book of
the Dead, that'd be a lot better.
You can wait until you die,
then you'll get your big trip.
That book is still confusing to me.
How would you explain it?
It's a little bit hard to explain.
So, basically...
when you die
your spirit leaves your body.
At first you can see all your life,
like reflected in the magic mirror.
And then you start floating
like a ghost.
And you can see anything
that's happening around you.
You can hear everything,
but you can't communicate
with the world of the living.
And then you see these lights,
all these different lights,
of all different colours.
These lights are the doors
that pull you into
higher planes of existence.
But most people...
they actually...
they actually like this world so much
that they don't want to be taken away.
So, that's when the whole thing
turns into a bad trip.
The only way out
is to get re-incarnated.
- Does it make any sense?
- Yeah, I guess so.
I don't know.
What's the bad trip?
Well, the bad trip is
you get all these nightmares.
You go like real crazy.
All your fears become reality...
and it scares the shit out of you.
It's like what's left of your mind
has to be on top of everything, right?
At that point
you wish you never died.
Then some darker yellow lights
appear to you.
They represent
all these couples making love.
And then, the light comes out from
their bellies and if you get closer
they give you a vision
of a possible future life.
And you choose the life
that suits you the best.
You know? You end up in a womb
and you're reincarnated.
End of story.
And basically
you do this forever and ever,
until you manage
to break the circle.
You follow me?
So you mean we are stuck in this
shitty world for all of eternity?
You mean there's
nothing better out there?
Hey, you know what?
I can't wait to see your sister.
She looks really beautiful man,
you know?
I know,
but she's still MY sister, okay?
I know. I'm just saying, you know...
I'm not blind.
I mean, what can I say?
She's gorgeous.
Fuck off!
Fucking taxis!
Well, you should
look after her, you know?
What are you talking about?
You're turning into a dealer.
I'm not turning into a dealer!
Yes, you are.
What are we gonna do tonight?
You know, look at
what your sister is doing.
She's trying to stop you
from doing that.
What, are you schizophrenic?
You're the one who introduced me
to your provider!
Ah, come on!
No, honestly, you should try
to get a job, you know?
I don't know.
I mean, you're a smart guy, you know.
You could DJ.
Maybe ask the club, like,
to give you a job, part time,
like bar tending.
It's really fucking easy,
I did it!
It's a piece of cake, you know?
Especially in Tokyo.
You're a foreigner,
you're good looking...
You know, there's a big difference
between taking psychedelics,
and being a dealer, you know?
- I said, I'm not a dealer!
- You're a dealer!
And you're a mother fucker, man!
I can't believe you're fucking
that old bitch, you know?
You're in Tokyo and there's a lot
of fucking cute chicks everywhere
and you're fucking some old bitch!
And she is a foreigner as well!
At least, if you're fucking
a Japanese old bitch... You know?
She fucked ME.
Anyway...
Oh, man! Look at that! Cops!
Fuck!
Hey...
I wanna dump my bottle.
I'll be back in a sec.
- Have you ever heard of datura?
- No.
- It's crazy shit.
- Why, what's datura?
- Is it a mushroom?
- Yeah! It's a plant...
that takes you somewhere, you know?
Pretty freaky!
What's it like? I mean,
what's the trip like on datura?
Like you don't even know
you're fucking tripping, you know?
You'd be on the floor, you'd be
talking to every fucking body,
but you realize two weeks later
that you were not talking
to anybody, you know?
I mean, I took it, I saw that chick.
Man, she was gorgeous!
- Hang on a sec! Hang on!
- Yeah?
She was fucking gorgeous,
I really fucking liked her, right?
And I tried to kiss her,
I'd been talking for thirty minutes.
She fucking disappeared,
she had never existed.
Look, Oscar.
I don't want to see you doing
that shit with Victor, right?
So I'll wait for you. I'll grab some
food and I'll see you in a minute.
- Okay.
- All right.
- I'll catch in a minute, man.
- Okay, see you later.
Linda's right.
Alex is more of a junkie than me.
I hope Victor is here already.
I don't want to wait for him.
Hey!
I've brought your stuff.
I'm sorry.
- What?
- I'm sorry.
Oh shit!
Hold on!
Police!
- Ah! Come on!
- Open up! Police!
What are you doing?
I'm gonna call my embassy!
Hold on! Hold on a minute!
I'm coming out!
Oh shit!
I have a gun!
I'm gonna shoot!
If you don't leave, I shoot!
Why do you want me to...
What?
They shot me!
I can't die now.
They shot me?
Did they kill me?
Did they shoot me?
No, I don't want to die like this.
Not right now!
My sister...
There's blood on my hands.
They're gonna test my blood.
They'll find me positive.
They'll put me in prison.
They caught me.
It's the police, isn't it?
They'll rape me.
No, I didn't do anything wrong.
I didn't hurt anyone.
Life sucks.
I can't feel my arms.
This isn't happening.
I'm just tripping.
That's what it is.
It's the DMT.
No, I'm still alive.
I'm dying.
Am I dead?
I hope this isn't real.
What will happen to her?
Linda, please help me.
I need your help.
Take me home.
I don't wanna die.
I don't wanna die like this.
Accident, accident.
Victor?
- Victor? What happened to Oscar?
- They shot him!
- They killed him!
- Get the fuck off me!
No, no, no! No stay!
Private! Private!
I have to get that.
Linda! The cops shot
your brother at The Void.
He was bringing some shit to Victor
and I don't know what happened.
I heard a shot.
And Victor said they killed him.
You should run...
- So, who was that?
- It doesn't matter.
Mario?
What the hell are you doing?
Bye.
Linda! The cops shot
your brother at The Void.
He was bringing some shit to Victor
and I don't know what happened.
I heard a shot.
And Victor said they killed him.
You should run and find out.
Sorry, I was outside.
I can't tell you more.
The cops are after me now.
I'll call you back.
And if you die?
What's gonna happen to us?
What will happen to us?
Will we ever see each other again?
You promised me.
We'll always be together.
Forever and ever.
Hey.
Oscar.
- Oscar, do you love me?
- Yes.
- How much?
- A lot.
What's a lot?
Mommy!
Do you remember the pact we made?
Kind of.
We said
we'd never leave each other.
Never ever?
Never ever.
- You swear?
- I swear.
- And if you die?
- I'll come back.
This is a blood pact.
Now we'll always be together.
Stop it!
I'm not letting you take...
Oscar!
Oscar! Don't let them take me!
You promised me!
Oscar, you promised me!
No! No! No!
Then she was sent to a foster home
and I was sent to a different one
and life became like a nightmare.
You should take her to Tokyo.
I miss her so much.
She's younger
and she's still in school.
Come meet my flatmate.
Oscar.
Hey-
- HEY-
Check it out!
What'?! Holy shit! No way!
- Wow.
- Pretty cool, heh?
Yeah, that's actually pretty insane.
It's like Tokyo on acid.
And this is the plane
that brings your sister.
Trust me, I really want to.
It's just money, man.
Money, money, money that I don't have.
Money, money, money.
You can make money, be smart!
- Rob a bank!
- Yeah.
Yeah. That's like the hardest thing
I can think of.
I'd rather be a drug dealer.
No, man,
that's fucking dangerous, you know?
Shitty job.
Good drugs are nice, yeah,
you can make a lot of money,
but you can go like really deep
into the shit, you know?
You can end up in prison.
My mom says
that when she was young,
to make money,
she was a go-go dancer.
- Really?
- Yeah.
She's an amazing woman! You
should come and meet her. Yeah.
Come out for dinner once,
and meet my parents.
When I met her,
she was a go-go dancer in Tokyo.
Yeah, I went down
to the club a few times,
got a disease...
- Anyway!
- That's just the story.
Anyway, tell us about you.
- Are your parents here, in Tokyo?
- No, no.
My parents passed away
a long time ago.
What happened?
If you want,
I can find the money to lend you.
How about it?
You don't have a lot
of friends in Tokyo, right?
And Victor?
What about Victor?
Nobody knows I'm here, right?
Nobody.
Hey, it's beautiful.
You know what it reminds me of?
- What?
- Smoking.
It reminds me of
sucking on my mother's nipples.
- The best thing in my life.
- You're a freak!
When is this acid
gonna be hitting me?
You know the good thing about LSD?
If you can manage
to overcome your fears,
you can take your hallucinations
wherever you want.
Hey, Mom!
What happens if you die?
I'll be with you forever.
I will always watch you.
I will watch you from the sky.
- You promise?
- I promise.
You love Daddy
more than you love me?
No. I love you both.
It's a different love,
a very different love.
Why?
Hey!
Do you remember me?
- No.
- No?
We were here last week,
you guys remember?
- Hey! Wait, wait, wait!
- Bye!
No, wait!
- Do you take drugs?
- Drugs?
- Yeah. Do you take drugs?
- No.
- Never once have you taken drugs?
- Never once.
- Never once?
- Never once!
But I like alcohol.
Yeah, so you like alcohol,
then you like drugs.
It's like one step,
then the next step.
One step? Yeah.
- So you're David?
- Yeah, what do you want?
What?
Some of my friends said
I could come by here
to get some stuff to party with.
Who's that?
Who's your friend?
- It doesn't matter. What do you have?
- Why doesn't it matter?
Who's that, your friend?
- Gaspar.
- All right.
Okay, what do you want?
Coke or X?
- How much is coke?
- Ten grams for sixty.
- Okay, yeah, that's good.
- Are you sure?
Here! Take it. Just...
There you go! Yeah!
- How strong they are?
- Be careful! They're really trippy.
- Hey, guess what?
- What?
- I finally found an apartment.
- That's great!
I have a job now.
Hey, and I have enough money
for your ticket.
- Are you kidding?
- Isn't it exciting?
Wow! My God!
How did you make enough money
to buy me a ticket?
That's crazy!
- Hey, I told you! I have a job.
- Wow! Oscar, I love you.
Start packing, okay?
What?
Nothing.
So, what are we getting?
E's and acid.
- And I guess I'll get some DMT too.
- Oh, nice.
- Can I come with you?
- No chance.
The guy's so paranoid.
- You have the money, though?
- Yeah.
Here you go.
The drug guy,
he's a dirty bastard, you know?
- Yeah, he likes boys.
- Who is this?
Bruno.
The guy that gets me drugs.
Don't even take a drink!
If you go there on your own,
and you take a drink,
you might wake up two days later
with his shit on your mouth, you know?
Or your own shit, you know?
Actually,
I'll introduce him to you today,
but I won't come back with you,
so you should be careful.
You know what his new trick is?
He can't even be turned on
by fucking now,
- so what he does is...
- Hey...
I'm not gonna jump
from here, am I?
Hey! When some new guy
gives him a blow job, yeah,
he sticks his finger
inside his own ass
and then he wipes his finger
on the back of their head.
So they walk around
with his shit on their hair!
That's the guy
I was telling you about.
Hey, you look just like me!
- What's your name?
- Oscar.
- So, what do you want?
- Do you have any LSD?
Let's have a look.
Cool.
Hey, Oscar, check this!
What happened to him?
Poor baby!
Screaming for his mum all night.
Yeah, this is what I'm looking for.
Cheers, mate.
- Nice.
- Hey...
- Do you have any DMT?
- DMT?
I might have a little bit left.
Have you ever tried GHB?
It's funny, you know?
DMT only lasts for six minutes,
but it really seems like eternity!
It's the same chemical
that your brain releases
when you die.
It's a little bit like dying
would be the ultimate trip, you know?
Hey.
Let's try this!
Be careful!
You see this tunnel?
It leads to these huge gutters.
You know,
all those bums are hiding there.
People go at night in those gutters.
What do you think?
- It's fucking awesome.
- Yeah?
Imagine if the walls were all clear
and all your friends
were inside it, fucking.
Massive...
Melt into this massive orgy.
- Oscar?
- Yeah.
Come and check it out.
I've got something for you.
You should read that
before you try DMT.
Tibetan Book of the Dead?
I assume it's about death.
It tells you how your spirit comes out
from your body after you die.
Have you ever had an
out-of-body experience?
- Have you?
- Yeah.
- Once as well.
- What's it like?
First it fucking took me so long
to get there, you know?
I had to practice slowing down my
breathing, slowing down, slowing down.
And it's like my mind is out
and I can see myself, you know?
Like, just above myself.
I really freaked out
because I was afraid I would
not be able to get back in my body.
Yeah! It's fucking crazy, you know?
Yeah, that's cool, you know, but...
- Hey! It's me, again...
- Hey! Check this out!
Hey! It's me, again....
- It's me, Linda.
- Your sister, is it?
Don't forget I'll be arriving at
the airport Monday evening at 6 pm.
You will be there, won't you?
- Hi.
I missed you so much.
Look at that!
No! Mommy!
Mommy!
When you die and Grandpa dies,
what will happen to us?
You'll be taken care of, dear.
We promise you'll be taken care of.
No! No! No!
Oscar!
Hey.
You know what?
I dreamt again of the accident.
Yeah?
Well... doesn't matter.
We're gonna be like
a family from now on.
Just you and me!
Do you want some more?
Was it good?
Hey.
It's for a club.
You wanna go?
Wow.
- Hey, take this pill!
- What is it?
It's ecstasy.
- I never did it before.
- Just take it!
- Is it dangerous?
- No! It's a drug.
- Come on, it's like a vitamin.
- Okay.
- You're gonna love it!
- Yeah? Okay.
My God!
It feels so fucking good!
Hey, Oscar, man! Your sister,
she's real fucking hot, you know?
You gotta take care of her.
Look at her, Oscar!
- Come and dance with me!
- Hey.
- Come on!
- Hey, hey, hey...
I think she likes me.
All right, here's the deal.
You front me the money for the E,
I take the risk of scoring
and selling the stuff.
And we go for a fifty-fifty split.
It means you get all the profit.
Listen. Wait, wait!
Who's your dealer?
That's none of your business.
Okay. So how much do you need?
Look, where were you?
- I was looking for you.
- That guy got you way too drunk!
Where were you?
Hey, guys!
Hey, seriously, let's go!
Come on!
Watch the step!
Let go of me!
You know that tomorrow is the
anniversary of Mom and Dad's death?
I'm having fun!
Wow!
This is like heaven!
It's so beautiful!
I really feel so happy
here with you.
I feel free.
I feel very, very free.
You promise me
you'll never leave me?
Of course.
- We'll die together?
- We'll never die.
- We'll never die?
- Never.
- We're immortal.
- Yes.
- We will never die.
- Good.
What?
I missed...
I just missed you so... so much.
- Have I grown?
- Of course.
I look like a woman now?
Do you believe in re-incarnation?
I don't have a
mental age of five anymore.
Don't you wanna find a real job?
Fuck, no!
Everyone who has a job
is just a slave.
There's one important thing though:
It's to have a goal... like...
Do you have a goal?
- I don't know.
- You should have a goal.
Maybe have a big love affair?
You know?
Hey! What did that guy
want with you at the nightclub?
- He offered me a job.
- Doing what?
Hey!
- You're Mario, right?
- Yeah.
Look, that's my sister.
Don't touch her, okay?
Don't be a bad brother.
So, how much do you want?
Fifty pills. It's for me
and my friend Victor.
Look, man, I don't want
to know your friend,
and I don't want him
to know me, okay?
Okay.
Hey, baby! You like snakes?
And don't look so nervous!
We're all friends here.
Does anybody want any coke?
Any ice?
No.
- Do you have any DMT?
- No.
Come here!
What are you looking at?
- You wanna try some?
- Sure.
Ready, you guys?
Shit!
What the fuck are you doing here?
It doesn't matter to you.
I'm not hurting anybody.
Shit!
- Don't touch my stuff!
- You're selling drugs to my girls!
- Fuck off, give it back!
- Fuck!
If I ever see you again here,
I'm gonna kill you.
Out!
- Do you know what Mom and Dad said?
- What?
That they would bring us
to Japan one day.
- Can Doggy come?
- Yes.
What's up?
Where the fuck were you?
You didn't come home last night.
You didn't call me.
You could let me know the next time
you get laid by a dicksucker.
If you mean Mario,
I wasn't with him.
What?
Are you jealous?
Oscar! Who is this man?
I'm his friend.
He's doing...
he's trying to fuck me.
- Bruno!
- Hey, Oscar, my man!
- How's it going?
- I'm glad you could make it.
Come on!
So I know you like MDMA, right?
- Sure.
- You wanna try some of this?
- Yeah. I can just take it?
- Sure.
You can worry
about the price later.
Straight from Amsterdam!
Real trippy shit, man.
Cool. Thanks, man.
And I got what you wanted.
I got you a little DMT.
Just light her up!
A bit longer, come on.
Real, real go for it.
That's a boy!
Just... You wanna be careful.
You might drop it and
you might fucking burn yourself.
So if you want...
I can help you out the next time.
I can hold it for you.
Hey-
- HEY-
What are you doing here?
I just came to see you.
You're fucking crazy.
Get off!
- Hello, Oscar! How are you?
- Hey! I'm fine.
Hey, darling!
Do you want to see what's on TV?
- Good.
- Let's go.
Hey! I brought your stuff.
Okay, let's go to your place.
I don't know why
I'm paying you for this shit.
Have you slept with my mother?
What are you talking about?
Have you fucked my mum?
Yeah.
Keep your fucking pills,
you piece of shit!
- You piece of fucking shit!
- Victor!
Victor!
Shit!
Victor, call me back.
- Hello?
- Oscar, it's Suzy.
Victor didn't come home last night.
Do you know Where he is?
No.
Will you call me if you
hear from him, please?
What did you dream about, Oscar?
Do you remember the pact we made?
Kind of.
We promised
to never leave each other.
No matter what.
Never ever?
Never ever.
I got into a fight
with Victor last night.
You want a trip?
Are you sick?
Linda!
I wonder what Tokyo
looks like from up there.
I don't.
Why not?
I'd be scared.
Scared of what?
Or dying-
Oscar, it's Victor....
I have to bring this shit to Victor.
You wanna come?
Sure.
By the way,
have you read the Book of the Dead?
I'm sorry...
Open the door! Police!
Don't worry!
I'm burning his stash now.
Yeah, everything...
gone.
They're fucking assholes.
First they said he had a gun
and now they won't even
take a fucking autopsy.
I can't believe this is real.
Fuck!
The police is still here.
They are looking for Alex.
You're Alex's friend, right?
Tell us about him.
I'm asking you, say something!
- I don't know anything.
- Yes, you do!
Don't lie!
I can smell when people lie.
And if you can help us,
we can help you out.
We can help you
to get out of this situation.
If you don't, you go to jail.
And you don't want to go there.
So, tell us about your friend Alex.
We know that he knows
the main supplier.
Say something!
What did he say?
They say
Linda's brother had a friend
who attacked one of the officers,
and they want us
to let them know any information.
It's in Japanese.
I can't read it!
Come on! I can do it for you.
It's positive, isn't it?
Yes, it's positive.
- You all right?
- Oh, man!
You're sweating a lot.
So?
You mean I can't get
any coke from you?
No. I got rid of my entire stash.
How do I know Oscar didn't give
my name to that slime bag Victor.
- It's your fault!
- Who made the call?
I didn't call the fucking bastards.
You called them!
- You get the fuck off me!
- Hey, we're a family here...
- Stop it!
- I'm so fucking ashamed of you!
You know, my mother is a bitch!
Don't talk of your mother like this!
You idiot!
She fucked my best friend,
and you think you can play
the man of the house?!
- I'm still the man of this house!
- You're not the man of this house!
Now get out!
Get out!
- Go fuck yourselves!
- Go fuck yourself!
- What do you think you're doing?
- What do you think YOU'RE doing?
You tell your son
he's a fucking psycho!
I fucking despise you!
I fucking hate you!
Don't you see
she's just using you?
No.
That's not the point.
It's just that I like Linda.
She even wants
to have a baby with me.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Hey, are you okay?
No, man, I'm not okay.
I'm in deep shit.
Look, can you do me a big favour?
Can you go to my place
and speak to my roommate?
Yeah, I need some money.
Yeah, he knows where it is.
And I need a jacket as well.
I'm freezing!
No, don't call him!
You go to my place.
I'm sure the cops
are tapping our phones.
Okay, look, I'll call you later and
I'll give you a place for the meeting.
All right.
All right. Ciao.
Mario is just a good fuck.
I should have
listened to my brother.
I should have been with Alex.
I really liked him.
Actually,
he contacted us, you know?
- What did he say?
- He's okay.
That's all we can say.
Why did you bring me here?
The manager isn't happy
with your dance.
We can't keep you anymore.
But what am I gonna do?
I'm not your daddy.
But I could take care of you.
Are you listening?
I would have already
committed suicide
if I didn't have this sensation
that Oscar is somewhere around me.
I wish he could come back to life.
Stop hurting yourself!
I know that it's hard to admit.
But dead... is dead.
Please let us know
if gets his speech back.
That thing is not my brother.
He's obviously not like he was.
That thing is fucking disgusting!
Shut up!
So, have you two decided
where we're going?
Have you two decided
where the fuck we're going?
So?
There's no way
I could put up with him.
Don't fucking touch me!
Fuck!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Hey, wake up!
Hey! Hey, wake!
Hey!
They burnt you, didn't they?
They torched you!
Come on! Think about it!
Close your eyes
and think about it!
If you're lucky,
you might find your ashes.
Go on, little cunt!
Go on! Close your eyes!
Think about it!
Go on!
- Mario?
- What?
I had another dream
where my brother
resuscitated from the morgue.
I find it creepy
keeping his remains in that box.
What are you gonna do?
That's your fucking brother.
Those remains are not my brother.
Do what you want.
Goodbye.
- Here you go.
- Thank you, man.
- Are you okay?
- Oh...
- Shit!
- Thanks.
- You got cigarettes?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, I do.
Hey! I'm gonna need some money.
Okay. I'll ask Linda to bring it
to you. She wants to see you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Is she still with Mario?
- Yeah, I think.
Fuck!
What do you want?
I wanna say sorry.
I'm sorry.
That's what you came here to say?
That you're sorry?
- Yes.
- Really?
Yes.
Why don't you
go make yourself useful...
and go kill yourself.
Yeah.
Why don't you go and make yourself
useful and fucking go kill yourself!
You don't mean that.
- I do.
- You don't understand.
I mean, it's partly my fault.
Listen...
For me and Oscar!
Go fucking kill yourself!
- No, you don't understand.
- You piece of shit!
But Oscar started dealing drugs
because you were with
all these sleazy people.
Because it's me?!
Because it's my fucking fault?
You piece of shit!
Get the fuck out of here!
I hate you!
FUCK you!
You piece of shit!
Because it's my fault?
Get the fuck out of my house!
Fuck you!
FUCK you!
I fucking hate you,
you piece of shit!
It's my fault?
My fault? Fuck you!
Get the fuck out of my house!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck!
I wanna fucking die!
It's the fault of my brother
and his stupid fucking friends!
My life is fucked!
Fucked!
Calm down!
I don't wanna be here!
I don't wanna be here
with these fucking evil...
evil fucking people!
They're fucking evil!
They're fucking...
evil people.
- I wanna be alone.
- It's okay.
- I just wanna be alone.
I just wanna be alone.
You people are evil!
Fuck off!
I just wanna die!
Oscar! Calm down.
Hey!
- Hey! Good to see you.
- Good to see you too.
How have you been?
I've been better.
Me too.
I'm sorry about your brother.
It's okay.
Watch out!
No! No! No!
No!
Daddy! Mommy!
No! No!
No! No! No!
Mommy! Daddy!
Come!
Linda!
Come inside me!