Mako!
In the confusion following
the great earthquake of 1923,
the anarchist Sakae Ôsugi was
assassinated, along with his wife.
She was your mother, Noe Itô, right?
You were seven years old
when your mother was killed.
Tell me what you remember.
You were seven,
so you must remember something.
When your mother left that morning,
what did she say to you?
Was your mother beautiful?
Did you love your mother?
I've wanted to meet you and
ask you these questions for a long time.
Since I left Tokyo,
I've been repeating them out loud.
Weren't you jealous of Noe?
I mean, as a woman.
All of a sudden, that day when
your parents disappeared from you,
you became jealous, right?
Yes, jealous...
During the 28 years of her short life,
she was married three times.
She left her second husband,
the poet Jun Tsuji,
with whom she had two children,
in order to be with Sakae Ôsugi.
She was responsible when Ôsugi's lover
Itsuko Masaoka stabbed him out of jealousy.
The case of "Hikage no Chaya" in 1916.
She joined the "Seitô" movement,
led by Aichô Hiraga,
becoming the youngest member of the group.
As the last remaining member,
she ended the movement.
During the last ten years of her life,
she gave birth to seven children.
In a few years, she lived as much as
the entire lives of several ordinary women.
Noe Itô...
was your mother, wasn't she?
Thank you. I have no more questions.
Tell me your name once more.
A-ko.
But I'm Eiko.
Eiko Sokutai, 20 year old student.
- Then, I'm B-ko.
- Good, B-ko.
A final word, please.
I have nothing to do with this.
You speak of my mother?
I have no mother.
You speak of my mother's mother?
My mother has no mother.
You speak of my mother's mother's mother?
Then...
It's you.
Spring, March, survivors of the massacre,
We dance among the flowers
- Sakae Ôsugi
Drunk upon the happiness of decadence,
this film is a dialogue with you and I,
the ambiguous participants in the erotica
and revolutions of Sakae Ôsugi and Noe Itô,
whose lives were dedicated
to the beauty of chaos.
EROS + MASSACRE
A GENDAI EIGASHA Production
In collaboration with BUNGAZUKA
Produced by:
Kijû YOSHIDA, Shinji SOSHIZAKI
Written by:
Masahiro YAMADA, Kijû YOSHIDA
Cinematography: Genkichi HASEGAWA
Music: Toshi ICHIYANAGI
Lighting: Yoshio UNNO
Production Design: Tsuyoshi ISHII
Sound: Yukio KUBOTA
Editing: Hiroshi YASUOKA
Mariko OKADA
Toshiyuki HOSOKAWA
Yûko KUSUNOKI
Etsushi TAKAHASHI
Masako YAGI, Taeko SHINBASHI,
Kazuko INANO
Kinji MATSUEDA
Kazunori MIYAZAKI
Takehiko TAKAGI
Yoshisada SAKAGUCHI
Toshiko II, Midori TAMAI,
Daijirô HARADA
Kyûzô KAWABE
Kikuo KANEUCHI
Directed by Kijû YOSHIDA
"Geneva Airport:
Israeli Plane Destroyed by Arab Guerillas"
"Combat Breaks Out
Between Police and Guerillas"
"Paris Conference: No Progress"
"Apollo 9 Mission Has Failed"
No, "Succeeded"
I'll never forget that moment.
- What moment?
- That moment.
That moment?
A spider descended
from the ceiling on a thread.
It swung in the air.
I burned it.
Then it said,
"I burst into flames and die!"
Who burst into flames?
Me...
You're crazy! Crazy!
The thief Kandata had saved the spider.
And I burned it.
Just to fill the emptiness of time.
No, that's an excuse!
Emptiness?
Well, look at the state of your love life!
His image is used
to hide your dry, empty heart.
Until recently, it was our slogan!
But now...
Now, these words
have been inscribed on my back:
"Oh Buddha, condemn me to Hell!"
"Kandata saved the spider, not me!"
Enough with the stupid stories.
My stories are stupid
because I don't say anything.
- What are you looking at?
- Your legs.
The hairs on your legs.
What about my hairs?
Will they keep growing after you're dead?
What are you gonna do next?
Go home and sleep.
I want to sleep soundly.
No, I mean...
What are you gonna do in the future?
What are your plans?
Marry a girl.
You got engaged?
A girl said "yes" to you?
I just decided...
You're a student, right?
When do you graduate?
What will you do afterwards?
A year and nine months maybe...
Really? The future should scare you.
I don't really get what you mean.
You should worry about your future!
Not really.
I'm not interested in anything.
We have come to
take the ashes of Sakae Ôsugi!
That anarchist was executed.
- He's forbidden to be buried!
- Don't let them!
Don't give them to the police!
He will have the funeral he deserves!
Band of thieves!
We must remove all that remains of Ôsugi!
"I have decided to die within 24 hours."
"Megumi"
Megumi... Blessing...
Bless... Blessed if you don't...
Bless... Bless...
Mercy... Grace...
For what?
Why didn't you respond?
I didn't write just out of curiosity.
Copper pollution in the Watase River
led to the nearby villages being abandoned.
That was 30 years ago,
before I was even born.
It's been over ten years since Shôzô Tanaka
made a fuss about it in Parliament.
I thought it had all been resolved.
Some villagers held on,
to stay in the desolate swamp.
But today the State forcibly
evicted them to build a dam.
It's like drowning illegitimate
children after the scandal.
It's exactly the same thing!
But nobody's doing anything...
Not a word in any newspapers!
When I heard about this,
it was like a slap in the face.
I was ashamed.
Ashamed of my ignorance
about what happens in the world.
That's why...
I want to ask what you would've done.
That's why I sent the letter.
The cherry trees are blooming.
Just like on that day.
To you,
a childish country girl
like me asking you for justice
must seem like nothing
but fleeting sentimentality.
That's what you told Tsuji?
He would have said,
"Instead of thinking about all this,
think about who you are."
"Because one of those bored, bourgeois,
'new women' from the 'Seitô' movement"
"happened to be moved by
the tragedy of Yanaka Village,"
"and talks nonsense like fever struck..."
Isn't that what you think?
"What can these 'new women' do?"
- But I...
- I can't do anything either.
Look behind you.
I'm being watched 24 hours a day,
thanks to your tax money.
An anarchist without arms to act
is like a duck with broken wings.
A duck?
All I can do is quack.
This way of talking...
It's not like the Ôsugi I know.
This is my true appearance.
A duck!
The duck wrote back to the duck,
but it wasn't sent.
Because it was so long,
it could've been taken for a love letter.
The cherry blossoms...
They dance before my eyes...
The cherry blossoms?
They're so beautiful!
Where I was born, in Imajuku,
they bloom a week earlier than in Tokyo.
"Spring, March, survivors of the massacre,
we dance among the flowers."
They were also in bloom that day.
When I got out of prison,
Shûsui and the others weren't there.
They had been killed.
We dance among the flowers...
The flowers...
There were cherry blossoms
at that time too.
My cherry blossoms...
Before he could get near me,
I had run away on my wedding night.
I couldn't bear to be trapped
in old traditions, or the role of a wife.
And Tsuji received a bird that
he treats like the woman he loves.
Now that she's exhausted her resources,
she wants to fly again.
Don't make fun. I'm not exaggerating.
I was being serious.
No...
I was supposed to escape
to a house free of old traditions,
but when I regained my senses,
I saw I was trapped in the same old house.
Tsuji's house...
Are you re-enacting the flight of "Nora,"
so popular at the Imperial Theatre lately?
I told you not to make fun of me.
Escaping isn't the issue.
It's knowing what to do afterwards.
Escaping is the only way of knowing.
How can you know beforehand?
- Noe...
- I'm serious!
I've thought about it for over six months.
Do you know what you're saying?
Mr. Ôsugi,
where is your usual cockiness?
You're being a coward.
I...
I'm pregnant!
Remember the first time I met you?
I've already given birth.
I named him Ryûji, Ryûji Tsuji.
A good name, right?
But I really am pregnant.
I don't know what it is yet.
It's so complex. And so new!
It's the one and only thing
that can be known only by a woman.
It's our one unique act!
I think I understand you.
But what will you do?
There's your wife, Yasuko Hori,
and also Itsuko Masaoka, your mistress...
And me as well...
- Why burn it?
- To relax.
Burn it!
It's burning.
No, I mean something else.
I read about it:
Barriers in your subconscious
that you aren't even aware of.
Childhood traumas, obsessions...
That explains why you play with fire.
You can't accept that you're an adult.
Psychoanalysis bores me.
You never know if the doctor is normal.
If the doctor is crazy, it's useless.
Hey, you think you could ignite me?
Set me ablaze!
Okay. Stand by.
- Rolling!
- Action!
- I gotta go.
- Where?
Megumi's apartment. She wants to die.
- Who?
- Megumi.
Let her die if she wants.
I know.
But I can't do that.
Do what you want.
Later...
Cut! Once more!
Excuse me, are you Eiko Sokutai?
Yes. What do you want?
Eiko Sokutai, student, 20 years old,
Tokyo School of Design.
Specialty: aesthetics of information.
Residence: Gifu Prefecture.
- Current address...
- Hurry up!
On February 28 at 7 p.m.,
at the Fairmont Snack Bar,
you met a man, right?
Sure, I meet men every day.
There are 5,300,000 of them in Tokyo.
Let's go. Stand by!
Rolling!
Action!
Certainly.
Cut!
Once more.
Excluding children under 9,
there are 4,200,000.
They all suffer from sexual needs.
What do you want?
Are you a reporter?
Insurance inspector?
Don't smile! You're models, not humans!
- Rolling!
- Action!
Police...
You're suspected of prostitution.
No expression! Be an actor!
You're still leaving?
It's the last day of "Seitô" magazine.
When I succeeded Aichô as editor,
nobody thought I would last two issues.
But this is already the fourth!
Four already?
You promised you would help,
but I'm still waiting.
It's your magazine. Do what you want.
But sometimes I wish I could rely on you.
I've already given you all that I can.
You talk as though you want to leave me.
Yes.
You eviscerate anything you
happen upon, then devour it.
I don't want that to happen to me.
You're the one who encouraged
me to study, to complete my training.
Yes, and you've made progress!
At 20 years old, editor of "Seito,"
militant activist for women's rights,
wife of the lazy man, Jun Tsuji,
and mother of Makoto and Ryûji.
What are you saying?
You always talk of "women's emancipation."
Surely, the plight of
women must be improved.
But, on my own,
I've been rethinking this recently...
All we've managed to
accomplish at this point are just words.
"Women's emancipation."
"Modernization."
"Ego."
What's the point?
You speak of women's liberation,
but you can't take care of Makoto,
and you don't do housework.
Sorry, I'm not being ironic...
I have lots of respect for your activism.
It's your best merit.
The Meiji Restoration, modernization...
We have the train,
and a skyscraper in Asakusa...
We have a Parliament.
These days, I play the shakuhachi,
but it doesn't console me.
"Do not seek for freedom, in self-denial,"
"but seek for yourself,
and become an Almighty Ego."
It's you who taught me
the words of Max Stirner.
That's why I stopped working.
Reading, sleeping...
I do what I want,
and concentrate on myself.
This way, I can look much farther.
You always look too far!
Why don't you look around you?
The peasants of Yanaka
could die in cold water tomorrow,
but you can't even see that!
I know!
Looking so far ahead
can be painful sometimes.
"Women's emancipation."
"Modernization."
When will it happen?
In 50 or 70 years? I don't know.
It's now 1916.
Trains go as far as Kyûshû.
And yet...
Where does this intense light come from,
to gradually change the ego from within?
This void in me grows day by day.
Like it's anticipating the day when
emancipation is finally achieved.
That's how I feel.
I...
I still love you.
Very much.
But you don't need me anymore.
No. I need you.
People are born free.
But despite this,
or perhaps because of this,
people fear freedom,
and desire to be chained.
Thus they destroy themselves.
Love...
Even our love... Has killed our freedom.
You know this very well.
You're like a bird who has
stopped flapping her wings.
I would ask you to stay in this house,
but you wouldn't be able to.
I'm not the type to go against the wind.
But you go against the wind,
whichever way it blows.
I'll return.
When I told you to forget about
the peasants of Yanaka, you were furious.
Abandoned for 30 years,
left on a frigid, dammed lake.
Those peasants
stubbornly cling to their land.
I thought that something in their hearts,
the source of their determination,
might be stronger than my own emptiness.
That's why I said what I said.
I don't understand.
You don't understand.
I don't understand either.
That's why I keep looking further.
Makoto is crying.
Please take care of him.
You go up the stairs.
From the first floor to the second,
from the second to the third,
from the third to the fourth.
I go from the third floor to the fourth!
You enter a room away from the others.
Yes, a secret room.
You take off your clothes.
I take off my clothes!
- What for?
- The customer likes it.
If you don't please him,
you don't get paid.
You are naked now.
I'm naked now!
- Then you say...
- Then I say...
- Say it.
- Say what?
How should I know? You said it.
Hurry up.
- What did you say?
- I don't know.
But it's you who said it.
"Hello," a hello to 1970.
That's not it...
"Hello, man. Hello, lover."
"Hello, customer."
That's better.
Then what?
You show him your goods...
I show him...
This is the case of February 28,
at 7:20 p.m.
This is the case of 20... 20...
- 28.
- ...at night.
Hey, why do you need the date?
Get straight to the crime.
- Was the guy killed?
- Don't say that.
The tape is running.
This could serve as evidence.
You made love.
I made love with that guy.
With my lover!
Before leaving the hotel,
you took his money.
How much?
This game is boring!
Should I just pretend that I killed him?
Broke a vase over his head!
The amount, please.
We still have plenty of tape.
I cut his artery with scissors!
How much?
- 300 Yen.
- Be serious.
I was going to ask for 5,000,
but I started to stutter,
and I couldn't pronounce the "go."
Ga...
Gi...
Gu...
Ge...
Go...
So I said "three" instead. That okay?
3,000 yen? Too cheap...
- So was he killed?
- He's alive.
He won't be arrested.
Under the laws of this country,
the one who pays isn't a criminal.
The law could surely seem unjust,
but we must denounce the crime,
the cause, and the system it's a part of,
if we are to eliminate evil.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Say your name again.
Eiko Sokutai.
"A" like "ABC" in English,
"A" like "Always," "Ageless"...
Whatever you want.
It's not important to me
if I'm the right woman or if I'm not.
It doesn't matter,
because to me, "I" don't exist.
Get it?
If this woman isn't me,
then she must be someone else,
but to me, "I" don't exist.
That is, my "ego" doesn't exist.
By definition, the ego doesn't exist.
If my ego doesn't exist,
then others don't exist.
Others exist as soon as I myself exist.
If there's no difference
between me and others,
Nobody can know if this
woman is me or someone else.
The search is futile.
From the start, this woman is nowhere!
Very well.
If, on the other side of that hotel door,
someone has taken your place,
I'd like if you could tell me her name.
Sure, we may have exchanged places,
even if we're both the same "I."
That's common in the world of prostitution.
Show a real pearl, but sell a fake.
You can go.
This is the time to wait. Yes.
Sometimes you must hide like a cat.
Any movement today is sure to fail.
The walls around us are too thick.
Face it, we would have to retreat.
We can't have that,
so we must wait.
You always say to attack immediately.
But waiting for the
right moment like a cat requires
determination and courage as well.
You waste time doing nothing
because you're afraid!
You're talking like a lazy coward!
Don't wait for an opportunity, create one!
What will you find outside?
Only a desert full of stones, and a prison.
At the end, there's a gallows!
They'll kill you like a dog!
I've waited for two years!
Nothing's happened! Nothing's changed!
Will you wait until you die like a dog?
Not me!
I don't want to die like a dog,
or die foolishly.
You said the same thing two years ago.
And I said that the
appropriate action was to
focus on the neutral zone of literature,
and publish "Modern Thought."
That's just intellectual masturbation!
It accomplishes nothing!
I'm sick of it!
Of intellectual masturbation?
Well said!
Affirming the ego,
developing the individual...
I'm in favour of it.
But it's only in dreams where one can
rule the world and satisfy the ego.
In reality, we're oppressed by thick walls.
Stop resisting, despite your resentment,
and retreat into your snail shell.
Eternal disobedience is eternal defeat...
Run away from society...
This is the prisoner's philosophy.
That's true.
We prisoners of thought had enough,
and shut down "Modern Thought."
We would rather resurrect the
"Common People's Newspaper,"
but we're bound by censorship
and prohibitions one after another.
It's almost March! Springtime!
What do we do now?
That!
Clubs or explosives?
Take that path to die like a dog.
You're eager to reach the summit.
Sure, men can get to
the top of the mountain,
but they can't live there for long.
Sakai! You've spoken of
hiding like cats and dying like dogs.
Are we monkeys now, climbing a mountain?
Monkeys who keep slipping and falling.
Seems like it.
Monkeys who can't live at the summit.
Reaching the summit is enough.
What do you mean?
What I want is
the freedom to reach the summit.
To climb the highest peaks of life.
When we can do that,
we'll know the ecstasy of freedom.
When the strike happens,
not an economic strike, but a general one,
propelled by the courage of the individual,
eager to know this ecstasy,
workers will be freed
from their enslavement,
to write their own history and values.
Ôsugi, your theories are too
personal and literary to follow.
They're like a philosophy of life, but...
Who ever said you talk about
your sex life, instead of universal life?
Not me!
Whatever...
But this "strike for life" is impossible.
In reality,
you can't even publish a journal.
It's hard to deal with reality.
Waiting, with arms crossed,
is a foolish death.
Tomorrow is the beginning of March.
What will we do?
Love? Revolution?
Both! If the "Common People's Newspaper"
doesn't work out,
we'll rebuild "Modern Thought."
We'll also focus on the workers,
and start research into unions.
I see...
Repeat the same mistakes!
It's better than sitting here, yawning!
Failure is better than inaction!
Speaking of love, Ôsugi, your wife...
No... Your eight-year partner in
misfortune has brought a package.
It's already spring.
I brought you some lighter clothes.
Oh. Thank you.
I can see you two make a perfect couple.
They say you're also crazy about
the brilliant English-language journalist
Itsuko Masaoka,
from the newspaper "Tônichi"!
Is that true?
Yes, it's true.
While we're at it, I also love Noe Itô.
Is that where we stand?
Our movement is at a standstill,
a complete failure,
and you're preoccupied with women!
The movement and love
are the same thing to me!
There's no difference.
Even today,
I love Yasuko with all my heart.
But I can't devote my soul only to Yasuko.
Love dies if it's not free.
Yasuko already knows about it.
I hadn't heard about it.
I'm Ôsugi's wife.
His only woman.
Certainly.
He's only espousing
his theories about free love.
I heard that he courted Yasuko
by setting his kimono on fire.
Going so far to prove your love...
Now that's something!
It's true.
I was being serious.
I'm searching for free love.
She's still out?
She'll be back soon.
I have no idea what Noe
has been doing these days.
You think she's changed?
We grew up together since the age of seven,
when her family fell into ruin.
We wore the same clothes,
ate the same food...
Just like twin sisters!
I used to know what she
was thinking at any time.
But now we're completely different!
At age 18,
she was in a hurry to marry you.
But I'm over 20 and I
don't know who I'll marry.
What is it?
Noe...
You left me...
From the beginning,
I expected this day would come.
But now...
Jun!
Looks like the wind picked up.
Noe said the cherry trees
were blooming that day.
But I don't remember
if the wind was blowing.
I am Haruko Hiraga.
...known as Aichô.
Of course!
I was trying to see if you were
different from how I imagined you.
So am I different?
Not at all.
I guess that's a lie...
But you wrote,
"In the beginning, woman was the sun."
"Now she is the moon,
dependent on another's brilliance.
"But now we must recover our hidden sun."
Your article in "Seitô" really shocked me!
So, how did you first picture me?
I can't tell you.
Maybe you imagined a much older woman.
Did you receive the money?
Yes, I used it to run away
from home and come see you.
Oh, I forgot to thank you for that.
I'll repay you when I find work.
Nonsense! It's nothing!
No need to repay it.
Yes, thank you!
This is Itsuko Masaoka.
I'm Noe. It's a pleasure!
I've heard of you.
The most brilliant
English student at University.
I'm resigning from "Seitô" today.
What a pity!
There's a limit to what
a group of women can do.
We must dive into male society.
A group of women is safe.
Among men, you won't end discrimination.
Equality must be fought for.
I'm going to write
for the "Tokyo Nichinichi."
Well, good luck...
Take care, "Aichô"...
Reading your letter has
generated a lot of discussion among us.
"She writes with the
determination of a man."
"Here's a woman, only 18 years old,
from a region afflicted with poverty,"
"but she writes with
such reason and clarity!"
"This proves that our movement
has finally become authentic."
Authentic? But...
You must know that people
think of "Seitô" as merely a distraction
for bourgeois young women.
But in reality, there are women like you
who are slaves to the family system,
ancient traditions, and poverty,
all over Japan.
Freeing these women
from their bondage is our goal.
This fight is your fight,
but it is not your fight alone.
We must join forces, and do all we can.
But I have no other choice.
I was raised by poor peasants in Kyûshû...
What will you do now?
I thought I'd go live with
my former teacher, Jun Tsuji.
You must also think
about how to make a living.
I know.
I have a job for you.
As a writer for "Seitô."
I've been looking for someone like you.
It was my goal from the start.
I gladly accept! I'll start tomorrow!
Isn't this the window
you wrote about in the magazine?
Can I open it?
The wind is cold.
I just wanted to look outside,
to see what's there.
Just a boring landscape.
Plums, bamboo, peonies in spring...
The moon in autumn...
Snow in winter...
So on...
One of these days...
You'll be the one who picks the fruit
that we have grown so carefully.
It's getting cold. How strange.
I was just wondering...
Where are we going?
And why did I come?
It's been two hours. How much longer?
It's like the North Pole in here!
The heater's broken.
Thank civilization for giving us the cold.
I know! I'm escorting a prostitute!
We're running away!
If only. We're going to save someone.
- I wonder if she's dead...
- I bet she is.
- Me too. But why bet?
- Not a bet like that.
There's no point rushing to a funeral.
That's enough. Stop!
Where's a hospital?
My wife swallowed pills!
Leave her alone.
She'll just do it again.
The hospital!
I don't know where I am,
and it's too cold.
All those who take this path
leave their hopes behind.
Perfect for death by jumping...
I kissed Noe.
She's in love with me.
That's what you came to say?
You are a cultured and intelligent woman.
You understand my way of thinking.
Yes... I know.
I told you from the beginning.
I'm married to Yasuko,
a simple, uneducated woman.
But her character is suited to
the wife of a revolutionary.
I cause her much grief, but I love her.
I love you too.
And you love Noe too?
That's good.
I'm happy for you,
from the bottom of my heart.
Yes. The three bonds will hold,
if we respect three conditions.
What conditions?
First:
Each of us is financially independent.
Second:
I won't live with any one of you,
but separately with each.
Third:
We must respect each other's freedom.
That includes freedom in sexual matters.
I have many friends,
but none of them complain
about insufficient friendship.
We are friends on fair and equal terms.
Our love...
is also based on equality,
and winning freedom.
In that case,
I must ask you to keep your promise.
Promise? What promise?
The first night we spent together...
Have you forgotten it?
I told you back then.
Marriage has no value to me.
I became convinced of this...
after observing
my sisters and their husbands.
These days, marriage can't
ensure the happiness of women.
That's why I don't want to marry.
Since I don't believe in marriage,
I was able to love you
without feeling guilty towards Yasuko,
or even feeling her presence.
But in return, I resolved to
make all my own decisions in life,
no matter what difficulties I encounter.
I'm listening. What was the promise?
Are you saying Noe is
different from Yasuko?
No! I told you the same thing
when there was just Yasuko.
I wanted you to
keep our relationship secret.
But you've told Yasuko everything.
Not just Yasuko but your friends too. Why?
I saw no reason to hide it from them.
So nobody would disturb us.
We could see each other freely.
Freely...
You mean so we could escape the rumours.
I don't care about rumours,
or what your friends who are
committed to monogamy think.
But we can't completely
change their way of thinking.
That's why, to preserve our love...
Don't worry about them. Ignore them.
Someday, the world will follow.
But we'll be attacked,
and we'll defend ourselves.
You say that because you're a man.
When I was 18,
I was in love with a married man.
I tried to pursue this love,
but it was impossible.
Not just my family,
but the whole world forced us to separate.
So follow society's morals?
Hide in the shadows?
You think there's freedom in the shadows?
Let's respect your three conditions.
For liberty and truth.
But I am a woman.
I said I wanted to escape from
trouble and responsibility last time.
You said you don't want children, right?
That's fine, if you want.
I guess that's the second condition.
And the third?
Hey...
You don't have to go now...
Noe was out of breath when I kissed her.
I could feel her trembling through me.
It was surprising.
You're doing this on purpose
to make the situation harder.
Seems like fun to you.
Are you going back to Yasuko's?
Wait!
You surely need money...
I don't know anything about you.
- You a student?
- I don't know.
Yakuza?
I've seen you sleep with a man,
but I haven't slept with you.
That's "psychological impotence."
Wrong!
That's why I want to sleep with you!
You accept!
We go to a hotel!
But I want more!
You refuse!
Say it!
It's my turn now?
No! I refuse!
Then, suddenly,
I punch you right in the stomach!
You groan and fall over.
I fall over.
I hold your arms behind your back,
and push you down.
You fight back!
Keep going, this is good!
I start strangling you...
You strangle me...
But you resist with all your might!
I resist!
Your skirt is up
and your underwear is torn!
I'm inside you!
You're inside me!
Wait! See that?
Everyone's running!
There's been an accident!
What happened? Tell me!
Murder? Revolution? Traffic accident?
Can't see. Too many people.
Someone's coming!
You saw the accident?
Yes! It was scary!
Tell us what happened.
A giant crane suddenly fell!
The cables loosened, one after another.
Why did they loosen?
- A support cable broke!
- And then?
The crane was carrying a gondola.
What was in the gondola?
I don't know...
Let's switch places.
It wasn't a gondola.
It was an iron arch!
What for?
It should allow us to survive the disaster.
But it fell!
It weighed 16 tons
and fell at a speed of 82 km/s.
And then?
It fell on a bus
that was passing underneath.
A bus...
full of old people from a retirement home!
It's a scene straight from Hell!
A sea of blood and flesh!
A small handbag rolls into the gutter.
Look here! There's a little doll inside!
Probably a gift for a granddaughter.
That poor old lady... had a granddaughter?
Old man!
Who said "old lady"?
Make way! We must help the wounded!
Make way! More!
More!
This world is no place for you!
You're right. I brought him to the room.
But there was another girl waiting inside.
You brought me here just to say that?
Yes. What else would I say?
You expect me to believe that?
But I was just an accomplice. It's true!
Here's my share.
I just got it.
Cut the crap.
You don't believe me...
Who put you up to it?
This isn't hard to understand.
You've already decided that I'm a criminal.
You gave me a motive.
The location is... No, find it yourself.
You can find anything,
even imaginary crimes.
I already gave you a motive for free.
Now go!
You're satisfied with a miserable life.
You think life without purpose isn't life.
But life has no purpose.
Life is miserable.
The only certain thing is that we all die.
Other than that,
no one can know the future.
That's why we live in our imagination.
We live... But life is suffering.
My murdered mother
taught me that life is a battle.
A battle! Is that what life is about?
Murdered?
By who?
By all our fathers!
Your imagination is often annoying.
What is imagination?
It's the illusion of the poor.
They don't become rich,
but imagine they are.
They dream of revolution.
The man on the phone in front of me...
What did he do with his left hand?
He started to imagine,
then he confused imagination with reality.
At that precise moment,
his actions became apparent to me.
It looked exactly like a crime.
And then I...
I sniffed him out, like a dog.
And arrested him.
How am I able to do this?
Because I don't live in my imagination.
I don't suffer.
I don't believe in the impotence of men.
You know, at this moment,
another me is a prostitute.
Those who suffer...
are already in prison, or an asylum.
There's no need to arrest them again.
You just had a
bad dream this morning, that's all.
I've already found the
prostitution network I was looking for.
Yesterday.
I'll show you something good...
I've decided to kill you.
I bought it yesterday in Nihonbashi.
The blade is 16.5 cm. It cost me 50 sen.
I decided not to leave you.
If I left you, I couldn't kill you.
I made the decision to kill you.
This freedom is the foundation of life...
We must give life to it...
Women's liberation...
is for men to...
No, the happiness of
all humanity resides in freedom.
If I recognize your freedom and your ego,
I'll write it down in a contract...
Based on the three conditions...
It was all a stunt to make fun of me.
Why?
It wasn't a stunt.
Eiko was just worried about me.
Nice friendship you have.
Wait!
I've never slept with a guy.
Don't leave! I'm scared!
Help! I'm scared!
I opened my eyes.
I looked at the time as usual.
It was 6:37.
I laid motionless and fell asleep.
When I looked at
the time again, it was 10:07.
I got up and looked in the mirror.
My face was rough, covered in dead skin.
It took 15 minutes to get dressed.
I wondered whether
to wear jeans or a skirt.
Then I realized
it doesn't make any difference.
I went into the
bathroom and brushed my teeth.
I realized that I already brushed them.
But it was just yesterday morning.
And the morning before,
I thought the same thing!
The bathroom window was open 3 cm.
The wind blew through it.
The warm wind of spring.
I took a look outside.
On the street, a porter was trying
to cram rolls of cables onto a truck.
But without success.
They would fall out every time.
When he finally finished, I came inside.
I hadn't put on makeup.
Just a little cream.
Recently when I do my makeup,
or when I put on lipstick,
I get a cold shiver.
Then I ate.
I drank milk, from a 180 ml bottle.
With salad and half a sandwich.
Afterwards, I sat in a chair doing nothing.
Maybe for an hour.
Then I remembered
I hadn't watered the plants.
I watered them for half an hour.
Maybe I watered them too much!
And again, nothing to do.
I sat in the chair some more.
Then the phone rang!
It was 11:12.
"This is the landlord,
concerning the phone bill."
I just said "yes."
Again, nothing to do.
I just sat there.
Help me, please!
Is there a way to live without fear?
All year long I only hear
the noises from cars below...
I need to be with someone! Anyone!
Calm down.
Don't think about anything.
You don't have to think. Think nothing.
Nothing.
It's my Dad.
I wrote a suicide note.
But I don't want to see my Mum or Dad.
Because I left them for Tokyo.
You have a country home to return to.
You should be happy!
Come on.
No! I don't want to see them.
I don't want to see anyone!
Tell them I'm out!
Stop this nonsense.
Here...
Dry your tears.
Go open it.
Where are you going? Home?
I need a vacation.
A long vacation.
Don't open it!
Please, don't open it!
They say that women shouldn't
do anything else when raising children.
But you're too lenient.
Noe has become too self-indulgent.
Don't worry.
If I didn't let her work,
she'd become unbearable.
But she always stays out late at night.
I'm used to it.
Used to it...
Why don't you scold her?
Well...
I guess I'm just lazy.
I'm fine just playing the shakuhachi.
You don't want to hear more.
Come here.
My poor brother...
It's strange...
Even just now,
I was considering living somewhere else.
Because you're in love with Ôsugi?
No!
I thought I would leave
both you and Ôsugi, to think quietly.
Chiyo...
She's the same age as me.
We grew up together like twin sisters!
How could she sleep with you?
She felt pity, that's all.
Right now, I understand how jealousy...
can be a violent feeling.
So how can you remain so calm?
That's all you can say
to your wife of four years?
Answer!
Would a truly good wife...
behave like you've behaved recently?
"I will do everything
to reveal the true Noe."
"Raise your skills to the highest level
possible and make you a wonderful woman."
Who said that?
You said yourself I was no ordinary woman!
You're right.
You are not an ordinary woman.
But what has our family become?
No...
Neither you nor I...
could bear to see us become...
the same ordinary people we despise.
We're unable to fool ourselves.
Two people,
desperate to be united to each other,
like any other couple.
Who realize they're only together...
because of their memories,
and the state of society,
their children,
and their own weaknesses.
We spend each day...
clinging to each other,
while laughing at ourselves.
Stop it!
I am now certain...
that I love you!
Impossible!
That's no longer possible.
You're upset, that's all.
You're right.
Jealousy perhaps.
Someone else slept with your husband.
Your pride as a wife is wounded.
- And that makes you angry.
- You're wrong!
I'm angry because you betrayed my trust!
Since this winter,
I've talked about our changing feelings.
With our state of detachment,
we can't speak as a couple.
There's no betrayal to talk about.
You've become angry...
over this meaningless marital offence.
Doesn't that reveal a little vanity?
How?
How can you be so calm and detached?
I can't understand you at all!
Makoto will probably be sad.
But at least you can leave this house...
with peace of mind.
Leave me.
Go where you want.
No...
I won't leave you.
Telling me to leave Ôsugi is a problem.
I'm crazy for him!
Even if he's a spy?
A spy? What do you mean?
The rumours are circulating.
He'd sell out to
the authorities if he's broke.
Just to support all his wives?
Now that's funny! So funny I'm crying!
- Ôsugi...
- It's not funny!
Maybe you want me to investigate?
Very well.
I'll tell you if I learn something.
But spy or not,
I want nothing to do with it.
Ôsugi is just the man I love.
Noe?
Please don't open the door.
I'm not a curious woman.
I don't need to know everything.
Do I need to see the face of the
woman who became my husband's mistress?
Wouldn't you feel the same way
if you were in my place?
Anything else?
If not, please go home.
Ôsugi isn't here.
Please tell him...
I...
I've decided to stop seeing him.
I would like to tell him in person.
But I'm in a hurry.
I want to settle this immediately.
Hey, when you're with me,
you're all mine, right?
You're free to think so.
But I don't believe I'm bound to anyone.
Not even me?
There's also Yasuko, and Noe.
Don't you think so?
I don't mean to worry you.
I just came to break up with Ôsugi.
Break up?
You didn't want to leave Tsuji, right?
Couldn't leave him after all these years.
No, I'm leaving Tsuji.
But I won't be with Ôsugi either.
I will live alone.
From now on,
I don't depend on Ôsugi, or anyone.
Ultimately,
you're only thinking of you and Tsuji.
- You may be right.
- Of course.
You don't want to be
responsible for destroying his family!
How dishonest!
You say you want to
live independently, just to save face!
You really think you can do it?
You never will!
Yes I will.
I've already made up my mind.
If you wanted to leave,
you wouldn't have come to say goodbye.
You have no intention of it.
Tell me...
For you, it's not important
if it's Ôsugi or someone else, right?
Life with Tsuji was too hard.
To escape that life,
an affair with any man would do.
No, it's all the same.
Maybe you wanted to
trade your old shoes for new ones.
But you barely took a step,
and they're covered in mud.
Take a look.
It's muddy wherever you go.
It's funny...
You... Me...
Covered in mud.
Do you love Tsuji?
Love him with all your heart?
Do you love Ôsugi?
Have you thought about what love means?
Love means...
To capture someone else's heart,
and monopolize it.
That's what love means to me.
Ôsugi and I are like this.
We belong to each other.
Since you became Ôsugi's lover,
you have interfered with the two of us.
You can't shake us off so easily.
Not until we're finished.
One person possessing another...
Nobody can do that!
Of course they can!
As a journalist, I make 150 yen per month.
He's an anarchist with no money.
I support both Ôsugi and Yasuko.
It's mutually beneficial.
But he knows it's a sham.
When I give him 10 yen,
he won't admit that he receives much more.
Driven by lack of money,
he would have to become a government spy.
There's no freedom without money.
But becoming a spy
would mean selling freedom for money.
And even if he had the money,
he couldn't escape me.
I would kill him if he tried to leave me.
They say you can't buy feelings,
but it's a lie.
You can even buy...
a revolutionary and his soul!
This is how Itsuko is.
Saying this kind of
nonsense makes her happy.
Don't listen to her.
But all this has nothing to do with me.
I'm leaving you.
The rest doesn't matter.
Well...
It's over then.
Yes.
Like Itsuko said,
maybe I've been dishonest.
Maybe I just used you
as a springboard to another life.
I only wanted to untie
the knot that restrained me.
But by untying this knot,
you managed to untie them all.
Goodbye.
I won't return.
I see...
You will end up settling with Ôsugi.
Yes.
There is also Yasuko,
and Itsuko too,
and this doesn't matter?
I see...
Be happy.
I now believe
that I am enamoured with myself.
The best thing is that
you go where you think you must.
Makoto and Ryûji...
will surely understand when they're older.
- Did you have a dream?
- You mean nightmare?
I did just now.
I hope to give it to you.
I wonder if it
worked out with Megumi and him.
Work out? What would be worked out?
Anything and everything.
We can't go back now.
What are you thinking?
I'm not too bad either, right?
I was in fifth grade.
Sleet was falling.
I saw him through the bank window.
I was standing outside, watching.
He was my mother's lover!
That's what I thought.
I often saw him around town.
That's enough.
It's the last time we'll meet.
The good-for-nothing
who made these films ten years late...
That filmmaker...
is exactly like my mother's lover.
You think he wants to use them for an ad?
On September 19th,
around nine in the morning,
Ôsugi and Noe left home together,
as I saw through the backyard hedge.
Mako, who was playing at my house,
hurried out as soon
as she saw their shadows.
But she immediately returned,
and said, "that's my Papa and Mama!"
That was the last time I saw Ôsugi.
The next day,
and the following days,
Mako came to play as usual.
One day when she was here,
playing like always,
a journalist came to take a picture of her.
The following day,
they officially announced Ôsugi's death.
"If Mako comes over to play today,"
"I forbid you to talk about her Papa!"
"It would break poor Mako's little heart."
I said this to my son.
And he seemed to understand
that something terrible had happened,
and he nodded in silence.
Just a moment later,
Mako came in
through the back door, as usual.
When she saw us, she said,
"Papa and Mama are dead."
"Grandpa and Uncle came to look for them."
"I'll go back with them in a car today."
That smart little girl
understood everything.
However, she understood it
like a seven-year-old child.
She knew the sad fate of her parents,
but she played like usual,
in total innocence.
My son took pity on her,
and gave her a doll that he loved,
plus all the colouring paper.
Roan Uchida,
People I Remember: The Final Days of Ôsugi
What are you hoping
to find in this dark library?
The past?
A story?
Documents?
Dust?
Or culture?
I would throw it all away.
I don't know what I did yesterday or why.
You know a lot about nothing!
Noe?
Aren't you Noe Itô?
Yes, I'm Noe.
I've been looking for you a long time.
I'm very happy to meet you.
I even went to Hakata and Imajuku.
This is my dream!
What can I do for you?
I just wanted to talk to you.
Do you know what will happen tomorrow?
Yes...
Do you know what you will do?
Today, I understand about tomorrow.
If you and Ôsugi hadn't been together...
In other words...
If Masaoka had won in your love triangle,
would you have avoided death
seven years later, in 1923,
in the aftermath of the earthquake?
Have you wondered about this?
I can't change my principles.
That's just what they are.
My principles.
One last question:
Between 1923 and 1969,
46 years have elapsed.
How do you see these 46 years?
I came for a fight!
- As a comrade or as a friend?
- Both!
This is my final advice, so listen!
This doesn't concern you.
Can you hear the voices?
- I hear a cat.
- Yasuko is crying.
Itsuko too! Can't you hear them?
- I hear them.
- Itsuko quit the newspaper.
While you and Noe were
romping around Onjuku with her money,
she was waiting for you at Ryôgoku Station.
She's losing her mind.
Do you even understand what you've done?
Are you done talking?
Aren't you ashamed?
I can't do anything.
What did you say?
I love these women equally,
with impartiality.
All three know it.
Impartiality? You've got some nerve!
Don't you pay more attention to Noe?
You live together in Kikufuji Hotel.
So... What will you do?
Let the other two die slowly?
I told you I can't do anything!
We were supposed to live separately,
in complete independence.
But Noe doesn't have a job right now.
She's broke.
All we can do is wait.
And the other two go crazy in the meantime!
You want me to abandon Noe?
Your advice is useless.
Noe has revived
the revolutionary inside of me.
When we were prohibited from meeting,
and our publications were censored,
we were all discouraged.
Speak for yourself!
We all were!
We had resigned ourselves
to the persecution of the ruling class,
and only watched the tragedy in Yanaka.
She reminded me
of my original determination.
She taught me to hate the hateful,
take offence at the offensive,
and adamantly support
the advancement of the oppressed.
Sakai defined it
as childish sentimentalism,
but isn't childish sentimentalism
exactly what we need?
And the result of your
determination is this miserable scandal?
If those words hadn't come
from one of your mistresses,
you wouldn't have lost a single comrade!
Comrades...
My comrades in revolution...
What does revolution mean to us?
It's a way to open up
a land of absolute freedom.
Our most valuable method of
ending man's exploitation of man.
But the existence of private property
sustains this exploitation.
And what is private property?
It's the system through which the state
renders the morals of matrimony absolute,
so wealth is something that's inherited.
Worse! It's our deepest desire!
That's the problem.
Revolution is the way
to blow this system to pieces!
Marriage...
Marriage that builds the family...
Family that builds the State...
As long as these are considered
to be sacred, absolute principles,
revolution will remain out of reach!
Think about this some more!
A man with mistresses
is the morality of the bourgeoisie.
Some reward for women's rights activists!
You all support revolution
to obtain freedom,
but as soon as I talk about
free love between a man and a woman,
you get riled up,
and shout "Traitor!" or "Whore!"
You retreat from it... I see...
I understand it's
difficult to keep a cool head.
But what will you do?
You want to become radical Confucianists?
What a strange situation...
You refuse to look around you,
and you wonder if true revolution
and freedom are really possible.
That's enough.
Farewell!
In Russia...
The situation is changing.
Some say it won't happen until next March.
Right!
Look after Yasuko.
Ultimately, you ended up
picking the fruit that I grew,
before throwing it to the ground.
But that's fine.
I left "Seitô" in your care.
Do you regret leaving it to me?
Honey!
Isn't the wind a bit cold?
Not the slightest regret!
Just when I wanted to
stop thinking about the magazine,
you had the desire to keep it going.
Our magazine could not have
hoped for a more appropriate end.
The number of pages
and the paper quality diminished,
then it died miserably like a dog.
Perhaps that's what it deserved...
Could you move please?
You're blocking the sun.
Why couldn't she have
told me to start up "Seitô" again?
Don't blame yourself.
On your own, you did a great deal of work.
But these efforts are nothing
to a bourgeois woman,
who sees the magazine as her child.
I wanted to protest.
Tell her I was trying something new.
But the words didn't come out.
Something was holding them back.
Something?
I don't mean you, of course.
Rather, a sort of apprehension from Aichô.
Maybe because we had
distanced ourselves from each other.
It's true you didn't
behave like you usually would.
When things calm down,
I'll resume the publication.
Otherwise, leaving Tsuji
to run with you would make no sense.
Run with me?
I see...
You certainly run quickly.
Yaeko Nogami also said that to me.
"If you keep running so fast,"
"won't you overtake yourself eventually?"
Maybe it finally happened...
I didn't think you were busy with Noe.
The maid said there were two of you,
but I assumed it was Yasuko.
I'll go home.
I'm sorry.
I probably shouldn't have come.
If you really believed that,
it would've been you who left just now.
But I wanted to see you.
You can understand that, right?
Yesterday,
and the day before,
I was waiting for you desperately.
When you didn't come, I got worried.
I wondered if you had gotten sick.
Sick?
Yes...
I have a bit of a cold and fever.
So let me sleep a little.
Sleep well then.
Is it Noe?
It's her. I'm sure of it.
I can't find the keys to Kikufuji Hotel!
I've looked everywhere!
I was going back to Yokohama,
but I turned back.
You're so forgetful...
Wait there. I'll come get you.
If you have a cold,
you shouldn't go out at night.
Bring me my coat.
I'm going home now.
Noe said she was leaving,
but maybe she's hiding nearby,
waiting for me to leave.
Can't you leave me in peace?
- You're thinking about Noe...
- Enough!
Noe...
You afraid she'll come back?
She won't come back!
She's not that kind of woman.
What do I know? She's sneaky.
I think we need to have a serious talk.
I can't bear this situation anymore!
You really think so?
I think so too.
You're right to find it pitiful.
I'm tired of it!
Let's end it once and for all.
So you...
Our story is over, you could say.
- That's all you have to say?
- What else?
Aren't you the proponent of free love?
I believed your theories
and did as you said.
But this is too much! Too much!
You're telling me to
acknowledge that my theory failed?
With pleasure!
It failed because it had to fail.
Happy now?
My egoism ruined everything.
That's what you're trying to say, right?
Nothing else is possible between us?
Free love?
It is within reach.
Within reach!
Some day, men and women, even spouses,
will make love with no concern for money.
- I...
- No, it's impossible!
Now I know what you're thinking.
You don't know.
On days when you have money,
and days when you don't...
Be clear!
Noe was wearing a pretty kimono.
When you have some money, you change.
Don't talk nonsense. I won't change.
Your way of thinking has changed.
You're good with words.
But what about actions?
What's the reality of our relationship?
What about Noe? She got between us!
Taking advantage of
your and Yasuko's money without working.
No...
Taking advantage of the sacrifices I made!
A little money,
and she struts around in fancy kimonos!
That's the reality of free love!
A little scandal, just like all the others!
Yes... Merely a scandal!
Started by all that money!
I see.
So that's it?
So I owe you money.
That's why you can smugly attack me!
I'll give it to you!
It's not spy money.
I got it by threatening
the Minister of the Interior.
Our movement is obstructing them,
so of course they'll give out money!
It's for you!
Look, it's money. Take it!
Take it and go home!
Now you're a stranger to me.
A stranger!
What are you doing?
I want you to hold me...
I don't know you anymore.
I offer my apologies.
Forgive me. I was wrong.
So...
Can you see how pathetic you are?
Since we haven't settled our problem...
I'm cold.
I can't sleep.
Putting aside problems
before they're resolved...
I hate that! What a way to think!
I have my rules... But please just hold me.
Not a chance.
You would accept Noe. But not me.
I've read her letters. I know it all...
Noe...
You complain that you're a victim.
You even went out to buy a knife.
But by driving me to her,
you have attacked Yasuko.
An aggressor like yourself,
under the pretext that you're Noe's victim,
should not complain.
I know Noe's presence
seems like an attack to you.
I've paid attention.
No...
I will never be a victim...
Wait!
Noe!
Noe...
The camera is loaded.
The past doesn't interest me.
I have no interest in filming the past.
What happens next?
I will do absolutely nothing.
Will boys say the same thing in 50 years?
Of course!
What did he do next?
Who?
Your mother's lover.
He smiled.
Through the bank window.
Then he said "come in," and I was there.
At his house, I mean.
- What was his house like?
- How should I know?
I was blindfolded.
He was a homo.
Or not.
He was just playing a trick.
That's all.
That's it!
He chose death.
Who did?
He realized death is the greatest pleasure.
Death reverses his value.
- Reverses what?
- Value!
So you're going to kill me?
Yes.
I have no other choice.
Ah...
In memory of our friendship,
I must ask you to do it quickly.
Why don't you escape?
Since you're going to kill me,
it would be pointless.
You want to escape from yourself...
Don't you?
It's not your theories that failed,
but the revolution itself.
It's yourself that has failed.
You set this trap to escape your fears.
This trap?
This trap, you say?
The three lines that you have entangled...
The three women...
The more they struggle,
the more entangled they become.
Then comes the ultimate moment.
The three lines constrict you.
It's all over. Like you expected.
Your fears will come to an end.
Believe what you want.
But the revolution is
something that nullifies itself.
To me,
that amounts to removing me.
This knife driven into my body...
It whispers words of love and dread.
Just like you...
Normal people would be afraid,
but to me there's no greater ecstasy.
I refuse to kill you if it helps you!
Something like this
happened to me before.
In 3rd year of Cadet School.
I was...
You were...
An out of control bully,
always armed with a knife.
A juvenile delinquent,
who was expelled after a knife fight.
Ending your dream
of becoming an army general.
Isn't that right?
No!
The other guy had pulled a knife.
I reached into my pocket
to take out my own knife.
But... I changed my mind
and fought him bare-handed.
He rushed at me.
I fell to the ground.
You knew...
You knew how it would end!
My body...
has suddenly become cold.
Hey, you...
You think you can ignite me?
You can't ignite me.
You can't do it!
You can't do anything!
I knew it. You were hiding.
But Ôsugi is mine. You can't have him.
You can't claim him.
Thanks to this, he'll be mine.
You won't just lose Ôsugi with that.
You'll lose everything.
Losing everything...
is still the best choice.
Ôsugi and his principles are
condemned to die sooner or later.
It's better if I do it right now!
Now he's mine!
Think a little, and drop the knife.
You won't gain anything but a corpse.
That's fine with me. That's fine...
Only in death can he truly belong to me.
I believe that.
You...
Why didn't you stab him?
What was it...
that held your arms back?
No...
I stabbed him!
Look...
The blade was plunged into his heart.
Can't you see?
The blood flows...
like sand.
His eyes no longer blink.
His lips have lost their colour.
Ôsugi is dead, my Ôsugi...
As soon as my love pierced him, he died.
My Ôsugi died at that moment.
It's true...
Death makes his face so sweet.
The cheeks that were once rosy...
now extend like a white desert.
All who venture inside are swallowed up.
These eyes that looked only at me...
don't look at anything anymore!
And yet...
I wasn't supposed to see his face of death.
Right?
I defeated Yasuko. I defeated Itsuko.
I followed in this man's path.
That's why I will
be killed with him some day.
That's why, right now,
I want to look at his sweet face of death.
You follow me, knowing that you will die?
Yes.
Hearing it from your mouth
further confirms my choice.
You know that.
What did Ôsugi say?
What did the dead man say?
He said, "Sayonara, Itsuko."
Sayonara...
Murdered?
But I'll probably kill our enemies first.
I am that kind of woman.
You will be killed because of me.
You know that?
I know...
You're afraid.
You're afraid because
you know they'll kill you.
You're just an ordinary woman.
You're wrong!
Our game of three is over now!
Finished!
Ôsugi is alive.
When I saw that you couldn't...
That you were incapable of stabbing him,
I understood what I had to do.
I...
I saw the future in front of me.
Ôsugi is dead!
- You can't kill a dead man!
- Wrong...
You took a chance on this knife,
thinking it was enough to pierce him.
But you failed.
It was I who did it!
It's all over!
It finished as it had to.
I stabbed you myself!
Noe has won the game
of love between three women.
At the same time,
you have taken the place of my wife Yasuko.
The position that you hate the most.
The grudge of another woman...
is no reason for a woman to kill a man.
It wasn't a man that you killed...
It was...
Yes.
It wasn't a man that I killed.
It was only Ôsugi.
Don't die! Open your eyes!
Why must you die?
Tell my comrades:
On November 7th, 1916,
Sakae Ôsugi was
killed at the hand of Noe Itô.
Ôsugi the anarchist
died the only death he deserved.
Blue...
I see the blue sky...
And many black chimneys...
And, bright as gold,
strands of wheat swaying in the wind!
I see it!
I see everything!
Even that which can't be seen!
My love...
My three loves...
The revolution!
The revolution that
brings about its own nullification.
The truth!
Noe has stabbed me.
She ran me through.
No...
Noe was able to do it...
only because she is pregnant.
Ôsugi's child is
beginning to grow inside her.
You thought that I didn't know?
Stupid woman!
Sleep well...
You who were mine.
There was nothing else I could do!
You understand, right?
I will be free of you.
I came back to tell you this.
At this moment,
there was no other way
to go beyond you.
You must not die!
One day,
you pierced me like the wind.
With that wound, I understood freedom.
But I knew that one day or another,
I would become your prisoner.
That's why I needed my turn to pierce you.
I wanted more freedom... More freedom...
He's dead.
He's really dead.
Ôsugi...
Say something! Anything!
What should I say if I'm dead?
Quick, call a doctor.
Ôsugi narrowly escaped death that day.
So, why did Itsuko Masaoka confess,
if she didn't stab him?
She confessed?
Soon afterwards, at Scotland Yard.
She chose to go to prison.
Is that what you think?
It's simple:
Noe organized an imaginary crime.
In order to win,
Itsuko committed the
real crime and went to prison.
That's all.
To win? Is winning that important?
I don't know.
Is there anything else?
If so, all this didn't even happen.
Noe!
When you were massacred,
what really happened?
Do you know?
Spring, March, survivors of the massacre,
We dance among the flowers
Lights!
Action!
This photo will be a great
monument for future generations.
Please look at the camera, everyone.
Thank you very much.
Someone lost his ears
getting them stuck in this door.
His ears?
So, can he hear himself crying?
EROS + MASSACRE