And here we are,
ladies and gentlemen,
in 1900,
standing on the very spot
where Desdemona first met
Othello many centuries ago.
Venice-Queen of the Adriatic.
Venice-the city of silence.
That cannon,
ladies and gentlemen,
is fired off every day to
indicate the noon hour.
Every day in Venice at noon,
you hear, boom.
In Venice,
there are 177 canals
measuring 28 miles,
and there are 156 bridges
connecting 114 islands.
And there is the great
Church of St. Mark.
The Church of St. Mark
was begun in 830,
but was not finished
until the 15th century.
There are
more than 500 marble columns
in the Church of St. Mark.
The mosaic work covers an
area of 45,970 square feet,
and the interior is completely
produced and decorated...
Are you finished, Caryl?
Yes. Until 7:00.
You're a darling
to have waited so long.
I didn't mind.
You know, you must be
made of strawberry ices.
Oh... did you ask Ilanti for
an increase in salary?
Yes. And he said no.
Then you shouldn't
be working here.
Darling, you're a genius.
Oh, please don't say that,
Fenella. I'm not a genius.
If you persist in thinking I am,
you're going to be
terribly disappointed.
Photographs of the big fair
and party, friends,
celebrating the opening
of the 20th century.
Photograph?
No, thank you.
I've got an idea.
Why don't you give a concert
of your own in a hall?
That's what I want to do,
but that takes money.
Don't you know some rich
person who'd sponsor you?
Even if I did, he mightn't
consider me a good investment.
Oh, silly, you'd be a wonderful investment.
Caryl Dubrok-
The son of the great composer.
- Alfred Dubrok.
Why, any sensible sponsor
would jump at the chance.
Grazie mille.
I know. Professor Heinrich.
Professor Heinrich?
Of course. Why didn't
we think of him before?
Professor Heinrich is
not only your friend.
He was your father's as well.
I'll ask him to arrange
a concert for you.
He's at home now.
No, I'm sure he wouldn't
consider me talented enough to bother with.
He'd be embarrassed,
and so would I.
Very well. If you
want to be stubborn.
I'm not stubborn.
It's simply a case of-
Then there's only one
thing left for us to do,
and that is to get married.
Married?
Of course. Papa and
Mama know we're in love.
And our marriage would solve everything.
How?
Don't be silly.
The Maclean money.
And the Dubrok genius.
No. No, Fenella.
Caryl...
What, darling?
Don't you want us to be married?
You know I do, Fenella. More
than anything in the world.
That's why I'm saving my money.
In a year's time, I'll have saved
enough to give a concert in Milan.
Then if I'm a success, we-
Look here, though, I shan't be able to save
anything if we always ride in gondolas.
I mean, wouldn't we get to your
house sooner if we walked?
The canal is so roundabout.
I don't want to get home
sooner, as you put it.
This is Wednesday, you know.
Wednesday?
Yes. That's why I don't
want to go home early.
I don't understand.
Well, I, Fenella Maclean,
am at present residing
in the Neroni Palace in Venice,
which is a famous city of Italy.
All of Venice is famous,
and the Neroni Palace
is especially famous.
It's very old and smelly.
It contains on the lower floor
priceless paintings
and frescoes.
The Macleans occupy
quarters on the second floor.
And on Wednesdays,
The public is admitted to the
art treasures of the palace.
Little barbarians.
Giggling females.
Good afternoon, Herr Heinrich.
Good afternoon.
My dear.
This schoolgirl visitation
gets worse every week.
The place is fairly swarming
with the little wretches.
But it does give the
palace a certain atmosphere.
You must admit that, Ivor.
I don't want atmosphere. I want peace.
Here, darling. Drink your tea.
And your rehearsals,
Herr Heinrich,
are they going well?
Rather well, yes.
But I miss my own orchestra.
It will be a relief
to get back to London.
Let me go. Let go.
Let me go.
Let me go, or I'll crack
your shins for you.
Let me go.
Giuseppe, who is that young person?
It's a thief, Signor Maclean.
We found her in the
Signorina's bedroom.
A thief, huh? Bring her in.
Let me alone. Let me alone.
Giuseppe, you may wait outside.
Oh, stop her. She'll
jump in the canal.
Yes, I will if you don't
let me alone, you ninnies.
Why all the fuss? I'm no thief.
Then what were you
doing in my daughter's room?
Oh. Was it your daughter's?
She has a lot of
clothes, hasn't she?
Well?
I was hiding.
Hiding? From whom?
The schoolgirls.
Then the teachers began to call roll,
and I had to skip.
You see, I'm not a schoolgirl.
But why did you
join them at all?
To get something to eat.
To eat?
Yes. You see, it's this way.
These school groups visit
the museums and stuffy
old places like this.
Then afterward, they
go to a shop for tea,
and I go along and eat with them
if they don't find me out first.
It's a good arrangement.
It works out
very well, generally.
But you mean you've done
this sort of thing before?
I do it all the time.
But that's stealing.
Aha. Someone has been
cheating at solitaire.
There's a red 8 on a red 9.
Cheating a bit at solitaire is
quite different from stealing, my girl.
Yes, it is. You have
no need to cheat at cards.
But sometimes,
I do have to steal food.
Oh, hello.
So your present costume
was merely put on
for the occasion, right?
You are a clever old
verwandte, aren't you?
What does she mean - verwandte?
It's difficult to translate,
fortunately.
Young woman, I shall call the police
unless you confine yourself to English
and sensible English at that.
If you call the police,
I shall tell them
you cheat at solitaire.
Now, then, what is your name?
Gemma.
Gemma what?
Gemma Smith.
You don't like Smith? Then
my name is Gemma Porloniovsky.
However, it's really Smith.
But you're English.
I was born of an English
father and a Hungarian mother
on a Dutch ship on the high seas.
But as soon as
we made port, they put my father in prison.
For fathering you?
No. For killing a man.
What?
Yes.
And later on, my mother
committed suicide.
And-and then?
Oh... nothing much. Grew up with
relatives of my mother.
Decided I didn't care
for them and ran away.
But how did you get to Venice?
On a wine cart from Padua.
But the driver wasn't a nice man.
And as soon as we came
to the edge of the city,
he kicked me off.
And in Venice, what did you do?
I went to a hospital,
a free one.
Oh, were you ill?
No. No, I felt fine.
But I was having a baby.
Perhaps you would like
me to tell you about it.
Thank you. We shan't go into that.
Oh, but the baby is wonderful.
I call him Piccolo
because he is so little.
This, uh, child, did it
have a father?
What do you think?
Certainly, it did.
The father was my husband...
for a while.
He is dead now.
Oh, dear.
Yes.
Well, that's about all.
Venice... my baby,
me discharged from the hospital
with no strength in my bones
and no money in my stocking.
But it all came out all right.
I'm like a cat.
I always land on my feet.
You know, inside of a day,
I'd fainted in the street,
and there my friend found me.
The baby and I are staying
with him for a moment.
And this friend of yours, is he-
Oh, no. He has no money either.
That's why I go about with the schools.
To get food for us.
This so-called
friend, who is he?
Young musician.
His name is Dubrok.
Oh!
Yes, he's the son of Albert Dubrok.
The composer.
A famous father, but the son,
weren't a much smaller bush
if you ask me. However he might-
You may go.
You mean it?
I do, indeed.
Please go at once.
Oh, all right.
Arrivederci.
Thank heavens
Fenella wasn't here.
By the way, where is she?
She... she's out with Mr. Dubrok.
Hello, everybody.
I have news for you.
Oh, I'm so glad you're here,
Professor Heinrich.
Darling.
Mama, papa.
Fenella, listen to me.
No. You listen to me, Papa.
I have a wonderful
surprise, and it won't keep.
I'm going to marry Caryl Dubrok.
Great scott. What did you say?
She said she's going
to marry Caryl Dubrok.
No, darling.
You couldn't possibly.
The fellow's a scoundrel.
We're leaving Venice at once.
It's just as well.
One can't trust it.
You know, the whole idea of fetching
a train in a boat is ridiculous.
I can't get used to it.
How are you?
Fenella, I...
What's happening? Are
your parents going away?
Yes. And I'm going with them.
You're what?
Fenella, come along.
I can't marry you, Caryl.
But why not?
Because of Gemma.
Gemma? Gemma?
But who is Gemma?
Ask Professor Heinrich.
Fenella, please wait a moment.
Really, I don't know any Gemma.
I've never even heard of such a person.
You've got to believe me.
Fenella...
Look, Professor, I don't know any Gemma.
I've never even heard of such a person.
You've got to believe me.
I do. The trouble is
the Macleans prefer
to believe Gemma.
That's why they are taking
their daughter out
to the Dolomites.
The parents would have
objected to you in any case.
They don't like musicians.
Musicians are not practical.
They don't make money.
Fenella doesn't care
about money.
Rich people
are always saying that,
but they don't really mean it.
Which way, Signore?
Diritto.
Diritto? Bene.
Listen.
Oh, it's an original tune
and rather diverting.
Why, that's one of
my father's things,
and that concertina's mine.
It is your concertina?
Yes. I loaned it to
Sebastian in Milan last year.
Don't you see? That must be
my brother Sebastian
playing the concertina up there.
Gondolier, stop.
The music's coming
from that upper window,
the one with the white rags
hanging out over the ledge.
Your so-called white rags are
baby napkins, my young friend.
What do you mean?
They're Gemma's.
Gemma, huh?
Piccolo, there is positively
no boy soprano part
in this composition,
so shut up!
Thank you.
I knew it.
Oh, hello.
Look here, Sebastian-
I'm glad you dropped in.
There's something
I want you to hear.
I've got something
Listen.
You've upset my applecart
again, haven't you?
Have I? It must be
a very poorly balanced
applecart to upset so easily.
Besides, how could I?
I haven't seen you since Milan.
Do you know a girl named Gemma?
Also, her brat.
He's a cute little
fella, isn't he?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, no, thanks.
I create music. It's Gemma's.
Would you be so kind as
to explain who Gemma is?
Certainly. I found her wandering around
in the streets one day,
sort of starving
and so on, you know,
so I thought the only humane thing to do
was to take her in, so I did.
Very noble of you.
It certainly was,
considering the state of my finances.
Uh, by the way-
Not a lira.
Loaning you money is like
feeding straws to a fire.
What's that you're whistling?
This little song I'm writing.
Gemma has got
a pretty nice voice.
I thought she might sing it some day.
Here. Take a look.
"Escape Me Never."
Mm-hmm. Words by Browning,
With slight additions
by Sebastian Dubrok.
Escape me never.
My beloved-
While I am I.
And you are you.
Of course, I'm not letting Gemma know
she's got voice enough to sing it.
You know how women are.
Once they begin to think they're
important, they get absolutely out of hand.
From what I've heard of Gemma,
she's already out of hand.
Why? Do you know her?
No. But she forced her way
into the Neroni
Palace yesterday,
and the palace happens to be
in the residence of
some friends of mine-
Mr. And Mrs. Maclean
and Miss Maclean.
And your precious
Gemma told them
she was living with a
musician named Dubrok,
so naturally, they
assumed it was me.
They-they thought I-
Oh, shut up.
Oh, that's very funny.
Hey, Gemma.
Signore.
Is your name Gemma?
If it is, you've put on
a bit of weight.
Gemma.
Yeah?
Huh?
Come on up.
Something's happened.
Come on up quick.
I'll be there in a minute.
All right, everybody to the fountain.
I'm in a hurry. Come on.
You must go now, Signorina.
Maybe someday, you will not have to go.
That would be nice.
All of us here feel the same way.
I know I'm older than you, and I'm fat,
but perhaps there's other things.
If you were my wife,
you will have all the
bread you want to eat
and love and 5 little ones.
You think 5 too many?
Ah, but everyone must have
at least 5, to be happy.
You marry me,
and you get 5 all at
once without no trouble.
Signorina, if you could-
Dino, can we talk
about it later, huh?
Antonino.
Up.
Ah, thank you, Antonino.
Thank you.
Piccolo.
Don't worry. He's all right.
Nothing wrong with him.
Gemma, hey.
Behold my brother - Caryl.
The fool of the family, huh?
But he's in trouble.
You remember that palazzo
you went barging into yesterday?
Mm-hmm. What about it?
The family are friends of Caryl's.
Ahem, especially the daughter.
You have no right
to laugh at Fenella.
You've never even seen her.
Nevertheless, I know
exactly what she's like.
She's the kind that is
always taking cold baths.
And she's frightfully
keen on croquet, you know,
and the only perfume she
ever uses is cologne water.
Why don't you be quiet?
But she has nice gloves.
Just my size.
You stole those gloves
from Fenella.
Of course. And what if I did?
Give them to me.
No. You try and get them.
Sebastian.
No.
You know... I like you.
Well, I don't like you.
How Sebastian can stand
having you around
I can't, for the life of me, see.
I am going.
Wait. Is she really
your sweetheart?
She was until you spoiled it.
Aw.
I'm sorry.
I had no idea you were
more than friends with her.
I shouldn't have laughed
a moment ago.
Why don't you just go to this Fenella
and knock some sense into her?
Being a woman, she'll
love you all the more.
She's gone.
Left Venice, you mean?
Yes.
Where did she go?
To the Dolomites.
What will you do?
I'm going to find her and tell
her about you and Sebastian.
Bravo. That's the stuff.
And I'll go with you.
Oh, no, you won't.
You better not go alone. I know women.
She'll never believe
you. You need a witness.
The Dolomites, yes.
We'll take my concertina
and set out immediately.
We'll cross valleys, climb mountains,
sing for our supper
in every swank hotel until you find her.
What do you say?
But it's not the way to
do it. It's not dignified.
Digni...
Oh... if she had wanted
someone dignified,
she could have had
her pick of them at home.
But, no,
she took you because you
are the opposite sort of person
her parents
would have chosen for her.
Besides, think how pleased she'll
be to have you come after her.
That's what a woman
really wants-
to be needed, pursued,
made to feel that she's-
Oh, what do you know about it?
I need a holiday,
and the Dolomites are
just the place for it.
Stop grumbling. It's all settled.
Very well. Come along if you've
got the money for your train fare.
Train fare? What do
we need train fare for?
We're going a piedi, on
foot, shanks' mare.
What's the matter with
you? Can't you walk?
Are you a cripple?
All right.
Good.
Yes, it'll be wonderful.
We'll eat wild
strawberries with our lunch
and sit under the pine
trees when we are tired
and pick edelweiss
and alpenrosen.
But you're not coming.
Well, what I mean is
somebody's got to stay here
and take care of Piccolo.
After all,
this jaunt of ours might be
nothing but, well,
a wild goose chase.
You can't haul a little baby.
Don't you think?
Caryl, what time is it?
Oh, that's the watch father
gave you, isn't it?
Yes.
Mm-hmm. Gold, too, eh?
Oh, no, you don't.
It's the last valuable
thing I own, and I won't part with it.
What? Do you mean to tell me
that you'd allow a miserable gold watch
to stand between you and Fenella?
Come on, we're going to need
a little dinero, aren't we?
I'll pawn it first thing in the morning,
and in return,
I shall bring you together with Fenella.
You shall be wed and go to live
in a little green-shuttered house.
Of course, there's a hitch.
You'll have to make
a living for her.
I'll expect to.
Don't worry. She'll expect you to.
Every morning you
leave the little house,
you'll have an attaché case
full of contracts and music,
and Fenella will be upstairs
waving good-bye to you.
And then after you
have children-
Oh, stow it. How do you know
so much about my future?
Because I know your past.
But it'll be a pretty good life for you.
Why wouldn't it be a
good one for you, as well?
My dear, Gemma, Caryl is
the nice, dependable sort,
solid from tip to toe.
I only wish I were like him.
I'll bet you do.
But I never shall be.
I'm what the lady poets
call a free spirit.
Meaning a selfish pig-
about everything but your music.
Uh-huh. Ah, but honest about it.
Don't you think?
Funny little codger, isn't she?
Good-bye, Gemma.
My little Piccolo,
My pupazzetto,
I still have you, haven't I?
For a while, I have.
But in a few years,
you'll grow up to be
a big strong handsome man,
who makes some woman very unhappy.
Oh, so sweet.
You'll make her
happy at first, no doubt,
but in the end,
it'll be the same story.
Yes, it will.
Oh, it's all right, yes.
It's all right, Piccolo.
Yes, it's all right, my Piccolo.
I thought Piccolo would have
a feather to wake up with.
He gets a lot of fun out of it.
I suppose you don't
like being left behind.
I don't mind at all.
You shouldn't.
You'll be all right here, won't you?
Perfectly.
But Dino has asked me
to marry him.
I think I'll do it.
You'll what?
Marry Dino.
In the name of Piccolo?
What for?
Well, it would be a
very good arrangement.
I could take care
of his children,
and he could take care
of Piccolo and me.
Why, that's absolutely nonsense.
I never heard anything so ridiculous.
You ought to be pleased
to get rid of me.
Maybe I should, at that.
Very well.
Then there's nothing
further to discuss.
You'll go your way,
and I'll go mine.
And we shall both be free
as we were before...
and Dino will be kind to me,
much kinder than
you've ever been.
So, he's been kind
to you, has he?
Why, that fat bread peddler.
I suppose the next thing
you'll be telling me,
He calls you his coricino.
I can hear him now.
"Ah, signorina, I love you."
Shut your mouth.
I don't understand
your wretched Italian.
You don't? Then
I'll translate it.
"Without you, my love...
without you on my arm, I cannot live."
But enough.
Come to think of it...
you don't sing as much through
your nose as you used to.
You might be useful.
Caryl can play the concertina,
and you and I
can do the singing.
But what would I do with Piccolo?
Piccolo? Put him in an orphanage.
He's not an orphan.
Well, all right.
I can live with it.
Take him along.
The mountain air would be good for him.
Good for you, too.
Wouldn't it?
All right. Then it's settled.
Dino.
Piccolo, Piccolo,
We are going with him, yes.
Behold-the Dolomites-
a region named
for the famous french geologist Dolomieu
because it was he
who made them known to the world.
I wish he'd made them less steep.
How much farther is it to Orzano?
Oh, about a kilometer.
Orzano tonight.
Tomorrow night, Martino.
She may have left Martino.
Heinrich's letter said they'd
be there until Wednesday.
They might have changed
their plans.
Oh... here. You carry Piccolo
for a while.
That'll give you
something to worry about.
Great scott, Piccolo. You're
getting heavier every day.
Naturally.
Look, Sebastian, edelweiss.
Isn't it beautiful?
Mm-hmm.
She loves me.
She loves me not.
No, don't. You'll ruin it.
Oh, come on.
You're wasting time.
We're not wasting time.
We're enjoying ourselves.
Don't tease him. He's
unhappy without his Fenella.
Just because he's unhappy,
he wants everybody else to be unhappy.
Come along, Monsieur le Duc.
We have to find Caryl's lady love.
Then he won't be so cross.
Come on.
Come, follow, follow, follow.
Follow, follow.
Follow me...
Come, follow, follow, follow.
Follow, follow, follow me...
Come, follow, follow me...
Come, follow, follow, follow.
Follow, follow.
Follow me...
Come, follow, follow, follow.
Follow, follow, follow me.
Oh, Sebastian, I think
we had better find another way.
Why? Afraid of getting
your feet wet? Go on.
Wait until I take my shoes off.
Oh!
You know, I think it might be deep.
Well, you go first,
then if you sink,
we'll know it is.
Come on, come on.
Come on, Monsieur le Duc.
Shove, Caryl.
Pull.
Piccolo, Piccolo!
What are you trying to do,
drown my baby?
Piccolo. Aw, Piccolo.
Oh.
I'm sorry, Caryl.
Does it hurt very much?
I can walk.
It can't be very far now.
Grüße, fraulein.
Grüß gott.
I wonder if you could tell us,
how far is it to Orzano, please?
Just a few kilometers.
You'll see it around the turn.
Uh-huh. And what about
lodgings-cheap ones?
Oh, there's an inn there that's
very cheap and also very good.
Just this side of the hotel.
Zumkefeldzen, it's called.
Well, that's very kind of you, indeed.
And may I say
that if all the natives of the
Dolomites are as charming as you,
our travels will be
most pleasant?
Oh, for heaven's sake,
Sebastian.
Auf wiedersehen.
There it is-
big as life and twice as wonderful.
Caryl, take this to the landlady
and ask her to fill
it with warm milk, huh?
All right.
Oh, don't take that off, Sebastian.
It's his good luck charm.
This?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, be careful.
That's valuable.
Valuable?
Yes.
It's a composition-my father's,
signed by his own hand. Look.
Boy, I could sell this
for a barrelful of money.
Then why don't you.
I'm keeping it for
something to shoot at.
Ah, he was a master of melody.
The old man.
You do better than that.
Hmm?
You're a master of everything,
but nothing ever masters you.
Miss-uh, madam, I think
it's just warm enough.
Danke schön, frau Huber.
I'll take care of your knee
in a moment, Caryl.
Piccolo, look.
Hmm...
pretty good...
for the price.
Sebastian, better
get over to the hotel
and see if they'll
let us sing tonight, huh?
All right.
Wait until I make myself seductive.
Hmm, you must expect the
manager to be a woman.
No, but he'll probably have a wife.
See if the hotel orchestra
will help us out.
It'll make a better concert.
That way, we can expect
a fee from the manager
on top of what we collect
from the guests.
Will you remember?
Mm-hmm. You know, you two
are lucky to have me along.
We've landed a concert engagement
every night since we left Venice.
Don't take all the credit for that.
You've had to use Gemma's baby
to clinch the deal more than once.
Well, how do I look?
Uh, like a duke in disguise.
What? Only a duke? Wow.
Oh, yes, you better
wear this tonight.
It's quite becoming. It
makes you look like a woman.
Well, arrivederci, children.
And don't forget to
keep the door locked.
There may be dragons in the forest.
Let's see.
Yes, it's a bad bruise,
all right.
Gemma.
You think this is going
to be too tight, huh?
Gemma.
You really are in love
with him, aren't you?
Ah.
He's a dreadful man.
That girl we met on the bike,
he could never expect
to see her again,
oh, but he had to spread
his charm on her
like jam on a piece of bread.
He does it all the time.
He's probably ogling some
woman at this very moment.
He just can't help it.
He's always been like that.
Now, you lie down and make
yourself comfortable.
I have to get Piccolo
ready for bed.
Women are nothing but
parsley to Sebastian.
Music, that's his meat.
I know.
That's the only thing
in this whole world
that he's really unselfish about.
It's a pity you don't
care more for music.
But I have the baby.
You know, Caryl, Piccolo
actually belongs to me.
He's my music
and much more wonderful than
anything Sebastian could ever write.
I still think it's a pity
you don't care more for his music.
What difference does it make?
Does a wife have to be-
I mean a woman-
mad about the profession
of the man she loves?
Is that necessary?
No. I suppose not.
I could take care of him-
cook for him, mend,
keep him well,
see that he worked when he should.
That's important, isn't it?
We could be happy together.
Except that it wouldn't be fair to you.
Sebastian's wife will have
a rather unpleasant
time of it, I imagine.
My dear Caryl, do
you expect love to be pleasant?
Has it been pleasant for you?
Is your Fenella perfect?
Practically. Yes.
Parsley. I don't even
mean that much to him.
But... ah, but surely-
No. It's not what you think, Caryl.
A pat on the head,
an occasional hug,
absent-minded kiss now and then.
That's all that's
ever been between us,
and it's not enough.
I want more than that.
I want my share of love.
I want him to be my husband.
Your brother's a beast.
He seems to think I have
no feelings whatsoever,
no blood in my veins,
no need to be happy like other women.
I hate him.
Caryl, I think you had better stay
home tonight with that knee.
Then you can take care
of the baby for me.
All right, if you and
Sebastian can manage without me.
Of course, we can.
Piccolo...
did you hear what he
said about my dress?
You know, he's never really
noticed my clothes before.
That's because I've never
had anything stylish,
and I wouldn't have had this time
if I hadn't bought the
stuff and made it myself.
And it'll look even
better in the moonlight,
because after the concert,
we'll walk home together,
and I'll take his arm,
and perhaps he'll
say more nice things,
but not about
my dress, about me.
Perhaps he'll even tell me
he's in love with me, huh?
We'll see you later.
Thank you.
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
And now for your pleasure...
for your pleasure,
a song- "Love for Love."
'Promise me.
Love for love.
And I'm yours.
Till the end of time.
Love is a wondrous adventure.
Something that
no one should miss.
If you want me, darling.
Take me.
All that I ask is this.
Give me love for love.
Nothing more.
Nothing less.
Don't promise me the moon.
Leave the stars.
Where they are.
Give me just your heart.
Say it's mine.
Only mine.
Promise me.
Love for love.
And I'm yours.
Till the end of time. '
Collect now.
What?
But we haven't given them a fair go.
Shouldn't we play
one or 2 more songs?
Go on.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
It was charming, monsieur.
Charming.
Indeed it was, madam. Charming.
Our pleasure, I assure you. Charming.
The manager's wife.
Of course.
Charming.
Your pleasure, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you, sir.
Madam, thank you.
Thank you.
Not there. The old geezer.
Oh, boy.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you, sir.
Melvin.
Thank you. And you, madam, thank you.
Our pleasure.
Did you do well tonight?
Uh-huh. Pretty well.
Aha. You did all right yourself.
I don't just mean the money.
You were wonderful-singing.
Thank you.
You're happy tonight, huh?
Yes, I am. And do you know something?
What?
I didn't mind your
flirting with that woman.
Me? Flirting?
What woman?
The manager's wife.
Oh. The manager's wife.
We got to be nice to people like that.
After all, they're our bread and butter.
Yes, I know, but, Sebastian,
we wouldn't even have
to bother with them
if you'd settle down and write-
and I know you can-
really good music.
Gemma, darling,
to write really good music,
you've got to be... inspired.
Inspired?
Yes. By a place, by somebody.
Somebody?
Look, a falling star. Make a wish.
Aw. Too late.
Yes, it generally is too late.
But if you had seen it,
what would you have wished for?
Well, what would you
have wished for?
Me? Ooh, a nice
cold glass of beer.
How about you?
Oh, I don't know.
A pair of new shoes
or a woolly for Piccolo.
Piccolo needs if a new woolly, buy one.
We can afford it.
Thanks, Sebastian.
And Caryl-
if he'd seen that falling star,
he would have wished
for the lovely Fenella.
Oh, that reminds me.
I must collect our fee from the
hotel manager in the morning.
Then we can go on to Martino.
Sebastian.
Hmm? Hmm?
Then we can go on to Martino.
Yes.
Did you really think my dress
looked attractive tonight?
Very...
very attractive.
Maledetto.
I forgot my concertina.
Well, is that important now?
Well, certainly, it's important.
Someone might pinch it.
I better go and get it.
Look, you go along
and I'll join you, hmm?
All right? Huh?
Go on.
Oh.
Good evening.
Please don't think me rude.
But I couldn't help noticing
you back there on the terrace.
I said to myself, I've seen
that face somewhere before.
Possibly Innsbruck. Was it?
I've never been
to Innsbruck. Sorry.
Oh. Monte Carlo, perhaps.
Don't you think this talk
of seeing me before is
a little old-fashioned?
Frankly, yes.
Well, would you be more
willing to believe me
if I admit that I've never
seen your face before,
but once having seen it,
I had to see it again?
If I say yes, I'd be a bit
conceited, don't you think?
No.
Really, I must be going in now,
but thank you for the
charming compliment.
Oh, please don't go, not just yet.
I hate to repeat the obvious,
but... you are beautiful.
There's something so
cool and lovely about you.
You're like...
well, you're like edelweiss.
Yes, that belongs on you.
Will you wear it?
Satisfied?
Thank you.
You know, I think
every woman's a little bit
like a flower, don't you?
Some are like roses,
some, poppies.
But you-you're like edelweiss,
preferring the mountaintops,
hard to reach.
That girl who sang, what of her?
Oh, you mean
my professional partner?
She's like a little buttercup.
You do have a way with words, don't you?
You think so? I think
I have a way with music.
You're a very talented
fellow, aren't you?
Oh, very. Tell me,
do you like music?
I adore it.
Oh?
Good music or just concertina?
Any kind that's really good-
symphony, opera. Why?
I do a bit of composing
now and then, that's all.
Really? How amazing.
Seeing you here at the hotel like this,
I should never have
taken you for a composer.
Well, even composers
have to eat.
Look at that.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes.
Tell me about your music.
What kind of music is it?
Would I have heard it?
I'm really interested.
Do you know what you look like,
standing there in the moonlight?
A picture I once saw in
Florence by Botticelli.
The Goddess of Spring-
in the Woods, I think.
I know the one you mean.
Primavera.
That's the one.
What a wonderful name for a ballet.
That's marvelous.
I can see the whole thing now-
the symbol of Spring.
You, you're Primavera yourself.
I am?
Listen.
That's the theme.
Do you like it?
Oh, yes.
It must be terribly exciting
to do things like that-
be able to create
something out of the air.
I never could.
You don't need to.
Some people are born to inspire.
I really mean it.
I knew that it was no mere coincidence
that sent me to seek you out tonight.
Do you believe in destiny?
I don't know.
I never did until now.
I'd better get back
to the hotel.
No. Not until you tell me your name.
Primavera.
Very well, then.
Don't go yet, Primavera.
I should.
Please.
Well, all right.
But only for a few minutes.
Can you tell me where
the manager is, please?
His office is just upstairs, to the left.
Oh, Miss Maclean, if you please.
A letter for you... Oh?
Perhaps the one
you have been expecting.
Thank you.
Uh, Fenella.
Oh, yes?
How do you know my name?
Well, Caryl told me.
What did you say?
I'm Gemma. What
are you doing here?
I thought you were
staying in Martino.
I'm spending the weekend with
friends if it's any of your concern.
So you're Gemma Smith.
That's right. I have some
news for you. Caryl is here.
What?
Yes, in Orzano.
Caryl Dubrok?
Well, do you know
any other Dubroks?
He's here with you.
In a manner of speaking, yes.
Now, listen...
I'm not Caryl's girl. I never was.
But you told my parents-
It was a bit of a crisscross.
I meant Sebastian, not Caryl.
Sebastian? Who is he?
Caryl's brother.
Ha ha ha!
Sebastian!
I have a wonderful
surprise for you.
Fenella, this is Sebastian.
Sebastian, this is Fenella.
How do you do?
You-you're-
Sebastian, Caryl's brother.
Oh!
Another raffle card, eh?
Which is Miss Maclean's room, please?
Number 5.
Thank you.
What do you mean by coming
into my room like this?
Sorry.
Please go. I have nothing
further to say to you.
Oh, yes, you have.
Look, we've been hunting
for you for weeks on end,
sleeping in the rain, bruising
our feet on stony roads,
just because we wanted to
straighten it out with you
about Caryl and me,
and now when we do find you
and things are apparently
in a worse mess than ever,
you climb on your high horse and-
Sebastian gave you this.
You have no right to take that.
No one has a better right.
Are you Sebastian's wife?
No.
What, then?
We belong together.
Then why did he assure me you
were only his professional partner,
someone to sing tunes
to his concertina?
Oh, that.
What about Caryl?
Do you love him?
Certainly I do. We were
engaged to be married.
That was in Venice.
How about afterward? Did
you change toward him?
Naturally I did, after my
parents told me about you.
Any girl would have.
No, some girls would have
believed in him,
no matter what they heard.
But that's neither here nor there.
Do you still love him?
I told you I did!
But did you mean it?
Get out of here!
You are mixed up. You don't
know whether it's Caryl
or his brother you want, do you?
Well, which is it, then?
Caryl or Sebastian?
Answer me.
I don't know. Will you
stop pestering me?
I tell you, I don't know!
I-I don't know.
I know.
What a pity.
Where's Caryl?
Gone to meet Fenella I presume.
He was getting dressed
when I left the inn.
Did you tell him
about you and Fenella last night?
What would have been
the sense of that?
Well, what did you tell him?
Simply that we'd met her
in the lobby of the hotel.
I said that she was
waiting for him
in the summer pavilion.
Then you did have an
appointment with her.
Did Caryl know about that?
Of course, he didn't know
about it.
And why don't you
stop badgering me?
I had no idea it was
Fenella last night.
I wonder if it would have
mattered if you had known.
Oh, for heaven's sake, Gemma,
why are you holding Piccolo
on your hip like that?
It looks like an old sack of
potatoes you bought at the market.
Here. Give him to me.
He's too heavy for you
to lug around anyway.
Now, if you'd care to listen,
I'll explain how I met Fenella.
Last night-
We haven't time to go into that.
Sebastian, I want to talk
to you very seriously.
Oh. Go ahead.
Who's stopping you?
We're leaving Orzano.
Leave-why? When?
Today. We'd have to see a lot
of Caryl and Fenella
if we stayed on,
and I think that'd be
a little embarrassing.
All right. We'll go back to Venice.
We are not going to Venice.
What-oh.
Afraid the Maclean's might be
going back there, aren't you?
We'll go to Vienna.
I don't like Vienna.
Then we'll go to Paris.
I don't like Paris, either!
Besides, you know we
haven't got the money.
Oh, yes, we have.
I sold the concertina
and... the duke.
You so-ha ha ha!
The concertina belonged to Caryl,
and so did half the donkey.
Getting rid of you and me
will be worth more to him
than a concertina and half a donkey.
Oh, why don't you stop-
Women.
I also sold your father's
autographed music.
You did what?
Sold your father's
autographed music.
Why, you-you little runt.
You've certainly got a nerve.
Well, instead of carrying
other people's stuff around,
you should be writing
great things of your own.
Yes. That's what
I'm going to do...
beginning with Primavera.
What?
Oh, I haven't told you
about that, have I?
That's to be the name
of my ballet.
What ballet?
It's a brand-new idea, wonderful,
symbolizing the very
spirit of Spring.
Primavera. Listen.
Oh, I'm sorry, Gemma.
Oh, I wish we could
go away somewhere
where I could get this down
on paper so it could be staged.
You'd help me, wouldn't you? Gemma? Hmm?
The way you always have?
Are you bawling?
If I am, it's my affair.
It's mine, too.
Sebastian, I've known a lot
of rotten people in my life,
but none the equal of you.
You lie and cheat and break
promises right and left
and then think because you put your
arms around me, everything's all right,
Forgiven and forgotten.
Wait a moment. I-
You're rotten. I say it again,
and I say it to your face.
I have a star to follow,
I've always told you,
and I must follow it alone.
What you follow isn't a star.
They don't come that low.
But whatever it is, go after it.
I'm finished.
What do you mean by that?
I'm leaving you, Sebastian.
Gemma! Gemma!
Put Piccolo down.
Put him down!
Now, come here.
You little fool.
Oh, if I could only tell you
how thoroughly I despise you,
then up and leave you, let it
be finished once and for all.
It'll never be
finished between us.
Gemma, you know it won't.
Loving you is the most awful
thing that has ever happened to me.
Is it?
Yes, it is.
Perhaps you're right.
Maybe you do deserve a better man.
But I don't want
a better man, Sebastian.
I just want you.
Fenella.
Oh, Fenella, darling,
you're looking wonderful.
I've never seen you
so-so beautiful.
Thank you, Caryl.
You didn't expect me to follow you
to the Dolomites, did you?
No.
Oh, it doesn't seem any
longer than yesterday
we were sitting
in the Café Galante.
I feel as if there had never been
a misunderstanding at all.
I know how you feel, but-
I say, Gemma explained the
mix-up in Venice, didn't she?
Yes. She explained very thoroughly.
Well, everything's the same,
and yet everything's
changed since I saw you last.
Yes. That's what
I want to talk to you-
I have a surprise for you. I've
come round to your way of thinking.
How do you mean? About our
getting married, of course.
Oh, Caryl!
Yes. I think it would
be a good thing.
And to make myself
acceptable to your parents,
I'm going to get a job.
Oh, not the sort of thing
I had in Venice,
but something with a future
and, at the same time, something
which will further my career.
I know it sounds rather vague,
but I'm positive
I can work it out.
What do you think?
Oh, I... I don't know.
Where would you find such a job?
Oh, lots of places.
Vienna, Salzburg, perhaps London.
Yes. London would
be best, I imagine.
My father had
a great many friends there.
A music broker by the name
of Steinach to name just one.
He'd be a good contact for me.
Would you marry me
if I had a proper job, Fenella?
Well-I can make you happy, darling.
I know I can.
Oh, Caryl, I don't know
how to say this,
but there's something
I've got to tell you.
Last night, I-
Excuse me. Mr. Caryl Dubrok, please?
Yes. What is it?
I have a note for you, sir.
Oh, thank you.
Excuse me.
It's from Sebastian, my brother.
Oh?
Good heavens. He and Gemma
are leaving for London.
London? Yes. He intends
to finish his ballet.
He says at last he's got a name
for it. It's to be called Primavera.
Primavera.
They're getting married
right away.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Well, that's just like Sebastian.
One never knows
what to expect of him.
Now, what was it, darling?
You said you had
something to tell me.
It was nothing, nothing at all.
So Sebastian's getting married.
Do you, Sebastian Dubrok,
take this woman Gemma Smith
to be your lawful wedded wife?
I do.
And do you, Gemma Smith,
take this-
take this man Sebastian Dubrok
to be your lawful wedded husband?
I do.
Then I pronounce you man and wife.
Won't you buy
my sweet-scented lavender?
There are 14 branches
for a penny.
If you buy it once,
you buy it twice
'cause it makes your clothes
and handkerchiefs
smell very nice.
I'll take a bunch, please.
Thank you, sir.
Won't you buy my
sweet-scented lavender?
Caryl! I ought not
to be glad to see you.
You have lunch with
Sebastian time after time,
but you never once come to visit me.
Time after time. Only twice.
Those lunches were business.
Oh, you have a new suit.
Let me see.
My, you are turned out
in style. Look, Sebastian.
Well, I can afford it now.
My job with Steinach
pays me £200 a year,
And besides that,
I get commissions.
Oh, that's wonderful.
How is Fenella?
Oh, splendid. We're planning
to be married very soon.
Well, well. Congratulations.
I'll congratulate you if
you've licked that finale.
Oh, yeah?
Hmm. It looks good.
Well, now I have
a surprise for you.
Have you?
A pleasant one, I hope.
Fenella and her family are
giving a party next Friday,
And you're both invited.
Oh, really?
Well, it's Fenella's doing, actually.
She's asked Mr. Steinach to come
on the idea that you're
to play your ballet for him.
If he likes it,
he'll probably offer to
produce your Primavera.
You could use Heinrich as conductor
and perhaps Natrova
as the prima ballerina.
That is, if we can get her.
Caryl!
Good old Caryl. We can
always rely upon you.
Little one, I'm going to
take you to a party, at last.
Yes. It'll be wonderful.
And if the ballet is a success,
we can all go back to Italy.
If it's a success.
Confound that gas. It's always going out.
Here. I have some change.
Oh, put it back in your pocket.
We don't need your money.
Gemma, put a shilling
in the meter,
will you, darling?
Don't know what I'd do without
her and that little sewing machine.
Between the 2 of them,
they support the 3 of us.
Where is it?
Huh? Oh, I wonder if I spent it.
Mmm, for beer.
Oh, yes. The beer.
There you are, Gemma.
Thank you, Caryl.
Well, I guess I'd
better be running along.
Oh, would you, uh, like these?
Oh, thank you, Caryl.
I have some Mexican jumping beans.
I thought they might amuse Piccolo.
Hmm?
They jump as soon as they get warm.
They won't do
much jumping in here.
This place is like an icebox.
It was very thoughtful of you, Caryl.
Piccolo will love them.
All right. I'll see
you two at the party.
If the baby is all right
and I can leave him.
He'll be all right.
Just got a bit of a cold.
No, Sebastian. Not a penny.
Oh, for heaven's sake, Gemma, will
you stop stitching those cuffs?
You're going to
sew yourself blind.
Well, when I finish
these, I get 12 shillings
we can use it, I imagine.
Oh, Sebastian!
Look.
A 5-pound note!
Uh-huh.
Mutton chops for supper.
Did you sponge this off Caryl?
If I did? What he's
solvent. He can afford it.
And there's not going
to be any mutton chops.
You're going to buy yourself
a new dress for the party.
No. I can use my blue one.
Oh, no, I can't.
What? I didn't pawn your blue dress.
No, but I did.
Oh. Well, we'll... buy a new one.
I tell you, I can borrow one
from the landlady's daughter.
That's a good idea.
Yes, the pretty one.
She's just about your size.
And by way of reward,
we shall allow her to
take care of Piccolo
while we go to the party.
You have a nerve.
Oh, go on. Hurry up.
Hurry up!
Amore mio.
It was beautiful, Sebastian.
Very good, my boy.
Thank you, Mr. Steinach.
I must talk this over
with your brother.
Fine. Thank you, sir.
You look lovely, my dear.
You may tell the dance
orchestra to start now.
Yes, madam.
We shall have supper later.
Oh, you are very kind.
Not at all, my dear.
May I have the pleasure of
dancing with you, Mrs. Dubrok?
Oh, thank you very much.
Rather odd having
to call you missus.
You don't look to have
a husband, you know.
Oh, sometimes I wonder
if I have.
I suppose wives do wonder
about that at times.
I beg your pardon.
Oh, no, no. It was my fault.
I don't dance very often.
I wish Fenella
didn't dance so much.
She's out practically every
night with her young man.
Never spends the evening in anymore.
Oh?
Restless sort of girl,
but marriage will settle her,
I suppose. At least, I hope so.
Well, then why don't you
let them get married?
Huh?
Well, why not?
You may be right. By jove, yes.
I think I'll speak to
her young man about it,
tell him it's time to dust off
the wedding bells.
I say, you're a smart
little thing, aren't you?
Oh, I wouldn't be
too sure of that.
Primavera is going to be a
marvelous success, Sebastian.
Of course, I never had
any doubts about it,
not even that first night when
you whistled the theme for me.
Then you do remember Orzano.
Did you think I'd forgotten?
Frankly, I didn't think much
about it one way or the other.
Bad business, thinking.
What do you mean?
Simply that the worst mistake
anyone can ever make in life
is taking it seriously.
It's too unpredictable,
too haphazard.
But you're a musician, and music
is based on order and purpose.
That's exactly why I am a musician.
I pursue art to help me forget
that life is not worth pursuing.
Surely you believe that it's
wanting things and getting them
that brings us happiness.
No. Who knows what they want?
Do you?
Yes. Of course, I do.
Then you're one
of the rare exceptions-
A woman who knows
what she's after.
Not only that, but I
always get what I'm after.
You do? Then you're
a very fortunate girl.
I don't see it that way at all.
My life is nothing
but a flat, stale vacuum.
I hate it, and I loathe it.
And...
if you changed it, would
it make you any happier?
Yes.
Are you sure? You'd better be.
Once you've made the break, it
might be difficult to get back.
But I shouldn't want to get back.
Never?
Never.
Sebastian!
Sebastian, I have a note. Piccolo
is ill. I think we ought to go home.
Would you try and find a cab?
I'll get your things.
Well, good night.
Fenella.
Fenella, I want to talk to you.
Yes?
This is very different
from Orzano, isn't it?
You are engaged to Caryl,
and Sebastian-
Please take your foot away.
You know, you aren't
the first distraction we have had.
There have been others.
But, you see, once Sebastian
makes a conquest of this sort,
he forgets it.
You're being spiteful,
and you completely
misinterpret our relation.
Oh, do I?
Yes. Sebastian is going to be famous.
He's not an ordinary man.
You are so right. He's an
utterly selfish, cold-hearted pig.
Don't you know
that he's a genius?
I ought to. He's
always telling me so.
Would you mind
my speaking frankly?
Haven't you been?
Gemma, give him up.
So that you can have him?
Yes. There's so much
I could do for him,
Just as I've already helped him.
Oh, have you?
Yes. I gave this party
so that he could meet Steinach.
I persuaded Heinrich
to conduct his ballet.
I- I even inspired Sebastian
to write the ballet
in the beginning.
He got the idea for it in
Orzano the night we met.
So, you see, if you
were to give him up, I-
Don't say that again.
Very well. But you must realize
that no woman can hold
a man like Sebastian
if he doesn't want to be held.
What do you mean by that?
Suppose he were to leave you.
Leave me? Never.
I've got a cab at the side gate.
Thank you.
Darling, I have good news for you.
Your father suggests we be
married early next Spring.
Isn't that wonderful?
My dress is torn.
I must go in and change.
Did you tell her?
Yes. Good. Then it's settled.
And so's your brother's
ballet, I understand.
What?
Heinrich says that they're going
to start rehearsals immediately.
No, no. That
curtain is 2 bows late.
All right, lads.
This is a quick change.
Now, come on, ladies.
Off the bloomin' stage.
Take your limes off, Fred.
Take up your tableau curtain.
Charlie, douse your foots.
Fred, turn off your limes.
Now, come on, lads.
Get a move on. Props!
What'd you think of it?
Oh, it's splendid.
The orchestration
is very effective.
Yeah? Thanks.
Sebastian. 5 minutes, gentlemen.
I wish it were your ballet
instead of Sebastian's.
You could write a ballet
if you really applied yourself.
I told you in Venice
that I wasn't a genius, Fenella.
I had my heart set
on you doing something
really important in music
I haven't given it up. I've merely
exchanged composing for a steady job.
You're so utterly
different from Sebastian.
He cares nothing for money.
I wish you wouldn't keep
dragging Sebastian into this.
He has nothing to do with it.
Or has he?
Sebastian's like his father-
a great, cruel, wind of a man
that no one can leave alone...
that women apparently
never want to leave alone.
I resemble our mother-
solid and proper and dull.
There are times, Caryl, when
I'm inclined to agree with you.
Fenella.
Well?
If you have made a mistake about
us, now is the time to say so.
Are you trying to break
our engagement?
I am, if it needs to be broken.
We can't talk here. The
next scene's about to begin.
Stop it! Stop it! It's
impossible! It cannot be done!
But why? You've been
doing it that way for the last 2 weeks.
Well, in short shirts, yes, but
today is the first time
in a long dress.
All right.
Change to short skirts.
How can I? The role calls
for a long, full costume.
If anything is to be changed,
it is your music, Monsieur Dubrok.
I hope you're not serious.
Professor Heinrich.
Madame Natrova,
if you would, perhaps-
May I make a suggestion?
Yes. What is it?
I was thinking that perhaps
something of Tchaikovsky
might be used at this point.
But Tchaikovsky!
That's wonderful!
His music is always good.
Don't you think so,
Monsieur Dubrok?
Certainly, madam, yes.
No one appreciates
Tchaikovsky more than I,
but not in my ballet.
This is my music, and it's
going to remain my music!
I tell you, it cannot be danced!
The tempo is too fast,
too exhausting,
and just when I must catch
my breath before the finale!
What about a slower
tempo, Sebastian? What?
What do you want me to
do, change a Spring waltz
into some sort of
funeral dirge? Nonsense
I have spent weeks on my solo.
It must be done my way
or not at all!
Excuse me. Would you
tell Mr. Dubrok
I would like to speak
with him, please?
I can't go out there now, miss.
Yes, but my baby
is very sick. Please.
I'm sorry, miss.
All right.
If she can't dance it,
let's get someone who can!
People come to see Natrova,
not to listen to the music
of an unknown composer.
If they'd sooner watch some
kangaroo hop around the stage-
Enough of this! Both of you!
I'm finished!
We are dismissed!
Sebastian-
Don't you realize
what this will mean?
The posters are all
ready. Some of them are up.
Well, take them down, burn them,
do anything you want
with them. I don't care.
Don't argue with him.
It's useless.
Sebastian, Sebastian,
please come home with me.
The baby is very sick,
and I'm so frightened.
Is he? Well, get
a doctor for him.
But how can I? We have no money.
Darling, please, please, don't
you see I've got so much on mind?
I've got to have time to think.
I must talk to you, Sebastian.
Caryl, I was right, wasn't I?
That stupid, preening woman.
With her ridiculous airs and-
It's not the ballet I want
to discuss at the moment.
Oh? What is it?
It's Fenella.
Fenella? Doesn't
anybody care about the music?
At least I expected you, a musician-
You're in no position
to force issues.
You behaved like a fool.
Thanks. Thanks very much.
Don't let them do anything
to your music, Sebastian.
Fenella. Why did you stay?
Well, I...
I thought there might
be something I can do.
Did you? How nice of you.
There isn't.
I'm not engaged to Caryl anymore.
Oh, but that's silly.
Caryl's a wonderful fellow.
What happened?
Please let's not talk about him.
I wish I could get away.
I hate London.
So do I.
I wish I could get away
somewhere, too,
somewhere where I could
pull myself together and-
I know a place, in the country.
Do you? Where?
Down in Kent.
It belongs to my family. It's lovely-
quiet and...
Is it?
Here we go.
He's coming now, darling.
Shh.
How is he?
Mrs. Cooper gave me some
medicine, and he's quieter now.
That's good. You shouldn't
let it upset you so much.
Babies always have earaches
or something like that.
Sorry I blew up
like that at rehearsal.
Oh, that's all right. Now that
you're home, I'm not so frightened.
That's the last time I'll
ever write a ballet, I swear.
But, Sebastian,
there's money in it.
And when they do pay you
for the ballet,
do you think we could
use some of it for-
well, to get some
warm things for Piccolo?
He just can't stand
this cold climate.
Fat chance there is of
them paying me anything.
You mean they won't pay you?
Oh, but, Sebastian,
that can't be.
The ballet might not
go on at all.
Oh, don't worry about it.
Something will turn up.
It always does.
I wonder.
I had to do it. There comes a point
when one more compromise
would have ruined the music.
That point was reached
this afternoon.
Well, that's that.
No ballet, no money.
Money's not that important.
Not to you, perhaps.
What do you want me
to do, hack work?
If so, you're going to
be very disappointed.
You always seem to be
complaining.
Because I don't make you
a fortune, I suppose-
Oh, it isn't that, Sebastian.
The baby's sick, and I'm tired,
and I don't consider a
shilling for the gas meter a fortune.
What are you doing
with those clothes?
I've got to go down
to Surrey tonight.
Why?
To see Natrova,
make her listen to reason.
She's down there,
staying with friends.
But you said everything was over
with the ballet and finished.
Exactly. That's why I have
to go down and see her.
You said yourself you wanted the ballet
to go on, didn't you?
Don't lie to me, Sebastian.
You're not going down there
to talk to Natrova.
I know you too well.
What do you mean by that?
You know exactly what I mean.
No, I don't, but I do know one thing.
I'm getting out of here.
So you were going down to Surrey
to talk to Natrova, were you?
Yes, I was! You liar!
I know who you were
going to see-
Fenella, and don't try to deny it.
Well, go on. Get out of here.
I don't need you. Go to her.
Let her tell you
what a genius you are!
Wait a minute. You'll
ruin that, you little fool.
That's yours
as much as it is mine.
Mine? It's never been mine!
It belongs to Fenella.
You wrote it for her.
That night in Orzano, you
got the idea for it, remember?
Well, go on. Take your
precious ballet to her.
And I hope I never set eyes on
it, or you again, as long as I live!
You mean that?
Yes. Yes, I do!
Now, get out of here!
Get out!
Get out.
Who is it?
Caryl.
Oh. Caryl, would you
mind putting a shilling
in the gas meter, please?
Where's Sebastian?
He's gone.
When will he be back?
He won't.
I'm sorry, Gemma.
What was it you wanted
to talk to him about?
Fenella and I have
broken our engagement.
Oh.
Piccolo! Piccolo!
Oh, Caryl!
Mrs. Cooper! Mrs. Cooper!
Yes. What is it?
Please, Piccolo is
terribly sick. I know he is.
Would you try and do something?
Do you think a little warm oil
in his hair might help?
I think you ought to take
him to the hospital, ducky.
They'd know what
to do with him there.
That sounds like good advice, Gemma.
Yes, but I'd have to
stay there with him.
You see, he just couldn't stand
it with a lot of strange people.
Don't worry. I'll go with you.
Nothing could happen to him,
could it, Caryl?
He's so little.
It just wouldn't be fair.
Thank you, Mrs. Cooper.
He is quiet now.
Do you think he's a little better?
You should have brought him sooner.
Oh, yes, I know, but-
There's nothing we can do now.
Well, then give him
back to me. I will take care of him.
It's too late.
No. That's a lie,
a dirty, hospital lie!
Give him back to me!
Give him back to me,
do you hear?
That's a lie!
Give him back to me!
It's a lie! It's a lie!
He'll be all right, Caryl.
He'll be all right.
It's just this awful
English weather.
As soon as he gets better, I'm
going to take him back to Italy,
where there's sun.
That's all he needs...
because back in Italy, he was
well and happy all the time.
And in Venice, he was...
in Venice, he was...
come on. Let me buy you a cup
of coffee. You're-you're cold.
A cup of coffee, please.
Here you are, sir.
You know, back in Venice,
I was going to marry Dino.
Dino was a baker. We would have
had all the bread we needed.
Caryl, you must marry.
You must marry Fenella
and be very happy
and live in a little warm house,
and every morning
when you go to work,
you will leave
your little house,
and you will have an attaché
case full of music and contracts,
and Fenella will wave good-bye
to you from the window-
Please, Gemma-
Oh, Caryl, please don't
let her go. Bring her back.
Marry her and never leave her...
because people
have to be families.
There has to be
a mother and a father,
And the father has to go to work
and the children go to school,
and then the children come home,
and they play.
Oh, Piccolo! Piccolo!
Gemma!
Gemma! Gemma!
2 bottles?
2 people.
Oh, not tonight.
Hey, I'll be needing that.
Tonight's too precious.
Later on,
you'll bring me back that bottle
with your own little hands.
Oh? Why should I?
You'll see.
To us. All the people who like
us and all the ones who don't.
Drink up. It'll help.
Oh, it was so cold and strange
on the way down here.
Let's go and sit by the fire.
Yes. It's burning nicely, isn't it?
What do you see in the fire?
Coal.
Oh, don't you see us?
I do, the way we're going to be,
perhaps in this very house.
It'll be mine one day, you know.
Will it?
Nice... parties, rooms full of
flowers and music, nice people.
Oh, nice. Will you stop
using that stupid word?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it, darling.
Oh, everything's going
to be wonderful, isn't it?
No more poverty for you,
no worry, no Gemma.
Let's leave Gemma out of it.
Out of it? Of course.
I quite like Gemma. I think
she has a lot of good in her.
Some of these girls have.
What girls?
Well, her sort.
Father says that every genius
has some little creature
like that in his past
because when he's
starving in a garret,
he has to have someone cheap.
Of course, they don't understand
about his art or his career,
but they're useful.
Useful...
loyal...
unselfish...
forgiving.
Why are you doing them up again?
Because I'm taking you home, my dear.
So...
You're angry.
No. Grateful.
Look at me.
Even the most selfish pig may have...
may have something he won't face,
even though it's the only decent thing
that ever happened to him.
I was afraid. That's it.
I was afraid to admit
what Gemma meant to me
because, I suppose,
I wanted to go on
being a selfish pig.
Sebastian, you mean
you brought me down here-
And that's the luckiest thing
that ever happened to you...
because I'm taking
you back, to Caryl.
Caryl-he's your kind of man.
And Gemma-Gemma's
my kind of woman.
Look, Fenella,
you're a sensible girl.
What you want is a nice
marriage, a nice husband-
Now you're using
that word "nice."
Ha ha ha!
I'll give it to you,
for a wedding present.
Friends?
Please?
Good friends.
Where's Gemma?
She's gone.
The baby died
while you and Fenella...
Good evening.
Oh, it's going to be
a great success, Sebastian.
Any word from her?
Nothing. I've looked
all over London.
I'm so sorry.
Good luck tonight.
Gemma!
Gemma. I hoped you'd come.
I don't want to talk to you. Please-
They're going to
start. Let me go. Let me go!
Gemma! Gemma, wait.
Please.
Gemma, I don't know what to say.
Say nothing. It's better.
I didn't know about Piccolo.
Don't tell me
you're sorry, Sebastian.
Be like you always were.
Not sorry about anything.
I wasn't going to say
that I'm sorry.
That's such a-
such a small word.
It's so easy for people to be sorry,
but no one can tell what it
means to a mother to lose a child,
because she's the only
one who understands,
who can imagine the kind of man
he was going to grow up to be.
I loved the little
fellow, too, Gemma,
in my own way.
Oh, Sebastian...
listen.
Your music.
Yours, too.
I could never have
written it without you.
You know that, don't you?
No. Don't lie to me,
not at a time like this.
I'm not.
Look.
I wrote it for you
long ago, in Venice.
It's your song.
You're hurt.
When we get home, I'll...
I'll try to change.
Perhaps-perhaps in time,
I'll be a better man.
But I don't want
a better man, Sebastian.
I just want you.