Nurse...
Do you know what day it's to be?
All I know is we got to get you
up and walking by next Saturday.
Wake up!
Eat your soup while it's hot.
I can't.
- I'll feed you.
- No, no, please. They'll punish you.
Even they have humor
enough not to try that.
Who gave you permission to walk?
I'm rehearsing.
Permit an actress the luxury.
Rehearsals are very important.
I have to know the kind
of spectacle I am making.
Stop talking!
Get back into bed.
Will my audience cry?
Or will they yawn and say,
"Oh, this was a bad performance.
Now, the day we burned the
synagogue was much more fun.
And the day we threw the
Archbishop through the window,
we had a better show."
You may go now.
- I'll shut her mouth for good.
- I said, go!
Nurse!
Put her in the next room for treatment.
Don't do that sort of thing.
You'll just get hurt needlessly.
You operated on me.
You saved me to be hurt, didn't you?
I operated in the line of duty.
Now you have a new duty?
To save me from being hurt by
anyone, but the executioner?
I never imagined you would be...
- as you are.
- What's that?
I'm going to say something I've...
I've wanted to say.
Long before you came here,
I knew all about you.
That is why it was such a great shock
for me to go into the operating room...
and see that it was Emmy
Ritter I was to save.
- And yet not save at all.
- Then why did you?
When I was a boy, I
lived in the country.
I never saw a theater or went anywhere.
And one day my father
went to the city...
and brought back a theater program
with your photograph on it.
I stole it.
I kept it hidden in a bureau drawer.
Many young boys fell in love with me.
Ooh, many old ones too.
In the photograph you are
dressed as Saint Elizabeth...
carrying a basket with loaves of
bread, and in your arms, roses.
- I remember.
- That's why you were important to me.
In my hungry empty world
you promised so much.
Bread for the hunger and
roses for the emptiness.
And now I suppose you have a new
picture in your bureau drawer.
A new saviour of your world.
- But his arms are full of guns.
- Why not?
Power is the only answer.
It's the only chance of survival.
Guns and blood.
A river of blood to
blot out all hopes...
for a decent future.
Is survival worth that price?
Our children will thank us for the
world we are making for them.
Thank you?
Thank you for what?
For a world filled with
the seed of new hates?
For a world in ruins?
If that's what your new
saviour can bring...
No thank you. I don't want it
for myself or my children.
My children...
I've been wondering if you...
if you would like to send
some word to your family.
I'm asking you if you would like
to write a letter to your family?
Yes.
You, ah...
You understand, of course, that I'll
only be able to send the letter...
afterward.
Your passports, please.
- Have you any money to declare?
- Yes, about 600 dollars.
You'll permit me to examine it.
Please, your passport.
Understand.
You can't take any more money out
of the country than you bring in.
It's the law!
Heil Hitler!
Thank you, sir.
Say, can you tell me if a certain person
was registered here about four weeks ago?
Yes, certainly, sir.
What was the name, sir?
Madame Ritter.
Emmy Ritter.
Yes, sir. Madame Ritter.
Just a moment, please.
Yes, sir. A Madame Ritter was our guest
for four days last month. She...
Well, where did she go from here?
What forwarding address did she leave?
We have no record of that, sir.
Look, here's a letter I addressed
to her in care of this hotel.
It came back stamped address unknown.
How do I find out where she went?
We have no record of that.
I don't know how you could find out.
Could I help you, sir?
I told you on the telephone.
He's been very ill. He sees no one.
- I must see him.
- I'm sorry.
Wait. Please listen to me.
Tell him it's a client from America.
America?
Yes, I've traveled 3000 miles to see him.
At least tell him I'm here.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
Good evening, sir.
I want to apologize for insisting
upon seeing you, but...
believe me, it's most important.
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
It's just that I'm in trouble, or I
wouldn't have been so insistent.
I'm used to people in trouble.
You see, it's my mother, Emmy Ritter.
Emmy Ritter.
You know her?
Slightly.
Many years ago.
Then perhaps you know she's been
living in America for a long time.
My father died and my
mother needed money so...
she came back here several months
ago, sold her house and...
I believe got in some sort of
trouble over the transaction.
She has been arrested?
I'm not sure.
I can't seem to find out anything.
I don't even know where to start.
This is the last address
she gave me, but...
all the letters came back
stamped address unknown.
I thought perhaps you
could help me find out...
Wait...
Your mother, is she
an American citizen?
No, sir. I am, and my sister is.
We were born in America...
but my mother,
well she always talked about
taking out citizenship papers
but she kept putting it off, just
like she did everything else.
In other words, she's still
a citizen of this country.
And subject to our laws.
Yes, sir, but whatever she did...
Well, a woman doesn't understand
much about exchange laws...
and all that sort of thing,
especially an actress like my mother.
She was always forgetting
things, or losing things...
Ya, ya...
She must have taken a small
token sum for her house...
and contrived to have the rest
deposited to her credit in New York.
Oh, that's quite enough to be tried
before the people's court...
- for treason.
- Treason?
Ya...the word doesn't
mean much to you?
I've seen it in history books, but
what's it got to do with my mother?
A great deal, perhaps.
There may be a death penalty.
- For selling a house?
- I'm serious, young man.
The sentence is not
necessarily death...
and even if it is, it is not
necessarily carried out.
But the possibility is always there...
- for death penalty.
- Stop saying that, will you.
My mother...
My mother... what's she got to do with death?
Why, she's life.
You say you knew her, once.
Remember, there's life in everything she does.
The way she walks and talks, and
even when she's just standing still
and just looking at you she's
the livest person in the world.
What's she got to do with death?
I'm sorry, I....
I've been so worried about her, I
guess I'm a little goofy, that's all.
Mr Henning, what can you do for me?
I?
I am a sick man.
There is nothing I can do for you.
Nothing, except to advise you to
return to America as soon as possible!
Don't you understand yet?
This is my mother, I've got to do something.
Yes, yes, I suppose so.
But in the end, you have to give up!
But a good lawyer..
They said you were the best.
Mr Preysing, this is
not the United States!
How long do you suppose I'd be allowed to
go on living here if I handled such cases?
Are you telling me there's
nothing I can do in a legal way?
Nothing.
Go back to America.
But I've got to know something.
What her sentence is,
where's she's being kept.
At least I've got to know that.
- You know. You must...
- I know nothing.
Those trials are secret.
I'd know nothing.
You do!
You're afraid to tell me.
- Well, you will tell me!
- Please!
I had heard you were an
exceptionally courageous man.
I'm sorry I troubled you.
Mr Preysing!
Maybe you should go to...
to the Commissioner of Police.
Did you hear him?
"I heard you were an exceptionally
courageous man, Mr Henning."
Mr Preysing, the Commissioner
will see you now.
Come in.
Sit down.
- My name is...
- Ah, yes, your name is Mark Preysing.
And you are an American citizen
and you are also a painter.
A very promising one, I understand.
You seem to know a lot
about me, Mr Commissioner.
I do hope you'll find time to do
some painting in our country.
Art has many forms, has it not?
For instance, the theater...
It is one of my great regrets
that I never saw your mother,
Madame Ritter, on the stage.
It's my mother I've come to you about.
Ah, yes indeed.
- Then she has been arrested.
- Your mother, Mr Preysing...
has a very sympathetic nature.
I have here a record of her
activities in America.
She had a charming custom of harboring
renegade citizens of this country.
She helped out people that she knew,
people who were in trouble... refugees...
We do not like the word refugee.
We prefer traitor.
My mother knew nothing about
international politics.
She has the mind of an artist. She sees people
as a general humanity, not as separate races.
Mr Commissioner, believe me, my mother's
done no harm in her whole life.
And she's done more good
than most of us have.
Good for whom?
For the enemies of our state?
State, state!
How about human beings?
Mr Preysing!
I am not concerned with
your mother, believe me.
I saw you for one reason...
and one reason alone.
The fact that the woman was in trouble.
How did you find that out?
The trial was secret.
Who gave you your information?
I thought it was your
business to know everything.
So, you do not choose to tell me.
Very well...
In the most friendly way, therefore,
I must advise you to go home.
Mr Commissioner, if you'd just
see my mother, talk to her...
you'd realize she couldn't possibly be a criminal.
She's just a simple ordinary woman.
I'm afraid I must ask you to go now.
If I can't see her, at
least let me write to her.
Yes, yes, I shall have to
make the necessary inquiries.
-When?
- I don't know.
Monday.
Yes, come next Monday.
No, perhaps Friday would be better.
But that's such a long time to wait.
Couldn't I possibly...
So, you are enjoying our town, sir.
Yeah, sure. You really ought
to call it The Friendly City.
Yes, sir.
Mr Preysing?
- Well?
- I didn't want to trouble you, sir...
but I found out what you wanted to know.
This letter you gave me...
The postmark, see?
The postman thinks it's from Felzenkirche.
- Where's that?
- Two hours by train. In the mountains.
- All right. Get me a ticket on the first train.
- Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Oh, Felzenkirche.
That's a beautiful place.
They say it's still winter up there.
Ice, snow...
Wonderful view of the Alps
there, near the border.
Border, eh?
Any restricted areas?
Concentration camps?
You shouldn't believe
everything you hear, sir.
Or anything I see, either?
Finish your drink, sir.
No, thanks. I've had enough.
I've had plenty of everything.
I've had it up to here!
What do you want?
- Are you Helda Keller?
- Yes.
Where can I find your brother, Fritz?
He is not in.
Why do you want to see him?
- We were friends in America.
- So?
Yes, Fritz was working for
my mother, Emmy Ritter.
No, you better stay away from here.
But wait, let me explain.
No, you better get away from here!
Go away!
Coffee.
Yes, sir.
Most Americans like our beer, sir.
I'm collecting reasons why people
think I'm American. What's yours?
It's your coat, sir.
We don't get such fine
woolens here anymore.
Except for the Army and a few others.
But, of course, that
is as it should be.
Oh, sure, sure.
Keep it.
Thank you, sir.
Fritz Keller is a fine
fellow, isn't he?
Fritz Keller?
Yes, I used to know him in America.
I'm on my way to his house now.
Oh, no, sir. You won't find
him home this hour of day.
He hauls wood down from the mountain.
Comes along the road
there every afternoon.
You'll be sure to catch
him if you wait here.
Thanks, I will.
Thanks again, sir.
- Watch us, Countess.
- Now you watch us.
That was all I needed.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You didn't hurt yourself, did you?
Only my dignity.
I couldn't help laughing.
Don't apologize.
It was a pleasure.
- Shall I do it again?
- Oh, no, no. No, please.
Don't worry. I was only what
we Americans call kidding.
- Oh, really? What do you call it?
- Kidding. Like if I say, I ah...
I love your beautiful country.
I'm kidding.
I see.
But, if I say...
May I sit down? Because you seem
awfully nice and friendly...
and I'm not kidding.
So you're an American.
Tell me, do you have Indian blood?
- Indian blood?
- Or are you a cowboy?
I love those cowboy songs.
Did you bring your ukulele?
Look, lady, there are other people in
America besides Indians and cowboys.
Oh, then you're a hillbilly.
Yeah, that's right.
From 57th street.
- West or east?
- West.
- Why?
- I was born on east 57.
- Well, for the love of... honest?
- Cross my heart.
But those girls called you countess.
Do you live around here?
I've lived here for many years.
Ever since my husband died.
- He was a native of this country?
- Yes.
Why don't you come back home?
Home?
This is my home.
Don't you want to go back?
I did go back, but...
all my relatives were scattered, and
my friends and I had grown apart.
There was nothing there for me.
Everything I care about is here.
Look, Countess, maybe you can help me.
Come on, let's get
something hot to drink.
Oh, thank you, but I must
keep an eye on my girls.
- Your girls?
- My pupils.
Oh, I see.
After my husband died, I turned our
house into a finishing school.
My name is Mark Preysing.
Preysing?
That's a familiar name over here.
Both my parents were
born in this country.
My father's dead.
My mother is...
- Emmy Ritter.
- The actress?
I saw her once in Vienna.
She was a very great artist.
Has she come back here to live?
I don't know.
Perhaps to die.
I am sorry, but..
But perhaps in this climate...
I'd like so much to meet her.
Where is she staying?
I'm afraid you'll have to
ask the political police.
It's like a nightmare.
I can't find out anything.
I came up here to meet an old servant
of my mother's. He sent me a letter.
Please, Mr Preysing.
I'd rather you didn't go on.
What are you afraid of?
Believe me, you have my
deepest sympathy, but...
But you don't want to listen.
Nobody does.
This place isn't a country.
It's a Coney Island madhouse.
Everything looks like a door
until you try to go through it.
Every person looks like a
human being until you try to
talk to him, then something
squirts in your eye.
It isn't that I don't want to listen,
but what can I do? How can I help?
I'm nobody. I'm a schoolmistress, I live
a very retired life, I have no contacts.
- But I thought that being an American...
- I'm legally a citizen of this country.
Legally, but not in your heart.
If I may say so, Mr Preysing, you don't
know anything about this country,
I know all I want to.
Especially, you don't know how
I feel about this country.
If I may say so, Countess,
I'm afraid you're just selling
yourself a bill of goods.
Shall we just leave that undecided?
I really must go. My girls will
skate all night if I let them.
I...
I do hope that you find things
not as bad as you believe.
Forgive me for being so rude, but
I've been terribly concerned.
And if by any chance I have the
opportunity to inquire, I...
Yes?
My...
My house is up there, near
the pass, the green one...
I just remembered,
- we're leaving for town tomorrow.
- Well, so am I.
- Are you? Where are you staying?
- At the Excelsior.
- Well, I'll call you.
- That'll be swell.
It's been good having
someone to talk to.
I'm sure you'll help me, if you can.
Goodbye.
Ah, Mister!
Here comes Fritz Keller now.
Fritz!
Fritz, wait a minute.
Frtiz!
Fritz, don't you know me?
Fritz, what's the matter with you?
I got the letter.
Where is she? Just tell where she is.
I'll see you don't get in any trouble.
I don't know what you
are talking about.
Fritz, in heaven's name,
what are you up to?
- You must want to help her.
- Get away from my horses.
Fritz, listen. I'm going back
to town, the Hotel Excelsior.
- If you find out anything...
- Get away from my horses!
I opened the door. I saw a long
table covered with food and wine.
And there were 20 officers
sitting around it.
The enemy!
But Excellency, what did you do?
Do? I said, I beg your
pardon, and shut the door.
It doesn't seem to amuse you, Countess.
I'm sorry, General.
I don't blame you. You must have
heard it at least a dozen times.
I could hear it a thousand times.
- I could hear it a million times.
- But not tonight. And now to bed, girls.
Oh, no. Countess, it's so early.
It's too early to sleep.
Well, you'll have to try.
Remember we must be back in
town before noon tomorrow.
Now run along, girls.
- Well, I must go too.
- Good night, General.
- Good night, Your Excellency.
- Good night.
Julie, my coat.
- Good night, Countess.
- Good night, General.
Thank you, Julie.
There he goes.
- He's a wonderful man.
- I think they're both wonderful.
In love for years and years.
I heard that he was the reason
why she came back from America.
- Like something in a book.
- What kind of a book?
- None they'd let us read.
- I don't think that's a bit funny.
The only reason the General has
anything to do with her is...
- is because he's lonely.
- Then why doesn't he join the Army?
Oh, I hate you!
I hate all of you!
Darling, it's been a long evening.
Those children shouldn't be
allowed to stay up so late.
Those children shouldn't be allowed to
fall in love with a general who tells
them such exciting stories.
Oh, is that what you teach them?
That it is bad to fall in love with a general.
- Of course, look at me.
- A horrible example indeed.
I hope that the girls profit by it.
They all have tremendous
crushes on you, Kurt.
Why do you suppose that is?
Perhaps because you
tell stories so well.
So well that you have to turn
to your bookshelf for relief.
Oh, while you were talking I just happened
to be reminded of some old memoirs.
- Are my stories are so old as that?
- No.
- But I wonder if...
- The only memoirs that interest me began
ten years ago in a certain
box at the opera.
Perhaps you remember.
- Tristan and Isolda.
- And you wore a red dress.
Our memoirs should be
called Ten Years of Escape.
- Escape?
- Yes...
from an unbearably cruel
and miserable world.
Kurt, I've been very lucky living
on my mountaintop above all that.
Everyone should keep his
real self on a mountaintop.
And yet there are those
who aren't so lucky.
It isn't luck, my child.
It's the survival of the fittest.
Kurt, are we so sure
who are the fittest?
Can it be you don't
read our newspapers?
Fit or unfit?
Emmy Ritter, yes.
I remember her.
Bad tempered girl.
Good legs.
Used to be very popular
15 or 20 years ago.
By the way, Stolbach is conducting
an all-Wagner concert Tuesday.
Kurt, do you know what became of her?
Who? Oh, Emmy Ritter.
I think she went to America.
Darling, I'll take a box for the concert
if you think you can get a red dress.
Somebody told me she was
somewhere here in this country.
Is she?
Why should that interest us?
Kurt, won't you tell me what's
happened to Emmy Ritter?
- Why do you insist?
- I want to know.
You're an unreasonable stubborn child,
but if it amuses you to
indulge your curiosity...
Emmy Ritter's in a concentration
camp and is to be executed Saturday.
Executed?
May we now consider the matter closed?
- They're going to kill her? Why?
- I didn't say kill. I said execute.
She's guilty of treason.
Who found her guilty?
Those horrible people?
That's enough!
Kurt, you're defending them.
You...
A man with your name, your
honor, your integrity.
I'm a soldier in the
service of the State.
And I tell you they have
found her guilty. Finished!
They? You know what they are.
I know what you think of them.
Or at least what you used
to think about them.
But now I don't know.
You're becoming more like them and...
I can't bear the change in you.
I'm trying to tell you... I'm...
I'm trying to tell you...
- Kurt, what is it?
- Nothing. Nothing.
Kurt, please come sit down.
Oh, what a thoughtless fool I've been.
The doctor warned me that...
- Don't mind the doctor.
- I'm all right.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm all right.
- I'm so sorry. I...
I didn't mean to start all this.
Poor Ruby.
How difficult it is for you.
I wouldn't have told you if
I'd known this would happen.
I know, Kurt, I know, I wish
you hadn't told me this...
There's nothing I can do.
- There's no use my knowing these things.
- No.
No use, my poor little child.
Stay on your mountaintop.
We have so little time for happiness.
So little time and so much need.
You take the tickets.
Section "N" in the reviewing stand.
Hmm. Front row.
Of course, the General got them for us.
It's a shame you have to miss
the biggest parade of the year.
Oh, there will be other parades.
And a headache like mine
demands tea and quiet, not a parade.
The sight of those goose stepping robots
is enough to give anybody a headache.
Mary, it's silly of you to have a thought like that.
You mean it's very silly to express it out loud.
- You say it out loud just once too often.
- Please, girls.
If I feel better I'll join you later.
Otherwise you come back here.
- All right, yes.
- Goodbye.
Are you sure there haven't
been any messages for me?
Countess!
Countess. I'm Mark Preysing.
Remember?
Yes, of course.
- Have you... Have you any news?
- I'm sorry.
I knew you'd telephone me
if you found out anything.
- Will you have some tea?
- I was just on my way to the parade.
I would like to talk to you.
You seem so sort of shocked at seeing
me, almost like you'd seen a ghost.
Like I got dirt on my
face or something.
- I'd love some tea.
- Good.
- Doesn't seem to be any waiters around.
- It's a very important parade.
One isn't supposed to
be interested in teas.
Tell me what has happened.
I've been swinging like a pendulum
from one office to the next.
American on the flying trapeze.
One official catches me, gives me a little
twirl, then tosses me on to another.
Officials are the same all the world over.
It's heartbreaking.
And I have that creepy feeling
of being continually watched.
I'm sure my room's been searched.
It's like trying to fight shadows, or clutch
at water running through your fingers.
I know.
It's such a relief sitting here,
talking to someone you can trust.
I can sort of kid
myself that I'm happy.
I know I oughtn't to, but...
Nobody can be unhappy all the
time without a moment's relief.
I remember I felt like you once.
When my husband died and I was left
all alone in a strange country.
Terribly young and wretched
with no one to turn to.
But there were things, simple things...
almost too small to speak of.
A walk in our forest one
September evening...
a smile of a neighbor's child...
firelight, music.
At times, I too had the illusion
of happiness and felt guilty.
- But you're not listening.
- No, I was thinking.
You talk so simply and yet you're not simple.
There's a sort of mystery.
A kind of unknown fear in your eyes.
You talk as if you were doing it just to
kill time, in preparation for something.
I'm not sure what
you're really thinking.
I'm thinking that...
if 12 years ago I had
not come to Europe,
had stayed at home,
married an American,
perhaps a boy like you,
you wouldn't find me
very extraordinary.
I wish I had met you 12 years ago.
You know, there's a thing
of Kipling's that says...
We meet in an evil land,
near to the gates of hell...
I wish I could get you out.
Out and away.
Perhaps I don't want
to get out and away.
That's because you've forgotten
what it feels like to be free.
I've forgotten so completely that...
that I'd be almost afraid.
I'd be with you.
- Would you?
- Countess!
- How do you do, Baron?
Baron Von Reiber, may I present Mr Preysing.
How do you do?
Will you be sure to give the General
my congratulations for a tremendous
success of today's parade.
You're most kind, Baron.
And don't forget, you and he are
dining with us on Thursday.
The General... a relative?
No, no, he's just a
friend of long standing.
The Baron exaggerated his importance.
Many army officers are not directly
connected with the political police and...
even if they were, why...
I see.
After all I've lived here many years.
It's only natural that I'd have a few friends.
Don't... it's all right.
It's just that I'm an incurable fool.
- I must be off, Mr Preysing.
- Just a minute.
Since this General is such a trusty old
friend and I'm in such desperate trouble,
why couldn't you have asked him for help?
That is, if you really wanted to help me.
Mr Preysing, you must believe me.
I have not the slightest influence.
- It would only make matters worse if I were to...
- Goodbye, Countess.
Well, what did you think of the parade?
Wasn't it wonderful?
- Everybody seemed very enthusiastic.
- They did indeed. I never heard such cheering.
The Marshall must have enjoyed it.
Oh, well, he's a good fellow.
A little bit crude, of course,
but he was certainly
very appreciative.
Wants me to sit at his right
at the banquet tonight.
It means, of course, I shan't
be able to go to the concert.
I'm very, terribly sorry, my darling.
Oh, that's all right.
What's the matter, Ruby?
This show today has been a
rather personal triumph for me.
I thought you'd be pleased.
Oh, Kurt, I am.
It's just that crowds always
give me a headache.
I apologize for the crowds.
Come, sit down.
I like to have you beside me.
Oh, do play something else, Kurt.
I thought Tristan was our favorite opera.
Well, perhaps I've heard it too often.
So...
By the way, I have news of
the Emmy Ritter affair.
I'll tell you tomorrow when
your head feels better.
Have they pardoned her?
No, no, no, of course not.
It's only about a son of hers.
From America.
Did you know she had a son?
Well, this boy has been going around
making an infernal nuisance of himself.
So they tell me.
- And?
- And...
Oh, it's 6 o'clock. I must be off.
Dinner's at seven.
But you were telling me that...
Oh, yes, about this boy.
Well, he's an American citizen...
More's the pity, however, if
he goes on bothering us...
- it can be taken care of.
- Taken care of?
Yes, taken care of.
I see.
I'm sorry, Ruby. It's just, you see,
there are moments that I cannot
resist the impulse to tease you.
To hurt me, you mean.
- It's not that I want to, it's just...
- No need to explain.
You're tired.
Be sure to have a rest before the concert.
Here are the tickets.
Oh, I don't feel like going. I...
I am very tired.
Do you go to hear music?
Take one of the girls, or
telephone some friend.
Yes, that might be an idea.
Then good night, dear.
Enjoy the concert.
The concert's almost over.
I was afraid you weren't coming.
Well, I was away from the hotel.
I didn't get your message until just now.
I was awfully unfair
to you this afternoon.
Someday I'm going to tell you how much
it meant to me getting this message.
I should have known you'd
find some way to help me.
- You're going to help me, aren't you?
- I have something to tell you.
- I want to be your friend, believe me.
- What do you know?
- Tell me!
- Keep your voice down.
Then answer me.
My mother, if she's dead, say so.
If she's alive, tell me
where I can find her.
Please, be quiet.
It's dangerous for you here.
What are you talking about?
- I don't care about myself.
- But I do.
You must get away from here.
Go home.
Go back to America at once.
- You say that to me too?
- Quiet. It's the only thing that I can say.
If you stay here you'll only get
into terrible trouble yourself.
I've done all that I can.
All that you've a right
to expect of me.
Yes, you've been wonderful.
You've told me to go home,
to forget I have a mother.
Why, you're worse than they are.
I was ready just now to tell you
that I'd found everything I ever
thought a woman should be.
I was wrong.
I haven't found anything except
a woman who wants to play safe
and hold on to what she's got.
You're not only, not the woman I thought
you were, you're not even a human being!
I could kill you.
Countess!
- Countess.
- Oh, Dr. Ditten.
- It's good to see you again.
- It has been much too long.
Tell me, have you been away in
the mountains all these weeks?
- Yes.
- How fortunate you are.
You know, all through the performance, I...
I couldn't take my eyes off you.
If your friend doesn't object.
Oh, that's right.
You haven't met, have you?
- Dr. Ditten, may I introduce....
- Ruby!
- Ruby, darling.
- Baroness, how nice.
- Countess.
- Good evening, Baron.
Well, it looks as if we were all
caught in the rain, doesn't it?
Yes.
It's almost as if we have been
together throughout the day, isn't it?
Would you mind dropping me, Edwige?
It would save my friends
going out of their way.
Darling, we would just love to
have you with us. Come along.
Goodbye, Dr Ditten, you must
come and have tea with me soon.
Thank you, I will.
Excuse me, but I have an umbrella.
May I share it with you?
No, thanks, I haven't far to go.
The evening is so young, I wonder if you would
do me the honor of having a drink with me.
Yes, thanks.
I could do with a drink.
That's fine.
So...
I like this place.
It's like my pipe.
Very old, not very fashionable.
Waiters!
I should have worn my uniform.
- Army?
- No.
Hello.
Two, please.
I have had a most unpleasant day.
Well, to life.
Good or bad, at least it is life.
Have you known the Countess long?
- Not in America.
- So, charming woman, the Countess.
- A happy one?
- Happy? Yes, I think so.
Her life is ordered and secure.
I see no reason why she
shouldn't be happy.
No, I suppose not.
When she first came to this country she and
I used to have long, passionate debates.
She was full of your naive American
political theories about the rights of...
No...
No, I don't think we'll
talk about that.
- Thanks, now I can enjoy my beer.
- Hmm, good.
Maybe, this would be a
good moment to confess.
Confess what?
I had an ulterior motive
in asking you here.
There are certain American medical journals
which are very, very difficult to obtain.
I know we are strangers, but this is an
opportunity which may not happen again.
- Would you do me...?
- Of course.
What do you want and
where shall I send them?
Oh, that's fine.
Very kind of you.
I'll write everything down.
I hope my handwriting
doesn't confuse you.
My name is Dr. Ditten.
Berthold Ditten.
48 Linnenwey.
Oh, my apologies.
I just realized I
don't know your name.
- Preysing. Mark Preysing.
- So, Mark Prey...
Did you say Mark Preysing?
Yes, what's the matter?
- That's very strange.
- Is it?
Are you Madame Emmy Ritter's son?
Yes.
Well, ahh...
...this is for you.
When did she give it to you?
On Monday.
- She's still alive.
- Yes.
- Who are you?
- I'm a doctor.
- At a concentration camp.
- Where is it?
I'm sorry.
How much time has she?
- Not much.
- How much?
Tell me!
Saturday.
Early in the morning.
It's Thursday now.
What can I do?
You better go now.
No, answer me.
What can I do?
Please keep your voice down.
- Nothing you can do.
- But there must be something.
- There's no chance of escape.
- I don't believe you.
Please, Mr Preysing, believe me,
this is not a place to talk.
- Mr Preysing, let me say this.
- Haven't you said enough already?
I'll try to make it easier for her.
- I'm sorry. My nerves are all...
- I understand.
Would you like to send her a message?
I don't know.
- Yes, tell her I...
- I must go now.
Would you come to my
flat tomorrow night?
How I'm going to live
until tomorrow night?
Until tomorrow then.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Hello, Mr Mark.
So it's you.
Leave me alone.
Why should you blame me?
I... I couldn't talk to you then.
My helper would have
told me my sister...
- and she would have turned me over like that!
- Stop talking so much!
They're going to kill her!
Do you hear me? Kill her!
Please, Mr Mark.
I did what I could!
The day before she was
arrested, I said to her...
"Madame, you have your money.
All right.
So take the next train and go!
Go now!"
But would she ever listen to me?
- She's still alive.
- But after she was arrested...
the trouble I had.
They took away my money...
my job, and they took away everything.
As if I was a criminal, not she.
Did you ever hear of such a thing?
And then the trial.
Would she keep quiet?
Oh, no. Oh, no. You know her.
She had to make speeches.
My tongue is my freedom, she said.
Well, she used it too much.
For years I have warned her, Mr Mark.
Madame, don't, I said.
Please, don't.
- Fritz!
- Mr Mark, what?
You've gotta think of some
way of getting her out.
When I was a kid Fritz, you
always helped me. Help me now!
Please, Mr Mark, let go of me.
But I've got money.
The money from the house.
Use any part of it. All of it.
You've got to do something.
- No.. No, I can do nothing.
- You've got to!
Who else here can help me now but you?
All right.
Shh.
- Fritz!
- All right, all right, don't get excited.
I think I can get her out.
Yes, Mr Mark, yes.
When it is over, they won't throw
her into any prison lime pit.
- What are you talking about?
- I now, I know my duty.
I'll claim the body, I'll
give her a decent burial...
Yes, now you have money, I'll give her
a coffin with those...bronze handles.
Fritz, are you crazy?
She's not dead yet. Not dead.
- Mr Mark, please. When the police get me...
- You always think of yourself!
Don't you ever think of her?
I've lived through enough troubles.
I've got to go now.
I have to go and sign papers.
In this country you even can't
get buried without papers.
Nurse! Nurse!
My heart! Help me.
- Help!
- Oh, stop it!
Dr. Ditten! Dr. Ditten!
Come!
Look at her.
The stethoscope.
Heart block.
- Well, It's not my fault.
- Quiet.
Well, it looks as if you're going to
lose your star patient, Dr. Ditten.
Maybe you think you can still save her.
Some of us overestimate our
abilities now and then, don't we?
Yes. We gamble everything
on being right.
Sometimes, of course, we lose.
Dr. Ditten, there's a Mr Preysing
waiting for you in the living-room.
Ah, Hilda, I won't need
you any more tonight.
Oh, thank you.
- Good evening, Mr Preysing.
- Good evening.
I was worried you might not come.
Have you seen her today?
- Have you seen her today?!
- Yes, yes, I've seen her today.
Tell me, your mother's
heart was always strong?
Why do you ask that?
Because today I did a criminal thing.
- You killed her?
- Well, I...
- You killed her!
- Please, Mr Preysing.
- But you said you...
- Please, Mr Preysing, let me explain.
Your mother was condemned
to die tomorrow.
- What's that got to do with it?
- You listen to me!
I gave your mother a certain drug which
produced a condition known as bradicardia.
A coma-like state, you
see, apparently death.
But she is not dead.
They called me in, I signed
the certificate of death.
But she is alive.
In a coma, yes, but alive.
Well, why don't you say something?
I don't understand.
I deliberately drugged your mother,
pronounced her dead, but she is not dead.
I can't believe that...
Tomorrow you would have
accepted her death...
I know that.
Today, why don't you accept her life?
- I'm all mixed up. It's happened so quickly.
- I understand, but...
now you've got your chance.
You must get her out of the camp.
- The camp? How can I go there?
- Huh?
I'm not even supposed to know where she is,
let alone that she's supposed to be dead.
Even if I got her out, where would I
take her, where could I hide her?
All I thought about was to save her.
Listen, Preysing...
You must find someone to help you.
You must get the coffin out of the camp.
Coffin?
- She'll suffocate.
- Oh, no, no, no.
Those coffins are loosely made.
But if you delay...
when you open it, she may be dead.
You must act quickly.
- Fritz.
- Fritz who?
An old servant. I'd almost forgotten.
He's already arranged to claim the body.
That's fine. The telephone.
Tell him its happened.
Tell him to go to the camp
at once and meet you.
Hello, operator.
Get me Fritz Keller in Felzenkirche.
No, I don't know the number.
Just Felzenkirche.
- Tell him to meet me where?
- At the White Swan Inn. It's close to the camp.
You'll have to work quickly.
Get her out of the coffin.
Dress her warmly.
Warmth is of the greatest importance.
Yes, operator, I'm waiting.
Is there any medicine, any stimulant?
No, no. The only thing is to get her to a
place where she can rest. Warmth and rest.
Fritz will know where to...
What's the matter?
- What if he won't help me?
- You said he was your friend.
I'm not sure.
He's so afraid of everything.
Then don't tell him that she's alive.
No, your only worry is to get her
out and keep her warm.
Blankets, yes, and a warm coat.
Hello. Hello, is that you, Fritz?
Yes, now listen.
Mother... my mother just died at the camp.
They're waiting for you...
Fritz, don't ask questions.
What?
They've already phoned him.
Now, Fritz, wait. When you get the
coffin, meet me at the White Swan Inn.
I want to be with you when you bury her.
But Fritz, there's nothing to worry about.
It's all over.
What's the difference if you are with me?
Don't argue, Fritz.
Get to the camp quickly.
I'll meet you at the White Swan at...
- Three hours.
- At eleven, Fritz. Do you hear me?
At eleven. Goodbye.
Come on.
Steady. I think I had better
get back to the camp myself.
Why are you doing all this for me?
My friend, to know the answer...
you would have to know my entire life..
my parents' lives, the lives
of everyone I have ever met...
you'd have to know every
word ever said to me...
every word I have ever said...
I've, seen, read, thought about...
But to put it simply,
say that for the moment I'm just like
a cat who chews green stuff so as
to purge himself of poison.
I can't let it go like this. Suppose I bungle
the rest of it, what will happen to you?
- I have to count on you, Mark Preysing.
- I'll see you again.
I'm afraid not.
It would be too dangerous.
My regards to America.
Now hurry.
Yes, sir.
- Coffee, please.
- Yes, sir.
- Get me some brandy, will you.
But I must serve them first.
Yes, sir?
- Beer.
Yes, sir.
- Waiter.
- Yes, sir?
Have you got a pack of cards?
Yes, sir, I will bring them to you.
Thank you.
Anything else?
- Will there be anything later, sir?
- Why?
We're closing in a half an hour.
- Closing?
- They are very strict here because of...
No.
What is that game?
- It's an American game.
- Oh.
What are you doing here?
What am I doing here? I might ask
what are you doing here at my table.
Political Police.
Oh, well, I'm an American.
You have your passport?
Certainly.
And what are you doing here?
I'm here to meet a friend.
What friend?
Is it a usual custom of this
country to annoy visitors?
You're required to answer all questions.
Unless, of course, you
wish to be detained.
Why are you so concerned with the time?
I have an appointment.
What's this?
Oh, a fur coat.
A woman's fur coat.
What is this for?
Maybe it is for his friend.
Oh... that kind of appointment, huh?
She's coming here?
No, I'm not to meet her here.
That comes later.
I'm waiting here for a
man, a friend of mine.
Who?
- A man I know.
- You said that. What is his name?
You're required to answer.
- His name is Ditten.
- Why do you want to meet him here?
Because he asked me to.
Isn't that a good enough reason?
Where does he live?
He's attached to a camp near here.
He's a doctor.
Might also interest you to know that
he's a member of the Political Police.
Why does he want you to meet him here?
I told you he's a friend of mine.
What time are you to meet him?
At... eleven. Yes, at eleven.
Then why is he not here?
- I must have missed him. I was late.
- Do you expect to go on waiting here all night?
Is there any reason why I shouldn't?
Why are you so interested
in our military transports?
I thought it might be the doctor.
What did you say his name was?
Ditten. Dr. Ditten.
Ditten.
Thank you.
We are closing now.
I am sorry, but we have to close now.
- Couldn't I stay just a little while longer?
- It is the regulation.
It's getting very cold.
I'm sorry to turn you out.
- When is the next bus back to town?
- In about a half an hour.
That's just enough time for you to go to
the camp and see if your friend is there.
Oh, no thanks. I think I'll wait
for the bus and go back to town.
Come.
Come!
We want to be sure you see your friend.
Well, what is it?
Commandant, I've picked up an
American down at the White Swan Caf.
Said he was to meet a Dr.
Ditten there. An American?
His name is Preysing. You know him?
No. I knew he was lying.
Snooping around like all... No, no...
You will excuse me, sir.
There must be a mistake.
I had an appointment with Mr Preysing.
I told him about his mother.
I mentioned your name.
Speak when you're spoken to.
I don't know your man. Send him away.
Wait.
Doctor, shouldn't he be
held for questioning?
Yes, yes, I suppose so.
I'll talk to him myself.
Here. The death certificate.
Nurse!
Help this man to get the body out of here.
So you were lying to me.
He doesn't even know him.
- You're under arrest.
- Wait.
I'll handle this.
Why did you tell these men you
had an appointment with me?
Why didn't you tell them the truth?
They were only doing their
duty questioning you.
Why didn't you tell them...
you came here about your mother?
Yes, I should have.
They're bringing her out.
Stop! Put that down.
What are you going to do with this?
We're going to bury her.
Do it here!
We've got a place at the back for it!
But we have permission to
take her to bury her outside.
Oh, have you?
Yes, sir.
Here. They say... I can read.
Would you mind hurrying, please?
She's dead, isn't she?
Then what's the hurry?
- And that is the coffin?
- Yes.
I will have to see the body.
Go on. Open it.
- Is this Emmy Ritter?
- Yes.
Wait a minute.
- Why isn't this nailed down?
- He said he would do it himself.
All right, then. Get to work.
- Nail it down!
- We'll do it before we bury her.
I'm not talking to you!
Come on, nail it down!
All right, get it out of here.
- All right, Fritz, pull up.
- What for?
I've got to get her out. She'll suffocate.
Poor Mr Mark, you have had so much trouble.
Try not to think about it.
Fritz, in heaven's name, stop the car.
She's alive!
- Mr Mark, such crazy talk.
- Fritz, stop the car!
No, Mr Mark.
Are you mad?
I'm going back with her.
As soon as I'm in, get going.
Mr Mark! Mr Mark!
The road ahead, it's blocked.
Mr Mark.
Mr Mark, the road ahead, it's blocked.
It doesn't matter, Fritz. She's dead.
Dead... What's the matter
with you, Mr Mark?
Of course she's dead!
Please, come out of there, Mr Mark.
She was alive, Fritz.
Oh, please, Mr Mark. You must try to
keep your mind away from what happened.
- Come on. I'll help you cover her over again.
- No, no. Leave her alone.
Please, Mr Mark, stop acting like a child!
Your mother was dead, she is dead.
And nothing you can do...
Mother!
Oh, madame! Oh, madame!
Don't just stand there, get the truck started.
We've got to get her to a house.
- Your sister's.
- But we...
- Go on, go on!
- But we can't go on.
The slide blocked the road.
- All right, then we'll take the other way.
- But this is the only way there...
You're lying! You're afraid.
All right I don't need you.
I'll get it through myself. Now get out!
Please, Mr Mark, don't talk to me that way.
Sure I'm afraid. Why shouldn't I be afraid?
But she is alive and wherever
you go with her I'll go too.
- So please don't tell me to get out, Mr Mark.
- She'll die if we don't get her where it's warm.
Ya, Herr, but where?
- Fritz, where are we?
- In the park, near Felzenkirche.
- Felzenkirche. I know?
- Where?
- The Countess's house.
- But how do you...?
Don't ask questions. She'll have to let us in.
It's a green house just below the pass.
Now get started.
Green house just below the pass...
Green house below the pass...
Kurt.
Why did you bother coming down?
Don't leave like this.
It's almost six. My skiing party
will be waiting for me at the Inn.
Kurt, don't be angry.
If I could tell you what's the
matter, I would. But I...
I can't seem to put it into words.
My dear, that stupid doctor you sent
me to warned me against two things.
One was violent exercise, like skiing,
the other was violent quarrels.
At the present I prefer skiing.
The doctor is an idiot, and so are you my dear.
But as usual, I forgive you. I'll see you tonight.
I've come to you for help.
What is it? My mother. Let me in.
I've no other place to take her.
- Oh, no. No, not here.
- But you must. She'll die.
No, please.
No, not in there.
- Where then?
- Let me see.
Upstairs.
Quiet, please.
The room at the end of the hall.
Those two in there,
they will never forget.
What happened?
They thought Madame Ritter died last night.
But we found she really was not dead.
So we got her out. Yes.
And that is how it was.
I don't think I believe you.
Well...
You know she can't stay in my house.
You must take her away
from here before tonight.
But not so soon, Countess.
Mr Mark is so tired. And she is so ill.
You must take her out of my house
or I'll have to notify the police.
Well, I do what I can.
Hello.
- Did I wake you?
- No!
As I left a car turned into your driveway.
A sort of a delivery truck.
Well?
Yes, I heard it, but it must
have turned around and gone on.
It didn't stop?
- No.
- Well that's all right then.
I was a little puzzled. It seemed so
strange, a delivery truck at that hour.
- You're sure everything's all right, hmm?
- Yes, of course.
- What are you doing now?
- Well, I was just going to get myself some coffee.
Good. Get some rest.
I'll see you tonight.
- All right.
- Goodbye, my dear.
Goodbye.
- The truck was seen coming in here.
- By...by whom?
I was just telephoned. You can't stay
here another instant. It's impossible.
Mother.
You're safe, mother.
There's nothing to worry about.
Everything is all right.
You're going home.
- To Mark...
- Yes, Mother.
- You're in prison too?
- No, Mother, no, nobody's in the prison.
I never thought I'd see you again.
Now, now, just lie back down.
We'll keep the door locked.
- Did you say we?
- We must let her rest for a few hours.
You did say we.
Yes.
And now you must rest.
- I'm all right.
- Oh, you can't do everything yourself.
- Who is the man who is helping you?
- Fritz.
He's arranging about the
funeral, the supposed funeral.
I see.
He also knows a man who
supplies forged passports.
Good.
We must get the girls out of the house.
Let me see now, I'll
send them skiing early.
And now you, please lie down
and try and get some sleep.
I just can't get it out
of my mind, madame.
There were all those strange noises.
My first thought was of the silver.
Julie, you read too many mystery novels.
But there was something, madame.
Somebody walking, as plain...
Julie, stop talking nonsense.
She's not talking nonsense.
There is something going on around here.
And I know what it is.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about Maria.
Oh, yes, she has a cold, poor girl.
She won't be able to go skiing with the rest of you.
She's not sick.
She just doesnt want to go with us!
She was the one who was sneaking around
last night, down at the ice box!
That shows how sick she really is.
It's nothing to laugh about.
She doesn't belong here.
She doesn't think right!
Well, I hope she eats right.
- Julie, will you take this tray up to her?
- Yes, madame.
Didn't you hear me?
She was the one who was walking
around last night. I heard her!
Oh, please answer the door, dear.
Tell the driver you and the girls
will be ready to go in a few moments.
You won't listen to me.
You don't like me. You like her!
Ursula, don't talk nonsense.
- Hello, Ursula.
- Why, Your Excellency, come in.
Thank you.
Good afternoon, Your Excellency.
- What's this? Going away?
- Yes, we are. Isn't it wonderful?
- All the way up to the skiing lodge.
- So.
And we're going to stay
there all night too.
Ah, really?
- Look, Your Excellency. I have a new skiing jacket.
- Very nice. The Countess is going with you?
No, I'm not.
- Good afternoon, Countess.
- Good afternoon, General.
You'd better go finish your coffee, girls.
The driver ought to be here any moment.
- Won't you have some coffee with us, General?
- Yes, yes, I think I will.
So you are going to be quite alone, eh?
Well, girls, looking
forward to your skiing?
Why don't you come with us and teach
us how to really ski, Your Excellency?
I'm afraid His Excellency is much too
busy to become our skiing instructor.
But we should have a man with us.
Countess,
do you think there's any
chance of our running into
that handsome young American
in the mountains?
The American would look very
handsome in skiing clothes.
Don't you think so, Helene?
May I ask who is this young man?
Oh, no one of any importance.
You'd better get started now, girls.
The automobile isn't here yet.
Thank you.
You should have seen him up at the lake.
He's so handsome.
We girls just couldn't take our eyes off
him, while he was talking to the Countess.
Really?
Oh, yes, some friends told me you were at the
concert with a young man. Is it this one?
- Yes, I met him quite by accident.
- Do I know him?
I don't think so, no.
- His name?
Mr Preysing, I met him once in America.
- I think I know of a Mr Preysing.
- Emmy Ritter's son, hm?
I think so, yes.
- He has no friends here and...
- How kind of you to think of him.
No doubt he's lonely even now.
Wouldn't it be nice, girls, to have Mr
Preysing join us on a skiing party?
- You might even join us then, huh?
- I have no reason to see Mr Preysing again.
But have you any reason not to see him?
Why, I think it would be terribly amusing.
Well, there you are, your young ladies
would enjoy a younger man about.
And perhaps you would enjoy
a younger man yourself.
Come girls, it's getting quite late.
Oh, no, wait. You ought to
telephone the young man at once.
Don't you think this has gone far enough?
Where is Mr Preysing now?
- I don't know.
- That's easy enough to find out.
Ursula call the Hotel Excelsior in the
city or try the Inn in the village.
Yes, Your Excellency.
Ursula, wait.
Have you forgotten why he's here?
No.
But undoubtedly he has.
He needs to be reminded.
Ursula, telephone him.
All right.
Operator, please get me the
Inn at the village. Yes.
Hello. Do you have a Mr
Preysing staying there?
You're sure? Thank you.
Operator. Operator!
Get me the Hotel Excelsior
in the city, please.
Yes, and hurry. Hurry, please.
Could you tell me if you have an American
by the name of Preysing staying there?
He's gone?
Oh, all right. Thank you.
Why, Mr Preysing!
- I was just trying to find you.
- Were you?
Oh, come in, come in. You certainly
picked the right time to visit us.
Look, I got him. Isn't that service?
- Mr Preysing.
- Just as I telephoned, he was coming in the door.
Yes, I didn't want to leave the
village without saying goodbye.
That's very kind of you.
Excellency, may I present Mr Preysing?
Mr Preysing, General Von Kolb.
How do you do.
This is really odd, Mr Preysing.
I was just talking about you.
- I wanted to meet you. Come in, Mr Preysing.
- Why, I'm sorry, I have an appointment.
Oh, no, no. The Countess'
invitations are not to be refused.
- Greta, take Mr Preysing's coat.
- I really can't stay.
Nonsense, we want you to.
- Don't we, Ruby?
- Yes, yes, of course.
Sit down, Mr Preysing, sit down.
Well, Ruby, aren't you going to
offer your friend some coffee?
No, thank you.
Something stronger, hm?
Some wine, Ruby.
Mr Preysing, has the purpose of
your visit been accomplished?
You did have a purpose in
visiting this country, I presume.
- Yes.
- No, no, no, put it here at my right, remember?
- There you are.
- No, thank you.
Now, that's a mistake.
Wine makes a man forget his troubles.
Or perhaps you have none.
Young and carefree, Mr Preysing?
You are carefree, aren't you?
Is anyone?
Ruby, where are my cigarettes?
My dear, you shouldn't wear that dress.
It washes you out. You look like a ghost.
Come now, it's only a spider.
Nothing to get excited about.
Spiders are not dangerous.
Mr Preysing, I once knew a lady
who had a tarantula as a pet.
I once new a tarantula who had a pet lady.
Mr Preysing, are you forgetting that
there are young ladies present?
Don't worry about the ladies.
They'll keep whatever pets they like.
Tarantulas or Pekinese, or even Generals.
What's that you say?
Who buys your uniform, your
gold braid, your saber?
Who pays for your motorcar
and your driver? Women.
They scrimp and save so
their men can pay taxes.
All over this country women are saving
carrot tops and potato peelings
just to keep a pet general.
Ruby, your friend has a
sense of humor. Yes.
Yes, get the whiskey.
We will drink a real toast
to Mr Preysing and his ingenious jokes.
Sit down, Mr Preysing.
We are enjoying your humor.
Sorry, I really must leave.
Ladies, if you'll excuse me, I'll
say goodbye to the Countess.
- I'm not going to leave you here.
- There's no time to talk about ourselves.
Tell me you'll come with us.
Say it!
- Say it.
- I'll be with you.
Ruby, have you forgotten the girls?
The car is here, they are
waiting to say goodbye.
Please excuse me, Mr Preysing.
I don't like you, Mr Preysing.
No?
Do you imagine I like you?
Unfortunately for you, I'm in a
position to enforce my dislikes.
- You must leave this country at once.
- How soon would you suggest?
Immediately.
I must try to do that.
You're not going to try.
You are going.
There's nothing more to keep you here.
This morning your mother was executed.
- You enjoy telling me that, don't you?
- And what are you going to do about it?
What can I do?
You take a great deal
from me, I wonder why?
I don't think I would take what you are
taking, not even in a strange country.
That's easy to say.
Come over to my backyard
some day and find out.
I shall, I promise.
- Goodbye, girls.
- Goodbye, Countess.
Julie, see that he doesn't
drive too fast, will you?
Yes, madame.
- Goodbye, madame.
- Goodbye, Countess.
- Goodbye, Mr Preysing.
- I'm sorry if I've caused you any trouble.
- Kurt.
- I'd rather not talk to you now.
I might say something which
both of us would regret.
Not many turned out.
I'm glad Madame Ritter wasn't in that box.
She would be so angry to draw such a
small audience at her last appearance.
- Is everything all right?
- Oh, yes.
Where's Mr Preysing?
Mr Mark.
Has he been here or phoned?
- No, that's why I'm worried.
- He mustn't find her in your house.
We've gotta get out of here, now.
All of us.
Fritz, you park the truck up at the side road.
We'll be upstairs.
You get your things packed.
Mother.
Oh...
Mark.
Darling...
do you think you can get up?
Well, of course.
No more truck rides, I hope.
Mother, there's still a lot ahead of us.
- You mean crossing the border?
- No, that'll come later.
Later?
Couldn't get a passport.
- Then you can't leave the country.
- We'll go somewhere.
But where?
Don't you worry about that, now.
We've gotta get out of here.
But why? Why tonight?
Well, you see, mother, there's
someone who might cause us a little
Wait!
I'll get you a passport.
Marion.
Marion, please.
Oh, I'm so sorry to have to waken you.
- Can you understand what I say?
- Yes, madame.
- Do you feel better?
- Yes.
What is it, madame?
I have a great favor to ask of you.
I ask it because I must.
What is it?
I want you to lend me your passport.
- Passport?
- Yes.
But, madame, I...
My passport, if I give it up,
there'd be such trouble.
It's to help someone who
needs our help very much.
Someone who believes
as I think you do.
Is it something to do with the American?
Take it.
How do I look?
- It's really wonderful.
- That makes me feel good, madame.
We are back in show business.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- It's good, but is it good enough?
- Oh, listen to him!
He's as bad as a Philadelphia critic.
Your bad notices were in
Boston, not in Philadelphia.
Well, let's hope they
don't look too closely.
- You ready, Mother?
- Yes, yes, darling.
- Wait a minute!
- What is it?
Luggage.
No, no, yours will be enough in case
anyone at the airport gets suspicious.
Well, ah...
you better have more.
You'll find some suitcases in the
closet at the head of the stairs.
- Please be ready, both of you.
- Come on, Fritz.
- Your passport is in your bag.
- Oh, thank you.
All set.
It takes 15 minutes to get to the airport.
The plane leaves at 9 o'clock.
21 minutes of nine.
21 minutes to freedom.
You any small luggage?
If you please, Madame Ritter.
What happened?
Why aren't you ready to go?
- Mark, I've thought it over.
- No, no, you're going.
- I can't go. Not now.
- Do you love that man, is that it?
- I can't leave him.
- But you can.
He'd never rest until he uncovered
everybody connected with this.
- Oh, that doctor who helped me.
- Yes, and Fritz too, they'd be tortured.
He'd see to that.
He can be unbelievably cruel.
If you know that about him,
then you don't love him.
But there's so much else, Mark, it...
it isn't as simple as that.
What are you trying to say?
I'm trying to say...
I'm trying to tell you that...
- That you love me.
- Oh, Mark.
But you do.
- Hold me.
- No past, no regrets.
Just you and I beginning right now.
- If I can only come to you later.
- You can.
Mr Mark!
And now you must hurry.
- When will it be safe for you to leave?
- I don't know, Mark, but soon.
It had better be.
Mr Mark!
Mr Mark, there's a car coming
with two soldiers in front.
In here, quickly.
Go out the back door.
Stay close to the hedge
and you won't be seen.
- Hurry, you can just make it.
- I'll be waiting on 57th Street.
Yes, Mark, yes, hurry.
Why, Kurt, I didn't expect you so early.
I'm glad you came.
Kurt, it's been such a long day.
It isn't 9 yet and it seems like 24 hours...
Kurt, if you're worried about Mr Preysing,
he's gone, and he shan't return.
Oh, well, all right, Kurt.
Emmy Ritter died suddenly
in prison on Friday night.
Oh, how sad.
But not sad for her son, was it?
Or was it great sorrow which
brought him here yesterday?
- Well, perhaps he didn't know.
- He buried her himself.
Perhaps he thought she was better off.
After all she...
- Stop these lies, Ruby.
- Kurt, please don't talk to me like that.
How they have used you, Preysing, your friend
Dr Ditten, the old servant Fritz Keller.
- Ruby, Emmy Ritter's in this house, isn't she?
- In this house? Really, Kurt.
- I had no idea you had such an imagination.
- Don't, Ruby. It's quite useless, she's here.
Is she?
Then there's only one thing to do.
Search the house.
You fool. I don't want her found in this house.
I want to protect you.
Well then, Kurt. Search it yourself.
So, she isn't here. Good.
- What are you going to do?
- I'm going to call the police...
Every road, every station,
every airport must be watched.
Do you wanna be made ridiculous.
Do you want people to say well where is this
resurrected woman and then laugh at you?
- You don't like to be laughed at, Kurt.
- I'll risk that.
All right. You win. I'm not clever.
Not nearly as clever as you are.
What if you won?
The death of a woman?
You're strong, Kurt.
But this woman is weak. She...
She only has a few more years to live.
Why not let her have them?
Let her have sunshine
and happiness in life.
We've had it. Let's reach down this once
and share it with someone who needs it.
Your interest in his
mother is very touching.
But it would have come better before you
had tried to trick me and lied to me...
as you are lying now. You're not pleading for
the mother, you're pleading for the son.
Then, when they arrest me, what then?
- You're getting out of the country now.
- Oh, no, Kurt, no. I'm staying.
You will have to arrest me, won't you?
Yes, it will be my... my duty.
Of course. Nothing must
interfere with your duty.
You're a hero, Kurt. First you must kill
this woman, and then there'll be my trial.
Imagine what it will be like.
You and I and all of our friends watching.
How they'll stare at us, at me.
They'll say there's the woman who
betrayed him for the sake of another man.
- A young man!
- Stop!
Oh, you think I'm so shy and timid, don't you?
But I tell you won't be.
I'll say everything I can think of. I'll tell them
you're crazy and that you're accusing my friends...
because you're insane with jealousy. A half mad, sick
creature who should be in a hospital, not in the army.
I'll tell them I loathe their
country and everyone in it.
That I'd betray it over and
over if I had the chance.
I'll make them cruel to me, do fearful things to me
and you'll have to be there and watch them do it.
You'll do what you must.
I'll do what I must.
This is General Von Kolb.
Kurt.
Hello.
Hello!
I did what I had to.
Ruby...
- don't leave me now.
- No, Kurt.
I won't leave you now.