A tidal wave is coming.
Soon, lam sure,
it will sweep us all away.
Production: Dentsu, lmagica,
Suncent CinemaWorks, Tokyo Theaters
a Suncent CinemaWorks Film
Starring: YAKUSHO Koji
KOKUSHO Sayuri
SAITOH Yohichiroh
RIJU Go
MATSUSHIGE Yutaka
SHIOMI Sansei
SHINGYOUJI Kimie
MITSUISHI Ken
MIYAZAKI Aoi
MIYAZAKI Masaru
Producer: SENTO Takenori
Production Designer:
SHIMIZU Takeshi
Sound: KIKUCHI Nobuyuki
Music:
YAMADA lsao & AOYAMA Shinji
Lighting: SATO Yuzuru
Cinematography: TAMRA Masaki
Written and Directed by
AOYAMA Shinji
Everyone into position!
There it is!
What's that number for the police?
Oh yeah!
Yes Sir!
Hello?
Mr. Detective?
Huh? You're where?
And where is that?
So you're outside?
Yeah?
Where are we, exactly?
I chose this place by chance.
Yeah, some are dead in here.
There are four survivors.
Everybody has to die sometime.
Hey Mr. Detective.
Who am I? Pop quiz!
Yeah, pop quiz.
Well, when you figure it out,
speak up, so I can hear you.
Hello?
Hello. Lost it.
Nothing. Can you hear me?
That's better.
It's stuffy in here.
I'm going out for a minute.
Hey Mr. Bus Driver...
Would you step outside with me?
How about letting the children go?
That's true.
Well, the children ARE our future
but all I really want right now
is to go out
and get some fresh air.
Wow... what a beautiful day.
Hey Mr. Bus Driver, you gotta name?
SAW N . .. SNNN Makoto.
Does Makoto mean anything?
Truthful, direct.
Great name!
Ever wish you were somebody else?
I don't know.
I really would have liked
to be someone else.
Now I'm just sick of everything.
Ready?
Aim!
Fire!
Busjack in Shiroishi,
Fukuoka.
Tragedy at noon.
Six shot dead,
including one policeman.
Two middle school children,
bus driver rescued.
Assailanfs identity
yet unknown.
Am I at fault for having survived?
Thank you very much.
A physician is leaving the house.
A doctor who has just seen Kozue
is coming out of the house.
Excuse me doctor,
what can you tell us?
How are the children?
ls little Kozue recovering?
Doctor!
Ignore it!
Hello?
Yes, thank you.
Who said such a thing?
That's not true!
Don't be ridiculous!
That's absolutely not true.
Yes... good bye!
What was it?
Hey, Mitsu!
Kozue...
There's a rumor in town
that she was raped in the bus.
Yoshiyuki's home...
Let's have him find him.
Makoto left a note?
Yumiko, give him the note.
Mom, don't be so pushy!
Yumiko...
Good evening, brother-in-law.
Sorry for the trouble.
Makotds my brother.
Yes, Yumiko, we're all family.
Did Makoto say anything, dad?
He just said
he was going out for a bit.
Kiyoko, tea please.
I'll check the station
and the police.
The sooner the better.
Thank you very much.
Don't mention it, Aunt Yumi.
TWO YEARS LATER
Naoki...
Where did mom go?
Won't she come back?
Dad told me
there's another man.
Why's she need a new man?
Daddy hit her.
Why did he hit her?
Who knows?
Is it because of us?
Put it out of your mind.
What's that?
Because daddy died
the insurance sends money.
Naoki? It's Aunt Yoshiko,
How are you?
I've been so worried about you two.
I keep planning to come visit,
you know.
Did the insurance company
pay you yet?
Of course your uncle did lose
his temper at the funeral,
but I really wanted you
to come and live with us.
I'm sorry.
Beer, please.
Isn't it great that Makotds back?!
Where did you go?
Here and there.
Here and there?
You're not leaving again?
Makoto...
You'll stay with us for good,
won't you?
Yumi went back home to Hakata.
One of her old friends called.
She's back at the beauty parlor.
You could go visit her.
Silly. It's not so easy.
So, let's drink to his health.
Sorry, I don't drink anymore.
Why?
He doesn't have to.
Makoto, the bath's ready.
What are you going to do for work?
I'll go see Shigeo tomorrow.
I see.
It's a good idea.
We should be able to help you.
No, thanks, really.
But that's day labor, isn't it'?
I'm not even sure yet.
I'll be OK.
He just said he's OK.
Leave him alone.
Now Mikiko, you stay out of this.
I'm going to bed.
Good night.
Good night grandpa.
Papa, here's your new toothbrush.
Good morning!
There's a typhoon coming.
You didn't sleep?
Not really.
Let's walk.
I gave everything to your brother.
He's doing well at city hall.
And his wife's behaving better.
Little Mikiko has all but grown up.
So you can do as you please.
Shigeo, see that? He's back.
Be cool about it, will ya?!
Hey Shigeo, look who we got here!!
Hey Keiko, where's my tea?
Like I said Shigeo,
your old pal Makotds back.
What's your problem?!
He'll start tomorrow.
OK?
Shigeo, is that OK?
Keiko, where's the tea?
Well, tomorrow morning then.
All right.
- Need a lift?
- No thanks, I'll walk.
Whatever, see you tomorrow.
What's with you, Shigeo?
What's with him?
He's probably happy.
Shigeo, you going drinking tonight?
I'm visiting mom, in the hospital.
So come along later.
We'll be celebrating his return.
Is it alright with you Makoto?
Don't bug him, idiot!
Makoto that's alright.
I'm not going tonight either.
OK, how about tomorrow?
Any time.
We can go drinking whenever.
So just shut that motormouth.
Why are you so angry?
Makoto!
See you.
Shigeo, let's go!
Don't go out after dark Mikiko.
But why?
You haven't heard?
A killer's stalking young women.
What do you mean?
Another body was found
this morning, by the river.
Really?
But I'll be alright.
Makoto will watch over me,
right Uncle Makoto?
Mikiko, listen to your mother!
They say
it was the new teacher in town.
You mean Takekawa's teacher.
Really?!
Good night.
Hey Makoto, see that house?
What about it?
That's where those kids live.
Mom vanished, dad died,
they're alone.
They don't go to school.
Let's get going.
Feels great!
What about the others?
They left already.
Lucky ones.
I'm always doing overtime.
Thanks anyway, but I don't drink.
Really? Not at all?
I can't handle it.
Really?
Then I'll have it.
Sawai-san,
are you going straight home?
Why?
These serial killings...
One of the victims
lived right near me.
I was wondering
if you'd walk me home?
To Shiroishi?
Did you know, there was
a shocking incident near here?
Haven't you heard?
Hear what?
That bus driver...
Was me.
You're kidding!
I can't believe it!... Really?!
But you're a hero.
That's great.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Many people died, didn't they?
I'm sorry. Please don't be angry.
No, I'm not.
Really?
Yes, really...
Well, good.
Here we are.
Alright, see you.
Aren't you going to ask?
What?
What everybody else asks...
whether I live alone?
Well...
Don't you want to come in?
No, I've got to get back.
Thanks, good night.
There's nothing for you today.
You can go home as well.
Watch out for my car!
Hey Makoto, let's go.
Shigeo...
The boss seemed strange today...
Is it something I did?
It's nothing.
Makoto!
So! I hear you've got a girlfriend.
No, I haven't.
Word is you were out with
a young woman late last night.
So this girl isn't your girlfriend?
No.
Just walking out late
with a woman not your girlfriend?
It wasn't late.
It was only 8 p.m..
You went to her place, didn't you?
Come on, speak up.
You know why I'm asking...
With these murders lately,
nobody's above suspicion.
Vicious rumors start
from the smallest things.
You vanish. And then
suddenly reappear...
that in itself is suspicious.
Get it?
Yoshiyuki, now don't pick on
poor Makoto.
Even if there's no connection...
if a rumor's circulating about you
we could be suspected as well:
me, my wife, my daughter.
It reflects badly on all of us.
We certainly don't care,
but think of Mikiko.
You're not involved?
Why don't you answer me?
Of course he's not involved.
Just like when we were kids...
you just clam up and stick it out!
Just like when mom died.
You refused to face the truth.
That's so long ago.
Enough already...
You're up early tomorrow.
Get some sleep.
Think about it.
I fixed your old bike.
It's got a few good years left.
Thanks.
Remember me?
I ran away from home.
Can I stay here with you?
You haven't had breakfast yet?
I'll make it for you.
May I have the day off?
Yeah, sure... why not.
I'll be in tomorrow.
No problem.
Hey Shigeo...
I'll come in by myself.
Dad fixed my old bike.
Yeah, sure...
Thanks.
Sorry.
Sorry... I was snoring, right'?
When summer arrives
in the hamlet,
the baby partridge chirps
with its high-pitched voice.
Good morning.
Sit down, breakfast's almost ready.
Is this it?...
It moves.
Remember me'?
Akihiko, your cousin.
We met at grandpa's funeral.
Remember?
Go ahead, dig in!
Delicious, right?!
Kokura octopus dumplings
are the best!
People think Osaka dumplings
are the best.
But the ones from Kokura
are better.
You agree? I'm glad.
Some have too much ginger.
That's a sin.
Should be just a shred.
Tonight.
Why not order some sushi?
Hello.
When they ordered for four,
I just thought they were hungry.
Yeah...
You mean... they spoke?
No, they held up four fingers.
I see.
Mr. Sawai,
please help yourself.
I had no idea you were here.
Sorry.
No I didn't mean it like that.
If it's cool with them
it's cool with me.
How long will you be staying?
Don't know.
How about you?
Hey, what's up?
What'd I say?
Sorry,
I really don”: have
anywhere else to go.
I see.
Oh, so
you're really living here now?!
I'll be leaving
when school holiday's over
in about a month.
Oh really?
He'll stay with us a month.
Good for you.
Hey, what gives?
Eat up!
Hey, Mr. Sawai, eat up!
I was a bit surprised.
I never imagined.
He seems nice enough.
The kids are enchanted by him.
He's some kind of day worker.
I'll call if there's anything
to report.
Give my best to dad.
Let's start with the easiest.
Naoki, be serious!
Wait! Where are you going?
Perfect score?!
Shigeo...
check point ahead.
Another victim?!
What's up?
Bad dreams?
Why do you ask?
Obvious, isn't it'?
Insomnia and night sweats?
See bad dreams often?
First time since I've been here.
Because I came?
No, that has nothing to do with it.
It is possible.
Could it be sub-conscious'?
Sorry.
Why do you always apologise?
Well, I...
I'm not asking for an apology.
Akihiko, how old are you?
Almost 22.
You're really mature for you age.
Well, that would be a first.
Maybe because I have
a past like yours.
What do you mean?
I'll tell you about it some day.
OK, good night then.
What now?
I just wanted to say
your presence has really helped.
I mean...
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
Sawai-san, there's something here
for you from the insurance company.
Thanks.
What do you think it is?
A second medical exam?
You OK?
I'm alright.
Put it on the desk.
Don't forget to go to the clinic.
Yes, of course.
Sorry...
The other day
I embarrassed you.
It wasn't your fault.
Want a sip?
I guess not...
The other night I had a glass
and slept through my alarm clock.
You really can't hold your liquor!
Overtime, again?
Is it true you are living
with children?
Yes.
I was orphaned as well.
Both my parents died
when I was little.
My relatives fought over me
for the insurance money.
They split it amongst themselves,
and put me in an orphanage.
I wish I had someone like you
to take care of me.
In fact, it's those kids
who are helping me.
They take care of me.
Oh, Sawai.
Sawai.
You have been called in
as a prime suspect.
Early this morning, your colleague
Ms. Kono Keiko was found dead.
Did you know?
Yes, I heard about it a moment ago.
Is that so?
Where were you
between midnight and 2 a.m.?
I was at home in bed.
Are you referring
to the Tamura residence
where you are a lodger?
Yes.
Can anyone corroborate your story?
Everybody was asleep.
Sawai-san, is something wrong?
No, I'm OK.
Are you aware of the implications
of your present position?
Moments ago I informed you
that you are as of now
our prime suspect in this case.
It follows that
everything you say can be used
as evidence in a court of law.
Do you understand?
Then we will proceed...
Please answer truthfully.
Last night at approximately 8 p.m.
you escorted Ms. Kono
to her residence.
Is this correct?
Did you enter her apartment?
What did you do there?
Nothing really.
You engaged in sexual intercourse,
didn't you?!
Nothing happened.
We drank tea.
Where did you go after you left
Ms. Kane's apartment?
I went straight home.
Do you know
where Ms. Kono went then?
No.
After she had you walk her
all of the way home,
why do you suppose
she'd go out alone after you left?
I have no idea.
Didn't you call her?
I did not call her.
Sawai-san...
Listen... this is
a murder investigation.
You do understand.
You are lying.
Concluding sexual intercourse
with Ms. Kono,
you left and then called her
or perhaps...
hid and waited for her to leave
at which time you hunted her down
and killed her by the riverside.
Isn't that the truth?!
What's the matter?
That is what happened, isn't it!'?
- I haven't killed anybody.
- But you did lie in wait for her!
No I did not.
I had no reason to kill that woman.
Let me be frank.
I believe you are the killer
and the perpetrator
of this spate of killings.
It's all just intuition
but since that incident
on the bus
I knew you would turn bad.
I knew that we would meet again
in circumstances like these.
Your eyes were just like
those of that killer.
I have done nothing.
Thanks.
I really appreciate it.
Hi.
Sorry.
You really are a loser, Sawai-san.
Our family is about ready
to kick you out, you know.
What will you do? Leave?
I told my mom
that you weren't the killer.
But they're really worried
you're after the kids' money
that they want to be spending.
I told her you aren't like that.
Thanks.
You may not realise it,
but you're quite a narcissist.
You can do whatever you want
but leave the kids out of it.
Sorry.
Boy, you're really a piece of work.
You think you can do anything
with an apology?
At least until now.
But it won't work when my family
descends on this place.
I won't be able to help.
They won't listen to me.
Did you see, Kozue?
The ocean.
Did you see it?
To.' Sawai Sex]!
From: Sawai Yumiko
Uncle Makoto, I'm sorry.
What for?
Mom and dad didn't try to help you.
Don't worry. It was expected.
Grandpa and I believe in you.
I believe in you too
and even in your parents.
Don't worry about it.
What's the matter?
Please don't cry.
You never cried as a child.
But you don't understand.
In the beginning,
I, too, suspected you, uncle.
But that's normal.
I feel so ashamed.
But it's not your fault.
It's not anybody's fault.
If anyone, it's me to blame...
for making you worry.
Please forgive me.
Now, dry your tears.
Go home to your schoolwork.
Uncle Makoto,
will you go to see Aunt Yumi?
I suppose.
I want to see her too.
Why don't you?
I'll tell her that you miss her.
She really loves you,
if“ make her happy.
NOTIFICATION OF DIVORCE
It's good to see you're OK...
Yes, you too.
Sleeping?
Some.
Still having nightmares?
From time to time.
I was surprised to hear
you'd returned.
Why'd you come back?
Homesick?
So I could start over.
But in the end,
it didn't work out.
I thought I could start over,
but things just continued.
Start over.
That's not true!
You just ran away.
Maybe you're right.
You were self-obsessed,
never thinking about me.
I'm sorry.
You left me
in that sad little town.
You're really a monster, Makoto.
I'm living with another man now.
Really?
Happy for me?
No.
I don't know.
You really are terrible.
Sorry.
Well then...
Yeah?
Take care of yourself.
You too.
Makoto?
Did you ever think about
starting over with me'?
That's why I came back.
It was too late.
Yumiko?
Do you think one can live
only for others?
Sorry. I'm talking nonsense.
I don't know...
It would be great if you could.
You. I think you could do it.
But you couldn't do it for me.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be.
Forgive me.
You really did live for me.
I know you did.
Come on. Get up.
He's crying.
Who are you?
I live here.
Kid's relation, huh?
I'm their cousin.
Makoto around?
- He's asleep.
- So wake him up.
Why?
None of your business, get to it.
Excuse me, but who exactly are you
to be giving me orders?!
Loudmouth! Tell him it's Shigeo.
Shigeo what?
You want your butt kicked?!
Then shut up and do as you're told.
What was that?
What are you on about?
Makoto, hurry up.
The boss' calling.
Are we from the same town'?
- Where's that'?
- Mo“.
So what's with the big city accent?
I grew up in Tokyo.
What's with your small-town accent?
You gonna watch your mouth.
Sorry, Akihiko.
Watch it, you little snot.
I'll kick his butt.
See'? This one raises the arm
up and down.
And this one operates the boom,
and this one's for the bucket.
Here's the safety lock.
Want to try it on your own'?
That's it.
Good. That's it.
Now move the boom.
That's right.
Now try digging-
Bring the bucket forward.
You're getting it.
Why did you miss your check-up?
I'll go in sometime.
That's a pretty nasty cough.
At least cut back on the smokes.
Yeah, I guess.
I'll put you on the steam shovel.
I just remembered.
What's that?
Remember how much we were
fascinated with bus drivers?
You could go back to driving.
It wasn't what I had expected.
In fact, all you do is follow
the same routes over and over.
Then that busjack happened.
And that was it.
That'd happen in any job.
But operating that steam shovel
kind of brought me back.
But not in the same way.
With another kind of bus.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
You don't know?
A new kind of bus, huh?
Hitoshi, we're taking off.
Naoki...
Naoki, look at me.
You smashed the graves, didn't you?
Feel better?
Go to sleep now,
don't worry.
I'm here with you.
Don't cry.
Are you in pain?
You hit your head, didn't you?
First thing in the morning,
Akihiko will fix everything.
So please don't cry.
Are you mad at Naoki?
Even after what he did?
Really?
How did you know
what he did?
I'm sorry, I won't ask...
Just please don't cry.
Hey Kozue,
let's all go away, together,
and start all over again.
OK, it's settled then.
That way,
we can always be together.
Listen,
Kozue,
first you'll have to eat
to get your strength back.
I'll go fix something for you.
You have to let me go,
if you want me to cook something.
Not yet, huh?
OK, I'll stay right here with you.
So just rest and relax.
What's that?
I bought it.
Wha... what for?
So the four of us can go on a trip.
What kind of moronic idea is that?
The kid's don't want to leave.
Stop trying to pressure them.
We've got to get out of this place.
Why?
Because we have to.
Your paranoia's got you
escaping reality.
They're better off staying put,
quietly, right here.
You want to upset them
by pure egotism?
It doesn't have an automatic door.
It's used, but if we fix it up
we can live in it.
With some beds and a table.
You want to help?
You're too much.
I didn't know
you were such a Peter Pan.
I give up.
You're impossible.
I'm outta here...
C'mon Naoki.
Kozue, let's go.
OK...
I give in...
Suit yourselves.
Let's take it out for a spin.
Wait for me!
Close the door,
it's not automatic...
Hey Shigeo, thanks a lot.
Here's the new kind of bus.
Yeah, completely different.
Hey Mr. Tokyo,
wake up and lend a hand.
Who's Tokyo?
You mean me?
Get in gear, Tokyo.
Enough small-town attitude!
You started, Tokyo.
I didn't say anything, Hicktown.
I'm from Yahata.
Well excuse me Mr. Yahata.
Sawai-san, dinner is served.
Thanks. I'll be right in.
What are you doing?
I bought a bus.
Planning another escape?
More or less.
That won't change anything.
You want to come along?
Is that supposed to be funny?
We need some time
to find ourselves.
Could you leave us alone
for a while?
Not if people
keep turning up dead.
There will be no more murders.
Sawai,
I really don't like you.
I can tell you think
my work is meaningless.
Maybe you are right.
But
I cannot admit that.
Well then, that's fine.
You'll be back, right?
I have no place to come back to.
OK, we're off.
Take care, Shigeo.
Isn't this your old bus route?
We're starting off from right here.
Take a good long look.
Oh, I should tell you...
What?
I said I'd experienced
what you had, remember?
Oh yeah!
In fact,
I came really close
to being killed once too
by a Yakuza, friend of a friend,
with a gun.
Really?!
My friend saved me
and I escaped.
When was this?
Four years ago.
High school senior year.
The Yakuza killed himself,
and my friend vanished.
I haven't seen him since.
Really?
I wonder what he's up to?
Did you ever go back there?
Of course not.
What would I do there?
That's like returning
to the crime scene.
I wasn't the criminal.
You watch too much TV.
It might be worth
revisiting some day.
Why?
But I don't want to.
I really thought I was a goner,
that he would kill me.
There were two corpses
in front of me.
I was terrified.
You know?
Weren't you afraid, yourself?
Three of us, Naoki, Kozue, and me,
we survived.
I wanted to go back
in order to start over.
Well I'm never going back.
Kozue.
Put some coffee in the curry,
it'll be good.
Hey Naoki!
Sawai-san!
Hey everybody!
Akihiko, I'm going to bed.
Good night.
Is Aomori too far?
My friend's a projectionist,
in the town hall there.
I thought about going this summer.
He knows a Native American
who can bend spoons
who healed him
with a miracle remedy.
Aomori?
D'you think our little bus
can make it?
Stop, brake!
The one the middle!
Welcome!
What're you gonna get?
Miss!
May I take your order?
Rice with hot pickles.
One green salad.
One meatball soup lunch.
Sawai-san, what about you?
I'll have the meatball soup, also.
Something wrong?
She looks just like an old friend.
Where from?
You OK?
Carsick?
Excuse me!
What is it?
My friend just threw up.
Naoki's gone.
We'll get further if we split up.
OK, I'll look over here.
Find him?
He was asleep when I got back.
Woman found murdered
Sawai-san, you look terrible.
Yeah?
- You sick or something?
- Sort of.
Wow, you're burning up!
I guess so.
Better stay in bed.
I guess I should.
You've still got that cold
from jail.
Naoki, let's go to the bath house.
Kozue, let's go clean up.
Aren't you coming, Naoki?
Are you sick, too?
That's too bad.
Water for the medicine.
You guys rest up and get well.
Don't forget your medicine.
Let's go Kozue.
What's happening?
He disappeared again.
Split up again?
No. Let's stay together.
Don't worry, I'm feeling better.
I no longer trust you.
What are you talking about?
A woman was killed
in the town we just left.
It's either you or Naoki.
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't trust you.
I know who you are.
I struggled like you.
I thought about killing.
It didn't frighten me.
Don't be foolish.
You never considered it?
Yes, I've thought about it.
I too had the urge.
How could I live if I ever gave in?
If I'm ever killing others...
it means I'm no longer who I am.
Well I resisted, too!
That's enough.
Stay here and watch over Kozue.
- No!
- Trust me, will you?!
Why can't I kill?
I didn't say that.
Let go of the knife.
Let go!
What shall I do?
Does it hurt?
Do you want me to try killing?
We could find someone
to kill together...
What do you think, Naoki?
Let's go. Let's kill someone.
What is it?
You want to kill somebody, right?
If you want to kill,
why don't we start with
the person dearest to you?
Naoki...
let's go back to the bus.
Hold on tight now.
You don't fall and hurt yourself.
We can ride in circles like this
or go back and kill Kozue.
What will it be?
Decide by our third time round.
We can keep going round here.
Naoki...
Promise me one thing.
I'm not saying that you must live,
but I am asking you
not to die.
We'll meet again.
We'll be waiting for you.
We'll come to get you.
Understand?
OK, now let's go.
POLICE STATION
What happened to your hand?
Nothing.
It was hard.
She suddenly burst out crying.
I'm no good with crying women.
I couldn't go in there.
She knows.
Without using words,
no matter how far apart,
she can communicate with him.
He'll spend the rest of his life
in jails or institutions.
It's sad,
but shouldn't we lock up
people who cross the line?
It's probably
the best thing for him.
Get out!
The best thing?!
What do you mean best for him?
It doesn't matter where he goes.
Some day he'll be back
to reclaim everything he's lost!
And when he does, people like you
will be standing in his path.
As for me, I'll stake my life
on protecting him.
Never forget that!
Come back if you change your mind.
I'll be waiting for you, too.
What's his problem?
Kozue,
can you see it?
The ocean, Kozue.
Go to the ocean.
Use your eyes,
show me the ocean.
Kozue, look, the moon...
Isn't it beautiful tonight?
It's always beautiful.
Ever been to the sea, Kozue?
After I left to wander,
I always stayed near the sea.
Sitting on the sand,
looking at the sea...
all else seems inconsequential.
What do you think?
Shall we go to the sea?
He forgot this.
I shouldn't have been so hard.
Naoki,
can you see it?
I'm looking at the ocean.
Moriyama Beauticians,
Yumiko speaking.
Daddy.
Mommy.
Busjack man.
Naoki.
Akihiko.
Look, out the window.
Daddy!
Mommy!
Busjack man!
Naoki!
Akihiko!
Mr. Sawai!
Kozue!
Let's go home!
YAKUSHO Koji
MIYAZAKI Aoi
MIYAZAKI Masaru
SAITOH Yohichiroh
KOKUSHO Sayuri
MITSUISHI Ken
RIJU Go
MATSUSHIGE Yutaka
SHIOMI Sansei
SHINGYOUJI Kimie
DEN DEN
SHIINA Eihi
NAKAMURA Yuji
ESUMI Eimei
NOMA Y Duke
ONO Machiko
INOUE Hajime
OZEKI Masayoshi
HONDA Tetsuro
Executive Producers
SHIOBARA Toru
(Dentsu)
NAGASE Fumio
(lmagica)
SENTO Takenori
(Suncent CinemaWorks)
TAKISHIMA Masayuki
(Tokyo Theaters)
Produced by
SENTO Takenori
Cinematography: TAMRA Masaki
Lighting: SATO Yuzuru
Sound: KIKUCHI Nobuyuki
Production Designer:
SHIMIZU Takeshi
Music: YAMADA lsao
& AOYAMA Shinji
Production and Distribution:
Suncent CinemaWorks
Written and Directed by
AOYAMA Shinji