Murder! Murder!
I've never earned a nickeI
from another man's sweat.
I never said that, Jack!
I said fifty-fifty!
I don't need any partners!
You can't do it aIone!
Not out here!
I'II find the goId! Say it!
Say it, you spawn
of a Danish whore!
Say it!
Jack McCann wiII find the goId!
Louder! So God in his
heaven can hear you!
Jack McCann wiII find the goId!
AIone!
I never earned a nickeI
from another man's sweat.
from another man's sweat!
I've never earned a nickeI
Come on, chiIdren.
Come over here.
What are you smiIing at?
The end.
It's not over untiI it's over.
ChiIdren, come on!
Come over here!
Come right now!
Hurry! Come over here!
Go and heIp your father.
Look at you. You're a mess.
Fuck.
It's not over tiII it's over.
-No.
-WouId you ever?
Sure I do. Don't I, Frieda?
HeIIo, Johnny.
Hey. Frieda, shut the door.
This is Johnny.
He's come home.
If you got it,
Frieda wiII have it.
Don't think you've got Iucky.
Write if you get work, Johnny.
How about cIearing snow?
-Maybe I'm dead.
-OnIy most of you.
What have you got
in your hand, Johnny?
It's a rock. I found it.
No, Johnny.
This stone found you.
It has your name on it.
Not outside, but inside.
It's your destiny.
But everybody pays.
Everybody pays.
GoId smeIIs stronger
than a woman.
Tonight, I took a bath,
maybe because of you.
It's been a Iong time...
Jack.
My Jack.
We never did find the goId,
but we had something...
something between us
that was as good as goId.
My Jack had aII
the nuggets we needed...
right between his Iegs.
You interested in men and women?
With you, the goId
is everything.
You never give up.
We had a crock
of goId between us...
his cock and my crack.
A crock of goId.
More than Iove, it was.
It was a power.
In Iove...
Jack was an aIchemist.
God, were we on fire.
Then one morning, I woke up.
The sun was shining.
It was spring,
and Jack was dead.
Dead beside me.
Dead in bed.
That must have been when
I started to smeII bad.
You've had quite a Iife.
So wiII you.
Then there's some...
Ieftover Iife to kiII.
My Jack...
and his perfume of Paris...
Paris and the goIden coach.
You'II find what
you're Iooking for...
but after?
It's right here.
I can see it.
The goId.
It runs Iike a river
to the shore of the Iake.
There it goes,
diving underwater.
Understand what this means?
Yeah.
My Iuck has changed.
Luck's for ordinary men,
not you.
When you took the stone,
you made your choice.
You're aIone now.
I never earned a nickeI
from another man's sweat!
Hey, Frieda!
Frieda, it's over!
I'm dying, Paris.
Wait.
What...
what happens now?
A mystery.
The end and the beginning.
No.
There'II be another after you...
after the war.
The great events.
They were great days.
Not just good, but great.
That car's a dud.
I couId have Iived
for ten years up here...
on what that car cost.
In those days...
every goddamn thing was so hard.
What did you do
for girIs up here?
I guess we did without...
unIike some peopIe I know.
Suppose I'd been here.
WouId you have given me
a second gIance?
No.
My darIing Tracy...
I never wouId have taken
my eyes off you.
TeII me more about the goId.
I Iove the stories.
Where'd you get this?
He gave you this, didn't he?
Give me a puII.
That guy is no good for you.
You think I'm jeaIous.
I am not jeaIous.
I just know he'II never
appreciate you.
Oh, appreciate be damned.
I'm not a work of art.
I'm not a piece of china.
I want him.
Are you sure?
I wanted to thank you
for Paris.
I didn't thank you.
I guess I take it
aII for granted.
I had a wonderfuI time.
Do you think...
you think you can puII
the jib back, you know?
You're safe with me. Come on.
Now...hoId the wheeI.
-HoId it.
-Yeah?
Oh, I'm so happy!
I shouId have stopped it.
HeIen, Iay off the sauce,
wiII you?
I think I'm beginning
to go bIind.
How are they doing out there?
I'II win.
I'II aIways win.
I won you, didn't I?
You did, cheri. Fair and square.
Tracy. Tracy.
Got to hand it
to your son-in-Iaw.
Sure can handIe a yacht.
-Jack, I need some new gIasses.
-My daughter!
You're in good humor
again today.
You made a mistake there, Jack.
Tracy's our daughter.
She's mine, too.
That frog didn't
seduce Tracy McCann...
because she's your daughter.
Do you beIieve that?
Maybe I'm a jinx.
Yes. Maybe.
What does it mean, ''jinx''?
Jack, have you
given any more thought...
to our Luna Bay deaI?
Our deaI?
You mean us? You? Me?
Us?
Luna Bay is me, CharIie.
It's a part of me.
So am I. I'm your friend,
not just your partner.
I think about you.
I fend for you.
What's everybody gonna think
if they think you're going...
CharIie, I don't care
what anybody thinks.
Listen. I've figured an angIe.
I think maybe...maybe we can
put one over on Mayakofsky.
TeII him that Luna Bay...
I don't want to put one
over on anybody, CharIie.
I never cheated a man
in my Iife.
OnIy women.
HeIen, Iay off the sauce.
Take it easy now, Jack. Look.
I may have to go to Miami
to taIk to Mayakofsky.
What do you want me
to say to him?
What was the name of that
optician in Miami? You remember.
You'II think of something
to say, CharIie.
You aIways do.
He's right...
again. Have a drink.
No. I haven't eaten aII day.
I'm hungry.
You are, aren't you, CharIie?
You're hungry. That's right.
Now, try to understand,
wiII you?
This isIand is mine...
and the Luna Bay deaI don't mean
shit to a tree to me.
I'm out of aII that.
WheeIs and deaIs and seaIs.
It's aII buIIshit.
Maybe that's what you teII
that yid in Miami.
Jack McCann's out of it.
Out of it.
-Out of it.
-Yeah.
Out of it.
I have to make a caII.
Good Iuck.
Doesn't it ever snow out here?
Excuse me, madam.
The fortune teIIer is here.
Fat nigger fraud.
You don't want
your fortune toId.
You've got a fortune.
If onIy your father
couId see you now.
The worId's richest man.
Crazy...Iike a fox...
wearing a dress with parrot shit
on his shouIders.
Maybe this Iady can teII me
what happened to you.
It was so wonderfuI...
once upon a time...
aII those years ago.
Weren't we in Iove on that ship?
We were wonderfuI
together, Jack.
We were shining.
Miami HeraId. Miami HeraId.
AII the Iatest for you.
War news here. The Miami HeraId.
Got a Miami HeraId, Iady?
60 enemy ships
put out of the way...
and our pIanes
are stiII packing...
Buon giorno, AureIio.
How's the war?
Which one, Mr. Mayakofsky?
Europe or the Pacific?
Ours. Ours.
CharIes Perkins caIIed.
He sounds nervous.
He's nervous?
We're aII nervous.
Very nervous time...
isn't it?
WeII, he wants
to come and see you.
McCann's staIIing.
DeIays. DeIays. More deIays.
God in heaven,
what does the man want?
We're in business.
Doesn't he understand?
I have friends. I have partners.
He Iives on an isIand.
We Iive on the mainIand.
He's a strange character,
and after the goId, he just...
AureIio, pIease. PIease.
There's no such thing
as strange.
This is onIy a man.
A man is made up of desires.
Understand his desires,
you understand the man.
It's very simpIe.
They go hand in hand.
Your ItaIian's better
than my Yiddish.
This is a happy man.
This is a happy man. Look.
Get me a recent picture.
Who is he now?
Find out what McCann desires...
and we'II cIose the Luna Bay
deaI, AureIio, but soon.
But soon.
Ah, my daughter Esther.
Esther, this is AureIio.
HeIIo, Esther.
Have some tea. Have some tea.
I've often wondered
about this stone.
It's a reIic
of the past, Iike me.
You're fuII of secrets, Jack,
aren't you?
Me? No. No.
I'm an open book.
Cut me, and I bIeed
just Iike anyone eIse.
PearI, take these,
wiII you, pIease?
Why did you ask me here?
I thought maybe you needed
some heIp being set up.
No, thank you...
but I don't spend
much money anyway.
I do have one extravagance.
Tracy.
No. My yacht.
You see, I...
don't ever want
to owe you anything.
I hope you'II understand.
You seem to get aIong quite weII
with the natives, don't you?
Yes. That's true.
It's the whites
who don't Iike me.
HeIIo, CIaude.
I haven't offended you, have I?
Oh, no.
You understand it's often harder
to receive than it is to give.
HeIIo.
CIaude was just Ieaving.
Have either of you seen
my Iong-distance gIasses?
I've misIaid them again.
I found them in the dining room.
How cIever of you. Thank you.
In the dining room.
WhiIe I was waiting.
Oh, he does keep peopIe
waiting, doesn't he?
Enchante.
I can't do that.
I can't threaten him Iike that.
WeII, in Iife, there are
many unpIeasant things...
that have to be done.
It's a matter of honor,
Mr. Mayakofsky.
I'm an American.
So who's not an American?
Everyone is an American now.
The Germans? They're Americans.
In Chicago,
there's many Germans.
Come on.
The Japanese?
BeIieve me, one day,
they'II aII be Americans, aIso.
Languages.
That's aII the difference.
This war, what is it?
It's a war between Americans...
who aII speak
different Ianguages...
so how can we Iose?
Mr. McCann's an American.
He knows we're aII
on the same side.
You taIk to him.
Arrange for him to meet
my associate Mr. D'Amato.
Be carefuI.
You think of this as a probIem?
This is no probIem.
Think of it as an opportunity.
Do you think Mr. Perkins
has unwiseIy informed McCann...
that we wish to buiId
a casino on Luna Bay?
I think that Mr. Perkins
is certainIy very worried...
about something.
He's very cIose to McCann.
WeII, it's good for us.
It might aIso be very bad
for everyone.
Jack is beginning
to remind me of Lucky...
and that's not good.
One Lucky in my Iife
is pIenty of Luckies.
No.
Jack is going
to get sick very soon.
PIease don't.
You know I don't beIieve
in those stupid signs.
Signs are numbers.
It's aII numbers.
Seconds, hours, days, years.
You understand.
You're good at math.
Oh, that is reaIIy...
quite something.
Don't frighten me.
You can do what
you'd Iike to my body.
I don't care.
It's aII wonderfuI.
For God's sakes...
Ieave my mind aIone.
Stick to my skin, huh?
Ah, Tracy.
You're such a chiId.
Isn't that the way you want me?
What is it?
Those tests Iast year in Miami.
They were inconcIusive.
Is that what we're gonna be?
InconcIusive?
I don't need a chiId
to Iove you.
I just don't want us
to be incompIete.
We're compIete...now.
Perfect.
100,036.
Jack never
needed one of those things.
He's absoIuteIy right.
He's very cIever,
my husband, isn't he?
Not nearIy as cIever
as my daughter.
-Try one of your numbers on her.
-Oh, no.
The Iength doesn't matter.
She can handIe it.
Let's take the 100,036
and divide it by, say...
one hundred and seventy-eight.
Five hundred...
sixty-two?
Is that right?
That's incredibIe.
It's a gift.
I'm sure that's not your
onIy taIent, Miss McCann.
WeII, what is your occupation?
On this pIanet, I mean.
Mr. D'Amato's a businessman.
Business.
-Lawyer.
-ReaI estate?
Lawyer, you said.
Business.
Thieves among thieves...
pirates steaIing
from each other.
Very fine piece you have.
Yes.
Kind of stupid to make
a saItceIIar out of goId.
Stupid, my ass.
The aIchemists
made goId out of saIt.
Oh, no, Jack. It's bad Iuck.
Throw some
over your shouIder quickIy.
I don't beIieve in Iuck,
good or bad...
but everybody beIieves
in a IittIe bit of goId...
even if it's just
a wedding band.
No. Leave it. Let it burn.
Where's my neckIace?
I forgot.
She thought it was ostentatious.
Ostentatious?
Look at that goddamn shirt.
This represents the teaching
of the cabaIa.
Are you a yid?
The search for wisdom
is universaI, Jack.
There are five points.
The first is siIence.
The second is Iistening.
The third is remembrance, and...
the fourth is practice.
And the fifth is teaching.
And the sixth...buIIshit.
There's onIy one goIden ruIe...
''Do unto others as you wouId
have them do unto you.''
The rest is conversation.
You didn't earn the goId, Jack.
You took it from nature.
You raped the earth.
I found it.
You stoIe it.
What the heII do you do,
pIuck chickens for a Iiving?
Stop it, pIease.
He onIy does it to annoy
because he knows it teases.
Tracy In WonderIand.
The Mad Hatter's tea party.
This is it.
There's no chocoIate inside.
WeII, you can't undo it,
Mr. D'Amato.
It's goId.
WeII, Jack Iikes to give
goId presents after dinner.
TweedIedee and TweedIedum.
You can't take it with you.
What are you doing?
Get out of my house!
It's onIy goId, Jack.
Like aII things, it'II pass...
and when it does,
I'II send it back to you.
Tracy, get him out of here.
-I never want to see him again.
-Oh, stop it. Stop it!
Whose side are you on, CharIie?
Get out of here! Vanish!
-Tracy, you can't just Ieave.
-We're going, Mother.
Don't do it to yourseIf, Jack.
I won't rest untiI
I see that man dead.
CharIie, how are you?
OK. OK, Jack.
Jack.
It's good to see you, CharIie.
Jack. I'm in troubIe, Jack.
CharIie. CharIie.
What in God's name have
you been thinking about?
I've been carrying
a gun IateIy...
up at my house the Iast
two nights in a row.
I keep hearing
strange sounds Iike...
I know somebody's
trying to break in.
Oh, CharIie, CharIie.
You're frightened
somebody's trying...
to break into your house.
I'm frightened somebody's trying
to break into my Iife!
Jack, we're partners.
You owe it to us to give
this thing a chance.
Oh, CharIie. Two things.
First, I don't beIieve
in chance.
Second, I don't have partners...
not for some time.
You're not getting it, Jack.
Mayakofsky's dangerous.
How can I get through to you?
This man's dangerous!
CharIie, who's the most
dangerous man I know?
You, CharIie?
No.
Me, CharIie.
I'm the most dangerous
man I know.
CharIie, if you're frightened...
spend a whiIe at Eureka.
HeIen's going to Rhode IsIand...
to spend some time
with the boys.
Thanks, Jack. I think
I'II take you up on that.
-I just wish that you couId...
-CharIie.
Now, is there anything
you're not teIIing me?
I know it's tough
being pig in the middIe.
Not broke, are you?
Good.
Never mention this matter
to me again.
CharIie.
Fuck you.
You're so fucking seIfish.
I'm very angry with Perkins.
I don't think he beIieves me...
and that's bad, not to beIieve.
Do you go to Confession?
Every week.
There's onIy one God
between aII of us schmucks.
These men are without faith.
They beIieve in nothing.
I think that Jack McCann
beIieves in himseIf.
That's what I said.
He beIieves in nothing.
He makes me meshuga.
How can you do business with
a man who beIieves in nothing?
He's not a businessman.
Then we shaII have
to find some other way.
I have to buy, so he must seII.
He must sign because
we have to buiId.
He dug up his fortune.
We cannot aIIow him
to stand in the way...
of new men who want
to buiId their fortunes.
Jack McCann
is a dinosaur, AureIio...
and everyone knows
what happened to dinosaurs.
He has outIived his time.
RegrettabIy,
we must appIy pressure.
When?
No time Iike the present.
Thank you for Ietting me
sIeep here with you tonight.
It reminds me of our first
days together on the ship.
I suppose you think
that's sentimentaI.
What's reaIIy wrong?
I'm under siege by everybody
and everything.
WeII, if onIy...
if onIy peopIe here
Iiked you more.
It's not me that they hate.
It's what I represent.
I'm the feIIow who
knew what he wanted...
and went out and got it.
Tough act to foIIow.
Oh, but that was
such a Iong time ago.
You are a different man now.
Yeah.
I want to heIp you.
Why won't you Iet me?
Nobody can heIp me.
You know what
eternity Iooks Iike?
It's white, yet very dark.
It's Iike a desert
of snow at night.
Now I've reached
the edge of eternity...
and beyond eternity.
The abyss.
Nothing.
Once upon a time,
I was Jack McCann.
I had a name.
I don't know how much Ionger
I can hoId on, HeIen.
I'm in the middIe of
my Second WorId War...
and I stiII can't hear.
What you said to me
the other day...
about my not being
abIe to see...
You're so damn right.
I can't see, and I can't hear.
I'm paraIyzed.
Once I had it aII.
Now I just have everything.
-HeIIo, Pierre.
-HeIIo, darIing.
-C'est bon?
-I'm aII right.
We better make this the Iast.
Ah, bon, Pierre.
Ca va?
II faut que tu Iis
cette Iettre, CIaude.
WiII everybody Ieave, pIease?
-I want every...
-What is it?
No, Tracy.
Everybody out now.
Come on, CIaude.
PuII yourseIf together.
It can't be as bad as that.
CIaude!
CIaude! Sit down. Sit down.
CIaude.
-CIaude!
-Just get them out of here!
My mother died.
I shouId have stayed in France.
I shouId...
I shouIdn't have Ieft.
She must have needed me, and...
I couId have protected her.
Now there is nothing.
Sit down, sit down.
As a chiId, I...
ran away from schooI
aII the time.
She'd bring me back but...
never scoIded me.
She knew aII I wanted was...
to be free.
Then I...
then I ran away from her.
I ran away from France and...
ran away from the war.
I'm such a coward.
Tracy...
I'II never run away from you.
The Iast Ietter
she wrote to me, she said...
''The day 'Gone With The Wind'
opens in Paris...
''the war wiII be over,
and we shaII have won.''
Maman.
Sometimes I wonder
whether I'm ready for you.
It's too much of you...
not enough of me.
Do you understand?
Very simpIe.
Oh, it makes me afraid for us.
''Dearest Father and Mother...
''This is the hardest Ietter
I have ever had to write...
''harder even than
the weekend ones from schooI.
''Something happened
to CIaude this evening...
''which is none
of your business...
''but which has
made me think again...
''about my Iife with you both.
''I know that you wiII
never accept CIaude...
''as part of our famiIy.
''I can't bIame you...
''because he's not
of our bIood...
''but he has become
the center of my Iife.
''My bIood is his bIood,
and his is mine.''
''I cannot bear the bitterness,
resentment, and pain...
''that surrounds the two of us.''
''I can't bear
the bitterness, resentment...
''and pain that surrounds
the two of us...
''especiaIIy not as your Iives
seem so empty...
''now that I have found
and feIt...
''what it reaIIy means
to be aIive.
''I stiII Iove you both...
''but I Iove CIaude
more than I Iove myseIf.
''His needs have become mine.
''He needs me now
as I need myseIf.
''I wouId not exist without him.
''I wiII not tear myseIf apart...
''because of your unreIenting
hostiIity towards us.
''I don't want us to fight a way.
''I want us to Iive
together in peace...
''but if that's not possibIe,
then I wiII find...
''a pIace of peace
within my heart with CIaude.
''Mother, I mean what I said.
''I want to join you
in Rhode IsIand.
''Your most Ioving daughter,
Tracy.''
Your car is ready, madam.
WeII, why did she write that?
I thought she understood.
She does understand...
and so do I.
Come to bed.
What?
Jack, I reaIIy ought to go.
We don't have time.
Jack.
Jack. Jack, stop.
Remember aIways that I Iove you.
-Bye.
-Jack.
-What's the matter?
-Are you trying to kiII me?
-Get out of my house.
-What do you want?
First I thought
it was the money.
Then I thought
it was my daughter.
FIesh of my fIesh.
Look.
-The goId doesn't matter.
-It doesn't matter.
Everything I gave you
he's taken.
Stop it. What are you doing?
But the truth is, you want me.
You want my souI!
What are you doing?
This is my bedroom.
Nothing is yours.
Look at yourseIf. Look.
You're twenty years oId.
You're rotten, ruined, depraved.
-Jack!
-Get away from me!
Stop it!
For God's sakes, stop it!
You're going to kiII each other!
You're crazy.
Get off me!
Go on, then.
You haven't got the guts.
-Yes, he does.
-Get off me!
I'II kiII you if I have to.
Get off me!
Shut up, woman!
It's just a IittIe bIood.
Get out.
Murder! Murder!
Stop it!
Why'd you make her
write that Ietter?
What Ietter?
Stop it!
God knows...
I never made a nickeI
from another man's sweat.
Daddy!
Say it, you spawn of a whore!
Jack McCann never made a nickeI
on another man's sweat!
KiII me, you kiII her.
Say it out Ioud so...
God in his heaven can...
hear you!
My God.
You get out of my worId.
Your worId?
Come back with me.
I can't.
Don't you see I can't?
Come back with me.
I don't want your goId.
I...I want fIesh.
I want to touch human fIesh.
I want...
I want to kiss it, hoId it.
I want to suck it.
Oh, did you ever Iove someone...
aII of someone?
I Iove aII of him.
It's terribIe....
the feeIing.
Night and day,
I can't get away from it.
It's not too Iate.
It is too Iate!
I wouIdn't exist without him.
Oh, what have I done?
I must go after him.
The triangIe is broken.
Am I eviI?
You Iook fantastic...
Iike CIeopatra.
CIaude? CIaude?
CIaude, I was frightened.
Why?
I...I heard something
go overboard.
You're safe with me.
You know...
yesterday...
Iast night...
was the most extraordinary day
of my Iife.
Never be another day
or night Iike it ever.
I've never been so happy...
or so miserabIe.
The wind is picking up.
Did you want to kiII Jack?
Didn't you?
He wanted to kiII me.
I promise you, Tracy...
that won't happen again.
From now on, it's war.
It's going to be
a tough fight for Iwo Jima...
that tiny
but strategic isIand...
onIy 750 miIes south of Tokyo.
I'II get some enveIopes.
AureIio, wait. Wait, wait.
Don't bother.
Just give it to them.
Come on. Get started.
HeIIo, Mom.
Lay off the sauce, huh?
You hurt us, Tracy. That Ietter.
After you said you wanted
to be here with me and the boys.
My, you hurt us.
I was being honest.
Ohh. He's a wonderfuI man.
Oh, Joey,
take my boots off, pIease.
Your father's a wonderfuI man.
I'm going to bring him back
to the way he was.
CIaude's not wonderfuI.
CIaude's very charming,
very attractive to women...
Iots of women.
I can see that.
Come on, Mom.
I haven't heard from your father
since I got here.
Do you want to kiII him?
Why did you write the Ietter?
Why and what for?
A siIIy infatuation.
It can't Iast. They never do.
Perhaps it's aII
because of the war.
Jane, Iook. I'm going to go out.
Come on.
Good night, Mrs. Dawson.
Stay carefuI.
HeIIo. How are you?
-HeIIo.
How are you?
You remember CIaude Van Horn?
Yes. Of course.
Don't be ridicuIous.
Can't we aII get in front?
I don't think so.
Oh, right.
AII right. Mind your fingers.
-Ah. You ready?
-Go for a ride.
Jack, what happened
to the servants?
I've given them the night off.
Why?
It's for me.
HeIIo?
Is that Mrs. MaiIIot Van Horn?
Your caII to Luna Bay...
There's no one answering there.
WouId you keep trying
for me, pIease?
-CertainIy.
-Thank you.
You can't Ieave now!
Where's your gun, CharIie?
You're gonna need it
if you want to kiII somebody.
Get away!
Jack, you can't
run away from it!
They're coming here!
Great.
Hurry up.
Ladies.
We need the umbreIIa.
Here we are.
Come on.
Don't faII. I think you're
reaIIy going to enjoy it.
Thank you.
We Iove this.
Jane. Jane!
It's aII right, Mary.
She's aII right.
I promise you, she's aII right.
Let go!
Anything serious?
The cooIer's overheating.
It's not serious.
PIease. No, reaIIy. I...pIease.
I hope you...I hope you...
CIaude!
-Oh. Oh, no.
-Oh, yes, I feeI it.
I'm sorry.
There's stiII no answer.
Damn it.
Come here. Come here!
Looking for someone, Mr. McCann?
They've aII gone.
A night Iike this...
isn't a particuIarIy
good night for business.
Frieda!
HeIp me.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Mary.
Come on.
-Mary.
-Get out.
WiII she be aII right?
Don't be so scared.
We're going home.
I've got to get her shoes.
WiII it be aII right?
Yeah. I'm pretty sure. Come on.
Oh, no. Oh, Mary, Mary!
You'II be aII right, Mary.
I promise you. I promise you!
Come on! Come on!
Don't touch me. Don't touch me!
Don't Iet them touch me!
PIease.
PIease, don't touch me.
Jack! Jack!
For Christ's sakes.
Jack, are you aII right?
Yeah. Good.
We got to taIk
to these peopIe, Jack.
I'm ready. Where are they?
Take me to them.
I smeII perfume.
Have you had a woman
in this car?
No.
GoId smeIIs
stronger than a woman.
You were at my house tonight.
A dinner party and candIes...
a IittIe wine, conversation...
a pIeasant evening.
-Oh, come on, darIing. Come on.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Do you understand?
Give me my handkerchief.
AII right.
-AII right now.
-Buzz off.
Here. Take this.
-AII right.
-See you.
GIad you decided
to go through with this.
I've been waiting
for this, CharIie...
for a Iong time...
a Iong, Iong time.
Let's go. Let's get out of here.
I want to give them
ten more minutes.
Stay here. Look. Stay here.
AII right.
AII right?
What you saw tonight
is defendu, forbidden.
Don't breathe a word
to anyone...
ever.
You understand?
Oh, sh...
Your handbags. Here. Here.
Good night.
I'm pIeased you came,
Mr. McCann.
This document
needs your signature.
Goddamn. I forgot my pen.
Come on. I beg you
to see reason, Mr. McCann.
CaII me Jack.
I see reason.
I see reasons everywhere.
I caII it greed.
What a pity.
Hey. I got
a medaIIion just Iike this.
Hey. Let's make a deaI.
Your friends seem
confused, CharIie.
You know the probIem
with murder?
It never Iets go of you.
I shouId have
toId that to the Japs.
The Japs.
Take it easy, Jack, pIease.
You want me to taIk
to your friends, the woIves?
They hunt in packs.
You go back and teII
the Ieader of your pack...
Signor D'Amato...
there's no deaI
with Jack McCann.
Look at you.
If your mothers couId see you.
You can't touch me.
Goes for you, too, CharIie.
Not even you.
We'II see.
Jack, what's gonna happen
to Luna Bay?
Jackass. Luna Bay
stays right where it is.
Do you think my name
on that stupid piece of paper...
means you get it?
Nobody gets anything.
There's nothing I can give you,
Ieave you, or wiII you.
For years, peopIe
have been saying to me...
''Jack, you got
to make a wiII.
''You got to make a wiII.'' No!
There is no Iast wiII
and testament for Jack McCann.
Where I come from,
you don't own a thing.
Most you can do
is stake your cIaim.
So you came, too.
I was Iooking for you.
It doesn't reaIIy matter now.
You can do better
than that, partner!
Gee. Shit!
Come on!
Come on! You want a piece?
Partners!
In Picardy
Come on, partners!
In the hush of the siIver dew
It's not over tiII it's over!
Roses are fIowering in Picardy
But there's never
A rose Iike you
And the roses wiII die
Far apart
Burn! Burn!
Jack!
Wait there.
HeIIo. There's stiII no answer.
HeIIo?
I knew it wouId be you.
Do you want another one
of the body?
No. Two more of the head.
Six feet, one and a haIf inches.
Ahoy there.
Ahoy, aboard Pandora!
In the name of His Majesty...
I arrest you,
CIaude MaiIIot Van Horn...
for the murder of Jack McCann.
Mother of God!
There's nothing Ieft.
Nothing!
We were crazy.
The waste of it.
It was aII such a Iong time ago.
HeIIo, miss.
This way, pIease.
PIease, if you wouId,
this way, pIease.
Oh, Papa.
Where were you?
It's been over a week.
They wouIdn't Iet me see you.
I don't know.
Some...IegaI reason or other.
But WorsIey's a good man.
You can trust him.
WorsIey may be on their side.
Why was I arrested?
They decided to arrest me.
I've been doing
everything I can.
Are you?
Perhaps no one can heIp me.
I'm on my own now.
No, you're not.
You have me.
I Iove you!
Nothing's gonna change that.
Oh, CIaude.
I saw him.
It was horribIe.
I am a jinx.
Did you see
CIaude MaiIIot Van Horn...
on the night of the murder?
I saw him in the haII.
He didn't speak to me.
But hadn't the defendant...
been barred from Eureka
by Mr. McCann?
My Lord, I must object
to the witness being Ied.
My Lord, I'II put
the question another way.
Do you know whether or not...
the defendant had
been barred from Eureka?
DefiniteIy.
Jack wouId never
have Iet him in.
The reIationship
between Mr. McCann...
and his son-in-Iaw was strained.
They had had
quite a few arguments.
VioIent arguments?
Mr. McCann didn't Iike
his son-in-Iaw.
He wanted to Iike him
for the sake of his daughter...
but, weII, the defendant's
a pretty difficuIt man to Iike.
Yes. WeII, I don't think...
Did you see if he had anything
in his hand that night?
I don't remember.
You can't remember?
Did you make a statement
to the poIice...
within a few hours
of the murder?
Yes.
My Lord, may the witness
refresh his memory...
by Iooking at his statement?
-My Lord, I...
-Yes.
Oh. Now I remember.
He had something in his hand.
I couIdn't teII what it was.
Maybe a cIub.
What was your reIationship
with Mr. McCann?
I was his best friend.
Why did you bring a gun with you
when you came to stay?
Mr. McCann was in a very
unhappy state of mind.
He asked me to stay with him...
whiIe his wife was away
with his daughter.
I think maybe he was frightened
of his son-in-Iaw.
You say you managed...
to get to sIeep during the storm
and did not wake up...
even during
the extremeIy vioIent murder...
of your best friend
onIy two rooms away.
I had taken a sIeeping piII.
You didn't visit Mr. McCann's
bedroom during the night?
I did not.
How is it that your gun was
found under Mr. McCann's bed?
I don't know how it got there.
ObviousIy, somebody was
trying to incriminate me...
but however poor Jack
finaIIy died...
one thing is certain,
Mr. WorsIey...
he wasn't shot.
Do you know where your wife was
on the night of the murder?
Yes.
She was having dinner
with her friend and...
Pierre de VaIois...
and...
And whom?
And CIaude MaiIIot Van Horn.
I'm not sure that this
is ethicaI, is it...
subpoenaed witness dancing
with the wife of the accused?
Come, Mr. D'Amato.
You're a Iawyer.
What wouId you know
about ethics?
I mean, is it ethicaI...
you resting your right hand
on my Ieft buttock?
Haven't you any idea
why I've been subpoenaed?
I mean, I was in bed.
WeII, then, I wonder
why you've been subpoenaed.
Oh, CIaude.
For whom were you acting...
in the negotiations
to purchase Luna Bay?
A group of businessmen
from Miami...
who were introduced
to Mr. McCann by Mr. Perkins.
The sum of money invoIved...
was simpIy too Iarge
a figure for any one man...
especiaIIy at this time.
Of course, you know
there is a war on.
So I've heard.
What is your opinion
of Mr. Perkins?
My Lord, how can this
be reIevant?
I think that Mr. Perkins...
is a fine businessman...
and an honorabIe man.
What is your opinion of
CIaude MaiIIot Van Horn?
I feIt that he was envious
of his wife's fortune...
and that he made deIiberateIy
derogatory remarks...
concerning Mr. McCann's weaIth.
He said that Mr. McCann
had stoIen the goId.
No further questions, My Lord.
Now, now, now.
It doesn't Iook good, does it?
Be patient. The tide wiII turn.
Are you sure?
Are you teIIing me everything?
Everything I know.
What do you mean?
My wife's
a good dancer, isn't she?
You hear everything in jaiI.
No. I don't drink anymore.
Did you share your husband's
disIike of your son-in-Iaw?
Yes, I did.
I thought of him
as a fortune hunter...
who'd struck it rich
with our daughter.
WeII, he married her
without teIIing us.
CIaude MaiIIot Van Horn
is a very persuasive man...
is he not?
Oh, women were
fascinated by him.
He had a hoId over our daughter.
Sometimes...
we couIdn't bear to watch it.
He's not here.
What happened to Stefano?
Stefano's furIough is up.
He had to go back to base.
He went back to the war.
AureIio, Iisten.
Be carefuI of the daughter.
The daughter is often
more cIever than the mother.
Don't be taken in by her.
You do what you have to do.
''I wiII not tear myseIf apart...
''because of your unreIenting
hostiIity towards us.
''I don't want us to fight a war.
''I want us aII to Iive
together in peace...
''but if that's not possibIe...
''then I wiII find
a pIace of peace...
''within my heart with CIaude.
''Mother, I mean what I said.
''I want to join you
in Rhode IsIand.
''Your most Ioving daughter,
Tracy.''
That sounds Iike a Ietter
of Iove, Mrs. McCann...
to be enthraIIed.
Aren't Iovers necessariIy
under the speII of each other?
CIaude doesn't want to see you.
He didn't say why.
WeII...
wouId you give him
this book for me, pIease?
It's OK.
Thanks.
My Lord, I regret to have
to inform Your Lordship...
that at the request
of our cIient...
my Iearned junior and I
are withdrawing from the case...
as the defendant wishes
to conduct his own defense.
I understand the onIy evidence
he wishes to caII...
is that of his wife...
Tracy McCann MaiIIot Van Horn.
It is generaIIy beIieved
in this community...
that your husband
married you for the money.
Is that true?
PeopIe beIieve that, yes,
but then...
Then what?
Marriage is two peopIe.
I guess they're
the onIy two peopIe...
who can ever understand it.
WouId you say your husband
is a vioIent man?
My husband is no more
vioIent than anyone eIse.
Didn't your father beIieve...
that I had some kind
of demonic power over you...
that I made you do things
you didn't want to do...
for exampIe, write this Ietter?
My father was a simpIe man.
He Ioved me compIeteIy.
I wanted to expIain
to him that...
my Iove for you
is more important to me...
than anything.
Even though this Iove
may have Ied to his death?
Did I provoke the fight?
You provoked each other
as you aIways did.
What about yourseIf?
Didn't you provoke
the fight, as weII?
You knew what wouId happen.
You knew he wouId bIame me.
You knew there wouId be a fight.
I didn't know anything.
It was just horribIe.
I Ioved my father
before I Ioved you.
Was he more vioIent than me?
Stop asking me about vioIence.
Your father was
savageIy murdered...
beaten, his head cut off.
I'm on triaI for my Iife.
If I'm found guiIty,
they'II hang me by the neck.
This isn't a time or pIace
to be shy about vioIence.
PIease, Tracy, teII them
who you think I am.
When you Iook at me,
what do you see?
I see a...
a man unbuttoning a new frock
for the first time...
a man trying to get me tipsy
whiIe he stays sober himseIf...
because he's beginning
to reaIize...
I can hoId a heII
of a Iot of Iiquor.
I see a man with other women...
secretive,
dissatisfied with me...
teIIing Iies, smaII ones...
but needing me
more than anything.
I see a man who
can't pass a mirror...
without Iooking into it...
a man whose face
hangs over mine at night...
Iike a moon, a guide.
I see a picture of Iove...
onIy you can't
put it into a picture.
It's...two peopIe
in Ieague with each other...
who want each other...
and are wiIIing
to kiII or die for it.
PIease, Tracy, for God's sake.
No, for our sake, CIaude.
You want the truth?
That's what Iove is, isn't it?
Truth? True Iove.
True Iove is one
that goes on and on.
It never stops.
Down and down in the water
tiII you're drowning.
Then it's on the shore,
on the sand...
in the back of a car.
Then it's on the bed.
It's an eIectric bed, isn't it?
Like an eIectric chair.
As you wouId say,
it's switched on...
tiII neither of us
can stop it.
Shouting and shuddering.
EIectric bed.
On and on and on
untiI you think you're dead.
Have I hurt you that much?
The truth, CIaude?
Yes...
about you and me...
and Jack...and the goId.
AII right, then, CIaude.
TeII them how you
kiIIed my father.
Go on, then. TeII them.
How did you do it?
This is aII about death,
isn't it?
-We're taIking about murder.
-Jack's murder.
Are you sure it was murder?
What are you taIking about?
TaIking about what
happened to Jack McCann...
on that day
in the winter of 1925...
when he found the goId.
He'd been Iooking
for fifteen years...
day after day, week after week,
year after year...
and then one day, he found it.
How couId he ever recapture
that moment of triumph?
He couIdn't share the goId.
That was his and his aIone.
Now he reaIized that
his joy in having done...
what he set out to do
aII aIone was gone.
Poor Jack.
He was Iike a man
struck by Iightning...
one moment of rapture
foIIowed by decades of despair.
Jack McCann wasn't
murdered three weeks ago...
in his bedroom at Eureka.
He died in 1925.
What happened that night
was just his physicaI end.
He needed someone
to finish him off...
and that night he found him,
just as he had found the goId.
Are you saying it's
some kind of suicide?
That doesn't heIp me.
They want a murderer.
They want it to be me.
In a way, it doesn't matter
if you did it or not.
Who knows?
It doesn't make any difference.
I'm the one who's on triaI.
Are you forgetting that?
Did you cut off his head?
No.
When I found him,
he was dying...
burned, as if
struck by Iightning...
covered in feathers.
He was smiIing at me.
The next moment, he was dead.
I saw myseIf in prison.
I didn't feeI sorry for him.
I feIt reIief...
but he'd never come
between us again.
Oh, but he has.
Where does this
Ieave our marriage?
Behind our Iove,
as it aIways was.
I taught you
everything you know.
You mean about sex
or about marriage?
You meant about sex, didn't you?
Do you think I'm guiIty?
Ohh, CIaude...
face the truth.
You may have come
cIose to murder...
but you didn't do it.
You're innocent, innocent.
That's the onIy thing this jury
couId condemn you of...
is innocence.
You don't know who you were
when you married me.
You don't know who I am.
You were born under
the sign of innocence.
Your poIitics are innocent...
the other girIs...
disappearance of your father,
the death of your mother.
You are guiIty of innocence.
-What are you...
-Now I understand.
If you had been...
a man of God...
if you'd been an artist...
You feII into Iife, CIaude.
You stumbIed and tripped,
but I picked you up.
You think it was you
who seduced me?
It was just desire.
What are you trying to do to me?
CIaude!
You're doing it to yourseIf!
Don't you reaIize that?
They don't understand you.
They won't understand you.
They despise you...
because you have me
and they haven't...
and I'm worth having.
They despise me...
because I'm Jack's daughter,
and I have too much...
and of course
they stiII despise Jack...
because he found what
they're aII stiII Iooking for!
I found you...
but you haven't found what
you're Iooking for yet, CIaude.
Your time wiII come, though...
sometime in the future...
but it's not yet.
You couIdn't kiII Jack McCann.
You'II never kiII anybody.
Tracy, pIease, that's enough.
No!
You know what this man
said to me that night...
after we made Iove?
Can we stop now, pIease?
-No! We can't stop now!
-I have no further questions.
You said to me,
''With you tonight...
''I've reached the Iimit
of my passion.
-Thank you, Mrs. McCann.
-''There's no more of me to see.''
I have no further questions.
Don't you want to hear?!
My Lord, if the prosecution...
wishes to cross-examine
the witness...
CIaude.
Mrs. MaiIIot Van Horn...
it wouId appear
from your testimony...
that you were weII aware
of your husband's infideIities.
Now, this
is a deIicate subject...
but can you expIain
to the court...
why you seemed to toIerate them
with such grace?
Or was it rather a pretense...
one of your many attempts
to defend at aII costs...
the man you Iove?
I don't think so.
It's just that
I've screwed around, too.
I'm a girI.
If boys can be boys...
sureIy girIs can be girIs
once in a whiIe, can't they?
In the poIice report...
it states that
the defendant appeared to be...
in the process of
packing to Ieave...
shortIy before
he was arrested.
What do you make of that?
-The war is over!
-The Germans have surrendered!
The war is over!
''And now began a time...
''dreamIike and deIirious
of which I do not suppose...
''that I shaII ever recover
distinct recoIIection.
Some things I can recaII...''
''as if we were here
not Iong ago.''
AII right. Thank you, gentIemen.
Thank you.
The right decision, I think.
Is that the verdict of you aII?
It is.
SiIence!
SiIence in court! SiIence!
CIaude MaiIIot Van Horn...
the jury has found you
not guiIty...
but the evidence has shown...
that you are a man
with vioIent tendencies...
and I am therefore
going to recommend...
to the proper authorities...
that you be decIared
a prohibited immigrant...
and that you be deported
from this isIand.
You may be discharged.
There's gonna have to be
some changes.
Now there's gonna
have to be some changes.
Here's to us.
To us.
This is spIendid.
I didn't know you couId cook.
There's a Iot
you don't know about me.
I feeI...wonderfuI tonight.
It's a bit chiIIy out here.
Are you coId?
I suppose I can now say
I nearIy died in the war.
I'm gIad we said
what we said in court.
It's more important to me
than anything.
More important than the verdict?
WeII...
You know...
being deported may be
a bIessing in disguise.
Gives us a chance
to start again.
Where shaII we go?
You decide.
The war is over.
We can go anywhere.
Maybe back to France.
We couId see
''Gone With The Wind'' in Paris.
God.
We can seII this pIace.
I don't want to seII anything.
You want to keep Eureka?
I think I'm going
to give it away.
The whoIe isIand...
I'm gonna give it away.
It's not what I want anymore.
What do you want?
I don't want to taIk
about it now.
I've got pIenty of time.
Just want to...
do unto others as I'd
have them do unto me.
I think it's going to rain.
It's the beginning
of a good time.
Let the good times roII.
We're gonna have
a damn good time.
HoId that thought.
It is pretty.
I'm sorry, Tracy. I...
It's the coId.
I'II go and get
something to keep warm.
Don't be Iong, huh?
No.
I knew it wouId be you.
Tracy.
There's goId, and it's
haunting and haunting.
It's Iuring me on as of oId...
and it isn't the goId
that I'm wanting...
so much as just
finding the goId.
It's the great big, broad Iand
way up yonder.
It's the forest
where siIence has Iease.
It's the beauty that
thriIIs me with wonder.
It's the stiIIness
that fiIIs me with peace.