Subtitles provided by MBC
This program is made possible in part
by the Ministry of Culture...
and the Korea Creative Content Agency.
Look at me. Your name?
Jung, Sire.
Jung.
Well, well.
And you made this?
Yes, Sire.
I get regular kiln reports, of course.
But this...
Father.
Father!
Artisans Yi Kangchon and Yu Euldam,
hear and obey.
His Majesty will select
the master artisan of Punwon Kiln.
We hear and obey.
A contest? And Artisan Yi?
What about him?
It's all right.
Royal ceramics are beyond a man
like Yu Euldam.
That's just perfect.
What is our nation's
most precious commodity?
Royal white porcelain.
And Punwon
is the finest of the royal kilns.
We must control those funds.
The master artisan must be our man.
Understood?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Go see Artisan Yi.
Artisan Yi.
Hurts the pride, doesn't it?
Who is Euldam?
A potter, a plodder, a nothing.
I will run the Punwon Kiln.
I'll sponge away today's humiliation.
I will do the Royal House honor.
No doubt.
But...
...suppose you don't...
You don't believe in me?
I do. But I'm not His Majesty.
Hello.
It's just you?
Did our artisans get the news?
Actually, sir...
I expect your finest work.
For me.
They're with Artisan Yi.
Then we should hurry.
Why haven't they started
stomping the clay?
Well...
Go on.
They took the Mt. Bong clay
you set aside.
Did they?
But it isn't resistant to heat.
He doesn't like it.
It's clear he intends to hurt you
with this contest.
All we have left is clay from Sonchon?
Yes, sir.
Good enough.
It's time I experimented
with Sonchon clay anyway.
But sir!
Maybe any other time.
But when the master artisan chair
is at stake?
I have you, Yonok.
You worked with Yi.
You know how he uses Sonchon clay.
This is your chance to shine.
My lord.
Let's get started.
Yes, sir.
A blessing on you. And on you.
Oh, and you. A huge blessing on you.
And you!
Your work always has such rustic charm.
Oh?
No one can match
the delicate purity of yours.
Feeling confident?
You seem quite sure of yourself.
I had a dream.
She seemed like she was my daughter.
And for her to present
her porcelain to the King?
We all have dreams.
With age, you get farther from that
especially since you are unmarried.
This way.
So white, the cherry blossoms
are so delicate.
I've been seated
on the royal throne numerous times.
Such form, such color...
But it's been years since
I've seen anything like it.
This is your work?
I had that honor.
Well?
Yes, Sire.
A work worthy of your noble forefathers.
Have Artisan Yi craft the royal porcelain.
Yes, Sire.
What have we here?
A colorful finger bowl?
Your Majesty, if I may?
Please.
It may not look like much at first.
But over time it has a peaceful effect.
Not much is right.
But oddly enough...
...its lack of artifice does my heart good.
Artisan Yu.
Sire.
You will craft the royal tea services.
You honor me, Sire.
Sire, if Artisan Yi crafts the porcelain
and Yu the tea services...
...who has won today?
There can be only one master artisan.
I'll have to choose.
Sire, with a tea service,
utility far outweighs cosmetics.
Perhaps a sip or two?
Perhaps you will do the honors?
Yes, Sire.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
Treason! Poison!
Guards! Where are my guards!
Guards!
Protect His Majesty!
Sire.
Is this your glaze?
Definitely.
The poison didn't come
from the kitchens or the eunuchs.
The problem lies in your glaze
on your cup.
Confess.
It's unforgivable.
There can be no pardon.
What did you use?
Arsenic?
Sire, there is no poison in my glaze,
none at all.
Believe me.
Traitor! Her Majesty is dead.
No poison? Believe you?
Men! Kill him!
Sire.
No, no.
Not so fast.
He wouldn't have dared
to do this on his own.
Who is it? Confess.
Who put you up to it?
I am innocent!
I'll drink every drop of glaze...
...if it will prove it to you.
Sire, Sire!
It wasn't poison.
She suffered from an allergy.
An allergy?
She was allergic to peach blossoms.
A light case can cause itching.
A severe case
can cause unconsciousness.
Fortunately, she's awake
and feeling better.
You! Does your glaze
contain peach blossoms?
This was due to my carelessness.
It was Her Royal Majesty.
This is high treason.
High treason.
Why did you use peach blossoms?
Did you know of
Her Majesty's condition?
Never, Sire.
The peach blossoms...
Sire.
He didn't know.
We've worked together for years.
He has committed no crime.
Please, Sire.
No crime?
Her Majesty's life was threatened
and there is no crime?
Is that it?
Your pardon, Sire.
I merely...
And you...
...have been misled.
Your thoughts?
I assumed his only thoughts
were of pottery.
Thought he only knew of pottery,
but he knews when to stand up.
He may be the man
to run the Punwon Kiln.
His Majesty said that?
Yes.
From the looks of things,
the heavens must be smiling on us.
How did you learn of her allergy?
At a picnic.
She's in good health so it's fine.
But if she were in premature labor
and ill...
Yi Kangchon has been named
Master Artisan of the Punwon Kiln.
Congratulations, sir.
Congratulations.
My lord.
Please, my lord,
is this because of the glaze?
What about Artisan Yu?
My lord, my lord.
I said no.
Please, just a peek.
I beg you.
...Absolutely not...
Sir.
How did you get in?
You're here because of me.
It wasn't you.
I made the glaze.
He put me over the tea services.
He said the designs did his heart good.
Sir.
I was worried I might not get to tell you.
Now it's all right.
I wouldn't have tried to be
master artisan without you.
As a woman you can never be an artisan.
Yet despite that you never gave up.
I admire that about you.
I let ambition rule my service
to the King.
A type of treason in a way.
Serve Lord Yi well.
Become a Bunwon artisan.
The first artisan in our country.
Wherever I am...
...in this life or the next...
...I'll be watching over you.
My lord.
[Euldam]
Such a flimsy bit of nothing...
...does his heart good?
His discerning eye surprised me.
If the Queen hadn't been there,
things would have been different.
But in the end
you were made master artisan.
My troubles with Euldam are finally over.
More importantly, look after the Kiln.
It will do no good to speak of this again.
Remember that.
My lord.
Why did you
give me the peach blossoms?
Their sugar content improves
the delicacy of the glaze.
It's the right glaze for Sonchon clay.
But you already knew that.
Is that why you took the rest of the clay?
So Lord Yu would be forced
to use my glaze?
Watch it.
I'm going to the Inquisitor's Office.
I'll tell them you said to use
the peach blossoms.
You would lie to them?
The real liar here... is you.
And your dream to become an artisan?
Don't let emotion get in your way.
I could help...
I have given everything...
...to be an artisan.
Including not killing myself
after that night with you.
But now I know...
There is no dream more precious to me...
...than Lord Yu.
You're not...
You're not in love with Euldam?
You think I would dare?
You know me better than that.
You open your mouth about the glaze...
...and you will die.
Be that as it may.
I must save Lord Yu.
I'm going to the inquisitors at dawn.
Worthless, pathetic...
Euldam, Euldam, Euldam!
Mapung.
No...
I'm...
I'm pregnant...
I'm in labor.
You know as well as I who the father is.
Will you kill your lord's own blood?
Go tell him.
I had a vision that the child
would be a divine artisan.
What? A baby?
'A divine artisan?'
You can't have another.
It's no laughing matter.
Another child will cost you
wealth, power, position, everything.
The signs are clear.
Father.
Yukdo, shouldn't you be in bed?
I nearly dozed off
waiting to tell you congratulations.
But then I didn't, tho.
It's late. Get some sleep.
I would wait all night.
I'm that proud of you being named
Master Artisan of the Punwon Kiln.
I want to be the bestest artisan ever
just like you.
And you will. You will.
Now off to bed, Yukdo.
Yes, Father.
Yukdo is all I need.
Thank you, my lady.
This is a great day.
I hereby declare a general amnesty.
Yu Euldam, you are stripped of rank and
expelled from the Punwon Kiln.
Yonok.
Is it you?
My lord.
Yonok, what is this?
Why are you...?
This baby... it's not...
You're not a dream?
You're really here?
Yes, it's me. It's no dream.
What is all this?
My lord, please don't ask... my baby...
...my baby...
I'll get a doctor.
My lord.
He'll be here any minute.
The baby... please... my baby...
He'll be here? Who?
My lord, please...
First we have to get out of here.
Give me the baby.
My girl.
Someday she will make porcelain
for the King.
Of course.
Now give her here and let's go.
First swear.
Swear you'll look after her
if anything happens to me.
I swear, now come on.
Yonok!
Yonok! Yonok...
No, Yonok...!
Yes.
Everything I have is yours, Yukdo.
You will grow up to be
the finest artisan in the land.
Yonok, can you see us?
Your little girl...
No, my little girl.
I dreamed of having a girl
that would make porcelain for the King.
I will rear her to be the first artisan
in our nation. Wait and see.
I swear it.
Goodness, look at that.
Here, one second.
Such a shame. Here.
There, there, hungry, sweetie?
That's it, that's right, there you go.
Artisan-schmartisan. Forget that.
Why do I have to do this every day?
Mine always fall apart.
Maybe if you didn't smack it so hard.
Huh? Who smacks what?
The old mister says yours leak.
Leak? Really?
I wonder why?
Hwalyong, Dad doesn't know, right?
The master said you'd make
three times the number that leaked.
Jung.
It's Taedo.
Taedo!
What were you doing?
Just makin' stuff.
Turn around... turn around... turn around
An arrow... pshew-pshew...!
Nice and easy.
Like this?
Eyes on the bear.
Chin in, neck here.
Shoulders straight.
When do I fire?
Hold your breath.
Now.
Now?
I can't.
I'm better with a sword.
Gimme that, it's dangerous.
Yu Jung, Swordmaster Extraordinaire.
Stop, Jung.
Jung... Jung, stop.
Jung, it's dangerous.
Jung...
Jung, you all right?
- Jung.
Hello, Dad.
Hwalyong, you go inside with your father.
Yes, Master.
Here we go.
Did you hear me when I said
we have an important visitor today?
Clean this up and go to your room.
Yessir.
The finest artisan as a teacher.
And a friend.
I'm a happy man.
Yes, Father. I'm lucky
to be learning from him.
Still...
Still what?
Go on.
I wish I had a friend to compete with.
Isn't Jung your friend?
Jung is the best friend in the world.
But she's not what I would call...
...competition.
Hwalyong.
It's true.
Competition hones one's skill.
I had someone like that
in my early days as an artisan.
Who?
Yi Kangchon. Punwon's Master Artisan.
Hwalyong, get us a drink.
Sir.
'Yi Kangchon was a good friend.'
Is that what you think?
He defended me when no one else would.
I heard some strange things after you left.
Enough.
Is Prince Kwanghae doing well?
Look at you.
You don't care about anything else.
Just His Royal Highness.
I was freed in the amnesty
following his birth.
We've never met, but I owe him my life.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Prince Kwanghae!
You wanted me?
I wanted a word before we start.
I'm listening.
I'm firstborn. No riding ahead of me.
Right. Of course.
And you can't
catch anything this time, understood?
Well?
Hunters usually hunt.
What? You dare disobey?
I'm here to hunt.
Not to show you up, don't worry.
See you remember that.
Wait.
For what?
That Father's deer.
You'll need different game
to show your stuff.
Which way then?
There. Lots of animals in the woods.
Animals?
You first.
No, you first.
Right.
Where you going?
Huh? Um... looking for clay.
That's strange.
And here Taedo is out hunting.
Oh? I had no idea.
I'll need to get back before dark.
Bye.
I said no hunting.
You should have waited.
Hurry up then.
It can't get far with an arrow in it.
You were thrown. No hunting for you.
Imhae!
Move out.
What the..?
Who put this here?
What did we catch?
Boar?
Elk? Deer?
The pit was my idea, so it's my catch.
You know that, right?
Your idea. But I did all the work.
Big talker.
What, and I just stood around?
I was...
You go on. I'll follow the deer.
Great. But I get what's in the pit.
No arguments.
Just in case. Take this.
Yes.
Wait, did we catch a huge animal?
Not a tiger perhaps?
Owie...! I swear!
You just going to stand there?
Give me a hand.
I didn't catch nothin'.
What? Nothing?
You dug this pit?
Yep. It's mine.
You didn't even ask permission.
You'll be sorry when I get out.
Pssh. Good luck with that.
Wait.
Hang on, give me a hand.
Get back here!
Why would I help you
if you'll make me sorry?
You know who I am?
I could have your whole family
put to death.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Better save your energy. Good luck.
Owie, a snake bit me.
Get me out before the poison spreads.
Really?
Uh-huh. Look.
It's so painful...
...hurts so much...
- Ow.
I swear, what will we do now?
How will we get out?
Kneel down.
Huh?
Kneel.
YOU kneel.
I'll climb out and toss you a rope.
Like I would trust you?
I'll get the soldiers to help. Kneel.
Soldiers, huh?
The poison must be kicking in.
Which hand was it? We have to treat it.
You lied?
You lied about being bit?
No.
Here.
Ow... Ouch!
Wait, what's this?
It's spreading to your shoulder.
Huh?
We'll have to amputate.
That some kind of joke?
A joke?
Poison spreading when I
wasn't even bit...
Lying liar. Too dense
to stay out of an animal pit.
You know who I am?
You dare compare me to an animal?
I'm...
I am a prince.
A prince?
I am. Now hurry and bow.
Your Worship, forgive me,
Your High-n-Mightiness.
I didn't recognize Your Pomposity.
It's all right. You didn't know...
Like I was gonna do that.
It's even a waste
to speak formally to you.
What?
A prince? Ri-i-ight.
Does that ever work?
Aren't you scared you'll get caught?
- Silence.
- Shut it!
Now listen up.
My brother will be here soon.
Keep lying
and I'll tell him to leave you here.
So watch it.
Oh, you're asking for it now.
Just you wait.
Scary. Good thing I don't scare easy.
Taedo, hurry! There's a creep in here.
Taedo! Hurry!
Halt.
That's my boar. Stand aside.
That's my arrow, for sure.
Peasant. There's one in its flank.
It wounded it.
But mine was the killing shot.
It's my boar.
How dare you!
Another thing. It's not your arrow.
See? It's not the same color.
You there. Seize him!
Sir.
Let go. What did I do wrong?
So where is this brother of yours?
Is he coming?
Do you even have a bother?
He'll be here.
He was hunting big game, that's all.
No doubt.
I'll go find him. Kneel down.
How will you recognize him?
I should go. YOU should kneel.
I told you, I'm a prince...
I can't kneel.
Anyone can kneel.
You just hunker down
on your hands and knees.
See?
Creep-boy!
Creep...? Right. You caught me.
So you better help me out
before I try something.
I'll find this brother of yours.
You'll try to run away.
I'm reporting you
when we get out of here.
To the police?
Fine, dig your own grave.
You have yourself to blame.
Blame? Worry about yourself.
What's keeping Taedo?
Did something happen?
Cheater! You call that hunting?
Stealing like a stealing stealer?
What?
Say that again.
You didn't loose a single arrow,
you stole other's game.
What kind of hunting is that?
Not a single arrow?
You want to see me shoot?
Fine. I'll show you.
What's this?
Who is he?
Where's your brother?
He's... er, um...
- Bring him.
- Sire.
On your knees before His Majesty.
You little...!
I was looking for Kwanghae.
This guy was trying to take game
with Kwanghae's arrow in it.
Kwanghae's arrow?
Yes, Sire.
I suspect he may have hurt Kwanghae.
I was questioning him.
Is that so?
No. I don't know him, never met him.
- I shot a boar...
- Sire.
Let me question him, I'll find Kwanghae.
With your permission.
We're off.
Which of you is Taedo's father?
I am. Why?
Arrest him.
- Why?
- What is this?
Darling!
- Taedo!
- Father!
Taedo.
Taedo...
Why did you have to take my dad?
I'm innocent, I tell you.
Shut up and wait for His Majesty.
His... Majesty?
What's happened to us?
Did Jung get away?
Hey, call His Highness.
We checked the inn.
No sign of Prince Kwanghae.
You call that a report?
Find him or your life is forfeit.
S-Sire.
Your Majesty.
This peasant can lead us to him.
You said you didn't know him.
I don't. But I know this mountain.
If I can find him before dark,
release us both.
Fine. And if you don't,
you'll be punished accordingly.
Taedo can do it.
Why can't I?
I'm freezing.
That's why I'm building a fire.
Summer or not, it gets cold here.
Well hurry it up.
You do it then.
What the...?
You want to freeze to death?
Taedo saved my life this way once
when we got lost.
But you're a girl and I'm a boy and...
You're worried about saving face?
Better alive and stinky than dead.
Hold still if you don't want to freeze.
What are you doing?
What you told me.
Oh.
Got to stay warm after all.
Easy now.
What? I don't want to freeze.
Creep! What are you doing to me?
My heart's beating a mile a minute
and I'm standing still.
What are you grinning at?
Well? Answer me.
You're attracted to me.
Attracted?
To... you?
- Your Highness!
- Where are you?
Your Highness!
'Your Highness?'
They're here.
That sounds like my men.
Listen. They're coming.
Your Highness? You're...
You're really...
...a prince?
Translated by D. Bannon
Subtitles provided by MBC
Suppose...
Suppose someone slapped the prince,
what would happen?
I'll have your head!
Did you find who you were looking for?
Wooden swords don't count.
We won't meet again.
Defend yourself.
I'm scared of what I'll lose
if we meet again.
Kwanghae, I'm placing you
over the Punwon Kiln.
Yes, Sire.
Make the memorial service vessel.
It is a command. I must obey.
You will never set foot in the Punwon Kiln.
Who are you to talk to him like that?