Woman: Memory is
a selection of images,
some elusive,
others printed indelibly
on the brain.
The summer I killed my father,
I was 10 years old.
My brother Poe
was nine,
and my sister Cisely
had just turned 14.
The town we lived in
was named after a slave.
It's said that when
General Jean Paul Batiste
was stricken with cholera,
his life was saved by the medicine
of a slave woman called Eve.
In return for his life,
he freed her and gave her
this piece of land by the bayou.
Perhaps in gratitude,
she bore him 16 children.
We are the descendants of
Eve and Jean Paul Batiste.
I was named for her.
(Cajun music playing)
He'd better grab it now
while it still fits in his hands.
From what I hear,
it ain't just him giving it.
Do tell.
Don't let nothing fall out,
or I might have to catch you.
Don't hurt yourself
with that thing.
Harry...
why do you always do that
when we're drunk?
Put down the camera,
darling.
My baby Mozelle thinks
pictures make her look fat.
Put down the damn camera.
Harry. Here's
your favorite niece.
Oh, there she goes.
Hold on, sweetness.
Hey, Red.
What you got for me, baby?
A kiss and a chocolate...
for a price.
Well...
what do I get for this?
Two kisses and all
the chocolates you can eat.
That's my baby.
Here you go, sweetie.
- Thank you.
- Eve?
Where did you get those
delicious-looking chocolates?
You told me
to help serve, Mama.
This tastes kind of good.
Crunchy.
Well, don't just stand here
and let Harry eat them all.
Mama:
There's my baby boy.
Are you having
a good time, honey?
Chocolates, Poe?
They're beans.
Chocolate-covered beans.
Eve Batiste!
"Tybalt, Mercutio,
the prince expressly hath forbidden
bandying in Verona streets."
Really, make yourselves useful.
Help me with the champagne.
- Vive les Batiste!
- Bonne chance et bonne santé.
Merde!
Oh, you in trouble now.
Look at Daddy.
You must be so proud.
Your son is the best colored
doctor in all of Louisiana.
Every goddamn woman
in the parish
thinks Louis's
the Second Coming.
I used to be able
to keep up with you.
You're just out of practice,
that's all.
Come on, baby doll,
let's show them how to dance.
Hey, can't
my daughter dance?
Louis:
Elle sait danser, eh?
Hey, Red. Red?
Do you want to dance?
No, thanks.
(squeaking)
- Woman: I can't see a thing.
- Louis: Just hold on to my hand.
(moans and kisses)
(clinking)
(Eve sobs)
Come here.
Shh...
Breathe, come on.
Breathe deeply.
Deep breaths.
That's right.
- That's right.
- (Eve sobs)
Sorry.
I was asleep.
It's okay, baby.
You scared us too.
You remember
Mrs. Mereaux?
Almost gave me
a heart attack.
Sorry I scared you,
Mrs. Mereaux.
Matty, would you mind going
inside and fixing me a drink
while I talk to my daughter?
Of course not.
Good night, Eve.
Good night, Mrs. Mereaux.
Would you like
to go outside?
- Hey, Willie.
- Bonsoir, Louis.
Daddy loves you so much.
I know.
I know you know.
Do you love Mama?
Your mama...
is the most beautiful...
perfect woman
I ever met.
Your mama's a lady.
And I'll always love her.
Always. Understand?
Daddy?
Yes, baby.
How come you never
dance with me?
How can you say your daddy
never dances with you?
When we're alone and stuff.
But not at parties.
You always dance with Cisely.
Tell you what.
From now on...
we'll dance at every party.
All right?
(Louis chuckles)
Mama:
There you are.
I was looking for you two.
Eve...
it is past midnight.
Your cohorts are
already in pajamas.
I was talking to Daddy.
Well, I guess
that's legal.
Hey, you.
Are you sober?
Yes, Ma'am.
Just barely.
Did you have fun tonight?
I bet you did.
Go say good night to Uncle Tommy
before I put him down.
- I have to?
- Yes, Ma'am.
Then, straight to bed. And don't
forget to say your prayers.
Never cheat
the man upstairs.
Good night, Mama.
Good night, Daddy.
Good night, baby.
Night night.
What's wrong with her?
Oh, she'll be all right.
- And what about you?
- What about me?
You sober?
Barely.
- You're coming in?
- In a minute.
Hey, Uncle Tommy,
I came to say good night.
Hi.
Oui, une grande party.
Cocktails...
you didn't miss anything.
It was boring.
Boring...
Yeah...
well, good night.
Boring...
Hey.
Where were you?
- I looked all over.
- (Eve sniffles)
I was outside with Daddy. Then
I said good night to the croaker.
Before that.
I was in the carriage house.
You was in there a long time.
(Eve sobs)
I fell asleep.
What's wrong, rabbit?
What's the matter?
What?
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Hey, don't tell me
it's nothing. What's wrong?
I saw Daddy.
I was asleep
and I woke up...
and Daddy...
- What?
- Daddy and Mrs. Mereaux.
What about Daddy
and Mrs. Mereaux?
I saw them kissing.
Don't be stupid.
Daddy wouldn't touch that cow.
It's true, I saw them.
He had his hands on her.
It's true.
He was all up against her,
and her dress was...
- That's a lie!
- I saw them!
He was all up against her
and her dress was up
- and they were rubbing.
- Shh!
Stop it.
Just stop it.
I'm going to tell you
what happened.
- What?
- I can't see a thing.
Just hold on to my hand.
Cisely: They came in to get
some more wine...
and Daddy told her a joke.
And she fell
against him laughing.
- And they woke you up.
- (glass clinking)
You sure?
I'm certain.
What would Daddy want
with Matty Mereaux?
Mama's the most beautiful
woman in the world.
Go to bed.
It's late.
You scared me.
Louis: God damn it,
Harry, wait.
Harry: I'm leaving, I'm driving,
I'm taking my damn wife...
- No, no, no.
- Mozelle.
You'll either let
Mozelle drive...
or you'll stay here tonight,
or I'll whip your ass.
Shit, get your hands off me.
I may be drunk,
but I'll whip your butt.
- Come on!
- Stop it, assholes!
Now, what is your monkey ass
gonna do, huh?
Just because you're a doctor,
you think you know everything?
- You don't know everything.
- God damn it, Harry!
Cisely:
Daddy, Uncle Harry.
Stop it. It's late.
You want to raise the dead?
Go back to bed. You're not dressed
and it's bedtime.
Not till Daddy
comes in.
Toi, t'es un vrai
cochon parfois.
Fuck you, doc,
I'm sick of your shit.
- Come here. Come on!
- Give me the damn keys!
Now get into the goddamn car
before I kill you.
(Louis laughs)
Mozelle:
Dis bonsoir, Harry.
- Good night.
- Good night, slugger.
Bonsoir, Mozelle.
- Nighty, Mozelle.
- Nighty, Mozelle. Night, Harry.
Good night, y'all.
Be good.
Good night, Red.
Good night, Cisely.
- Fuck you, Doc.
- Shut the hell up.
What do I get for this?
Woman: I don't know why
the Lord sees fit...
Good night, Red.
(phone rings in the distance)
Mama: Mozelle, are you...
Oh, my God.
Louis, Louis, wake up!
Red:
God bless Uncle Harry...
May God bless
Uncle Maynard...
and Uncle Anderson.
(knock on door)
(whispering)
Aunt Mozelle, wake up.
What for?
You got clients coming.
Harry's voice: Mozelle.
Eve:
You don't look so bad.
I loved them...
I swear I did.
Eve: I know.
It's not your fault they die.
Which one did you love best?
I don't know, Eve.
They was all different.
Anderson was the handsomest
man I've ever seen.
Your uncle Harry,
he was the sweetest.
And Maynard...
Maynard loved me
most of all.
Even when I was your age,
before I ever did the counseling,
I could look at people, complete
strangers, and see their lives.
But I looked at each
of my husbands...
and never saw a thing.
That's the way it always is...
blind to my own life.
(bell ringing)
Eh bien...
now go and...
make yourself invisible
for a while.
If you're quiet...
you'll be able to hear.
I'm so sorry about Harry.
I don't know
why the Lord sees fit...
We're all servants
of divine will.
The Lord giveth
and taketh away.
Oh, well.
Close your eyes.
Lord, lead us in the direction
of righteousness.
Advise us that we may
become wiser in Thy will.
- Amen.
Speak your mind, my friend.
It's my boy.
My boy's ran off
and I don't know where.
My husband and I have been
praying for two months.
And I pray for patience, but...
I can't take it anymore.
I have to know.
(sirens blasting)
He's alive, Hilary.
You'll find him in Detroit,
at St. Michael's Hospital.
Next Tuesday.
Is he sick?
Tell me.
Your son's on drugs.
Go home and pray for strength.
You'll need strength
to help you through this.
Mozelle: The money is gone,
Madame Renard.
Your niece spent it all.
I'm sorry.
(sobbing)
Oh, help me.
My God.
How will I live?
Please, help me.
I want you to get a small bag
made of skin of chamois.
In it, place this piece
of moon stone
and John Conqueror root.
Tie it with a piece
of devil shoestring.
And in your right hand,
sprinkle five drops of holy oil.
Thank you, Madame.
I'm in no position
to repay your kindness
- with my money gone.
- C'est rien, ma chére.
Keep the bag
next to your skin.
I'm so sorry
about your husband.
He was such a fine man.
Thank you.
Don't be cute.
You told Daddy you don't
practice no voodoo.
She was desperate.
Does it work?
We'll see.
What if it don't?
I don't think she'll sue me.
(Mozelle chuckles)
Mozelle: Oh Lord.
What is it now?
(faint)
What did you say?
Ros: I said, I've got three
of his damn babies.
I can't stand
that woman called my house!
There is nothing in this world
lower than eavesdropping
- on the conversation of others.
- This is important.
If they wanted you to hear,
they'd have left the door open.
- I'm telling.
- (both gasp)
Women have been lying about this
ever since God invented them.
Daddy.
Hey, Cis.
You're in trouble. Go to Kings
and come back later.
- They're really mad.
- Who's mad, baby?
Who, them?
They're always mad.
People fantasize
about their doctors...
No, don't talk, Louis.
- I feel like I'm falling.
- I'll catch you.
Don't.
- Eve: He's that old?
- Yeah.
Eve:
He seems like he's 100.
Not 100. I think he used
to go out with grand-mére.
H uh? They do seem like
they could make a good couple.
You really think so?
Wait, grand-mére doesn't really
seem like she's that old.
Oh, grand-mére is old,
let me tell you.
You've been taking
your pills. Good girl.
Yes, Doctor,
I'm feeling much better.
Everything will be
just fine.
Yes, everything's going
to be just fine.
As long as you keep
taking your pills.
- Good bye, Mrs. Renard.
- Bye.
Yes, Lord...
everything will be
just fine.
Your lungs are clear
as a bell, Stevie.
I think you'll live.
Doctor...
could you give me
something for the pain?
Eve...
go on outside and play.
What pain is that,
Stevie?
What was wrong
with that lady?
Mrs. Hobbs?
Some illnesses are hard
to put a finger on.
- Is she having a baby?
- No. Why do you ask?
Do you ever want other kids?
No, your mother and I are happy
with the three kids we've got.
No, I mean, other kids...
besides us.
Open your mouth
and say, "Aaah."
No, I don't see
anything in there
that would make you say
something so stupid.
I got to go to the hospital.
I have to take you home.
Oh no.
Please, Daddy.
Tell you what,
I'll race you.
- I'll give you a head-start.
- Okay. Bye!
(whistling)
We're supposed to be
cheering each other up.
I know.
I was just wondering
what happened with that woman.
I supposed he fixed it.
He knows how to fix things.
When I first met Louis,
I watched him set this boy's leg
who'd fallen out of a tree.
I said to myself,
"He's a man who can fix things.
He's a healer.
He'll take care of me."
So I leave my family...
and I move to the swamp...
and I find out
he's just a man.
We're two of a kind,
my brother and I.
One day,
he'll turn around...
and he will see you
for the first time.
And then he'll stop looking
for what he already has.
What if it's too late?
Let's eat pomegranates
till our hands turn red...
and all we can think about
is getting the juice off.
Mo, let's get
our fortunes drawn.
Not by her.
Come on, you said
you wanted to cheer me up.
She couldn't predict
heat in August.
Mozelle Batiste...
if I didn't know you better,
I'd say you have a case
of professional jealousy.
Roz, I am a psychic counselor.
Elzora is a sideshow
attraction.
Then there's nothing
to be afraid of.
Which one first?
My sister-in-law's
something of a skeptic.
But I'd very much like
my fortune drawn.
Sit down.
Empty it.
You're in pain,
my daughter.
Yes.
There is an end
to your problem...
though not
one you imagined.
Stay quiet...
and wait.
Wait?
Sometimes a soldier falls
on his own sword.
In three years time,
you will be happy again.
Three years?
Look to your children.
Dollar.
That's it?
Just wait three years
and everything will be fine?
Look to your children.
Thank you.
I feel most enlightened.
Good afternoon.
- You were right. Come on.
- Wait.
Some things are
better left unsaid.
I paid you a dollar,
old woman.
No, tell my fortune.
I don't need no cat bones
to tell your fortune.
You are a curse!
A black widow.
Next man who marries you
is a dead man.
Like the others.
Always be that way.
Sale menteuse!
You're an old lying witch!
Wait a minute.
For heaven's sake,
what did she say?
It's all right, it's just...
I need...
Come on, let's not be
in the street.
Mo.
It's dead.
Are you sure?
It's not moving, is it?
Maybe it's just sick.
It's dead,
you little chicken.
(both scream)
Oh, Cisely,
thank Heavens.
Where are Eve and Poe?
- Mom, I don't know.
- (distant screaming)
Oh, Lord.
Are you all right?
Just go. Don't ask me.
Just go.
You're going to lock
these kids up in the house
for the summer 'cause of what
that fortune teller told you?
She kept saying,
"Look to your children."
And no sooner do we leave,
that Mozelle has this vision
- of a child getting hit.
- (laughs)
Roz, I love my sister,
but she's not unfamiliar
- with mental hospitals.
- Not in front of the children.
- They know.
- Of course, we know.
- Poe: Know what?
- Aunt Mozelle is crazy.
Eve: She is not! She knows things.
People trust her.
Sweetheart, Aunt Mozelle's
a little eccentric.
We let her tell fortunes
to keep her out of trouble.
She may be crazy, but
them visions always come true.
Anyway...
I've made up my mind.
- They're staying in the house.
- Till when?
Well, I don't now.
Till Mozelle says it's safe.
- Can't believe I'm hearing this.
- What if we don't play in traffic?
Don't you use that tone
of voice with me.
And don't roll your eyes
at your father behind my back.
You're looking right at us, Mama.
Nothing ever happens
behind your back.
Don't talk back to your mother.
- You're not too big to beat.
- Don't threaten my daughter, Mama.
You let her threaten me.
When I was growing up,
children did not
participate in
a conversation of adults.
You can let them kids back talk
and run wild if you want to.
You won't hear
another word out of me.
In my day, we were thankful
for signs and warnings.
Let the little hooligans
get run over.
Ça va plus tranquille
autour d'ici.
Could be much
quieter around here.
I want to thank you
for the delightful family chat.
- I have patients to see.
- Louis...
- it's Sunday.
- When you manage to put sickness
on an eight-hour, five-day
schedule, let me know.
- Why can't they wait a day?
- Are you two gonna fight?
"Some sicknesses are hard
to put a finger on."
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
Which one of your patients
are you going to see?
Woman, go get your palm read,
let me do my work.
You love your daddy,
baby?
- You know I do.
- That's all I need.
Excuse me, darling.
Don't you think you're being
a little immature?
I beg your pardon?
Keeping us in the house
'cause Mozelle's seeing things,
and not wanting Daddy
to go to work.
What's wrong with you?
If you're lucky,
you might live long enough
to one day have
a husband and children.
But until then, this is my house
and you'll do as I say.
Do you understand?
I said, do you understand?
Yes, Ma'am.
Good.
No one leaves this house
until I say so.
"What a man art thou,
that, thus be screened in night,
So stumblest
on my counsel?
"By a name... I know not
how to tell thee who I am.
My name, dear saint,
is hateful to myself
Because it is
an enemy to thee."
(heavy sigh)
What are you
doing in there?!
Cisely: Go away.
Ah!
Ouch!
God damn it!
Ferme ta gueule, hein?
I heard you.
You said, "God damn it."
Eve.
You shouldn't be sneaking up
on people when they're swearing.
- Does it hurt?
- What?
Your finger, Mother.
No, not too much.
You'll cut your finger off
one of these days.
"Tis not so deep as a well...
Nor so wide
as a church door...
But 'tis enough,
'twill serve."
Romeo and Juliet.
What?
We've read most
of the tragedies.
We're starting on
the goddamn comedies.
You are asking to get hit.
- (distant scream)
- Baby?
The Lord have mercy.
What happened, baby?
You all right?
Mozelle:
Hey, everybody.
Hi, Mo.
Poe, are you all right?
Look what I found in the attic...
a Monopoly board
and Chinese checkers.
You could find the czar
of Russia in that attic.
I despise Chinese checkers.
Poe: I hate her!
I wish she was dead!
I feel like I walked
into the middle of a cyclone.
Eve... what did you do
to your brother?
I'll push him out of a window
if I don't get out!
Cisely has been in the goddamn
bathtub for an hour.
She stayed in it
three hours yesterday.
There's more than
one bathroom in this house.
Ain't that much dirt
in all of Louisiana.
Get out of the damn tub!
You watch your language,
young lady.
Mama keeps stabbing herself
in the kitchen.
- Show her your hands.
- You'd better hush.
And where is Daddy?
He's never home.
He's supposed to be
home sometimes.
Listen, you little ingrate.
Your father works hard so we can
have a house with four bathrooms.
He's not working every night.
I know he's not.
- I mean...
- Let me borrow you for a minute.
Poe?
Is that your idea
of being a good daughter?
It's true.
He never comes home,
and it's making her nervous.
She cuts herself.
And you're being helpful
bringing it up?
She's nervous 'cause
he's messing with other women.
What did you say?
Nothing.
Play games with me
and I'll slap you blind.
- It's true, I saw them.
- You saw who?
You have five seconds.
Daddy and Mrs. Mereaux.
God.
It was at the party.
I was in the carriage house
and they didn't see me.
And it was worse
than just kissing...
Shh. Let me think
a minute.
Have you told anyone?
- No.
- Well, that's good.
Because if you tell anyone,
anyone at all...
I'm going to kill you.
And if you get callous again
with your mama's feelings,
I swear I'll do you harm.
- You understand me?
- Yes, Ma'am.
Listen...
your daddy loves you,
- and he loves your mama.
- I know.
We are a lot the same,
your father and I.
Except I don't have
no children to catch me.
You all are my children.
That's why Maynard got
tired of me, 'cause I'm barren.
But...
Maynard loved you.
Maynard loved you
most of all.
I think he did.
But I didn't know that
until I met Hosea.
- Tell me about Hosea.
- You're too young to understand.
But when I was with Hosea,
it was like my whole
body was burning.
I'd come home
and have to rub ice
on my face and neck
to cool down.
If Maynard knew,
he never said a word.
Then one night, Hosea
showed up at the door.
He said, "Pack your bags.
I've come to take you with me."
And God help me...
I pushed past
my startled husband.
I was going upstairs
to pack my bags,
when I heard Maynard say
in a tone I'd never heard him use,
"I don't care
who you are, sir,
but if you don't leave my house
at once, I will hurt you."
And I turned
just in time
to see Hosea pull a gun out
and aim it at Maynard.
"I'm in love
with your wife,
and if you try to stop us,
I'll kill you."
Maynard walked right up and pushed
his chest in the barrel of that gun,
and he said,
"Well, then, you'll have
to kill me
because my wife ain't
going nowhere."
Oh, Eve...
in that moment, I knew
that I loved Maynard.
He was so calm and brave...
and it was Hosea
who was trembling.
Maynard said...
"Mozelle...
tell this man you ain't
going nowhere with him
so he can get the hell
out of my house."
Mama was standing in
the doorway of the kitchen
and she was holding
her heart like this.
I walked slowly over...
and I stood
next to my husband...
and I looked at my lover...
this man who had lit
this great fire in me, and said,
"Please, leave our house.
I never want
to see you again."
Hosea's eyes went another color
and he stopped trembling.
He looked right at me...
and he said...
Hosea: All right, then.
(gunshot)
And he shot Maynard
in the chest.
And I was alone...
for a while.
(knock on door)
- Can I help you?
- I need Mozelle Batiste.
I am.
Am I disturbing you?
I don't know yet.
My name is Julian Grayraven.
Folks around here say
you read the future.
Julian: My wife
left me a year ago.
I've been to many cities,
searching for her.
I have no place
to return to anymore.
I'm exhausted.
I cannot continue and yet...
I cannot stop until I know.
Where is my wife?
♪ Now, darling ♪
♪ I think I really
love you... ♪
- Daddy, it's late.
- What are you doing up?
Waiting for you.
What do you think I'm doing up?
(heavy sigh)
What's your pleasure
this evening, Doctor?
Scotch and water,
bartender.
Where's your mama?
Everybody's asleep, Daddy.
Mom was nervous.
So grand-mére gave her a tablet.
That woman's got
every pill in the world.
Speaking of the infirm...
guess I better
check on Tommy.
Maybe I'll take him out
for a late-night stroll.
Or should I say, roll.
I think you're drunk.
Mmm...
I've delivered
babies drunker...
conceived babies
much drunker.
Daddy!
Did I ever tell you
about the night we made Poe?
No.
I got in a fight with
some knucklehead over at Kings
and came to under
the pool table.
Now, Roz was sore at me
about something,
so she hadn't spoken to me
in about a week.
I thought, " Damn...
the woman finds out
I've been drinking and fighting,
she'll leave me."
Anyway, they take me home,
and she sees me
all messed up,
and she starts weeping,
and kissing me,
and weeping,
and nine months later...
Poe.
Do you still love her?
Sweetheart...
let me tell you something.
When I met your mom...
men fought each other for
the privilege of speaking her name.
She was so pretty, it was
painful just to look at her.
And she could dance
almost as good as you.
But not quite.
No, not quite.
But holding Roz
was like holding
your favorite feather pillow.
The one you just
can't sleep without.
- And now?
- Well...
you know how it is
with feather pillows.
Over the years, they get
lumpy and deflated.
You have to fluff them up
all the time to keep them...
comme un pelochon.
- Daddy!
- (both laugh)
- Hey, Daddy.
- Hey, pumpkin head.
Look who's up.
Do you know what time it is?
It's time for
you girls to be in bed.
- No, Daddy.
- Yes.
Your mama would kill me
if she found out I had you up.
I'll just finish my drink,
check on Tommy,
then I'm headed to bed myself.
Night, night owls.
Night, Daddy.
(hammering)
♪ I want a Sunday... ♪
♪ Kind of love ♪
♪ A love to last ♪
♪ Past Saturday night ♪
♪ And I'd like to know ♪
♪ It's more than
love at first sight ♪
♪ I want a Sunday kind of love ♪
♪ Sunday, Sunday, Sunday... ♪
♪ Kind of love. ♪
Eve? Where's Cisely?
Officer, I'm afraid
she might be hit by something.
Being like it is today,
there's bound to be accidents.
Mama, please!
Cisely! Oh God!
Oh thank God.
Thank God.
Why did you
run off like that?
You almost gave your mama
a heart attack!
Where the hell
did you go?!
I went to visit Daddy.
Then I went
to the beauty parlor.
You what?
I walked all the way
to Daddy's office,
and then I caught
the bus to Opal's.
I had to cross
the train tracks to get home.
And I'm alive, Mama.
I didn't get hit
by anything.
Roz: Come here, Cisely.
When I was your age,
I was just like you.
I thought I knew everything.
Now, even the things
I'm most familiar with
seem mysterious to me.
But I know I love you.
And it's my job
to protect you as best I can.
If you disobey my orders,
or leave this house again, I swear
I'll lock you in your room.
Yes, Ma'am.
Go back to bed.
I'm waiting up
for your father tonight.
I don't want you
waiting up for him anymore.
But, Mama...
I'll say it one more time, Cisely.
I know you love your daddy.
And your daddy loves you.
I don't want you
waiting up for him anymore.
Cisely!
Did you hear me?
Yes, Ma'am.
But you don't understand him.
And you'll drive him
away from us!
I'll never forgive you.
If you drive him away...
(loud arguing)
Roz: I am sick...
You get yourself straight,
or you're out of here!
Mozelle:
Isn't it beautiful?
Julian:
You're beautiful.
Mozelle...
it's time for me to go.
I have to find my wife.
Mr. Grayraven, I told you
she's not coming back.
I have to find my wife
so that I can...
divorce her...
and marry you.
Oh, Julian...
it's enough that
you're here with me.
You have made me
so happy.
But you can't
possibly marry me.
I can't let that happen.
- Is it that you don't love me?
- No!
No, it's not that. It's...
bear with me.
I'm cursed.
I can't have children.
I'm barren.
You're not barren.
You're wounded...
here.
And it's here that
I'll plant seeds.
(distant honking,
tires screeching)
- (car crashing)
- (woman screaming)
We're free!
And tonight, we'll barbecue outside
- and have a picnic!
- I'm going outside!
C'est pas juste de fêter quand
I'enfant de quelqu'un est mort.
These children have been
in the house for weeks!
Go get Cisely. She hasn't
come down all morning.
I think she's still
mad at me.
Cisely!
It is not right to celebrate
when somebody's child is dead.
Well, whose child
was it anyway?
Dickey's boy.
Wake up, we're free!
We can go outside now.
Cisely!
Cisely: Go away.
Some other kid got hit.
We're free!
- Go away!
- Ow!
Oooh...
so that's what's
wrong with you.
Look, you think just 'cause
you got blood in your pants
you don't have
to act civilized no more?
Shut up!
Cisely's got her period.
I'm gonna tell Daddy.
(Cisely screams)
No!
Mama!
Cisely's trying to kill me.
Help!
Mama!
- She's trying to kill me!
- Julian: Come on.
What happened?
I don't know what happened.
It's like she went crazy.
We thought she was having a seizure.
We were so scared.
Is it my fault, you think?
'Cause I hit her.
No, Roz. It's not your fault.
Let me look at her.
Louis.
She started her period.
- Did you know that?
- No.
Roz:
She didn't even tell me.
Go away, Daddy.
I don't want you here.
I just want to take your pulse
and your temperature, baby.
- Doctor stuff.
- No!
I don't want you
looking at me.
Okay.
I know a nice lady doctor
we can take you to.
Would you like that?
(humming "Amazing Grace")
Excuse me?
How much for this pineapple?
I said, how much
for this pineapple?
¢ 25.
You want it?
That's too much.
Man:
Hey! Arrê tez-la!
Bad girl.
Méchante fille!
Eve: I'm going to beat you,
'cause you are a chicken!
She blames me for
not making you happy.
She thinks I'm driving you away.
She's a child, Roz.
Just give her time.
How much time, Louis?
It's already been two weeks.
She won't eat, she won't speak.
It's like she's sleepwalking.
Louis: This...
psychologist fellow
seems to think
you need kind of a...
vacation from us.
It's just a suggestion.
We'd never send you away
unless you wanted to go.
Listen...
whatever it is, we can
work it out together.
Everything's going to be
fine again. I promise.
I want to go.
What?
What did you say, baby?
I said I want to go.
It's all settled.
I talked to grand-mother...
and she just can't
wait to see you.
If you leave me
alone with them,
I'll die.
I'll die, Cisely.
What's wrong with you?
Why won't you tell me?
Is it me?
Is it something I did?
Why won't you talk to me?
Of course
it's not you, rabbit.
You're my only friend.
Then...
what is it?
Tell me. I promise
I won't tell anybody.
Do you remember the storm?
The day you cut your hair
and Mama hit you?
Did you hear Mama
and Daddy fight that night?
Yeah.
Part of it was about me...
and how he let me
visit him that day.
The other thing
they were fighting about...
was Matty Mereaux.
Mama knows about
Daddy and Matty?
Everybody knows.
She's been hanging around
his office in front of everyone.
You believe me now about
what happened at the party?
I believed you then.
Anyway...
I waited until I heard
Mama go upstairs.
I went downstairs.
I was afraid of
what she might have said.
I was afraid he would divorce us.
I wanted to make him
feel better.
I sat on his lap...
and I was scared.
I was trying to get away
and he was hugging me
and kissing me,
until I finally pushed him
away with my knee.
I must have hurt him
because...
he's never hit me.
Louis: Sorry...
Then I ran.
I'll kill him, Cisely.
I swear!
I'll kill him
for hurting you.
Bye bye, baby.
Roz: I'll be gone a week or so.
I want to get her settled in.
Bye, Poe.
Louis: I'll just drop them off.
I'll be back before dinner.
- Maybe he ran into traffic.
- It's Sunday.
He'll be back,
and so will Cisely.
I know she will.
Life is filled with goodbyes.
A million goodbyes.
And it hurts every time.
Sometimes, I feel like
I've lost so much,
I have to find
new things to lose.
All I know is, there must be
a divine point to it all,
and it's just over my head.
When we die,
it will all come clear,
and we'll say,
"So that was
the damn point."
And sometimes I think there's no
point at all, and that's the point.
All I know is most people's lives
are a great disappointment to them.
And no one leaves this earth
without feeling terrible pain.
And if there is no divine
explanation at the end of it all,
well, that's sad.
How do you kill someone
with voodoo?
(Mozelle chuckles)
I almost forgot you was there.
I mean, do you just wish
real hard they were dead?
Or do you have to do
something special?
I suppose you put
some of their hair on a doll
and stick pins in it
or something. I don't know.
What makes you ask
a thing like that?
Nothing.
You must have been
thinking something
right before you were
thinking that.
What led you
to that particular thought?
I don't know.
Is there someone around here
that you're angry with?
Someone that you want dead?
- I'm going inside.
- You better tell me
what's on your mind.
You have five seconds.
Give me your hands.
Give them to me.
Go on and keep secrets
if you want to.
I won't squeeze it
out of you.
But you can't kill with voodoo.
That's ridiculous.
Hey, Red. Didn't mean
to startle you.
- Hi, Mr. Mereaux.
- Hi.
- How's your family?
- Everybody's fine.
- How's Matty?
- Same as always.
Salty and sweet.
- What are you looking for?
- H umm...
- apples.
- Apples?
You know, you just
walked right past them.
Oh, thanks.
Lord have mercy.
- Mr. Mereaux?
- Yes, Eve.
You're still teaching?
Sure, darling. Down at Xavier,
in New Orleans.
Been there for years.
- That's a long drive.
- Yeah.
Sometimes if the weather's bad,
I just stay on campus.
But usually,
I try to get home,
so Matty don't get
too lonely.
Matty don't seem
like the lonely type.
No...
I guess not.
You must get home real late.
Well, when you get home.
Sometimes.
So does my daddy.
Every night.
My mama gets real lonely.
But then, she is
the lonely type.
Not like Daddy and Matty.
Well...
bye.
Excuse me.
Méchante petite fille.
I remember you,
pineapple thief.
Hi.
I've been looking for you.
Only people who look for me
got a good reason.
- I got a good reason.
- You got money?
- $20.
- 20...
let me see.
Give me.
You stole that money
from your daddy?
- Why you think I stole it?
- You didn't get it laying bricks.
Come. Follow me.
Eve: Where are we going?
My office.
Are you related
to Mozelle Batiste?
I'm her niece.
- And she's the one you want dead.
- No, someone else.
Mmm... too bad.
Tant pis.
Why you want this person dead?
- Pour quoi faire?
- Raison privée.
Did this person...
harm you?
Others in my family.
I will give you something
to protect you and your family.
I want him dead!
For certain?
You are sure?
Yes, Ma'am.
People have a way of dying
at their own speed.
But I will see
what I can do.
I will need some hair...
from the head of this person.
I brought you some
from a comb.
I hope it's enough, though.
Well... eh bien...
woman, don't be
too weak.
You come back Thursday night,
and we'll see.
We'll see.
Get the hell off my property
before I cook you and eat you!
Is that you, pineapple thief?
Come.
I thought you was one
of those town kids
who was bothering me.
Is he dead yet?
How could he be dead?
- You didn't give me the doll.
- What doll?
I didn't say nothing to you
about no doll.
The voodoo doll.
I didn't make you
no voodoo doll.
I made you a wax coffin.
I put his hair inside
the mouth of a snake,
and buried it
in the graveyard.
- He should be dead by now.
- I thought I had to do something,
like stick pins in it or...
You did something!
You brought me his hair.
- And you paid me $20.
- But...
I wanted it.
I wanted to have it.
I need it!
Oh God.
Where...
- where did you bury it?
- Down there.
Where all them Batistes
are buried.
But I don't think
you'll find it.
You said
you wanted him dead.
You said you was certain.
(woman laughs hysterically)
(loud music plays)
Daddy!
Oh Daddy, I'm so happy
to see you.
What are you doing over here
at this time of night?
What's wrong?
Is it grand-mére?
H umm...
Daddy, let's go home.
Please, I want you
to come home with me.
Of course, baby.
You walked all the way over here?
- What's wrong?
- Man: You've been busted, Doc.
The last one's on me.
Go outside while I say
good night to Miss Mereaux.
Hurry up.
Oh, hey, Mr. Mereaux.
Hey, baby.
Hey, just in time to have
a last one with us.
- I don't think so, Louis.
- What's wrong? You crazy?
- You fucking my wife?
- Don't be ridiculous.
- You're fucking her?
- You're drunk.
You like her?
She's very beautiful.
You fucking her?
Matty and I are old friends.
You know that
as well as anyone.
I trusted you, Louis.
And you've been
fucking Matty.
I loved you, Louis.
I love you, Lenny.
Come on, Daddy,
let's go home.
That's right. You're drunk.
Let me take you home.
Listen...
you so much as speak
to my wife again...
and I will kill you.
Do you understand?
Bartender:
Take it outside.
Let's get the hell
out of here.
You go home sleep off
that whiskey, old man.
You'll apologize
to me tomorrow.
You speak to her again,
you're dead, Louis.
Come on, Daddy, let's go home.
Please.
Okay, baby.
Night, Matty.
No!
Eve: Daddy!
All: "Our Father,
Who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
on Earth as it is
in Heaven..."
No!
"...as we forgive those
who trespassed against us.
And lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us from evil,
for Thine is the kingdom,
and the power,
and the glory
forever and ever."
Amen.
(Roz softly hums)
Last night, I had a dream
that I was flying.
It was such a fine feeling.
But in the corner of my eye,
I saw a woman drowning
in the very same air
that was keeping me afloat.
And I knew, without looking,
it was me.
Should I save her?
And then I heard
Louis' voice saying,
"Don't look back."
So I kept on flying...
and I let her drown.
When I woke up...
I told Julian
I would marry him.
He wouldn't have it
any other way.
Maybe God will be kind
and allow me to go with him.
I'm so tired of being
left alone.
Your daddy gave me
a message for you.
"Tell Eve I still
owe her a dance."
"To Mozelle."
"Mozelle, it's been two hours
since we spoke
and finally, I feel
calm enough to write this.
I realize that your accusations,
however shocking and cruel,
stem from some
weakness in myself
that allows you to believe
the worst of me.
As you and I know,
I'm just a small-town doctor
pushing aspirin to the elderly.
But to a certain type
of woman, I'm a hero.
I need to be a hero
sometimes.
That's my weakness.
That much is true.
But how, Mozelle, could I have
sunken your estimation
to the leechy depths
where you would accuse me
of deliberately abusing
my most beloved child?
I am guilty in the sense
that I adore her,
and I allowed her
to adore me.
It was a sweet
indulgence,
but nothing
in her behavior
prepared me for what happened
the night of the storm.
Roz and I had
a terrible fight
and I guess
it was inevitable.
I knew Cisely could never sleep
through a fight like that.
So, I wasn't surprised
when she came downstairs.
Maybe I was even
waiting for her.
I let myself wallow
and feel comforted.
Mozelle, I swear...
the first kiss was
the sweetest kiss
a daughter could give
her drunk, guilt-ridden father.
A kiss of redemption.
And the next moment,
it had gone wrong.
From my scotch haze,
it took me a second to realize
that my daughter was
kissing me like a woman.
This is where
I blame myself.
I was so startled
that I hit her
and she fell to the floor.
The look she gave me
almost stopped my heart.
And I knew I had lost her.
Mozelle, I would give my life
to have that moment back.
I would hold her and comfort her.
We would talk through her confusion
and I'd put her to bed,
with the boundaries
between us intact.
I love her
more than my life.
I hope that one day,
she can forgive me.
I felt I could not
betray her again
by telling you or Roz.
Forgive me."
Eve: Liar!
Red?
You lied to me about Daddy.
You lied!
Daddy wrote Mozelle
a letter!
- You lied!
- I wasn't lying.
I believed you...
and I hated him.
I hated him
for you.
He hurt me, Eve.
He hurt me so badly...
I wanted to die.
Tell me what happened.
Please.
I have to know.
I can't.
Please.
I don't know what happened.
I don't know.
- It's okay.
- I can't.
Adult Eve: Memory
is a selection of images,
some elusive...
others printed
indelibly on the brain.
Each image
is like a thread,
each thread woven together
to make a tapestry
of intricate texture.
And the tapestry
tells a story...
and the story is our past.