1
00:01:01,269 --> 00:01:04,396
ln memory of Howard Zinn

2
00:01:11,654 --> 00:01:15,074
Cochabamba, Bolivia. Year 2000

3
00:01:24,292 --> 00:01:26,418
Come on.

4
00:01:35,553 --> 00:01:37,679
You see?

5
00:01:37,806 --> 00:01:39,431
Look, look, look.

6
00:01:39,557 --> 00:01:42,392
There are more coming.

7
00:01:51,611 --> 00:01:54,404
Hello.

8
00:01:54,531 --> 00:01:56,740
Good morning.

9
00:02:00,829 --> 00:02:04,331
So, an open casting, Sebastian?
Fucking great.

10
00:02:04,457 --> 00:02:06,750
l told you this would happen.

11
00:02:06,876 --> 00:02:08,168
Hello.

12
00:02:08,294 --> 00:02:10,337
Good morning.

13
00:02:14,884 --> 00:02:21,723
Excuse me.

14
00:02:21,850 --> 00:02:24,309
How's it going?

15
00:02:24,435 --> 00:02:27,187
They all want to be seen,
and there are hundreds. . .

16
00:02:27,313 --> 00:02:28,605
Okay, well, tell them
that we don't need anymore.

17
00:02:28,731 --> 00:02:30,107
We'll just see the ones here.
The rest can leave.

18
00:02:30,233 --> 00:02:32,401
No, Costa, wait, we can't do that.

19
00:02:32,527 --> 00:02:34,611
Shit, we can't see them all,
Sebastian.

20
00:02:34,737 --> 00:02:38,073
lf you prefer, pick the ones you like
and get rid of the rest.

21
00:02:38,199 --> 00:02:40,117
But do it now! Come on.

22
00:02:40,243 --> 00:02:41,827
Come on.

23
00:02:44,831 --> 00:02:47,916
Come on.
Choose the ones you like.

24
00:02:53,464 --> 00:02:54,506
-Hello.
-Pleasure.

25
00:02:54,632 --> 00:02:56,550
Could you go with the girl? Yes?

26
00:02:56,676 --> 00:02:58,594
How are you?

27
00:03:04,684 --> 00:03:06,560
Go ahead.
Yes, go ahead.

28
00:03:06,686 --> 00:03:07,978
They're very good.

29
00:03:08,104 --> 00:03:10,480
-How many men are going?
-Five, and two women.

30
00:03:10,607 --> 00:03:12,608
Okay, okay. Okay.

31
00:03:12,734 --> 00:03:14,109
-Hello. Could you go?
-Yes.

32
00:03:14,235 --> 00:03:16,361
Yeah?
Thank you.

33
00:03:16,487 --> 00:03:17,905
And we're not going to go?

34
00:03:18,031 --> 00:03:19,239
Uh, yes.

35
00:03:19,365 --> 00:03:21,491
Okay, in a -- in a minute.

36
00:03:21,618 --> 00:03:22,659
-Sebastian?
-What?

37
00:03:22,785 --> 00:03:24,661
-We've got enough.
-Already?

38
00:03:24,787 --> 00:03:27,789
We've got more than enough inside,
and this is pointless.

39
00:03:27,916 --> 00:03:30,167
We have to tell them to leave.

40
00:03:30,293 --> 00:03:32,544
Well, apologize to them.

41
00:03:32,670 --> 00:03:35,464
-This can't be.
-Come with me, please.

42
00:03:38,718 --> 00:03:40,761
Sorry, sorry.
We're very sorry, really.

43
00:03:40,887 --> 00:03:43,680
l'm sorry.
We don't need anyone else.

44
00:03:43,806 --> 00:03:45,933
No, we can't see everybody.
There are too many.

45
00:03:46,059 --> 00:03:48,685
No, no, you have to be able to.
We've been waiting for hours.

46
00:03:48,811 --> 00:03:51,230
You have to go, gentlemen.
We can't see anyone else.

47
00:03:51,356 --> 00:03:52,481
No, Ma'am, we're not leaving.

48
00:03:52,607 --> 00:03:54,066
We're going to wait here
until we're seen.

49
00:03:54,275 --> 00:03:56,443
-Listen, didn't you hear her?
-l did, but --

50
00:03:56,569 --> 00:03:57,736
You have to leave.

51
00:03:57,862 --> 00:03:58,820
You have to go.

52
00:03:59,030 --> 00:04:00,447
-Get out of here!
-Hey, bastard!

53
00:04:00,573 --> 00:04:02,324
Get out of here!
You have to leave!

54
00:04:02,450 --> 00:04:04,952
Enough! Enough!

55
00:04:05,078 --> 00:04:07,496
-Enough! Enough!
-What's going on?

56
00:04:09,958 --> 00:04:11,833
Easy, easy, easy, easy, easy!

57
00:04:11,960 --> 00:04:13,877
Calm down, calm down, calm down!

58
00:04:14,003 --> 00:04:16,004
What's wrong?

59
00:04:17,465 --> 00:04:19,091
"Everyone gets a chance."

60
00:04:19,217 --> 00:04:21,510
That's what it says.
And my girl wants to act.

61
00:04:21,636 --> 00:04:24,012
Yeah, her and 200 others,
but we can't see them all, understand?

62
00:04:24,138 --> 00:04:27,099
You don't understand, white face.
We've been waiting for hours.

63
00:04:27,225 --> 00:04:29,434
Some have come from very far
on foot.

64
00:04:29,560 --> 00:04:32,729
Now you tell us to leave.
You have to see all of us.

65
00:04:32,855 --> 00:04:34,606
We're not leaving
until you see us all.

66
00:04:34,732 --> 00:04:36,858
We're not moving from here!

67
00:04:39,279 --> 00:04:42,739
Tell him anything,
but get rid of him.

68
00:04:44,200 --> 00:04:45,534
-What's your name?
-Daniel.

69
00:04:45,660 --> 00:04:46,952
Daniel.

70
00:04:47,078 --> 00:04:50,163
All right, Daniel's right.
We're going to see everyone.

71
00:04:50,290 --> 00:04:51,832
-Fuck!
-Okay?

72
00:04:51,958 --> 00:04:54,418
We'll see you all,
no matter how long it takes.

73
00:04:54,544 --> 00:04:55,585
Sebastian, we have to leave.

74
00:04:55,712 --> 00:04:59,631
Yes, calmly, though, calmly.
Okay? Okay.

75
00:04:59,757 --> 00:05:01,633
Film that bastard for me.

76
00:05:01,759 --> 00:05:04,469
And his daughter, too.
He's good.

77
00:05:04,595 --> 00:05:07,306
Okay, as you heard,
we're going to see everyone.

78
00:05:28,494 --> 00:05:29,911
-Let's go!
-Let's go.

79
00:05:46,095 --> 00:05:52,309
EVEN THE RAlN

80
00:05:56,939 --> 00:05:58,565
Costa, are you crazy?

81
00:05:58,691 --> 00:06:00,942
Slow down!

82
00:06:01,277 --> 00:06:03,153
Sebastian, tell me something.

83
00:06:03,279 --> 00:06:07,240
We're in Bolivia.
lt doesn't make much sense.

84
00:06:07,367 --> 00:06:10,911
Because we're 7,500 feet
above sea level,

85
00:06:11,037 --> 00:06:12,412
surrounded by mountains,

86
00:06:12,538 --> 00:06:14,081
and thousands of miles
from the Caribbean.

87
00:06:14,207 --> 00:06:17,084
Well, Costa thinks
Columbus landed by parachute.

88
00:06:17,210 --> 00:06:20,545
No, Costa knows this place
is full of starving natives,

89
00:06:20,671 --> 00:06:22,839
and that means thousands of extras.

90
00:06:22,965 --> 00:06:24,800
None of that digital shit.

91
00:06:24,926 --> 00:06:26,885
l want scale,
all the money up on the screen.

92
00:06:27,011 --> 00:06:29,304
No, Costa, no.
This could be a mess, really.

93
00:06:29,430 --> 00:06:31,390
Have you seen their faces?
Please, they're Quechua.

94
00:06:31,516 --> 00:06:32,891
-So?
-What do you mean, "so?"

95
00:06:33,017 --> 00:06:34,518
They're from the Andes!

96
00:06:34,644 --> 00:06:37,396
What's Columbus doing
with natives from the Andes?

97
00:06:37,522 --> 00:06:39,773
From the Andes or wherever,
they're natives.

98
00:06:39,899 --> 00:06:42,943
-That's what you wanted, isn't it?
-Oh, no, no, no, no.

99
00:06:43,069 --> 00:06:45,737
Give me a fucking break.
They're all the same.

100
00:06:45,863 --> 00:06:46,613
No.

101
00:06:46,739 --> 00:06:51,535
You can negotiate things here --
hotels, transport, catering, whatever.

102
00:06:51,661 --> 00:06:53,537
So, it's about money.

103
00:06:53,663 --> 00:06:55,747
Yes, yes!
lt's always money, always, always.

104
00:06:55,873 --> 00:06:58,125
Well, in this case,
very little money, right?

105
00:06:58,251 --> 00:07:00,585
Right, you miserable cheapskate?

106
00:07:00,711 --> 00:07:03,296
lf we'd filmed in English,
we'd have double the money

107
00:07:03,423 --> 00:07:04,464
and double the audience.

108
00:07:04,590 --> 00:07:06,299
Almost had the deal done
till you fucked it up.

109
00:07:06,426 --> 00:07:08,468
Because Spaniards speak Spanish.

110
00:07:08,594 --> 00:07:10,762
What if we'd done it in English?

111
00:07:10,888 --> 00:07:12,180
We'd have been fucking smart.

112
00:07:12,306 --> 00:07:14,516
So, the Spaniards speak Spanish,

113
00:07:14,642 --> 00:07:18,854
and the Tainos that Columbus found
speak Quechua?

114
00:07:18,980 --> 00:07:21,398
ls that how you're going to be?

115
00:07:21,524 --> 00:07:24,276
l just want to know.
l just want to know.

116
00:07:24,402 --> 00:07:29,448
We'll do it, Sebastian!

117
00:07:33,619 --> 00:07:35,203
Up!

118
00:07:35,329 --> 00:07:37,247
Come on, come on, come on!
That's it!

119
00:07:37,373 --> 00:07:40,125
Careful!
Costa, slowly, it's very dangerous!

120
00:07:40,251 --> 00:07:41,835
Come on, come on, come on.

121
00:07:41,961 --> 00:07:43,628
Pull it up!

122
00:07:44,255 --> 00:07:46,381
-Careful! Careful!
-Watch out!

123
00:07:50,928 --> 00:07:52,762
Everyone all right?

124
00:07:52,889 --> 00:07:55,932
Okay, let's see if we can do this.
Come on!

125
00:07:56,058 --> 00:07:57,934
No, Costa, please.
We have to do it some other way!

126
00:07:58,603 --> 00:08:00,353
lt has to be done another way, please.

127
00:08:00,480 --> 00:08:01,813
One, two, three. . .

128
00:08:01,939 --> 00:08:03,940
Up!

129
00:08:04,066 --> 00:08:05,942
One, two, three. . .

130
00:08:06,068 --> 00:08:07,652
Up!

131
00:08:10,448 --> 00:08:12,032
Once more, on three.

132
00:08:12,158 --> 00:08:14,034
One, two, three. . .

133
00:08:14,160 --> 00:08:15,577
Up!

134
00:08:22,210 --> 00:08:22,959
Alley-oop!

135
00:08:23,085 --> 00:08:26,171
Listen, Costa, we should've gotten
professionals and used a crane!

136
00:08:26,297 --> 00:08:28,507
Things can't be done like that.
Someone could get hurt!

137
00:08:28,633 --> 00:08:30,759
Yeah, and an engineer, too.

138
00:08:30,885 --> 00:08:32,469
Do you know how much we've saved?

139
00:08:32,595 --> 00:08:36,765
35,000, so calm down.
lt's all done.

140
00:08:36,891 --> 00:08:38,767
Great work, guys.

141
00:08:38,893 --> 00:08:40,977
The beers are on me.

142
00:08:41,103 --> 00:08:42,854
Turn that fucking thing off!

143
00:08:52,114 --> 00:08:55,450
-Sorry.
-lt's okay.

144
00:08:58,746 --> 00:09:01,498
l hope l can get through this.

145
00:09:23,771 --> 00:09:25,730
ls he drunk?

146
00:09:27,233 --> 00:09:28,858
Are we all here?

147
00:09:28,985 --> 00:09:30,235
We are now.

148
00:09:30,361 --> 00:09:33,863
All right, when you're ready.

149
00:09:34,991 --> 00:09:39,494
"We see the stunned faces of Taino
children hiding in the bushes.

150
00:09:39,620 --> 00:09:40,704
From their point of view,

151
00:09:40,830 --> 00:09:44,666
we see Columbus and his men
landing in the New World.

152
00:09:44,792 --> 00:09:47,002
Some small boats are on the shore.

153
00:09:47,128 --> 00:09:49,087
The children are hit
by a disgusting smell

154
00:09:49,213 --> 00:09:52,132
while the strange creatures,
wet and dirty,

155
00:09:52,258 --> 00:09:56,886
some bearded, others bald,
stumble on the sand.

156
00:09:57,013 --> 00:10:00,140
The children laugh
and make comments,

157
00:10:00,266 --> 00:10:02,183
trying to understand
who these strangers are --"

158
00:10:02,310 --> 00:10:05,937
l, Christopher Columbus,

159
00:10:06,063 --> 00:10:09,065
humble servant
of King Ferdinand of Aragon

160
00:10:09,191 --> 00:10:11,693
and Queen lsabella of Castile,

161
00:10:11,819 --> 00:10:13,695
in the name of Jesus Christ,

162
00:10:13,821 --> 00:10:16,865
Son of the one true God,

163
00:10:16,991 --> 00:10:20,744
take possession of these lands
and seas

164
00:10:20,870 --> 00:10:24,956
and all they contain.

165
00:10:25,082 --> 00:10:27,375
And with this act. . .

166
00:10:31,380 --> 00:10:34,674
. . .l proclaim sovereignty
over these lands and seas

167
00:10:34,800 --> 00:10:38,094
on behalf of their most
gracious Majesties.

168
00:10:42,600 --> 00:10:45,060
Let us thank the Virgin Mother

169
00:10:45,186 --> 00:10:49,898
for delivering us with good health
to this great triumph.

170
00:11:18,844 --> 00:11:21,554
This must be their village.

171
00:11:21,681 --> 00:11:25,308
Thank God, they look peaceful.

172
00:11:25,434 --> 00:11:28,186
A good site for a fortress.

173
00:11:28,312 --> 00:11:30,772
Mingle with them.

174
00:11:30,898 --> 00:11:33,650
The first man to find gold
will be rewarded.

175
00:11:33,776 --> 00:11:35,402
Captain. . .

176
00:11:35,528 --> 00:11:37,153
treat them well.

177
00:11:37,279 --> 00:11:39,698
We need their food.

178
00:11:42,702 --> 00:11:45,537
And find out what arms they have.

179
00:11:49,875 --> 00:11:50,917
Admiral!

180
00:11:51,043 --> 00:11:53,294
Quickly!
You have to see this!

181
00:12:09,186 --> 00:12:10,478
-Gold!
-Gold.

182
00:12:10,604 --> 00:12:13,940
-Gold.
-Gold.

183
00:12:14,066 --> 00:12:15,108
lt's gold.

184
00:12:15,234 --> 00:12:17,360
Where is the gold?

185
00:12:17,486 --> 00:12:19,738
Gold!

186
00:12:19,864 --> 00:12:23,158
Where is the gold?

187
00:12:23,284 --> 00:12:26,453
You know what l'm talking about!
Gold!

188
00:12:28,456 --> 00:12:30,331
Where is it?!

189
00:12:35,045 --> 00:12:36,921
Who gives a shit about gold?

190
00:12:37,047 --> 00:12:40,258
l need a fucking drink!

191
00:12:40,384 --> 00:12:41,593
Forgive me, Miss.

192
00:12:41,719 --> 00:12:44,137
We actors are totally selfish.

193
00:12:44,263 --> 00:12:46,514
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.

194
00:12:49,727 --> 00:12:51,770
Remember him?

195
00:12:59,487 --> 00:13:01,863
See the look in his eyes?

196
00:13:01,989 --> 00:13:05,366
The piercing stare, really deep.

197
00:13:05,493 --> 00:13:07,660
He's little,
but he's got great presence.

198
00:13:07,787 --> 00:13:10,038
Yeah, and he stinks of trouble, too.

199
00:13:10,164 --> 00:13:12,582
-And he's never acted in his life.
-No, but l'm the director.

200
00:13:12,708 --> 00:13:14,584
lt's an advantage.
He's very natural.

201
00:13:14,710 --> 00:13:16,586
What about the Peruvian actor?

202
00:13:16,712 --> 00:13:21,257
He's terrible, totally predictable.
No. No, no.

203
00:13:21,383 --> 00:13:22,675
But this one's a troublemaker.

204
00:13:22,802 --> 00:13:25,553
You saw what he stirred up
at the casting the other day.

205
00:13:25,679 --> 00:13:28,139
He's a leader.
You're looking for a leader.

206
00:13:28,265 --> 00:13:32,018
Costa. . .
l want him and his daughter.

207
00:13:32,144 --> 00:13:34,395
No, don't fuck with me, l don't
want this guy on the fucking shoot.

208
00:13:34,522 --> 00:13:36,064
He'll wreck it.
l don't want him. That's it.

209
00:13:36,190 --> 00:13:39,359
Let me show you something.
Look.

210
00:13:39,485 --> 00:13:40,819
-What's this?
-Who's that?

211
00:13:40,945 --> 00:13:43,154
l know perfectly well who it is.
When did you shoot this?

212
00:13:43,280 --> 00:13:46,282
-This morning.
-Without telling me?

213
00:13:46,408 --> 00:13:48,201
Look, look, look!

214
00:13:49,245 --> 00:13:52,288
Hatuey! Fuck, it's Hatuey!

215
00:13:52,414 --> 00:13:54,040
-Right?
-He's very good.

216
00:13:54,166 --> 00:13:56,292
-lt's amazing!
-Okay, he's Hatuey, fantastic.

217
00:13:56,418 --> 00:13:57,585
You're not going to be able
to control this guy.

218
00:13:57,711 --> 00:14:00,880
You're going to regret it.
Just remember l told you so.

219
00:14:04,468 --> 00:14:07,262
He's right in a way.

220
00:14:07,388 --> 00:14:10,473
But the film comes first, always.

221
00:14:19,733 --> 00:14:22,360
As governor of this island,

222
00:14:22,486 --> 00:14:25,321
l want to thank you
for coming to see me.

223
00:14:29,952 --> 00:14:31,661
After my first voyage,

224
00:14:31,787 --> 00:14:34,289
l spoke personally
with their Majesties,

225
00:14:34,415 --> 00:14:38,877
who instructed me to treat you
with respect and cordiality.

226
00:14:39,003 --> 00:14:42,630
We ask that you recognize
the Church and the Pope

227
00:14:42,756 --> 00:14:44,382
as rulers of the universe.

228
00:14:48,762 --> 00:14:52,140
And also that you accept the King

229
00:14:52,266 --> 00:14:54,726
and the Queen of Spain

230
00:14:54,852 --> 00:14:57,312
as rulers of these lands.

231
00:15:03,152 --> 00:15:04,193
ln exchange,

232
00:15:04,320 --> 00:15:07,989
you will receive our love
and our charity.

233
00:15:14,955 --> 00:15:16,289
And if we do not?

234
00:15:16,415 --> 00:15:18,583
Captain. . .

235
00:15:18,709 --> 00:15:21,169
lf not. . .

236
00:15:21,295 --> 00:15:25,465
we will enslave you
and dispose of you as we wish.

237
00:15:25,591 --> 00:15:28,092
We will seize your possessions,

238
00:15:28,218 --> 00:15:31,387
and we will do you
as much harm as we can.

239
00:15:41,649 --> 00:15:44,275
What do you want from us?

240
00:15:49,740 --> 00:15:51,282
Taxes.

241
00:15:52,952 --> 00:15:56,704
Every lndian over the age of 1 4
must fill a bell.

242
00:16:05,881 --> 00:16:06,589
What did he say?

243
00:16:06,715 --> 00:16:08,925
With what?

244
00:16:09,051 --> 00:16:11,427
With gold. Here.

245
00:16:13,097 --> 00:16:14,389
lt isn't very big.

246
00:16:16,517 --> 00:16:18,101
Captain.

247
00:16:28,570 --> 00:16:31,072
Alberto, can you tell us
about your character?

248
00:16:31,198 --> 00:16:34,450
Well, my character is
Bartolome de las Casas.

249
00:16:34,576 --> 00:16:37,954
He came to the lndies when he was 1 8
to take charge of a plantation

250
00:16:38,080 --> 00:16:41,124
and the lndian slaves
who worked there.

251
00:16:41,250 --> 00:16:46,045
But later, traumatized
by the massacres he witnessed,

252
00:16:46,171 --> 00:16:49,507
he devoted his life to the lndians.

253
00:16:49,633 --> 00:16:50,758
He became a Dominican.

254
00:16:50,884 --> 00:16:52,593
He was nearly murdered twice.

255
00:16:52,720 --> 00:16:55,179
On his deathbed --
and l'm quoting verbatim.

256
00:16:55,305 --> 00:16:57,265
Don't laugh, listen.

257
00:16:57,391 --> 00:16:58,391
He said,

258
00:16:58,517 --> 00:17:01,519
"l condemn the blindness
of those who ignore the genocide

259
00:17:01,645 --> 00:17:03,187
and give orders to the world."

260
00:17:03,313 --> 00:17:06,482
This guy was the father
of international law,

261
00:17:06,608 --> 00:17:09,027
and l'm only in eight scenes!

262
00:17:09,153 --> 00:17:10,153
And you, Juan?

263
00:17:10,279 --> 00:17:12,488
l play Antonio Montesinos.

264
00:17:12,614 --> 00:17:16,200
Sebastian gave me 20 books to read,
but l'm not a reader like him.

265
00:17:16,326 --> 00:17:19,370
My character isn't
as famous as Bartolome,

266
00:17:19,496 --> 00:17:20,830
but he's more important.

267
00:17:20,956 --> 00:17:22,206
He's more important than Bartolome

268
00:17:22,332 --> 00:17:24,834
because l was the first to intercede
for the lndians.

269
00:17:24,960 --> 00:17:28,838
l was the one who started everything
and gave that famous sermon --

270
00:17:28,964 --> 00:17:31,716
"l am the voice of Christ
in the desert of this island,

271
00:17:31,842 --> 00:17:34,302
and you are in mortal sin!"

272
00:17:34,428 --> 00:17:35,803
That was me.

273
00:17:35,929 --> 00:17:40,099
Daniel, can you tell me
what made you do this film?

274
00:17:40,225 --> 00:17:41,225
What do you mean?

275
00:17:41,351 --> 00:17:44,645
What did you like
about your character?

276
00:17:44,772 --> 00:17:49,233
Maybe he represents
native resistance

277
00:17:49,359 --> 00:17:52,695
or shows colonization
from a different angle?

278
00:17:52,821 --> 00:17:54,489
He just wants the money!

279
00:17:54,615 --> 00:17:55,531
What?

280
00:17:55,657 --> 00:17:57,533
He just wants the money!

281
00:17:58,619 --> 00:17:59,869
Do you have love scenes?

282
00:17:59,995 --> 00:18:01,454
How many girls do you kiss?

283
00:18:01,580 --> 00:18:03,664
Do you have to strip off?

284
00:18:03,791 --> 00:18:05,666
A little squirt like you!

285
00:18:05,793 --> 00:18:08,544
No, guys.

286
00:18:08,670 --> 00:18:09,670
What are you digging?

287
00:18:09,797 --> 00:18:14,300
We're running out of water here,
and between all of us, we've bought --

288
00:18:14,426 --> 00:18:16,552
See that hill?

289
00:18:16,678 --> 00:18:21,349
We bought a well there,
and now we're digging a ditch.

290
00:18:21,475 --> 00:18:23,893
lt's about 7 kilometers long.

291
00:18:24,728 --> 00:18:27,522
-7 kilometers?
-Yes, 7 kilometers.

292
00:18:27,648 --> 00:18:32,985
We're digging a ditch to bring
the pipeline along the hillside

293
00:18:33,112 --> 00:18:34,821
and have water here.

294
00:18:34,947 --> 00:18:37,031
Why are you here?

295
00:18:37,157 --> 00:18:39,492
We're making a documentary
about the film.

296
00:18:39,618 --> 00:18:43,037
You're asking a lot of questions.
Daniel, don't trust her.

297
00:18:43,163 --> 00:18:45,623
Here come the bastards.

298
00:18:57,052 --> 00:18:59,762
They're stopping.

299
00:18:59,888 --> 00:19:03,391
They've stopped.
What do they want?

300
00:19:11,066 --> 00:19:13,734
What the fuck do you want here?

301
00:19:15,237 --> 00:19:17,613
What are you looking for?
What are you looking for here?

302
00:19:17,739 --> 00:19:19,699
What are you looking for?

303
00:19:48,187 --> 00:19:49,812
-How do you say "food"?
-Mikuna.

304
00:19:51,064 --> 00:19:54,692
-How do you say "lt was delicious"?
-Ancha miski.

305
00:19:56,528 --> 00:19:58,112
How do you say "l love you"?

306
00:19:58,238 --> 00:19:59,822
Anchata munaiki.

307
00:20:04,620 --> 00:20:06,412
-And "wine"?
-Vino also.

308
00:20:06,538 --> 00:20:08,289
-And "water"?
-Yaku.

309
00:20:09,499 --> 00:20:10,958
l'll have some yaku.

310
00:20:11,084 --> 00:20:12,835
Nothing like getting into character.

311
00:20:12,961 --> 00:20:15,213
God bless you, Father.

312
00:20:15,339 --> 00:20:18,674
Why not fill a plastic bag
with the leftovers from this meal,

313
00:20:18,800 --> 00:20:20,593
which costs more
than what they earn in a month,

314
00:20:20,719 --> 00:20:22,970
and give it to them,
so their scrawny children

315
00:20:23,096 --> 00:20:25,181
can gobble it up
like starving rodents!

316
00:20:25,307 --> 00:20:28,059
Then you'll feel
like a real missionary.

317
00:20:28,185 --> 00:20:32,396
Anton, relax.
lt's Saturday night.

318
00:20:32,522 --> 00:20:35,775
How long will you remember
that "water" is yaku?

319
00:20:43,116 --> 00:20:46,702
That's not very pious, Father,
but the director will cut it out,

320
00:20:46,828 --> 00:20:48,537
along with other important details.

321
00:20:48,664 --> 00:20:52,833
For example, the fact that Las Casas
wanted black slaves from Africa

322
00:20:52,960 --> 00:20:55,336
to replace the lndians.

323
00:20:55,462 --> 00:20:57,046
Why not put that in the film?

324
00:20:57,172 --> 00:20:58,714
Don't let him needle you.

325
00:20:58,840 --> 00:21:01,634
No, no, no, but -- but, no,
it's true. lt's true.

326
00:21:01,760 --> 00:21:05,054
He did think that when he was young,
but for a very short time.

327
00:21:05,180 --> 00:21:07,473
He always regretted it.

328
00:21:07,599 --> 00:21:10,059
-And his deal with the slave traders?
-What?

329
00:21:10,185 --> 00:21:12,144
A mistake, a disaster
that ashamed him.

330
00:21:12,271 --> 00:21:14,897
Don't lose your marbles, Reverend.

331
00:21:15,023 --> 00:21:17,775
l'm not, l'm just informing you.

332
00:21:17,901 --> 00:21:21,612
Until his dying breath,
Las Casas condemned corrupt bishops,

333
00:21:21,738 --> 00:21:23,447
merchants, royal officials. . .

334
00:21:23,573 --> 00:21:24,949
The whole State hated him.

335
00:21:25,075 --> 00:21:27,952
-They hated him?
-Yes. Listen to me.

336
00:21:28,078 --> 00:21:31,205
He said the lndians had been
sacrificed, and l quote,

337
00:21:31,331 --> 00:21:35,751
"for private appetites and profits,"
500 years ago.

338
00:21:35,877 --> 00:21:40,840
Then cynics like you try to reduce
his life to one mistake.

339
00:21:40,966 --> 00:21:44,385
Like in football,
history is always cruel to the losers.

340
00:21:44,511 --> 00:21:47,263
Just cut them out
and make the film about me!

341
00:21:47,389 --> 00:21:48,639
l'm better-looking, right?

342
00:21:48,765 --> 00:21:51,183
More handsome than him.

343
00:21:51,310 --> 00:21:53,644
He never -- Beto.

344
00:21:53,770 --> 00:21:57,231
He never questioned Spanish authority
over the New World or royal authority.

345
00:21:57,357 --> 00:22:00,693
ln other words,
he was a conservative.

346
00:22:00,819 --> 00:22:02,778
He was a radical!
A radical!

347
00:22:02,904 --> 00:22:06,157
He demanded that lndians be treated
equally as Spaniards!

348
00:22:06,283 --> 00:22:07,616
Under the Crown!

349
00:22:07,743 --> 00:22:12,079
But with the lndians' consent.
He was ahead of his time.

350
00:22:12,205 --> 00:22:16,125
How the fuck
did Disney pass on this?

351
00:22:16,251 --> 00:22:17,460
You have an agenda.

352
00:22:17,586 --> 00:22:20,546
You sanctify this pair of bastards
and string me up!

353
00:22:20,672 --> 00:22:24,258
This isn't art.
lt's pure propaganda.

354
00:22:24,384 --> 00:22:26,844
-So why are you here?
-What?

355
00:22:26,970 --> 00:22:28,304
Why the hell are you doing it?

356
00:22:28,430 --> 00:22:30,348
For the gold!

357
00:22:31,016 --> 00:22:33,517
And for Jesus Christ!

358
00:22:33,643 --> 00:22:36,687
May l say something?
Just one thing?

359
00:22:36,813 --> 00:22:41,275
l am the voice of Christ
in the desert of this island!

360
00:22:41,401 --> 00:22:45,279
And you are in mortal sin!

361
00:22:45,405 --> 00:22:47,823
Good night, Cochabamba!

362
00:22:59,795 --> 00:23:03,130
What are you doing?

363
00:23:03,507 --> 00:23:05,424
Get the other padlock.

364
00:23:05,550 --> 00:23:07,426
What are you doing?
Why did you break the padlock?

365
00:23:07,552 --> 00:23:09,428
What are you doing to the well?

366
00:23:09,554 --> 00:23:14,892
We dug this well with our own hands
so our children could drink.

367
00:23:15,018 --> 00:23:17,228
You've got no right
to close the well!

368
00:23:17,354 --> 00:23:19,230
How can we live with dirty water?

369
00:23:19,356 --> 00:23:22,108
You take our lands,
you take our wells.

370
00:23:22,234 --> 00:23:25,486
Are you going to take the air, too?

371
00:23:26,238 --> 00:23:28,155
We're not paying more money.

372
00:23:28,281 --> 00:23:31,784
Don't all talk --
don't all talk at the same time.

373
00:23:31,910 --> 00:23:33,619
Listen to me.
Listen to me.

374
00:23:33,745 --> 00:23:36,163
These men are doing their job.

375
00:23:36,289 --> 00:23:38,457
What job?
Taking our water?

376
00:23:38,583 --> 00:23:40,501
No, Ma'am, it's not that.

377
00:23:40,627 --> 00:23:43,838
The well is ours.

378
00:23:43,964 --> 00:23:47,091
Water for our families,
for our children.

379
00:23:47,217 --> 00:23:48,926
You are fathers, too.

380
00:23:49,052 --> 00:23:51,220
So don't put another lock on there,

381
00:23:51,346 --> 00:23:54,348
otherwise we're going to fight you
all the way!

382
00:24:02,482 --> 00:24:05,234
The water is for our children!

383
00:24:05,360 --> 00:24:09,113
This water is for our children!

384
00:24:09,990 --> 00:24:13,075
Don't take away our kids' water!

385
00:24:30,677 --> 00:24:35,931
All right, it's March of 1 51 1 .

386
00:24:37,017 --> 00:24:40,936
Boys! 1 0 minutes.
Thank you. Thank you.

387
00:24:41,062 --> 00:24:42,646
Okay, March of 1 51 1 .

388
00:24:42,772 --> 00:24:46,150
The Dominicans gather the rich
and powerful of Santo Domingo

389
00:24:46,276 --> 00:24:47,443
to listen to the sermon.

390
00:24:49,654 --> 00:24:51,238
Bartolome is sitting there.

391
00:24:51,364 --> 00:24:53,240
-Here?
-Yes, exactly, here.

392
00:24:53,366 --> 00:24:56,702
He's just like the others.
He still has lndians and lands.

393
00:24:56,828 --> 00:24:58,120
Okay? Yes?

394
00:24:58,246 --> 00:25:00,748
So, yes, you're back there.

395
00:25:00,874 --> 00:25:02,875
We hear the hymn in Latin.

396
00:25:04,044 --> 00:25:07,671
lt ends.
A slight pause.

397
00:25:07,797 --> 00:25:10,841
You exchange a look with Bartolome.

398
00:25:12,385 --> 00:25:14,386
And we begin.

399
00:25:18,433 --> 00:25:24,897
The Pharisees sent someone
to ask John the Baptist who he was.

400
00:25:25,023 --> 00:25:31,695
And he replied, "l am a voice
crying in the wilderness."

401
00:25:33,949 --> 00:25:39,578
The lndians mine the gold
which builds our cities

402
00:25:39,704 --> 00:25:42,164
and even our churches.

403
00:25:42,290 --> 00:25:46,168
Gold finances our conquests
in far distant parts

404
00:25:46,294 --> 00:25:48,796
and so the great wheel
of commerce turns.

405
00:25:49,464 --> 00:25:51,966
Not one of us is untouched
by lndian sweat,

406
00:25:52,092 --> 00:25:55,344
least of all His Majesty
and his bishops!

407
00:25:56,972 --> 00:26:02,268
As a priest, l must follow
Gospel imperatives,

408
00:26:02,394 --> 00:26:05,729
the first of which
is to preach the truth.

409
00:26:07,274 --> 00:26:10,609
l am the voice of Christ
in the desert of this island,

410
00:26:10,735 --> 00:26:12,736
and you are in mortal sin!

411
00:26:12,862 --> 00:26:14,655
What's he saying?
This man's gone mad!

412
00:26:14,781 --> 00:26:16,991
You live in sin, and you die in it!

413
00:26:17,117 --> 00:26:18,409
Why?

414
00:26:18,535 --> 00:26:22,997
Because of the cruel tyranny
you impose on these innocents!

415
00:26:23,123 --> 00:26:25,916
Tell me by what right
and with what justice

416
00:26:26,042 --> 00:26:30,170
you keep these lndians
in such cruel, horrible slavery.

417
00:26:30,297 --> 00:26:32,131
They were living peacefully
on their land!

418
00:26:32,257 --> 00:26:33,382
This is outrageous!

419
00:26:33,508 --> 00:26:37,261
By what authority have you
waged such terrible war on them?

420
00:26:37,512 --> 00:26:42,891
By what right do you keep them
so oppressed, starved, and exhausted?

421
00:26:43,018 --> 00:26:46,562
They're dying because of you.
Or rather, you murder them!

422
00:26:46,688 --> 00:26:49,440
What a disgrace!
This is intolerable!

423
00:26:49,566 --> 00:26:51,483
How can you be so asleep?

424
00:26:51,610 --> 00:26:56,071
How can you be so deep inside
that lethargic dream?

425
00:26:56,197 --> 00:26:58,073
Look into the lndians' eyes.

426
00:26:58,199 --> 00:27:00,659
Are these not men?

427
00:27:00,785 --> 00:27:04,121
Do they not have rational souls?

428
00:27:04,247 --> 00:27:09,043
Are you not obliged
to love them as yourselves?

429
00:27:10,253 --> 00:27:12,171
Who do you think you are?

430
00:27:12,297 --> 00:27:14,798
Your sermon today
has called into question

431
00:27:14,924 --> 00:27:16,925
my authority and that of the King.

432
00:27:17,052 --> 00:27:20,971
You know that the lndian concessions
are all legal.

433
00:27:21,097 --> 00:27:25,309
l demand an official retraction,
Father Montesinos.

434
00:27:28,980 --> 00:27:32,316
The truth has many enemies.

435
00:27:32,442 --> 00:27:35,152
The lie has many friends.

436
00:27:37,614 --> 00:27:40,991
This is a capital offense!
Hang the traitor! Burn him!

437
00:27:41,117 --> 00:27:45,412
Montesinos, go back to Spain
before we cut out your tongue!

438
00:27:49,709 --> 00:27:51,043
Very good.

439
00:27:51,169 --> 00:27:52,461
He goes right for them, doesn't he?

440
00:27:52,587 --> 00:27:54,963
Yes, this man never retracted.

441
00:27:55,090 --> 00:27:57,299
No, the next Saturday,
he preached the same sermon.

442
00:27:57,425 --> 00:28:00,344
He continued denouncing them like that
for years until they killed him.

443
00:28:00,470 --> 00:28:01,345
ln Venezuela.

444
00:28:01,471 --> 00:28:06,684
Yes, he was the first voice
of conscience against an empire.

445
00:28:07,268 --> 00:28:10,896
Like that,
from a little church like this.

446
00:28:11,856 --> 00:28:13,440
-Okay?
-Yes.

447
00:28:13,566 --> 00:28:15,150
To the dressing room.

448
00:28:15,276 --> 00:28:17,444
Great.

449
00:28:17,570 --> 00:28:20,030
-Great.
-You can continue.

450
00:28:36,840 --> 00:28:39,883
They sell our rivers against our will.

451
00:28:40,009 --> 00:28:42,845
They sell our wells, our lakes. . .

452
00:28:42,971 --> 00:28:46,515
and even the rain
that falls on our heads!

453
00:28:46,641 --> 00:28:48,517
By law!

454
00:28:48,643 --> 00:28:49,852
Friends, it's incredible!

455
00:28:49,978 --> 00:28:52,563
They don't allow us to collect
the water that falls from the rain,

456
00:28:52,689 --> 00:28:54,022
by law!

457
00:28:54,149 --> 00:28:57,192
And who takes even the rain?

458
00:28:57,318 --> 00:29:01,071
A company whose owners
are in London and California.

459
00:29:01,906 --> 00:29:04,742
Friends, what are they
going to steal next?

460
00:29:04,868 --> 00:29:07,244
The vapor from our breath?

461
00:29:07,370 --> 00:29:09,830
The sweat from our brow?

462
00:29:09,956 --> 00:29:14,084
All they'll get from me is piss!

463
00:29:22,343 --> 00:29:24,470
Take it easy, comrades!

464
00:29:24,596 --> 00:29:26,764
Take it easy, comrades. . .

465
00:29:32,353 --> 00:29:35,397
Costa, they say that they want
to mobilize thousands.

466
00:29:35,523 --> 00:29:36,565
-So?
-From the countryside. . .

467
00:29:36,691 --> 00:29:38,567
. . .from the city, the unions.

468
00:29:38,693 --> 00:29:41,236
People are furious.

469
00:29:41,362 --> 00:29:43,489
No wonder,
they're taking their water.

470
00:29:43,615 --> 00:29:45,491
They're taking their water.

471
00:29:45,617 --> 00:29:47,785
-Enough.
-lmagine a documentary about this.

472
00:29:47,911 --> 00:29:49,244
Costa, let me do it.

473
00:29:49,370 --> 00:29:50,662
No, l'm not spending another penny.

474
00:29:50,789 --> 00:29:53,248
Costa, they're going to raise hell.

475
00:29:53,374 --> 00:29:56,168
And if we don't tell the story, we're
going to let a great chance escape.

476
00:29:56,294 --> 00:29:58,545
l said no!
l'm not a fucking NGO!

477
00:29:58,671 --> 00:30:00,380
This story has nothing to do with me.

478
00:30:01,132 --> 00:30:03,383
But you're in the middle of it!

479
00:30:12,393 --> 00:30:14,394
Come in.

480
00:30:16,105 --> 00:30:18,023
Shit, the big boss himself.

481
00:30:18,149 --> 00:30:20,567
Told you need a hand with this.

482
00:30:20,693 --> 00:30:21,443
You?

483
00:30:21,569 --> 00:30:23,737
Come in, come in.

484
00:30:23,863 --> 00:30:27,199
No one else dares enter
the ogre's den.

485
00:30:27,325 --> 00:30:29,493
lt's me, again.

486
00:30:29,619 --> 00:30:32,371
l've tried all the numbers.

487
00:30:32,497 --> 00:30:34,498
There's no way l can contact you.
What's wrong?

488
00:30:34,624 --> 00:30:37,376
Don't the kids have my number?
And the little one?

489
00:30:41,422 --> 00:30:43,465
Call me.

490
00:30:45,134 --> 00:30:48,262
Fucking machines.

491
00:30:50,348 --> 00:30:51,807
You got a family?

492
00:30:52,600 --> 00:30:55,185
Yes, a boy of 1 4.

493
00:30:56,396 --> 00:30:58,522
What's he like?

494
00:31:01,818 --> 00:31:05,445
Well, to be honest, l have no idea.
He lives with his mother.

495
00:31:06,155 --> 00:31:09,157
This business fucks up families.

496
00:31:10,743 --> 00:31:12,327
Here.

497
00:31:14,247 --> 00:31:16,331
Something wrong, Anton?

498
00:31:19,085 --> 00:31:20,335
My bloody head!

499
00:31:20,461 --> 00:31:23,380
l can't remember
the fucking beginning.

500
00:31:23,506 --> 00:31:25,007
Start at the beginning.

501
00:31:25,133 --> 00:31:26,425
"They are so naive --"

502
00:31:26,551 --> 00:31:29,595
They are so naive
and generous with what they have

503
00:31:29,721 --> 00:31:31,930
that they never refuse anything.

504
00:31:32,056 --> 00:31:35,350
Whatever they have, if you ask them
for it, they will give it to you,

505
00:31:35,476 --> 00:31:38,854
inviting the person
to share it with them.

506
00:31:39,772 --> 00:31:43,859
l have still not found out
if they have private property.

507
00:31:45,528 --> 00:31:47,446
With just 50 men,

508
00:31:47,572 --> 00:31:51,325
you could subdue them
and make them do whatever you want.

509
00:31:53,077 --> 00:31:55,454
Whatever you want.

510
00:31:57,874 --> 00:32:01,251
-On the first --
-On the first island l found. . .

511
00:32:01,377 --> 00:32:03,837
. . .l took several by force.

512
00:32:03,963 --> 00:32:06,131
Your Majesties will see

513
00:32:06,257 --> 00:32:11,053
that l will give you all the gold you
desire in exchange for a little help.

514
00:32:11,179 --> 00:32:14,598
Besides spices and cotton,
there are slaves,

515
00:32:14,724 --> 00:32:17,309


as many as you require.

516
00:32:17,518 --> 00:32:24,358
All of Christendom should be joyful
and solemnly thank the Holy Trinity

517
00:32:24,484 --> 00:32:28,654
for having converted so many souls
to the holy faith,

518
00:32:28,780 --> 00:32:33,283
and for the countless
material benefits

519
00:32:33,409 --> 00:32:35,035
this will bring us,

520
00:32:35,161 --> 00:32:39,081
since not only Spain,
but all of Christendom

521
00:32:39,207 --> 00:32:45,170
will enjoy solace and profit.

522
00:32:46,047 --> 00:32:50,008
No wonder you can't remember it.
No one talks like that.

523
00:32:50,218 --> 00:32:55,097
That is exactly the first letter
Columbus sent from the New World

524
00:32:55,223 --> 00:32:56,848
to the Spanish Crown.

525
00:32:56,975 --> 00:33:00,268
That's why Sebastian
is so faithful to the text.

526
00:33:00,395 --> 00:33:03,689
l don't know if it'll work.
lt's a little risky, but l like it.

527
00:33:03,815 --> 00:33:08,986
But if he'd just
give me some space to present

528
00:33:09,195 --> 00:33:12,030
the man, with his doubts,
his anxieties. . .

529
00:33:12,156 --> 00:33:13,156
Tell him.

530
00:33:21,332 --> 00:33:26,878
-Why do you drink so much, Anton?
-Because l'm always. . .

531
00:33:27,005 --> 00:33:32,426
very. . . very thirsty.

532
00:33:33,928 --> 00:33:36,805
But can you get through this?

533
00:33:36,931 --> 00:33:39,349
We are screwed without you.

534
00:33:42,937 --> 00:33:46,648
lt's great to feel needed.

535
00:33:56,784 --> 00:33:59,077
Look at the size of it.

536
00:33:59,328 --> 00:34:02,247
-Can we go on board?
-We'll ask Costa.

537
00:34:16,888 --> 00:34:19,097
Hi, there.

538
00:34:19,223 --> 00:34:21,516
They really had to fill these
with gold dust?

539
00:34:21,642 --> 00:34:23,935
Seems so.

540
00:34:24,062 --> 00:34:27,606
Daniel, l saw you in a demonstration
with the police.

541
00:34:27,732 --> 00:34:32,944
Do you realize that if something
happens to you, we're fucked?

542
00:34:33,071 --> 00:34:35,530
Without you,
we can't finish the film.

543
00:34:35,656 --> 00:34:38,366
Can you not keep out of this?

544
00:34:38,493 --> 00:34:40,327
Just three weeks.

545
00:34:41,579 --> 00:34:43,038
Excuse me.

546
00:34:45,583 --> 00:34:47,667
Yes?

547
00:34:54,342 --> 00:34:55,133
The money men.

548
00:34:55,259 --> 00:34:57,344
They saw the rushes,
and they say you're great.

549
00:34:57,470 --> 00:34:58,678
Very good.

550
00:35:44,725 --> 00:35:48,270
Daniel, we're going to make
a fantastic film, you'll see.

551
00:35:48,396 --> 00:35:49,688
No, really.

552
00:35:49,814 --> 00:35:52,357
Sebastian is preparing
some amazing scenes --

553
00:35:52,483 --> 00:35:55,360
hundreds of guys in the ravine
panning for gold.

554
00:35:55,486 --> 00:36:00,157
Fucking epic, and you're there!
You're there, man!

555
00:36:02,994 --> 00:36:03,743
What?

556
00:36:06,497 --> 00:36:11,293
Two fucking dollars, right?
And they're happy.

557
00:36:11,419 --> 00:36:15,172
l worked in the States for two years
in construction.

558
00:36:18,926 --> 00:36:21,595
l know this story.

559
00:36:23,431 --> 00:36:25,891
Belen, leave that.

560
00:36:26,017 --> 00:36:27,350
Come on.

561
00:36:32,857 --> 00:36:36,443
-We're not going on the boat?
-We have to go home.

562
00:37:03,012 --> 00:37:06,765
Come on, come on.
Stay in line.

563
00:37:17,985 --> 00:37:18,818
Move.

564
00:37:26,160 --> 00:37:28,161
Captain. . .

565
00:37:29,330 --> 00:37:30,580
What's this?

566
00:37:31,582 --> 00:37:33,500
Do you think l'm stupid?
Are you trying to fool me?

567
00:37:33,668 --> 00:37:36,753
Nothing here but sand.

568
00:37:38,089 --> 00:37:40,173
Speak like a Christian!
l don't understand you!

569
00:37:41,759 --> 00:37:42,550
This is sand.

570
00:37:44,762 --> 00:37:46,596
Have him clipped.

571
00:37:50,810 --> 00:37:51,768
Next.

572
00:38:14,125 --> 00:38:15,583
There's not enough here.

573
00:38:17,003 --> 00:38:18,753
There isn't enough.

574
00:38:19,505 --> 00:38:20,380
A lot of sand.

575
00:38:28,472 --> 00:38:30,390
Come on, take him away to be clipped.

576
00:38:30,516 --> 00:38:32,267
Father! Father!

577
00:38:32,393 --> 00:38:33,268
You, come on!

578
00:39:21,984 --> 00:39:24,861
-Well done, kid, you were great.
-Thank you.

579
00:39:25,738 --> 00:39:27,030
-Happy?
-Yes.

580
00:39:27,156 --> 00:39:28,698
Thank you.

581
00:39:31,494 --> 00:39:34,871
-Young lady, well done.
-Thank you.

582
00:39:34,997 --> 00:39:39,000
You've got talent.
A scene to be proud of.

583
00:39:39,502 --> 00:39:41,961
l hope they're paying you
like they should.

584
00:39:42,088 --> 00:39:44,005
Paying me
a lot more than the extras.

585
00:39:44,131 --> 00:39:45,757
More than the extras?
My God!

586
00:39:45,883 --> 00:39:47,217
Do you want to know
what they're paying me?

587
00:39:47,343 --> 00:39:49,469
-What?
-Two million bolivanos.

588
00:39:49,595 --> 00:39:50,470
Wow.

589
00:39:51,347 --> 00:39:54,057
-Dad!
-Hello.

590
00:39:54,183 --> 00:39:57,227
l've just seen
the scene in the jungle.

591
00:39:57,353 --> 00:39:58,686
lt was very interesting, yes.

592
00:39:58,813 --> 00:40:00,730
lt was sad but interesting.

593
00:40:00,856 --> 00:40:05,026
l really liked it.
lt isn't real, but it's lovely.

594
00:40:05,152 --> 00:40:06,820
-You liked it?
-Yes, a lot.

595
00:40:41,063 --> 00:40:43,273
l owe you an apology.

596
00:41:45,503 --> 00:41:50,715
Help!

597
00:44:30,292 --> 00:44:32,794
lt's a horrific choice. . .

598
00:44:32,920 --> 00:44:34,504
heartbreaking.

599
00:44:35,172 --> 00:44:39,884
You can't bear the idea
that the dogs will eat the babies.

600
00:44:40,761 --> 00:44:42,970
We'll see you talking to Hatuey

601
00:44:43,097 --> 00:44:45,807
and how you understand
that there's no other solution,

602
00:44:45,933 --> 00:44:48,893
that you have to make this decision
and you have to make it together

603
00:44:49,019 --> 00:44:51,062
to give each other courage.

604
00:44:51,188 --> 00:44:52,772
So you'll take the babies. . .

605
00:44:54,024 --> 00:44:55,900
. . .slowly,

606
00:44:56,110 --> 00:44:59,070
wade into the river,

607
00:44:59,279 --> 00:45:01,280
put them in the water,
and drown them.

608
00:45:02,282 --> 00:45:05,243
Okay, how are we going to do it?
We're going to do it like this.

609
00:45:05,369 --> 00:45:08,830
ln the first take,
you'll go in with the babies,

610
00:45:08,956 --> 00:45:12,917
and as soon as
you're up to your waists, we'll stop,

611
00:45:13,043 --> 00:45:16,337
and we'll bring over
the dolls you can see there

612
00:45:16,463 --> 00:45:19,882
and swap them for the babies,
okay?

613
00:45:21,051 --> 00:45:25,138
Everything okay?
ls something wrong, Daniel?

614
00:45:31,103 --> 00:45:34,522
Listen, it's complet--
Tell them that it's totally safe.

615
00:45:34,648 --> 00:45:36,983
The babies won't even get wet.
They won't even get wet.

616
00:45:37,109 --> 00:45:40,695
When the water is up to your waist,
we'll cut and bring those dolls, look.

617
00:45:40,821 --> 00:45:42,280
Bring those dolls so they can. . .

618
00:45:42,406 --> 00:45:45,950
Sebastian, give me a moment.

619
00:45:46,076 --> 00:45:48,619
Okay, but we don't have much time.

620
00:46:23,781 --> 00:46:25,907
What's up?

621
00:46:26,033 --> 00:46:27,909
l don't know.

622
00:46:57,815 --> 00:47:00,316
-Well?
-They won't do it.

623
00:47:00,484 --> 00:47:04,821
Look, l know it's difficult,
but we have to get them to do it.

624
00:47:04,947 --> 00:47:06,197
We need it for the film. . .

625
00:47:06,323 --> 00:47:09,617
Sebastian, they can't even imagine
the idea of doing it.

626
00:47:09,827 --> 00:47:11,953
l'm not making this up.
lt's what happened.

627
00:47:12,079 --> 00:47:13,454
We have to show it.

628
00:47:13,664 --> 00:47:16,541
lt's important for the film.
Please.

629
00:47:16,667 --> 00:47:20,169
Sebastian, some things
are more important than your film.

630
00:47:21,839 --> 00:47:23,422
Good Lord!

631
00:47:23,632 --> 00:47:25,424
God!

632
00:47:26,760 --> 00:47:28,261
What do l do?

633
00:47:29,263 --> 00:47:31,305
Nothing.

634
00:47:31,431 --> 00:47:34,016
Let's do the next scene.

635
00:47:45,445 --> 00:47:48,072
Comrades, silence, please!
Listen.

636
00:47:48,198 --> 00:47:50,408
We're taking too long,
and it's getting very hot.

637
00:47:50,534 --> 00:47:52,201
We're going to get tired.

638
00:47:52,369 --> 00:47:54,996
Comrades, we are debating
the possibility

639
00:47:55,122 --> 00:47:57,790
of occupying September 1 4th Square.

640
00:48:01,712 --> 00:48:02,461
Comrades!

641
00:48:02,629 --> 00:48:05,882
And taking over
the Water Company building

642
00:48:06,049 --> 00:48:08,801
and not budging
until they give us back the water!

643
00:48:09,052 --> 00:48:10,511
No, that's what they want.

644
00:48:10,637 --> 00:48:12,638
lt'll give them an excuse
for another massacre.

645
00:48:12,848 --> 00:48:14,765
l'm not in agreement.

646
00:48:14,892 --> 00:48:16,851
Comrades!

647
00:48:17,060 --> 00:48:18,561
We all drink water, don't we?

648
00:48:19,897 --> 00:48:23,691
Then we all have to go on the march.

649
00:48:26,653 --> 00:48:29,280
Comrades, comrades, please.

650
00:48:29,406 --> 00:48:31,157
l don't agree.

651
00:48:31,366 --> 00:48:35,453
They'll beat us up. They'll gas us.
What about our children?

652
00:48:35,579 --> 00:48:37,246
Will you look after them?

653
00:48:37,456 --> 00:48:41,834
We are women, we have children.
We shouldn't go.

654
00:48:53,680 --> 00:48:57,475
How can we pay $450 a year?

655
00:48:57,601 --> 00:48:58,976
lt's robbery.

656
00:48:59,102 --> 00:49:01,520
Better if they just shoot us now.

657
00:49:03,273 --> 00:49:04,607
Silence, please!

658
00:49:04,816 --> 00:49:08,653
We'll decide by voting, comrades.
We'll take a vote.

659
00:49:08,779 --> 00:49:10,738
Those who want to fight,
raise their hands and say,

660
00:49:10,864 --> 00:49:12,031
"The water belongs to us!"

661
00:49:12,240 --> 00:49:15,326
The water belongs to us!

662
00:49:45,774 --> 00:49:47,024
ls that Daniel?

663
00:49:48,485 --> 00:49:50,027
What's he doing here?

664
00:49:50,237 --> 00:49:53,197
After consulting
with the residents. . .

665
00:49:53,323 --> 00:49:55,574
Causing trouble, what else?
l told you, Sebastian.

666
00:49:55,701 --> 00:49:57,868
Now what?
Do l lock him up?

667
00:49:57,995 --> 00:50:00,371
. . .and with our union comrades,

668
00:50:00,580 --> 00:50:01,872
we, the people of Cochabamba,

669
00:50:01,999 --> 00:50:05,960
declare that if
the privatization of water

670
00:50:06,086 --> 00:50:08,045
is not revoked within 48 hours,

671
00:50:08,171 --> 00:50:12,717
we will begin an indefinite blockade
of the city and the roads!

672
00:50:19,516 --> 00:50:20,641
What do we want?

673
00:50:20,767 --> 00:50:21,434
Water!

674
00:50:21,560 --> 00:50:22,560
When do we want it?

675
00:50:22,686 --> 00:50:23,561
Now!

676
00:50:23,729 --> 00:50:26,439
lnside.
Let's go inside.

677
00:50:28,442 --> 00:50:35,823
Rifle or gun, the people never run!

678
00:50:36,783 --> 00:50:38,909
Thank you.

679
00:50:43,040 --> 00:50:45,249
-Welcome.
-Thank you.

680
00:50:45,375 --> 00:50:47,918
-lt's a pleasure to meet you.
-The pleasure is mine.

681
00:50:48,045 --> 00:50:50,087
-l've seen all your films.
-All of them?

682
00:50:50,213 --> 00:50:53,257
We're honored to have you in our city.
Come in, please.

683
00:50:53,383 --> 00:50:55,551
-Thank you.
-A photo of the occasion?

684
00:50:58,055 --> 00:50:58,929
Thank you.

685
00:50:59,056 --> 00:51:00,848
-This way.
-Thank you.

686
00:51:00,974 --> 00:51:04,351
We are doubly honored
that you are here

687
00:51:04,478 --> 00:51:08,022
to tell the story
of Bartolome de Las Casas,

688
00:51:08,148 --> 00:51:10,524
an underestimated man, in my view.

689
00:51:10,650 --> 00:51:13,194
Yes, that's true.
Yes, listen. . .

690
00:51:13,320 --> 00:51:15,863
Thank you for the policemen
you sent us.

691
00:51:15,989 --> 00:51:19,241
-We feel much safer.
-lt's an honor for me.

692
00:51:21,036 --> 00:51:22,787
Wow.

693
00:51:26,500 --> 00:51:29,710
They're burning the water bills.

694
00:51:29,836 --> 00:51:33,672
Excuse me, a little domestic row.

695
00:51:33,840 --> 00:51:35,257
Nothing for you to worry about.

696
00:51:35,467 --> 00:51:36,550
Don't worry.

697
00:51:36,676 --> 00:51:38,385
While there's champagne to drink,

698
00:51:38,512 --> 00:51:43,307
"Let them eat cake,"
as Marie Antoinette said.

699
00:51:43,433 --> 00:51:46,060
lt's only an excuse for some fanatics

700
00:51:46,269 --> 00:51:50,397
to stir up the desperate
and gain a name for themselves.

701
00:51:50,524 --> 00:51:52,149
Forgive me for saying so,

702
00:51:52,275 --> 00:51:55,152
but l think their demands
are reasonable.

703
00:51:55,362 --> 00:51:58,072
Perhaps if you were
better informed. . .

704
00:51:58,198 --> 00:52:00,074
We're a country with few resources.

705
00:52:00,283 --> 00:52:05,830
lt's hard to maintain a water supply
without major foreign investment.

706
00:52:06,039 --> 00:52:10,417
These people think that
government money grows on trees.

707
00:52:10,544 --> 00:52:11,502
Very good.

708
00:52:11,628 --> 00:52:14,463
Given their long history
of exploitation,

709
00:52:14,673 --> 00:52:17,133
lndians' distrust
is embedded in their genes.

710
00:52:17,342 --> 00:52:19,677
lt's very difficult
to reason with them,

711
00:52:19,803 --> 00:52:21,762
especially when they're illiterate.

712
00:52:21,888 --> 00:52:23,514
But that's how it is.

713
00:52:23,723 --> 00:52:27,726
We have objective reports
from Harvard professors, the lMF...

714
00:52:27,936 --> 00:52:32,857
l'd love to see those bastards

715
00:52:32,983 --> 00:52:36,819
feed their families
on 40 fucking dollars a month!

716
00:52:37,821 --> 00:52:39,989
Anyway, in this globalized world...

717
00:52:40,198 --> 00:52:43,284
-Excuse me, l'm wanted.
-Of course.

718
00:52:43,410 --> 00:52:46,787
ln this globalized world,
the lndians burn water bills

719
00:52:46,913 --> 00:52:48,706
and hurl rocks at the police.

720
00:52:48,874 --> 00:52:51,083
lt's the cult of victim
versus modernity.

721
00:52:51,293 --> 00:52:53,377
l don't want to be rude,

722
00:52:53,503 --> 00:52:57,798
but if someone earns
two dollars a day,

723
00:52:57,924 --> 00:53:02,386
he can't pay a 300% increase
in the price of water.

724
00:53:02,512 --> 00:53:04,430
At least that's what l'm told.

725
00:53:05,515 --> 00:53:07,141
How curious.

726
00:53:07,267 --> 00:53:11,979
That's what l'm told
you pay the extras.

727
00:53:13,023 --> 00:53:18,402
Yes, but we have
a very tight budget.

728
00:53:18,528 --> 00:53:21,155
Don't we all?

729
00:53:21,281 --> 00:53:24,825
l'll be honest.
The rumors are very worrying.

730
00:53:24,951 --> 00:53:26,660
This water dispute...

731
00:53:26,786 --> 00:53:31,165
might get out of hand
and stop us from filming.

732
00:53:31,291 --> 00:53:33,375
l don't know if you
could do something about it.

733
00:53:33,585 --> 00:53:37,296
l imagine you're trying
to reach an agreement.

734
00:53:38,798 --> 00:53:41,008
lf we give one inch,

735
00:53:41,134 --> 00:53:45,054
these lndians will drag us
back to the Stone Age.

736
00:53:47,432 --> 00:53:50,100
Now, if you'll excuse me,
make yourselves at home.

737
00:53:50,227 --> 00:53:52,144
Thank you.

738
00:54:53,373 --> 00:54:56,375
Fuck it!

739
00:55:01,047 --> 00:55:02,673
How is he?

740
00:55:02,882 --> 00:55:05,175
-They beat him up.
-His face, too?

741
00:55:05,302 --> 00:55:07,511
We'll have to cover it with his hair.

742
00:55:07,637 --> 00:55:10,597
Jesus fucking Christ!

743
00:55:10,724 --> 00:55:15,769
Costa, make him understand if we get
the scene with the cross, we're okay.

744
00:55:15,895 --> 00:55:17,771
lf not, we're fucked, Costa.

745
00:55:17,897 --> 00:55:20,899
Make the bastard give his word!

746
00:55:32,871 --> 00:55:36,040
What the fuck
are you playing at, Daniel?

747
00:55:36,166 --> 00:55:37,916
Can you not think

748
00:55:38,084 --> 00:55:40,544
of the time and effort
that have gone into this film?

749
00:55:40,754 --> 00:55:43,297
The hundreds of people
working on it,

750
00:55:43,423 --> 00:55:45,257
the money we're spending?

751
00:55:45,383 --> 00:55:48,218
lf you get fucked,
we all get fucked!

752
00:55:48,345 --> 00:55:50,471
ls three weeks too much to ask?

753
00:55:54,017 --> 00:55:57,436
Can no one else do this water stuff?

754
00:55:58,688 --> 00:56:00,773
Are you listening?

755
00:56:01,900 --> 00:56:04,902
Ah... playing the silent,
dignified lndian?

756
00:56:05,028 --> 00:56:06,820
Fucking great.

757
00:56:06,946 --> 00:56:08,697
lf we catch you
at another demonstration,

758
00:56:08,823 --> 00:56:11,158
you won't get a fucking penny.

759
00:56:11,284 --> 00:56:13,285
ls that clear?

760
00:56:19,584 --> 00:56:22,086
l'll tell you what.

761
00:56:22,212 --> 00:56:24,338
We'll give you an extra $5,000

762
00:56:24,464 --> 00:56:27,591
if you stay away from demonstrations
until we're finished.

763
00:56:27,717 --> 00:56:28,759
Okay?

764
00:56:33,640 --> 00:56:35,557
What?

765
00:56:37,310 --> 00:56:40,562
Forgive me, it's beneath you.

766
00:56:45,151 --> 00:56:46,652
Or not enough?

767
00:56:47,487 --> 00:56:49,655
Eh, Daniel?

768
00:56:51,741 --> 00:56:53,158
Not enough?

769
00:56:55,203 --> 00:56:56,995
$8,000?

770
00:56:59,082 --> 00:57:00,999
$1 0,000?

771
00:57:01,918 --> 00:57:03,961
$1 0,000, Daniel, $1 0,000.
$1 0,000.

772
00:57:04,087 --> 00:57:06,046
Half now, half when we finish!

773
00:57:06,172 --> 00:57:09,466
You've never seen
so much money in your life!

774
00:57:11,094 --> 00:57:13,095
lt's your only fucking chance

775
00:57:13,221 --> 00:57:16,223
to get out of this shithole
where you live,

776
00:57:16,349 --> 00:57:17,975
and you're smart enough
to see that!

777
00:57:18,101 --> 00:57:20,227
Or not?

778
00:57:23,022 --> 00:57:25,023
Fuck!

779
00:57:25,692 --> 00:57:27,151
All right.

780
00:57:27,277 --> 00:57:28,235
What?

781
00:57:28,486 --> 00:57:30,737
All right.

782
00:57:32,115 --> 00:57:34,324
No more demonstrations,

783
00:57:34,451 --> 00:57:37,536
and you'll do as we say
until we're finished.

784
00:57:38,872 --> 00:57:41,039
Do l have your word, Daniel?

785
00:57:42,625 --> 00:57:44,793
Do l?

786
00:57:46,463 --> 00:57:48,714
Teresa, put the money away.

787
00:57:59,017 --> 00:58:01,185
Put it away.

788
00:58:04,564 --> 00:58:06,732
We're going to need it.

789
00:58:19,829 --> 00:58:20,913
Bruno!

790
00:58:21,039 --> 00:58:23,290
Shit, Bruno!

791
00:58:23,833 --> 00:58:28,295
l'm talking to you.
Tell them to shut up, please.

792
00:58:28,421 --> 00:58:30,797
Okay? Please.

793
00:58:30,924 --> 00:58:33,509
Bruno, Bruno, are you deaf?

794
00:58:33,718 --> 00:58:36,220
Listen, get them
to the first position.

795
00:58:36,346 --> 00:58:38,305
We're here to work,
not to lie around.

796
00:58:38,431 --> 00:58:39,556
What do you want?
What?

797
00:58:39,682 --> 00:58:42,434
-lt's Costa.
-Let me have it.

798
00:58:43,102 --> 00:58:44,394
Hi.

799
00:58:44,521 --> 00:58:46,563
Where are you?

800
00:58:46,689 --> 00:58:50,484
No, Costa, no, no, no!
Where the fuck are my natives?

801
00:58:50,610 --> 00:58:54,446
Where the fuck is Daniel?!

802
00:58:54,614 --> 00:58:56,823
A day of disturbances
in Cochabamba.

803
00:58:56,950 --> 00:58:59,159
Since the crack of dawn,
peasants and their allies

804
00:58:59,285 --> 00:59:01,411
have blockaded the city.

805
00:59:01,538 --> 00:59:06,750
Ηundreds of city dwellers
affected by the water problem

806
00:59:06,876 --> 00:59:11,880
have threatened to escalate
actions starting next week.

807
00:59:13,841 --> 00:59:16,677
Hundreds of people,
some from private companies,

808
00:59:16,803 --> 00:59:19,680
joined the protest
organized by the peasants

809
00:59:19,806 --> 00:59:22,349
who have said,
"We'll maintain the pressure."

810
00:59:22,475 --> 00:59:26,270
Bruno, this looks really bad.

811
00:59:26,479 --> 00:59:28,981
-Can we shoot like this?
-Yes, we can.

812
00:59:29,148 --> 00:59:31,525
...and the military forces
have only caused more violence.

813
00:59:31,651 --> 00:59:33,694
"lf they don't listen to us,"
citizens groups said,

814
00:59:33,820 --> 00:59:37,155
"we'll bring the city
to a standstill tomorrow."

815
00:59:38,157 --> 00:59:43,036
ln various parts of the city,
serious confrontations...

816
00:59:43,162 --> 00:59:44,538
What an animal!

817
00:59:44,664 --> 00:59:46,707
...demonstrators blocked key points...

818
00:59:46,833 --> 00:59:48,750
What a bastard!

819
00:59:49,335 --> 00:59:53,463
...violent youths fought
with riot police...

820
00:59:57,343 --> 00:59:58,594
ls that Daniel?

821
01:00:01,097 --> 01:00:03,473
They've smashed his face.

822
01:00:03,600 --> 01:00:07,060
He's a fucking idiot!
They'll throw him in jail!

823
01:00:07,186 --> 01:00:08,186
What?

824
01:00:08,354 --> 01:00:11,231
What are you staring at, you drunk?

825
01:00:17,864 --> 01:00:22,743
Look, without the cross scene,
there's no film.

826
01:00:22,952 --> 01:00:25,162
Right?

827
01:00:25,288 --> 01:00:27,122
Cris? lt's Costa.

828
01:00:27,248 --> 01:00:30,125
How much cash
can we get by tonight?

829
01:00:31,044 --> 01:00:33,086
Yes, tonight.

830
01:00:33,212 --> 01:00:34,338
$5,000.

831
01:00:34,464 --> 01:00:35,505
Okay.

832
01:00:35,632 --> 01:00:37,591
Look, Daniel's been arrested...

833
01:00:37,717 --> 01:00:39,176
Listen!

834
01:00:39,302 --> 01:00:42,262
Find out where he is
and the name of the police chief,

835
01:00:42,388 --> 01:00:43,764
and set me up a meeting.

836
01:00:45,058 --> 01:00:47,726
Yes, now.

837
01:00:48,478 --> 01:00:50,187
Look, wait, one more thing.

838
01:00:50,313 --> 01:00:53,649
Call everyone and tell them that
we're doing the cross scene tomorrow.

839
01:00:54,484 --> 01:00:56,693
l don't know, and l don't care.

840
01:00:56,819 --> 01:00:58,820
Yes, you heard right.
Move it.

841
01:00:59,238 --> 01:01:02,407
That bastard won't screw us.
Let's go.

842
01:01:23,680 --> 01:01:26,139
Here's $2,000.

843
01:01:26,265 --> 01:01:29,518
We need that man to finish the film.

844
01:01:32,855 --> 01:01:34,523
Very well.

845
01:01:35,858 --> 01:01:37,984
On one condition.

846
01:01:38,111 --> 01:01:42,906
When you finish filming,
l bring him back.

847
01:01:43,074 --> 01:01:43,990
No.

848
01:01:44,117 --> 01:01:45,992
Okay.

849
01:01:46,119 --> 01:01:48,578
-We can't do that.
-Why not?

850
01:01:48,705 --> 01:01:49,913
We can't.

851
01:01:50,039 --> 01:01:51,998
Can we talk a moment?

852
01:01:52,125 --> 01:01:54,167
Will you excuse us?

853
01:01:54,293 --> 01:01:56,128
lf you'll excuse us...

854
01:01:58,715 --> 01:01:59,756
-Costa!
-What?

855
01:01:59,882 --> 01:02:02,008
What if he's beaten up
when he comes back?

856
01:02:02,135 --> 01:02:04,302
lf he's tortured, killed,
or disappeared?

857
01:02:04,429 --> 01:02:07,806
These bastards can do anything.
l don't want that on my conscience.

858
01:02:08,015 --> 01:02:10,267
But he's in jail already!
We didn't put him there.

859
01:02:10,393 --> 01:02:12,519
And the bastard tricked us.

860
01:02:12,645 --> 01:02:14,604
Without the scene,
there's no film.

861
01:02:14,814 --> 01:02:17,107
-You fucking know that.
-Yes, l know.

862
01:02:17,233 --> 01:02:18,817
l say we do it.

863
01:02:20,486 --> 01:02:21,361
Okay, but we tip him off.

864
01:02:21,571 --> 01:02:24,531
All right, whatever you want,
but after we film the scene,

865
01:02:24,657 --> 01:02:26,074
or he'll be off like a shot.

866
01:02:26,284 --> 01:02:29,119
Shit, it's...too much...

867
01:02:29,245 --> 01:02:31,496
-For fuck's sake.
-l can't.

868
01:02:31,664 --> 01:02:33,248
Yes, you can.
Yes, you can.

869
01:02:35,835 --> 01:02:37,836
Yes, you can.

870
01:02:41,841 --> 01:02:43,967
Daniel?

871
01:02:57,190 --> 01:02:59,107
You promised me.

872
01:02:59,275 --> 01:03:01,693
We made a deal.
You broke your word.

873
01:03:03,529 --> 01:03:06,531
Water is life.
You don't understand.

874
01:03:39,148 --> 01:03:41,233
Thanks, boys.

875
01:04:44,797 --> 01:04:47,716
Awake all night and vomiting.

876
01:05:01,314 --> 01:05:04,316
l don't know if l can do this, Costa.

877
01:05:08,487 --> 01:05:11,197
So, now the nutcase
who dragged us here

878
01:05:11,324 --> 01:05:13,325
says he can't do it.

879
01:05:19,498 --> 01:05:22,500
Do you know when l realized
how crazy you were?

880
01:05:24,503 --> 01:05:26,671
Seven years ago.

881
01:05:27,423 --> 01:05:30,133
You called me at 2:00 a.m.

882
01:05:30,259 --> 01:05:32,344
You won't remember.

883
01:05:33,262 --> 01:05:35,931
"You have to hear this, Costa!"

884
01:05:37,350 --> 01:05:40,226
You said it was written by a priest

885
01:05:40,353 --> 01:05:42,270
called Montesinos
in the 1 6th century.

886
01:05:42,438 --> 01:05:43,480
As if l gave a fuck.

887
01:05:43,606 --> 01:05:44,648
l was in a bar --

888
01:05:44,774 --> 01:05:48,985
deafening music, blind drunk,
everyone waiting for me.

889
01:05:49,111 --> 01:05:53,531
l could hardly hear you,
but you kept going, yapping...

890
01:05:55,534 --> 01:05:58,370
From a humble straw church...

891
01:06:02,041 --> 01:06:04,000
One man against an empire,

892
01:06:04,126 --> 01:06:07,045
a voice crying in the desert.

893
01:06:08,047 --> 01:06:10,298
Are these not men?

894
01:06:11,050 --> 01:06:14,052
Do they not have rational souls?

895
01:06:15,054 --> 01:06:19,724
Are you not obliged
to love them as yourselves?

896
01:06:22,561 --> 01:06:25,313
That's what got you.

897
01:06:27,817 --> 01:06:30,151
That's what gripped you...

898
01:06:31,779 --> 01:06:35,573
...lodged in there,
like a virus.

899
01:06:38,411 --> 01:06:41,079
You're not the kind to give up,
Sebastian.

900
01:06:43,332 --> 01:06:45,500
You're not.

901
01:06:49,088 --> 01:06:51,339
You can't quit now.

902
01:06:52,341 --> 01:06:54,509
Come on.

903
01:06:58,097 --> 01:06:59,931
What's wrong?

904
01:07:13,612 --> 01:07:17,532
Let's go.

905
01:07:19,869 --> 01:07:21,036
Come on.

906
01:07:21,162 --> 01:07:23,038
Come on!

907
01:07:23,164 --> 01:07:24,748
Let's go.

908
01:07:24,874 --> 01:07:26,249
Keep going.

909
01:07:26,375 --> 01:07:27,625
Come on, let's go.

910
01:07:33,632 --> 01:07:37,218
Bring them!
Women, children, old people.

911
01:07:37,428 --> 01:07:39,471
Everyone must see this.

912
01:07:41,807 --> 01:07:43,266
l beg you, Commander.

913
01:07:43,893 --> 01:07:48,688
This will turn the lndians
against us for generations.

914
01:07:48,814 --> 01:07:51,441
The Crown will prosecute you!

915
01:07:51,567 --> 01:07:53,359
l doubt it, Father.

916
01:07:53,486 --> 01:07:56,071
This isn't Christian!

917
01:07:57,740 --> 01:08:00,700
Choose 1 3, and the rest go free.

918
01:08:00,826 --> 01:08:03,369
One for each disciple
and one for Christ Himself!

919
01:08:03,496 --> 01:08:05,622
Want to choose them, Father?

920
01:08:05,748 --> 01:08:07,373
This is a sacrilege.

921
01:08:07,500 --> 01:08:10,502
No, Father.
lt's an example.

922
01:08:11,337 --> 01:08:14,172
Why not join the Franciscans
and save their souls?

923
01:08:15,424 --> 01:08:17,050
lf they have any.

924
01:08:17,176 --> 01:08:19,302
-lf he interferes, arrest him.
-Come on!

925
01:08:20,346 --> 01:08:21,971
The Evangelists.

926
01:08:22,098 --> 01:08:23,056
Matthew.

927
01:08:23,182 --> 01:08:24,140
Mark.

928
01:08:24,266 --> 01:08:24,933
Luke.

929
01:08:25,142 --> 01:08:26,893
John.

930
01:08:27,019 --> 01:08:32,148
Father, help me.
l've forgotten the names.

931
01:08:32,274 --> 01:08:34,067
-Cesar.
-Carlos.

932
01:08:34,193 --> 01:08:35,318
-Manolo.
-Paco.

933
01:08:35,528 --> 01:08:36,444
Federico.

934
01:08:36,570 --> 01:08:37,403
Felipe.

935
01:08:37,530 --> 01:08:39,697
Let's see.
Who'll be Jesus Christ?

936
01:08:45,121 --> 01:08:48,331
l'll baptize you, and you'll have
glory and eternal peace in Heaven.

937
01:08:48,457 --> 01:08:52,544
Otherwise, you'll suffer
eternal torment in Hell.

938
01:08:53,546 --> 01:08:58,216
ln the name of Christ,
you can still save your soul.

939
01:08:58,342 --> 01:09:01,594
You must understand the difference
between Heaven and Hell.

940
01:09:01,762 --> 01:09:06,516
Ask the Lord for forgiveness,
and l'll baptize you,

941
01:09:06,642 --> 01:09:10,353
and you'll have glory
and eternal peace in Heaven.

942
01:09:10,479 --> 01:09:13,648
Otherwise, you'll suffer
eternal torment in Hell.

943
01:09:14,150 --> 01:09:15,525
Has he understood?

944
01:09:19,572 --> 01:09:21,156
Do Christians go to Heaven?

945
01:09:21,365 --> 01:09:22,866
Good Christians do.

946
01:09:25,870 --> 01:09:27,579
Send me to Hell!

947
01:09:29,582 --> 01:09:30,874
Silence!

948
01:09:31,000 --> 01:09:35,086
This is what will happen
if you defy the Christians.

949
01:10:12,374 --> 01:10:17,670
What are they saying?

950
01:10:17,796 --> 01:10:19,005
"l despise you."

951
01:10:19,131 --> 01:10:20,757
"l despise your God."

952
01:10:20,925 --> 01:10:22,926
"l despise your greed."

953
01:10:34,730 --> 01:10:36,105
May God forgive us.

954
01:10:49,411 --> 01:10:51,621
Shut them up!

955
01:10:59,004 --> 01:11:01,089
What are they saying, Father?

956
01:11:01,590 --> 01:11:04,550
His name!

957
01:11:04,677 --> 01:11:07,929
Thanks to you,
it will never be forgotten!

958
01:11:27,950 --> 01:11:30,159
Okay, cut!

959
01:11:30,286 --> 01:11:33,538
Okay, guys, that was incredible!
Thank you.

960
01:11:45,467 --> 01:11:48,136
We're going to do it!

961
01:12:07,573 --> 01:12:10,283
Who is Daniel?

962
01:12:10,409 --> 01:12:11,576
Come with us.

963
01:12:13,412 --> 01:12:16,080
You're under arrest.
Come with us.

964
01:13:12,596 --> 01:13:14,806
Get back!

965
01:13:15,307 --> 01:13:16,265
Excuse me!

966
01:13:16,392 --> 01:13:19,185
Take it easy! Take it easy!
Please, please.

967
01:13:19,311 --> 01:13:20,353
Please, please!

968
01:13:20,479 --> 01:13:21,604
Get them!

969
01:13:27,986 --> 01:13:29,904
Leave him alone!

970
01:13:41,417 --> 01:13:43,418
lt's like a dream.

971
01:13:44,753 --> 01:13:48,923
l can't believe it.

972
01:13:55,931 --> 01:14:00,059
The Water Committee has said that
if Bolivian Waters doesn't leave,

973
01:14:00,185 --> 01:14:04,147
blockades will continue
on the streets and on access roads.

974
01:14:04,273 --> 01:14:08,484
The Committee has asked
that the blockades continue,

975
01:14:08,694 --> 01:14:14,157
so the majority of roads and streets
will remain in that state.

976
01:14:14,283 --> 01:14:17,410
Τhe government has declared
a state of emergency

977
01:14:17,536 --> 01:14:21,080
and has sent special police forces
from La Paz

978
01:14:21,206 --> 01:14:24,917
to prevent acts of vandalism
and violence.

979
01:14:25,043 --> 01:14:28,713
September 14th Square
is still held by citizens.

980
01:14:30,966 --> 01:14:34,177
Τhe roads linking Cochabamba
with the rest of the country

981
01:14:34,303 --> 01:14:36,971
are still blocked.

982
01:14:37,890 --> 01:14:42,435
The Republic's vice-president
says this is an act of subversion

983
01:14:42,644 --> 01:14:45,062
aimed at destabilizing

984
01:14:45,272 --> 01:14:48,941
a democratically elected
constitutional government.

985
01:14:49,067 --> 01:14:51,194
lt is an opportunistic protest

986
01:14:51,320 --> 01:14:56,282
intended to submerge the country
in disorder and chaos.

987
01:14:56,492 --> 01:14:57,783
Guys...

988
01:14:57,910 --> 01:15:00,036
Guys! Guys! Guys!

989
01:15:00,162 --> 01:15:01,954
l'm sorry, but l'm scared.

990
01:15:02,080 --> 01:15:04,874
l want a ticket home right now.
And l'm serious.

991
01:15:05,000 --> 01:15:05,750
Me too.

992
01:15:05,918 --> 01:15:08,711
How the fuck can you leave the film?

993
01:15:08,837 --> 01:15:10,963
You can't just dump us.

994
01:15:11,089 --> 01:15:13,716
-You signed a contract.
-Don't bullshit me!

995
01:15:13,842 --> 01:15:16,219
-You can't even guarantee our safety!
-Yes, l can.

996
01:15:16,345 --> 01:15:18,638
-You can't!
-l can! Shut up and listen!

997
01:15:18,764 --> 01:15:20,473
This is an eight-hour drive away.

998
01:15:20,599 --> 01:15:23,059
The countryside is practically
the same, and it's safe.

999
01:15:23,185 --> 01:15:25,728
Costa! l'm scared!

1000
01:15:25,854 --> 01:15:27,396
Understand?

1001
01:15:27,523 --> 01:15:29,315
Scared.

1002
01:15:29,441 --> 01:15:31,150
And l've got a new baby.

1003
01:15:31,276 --> 01:15:34,070
Anything could happen.
l don't want to be here when it does.

1004
01:15:34,196 --> 01:15:36,906
Run, little rabbits. Run, run.

1005
01:15:37,032 --> 01:15:38,741
Fucking cowards.

1006
01:15:38,867 --> 01:15:40,826
-What would Bartolome do?
-Piss off.

1007
01:15:40,953 --> 01:15:43,996
Yeah, lots of yaku, lots of
"poor lndians," and now what?

1008
01:15:44,122 --> 01:15:45,122
Fuck them!

1009
01:15:45,958 --> 01:15:47,375
What can we do?

1010
01:15:47,543 --> 01:15:48,751
They're telling you!

1011
01:15:48,877 --> 01:15:51,087
Go to a safe place
and finish our work!

1012
01:15:51,213 --> 01:15:54,423
That's what we have to do!
We owe it to them!

1013
01:15:54,550 --> 01:15:56,676
l promise this place is safe.

1014
01:15:57,219 --> 01:16:01,430
l spoke to them 1 5 minutes ago.
They've hired private security.

1015
01:16:01,557 --> 01:16:05,101
We'll pack essentials
and get out before we're trapped.

1016
01:16:05,227 --> 01:16:06,435
The roads are still clear.

1017
01:16:06,562 --> 01:16:08,646
Yes, but l don't know for how long.

1018
01:16:08,814 --> 01:16:11,566
Please, really...

1019
01:16:12,985 --> 01:16:14,902
l'm begging you.

1020
01:16:18,740 --> 01:16:20,324
l'm going.

1021
01:16:22,244 --> 01:16:23,536
Come on!

1022
01:16:23,662 --> 01:16:25,496
Come on, guys.

1023
01:16:27,082 --> 01:16:28,833
Yes?

1024
01:16:39,094 --> 01:16:41,429
-Yes.
-Thank you.

1025
01:16:57,195 --> 01:17:02,116
Can you hear me, Costa?
We're leaving now.

1026
01:17:02,242 --> 01:17:03,909
Okay, perfect.
We're leaving, too.

1027
01:17:04,036 --> 01:17:06,662
Get a move on. Don't wait for us.
We'll catch up.

1028
01:17:06,788 --> 01:17:08,080
Bye.

1029
01:17:08,206 --> 01:17:11,334
They're about to close the road.
We have to go now!

1030
01:17:11,460 --> 01:17:13,794
Everyone into the cars!
Come on, we're going!

1031
01:17:16,298 --> 01:17:17,923
Who's left?

1032
01:17:18,050 --> 01:17:21,302
Shit, wardrobe!
lt's always the same! Let's go!

1033
01:17:32,981 --> 01:17:34,023
Teresa, what's wrong?

1034
01:17:34,149 --> 01:17:36,859
l came to ask you a favor.
My daughter ran off.

1035
01:17:37,069 --> 01:17:39,320
She was playing with her friends,

1036
01:17:39,446 --> 01:17:42,114
and they went off
to the demonstration.

1037
01:17:42,240 --> 01:17:44,617
-The demonstration?
-And now she's hurt.

1038
01:17:44,826 --> 01:17:46,535
They rang me from the post office.

1039
01:17:46,662 --> 01:17:47,620
She's hurt?

1040
01:17:47,829 --> 01:17:51,290
Some neighbors called me
and told me she's injured.

1041
01:17:51,416 --> 01:17:53,876
How could you leave Belen
in the middle of this?

1042
01:17:54,002 --> 01:17:58,964
lf we don't go, she might die.
Please, help me!

1043
01:17:59,091 --> 01:18:01,926
Help me get her to the hospital.
Please.

1044
01:18:02,094 --> 01:18:04,261
She's bleeding badly.

1045
01:18:04,429 --> 01:18:06,681
l'm desperate.
l don't know what to do.

1046
01:18:06,890 --> 01:18:11,811
-l'm begging you, please.
-All right, l'll send someone now.

1047
01:18:11,937 --> 01:18:13,646
No, not someone else!

1048
01:18:13,772 --> 01:18:17,358
They won't let anyone through.
The police are there.

1049
01:18:17,526 --> 01:18:21,445
No one can get past them,
but maybe you can.

1050
01:18:21,613 --> 01:18:24,740
But l can't go.
l'm about to leave with the crew.

1051
01:18:24,866 --> 01:18:28,077
Who else can l turn to?
There's no one else.

1052
01:18:28,203 --> 01:18:30,496
-There's only you.
-What's wrong?

1053
01:18:30,706 --> 01:18:34,291
Help me, l'm begging you, please.
l'm begging you.

1054
01:18:34,459 --> 01:18:36,711
Wait here.

1055
01:18:39,589 --> 01:18:41,757
-Something's happened to Belen.
-What?

1056
01:18:41,883 --> 01:18:42,925
l don't know.
She's been hurt.

1057
01:18:43,051 --> 01:18:44,510
Fuck!

1058
01:18:44,636 --> 01:18:46,178
She asked me to go with her.

1059
01:18:46,304 --> 01:18:50,516
No, you're not going anywhere.
lt's a war zone, Costa.

1060
01:18:50,642 --> 01:18:53,102
-But she asked me.
-You can't do anything!

1061
01:18:53,228 --> 01:18:57,440
Don't fuck me about!
Tell her you're not going.

1062
01:18:57,566 --> 01:19:00,317
We need you with us!
Please, Costa.

1063
01:19:06,742 --> 01:19:09,201
-l'll send someone, okay, Teresa?
-You have to help me, please.

1064
01:19:09,327 --> 01:19:11,287
Help me.
Don't leave me like this.

1065
01:19:11,413 --> 01:19:14,874
No one else is any use.
They won't get through.

1066
01:19:15,000 --> 01:19:18,544
l can't go, Teresa.
l'm responsible for the whole crew.

1067
01:19:18,670 --> 01:19:23,299
l can't leave them now.
l can't do it, Teresa!

1068
01:19:23,425 --> 01:19:25,259
Come on, let's fucking go!

1069
01:19:25,385 --> 01:19:28,345
-Let's go!
-Please, you're a friend.

1070
01:19:36,605 --> 01:19:37,438
Wait here.

1071
01:19:37,606 --> 01:19:40,816
Just a second, Bruno.
Just a second.

1072
01:19:40,942 --> 01:19:44,403
-l'm taking Belen to the hospital.
-No, no, you're crazy!

1073
01:19:44,529 --> 01:19:46,155
No, Costa, listen to me!

1074
01:19:46,281 --> 01:19:48,991
This confrontation is going to end,
and it'll be forgotten.

1075
01:19:49,117 --> 01:19:51,744
But our film
is going to last forever.

1076
01:19:51,870 --> 01:19:55,331
Please, come with us. lf anything
happens to you, we're all fucked!

1077
01:19:55,457 --> 01:19:57,166
-Listen, listen, listen.
-No, no!

1078
01:19:57,292 --> 01:19:58,667
Listen to me for once in your life!

1079
01:19:58,794 --> 01:20:01,754
lf anything happens to that child,
l'll never forgive myself.

1080
01:20:01,880 --> 01:20:06,425
The army is on its way!
They'll crush everyone! You too!

1081
01:20:06,551 --> 01:20:09,678
-l can't leave the child there!
-What can you do?

1082
01:20:09,888 --> 01:20:12,681
l can't leave her there.

1083
01:20:12,808 --> 01:20:15,267
-Help me out, man, please.
-Fuck!

1084
01:20:15,393 --> 01:20:19,021
Help me, Sebastian, please!
You go with the crew.

1085
01:20:19,231 --> 01:20:22,566
l just can't leave that child.
l can't.

1086
01:20:23,860 --> 01:20:25,986
You go with them.

1087
01:20:27,239 --> 01:20:28,322
Teresa, come on.

1088
01:21:08,989 --> 01:21:10,614
lt's blocked!

1089
01:21:11,366 --> 01:21:13,492
There's no way through.
Go down there.

1090
01:21:13,618 --> 01:21:16,829
-This way?
-Yes, go down there.

1091
01:21:33,889 --> 01:21:37,349
l can see
the Water Company building.

1092
01:21:37,475 --> 01:21:40,102
l'm at the corner.

1093
01:21:40,228 --> 01:21:42,855
One block away.

1094
01:21:42,981 --> 01:21:45,316
l can see the flagpole.

1095
01:21:45,483 --> 01:21:49,194
The soldiers are entrenched
behind their shields.

1096
01:21:49,321 --> 01:21:54,116
Τhey're armed with rifles,
tear gas, rubber bullets,

1097
01:21:54,242 --> 01:21:56,243
or something worse,
l can't see clearly.

1098
01:21:56,453 --> 01:22:00,205
But behind me, the image is
an incredible sight.

1099
01:22:00,332 --> 01:22:03,375
Young and old,
people of all ages from the city,

1100
01:22:03,501 --> 01:22:07,463
peasants and coca growers
are lining up.

1101
01:22:07,589 --> 01:22:10,215
l think they're going to the charge.

1102
01:22:10,342 --> 01:22:11,884
There must be 2,000 of them,

1103
01:22:12,010 --> 01:22:15,304
and more are flooding in
from the side streets.

1104
01:22:15,430 --> 01:22:16,388
Here they go!

1105
01:22:16,514 --> 01:22:21,852
A citizens' army
with sticks for weapons!

1106
01:22:28,944 --> 01:22:30,569
What do we do?

1107
01:22:30,695 --> 01:22:31,779
l'll talk to them.

1108
01:22:55,637 --> 01:22:58,389
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you!

1109
01:23:05,563 --> 01:23:09,775
The army is firing with live ammo!

1110
01:23:09,901 --> 01:23:11,902
l've seen a dozen drop,

1111
01:23:12,112 --> 01:23:14,613
but the demonstrators still charge.

1112
01:23:14,739 --> 01:23:16,448
Rocks against bullets!

1113
01:23:16,574 --> 01:23:18,701
Bodies fall all around me.

1114
01:23:18,827 --> 01:23:21,829
Dozens of injured.

1115
01:23:34,634 --> 01:23:37,553
Fuck, Costa, answer!

1116
01:23:49,774 --> 01:23:52,109
Pull over, Mister.

1117
01:23:53,028 --> 01:23:57,031
We'll never get out of here, guys.
No fucking way!

1118
01:25:26,579 --> 01:25:27,746
Shit. Fuck.

1119
01:25:32,919 --> 01:25:34,503
Get down!

1120
01:26:28,266 --> 01:26:31,476
Belen, love,
what did they do to you?

1121
01:26:31,603 --> 01:26:33,562
What did they do to you?

1122
01:26:33,688 --> 01:26:37,691
l'm here, love.

1123
01:26:38,359 --> 01:26:40,569
-Are you relatives?
-That's her mother. How is she?

1124
01:26:40,695 --> 01:26:42,487
She's getting worse.
She's very weak.

1125
01:26:42,614 --> 01:26:45,574
l've got a car. We can take her
and others to the hospital.

1126
01:26:45,700 --> 01:26:47,743
No, the roads are blocked
by the police.

1127
01:26:47,869 --> 01:26:49,411
How will you get through?

1128
01:26:49,537 --> 01:26:52,664
-With money, that always works.
-Yes?

1129
01:26:52,790 --> 01:26:54,708
All right.

1130
01:27:02,800 --> 01:27:06,887
Belen, it's Costa.

1131
01:27:07,388 --> 01:27:08,680
Where's Dad?

1132
01:27:08,806 --> 01:27:12,351
Don't worry, love,
he'll be here soon.

1133
01:27:12,477 --> 01:27:16,146
l'm here now, you're not alone.

1134
01:27:16,731 --> 01:27:18,732
l can't feel my leg.

1135
01:27:19,317 --> 01:27:22,527
Belen, can you hear me?

1136
01:27:22,654 --> 01:27:25,822
We're taking you to the hospital.

1137
01:27:40,338 --> 01:27:44,007
What the hell's going on?
Can't you see we're working?

1138
01:27:52,433 --> 01:27:54,518
The others are out.

1139
01:27:56,020 --> 01:27:57,688
What are they up to?

1140
01:27:58,856 --> 01:28:02,859
You're a moron, shut up!

1141
01:28:03,027 --> 01:28:04,695
Bastard!
He broke his neck!

1142
01:28:04,862 --> 01:28:05,988
Calm down! Calm down!

1143
01:28:06,114 --> 01:28:07,155
-Bastard!
-Shut up!

1144
01:28:07,282 --> 01:28:11,159
What the fuck is this?
Look out the fucking window!

1145
01:28:11,369 --> 01:28:13,078
Just look out the window!

1146
01:28:13,288 --> 01:28:15,247
What the hell are we doing here?

1147
01:28:15,456 --> 01:28:17,499
Look at that! That's it.

1148
01:28:17,625 --> 01:28:20,210
Sebastian, we're getting out.

1149
01:28:20,420 --> 01:28:23,755
We've decided.
We're going to the airport.

1150
01:28:23,923 --> 01:28:27,759
lt's over, Sebastian.
Can you not see?

1151
01:28:27,927 --> 01:28:29,094
l'm staying.

1152
01:28:29,220 --> 01:28:32,097
Sebastian, l'm sorry, look, it's over.
We're going.

1153
01:28:32,223 --> 01:28:33,682
Maria, we're going with them.

1154
01:28:33,808 --> 01:28:36,601
We're going, Maria.
l've got your case.

1155
01:28:36,853 --> 01:28:38,353
Sebastian, come on.

1156
01:28:43,985 --> 01:28:45,861
So stubborn.

1157
01:28:51,659 --> 01:28:53,785
Are you going, too?

1158
01:28:53,911 --> 01:28:55,454
l'm sorry.

1159
01:28:58,166 --> 01:29:00,250
Come on, Sebastian.

1160
01:29:29,280 --> 01:29:32,866
-Anton?
-No one's waiting for me.

1161
01:30:00,228 --> 01:30:04,481
Hey, you! You can't speak
to the prisoners!

1162
01:30:56,492 --> 01:30:59,703
-Can l see her?
-Yes, on you go.

1163
01:31:00,955 --> 01:31:03,081
Doctor, how is she?

1164
01:31:03,207 --> 01:31:05,250
Got her just in time.

1165
01:31:05,376 --> 01:31:07,919
She lost a lot of blood,
but she's stable.

1166
01:31:08,045 --> 01:31:10,255
She'll pull through.

1167
01:31:10,381 --> 01:31:13,717
-The thing is...
-What?

1168
01:31:15,219 --> 01:31:19,848
We saved her leg,
but it's badly damaged.

1169
01:31:19,974 --> 01:31:23,477
She'll have problems walking,
if at all...

1170
01:31:28,816 --> 01:31:31,276
l have to find her father.

1171
01:31:31,402 --> 01:31:33,320
Thank you, Doctor.

1172
01:32:35,049 --> 01:32:37,384
Where's the army?

1173
01:32:47,979 --> 01:32:50,397
Stop the fighting.

1174
01:32:51,315 --> 01:32:53,608
The water is yours.

1175
01:32:53,734 --> 01:32:58,613
Stop the fighting.

1176
01:32:58,739 --> 01:33:02,909
The water is yours.

1177
01:34:33,417 --> 01:34:34,918
How's Belen?

1178
01:34:55,773 --> 01:34:57,774
You're in the news everywhere.

1179
01:34:59,026 --> 01:35:02,654
"Multinational pulls out of Bolivia
after water war."

1180
01:35:02,780 --> 01:35:04,614
That's you.

1181
01:35:06,450 --> 01:35:09,369
lt always costs us dear.

1182
01:35:09,954 --> 01:35:13,581
lt's never easy.
l wish there was another way.

1183
01:35:13,791 --> 01:35:15,792
But there's not.

1184
01:35:17,795 --> 01:35:20,296
And the toughest bit
is still to come.

1185
01:35:23,134 --> 01:35:25,135
What are you going to do?

1186
01:35:27,304 --> 01:35:29,055
l don't know.

1187
01:35:30,141 --> 01:35:32,809
Help Sebastian finish this.

1188
01:35:34,395 --> 01:35:36,312
Somehow.

1189
01:35:38,149 --> 01:35:40,233
Somewhere.
But l don't know how.

1190
01:35:41,569 --> 01:35:43,903
And you, Daniel,
what are you going to do?

1191
01:35:46,991 --> 01:35:49,784
Survive, like always.

1192
01:35:49,910 --> 01:35:52,245
lt's what we do best.

1193
01:35:55,666 --> 01:35:58,752
Listen, Daniel, l'm going to help you
with Belen, l promise.

1194
01:36:05,843 --> 01:36:07,761
Will you come back?

1195
01:36:13,934 --> 01:36:15,935
l don't think so.

1196
01:36:30,534 --> 01:36:32,619
lt's a gift.

1197
01:36:36,540 --> 01:36:39,292
Thank you.

1198
01:36:40,544 --> 01:36:43,254
You saved my daughter's life.

1199
01:36:43,380 --> 01:36:45,381
l won't forget that.

1200
01:36:50,971 --> 01:36:53,139
Listen, l have to go, okay?

1201
01:36:56,977 --> 01:36:59,062
Take good care.

1202
01:36:59,730 --> 01:37:01,773
Please.

1203
01:37:01,899 --> 01:37:03,316
Take care.

1204
01:37:03,484 --> 01:37:05,568
You too.

1205
01:38:10,885 --> 01:38:11,885
Yaku.

