Ladies and gentlemen, it is
very gratifying to Ms. Green,
it is very gratifying to the
management, to listen to such
heartfelt appreciation as
you have just expressed.
You all know that this is the
last appearance of Ms. Green,
of our Harriet, on this
or any other stage.
She'll be back on the stage
in two years, sure as I'm
breathing.
Whether in two years or
twenty, they always do you know
it's like a favor.
To celebrate this unique
occasion, the last appearance in
public of our favorite, before
Cupid snatches her from our
mitts.
As I was saying, Ms. Harriet
Green, to celebrate this unique
occasion, has consented with
her company to sing the song
that first endeared her to
you, to me, to all of us.
Daddy Wouldn't Buy Me a
Bow Wow.
Thank you.
? I love my little cat, I do
? It's coat is oh so warm
? He comes each day with me to
school and sits upon the form
? Then teacher says why do
you bring that little pet of
? Yours, I tell her that I
bring my cat along with me
? Because daddy wouldn't
buy me a bow wow bow wow
? Daddy wouldn't buy me a bow wow bow wow
? I got a little pet,
I am very fond of that
? But I'd rather have a bow wow wow
? We used to have two tiny
dogs, such pretty little dears
? But daddy sold 'em 'cause
they used to bite each other's
? Ears, I cried all day and ate all night
? Papa sent me to bed
? When mom came home and
wiped my eyes I cried again
? And said daddy wouldn't
buy me a bow wow bow wow
? Daddy wouldn't buy me a bow wow bow wow
? I've got a little pet
and I'm very fond of that
? But I'd rather have a bow wow wow
? Daddy wouldn't buy me a bow wow
Maudie.
She's actually waving to me.
It's the old structure look at that.
The old walrus, I'll throw
him a fish in a minute.
What are you going to sit with him for?
Oh a hundred reasons.
You know it means I'm going
out of your life forever.
That's one of the reasons.
? Daddy wouldn't buy me a bow wow bow wow
? I've got a little pet
and I'm very fond of that
? But I'd rather have a bow wow wow
Ladies and gentlemen I want
to cry, but I mustn't because
I don't want to look horrid
the last time you see me.
Nonsense, you look wonderful!
I would rather leave you
all at this moment, the moment
when you love me most.
I would never like to
grow old before your eyes.
You'll never grow old Harriet Green.
Evergreen.
As you all know, tomorrow
I'm getting married, and what
more can I say except that
I'm marrying a kind and a
splendid man.
? For he's a jolly good fellow,
for he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a jolly good
fellow, a toast to all of us
? A toast to all of us,
a toast to all of us
? For he's a jolly good fellow,
for he's a jolly good fellow
? For he's a jolly good
fellow, a toast to all of us ?
Hip hip.
Hooray!
Hooray, hooray!
Oh Shropshire Isn't it
touching, I've got a lump in me
throat.
Maudie, do you know
why I'm attracted to ya?
No, now tell us, go on.
Because you are figured
like an hour glass, and that
intoxicates me.
Hourglass, oh.
Hourglass.
Have some more San, you'll
need it if you want to boil
that egg, huh?
You've made me the happiest
man in the world little woman.
Oh, clever, cheers.
Maudie my dear, you are
Harriet's understudy, are you not?
Yes I am, or rather I was.
If she doesn't turn up at
the wedding, someone's gotta
take her place haven't they?
I don't know, I suppose so.
Maudie, will you marry me?
Don't say this is so sudden,
because it would be a wooping
big lie.
Oh really, I'm not good enough for you.
Shropshire, the pleasure's mine.
Mine too, and damn the county.
Ladies and gentlemen, I have
the honor to present to you
the future Lady Shropshire.
But this may mean that I may
never grace the boards again.
London will never get over it.
A treat ladies and gentlemen,
a treat never before seen on
any stage, the future Lady
Shropshire will sing a duet with
the future Marquis of Staines.
Harriet do you really think
we ought to, I mean remember
our positions.
Orchestra, orchestra.
? Why I wouldn't leave my
little wooden house for you
? I've got a lover and a good one too
? What might happen there
ain't no knowing, if he comes
? Around so you better get going, woo
? I wouldn't leave my wooden
little house for you ?
Come on now, come on, all together.
? I wouldn't leave my
little wooden hut for you
? I've got a lover and a good one too
? What might happen there ain't no telling
? If he comes around,
you better get going ?
I beg your pardon, I have to leave.
I love you all, goodbye.
What's the matter?
Cab please.
No dear, you must stay behind
and look after our guests.
But I--
Hawke will see me home, goodbye.
Ms. Green's apartment.
This is peculiar.
I'm very sorry miss.
It's all right Hawke, I felt
all along it was too good to
be true.
Where is he?
11 Mock Street Heckney,
should I tell the driver?
Hi Cabby, 11 Mock Street Heckney.
Right you are lady, at
your case, if you say so.
My darling long lost girly.
All right Hawke, you can
wait for me downstairs.
I thought I'd seen the
last of you this time.
You really mustn't be so
pessimistic about the future my
love.
Spent all the money I gave you?
I'm afraid so.
How?
And our little daughter?
In a place where you
will never find her.
Well George...
My ship got in this morning,
and the first thing I read in
the paper was you are
going to be a Marshonest,
congratulations.
Very sweet of you George.
He's a millionaire, isn't he?
Well little girl we're in clover.
We?
You and me.
I see.
Good thing I never
married you eh my love?
Or else this would be bigamy.
Are you coming to the wedding George?
You bet.
You wouldn't like me to
give you away, would you?
Ooooh.
Harriet you must go
on with this marriage.
And be blackmailed by you
for the rest of my life?
Oh I'm a reasonable man,
I'd ask for a little and I'd
cheer off.
After a price, and unfortunately
you'd cheer back again.
Oh no George, I'm not so
keen on marriage as to let
myself in for that.
But this means everything to you.
Perhaps it does, but my
own peace of mind means still
more.
Harriet, this is a chance of a lifetime.
For you, yes.
Oh it's no use George, I'm sick
of having you hanging around
my heels, and if I marry
Staines it'd be a thousand times
worse.
Oh lovely how can you
say such things about me?
Besides, your engagement's been announced.
If I thought you were
going to turn up like this I
wouldn't have dreamed of going on with it.
But you must go on with
it, my dear it's a gift.
And think of the poor Marquis,
how could you be so cruel to
him, break the young man's
heart, they say he's as sensitive
as they make 'em.
And if you let him go why he's
liable to throw himself in
his own battlements, and his
blood will be on your hand.
You can't go to Heaven
branded as a murderess.
Hawke, I've made up my mind.
Go up and tell him that
I've left the stage.
Tell him that I am not going
to get married, but I'm going
to clear off and go back
home to South Africa.
And me, aren't I coming with you?
No Hawke, you're going
into the country to bring up
Harriet Junior.
Couldn't you bring yourself
to take her with you?
No Hawke, her father stands
for too much that has been
miserable in my life.
My life is going to be my own from now on.
You'll bring her up beautifully
Hawke, I'm sure of it.
Harriet, Harriet my love,
you must listen to reason.
She would've made such
a lovely Marshonest.
Don't I know it.
? I wouldn't leave my
little wooden house for you
? I've got a lover and a good one too
? What might happen there
ain't no knowing if he comes
? Around so you better get going, woo
? I wouldn't leave my little
wooden house for you ?
Good luck dear.
Thanks darling.
Cut, cut, yeah yeah,
what's all this about.
I'm all right really, I was
a bit overworked from my last
job, that's what it is.
And when was your last job?
About six months ago,
but today's my lucky day.
Had any breakfast this morning?
I'm dieting.
That was
terrible boys, terrible.
I'm going to send you
home to your mothers soon.
And keep work, there's
nothing to laugh about.
Charlie, let her go, one two.
No.
Yes Mister.
Vivvy Abbington would like
you to go to lunch with her on
Friday.
Oh take a note of it.
Yes Mr. Ben.
I wanna see those girls.
Skirts up.
Mr. Ben have you decided on
the blue carpet or the pink
for the ballroom scene?
I want red.
Yes Mr. Ben.
Now tempo, tempo!
Would you give me a
rehearsal group Mr. Ben?
No.
Yes Mr. Ben.
Stop, stop everybody, stop.
This is a nice time for one
of my chorus ladies to turn up
in the morning isn't it?
Yes Mr. Ben.
Don't you get enough sleep?
What do you think Mr. Ben?
Keep quiet everybody, from
the commencement Charlie, one
two.
Stop, it is ordered, stop.
Rest up 15 minutes girls.
Mr. Ben what about these other girls?
I don't wanna see anymore girls today.
All right Mr. Ben.
Sorry ladies, no more auditions today.
Now what is it?
I'm livid.
You look a bit off what the
hell's the matter with you?
Am I supposed to be your
young and glamorous leading lady
or not?
Supposed to be, yes.
And didn't you promise me
some really good publicity?
I was tight at the time but I did yes.
Well listen to this?
Ms. Marjorie Moore, the
well known divorcee, that's a
great help for God's sake,
celebrated her 35th birthday very
quietly in her tiny Knight's
Bridge flat with a little tea
party.
Fish me Mr. Thompson, go
on fish me Mr. Thompson!
Mr. Thompson!
Here I am Mr. Ben.
How dare you.
What do you mean by this?
I'm not sitting anymore today!
How dare you say I'm 35,
the whole world knows I'm 28!
It's a new idea of mine,
truth in advertising, besides it
says in the theatrical
who's who that you're 38.
Oh.
And how dare you describe
this lady's flat as tiny, it is
enormous.
Well you know it better than I do sir.
What does he mean by that?
We'll let that pass.
I thought it might be good
to suggest that Ms. Moore has
simple tastes.
And as far as the public's
concerned, Ms. Moore's flat
isn't in Knight's Bridge it's in Mayfair.
Yes Mr. Ben.
Don't you realize that what
this theatrical profession
wants to put on it's feet is
a new and original idea, can't
you think of something
startling and original?
I have Mr. Ben, I though of
it this morning while I was
cleaning my teeth.
What was it?
Couldn't we suggest that
Ms. Moore had all her jewels
stolen?
Marvelous.
Get out.
But Mr. Ben--
Get out!
Ooooh.
Where's my chair?
Damn Ms. Marjorie Moore, oh sorry.
It's all right.
I don't know you from any
Johnson, but there's something
I'd like to get off my chest,
I'd give anything in the world
to boil Mr. Leslie Ben in caster oil.
So would I.
Can you afford the caster oil?
No, can you.
No too bad, but good morning.
I have good news to tell Mr.
Pryde, the Lady Shropshire is
here.
Oh, yes your honor, miss,
but he's with Mr. Ben now.
Mr. Ben?
Oh I knew him well.
I said nobody was allowed in
here while I'm with Mr. Ben.
Oh but Mr. Ben knows me so well.
God bless it's Maudie.
Maudie is one of my names,
but really I'm Lady Shropshire.
Hm, you haven't gone grand
on us by any chance have you?
And what do we owe the honor
of this visit Lady Jabaja?
Shropshire if you don't mind.
Well as you read in the
papers I am widowed.
But the rumor that my husband
left me in an acute state of
mortgage is quite untrue.
Sounds rather rude to me.
Really.
But I have begun to feel, now
how can I put it, the desire
to return to the old profession.
What?
You never at the foot light.
Do you mind telling us
what the big idea is Lady
Shropshire?
Oh Les it's like this, see
I've been studying grand opera
and I thought well for old
time's sake, I'd like to give you
the first chance of presenting me.
Charming of you.
Can you play that.
? Na na na na na na
? Ah ha ha ha ha ha a ha ha ha
Maudie, you've moved us strangely.
Hello.
Oh, hello.
I thought you were a publicity man.
So did I, so I was, but
I've decided to go back to the
stage again.
How nice.
You couldn't get me to touch
that damn publicity record
not with a barge pole.
I haven't got a barge pole.
Oh clever aren't you.
Nothing new today folks.
They always say that, I'm going to wait.
Well if you'll take a chance, so will I.
And here am I one of the
greatest showmen in the business
prepared to spend any amount
of dough on the public and I'm
stuck, I can't bring them in.
And I've got to watch the man
that runs the Picture Palace
down the road turn away from his, and why?
Because he's got something
really good to show them.
Now I've got to have something
that will make them sit up
in their seats and rub
their eyes, oh for a stunt.
Have a cup of tea, we
can talk about old times.
Oh, for a stunt.
A stunt?
A really marvelous publicity
stunt, so daring and original
that it'd make old Ben go down
on his knees begging me to go
back to him, gosh, what a triumph.
But I thought you'd finished
with the whole damn record.
So I have, still.
Oh I'm so tired of looking for a job.
Am I seeing things?
What's the matter, are you ill?
It can't be Harriet Green.
I'm afraid you've made a
mistake, my name is Harriet
Hawkes.
The voice is the same,
oh I'm going off my nut.
You're not Harriet Green's
daughter by any chance are you?
I'm afraid you're
mistaken, I'm, my name--
Well what do you know about that?
And I thought I knew all there
was to know about Harriet
Green.
Her daughter, well well.
Do you mean the famous
Harriet Green of the olden days?
Yes, oh but that was before your time.
I remember the door, the
top, the champagne, suppers.
And you're her daughter.
Oh please, I told you my name is Hawkes.
What's the matter with you?
Don't talk to me I'm giving birth.
Really, what is this world coming to.
Who is that young man.
I don't know, but I
think he's awfully silly.
I've got it.
I'm going to put you at the
top of the tree my girl by a
stunt.
By a stunt that will make
Leslie Ben's hair stand on him,
a stunt that will put Hitler
and Amy in the shade, a stunt
that will make all of London
cue up to see you my girl.
Did you hear me say nothing new today.
You're wrong old man,
gosh how wrong you are.
Come on, let's go to lunch, I
don't know who's going to pay
for it, but come one let's go to lunch.
Mr. Leslie Ben.
What the devil do you mean by this?
Oh you two knew each other, how nice.
We do not.
Oh but you must meet, such
a clever young man Leslie, and
a great friend of mine.
Mr. Ben, Mister, what did
you say your name was?
Thompson.
Now Ms. Maudie, I thought
I came here to talk about old
times.
Oh did you?
Of course you did, and while
you're here, I'm going to
show you the greatest idea ever presented.
A chance that comes to a
man only once in a lifetime.
? When you're young, it's always
spring and light as a happy
? Song, how many laugh at
her and sing as we all along
? Though the years go rushing
by and spring is a memory
? Life will always be
the same sweet song to me
? When you've got a little
spring time in your heart
? You can knod at all the
wintery winds that blow
? Though December comes your
way don't worry about a thing
? And the buttercups come
peeping through the snow
? You will be young you'll be
loved your whole life through
? Just as young and more
in love than at the start
? And each happy thing will
be Evergreen and as sweet as
? A blossom in June
? When you've got a little
springtime in your heart ?
Harriet Green.
Well?
Good Lord.
Remember you of anyone Duckie?
It is Harriet Green.
Of course it is.
Her daughter?
Yes.
It isn't anything of the
sort, it is Harriet Green,
you said it yourself, it is Harriet Green.
What are you driving at?
A stunt, the biggest
you've ever heard of.
Well go on.
I don't know, I'm not so
sure I want to talk about it
after your extraordinary
behavior to me yesterday.
Oh drop that for the love of Mike.
Well my idea is that from
now on this girl becomes her
own mother.
Impersonate her mother.
Yes, that's the idea.
You're all mad.
Oh don't go Leslie, don't go.
Just clever, objections please.
But her mother died years ago.
In South Africa, and there's
nobody who was interested,
nobody realized it, next.
Do you realize that her
mother was a very great artist?
I know I could do it Mr.
Ben, if only you would give me
the chance.
And don't forget I was
her mother's understudy.
And I was her dresser for years.
And I remember all
the little ways of her.
We could teach her.
You bet.
Do you seriously mean that
you think you could persuade
the British public that this
girl is a Harriet Green of
times?
Well, we persuaded you she
was two minutes ago, and you
knew her mother well.
You are no fool Mr. Ben now are you?
Yes, no, I only believed it
until I remembered my dates.
Do you realize if this
child's mother were alive today
she'd be about 50 years of age.
Good Heavens of course I do.
Oh but damn it, this kid looks sixteen.
Well of course she does.
Well?
Meet the star that will never grow old.
What?
The idol that brought
the look of the age of 16.
What charm the use of 1934?
By looking like sweet 16.
Meet the miracle of the
age, Ms. Harriet Green.
? If I give into you
I'm giving into myself ?
Now Harriet come along, I'm
gonna show you how your mother
always finished her numbers, come on.
Like this, big smile.
Yes, but that must come out
more and these must be down.
You've forgotten this one Madam.
Oh yes, she always did that.
How lovely.
Isn't it touching?
Oh I can't go through with
it, it is indecent to go about
pretending to be my own mother.
Oh but Harriet, you never saw
your own mother so to speak.
I'm sure if she knew she'd
be ever so pleased that you're
keeping her memory green and
not meaning any funds either.
Come on Harriet, be a
big girl, one one two.
Oh all right.
? If I give into you
I'm giving into myself
? If you shatter my resistance
Lovely deary.
Just like her mother.
? I know it may be wrong but
that would never have hold
? And against my better judgement I fall
? I am weak, now you can
go and bring your speak
? And I hear no one grin oh hush
? It's not my fault if I am
tucked away on your shelf
? I am giving into myself ?
That was lovely deary.
Oh give me a hankie.
You could never sing like
that, they'll think you've been
taking some monkey
glands to make you young.
Besides Harriet, you look
so lovely dressed as your
mother, all the boys will fall
in love with you as they did
with her.
Now listen kids we only
got three more days for
rehearsing.
Good morning.
Morning.
Quiet.
I wanna get a polish on.
Now you watch your tempo,
and you're very ragged.
And listen kids for Heaven's
sake look as if you're enjoying
it.
? I'm the only doctor
who can cure your ills
? No funding medicines,
no bitter tasting pills
? I have a magic pure and simple as can be
? I just prescribe this
sweet little melody
? Tinkle tinkle tinkle, what
if the raindrops sprinkle
? Tie a little bell to your
dancing shoes and the sun will
? Shine
? Tinkle tinkle tinkle, what
if the stars wouldn't twinkle
? Tie a little bell to your
dancing shoes and stars will
? Shine
? When you moan and groan
in trouble comes around
? Heave my miles and
miles of very happy sounds
? Tinkle tinkle, what if
the raindrops sprinkle
? Tie a little bell to your
dancing shoes and stars will
? Shine
Now listen old man, you can't
keep us in the dark all the
time.
You've got to know something,
tell me, is Harriet Green
rehearsing today.
No.
Is she ever gonna rehearse?
Is anybody ever gonna see her at all?
No.
Thanks so much.
You're welcome.
Morning.
Hello.
Ben's a grand old trainer.
He's not that bad.
And what about Harriet Green?
Oh, come with me up in the
box, I'll give you a really
grand story.
Not at all bad kids.
Leslie, Harriet's ready,
she got to run through a
rehearsal with you.
Right, now everybody go to
your dressing rooms and on no
account must anybody come onto this stage.
Now come on kids get on with it.
We'll be just in time to see it all.
When are we gonna see this old hag?
Time will show.
Time will show in her
figure too I'll bet.
See you on the first night boys.
Now Tommy, see that the
critics get their drinks in the
second half.
Oh naturally.
Yes I got an idea that the
second half's a bit weak.
As usual.
Oh will you stop
walking about everybody.
This is a quick change not a skating rink.
Now Harriet there's nothing
for you to be nervous about.
You know what's at stake?
I put every penny I've got into
this show, if we don't make
good tonight I'm absolutely ruined.
Everything's on your shoulders.
I've done everything I can.
? When you're young it's always
spring and life is a happy
? Song, how we love it yeah,
and sing as we're all along
? Though the years go rushing
by and spring is a memory
? Life will always be
the same sweet song to me
? When you've got a little
springtime in your heart
? You can love with all the
wintery things that blow
? Though December comes your way
? For you the buds will sing
and buttercups come peeping
? Through the snow
? You'll be young and in
love your whole life through
? Just as young and more
in love than ever before
? And these happy things will be evergreen
? As the sweetest blossom in June
? When you've got a little
springtime in your heart
? And each happy thing will
be evergreen as the sweetest
? Blossoms in June
? When you have a little
springtime in your heart ?
Ladies and gentlemen of the
press please have a little
patience, Ms. Green is not
so young and is easily tired.
The excitement of her great
triumph last night has exhausted
her.
She wishes me to apologize to
you for the delay, she will
be with you in a few moments.
Oh there you are.
My dear you look beautiful, are you ready?
Yes.
I'll conduct them in.
Has a romance played a big
part in your life Ms. Green?
Oh yes, but the 20th century
isn't a patch on the 19th.
Do you think is
more becoming than they used to
be.
Yes, but red flannel had it's moments.
How old do you feel Ms. Green?
As old as I look.
Do you remember Merican Knight?
As if it were yesterday.
Were you Ms. Green?
Oh no, I've always liked my
men to have the upper hand.
Did Glaston ever say
anything interesting to you Ms.
Green?
Well, it was not so much what he said.
What is your greatest ambition?
To have the same effect on
your grandchildren that I had
on your grandfathers.
Clever, thank you so much.
You know why she wears
that high collar don't you?
No.
To hide the scars.
Scars, has she had her face smashed?
No, lifted.
And is your husband
still alive Ms. Green?
No, he died in South
Africa three years ago.
Really, what of?
Old age, he was a good ten
years older than me you know.
Have you any questions
of a more general nature?
Have you any children Ms. Green?
Oh really, please.
Come Ms. Green give us a
break, look what I did for you
this morning.
Oh, how charming.
Oh, excuse me I must go
consult my general manager.
What are you trying to palm off on me.
A most interesting news,
this should get us a long run.
Maudie.
Now that's in the second
act, and that's in the third,
and oh you must publish that one.
That's the scene with the comic, remember?
This'll be ten years not three.
Listen Leslie, keep your hair on.
We're the only four in the
know, and who else is going to
find out?
The Marquis of Staines.
My mother's old fiance.
My dear, amazing, not a year
older, not a muscle changed.
This is the most touching moment
I've experienced since you
consented to marry me.
Let me see, why it must be
quite the odd years ago.
Don't you remember?
Is it such a dreadful shock?
Have I changed so much?
My dear old Staines.
Maudie.
How this does take one back.
Why it's quite shaken me.
It's quite shaken me too.
Me too.
And me.
You don't know what a shock
it was to me when I got your
letter that night.
By the way you never told me
in that letter was the child
a girl or a boy.
My dear boy, how foolish
of me not to notice the
resemblance.
Yes yes, I'm delighted
to meet you, delighted.
And I must congratulate you
too my dear, a splendid champ.
Thank you.
And if you have half the
beautiful nature your dear mother
has, you'll be a model son.
I was wrong, this means 20 years not 10.
Do you think we better go and confess?
After all none of us
realized it was a crime.
Ignorance is no excuse
in the eyes of the law.
There's no earthly reason why
anybody should find out is
there, author of my being.
So you really think
we're safe, offspring?
Oh safe as houses.
Simple see there's you and
me, and Maudie and Leslie.
Who else is there to know?
Oh.
Hello deary.
What are you doing in my room?
The porter let me in.
Well I'll let the porter throw you out.
Here, here Harriet, don't
you know me, I'm your long lost
husband.
You mean your my...
Do you mind if I open the window?
Not at all my dear.
So long as you don't give me the air.
Well little girly, we're in clover.
We?
Yes, you and me.
Won't you introduce me to your boyfriend?
He's not my boyfriend.
No I'm this lady's son.
Oh an only child eh, it may
interest you to know young man
the last time I saw you I
distinctly remember you as a
little girl.
No you don't.
I do indeed I remember quite
well, I never could make up
my mind which one I
wanted, a boy or a girl.
Just goes to show.
Are you my father?
No chap, but I'll tell you
what I am, if you're this
lady's son, then I'm your grandpa see.
Now there Harriet, you say
you're glad to see your dear old
daddy.
I'm delighted.
I must run along, one
or two calls to make.
What calls?
Well I just thought I'd barge
in on the Marquis of Staines
and have a chat about the old
days when he was in love with
your mother.
Oh no you don't.
He may remember to pay me
a little sum that he lent me
some time ago.
How much?
Oh it isn't much it's 200
pounds, I'm a reasonable man and
as long as I can keep body
and soul together that's all I
ask for here below.
Thank you sonny.
Pleasure's mine pop.
Well goodbye til our next
meeting Harriet Green and son.
Harriet Green and son.
What an idea.
Good morning mother, good morning sir.
Good morning my boy.
I just fixed up the most
marvelous picture contract for
you, best bit of waning I've ever done.
Splendid.
Well I must be off to
the club, late already.
Think it over my dear, think it over.
How would you like to
have a stepfather, what?
A step what?
He's asked me to marry him.
Ha ha.
What do you mean ha ha?
Another of my schemes hashing out.
You've been expecting it?
Expecting it?
Engineering it.
I see.
Can't you see the marvelous
publicity angle of it?
Just as we're starting in on the show too?
You mean I ought to accept?
Course, later on if you like
you can call the whole thing
off, wouldn't break the old
boy's heart, it's only a
sentimental idea of his.
And suppose I were to fall
in love, to take a fancy to a
man of my own age.
Shh, do be careful my dear.
Well it has been known
to happen you know.
Well it mustn't happen
in your case old girl.
And don't you call me old girl.
And if it's any news to you
as my publicity agent, I'm not
only going to accept the
Marquis, but I'm going to go
through with it to marry him.
And we can sit by the fire and
talk about the good old times
for the rest of our lives.
It's not like Harriet to be late.
She's never been late before?
That doesn't prevent it being
excessively irritating that
she is today.
You're very pevish today
young man, what's the trouble?
Come on, tell Auntie Maudie.
I'll tell Auntie Maudie
to mind her own business.
Oh what a very rude
thing to say to a lady.
Would it be?
Thank you.
You're late.
I've been driving around
the park with my fiance.
Oh not the damn Marquis.
Don't be such a damn snob Maudie.
Oh I like that coming from
you, when you worked the whole
thing, you knew you did you naughty boy.
That was a publicity stunt.
And publicity's everything,
believe me, isn't it
Mr. Thompson?
Oh you.
Now kids, give me a romance.
Now here's the spot for it in the show.
Now in this number here, you're chased.
I'm in your pursuit, you're very coy.
You the pursuer got that?
Right, now in the first little
ta ta ta, I want a kiss.
Very coy again, then in
the second ta ta ta, a more
passionate kiss, and at the
end of the refrain, you're
abandoned.
All right.
? As you drum in here
you I ought to fear you
? Rather than think you ran
? But I can't assemble, it
makes me tremble merely to touch
? Your hand
? Though we're under
conditions I'm so glad
? No proper apprehensions have I had
? All of our transgressing
seems such a blessing in my bed
? Dear dear this is much too
nice, it won't happen twice
? Dear dear do you think we should
? Dear dear this is all so
quaint and I'm not a saint
? Dear it's too good to be good
? No love scenes on movie
screens compare with the one
? We've staged now
? With the urge completely
to merge you'd think we were
? Both engaged now
? Dear dear one is made from two
? Which of us is you
? Dear it's too good to be true ?
Get ready for your first
kiss kids, you missed it, all
right carry on.
Watch it there's another
kiss coming, oh dear.
Give me romance, come on.
Look happy, there, smile.
Now this is where we kiss.
And hold it while I fade out the lights.
Well if that's romance kids, it's lousy.
Harriet Green and son, there's
a limit to family feeling
you know.
Oh there you are my boy, I
want a word with you, will you
excuse us my dear?
Certainly.
Has your mother told you?
The marriage, oh yes,
yes, congratulations.
Oh thank you my boy, thank
you, I knew you'd be delighted.
Now I have a little
proposition to make to you.
It'll be sometime before the
details in my marriage to your
mother can be simple.
Now with her age I don't like
to think of how frail she is,
living alone liable to be
accusted by the first newcomer
who might be deceived into
thinking she's a young girl.
So what do you think I've done?
I've taken a charming little
house for the two of you so
that you can look after your mother.
Oh, well that's very kind
of you but we couldn't, could
we?
No, we couldn't possibly
accept a house from you.
It's lovely, oh it's beautiful.
I'm delighted you like the
new house and I hope you both
sleep well on your first night here.
Now goodbye my dear, goodbye.
Goodbye my boy.
Goodnight sir.
Dear old gentlemen, isn't he?
Why didn't you think of one
of those great ideas of yours
to get us out of this one?
Well after all, it's grand publicity.
Mr. Thompson if you mention
the word publicity again I
will scream.
You seem to think I exist to
give you a state in the papers.
Is there anything in the
world you care for except
publicity?
Well it's my job, and I'm ambitious.
And you'd sacrifice everything
for that, wouldn't you?
Good evening my children,
I hope I don't intrude.
Not at all, it only needed
you and the day's complete.
As a matter of fact
my boy I'm shy of cash.
I thought as much.
So if you would let
me have 2, 300 pounds.
You've had 1500 from us already.
So I have, but I've got
a lot on my conscience.
I'll let you have the
money tomorrow, now get out.
But my daughter, my only daughter.
I'm a reasonable man as long
as I can keep body and soul
together that's all I ask for here below.
In your state it's not safe
to let you have the money.
It's not safe not to.
Not a word, I'm a man of the world.
Now come on come on.
Well, there should be
some good publicity in that.
I'm rather tired, I think
I'll wish you a good night.
Goodnight.
Won't you have a cup of tea.
Thank you.
I can't sleep a wink.
That's funny, neither can I.
My tea's hot.
That's funny so is mine.
I never sleep in a strange bed.
Neither do I.
You know Harriet, I don't
think this stunt is treating you
fairly.
Oh I don't know, it's brought
in a lot more money than I
ever thought I'd have, a career
which I've always wanted,
a charming fiance which I'd
always hoped for, and a dear
little son which I never expected.
Goodnight.
? The world little because a
miracle has brought my lover
? To me, though it's another
place, his face I see
? At night I creep in bed,
but never sleep in bed
? Just look above in the air
? And do my sweetest joy, my boy is there
? It is my prince who walks
into my dreams and talks
? He dances overhead on
the ceiling near my bed
? In my fight through the night
? I try to hide in vain
underneath my counter pain
? There's my love up above
? I whisper go away my lover it's not fair
? But I'm so grateful to
discover he's still there
? I love my ceiling more
since it is a dancing floor
? For my love ?
And I hope that I may still
remain the public's most
obedient.
I've got a great idea.
You have, cough it up my lad.
I think it's just the way
to finish things off a sort of
marvelous finale.
I suggest that Harriet Green vanishes.
Vanishes.
Into thin air?
No no no, to South Africa.
I see, on the day before
her first night, why?
Because she's tired of it all.
Yes well we don't want
her to be tired of it all.
Have you seen the box office receipt.
Now wait a minute, she
vanishes, and three weeks later,
her young and beautiful
daughter arrives in England to
console her mother's heartbroken
public by taking her place.
You see, she's been studying
singing and dancing hard.
On the belt I suppose.
Yes.
No, do you realize what this means?
Impersonation fraud, we've
been lucky enough to get away
with it up to now, now
we've got to go on with it.
Well suppose I tell
them it was all my idea.
This young man's crazy Harriet,
do you know what's wrong?
Yes, I think I do.
Don't you see Harriet, Harriet
Green the star disappears
and the daughter comes to England.
I see.
And you go to South Hampton
to meet your sister.
My sister?
Oh Lord yes.
Oh Lord my sister, oh Lord my sister.
It's the excitement,
that's what it is, he's been
overworking.
Suppose we do follow
up that idea of Tommy's.
Suppose we do, then
everything gets found out.
Exactly how many of
us would be for the--
High drum?
Yes.
Well you'd be first,
impersonation and fraud, and then
Tommy for posing as your son.
What about you and Maudie?
Well of course if you'd like
to have it that you took us
in the same as Staines and the
public, I suppose we get off
without a blood or a scratch.
I see.
Ah my boy, did you get it.
What would you do if I
didn't give you this money?
I'd go straight to Scott and
Yard and give the whole game
away, that's what I'd do.
Is that a promise?
It is.
Hey.
Darling, thank you.
Now you mustn't get too
tired tonight my dear.
I won't.
Darling, come here a minute.
I've got something to confess to you.
Don't tell me you've
kept all my letters.
No, no it's something
much more serious than that.
Look at me closely, is this
the Harriet Green you loved
years ago?
Well aren't you furious at
being taken in like this?
I haven't been taken in,
I knew the minute I saw you.
I remembered your mother better
than most people you know.
But why did you let us--
Because I admired your plaque.
Because I like the look of your
young man, because I wanted
you to get away with it, and
because you're Harriet Green
Junior.
Come on my dear, I'm sure
it's gonna be a most exciting
first night.
I have a feeling it is too.
Well that went over all right Tommy.
? I've been a prisoner locked in a jail
? Love held the only key ?
Here my girl.
What are you doing here?
Never you mind, I'm
here and I want my money.
Ms. Green it's your quick change.
? I want a wonderful feeling
to be free, really free
? So over my shoulder goes one hair
? And over my shoulder goes two hairs
? Why should I cry above
? I'm free at last and I'm in love
? Over my shoulder goes three ?
Of course I know the young
man was only having his little
joke with me this morning when
he wouldn't give me my money.
So he didn't pay you?
No he didn't, so I've come to you.
After all daughter, I'm a
reasonable man as long as I can
keep body and soul together
that's all I ask for here below.
What would you do if I didn't pay?
Well I'd go straight to Scott
and Yard and get the whole
game away that's what I'd do.
Is that a promise?
Yeah.
Mr. Ben, Mr. Ben.
Oh what's the matter, what's the matter?
What's she doing?
I don't know, she's
never done it before.
She'll never do it again.
I can't believe it.
That isn't Harriet Green.
I don't believe she can do that at 60.
She's a fraud.
Now you know what I've been
dying to tell you for weeks.
A woman of 60.
Put your house lights up
and bring down that curtaiin.
What's the matter, put
out the houselights stop the
orchestra.
And what are you doing on my stage?
Nothing, it was by mistake.
She's not Harriet Green, she's a fraud.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I'm not gonna make a speech,
I'm just going to appeal to
you as the sporting British public.
Give us our money back.
Who's baby are you?
We've been had.
You've been had, how about
me, I've been in love with
her for weeks and had to
go about calling her mommy.
But she's not Harriet Green.
I know that my friend, but
let me tell you something,
she's the daughter of Harriet Green.
She hadn't got a job, she was
hungry, a few of you here may
know what that means.
But she had the talent she
had inherited from her famous
mother, the talent that
has charmed you tonight.
Now be honest ladies and
gentlemen, it has charmed you
hasn't it?
Now ladies and gentlemen, this
girl got a chance to prove
that she had it in her to be a star.
She wanted you to take her to
your hearts, do you blame her?
No.
Some may say she tried
to defraud the public.
I respectfully ask you to
note that phrase which is of
imperative importance.
Defraud the public, that means
surely to promise something,
to take payment for same, and
then to prove yourself unable
to fulfill that promise.
In plain English my Lord,
unable to deliver the goods.
Well ladies and gentlemen of
the jury, this is my case that
this young lady could not
possibly have defrauded the
public, because she delivers
the goods and I so prove it.
I call the prisoner.
You are charged with
defrauding the public by
impersonating your mother,
the late Harriet Green.
What is your name?
Harriet Green.
You see my Lord.
Proceed, proceed.
What is your profession?
I am an actress.
And your mother?
She was an actress.
Who was?
Her mother my Lord,
the late Harriet Green.
Who was Harriet Green?
Silence in court.
Harriet Green my Lord
was a famous stage star.
So you've been singing
several songs of your mother's
reportou.
Yes.
You sing them as well as she did?
Well, it's rather difficult
for me to answer that
question.
My Lord in my submission it
is a question of facts for the
jury to judge.
Exhibit A please.
I have here my lad a
phonographic reproduction of one of
the late Harriet Green's
most famous songs.
I submit that this is
not admissible evidence.
In the case of Smith vs.
Smith 1914, to the King's bench
my lad, page 493.
Was allowed to prove his
statement by demonstration of his
art my Lord.
Hear the evidence.
? When you're young it's always spring
? And life is a happy song,
how we care and sing as we go
? Along, though the years go rushing by
? And spring is a memory,
life will always be the same
? Sweet song to me
? When there's spring in your heart
? And the wintery winds that blow
? Buttercups come peeping through the snow
? And you love your whole life through
? And in love
? And each happy thing will
be evergreen as the sweetest
? Blooming in June
? When you've got a little
springtime in your heart
? Over my shoulder goes one
hair, over my shoulder goes
? Two hairs, why should I cry
? I'm free at last and I'm in love
? Over my shoulder goes three hairs
? Over my shoulder goes four hairs
? Over my shoulder goes it all ?
This is all I ask for here below.
? When you've got a little
spring time in your heart
? You can love the wintery winds that blow
? And the memory will be
evergreen when the spring time's
? Coming through
? When you've got a little
spring time in your heart