Subtitles by OnDemandKorea
(This program is about 2 MCs)
(who are praised and survived)
(in a jungle of variety shows.)
(This is a documentary about these two)
(going on a trip to find dinner.)
(1793, on King Jungjo's 17th year.
(King Jung Jo.)
I'm building a new city here.
Every wealth will be spread out.
There will be no class.
Everyone will be equal.
It's my dream...
My passion...
Will you...
Help me?
(2017, on Let's Have Dinner's 1st year.)
(City of Suwon, Gyeonggido.)
2017 is so hot.
(So hot.)
(Burning.)
It's been hot for a while.
It still is!
(A Sunday under the last heat wave.)
Do you know where we are?
Hwasung in Suwon.
Suwon!
It looks very old.
We should do a new version
of Let's Have Dinner Together.
Why don't we do a version
that focuses on humanities studies?
Sure.
Let me start.
The city of Suwon...
Has a UNESCO's...
World Heritage site.
Did you know that?
Of course.
King Jungjo...
(Google search battle...)
King Jungjo was Chosun's 22nd king.
He gave orders...
To Jung Yak-Yong to build a castle
in Suwon.
He got a lot of people to move here.
This is the first new town in Korea.
It's a planned city by King Jungjo.
It's Chosun's Bundang.
Thing of it as Bundang.
He's right.
Chosun's first planned city,
Suwon, Gyeonggido.
The 22nd king of Chosun, King Jungjo
opened the Renaissance era in Korea.
As he moved his father's grave
to Yunggeollung,
the best site in Korea,
he planned to build a new city
of his dreams here.
We know that city as Suwon today.
He hired noted scholars such as
Jung Yak-Yong
he built Suwon and Hwasung castle
with meticulous planning.
With unrivaled building technology,
it was chosen as UNESCO's
World Heritage in 1997.
In a city of King Jungjo's dreams,
can the 4 spoons dream
to have a meal become true?
Let's Have Dinner Together,
episode 46.
A Dream of a Meal.
What can you tell us about Suwon?
Suwon is...
An amazing place.
(Kyu-dong tours Hwasung.)
They're all walls.
Wait...
Is that a bow?
This is an archery.
That's awesome.
(200 years old training ground)
(where soldiers used to train.)
They're amazing.
Should we try?
(And...)
(These two stand out)
(amongst the rest.)
I'm sure our guests are here too!
(Are archers today's guests?)
Hi!
Hi.
Did you see any famous people here?
You guys aren't Koreans?
Taiwan?
(While they failed to get a hint...)
(Who are they...?)
It's them.
Hi guests!
(Ignores them for now...)
Guests!
Hi!
(Who are today's guests?)
They shot some arrows as a girl group.
The definition of Korean girl groups,
Girls' Generations's
Sunny and Yu-ri are today's guests.
Sunny!
Yu-ri!
(Welcome.)
You came all the way to Suwon!
The only generation that I know...
Is Girls' Generation.
They have 10 people!
What?
(They don't?)
I read the news article...
I heard for the 1st time in 10 years...
No, not 1st time in 10 years...
Oops.
I heard this is their 10th year.
They came to Ask Us Anything and Sunny
chose you as her role model.
Really?
Because you don't listen to others.
She said you're her hero.
I want to be the little Lee Kyung-kyu!
Sunny and I went to
a lot of traditional bazaars.
Sunny told me that
you take so long to record a show!
I even ran away from him.
She said you take at least 6 hours.
(I completely understand.)
I hope that doesn't happen today.
There are a lot of bazaars here.
How much do you know about Suwon?
I shot a drama called Neighborhood Hero
in Suwon.
You did?
I spent about 3 months here.
Then tell us a little bit about Suwon.
Suwon is...
Known for galbi!
It's here!
(Where are we going today?)
Go to Hwaseodong in Suwon
to have a meal.
Where's Hwaseodong?
Close by?
Look what's inside.
There's a transportation card...
There's a ticket for Hwasung Royal Train!
I saw it right in front.
Let's go!
(Before going to Hwaseodong...)
They decide to get on
the Hwasung Royal Train
to look around Hwasung.
(What does it look like?)
There it is!
This way.
(Made with inspirations from)
(Emperor Sunjong's car and carriers.)
It even has seat belts.
Let's go!
Here are some facts about Suwon's Hwasung.
They're teaching us about Hwasung!
You can see Dongjangdae to the front.
This is where King Jungjo
inspected his soldiers too.
It's telling us what each area was
as we drive by!
(Time travel back to 200 years ago...)
(Very detailed explanation.)
Willow trees!
(Google search not necessary.)
You'll be the one shooting arrows,
and I'll be order you to shoot!
Because you're my general?
(Acts like a general.)
(They reply history with comedy.)
It's nice here.
It feels so nice!
This wind feels nice.
(There's no need to walk.)
Hi!
(Tries to have a conversation right away.)
When did you guys get on?
Make some noise!
There were that many people?
I didn't see either.
(This train is very popular.)
King Jungjo!
(King Jungjo?)
(A giant statue.)
(Welcome.)
He was also famous for being good looking!
What else do you know about him?
Hyun Bin from The Fatal Encounter!
That's why I asked.
His back muscles.
(Angry back muscles.)
To protect himself,
King Jungjo worked out day and night.
Hyun Bin's back muscles shed light
to this story again.
I think it was when
he was shooting that movie
and had to work out a lot.
I met him at a sauna.
For the first time, I thought
my body was disgusting.
(Found the truth after 45 years.)
I walked in that sauna
and it was Jang Dong-gun, Hyun Bin and me.
(Embarrassed in a sauna.)
I wasn't there but I can totally see it.
The thing is...
Hyun Bin played King Jungjo
in The Fatal Encounter...
Lee Seo-Jin played him in Lee San.
All handsome actors play King Jungjo.
King Jungjo in The Throne...
Was played by So Ji-sub.
Hwasung is big!
(Total length of 5.7km.)
Is this wall...
The original wall?
Yup.
I'm sure it only had minor fixes.
That's why preservation is much more
important than development.
Preservation is...
Preservation is much harder.
The Royal Train carrying 4 spoons
goes straight through the city
following the foot steps and dreams
of King Jungjo.
(He wanted this castle to protect)
(his father's grave)
(and have people live inside happily.)
(The King's march.)
King Jungjo's dream
has been protecting this city
for more than 200 years.
This whole town is historic and cultural.
I've never looked at Suwon this carefully.
Same here.
My grandma lives in Suwon.
I used to come here as a kid.
But I didn't know it was this big.
This street is named, King Jungjo Road.
King Jungjo is every where in Suwon.
He's the one who made the city.
(The train is in the city center now.)
Like in dramas,
this road existed 200 years ago!
I feel like a king!
Are we here?
Yup.
But it was so nice.
I want to get on it again.
(Arrived at Paldalmun Bazaar.)
200 years ago,
King Jungjo wanted Suwon to become
a hub of commerce.
He opened this bazaar and called
every famous merchants in the country.
This bazaar made by a king
is next to other 8 bazaars.
As one of the biggest bazaars,
it boasts a huge size and choices.
Ho-dong.
Sit over here and drink with King Jungjo.
I can join him?
Then take a picture.
(Shows how it's done.)
(Good day to drink.)
King Jungjo and a king of variety shows!
Do your job!
(How dare you!)
The records say that
drinking with King Jungjo
didn't end until one person passed out.
Some people say drinking
was his way of dealing with his stress.
(He died at 49 without seeing)
(reforms he dreamed of.)
Let me take a picture.
That's a nice photo.
One, two, three!
The king of variety shows meets King Jungjo
to share a drink.
Kyung-kyu!
Let's check out the bazaar!
There are tons to do here!
No!
(Will they take 6 hours here too?)
It's pretty big.
This bazaar is open to all directions!
I heard it's made of
9 different bazaars.
9 different bazaars?
That's why it's so big!
It's huge.
(Someone comes up to Ho-dong.)
You're really skinny!
(Here he goes again...)
Do you know who this is?
Hi!
She's a singer.
What generation?
Let's keep up with Kyung-kyu!
Yu-ri!
What do you want?
(Annoyed.)
If you could choose only one...
Are you buying?
Why are they wasting their time?
They can't even eat and
they're wasting their time.
You think we'll be successful today?
Today?
To be honest...
I'm really shy...
Eating at a stranger's house...
Worries me.
I'll be worried whether we're
both successful or not.
It's okay.
It might be awkward at first.
But the other people will be too.
It will be for both of you.
Not just for me?
They'll be awkward when they open the door.
But once you get to talking,
you'll get close to them.
Really?
You wouldn't want to leave at the end.
Every time.
Just see it for yourself.
(He became a philosopher.)
(Arrived at the bus stop.)
We have to take the bus to Hwaseodong.
(Still a transportation hub for Suwon)
(even after 200 years.)
Here's Paldalmun!
(Needs to take Bus #3 to Hwaseodong.)
(Finally arrived...)
It's here!
The bus is here!
Let's go.
(On their way to Hwaseodong for a meal.)
Hwaseodong gets its name
from Hwasung's west gate.
Will they be able to find a meal there?
(They arrived at Hwaseodong.)
(How does Hwaseodong look like?)
Let's go to where houses are.
Okay!
Kyung-kyu!
Smell...
Even their sign looks delicious...
I can smell the charcoals!
(Galbi on charcoals.)
Wait.
Why is Suwon famous for galbi?
There are a lot of theories...
One theory says that killing cows
were only allowed in Suwon
to meet the nutritious needs
for workers who built the city.
Another suggests that it's famous because
one of Korea's biggest beef market
is in Suwon.
How can there be a Korean BBQ restaurant
right on the entrance?
(I know.)
I wish we can eat some galbi today.
Apartments, condos and houses
are all mixed here.
But most of them are houses.
Houses, condos...
(Which one would they go into today?)
Look at those persimmons.
I see!
(They'll ripe very soon...)
Sunny, did you ever live in a house?
I used to live in a house.
We had a persimmon tree like that too.
It brings me back memories!
I think my family was closer
when we lived in a house
to our neighbors.
Dates tree.
(From a tree full of dates...)
They're all peppers.
Everyone grows something here.
(A lot of fruits and vegetables)
(growing in this city...)
Will Girls' Generation...
Last forever?
What?
What are you talking about?
This is their 10th year.
No one knows.
Will it be Mothers' Generation later?
We'll still be Girls' Generation
even when we're mothers.
Girls' Generation is forever.
You think you can do it for 20 years?
We didn't think we can do 10
at first either.
Because you hated each other?
You almost got me to say yes!
Not a lot of idols lasted 5 years
back in our days.
They say 7th year is crucial these days.
It was 5 back then.
History is always written again.
Every step you take now is a history.
I guess so.
11th year, 15th year...
I think that's why I feel
more pressured these days...
I can't just blurt things out.
Really?
Solar panels!
That's a good idea.
Something is connected
to that solar panel.
That's cool.
Everyone has solar panels!
That house has one too!
(Another solar panels!)
Are they for doorbells'...
Power?
Just doorbells?
I'm sure there's more...
Excuse me miss!
Those solar panels...
What are they for?
For the lights!
The address plaque lights up?
That's cool!
For the lights!
(Used to light up the address plaques)
(at night.)
Thank you!
(Good luck!)
There aren't a lot of people here...
It's vacation season.
That could be our disadvantage.
I think I can do a good job
if I can talk to someone
face to face.
But talking into a speaker
seems really awkward.
Hello.
I'm Yu-ri from Girls' Generation.
(What is she doing?)
Did you eat yet?
(Do it again...)
(Already?)
Are you doing it already?
Did you start already?
She started already?
(She's a good actor.)
I'll be waiting!
Practice.
I thought I heard someone!
Practice!
No one answered?
I heard something!
Inside voices.
I must be hearing things!
(Time to talk strategies.)
Double Kyu!
What's that?
Sun-kyu and Kyung-kyu!
Double Kyu!
But that sounds so weird!
You're both too violent.
What?
Sunny, come here.
(Ho-dong and Yu-ri are in a team.)
In Hwaseodong with Girls' Generation.
Let's not have them regret their 10 years.
Kyung-kyu!
Let's make it worthwhile!
Let's Have Dinner Together!
Time to dream about a meal in Hwaseodong.
Let's get started.
Are we starting?
They really do pick any houses.
Yup.
Sunny, go for it.
This is our first attempt!
It's only our first house...
It's a practice.
But, we're rewriting history today!
(Sunny's first attempt!)
(But...)
It's broken.
That was anticlimactic.
(Sunny's first attempt fails.)
Did we fail?
Is it my turn now?
The door's open!
(Can Yu-ri rewrite history in Suwon?)
(Yu-ri's first attempt!)
(Will she fail too?)
Who is it?
Hi!
I'm Yu-ri from Girls' Generation!
Someone's coming out!
The noise is coming from up there!
Give me a minute!
Should we hide over there?
(Camouflaged?)
His voice sounded really nice!
I hope you're successful.
I will.
He's here!
Hi!
I'm Yu-ri from Girls' Generation.
Do you know me?
Yup.
(Great start!)
Did you eat dinner yet?
Not yet.
I see...
I even have my own spoon with me!
If it's okay...
(Sounds very convincing so far.)
Is your family home?
My wife is home!
What do you think about...
All of us talking...
And having a meal together?
Let me go ask my wife.
I think she's got it!
(Success on first attempt is close!)
I think we got it!
He looks really nice.
Should we go upstairs
after you're successful on the 1st floor?
Should we eat in the same house?
Hi!
We're from a TV program.
It's called Let's Have Dinner Together
from JTBC.
I know.
It'll be just me and Yu-ri.
If it's okay...
Would you like to eat with us?
(Will Yu-ri be successful?)
My wife said no...
(Oh my god.)
(Yu-ri's first attempt failed!)
Thank you for talking to us on Sunday
while getting a rest.
(Huge smiles.)
Thank you for recognizing me.
Good luck in this hot weather.
We thought we'd be successful.
It would've been nice to eat with you.
(He's happy they didn't.)
Why are you so happy?
Then good luck in everything...
Be careful in this heat...
Enjoy your dinner.
Thank you.
It's pretty easy!
I thought it'd work...
I thought so too!
A spousal agreement is a must
to have a meal.
It's summer.
Inviting guests in isn't easy.
Sunny!
We can tell if someone's home
by looking at the air conditioner.
(No sound again...)
(Rings one more time.)
Who is it?
Hi!
I'm Sunny from Girls' Generation!
Okay.
Do you know who I am?
Not really...
I see...
Are you from JTBC?
That's right!
I saw you guys earlier.
Really?
Would you like to...
Join a program you normally enjoy...
(Very smooth.)
And have a chance
to talk about all kinds of things?
Sure!
Thank you!
You have to ask her if she ate!
(We don't know if she ate yet...)
Some people still want to offer meals
when they ate.
That's our most important rule.
Yes?
I forgot to ask you a question.
Did you eat yet?
Dinner?
We barely ate.
(No way...)
(The car got angry!)
(Chaos.)
I'm sorry!
That wasn't me!
Don't get the wrong idea!
Hello?
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu!
Hi!
What did you mean by barely ate?
We just had bean stew...
So you already ate...
(The car started.)
If you ate already,
we can't go in!
Thank you!
There's no one in there!
What's going on?
Some cars can be started by their keys.
There she is!
Sorry to bother you!
(Yu-ri's attempt.)
Whose turn is it?
Yu-ri.
That's a nice noise!
(Someone picked up!)
Hi, I'm Yu-ri from Girls' Generation.
Girls' Generation?
Hi!
Wow!
Who's your favorite?
Yu-ri!
(Hopeful.)
You're my boss' niece.
What?
Your boss?
Mr. Cha...
That's right!
I'm sorry but my house is too dirty...
That's fine!
How do you know her?
How do you know my uncle again?
I work for him!
She works for my uncle!
Wow!
That's so awesome!
Out of everyone in this world,
you and I met today!
That's so cool.
Ask her to come down.
Let's talk face to face.
Why don't you come down?
Let me get dressed.
Okay!
That's so cool!
I know!
The world is so tiny!
Sunny.
What does your uncle do?
Nothing much...
How awesome.
My uncle owns a company...
It's pretty big.
I'm her uncle's employee.
Me too!
(Who's her uncle?)
Lee Soo-man.
Soo-man?
He's your uncle?
(Everyone here is his employee.)
Sorry Soo-man.
(She has some connections.)
(Kyung-kyu's question backfired.)
I don't think she's coming.
Should I call my uncle?
And ask him to...
Don't.
Don't put him in that position!
I was just gonna say it was nice
to meet her!
But today's Sunday...
She could get wrong ideas.
You're right.
She's here!
Hi!
I knew she'd wear a mask!
Isn't that what celebrities do in airports?
Hi!
You look like a celebrity at the airport.
Why don't you eat together?
Is your house dirty?
Let me take a photo of you two.
I'll get the address in there too.
You can't even see her!
(Huh...?)
She doesn't look at a camera either.
Look.
She's not looking at the camera!
What was the point of this?
(No one will recognize who that is.)
It was nice seeing you!
How about that house?
(Confidently walks up to the next house.)
Who is it?
Hi!
I'm Sunny from Girls' Generation.
Do you know who I am?
Yes!
Really?
(She opened her front gate.)
I went to watch you guys shoot.
I've been waiting...
But we just ate.
You should've waited a bit longer!
That sucks...
She just ate.
(As soon as Sunny failed,)
(Yu-ri goes to the next house.)
(Nervous.)
No one's picking up...
Are you normally a lucky person?
Yes?
Hi!
I'm Yu-ri from Girls' Generation.
What?
Hi.
I'm a singer.
Do you know who I am?
Not really?
Sing her a song!
Girls' Generation!
She's Yu-ri!
I'm Kang Ho-dong!
We're doing a TV show for JTBC.
Is this Let's Have Dinner Together?
You're absolutely right!
Don't feel pressure to talk on TV.
You can take it easy.
You can talk about whatever you want.
Did you eat dinner yet?
Well...
My husband isn't home...
I'm alone right now.
I didn't eat dinner yet...
You didn't eat yet?
But I'm dying my hair right now!
We can help you!
I'm doing it right now!
Yu-ri said she can help you!
Yu-ri's really good!
I'll even wash your hair!
I'll wash your hair!
That's not the problem...
If you came just 30 minutes earlier,
I would've given you everything I had...
I can't eat with you because
I'm dying my hair!
I hope we can see you next time
we have a chance then!
Thank you. I'm sorry!
Thanks!
Have a nice weekend!
(Dying her hair.)
It's really okay!
(Disappointed...)
Just do it!
Eat with them!
I was waiting but I just ate!
(But, I'm dying my hair!)
Bye!
That was amazing.
The whole street was united just now.
(Goes to their next target.)
I have a good feeling about this house.
This doorbell is so high up!
Who is it?
Hi!
(Someone picked up again!)
Hi, I'm Sunny from Girls' Generation.
Really?
Yes!
Oh my god!
Ask her if what song she knows.
(We'll take care of it.)
If it's okay...
Would you like to...
Have dinner with me?
I was actually looking forward to it...
But I just ate...
You ate already?
I just ate!
(Terrible timing!)
Well, it was nice seeing you anyways!
Thank you!
Dying hair and early meals...
Their dreams of having a meal
on a holiday is not looking good.
(Yu-ri's turn.)
(In position.)
Who is it?
Hello!
Wait!
What?
I'm...
Wait!
(What's going on?)
Who is it?
Hello!
Wait!
What?
I'm...
Wait!
I thought she saw Yu-ri as a ghost!
(Loudest reaction yet.)
Hello?
Yes!
(Sounds nervous.)
I'm Yu-ri from Girls' Generation!
I know!
Nice to meet you.
Please calm down.
Did you calm down?
Yes...
Did you eat dinner yet?
No...
(Nice timing!)
Your voice suggests...
You're a student?
Yes...
College or high school?
College.
Who do you live with?
I live with my family.
Are you with your parents now?
They're grocery shopping right now.
They went to a grocery store for dinner?
(Automatically kneels down.)
Then...
Hey!
We'll wait out here.
This isn't something you can decide
on your own.
Call your parents and ask
if Let's Have Dinner Together can join you!
Okay!
(All they need is her parents' permission.)
I think...
It's 50-50.
No!
I'm sorry!
I can't!
My mom said no!
(Great acting performance.)
I want to.
But mom says no!
(The most intense rejection ever.)
My mom said no!
But things are looking up!
I think she's a big fan!
Her parents are grocery shopping
and she really wants this to happen.
She's on the phone right now!
Hi!
Freshman?
Senior.
You looked really young.
We can just talk while having dinner.
Can we go inside?
Are you her father?
Dad!
What's wrong?
(She has special reactions...)
We're from JTBC.
It's a show called,
Let's Have Dinner Together!
We just talked to your daughter.
There's her mom!
(Her mom finally arrived too.)
Hi!
Let me explain it to you in 1 minute.
It's about sharing a meal together,
whatever you have in your house is fine.
At my house?
That's what our program is.
Sure!
(Amazing.)
(Ho-dong and Yu-ri succeed!)
Hi!
How did you know about our house?
We choose random houses.
We had no idea you lived here.
I thought something was wrong...
Your daughter caused the scene.
My heart's about to explode...
We came back from the movies.
Why didn't you go with your parents?
She had to study...
You can eat with them
because she didn't go!
Then let's go inside...
We have to go.
Kyung-kyu and Sunny has to go.
It'll be just me and Yu-ri.
I have to take a picture...
(Holding Sunny's hands.)
Mom, take a picture of us!
(Despite being excited, can't forget)
(to take pictures.)
Sunny has to go.
Then me too...
(Taking pictures is a must.)
Kyung-kyu too!
(Kyung-kyu finally joins in as well.)
We don't have a lot of time.
(Smile.)
(Satisfied.)
You should get going.
(Time to say goodbye.)
Good luck!
Thanks Sunny!
See you later!
See you next week!
Good luck!
Sunny, don't give up!
Of course!
It's our 10th year!
I know!
Good luck!
Let's go.
With passionate welcome,
they enter a house in Hwaseodong.
Miss!
Could you give us a tour of your yard?
Our yard?
Me?
Dad, help!
She sounds calm now.
Through the intercom, she was...
I've never seen that before.
I thought I was a ghost.
Dad!
Dad, help.
(Doesn't let go of her dad's hand.)
Where are you going?
To get the grill...
(Today's menu is pork belly.)
We eat with my parents every Sunday.
But they're at the movies.
So we were just going to eat ourselves.
That's when you came!
It's not a special menu for us,
but you were gonna eat that anyways?
It's been defrosting for a while now.
(Let's go inside!)
A living room has photos
of the family's happy memories
from the past.
What movie did you watch today?
A Taxi Driver.
It's setting all kinds of records!
What should I do?
Do you go on a lot of dates
with your husband on weekends?
Yup.
That's so romantic!
You, your husband...
Is Ji-hye your oldest daughter?
No, my youngest.
Her sister's on her way home.
Is she a college student too?
She's a senior.
But she's a senior too.
Her older sister took some time off.
(Still incredulous.)
This show doesn't even have a script!
(Shy.)
Mom, there's a camera on me.
That's not important right now!
I don't know what to do...
Wash vegetables.
(They get ready for dinner.)
(Perfect combination)
(of Kimchi and pork belly.)
Did you ever watch our show before?
Nope.
He hardly watches TV.
If you didn't know about this show,
why did you invite us in?
He's famous!
The whole country knows who he is.
Do you know who this is?
Yup.
That's a song!
Girls' Generation.
That's right!
She's Girls' Generation?
(Hears everything despite being busy.)
Do you need my help?
It's okay, I can do it!
I...
Should've showered.
I can't take my hat off either!
Should I put on some make up?
Go put something on!
I'll wash these.
(While Yu-ri helps out,)
(Ji-hye gets ready too.)
(Embarrassed.)
Was the movie good?
Yes...
I'm a bit angry right now...
It reminds me of the old days...
Where are you from?
Seoul.
How about your wife?
Jeonju.
When did you move to Suwon?
In 1999...
In 1999,
I came here to build apartments
then settled down.
Are you in constructions?
Part of LG.
Then you lived in this house for 18 years?
We moved here in 2007.
It's been 10 years.
Suwon's a great place to live!
Why is that?
Everyone likes it here.
To go watch baseball...
Or movies in Seoul,
it takes forever with traffic.
But not here.
There aren't as many people here.
When we go somewhere...
We can exit the highway
right when traffic starts in Osan.
It's got good transportation.
Suwon and Osan are where
traffic starts!
But that's when I exit.
Isn't that your daughter?
Come in!
I thought she was our writer!
She kept taking pictures!
(She couldn't come in)
(so she just took photos.)
Welcome back!
(Choi Seol. Age 24.)
Is this okay?
Hi!
(Today's oldest daughter, Yu-ri.)
Shake her hand!
We have to eat together!
Did you set the spoons?
Yup.
With the help of her 3 daughters,
the dinner is quickly being made.
(Korean pancakes made from scratch.)
With a perfect teamwork of
3 daughters setting the table
and their mother cooking...
The meal was ready in no time.
(Ji-hye put on a makeup.)
Are you crazy?
Am I too white?
Ji-hye, go put this over there.
No!
Aren't I too white?
(It's okay.)
I didn't put a makeup on in 4 weeks.
4 weeks?
Your eyebrows are too thick.
Do you want my help?
It feels like you have a lot of daughters.
You don't look out of place in there!
(3 sisters cooking with their mom.)
Welcome to my house.
Can we drink on TV?
Of course!
Is that what you normally do?
Yes.
That's what's most important here!
Sir, you don't have to act differently...
Don't call me sir!
I'm not that much older than you!
You are!
(He still feels young inside.)
I tend to do that to fathers...
Is that right sir?
(Si-hoo's father.)
What year were you born?
1966.
You're much older than I am!
I was born in the 70s!
Weren't you born around 70 or 71?
1970...
(Only 4 years older.)
You just married earlier than I did.
Of course!
I got married when I was 27.
Mid 20s...
My wife was 24.
In prime of her life.
If you look at our old photos...
She's beautiful.
(When she was more beautiful than flowers.)
How did you two meet?
My little sister was in her major.
In a same university?
You knew her through your sister?
My sister...
Did it...
Do what?
She set us up.
Where did you two first meet?
At Jongno.
With your sister?
Was she there?
She came too.
Did having her there help?
She didn't...
Introduce me as her brother.
I heard she told my wife
that I was just someone she knew...
In case my wife didn't want
to meet her friend's brother.
Because it could be awkward...
(That's how they first met.)
We'll ask about your love story
in more details soon.
(Already embarrassed.)
Which cup should we use for rice wines?
We normally use this cup.
Okay, I'll just take these then.
I'll do it, I'm the expert!
(Here comes the technique.)
(Exquisite wrist snaps.)
(A true expert.)
(Even uses a spoon as a tool.)
What was that?
You have to knock...
Before you open it.
(How an expert handles rice wines.)
(Closes the bottle.)
(Knocks again.)
I'm going in!
(More careful than going into)
(his kid's room during puberty.)
It didn't overflow.
There's no gas!
Do you drink rice wine often when you eat?
All the time.
All the time?
I drink it instead of eating rice.
He doesn't eat rice.
You don't eat carbs?
Not that much.
Just for dinner.
So you do eat it for breakfast and lunch.
But carbs for dinner is rice wine?
Wow, this table might break
with so much food.
I have to take a picture of this first.
We do?
(Pork belly goes on the grill.)
I can't fit everything!
(Uses a huge camera from the kitchen.)
A meal from Hwaseodong in Suwon.
This meal...
Is a dinner on a weekend by a family
of their normal menu, pork belly
with assortments of vegetables
and side dishes.
Ma'am!
It's called  The Dinner Theater.
Imagine as if we don't exist.
Come here.
(A Sunday dinner in Hwaseodong.)
(He pours rice wine for his daughters.)
Who's going to pour it for me?
I will!
Fill it up!
Come here!
Cheers!
Cheers.
(A dinner scene with rice wine.)
Let's eat.
Bon appetit!
Enjoy.
Where are you going?
(She tried to run away.)
Why are you home so early?
I got out 30 minutes early today.
(Her mom ran away to the kitchen.)
This is so awkward...
I know.
I'm still wearing a hat...
(How cute.)
This isn't the debut I had in mind.
Can you come already?
This isn't easy, is it?
Please take a seat.
Ho-dong, do you want some rice wine?
How about Yu-ri?
Of course I have to drink!
What are you talking about!
Girls' Generation drinks rice wines too?
(Rice wine is the best.)
But isn't this cup too big?
It's okay!
(Drinks rice win out of a beer cup.)
Thank you.
I didn't know Girls' Generation
drinks rice wines too.
(Only half full because the cup is huge.)
(Disappointed.)
(Ho-dong gets a glass too.)
Thank you for the food!
(Cheers!)
Sorry.
(To the staff members.)
(Starts with rice wine first.)
(Pork belly is almost cooked.)
(While the meat is being cooked,)
(she tries the Korean pancakes first.)
I can't finish the whole thing.
How is it?
Very delicious!
We always have food like this
so he can eat with rice wine.
He doesn't eat...
Put it on top of the rice.
Then eat it with Kimchi.
Can't get full just yet...
The real deal is still waiting.
(Yu-ri gets a piece of meat.)
Try this with it.
(Puts the vegetable on the wrap.)
Yu-ri, the daughter for the day,
eats the wrap made by her mom
and drinks the rice wine poured by her dad.
Then drinks some more
after a bite of a pancake.
We always thought she was a girl...
But now she's a lady who knows
how to drink rice wines.
(Huge.)
Ho-dong is trying to beat his record
for the biggest wrap again.
With an incredible size
and the size of his mouth,
there's no room for rice wine.
This is what Sunny was talking about!
Sunny was doing a show with Ho-dong...
When he was eating wraps,
she thought they reached
the back of his head.
(An extraordinary size.)
This is what she meant!
It's that big!
The back of my head moves when I eat.
Eww...
She said eww!
(Shocking.)
While they're enjoying the unexpected
rice wine and pork belly party...
These two can't even dream
about eating pork belly.
Sunny.
Good sound.
Who is it?
Hi, I'm sunny from Girls' Generation...
Are you joking?
No, I'm really her.
We're shooting for a show from JTBC,
Let's Have Dinner Together.
Okay.
If it's okay...
Can we eat dinner together?
We were just about to head out.
We're eating ice cream right now...
Did you eat already?
Yes!
Okay.
We ate sundae soup!
I see...
(Even tells them what he ate...)
(Even more hungry now...)
(Which house will let Kyung-kyu and Sunny)
(in for dinner...?)
It's 7:30...
Everyone must've eaten by now.
Here?
(They press on...)
No noise.
Nothing.
(They're both broken this time...)
Why are they all broken?
(Tries the house right across.)
(It's broken here too...)
We should get out of here.
(The time keeps passing...)
We still have time!
(But...)
There's no sound.
(Don't have time anymore...)
They're all broken.
(No matter how much they ring,)
(not a single one works...)
They're all broken...
They're all broken!
(And to make things worse...)
Oh, here's the bell.
Who's gonna use this?
(Tries to get his hand in there...)
Hello?
(This bell is broken too...)
(Are they gonna end up)
(at the convenience store?)
(Soaked by sweat...)
Why are they all broken?
Everyone should fix their bell.
(Finally the one that works!)
Hello?
Who is it?
Sunny?
Come inside and eat!
(What are you doing?)
I've been waiting.
Why don't you come in?
I know who you are...
Someone's coming!
Umm...
Hi!
This is Sunny from Girls' Generation!
Do you know Let's Have Dinner Together?
Yes!
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu!
Hi!
What were you up to?
I was eating dinner.
Are you done eating?
Can I come outside?
Of course!
Why are you all wet?
It's too hot.
Here's Sunny.
How can I help you?
We're from Let's Have Dinner Together...
(Looks like it's a secret conversation...)
Are you eating here?
I don't know the show too well...
We go in if you let us...
(Needs the whole family's permission.)
We even brought our spoons.
Are your parents home?
Yes.
Could you go ask?
(Goes in to ask his parents.)
(A success finally...?)
The moon's out!
Look at the moon!
(That's not important...)
The moon's out and we were
just talking about lunch...
Look how bright the moon is!
Hi!
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu.
Hello.
I know this show.
Did you eat...?
My wife doesn't want to...
Thanks.
(Thanks for coming out.)
I love this show.
Thank you.
We have to get going!
Sorry...
It's okay!
(Things were looking good...)
(But failed again.)
(Kyung-kyu's hair is getting more wet...)
I haven't been to a convenience store
in a while.
(Tries an apartment this time.)
Oh my god!
Hi!
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu!
Hi, I'm Sunny from Girls' Generation!
(Intense welcome.)
Give me a minute!
Okay!
(Then the gate opens.)
(Sunny's back is soaked too.)
Hi!
Hello.
(Things are looking up?)
Did you eat yet?9
We already did...
You ate already?
(Didn't know about the show...)
We can't go in if you ate.
That sucks...
(Sunny rings the next door.)
Hi.
I'm Sunny from Girls' Generation.
Give me a minute.
Give me a minute?
(Kyung-kyu is ready to go upstairs.)
I'll wait here!
(It's 7:53!)
(The door finally opened...)
(Failed after 1 second.)
Who is it?
(Met another residence...)
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu.
Did you eat dinner already?
Yes...
(Already ate...)
(There's not a lot of time left!)
Hello?
Hi!
I'm not in a state for a TV camera...
(Failed again...)
(They ring together this time.)
(Please...)
We only have 5 minutes!
(Can't waste anymore time.)
Hurry!
We don't have time!
(Failure means going)
(to the convenience store...)
(Anyone home?)
(Can't wait.)
(1 minute left!)
Hello?
Hi!
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu!
I know, but what are you doing here?
If you didn't eat yet...
And if you invite us in...
It's a show where we eat together.
Give me a minute!
Okay!
Not yet!
(The door opens.)
Hi!
Hi.
Hello.
Here's Sunny from Girls' Generation.
(Sunny?)
Hi!
Her name is Sun-hee.
Really?
Hi Sun-hee!
If you invite us in...
Is it okay if we eat...
But we're out of food!
Ramen is fine.
We only need rice and water.
Did you eat yet?
We were about to.
Ramen is fine too.
Anything is okay!
Our time's up at 4.
4?
I mean 8!
But our house is such a mess!
We'll give you time to clean.
What time is it right now?
It's 8!
If you don't invite us in...
We have to go to the convenience store.
No, don't go!
She said, don't go!
Which ramen do you want?
(Anything is fine.)
(He just goes in now...)
Would you like to eat with me and Sunny?
Thank you!
(Finally succeeds!)
Thank you so much!
Success!
(Right at the buzzer...!)
We can give you time to clean.
Hi!
Sun-hee's house in Suwon
opened their door for Sunny.
Can we go in?
Don't feel pressure about the cameras.
Did you watch our show before?
It's called Let's Have Dinner Together.
It's on JTBC...
I like that station!
Do you know who I am?
Lee Kyung-kyu!
(Caught off guard by a foreigner.)
(He's a Filipino American!)
He's a Filipino American.
(First multi-cultural family!)
Only a little.
(Relieved.)
He loves Girls' Generation.
(Her husband was a huge fan.)
How old is your baby?
13 months.
Hi!
Sunny?
She's Sun-hee.
Ma'am.
Can I go wash my face?
Of course!
(He had a tough day today...)
You should probably take a shower...
((Goes to freshen up...)
Sun-hee lives with a happy family
of two cultures.
(Kyung-kyu bravely asks a question.)
4 years.
(That's the end of his English.)
My last name is Cho.
She must've gotten her mom's last name!
(He's funny.)
He did it way before Park Myung-soo.
How long have you been married for?
About 2 years.
How did you guys meet?
I used to hire English teachers.
I hired my husband.
Then hired him at your home too.
I got him his current life.
(His new life thanks to his wife...)
I think he came to Korea for girl groups.
Who's your favorite?
(Disappointed.)
But I like Girls' Generation too.
The order doesn't matter...
(Keep it up Sunny.)
Did you study in America?
No, I always lived in Korea.
Do you guys work in a same company?
No, he works at a school now...
Is his school close by?
It's an elementary school in Yeongtong.
An elementary school!
That's cool.
He's an immigrant.
(Jason was born in the Philippines.)
Say hi.
(The water starts to boil.)
(Stands up.)
(He helps out in the kitchen.)
We don't always eat like this...
We went away for the weekend...
It's okay.
Whatever you were gonna have
is fine with us.
When the meal they dreamt about
is cooking inside a boiling pot...
Where did you live before moving here?
Songpa.
Then we moved here.
I see...
How's Hwaseodong like?
It's great.
It's a great place to raise a baby.
There are a lot of babies here too.
I think it's much better than Seoul.
Why did you choose to come to Korea?
Korean food is delicious.
I'm grateful that he's using easy English.
That's how he teaches his kids
in the elementary school.
His using his experience
to stoop down to your level.
That's why you understand.
I don't speak English...
I can speak Korean.
Do you need help?
I'll take the plates out.
Could you pour the sauce then?
(Got it.)
Kyung-kyu, the ramen expert
stands in front of the oven
to help out.
Come here!
You're so cute!
(Sunny finds Sun-hee adorable.)
I'm with Girls' Generation...
And we're about to eat together!
We're eating ramen together!
I always thought I'd meet Kyung-kyu
at least once in my life.
(It was predicted?)
Shows like Compassion Fridge...
You're right.
Because of you, I always thought
I'd get to meet you once
if I kept doing the right things...
Amazing.
(Talks and works at the same time.)
But I was able to be a better person
because of you.
(And that person is making ramen)
(in her kitchen.)
(Became a chef without realizing it.)
Kyung-kyu, who she thought
she'd get to meet
if she stayed as a good person...
Became a passionate chef
on Sunday night!
It's done!
Okay!
(Ramen is complete!)
Jason puts down the table...
His wife puts ramen in plates.
Then today's dinner is ready.
(Can't forget to take a picture!)
This meal
was quickly made
by a multi-cultural family in Hwaseodong
on Sunday night.
Thank you for the food.
Thank you.
This is Kyung-kyu's first ramen
in Let's Have Dinner Together.
Can I have some more?
Of course!
He cleared his plate in a hurry
as it was very delicious.
Sun-hee's new family, Sunny
hurries to eat ramen
to alleviate her hunger.
Delicious.
A father, a fan of Girls' Generation...
A mother who knew she'd meet
Kyung-kyu one day...
They all enjoy a delicious Sunday dinner.
Why did you let us in?
Why wouldn't we?
We know who you are!
Did you know what program this was?
I thought...
This can't be Healing Camp...
What could it be?
(Healing Camp was so long ago...)
I always had 30% of doubts on all TV shows.
But I guess programs like these
are really unscripted.
That's why we're eating here!
(This is a 100% genuine show.)
Did you major in English too?
I majored in law first.
English was my second major.
But law wasn't for me...
So I continued with English.
(Cute trick by Sun-hee.)
Do you know any of their songs?
Girls' Generation?
(Goosebumps.)
I just heard it live!
He knows a lot.
He's a girl group expert!
Is that why he's in Korea?
When he was a teenager...
He liked H.O.T.
(He used to wave the white balloons.)
He knows!
He even visited SM a couple of times.
Her uncle...
Is Lee Soo-man!
Is he still alive...?
Yes...
(He's like a living legend...)
He's her real uncle!
He's my uncle.
She's a golden parachute?
I heard that a lot...
It's been 10 years so...
(Now, she's a part of the best girl group.)
Who do you like now?
Out of the recent ones.
BTS!
You don't know who they are, do you?
Of course I do!
How many people are in it?
7?
EXO was on here.
And Wanna One came last week!
Wanna One was here!
Do you know Wanna One?
(Of course.)
101 people!
There aren't 101 people!
They were chosen from 101 people.
It was...
Kang Daniel.
And Ji-hoon.
Park Ji-hoon.
We went to Jeonju together.
He remembers because it was last week!
No!
(He'll forget in a few days...)
Who came from EXO?
We had two guys.
Chan-yeol.
Soo-hwa?
Who's Soo-hwa!
Soo-ho...
Soo-ho!
I know everyone.
Not everyone...
I even studied...
I started studying after I got
a lot of bad press.
Through this show,
a celebrity in his 37th year is
finally learning about other celebrities.
(They're deep in a conversation.)
(Downs it.)
(Puts her cup where everyone can see.)
It's like an oasis in a desert.
(Over here.)
(She finished!)
(Is this cup leaking?)
(Just for Yu-ri...)
(Rice wine refill.)
(Ji-hye isn't saying anything.)
She's so quiet.
She doesn't normally talk much...
But my heart still drops a beat
when I think about what happened.
We really caught you off guard, didn't we?
(Never imagined Yu-ri)
(would come to her house.)
I thought Ji-hye was really pretty.
But she wasn't!
(Her father's betrayal...)
How could you throw me under the bus?
I'm sure he loves her the most!
I should've put on some makeup.
You didn't put any on?
Nope.
Your skin is so fair.
I hear that a lot.
(Honest.)
(My wife is so pretty.)
I'm an old fan of JTBC's Son Suk-hee.
I was even in his fan club before.
(Comes out as a fan.)
He played a huge role in TV
during the mass protests.
I would like to tell him
that he did a great job.
Why don't you...
Should I leave him a message?
Hello.
I used to go watch
100 Minutes Debates all the time.
Please keep up
your hard work for our country.
Thank you.
(Just couldn't hide that she's a fan.)
Sir...
If you hear about how she was
in his fan club,
don't you get jealous?
Nope.
Not at all.
Not even a little?
Nope.
I'm sorry I asked...
After 20 years of marriage...
His sister is your sister in law now.
But at first, she didn't tell you
that he was her sister
and you went to meet him.
Who was there first?
I came later.
I went because my friend said
she wanted to set me up on a date.
When he came in...
That's when she said he's my brother.
I couldn't leave...
There wasn't much that I could do.
It's not like you can say,
I'm out of here, right?
Be honest.
As soon as I walked in,
she knew I was the one.
(Admits it.)
Really?
Why?
I regret it too...
He perfectly fit my ideal type of a guy.
So I thought he was the one.
What is your ideal type?
Weirdly...
Ever since high school,
I liked Joo Hyun, the actor.
(They do kind of look alike.)
(Impersonation.)
He does look like a nice person.
And warm.
How about you?
When you walked in...
But...
It's a bit complicated.
That was when he couldn't get married.
Can I tell them?
He was a wanted man
for protesting...
But that was the norm back then.
That's why we couldn't get married...
I see.
Meeting someone to plan
a future together wasn't possible.
He could've thought it was
an extravagance.
He wasn't ready.
That was then.
Your sister didn't tell you anything?
No, she told me
it was a blind date.
(Hesitant.)
She told me a lot about my wife.
I heard...
That she just broke up
with her boyfriend
and she was hurt...
(Way too honest.)
It was so beautiful until now...
So I was just going to...
Go meet her once since my sister asked...
Then let her be.
Then were you the one who hung on to him
and stayed in contact?
Well his sister kept telling me
to see him again
and as I did, things just happened
naturally.
How long did you date then?
We dated for about 1 year and a half
then got married.
But cell phones didn't exist back then.
(How did you talk to each other?)
His sister played a big part.
If we wanted to meet...
Plus, minus was important.
What's that?
If we wanted to meet on January 3rd,
our phones could've been tapped.
We say we'll meet on January 5th
but agreed to subtract 2
on every number that ends in 5.
If we wanted to meet on 12 O'clock,
we would've added 3 hours to it.
That's how we met.
It was that bad?
That's how it was back then.
That sounds like a movie.
It's like a plot of a drama!
Weren't you scared?
I was young.
I didn't mind.
Did he propose to you?
From who?
Your husband.
He didn't propose to you?
Well...
I proposed to him...
You proposed to him?
He couldn't get married.
But I proposed anyways.
It just happened.
(A very rare thing back in the days.)
Everyone has to get married at some point.
So...
(Dad, be careful.)
She said she'll take care of me
financially.
Dad...
(He married her for money?)
Where did the romance go?
(Joking.)
Say what you really mean!
I loved her.
You guys are very brave.
She's perfect for me.
What a beautiful ending.
We're happy now.
(We're happy after overcoming)
(every obstacles.)
Even during the toughest time...
With their love and trust for each other,
they ended up together.
The past has become a story to tell
their daughters while drinking rice wine.
(Proud.)
Our kids are all grown up now
without any troubles.
Since they're both seniors,
all I want now is for them to be able to
get a job easily.
What do you want to do?
Just...
Something related to my major.
What's your major?
Electric engineering.
Ji-hye, what do you want to be?
I...
Don't have a definite plan.
I just wanted to be rich since
I was a kid.
Let's assume that you did.
What 3 things do you want to do ?
Travel.
Yes, travel.
I want to buy land.
(Ji-hye wants real estates.)
I like that idea.
Then what?
Then...
Plant some trees.
I want to grow trees.
Not raise buildings?
I just want to grow trees.
(Embarrassed.)
Which ones?
Apple trees and date trees.
Fruit trees...
Then sell the apples...
And earn millions of dollars...
Then buy more land!
Make half of Korea yours.
(He's too realistic too understand.)
Travel or buy land first?
Buy land first!
The price always goes up...
(So she can plant more trees.)
(And the third plan?)
My mom and dad...
I had everything I wanted.
I have so much to pay back for.
I tried to add everything up recently...
And?
It was too much...
Just thinking that is amazing.
That's so nice.
She's graduating soon.
Maybe that's why she did that.
We don't need anything.
(This couple reminisce)
(the old times...)
How long did you guys date?
We dated...
For 1 year.
I'm a bit confused...
We were just friends at first...
And things happened so fast.
I want to know what happened!
What made you decide to marry him?
We went to the same church...
I go to church too!
Is he older than you?
He's younger than me.
And you met him at church?
I'm only a little bit older.
7 months...
7 months?
That's pretty much the same age in Korea!
Did you hear that?
Friends!
No, noona!
(Oh, Jason...)
(Funny...)
That was quick...
I was just over 30 back then.
I was already thinking about marriage.
But I didn't know if I could trust him
when we first met.
But I was able to see that eventually.
As you became friends with him.
We were able to have deep conversations.
As friends first,
they eventually became a couple
after being able to relate to each other.
What did you like about him the most?
I already knew that...
He's a hard worker.
I thought he was a good person at first.
He looks like a nice person.
He's honest.
And...
I wasn't attracted to him at all at first.
Then I started feeling attracted to him.
After a while?
Yes.
That's falling in love.
I totally understand now.
Personalities does matter in a marriage,
but there are other factors such as
finances and how we lived our lives
until now.
I gave up on finances back then!
I thought I could just earn the money.
If you really love each other,
other things don't really matter...
If I were to advice women who are
dating foreigners...
Koreans...
Save money to get ready for marriage.
But unlike Koreans, they don't.
Exactly!
And their parents don't think about
helping us out to buy our house.
You have to do everything
with your own money.
And...
Some people, even if they don't have
any money saved up,
they're capable of doing so.
If they want to save up
instead of enjoying their lives every day,
it will help.
That's a good advice.
Why did you choose marry her?
What do you like about her?
She's smart.
And...
She's pretty.
Be honest!
(How all husbands are...)
He thinks everything about her
is pretty
including how she acts or talks.
Apple of my eyes...
You both are to each other!
I can see how much they love each other.
Were your parents okay
with your marriage?
They weren't happy at first...
I'm the only daughter
and they were scared that
I'll move overseas.
But he's really good with kids.
And with his job,
he has a lot of free time.
He's really good with our kid.
So my parents are really happy now.
He's still watching his kid!
I know!
I completely forgot about my kid...
Sun-hee's mom isn't concerned
with her child.
She talking about her philosophy...
While he's watching their kid.
He's such a nice person.
Everything she imagines, happen!
Right?
She thought she'd eventually meet you,
and she did.
She always thought she'd marry
a foreigner,
and she did.
They look happy, don't they?
(Very happy with love.)
An American man and a Korean woman
fell in love.
They recognized their differences
and became  lovers.
And with their beautiful daughter, Sun-hee
they became a family.
We have a segment
where you guys need to compliment
and say your disappointments.
What are you thankful and disappointed
by your spouse?
Compliments?
Jin-hee...
For taking care of Sun-hee.
He said, she's the best mother.
And the second?
She's a hard...
Worker?
A hard worker.
(You know what I'm saying?)
(The best compliment.)
This body language is universal.
He understood.
Then...
Is this a restaurant?
We have a complaint!
I want to speak to a manager!
(His Complaints!)
Just like you...
I'm...
Very frugal.
But that's good!
Of course.
And the last one.
(Jason's unafraid.)
A language...
Just can't be taught easily!
(Their love even beat a language barrier.)
That was much quicker...
Than his compliments.
What would you like to compliment him on?
Compliments!
After school, he comes straight home
to see the baby.
That's the best.
Of course.
I make a lot of mistakes...
But he's always there for me.
Is he understanding?
Yes.
All the time...
And your complaints.
Complaints...
I think he's slow sometimes...
Koreans are very impatient.
I should take longer to get ready
as a woman...
And...
Complaints, complaints, complaints...
You don't have to say anything,
if there isn't any.
I have too many.
She can't choose.
And...
If he were going to help me,
I wish he'd help me until the end.
Could you write the subtitles in English
for him?
I don't know how to say it in English.
Did you understand that?
(Confused.)
We got you covered.
He'll be able to understand.
(Subtitles just for Jason.)
What's difficult about living in Korea?
I see...
That's the difference between
a first and a second language.
Did any of the racial bias
give you any hard time?
And this man...
Few people just get angry at him
for being a foreigner.
I see...
Was he...
Drunk?
(Totally inappropriate.)
Other Koreans won't understand that either.
She's the weird one.
(Upset.)
What are your dreams?
Like her mom...
To you guys...
Sun-hee must be
a good middle ground in your marriage.
Yes...
When things get tough...
Or lonely...
You two will always be connected
through Sun-hee.
We'll do the dishes.
Yu-ri, the oldest daughter for the day.
You look like you know what you're doing!
I do it a lot at home.
The dishes?
I do the dishes and cook.
Sun-hee's new family, Sunny
finishes her night with doing the dishes.
(Kyung-kyu cleans up too.)
(Photo time.)
A meal that offered us a meal
#72 and #73
were born in Hwaseodong.
Let's Have Dinner Together.
Good luck!
Let's Have Dinner Together in
Hwaseodong, Suwon.
Good luck!
We're in Gangwondo?
The Korean Alps.
(Among the sheep...)
(Confused.)
We're in Pyeongchang!
Kim Yu-Na!
Yu-Na!
I thought that was a sheep!
(Nope.)
(King of Music, K-Will.)
(Queen of music, So-you.)
The Winter Olympics will be in Pyeongchang.
What are you guys doing here?
(A place with strong accents.)
Jinbumyeon, Pyeongchang.
We've never been to a myeon!
(Myeon: Smallest classification of cities.)
This is the strongest rain we've had!
(A fantastic duet)
(with Pyeongchang's fresh air.)
I won as the best singer
for the rainy season.
You're KCM!
I'm not KCM!
I'm K-Will!
I've been K-Will for 10 years!
Is that Dae-sung?
I'm K-Will...
(A singer for 10 years...)
I'm K-Will!
Heongseong is famous for beef.
I want beef...
(So-you's obsessed with food.)
(Even knows local delicacies.)
I don't know what that is.
(A big eater in a different class!)
(Awestruck.)
I've always wanted to do that.
(Rings a doorbell with high hopes.)
Did you eat yet?
There's nothing to eat...
(They're nice, but have no food!)
I'm K-Will, a singer...
I dare ask if I can have a meal
in this friendly neighborhood.
I'm K-Will, a singer.
We were soaked by the rain.
We're desperate for a meal.
Do you have to ask your parents?
There's a thing called telephone!
It's not up to me...
It's not a success or a fail.
(Will they successfully get a meal?)
It was so nice to see.
I had a great meal.
I sympathized with them...
Sunny went to Sun-hee's house.
New dreams of two famils in Suwon,
a city of King Jungjo's dreams.
Would you like to joins us for dinner
and talk about your dreams?
Subtitles by OnDemandKorea