The Museum of Contemporary
Art Tokyo, in Koto Ward.
During summer 2007,
an exhibition of work...
...by Studio Ghibli's
"image artisan" took place here.
His works were framed
for the exhibit.
These works were originally
backgrounds and art boards...
...used for scenes in
animated films.
No characters appeared
in these images.
Only the background
for that scene was on display.
But each day the exhibition
was thronged with visitors.
All of them came to see
these "empty" backgrounds.
The exhibit ran for 66 days.
Over 200,000 people
saw Oga's work during that period.
Visitors included people of all ages.
The museum staff
were amazed at the crowds.
Most backgrounds are discarded
after production is finished.
But these works found their way to
an art museum, framed for display.
The artist: Kazuo Oga.
Did he ever dream his work
would end up in a museum?
It never occurred to me.
Animation backgrounds and cels
aren't meant to be preserved.
They're usually thrown away
after the film is complete.
Animation background art
is discarded every day.
Background art is the stage
on which the characters interact.
Background art was thought
to have little value in itself.
Among the works
on display here...
...were many that Oga
himself had saved.
Background art rarely survives.
But much of this art
captured the hearts of audiences.
Kazuo Oga was art director
for such Ghibli films...
...as "My Neighbor Totoro"
and "Only Yesterday".
Oga's background art evokes
feelings of nostalgia in audiences.
Now his backgrounds, which were
only part of the finished animation...
...are drawing attention
as artworks in themselves.
Oga works quietly
behind the scenes at Studio Ghibli...
...creating backgrounds
that move audiences.
Looking back on Oga's
single-minded dedication to his art...
...we decided to call him
Ghibli's "image artisan".
KAZUO OGA GHIBLl'S IMAGE ARTISAN The
Artist Who Made Totoro's Forest
1972. Kazuo Oga was 20.
One day he saw a job listing
for "people who like to draw".
And so he joined
Kobayashi Production.
It was a company specializing
in animation backgrounds.
It was here
that Oga discovered...
...the profession of
background artist.
At that stage, Oga actually
had almost no training in art.
"THE ADVENTURE OF GAMBA"
He learned the techniques
as he went along.
"THE CHAMPION"
It turned out that
the paper for backgrounds...
...was about the size of
the sketch pads I used in school.
I was doing backgrounds
day after day.
I felt pretty lucky.
This is a background from
”The Giatrus, The First Man”.
Art director Shichiro Kobayashi...
...designed daringly abstract,
abbreviated backgrounds for the series.
The style differs completely
from Oga's recent work.
Shichiro Kobayashi is the founder
of Kobayashi Production...
...where Oga started out.
Oga regards Kobayashi
as his mentor.
What was his
first impression of Oga?
SHICHIRO KOBAYASHI
KOBAYASHI PRODUCTION
I suspected he had
potential, that's all.
He had a delicate sensibility.
It was reflected in the way
he handled straight lines.
That stood out
at the time.
Not good for much at first,
but I sensed he had huge potential.
But he was extremely sensitive.
In those days, the company
was very busy with TV animation work.
Oga was exposed to
a wide range of techniques.
I had to minimize detail
to complete my work quickly.
I also learned which things
to emphasize, to minimize detail.
The goal is to get the essential
point across effectively.
No need to detail
what people will overlook.
"THE CHAMPION"
BACKGROUND ART
I learned a great deal about
how to eliminate unneeded details.
Oga delivered everything
I asked, and more.
The backgrounds he produced
were extremely tidy.
His work had
a consistently abstract touch.
His approach to images
was efficient and skilled.
"HARMAGEDON"
BACKGROUND
Art director Takamura Mukuo
invited him to work on "Harmagedon".
Oga supplied backgrounds
for several key scenes in the film.
He also supplied promotional
artwork for the movie poster.
"HARMAGEDON"
ILLUSTRATION
"DAGGER OF KAMUI"
BACKGROUND
...and further developed his skills
as a background artist.
Boundless blue sky,
white snow.
Mighty boulders,
crimson flowers.
These backgrounds reflect
Oga's keen powers of observation.
They are glimpses of
his future direction.
"Barefoot Gen".
Oga has accumulated
a decade of experience.
Now he will serve as art director
on an animated feature.
Oga made numerous trips
to Hiroshima to scout locations...
...and used photographs of prewar
Hiroshima to create his backgrounds.
But later, a friend who knew
prewar Hiroshima saw the film...
...and told Oga that his
backgrounds were not accurate.
I visited Hiroshima and used
photographs of the old buildings...
...as reference
for my backgrounds.
The material I had assembled
turned out to be weak.
Looking back, I realize that
I should have made more effort...
...to consult people who had
clear memories of the prewar city.
"Time Stranger" was an animated version
of Taku Mayumura's SF novel.
It tells the story of
a boy from the future...
...and the teenagers who join
his adventures through time.
The story spans
past, present and future.
The characters experience
World War II...
...the era of the Shogun,
and Japan's ancient civil wars.
Oga's many detailed environments
brought the past to life.
I thought the backgrounds
would go more smoothly...
...if I worked out
the settings thoroughly first.
I created a lot of images
that weren't needed.
But I had a lot of fun.
As art director, Oga created
detailed environments...
...based on extensive research
and consultations with experts.
In the course of his work,
he worked with many directors...
...on a diverse range of
background art styles.
During this period, Oga worked on
animated television series...
...and many
short-turnaround features.
"WICKED CITY"
BACKGROUND
All these backgrounds are
from Oga's personal collection.
"HARMAGEDON"
BACKGROUND
Permission to display
these works...
...was readily granted by the
production companies involved.
Their response is e testament
to their respect for Oge.
Oga's first project for
Studio Ghibli...
"MY NEIGHBOR TOTORO" (1988)
...was Hayao Miyazaki's
"My Neighbor Totoro".
The place: the countryside
outside Tokyo, in the late '50s.
An unpaved road
winds through rice paddies.
Scenes like this were once
common just outside the city.
Oga began working with Ghibli
purely by accident.
"TOTORO" IMAGE BOARD
(HAYAO MIYAZAKI)
An art director for "Totoro"
was urgently needed.
One day Oga received a call
from director Hayao Miyazaki.
Miyazaki had
a close relationship...
TOSHIO SUZUKI
PRODUCER
...with an art director
named Nizo Yamamoto.
That's how Miyazaki
heard about Kazuo Oga.
Miyazaki assumed
Oga would be suitable.
Miyazaki has this
interesting trait.
You see,
if Miyazaki trusts you...
...he assumes
he can trust your friend.
TOTORO PRODUCTION TEAM
So Oga joined the
"Totoro" production team.
Oga vividly recalls one of
his early exchanges with Miyazaki.
Once the storyboard was done,
I set to work on the backgrounds.
Miyazaki didn't present me
with any difficult requirements.
So I assembled and checked a set of
backgrounds for him to look at.
I think it was his first look
at the backgrounds.
His reaction was,
"So this is the best you can do?"
He wasn't really upset.
But for me,
it was quite a shock.
Miyazaki asked Oga to pay
close attention to rural landscapes.
To grasses, trees and flowers.
HAYAO MIYAZAKI
SCOUTING LOCATIONS
IMAGE BOARD
(HAYAO MIYAZAKI)
Oga had received
such guidance from a director.
I decided to go back
and redo everything myself.
After that I checked
all the backgrounds very closely.
Oga worked hard to capture
every type of foliage...
...and the changing face of
the landscape throughout the day.
The result was something
rarely seen before in animation.
A clear summer sky.
An acorn, through a hole
in a bucket.
The changing faces of clouds,
moment to moment.
The house where sisters Satsuki
and Mei and their father will live.
The house combines
Japanese and Western elements.
This style of architecture
was actually popular at the time.
BACKGROUND
(WITH KIYOMI OTA)
The earthen-floored kitchen.
There is no plumbing.
Water is drawn from a well.
Father's library, in
the Western room of the house.
The wood-fired bath,
heated from below.
Everything is bathed in
warm light from the kitchen.
The scene is empty, but the image
immediately brings to mind...
...z'he father and
his daughters taking a bath.
The veranda, open
to the outdoors.
One can almost feel
the refreshing breeze...
...of a summer afternoon.
Someone from the neighborhood
could drop by anytime.
These unlocked doors are
a link to another time.
Oga based his realistic rendering
on the house of a relative...
...in rural Gunma Prefecture.
Oga thought the house matched
Miyazaki's storyboard concept.
He had his relative send
photos of the house.
The way upstairs
is steep and dark.
It looks like the gateway
to another dimension.
Near the house stands
a huge camphor tree.
It almost seems supernatural.
This is Totoro's home.
And here's the entrance.
Inside, the floor is carpeted
with grass and flowers.
Everything is finely detailed.
Oga made the floor
soft and spongy...
...so Mei would not
hurt herself as she falls in.
Nature's face changes
with each change in the light.
Depending on the weather
and time of day...
...the same place can take on
a completely different appearance.
Oga brilliantly depicts these
changes in mood.
A late afternoon shower.
The bright scenery
is transformed.
When the rain stops,
the once-sunlit landscape...
...becomes a world
of shadows.
This background is for a
memorable scene in "Totoro".
Here, the sisters encounter
Totoro and the Cat Bus.
Later that evening,
the sky is full of stars.
You can almost hear
the crickets in the distance.
The most' notable
"To taro " backgrounds...
...depict nature's
transformation as night falls.
The aspect of "Totoro"
that impressed me most...
...is the sequence where
Satsuki goes looking for Mei.
The backgrounds convey
the passage of time.
Without Oga, I doubt that
sequence would have worked.
Mei!
Naoya Tanaka is an
art director at Studio Ghibli.
Here is his perspective
on Oga's backgrounds.
It's as if Oga has
a kind of special filter...
NAOYA TANAKA
It's not a naturalistic effect.
He extracts the essence of
important elements of the scene.
Then he augments them
to enrich the image.
Oga is very adept at this.
What this does is change
the landscape from something familiar...
...to something that
feels more like déjé vu.
The audience shares the experience
with the character.
A landscape already
stored in the mind.
The audience feels a
mysterious nostalgia.
After "My Neighbor Totoro"...
...Oga becomes an indispensible
part of Studio Ghibli.
So what is animation
background art all about?
In the production process,
characters drawn by the animators...
...are moved frame by frame
against a background.
Before the advent of automated tools,
characters were hand drawn...
...on transparent
acrylic sheets called cels.
PRODUCTION PHOTOGRAPHY
...of cel and background,
photographed with special techniques.
Take this vertical background.
Can you guess
which scene this is from?
This technique is called
"pan with action".
Ashitaka gallops down the cliff
in "Princess Mononoke".
For the completed sequence,
foreground leaves are superimposed...
...and moved a few millimeters
in each frame.
It's over in four seconds.
Sliding overlays is another
specialized technique.
Five separate background cels
with different perspectives...
...are superimposed over
a background base.
The cels are separated
for the exhibit.
But during photography
they are in contact.
Character cels and background overlays
move at different speeds.
This is the completed sequence.
Quiet your rage,
I beg you!
A mere three seconds!
A tremendous amount of effort
for only three seconds of action.
A panoramic background
from "Kiki's Delivery Service".
In this "follow and pan" shot,
the characters move...
...across the field of view
and into the distance.
In e live action film, the camera
just' follows the action.
For animation, a correspondingly
long background is necessary.
Some panoramic backgrounds
are quite specialized.
This background
from "Only Yesterday"...
muses e technique
celled "track up and pen”.
As adult Taeko turns,
the camera pans left.
The camera points
to a scene from the past.
The background is drawn
to simulate a wide-angle shot.
With some simple
camera work...
...we jump from
present to past.
We can see the distortions
used to achieve this effect...
...when we view
the entire background.
These distortions
are carefully calculated...
...so the result will appear natural
as the camera moves.
Didn't you promise to ask only
at Christmas and birthdays?
You always spoil her, Daddy!
Nowadays, cels are produced
with the help of computers.
Photography is also digital.
Cels and backgrounds
are composited digitally.
But backgrounds are
still produced the same way.
Each one is carefully hand painted,
usually with poster color.
"ONLY YESTERDAY"
BACKGROUND ART DESIGN
...and supervise
the background artists.
He designs the film's
objects and structures...
...to convey the look
of the film to each artist.
He creates art image boards
needed for each background.
He checks each background
produced by the artists...
...and makes corrections
as needed.
STORYBOARD
(HAYAO MIYAZAKI)
He translates that vision
into a more detailed, concrete form...
IMAGE BOARD
(HAYAO MIYAZAKI)
The art director
is truly an artisan.
COMPLETED FRAME
After "Totoro", Oga next
served as art director...
"ONLY YESTERDAY" (1991)
...on director Isao Takahata's
"Only Yesterday".
Takahata was extremely impressed
by Oga's backgrounds for "Totoro".
With Japanese artists,
especially background artists...
...the look of their work differs
depending on where they come from.
The quality of
the air is different.
Artists from northern Japan
render air very transparently.
With artists from the south,
the air seems mistier.
This probably comes from
their childhood environment.
Takahata is actually from
Mie Prefecture...
...which is more toward
the south of the country.
But the truth is, he actually
prefers northern Japan.
So he probably likes the
style of northern artists.
When Takahata saw "Totoro"
he was very impressed.
So when he began preparing
for "Only Yesterday"...
...he wanted Oga
as his art director.
"Only Yesterday"
is based on a serial comic.
It tells the story
of little Taeko...
mend her experiences
as a child in the late 7.960s.
TAEKO (AGE 10)
Takahata created a story
about Taeko as an adult...
...combined with
flashbacks from her past.
TAEKO (AGE 27)
...Taeko feels drawn
to rural Japan.
So she goes to visit relatives
in Yamagata Prefecture.
Why did Takahata choose
this location for his story?
Oga is actually
a native of Akita.
So Takahata wanted
to use Akita as the setting.
But to drive the story, we needed
to find a special local product.
Something distinctive
that would work for animation.
We did a lot of research
and discovered Yamagata's safflowers.
Akita didn't have
anything to rival that.
So Takahata set
the story in Yamagata.
"Only Yesterday" features flashbacks
with pale, simple backgrounds...
...and scenes of today's Yamagata
with rich, detailed backgrounds.
The contrast alternates
throughout the film.
Taeko's childhood.
The backgrounds are
somewhat indistinct...
...like nostalgic images
stored deep in the memory.
Takahata wanted to emphasize a
feeling of the distance of memory.
So Oga's backgrounds were
rendered in pale colors.
The simple lines and pale colors
of distant memories.
Unnecessary detail
was to be omitted.
Only the content of memory
would be depicted.
Anything not recalled
clearly would not be depicted.
The flashback scenes were created
according to this artistic vision.
Backgrounds for the film's
present-day scenes...
...are in complete contrast
to the pale colors of memory.
Based on careful research,
these backgrounds are highly detailed.
LOCATION SCOUTING (1990)
...for firsthand experience
in safflower harvesting.
Everyone on the
production team went along.
Visiting the actual scene
of the story is essential.
So much to see
and experience.
The lessons learned have a
major influence on the film.
Photographs alone can't convey
the atmosphere or the scale.
When you actually go, you see
the way mist rises from the valleys.
You have to see the way
the mist looks with your own eyes.
Later you can use
what you've seen...
...as a point of departure
for your creativity.
With photos, you can't judge
how conditions change through time.
The staff boarded the same night train
Taeko uses on her journey.
They left late at night
and arrived early next morning.
This background
approaches photorealism.
It also brings the period
vividly to life.
Background artist Yoji Takeshige
also visited locations in Yamagata.
He speaks about
the role of location visits.
Actually visiting the locale
helps us do a better job...
'(OM TAKESPHGE
...in conveying the
atmosphere to audiences.
Much more so
than with photographs alone.
You have to
see it first hand.
The quiet of an
early morning train platform.
The look of a car driving along
an empty road before dawn.
The silence, the chill
of dew in the morning.
The warmth
of the sun's rays...
...as it rises over
a field of safflowers.
You have to actually
experience these things.
Then what you create...
...will more effectively convey
an impression to the audience.
Like Taeko, the production staff
began picking flowers before dawn.
The thorns of the safflower
are softest in the morning.
That's why safflowers
are harvested early.
The lessons learned
from actual participation...
...make for more
convincing backgrounds.
The sun rises over
a majestic field of safflowers.
You can almost
feel the scene physically.
"Only Yesterday" used a number
of animation techniques...
...that had hardly
been seen before.
For example,
realistic physical movement...
...and natural wrinkles
in the faces of characters.
What impact did this
detailed character animation...
...have on the backgrounds?
I didn't consciously plan to make
the backgrounds very detailed.
But I think I ended up
being swept along...
...by the animation.
Realistic backgrounds
for realistic characters.
The result was minutely
detailed background art.
But Oga learned something
from this experience.
I thought the backgrounds
were simply too detailed.
This was a lesson
I've never forgotten.
I don't think it was necessary
to include that much detail.
The backgrounds
could have been simpler.
"Only Yesterday" featured extremely
detailed backgrounds.
They garnered praise
when the film was released.
But Oga himself came
to a different conclusion.
The lesson he learned was -
do your research thoroughly.
Once you know what
you are doing, you can omit detail.
The result will be environments
that audiences find appealing.
In other words,
less is more.
Before and after "Only Yesterday",
Oga worked on background art...
"KIKl'S DELIVERY SERVICE" (1989)
"PORCO ROSSO" (1992)
With its European settings
of stone and brick...
..."Kiki's Delivery Service" was
completely different from "Totoro".
A former colleague of mine
from Kobayashi Production...
...was the art director
on this film.
I really put
a lot of work into it.
But the chance to participate
in the production...
...was very good
for me too.
Oga's work in
"Kiki's Delivery Service"...
...naturally focused on scenes
filled with flowers and trees.
Miyazaki supplied the concept,
but when Oga was finished...
...Kiki's house was surrounded
with lush greenery.
"Porco Rosso" was also
set in Europe.
Oga says he was not
originally slated to work on this film.
But he decided
to join the project...
...when he heard his friend
Katsu Hisamura would be art director.
Once again, Oga handled many
scenes featuring natural beauty.
To depict the beauty
of the Adriatic...
...Oga imbued sea and sky
with rich, deep color.
Porco Rosso's hideout.
Steep cliff, ocean inlet
and blue sky contrast sharply.
Chanteuse Gina's secret garden.
Beyond the beautiful foliage
spreads the blue Adriatic.
Again, contrast is the key
to this background.
Oga's next project
was "Pom Poko".
The setting for director
Isao Takahata's film...
"POM POKO" (1994)
...was the rural Tama Hills
district, near Tokyo.
Drawing on his experience
with "Only Yesterday"...
...Oga decided not to make
the backgrounds too detailed.
I created the backgrounds
for "Pom Poko"...
...based on what I felt was
the right level of detail for the film.
I didn't work on
the basis of what to omit.
I was familiar with the
natural environment of Tama.
I had a sense of
the foliage and the scenery.
I simply created backgrounds
with the level of detail...
...that seemed appropriate
to convey the settings.
In fact, Oga had already moved
to Hachioji City in the Tama area.
This was in 1987,
during production of "Totoro".
Oga was excited that
the area where he lived...
...had become the setting
for an animated film.
He drew on
first-hand experience...
...to depict the loss of forests
and mountains to development.
Along the way, he portrayed
the changing seasons...
...with an accuracy
seldom seen in animation.
We wanted to show the lives
of raccoons in detail.
So we had to show how
the raccoons lived in each season.
That was the goal.
Working on the backgrounds
for "Pom Poko" was a lot of fun.
A construction site
on New Year's Day.
A power shovel
stands deserted.
Through the sparkling air,
snowy Mt. Fuji rises in the distance.
This background is like
a modern woodblock print.
Naoya Tanaka recalls an anecdote
behind this snowy scene.
One day during production,
there was a rare, heavy snowfall.
It was still early, but Oga said
he was leaving to scout locations.
He left everyone else
slaving away.
He said it was a great chance
to get a feel for the snow.
To be honest,
I didn't do any research.
I just wanted to play
in the snow, so I left early.
But you know,
it's always good to get out...
...and actually experience
unusual weather conditions.
The changing face of the Tama Hills
throughout the season.
Natural environments
destroyed by development.
Photographs leave a record,
but there is much they cannot capture.
The smell of a breeze.
And the nostalgia
that is "memory".
Oga's work has the power
to awaken those memories within us.
Director Yoshifumi Kondo's
"Whisper of the Heart".
"WHISPER OF THE HEART" (1995)
Satoshi Kuroda, who
had long worked under Oga...
...was selected to serve
as art director.
The setting was modeled on
Tama City, in the Tokyo suburbs.
The Tama Hills again served
as the backdrop for the story.
A major theme was the urban
environment as nostalgic home town.
The question was whether
Ghibli's artists could breathe life...
...into such an environment.
The art staff made trips together
for detailed location scouting.
"Whisper of the Heart" opens
with this panorama of the city by night.
The film ends with the same view,
this time shrouded in morning mist.
It's hard to tell
this is the same city.
Oga was responsible
for both of these key images.
This is based on the view from
atop the ski jump at Yomiuri Land.
We got permission to enter the park
very early in the morning.
I took the first
morning train out there.
I saw the same sunrise
that was depicted in the story.
"Whisper" sensitively portrayed...
...the emotional lives
of middle school students.
The final scene is
dedicated to their future.
I wanted you to see this.
"Princess Mononoke".
"PRINCESS MONONOKE" (1997)
This enormous background
forms part of the exhibit.
It was used in
the film's opening scene.
This awe-inspiring vista
remains on screen for 26 seconds.
Eight large cels with images
of mountains and clouds...
were photographed
over a large background.
In ancient times the land
lay covered in forest...
...where from ages long past
dwelt the spirits of the gods.
No fewer than five art directors
were assigned to "Mononoke".
This was unheard of.
Why was it necessary?
In "Princess Mononoke",
the hero travels south and west.
Each art director handled
the region he grew up in.
Oga did most of
the northern backgrounds.
A representative scene
from each art director.
- The Em/sh/ Village.
- Ash/take's Journey.
- The Iron Works- - Moro's Lair.
- The Deer God's Forest.
With five art directors,
the settings were extremely varied.
Ashitaka's home,
the "Emishi Village".
This was Oga's responsibility.
Oga's village was based
on the Shirakami highlands...
...and the Shizukuishi
area in northern Japan.
While other staff headed south
to scout forest locations...
...Oga traveled alone
to northern Japan.
He saw mountain highlands
and pristine beech forests
The images he brought back
majestically open the story.
Oga was responsible for
many striking images in "Mononoke".
The awe-inspiring sunrise
over the Deer God's forest.
The giant Deer God
rises into the night sky.
Life returns
to the ravaged forest.
What did Oga have in mind
when he created this image?
When I was scouting locations...
...I saw green shoots coming up
in places where the snow had melted.
I used that image
for this background.
During the creation of
backgrounds like these...
...the director provides feedback
at meeting after meeting.
During production of
"Princess Mononoke"...
...one of these meetings
was preserved on video.
Studio Ghibli, during
production of "Mononoke".
Oga shows director Miyazaki
one of the backgrounds.
Shafts of sunlight illuminate
the lake of the Deer God.
Miyazaki sees room
for improvement.
The light should fall a bit more naturally.
Like it's always that way.
The location was dark, right?
That's how it looked.
If we make it too dark...
...this part will be black.
I think if we just add
a few more rays of light -
This part can be in shade.
But there should be
light falling here and there.
The beams of light should be
distributed across the frame.
I kept thinking the light was too bright...
...but I think this is OK.
I don't think...
...we have to make this ultra-realistic.
How can I say...
...we don't have to make this look real.
I'd like it to have a lot of impact.
Sometimes even real sunlight...
...looks very majestic...
...when it shoots down from the clouds.
We need light beams from
more than one place.
Based on Miyazakﬂs storyboard,
the art director creates an image.
Seeing the image, the director
further develops his vision.
Using all his skill, the artist
realizes that vision in more images.
This is the role
of the image artisan.
"SPIRITED AWAY" (2001) "HOWL'S MOVING
CASTLE" (2004) "TALES FROM EARTHSEA" (2006)
A residential development
cut into a hill.
This is the opening image
from "Spirited Away".
Deep in the forest, a gateway
to a mysterious town.
Oga created this imposing
red gate amid lush foliage.
Chihiro and Haku pass through
this garden of rhododendrons.
Here is Oga's background,
rendered with computer animation.
The magical marshes
from "Howl's Moving Castle".
A vast expanse of meadows
and flowers of dreamlike beauty.
Of course, each flower had to be
added by hand, one by one.
I can't imagine
how many I painted.
How long did it take you?
I don't even remember
how long it took.
The flowers in the foreground
are rendered precisely.
Those in the distance
are less detailed.
This marked contrast between
rough and detailed rendering...
“imparts a feeling
of broad expanse.
Ghib/I artist Na 0 ya Tanaka
sees something special...
...in Oga's depictions
of foreign environments.
I think Oga's European
environments are superb.
When Oga sets out
to depict a scene...
...that he has not seen personally,
he proceeds slowly and carefully.
He examines reference
photographs very closely.
He looks very
carefully at buildings.
He notes differences in
the style of roofs...
...or the way signs look.
Roads and structures are different
from their Japanese counterparts.
He takes all this
carefully into account.
"Tales from Earthsea"
also contains scenes...
...that are completely different
by night and day.
Oga's backgrounds played
a central role...
...in this tale of the struggle
between light and darkness.
0ga's backgrounds also
impart a sense of majesty...
...to the Ghibli stories
in which they appear.
Art directors often look to Oga
to handle certain scenes.
These scenes have
certain special characteristics.
What might those be?
Yoji Takes-hiya was
art' director for "Spirited A way".
He offers some insight
into Oga's special strengths.
There are several types
of backgrounds I'd want Oga to handle.
One would be comparatively
soothing backgrounds.
Refreshing or
heart-warming backgrounds.
When I see this kind of
scene in a storyboard...
...I would want Oga's
backgrounds for that scene.
Over 200,000 people
saw Oga's exhibition.
What is so alluring about animation
backgrounds without characters?
I think animation backgrounds...
...are very accessible
for the average person.
That's because backgrounds
aren't solely the creation...
...of the artist
who created them.
They were created
to fill a need.
Backgrounds don't express
the artist's inner world.
The viewer can
easily relate to them.
That's a major characteristic
of background art.
Animation backgrounds
are only part of what Oga does.
He is active
in many other areas.
Oga supplied lively illustrations...
...for Soseki Yamamoto's story,
"Mouse Tempura".
In the story, a group of men
try to swindle foxes and raccoons...
...by offering them mouse tempura
in exchange for huge fish.
It's a story replete with natural beauty
and humorous characters.
To transmit the experiences
of atom bomb survivors...
...actress Sayuri Yoshinaga produced
a CD titled "Second Movement".
The CD contains poems and recollections
by survivors of the bombing.
"BAREFOOT GEN"
BACKGROUND
...as well as the series
of books based on it.
It was Yoshinaga's strong desire...
...to have Oga
provide the illustrations.
"SECOND MOVEMENT:
FROM NAGASAKI"
Oga's first work as director is
"The Night of Taneyamagahara".
Oga presents Kenji Miyazawa's drama
in traditional story card format.
Filled with heart-warming images,
Oga's retelling...
...is a fresh approach
to this famous story.
He's lonely and can't sleep.
People and birds,
they're no different.
Kisuke and Kakko came already,
and the mowing's done.
Oga's work beyond the realm
of animation backgrounds...
...conveys the same feelings
of peace and nostalgia.
This is something I like
to point out to people.
See here?
Those are dendrobium orchids.
It's a parasitic plant
that grows around Mt. Takao.
You can see them
in May and June.
I just added these on a whim.
But no one notices them.
0ga's orchids are the product of
attention to detail, a playful mind...
...and a deep attachment
to the natural world.
These little flowers are the work
of a quintessential image artisan.
What I try to do
is create backgrounds...
...that do justice
to the actual setting.
That includes natural phenomena...
...such as the wind blowing
or snow falling.
I want my backgrounds
to encompass all these things.
Kazuo Oga,
Studio Ghibli's image artisan.
Oga has said...
”There are no fixed colors
for plants or natural scenery. ”
In animation backgrounds
yet to come...
...who knows what colors
Kazuo Oga will discover?
Planning
Toshio Suzuki
Written and directed by
Maiko Yahata
Producers
Toshikazu Sato, Chikashi Saito
Production
TV MAN UNION
English subtitles by AURA
English translation by
Jim Hubbert