Previously on
Covert Affairs...
I'm sending you
back to the DPD.
But this mission
isn't dead yet.
Langley has asked me
to evaluate your well-being
in the field.
Who ordered the assessment?
I can't marry you.
You should have this back.
Good-bye, Auggie.
You'll begin therapy.
This is mandated.
I didn't need it
after my injury,
and I don't need it now.
[Timer ticking]
[Strained breathing]
Yesterday, Yemeni
Prime Minister A'zam Halabi
suffered a heart attack.
State is allowing him
to enter the U.S.
for medical treatment only.
He's currently en route
to the Mayo Clinic,
where he will undergo surgery
later today.
This is a special situation.
We defer to State.
No planned action
at this time.
What are we getting
in return?
I assume it has to do
with oil.
It does have something to do
Yemen is not an OPEC nation.
They make their own deals.
So State is trading
lower gas prices
for a man's life.
Is that why the CIA isn't
allowed anywhere near the place?
They're worried
we'll mess up the deal?
While the prime minister's
here in the country,
I'd like to try and turn
his Chief of Staff.
His name is Sayid al-Muqri,
and I think he could be
a valuable asset.
Annie, you're not the first
person in this building
who's wanted to turn
Sayid al-Muqri.
I've been following him, and
I think he could be a friend.
How so?
When he was a grad student
at Oxford in 2000,
an editorial appeared
Political Analysis.
The article condemned
the attack on the U.S.S. Cole
and called for greater
collaboration
between Yemen and the west.
And although there was no byline
to the editorial,
I could hear his voice
in the article.
If he wrote it,
I think he could be turned.
I'd like to make the play.
Halabi took in al-Muqri
when his parents died.
They're like family.
Al-Muqri will definitely be
traveling with him.
Surgery lasts three hours.
After which they get on a plane
straight back to Yemen.
It's a very short window
of time.
How do you plan
to approach?
A cold pitch.
It's the only way,
given the time frame.
So you think
you can turn
the prime minister's
right-hand man
based on an article
he might not have written.
He's being under-utilized
at home.
He's ambitious,
and he's itching to do more,
to find a bigger way
to contribute.
We could be that way.
But the risk is too high
and the timeline too short.
So let's move on.
[Knocking]
- May I have a moment, please?
- Sure.
I wanted to give you a copy
of the brief I wrote
on Sayid al-Muqri.
Maybe it'll change your mind.
Annie, your interest
in this individual
is not the issue here.
We don't have
a single asset in Yemen.
The CIA's decided the whole
country's a black hole,
that no Yemeni man or woman
would ever work with us.
I don't accept that.
Do you?
I am not responsible
for CIA policy.
I am responsible for you,
and I am not prepared
to send you into a situation
that's primed for you to fail.
Never mind the State
doesn't want us
to jeopardize their deal.
What you are proposing
is akin to flying to Cuba
for three hours
to try to turn Castro's son.
Sayid and I may have grown up
on opposite sides of the globe,
but we both raised ourselves in
the absence of strong parents.
We traveled by ourselves,
we learned other languages,
we chose a life of service
to our nations.
I may not have met him yet,
but I already know
how to speak to him.
If anyone
from State Department sees you,
you will turn around
and fly home.
If you meet with Sayid
and he turns you down,
you will fly home.
If you even think
you're about to get caught,
you will fly home.
That's a yes?
You have three hours.
Don't make me regret this.
Good luck, Annie.
[Can You Save Me?
By Apple Trees & Tangerines]
♪ Covert Affairs 03x06 ♪
Hello Stranger
Original Air Date on August 21, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪ Can you save me
♪ from this nothing
I've become? ♪
♪ it's just something
that I've done ♪
♪ I never meant
to cause you worry ♪
♪ Don't you blame me
♪ for this nothing
I've become ♪
♪ it's just something
that I've done ♪
♪ I never meant to show you
my mistakes ♪
Oh, hey.
Let me walk you to the elevator.
You only say that when
you wanna talk about something.
Whey do you assume I wanna
talk to you about anything,
particularly
about Joan's decision
to let you do this mission?
How could you know
she gave me the Op?
That just happened.
Because I know you,
and when you believe
in something,
whole armies won't stop you.
Which is why, despite your
attempts to keep things quiet,
I know about Parker...
and what happened at Allen's.
Well...
She flipped the script.
She did.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Auggie.
I'm going to be fine.
Now you have a plane to catch.
We're gonna talk about this,
all right?
Drinks at Allen's this week.
We might need to find
a new place.
But hey, variety's
the spice of life, right?
Now I am going to get blamed
for undermining your Op.
I'm sure Joan will find
some other reason
to keep me in the doghouse.
What is going on
between you two?
The friction's so palpable,
I'm almost glad I can't see it.
She asked Eyal Lavin
for a full cogent profile on me.
Well, you have been through
a lot lately.
Maybe she just wants
to make sure you're doing okay.
Eyal knows you well.
That's what he said.
Well, it just might be true.
You sound like you're
on her side.
I'm on your side.
Which reminds me why I wanted
to talk to you.
Oh, you admit it.
You do wanna talk to me
about something.
What can I say?
I'm a talker.
What you're about to do
is a huge gamble.
If you get there
and decide not to go for it,
I won't think any less of you.
No one will.
I know what I'm doing.
[Elevator dings]
Like I said--
whole armies.
Call me when you land.
Halabi will be arriving
by a private medical jet,
pre-cleared for landing
by the FAA.
[Siren wails]
So hit me.
What are my roadblocks?
Sayid and Halabi
will be traveling
with a small protection detail,
but your real problem
will be the State Department.
[Elevator dings]
[Indistinct chatter]
So the scary part is that
they bought out the whole wing
or the whole floor?
Neither.
A shutdown on any level
would draw too much attention,
and they don't want anyone
poking around
while we treat the leader
of a hostile nation,
and I mean anyone.
The public, the press, or
your friendly neighborhood CIA.
I got to admit.
It seems a little
counterproductive,
working against
our own government.
Yes, why can't we all
just get along?
Come home safe and unseen.
You can rant
about bureaucracy later.
It's not a rant.
It's a difference of opinion.
Spoken like an operative,
all fired up to turn an asset.
You got a game plan ready?
Yeah, I think I'm gonna go
with the basic version.
Everyone has a favorite vice.
Well, looks like you're gonna
have to wait to hear about mine.
They've just begun
the procedure.
Your three-hour countdown
starts now.
Okay.
Here I go.
Sir, I'm sorry.
Smoking's not permitted
in or around the hospital.
Claim this
is a free country.
It's hard waiting
for important news
without a cigarette.
You must know some secret.
No secrets.
I know a spot--
probably the only spot--
where they'll let you smoke.
- I'm okay.
- Not here.
Mayo Clinic is the size
of a college campus,
and security has a problem with
smoking for some unknown reason.
Where?
Out this door.
- It's a good spot.
- Yeah.
As-salaam alaikum,
Mr. al-Muqri.
I've been looking forward
to meeting you.
Forgive me,
we don't have a lot of time.
[Cursing in arabic]
Unbelievable.
The CIA can't even let
a sick man see a doctor.
We're welcoming to see
the best doctor in the world.
At tremendous cost.
We're just having
a conversation.
Conversations with the CIA
are never free.
We haven't demanded
anything.
The CIA and the State Department
are too separate things.
That's a distinction
you like to make, isn't it?
I don't know which operatives
you've met in the past,
but I'm not them.
No, you're blonde.
Perhaps someone now thinks
that's my type.
There's no agency plot here,
Mr. al-Muqri.
We have things in common,
and so I came to see you
on my own terms.
The only thing worse
than a CIA operative
is a CIA operative
with a personal agenda.
We have a shared agenda.
"The distance between villages
is short."
You wrote that,
and I believe it.
That we are all related.
I didn't write that,
but okay.
We're great friends.
Great friends
who pounce on each other
in moments of crisis.
The man who I have sworn
to serve faithfully
is fighting for his life
downstairs,
and you see that
as a political opportunity.
I see this as the only
opportunity to speak with you
to convince you that we have
a chance to change things.
Spoken like an American.
All promise and hope.
No regard for risk.
- We're both at risk here.
- No.
I am the one standing
in a hostile nation
under careful watch.
I have traveled far
and fought hard
to stand here with you.
I don't even know
your name.
You know everything
about me.
I'm exposed and vulnerable,
while you remain anonymous
and protected.
How can you have
a conversation with me
and hide your identity
at the same time?
How can I connect
with you...
When you haven't even
shared with me your name?
Annie Walker.
How do I know
that's the truth?
Because it's the truth.
Do not approach me again...
Annie Walker.
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
There she is.
Go, go.
Arthur Campbell
or Joan?
Uh, excuse me.
I'm asking you
a question.
Who sent you?
I don't--I don't know
what you mean.
All right,
you can play it that way.
You being here is
in direct violation
of American diplomatic
policy.
Come on,
let's go call your parents.
Steve, we respect the fact
that the State Department
is facilitating this.
Are you trying
to apologize?
Because you're terrible at it.
I apologize.
The Agency never intended
to compromise your authority.
But that's exactly
what you're trying to do.
Why else would you send
an operative here?
- We didn't send her.
- To build national security.
You're either deliberately
breaking a promise you made,
or you've got a rogue agent
under your roof.
We didn't make any promise.
You dictated terms.
Perhaps while temperatures
are running high,
we should avoid questioning
each other's motives.
Everyone on this call wants
the State Department's deal
with Yemen to succeed.
Are you suddenly my partner
in this, Arthur?
I'd like to think
we can work together, yes.
The American people
finally get some relief
from soaring energy costs,
and an old man
gets to see a great doctor.
Do you support
both those ideas?
Of course I do.
Then why are you
screwing it up?
The CIA comes in,
everybody gets nervous.
They start
to reconsider deals.
I know you don't wanna be
responsible for that.
I understand
your point of view, Steve.
- You understand, or you agree?
- I agree.
Then you'll send her home
right away.
Right away.
Good.
Play the "what if" game
with me.
Ooh, one of my favorites.
Okay, a brilliant,
young operative
flies to Minnesota
to turn a valuable asset--
What if she's caught
by the State Department?
She calls for advice.
What if Joan and Arthur
cave to State and send her home?
If we're talking
about the same operative,
she uses whatever time
she has left
to pursue her objective.
What if she's been banned
from the building?
Then she finds a way
to make him leave it.
Auggie, you're brilliant.
That's not a "what if"
statement.
- You win.
- I usually do.
Listen, I'm stepping into
a meeting for the next hour.
Call me if you need anything,
all right?
You're my top priority.
I'll be fine.
No worries.
Auggie.
How's it going?
Fantastic,
and I have a feeling
it's about to get even better.
It is?
Today's your lucky day.
We're gonna shake things up
a little bit.
- How?
- A field trip.
You could probably use
some fresh air.
I don't live in this office,
Auggie, I just work here.
Besides, we'll be here
for the hour.
That's how this works.
Oh, I'm sorry.
The other week,
you presented yourself
as an unconventional shrink:
working with veterans,
offering
to let me skip sessions.
Is that just a cover?
What did you have
in mind?
- I'll take the cigarettes.
- Which ones?
All of them.
You're going
to show me
how to get
across the street blindfolded?
Orientation
and mobility training.
When I did it,
I didn't have a choice.
It'll help you
to understand me better.
Auggie, I--
And the more
that you protest,
the less time you're gonna have
to get the hang of it.
That's the spirit.
[Horn honking]
You ready?
I'm ready.
- Here you go.
- All right.
How does this work?
Okay, this cane's a couple
of inches too tall for you.
So choke down a little bit.
You're gonna hold it
waist high,
about a foot in front
of your body.
Think of it as an extension
of your index finger,
but it should be
underneath the shaft.
That way,
if you hit something,
you're not gonna stab yourself
in the stomach.
See?
Mmhmm.
Very good.
This little aluminum tube
is about to become
your best friend.
Cigarettes?
You can bum
one of mine.
Takes me four minutes
to smoke a cigarette.
That's how much time you have.
Mr. al-Muqri,
I'm surprised.
I didn't take you for a man
who shuts down conversations.
What sort of man
did you take me for?
If given the right support...
a leader.
That's what you tell
all of us, isn't it?
Flatter us,
make us feel special.
I've never said that
to anyone before.
I came here to speak to you.
Then speak.
I'd like
to work with you.
That's never going
to happen.
Why not?
Because the CIA has wreaked
havoc in my part of the world.
You keep referring to me
as a mouthpiece for the Agency.
I know you wouldn't like
to be thought of that way.
You're your own person.
A person
whom you have just met
and yet claim to know so well.
This is why we are enemies.
Because you make assumptions
about us,
and you act
as if they are true.
You don't really believe
we're enemies.
I believe your country
is only interested in mine
because we have oil.
You're right.
If that's your pitch,
it's not a very good one.
I'm being honest.
We're interested in you
because of oil,
and you're interested in us
because of our technology,
our universities,
and sometimes our health care.
As you can see,
we can be very giving.
The empty hand, reaching for
help in the guise of affection.
Reminds me of the prose
you wrote in that article.
I didn't write
that article.
You've fallen in love
with a ghost.
Sayid, I don't have time
to play these games,
and neither do you.
You can't be happy with your
country's place in the world
or your position in it.
Work with me.
- You mean spy for you.
- I mean work with me.
We can share information
and ideas.
We can build a bridge
between our nations
that no one else
is willing to build.
I am not a builder
of bridges.
I serve at the pleasure
of the Prime Minister,
and I accept the position
he has given me.
But you're here now.
You had cigarettes.
The only cigarettes
in Minnesota?
Maybe.
Or maybe
you just like talking to me.
Come on.
What are you doing?
I don't think we've been seen,
but we have to go now.
What are you talking about?
That car over there
has State Department plates.
Can you run?
I'm not running
anywhere with you.
We don't have time
to negotiate this.
You're unsupervised
and off the hospital campus,
which is a violation,
and puts us both at risk.
We have to go now.
Which way?
[tires screech, horns honk]
We should go.
Out the front.
Wait, wait.
[Cart rattles]
Okay, we're at the corner.
I've got you all lined up.
There is a dip in the concrete
called a cutout.
And I want you step out
into that cutout.
[Horn honking]
Uh, wait, wait, wait! Stop!
Watch it!
I said onto the cutout,
not into the street.
- Sorry, I thought that--
- No, it's okay.
Just take a breath.
Very good.
Now, here are
the ground rules.
You are gonna have to lean
into your other senses.
Listening is everything.
I want you to feel the ground
with your feet.
It'll tell you everything
that you need to know.
Now take a breath.
What do you smell?
Exhaust.
Something
even less pleasant.
Hmm, a dog.
Who's left a calling card,
so watch your step.
[Chuckles]
Now, you're gonna
sweep the cane
back and forth
in front of you
like you're clearing the way
for each step.
When we start, you're gonna
keep sweeping and breathing.
That's right.
Okay,
we've got parallel traffic.
You hear that?
Uhhuh. I hear it.
Then we're safe.
Let's go.
Okay.
That's it!
Nice and steady.
[Horn honks, tires screech]
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Take your blindfold off.
- That's crazy.
- Yeah, it happens.
Most people veer toward
their dominant leg.
Now come line yourself back up,
put your blindfold on,
and keep going.
Okay.
That's it.
Keep going.
All right, you did it.
I did it!
Oh, my God,
that was amazing!
Let's do it again.
That a girl.
You sure we lost them?
Let's sit near the back door
just in case.
How are you feeling
about those cigarettes now?
Oh, not winded.
It's just adrenaline.
Yeah,
keep telling yourself that.
- Counter?
- Booth.
The one at the back, please.
Mmhmm.
Does this, uh, sort of thing
happen to you a lot?
It happens.
Mostly my job
consists of talking to people.
I'm hungry.
Let's order something.
Western food doesn't
really interest me.
Everything's on a bun.
Can I have a turkey sandwich
on whole wheat,
and can you bring
the check with it?
I'll have a hamburger,
toasted bun, please.
What? It's like going to Japan
and not ordering Sushi.
I barely recognized you
in that meeting today.
I read you in
on the Yemen deal,
I told you
it wasn't actionable,
and you used it to make a play.
I showed initiative.
How could you
send Annie there?
Because she showed me
initiative.
And why not send her there?
Because State Department's
nervous?
No, because
the State Department
is trying to navigate
very fragile terrain,
and they're doing it well.
Since when do you compliment
the State Department?
You detest Steve Barr
and all his cronies.
You always have.
You put me
in an impossible position.
Arthur, I probably should've
talked to you first.
Yes.
But I took a chance.
Are you angry because
I didn't defend your operation
or because
I didn't defend you?
You know, in this case,
they're the same thing.
You realize
you're almost out the door?
No.
Yes. The promise
of the Chinese ambassador post
is pulling you away
like you no longer work here,
like you've already gotten
the job.
The choice I made today
was the right call,
given the facts
that I had.
You know what, Arthur?
You're gonna make
a great politician.
Mmm.
It's pretty good.
My, um--
my father was a dear friend
to Prime Minister Halabi,
and when my parents died,
he took me in.
I was 12 years old.
I remember, not long
after I moved into the palace,
a small bird hit the bedroom
window and injured its wing.
The Prime Minister,
he had falcons for some time,
so he knew something
about birds.
So he taught me
how to repair the wing
and nurse the bird back
to health.
And I remember asking him
every day
if we can let the bird go,
and he said something to me
I'll never forget.
He said it would be cruel
to let the bird go too soon,
that it would surely die
on its own,
being weak and unable to fly
and that just because I want
the bird to be free
doesn't mean
that it's ready.
You think
the Yemeni people
are little birds
with broken wings?
I think a nation chooses
when and how to change.
It's up to their leaders
to listen.
That's a progressive thought.
Does your mentor
share your views?
He's not just my mentor.
He's my family.
He saved my life.
So you share
all his views.
You disagree
with your mentor?
I've had a few mentors,
and I disagree with them
every day.
How do you respect a man
you disagree with?
Both my mentors
are women.
The CIA is indeed
a complicated place.
I respect them.
They succeeded
where few women have.
And even when we disagree,
I know they'd look out for me.
They believe in you.
Now imagine how it would feel
to lose that.
It'd feel horrible.
So is this, uh,
how the CIA works?
You talk to people like they are
on Oprah's couch?
I asked you to reveal
something about yourself.
I thought it only fair
I do the same.
They won't stay out long.
Let's circle back.
We're walking, huh?
Wish I would've worn
comfortable shoes.
I'm, uh, sorry this didn't
work out the way you wanted.
Oh, it's not about me.
What do you want
to happen?
I want A'zam
to make a full recovery.
That's all.
Yeah.
You're right.
I'm right?
You couldn't have written
that article.
Whoever wrote it
has courage and vision.
That's not you.
You have fear and caution.
So now you've taken
to insulting me.
You really think
that's going to work?
I don't know.
How do you convince someone
in ten minutes
that you believe in them more
than they believe in themselves?
Be grateful for what A'zam
has given you,
but look for ways to realize
your own potential.
I am one of those ways--
we are, right now.
Annie, I can't.
Where are you going?
I'm done.
Annie, you don't know
what you're asking of me.
I do.
Even if I agreed to work
with the CIA,
I wouldn't be talking
to you.
You would disappear.
I wouldn't.
And what happens
if I get caught?
If someone in Yemen
discovers our work?
We have emergency protocol
for asset protection.
I could teach that to you.
Does that apply to my sister
and her family?
Yes.
You can guarantee that now, or
you'll have to ask your mentor?
I have to ask her.
But here's a number
where you can reach me.
Memorize it,
and destroy the card.
- Hello?
- Hey, it's me.
Annie,
you missed your plane.
We agreed
that if you got caught,
you would get on a plane
and come back home.
Joan, I got him
to talk to me.
You did what?
He has some requests
regarding asylum
for him and his sister,
but it's all pretty standard.
Stop. There's something
we need to talk about.
The Prime Minister
had another heart attack.
He's in critical condition.
I have to talk to Sayid.
I don't wanna lose him, Joan.
You have to come home.
If the Prime Minister of Yemen
dies on our soil,
the last thing
anyone wants
is for a CIA operative
to be found on the scene.
Can we grant him asylum
or not?
Annie,
you're not listening to me.
We cannot grant asylum.
State will never allow it.
Not after today.
No, we have to make
this happen.
The State Department
is trying to avoid
an international incident.
They're looking for you.
Annie, you need
to get on a plane.
No, not before I talk to him.
Sorry, Joan.
Ow!
Ooh, you okay?
Yeah.
Fire hydrant
came out of nowhere.
Yeah, they do that.
Oh, even to you?
Oh, I bump into stuff
about 14 times a day.
And I've been known to walk
into the ladies' bathroom.
Sometimes on purpose.
[Laughs]
The truth is being blind
is hard.
It's difficult every day.
Do you ever wanna
stay home?
Yeah, sure,
but I don't.
So when you're not up to it,
what do you do?
I keep going
'cause I have to.
About five years ago
after my injury,
all I wanted to do was get
back to my unit,
keep serving my country,
but I didn't see
how I could do either
of those things
when I couldn't even
cross the street.
I found myself on a corner,
just like that one--
frozen, turned around...
lost.
So I threw my cane away,
I heard it hit the ground,
and just walked into traffic
counting on somebody else
to finish the job
the explosion didn't.
Some drivers
have good reflexes.
You're a survivor.
What does that feel like?
I'm lucky.
I'm a lucky guy.
Oh, hey, look at that.
Our time's almost up.
You better get back
for your next victim.
Because--
I opened up,
I shared.
Come on, Doc,
congratulations.
You got what you wanted
after all.
I got my gold star, right?
It was nice knowing you.
No, we're not done yet.
How do you figure?
We haven't talked about
what inspired this field trip
in the first place.
You walked into my office
with your own blueprint
for what therapy should be.
Yeah,
it was pretty damn good.
Are you always trying
to manage people in situations?
Sayid!
What are you doing?
This is my last chance.
I really need you
to listen to me.
Listen to me, please.
A'zam had another
heart attack.
- I know.
- I'm going to see him.
Now let me out of here.
We both fear
that we may lose our mentors
or that our mentors
may lose faith in us.
But this is your choice.
Your wings have healed.
Annie, please.
Let me out of here.
I fear you'll see
the Prime Minister's
second heart attack
as some kind of sign that
he needs you now more than ever,
but your loyalty
cannot save him.
There is something bigger
that we can save now.
Save what, Annie?
Yemen? America?
The world?
Not today.
Not all at once.
But a piece of it.
Did you speak to your boss
about my request?
She said
it's not possible.
I'm sorry.
And do you disagree
with your mentor on this?
I do, absolutely.
But not enough
to do anything about it.
What can I do?
So now you understand
my position.
Perhaps we do have
a lot in common.
"Only a fool confuses fate
with destiny.
"Fate is what happens
to us.
Destiny is what we make
in spite of our fate."
I wrote that article
such a long time ago.
How did you know
it was me?
Because it
was courageous.
You weren't waiting
for someone else
to tell you you were ready,
you already knew.
[Elevator dings]
Where is A'zam?
Take her.
Prime Minister A'zam Halabi
of Yemen, passed away last night
at the Mayo Clinic
in Rochester, Minnesota.
The U.S. State Department
had made arrangements
for Halabi to receive
medical treatment there
after suffering his first
of two myocardial infarctions.
The late Prime Minister's aides
and personnel
have returned to Yemen, where
the state of the government
remains in flux.
We turn now
to our correspondent in Sana'a.
So this is what a deal
with State looks like.
You gonna say
"I told you so"?
I don't believe in
"I told you so."
The thing went sideways.
That is not your fault.
If I had two more minutes,
Sayid would've said yes.
You know the great truth
about turning an asset.
You gotta cast a lot of lines
before you catch a fish.
This is the toughest thing
that we do.
I thought I had him.
The strangest thing--spending
so long reading about someone,
their whole life
unfolds in front of you.
I felt like I could see
his potential.
- You believed in him.
- Yeah.
How angry is she?
Annie.
Will you step inside, please?
Close the door.
Have a seat.
Do you have questions
about why
I couldn't grant
Sayid's request?
They don't matter now.
They matter to me.
Annie, this job,
this life is wonderful.
To me it is.
But it can also be
frustrating.
Never more so than when
uncertainties drive decisions.
Well,
the future's uncertain.
Yeah, it is.
Look, I know
this was painful.
And it's okay to be angry
with the CIA.
It's even okay
to be angry with me.
Joan, I've thought
about this a lot...
and I've requested
a department transfer.
Do you want to go back
to work for Lena?
I don't know.
I left it blank on the form.
Well, I'm sorry
to hear that.
I appreciate everything
you've done for me.
I just think
it's time to move on.
Annie, there's a Yemeni man
on the asset line.
He says
he'll only speak with you.
What?
Does Joan know?
Of course.
We spoke this morning.
She made it clear
that if he called,
he was to be your asset.
Congratulations.
Annie.
You gonna take the call?
Yeah.
Hello?
== sync, corrected by elderman ==