Yeah, you know
how pumped they get
over the sports interviews.
- Tom Brady has everything, right?
- Yeah.
So, what Mike Wallace
says to him is...
he says, "here you are,
youngest quarterback
"to ever win three super bowls,
three MVPs,
"absolute top
of your profession.
How does it feel to have
all your dreams come true?"
And so he said,
"when it all happened,
"I said to myself,
'is this really it?
There's got to be something
more than this, right?'"
wow. That hit you,
clearly, big.
What are you doing?
Getting a granola bar.
You're stealing a granola bar.
We haven't bought these yet.
- Can I have a piece?
- I'm not stealing it.
- She's not stealing it.
- Mom would let me have it.
- You're gonna buy them.
- Mom would let you do this?
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm gonna have a little chat with mom.
- You just go and you...
- I'm not stealing it.
You are eating something
you haven't paid for yet.
- Come on.
- That's kind of like...
if you look up what stealing is,
that's what stealing is.
She was just about to take
a shot, and then she threw up.
Oh, my God. And you weren't
there to see this one?
No, no, it's the one
that I missed.
- Wow.
- Get your thing.
- Yeah.
- Man.
I wish... hey, will you
do me a favor
and tell me the next time
someone's gonna barf
- all over the ice?
- Yeah, that would be nice.
Hey, when is the funeral?
Um, Friday, I think.
You think Dave's gonna come?
I don't know, man.
I haven't talked to him.
Have you talked to him at all?
No, I haven't talked to him
in like a year.
You talk to him more than I do.
Sam, pull over here, will you?
All right. Sure.
Yeah.
I feel like walking.
Bye, banana head.
- Yeah.
- I'll see you later.
What do you mean,
you're gonna quit the boat?
What are you gonna do for work?
I don't know.
I'll figure something out.
Don't worry about it, mom.
Yeah, okay, I won't,
but I do, all right?
I do worry about it, yeah.
I mean, most people
would have lined up a job
before they even think about
quitting something.
Well, you know
I'm not most people.
Yeah, but guess what.
The basement
is rented out, so...
I'm not gonna be
in the basement.
I did that for two weeks.
No. Maybe like two months.
It was two weeks
five years ago.
You haven't stopped
giving me shit about it.
And when does Davey
get to town?
I don't know.
I haven't talked to him.
But I assume soon.
- He's coming.
- I assume he is, yeah.
"I assume."
It's his father's funeral.
He's coming, right?
Yes, he's coming.
Okay. Well, then you bring him
around for dinner when he comes.
- Okay. I will.
- Okay. Okay.
That's good.
I sent flowers from us.
- Oh, nice.
- Hi.
Hey, Sara.
How are you?
I'm all right.
I'm sorry I missed the show.
How'd it go?
- Oh, it's all right.
- Yeah?
- I sold one piece, but...
- You did?
- I did.
- Oh, congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
- That's awesome.
- I'm good.
- I'm gonna come by.
- You should.
- Yeah.
- See for yourself.
- Friday, right?
You gonna buy something?
- I hope so.
- Uh-huh.
What?
- She is a sweet girl, that Sara.
- I know she's a sweet girl.
- Yeah, she is.
- Yep, she is.
- She has a cute ass, too.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
- Seriously.
- What? I'm just saying.
- Will you stop, please?
I'm not... what?
I'm just saying that...
will you stop checking out
girls' asses?
You're the checker-outer-er,
whatever.
- I got to go.
- Anyway, I just...
you know, I would like to have
a grandchild at some point.
I know you would. You should
have had more kids, though.
- What do you want me to do?
- I know.
I really should have,
maybe 5, 10, 20.
Right. Exactly.
Where are you going?
You know where I'm going.
- I told you.
- Oh, right. Be happy.
You're hilarious.
- I love you.
- Love you, too.
Okay, okay, we're gonna
do the chicken dance.
You guys remember
the chicken dance?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Okay.
You know Chet.
That's his favorite.
Let's get in...
hands right in there like that.
Yep...
Really make eye contact
with each other, guys.
Everybody!
Everybody, drop!
Let's get together
to do the chain gang, okay?
Get your head
on someone's stomach, everybody,
and then someone's gonna
put their head on your stomach.
Here we go. Ha!
- Ha ha.
Ha ha.
Get in that belly.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
If you start doing it, you'll
start feeling it, right? Right?
That's it, guys.
That's it.
Very nice.
That was terrific.
I love you guys.
You guys are so great.
There's so much love in here.
I love it.
Thank you. Thank you.
Good job... our new...
our new people, too, today.
Really good work.
Bye, guys. We'll see you
next week. Thank you.
Oh!
You're so great.
Hey.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Oh, my God.
- So good to see you.
I'm so surprised to see you.
That was fun.
You're a great teacher.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
It's... yay.
So fun.
Thank you so much again.
Thank you, Theresa. It's always
so great to see you.
You have a good day.
- See you.
- Your people love you.
Oh.
No, I mean, you really seem like
the people really...
- Hey.
- How are you?
- It's so good to see you.
It is really good to see you.
- Yeah.
- That trip was... was long.
Yeah, a few weeks.
- It was amazing.
- Yeah?
We took alpacas, like,
down the mountains and...
but just the whole time,
all I could think of was the
laughter that I brought with me
really just affected everyone.
It just made a great trip.
- Chet has come a long way.
- Really?
When he came in here, just...
he was a sourpuss.
- You're kidding me.
- Yeah.
This guy?
- Yeah. Wouldn't believe it, right?
- This guy.
This is Jon.
Yeah. I already laid
on your belly, so...
Beautiful.
It's a beautiful thing.
It was so good
to see you again.
Yeah. Cool.
- Great to see you.
- Well, it's good seeing you.
Yeah, nice to meet you.
Have a good night.
- I'm glad you liked it.
- It was fun.
It was a lot of fun.
I thought maybe you were gonna
be a little freaked out by it.
Oh, I was completely
freaked out by it, but...
It was cool.
- You did good.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I was terrible.
I had fun the other night,
too, hanging out.
That was fun,
wasn't it? Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean... hi.
- Um, yeah, it was cool.
- Yeah.
Do you meditate ever?
Uh, no.
I've always wanted to, but
I just haven't had the time.
You haven't had the time?
- My life's very busy.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
What?
- Right now?
- Yeah.
We gonna meditate now?
- Okay.
Just leave your car.
We'll take mine.
Oh. All right.
Did you have trouble finding...
It's not an openness
like sleeping around.
It's just an openness
with your partner,
just being completely honest
about everything.
Like, everything?
Yeah, everything, you know, any
desires or impulses, anything...
you know,
you're attracted to somebody,
you tell them instead
of not... not telling them.
It's just keeping it open
and honest,
a communication, basically.
So, do they get annoyed
if you're constantly, like,
telling them, like,
"that person's hot"?
No, because I don't do that.
I'm not like, "oh, that guy's
so hot," you know?
- I'm still respectful.
- Right.
And I do it more
out of honoring that person.
If I feel it's important enough
to say something, I will.
- Right.
- But you really think hard
about if you actually do
want to sleep with that person.
- Right.
- 'Cause you're gonna tell them about it.
- Sure.
- You know?
But what if it, like,
happens spontaneously and...
you can't really do that,
right,
'cause you got to
tell the other person?
Yeah, that's...
you know,
there's some loopholes.
No.
No, I mean, it's...
if it happens, it happens,
and then you can
talk about it afterwards,
- you know, too, but...
- Yeah.
When you call them from the
other person's, like, bedroom?
"I'm here.
It's looking good.
I feel like
it's gonna happen."
Does that work out?
No. Somehow,
it hasn't happened like that.
You know, it's not like
I'm walking around
with my pants down.
Like, I'm not trying to get laid
all the time, you know?
Right. Sure.
Yeah. No. No. No.
So, how many people
have you been with at one time?
- At one time?
- Yeah.
- Like...
- No, no, no, not like...
how many guys?
Next.
Yeah, exactly.
No, but, like, how many people
have you dated at once?
- I think two.
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
And they both
knew about each other?
Yeah.
Yeah. And they were cool
with it?
- Yeah.
- That's awesome.
I've... I've been
at the point where I'm like,
"I really care about both
of these people," you know?
Yeah, no, I mean, I love all
this because, like, for me,
I've never felt right
in any kind of normal,
structured relationship,
you know?
But I always just thought
that there was something wrong
with me, so...
Right. And there's nothing
wrong with you.
You're just being true
to yourself, you know?
Right. That's cool.
Yeah, it is.
It's a cool way
to look at it. Yeah.
I don't know if I could handle
it, but it sounds awesome.
Don't know until you try,
you know?
That's true.
- Okay. Enough.
- All right.
- Here we go.
Are you ready?
- I am so ready.
- Good.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Okay, just shake it out.
- Shake it out.
- Bl-bl-bl-bl-bl.
- Okay.
- Just be totally relaxed.
- All right.
- And just put your hands on your knees.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- This is cool.
- That's it.
Okay. I'm gonna close my eyes
with you, so don't worry, okay?
Okay.
That'll help me.
Yes.
Don't worry.
- I'm not gonna be staring at you.
- Okay.
Deep breath in.
Deep breath out.
Just focus on your breath,
watching it go in and out.
Just notice your thoughts.
They're just gonna come up,
but you can just watch them
drift by like clouds.
Just pass on by.
Okay.
Keep breathing.
Keep your eyes closed.
Your eyes are open.
I know, but I'm...
I'm the instructor.
- Oh. Sorry.
- It's okay.
I'm just gonna
put my hand right there.
Okay.
That's good.
Now just... okay.
That feels really good.
Good. Good.
Just breathe into it.
Just let it all go.
- Jon?
- What?
- What are you doing?
- We're meditating, okay?
- I know. It's awesome.
- I love meditating.
- Okay. Well, it's actually supposed to be
- on your own, okay?
- Oh, okay.
Okay, so...
it's okay.
This connection
that we're feeling...
Yeah.
...is great, but it doesn't
always have to be sexual, okay?
Oh, no. Yeah.
No. Absolutely.
Okay, cool.
Thank you.
What's up, man?
Your beard.
Look at your beard.
Wow!
- Here. Take this.
- Yeah?
Younger than us,
and he's accomplished more
than any other quarterback
in the history of the game.
So, when Mike Wallace
asked him, like,
how it felt to have
all his dreams come true,
he said he thought to himself,
like, "is this really it?
There's got to be something
more than this."
- Yeah.
- Isn't that crazy?
Like, he's got
a supermodel wife,
he's got four super bowls,
and he's not satisfied
with his life?
No, I get it.
He's a quarterback.
You used to be a quarterback.
You're into it.
No, I mean... it's just...
I don't know.
I thought it was interesting.
What should I fucking care about
tom Brady for?
I don't care about
tom Brady, either.
- I'm just saying.
- The fort!
Yep.
Oh, man,
I can't believe I'm here.
I know. I was surprised
you showed, actually.
I didn't think I was gonna.
Really?
I was driving today
to the club.
I was like...
"I should go," you know?
And I was like... I just fucking
went right to the airport.
I got to borrow more shit
from you if I can.
Oh, yeah, you can
borrow whatever you want.
It's fucking cold as hell.
- I'll tell you that.
- I know.
Ain't like this
in Vegas, right?
- I'm not there anymore.
- What?
Yeah, I told you that.
I'm in Arizona, in Phoenix.
The last time I talked to you,
you were working
at that casino in Vegas.
No, no, I'm running the club.
- Yeah, heaven.
- I had no idea.
- I told you that.
- No, you didn't.
Yeah, I went there with a girl.
Dude, I haven't talked to you
in four years.
What do you mean,
you told me that?
I was down there
with her. We moved in.
Who's the girl?
We're not together anymore.
She's just a fucking cunt.
- Let's get high.
- All right.
I bet you haven't thought about
Trish Dowling in a while.
She was amazing, man.
You had those, man.
- You had them.
- Yes, I did.
How did you get her?
Like, how did that happen?
What did you do?
Did you fucking...
did you bribe her?
- Yeah, I did.
- How did you do that?
What, you don't think my charm
and good looks was enough?
No, I definitely
don't think so, man.
No. She looks good,
though.
Does she?
Who else do you see?
Nobody.
I see, like, Sam.
Right.
He's good?
He's good. He's happy?
I mean,
I wouldn't go that far, but...
I just burned the shit
out of my finger.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- You high?
- I'm really high.
It's good weed, right?
It is good.
Arizona's finest, man.
Arizona's finest.
I see Kate once in a while.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- How's she doing?
- She's all right.
She got remarried, you know.
Yeah?
Who'd she remarry?
Um, this guy Steve
from Mattapoisett,
older guy, like 55.
- 55?
- Yeah.
Wow.
- It's fucking dead.
- Is it tapped out?
Yeah.
Do you think that's a little old
for her or what?
What, for her?
Yeah.
Does Sam hate him?
I mean, he doesn't hate him,
but I think it's hard
for Sam, you know?
Yeah.
I mean, he's not like dating
anyone else or... you know?
Really?
How long has that been?
Been like, whatever, five, six
years now, something like that?
- That's too long.
- Yeah.
No, we got to take him out
while you're here
and just get him laid.
You guys don't fuck around,
you and Sam?
Get the fuck out of here.
You still got it?
I still got it.
Get the fuck out of here.
You fuck.
You writing a lot?
Yeah. Always.
You know,
always got something going.
- Yep.
- Yeah.
So, you like it out there,
though?
I fucking love it, man.
You got to come over, man.
- You got to come visit.
- No, I want to.
We've been wondering
about you, though.
Surprised not to hear from you
for a while.
It's fucking freezing here.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
- Yeah? Come on.
- Yeah, it's freezing.
Right. This is the one
on Windsor terrace.
- Look at him.
- What is he doing?
He's in there.
Go through it, and I think
it'll be clear on... right.
No, I think that... I think
it's not gonna be a problem.
It's just...
they just didn't know.
- They weren't fully...
- Hey, rose.
They think that we've already
done the inspection, obviously.
And that was just a little bit
of a miscommunication
on our part.
And... yeah.
Well, no, that's what we can...
look at the suit.
And I'm on your s...
you know, there's been...
no, I think that's something
we can clear up.
- You want us to come back, man?
- I'm on your side.
Can you just give me
like two minutes?
Rose, this is our friend Dave.
He's in from out of town.
- Enchanted.
- Okay, well... right. Right. Sorry.
And Mr. George
is over there.
All right. Okay.
5:30. Thanks. Davey!
Look what I brought in.
- What's up?
- Oh, it's good to see you.
Good to see you.
- When did you get in?
- Like an hour ago.
Jesus.
Yeah, we went to the fort.
I got that...
I got that picture.
- Yeah.
- Let's go outside.
Okay.
Hey, rose.
Um...
Oh, God.
I'm so high.
- I'm sorry.
- What is happening?
What's going on, man?
- Good to see you.
- Wow, so you guys have already... clearly I missed...
I missed the, uh, the overture
to this little event.
Dude, I love you.
♪ When you say forever ♪
It's not like open like, you know, you're
fucking around with so many other people.
Right, but you're cool with it
if she fucks another guy.
- It's open.
- Um, yeah.
- Yeah.
But it's more like open
like we're gonna be open
about what's...
what's happening.
So, if there's like...
she fucks other girls. No.
Well, then she's not open.
No, but it's not even
open like that.
It's like... like,
how she puts it is that, like,
if you love somebody
unconditionally,
wouldn't you just want them
to be happy,
even if that means they're gonna
be with somebody else
or not with you?
But it's good, though.
You know, it's like everyone
in this town is so the same.
She was different,
and I think that's
what I need right now.
- Hey. How are my boys?
- We're good.
Do you know what you want?
We are good. Yes, I'm gonna
have surf and turf, as you know.
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna get the, uh...
You should get surf and turf.
It's really good.
Hey. How's your mom doing
with everything?
Oh, she's good, Maddy.
Thanks for asking.
Yeah.
It's a hard time, huh?
Just get the surf and turf,
man. It's good.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Hey, did, uh,
did, uh, my baby tell you
that he is quitting
his fishing job?
- He did.
- Yeah.
He's a writer.
- Okay. All right.
- I'm proud of this guy.
Well, that makes one of us.
- Good for him.
- Look at that.
Yeah. Mr. Hemingway needs
more time for his writing.
Oh, thanks for the support, mom.
That's great. Yeah.
I'll get the... let's do
two surf and turfs.
Two surf and turfs.
Okay.
- Yeah. I miss you.
You know,
you talk some sense into him?
I'm gonna smack some sense
into this guy.
I'm gonna fix him up right now.
- Thanks, mom.
- She's fantastic.
Sorry.
Hey, man,
these new-age chicks...
I had a bunch of those.
I don't think she's that
new-agey, to tell you the truth.
I mean, maybe she...
I don't know her that well,
but... you know,
it's not like she goes
to burning man every year
- or something.
- When you're fucking her,
does she light candles
and stuff?
I mean, not while...
she doesn't light the candle
while I'm fucking her.
No, I'd hope not 'cause...
that would be dangerous.
But I like candles.
Like a candle around each,
you know, area.
Yeah.
You know what I'm hearing
from you?
What?
That you finally
found the ass of a lifetime.
I might have.
You got to be careful
of these new-agey broads, man.
They'll fuck with your head.
I've had it happen to me.
In Vegas, a couple of them...
they wear these flowing dresses
and they chant
and they fucking
light candles and incense
and they fuck with you.
They fuck with you.
Just be careful.
Sounds like you know
what you're doing.
I can't wait to meet her.
Does she have friends?
You know, at some point
in our lives we should take...
take a boat out
and just never come back, man.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Where would we go?
I don't know.
Me, you,
and a bunch of broads on a boat.
That sounds good.
What are we gonna do?
We got to do something.
I don't know.
There's not much to do
in this town, as you remember.
Yeah. I wasn't gonna
come at all, man.
I know.
I was surprised
when I got your call.
I kind of felt like I should
do it for my mom, you know?
Yeah.
Like, do you and your mom
talk on the phone and stuff?
We try.
It's hard to fucking talk
with her, you know?
♪ On my way home ♪
♪ and there goes something ♪
Whoo!
♪ On our way home ♪
♪ by that lonesome graveyard ♪
♪ a ghost jumps up and says,
"come on, be my man" ♪
♪ no ghost at all ♪
♪ someone asking for a ride ♪
Okay.
You have your bag?
Come on. We got to go.
Let's go.
But it's not her turn.
Cara, please do not
give me a hard time
about this right now, okay?
- I'm not.
- Why does mom get two turns?
Hey, trey, can you just keep
them busy for like 20 minutes?
I got to drop Cara off
at Kate's, okay?
Thanks.
Why does mom get two turns
in a row?
She does not get two turns
in a row, okay?
I promise you
I will come back and get you
after I show these people
the house.
You will wake up here
tomorrow, okay?
- Fine.
- Thank you.
Bless you.
It was a cough.
- That was a cough?
- Yeah.
Hey,
bunny-boo.
Hey, mom.
Hey. Long time no see.
Thanks again for doing this.
Couple hours, tops.
Sure.
It's not a problem.
She can stay here tonight,
if it's easier for you.
No, she's got
the hockey thing tomorrow.
I'll come back.
It's good.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Here's Gemmy.
Gemmy.
- And that is all.
- Okay.
Oh, hey, uh, by the way,
David's back in town.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, for a little while.
His dad died...
A couple days ago.
Oh, no.
Yeah. It was like Monday or
Tuesday or something like that.
- I thought you'd want to know.
- I do. Thank you.
- All right.
- Hey, Sam.
Hey, Mr. Steve.
How are you, man?
Good to see you.
Yeah.
You too.
It's good to, uh... okay.
All right.
Call me later
if you change your mind,
if you decide you want her
to spend the night.
It's really not a problem.
Okay.
Can we eat now?
So, it's all original woodwork,
built in the late 1800s,
and six bedrooms.
It's everything you guys
are looking for.
Oh, great. And this
is the kitchen?
Yeah. Go ahead.
Take a look.
Okay, great.
Thank you.
Where's Sammy?
He's got the kid tonight.
I want to see some ass.
Where's the spot to go, man?
- I know where we can go.
- Where?
That's amazing.
Whoa!
That's got to hurt, right?
Wow.
That's amazing.
The girls in this town, man.
- Like... That.
- They're bad-ass.
They are.
You forgot.
Oh, my God.
Hey, man.
I fucked around with Kate.
What?
No, you didn't.
I did.
You kidding me?
No, it was like
a million years ago.
I'm sure Sam... he wouldn't even
fucking care at this point.
Wait, when was this?
Right before I left.
Remember they had that break?
Yeah.
It happened a bunch of times.
You think I'm an asshole?
Hey, boys.
- Hey.
How's it going?
Good. How are you?
Good. Jonny,
you want a lap dance?
No, man. Go ahead.
Go for it.
You sure? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How about you?
Yeah, I'd love one.
♪ I'm ready for
action, I'm tired of watching ♪
Let's get out of here, man.
Just give it another minute.
Are you serious?
Come on.
- It's nice.
- It's nice?
I want to
show her appreciation.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing. I just want to
get out of here.
You thinking about
the hippie chick?
No. I'm thinking about the bomb
you dropped on me about Kate.
Oh, I shouldn't have
told you that shit.
- Just forget about it.
- How do I forget about that?
Hold on a second.
Hey. What's going on?
Great dancing tonight.
We just... we're big fans.
We wanted to say it was awesome.
- Thank you.
- All right, guys.
Time for you to go,
though, guys.
No, it's okay, Jeff.
Yeah, it's okay, Jeff.
We're just talking.
- Yeah.
- Always the little guys, huh?
Easy, tiger.
Excuse me? What did
you say to me?
What, do I fucking stutter?
- Hey. No, no, no.
- Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.
- We're fine here.
- It's all good. It's all good.
These guys are my friends.
It's okay.
These are your friends? You need
to pick some better friends.
They're fine.
You're sure
you're gonna be okay?
I'm fine. Thank you.
Go inside.
I'll stand near the door
until they go.
- All right.
- Wow.
- Very protective.
- Yeah, he is, huh?
Is that your boyfriend?
No, we've just had
some trouble with folks
hanging around after the show.
- Oh, I'm sorry. We were just...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We just wanted to say
you're a great dancer
- and we loved your stuff.
- Phenomenal. Yeah. Really good stuff.
Thanks, guys.
That's really nice.
What's going on tonight?
Where's the party?
I don't know.
I'm going to bed.
- Going to bed?
- Yeah. I'm tired.
- Really?
- I just got off work.
Listen, I don't go
to strip clubs that much, but...
and correct me if I'm wrong,
but did we have
a real connection
going on in there or what?
Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Uh... You're right.
See?
You don't go
to strip clubs much.
- Oh.
- Ohh!
- Wow.
- Cute, though.
Oh, she said you're cute.
- Where you going?
- I'm going home.
Why?
It's early.
I mean, that's...
he's a football player, okay,
but, like,
he's been there, right?
And he's saying,
"it's not what you think it is,
- and this is life," you know?
- Yeah, you can't get what you want.
- It's... that's how it is.
- No, but that's not what I'm saying.
I'm saying that, like, there's a beauty
that you can't get what you want.
- Right. Yeah.
- Right?
That's... but I don't think
we're seeing the beauty of it.
Do you know what I mean?
- No. I get it.
- You do?
Yeah.
Yes!
I'm just not sure you're...
I think
you're just being nice now.
♪ Alone on the water ♪
♪ alone in the clouds ♪
♪ alone through the clouds ♪
♪ alone in the water ♪
♪ alone on the ground ♪
♪ we were born to be alone,
everybody all alone ♪
♪ born alone to be alone,
we'll stand alone forever ♪
♪ standing on the world alone,
learning how to stand alone ♪
♪ and always to be alone,
we'll be alone forever ♪
♪ we were born to be alone,
everybody all alone ♪
♪ born alone to be alone,
we'll stand alone forever ♪
♪ standing on the world alone,
learning how to stand alone ♪
♪ and always to be alone,
we'll be alone forever ♪
♪ we were born to be alone,
everybody all alone ♪
♪ born alone to be alone,
we'll stand alone forever ♪
♪ standing on the world alone,
learning how to stand alone ♪
♪ and always to be alone,
we'll be alone forever ♪
♪ there's nothing left here
to worry about ♪
♪ we're on the ground ♪
♪ we're in the clouds ♪
♪ the world is spinning around ♪
♪ alone through the clouds ♪
♪ alone on the ground ♪
♪ alone on the water ♪
♪ alone in the clouds ♪
♪ everybody all alone ♪
♪ born alone to be alone,
we'll stand alone forever ♪
♪ standing on the world alone,
learning how to stand alone ♪
♪ and always to be alone,
we'll be alone forever ♪
♪ we were born to be alone,
everybody all alone ♪
♪ born alone to be alone,
we'll stand alone forever ♪
♪ standing on the world alone,
learning how to stand alone ♪
♪ and always to be alone,
we'll be alone forever ♪
♪ there's nothing left here
to worry about ♪
♪ we are on the ground ♪
♪ we are in the clouds ♪
- What?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- We get got her going.
It's all set up.
Man, come on.
No, I can't do it. I can't.
I got to get some air.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm awesome.
- Get back here.
- All right, I will.
♪ Alone in the clouds ♪
♪ alone through the clouds ♪
♪ alone in the water ♪
♪ alone on the ground ♪
- Hey.
How are you?
It's so beautiful here.
Yeah. Thanks. Yeah.
It's amazing.
Did you hear the geese?
I-I did hear...
oh!
You.
- So amazing.
- Thank you.
Well, it's... yeah,
it's night, nighttime.
So the geese
are probably sleeping.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to wake you up.
It's okay.
Were you sleeping
with the geese?
No, I was just...
I was like half asleep.
Oh, my God. I forgot
how beautiful it is.
Yeah. What were you doing
out there?
I was about to do a threesome
with a buddy of mine and some
coke-infested stripper.
It was crazy.
It was really insane.
Why would you leave?
I know.
- It sounds good, right?
- Yeah.
That guy freaks me out!
What is that?
Is that your dad?
I told you that's a photograph
of my dad my mom took.
Oh, my God. Thank God
I didn't do that.
Thank God I didn't do that.
I just wanted to come here.
You're like the oasis
in the desert for me.
- Me?
- You look really pretty.
How did you wake up so pretty?
You're really funny.
How do you do it?
- Seriously.
- Jon, look at me.
What?
All right,
I'm a little fucked up.
You are a little fucked up.
- Yeah.
- It's okay, though.
Where are your hands?
They're in...
in sleeves.
- There they are.
- Those are nice hands.
Thank you.
Sounds like
you had a fun night.
No.
It wasn't fun.
It was a little fun
but not a lot of fun.
This is more fun.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
This is such a soft sweater.
Thanks.
Really soft.
- Feel free to...
- Can I just...
Jon, just...
yeah.
I'm gonna let you
go back to bed in a second.
- I just...
- You are?
- Yeah.
- Um...
I'm just gonna stay
right here for a minute.
- Okay.
- It's a beautiful sweater.
- Thank you.
- And you're beautiful.
And the geese
are really beautiful.
You're so cute.
You're like the wild geese...
And the stars and your snow...
And the ocean...
The ocean circling downward...
Finding the call
of the geese...
Swimming, flying,
daring into nothingness...
Until the breath of trees
stirs them...
...until they're gone.
That's not my best work,
but, you know...
Look at me.
...I could give it
a little time to...
you're gonna be good.
- You're great.
- Thank you.
And I really like that poem.
You are such a good liar.
I'm not lying.
You know I'm not a fisherman.
What is this,
the writing business?
Yeah, it is the writing.
Yeah. So, what are you
gonna do for money?
How you gonna live?
- I got some money saved.
- Yeah?
I got to give it a shot now,
you know?
- It's now or never.
- Yeah?
Well, you help me
get a replacement,
and then you go go
write "Moby-dick," all right?
- That sounds fair.
- Yeah?
Jonny Melville, huh?
Yeah. Right.
♪ Extraordinary on my soul ♪
♪ I mean, it's very necessary ♪
♪ whoa, Nelly, whoa ♪
♪ I'm so ready ♪
♪ I'm so steady ♪
♪ drop so heavy ♪
♪ bout to flood the hood
like I broke the levee ♪
♪ now my wiggity won't stop
till I'm on top ♪
♪ when it's all said and done ♪
♪ I will be number one ♪
♪ you'll see ♪
♪ you'll remember my name ♪
- It was fun last night.
- Mm-hmm.
You working tonight?
All right, well, maybe we'll
stop by and check you out.
Good.
All right.
Have a good day.
Oh. Oh.
Hey, ma.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Come in. Come in.
Where's your stuff?
Uh, this is it.
This is all I got.
Oh. Okay.
- It's good.
- Mm.
It's really good, ma.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I miss...
I miss your quahogs.
Well, you're in luck...
Hmm?
...because I made a bunch
for tomorrow.
I'll give you some
to take back.
Lorraine is, you know,
organizing everything,
and I felt it's not
really my place to,
you know, get in her way.
- Not really your place?
- Mnh-mnh.
You were married to him, too.
I know, but... They had
the three girls, you know?
They're all doing a lot
to help out, so...
And you're okay with that?
I am.
Yeah, they're letting me
have the reception here,
so that's good.
They're letting you?
Wow, that's really nice
of them.
They're letting you.
That's unbelievable.
I wish you'd got to see him.
Yeah.
I've been busy.
I just... I couldn't
get back, you know?
What are you gonna do?
He loved you.
He did.
Why didn't you tell me?
He had a whole other life
with a whole other family,
and here you are.
You're still sticking up
for him.
I have to go find out
from other people, you know?
I had to... I mean, I wish
you were there that day.
Oh, please.
I don't know.
I don't want to do this
with you.
I don't want to
fucking do this with you.
This is why... this is why
I didn't want to come back.
This is why
I stay away from you.
This is why I stay away
from this fucking house
and this fucking town
and this...
Why wouldn't you tell me, mom?
I have to hear about it
from my fucking friends?
Why?
Because I didn't want to put
you through what I went through.
You were so little.
Cara!
- Cara!
- Yeah?
Are you ready?
We got to go!
I'm coming!
Your mom's coming
in like 10 minutes!
- Okay!
- Yo, what's up with Jon?
He's not picking up the phone.
Yeah, he's...
he's in therapy
till 7:00.
What?
He's been going to a fucking
shrink like two months.
Really?
What's wrong with him?
I don't know what the fuck
is wrong with him.
He's feeling it?
He's got a lot
of feelings inside of him.
He's feeling all of it,
getting all of it at once.
- Give me.
- You're a dad.
Fucking weird.
You like being a dad?
Yeah, I like being a dad.
I mean, I hate parts
of being a dad,
but mostly, I like being a dad.
You better get fucked up
tonight.
- You gonna get fucked up?
- Dad, I can't find my other shoe.
I'm gonna
get fucked up tonight.
You do not need
to worry about me.
You don't need
to worry about shoes.
I'm gonna find shoes.
Say hi.
I'm gonna find your shoe!
Hi, Cara.
What do you got there?
- Giraffe.
- Giraffe? Can I see?
Wow.
What's his name?
Or is it a her or...
what is it?
- Gemmy.
- Gemmy?
What's up, Gemmy?
You guys partying
up there or what?
- No.
- No?
What do you got
going on tonight?
Going to my mom's house.
That's got to be cool, right?
- Yeah.
- What are you guys doing?
Play games.
Do people tell you
you look like your mom a lot?
I don't know.
- Cara!
- I'm coming.
Hey.
Do you have
your stuff with the...
- yes.
- Okay.
So, were you upset that
he didn't tell you about it?
No.
No?
No. I mean, I wasn't upset
that he didn't tell me about it.
I guess I'm just, like,
a little thrown.
Yeah?
'Cause it kind of changes
my whole idea of, like,
what we all were to each other,
like we were these brothers
or something, you know,
which just isn't true, so...
- Yeah.
- That's fine.
That's just the way it is.
People are out for themselves.
Mm-hmm.
It's like I'm still trying
to hang on to this... Thing
that, like, just never existed
to begin with.
- Mm. Mm-hmm.
- Sam?
Hey, I'm telling you...
tie your shoe.
Cara?
Are you ready to go?
- We'll be right down.
- Kate.
Hi.
- How you doing?
- I'm okay.
- How are you?
- How do I look?
Hey.
I'm really sorry
to hear about your dad.
How you holding up?
Good.
You look good.
I don't look good.
I look tired.
- Your eyes got bigger.
- Let me see. Let me see you.
You look exactly the same.
- I do?
- Yep.
I got grays in here.
Yeah.
It suits you.
So...
What's going on with you?
You know I got married again.
Yeah, I heard.
Jon told me.
Yeah?
What'd he tell you?
Uh, he told me that the guy
has a Walker? Is that...
you're such an asshole.
- Yeah, I heard that.
- Did you do that?
You get married?
No, no kids, no marriage.
I don't believe in that
institution, I don't think.
I had this... I was living
with this girl, but it didn't...
- Work out?
- Not the one.
What are you looking at me
like that for?
I'm just looking at you.
Come on.
Don't do that.
- What?
- Don't do that.
- Don't do what?
I wanted to keep in touch
with you.
I just thought, um, that you
didn't want to keep in touch.
I was just trying
to leave you alone, so...
It's not that I didn't want
to keep in touch.
I didn't know
where to find you, Davey.
Yeah, I didn't know
where to find me,
and I still don't know
where to find me.
Put on...
put on your...
You look good.
When's the service
for your dad?
Uh, Friday.
You gonna do it
at St. Bart's?
That's what they say,
yeah, St. Bart's.
- What time?
- Oh, don't... don't come.
It's gonna be quick.
That's nice of you, but...
that's good. It's...
it would really mean a lot to me
if I could be there.
Well, then we'll see you there.
Mom!
That's me.
Yes, sweetheart?
Where's your jacket?
Dad's got it.
- Hey.
Turn around.
There we go.
Here's this.
Uh, it's art things,
and then there's drawings, too.
They're a little bit unruly.
No, they're not.
Yeah. Well,
they're like rolled up...
- it's like a poster-sized thing.
- Okay. Go get it.
It's like butcher paper
or something.
What do you mean,
it's in a scroll?
I don't know. It's like a...
what's-her-name's class.
- Oh, miss Gibbs.
- Miss Gibbs' class.
Yes, miss Gibbs and her
unorthodox art projects.
- She's fucking weird.
- Do you still design?
- Do you still do that stuff?
- Yeah.
Oh, you got to see her stuff.
It's amazing.
She's still doing amazing stuff.
She's got her own place now.
- Sam.
- Oh, good for you. That's great.
He's really
over-selling it.
Yeah, it's like a shop
on route 6.
- It's amazing.
- It's really... it's not all that great, but thank you.
- Thanks.
- I think it's good.
So, uh, what are you guys
doing tonight?
Uh, we are gonna see if
the caplog will still let us in.
- Caplog? Wow.
- Yeah. You want to come?
You should come with us.
- No.
- What?
- No, I am not coming.
- Why not?
'Cause I've got,
you know, plans.
- You too good for us?
- Not too good for you.
I just have other plans.
She's good. The...
the old man she's got.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
No. You have plans.
He's not an old man.
He's 47 years old.
No, you got to plan out
his meals.
- It's really not that funny.
- You got to make sure
that everything
is chewable, soft, soft.
- Change his diapers.
- You guys are awful.
- Cara!
- Chew foods for him.
- Shut up!
- Do you put diaper cream on his...
- be quiet.
- How many teeth are still good?
Hey, sweetheart.
Come on.
- Where's your backpack?
- I'll get it.
See you at the service.
It's, uh... I think, like,
if someone will get it,
then, like,
I can stop talking about it.
Yeah. Mm.
But it's like... it's not that
I'm obsessed with tom Brady.
It's just like...
you know,
because he was the quarterback
like me, and he was the...
you know, that was the guy
you wanted to be or whatever.
And not that I'm gonna be
tom Brady, but...
Well, why don't you
just try to be you?
I love how you always say that.
But it's true.
I know.
But I don't even know what
that even means, like, being me.
I feel like I've been trying
to be other people for so long
that I wouldn't even know
how to be me.
You could try being you
right here.
Right in this moment.
That doesn't feel good.
It doesn't have to.
It's whatever it is.
No, I just...
I don't want to do that.
- What else have you got?
- I don't know.
I just...
I don't want to do that.
I want something else,
you know?
- Like what?
- I don't know.
- Anything, anything else.
- Such as...?
Like, anything besides this.
It just doesn't feel...
it doesn't feel right, you know?
- I'm just sick of it.
- Yeah.
I'm sick of all the bullshit,
all the fucking bullshit,
just trying to let go...
"I'm trying to find myself."
You know? Why do I have to
be that guy, you know?
I don't want to
be him anymore, all right?
Like, I'm fucking sick of it.
I don't want to be him anymore!
I'm sorry.
I'm just...
Stupid.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm... I'm sorry.
I'm ridiculous.
I just
feel ridiculous right now.
There's nothing
to be sorry about.
That's how
you were feeling just now.
Hey, Jonny,
you finally get
the ass of a lifetime?
Jonny!
How you feeling?
Do you enjoy any of the
new things that you...
Yeah. No. I enjoy everything.
I enjoy it all.
Jonny!
You got some feelings up there!
- Talking it out?
- Jon, is your therapist okay? Is she hot?
I think that's my ride.
I think it's about time,
anyhow.
Oh, there he is.
Oh, yeah, tell him.
Coming.
Hi, Jonny.
Unbelievable.
You guys are unbelievable.
- You feel better?
- Yeah. That's great.
- Is everything better?
- Yeah, everything's better.
Did she tuck you in tonight?
- Get the fuck away from me.
- Here you go.
- This will make you happy.
- Jesus Christ.
You sure you don't
want one, Sammy?
No. I'll have one
in like four minutes.
Can we please get away
from my therapist's office?
Promise me you'll get
fucked up tonight.
- It's left. Go left.
- Go left?
- Go left. No, left. Left.
- Go left. Go...?
Left. No. Straight,
straight, straight.
Hey, Tommy, is this is Shehee
in this picture here?
Oh, yeah. Yep.
He's still around.
Mark Shehee?
- Yeah. Look at this.
- Really?
He's still fucking ugly.
- Oh, my God!
- Right?
He looks like
he's 10 years old.
It's like a fucking
time machine in here.
Is he around anymore?
He's still here.
He's kicking around.
I haven't seen in maybe like
a year, but... He's around.
He works at the drugstore.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, sir.
- All set, guys.
- I got this. I got this.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- All right, here's to you, man.
- Great to see you.
- Good to see you guys.
Fuckers.
- Whoo!
- Ohh!
Ugh.
♪ Wait for me, babe ♪
♪ no, it's gonna take... ♪
Oh!
Fucking come on.
That's all right, Sammy.
I'm sorry.
- You sorry?
- Get the fuck off me.
We're gonna go 11 out of 20.
It was a good game.
It was...
yeah, it was a great game.
You had a great game.
Also, go fuck yourself.
It's on, Sammy.
- Good-looking shot.
- Can you...
have you not won enough
without fucking hitting my hand?
What are you talking about?
- What does that mean?
- Oh, no!
- What'd you hear?
- I remember...
I was just saying
I liked it rough.
- Oh!
- I like it rough.
It wasn't me.
It was not me.
- I like to pull hair.
- Yeah, yeah.
- You started it?
- No.
- My goodness, no.
- "My goodness."
Look at this hair, this fucking
red hair... beautiful.
Yeah.
He likes redheads.
Wow. Does he?
Yeah. It's this little thing
that he has.
Oh, I thought I was special.
No, no, no, you are special.
You're the most special redhead
I've ever seen.
- Yeah.
- Whatever.
I had a friend...
Who was on a date with a guy...
Who she didn't like at all.
And he went
to kiss her good night
and he pulled her hair
and asked her if she wanted
to take a shower.
- And because...
- Are you serious?
Yeah. Because he pulled her
hair, she said okay.
That's great.
Wait. What?
- It was about the hair-pulling.
- Really?
Yeah, I've been with
a bunch of girls
that like their hair pulled.
- That was her thing.
- She liked it.
- Is that, like, a thing?
- I've never heard, but she liked it.
Do you need another drink?
Write that down.
- Yeah.
"Must pull hair."
But I think that
if you did that 100 times,
- 99 times it would work.
- Right there.
Ready? Sammy?
Beautiful, baby.
Here we go.
For you.
♪ And I'm going on ♪
♪ no time to lose ♪
- To Sammy.
Sammy.
It just went bang.
Hey!
What'd you say?
Sorry.
She's a very lovely young lady.
- Let's get out of here.
- Yeah, we should.
Where we going?
Great plan.
What?
What's the plan?
Grab your coats.
Tommy, we're out of here.
We all paid up?
- Yep, all paid up.
- You'll love it. It's a surprise. It's gonna be great.
- Okay, guys.
- Tommy.
- See you soon.
- See you later.
Hey. Be safe.
Night, guys.
Hey, man, it was nice
to see you again.
Ugh! Goddamn it.
Where's my coat? Oh.
It's warmer inside.
I promise.
That's it. That's it.
After you, Sammy.
- Wah!
- Go inside.
Just go inside.
Go inside.
It's warm.
Whose is it?
Is this your boat?
No, it's not mine.
It's my boss' boat.
I mean, it was kind of awful.
He... they... we switched
all of their license plates.
Just to...
are we moving right now?
No, we're drifting.
We're anchored.
Sammy, you dancing down there?!
Party!
What the fuck are they doing?
I don't know what the fuck
they're doing.
What the fuck is anybody...
- Sammy!
- Yeah?
- You want to dance?
- I'm... I'm good.
Thanks, Davey.
I'm good.
You want me to come up?
- No, I don't.
- No. Are you okay?
- What's that?
- Is she okay?
She's perfect.
What are you doing up there?!
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
Let's remember...
Yep.
Well...
♪ You're gone ♪
♪ you're gone ♪
♪ oh ♪
Sorry.
- She does like him.
- Yeah.
How long have you known Sammy?
How did that happen?
I missed that.
No, no, I saw that coming.
- You saw that happening?
- I saw that happening.
It was... it was...
it was beautiful.
Okay.
Hold on. Hold on.
Wait.
Mnh. Mnh.
- Wait. Ah.
- Oh.
I'm... I...
Did you... did you...?
Um... Sorry about that.
No, it's fine.
It's, um, like...
Sorry about that.
Hey, it's...
it's okay.
Been a little while for me.
Hey... It's...
it's okay.
It's fine.
You all right?
Yeah. What happened
with the girl?
She's cute, right?
Yeah.
She's good for you.
Like her?
I...
What's tomorrow night?
This town, man...
I got to...
It's beautiful from far away.
Are you pissed at me?
Pissed at you?
Sometimes.
I-I know you're pissed at me
about... about Kate.
I just can't believe
you never told me that.
I shouldn't have told you
'cause I...
no. I mean, why didn't you
tell me when it happened?
I was trying
to protect you, man.
I didn't want to
get you involved, so, I mean...
I shouldn't have told you that.
You've been giving me
fucking an attitude
ever since I told it to you.
Well, what do you expect?
You fucking dropped a bomb on me
that you fucked Kate?
It's like...
Okay.
Well, deal with it.
Like it's nothing.
Like, you said it like
it was fucking nothing.
I didn't say it like
it was nothing.
That's how I heard it.
- Like it was nothing?
- Yeah.
Well, fuck you, Jon.
It's something to me, okay?
- Yeah?
- It's none of your fucking business.
Yeah, it is
my fucking business.
Do you ever
think about another person?
You think about what your
fucking actions do to people?
'Cause I got out of here,
you're fucking mad at me?
- That has nothing to do with it.
- Get out, then. Get out.
- Why does it always...
- Go work on a fucking fishing boat.
Why does it come back to that?
I don't want to get out.
- It's not my fucking fault.
- Maybe I don't want to get out.
Why do you assume everybody
wants to get out like you?
Everyone wants to
fucking run away?
I get it.
I'm sorry I'm not a...
I don't go to therapy, okay?
I'm sorry.
Is that
what I'm saying right now?
I don't know
what you're saying.
Why don't you fucking listen
for once in your life?
You're so much better than me.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. 'Cause you meditate.
'Cause I don't
dick my friends over
and fucking hightail it
out of town.
I take responsibility
for my fucking life.
I don't just
leave a fucking trail
and run away
from my whole fucking life.
You want to go upstairs
and tell him?
- You want to go?
- No, it doesn't matter.
You fucking did it.
Why should I tell him?
Fuck you.
Sure you're gonna go on
to greener pastures, you know?
You're gonna
leave that situation
and you're gonna go
and you're gonna
find someone else quickly,
but, you know,
first you have to wait for...
for some of that situation
to burn off,
and then you go out and...
you know, responsibilities.
I've got Cara, and I...
Eventually,
I think you just forget
that you even want someone.
I don't know.
And you haven't met anybody?
No.
But if you might
consider sometime
maybe going out
to a... Restaurant...
...or perhaps
to a movie house.
Movie house?
A... a cinema.
I don't know.
I would... Love that.
- What?
- This is gonna sound crazy,
but are you seeing
anybody else right now?
- No, I'm not.
- You're not. Okay.
- I'm not.
- All right.
I just... I've been obsessing
about the whole open thing,
and I just...
it popped into my mind.
I don't know why.
No, it...
it makes total sense
that would pop into your mind.
Okay. I just
wanted to check.
I'm fine.
- I like you.
- I like you, too.
A reading from
the first letter of St. John...
"beloved, we receive of him
whatever we ask
"because we keep
his commandments
"and do what pleases him.
"And his commandment is this...
"that we should believe in the
name of his son, Jesus Christ,
"and love one another
just as he created us.
"Those who keep his commandments
remain in him and he in them.
"And the way we know
that he remains in us
"is from the spirit he gave us.
"Beloved,
do not trust every spirit,
"but test spirits to see
whether they belong to God
"because many false prophets
have gone out into the world.
She's a very nice girl,
and I'm glad that it happened.
You've said it
like seven times.
I... fuck you.
She's a bartender.
- No, honestly, I'm happy for you.
- Thank you. I think...
I've never seen you
glow like this.
I'm not fucking glowing.
I'm sweating.
- I'm not glowing.
- There's a difference?
- And she's a bartender.
- Hey.
Hi.
- How are you?
- I'm good. How are you?
Good.
She is a bartender, isn't she?
Yeah, in Wareham,
and she bartends on Wednesdays,
- and we'll go and...
- What's the name of the place?
It's called Moriarty's.
Hi.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah, I just...
I'm just tired.
Thanks for coming.
Oh.
Yeah, I wouldn't have, um,
I wouldn't have missed it.
I think I had a little bit
too much to drink downstairs.
That's good.
What were you drinking?
- Bourbon.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Good.
How much longer you gonna stay?
Tomorrow.
I got to get back.
Tomorrow? God.
Yeah.
It's been really good
to see you, Davey.
Yeah, it's great to see you.
You know...
There's so much
I want to say to you.
You know?
But I, um...
'Cause I was really mad at you.
I'm gonna go.
Hey, wait a minute.
No, no, I really don't want...
I don't want to. Please...
hold on a second.
I left because I thought it was
right for everybody, okay?
I think about you all time.
I never stopped.
Yeah, I think
it's been a long day.
Sounds like he's sacked out.
It was nice to see you, though.
Very nice to see you, too.
- Yeah. Take care.
- Okay. You, too.
- Thank you.
- All right. Yeah.
Hey.
I'll see you
in the morning, all right?
Okay.
- Hey, man.
- What's up, man?
How you doing?
Thanks for coming, all right?
Yeah, of course, of course.
Look, I'm sorry about
all that shit last night.
No, no, don't worry about it.
- That was fucked up.
- It's my fault.
No.
Look at this guy.
I know. Right?
I think he's tired out
from last night.
Did he get laid?
- Yeah, he did.
- That's fantastic.
It's great, right?
It's good for him.
He needs it.
Ugh. Fuck.
So, you psyched
to get out of this snow
and get back to
the warm weather or what?
No, it's not that bad.
Where'd you go last night?
I just went to Angela's.
Everything cool?
Yeah. Fine.
There he is.
Ah.
- It's Davey's last night.
- That's right.
It is.
We got to put
our fucking rally caps on.
- Get out of here.
- I love you, Sammy.
I love you.
- Jonny?
- We're gonna do it.
What, we're gonna
fucking not see this guy
- for 10 more years and...
- No, you'll see me.
- It's true.
- You'll see me.
Where we going?
I happen to know
a bartender in Wareham.
Why, what's Wareham?
That's his girl
from last night.
Oh, I heard about that.
- Yeah.
- Congratulations.
It's the end of the world's
longest dry spell.
- It's not, uh...
- How do you feel?
I feel better.
I'm not, uh...
he's like 25 pounds lighter.
Jesus Christ.
♪ It's not when it rains hard ♪
♪ it's when it rains long ♪
♪ and the shadows of the drops ♪
♪ upon the windshield
fleck the dawn ♪
♪ it's not when it rains hard ♪
♪ it's when it rains slow ♪
♪ and tires set off spinning ♪
♪ over yellow lines below ♪
♪ it's not when it rains hard ♪
♪ it's when there's nothing
but the rain ♪
♪ and all the lights
make it difficult ♪
♪ to just explain away
♪ I've been damned and redeemed,
damned and redeemed ♪
♪ there's a logic to love ♪
♪ but it's not one
that I've ever seen ♪
♪ but what I have seen? ♪
♪ I've been damned
and redeemed ♪
♪ and wan and alone ♪
♪ there's a logic to love ♪
♪ but it's not one
that I've ever known ♪
♪ but what do I know? ♪
♪ it's not how it rains hard ♪
♪ it's how the rain
won't ever leave ♪
♪ still,
she's making for the doorway ♪
♪ clutching car keys ♪
♪ it's not how it rains hard ♪
♪ it's how she didn't stay ♪
♪ as the rivers
rose to wash us ♪
♪ but then carried her away ♪
♪ it's not when it rains hard ♪
♪ it's when the rain got her ♪
♪ and shadows of the drops upon
the windshield fleck my shirt ♪
♪ I've been damned and redeemed
and damned and redeemed ♪
♪ I would love to be able to say
what it was that I mean ♪
♪ but what does it mean? ♪
♪ I've been damned
and redeemed ♪
♪ and loved and unloved ♪
♪ there's a logic to life, but
it's not one that I'm aware of ♪
♪ it's rain from above ♪