[wind whistling]
[crickets chirping]
[birds calling]
[♪]
[horse snorts]
[barking]
[snorts]
[barks]
[barking]
[geese honking]
[people chattering]
[cattle lowing]
[radio playing light rock music]
[laughing]
Hurry up.
Put it in the back.
Lift the bloody thing, man.
You wanna go work
with the women?
[man 1 laughs]
Man 2:
Yeah. Heh-heh.
[horn honking]
[♪]
[radio clicks]
Man [on radio]:
The violence
has continued unabated.
Vigilante factions have
taken law into their own hands.
The government
is asking for restraint.
That's the end
of the news headlines.
Our next bulletin
will be at 8 p.M.
[people chattering]
[snorts, whinnies]
[grunts]
[snorts]
How is he?
Oh,
not good.
[snorts]
He's not gonna make it.
You sort it out.
And, uh,
when you've finished,
Can you park the landie
at the tree there by the house?
Okay.
[snorts weakly]
[horse neighs, snorts]
[♪]
Man:
They say that the condition
For a great miracle
is impossibility.
But nothing on earth could
help me keep my farm in zambia.
[cattle low]
But I was left with no choice.
The war, the lack of education
for our children
And an uncertain future
for white farmers
Has left me with no option.
[birds chirping]
[boy mimicking truck engine]
Man:
Well, then I'd rather
sell the farm.
They're getting worse
in the bush war in zimbabwe.
I can't believe...
We're even considering this.
We belong here.
We built this place up.
We'll start again together.
We'll find
another farm somewhere
Where the kids can go to school
from home.
I'm not sending my kids
to a boarding school in zambia.
[dishes clatter]
The farmers in south africa
seem to be doing well.
[board creaks]
[mimicking tractor sounds]
God will give us a farm.
[people chattering]
And the stuff for the bank?
Yeah, well, they're as sorted
as they'll ever be in zambia.
We're gonna have to smuggle in
some dollars.
Is that wise?
[horn honks]
Angus, is that wise?
Yeah, well,
we have to do it.
[horn honks, brakes screech]
Bloody idiot, man,
look where you're going!
[people shouting]
Angus, don't. Stop it.
[insects buzzing]
Stupid man. Now we really
have to leave zambia, and quick.
[♪]
Boy:
Dad, what other things
can we take?
Anything we can fit in.
Put it in the back.
[workers chattering]
We got such a bad price
for this farm.
But at least we've got
each other and the kids.
I'll make it work.
I know you will.
[workers speaking
in foreign language]
[♪]
[woman speaking
in foreign language]
Woman:
We'll miss you.
[♪]
[bird chirping]
Well, we can't afford
a sugar-cane farm
Or anything fancy,
But, um,
welcome to our new home.
What are we gonna
farm here?
Uh, beans and maize, cattle.
And water?
What about water?
[objects clattering]
Where's our house?
Our house has wheels on it.
We're like gypsies now.
Gypsies in the garden of eden.
It's gonna stand right here.
Angus:
What are we gonna call
our new home?
"shalom."
Angus:
Shalom?
Why shalom?
It means "peace."
[♪]
Peace.
[bird chirping]
[insects buzzing]
[tractor rumbling]
[shovel clanging]
Oh, no, man.
Come on, man.
I said the stump,
not the bloody rope, man.
You bloody idiot, man!
Come on, man,
have you got no brains?
Hamba, man.
Get off my farm.
[in foreign language]
Angus:
I need men with brains.
With some sense
in their heads.
[worker mutters]
Bloody idiot.
Was that necessary?
He just wanted to help.
Angus:
I didn't like the look of him.
These zulus
are a devious bunch.
I don't understand
what they're saying.
We need the help.
If the right men come along,
I'll knock some sense into them.
In the meantime,
I'll do everything myself.
[water splashes]
I'll build this place up alone.
I can do it if I have to.
I don't need anybody.
Love, be sensible.
No, jill.
I'll make this work my way,
like I've done before.
Jill: Andy, come now.
Andrew: Don't forget to take
The bucket for the water, mom.
Come, let's go to the car.
[speaks zulu]
[men grunting]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[speaks zulu]
[men grunting]
[grunting]
I'll get you out,
you cursed stump.
[grunting]
[grunts]
[insects buzzing,
birds chirping]
Jill:
The kids seem to be happy
in their new school.
[radio playing]
And there's a polocrosse club
in the neighborhood.
You should go
and meet some people.
Man [on radio]:
--Stating that there would be
suspicious characters around.
In fact, these are the police
That are being sent
to patrol the area.
Another white farmer was shot
and killed at the weekend
Near greytown
in the natal midlands.
The farmhouse was ransacked,
And the farmer's wife
and children
And two of the farmer's workers
Were assaulted and tied up.
This is the second attack
on farmers...
I don't know if we did
the right thing.
Maybe we should just
move to town.
I can sell tractors
or something.
People get robbed
and hijacked in towns
In this country too, love.
We'll pray that god
protects us.
You pray.
Why should god listen to me?
Announcer:
That was another uprising...
[radio clicks off]
[birds singing]
[water splashes]
Uh...
[speaks zulu]
Do you speak english?
Fanagalo?
[speaks zulu]
Well,
can you drive one of those?
[♪]
Angus:
Then what can you do, man?
[people chattering]
[horses whinny distantly]
[children chattering]
Hi there.
I'm koos smit.
Welcome to greytown.
Name's buchan, angus buchan.
Do you play?
Yeah, I've played before.
Well, you can practice with us,
but, uh, don't get hurt.
I-I mean, I don't want your wife
on my back.
Heh. 'cause we like to play
rough, us policemen.
And, uh, the farmers,
they really give it stick.
But if you wanna play, there's
some gear in the clubhouse.
And jonah will sort you out
with a pony.
See you.
Hey, boet, it's not too late
to change your mind, all right?
It's okay.
If you don't have the guts
to play with us,
Go play bowls
with the old people in town.
[chuckles]
[horse snorts]
[people chattering]
[horse whinnying]
Referee:
Horses on up.
[whistle blows]
Pawn.
[horses whinny]
[woman shouting]
[snorting]
[players chattering]
Hiya.
[horses snorting]
[whistles]
[whinnies]
[players chattering]
[horses whinny]
[spectators cheer]
[grunts]
Player:
Right towards you.
[indistinct chatter]
[horses snort, whinny]
[players shouting]
Player:
Come on. Go.
Ha.
[radio playing light rock music]
[children chattering]
[man laughing]
The green mamba.
[laughing]
[radio playing light rock music]
Hey, angus.
You, my boet,
have five seconds flat.
Starting now. Five--
Both:
Five, four, three, two--
Four, three, two, one, zero.
One.
[ice rattles]
koos: Hey-hey.
Not bad
for an englishman.
Hey, I'm a scotsman.
[koos mutters]
Welcome to greytown, boet.
Meet percy hawkins,
a sugar-cane farmer.
Hello, angus.
Let me give you
some good advice, old boy.
You're gonna need eyes
in the back of your head
At dixon's old farm.
You probably heard the news
that our zulus
Are a treacherous bunch.
I'd watch my back
if I were you.
Hey, you've heard the news.
It's a bloody war out there.
Gotta have good firepower.
I carry mine every day.
Don't take any nonsense
from these natives, old boy.
You've gotta show them
who's boss, simple as that.
They respect that.
It's bloody,
absolutely bloody.
That's the way it's done,
though.
It's no different in zambia.
[ax chopping]
[angus grunting]
[panting]
[speaks zulu]
What's that?
No, man, slower, man.
Slower.
I know very little zulu.
Uh...
[speaks zulu]
I think he wants us
to build a house.
He's madder
than I thought.
[speaks zulu]
Hi. I'm steyn.
You must be angus and jill. Hi.
Ja, we heard you guys
moved in, hey.
I'm the farm manager
just here across the river.
Oh, it's good to meet you,
steyn.
Do you speak zulu?
I only know a few words.
Ja, I can speak zulu.
I think he wants us
to build a house, but, uh...
Can you tell him that we've
gotta do other work today?
When I've got more money
after the first crop
Then I'll get a proper builder
to do it.
Hm.
[speaks zulu]
Uh-- uh-- um, angus, you know,
these guys, I've seen them.
They build their own huts
within a week.
They use natural materials.
They're very skilled at this.
He says
That, um,
if you help him,
He could build you a nice place
within three weeks.
Okay. Tell him
I'll think about it tonight.
But today
we're gotta clear more wattle
To make room for planting.
Come, steyn,
come join us for some coffee.
Steyn [sighs]:
Boet.
There you go.
[speaks zulu]
[man speaks zulu]
Uh...
[speaks zulu]
Isaiah [in zulu]:
Let me help you, nkosana.
Simeon says there is
much to do on the farm.
Do you drive a tractor?
[chuckles]
Yes, nkosana,
I can drive a tractor.
Okay, come and help me inside.
Simeon [in zulu]:
[chuckling]
[speaks zulu]
[chuckles]
[both chuckle]
[♪]
[angus grunts]
[grunts]
Today we're gonna finish this.
And tomorrow, we'll try and get
a contract for seed maize,
For cattle, and we can start--
Angus, take a break.
[grunts]
Love,
we've done so much already.
We've found water,
we've found land.
We've built,
or nearly built a house.
Just take a break.
[chuckles]
What do you think
you're doing, eh?
[jill chattering]
[chuckles]
[all chattering]
[laughs]
[chuckles]
[sighs]
Angus:
Well, you lot,
welcome to the buchan mansion.
[♪]
[andrew making tractor noises]
[tractor noises continue]
[baby crying]
[chuckles]
My beautiful little nephew.
Joanne, it's great
to have you and fergus here.
It's really good for angus to
have his brother around, really.
And apart from polocrosse,
he just works.
The farm attacks
don't help either.
And you know what he's like
when his blood's up.
[laughs]
Ladies, the water's ready.
Jill:
He needs help, joanne.
He needs help.
He's strung out like a tight
guitar string all the time.
And I'm just waiting
for the snap.
All I can do is love him.
A friend of fergus'
was in the same way,
And the doctor put him
on some tranquilizers.
But it has helped.
The pills detach you
from your problems.
Maybe angus needs a little help
for a while,
Just to get him through.
Why don't you plant potatoes?
They say
there's good money in it.
Steyn:
Hey, man, planting potatoes
is a very expensive exercise.
Aside from getting
the seed potatoes,
You need about a ton
of fertilizer per hectare.
With mealies, you put down
less than half as much.
What,
3, 400 kilos, eh?
It's something like that,
but that's not what bothers me.
It's the-- it's the water
and the spray program.
It's expensive,
and we don't have the water.
Fergus:
What for, blight?
Steyn:
Exactly, man.
The spray is about 6000 rand.
Angus:
Ja, something like that, 6000.
Sorry. Let me get
that for you, jilly.
Angus:
But nobody plants potatoes here
Unless they've got
a lot of water.
'cause if you don't
get enough rain,
Well, you can kiss
your farm goodbye.
Jill:
Who wanted the black coffee?
Right here, jilly.
Chickens.
Thanks.
Broiler chickens.
Now, that's the future.
Ja, people love chicken.
Alistair, look here.
Alistair.
Ja, that's right.
[camera whirs]
That's it.
Auntie angus,
please can you come and play?
[angus chuckles]
We'll play later, okay?
I'm just having some coffee now.
Alistair calls me
auntie angus.
[chuckles]
[vehicle approaching]
[brakes screech]
Angus:
Hey. What's wrong?
[speaks zulu]
Uh...
If there's a puncture,
you run out of diesel.
Angus [in zulu]:
Ah...
[speaks zulu]
Well, show me.
[birds chirping]
[vehicle approaching]
[engine shuts off]
What the heck happened here?
No. No, no, no, man!
What happened here?
What have you done, man? Huh?
[speaks zulu]
Simeon, I expressly said
you don't drive this tractor!
How many times
must I tell you?
How am I supposed
to farm with this?
You're supposed to be my induna!
You'd better run!
I'm gonna kill you!
Never come back!
[footsteps receding]
[speaks zulu]
Come back.
[breathing heavily, sniffs]
I'll think of something.
We'll fix this.
How am I supposed
to farm with this?
[♪]
Huh? Bloody idiots! Huh?
I'm gonna kill you!
[♪]
Angus:
You have to help me every night.
[speaks zulu]
We have to do this ourselves.
You have to help me
Fix what you've broken.
[speaks zulu]
You're right.
[light rock music playing
over speakers]
[chair rattles]
Shoot, man.
[laughing]
Sorry, koos.
I'm falling apart.
What you need, boet,
is a shot of whiskey,
A beserol and your bed.
[hand thumps]
[sighs]
Oh, koos, it's hectic.
[sniffs]
I've never been
like this before.
I work every day.
Eighteen hours a day
on most days.
I'm stressed.
I, uh...
[object clatters]
[sighs]
I feel ready for the funny farm.
I make those pit bosses
on the farm
Work just as hard as I do.
You know what amazes me?
They keep up to my pace.
[lighter flicks]
My induna, simeon.
[lighter thunks]
what a beauty.
That's one tough zulu there.
When last
did you have a holiday?
What is that?
Jill's even got me
some tranquilizers.
And are you gonna take them?
I don't know, man.
[sniffs]
Those things
are for fruitcakes.
I'm a pussycat.
[scoffs]
but I'm not a bloody fruitcake.
Well, if it isn't
mandela's little policeman
And the manic zambian in
a conversation about psychiatry.
[children chattering]
Is your john deere
fixed yet, buchy?
Get lost, percy.
Mm. I would've beaten the life
out of those idiots,
And fired them.
They won't respect you now.
Ag, bull, percy.
Keeping the peace is the best
security for our farmers.
I mean, you know what happened
to engelbrecht
A couple of months ago.
The man had two kids
with a zulu worker.
Wouldn't have anything
to do with them.
And on top of that,
he refused to pay lobola.
Mm-mm.
Let me tell you something,
percy.
If there's one nation
that knows how to retaliate,
It's the zulus.
These guys have been fighting
blood feuds for generations.
And if they can kill
each other today
For cattle that was supposedly
stolen over a hundred years ago,
What chance do you have?
No, boet.
Respect the law, but above all,
respect the people.
[scoffs]
and I thought you afrikaner cops
knew better than that.
Let me tell you something,
koos,
And you'd better
listen carefully.
The most dangerous job
in the world
Is being a farmer
in south africa.
You know,
I read in the farmer's weekly
That more than 1600 farmers
had been murdered
In 8000 farm attacks.
One thousand, six hundred.
And some of those
were my friends.
So that is what
your so-called freedom brings...
[coughs]
[vomiting]
Those were my favorite pants,
you twit.
So if that is what
your so-called freedom brings,
You'd better recognize
the place and times.
Not me, boykie. I'm not
going down without a fight.
Jill:
We're doing okay here, love.
One or two big crops,
and we'll pay off our debts.
Now, stop it, jill.
I'm sorry.
It feels like I'm getting
nowhere. I'm trying my best.
But it's just work, work, work,
and I can't stop, jill.
I hate it.
I know, angus,
But it's hard on me too.
But it feels like
everything's on my shoulders.
I can't go on like this.
I want my husband back.
Just take the pills.
Just do something.
Okay, I'll try them.
I'll take these stupid pills.
This is how you want
your husband back?
With his head full of pills?
Maybe I should go and smoke some
dagga with the zulus in town.
[baby crying]
Please come back.
[door closes]
Jill:
Come on.
Come, andy. Come, boy.
Come, come.
Have a good day.
Have you got everything?
Come. Cheers, andy.
Don't forget your homework.
Okay.
Okay, come.
Jill, how's it going
at the farm?
Uh, hi, dawn. Well, thanks.
Um, things are well.
Thank you.
And how's angus doing?
Oh, you know. Um...
He's okay.
Uh, we're-- yes.
We're good, we're okay.
Do you have time
for a cup of tea?
It's difficult.
It's very difficult.
It's-- it's a lot of stress.
And, uh, angus,
I-I worry about him.
The pressure's just, you know--
it's...
[sighs]
I thought tranquilizers
would help, but they...
And I wanna help, but, uh,
We've lost touch.
We just...
The local methodist church
is having
A missions breakfast
on Saturday.
It's a lot of fun.
Why don't you guys come along
and meet a few new friends?
[thunder rumbles]
[gunshot]
[whinnying]
[insects buzzing]
[footsteps]
[panting]
Got you, fat hog.
You've been eating my corn
for far too long.
Where's my horse?
Out now.
Wait for us in the car.
Andrew: And we're so late.
Girl: Can we eat there, daddy?
Jill:
Daddy will be done now.
I'm not wearing this stupid tie.
I look bloody ridiculous, man.
You look fine, love.
Come, let me help you.
You know what?
I'm not going.
You take the kids.
I'm staying.
I'm not going
without you, angus.
Please.
You go.
I'm not the type for church.
You don't have to wear
the stupid tie. Go without one.
Please come.
I'm staying, jill.
[baby crying]
Angus, please. We need this.
Angus:
Jill, just stop hassling me
about the tie.
You're lucky I've come
to the stupid meeting.
Jill:
Angus.
Don't hush me.
Come on.
[claps]
Want me to bring the carry cot?
No, love.
Angus:
Come, boy. Let's go.
[people chattering]
[inaudible dialogue]
[man whistling]
[crowd applauds]
[inaudible dialogue]
Speaker:
Right, thank you, everybody.
Good morning.
Beautiful day today,
isn't it?
I'd like to start off
reading psalm 100.
Why don't you come
to church tomorrow?
The local farmers
are gonna be speaking.
Speaker:
Make a joyful shout to the lord,
all ye lands.
Serve the lord with gladness.
Come before his presence
with singing.
Know that, the lord, he is god.
Know that it is he who has
made us, and that we...
[loud ticking]
[bird calling]
[whispers]
jill, there's no space.
Come on, let's go.
There's no space.
Jill, not
the front row.
Man:
That's when I put my hand
in front of my mouth.
I didn't want them to smell
my breath, you know,
Because, uh, I was
a little bit drunk.
[crowd chuckling]
But then the gentle guy asked:
"what about--?
What about you?"
[♪]
I was cut to the heart.
My life was a mess.
I had nowhere to go to.
I had no interest in religion.
My heart cried out for reality.
Hey, angus.
Psst, psst. Come here.
Hey, angus. Psst.
Good evening,
Ladies and gentlemen, kids.
Thanks for coming
to tonight's show.
When you watch
a show like that,
It just shows us
there's an emptiness
In the hearts of all people.
An emptiness...
That nothing
but the lord himself can fill.
For god so loved the world...
That he gave his only son,
So that whoever--
And that means whoever.
--Believes in him
Will not die,
But will have everlasting life.
And no one can deny the reality
of the testimony of jesus christ
In these men's lives.
Ordinary farmer folk
from this district,
If you want that relationship
with jesus christ,
You can have it right now.
Like these guys, you can
invite jesus into your life,
And we invite you now
to come forward.
Receive jesus christ today
and let him change your life.
Come forward.
[♪]
Give your life to jesus.
Let him change you.
Give him an opportunity.
That's right.
You'll never be
the same again.
[♪]
[church bell tolling]
Angus:
My dad is a scotsman.
He moved from aberdeenshire
To zambia and then
he started farming there.
And like him, I'm a little bit
stubborn and crazy. Heh.
Like the scotsmen
gave it to the english,
Lifting their kilts and shouting
obscenities in battle. Heh.
It's in my blood
and I feel it.
Now, some people think
I'm a wild farmer,
But I'm proud of my roots,
And I'm still gonna
go to scotland.
Yeah.
Hey, I'm a scottish-african.
Talk about a crazy combination.
Heh-heh-heh. Angus.
Well, god loves wild men who
are excited about him, angus.
He put that wildness in you.
He put that wildness in you
because he loves you.
He loves you.
He's crazy about you.
It makes me think of david,
dancing naked before the lord.
Actually, not naked.
He was in his jocks.
I'm...
And I wanna give you something.
I've got a little bible
around here.
Or paul and the disciples.
They turned villages around.
The world upside down,
it says in the bible.
Crazy men.
But holy.
You know I, um...
I have this urgency in me.
I feel it in my heart now.
I really wanna know god.
And I-I wanna know why he--
why he knows me, and, uh...
I don't know, what can I do?
Is there something I can do?
That's god's spirit in you.
Tell you what.
You tell the first three friends
you see today what you did.
Tell them
you gave your life to jesus.
Now, that's a challenge.
[exhales]
[chuckles]
They'll think I'm a nutter.
Just do it.
This is a little bible
somebody gave me
A long, long time ago.
You'll like it.
Man:
Cheerio, I just have to go
to the bank to draw some money
But I'll be coming back
this afternoon.
Hey, angus. Angus.
What's up, boet?
You look like
death warmed up.
What's wrong?
You haven't been taking
those happy pills have you?
No, uh, koos, there's, um,
something I gotta tell you.
Well, you're in luck.
Koos is off duty.
I'll buy the drinks,
you do the talking, okay?
Hey, buchy,
don't look so dang serious, man.
You look like the springboks
just lost against the all blacks
Or even worse,
against the english.
Okay, boet, shoot.
I made a decision yesterday,
Uh, to give my whole life,
my family and my farm to jesus.
[chokes]
Bliksem, buchy.
You almost had me there
for a second or two.
You shouldn't joke
about these things.
No, koos, really,
I'm being serious.
It's like god just
took me by the throat
And shook me until I listened.
You're not gonna turn all weird
on me now, are you?
[speaks dutch]
Another one bites the dust.
[laughs]
[♪]
[speaks zulu]
[both laughing]
Simeon [in zulu]:
[men yelling]
[speaks zulu]
[both laughing]
[fire roaring, crackling]
[♪]
No. Hey.
[speaks zulu]
[all shouting]
Jill. Jill.
Call the farmers.
We need help.
We've got a runaway fire.
[♪]
[people yelling]
[all shouting]
[grunting]
[screaming]
Angus, are you okay? Angus?
I'm burnt. Argh.
Listen up. I've got
to go back into town, man.
Let me get the doctor.
No, we've gotta
put the fire out first.
Okay. Where can I help?
Start here.
The lion match plantation.
They'll sue me.
Get it, get it out.
[shouts]
Simeon!
Simeon.
[speaks zulu]
[coughs]
[indistinct chatter]
You can stay there.
[grunting]
Angus:
What things soever you desire,
When you pray, believe
that you shall receive them,
And you shall have them.
What things soever you desire,
when you pray,
Believe that
you shall receive them,
And you shall have them.
Simeon.
[speaks zulu]
[♪]
Jesus. God, please.
[grunts]
[♪]
[muttering]
[thunder rumbles]
[thunder crashes]
Simeon.
Angus [in zulu]:
[all cheering]
[speaks zulu]
[laughs, cheers]
[laughs]
[♪]
[birds squawking]
How do I do this, lord?
How do I speak to people?
[sighs]
[♪]
Tell them what's in my heart?
What you've done?
You make me lie down
in green pastures.
You still my soul.
Reverend:
Angus?
Angus.
Rev.
Hey.
How are you?
Great.
And you?
Nice to see you. Good.
Well, welcome to my church.
Impressive.
It's my green cathedral.
God spoke to me
in there.
He said,
"just trust me."
And I've seen some miracles.
I know. I heard.
Heh-heh.
The fire breaks.
Yeah.
That's great.
I gotta tell people,
reverend.
Something's changed in my heart.
I've changed.
[chuckles]
Surely, there's gotta be
people out there just like me.
Like I used to be.
Hmm.
Despairing.
Working their heads off
every day.
For what?
Yeah.
You're right.
And another thing,
when I was in there was--
It just struck me
that god used ordinary people.
Everyday people.
I mean, doctors,
farmers like me.
Mm-hm.
Incredible.
Those who dared to follow jesus
and believe that he was god.
Yeah.
Believed that he could
heal the sick and...
[sighs]
...Fix broken hearts
And brought messed up families
back together again.
Yeah.
That's real faith.
And that's what I want.
What you doing?
[♪]
What are you doing?
Seventeen November.
I believe this day
is very significant.
I believe god called you.
Remember this date.
Seventeen November.
[♪]
[indistinct chatter]
Bongani, be careful,
he's smaller than you.
We'll bring the musicians
and the singers
And anything else
as necessary.
All I need is for
the local ministers and pastors
To tell their people to come.
I wanna tell them my story.
I've booked the town hall
for a week.
A week? Really?
Well, come if you want to,
but as far as I'm concerned,
The town has been
over-evangelized.
They've heard it all before.
Over-evangelized?
But if there's one person--
The people of ladysmith
Are just like the rocks
and the thorn trees.
Hard and dry.
You will get nowhere
with them.
[bell tolling]
Lord, do you really
want me to do this?
Man:
With absolute pleasure.
No, not at all. You know where
to get hold of me.
A-anytime.
Okay. Okay, bye-bye now.
Sorry about that, mr. Buchan.
So all you need is some help
from the-- the local church?
Angus:
Yes.
Well, let me tell you
a little story, mr. Buchan.
Three months ago, two of
south africa's great evangelists
Came here to hold a top-notch,
bells and whistles campaign.
Thirty-nine people arrived,
mr. Buchan.
Eighteen of them
were from my church.
It was an exercise in futility,
preaching to the choir.
Tell me, mr. Buchan,
who are your great evangelists
That you've booked?
I am. Uh, in fact,
I'm the only speaker.
[scoffs]
yeah.
Well, brother...
Maybe the lord
has brought you here.
To bend you a little.
[thunder rumbles]
They look good on the outside,
But inside they're a bunch of
dead men's bones.
I couldn't believe my ears.
Andrew, finish your food.
There's many churches
in ladysmith.
You would think
they would have--
They just sound
so cold and religious.
[grunts]
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
John called earlier.
John-o?
How's my brother-in-law?
Oh, he says he's fine.
[thunder crashes]
That was close, eh?
Can you go check
how fergus is doing?
Oh, you know, he sounds fine.
He said he'd, um,
help with the posters
And he'll immortalize you
on videotape.
At least that's some good news.
[phone rings]
Come, honey, I asked you
to look on fergus.
Come, bedtime.
Angus:
Angus buchan.
Oh, brian.
Thanks for calling back.
Okay.
[chuckles]
That sounds fantastic, great.
Okay. Bye-bye now.
Jill, some great news.
That was a pastor brian jubber.
I left a note under
his office door this afternoon.
He says they've been asking
for the lord to send someone.
They wanna help us
and they are so enthusiastic.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
[woman yelling]
[thunder crashes]
[shouting]
Angus [in zulu]:
[speaks zulu]
[♪]
[indistinct chatter]
Angus [in zulu]:
Woman [in zulu]:
[speaks indistinctly]
Woman 1 [in zulu]:
Woman 2 [in zulu]:
[thunder crashes]
Woman 3 [in zulu]:
Oh, god. Lord jesus.
Lord jesus, help me.
[women chatter indistinctly]
God, I don't know what to do.
Oh, god.
[♪]
Bring healing to her body, lord.
In the name of jesus, stand up.
[thunder crashes]
[gasps]
[woman shouting]
[♪]
[speaks zulu]
[thunder crashes]
[indistinct chatter]
[thunder rumbles]
[speaks zulu]
Stand up, stand up, mama.
Do you understand?
Angus [in zulu]:
[♪]
[indistinct chatter]
[speaks zulu]
Just like
when we had the fire.
[speaks zulu]
That won't be necessary,
simeon.
[speaks zulu]
[women chattering]
Oh, lord, please let me speak
to them simply.
Let the words
you put in my heart come out.
Please, lord, speak through me.
[distant singing]
[singing]
♪ jesus, you're all I need ♪
[distant singing]
Oh, lord, don't embarrass me.
Don't embarrass me.
♪ jesus, you're all I need ♪
[music playing, singing]
[crowd chattering]
Thank you, lord.
[softly]
thank you, lord.
Angus:
No matter what you're facing,
God can turn your situation
around like that.
[angus snaps finger]
I was speaking
to a friend of mine
Who had marital
and financial problems.
I was telling him, "trust god.
Just trust god.
He's in control of everything."
And then suddenly
out of nowhere,
This violent hailstorm came
And destroyed my entire crop
of maize.
Razed it to the ground.
The whole crop was gone.
My livelihood,
in a few seconds, gone.
What do you do?
[camera humming]
Angus:
But you know what? I--
I decided to put my hope in god.
I decided to trust him.
I-I didn't want to.
To be honest with you,
I really didn't want to.
But I decided
to trust god completely.
And you know what?
Three days later...
Just three days...
And the entire crop just picked
itself up off the ground.
I was amazed.
Look, it had a permanent
bend in it but...
[all laugh]
...Praise god.
At the end of that year,
We had a bumper crop
of seed mealies.
I wanna challenge you.
If god can pick up a crop
of broken maize,
How much more can he not pick up
Your precious broken heart?
Your broken life?
When god's creation's broken,
He's more than able to fix it.
So come on, what about you?
Let god pick up
your broken life today.
[crickets chirping]
Hey, john.
Angus.
[sighs]
How about you?
Yes.
[♪]
Dear lord,
Thank you for john's life
And for what he has meant
to our family.
Thank you for his heart.
I pray that you make him
To amend
what is not meant to be.
I pray that you protect him
And that you lift him up.
[♪]
[birds chirp]
Man [on radio]:
In the southern part
of the country,
Farmers say it's the worst
drought in a decade.
Agricultural unions
have asked the government
To declare
the kwazulu-natal midlands
And other regions
a disaster area.
Many farmers are facing ruin.
[music plays on radio]
Jill:
Would you like some more juice?
Yeah, thanks.
Girl:
Me too. Me too.
I'll have some, mommy.
Please, can I have some?
Man [on radio]:
On the weather front,
The weather bureau
said in a statement
That the effects of el niño
Will probably continue
indefinitely.
The region's heading
for the worst drought
In living memory.
Farmers are losing farms
at an unprecedented rate,
And this could cause
a severe blow
To the gross domestic product.
And that is the end
of the news.
Angus:
People are making way too much
of this el niño thing.
Angus,
I forgot to tell you,
Um, there were two calls
for you this morning.
One from a pastor in scotland.
He says he looks forward
to meeting you tomorrow.
And a call asking you
to come preach.
Maybe--
[giggles]
Maybe we could get someone--
[laughs]
Maybe we should get somebody
to manage the farm and--
I was thinking maybe we should
even consider selling it.
There we go.
Come on, fergus,
finish your milk.
I'll farm for you, daddy.
Angus:
In time, son, in good time.
I'll also farm for you, daddy.
Me too, me too.
Angus: Whoa. Whoa.
Jilly, maybe we should
get a bigger farm.
That's right,
we can all farm for daddy
While he preaches
all over the country.
And all over africa.
And zambia, and tanzania.
All the way to cairo.
[grunts]
[speaks zulu]
Simeon, you're my induna.
And, ah...
[speaks zulu]
[chuckles]
[twigs crunch]
[wood creaks]
[twigs crunching]
[floor creaks]
[speaks zulu]
Ah.
[bird hoots]
[speaks zulu]
[both laughing]
Okay.
Yeah.
Mama.
[speaks zulu]
Oh, hey.
I...
[speaks zulu]
[chuckles]
Nilale kalhe, my friend.
[speaks zulu]
Are you sure about the tie?
Aye.
You do know
I'm ridiculously fond of you?
[crickets chirping]
[angus clears throat]
Hey, hey, hey, you lot.
I'm a crazy scotsman,
and I'm not a crazy italian.
I speak the doric
of the werenvolk
Of buchan county.
[all laughing]
what?
Have you never seen a kilt?
Crowd: No.
A man in a skirt?
Well, I'll tell you what.
This is what real men wear.
Oh.
This is what they used to wear
in scotland all the time.
[exhales]
The sporran.
[speaks zulu]
[crowd laughs]
angus: Hey, hey, hey.
[speaks zulu]
[angus laughs]
Somebody gave me
this one as a--
As a gift
when I was in scotland.
It's, ah, made
of the buchan tartan,
Which is my clan's colors.
And it means
the same to me as...
When you put on your--
your zulu tribal clothing.
Woman:
Ohh.
[woman speaks zulu]
[speaks zulu]
It's the most beautiful
place I've ever seen.
And the people's hearts are
so warm. They're so friendly.
I've taken some slides.
Light 'em up, john-o.
Oh, that's me on the bridge.
Standing near my father's
family home in aberdeenshire.
Do the next one.
Aha.
The memorial
to william wallace.
He was a great
scottish warrior.
And that is him.
William wallace
defeated the english
In the north of England.
He's a fantastic warrior.
And, of course,
Angus buchan...
[all laughing]
...A warrior from africa,
In the middle of scotland.
Simeon [in zulu]:
[all chuckle]
[speaks zulu]
I've asked myself that question.
I've even prayed about it.
And you know what
I finally understood?
I'm an african.
[speaks zulu]
[♪]
My heritage is scottish,
and I'm proud of that.
And always will be.
Just like you're proud
of being a zulu.
[speaks zulu]
There are lots
of problems between--
Between black and white people.
I know.
And we all know how difficult
it is in this country.
But I really hope
with all my heart
That when you see me,
You see an african brother.
You see a christian brother.
[speaks zulu]
[birds cawing]
[mooing]
Simeon [in zulu]:
Hey, you honor me
that you call me ubaba now.
[speaks zulu]
[moos]
Gidli.
[chuckles]
[speaks zulu]
Simeon [in zulu]:
[cattle lowing]
[children laughing]
Jill:
They brought in two more kids
this morning.
Angus:
Aids orphans?
Jill:
No, not these two.
Their mother died
of hepatitis b.
We now have almost 20
little ones to look after.
We'll need to build them
a bigger house.
Well, god has looked after us,
So we can look after others.
This morning
in the green cathedral,
He asked me three questions.
What did he say to you?
Are you prepared
to be a fool for me?
[laughs]
That must have been
an easy question to answer.
Yes, and it won't be
a new experience for me.
And the second question?
Thandiwe.
Am I prepared
for people to badmouth me
And persecute me
because of his name?
Are you?
Yeah,
I'm prepared for that.
But then he asked me:
"are you willing to spend
less time with your family?"
Well?
[sighs]
I said, "I'll drink
from that cup."
God help me.
I don't know, angus.
Is that really
what he wants, hey?
I don't know how we'll manage
with you away so often.
Are you a farmer or a preacher?
[fire crackling]
Thanks.
I know how hard
it is for you
To be away from us
when you're preaching.
And I really didn't want
to sound negative about it.
But we miss you.
I miss you.
[♪]
I miss your arms around me.
Whenever you see
the southern cross,
You can think of me
and know this:
My heart is with you.
And I love you
more than life itself.
[♪]
[apple splashes]
Oh, this wretched el niño.
It's a disaster.
The worst drought in years.
I'm telling you,
some farmers are gonna go down.
Peter and jimmy
are also losing their farms.
What are we gonna do?
What can a man do?
You can't plant in dust.
[mooing]
simeon: Aye, aye, aye.
[shouts in zulu]
Hey.
You know, I'm convinced
that god wants me
To organize
a big prayer meeting.
Get all the farmers together.
We must pray about the violence
and droughts and everything
'cause, you know,
th-the problem is,
Every farmer
thinks he's on his own.
Well, feels like
he's on his own.
And I wanna get them together
and we're gonna pray.
And I've spoken
to simeon and isaiah.
And they said they'll speak
to farm workers in the area,
And we'll get everyone
together and we'll--
We're gonna pray.
[speaks zulu]
Reverend:
You know how difficult it is
To get a bunch of christians
together
From different denominations?
Let alone being
black and white and indian.
Hmm.
Getting it together
will be a miracle.
Ah, you can have my church
If you wanna get people
together.
Your church is about, what,
300 people now?
I wanna go bigger.
Well--
Come on.
--The town hall
is about 700.
Why don't you take that?
No, I wanna go bigger.
How big?
[door opens]
Woman:
Mr. Buchan.
Mr. Buchan, allen kruger.
Good to meet you, allen.
Have a seat.
Thanks.
How can I help you?
I, uh, would like to hire
king's park stadium.
Yeah? What for?
We wanna get the farmers
and their workers together
For a peace gathering.
To pray about the violence
and the murders.
And of course this drought
we're facing.
Yeah,
it sounds very interesting
But I'm not sure you've got
the right place for that.
No, this--
this is the right place.
Do you know how expensive
it is to hire the stadium?
Yeah, I've got some idea.
Let me put it into
perspective for you.
When guys like michael jackson,
and international rock stars--
Ah, they pay millions
for this stadium.
We've got the b-field
down the road here
Where the players practice.
Shouldn't we sort you out there?
No, allen, we gotta have
king's park stadium.
Give me a few weeks,
I'll get back to you.
[cheering, horns blowing]
[gasps]
this is big.
Coming at you.
Get it.
No ball.
[angus chuckles]
Good one.
[all shouting]
catch it.
Angus:
How dare we laze in front of
Our television sets--
Carol, grab the buns.
And criticize the government
and laws of land
And we ourselves do nothing?
I'm tired of the church
not being relevant.
That's why we're having this
meeting at king's park.
Don't get so serious, love.
It's my birthday.
Fergus.
Fergus: Yeah?
Will you please stop
your brother?
You know what he's like
when he gets started.
[chuckles]
that will be the day.
Fat chance.
The reverend buchan
has mounted the pulpit
And the sermon's
just started. Ha-ha-ha.
[scoffs]
I'll get something to drink.
I'll help.
Fergus:
Quickly, alistair, come back.
There you go.
[fergus chuckles]
Alistair:
I missed the ball.
You know, angus,
someone once said:
"it's not the violence
of the few that scares me
As much as
the silence of many."
[laughs]
oooh.
Angus:
That's right, sis.
If we don't get off
our fat backsides
And do something and stop
complaining, who's going to?
You know, god says,
If my people
are called by my name,
Will humble themselves
and pray,
Seek my face and turn
from their wicked ways,
I'll hear from heaven--
Hear from heaven, forgive
their sins, heal their land.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Now, fergus,
that's a promise from god.
That's it.
Girl:
Get the ball, quickly, robyn.
[simeon shouts]
[sighs]
Let me sort this out.
Fergus: Come on, guys.
Simeon.
[speaks zulu]
Simeon [in zulu]:
Alistair:
Where you going, auntie angus?
Angus:
The tractor's stuck
in the field, my boy.
We have to pull
it out with another tractor.
Can I go with auntie angus?
Angus:
No, you're gonna have
to ask your dad.
Daddy, can I go with her?
Okay, alistair.
I'll see you later, son.
Kirstie:
Daddy, can I go too?
Sure, my dear.
Alistair.
Angus:
Okay, here we go.
[tractor revs]
Here we go.
Whoo-hoo.
Steyn:
Who's got the ball?
Can I go too, daddy?
I'm gonna go and see
if I can help them.
Okay.
Angus and kirstie:
♪ old macdonald had a farm
♪ e-I-e-I-o
♪ happy, happy, happy
happy song ♪
happy, happy, happy ♪
♪ happy, happy, happy
happy, happy song ♪
[both laugh]
Auntie angus, are we going
to fix the tractor?
The tractor is stuck and we have
to pull it out, alistair.
Where's the tractor,
uncle angus?
It's in the field, kirstie.
[alistair screams, angus shouts]
[♪]
Simeon.
Oh, my god.
[kristie screaming]
Angus:
Take kirstie. Take her home.
Kristie: Alistair!
Alistair.
Kristie:
Alistair. Alistair!
[♪]
Help. No.
[breathing]
[chokes]
[screams, sobs]
[panting]
[chokes, gags]
[sobs, screams]
Steyn.
Steyn. Steyn.
Steyn:
Help.
We need help, somebody.
Where's the doctor?
Come. Come. Come.
[sobbing]
What happened?
We had
a tractor accident.
Mr. Angus,
just wait here.
Jesus. God, please.
Jesus, let him live.
God, jesus, please.
God. God, please.
Please, just let him live.
Please.
[softly]
please, god.
[♪]
I'm sorry. It's too late.
No.
[sobbing]
Angus.
My son.
[sobbing]
I'm so--
I'm sorry, fergie. I'm sorry.
My son.
I'm sorry.
[both sobbing]
Woman:
Fergus. Fergus.
[all sobbing]
I'm sorry.
[♪]
[sobbing]
It's not your fault.
It was an accident.
Daddy, please
don't blame yourself.
All this guilt
and the shame and--
Just pushes up at my gut
like vomit.
It's just...
I can't keep it down.
And I think...
...I'm not supposed
to be angry.
It's life.
But I am angry.
[sobs]
I get so angry
And I miss him.
[sobbing]
I loved that boy.
It's not your fault,
angus.
I miss him.
It's not your fault,
angus.
I'm really sorry
to hear about
What happened with angus
and that little boy.
Thank you,
it's very kind of you.
It really must have
been terrible.
It's um--
Did angus pray
for the little boy?
He's such a man
of faith.
You know, god could have
raised him from the dead.
Think what a glorious testimony
that would've been.
Hi, sorry I'm late.
It's okay,
I just got here myself.
What's the matter, dear?
What's wrong?
[sobbing]
He's supposed to be
the one.
[sniffs]
People are so cruel
And so insensitive.
I'm sorry, joanne,
I'm here to comfort you.
That's okay.
What happened?
Thanks.
Someone said
a thoughtless thing.
How's fergus doing?
And the kids?
Oh, how can you
bear it?
[sighs]
It's been difficult.
And fergus
is really struggling.
Who can understand this?
[both sobbing]
Woman:
Good morning.
Hi. Can I get you
anything to drink?
Um, two teas,
please.
Two teas.
Would you like to see
the menu?
No, thanks.
How's angus?
[sniffs]
Reverend:
Are you gonna have yours?
No.
You got a firearm?
I have a shotgun.
I shoot vermin.
Give it to me.
Why?
Just give it to me
for a while.
I'll be okay.
I won't do anything stupid.
[sighs]
[insects buzzing]
[angus grunting]
[♪]
[laughing]
Daddy!
[laughs]
My son.
Alistair?
[dog barks]
[phone ringing]
[clears throat]
Angus buchan.
Fergus:
Angus.
I've seen him.
Uh, fergie, is that you?
I saw him, angus.
Uh, what are you
talking about?
I saw alistair, angus.
He was running
In the green veld.
And I spoke to him, boet.
I asked him
If he wanted to come back.
And he said, "no, daddy.
I'm waiting for you."
[sighs]
Thank you.
[shouting indistinctly]
[speaks zulu]
[♪]
[all speaking in zulu]
[speaks zulu]
[shouting in zulu]
[laughing]
[sighs]
[phone rings]
Hello?
Allen, hi.
It's angus buchan speaking.
Angus. Thank you for phoning.
You won't believe it.
I lost your number
And I couldn't remember
your surname.
Hey, how are you doing?
Oh, fine, fine, it's just--
Uh, it's just so dry out here.
We-- we're just holding out.
Yeah, I know the farmers
are struggling.
Well, that's why we wanna get
The farmer's together
and just pray for rain,
Against the violence and--
Well, I've got
good news for you.
You've got the stadium.
Wow, allen,
that's fantastic.
I can't let you have it
For nothing, but we'll do
what we can to help.
Great.
We'll speak again soon.
Okay, allen, thanks again.
Bye-bye.
Yes.
Jill:
You got the stadium.
We got it.
Can you believe it?
Yes.
[laughing]
[all quacking]
Simeon [in zulu]:
Angus:
I'm sure you guys are starting
to get the drift,
I'm sick and tired
of the drought
And the violence and stuff.
So that's why we're having
this king's park gathering.
You know what, when I read
my agricultural handbook...
Then, uh--
then I know what we gotta do
Is we gotta have
a peace gathering.
And that's what I'm trying
to organize at king's park.
[♪]
To heck with el niño.
Put your trust in god.
Not in a weather phenomenon.
Put your trust in the creator
of heaven and earth.
Not in a promise
of a drought from hell.
That's where
el niño comes from
And that's
where it belongs.
That's why I say
trust god.
Trust god.
Don't be gripped by the fear
of what el niño can do to you,
But be gripped
by what god did for you
Through jesus on the cross.
And I know that god
answers the prayers
Of his people.
And that's why,
This year at this time,
We're going back
And we're gonna
plant potatoes.
And you farmers know
what that means.
[speaks zulu]
[laughs]
Angus:
Let's ask god
for a breakthrough.
That was my idea.
Angus:
I know he will do it.
Potatoes in the middle
of a drought.
That's impossible.
Heh.
Oh, lord...
...Hear our prayer.
God, give us the rain we need.
Deliver us from the violence
and the murders, god.
Bring peace
in our land, lord.
And bring peace
in our hearts.
Shower this land, lord,
with your blessing.
It's so dry
and so thirsty, god.
Bring your blessing, lord.
God says:
"that if my people
who call by my name
"will humble themselves
and pray...
"...Seek his face and turn
from their wicked ways,
"that he will hear
from heaven.
"he'll forgive their sins.
And he will heal their land."
He will heal our land.
[♪]
Well, you've been such an
inspiration to all of us, angus.
I just don't
want you to make
A stupid mistake, I--
You know,
there's a very fine line
Between faith
and foolishness.
I don't want you to--
I don't think
you should plant potatoes.
What do you think, steyn?
Mm. I don't know.
But angus has been right
so many times before.
There's one other
possibility.
We could just wait a few days
until it rains.
I mean,
look at the field.
Look at the dust.
Nothing can grow
in this.
If you plant the potatoes now,
they're gonna die and that's it.
You know that.
If god spoke to you,
I mean,
I'd be the last one who would
wanna go against that, I hope.
I just don't know.
Did he speak to you?
I just--
When I prayed,
I just felt god say to me:
"don't look
at the weather phenomenons
And the weather conditions."
But I needed
to trust him.
And then I read a scripture
In ecclesiastes and it said:
"those who observe the wind
will not sow.
And he who regards the clouds
will not reap."
Will not reap, yeah.
Angus,
sorry.
The bank manager
is on the line.
[sighs]
I just hope he doesn't burn
his fingers, you know?
Harry? How are you?
Harry:
Angus, I'm concerned.
About what?
I see you've placed
a massive order
For seed, potatoes
and fertilizer.
That's right. That's right.
And no one else
is planting this year.
The scientists are saying
it won't rain.
Your farm is on the line.
I don't want to see
you and your family go down.
Look, thanks for your concern.
It-- it really touches me.
But I'm going ahead.
Angus, if this crop fails,
you're finished.
[chuckles]
When this crop comes through,
I'm gonna own the farm,
not the bank.
So, uh, thanks for your concern
and, uh, just relax.
I'll speak to you later.
Angus, I--
cheers.
Sorry about that, gents.
Steyn:
Angus.
I still think
it's gonna be impossible
Planting those potatoes.
You know what?
The condition for a miracle
is difficulty.
But for a great miracle,
it's impossibility.
Come on,
let's go and prepare the land.
Didn't mean to make it sound
like I'm doubting you.
Ah, don't worry.
[speaks zulu]
[♪]
[all singing]
Angus:
We haven't had proper rain
in weeks.
Soil's dry.
Plants seem to be dying.
We're on our knees,
reverend.
To make matters worse,
People are running
from everywhere
Wanting to know how it's going
with the potatoes.
They should have been
formed by now.
What?
You mean,
you haven't even had a look?
No, when--
when we're ready,
We'll harvest
and see whatever's there.
[chuckles]
they are stuck away.
How do you know
there's even anything here?
Look at this.
No, it's not like maize.
Maize you can see.
But potatoes...
You gotta have faith.
Simeon [in zulu]:
[speaks zulu]
We'll have to wait
till tomorrow.
[speaks zulu]
And then get ready
for a long day's work.
[♪]
Gidli, my friend,
just before we get started
I just wanna tell you
how much I appreciate you.
What you've done
for me and my family.
I don't think
we would've been here
If it wasn't
for you.
And, uh, I know you love
this land as much as I do.
I really
appreciate you.
Come, let's pray.
[sighs]
God,
Thank you for this harvest
And thank you
for giving us the land.
We don't know
what's in this ground,
But we pray
that you'll bless it.
Amen.
[♪]
[chuckles]
[gasping]
[speaks zulu]
[both laughing]
Yes!
[speaks zulu]
Yes.
[shouting in zulu]
[speaks zulu]
Yes!
[tractor approaching]
[♪]
[laughs]
Did you not think
I'd have faith
in these potatoes?
[laughing]
Koos:
Hey, buchy,
Got to show us your potatoes.
Wait till you see them.
Heita, simeon.
Big potatoes here.
Potatoes.
[laughing]
Angus:
Hey, jabulani,
Feel this potato.
[sniffs]
Smell it.
Your faith in god
must be like that.
It must be real.
You can feel it.
You can smell it.
Your faith
has gotta be like--
It's gotta
be like potatoes.
[all laughing]
[joe niemand's
"a new day" playing]
♪ this could be
♪ my last day
♪ I am ready
♪ come what may
♪ you are love
♪ you have given me
♪ a new day
♪ you saw me in
♪ hard land
♪ and dared me not
♪ to grow
♪ I wonder why
♪ and underground
♪ when no one else
♪ could see
♪ you turned
♪ my shallow grave
♪ into a cradle of life
♪ in the dust
♪ in the dark
♪ you put colors
♪ inside of me
♪ this could be
♪ my last day
♪ I am ready
♪ come what may
♪ you are love
♪ you have given me
♪ a new day
♪ my last day
♪ I am ready
♪ come what may
♪ you are love
♪ you have given me
♪ a new day
[♪]