Subtitles by DramaFever
My hardworking kiddo... Looks like
I made you cry. I'm sorry.
Episode 9
Seo Yoon!
I... just got a call from the hospital.
Father... is in critical condition.
Sung Jae, call Won Jae.
I'll head out first.
Seven years ago... when you
had your brain surgery...
I prayed all night
that your surgery would be successful...
that you'd live longer.
I wasn't ready for it...
what if you'd just leave...
I was worried.
But... now it's okay for you to leave.
Thank you for your gift...
the shares of Sung Jin Cement.
Won Jae will flee overseas.
Do you remember?
You made my husband's brother
run away overseas.
Be careful. The vase might fall.
If Jung Yoon becomes empty-handed,
greedy Dong Hui will divorce her.
My husband's sister got a divorce
after Chung Ma Construction fell apart.
Then she suffered from alcoholism
and died a few years after.
Don't touch... Seo Yoon.
Thanks to you, his brother went
to prison for five years.
Don't worry.
Since Seo Yoon is still young, she can
endure a few years in prison.
Don't blame me.
I'm just reciprocating exactly what
you did to my husband.
For a such a suspicious man...
how did you get so completely fooled?
Sung Jae... I taught him since he was little.
I taught him to like your favorite dishes.
Prepare the pickles that he likes, too.
Sung Jae is not the only one who likes it.
Even our favorite dishes are the same.
Your habits, your practices...
I taught him every day again and again.
Don't take after my personality,
your mom will be worried.
I told him to say only the things you like
and I told him not to go against your wishes.
I'll stop horseback riding.
Aren't you proud of my Sung Jae?
What to do...
The man who used to move
the world with one hand...
can't even move it any more.
He was the same way, too.
He collapsed in front of the door...
He used to be healthy, but he was in bed
for a week then he left this world.
Don't leave yet!
I still have things to say.
I'm sending you off from this life...
and my husband will come pick
you up from the after-life.
Tell him for me...
that I've never once forgotten about him
for the last 27 years.
I've always been the wife of Bae Young Han
and I will live as Bae Young Han's wife
in the future as well.
Farewell.
Dad.
Your mom...
Dad...
Don't worry about Mom, Dad.
Your mom...
Yes, I will take good care of Mom.
I'll take care of her, Dad.
Dad.
I love you, Dad.
Dong Sung, we started this to eat sweet
potatoes to our heart's content.
Father, just say one thing to me.
'My son Choi Won Jae, you worked hard,
well done, I'm proud of you!'
Just anything.
Dad!
Dad... I love you, Dad.
The incense burning ritual will be set up
in the lobby of the headquarters.
And we also set up the incense altar in
72 Sung Jin plants and offices in the country.
Check the condolence visit schedule of senior
secretaries and ministers in the Blue House.
Yes, ma'am.
But Choi Won Jae's close friends, who were
pushed out to other regions and countries
after you became Vice Chairman,
are gathering now.
Some executives in the department
stores are also supporting Jung Yoon.
And President Choi Min Jae will
start to make his move.
At this rate, Managing Director Choi
Won Jae will lead the funeral
since he's the first son.
The press release, the procession of the funeral,
the decision on the burial site...
leading the meeting of the presidents
to help with the funeral...
For the next five days of the funeral period
Managing Director Choi Won Jae will be
at the center of all the Group's functions.
For Dad's final trip, I will stand in front.
- Don't worry.
- Yes, ma'am.
This is the plan for the Group's
assistance in the funeral.
Please take a look.
[Choi Dong Sung
Funeral]
Seo Yoon!
Don't become a good person.
Become the person others are afraid of.
I love you, my daughter.
Won Jae.
Jung Yoon, don't cry.
Eun Jung, you too. And Uncle, too.
All the important politicians and businessmen
will make a condolence visit.
What they want to see is not our tears.
It's the future of Sung Jin Group.
Let them remember Dad and
make them shed tears.
Chairman Choi Dong Sung of Sung Jin Group
who led the company for 40 years
passed away last night from a chronic illness.
Chairman Choi Dong Sung was a live
witness to economic development and
the great tree of the Korean economy.
The sudden news of his death has
politicians and businessmen in shock
as they are making condolence
announcements one after the other.
He's from the same hometown as my mom.
He even built an elementary school there.
My mom went to that school.
When I was little, my father drove a
remicon truck in the Middle East.
With the money he earned working for Sung
Jin Construction, he bought a house, too.
The picture that was taken when Chairman
Choi Dong Sung went to the construction site...
it's still at home.
Review the bid proposal for
Han Sung Steel again.
Raise the bidding price, too.
Someone has died. We can
talk about work later...
About 700 people die in Korea every day.
He's one of them.
What's different?
This is Jang Tae Joo.
I saw the news.
Tae Joo, even if we have one billion,
two billion, or more...
the atmosphere of commemorating
Chairman Choi Dong Sung has created...
Then Han Sung Steel will be
handed over to Sung Jin Group.
There is no plane leaving from JFK
because of heavy rain.
If I leave from Logan Airport in Boston,
I'll arrive there tomorrow morning.
Just give me one card.
I need a card that will shake up Choi Seo Yoon.
Do you have one?
I rented out the school yard nearby for parking
and I requested security around
the house from the police.
I had the meals be prepared in the
guest house, so they can eat there.
Eun Jung, the routine personnel change
of the department store is tomorrow, right?
Please proceed as usual.
Yes, I will.
Director Kim Hong Sik and others
who got pushed out...
want to see me after the funeral.
Meet them.
The ones who want to carry you to the
department store again will gather around.
Seo Yoon.
We're in the middle of the
mourning period for Dad
so it will be better to postpone
the personnel change...
Routine appointments, meetings,
business trips, investments...
I'm going to proceed with all
the company duties as usual.
Even if we stop for a few days
while we say good-bye to our dad...
we have to show that Sung Jin Group
keeps moving forward.
- Please do so.
- Understood.
I'm going to send one president to each
incense altar in the country.
Hey, President Kim.
Yes, bring President Bae and Kang,
and other minions together.
After you make a condolence visit,
let's have a chat in my room.
How long will you stay in Sung Jin Packaging
with only 600 employees and
keep sniffing glue?
You should return to the main force.
Okay.
I should return to the main force, too.
Tell the presidents you're friends with, Won Jae.
Regional assignments were
made by the General Affairs team
so tell them to head out in the morning.
Seo Yoon, the presidents should check in at
headquarters and come here for a visit...
All the regions should have a head mourner, too.
Presidents should talk about Dad and
memories about him with the visitors.
Let's have them console the visitors.
Let's do that, then.
It won't be an easy five-day period.
Uncle, Won Jae, Dong Hui and Sung Jae.
Since we have four men
greet the visitors for two hours in teams
of two, then take a break for two hours.
You can't do that.
If the head mourner leaves the room,
he'll get a bad reputation.
I couldn't keep Father's company,
but I can keep the mourning altar.
The head mourner should stay in the room.
I got a call from the Office of Civil Affairs.
They would like to make it a state funeral.
One of the ex-prime ministers
will head the funeral.
Cabinet members and other leaders of
society will help with the funeral.
Oh, and they pointed me as the
representative of the family.
Since I'm heading the Group, they
probably thought it was appropriate.
I'll do my best, Won Jae.
- Sung Jae, you...
- Seo Yoon.
Let's make it a family funeral.
I'm sorry, I already said yes
to the Office of Civil Affairs.
It's Father's last trip!
And I'm his first born son!
Kim Tae Sung of Daemin Group drove it to
bankruptcy and crushed the family...
but he was still the head mourner
when his father passed away.
Seo Yoon, I did what you told me to
do for the last three years.
Let's just do what I want for once, okay?
- Won Jae.
- I'd like a family funeral, too.
I don't want other people to interfere
on my dad's last trip, Seo Yoon.
Seo Yoon, I think the family funeral will be better.
Won Jae can be the head mourner and
Myung Hoon should hold the portrait...
That's what I think, too.
Let's have a family funeral, Seo Yoon.
Mom.
Once Seo Yoon falls apart,
the Group will be in our hands.
Sung Jae, grab a hold of Won Jae's hand.
I will push off his back.
After he came back from the funeral of
Chairman Kim of Daemin Group...
your father made fun of the loud ceremony
when it was just an empty departure.
He doesn't like anything cumbersome.
Let's send him off quietly.
Mom.
The burial place is Hampyung Farm.
Let's put a small tombstone on the hill in the back
and serve him the seasonal herbs
and vegetables he liked.
Seo Yoon...
once Sung Jae gets married
I plan to go to Hampyung Farm.
Please let me send him off quietly,
just like his personality.
Seo Yoon, let's make it a family funeral.
Mom.
Let's have a state funeral for Father.
Father filled the coastlines and reclaimed land
then built Han Sung Steel, but...
['Unethical Businessman' who
privatized public company]
Without Father, there was no Han Sung Steel.
With the money Father earned from
the Middle East, he built the shipyard
and created thousands of jobs.
But right now, those people are
pointing their fingers at Father.
Sung Jae.
You and Seo Yoon were the only ones
who saw the last moments of Father.
Father passed away lonely.
Let's do the state funeral.
I want to send Father off in the grandest way.
That's how I want to send him off, Mom.
Sung Jae.
Grab a hold of Won Jae's hand.
You should say what you're thinking.
I should return to the main force, too.
Hold my hand for a few months,
then I'll divorce you.
I'll let you leave with the department
stores from this house.
I should it give some more thought.
I don't have anything to say today.
When we went to see the reclaimed land
to build a steel mill...
we heard the waves and Dong Sung said
that it sounded like molten
iron boiling, not ocean waves.
'Let's build plants, roads and even buildings
with the steel we make from here.'
I remember Dong Sung's face from back then.
Dong Jin.
How dare the ones who never held a shovel
even once badmouth my brother!
Seo Yoon, let's do the state funeral.
Let's make it a loud one so my brother
can't hear those who badmouthed him.
Uncle!
If my brother curses at me later
for making it too loud...
Jung Hee, I'll take the blame.
So Seo Yoon, proceed with it.
This is the first state funeral for a businessman.
It's an honor to Dad. And our family
and Sung Jin Group should be proud of it.
The state funeral will be
officially announced tomorrow.
And visitors will be coming. Let's get ready.
Knowing who you were,
knowing you were not his son...
he paved the road because he
didn't want you to get hurt
and cleaned up around the grave.
My son must have been hurting
when he heard those words.
Mom, let's give the shares of
Sung Jin Cement to Seo Yoon.
You and me... let's leave this house.
I felt that way once, too.
When you were little,
when you had a high fever...
I was holding you and he was driving.
On our way to the hospital, looking at you
when you couldn't even breathe well...
he was crying and saying 'please live'
while he was driving...
I was thankful.
Sure, the one and only time when
you and I were thankful...
let's pay it back by making this a state funeral.
Mom.
Hold Seo Yoon's hand tightly.
My Sung Jae, Seo Yoon will hurt a lot
when you shake off her hand.
Mom, I won't let go of Seo Yoon's hand.
Your father was a quiet gentleman.
Someone like that grew Chung Ma Construction
to the third biggest company in 10 years.
How will you fool that blood?
I'll wait.
It'll have to be longer than the
27 years you've already waited.
Sung Jae.
It's time to switch with Dong Hui.
I'm leaving.
It'll be a state funeral for
Chairman Choi Dong Sung.
There will be several special programs on TV.
Chairman Choi worked hard to build Han
Sung Steel but President Kim snatched it away.
What to do... we became the bad guys.
Johyung Industrial called and said they'll
drop from the consortium to take over Han Sung.
They only saw the face value.
If we lose on the face value... we're dead.
If we're losing on the surface,
then we should look at the hidden card.
Choi Won Jae... I need to meet with him.
Tae Joo, what a realtor is most scared of is
one with lots of fear.
He'll keep looking after he makes
a promise to sign the contract today.
He promises to give another payment,
then he wants his down payment back.
Getting the remaining payment
out of someone with fear is
harder than getting a penalty
out of a corporation.
Choi Won Jae, that man... won't bite.
Of course, because he's too scared.
The one with lots of fear doesn't trust himself.
I'll make him trust me and
President Choi Min Jae.
Call Johyung Industrial.
There will be no state funeral for
Chairman Choi Dong Sung.
Congressman Park, Congressman Jo...
thank you for coming in the
middle of the assembly audit.
- Where is Vice Chairman?
- She's in the library.
This is Choi Won Jae.
This is Jang Tae Joo.
President Choi Min Jae asked me to call you.
Could I pay a visit now?
Thank you for keeping a big burden until now.
I now plan to put the Sung Jin Cement
shares under my name.
Excuse me...
Was that really the Chairman's wish?
Seo Yoon and I were there for the last moments.
He asked Seo Yoon to leave...
then he asked me to take care of that load.
Could I confirm with Vice Chairman?
Of course you should.
Now that I see the four of you, I remember
when we went to the vacation house in Jinhae.
We spent several summers together
with all the family members.
Did Chairman leave any words for us?
He often used to tell me
that I could say what's really
on my mind to you.
And that I should consult with you
if I have a tough time.
I'd like to ask for your help in the future.
We'll follow the Chairman's last wish.
We'll proceed with transferring
the shares to your name.
I'm going to live like you,
Chairman Choi Dong Sung.
I saw this statistic before.
More than half of those
who died from drowning
died in water that they could have
stood straight up in if they tried.
The current is strong, the sea water
is coming into their mouth...
They're afraid that their feet won't touch
the ground if they tried.
They can't even straighten their knees,
so they just...
What killed them was not the sea.
It was the fear in their mind.
Why don't we try straightening our legs?
I straightened my legs once,
and I lost everything.
I lost everything in the
recapitalization three years ago.
That's good, you don't have any more to lose.
Let's try again.
If you win, you'll become the
owner of Sung Jin Group...
If you stay still, you live as the cute brother
who wags his tail for his little sister.
Seo Yoon has a grip on the Group.
All objects remain in their current
state without an external force.
The law of inertia.
I'll stir up Sung Jin Group from the outside.
The takeover of Han Sung Steel.
I understand you led the takeover
of Han Sung Steel until recently.
Hand me the bidding price and
issues of non-price elements.
Vice Chairman Choi Seo Yoon, who failed
at the takeover of Han Sung Steel
even when she put in the full
capabilities of Sung Jin Group...
she will be very shaken.
The state funeral will proceed.
When the mood changes, Seo Yoon
will take Han Sung Steel...
Make it a family funeral.
In the funeral, the head mourner's
wish is the family's wish.
When the funeral is over, you'll have to live
as the nice big brother for the rest of your life.
I need time to think.
Vice Chairman would like to
see you, Mr. Jang Tae Joo.
Sung Jin Shipping will start its plant
construction at the end of the year.
The estimated construction
price will be pretty high.
I'm planning to leave it to
Sung Jin Construction and Eden.
If I let go of the takeover of Han Sung Steel...
then you'll at least take care of my meals?
It'll be nice if Eden took charge of a research
building of Sung Jin Auto next year, too.
You must have a really bad memory.
I told you I wouldn't grab the rope.
I'm going to fight the tiger.
We're in mourning.
To behave this way in a house in mourning...
The first person who came to visit after the
mortuary for my late father was arranged
was a bank employee in charge of loans.
He was afraid that he wouldn't get paid
back the loan on the noodle shop.
He looked around for a long time, looking
for something to seize, then left.
Flies come to the family in mourning.
More flies come to a bigger family in mourning.
The mourning family of my father Jang Bong Ho.
The mourning family of your
father Choi Dong Sung.
Why should they be different?
Born to a poor family, you
work, then work, then work...
then you leave.
How is that different?
My dad grew 42 affiliates of Sung Jin Group.
I'm envious.
He committed so many sins, but left
with all the prizes in the world.
Many people respect my dad.
Mr. Jang Tae Joo, this is a house in mourning.
When I was in high school, there was
a teacher with the nickname 'Jaws'.
He spent more time counting bribe
money than teaching classes.
One day, my friend Choon Ho called him by his
nickname 'Jaws' so he got really beat up.
And the teacher told my friend to respect him.
I thought about it...
just do one or the other.
Either be the teacher who is respected
or be the working man who loves a bribe.
And your father should just
be one or the other, too.
Either be a respected businessman
or be a greedy old hag who made lots
of money from stealing others' lands.
Sung Jin Group employees and their
families, the people of this country...
many are in mourning.
Usually when a rich lord dies,
his servants will cry the most.
Don't stir up Won Jae.
If Won Jae comes back to this game...
Why do you care if my bet comes from
my pocket or my loan?
Win the bet.
You and I are sitting at the same gambling table.
If you want to win, make a run for it.
I won't fold.
Choi Seo Yoon, I have what you have.
I have money and a dream.
You have a bit more of a stake than me.
I'm a little envious of that.
Director Park, raise the bid price of
Han Sung Steel to the maximum.
Schedule the creditors' visit for today.
The minister of commerce, the officials, and the
finance committee members in the assembly
should come tomorrow.
The senior secretary of commerce
was here today, right?
Call him and invite him to the
final departure ceremony.
Sung Jin Group... is great.
Let's make this clear though.
Choi Seo Yoon, you were born
in the master bedroom of this house
and walked through the living
room to get to this library.
But I, Jang Tae Joo, was born
in a shack in Shillim-dong...
and I'm sitting across from you in this library.
It won't be easy.
Be careful.
I think I'll really appreciate this advice.
If you win, you'll become the
owner of Sung Jin Group...
If you stay still, you'll live as the cute brother
who wags his tail for his little sister.
Uncle went home.
He's exhausted after greeting visitors
and crying all day at his age.
I asked him to go home and come
back tomorrow morning.
What could it be?
He argued with Dad for over 10 years
and sent off Yong Jae, too.
But Uncle looked like he lost half
his world after Dad passed away.
Hey hey, that's the love between
brothers and sisters.
I think of you whenever I go
see a ballet performance.
You really wanted to continue ballet.
How long has it been?
You were crying for days because you couldn't
continue any more with your flat feet...
You said you'd make your daughter a ballerina.
I ended up with three sons.
What if I don't even get a granddaughter?
Dad, help my kids to have daughters.
I miss Dad.
Jung Yoon.
I can't leave Father's last trip to someone else.
Let's have a family funeral.
Dong Hui, I'm hearing bad rumors in
the prosecutor's office.
How can you work there when
your heart has already left?
You should work in the company, too.
Jung Yoon.
Min Ho, Jae Ho, Sang Ho...
As a parent, you shouldn't let their
lives rust away in golf courses.
Honey, you too. Give some serious thought
to what I said to you earlier.
Hold my hand for a few months,
then I'll divorce you.
I'll let you leave with the department
stores from this house.
Let's have a family funeral for Father
and I'll become the head mourner...
Jung Yoon, Dong Hui.
I'll summon the presidents
and appoint my people...
I'll make another run for it.
It won't be easy. Seo Yoon is really...
Min Jae said he'll help me.
Jang Tae Joo, too.
Jang Tae Joo... he's the one who grew
Sung Jin Construction in 3 years from Eden...
He has money, a stake, and a
reason to help us.
He wants to own Han Sung Steel.
I'll give it to him.
Jung Yoon.
The golf courses are already yours.
Even if you tried and got crushed, Seo
Yoon can't take away your golf courses.
Let's hold a family meeting again.
Uncle is not here, and send
Sung Jae to the guest house.
Us four and Mother can push for a family funeral.
Then how would Seo Yoon go against it?
Won Jae, if you just let me have
the department stores...
We have a routine personnel change tomorrow.
I'll take good care of you.
Jung Yoon, let's do as I say.
Dong Hui, who should we side with?
If we have the state funeral for Father,
Seo Yoon will lead it.
And since the Group is
focused on the funeral now...
Seo Yoon will continue to lead the Group.
Seo Yoon will be on the news and TV, too.
Then people will really know that Seo Yoon
is the owner of Sung Jin Group.
Then we'll just end up
with three golf courses...
Whatever! So which side will benefit us?
If we have a family funeral for Father,
Won Jae will lead the funeral.
Won Jae will be everywhere on the news and TV.
If that happens, the Group might lean
a little towards Won Jae.
Dong Hui, I made up my mind when I quit ballet.
I'd let my children do whatever
they wanted to do.
I want to put the department stores
in the hands of our children.
What do we do, Dong Hui?
Let's do it like this.
Seo Yoon, I really tried to stop Won Jae.
Dong Hui tried to convince him, too...
But he said he was doing a family funeral.
He said he'd take hold of the Group again.
I'm sorry, Seo Yoon. You're busy
greeting the visitors and working...
I really tried to convince Won Jae, but...
Dong Hui did enough.
He didn't listen to Dad, so why
would he listen to Dong Hui?
Father was an elder of this society.
You were right about the state funeral.
What do we do, Seo Yoon?
Even Eun Jung is standing behind Won Jae.
If the department store stands with
Won Jae, it'll be tough for you, my Seo Yoon.
Postpone the routine personnel
change of the department store.
Thank you, Jung Yoon, Dong Hui.
Go back to the altar.
I'll go to the guesthouse and see if the
visitors' meals are being prepared properly.
It's the last meal that Dad is hosting,
so I should take care of it.
We'll get going, Seo Yoon.
My daughter Eun Jung wouldn't do such a thing.
It just happened an hour ago.
Jung Yoon and Dong Hui probably thought
about which side would benefit them.
Eun Jung is still thinking.
I'm very disappointed.
Dad gladly wanted to give Eun Jung
the department stores.
But Eun Jung...
Call Uncle and ask him to come right now.
There will be no family meeting.
Seo Yoon, I'll try to convince Won Jae.
I didn't know about the
state funeral or family funeral.
He didn't want anything bothersome,
so I wanted it to be a quiet send off...
I know, Mom.
You don't need to see Won Jae.
Who is the Managing Director of
the Corporation in Europe?
Director Lee Sang Min.
Tell him to come back to Korea by tomorrow.
As soon as Dad's funeral is over,
Won Jae will leave for Europe.
Check Won Jae's schedule for
the past three months.
The presidents and executives that
Won Jae met with... identify all of them.
They will be assigned to other
regions within a few days.
And Eun Jung will go to Europe, too.
I'm sorry, Director Park.
It'll be better for Myung Hoon to finish college
in Rome before he comes back to Korea.
Mother, Myung Hoon is in junior high right now.
He started in the international
school when he was eight
and he only went to school abroad.
If he comes back in the middle of it,
he'll have a hard time adapting to school here.
I can't go, Mother.
I'm asking you, Won Jae.
I don't want to show a messy sight
on your father's last trip.
When the Group matter gets settled,
Seo Yoon will bring you back, too.
Let's be a happy family again like before
when that day comes.
You'll be leaving right after
the post-funeral ritual...
you should start packing
and wrap up work, too.
Mother, with my work on the department
stores, I should be here...
The routine personnel change will be delayed.
I think she was disappointed.
Jung Yoon came to Seo Yoon to ease
Won Jae's feelings...
but you didn't say anything, so
Seo Yoon felt really hurt.
Don't worry. Seo Yoon is very thoughtful.
She'll forgive you in a few years.
Dad!
When Won Jae was having foolish thoughts,
you should have at least let me know.
He said he'd give me a divorce.
You know well... there were more days
he slept outside than in the bedroom.
You met with a few of the women
and ended things for me, too.
I wanted to leave, but because of you...
and because of Father-in-law's wish...
he said he'd let me go with the department
stores, so I was conflicted for a bit.
Dad, ask Seo Yoon so that
only Won Jae can leave...
How many political purges happened
during the Joseon Dynasty?
Many innocent people were executed and exiled.
Eun Jung, even if you have a lot to say,
just leave quietly for now.
Dad!
If I hold your hand, Won Jae will come too.
I served the Chairman for 35 years.
His last wish for me was to help Vice Chairman
become Chairman and make it solid as a rock...
I'd like to follow that wish.
I am your daughter.
Eun Jung, when you come back from Rome...
I'll live the rest of my life as your father then.
I'm sorry.
I thought about it for the first time.
I feel bad for my husband.
One sister betrayed him with the words from his
heart to get the department stores...
And another sister pushed his back
and kicked him out of the country.
Is Sung Jin Department Store opening in
Seocho-dong early next year?
You attended the groundbreaking ceremony...
my goodness. Looks like I'll be attending
the building dedication.
I don't need alimony.
Just let me leave with the department stores.
And guarantee the visiting
rights of Myung Hoon.
This is your last glass.
I'll hold your hand, Won Jae.
My Mom used to call me when the sun went
down asking me when I was coming home...
But then I made money and bought
her a house and a car...
now she doesn't even call when
I haven't been home for three days.
'It's okay if my daughter doesn't come home. As
long as the money comes to my account.' Is that it?
The takeover of Han Sung
Steel might not happen.
To chat about family at a time like this...
Smile!
You still don't know that Tae Joo and I talk about
family and the old days when we get nervous?
When I was 17, I went to the juvenile
detention center for the first time.
I walked through the gate of the detention
center, listening to Christmas carols...
This is Jang Tae Joo.
This is Choi Won Jae.
Sure, let's straighten our legs.
We'll make the preparations. Alright.
We'll start the plan at 9 o'clock tomorrow
morning. Let the media know at 8:45.
Director Yoon, make arrangements for a
place and prepare a press release.
No one in Sung Jin Group can know about this.
What time does President Choi Min Jae arrive?
7:45 in the morning, Kimpo Airport.
Han Sung Steel will be ours soon.
The bishop came for a visit.
He even missed the mass for the dead
at 6 o'clock this morning.
Wake Won Jae up.
He must be tired. He drank a lot.
I'll wake him up before the visitors come.
About Dad's state funeral...
the government will make an official
announcement at 10 o'clock this morning.
The funeral committee meeting will
be held at 2 o'clock this afternoon.
I'll be there.
Business groups will come and help
with the meals for the visitors.
Jung Yoon, dismiss the Group employees
working in the guest house now.
Vice Chairman.
Managing Director Choi Won Jae is holding
a press conference right now.
I am Choi Won Jae, the Managing Director of
the strategic planning division in Sung Jin Group.
I'll announce the decision from my family regarding
the funeral procedure for my late father.
After a family meeting last night
we decided to hold a family funeral for
the late Chairman Choi Dong Sung.
- Eun Jung.
- I'm shocked too.
I was also disappointed to hear that
I should leave with Won Jae to Europe.
Between you and me...
I thought you'd at least confirm with me
before you made a decision.
What to do?
Looks like I'll end up at the dedication
for the department store in Seocho-dong.
Jung Yoon, do you want more soup?
For commemorating the accomplishments
of my late father Chairman Choi Dong Sung
and acknowledging his contribution to society...
To those in the government ministries and others
who proposed a state funeral for my late father
I'd like to express my gratitude at this time.
I'll be helping the head mourner Choi Won Jae
and lead the funeral procedure. I am Choi
Min Jae, President of Sung Jin Construction.
We've decided that the burial place will be
on the family site in Hampyung Farm.
The presidents assigned to other regions
will return to Seoul immediately
and attend the funeral committee meeting
at 2 o'clock this afternoon.
Managing Director Choi Won Jae,
the head mourner, will lead the meeting.
All the official details regarding
the funeral matters
will be handled by Managing Director
Choi Won Jae and me from this moment on.
We will end the family announcement now.
I'm sorry, Minister.
We had a family meeting early this morning,
and that's what Mother wanted.
It's been chaotic, so I haven't
been able to call you.
I'll invite everyone who helped with
proposing the state funeral soon.
We can't just accept the family funeral like this.
Then what can we do?
Won Jae for the family funeral,
me for the state funeral.
We can't reveal our conflict to the world.
This is the last trip for Dad.
Managing Director Choi Won Jae crossed
the bridge that he can't go return on.
Then I should make sure he doesn't return.
Won Jae and Min Jae both.
Seo Yoon!
The father I saw was...
a horseman who drove Chairman
Choi Dong Sung's carriage.
This is the altar that will determine
the owner of Sung Jin Group.
This time, I'll be the priest.
[3 Days Later]
I thought all the rumors in the world
came out of women in hair salons.
But it came out of men in saunas.
The rumor that Choi Won Jae is pulling
the presidents has become widespread.
Some brothers I know called me and
asked for a steel distribution store...
President Jang.
The one who set the table for us is leaving today.
The family funeral of The late Chairman
Choi Dong Sung will happen today.
The coffin will leave the house soon
and a ceremony will be held in
front of Sung Jin headquarters
then it will be leaving to a
burial ground in Hampyung.
At 9 o'clock when the ceremony commences
all the employees of the 42
affiliates of Sung Jin Group
will have a moment of silence to commemorate
the great tree of the Korean economy.
Seo Yoon.
Father...
Subtitles by DramaFever
We have to win the bid of Han Sung Steel.
There are more than a couple of
problems with Seo Yoon's plan.
The game became simple.
Who will put in more money?
- Put in everything, 1.5 trillion.
- Let's go all-in.
I'll give you one piece of advice.
Watch out for Min Jae.
Could we start again?
Seo Yoon will go to prison soon.
I got the acceptance letter from Princeton.
Let's go to the States together.
Han Sung Steel will be in our hands soon.
There is nothing you can own.
Han Sung Steel will be taken over by...
I'll make sure no one remembers...
that Chairman Choi Dong Sung
existed in Sung Jin Group.