The cinema association "Zespole Filmowe".
Film studio "Thor"
presents the film.
FAMILY LIFE
Stop worrying and turning around.
We only for a minute.
What are you looking out for, young ladies?
"Is this your Octavia?"
- Yes.
You have an honorable escort.
Jacek, let's play.
All right, 13.
Pan Brown, figure, please.
- What for?
- This is a sportlot.
If it's a sport, then the number.
What's the difference.
Pani Bassia...
6.
Pan Marek, the figure.
17.
Thank you.
Marek, you noticed that people very
rarely cross out the unit and 49.
Well...
They see a target in the coupon,
they choose in the middle,
and the probability of hitting
the corners is the same.
Naturally, you are absolutely right.
And how much did I bet?
- 17.
- So what?
And I'm 6.
And you?
No, I have principles, and,
besides, I do not have a trifle.
I'll take care of you.
After all, still lose.
You will be embarrassed
when we win.
On the contrary.
Here is our design office.
I beg.
Pan is the manager, tell us...
No, it's details, maybe next...
I ask here.
In general, we manufacture
mechanisms for transport equipment.
Please, please.
And here we have just our new technical
solutions for the so-called boat.
Here they develop
original solutions...
bolts for boats...
I'm sorry, what?
You know, I do not know
much about technical terms.
These are not bolts, they are clamps.
They are used on ships.
- A, clear.
- Thank you.
- Many thanks.
- You are welcome.
I beg.
After all, I said the right thing, right?
Yes.
You'll go to India, you'll see.
Well, of course.
Do you want a pear tree? I have two.
"Did they send you from home?"
Yeah.
What are you doing on Sunday?
Who!
Well, are you with Christina?
Why are you marrying us like this?
So what do you do?
I do not know.
Christina, truly, will be engaged.
Maybe go to the Vistula?
And you will go?
Well, I'm thinking about it.
I'm listening, CB.
Now.
You are asked to the secretariat.
"They did not say why?"
- No.
I told you.
It is already being sent.
Excuse me, please,
but you called me.
Yes, a moment.
I accepted the telephone message.
Here you are.
FAMILY LIFE
Written by: KSHISHTOF ZANUSSI.
The film was shot:
MAYA KOMOROVSK.
HALINA MIKOLAISKA
YAN KRECHMAR
YAN NOVITSKI
DANIEL OLBRYHSKI and others.
Composer: Wojciech Kylar.
Operator: VITOLD Sobotinsky.
Producer: KSHISHTOF ZANUSSI.
Have you answered them by telegram?
No, we will come faster than
they will receive an answer.
Listen, how old is your old man?
Over sixty.
Well, it's not age yet.
Well, you know, if you have
not been ill all your life...
now to the right.
"What are they releasing here?"
Glass.
Before the war, they made
crystal and laboratory glass.
Now I'll bring you water.
Listen, you get your bearings,
maybe you need to go to the pharmacy
or the doctor, I'm in no hurry.
Is anyone at home?
- I arrived?
- Yes.
So what? Will not you say hello?
Good afternoon.
Rather, good evening.
Previously, he could not come.
I just said so, just
a good evening.
I thought that if you come at all,
it's more likely tomorrow morning.
And why "if"?
You still ask?
We will not quarrel, what with the father?
Sleeping.
I ask, what's wrong with him?
I do not know. A bit of everything.
- Specifically.
- I do not know.
I told you that
nothing is known.
Well, well, what are the symptoms?
Talk to him, you'll see.
"Is he at home?"
- Yes.
Good dog, good, well, everything...
Caligari, come here...
He does not bite. Only flea.
The dog is not to blame,
you know, that flea.
In the end, there are so
many people hanging out.
Well, Caligari.
But this is not a reason
to look at me indecently.
Oh shit.
Did not work out.
I wanted to embarrass you.
"Did you bring the goods?"
No. I brought Vita.
Very nice.
I am his sister, Isabella.
No, it's dirty.
I just broke it.
Thank you.
Caligari!
A dog with a bad
heredity, Caligari!
There is no water?
Nope. Water for two
years as spoiled.
- It was impossible to repair it?
- Of course you can.
And what? Someone in a faint,
why do you need so much water?
Wit!
Hey. How are you?
Good afternoon.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
The prodigal brother returned.
Stop pretending to be crazy.
Pretend?
I can pretend to be normal...,
but I do not want.
Is it enough?
Why do not you invite a
guest into the house?
No, thank you, I need to go.
I'm going to Warsaw, and in the
morning I have to be in Chorzow.
- In Chorzow?
- Yes.
- What for?
- Job.
God, how people work.
You'll stay for tea.
Aunt, we have a guest for dinner.
"What about the father?"
"God knows."
Please, from the front door.
Well, let's go! Come on.
Wit!
This is my friend, fellow student.
Sobota.
- And this is our aunt.
- Please, please.
Why do you pretend that
you do not look around?
This is normal.
Wit did not tell you
about our family nest?
You're friends.
But now it's running...
And this is our mother.
Aunt's own sister.
Are not they alike?
Our mother is so beautiful, only her
dad does not distinguish between them.
Especially in the dark.
Could, at last, collect
their belongings.
You see that I can not.
Was there an accident?
I saw my father's bandaged too.
- Accident?
- Yes.
It is not enough. It was a disaster.
Why is not he in the hospital?
Why is not he in the hospital!?
Ask him.
Maybe he will explain to you.
"In that case, who heals?"
"Doctor Romer.
"He's a sclerotist."
"But he plays bridge well."
That is, he loses
wonderfully to dad.
Is it not possible to call a
serious doctor to the father?
You speak as if you do
not know your father.
It's more than likely that
Wit could forget Daddy.
And you must know that
he is a rare guest here,
last time was 6 years ago
and very quickly left because of the
difference in opinion with the daddy.
You can not do without memories?
No. I can not.
Well, it's time for me.
No, it's dinner.
- But, I really need to go.
- Come on!
Now there will be tea.
No, stay, if you can, until you
find out with your father.
Is it not necessary for
someone to be with him?
How to wake up, he will let me know.
We talk here, we can not hear.
Well, no, tell me
what happened here.
You telegraph that the
condition is serious.
Because it's serious.
Then I do not understand.
I just do not understand,
how can a sick person
be left unattended.
We do not take good care of Daddy.
Do you hear, Aunt?
Wit believes that we do not
take good care of Daddy.
Itself is good!
When last year my father wore
buckets of water all winter long,
because the pipes burst,
then his heart did not hurt!
I did not wash at all for two months.
But no one forced you
to live in this house.
Well, never mind, it's such
a way of life... Vita.
We really love each other,
only platonic, at a distance.
Well, what is he like now? Well?
Look, you'll collapse.
No, I will not.
Well, what it is now, tell me.
Well, I can not betray a friend.
Oh, give it away!
And I'll tell you everything
about him, I'll give out,
although he is my brother.
You can not imagine how
he was a good, sweet boy.
Mom's favorite.
And he was hardworking and polite.
And how conscientiously
he served in the temple.
Do you know that he
served in the temple?
Yes, and treated
animals perfectly.
And then he was with the hermits
and got under bad influence there.
Well, he decided that he did
not want to see us anymore.
Come, look, this is Vitek, and this is me.
Does he look like an angel?
And, truly, in the depths of
my soul I stayed like this.
He probably thinks about us.
Or maybe he is praying in secret.
Praying? It's impossible.
A member of the society of secular schools.
An activist? Ha, ha, ha!
The figure! Vit.
- Bella!
- Watch out!
Well, what did you do?
Floor...
sold...
in antiques.
Watch it too...
And the sconces, those
silver ones, remember?
Also sold...
And the carpet on which you are going is sold,
and in a month it will be taken away for coal.
Well, are you offended?
- No.
- No?
Or maybe you should
ask your opinion.
Legally there is your share...
Oh, well, yes, there's Mummy.
And we'll sell Mom too.
Only for pennies, it's not old.
Well, if only to draw her a halo,
then she can go for the Madonna.
Icons are now fashionable, are not they?
Some American will
buy our mummy.
Bella, Bella,
why should I always do
everything in this house alone.
I have nothing against,
you are doing great.
You, Bella, I advise you, do not be daring.
You know perfectly well that I am
the only one working in this house,
and you come here as a guest
to rest, from time to time,
when at you this suspicious company
from a tavern disintegrates!
Aunt hints that I am a
secular way of life.
Well, of course, a secular way of life!
You really do not know that
it does not work at all.
Because I do not like.
Yes, I know that you like it!
That's it.
What do you want to bring from the garden?
Do you know why it does not work?
Dill and salad.
Excuse me, please, Pan, but in
this house all the abnormal.
Even the dog.
You might not want to
demonstrate with my friends.
In the end, these
are normal people,
and they do not need to know about all
the pitiful secrets of this house.
Do not cling. You yourself
brought this guy here.
To be precise, it was
he who brought me.
Clearly, it means that you
have not yet earned a car.
Maybe I'll earn some more.
Maybe you're hungry?
So take it and eat it.
No I do not like...
"What's that noise?"
- Wait a minute. It's true, father. I myself.
Caligari, well, come on, let's go,
Caligari, come on...
We go, we go.
You have a beautiful garden.
Grandpa wanted to create a
wonderful paradise garden here.
Wrote flowers, which,
of course, froze.
And then there was a corner of lovers.
And this is the goddess of love.
You see, here, where
these block houses are,
also once was our park.
It is planned to build it all.
In the meantime, we sell
everything we can by pieces.
And who is your father?
Well?
Well, not a priest?
No. A man.
That is... the tiller.
Yes, the peasant.
Peasant.
So nobody bothers you.
"No one bothers Vita either."
Because Wit is special.
Caligari, Caligari,
Come on, let's go, Caligari!
Do you lock it from your father?
I did not invent it, he himself asked.
- So, then, still drinking?
- Yet!
So you do not know that he
was treated for alcoholism?
Well, now?
Now? I do not know.
What does it mean "I do not know"?
Listen, Wit, this kind of talk about
the main thing is not with me.
My business is a kitchen, pots.
I heard that Bella said.
And, however, when the father
gets up, he'll talk to him.
How does it "stand up"?
"Well, there will be dinner."
Dinner will not be.
Why all this lies with the telegram?
So that you finally understand that you
have responsibilities in this house.
Caligari trampled all
the beds of the salad.
And the dill is gone.
I always said that this dog
should be kept on a chain.
Through my dead body!
I will never agree to this, I
must be completely heartless,
to offer such things.
Who sent the telegram?
Bella.
Do not let the dog come here! Caligari!
Caligari, come here!
Ugly! Get out of here!
"He will not bite?"
- Go away!
Now back.
Close the doors!
"Did you send a telegram?"
- I.
For what?
Ham, the female offender.
Damn, he wanted to grab my hand.
My name is Brown.
Sobota.
Student Vita.
Ah, very nice, please, I beg of you.
Please sit down.
So you are a colleague of my son?
Yadzya, do not get distracted, do dinner.
You, really, are hungry after a trip.
Bella, sit down properly.
So you are the friend of
the person who was my son.
You, indeed, are surprised
that I speak in the past.
No, no, this man is not dead, no,
and in the sense of the
law he remains my son,
as it is in the biological
sense, flesh of my flesh.
Only my mother knows for sure.
Bella, not sharp, and then I'll put it out.
So, your friend
gave up his duties
and, thus, lost his rights.
Has ceased to be our son.
It seems to him that
he has chosen freedom,
but this, of course, is only an illusion.
He just ran out of the house.
It seems that he now
lives in Chorzow?
Yes.
What are you looking for?
What is this person looking for?
Train schedule.
And where are you going?
I ask: Where are you going?
"Are you talking to me?"
Yes, to you.
To Warsaw.
What does it matter?
In vain you hurry.
No one puts you up.
Once in six years you can drink tea
in the house in which you grew up.
Excuse me, I really need to go.
I'll drop in again in Warsaw, and in
the morning I have to be in Chorzow.
And there can be no talk,
dinner on the table.
Excuse me, but I really need it.
If I can ask you for anything,
if a stranger, an old man
can ask you for something,
then I ask you to stay.
There is nothing to ask him.
He will not go anyway.
Why?
Because it's dark, but your car
does not have lights, sit down.
"How can it not be?"
But not here.
No far, no passing
beam, no stop signal.
And what happened to them?
I unscrewed the fuses.
What? Do not trust?
I can twist it.
Stay, if you want, I
already have a train.
Wit!
Leave these theatrical gestures!
It's not I who arrange a theater here.
You ruined such a wonderful
scene for your father.
He pondered it for 6 years.
You see? You are funny.
Spare yourself and us from cheap gestures.
Excuse me, these are family matters.
Your friend is to blame
for us and so I'm glad,
that you will become an
objective witness here.
Sit down!
He becomes more
and more like me.
Especially now.
How old are you?
Well, at least you
could remember that.
I'll remind Daddy when it was -
it was when we wanted
to add a family,
that lived opposite.
In the autumn, in the 45th.
The doctor gave a certificate
that there will be twins,
and Vit saved us from condensation.
Vit is our only
hope to this day.
Listen, Marek, you really
want to wash your hands.
Show him where the bathroom is.
I'll show you.
Well, let's go.
Did you have anything in
common with this telegram?
Hence, had.
What? Bella called me
without your knowledge?
Accident? What happened?
Tell me, finally,
what's going on here?
What's wrong with you, actually?
You die - do not you die?
Do you need help?
I see I disappointed you.
You came with the idea of a funeral.
Leave it.
I want to know why
you called me here,
What do you want from
me, and what do I do.
So far enough that you are here.
There are worms.
The centipedes.
They creep out after the rain,
and Caligari loves to lick them.
It's an abomination, right?
Have you ever considered a
person's skin under a microscope?
Pores like craters.
Too nasty, nasty...
"Ugly hands."
- I know.
Never mind.
I love an abomination.
I'm a humanist, true.
Love people...,
you understand?
Yes, I understand...
Do not try to be smart.
You do not even know how
much you lose on this.
Bella!!
Bella, are you taking the
guest in the bathroom again?
What does it mean: Again?
Should I answer you?
You know that this woman -
a stranger in our house?
She's a parvenu.
Be careful with this girl.
Come on. The Envious One.
Please, sit down, please.
I ask you to.
Thank you.
You'll forgive me for being so Spartan,
but his wife is abroad, and the
whole house is a little lame.
Yadzya, stop messing
around and sit down.
Put some alcohol on the table.
We have guests.
I, unfortunately, at the wheel.
So in fact till the morning
you will sober up.
No, I must go. I would not want
to make it difficult for you.
Do not fool around.
Where are you going to spend your night?
Places are enough.
In the morning, go.
Yadzya, I told you.
Do not force yourself to
persuade, take, impose.
Thank you.
I told you that I do not drink.
I do not persuade.
Well, for the health of
the guests, Pan Marek.
All the best.
Well! Daddy will arrange
a concert for us today.
What did you say?
It's a secret.
At guests do not talk about secrets.
Repeat what you said.
I was sorry for what is
waiting for us today.
She was sorry.
This girl is always unhappy.
Always offended.
Did she tell you she was in prison?
Dad!
I'm only asking if
you mentioned this.
I did not say why.
And Dad was also sitting.
Indeed, he was sitting,
almost two weeks.
Prophylactically, so to speak.
During nationalization.
Then, as a rule, everyone was put.
Fearful of sabotage.
And Wit did not tell you that
this factory belonged to us?
No.
You see, my great-grandfather,
Alfred Brown,
was a dissident and
arrived in Poland,
escaping religious persecution.
He built a workshop here.
History goes in a circle.
At the beginning and at
the end was a workshop.
Alfred reached the point
that he had 20 employees.
Over there, the kind of enterprise
of the middle of the last century.
You can view.
After it the factory was headed
by the grandfather Wlodimierz,
he also expanded it...
and contrary to what you are
taught in the lessons of Marxism,
he was not an exploiter.
Before the war I began to
produce laboratory glass,
and laboratory equipment,
and even bought Zeiss license.
And they are now expanding
the fireproof glass shop...
heat-resistant glass
and heat treatment,
many export...
To Holland, to France.
After all, heat-resistant glass today -
the important thing for everything...
even in satellites.
Bella, stop, the piano is upset!
The pope was a harbinger of the
latest achievements of technology.
This girl ruined her talent.
Her mother is incredibly musical.
My mother is incredible... musical!
My children are ruining themselves.
Wit - too.
Why is that?
I see you do not know,
but Vit is an excellent specialist.
Do not try, Marek.
I try to pass the fire,
where shadows grow,
immersed in the pristine
abyss of nothingness.
Wash happy,
which life does not know.
Fire, the eternal element,
but in you is liberation.
Well, how did you like it?
"I do not know, I do not understand this."
Never mind.
Well, who wrote this?
Well?
Slovak? Byron?
Schopenhauer?
I'm not a fan of poetry.
You see, daddy, he does
not know who wrote this.
I wrote this.
In the end, there is
nothing to be ashamed of.
You're right, there is nothing.
Has published at own expense.
No one has lost it.
Now the state pays for writers.
And I became an industrialist
instead of a poet.
Go for the tube to
my room upstairs.
You will not smoke both at the same time.
And this you will carry.
I did not ask you. You're a guest.
You must be very tired.
"I'll make you a bed now."
Do not drink, Father.
From what?
By what right do you want
to forbid me something?
By the right of the son, you mean.
After all, you denied
me this right.
What does it mean, refused?
In your opinion, sons of love -
it's a love for the things that you love,
to this garden, to this wreckage,
to the sweats in the bathroom?
Without this, you can not love everything?
You can not.
In that case, I'm a geek.
You think you're a geek.
You would like to be, but
you overestimate yourself.
I know that in the end
you will return to us.
How do you know?
Why do you predict a loss to me?
This is cowardly.
I know, because I myself once
wanted to get out of here.
I once wanted to quit
this house, this circle.
And you look like me.
Predefine in advance.
You say I look like you.
Or maybe I should ask if
I want to be like that.
You know that I do not want to.
Each person has his own limit -
you can not jump yourself.
No, Wit. You generally overestimate
the strength of the will of man.
You overestimate the power of personality.
I do not know why you are taught
Marxism in the university.
You speak of an isolated person, about
the character and strength of the will,
but you forget about all conditionality -
social, class, biological,
historical and so on.
That's it.
It is - I changed
my conditionality.
Its history has changed.
You yourself would not have done this.
Do not forget that you have always
been in a privileged position.
The child studied English.
And then another couple
of years was a governess.
Can you compare yourself with
an ordinary peasant son?
Yes, you just forget that in high
school I lived on a scholarship
and fed up at the expense of parcels,
which were given to peasant children,
for example, Marek.
And I was not, as he, accustomed to the fact
that at five in the morning to kindle a stove
and potato grout is
six times a week.
You would not have experienced
this if we had a factory.
You know, I understand why you
have to say that now, but...
I have a serious advantage
in front of you.
What kind?
I do not really need
to convince you now.
You, Wit, are a terrible egoist,
You want only to save yourself,
and nothing interests you more.
But you do not understand that
you are digging your own grave.
You can not live without roots.
Leave, I knew many,
they are doing great,
Do not look back,
live and rise up.
Up!
And where can you go up?
You're an engineer, even, maybe,
capable, if your friend does not lie.
So, what is next? You can
someday become a director.
Do you know how I
treated the directors?
Do not pretend, Vit, that you
need professional success, work.
It is not true.
You live only in denial,
You live in order to
prove something to me.
You live in defiance of me, Bella,
my aunt, against this house...
and therefore, when we are not,
you will feel a huge emptiness.
Bring firewood, let's light the fireplace.
After all, there is.
I beg you, bring it.
Where to bring?
From the workshop.
Excuse me, I need a key
from the workshop.
Through the window... enter...
True, through the window.
I'll escort you.
Bella, what did I send you for?
"Behind the straw."
Not necessary.
Leave Vita, go, help
your aunt wash dishes.
In the meantime, I'll
talk with Marek.
Daddy wants to talk with Marek.
Yes?
Well, what, Marek?
Well? You wanted to talk to me.
Yes Yes Yes.
You, really, traveled a lot?
Yes, I traveled.
I've been to India,
even several times.
You, of course, will be surprised,
you do not remember those times,
When a person could take a
train or even an airplane
and go wherever he wants.
At least to India.
My father did not go much.
In vain it is he.
Well, it was...
And you know, if everything goes well,
then our enterprise
will build something,
just in India or in Pakistan.
Well then...
It is wonderful.
Yes, we would then... went.
"Well, and when did this happen?"
Day before yesterday.
In addition to his father, no one was hurt?
The employee just had a day off.
- What is the next?
- Do not ask silly questions.
Answer yourself.
Listen, Marek, you
forgot to lock the car.
What are you? Are you afraid for this junk?
Junk is not junk, there can always
be someone spinning around.
"Was the workshop insured?"
It's insured!
If I had been insured, my father
would not have summoned you here.
So, it was you who called me.
Well, you see, Vit.
So, now ask me for forgiveness.
With witnesses, well.
"Do you know how it happened?"
"Bella, go away."
Do you know how it happened?
I told you: Get out of here.
But Vit must know if
he should help us.
Wit does not yet know what
you were sitting for.
A year is conditional for
insulting the authorities.
And something for that.
For prostitution.
Well, now I'll tell
you how it happened.
The father drove moonshine in the workshop.
A secret from my aunt.
- Well, it exploded.
- You're lying!
To whom are you saying this?
I was at the same time.
Have put the boys to bed with me.
I'll sleep on the veranda.
Well, that's enough. Enough!
Get out of here.
I do not have long left, Vit.
Father...
I wanted to tell you a
lot, it does not matter.
Listen,
you told me today -
it's good that I'm here, right?
So listen...
I'll stay, okay?
Or, if you want,
You know, I'm getting married soon...
and in fact you could settle with us.
Would not be so alone.
Tell me.
Do you want it? Tell me.
No.
Answer.
I do not want your sympathy.
Go away.
You ran away from home like a rat.
I told you: Go.
Anyway, you always
liked me something.
Pedestrians using
a daily crossroads.
Completion time:
The first quarter of next year.
So, we must wait until spring.
The 151st ship, built on
the Szczecin shipyard,
the first of twenty-one,
ordered by the Polish armature
"Polish Maritime Shipping",
dry cargo ship "Silesian rebel".
In the presence of numerous delegations
of those who three times took up arms,
to protect Poland's
right to Silesia,
The new Polish thirty-two thousand
comes off the slipways "Vulcan",
to serve the glory of the
Polish merchant marine.
In these days Silesia was visited by a
delegation of Indian industrialists.
The goal is to purchase
complete industrial equipment.
Visitors, visiting our
metallurgical enterprises,
carefully observed the cycle of
production of the highest quality steel.
They were keenly interested not
only in production results,
but also the working
conditions at the enterprise.
In a number of conversations with
representatives of our metallurgical industry.
The topics of interest to
both sides were touched upon.
On the last day of the visit, the guests laid
flowers at the monument to the heroes of Silesia.
The European Cup!
At the stadium "Legia"
in the pouring rain.
The Belgian "Standard"
and the Warsaw "Legia"...
Why are you closing?
We will suffocate.
You want us to be robbed, right?
What? Tell me, what can they steal from us?
You speak just like your little sister,
she always leaves everything open.
Only she hopes that maybe
someone will kidnap her.
But so far there are no volunteers.
Come on, I'll give you a towel.
Does your mother write to you often?
Often? Regularly, once a month.
And what does he write recently?
Lately? What always writes,
she's very business-like, you seem
to have inherited it from her.
When will it be back?
Will he be back?
Will come back. Where? In this slum?
To these ruins?
Absence of everything?
Who told you that she would return?
Father.
She - to him!
He only seems that he
was someone for her.
Believe me, I know better.
"What does the mother write?"
What he writes what always.
Two pairs of socks, some nylon
shirts in a commission,
in conclusion - a whole, Zulia.
It was a very fashionable name,
naturally not in life,
but for the stage.
And she always knew how to be fashionable.
- This is bad?
- No.
Only depends, at whose expense.
What are you talking about, aunt?
You're stupid, just like your father.
What did you want to say?
How much do I owe her?
Terribly owes much -
this crumbling slum and
the worn out hands.
- True?
- Yes, that's it.
I thought that if she
does, then I am with her.
She was younger, prettier, and she
had a talent for this, you know...
Father knew everything about her.
Only it excites him.
And you, in fact, are
very much like him.
Good night. I will repay.
I'm sorry that you
had to wait for me.
Actually, I need to
apologize to you for that,
witness what you
had today to be.
Never mind, Vit.
You, truly, are offended at me, that
I have been for so many years...
That I did not tell you
anything about our house.
Late already, let's sleep.
The torch is below, but
there is no more water.
Well?
The belly lost the towel.
We'll take them out so as not to wake him.
As a purr, a Renaissance pussy,
and now Marecek will lie
down near Bellyuni,
quietly fall asleep.
Do you sleep?
Are you asleep?
I'm waiting in the garden,
you can go out the window,
just look, there's nettle.
Well?
What are you watching?
Pig!
Drive carefully, because you
are slightly under the fly.
Do not worry.
Listen, old man, I
told you: "I'm sorry"?
So I told you "sorry" or not?
No, that's not the point.
No, I told you to "excuse me,"
and that's the point, you know?
What are you telling me here?
Go carefully, because you're under a fly,
get dressed, otherwise you'll get cold.
And if you would instead come to
me and gave me just on the muzzle.
You are not capable of this?
Remember in the hostel, I...
you knew everything about me, I told
you, who is my old man, who...,
and you - nothing.
When you received this
telegram, I thought, damn it,
I must come here, I
must see this hut,
entered and circus,
Bella, Vit, brother, Caligari,
what kind of house, God you are!
The old man is ill, my
aunt is working hard,
but what are you doing, you washed your
hands, brother, and gave you a hand?
Because you do not care!
Why so scream?
Then.
How did you react to
me, brother, well?
How did you react to me here?
Bye, brother.
And I also wanted to
tell you one thing,
that never, never again,
when you come to Khozhov,
it will not be that we
are friends, you lost.
You know, you've always been
so good, better, you know.
And I...
Hey. What?
Moving yourself or pushing?
Thank you. I'll go.
And say hello to your sister.
Hell, I will not even tell you why it
happened that happened between us,
because you do not understand.
"Maybe..."
- What can?
What can? Till!
Bella, will you go with me to Chorzow?
Where?
To me, to a normal house.
How kind you are.
Okay, I'll go.
I beg.
What do you think? What?
What are you whistling and I'm going?
Do you think I have no one to go with?
Well, sit down, go.
Till!
Hole.
I'll tell you, I'll write it.
Here you go.
Why would you wake him up again?
I want to say goodbye.
- Are you leaving?
- Yes.
Daddy, Vit wants to say goodbye.
He does not answer because
he thinks it's a supplier.
Well, come in.
Well, I refueled. He must have
reached the bar at night.
You, really, left the keys.
Really.
Wit, Wit...
Wit!
I told you - if you
stay and do a workshop,
then in six months you
will have your own car.
Yes.
Listen to this.
I very much ask you,
I implore you,
whatever happens,
do not write to me, do not wire,
as if I just died
or went somewhere.
The sleeve... will fall off.
I'll tell you.
No, do not. Thank you.
I, however, probably,
and so I will go abroad.