CJMONSTERNATOR Titles
I get so bored
From six to ten
From ten to six
From six to six
For all my life
Both day and night
I get so bored
If only
I could find
Alive or dead
A man or body
An animal
I don't care
Just to dream
For I get so bored
From six to ten
FAT GIRL
From ten to six
From six to six
All my life
Both day and night
I get so bored
If only
I could find
A man or woman
A body or soul
A werewolf
I just don't care
Just to dream
Anyway when you're in love with a boy, you always want to pin him down,
so after three days, he wants to break free
and get as far away as possible.
Oh yeah? We could see who can get a nice guy first.
And I'll be nice. He doesn't
even have to be that great.
Any guy will do,
even a fatty like yourself.
That shows how stupid you are.
You might look great,
but as soon as they get to know you,
they're no longer interested.
But they're not even interested in getting to know you.
I'm too young.
They'd be scared to sleep with me,
whereas you have no morals at all.
But I don't sleep around.
That's the only thing you don't do.
You have an odd idea of what
'not sleeping around' means.
Well that's what matters.
I don't think so.
If I meet a man I love,
then I want him to be my first time.
He won't think that my first time's important.
The first time should be with a nobody.
I don't want some guy boasting
that he took my virginity.
Men are all sick.
#Vene Carnevale/Tavernanova#
Let's stop here. I'm knackered.
Come on, let's keep going.
I thought you wanted a drink.
That place is shit.
You can sit at my
table if you want to.
Tell your friend to join.
She's my sister.
You can't just sit down like that,
you should ask if people mind.
No it's fine, I offered.
Go ahead.
It's very kind of you.
Because when there's no seats,
and you're tired and thirsty...
It's nice to meet someone friendly.
Fernando.
Elena.
My little sister, Anaïs.
Don't just stand there like a lump.
Can I buy you a drink?
Coffee.
Are you Italian?
Yes, from Rome.
A banana split,
my favourite.
We're on holiday here,
we're staying in a residence.
It's nice because it's quiet,
but we can't get out easily.
We're not allowed out anyway.
Speak for yourself.
Don't worry!
He can't understand a word you're saying.
He's just being polite.
No, no it's fine.
But can you speak slower?
As I need to improve my French.
I'm in secondary school.
Well I've just finished year 11
and now I'm going to be in year 12.
I don't know what I'll do in the future,
but it's useful for now.
I'm doing literature and science.
I've not been in secondary school for ages,
I'm a student now.
I study law.
Avvocato.
You're a student?
That must be different. You're free.
That's the problem.
Because we don't have to attend classes,
and then we have to take exams.
You can always retake them in June,
but you don't want to fall behind.
Besides, my dad wouldn't understand.
What does he do?
My dad?
He's an avvocato internazionale.
Mine's a managing director.
Sorry, my shift's about to end.
I'll see you back at the gate.
Don't tell me you've been waiting that long.
I almost went home.
You're a babe.
I couldn't believe there was a tornado.
We're in France.
Exactly. We never have tornadoes.
And the bed was shaking and I was petrified.
so I didn't go downstairs for safety,
I just pulled the sheets over my head
and decided to ignore it
and go back to sleep.
I must have been crazy, as if sleeping would help-
What do you study?
Sorry?
I study law. Next year I'll
be in my third year of law.
Criminal law?
Yes, I'm more interested in that,
as I think it's a lot more useful.
But I'd like to do international law,
in order to be a business lawyer.
Bu I'd like to start by working for good causes.
So you're going to be doing international law?
Yes, my father insists on it,
because he's already an international lawyer,
and so he wants me to follow in his footsteps.
Have you got to know each other?
Thank you.
Is that OK for you?
Yes that's fine.
I'm putting him on a diet.
So you think I'm fat?
No, but you're not exactly thin for your age.
Haven't forgotten anything?
I was worried there wouldn't be any left.
And people wonder why she's fat.
It's easy to see.
She scoffs it down like a pig.
What's the point of saying that?
It's obviously hormonal.
It's not her fault.
Maybe, but she won't stop eating.
I've lost my appetite.
Oh, come on.
So how did you meet my daughters?
François!
Young people meet as they do.
It just happens like that these days.
For I get so bored,
It's not over yet,
After my life,
And my survival,
After I've died,
I'll still be bored,
More than ever before,
If only I could find,
A specter or ghost,
A woman or man,
An animal,
I don't mind,
To dream,
Aren't my lips soft?
And don't I kiss well?
Yes, I love you,
But I don't want to marry you yet.
Because I now know that men like me,
I want to try other things.
Don't I kiss well?
I've only been kissed once.
Are you jealous?
I didn't really cheat on you.
Women aren't like bars of soap.
They don't wear away!
Each over gives them something more.
It's you who benefits from it.
You disgust me.
How can I find you so attractive and repulsive?
I'll give everything to you.
I've never slept with anyone before, you know?
What are you doing?
Can't you ask?
Shut up.
You going out?
No how the hell could I?
Did you invite him here?
Go to sleep.
You hear nothing, see nothing
and know nothing.
You don't need
make up to sleep.
I told you to go to sleep.
And remember to not start looking
You got the right place.
You told me it was the
first door on the left
My little sister's sleeping.
The gateman almost didn't let me in.
How did you get in then?
I gave him some money for a drink.
Shall we put some music on?
No we can't.
It's no big deal.
What's no big deal?
It's as if the music was
more important than me.
As if it was more important to you.
I could get offended.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
Sorry If I don't speak you language well.
I'd like to to tell you
all sorts of things.
That you're so pretty.
Yeah I know. It's hard to not be
able to understand.
To think that I could've studied Italian
but did Spanish instead.
They're all macho.
I can learn Italian next year.
No I need to learn French.
I don't see why.
When I come to see you in Paris,
I'll have learnt more French.
You're gonna come and visit me in Paris?
Yes.
Well, I don't actually live in Paris.
I live in the suburbs.
But my house is great.
That doesn't matter.
I'm coming anyway.
You were your bra to bed?
No, I just forgot to take it off.
Can't you help me?
A boy has to work.
If it's too any, then it's no fun.
Don't worry. These things
are always complicated.
Really?
Did you have many before me?
Am I not the first?
No, you're not the first.
Yeah, but I'm asking if
you've had lots and lots.
What does it matter?
Right now, I'm here with you.
Yeah, but how many have you had?
Not that many.
How many?
Dunno.
But if you don't know,
then that means lots.
Are you jealous?
I've never had one like you.
You sure?
Even if I don't sleep with
you but the others do?
It makes a difference.
I haven't been interested
in a virgin since...
Since?
Since I was 15.
So did you sleep with all the
other girls on the first date?
First or second, same thing.
No, it's not the same.
You can tell it's all they want.
And sometimes it's so obvious
that it repulses me.
There was one...
She invited me to dinner,
then straight to her room.
Well you're in my room.
But it's not the same.
This is different. There's no other way.
But listen.
Someone told me that this girl
had wanted to go out with me since
the start of the year, but I hadn't noticed.
So she asked me to dinner
and then we were in her room.
So we started drinking and there
were four bottles of wine.
Four of them, just like chance.
So we started drinking and
didn't eat anything.
I thought to myself,
'you went get me, bitch!'
I mean a girl can't drink
as much as a guy.
So I slow down my drinking
and I keep filling up her glass.
And half past midnight, I
look at her and tell her,
'Gotta go. I'll miss the last tram.
Good night!'
I left her absolutely hammered
and mad at me
and she's never spoken to me since.
Didn't you like her?
Well she was pretty cute, but I got
a thrill out of leaving her like that.
Besides, she wasn't the only one.
I've done that loads of times.
It's too easy with girls.
Were you in love with
the others you slept with?
I can tell you're getting jealous.
Yes, you're jealous.
The others don't count.
I only sleep with them as I'm a guy. That's all.
So if you slept with me,
Wouldn't I be like all the other girls?
No.
I'd respect you.
Even if you sleep with me?
Promise me you won't do it.
Because I wouldn't want that.
I swear on my mother's head
that I'll stay on the edge.
On the edge doesn't count.
It does count.
It doesn't.
It does.
Because I count.
You're the only one that counts.
I'm scared you won't hold back.
Don't worry about it.
That's my problem.
I'm a man. I know if I can hold
back or not and I can.
But I'd like to have you properly.
That's not possible.
Isn't it stupid if I have to get with
another girl who I don't like?
Will you need to?
Well yeah, but I don't want to finish myself off
in the toilet, it's sick.
I love you.
I really love you, but give me some time.
I told you I didn't want to.
I haven't done anything.
I thought you wanted to.
I didn't do anything.
You realise that you've
ruined everything?
You've ruined everything.
It was fine.
Yeah it was fine.
Can't you see that things were going well?
I can't.
I can't like this.
Not so early on.
I didn't trick you.
I warned you.
I'm not a pricktease.
Are you mad?
How can I resist you pressing
up against me like that?
You think I'm some sort of saint?
Can't you see what you're doing to me?
Do you think this is good for me?
No.
But...
Don't you think your first time
should be with someone who loves you?
Yes.
That would be a real test of your love.
A real test of love.
From you to me
and from me to you, too.
You know that there are so many guys
who run when they see that a girl's a virgin?
As it's too much hassle and responsibility.
Then they come back once the job's done.
Really?
Yes.
That's disgusting.
Otherwise, I'll have to find
a girl who's older than you.
That's disgusting as well and I don't want that.
I don't want that.
You're a little girl.
You're a little girl who looks like a woman.
You have to forgive men.
You're not mad at me?
Are you mad?
I want you.
If you were kind...
If I were kind?
All girls take it in the rear.
All girls?
Yes.
Because then it doesn't count.
They can say that they've
never slept with anyone.
That's sick.
No, it isn't.
No it's not sick. It's proof of love.
If you love me the way I love you...
I feel like crying.
No, don't.
You musn't. That was a wonderful gift.
Didn't you feel what it did for me?
Yes, but I'm ashamed.
You've shown your love for me.
It was a test of love.
A proof of love, you see?
From me to you and you to me.
Do you still love me?
Yes.
Don't worry.
You're the sort of girl
who men dream of marrying.
You'd like to marry me?
If you weren't so young then yeah.
I have to sit my exams first.
Would you wait for me?
What else am I doing except waiting for you?
Stay.
Yes.
It's morning.
I have to go home.
You know what I'd like before I go?
I'd like you to take me in your mouth.
Not with my little sister here.
She's asleep.
Yeah but she might be pretending.
You don't know what she's like.
She's jealous.
She doesn't realise that I'm older than her.
I told you she's sleeping.
No, it'd really bother me if she saw me.
I want to sleep!
I'm sick of your noises.
You weren't asleep?
You've been spying on us all night?
No, I was trying to sleep.
I'm not interested in your anal adventures.
You little bitch!
And I'm the little bitch?
That's a good one!
My sister gets played with all night long
without thinking about me and I'm the bitch!
Are you mad at me?
I feel dirty. I just feel uncomfortable.
Is it because of my sister?
No, it's not her.
It's because what should be so natural
been two people who love each other-
It's just sinister.
I just don't want it to happen again, you see?
Do you want to break up?
I want to love you.
Next time.
Next time we'll do it.
Do you want to? Do you still want to?
Answer me!
Of course I do.
If you'd said no, I would've died.
I'll be your first lover.
You're very very first...
who'll make you dream of love.
And you'll always remember me.
Even afterwards when you're with other lovers.
I'll always be the first.
And won't you always remember me?
Guys aren't like girls.
No, you can't ever leave me.
Stop.
Stop!
Stop it!
Stop, you'll catch a cold.
No I'm not cold.
No, no!
Do you know what we risk by doing this
together, under my country's law?
Tell me.
I'll go to prison.
It's too dangerous. You're not sixteen.
That's not fair. It's me who wants it.
See, it wasn't me who stopped first.
Next time...
I'll teach you all about love.
Returned goods?
In the returned goods column then!
There's a lot? No difference!
Well what did you fuck up then you idiot?
It was all going so smoothly!
Just when I turn my back!
You want me to come back, eh?
You know, that idiot is forcing me to go back.
No, you should let them deal with it by themselves.
You should enjoy this holiday, then return.
Do you think it's easy to
start a company from scratch?
Everyone's so lazy at first
before it starts to take off.
If you start off on the wrong path,
things mess up very quickly.
Dealing with one arsehole can leave you with no money.
Oh, come on.
It's the old story of things going wrong.
You're ten years ahead of the
competition and you feel strong.
And then you could screwed
over by a financial problem...
Eat, you'll feel better.
What's Anaïs doing?
Nothing much.
Don't shout, I'll go get her.
Okay I was a bit harsh,
but you understand right?
I'm not a bitch, but I get annoyed easily.
It's not your fauly.
I'm sick of following you around.
No it's not like that.
But you know that if you're not with me,
then they'll never let you out.
It reassures them when I drag you along.
See? You said 'drag me along'.
Yes, tomorrow.
No, the morning's best.
Oh well, never mind.
Ten past eight.
Finally!
What's the point of being here,
if we can't be here together?
Yes, thanks, good bye.
What's wrong with her?
Nothing.
You don't seem that happy.
I don't work tirelessly all the time
to see a face like that on holiday.
I can't even stay on holiday, I'm supposed to go back,
and I'm the only one not looking upset.
Look at you all!
It's good to see you looking happy.
I'm glad I'm going home tomorrow.
What's wrong with you?
What's wrong with her?
It's adolescence, she'll be fine soon.
She'd better be fine soon.
It can't be that bad.
You haven't lost your appetite.
It'll do you some good.
When you eat, you don't think of anything else.
François, you almost forgot this.
But if dad's flying back-
Then what?
We'll go back by car.
I'll drive.
If I'm tired then I'll stop at a
service station to have a nap.
It'll just take a little bit longer.
So you'll be driving?
Oh come on, I can do it.
I just don't like to, That's all.
Each year I wonder how long it'll take
for your dad to get called back.
He broke his record this time.
He can't stand going on holiday and
hates it even more when his partners do.
You'll see, he'll get them
back to work immediately.
I'm not like him then.
I understand him.
Holidays suck.
Don't start that again.
You're not getting the
exact same dress as me.
Aren't you tired of copying me?
You can try and be original sometimes.
It's not the same colour.
It's the same dress.
I always have to be stuck with you,
then you copy me as well.
I'm not copying. I didn't
know you tried the same one.
Not my fault if I think it looks nice.
Yeah, you could take my boyfriend as well.
And say, 'oh didn't see he was already yours.'
He's not yours. He's not a dog.
Yes, he is mine. And you're just a little
bitch who's always trying to copy me.
You don't stand a chance.
You'll never be like me.
You must be joking.
I'd never want to be like you.
Well you better not copy me anyway.
It's not my fault that I didn't
see it was the same one.
Shorter.
No, I want it to be shorter.
It's prettier below the knee.
It's me who's going to be wearing it,
so I want it to be shorter.
No, I'll do it.
You're being so difficult,
I can't take you anywhere!
It's a bit scary out here.
Well I think so,
but I feel safe with you.
No it's great out here.
You can't even see the road.
I hope we get lost and never make it out.
Like an urban legend.
Are you nuts?
I left my heart to decay,
On the windowsill,
I trust in a future day,
The crows will come,
With their beeks so very sharp,
They will peck away,
At this lump of raw meat,
That they wanted to eat from,
I left my heart to decay,
On the windowsill,
Although I can still enjoy myself,
I still feel anxious,
If you still see the flock,
Of crows fighting over it,
Don't be worried by them,
As I'm not worth a bit,
I left my hear to decay,
On the windowsill,
I trust in a future day,
Maybe the crows will come,
With their beaks so very sharp,
They will peck away,
At this lump of raw meat,
Over which you thought you had control
Slut.
You'd never know that we're sisters.
It's true.
We don't look like anyone.
It's as if we were born from ourselves.
It's funny as we have nothing in common.
I mean, look at you.
You have small, beady eyes.
Whereas mine aren't.
But when I look deep into your eyes,
it makes me feel like I belong,
as if they were my eyes.
I feel the same thing.
That's why we're sisters.
When I hate you, I look at you
and I can't anymore.
It's like hating a part of myself.
That's why I hate you so violently.
Because you should be like me.
But sometimes I feel like you're the complete opposite.
Yeah I feel that as well.
That's why you make me angrier than anyone else.
I don't want to forgive you for anything.
You have no rights,
but I have the right to look at you.
We hate each other,
as we're raised as rivals.
It's mum and dad's fault.
But it's not really their fault.
They think that it's good
and makes us competitive.
I think you hated it when I was born.
I mean when I was a baby,
you used to act like my mummy.
But when I got bigger-
Fatter!
Bitch!
When I couldn't look down at you
any more for ordering me about,
When you couldn't play mummy with me anymore,
And when I caught up to your language level as well,
Really? I don't remember that.
Are you sure you're not
just making this up?
No, I remember it all well.
The day you weren't so keen on educating me
was one evening, when we were together
in our pink twin beds
and you started bossing me
around all of a sudden.
and just like that I pounced on you.
I was happy as you complained to mum,
as I pinched you really hard
and you had two really bad bruises.
Since then,
you've lost all your power.
You never bossed me around again.
I don't remember that at all.
I remember it well.
But I was nice to you.
I use to push you in your buggy.
And call myself Maman LéLaine.
I hated that.
Really?
But it's so unfair.
You're allowed to do things
two years earlier than I was.
Yeah OK, that's true.
But what else would be good about being second?
Besides so many people can't
remember which one of us is which.
I mean we have the sirname,
but nothing else in common-
We have absolutely nothing in common!
Bitch!
I said nothing nasty!
Do you want to know a secret?
Fernando gave this to me.
It's an engagement ring.
A mauve opal.
He can't have given you that!
You're out of your mind.
There's got to be a catch.
No, this way we're engaged now.
It's a promise.
I'll get it resized.
When did he give it to you?
In the dunes.
That's dodgy. I don't think
you should've accepted it.
It's not right. It's just too valuable.
Yeah it is, I mean I didn't
want some shitty ring!
And you didn't ask where he got it from?
He said he got it from his grandmother.
I think I'm going to give myself to him tonight.
'Give yourself to him?'
What do you mean?
If he uses a condom,
then I'll let him go all the way.
Spare me the details, please.
You've no idea how scared I am.
Still, I have to go through it one day.
So it may as well be with someone I love.
What do you think?
What do you suggest?
Well between what you've already done and that,
there's no moral difference in my opinion.
There's a massive difference!
Well for my first time,
I want it to be with someone I don't love.
Because afterwards,
you realize that he doesn't love you
and that you don't love him and you feel stupid.
You'll change your mind when you fall in love.
Doubt it.
In any case, don't mind me.
As long as you don't wake me up,
you can go at it all night.
Kiss me.
I'm scared.
Be gentle.
No.
One hard push and then it's over.
No, gently.
Trust me.
Do you think the public come to see you,
just for the thrill of it?
No, not at all.
Why not?
Why do you say that?
My show deals with sexual issues.
There's no sex. I believe that's different.
Maybe I confuse sexual issues and sex itself.
It's research into sexual issues. That's all I think.
It's a big problem in France.
You have Bardot, who's a sexual issue.
No, she's a case, not an issue.
No she's a case, so she is an issue.
You should read what De Beauvoir wrote.
She wrote some amazing things.
I love Bardot, but she's an issue.
So why do you investigate these sexual issues?
Because it's an obvious issue that everyone understands.
It's a very simple human issue.
And no one is perfect in this way.
Whilst there are many more difficult issues,
there's so much confusion in the world.
What about you?
How do you feel about this issue?
I'm not saying.
Isn't this woman great?
I'll never know the people I'd like
to know. They were before my time.
Excuse me, is this
the Pingot household?
It's not that difficult to say yes.
But it would be stupid to expect an answer.
In that case. I'll come in.
I'm Fernando's mother!
Sorry for just walking in!
Are you Elena's mother?
Am I disturbing you?
Not at all.
The moss grows so quickly with all this wet grass.
Well you see, this is awkward.
Very, very, very awkward.
No, not at all. Really.
This is a very awkward situation.
No, not at all.
I'm bothering you.
No, I must compliment you. Your son is-
No, no, no, this situation is awkward.
I don't know where to begin.
You see, every Summer I bring along a few valuable jewels with me.
Some are precious, some are not so much. There's a variety.
I don't check on them every day.
The problem is that they're souvenirs.
Rings represent the men,
who we made realize that they had to offer them to us.
I don't understand.
But it's completely ridiculous and unthinkable
to give such a valuable ring to such a young girl,
who you just happened to meet,
on holiday.
It's absurd!
What ring do you mean exactly?
My mauve opal!
I just don't see how she could've accepted it so easily.
My son is too young to dispose of my belongings.
I'm not dead!
But-
I don't intend to die!
He's such an idiot!
Look I don't understand a thing that's going on,
but neither of my girls would do this.
Elena!
There you are!
Where's your sister?
I'm not paid to keep an eye on her.
You're scaring me.
You're always ready to back her up when she fucks up aren't you?
You're crazy.
Don't pretend you don't know what's happening.
She has a ring that belongs to this lady.
Couldn't your son have come himself?
Stop it!
You're leaving already?
We have to go home one day.
You didn't stay very long.
That's life.
Can we put some music on?
I didn't do anything.
I always get yelled at because of her.
And my holiday's been ruined.
I'm warning you that your father wants to have you examined.
How about a police report too?
Published in the papers.
He has no right to.
Yes, he does.
You should've thought of that first.
So you never had a first time?
Did you ask for your father's permission?
This isn't about me.
I'm sick of this.
Stop acting up, I'm sick of your sniveling!
It's not my fault I'm crying.
Well cry in silence then!
Mum.
Please stop the car. I'm going to be sick.
Isn't she a bitch?
She seems happy.
Shut up!
I hate her.
I hope she dies.
But I don't care. I'll die with her.
Speak for yourself.
I don't want to die.
No risk of that.
You're not the one in trouble.
Turn that down, it's horrible!
It's me who's driving. I need to keep myself company.
People are all pigs.
Like all French people.
Well, we have our own problems as well...
You're still eating?
Mum, that's bad.
Yeah, but there are many other things you shouldn't do...
I'm shattered.
I need to sleep a bit.
I need to pee.
Do you think she told dad everything?
And that he'll have me examined?
I don't know.
It's disgusting that people think it's their business.
It's disgusting to be a virgin.
I'm scared.
And he was a bastard, for making me think we were getting engaged.
And with his mother's wedding ring as well...
Stop thinking about it.
Go to sleep.
I can't stop thinking about it.
He was the first.
You'll have many more.
So now you won't give them such a hard time.
Yeah, but I can't stop thinking about him.
Go to sleep. He's already forgotten you.
You're a bitch.
No, I'm just being honest with you.
You deserve a lot better.
Go to sleep.
Lock your door.
You're not going to hurt me?
Shut up!
We found her in the woods.
She said she wasn't raped.
If you don't want to believe me, then don't.
CJMONSTERNATOR Titles
Those were my first ever subtitles!