It's over. It's over.
Easy, easy.
Calm down.
It's over. It's over.
It's over.
You saved me again.
If not, they would have killed me.
Killed me.
Scream louder next time.
If I don't hear you, they'll kill you.
Weren't you asleep?
Not anymore.
I love you.
Yes.
Where are you now?
I see trees.
There's a road.
Are you over there again?
The sun.
Where is it?
It's beautiful.
Am I over there too?
No.
I'm all alone.
All alone.
- It's raining.
- Don't catch a cold.
It's warm.
You should have dressed.
I see the road too.
Yes.
Now I see you.
We'd better go.
They're coming this way.
Come here.
You know Alexei? He's second year.
Send him over here.
- Just send him over.
- All right.
Come on, do it. It's okay.
Tell him his father is here.
- Hi there.
- Hello.
Go on! One, two!
Show some spirit!
Don't stop!
What's up?
Nothing.
He's going to get it.
Hey, Dad.
Sorry, it took so long.
They keep close watch.
- I understand.
- They could kick us out.
- Something wrong happened?
- No.
I just wanted to see you.
Nothing more.
I like your smile.
You don't look well.
-I'm fine. Just your imagination.
- My imagination?
Go on. I don't want to bother you.
Don't you want to watch practice?
- Let's go.
- Okay.
By the way, I saw your x-rays.
You don't have any spots in your
lungs.
You're in good health.
Aren't you glad?
I thought you'd be happy.
lam.
You know that they teach us
how to read x-rays.
Go to practice.
I'll come and watch.
In 10 minutes, okay?
- Have you seen Andrei Danilov?
- He's on duty in the barracks.
What are you doing here?
You can't stay here!
What?
- You saw and heard everything?
- I heard your father.
- So you saw him?
- Yes.
- The exam's on Monday.
- Today is Saturday.
Exactly.
You could have come to see me.
You're on duty.
I didn't want to bother you.
That never stopped you before.
I don't understand.
I asked you to forgive me.
It's forgotten.
I just needed to be alone.
So why didn't you tell me?
Why not?
You always move ahead alone,
without me.
Without me.
I understand now.
You're afraid of something else.
You're afraid that your father
will think that he is a bother.
You take his side.
Why can't I love both of you?
Why?
I really need to go.
You are seeing someone else.
Think what you like.
Is he better than me?
It's not the same.
He's older. You're still a boy.
You and I are the same age.
Women are always older.
Who?
Women.
I want to see him.
What are you saying?
What for?
That's enough. I'm leaving.
Watch your take downs.
Cut the distance.
Alexei, pay attention!
Alexei, I don't like you today.
Pay more attention.
Watch your falls.
Bend your legs.
Watch your stands.
Grabs should be higher,
at the shoulder level.
Here we go. Good.
Once more.
Punch him.
Throw him down.
Finish up. Finish up.
Where is your finish up?
Concentrate.
Dad.
Dad!
Here is my laundry bag.
Good evening.
- Are you hungry?
- I ate at the canteen.
Was it good?
I guess it was.
- What's that?
- Your portrait.
It's for scaring children.
Why is that?
It's still a photo.
Just a little more revealing.
You're not hiding behind clothes.
Nor your muscles.
Yes, of course.
I think muscles are an exaggeration.
Why is that? You admit
you worked out, lifted weights.
- Where are you going?
- That was when I was your age.
All right!
Where's my ball?
Why didn't you change?
- Don't stay in your uniform!
- I don't feel like changing.
You're beautiful.
You're like a tree.
Your legs are the roots.
Your chest is like a trunk.
- Sasha, have you eaten?
- Yes, thanks.
- Looking for something?
- I found it and ate it. Got to go.
Are you leaving?
Wait, where are you going?
Got something to say?
You didn't come by school today
for nothing.
I don't want to talk about that now.
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Wait a second.
Tchaikovsky.
You like Tchaikovsky, don't you?
Yes.
We're so different.
You're the next in line.
I'm behind you.
So?
That's your answer
to all my questions?
Not all questions have answers.
You know what the saints say?
- About a father's love?
- The saints? About love?
Where did you read that?
Where?
A father's love crucifies.
A loving son
lets himself be crucified.
I don't even get
the meaning of that.
Go to bed. Enough.
And change clothes, please.
Just don't die.
Kolya.
Kolya!
Can you hear me, Kolya?
If your son comes here again
tomorrow, what should I tell him?
Can I...
...show him these photos?
Maybe give him this one?
Dad.
I start to forget your face.
Dad!
What?
Where's Mom?
They gave us new uniforms.
- What about the tie?
- I have it.
I had this dream today.
I almost killed you.
Again?
Well, it means that somebody
wished us bad luck.
Now I'm scared to sleep.
Scared to sleep?
Go whisper to the water.
- As if it were that simple.
- Try it.
Okay, I'll try.
Troubles wash away with water
Like the night goes away with dreams
- Dad! Water's boiling.
- Turn it off!
Like the night goes away with dreams
Troubles wash away with water
Alexei!
Your dreams are getting out of hand.
I whispered to the water.
Don't turn on the light.
How old were you when I was born?
20.
How old?
Almost 20.
Feeling better?
What do you mean?
- You argued with her.
- Why do you say that?
Does it show that much?
Come on, get up.
Yes, I need to get up.
Back to the barracks on Monday?
Do you have duty?
Yeah, yeah.
- When are you coming back home?
- I don't know myself.
Come on, get up!
Or go sleep in your bed.
Come on, Dad. Get up.
Come on.
Remember I said
I had an opportunity to leave?
That the pay would be better?
But I won't let you leave.
I want you to be happy.
You think that I'll be happy
if you leave?
- Dad, catch up!
- Run, run!
Dad, someone's at the door!
Open it!
Can't you hear?
Open it yourself.
I'm covered with soap!
What's that? Dew?
- The roof is all wet.
- Yes, it's dew.
The sun's coming out
from behind the clouds.
It won't rain today.
You sleep too late, soldier.
Just go open the door.
Alexei, who could be dropping by?
Did you recognize me?
ls it too early?
Come in, come in.
Of course, I recognized you.
- Put your things there.
- Thank you.
I don't have much.
Open again?
Alexei, keep the doors closed!
I was wondering if you would stop by.
I've been waiting.
Don't just stand there. Come in.
Alexei, keep the doors closed.
I wanted you to drop by.
Really? Actually,
I'm leaving with my Mom today.
Already?
Well, our three days
of sightseeing are done.
This city's beautiful.
But living here must be tough.
Come on, come on.
- I woke you up.
- No, don't worry.
- Come on in. Are you afraid?
- No.
Where do you want to sit?
At the table?
Sit down.
- My same seat as yesterday.
- That's it.
- With the photos.
- Go ahead.
- I'll be right back. Are you hungry?
- No, thanks. I ate at the hotel.
- I have to dress.
- Of course.
If you remembered anything, tell me.
Be right back.
I didn't see this one before.
Oh, yes, the helicopter.
I saw it. Did it crash?
I don't know
if it's important, but...
- Can I sit down here?
- Sure.
Thank you.
I don't know if it's important or not.
I asked my father once
why he and my mother divorced.
I asked my mother before.
But she told me to ask my father.
He told me he had become
a different man after the war.
- True. Me too.
- And that no one understood him.
I asked him to explain to me
what he meant by "a different man."
He said I didn't need to know.
That it didn't matter.
I don't see a connection
to what happened.
Pity. I'm just trying to figure out
why he disappeared.
Nothing is simple.
Maybe he killed someone.
- Nonsense.
- Then where is he?
Your father is a good man.
A good man.
So he didn't kill anyone.
Even if he had, I'd stick by him.
- Do you have a cold?
- No.
- You've got a cold.
He didn't do anything wrong.
I'm sure.
Yes. I know, I know.
But there must be a reason.
You must have some theory.
Some idea.
Some idea...
You know, don't you?
Meet, you two!
He came by last night.
He's the son of my friend whom
I visited last summer, remember?
- Hi.
- My friend disappeared last winter.
- I didn't know that.
I was in the military.
When someone disappeared,
we looked, we didn't write him off.
But he left the military by that time.
You left the military too.
Now it's my turn to talk to you.
Let's go and talk.
- You didn't disappear.
- Don't bother my Dad.
- Hey, hands off!
- This way!
- Where?
- In my room. I want to talk to you.
- Maybe I don't want to.
- Go on, move.
- Don't be stubborn.
- Why are you closing the door?
Come on! This is my room.
- Don't bother my Dad!
- Stop pushing me.
- Come on!
- Stop it!
Is that your bed?
Yes.
- Look at this.
- Are those ribs?
It's called a thoracic cage.
- My father's thoracic cage.
- Those could be anyone's.
Very funny!
Look at the lungs, not the ribs.
- He had a lung wound.
- I can't breathe!
Can't breathe?
What are you looking at?
I guess you don't know
that I came by here last night.
No.
Strange.
Why didn't he tell you?
He didn't have time.
Are you really studying medicine?
- Yes, in the military.
- Military?
Yes, I'll be a military trainer.
Why the military?
It's in the family.
- My father was in the military.
- That's beyond me.
Too bad.
There's my friend, wait.
Sasha, what's that music?
- Get out of the house!
- Don't blind me.
- Alexei, come out here!
- Okay, I'm coming out.
Dad's home.
I know, it's Next.
You kidding!
I don't listen to that.
I'll knock you down!
Give me that CD!
Don't be afraid!
What is this, then?
Sit down!
Hey, Alexei!
Alexei, stop it!
I give up! I give up!
Come on, get up!
Who's that?
A guy looking for his father.
I can't get rid of him.
Bring him out here. Go on.
- Then leave. Go on!
- Alexei, don't or I'll fall!
Come here.
Come on!
- Come on.
- What for?
Come on!
Careful.
Come on.
Hold on.
That's it.
-I'm standing.
- Don't hold on to me!
Hold on, hold on.
Nothing compares to
my father's disappearance.
I know you don't care much.
Hold him!
It's good not to be afraid.
So don't be afraid.
I have no pity for those who fear.
Listen to me.
Never be afraid of anything.
Got that?
Alexei!
What do you want?
Why did you make him go out there?
Tell me!
Come back in, you two!
Come on!
And you, why did you go out there?
NOW, you. Hurry!
Did you hear me?
-I'm coming. No need to shout.
- Hurry up!
- Haven't I warned you?
- Yes.
- So?
- So what?
- Why are you mocking me?
- Excuse me.
Just because.
Just because, right?
Then you get what you deserve.
- What are you doing?
- There are consequences!
I'll teach you once and for all.
Next time, I'll beat you!
What?
Alexei!
Don't just stand there!
So you're here too?
You like playing acrobat?
I've got him, Alexei!
Don't just stand there!
All right, I'm coming.
I'll help you!
Will you go back out there?
- I can't breathe, Dad.
- Do you give up?
- No.
- Will you go out there again?
- Yes, I will.
- ldiot!
Come on, guys. Stop it!
What?
You tore my tank top.
- Go back to your nest.
- Fix it!
Go, go!
Go, defender.
- You tore my tank top.
- Yeah, sure.
I'll get a needle and thread.
- You'll fix it!
- Just throw it out!
- What are you up to today?
- Why?
I need to talk to you.
- Today?
- l'm leaving tomorrow.
A little later, then.
- I have an appointment.
- How about in an hour?
Okay.
Tell your father I said bye.
In an hour.
Keep it quiet!
Alexei, where's your cat?
I already told you.
Get off my back!
I'm not interested in you.
I'm interested in your cat.
Dad.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
You knew about his father,
didn't you?
You lied to him.
- You can't hide it. Tell me.
- It's true. I can't hide.
In 1998, my friend received orders.
A dangerous mission.
All his soldiers were killed.
Only he survived.
He came up with this crazy idea
to kill the guy who gave the orders.
Actually, it's not crazy at all.
I know exactly how it feels.
It's not crazy at all.
He wanted to kill the guy
who gave the orders?
Who was he after?
Do you know?
He didn't say.
It's the man at the top.
The one who decides.
You two were tight. You saw him.
You kept his secret.
He chose you.
He knows we have a place,
where he's always welcome.
We fought together,
but he won't come here.
Why not?
I'd really like to meet him.
See what he looks like.
Really.
Well, should I make something to eat?
- Not now. I'm late.
- Late? On Sunday?
- I promised him.
- Who? Our guest?
All right, go on.
- That's where you hid the ball!
- Bad hiding place, I guess.
Over here!
I already told you,
don't play ball here!
Do you hear me?
Hey, do you hear me?
Dear soldiers!
Want some soup?
Go or you'll be late.
Get dressed.
Careful with him.
Don't say too much.
Alexei!
Do you hear me?
Don't come home too late.
I'll cook for us.
Do you hear me?
Hi.
- You're late. Where are we going?
- This way.
I played ball with my father.
I'm training him.
You training him?
This city is all hills.
We'll have to go up after.
- Look at this.
- This way.
That dog has barked from that balcony
since I was a kid.
Nothing changes here.
Let's hope it stays that way.
Great door.
It's just old. Come on.
Look, a plane!
I wanted to talk.
All we're doing is walking.
What's that over there?
Come back and see us next summer.
- Next summer?
- Look, a street car.
Let's stop it.
- Hey, stop!
- It's quicker this way.
No need to shout.
It has to stop.
- How much is it?
- More expensive now.
- Thanks. I went to that school.
- I know, I know.
- Let's go to the back.
- Okay.
Where are you?
Come back here.
- I want to speak about my father.
- Your father? Okay.
Hi, Alexei!
Hi.
Tell me.
Well, where do I begin?
He gave me a key.
So I could see him whenever I want.
So I would be there
when he came home.
He wanted me to.
But I never used that key.
Now I realize how he needed me.
I don't get it.
Didn't he live with you?
Mom chased him away.
He started drinking after the war.
Why did you let her
chase him away?
How is a man chased
from his home?
This is a strange city.
Where are you taking me?
To the past?
Let's get off. Okay?
Fine.
I'll call you, Alexei.
Stop, please!
We're getting off.
It's dangerous to get off here.
I don't recommend it.
Hope he won't run us over.
- Hey!
- Hello there!
- Where are we? Where now?
- Down there, to the right.
Going over there, right?
- Can I ask you something?
- Go ahead.
What does your mom say?
About my father?
She doesn't love him anymore.
Too bad we don't live
in the same city.
Look.
That bird is looking for someone.
You know the parable
about the prodigal son?
Rembrandt.
Painting in the Hermitage. Yes.
Why the son? Fathers
are more often on the run.
The son always knows
where he has to go.
And why does he know?
Because he only has
one path in front of him.
If you say so.
We are always with somebody.
But the father is ultimately all alone.
Everybody will outlive him.
Those aren't your words,
or your ideas.
You have a father.
But I don't even envy you.
All right, go home.
I'll get to the station on my own.
So that's it.
You're late.
What?
We didn't have a date.
I can't take it anymore.
Tell me who he is.
Does it matter?
- But...
- But what?
I had no choice but to leave home.
So I did.
- You never told me that.
- Yes.
No.
Yes, I did.
Take off your necklace.
What?
- Take it off. Throw it here.
- What for?
It's warm.
That's all that remains.
I had so many dreams last night.
All of them strange.
First I dreamed about my father.
Then about our son.
Our son?
Yes. Really.
What did he look like?
I didn't see him.
I only heard him.
I felt him moving about.
You didn't want a baby, did you?
You were always so careful.
It's not a reproach.
Your time hasn't come yet.
- A father's love crucifies.
- Yes.
A loving son lets himself
be crucified.
Yes.
Give me back my necklace.
Come on, come on.
Poor crucified boy.
Crucified love means
you can't be equal.
You're not brothers.
No, you are not.
- Are you hungry?
- No.
It's all ready.
You eat.
You eat!
I waited for you.
lam not hungry.
l saw him.
- And?
- I showed him the city.
What did you tell him?
- I invited him for next summer.
-ls that all?
Yes.
He thinks his father is alive.
He loves his father.
Do you have a headache?
Do you think he's alive?
- Of course.
- It's your intuition.
- That's a new one.
- l'm serious.
- When you were 4--
- Stop it!
My childhood
doesn't really interest me.
I didn't need my own life then.
Everything was about you.
Without you, I was nothing.
Every story has two sides.
Now I'm just a bother to you.
Don't say that.
It's what I think.
Then don't think.
Dinner's ready.
You might as well eat.
Let's go outside.
It's better outside.
But I made your favorite.
Where are you?
Come out, Dad!
Come out here!
Come on! It's better out here.
I'm coming.
She said we built a fortress.
That we don't let anyone inside.
- Does this look like a fortress?
- Yes, this is our fortress.
I don't remember
what grade you were in.
Your friends hardly ever came by.
That worried me.
- You seemed bored.
- But I never felt alone. I had you.
She said she's tired of
banging on our door.
I see everything differently now.
What she thinks, what she wants.
I'm not interested.
She never understood me.
So I don't need her.
I've almost forgotten her already.
- Do you believe me?
- If you believe, so do I.
- Come here, Dad.
- Why?
- Stop it, you're not a kid.
- Squat down.
You're not a kid anymore.
When I graduate, I'll leave here.
If ever I see her,
I won't recognize her.
You'll leave here?
I wonder how I'll feel alone.
You won't be alone.
- You'll get married.
- Alexei!
- Sasha, not now!
- Let's fly!
- Higher!
- The army doesn't feed you.
Careful!
Again!
Next time.
Right?
You won't be alone.
You'll get married.
I'm glad you said that.
Sad about something?
Did it really mean that much to you,
what I said?
You are so much like your mother.
God sent you to me.
Everything about you is important.
Sasha, come here.
- Come here.
- Me?
- Come here!
- Okay, I'm coming.
Sasha, come here.
- Hi.
- This is my father.
And he is my friend.
I love him very much.
Can I be with you, guys?
I'm a nice guy.
Yes, Sasha. You're really nice.
Do you want to stay with us?
Don't be sad.
You live right next door.
We're already together.
Together.
But next door.
It's cold. Very cold.
I should go.
Where are you going?
You know very well.
For a walk. I can't sleep.
I'll go with you.
- No, I'll be right back.
- I'll go with you.
I feel bad.
Yes, I can tell.
Something hurts here.
Help yourself.
You'll work it out on your own.
Will this happen often?
I don't know.
I don't know how it will be with you.
If you're human,
it hurts all your life.
I got it.
Very clear.
Well, good.
It's snowing.
You.
Where are you?
I'm not far away.
And me?
- Am I there too?
- No.
I'm alone here.