Hi, Dad.
Hello, Jim.
You're home early.
Yep.
Hey, I'm going to work
on that slide again.
Can you watch me?
Later. Go on.
Okay.
I told you that squirt of a foreman
was going to be trouble.
He talked to the wrong man
when he talked to me like that.
There are other jobs.
Hey, Dad, watch!
I'm the union steward.
The men expect me to speak up.
There'll be other jobs.
See the farther away
you take off
the sooner you get in there,
and then you hook it in.
Now you try it. Come on!
Zip up in there.
Come on now!
The sooner you take off,
the faster you get in there.
All right, now,
don't forget... as you come in,
you fall away from the bag.
Let's go.
Move!
Oh! Hey, that was pretty good.
You hooked in there nice.
But, you know, a low throw
would've nailed you.
Don't give me that look, now.
A low throw would've nailed you.
It wasn't bad, though.
Keep it up.
Yeah, you'll be able to do it...
just keep at it.
That old trouble again?
Yeah. Too much gabbing today,
I guess.
I'll fix a cup of tea.
I don't like the look of it.
I've been after you to get
a checkup, haven't I?
I don't want you
going away again.
Jimmy always looks so
serious when he plays.
He's a good boy;
he tries hard.
Too hard sometimes.
Nothing comes easy,
and you know it.
If we work hard enough he
could be a great ball player.
- Just like his dad.
- Nah.
- You were the best I ever saw.
- No, nothing like that.
Playing for a factory team?
Making a few dollars
on my spare time? Oh, no.
What I'm thinking about
is the big leagues.
Boston Red Sox.
That's where Jim's going.
Jim!
That's enough, of that, Jim.
Come on, let's toss a few.
Right in the old mitt.
Right in there, now, Jim.
Come on!
Come on, Jim, like a big leaguer
a big leaguer now.
Come on, let's go now!
Come on, Jim!
Let's go, let's go!
Hustle in there!
Right here, now,
right to me, Jim.
Come on, Jim, come on.
That's the one. That's it.
We'll show 'em, Jim.
That's it, come on, now...
right to me!
You're out!
Your kid played a great game.
What an arm!
What a bunch of bums.
Great throwing, Jimmy.
You saved the game for us.
If you're going to play,
Mr. Tracy
you might as well win, you know.
That's right.
Bernie!
That was a good game, boy.
Hey, Mr. Piersall,
your boy played
like a real pro
today, didn't he?
Now we made it, huh?
Yeah, you made it.
With luck you made it.
It's a good enough game
for high school, but, uh...
you weren't on your toes all
the time, and you know it.
Don't you think?
Jimmy, you got to think ahead.
You got to be
ahead of the play.
For instance,
in the fifth inning
when the ball got away
from your shortstop
why weren't you
backing him up in there?
You got to think ahead.
Come on, take your shower.
Don't catch cold.
Hey, Jimmy.
Hurry up, boy,
I'll give you a ride
over to the party.
Come on.
Oh, I got two gas pumps
waiting, you know.
Aw, come on,
this is a celebration.
Skip work for once.
I can't skip work for a party.
Oh, come on, huh?
We won.
Oh, that's wonderful.
I thought we were
going to lose it.
I really did.
I knew you would.
But the third and fourth
inning, I thought
we were going
to lose it, but...
Mrs. Piersall,
your son made a play
like a big leaguer today,
and don't think
they don't know it up there.
Where?
Boston.
What's that?
I didn't want to tell you
during the season.
I was afraid you'd get nervous.
Tell me what?
The Boston Red Sox
are interested, Jim.
Tracy's heard from them.
The Red Sox are
sending down scouts
next year to see me?
Ma.
The Boston Red Sox are
sending down scouts
next year to see me.
What do you think
about that, huh?
You deserve it, Jimbo.
What do you think, Dad?
Well, we're on our way, Jim.
Big leagues...
big money.
Everything we've ever
dreamed about.
We're going up fast
no ten years
in the minors for us.
Hanging around
Louisville, Scranton.
No small towns,
none of that for us.
We'll give them one year
and then the Boston
Red Sox, right, Jim?
Right, Dad.
First we got
to be great next season
when the scouts come down.
You got to stay in shape,
keep healthy
then nothing can stop us.
Right, Jim?
Right.
Jimmy, you're going
to be late for work?
Yep.
Straight home
after work, son.
Oh, doesn't he always?
Can I have the letter?
Jim!
Hey, Jim! Don't lose the letter!
And bring it home!
Hey, how about a little
service here, huh?
Get that heap out of here.
Gives the place a bad name.
How's the big leaguer?
Heard from the Red Sox again,
huh?
Yeah.
Great, Jimmy.
It's really wonderful.
They're coming all the way down
from Boston
huh, for the opener.
That's what Tracy says.
Well if he says it, it's fact.
How about celebrating, huh?
Oh...
Aw, come on, Jimmy, once, huh?
No, I should go straight home.
Come on, do a little
ice-skating, huh?
Oh, Bernie, I'm not supposed
to ice-skate, you know that.
Oh, come on, Jimmy, relax.
You should relax
once in a while.
No, I got...
I got to get home.
Come on, boy. Once, huh?
I'll have you home
before you know it.
Come on.
Ten minutes.
Okay, ten minutes.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Come on, hurry up,
then, ten minutes.
- Let's go, huh?
- Let me just lock up.
Maybe he had to work
overtime.
I tell you, there was no answer
at the gas station.
Why don't you call
some of his other friends?
I did... nobody's home.
Nobody's seen him.
I'm going to call
the police.
John, for goodness sake,
he's an hour and a half late.
That's like 24 hours
with anybody else.
John, will you
be sensible?
Now, you know Jim...
he's never been late before.
I know.
The gas station.
It's the gas station.
I should never have let him take
that job at the gas station.
- John, will you stop it?
- Stop what?!
He's probably out with Bernie
and just forgot the time.
He knows how important it
is for him to get his sleep.
If he's not ready
when those scouts
come down from Boston...
Have you seen Jim?
Yes, sir.
Well, where is he?
He's downstairs
in the car, sir.
What happened?
We went skating,
sir, and...
Sorry, Mrs. Piersall.
Jimmy.
I'm all right, Mom.
Now, Pop, it's okay.
I'm... I'm going to play.
John!
Dad.
I'll be back the first thing
in the morning
and we'll have a cardiograph
down at the office.
Oh, thank you, Doctor.
Jimmy... Dad's going to be
all right.
Doctor says it wasn't really
a heart attack, just a warning.
He'll have to take it easy
for a while.
It was my fault.
Oh, Jimmy, it wasn't your fault.
Doctor says it could've happened
any time and for any reason.
Try and get some rest, son.
And don't worry.
Say, are there scouts
out there or not?
Yep.
Dad, no bending, you know
what the doc said, huh?
That was two months ago.
Well, you still
got to be careful.
I think you ought
to skip the game.
Are you going to play?
- Yes.
- Then I can watch it.
Okay, let's get out there
and play a little ball.
Jim... no sliding today.
Keep your weight off that ankle
as much as you can.
Come on, Jim!
Come on, boy!
Wait for a good one, baby!
Take it easy!
You're out of there!
All right, this is our
last inning, fellas.
Get a hit, kid.
Now, we're in trouble.
Those two strikeouts,
they don't like it.
I'm trying, Dad.
I know you're trying, I know.
But we've got to show
them that you can hit.
Now, you've got
to get your hit.
Come on.
Get your hit now.
Come on!
Stee-rike!
Come on, stay in there...
Keep your eye
on the ball, Jim!
Go! Go!
Go!
No! Don't slide!
Safe!
Jim!
Jim, are you okay?
I told you, Dad, worry
about nothing, huh?
- This is Jim.
- Hello, Jim.
Sakulavich and Silvera. Scouts.
- Nice hit, kid.
- You made a nice slide there.
Keep your weight off the ankle.
Come on.
Sit down.
Well, good-bye, Dad.
Good-bye, Jim.
Now, Scranton's a good beginning
but it's only the beginning.
Remember, next year,
it's got to be the Boston...
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, wish me luck.
No, luck won't do it.
You're going to have to think.
You're going to have to work
hard and think for yourself.
Remember, no one's
going to be there
doing your thinking for you.
Board!
Good bye, Jim.
Dad!
Next year!
Next year the Red Sox!
Huh?!
Next year.
Where's that arm?
- Watch it, Jim!
- Hey, look out!
Hey, are you okay?
What are you trying to do,
ruin the customers?
Hmm?
Look at your skirt,
it's a mess.
Holy cow,
what do I do now, Sandy?
Tell her you're sorry.
Come on, I'll introduce you.
They're friends of mine.
Nurses at St. Vincent's.
Come on.
Girls...
this is Jimmy Piersall
- our latest misguided missile.
- Hello.
- This is Joan Kelly
- Hi.
Doris Fleming, Edna
McGuire, and, uh...
Oh, Mary Teevan.
Mary's new in town.
She just started
at the hospital.
You almost put her back
in there.
That's a nice way
to treat a stranger.
I'm-I'm very sorry,
Miss...
- That's all right.
- Uh, let me...
It doesn't really
make any difference.
No, that's terrible.
Let me get you another
mirror, all right?
Oh, no, really,
please, I'm so...
I guess I got in the way
or something.
Oh, you didn't...
get in the way.
Thank you.
Well, you know,
I shouldn't go running...
Hey, Piersall, get it! Piersall!
Well, I like the way
you play baseball.
Well, now if one of
us could only cook.
Cook, yeah.
Where are your friends?
Oh, they're busy.
Well, good-bye.
Oh. It was nice talking to you.
Good-bye.
That's all for today.
Okay, men, let's hit
the showers.
Jimmy.
Get out of that hotel room, man.
Get yourself a date.
Miss Teevan?
Who is it?
- It's Jim Piersall.
- Who?
Uh, Jim Piersall.
You remember?
From the ball park?
Oh. Hi.
How are you?
Fine. How did you find out
where I lived?
I called the hospital
- and told them I'm your brother.
- What?
Called up the hospital and
- told them I was your brother.
- Oh.
Say, can I come in?
Well, I guess
it'll be all right.
Uh, I-I wanted to ask
you out to dinner
and then I figured maybe
if I brought dinner here,
you'd let me cook it.
- You brought what?
- Dinner.
Remember you said
- if one of us could only cook.
- Oh.
- Remember you said that?
- Yes.
Well, as it so happens,
I can cook.
Oh.
Well, I, I was going out.
Oh, you have a date.
Well, no. Not exactly.
Well, you don't have
to go out, then.
No.
Well, look, I've got
a perfectly good steak here
and asparagus and olives
and muffins
and ice cream and stuff
like that... what do you say?
I mean, I'm very
tired of eating out
at all these restaurants around
here all the time, aren't you?
And you won't have
to do anything.
I'll cook it all myself.
I'm a very good cook.
I'm practically a chef.
I need a couple of saucepans
and a double boiler
and Worcestershire sauce
and muffin tins and...
and, uh... well,
to light the oven to 450.
Oh, and the ice cream...
maybe it should go
in the icebox right away.
It should go in there
right now.
Oh, yes, sir.
The trick is to do these
before you get comfortable.
All right.
Here, come on,
you got to wear this.
How long do you expect
to be in Scranton?
Just one year.
Then Boston if
I'm good enough.
You'll be good enough.
You think so?
Well, sure.
You know, you can't just stand
there and watch
while I do dishes.
Okay. Let's go.
Come on!
Get over there!
Hurry! Hurry!
Come on!
Okay, Piersall, that's all.
That's all?
Jimmy?
What's the matter?
Well, you saw me at the plate.
Well, you hit almost every one.
With no power, with nothing.
Aw, Jimmy, now
are you or are you not the third
leading batter in the league?
What league?
What league?!
I've got to get out of the
minors this year, Mary.
This year.
No more of this.
Well, I know it,
but my goodness
you have an off day,
you'll get over it.
It's a double hitter tomorrow.
Pop's coming down.
It's the first time he's ever
seen me play professional ball.
Listen, I'm in trouble,
I'm in real trouble!
Jimmy, your father
knows baseball.
He knows how these things are.
He knows what it takes
to make the big leagues
and so do these guys.
Every week a fat report
goes up to Boston
how I'm running up bases
how I'm feeling,
how I'm hitting...
There's only 15
games left, Mary.
I've got to make
a showing or...
- Jim!
- Don't...
Hi, Dad!
Hey, everything under control?
Sure. How are you?
Fine. You look all right.
You look good.
Yeah, I feel good.
Well, I'm having
a great year, Dad.
Yes, you are.
There's 15 games to go
and I'm batting third
in the league.
Well, that isn't first.
Mary...
I'd like you to meet my dad.
Give me that beautiful cup.
Oh, look at that baby.
Oh, baby, I love it.
I love it.
Jim, Jim, look,
you got a telegram.
Wow, look at that.
Come on, what do you say?
What's the matter, Jimmy?
What's wrong, Jim?
I wish I didn't have
to go home tomorrow.
I-I-I wish we had more
time to think things out.
There's time.
Listen, you...
you don't want to be tied down
to a ballplayer all your life
living in trains and hotels;
no, you don't.
It doesn't make any difference.
There's no security
in it and-and...
one bad year
and I'd be out of it.
You'd do something
else for a while.
Well, there's a great career
waiting for me
loading freight cars
for the international...
but I... I can't
do anything.
I don't know how
to do anything else.
You're going to make
the Red Sox.
Mary, you don't understand,
the competition is terrific.
You're terrific.
I've got my folks
to support.
If I got married, I'd
have to live with them.
That would mean four people
living in that house.
It wasn't even
big enough for three.
It's not possible.
It's impossible.
I have to go in now.
Mary.
I don't care what happens,
I love you, Mary.
- Oh, Jimmy, I love you!
- You know I love you.
Let's get married.
Let's go back to Waterbury
and get married, okay?
Okay?
- Yes.
- Right now.
But I-I can't just walk
out on my job here.
Why not? You talk
to them, you can do it.
Just talk to them.
All right, I'll, I'll ask
the head nurse tonight.
- I'll wait.
- Oh, no, it may take a while.
I'll call you.
No, I'll wait right here.
You go ahead.
Well, maybe you'd better
go back to the hotel
and I'll call you there.
- You promise?
- Yes.
Oh!
Hey, Jimmy! Come on,
the old ball game.
Just what we need,
a center fielder.
No, no, no, I got...
Come on, Jimmy.
- No, I got to get upstairs.
- Come on.
I got a phone call coming,
please.
- Phone call.
- Come on, Jimmy, come on, Jimmy.
Play a little ball, will you?
Foul ball!
The weatherman says tomorrow
will be fair and slightly warmer
with probable evening showers.
We now bring you
Hal Morrison's sports review.
Good evening, fans.
With no ball game scheduled
today in the majors
the rival manager spent the time
juggling their lineups
for the crucial games ahead.
Locally, the whole town is
talking about Jim Piersall
a flashy, young outfielder
of our pennant-winning
Scranton Club.
Bug-eyed Piersall fans
are boosting him
as a hot major-league prospect.
Some are even comparing him
to the immortals of yesteryear.
Now let's get a few things
straight, folks
in all this hullabaloo.
Young Piersall has had
just one simple...
Hey, uh...
Scranton is a long, long way
from Fenway Park...
Will you turn that down
in there, please!
More than one rookie has flashed
like a comet in the minors.
Uh... your radio's on
awfully loud!
Will Jim Piersall
make the Red Sox?
Uh, turn it down!
Has he the wrist power,
the stamina...
Your radio's on a little bit
loud in there, you know!
Here's my prediction...
Turn it off, will you please?
...will not be wearing
the major-league uniform.
Turn it...
Turn it off!
Hello?
Hello, darling.
It's all fixed.
I can go with you tomorrow.
That's great.
It's 25 minutes
since we became engaged.
You love me?
I love you, Mary.
I love you, Jimmy.
I love you.
Get up.
Oh, Jimmy...
You know?
Jimmy...
Why, you got to, that's all.
I can't.
No, no, you have to.
Jimmy, why, why, why does
breakfast have to be at 7:00?
Well, it just does, so
come on, get up, okay?
Oh, Jimmy, I can't.
You can't?
Please.
- You just...
- Oh, please...
You just stay there.
I'll tell you what,
you stay there and, uh...
and I'll bring you some
breakfast in bed, all right?
How would that be?
Oh...
On a tray?
Marvelous.
Yes.
What would you
like to have most?
- Oh, wh-what...
- Most of all.
What are you doing?!
Oh, Jimmy!
The ice, no!
Oh... oh, oh, oh!
That's not funny.
- Is it cold?
- Oh, God, ice.
Oh, it's freezing!
Oh!
Hey, let go of the arm,
will you?
I'm going to need that in
a couple of months, please.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, all right, then.
All right, all right.
You can tell me what team
you're going to be with
and I might mail it
to you. Oh!
Okay, if it isn't Boston,
don't bother.
Oh!
Ugh! Ugh.
Ugh!
Really!
Oh...
Um...
You know, we need
traffic lights already
and I have to know what we're
gonna do when the baby comes.
Find a bigger house.
Mmm... oh...
You cold?
I think it's kind of cozy
like this, don't you?
Oh, the ice. Ah...
You warming up in there?
No.
All right. Okay.
Dirty trick.
Shh. Ready?
Yes.
Oh... Good morning.
Good morning!
Your son put
an entire window sill
filled with snow down my back.
- Oh, Jimmy!
- Yes, he did.
I'll take him over my knee.
We missed the boat, Jim.
We didn't make it.
"No trip to the majors
for Jim Piersall."
"The Boston Red Sox
have decided
the outfield flash isn't ready
for the big leagues yet."
"He'll be sent
down to Louisville
next spring
for further training."
Well, what do they want, Dad?
I was the best fielder
in the league:
I stole bases, I scored runs.
What do they want from me?
What you didn't give them:
Hitting.
That's what they want.
"What do they want from me?"
A man can rot in the minors.
Jimmy, Jimmy, it's not
the end of the world.
It's another year.
Jim...
Come on, sit down.
Feeding time.
Sit down, come on.
Fine little girl, Jim.
Six pounds, eight ounces.
Well, how's Mary?
Okay, she's okay.
Well, why can't I
go in there?
You'll be in soon.
Your mom's with her now.
Well, uh...
you know how I feel,
don't you, Jim?
Thanks, Dad.
How did you make out
after the fifth?
I got my hit in the seventh.
Great.
That's fine, great, great.
That makes 15 straight
days in a row.
We're going to double it.
Come on in.
Hello, Daddy.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Look.
Well, she's beautiful.
Isn't she, Dad?
You're a lucky boy, Jim.
And you've got to
give her the best.
Jimmy, you really think
she's beautiful?
Yeah.
She's pretty small.
You'd be surprised
how those small ones
can fill up a room
once they start crawling around.
You know what we
need is a new house.
I mean, a... a place she
can really grow up in...
with rooms for everybody.
What do you think, Mary?
I think it would be wonderful,
but we can't afford it.
Sure we can.
Look at the way I'm hitting.
I got the whole league
on the run.
I'm going to make the majors...
I can't miss.
Why shouldn't we live
in a nice place?
Well, why shouldn't we have
a nice place?
We're going to have
a nice place.
Jim's right.
The way we're going
it's about time we got out
of that dump.
Sorry, folks.
My girl needs her beauty sleep.
Oh...
Well, see you in
the morning, dear.
Bye.
I'll see you in the car.
Jimmy...
Are you really serious
about getting a house?
Sure I am.
I've never been more
serious in my life.
You-you just hurry up and
get out of the hospital
and get back up to Waterbury
and find one, okay?
Okay.
And I'll keep on
hitting, okay?
Okay.
Jim!
Hi, Dad.
Jimbo...
Great season.
Hey, you look wonderful.
Oh... where's Mary?
She has a meeting
with a contractor.
Wait till you see
the new house, Jim...
real high class.
We're moving in tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Uh-huh.
Have you heard from Boston?
You will.
Reporters.
Come on... I'll introduce you.
Ed Slate from The Sentinel.
Hello, Jim.
Hank Gibbons
from the Danbury Globe.
Okay, fellows, start pitching.
Say, what's the story
about Boston, Jim?
Are you going up
there next season?
Well, I guess you'll have to ask
Mr. Cronin that.
Buying a house, aren't you?
Does that mean you're set
with the Red Sox?
Papers up there say the Sox
would like to have you
if you can hit
the big-league pitching.
Well, it'd be
a lot tougher, okay...
We can out-hit
anybody in the league.
Lots of stars in
that Sox outfield.
We can outplay anybody
in the business
and I don't care who it is.
The boy's had a long trip,
Slate.
You've got your story,
right, Jim?
Thanks, Jim, very much.
Good bye, Mr. Piersall.
Thanks for coming.
Thanks for calling us.
We're on our way, Jim.
Come on, you want to drive?
No, you drive.
I'll take you to the new house.
You'll like that.
Oh, no, Dad. Uh...
Let's go home.
I want to see Mary.
I want you to see Eileen.
Mary?
Yes?
Listen...
Finally, finally.
I've got to finish packing.
Jimmy...
I bought a new high chair
today for Eileen.
As soon as we move in,
I thought I'd put it
Mary, Mary...
right in the room
that's going to be hers.
What?
We're not moving in.
We're not taking the house.
What happened?
I don't understand.
It's too expensive.
I thought it was a bargain.
Uh, yes... uh...
but it's too much.
Jimmy, what's the matter?
Nothing.
Jimmy, please, Jimmy.
I know something's wrong.
Now, please tell me.
Jimmy...
I'm sorry.
I can't.
It's his nerves.
That's what it is: Nerves.
He'll be all right the minute
he hears from Boston.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Morning...
Honey, can I get
a spring training roster?
Here. I'll write you
from Florida.
Send Piersall in.
Mr. Cronin will see you now.
Hello, Jim. How's the boy?
Fine, Mr. Cronin.
Good.
Sit down.
Have a good winter?
Yes, sir.
Keep in shape?
Yeah. Yes, sir.
Jim, we want you to start
the season with the Sox.
Mr. Cronin...
ever since I was a kid
I've wanted to play
in the Red Sox outfield.
You ever think
about the infield?
No.
We got a big hole
at shortstop, Jim.
With your speed and your arm,
you could fill it.
And as an infielder
you wouldn't be expected
to hit so hard.
You know, the pressure
would be off.
What do you say?
Uh... I don't know.
I do.
You can do it.
Um...
I've-I've been trained
for the outfield.
And... I've never played
shortstop
and I don't know
anything about it.
We'll have you in the Red Sox
lineup opening day.
Hmm?
Now Monday,
you'll leave for Florida.
Arrange transportation
for Piersall to Sarasota.
Yes, sir.
Um, Mr. Cronin...
Hmm?
You mind if I call
my father first?
Oh, sure, Jim.
Here you go.
Uh, Waterbury, Connecticut,
2095J.
Glad this spot
opened up for you, Jim
because we want you with us.
We're loaded
with outfielders.
You'll do okay at short.
You'll pick it up
in no time.
Be out in a minute, boys.
Hello, Dad.
Jim.
It looks like I'm going to make
the Red Sox, Dad.
We finally made it.
We made it, Jim...
Great... that's great.
Great, Jim, great.
Now listen, Dad, they want
to put me at shortstop.
Shortstop?
Hello?
Jim...
Yeah, Mr. Cronin says they've
got an opening for me there.
We made it, Jim.
We made it.
Short, outfield,
what's the difference?
It needs a little work,
that's all.
Just a little hard work, Jim.
Come home fast... next train.
Okay.
Jimmy.
You made it.
Oh, Jimmy, where have you been?
We've been worried sick.
What took so long?
Where's Dad?
He's at the bus station.
We were waiting all afternoon
and he went down there
to see if he could find you.
What happened?
Listen, listen.
I went to Boston.
Yes, yes.
They don't want me there.
What? They... they...
who doesn't?
No, they don't want me there.
Who doesn't, Jim?
Cronin and the Red Sox,
they... Mary?
They want to get rid of me.
Oh, Jimmy...
Yes, they do.
They're trying to put me
at shortstop
and I can't play it.
I can't play it.
Oh, Jimmy, no, no, no, no.
I can't play that.
I don't want to go
to spring training.
I don't want to go there.
All right...
all right then.
You don't have to go.
I don't have
to go, do I?
No, no, you don't.
You don't have to do anything
you don't want to.
I don't want to be hurt.
Okay, Jimmy,
you don't have to go there.
I don't want to be hurt.
Mary?
Jim!
Oh, Dad, Dad...
he's sick
and we've got to get
him to a doctor.
Well, I just talked
to him this afternoon.
How can he be sick?
Oh, Dad, Dad,
he doesn't even want
to go down
to spring training.
He doesn't.
Jim!
Jim?
What are you doing here?
What's this I hear
about you not going
down to spring training?
Is that right, Jim?
That doesn't sound like you.
We don't go in for that
kind of stuff, do we?
Now, it's no time
to get cold feet.
Well, sure, they put you
in the infield
so you'll have to work
a little harder, so what?
You're making
the majors, Jim.
That's what counts.
What have we been
fighting for
and scraping for
all these years?
And what have we been
pouring our blood into?
Oh, Jim.
Now... boy, this is
no time to buckle up.
You want them
to call you yellow?
Well, if that's what you want
you're no son of mine then.
Now you promise me
you'll be on that
train tomorrow.
Come on, Jim, promise me.
I'm waiting, Jim.
Okay.
I'll go.
Oh, now, that's more like it.
For a minute there, you know
I thought you were going
to ditch everything.
Fine thing, trying
to put a scare
into your old man.
That's not good enough,
that's not hard enough...
Take it easy!
You take it easy.
Come on, throw harder,
throw harder.
Show me more.
We've got games to win.
Take a break now,
huh, Jimmy?
No, I... I...
Cool off, huh?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir...
yes, sir.
Gotta work!
Gotta work...
gotta work.
The Boston Red Sox Baseball Club
of the American League
welcomes you to Fenway Park
for this season's opening game
with the Chicago White Sox.
This is the first
of a four-game series.
Play ball!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah...
Can you see me
back there?
standing back there?
What do you think we're playing
here, high school ball?
Huh, huh?
Keep your eye on me, mister.
Knock it off.
Let's play ball!
Watch 'em play, will ya?
Come on, come here!
Come here, you're up!
Boy, we need a hit, man,
and you've got to get it!
You haven't had one
for four days.
You've got to get
one now, okay!
Huh, you're going
to get a hit?
You're going
to get one?
I'll get my hit, kid;
you get yours.
Okay, go get it.
That's all I'm asking.
Aw, shut up.
Jimmy!
I said, break it up!
I won't stand
for this kind of fighting.
You're up.
You end in the dugout, Jim.
You're benched for the day.
You can't bench me,
Mr. Cronin.
I said you're benched.
You're out of the game.
You're suspended, Piersall.
As of right now,
you're suspended.
Now get to the showers.
Jimmy?
Mary. Wha?
Well, now, w-w-what
are you doing here?
I wanted to see you.
Well, how come?
I just wanted to see you.
Are you all right?
Sure I'm all right.
I'm fine.
You were there today?
Yes.
See what he did to me?
That Cronin suspending,
suspending me
kicking me off the team
for two weeks.
I'm the one player
on that team
that plays to win games.
I play to win games.
He won't let me play.
- Oh, Jimmy.
- He won't let me play.
Jimmy...
maybe you should take
a rest for a while.
Don't you turn
against me, Mary.
Don't turn against me.
I won't lift the suspension
until Jim's ready
to settle down.
He'll settle down, Mr. Cronin
if you put him in the outfield.
You put him in the outfield
where he knows everything
and I'll...
listen, I'll guarantee you
he'll play a whale of a game.
I guarantee that.
What do you say, Jim?
You ready to cut out the yelling
and play ball?
Well, you heard Mr. Cronin.
Yes, sir.
...will be starting
in center field.
In right field for Boston...
Jim Piersall.
Jim!
Jim.
Now you show them, Jim.
Don't let me down.
I said you were at bat, Jim.
Let's go, huh?
You can do it.
Come on, Jim, you can do it.
Use your head, Jim.
You can do it!
We're with you, Jim.
Come on, Jimmy, show them how.
Come on, Jimmy, boy!
Show them, Jimmy!
Strike!
Come on, Jim, let's go!
Ball!
Strike!
Come on there, Jimmy!
All the way!
How was that?
How was it?
Was it good enough?
Get in the dugout.
Did I show them?
Get in the dugout, Jim!
Answer me, Pop,
did I show them?
I showed 'em.
Pop, Pop, Pop, Pop,
I showed them.
Pop... Pop... Pop...
Was that good enough?
Was that good
enough for you?
Come on. Let's go.
Don't let them take me!
Oh, God!
I don't want to go! No!
Come on.
I don't want to go!
Jimmy, let's go!
Come on!
Don't hurt him!
Don't... Jimmy!
Jimmy! Jimmy!
Let me out there!
I'm Piersall!
Get away!
Jimmy! Jimmy! Jimmy!
I want to play!
Let him go! Don't hurt him!
Don't hurt him!
Let me play!
Ticket these for Piersall.
- Mr. Piersall...
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Brown.
I'll be taking care of Jim.
Now where is he?
Can I see him?
Your son's a pretty sick boy.
He's had a breakdown,
Mr. Piersall
a mental breakdown.
- Can I see him?
- No.
Just for a minute.
No, no, I'm sorry.
I suggest you go home.
I'll get in touch
with you tomorrow.
We may have a clearer
picture then.
Excuse me please.
Doc.
You handle Jim easy,
won't you?
I know.
Hello, Jim.
I'm a doctor, Jim.
I'm here to help you.
I'm going to give you
something
that'll make you relax
and feel better.
Jim, Jim...
first I want to take
the straps off.
Would you like me to take
the straps off, Jim?
I want you to trust me, Jim.
I mean to help you.
I have a feeling
we're going to be friends, Jim.
I want you to trust me.
You know, you've had
a rough couple of hours.
Would you like to rest, Jim?
Would you like to have
some sleep?
I can help...
I can help you
have some sleep, Jim.
Give me your arm, Jim.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Give me your arm.
I want to help you,
Jimmy Piersall.
Can you hear me?
Jimmy Piersall?
You know that name,
that's your name, Jim.
Jimmy Piersall...
can you hear me?
Jim?
I got here as
quickly as I could.
Thanks.
I'm sorry this
couldn't wait.
Sit down.
I need your help.
What is it?
We're not getting anywhere.
It's three weeks
and I still haven't
been able
to make contact with Jim.
I tried almost everything
and there's only
one other possibility.
I need your consent
for that... electroshock.
I can't even
promise anything.
And I won't
minimize the risk.
I can tell you
if we don't, if we don't
make contact with Jim soon
he may withdraw so far
he'll never be
able to reach you.
That doesn't leave me
much choice, does it?
He may not
recognize you, Mary.
Hello, Jimmy.
It's so good to see you.
Everybody sends
their love to you.
Mom and Dad and Eileen.
You should see Eileen now.
She's walking, Jimmy.
We're all fine, Jimmy.
The Red Sox have taken care
of everything for us.
And Mr. Cronin calls all
the time to see how you are.
Mary.
Jimmy.
Oh, he wanted
to get rid of me.
He, uh...
Mr. Cronin wanted
to hurt me.
- He wanted to hurt me, didn't he?
- No.
Um, he wanted to... hurt me...
Put me in here.
Oh, Mary, why did you let him put me in here?
Oh, Jim... no!
That was wrong. That was wrong.
He shouldn't have done that to me, Mary.
You shouldn't have done that to me, Mary.
Mary, why did you put me in here?!
M-M-Mary? Mary! Mary!
M... Mary!
I don't understand it.
I don't understand.
What's that, Jim?
I don't understand
the things I do.
Maybe I could
help you understand
if you want me to.
Hello, Jim Piersall.
How are you this morning?
Getting used
to these sessions?
Got a letter.
Anything interesting?
Yes, a picture
of my baby, Eileen.
Pretty little thing,
isn't she?
You know, Jim,
she's got your eyes.
My wife says she has
my appetite.
I bet her grandma takes
good care of that.
Quite a cook your mom,
isn't she?
Oh, yeah.
I remember when
I was a kid
I couldn't get home
from school
fast enough.
Pretty good pals,
you and your ma?
Oh, we were a regular team.
We did laundry and, uh...
and, uh, I'd pour the hot water
over it, and...
I remember once
when I was a kid...
Uh, she was away a lot...
And then your father
took care of you.
Yeah, well, we were
a regular team, too.
We'd, uh, play baseball
all the time.
You were happy
with your father?
Sure.
He's a wonderful man.
Well, when I won
a big game or something
nothing was too good for me.
How about when you lost?
No, I didn't lose.
You mean you, you won
every game you played?
Well, no, I mean,
you don't win every game.
I lost sometimes.
What happened then?
What did they say, Mary?
Can we see him?
No.
Well, what are they
doing to the boy?
Why can't I see
my own son?
Dad, Dr. Brown is doing
all he can.
We've got to go
along with it.
There must be
something I can do.
I know Jim.
He's up there alone,
nothing but strangers.
Oh, Mary, if... if they'd just
give me a minute with him
I know I could
help that boy.
Dad, we've got to leave
that to Dr. Brown.
You know the rule
in these sessions, Jim.
This time is yours.
You don't have
to say a thing
but if there's anything
on your mind.
Look, uh, I like you, Doc
but I don't think we're getting
anywhere with this thing.
It's just going to be
like last week
and the week before.
Well, since we have to spend
this hour together anyway, uh...
how about watching
the ball game?
It's been a long time
since you've seen
a ball game, hasn't it, Jim?
It's outside and high.
There's the ball going
into right field, and it's...
foul, by inches.
It's a long belt
down the left-field line.
It's a hit!
Come on, make your turn.
It's a stand-up double.
Oh, go to third.
He made it to second fine.
Yeah, but he should've gone
all the way to third.
He played it safe.
Oh, Doc, don't make me laugh.
Say he made a mistake.
He made a mistake,
he should've gone to third.
If I'd a done
something like that
I would've heard
about it for days.
Dad would've made
my life miserable.
How, Jim?
Well, oh, Doc, he would've...
I don't know
not talk to me, something,
I don't know.
That would've been
pretty tough, huh?
Yeah, but, he's my father
and I wanted to do good for him.
I owe him something, don't I?
You have a little girl, Jim.
Would you like her
to grow up feeling
she owed
you something?
Now, look, Doc,
let me tell you something...
let me get you
something straight.
I love my dad.
He's the biggest thing
in my life.
He taught me,
and he straightened me out
and he kept me in line.
If it hadn't been for him
standing behind me
and pushing me and driving me,
I wouldn't be where I am today.
Hello, Doctor.
How are you, Mr. Piersall?
Mary tells me that
Jim is feeling better.
There's, there's been
considerable improvement, yes.
Good.
Sit down.
Well, I, uh,
I want to apologize
for busting in
on you this way.
And, uh, well, we
appreciate everything
you've done for Jim.
We appreciate it
very much.
But now that the boy
is feeling better
isn't it about time
he came home?
Well, no.
It's not that simple.
Physically,
Jim is getting back to normal
but he's not nearly ready
to go home.
When will he be ready?
I can't tell.
Do you know what
they're saying?
"He'll never be ready.
"That mental institution
looks like it'll be
Jim Piersall's
permanent address."
That's not true.
Well, three million
readers think it is.
Every day that you
keep him in here
it makes it a hundred times
harder for him to come back.
Mr. Piersall, Jim has been sick.
Mental illness is no different
from any other kind.
Try and tell that
to the people outside!
Dr. Brown, you let my boy
come home!
I'm sorry.
It's out of the question.
Jim is coming home, Doc
even if I have to go
to the papers
and the ball club
about it.
Mr. Piersall, Jim is my patient,
my responsibility.
He's making progress here
and I won't have that progress
interrupted.
Why don't we go and ask Jim how
he feels about it?
Jim isn't ready to talk to you
or even see you.
I'm sorry, Mr. Piersall.
It's me, Jim.
You know they tried
to keep me out of here?
Fat chance.
How are you, boy?
You know, I... I was...
I was just telling
the doc
what's the sense in hanging
around here
when you got a family can give
you everything you need?
Come on, Jim.
You stick around here
and they'll make you
an invalid for life.
We know that, don't we?
You've got to fight this thing,
Jim, just fight it.
Start feeling sorry for yourself
and you're through.
You know that's what
the sports writers are saying...
that you're through?
That you're washed up,
you'll never play again.
You put your things together
and go down there
and tell that doc
that we've got to get back
so we can tell those wise guys
we're not through.
We're not washed up!
Oh, you just listen
to me, Jim.
We can still make it.
No, Dad, um...
it, uh, it won't
it won't work anymore.
I... I can't make it.
It's all right, Jim,
you're okay.
I'm trying, Dad.
I'm really trying,
but it's very hard
and it takes
everything I got.
Jim, listen to me.
Dad, please.
Listen to me, now.
You've always listened to me,
haven't you?
Yeah.
Haven't you?
All my life, I've been splitting
my gut to please you
and I never could.
No matter what I do,
it's not enough.
Dad...
you're killing me.
No, I'm... I'm trying
to help you, Jim.
No, you're not!
You don't care about me!
You never gave a damn!
"Win, Jimmy, win!"
That's all you
ever cared about.
And you're killing me.
You've been killing me
for years.
Yes, you have,
and it's too much!
I can't give you
any more!
I've got nothing
left to give!
Now get out of here, Dad.
Get away from me.
Go on. Get away from me.
Get out!
Get that guy
out of here!
Get him out!
Jim, Jim, Jim.
I wanted to kill him.
But you didn't, Jimmy.
Everyone... all of us,
we have irrational impulses.
It takes a sane man
to control them.
Help... me.
Help me.
All right, Jimmy...
I'll... I'll try to help you.
You wanted to hurt your father.
There was a reason.
You know the reason.
Uh-uh... uh-uh.
You know the reason, Jim.
I wanted to s...
tell him no...
Tell him I couldn't...
I couldn't do it.
Tell him I couldn't.
I wanted to say no
for all the...
every time... that he wanted me
to do something
and he wouldn't let me say no.
You couldn't satisfy that man.
I couldn't satisfy him.
He wanted good things for me.
Big league baseball, big money.
It was for me he wanted that.
He's a good man, Doc.
Yes, he is.
He didn't want to hurt me.
No.
Jimmy, your...
your father had his dreams.
He wanted you to make them
come true.
But it didn't work.
It never does.
You had dreams of your own
and needs of your own.
You couldn't go on living out
someone else's dreams.
I can't ever see him again.
What'll I ever say to him?
When you're ready to see him,
you'll know what to say.
What about baseball?
What'll I do?
Well, that's up to you, Jimmy.
Do you want to be a ballplayer?
Huh?
Is that what you want,
to be a ballplayer?
Yeah.
But I don't know if I can.
There's...
Everybody... knows about me.
Where I've been.
He's right down there.
You sure it's okay?
Jim wants to see you,
Mr. Piersall.
He asked for you.
Mary.
Hi, Dad.
Hello, son.
You have a good trip up?
Fine, fine.
How's the family?
Okay. Fine, fine.
I'm trying to get
back into shape.
It's, uh, pretty tough.
Dr. Brown... Dr. Brown
comes out sometimes.
We throw it around a bit.
You think I'm out of shape,
you should see him.
Just stay well, Jim.
You know, I was
thinking, uh...
it might be good to take another
try at the Red Sox outfield.
Even if I don't make it.
I might not make it.
Opening day next spring
he wants to be
in Fenway Park.
It won't be easy.
Good crowd out there.
Yeah.
Good luck, Jim.
Jimmy.
Hi!
Oh, Jimmy,
don't go out there today.
Oh, you're scared.
Yes.
Well, uh, I'm scared too.
Oh, Mary, I love you.
You don't know
how much I love you.
Look, uh... I know it's not
going to be easy out there
but I... I want to.
I want to play.
So? Huh?
So go ahead.