FEMALE AGENTS (2008) CD 2/1
APRIL 1944
BOURG-EN-BRESSE STATION, FRANCE
Search the warehouses!
Spotlight!
Bring him here!
I'll deal with him.
A sniper! That window up there!
FEMALE AGENTS
In 1940, Winston Churchill
created a new kind of secret service,
the Special Operations Executive,
better known as the SOE.
One section was responsible
for overseeing operations in France.
In 1941, a new head was appointed,
Colonel Maurice Buckmaster.
In 1944, the SOE's "French Section"
was dedicated, at a heavy human cost,
to ensuring the success of D-Day.
SATURDAY 27th MAY, 1944
TEMPSFORD AIRFIELD, ENGLAND
I heard about your husband.
I'm sorry.
Claude was shot 40 days ago.
I intend to fight on.
With or without your blessing.
How did you find me, Louise?
A liaison officer told me he'd trained
with a Desfontaines in London.
I thought nothing of it.
I was sure you'd given up.
That I was like Father...
saying, "The war's over, let's just capitulate. "
And blindly follow Pétain? Yes.
I was sure of it.
That you'd bailed.
Actually, by going to London,
you found the best way to fight on
and get away from Claude and I.
I never got what you saw in him.
Not to mention he was a communist.
SOE HQ, LONDON
COLONEL BUCKMASTER'S SECTION
How long did you work as a nurse
in Bourg-en-Bresse?
I never really stopped.
Would you care to go back to it?
I'm not here to heal casualties.
You'd be evacuating one.
From a German hospital in Normandy.
A German casualty?
A Brit disguised as one, actually.
What is this madness?
Probably what the poor fellow said
when he saw what had happened.
The "poor fellow" is a geologist.
On a mission for us,
he was spotted by a German in Normandy.
Our man shot him and stole his uniform.
- That's pretty cheeky.
- Stupid, you mean.
He was in Lisieux when
the Royal Air Force bombed it.
So he became a German casualty.
And was sent to a Wehrmacht hospital
in Pont-I'Evêque.
Why was he in Normandy?
That's just what the Nazis
must never find out.
You think I can get him out all on my own,
dressed as a nurse?
Not all on your own.
There'll be five of you.
Five women under Pierre's command.
Your brother devised the whole mission.
We already have one agent in place.
An Italian from Milan's Jewish aristocracy.
How are you?
Her codename is Maria.
She'll liaise with you.
She's already made contact
with the geologist.
To complete the unit,
here are some potential recruits.
Some have already done
a commando course.
How long do we have to train?
A one-day refresher course,
then you fly straight out.
That's insane!
Have you heard of Colonel Heindrich?
No.
He was with the Abwehr,
counter-espionage,
and he just joined the SS's intelligence unit.
He must be on the geologist's tail.
These were taken by one of our spies
on the English coast.
What are those strange objects
in the harbour, Colonel?
They look like floating grain silos.
Grain silos protected by ack-ack guns?
I believe these blocks play a role
in landing the enemy's invasion forces.
Colonel Heindrich,
why have we concentrated the majority
of our units around Calais?
The Allied fleet can unload troops
and equipment faster in an existing port.
And don't forget,
it's the shortest route
between the English and French coasts.
I'm sorry to insist, Field Marshal,
but what if it's all a diversion?
What if the landings
took place somewhere else?
Such as, Colonel?
Across from Southampton, in Normandy,
on one of the beaches.
Where we spotted an English geologist.
Compass, readings, samples...
In his panic, he left all this behind.
I'm sure he hasn't made it back
to England yet.
The thing about you SS people
that most amuses me
is that you never have any doubts.
Colonel, do you seriously believe
I will move all my Panzer divisions
because of a phantom geologist?
Colonel, if I may say so,
you see the world with different eyes.
The Field Marshal's Prussian.
As far as I know, we're not fighting Prussia.
Talk to someone
who has access to the Führer.
Who? Rommel?
He'd listen to you.
He could get you a hearing in Berlin.
First, let's find the English geologist.
Without him, I've no hope.
SUNDAY 28th MAY, 1944
HOLLOWAY PRISON, LONDON
A stay of execution
by order of the Lord Chancellor.
It's not a mistake?
I killed a man, remember.
Your pimp? I don't call that a man.
Nobody forced me into anything.
Stop being silly.
If not for us, you'd have been hanged.
That's your only alternative
to our proposition.
I knew there'd be a catch. What is this?
We need you for a mission in France.
Who do I have to fuck? Pétain?
We are reliably informed
that you used to perform nude in Soho.
You need a girl who'll get her leg over,
so here I am?
You must be desperate.
We also need a girl who can kill.
What do I get out of all this?
What are you thinking?
That you can refuse?
I'm not the type who works for nothing.
Thanks anyway.
You'll die like a whore
who never had a chance.
Is that what you want?
If the mission's a success,
you'll be pardoned.
I'm sure she's the right choice.
We can't trust her, she's a nutcase.
A rope round her neck and she said no.
That takes a hell of a nerve.
When the next one finally arrives,
let me do the talking.
What are you doing?
I'd hate to cramp your style.
I'm Gaëlle Lemenech.
We have an appointment?
I'm Louise. Please, sit down.
Sorry I'm late.
The General often keeps us back.
Hello, Hoe.
Hi, Pick.
- Still owe me a drink.
- Tomorrow?
"Hoe"?
Yes, it's a tradition in our unit.
They give us the names of tools.
They wanted to call me Saw but I refused.
"Eye-Saw!"
You see my point, don't you?
Besides explosives,
what do you do for De Gaulle?
Do you ever go on missions?
Never. It's my only regret.
Thanks.
Making bombs without blowing them up
is frustrating.
You can vent your frustrations
with me in France.
Sorry, but I can't.
I work for De Gaulle, not Churchill.
If you don't mind me saying,
you're in with that officer.
Sorry?
The lieutenant.
He can't take his eyes off you.
If I were you, I wouldn't think twice.
Who knows? Tomorrow, we may be dead.
You realise what you're asking?
Explosives expert and trained commando.
If you can do better...
It's humiliating.
You weren't always so picky.
- Well?
- She'll do it.
Was it hard?
The scouts, the cancelled wedding,
the fiancé sent to work in Germany...
Listening to that all night was tough, yes.
Is it true the Gestapo tortured you last year?
Yes.
Why go back?
What are you trying to prove?
I'm not trying to prove anything.
MONDAY 29th MAY, 1944
FANY HQ, LONDON
You're sure it's for me?
Who told you I love Paris-Brests?
We talked to your parents in Orléans.
Apparently, they bake wonderful cakes.
Their only daughter runs off to Paris.
That must really hurt.
Especially when she flees to London
under an assumed identity.
Mademoiselle Suzy Desprès.
Very pretty, Liliane.
I wonder if that doesn't suit you more.
We know you were
the mistress of a Nazi officer
when you danced
at the Folies-Bergères in Paris.
And here we have the banns for a wedding...
due to take place on 14th October, '41,
at the church of Saint-Germain-des-Prés.
Curiously, the ceremony never took place.
Why?
Stand up. Remove that uniform.
You're unworthy of it.
Leave this one to me.
Why not come for me before, if you knew?
Because we need you now.
For my secretarial skills?
No, dancing back home. For a good cause.
I'll never go back to France.
It's that or a court martial. Choose!
I put my past behind me.
I broke off the engagement.
If you want to put it behind you,
I have the solution.
TUESDAY 30th MAY, 1944
TEMPSFORD AIRFIELD
For unforeseen expenses.
How much is in there?
And these are your travel permits
and ration books.
You must each learn
your new identity by heart.
It's very important.
Raymonde? Do I look like a Raymonde?
Funny name for a music-hall artiste.
If the Gestapo arrest you,
you hold out for 48 hours.
- 48 hours?
- Long enough for the others to reach safety.
What if they torture us?
Detach yourselves from reality.
Always remember, talking too soon
can cost people their lives.
As a last resort, you have this.
- Cyanide?
- Yes.
If ever you need it, bite on it.
The poison acts in five minutes.
And farewell, Raymonde!
- Have you ever been blessed?
- Never.
If I get on my knees, it's not to pray.
Your brother's a sweetie,
but I'm not stupid.
Did you ask him to chat me up?
Careful what you say.
Actually, I'm glad.
I was bored and underpaid with De Gaulle.
- You lost this.
- It doesn't matter.
I'd never use it.
It's against my religion.
God doesn't care
what goes on down here.
You say that because of your husband?
My brother was shot on his 20th birthday.
But I never lost my faith.
Field Marshal Pétain, head of state,
will address you now.
French people,
don't make our situation worse
by resorting to acts
that give rise to tragic reprisals.
It will be innocents in the French
population who suffer the consequences.
Don't listen to those
who try to exploit our distress.
They will lead the country to disaster.
France will save herself by observing
the highest standards of discipline.
Obey, therefore,
the orders of the government.
Colonel? She's waiting at the bar.
It wasn't easy, but I've found you a little gem.
My dear Eddy, if it was easy,
I'd find her myself.
Colonel, I have something to ask you...
Not your export business again?
If you help me, you'll triple your income.
Triple my income?
You think that interests me?
NIGHT OF 31 st MAY, 1944
NORMANDY COAST
Stop praying!
You'll bring us bad luck!
Leave me alone.
I do what I want.
Nurse!
Come quickly!
Everybody, prepare to jump!
Suzy, clip yourself on. Hurry!
Check your gear.
Number four, OK!
Number three, OK!
Number two, OK!
Number one, OK!
THURSDAY 1st JUNE, 1944
HOTEL REGINA, PARIS
Colonel, I got a call from
the military hospital in Pont-I'Evêque.
I'm waiting for confirmation,
but we may have our geologist.
ROAD TO PONT-L'EVÊQUE, NORMANDY
Your permits, please.
Who's she? I don't know her.
She's new. Replacing Lucienne.
Your papers, please!
- We're here for the show.
- Go right ahead.
Find the Englishman
and I'll catch up with you.
What are you going to do?
I need a word with my brother.
Nobody gets out until I say so.
There's a problem.
Suzy's ex just arrived.
- Are you sure?
- Positive. The one In the photo.
We can't let him take the geologist
or see Suzy.
The SS-man she was to marry,
was it Heindrich?
What are you keeping from me?
Get back to Maria.
That's an order.
Come on, everybody out.
Careful, girls, you're being watched.
- They transferred him upstairs.
- Shit!
Come on!
I'll get a stretcher.
I'll wait here.
In 30 seconds, you're on.
A word of advice.
Don't look, you may get a shock!
- The patient needs treatment.
- Nobody enters.
- Colonel's orders.
- Get off!
- I won't allow this, Colonel!
- What are you talking about?
The man you're beating.
It's a hospital, not an abattoir.
You are forbidden to enter that room.
Understood?
What are you doing there? Get out!
Finished?
I won't be long.
Excuse me, can I make a call to Paris?
Encore! Encore!
Louise! The show's ended.
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Open the windows!
Jeanne!
Come on!
Cover them, with me! Come here!
Open up! Back a bit more!
20 seconds!
Ten seconds!
- Hurry!
- Let's go!
Tell the Wehrmacht
to sweep the whole area!
I can't, Colonel.
The radio room's been blown up.
This is Colonel Karl Heindrich.
Put me through to Wehrmacht HQ in...
- Colonel...
- Wait!
.. Wehrmacht HQ in Pont-I'Evêque.
I need reinforcements! What?
One of the soldiers took photos of the show.
What?
Well done, ladies.
You did a good job.
When the war's over,
I'll light a candle in church for you.
You may think it's stupid,
but promise me you'll do the same.
You too, Louise.
I'll never go back into a church.
And candles are for the dead,
not the living.
Maria, have you got a pencil?
Colonel, an English aircraft
was spotted over the coast.
Message received.
Is there a spot nearby
where a plane could land?
- Bernard, René, get the fires lit.
- OK.
Stay in the ambulance.
Louise, we need to talk.
- We're heading for Paris.
- What's Phoenix mean?
- I can't tell you.
- Or about Heindrich either?
If he'd seen Suzy,
we'd all be dead by now.
Why did you lie to me?
Don't you trust me any more?
- You haven't changed.
- Wait...
- We can still eliminate Heindrich in Paris.
- Paris?
It's crawling with collaborators.
It's too dangerous. With Suzy?
She's our best chance.
It's why we chose her.
You want to use her as bait?
That's your Plan B?
She won't have the nerve.
She'd rather kill herself.
The girls did their jobs.
They were chosen for a single mission.
I gave my word.
Let them go.
We'll find a way without them.
Maria, René and I drive to Paris tonight.
Bernard knows a safe house.
You'll join us tomorrow.
We'll meet at the Institute for the Blind
at Duroc.
The director is with us.
They'll be risking their lives, you realise?
Every day, agents die
accomplishing their missions.
You'd never have done this to men.
Girls, here comes our taxi to Buckingham!
The mission's not over.
We must be in Paris tomorrow.
Paris? Is he insane?
Nobody said anything about Paris.
We had a deal. I respected my side of it.
You gave me your word.
I'm going back.
We're all going to Paris. No exceptions.
Go on, fire!
Jeanne, not now. We have to obey orders.
You're a bunch of shits!
Hurry back to the safe house.
Stop! Get your hands in the air! Don't move!
Cease firing!
No, don't. I'll go.
I want him alive. Aim for his legs!
Grab him, quickly!
Get his pill!
Move it out!
Don't.
Is the mission confirmed?
You spend the night here.
Bernard will take me to Lisieux.
I'm going ahead to Paris.
Sleep in the cellar tonight,
just to be on the safe side.
I'm really sorry about your brother.
A freezing cellar and rotten apples
when we have millions in cash.
What better time to spend our cash?
How can you think of money now?
It's the way I am.
I'm a whore, not a choirboy. Never forget it.
You're used to humiliation. I'm not!
- I refuse to crawl to the Germans!
- Let go of me!
If we're ordered to Paris,
we don't argue, OK?
Stuff your orders!
I'm not a spy or a resistance hero.
Find some professionals.
Pierre's been arrested. René's dead.
It's our duty to take their place.
Our duty?
As soon as the war's over,
we'll be whores and slaves again.
I'm not dying for the French flag.
In fact, I'll take my share
and be gone tomorrow.
Anybody touches the money...
Stop!
Hurry, it's light already.
We did our best, Colonel,
but the negative was partly damaged.
Only this one is of any use.
- Have you had it enlarged?
- Naturally.
FRIDAY, 2nd JUNE, 1944
GESTAPO HQ, AVENUE FOCH, PARIS
Shaky handwriting. A wounded man, maybe.
I found it in your pocket.
The geologist wrote it, didn't he?
I have no idea.
I don't know who you're talking about.
And I've no idea who you are, Mr SOE.
But given your nerve,
you can't be just anybody.
And if you're not just anybody,
you must know what Phoenix refers to.
What are these blocks for?
Is it to do with the landings?
I've no idea.
Continue.
- Who do you think you are?
- Don't play hard to get.
Call me a slut, why don't you?
Leave my friend alone
or I'll call the Germans.
Coffee, ladies?
No, thank you.
Miss, is something wrong?
A doctor! Find a doctor!
Louise fainted in the restaurant car.
Why didn't you help her?
You're joking! It's packed with Germans.
Come on, we're going back.
- That's not yours.
- It's a friend's. We're looking for her.
She's in that compartment. She fainted.
A doctor's examining her.
Your blood pressure's low.
You need to eat something.
- Are you a doctor?
- I wouldn't have examined you otherwise.
When was your last period?
Some time before the war.
It must be all these people.
I couldn't breathe.
I feel much better now.
Congratulations to the mother...
and father.
You didn't know?
- What about Louise?
- She's with a German doctor.
Shit! Where's Jeanne?
She was right behind me.
Did she have the suitcase?
Yes.
Stay here. Don't move!
Louise is with a Kraut.
We're fucked. Come with me.
- Running won't win over your mum.
- Or save my dad from Verdun.
Don't get preachy with me.
What's that?
"Thou shalt not kill"?
Who's getting preachy now?
All aboard! We'll soon be on our way.
Louise, it's Suzy. Open the door.
Are you OK? Do you need help?
I'm fine. Tired, that's all.
Colonel...
Look at this one!
A definite resemblance.
Eddy, I'll have to transmit your file
to your Gestapo friends on Rue Lauriston.
Her lookalike's
under a stone somewhere, but it takes time.
Time is running out.
For you and for me.
Look where you're going!
Sorry, I was miles away.
- Are you OK? Are you hurt?
- It's nothing.
Perhaps I could buy you a drink.
SAINT-LAZARE STATION, PARIS
Be at the Institute for the Blind in one hour.
Make sure no one follows you.
Or else, tomorrow noon at Concorde,
on the Pont de Neuilly platform.
Now, let's split up.
- May I?
- Thank you, doctor.
- This is my friend, Suzy.
- It's a pleasure to meet you.
Follow me.
The ladies are with me.
Goodbye, miss.
Officer, all the way from Lisieux,
that fellow with a moustache
couldn't keep his hands to himself.
Fine, we'll have a word with him.
Go through, miss.
Please come with me.
- And our prisoner?
- Still nothing.
We've got to make him talk.
I need something to persuade Rommel.
Colonel, these photos
are from the SS archives.
They're close to the woman you described.
Louise Desfontaines.
That's her. I'm sure of it.
I'm late. The postman overslept.
Hurry, they're waiting for you.
Your rooms will soon be ready.
We were worried. Any problems?
I got lost a few streets away.
- Gaëlle isn't here?
- Not yet. I left her at the checkpoint.
- Why are you all dressed up?
- I wish I knew.
But apparently it's top secret.
- I'm taking her out.
- Promise me, no Germans.
- I promise.
- Can we talk?
Not now, we're in a hurry.
All right. In that case, Suzy stays here.
Come on, then.
This Eddy guy, can we rely on him?
I made sure he'd arrange
for Suzy to meet her colonel.
Help me.
Where do you plan their reunion?
Where they fell in love.
Room 813, at the Regina.
- Who'll pull the trigger?
- Suzy.
The gun will be in the room.
Suzy kill Heindrich?
Forget it, she wouldn't hurt a fly.
You'll have to convince her, then.
For the last time, where is this woman?
I don't know.
I've never seen her before.
I find that hard to believe.
Our men picked this one up
at Saint-Lazare an hour ago.
Off the Lisieux train.
Introductions are unnecessary.
You may be indifferent to your own pain,
but perhaps not to that of your friend.
Stop! Enough.