Well?
Carletto.
A glass of water, please.
- Want to dance?
- No, I don't feel like it.
- Why not?
- I don't feel like it.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
You're in a bad mood tonight.
Look, if I don't take it,
there are ten others who will.
What do you think it will change?
You get such crazy ideas.
About a year and a half in Sicily.
We have to build a new department,
and we need specialized workers.
Sorry, sir, but at the moment
he's not specialized.
We'll promote him.
For once a poor guy like me
gets the chance to get ahead...
and all she can do is whine.
Come on, let's dance.
Are you married?
Good. Fewer complications.
You know how it is with transfers.
How old is he?
Seventy.
They're treated well.
They can't complain.
The only problem is loneliness.
They feel abandoned...
and if they don't get used to it,
after a while, they just waste away.
Is he a relative?
No, he's...
Your dad?
Yes.
Well, if you have no other choice,
I guess you'll have to accept it.
What is it?
- Are you Tommasini, the engineer?
- Yes, I am.
Hello, I'm Mr. Lo Giudice.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Mr. Malpiani sends his regrets
that he couldn't come.
Thank you, miss.
- Is the car here?
- Yes.
Did you have a pleasant trip?
- Yes, thank you.
- Excuse me.
- Of course.
- Have you been with us long?
- Three or four months.
- Where did you get your degree?
- In Rome.
With whom?
Professor Tesorieri.
Ah, yes.
What department are you in?
- Sulphuric.
- Really?
How do you like it?
Well, actually,
I've only been there four months,
but I like it.
I don't think I can make
an accurate judgment yet.
I've only been there since graduation.
It hasn't been long.
What a knucklehead!
Did you see how he came out?
He's in the middle of rush-hour traffic
and he acts like he's in the country.
He rushes out like a bullet.
Some people are so rude.
That animal belongs in the wild,
not in the middle of traffic.
Just this morning
a cyclist cut me off.
I almost ran into a wall.
You gotta have nerves of steel.
These days you got cars
coming at you from every which way.
It's unbelievable.
Look there.
See those lights over there?
Those are our plants.
Maybe later we can call Moranzi.
I don't think we'll find him.
He does his own thing.
- Have you had dinner?
- Yes.
- Then thank you, and good night.
- Good night.
- Are you staying here too?
- No, I live in town with my family.
- Good evening. How are you?
- Fine, thanks. Welcome back.
- Any calls?
- No calls.
I need a room for Mr. Cabrini.
He'll be staying for three or four days.
- Very well.
- Thank you.
Tommasini, how are you?
- Get settled, and I'll see you later.
- All right.
And now...
Mr. Cabrini can only stay
four days at the most.
I have a reservation for that room.
Yes, just a few days,
until we find him a place to stay.
Will I have my usual room?
- Of course.
The spaghetti is ready.
- And the chicken.
- All right.
What would you like?
The kitchen's closing.
- What do you have?
- Do you know what time it is?
We're supposed to close at 9:30.
- I didn't know.
- Spaghetti or soup?
- It doesn't matter.
- Do you have coupons?
- No, I just got here.
- You'll have to pay me later, then.
Very well. Thank you.
Coming in this late?
You're working too much, sir.
It may surprise you, but waiting
tables is exhausting work.
Can you imagine serving
a hundred meals, just the two of us?
Not to mention lunch.
Ninety, a hundred.
I've done 150 on occasion.
Then, when I get home,
I have to start all over again.
My wife's not there,
so I have to manage on my own.
Our little boy is in the hospital,
so she's staying with my mother.
Two months and they still
don't know what's wrong with him.
The local doctor always said
it was an ear infection.
Then we took him to a specialist,
and he said it wasn't.
Is he in pain?
How can we be sure?
He's only a few months old.
He cries and spits up
everything he eats.
I'm sorry.
- Spaghetti is up.
- Excuse me.
Of course.
Good evening.
Please don't get up.
Mr. Tommasini
asked me to tell you
that in the morning you're to report
to the plant and ask for Bertinotti.
All right. Thank you.
Number 17, please.
Thanks. Good night.
- Wake-up call at 7:45.
- Okay.
- I'm calling Milan.
- All right.
Number 30.
39. Thanks.
Number 24.
Excuse me, I have to be at the plant
tomorrow morning by 8:00.
There's a bus at 7:30.
It'll get you there by 8:00.
I'm going out.
Good night.
If I don't take it,
there are ten others who will.
They're going to promote me
to specialized worker.
What are you afraid of?
You think I'm just going to disappear?
Good night.
Who is it?
- Hello?
- Your wake-up call.
Oh, thank you. Sorry.
Excuse me. I'm supposed
to report to Mr. Bertinotti.
Second floor.
- Mr. Bertinotti, please.
- He'll be right here. Have a seat.
Have a seat.
Paging Mr. Padellaro.
Salvatore Clementelli is
needed urgently at PS3.
Please come in.
Mr. Bertinotti
is busy at the moment.
Meanwhile, here are your ID cards.
Excuse me just a moment.
Come with me.
Can we come in?
Excuse me.
I told you,
only your daughter can come in.
If all the employees brought
their families to work...
They won't wear
their protective eye gear.
They've been working like this
for too many years.
They have a different work ethic,
and it goes back generations.
Just think: At first, when it rained,
they wouldn't come to work.
- You're kidding.
- Everything stops here when it rains.
They don't have an industrial mentality,
and there's nothing you can do.
We need to start all over.
With the new generation, who knows?
Hello.
Last night, on Via Enrico Toti,
or on Via Garibaldi,
or at the Splendido Theater,
a wallet containing 5000 lire
and other important papers
was lost.
Whoever finds it is welcome
to keep the 5000 lire
but is requested to return
the papers to their owner.
Children, how many times
do I have to tell you?
When you come into church,
you mustn't talk or run
or laugh or spit!
You must pray.
Keep still, children.
Go back to your seats.
What can I do for you?
- I'm looking for a room.
- Come in.
Come in, please.
When do you need it?
- As soon as possible.
I'm staying at the plant's hostel,
but I don't know how long I can stay.
Everything's full right now.
There's that bed in the corner.
It might be available in a few days.
Come and I'll show you another room.
This is available right now,
but it's a single.
It goes for between
10,000 and 12,000 a month.
This one even has a nice terrace
with a view of the street.
You can get some fresh air.
- How much is it?
When the plant opened it was different,
but now it's hardly worth it.
They've wised up
and hiked up all the prices.
Things cost the same as in Milan now,
and some things even more.
Before I got transferred, I'd have a little
left at the end of the month. Not now.
All things considered,
it's not really such a good deal
to come work down here anymore.
Maybe if your family
comes with you.
A lot of them bring their wives,
but it's a heck of a life.
They can't handle it.
The people down here aren't bad.
They've always been hungry,
so it's only natural
that when they see a little
cash going around, they want some.
You know there are school
teachers working in construction?
With the first money they set aside,
they start building a house.
They don't care if they have
to abandon it halfway through.
They're happy just having four bricks
one on top of the other.
They eat bread and lemons
and save their money
to pay off debts.
They plant oranges
and tangerines,
but mostly lemons and tangerines,
because they're fast growers.
In a few years, as soon as
the orchard starts making some money,
they leave the plant and go
to live on their plot of land.
It's not that they're lazy.
They do their work.
They're just a little crazy.
The sun's real hot,
and they never have a chance
to blow off steam.
Want a cigarette?
- No, thanks.
- Take one.
- No, I just had one.
I was one of the first
to come down here.
You should have seen it.
It was full of Algerians back then.
They'd bring their lunch
wrapped up in a rag.
Now they all carry briefcases
and look like executives.
They've moved up in the world.
It's amazing.
Wait till you see them.
It only lasts a week,
but they party enough to last all year.
You should see the getups
the women put on.
They don't even talk,
so no one will recognize them.
What are you honking about?
Just get off your mule?
You won't catch me
driving around here.
Who lets them drive? They'd be
better off driving bumper cars.
Hey, idiot! Watch your step.
I'm not wearing clogs, you know.
Keep together
or we'll lose each other.
If we get separated,
meet up later at the car.
Coming through.
Stay back, knucklehead.
Hey, guys, you gotta watch out.
Look what I found.
She looks like a beached whale.
Leave some for me.
I hope she isn't a man.
With this getup, who's to say?
He's been drinking again.
May I come in?
These are the papers, ma'am.
If he really can't take it -
- All right.
- I've signed them.
It's no use.
He'll just have to stop.
If an old man can't even have
a glass of wine, what's left to live for?
- Where are you from?
- Catania. How about you?
I'm from up north.
Poor thing, so far from home.
I'll give you a kiss,
just to console you.
- No, that's not allowed.
- It won't be any fun then.
You'll see. It'll be wonderful.
I'm not paying.
Have fun paying up!
Oh, go to bed!
You're a real piece of work.
Not you, sir. I meant the horse.
Who's there?
Quick, run!
Hey!
I saw you!
Where did you go?
Show your face, if you've got guts.
Come on.
Are you done
making a racket out here?
Aren't you tired of fooling around?
- They're the ones playing around.
Sure, it's their fault.
Go to bed. It's late.
Just a minute.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Very kind of you.
Blessed mother.
Here are the keys.
One for the apartment
and one for the front door.
Good. By the way,
I couldn't open the bathroom door.
It's a little tricky.
Come and I'll show you how it works.
When you open it,
you have to hit it hard.
Then give it a push, see?
Please have a seat.
Someone will be right with you.
Just a minute, sir.
This letter came for you
two days ago.
I always put the mail here.
You should always check.
Sometimes I forget.
You've been shopping, I see.
Mom, the door!
Excuse me.
Who told you that?
It was Marco, wasn't it?
That dirty, rotten -
What are you so angry about?
I'm the one who should be angry.
You mean you're not angry?
I'm insulted and disappointed.
I'm going to ask you a question,
and I want a straight answer.
Evening.
Do you still want to marry me?
Now?
How would we manage it?
I didn't ask you when.
I just want to know
if you still want to marry me.
There's no water.
Why not?
They turn it off on Sundays.
- Would you like a little of mine?
- No, thank you.
- It's nice and cold.
- Thanks all the same. Don't bother.
It's no bother. Come on.
Come on.
I'll pour it for you.
Good thing I kept a little aside.
That was smart, huh?
It's so hot.
Shall I pour a little on your back?
Nice and cold, eh?
You like that?
Thank you. That's enough.
In your letter
you wrote only of my father...
and said nothing about yourself.
How are you?
Are you keeping your spirits up?
Why haven't you written?
I sent my postcard two weeks ago,
and still no answer from you.
My address is the same as before,
at the pensione.
The last address I sent you.
My regards to everyone,
and a kiss for you.
Dear Giovanni,
I received your postcard
and your letter.
I hesitated to write back.
I wasn't sure you wanted me to.
When I received your letter,
I got scared.
I wanted to open it right away,
but I couldn't work up the courage.
I felt excited and happy
running up the stairs.
But then suddenly
that happiness frightened me.
I was afraid. I don't know why.
A thousand thoughts
raced through my mind,
most of them disturbing.
I even thought
this might be your last letter.
I admit I was afraid.
I had lost faith, and hope as well.
Now I'm sorry I thought ill of you.
I went to see your father.
He's fine,
and he sends you his love.
In the evenings he sits in front
of Mrs. Seminari's open door.
They keep it open because of the heat,
and this way he can watch TV.
At least it keeps him
from going to the bar.
In other words, the reacting gas,
that is, the ethylene,
mixed with air and an inhibiting agent,
passes through
an exchange chamber,
where the mixture is heated
and then sent to a reactor.
My dear Liliana,
the heat here has become unbearable:
up to 140° in the sun
and 113° in the shade.
Only the classroom
at the plant is bearable,
because it's air-conditioned.
I bet it's hot up there too.
Do you still go dancing at night?
I've stopped going.
There are no dance halls here.
But that's not the only reason.
I was used to dancing with you.
I'm not comfortable with other girls.
On Sundays I don't know what to do.
I just wander around aimlessly.
Besides, without my motorcycle,
I can't really go anywhere.
Write me when you get the chance,
because it's nice to get home at night
and have the lady at the pensione
tell me I have mail.
Regards to my father
and everyone else.
And a kiss for you.
Dear Giovanni,
it's been so many days
since you left.
Over two months.
I don't go dancing anymore.
I don't want to go to the Speranza
and see all our friends.
I don't want them asking about you...
with those insinuating smiles -
you know how people are.
I'd be embarrassed.
We have so many memories
from that place.
You could say that's where we met,
when I used to accompany
my older sister there.
I was 1 5 or 1 6, remember?
You were just back
from the military.
I've never told you this,
but the first time
you asked me to dance,
I said no because I didn't know how.
I had my girlfriends
teach me at home,
and every night after that,
I hoped you would ask me again.
How many memories since then,
good and bad.
Ever since you left,
I cherish even the bad ones.
At times all those memories
made me want to cry.
But I didn't want to cry.
I wanted to be strong.
So I would try to feel resignation,
just in case
you decided not to come back.
I tried to forget you,
to erase you from my thoughts.
But now, thank goodness,
everything has changed.
Those sad thoughts seem so far away.
What beautiful letters
you write, dear Liliana.
You're so good at expressing yourself.
I'm not as good,
and I often can't say
everything I feel.
But I'm sure you understand me
just the same,
because the feelings you express
are the same ones I feel.
You speak for us both.
You know, Giovanni...
perhaps your trip
was good for us both.
I think the distance helped us
understand a lot of things.
We've been sweethearts for so long.
So many years.
More than sweethearts -
you know what I mean -
but we've never really spoken...
the way two lovers should.
We each kept
our thoughts to ourselves
and were content
just being together.
But perhaps our being together
was becoming a mere habit.
Perhaps we didn't realize
we were each still alone.
We're much closer now.
I realized it when I thought back
on all our time together.
I feel as if we're starting
all over again.
It's like reliving the same feelings,
but as if we're somehow different,
somehow better.
Hi.
It's me, Giovanni.
No, nothing. No reason.
I felt like calling you.
How are you?
No, nothing.
I just thought I'd call you.
It's Sunday and it's half the rate.
How are you?
It's cooled off a bit,
but a storm is gathering.
What are you doing?
I have to go to work now.
My bus leaves in 15 minutes.
I don't feel like working today.
I'd rather stay home.
They could do without me
for one day.
- Three minutes.
- Thank you.
Maybe I'll call again next Sunday.
But write me anyway, okay? Bye.
THE END