Hey, hey, hey,
hey, slow it down.
Dear Mr. And Mrs. Andrews.
Mr. And Mrs. Baldwin.
Dear Lieutenant
and Mrs. Franks.
Dear Mr. And Mrs. Peterson.
Dear Mr. And Mrs. Lupo.
I'm sure you've never received
a letter of this nature before,
and I'm also quite sure
you'll be surprised
by the circumstances
under which I'm writing it.
My name is Alex Chivescu,
and I'm a junior,
soon to be a senior at
Eagle Creek High School
in Rochester Hills.
My parents moved to Michigan
to go to college here,
they divorced when
I was two years old
and I have not heard
from my father since.
My mother is a nurturing
and caring person
who inspired my love
of learning.
This paper says
you're a doctor.
Well, sort of.
This is more
than a piece of paper, Alex,
this is why I came
to this country.
It's why I've studied
so hard.
Education is like a magic key
to open any door.
With it, anything is possible.
Can I go to a school
like this someday too?
Absolutely, absolutely.
Your education is going
to be even better than mine.
You'll go to a great university
like... Harvard.
Is Harvard the best?
The very best.
Then that's where I'll go.
You'll have to work hard.
I will, I promise.
You'll see.
You make me so proud.
So proud.
Perfect,
what do you think?
I think I want one too.
You can get a head
start on that.
You do your homework
while I make us some dinner.
Okay.
You hungry?
Yes, I'm starving.
Good.
Um, my teacher said you wanted
to see me, Mrs. Thomas?
Yes, Alex, you know your
mother's friend Miss Carson?
Hi, Miss Carson.
Hi, Alex, why don't
you have a seat?
Alex, I'm sorry to have to be
the one to tell you this,
your mom's been
in a car accident.
She's in the hospital.
But she's got good doctors
taking care of her
and I'm sure she's
going to be fine.
Can I see her?
Can I go in?
Not yet, hon.
They'll be moving her
to a regular room
in a couple of days and you
can talk to her then, okay?
Is she gonna be okay?
She's going to
be fine.
Come on, in you get.
You know, Alex, we can visit
your mom as much as you want
once she's out of
intensive care.
Would you like that?
Okay, good night.
I'll see you
in the morning.
Miss Carson?
Yeah?
Could you leave a light on,
please?
Of course I can, honey.
It's going to be okay, Alex,
you'll see.
Okay, I bought some groceries,
made soup and casseroles;
you won't have to cook
for a while.
Oh, thanks, Ellen,
you've been so helpful,
especially with Alex.
Here, have a seat.
All right.
Would you like me to stay
with you and Alex tonight?
No, we're fine.
You sure?
It's okay.
You be a good boy and take
care of your mom.
I will.
You know what?
I'm going to make you
some tea before I go.
Want to help me, Alex?
- Sure.
- Okay.
My mother suffered
a serious head injury
from a car accident and
developed bipolar disorder.
When she was on her medication,
she was able to work
as a professor and things
were mostly normal.
But the medication
had harsh side effects.
The drugs made it harder
for her to think clearly.
Mom, I'm home.
She hated that so she
stopped taking them.
Mom?
Then she spiraled down,
couldn't work,
and became neglectful
and abusive.
Mom, I got my report card.
Are you okay?
I have a headache, Alex,
leave me alone.
Okay.
I'll leave it here so you
can sign it later.
Have a seat, Alex.
Your mom had to go back
to the hospital.
What?
What happened?
She just had a little setback,
but the doctors are taking
really good care of her
and she'll be home
as soon as possible.
Now this is Mrs. Edenger.
Hi.
Hello, Alex,
nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
I'm from Child Protective
Services.
Do you know what that is?
Well, we find nice people
to take care of children
when their parents can't.
So while your mom
is in the hospital...
you'll stay with a family
who live near here.
Why can't I stay
with Miss Carson?
Well, she won't be able
to take care of you
for as long as your
mom is going to be
in the hospital this time.
See, this isn't so bad.
Please don't make me
stay here.
It's just for a few weeks, 'til
your mom gets better, okay?
Please don't make me!
Alex, I need you to be
a big boy.
Let's just sit down
right here.
I've got to go
and talk to your foster mom.
Maybe you can unpack
your suitcase.
I'll come check on you
sometime next week, okay?
It's going to be okay, Alex.
When my mother was
taken away from me
I felt alone, abandoned,
and I was terrified that I
would never see her again.
I will never forget
the first time
I was put in a strange home
with people I didn't know.
Days felt like weeks,
a month without my mom
felt like a lifetime.
Mom!
Please don't leave me
again, Mom.
Please!
I'll try not to.
I'll do my best,
okay?
There were times when my mother
returned from the hospital
that I thought I had
my life back,
but it never lasted for long.
Mom, come on,
it's Christmas!
Mom, come on!
Mom!
Mom?
Can you leave me
alone please?
But it's Christmas, Mom.
I have a present
for you.
I made it myself.
Please not now.
My mother struggled constantly
with the symptoms
of her condition
and the harsh side effects of
the drugs she had to take.
Even when I was home
with my mom
it often felt like she wasn't
really there.
Mom.
Mom?
Can't you see I'm looking
for a job?
I need some lunch money.
Your lunch is supposed
to be free.
You didn't fill out that paper
I brought home from school.
I can't get free lunch
until you do that.
I'll do it later.
What about lunch today?
There!
That's all I can do!
I don't have a job,
I don't have money!
There was never enough money,
and I always worried that
we'd have enough food
or that my mom would be
able to pay our rent.
It wasn't easy, but I learned
to fend for myself.
Open this door!
Do you hear me?
This is what I get for taking
care of you
and feeding you,
devoting my life to you?!
I pay the rent here!
You open this door
right now!
I'm going to kick it in, Alex.
If you don't open
this door right now
you're going to be so sorry!
Hey!
Hey, what's going on
in there?
What?
Look, lady, how many times do
I have to come down here?
If you don't keep it down,
I'm gonna call the police.
You don't have to do this,
let me go back to my apartment.
I'll... I'll calm down.
I'll be fine, okay?
Just let me...
Please...
I don't want to go.
I... I... I can't do this.
I'll be okay.
Oh, there's my son,
don't put in front of him.
My mother was taken away
from me many times.
Sometimes my mom was
taken away for weeks,
other times for months.
She'd be hospitalized
and put on medication
and I'd end up living
with strangers again.
After a while,
she'd return to stability
and I'd be placed
back in her care,
but it always felt precarious.
I lived in fear
because I knew that a life with
my mother could never last.
Before long,
she'd go off her medication
and everything would
fall apart again.
I felt bad for my mom
because she couldn't
take care of herself
let alone take care of me.
When I was 16
I left my latest foster home
and returned to live
with my mother.
Fortunately for me,
our apartment was located
in the Eagle Creek
High School district,
one of the best in the state.
It wasn't easy
coming in as a junior
after the semester
had already started.
Your transcript is certainly
impressive, Alex.
I mean, one point below
a perfect score on your ACT.
Wow!
I mean, considering how many
schools you've attended,
your GPA is especially
remarkable.
Yeah, I, ah, I moved a lot.
Well, you keep this up and
you're well on your way
to getting into a top school.
Any idea where you'd
like to go?
Harvard.
Well, that's a lofty goal,
but one I think you can reach.
Now, look, you're going to have
to keep up your grades.
I will.
I made a promise.
Okay then.
I'll do my best to help you
keep that promise.
That needs to be
much better.
This is a nice start.
Exceptional work, Alex.
- You need to buck up.
- He got an "A."
All right, people, listen up.
The midterm assignment for this
semester is a 50-page paper
on an aspect about government
that you will choose.
Okay, okay, don't worry.
You can work in groups
of up to three people.
Hey, new kid.
Nice work in Rowe's class.
- That guy never gives an "A."
- Yeah, it's like his thing.
An "A" represents perfection,
and I've never seen
a perfect paper.
I'm Lucy, this is Danny.
Alex.
We were wondering
if you wanted to work
on the midterm with us?
Really?
Yeah, I mean Danny here is
a straight "C" student
so he'll be tons of help.
Hey, you should
talk, Picasso.
All she cares about
is art and poetry.
Social studies isn't her thing.
You can see what you'd be
getting yourself into.
I mean, neither one
of us is a brain like you.
Not a problem, when do
you want to start?
Do you want to meet at my house
on Saturday, 10:00?
10:00?
You know I sleep 'til noon
on Saturday.
Fine, 11:00.
Alex?
Sounds good.
Okay, but I'm going to be in
a coma for the first hour.
You're always in a coma.
Eagle Creek High
became everything to me.
I immersed myself in studies
and found compassion and
support from my new friends.
When chaos reigned at home,
the school became
a refuge for me.
Mom?
What are you doing?
I'm sick of these medications,
the side effects are
making me worse!
I can't focus,
my... my head is throbbing.
- I can't think!
- Stop it.
Please!
- Mom!
- It hurts!
But you know what happens
when you stop taking them!
I don't care anymore!
We really lucked out
with you, Alex,
we might actually do
all right on this paper.
We're going to get an "A."
You sound pretty sure
of yourself.
We have to.
I've got to maintain a 4.0
to have any chance
at getting into Harvard.
Harvard?
Right, and I'm going
to play shortstop
for the Detroit Tigers.
So you think
I'm delusional?
Yeah.
I don't.
I'm 1,000% positive
you can do it.
Mom?
I'm home!
Mom, there's no food!
I'm gonna get going,
my mom and I are going
to an art show.
Whoa, check this out,
crazy lady, 9:00.
Alex!
What are you doing here?
You should be home!
I've been looking everywhere
for you!
Why do I have to track
you down?
I had to come all the way
over here, why?
Calm down.
You don't tell me what
classes you're taking
or what you're doing
after school!
Nothing!
Mom, don't do this to me,
please!
Don't you dare tell me what
to do, I'm your mother.
You respect me!
Ah, excuse me, Mrs. Nistor?
Ah, did you stop by the office
and get a visitor's pass?
What?
No.
I'm sorry,
it's school policy.
Wanna come with me?
You wanna come?
Alex, wait!
Leave me alone!
Alex, please can
you talk to me?
There's nothing
to talk about!
My mom is crazy, okay?
Well, what's wrong with her?
Well, she's sick,
and she can't help it.
We can't afford insurance so
she can't get good treatment.
They hospitalize her
when it's a crisis
and when she's on her own,
she just can't cope.
If you knew what she
used to be like
before she got sick...
She has a PhD.
It kills her when her mind
can't function the way it did.
That must be really hard
for her, and you.
I think I know what
you're going through.
Oh, I doubt that.
My father's a
recovering alcoholic.
Before he got sober, he was
completely unpredictable.
- Sorry, Lucy, I had no idea.
- It's okay, he's good.
He's in a program and
he's doing really great.
He's my dad again.
What are you going to do
about your mom?
I don't know.
I mean, I want to save her,
but I don't know how.
Sounds pretty stupid,
huh?
No, it sounds heroic.
What happened?
I'm sorry, Alex, your mother
couldn't pay the rent.
You've been evicted.
- Where is she?
- Hospitalized.
She went off her meds again!
I told her she's got
to keep taking them
but she won't listen.
I found an emergency
foster home for you.
Great, my fourth!
Well, hopefully your mom will
stabilize in a couple of weeks.
Aww, what's the point?
She'll just go off her meds,
go crazy and wind up
right back in the hospital!
I understand how frustrated
you must be.
- No, you don't!
- Yes, I do!
Now, I've made arrangements
for someone to come
and take these
into storage, okay?
Just pick out a couple things
that you need
and I will take you to
your foster placement.
My mom was always being
taken away from me.
And while my social worker
helped keep me fed,
clothed and sheltered,
the cycle of instability
started to take a toll.
For six years I had been
in and out of foster homes,
my mom in and out
of hospitals.
I kept telling myself that
someday she'd get better,
be like her old self again
and stay that way,
but I finally had
to face reality;
it just wasn't going
to happen.
If anything was going
to change
it would be up to me
to change it.
I just, I can't take it
anymore.
The depression, the rants,
the constant uncertainty.
Nobody should have
to live like that.
What exactly are you
asking, Alex?
I'm asking to terminate
my mom's parental rights.
I have the right do
that now, I'm 16.
Do you fully understand
what that means?
Means that I don't
have to be afraid
of her hurting herself anymore.
Or me.
It doesn't mean
I don't love her.
Let's begin.
Alex, these attorneys are here
representing your mother.
The court doesn't allow her
to be present
during your testimony
so that you may speak
freely and honestly.
Do you understand?
Very well, let's proceed.
Alex, explain to Judge Brady
why it is
you want your mother's
rights to be terminated.
Please believe me,
Your Honor,
this was the hardest decision
I've ever had to make.
I love my mother;
she was a role-model
for me when I was little.
I got my curiosity and love
of learning from her.
But she's a very
different person now
and if I'm put back in her
custody, the circus will go on.
The circus?
The craziness.
Being evicted
from our apartment,
not having enough food,
police being called by neighbors
because of her screaming,
going in and out
of foster homes.
Do you understand
what this means, legally?
Yes, ma'am.
It means that,
according to the law,
I won't have a mother anymore.
Alex... how could
you do this?
I'm sorry, Mom.
Well, your mother's testimony
didn't help her case.
The judge has granted
termination of parental rights.
You won.
No, I didn't.
Nobody won.
You're 16, Alex,
finding a permanent placement
for a teenager, I'm sorry.
You'll be living here now.
What about school?
Well, you can stay
at Eagle Creek.
Umm, the orphanage has a driver
who will transport you
and the school district
will reimburse them.
So I guess it's official now.
What?
I don't have a family anymore.
All right, here's an
information packet.
As long as you accept all the
rules here, you'll do just fine.
Rules?
There's no fighting, no loud
music, lights out at 10:00.
But I usually stay up
studying later than that.
Well, you'll have to have your
homework done by 10:00.
I have five or six hours
of homework a night.
Well, we could possibly
make an exception.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
It says here we're not allowed
to have a checking account.
That's correct.
But I need mine so I have
a safe place to keep
what I earn from my job
at the bookstore.
No, no, no, no, you're not
allowed to have a job, son.
I've never lived in an
institution like this before.
This is different for me,
but maybe I'm different
from the kids you're
used to dealing with.
I work hard and
I'm highly motivated,
I'm saving money
for college.
Don't you want kids
to come out of here
and go on to make something
of themselves?
That's what
I'm trying to do.
All right, but that does
not mean you are free
to come and go as you please.
Okay.
Oh, one more thing, do
you have a cell phone?
Yes, sir.
All right, hand it over, you're
not allowed to keep that.
But I won't be able to stay
in touch with my friends.
Well, it's a security issue.
Phone please.
Hi.
I'm Alex Chivescu.
What kind of name is that?
Romanian.
But I was born here
so I'm American.
Yeah, I was born here too,
people still call me Mexican.
Hey, hop in, Alex.
How do you know
my name?
Oh, I've heard all about you.
- You have?
- Hmm, let's just say
you don't exactly fit
the profile around here,
you know what I'm saying?
Listen, this is a long drive
to Eagle Creek.
Why don't you hop up front
here with me?
All right, buckle up,
my man.
By the way, I'm Henry.
Can you let me out here?
Well, we're not
at your school yet.
That's okay,
this is good.
Your friends don't know
where you're living, do they?
No.
Okay, well, I'll pick you back
up here after then.
That would be great,
can you come at 5:00?
Sure thing,
5:00 it is.
Thanks, Henry.
Wooo!
Check it out,
we got an "A."
That's capital "A," baby!
Thanks to Alex.
We should celebrate.
Do you guys want to come
to my house and order pizza?
I can't.
I have something to do.
I'll catch you
guys later.
Later, dude.
Ahh, my first "A"!
I love that guy.
Oh, my God.
Hey, Henry, thanks
for picking me up.
It's so stupid!
I hate this crap.
I mean, who cares
about "X"s and "Y"s?
What's the point?
You know, it's really not that
hard once you get the basics.
Yeah, well, I'm never
gonna get it!
What, you win all these?
Yeah.
What's this one for?
It's a National Merit
Scholarship.
And what's that?
It means I get a scholarship for
$2,500 when I go to college.
2,500 bucks?
What if you don't go?
Do you get to keep
the money?
No, but I'm definitely
going to college.
Man, kids like us don't go
to college.
I will.
My mom told me
a long time ago
that education was like a key
that could open any door.
What are you,
some kind of brain?
Yeah, I guess.
I mean, I could help you.
I tutor kids at school
to make extra money,
I'd tutor you for free.
And why would
you do that, huh?
Make sure I don't
beat you up?
Yo, I'm just messing
with you, man!
Yo, I could tell you
was kinda scared!
Yeah, well.
Hey, man, I can't
have guys thinking
I'm an easy target, you know?
You wanna have a look
at that equation?
Not really.
Come on, I'll show you.
Open it up.
Where'd you start?
It's right over here,
right?
Look what
I ran across today,
"A Tale of Two Cities."
You remember?
You used to read this to me
when I was little.
"It was the best of times,
"it was
the worst of times,
"it was the age of wisdom,
"it was the age of
foolishness,
it was the epoch of belief..."
I've been in the system
since I was five,
how 'bout you?
Since I was 10.
Newbie.
So, what's the deal
with your parents?
Dad gone, mom crazy.
Same as me, man.
We could be brothers.
Your dad's not around either?
Hell no.
I don't even know
who my dad is.
So why is your mom crazy?
She's a crackhead,
your mom on dope too?
No.
What's so funny?
It's just being on drugs
makes your mom crazy, right?
Not being on drugs
makes my mom crazy.
I don't get it.
She's sick.
She needs medication
but she hates taking it.
That sucks.
All right, 8 ball
corner pocket.
All right, pressure's on.
Oh, I'm so good.
Now who's going to school,
professor?
Rack 'em up.
- Fight, fight!
- Take him!
- Yeah, yeah!
- You got him, you got him!
Good!
Fight, fight, fight!
Come on, man, you're
on top of him!
Fight, fight, fight, fight!
Come on, come on!
Carlos, what are you
doing, man?
- Let him go!
- What's going on?
That's enough, get up!
Hey, that's enough!
Back up!
Now you know the rules!
Carlos, I warned you
about this.
But he was trying
to steal...
No, no, no, no, no,
no excuses.
Both of you get
to my office.
Now!
Carlos!
What's going on?
They're kicking me out,
sending me someplace
with more supervision.
Probably be some
kind of lockdown.
- No, they can't do that.
- It's my third fight.
That jerk Feldman won't
even listen to my side.
All he cares about
is the rules
so I told him what he could
do with his stupid rules.
Ahh, Carlos!
I'm gonna
miss you, bro.
I'm gonna miss you, too.
Won't be missing your
algebra lessons, though.
Stick with it,
you can do it.
- Yeah, right.
- I mean it!
Don't give up.
Don't you give up either.
Harvard?
Man, that's gonna be cool.
Hey, man, check it out.
My dad let me borrow
the car.
Why don't you hop in,
we can give you a ride.
Oh, that's okay.
I've already got a ride.
All right.
Your friends?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Alex.
Hi, Alex.
Something wrong?
Is it my mom?
Your mom's okay.
But I'm afraid we have
some bad news.
Due to budget cuts, the
school district can't afford
to transport you here
next year.
And I've spoken to the director
at Mercy Point
and unfortunately they
cannot cover the costs
of driving you either.
What does that mean?
Where will I go to school
for my senior year?
You'll have to attend a high
school closer to the orphanage.
No!
My counselors, teachers
and friends are all here!
Alex, I am sorry...
Don't you understand?!
This school is the only real
home I've ever known
and now it's being
taken away, too.
It's not fair!
Alex!
I'm sorry, Alex.
I tried, I really tried.
Apparently there's some rule
against me driving you
on company time.
That's not fair, Henry!
Changing schools, it could
keep me out of Harvard!
Man, that school was
everything to me.
I know how you must feel.
No, you don't!
You have no idea
how it feels,
I've worked so hard
for so long
and now you're just going
to take this away...
You just hold on!
Now maybe I didn't
go to college.
Hell, I didn't even graduate
from the 8th grade,
but I sure know what it feels
like to be disappointed!
And I know what it
feels like, Alex,
to have something
taken away from me.
I'm sorry.
Henry, I didn't mean
to take it out on you.
Yeah, you did.
Now you may be
all book smart
but you sure ain't
people smart.
It's just that's all I have.
Listen, that's not true.
That's not true,
you got friends.
You got people
who care about you.
You know,
I might not be much,
but you got me, too.
Come on, let's get out
of here.
It's just I don't know
what to do, Henry.
They're taking school
away from me.
Listen, man, you got a good
head on your shoulders,
so think.
You can come up
with a plan.
Use those famous smarts of
yours for something other than
trying to keep people
from getting close to you.
Think, man.
You're right.
Social services is
never going to help me.
Maybe not.
Come on, let's get back.
What's the rush?
You going to make me
drive, Henry?
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
All right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
slow it down.
You've reached Mrs. Edenger
at children's welfare,
please leave a message.
Mrs. Edenger,
it's me, Alex.
I just wanted you to know
that I'm through
waiting for you to
find a family for me.
I'm going to find
one myself.
I'm sure you've never received
a letter of this nature before
and I'm also quite sure
you'll be surprised
at the circumstances
under which...
My mother is a nurturing
and caring person
who inspired my love
of learning...
I understand it
is a great emotional
and financial burden to take
a 17-year-old into your home...
...straight "A"s,
advanced-placement college
classes
and a strong desire...
My most fervent dream
is to be accepted
into Harvard University.
You have no commitment to me
after I graduate from
high school next year...
...fail to respond to
my urgent and dire...
...as of now I am a ward
of the state...
My social worker has kept me
fed, clothed and sheltered
but she doesn't understand how
desperately I want to stay
in the same school
for senior year
where the counselors who know me
will help me apply to colleges,
where the teachers who
know me will help me
write letters of
recommendation and advise me
and where my friends will be
there to support me.
I'm a good kid in
a bad circumstance.
I need a home.
Thank you.
Alex Chivescu.
Hey, any replies
to your letter yet?
Yeah, all negative.
Look, there's something
I want to tell you, man.
I kinda asked my parents
if you could live with us
but they said no.
It's nothing personal.
It's just, y'know, they both
work such long hours.
It's okay, I understand.
Sorry.
Hey, don't be.
I asked my parents too.
They actually
considered it but...
You guys, it means a lot
to me that you asked.
Thanks.
I got a letter
for you, bud.
Dear Alex, my wife and I were
deeply moved by your letter.
We'd like to meet you
and discuss
the possibility of
sharing our home.
Yes!
I made you some
chocolate chip cookies,
I hope you like them.
Wow, thank you, Mrs. Franks,
they sure look good.
They're our son Paul's
favorite.
He's at Camp Lesjune
for basic training.
Takes after me, I'm a
lieutenant in the US Army.
We live off base.
Our house is modest
but we have an extra room
now that Paul's gone.
Did you get a lot of responses
to your letter?
No, sir, only you
and Mrs. Franks.
And you can call us
Julia and Richard,
and don't you dare
call him sir.
We might be in the army
but we do not run our house
like a barracks.
Well, I'm sure you want
to know more about me.
Ever done drugs?
No, sir.
- Drink?
- No.
Been in trouble
with the law?
No.
That's all we need to know.
You mean that's it?
No more questions,
no thinking about it?
We took Paul in
as a foster child
and ended up adopting him,
we have no reservations
about taking you in, Alex.
Well, thank you, Mr. Franks,
Mrs. Franks.
I mean, Richard and Julia.
Wow.
All right, hustle up!
This will be the kind of home
I never had.
After everything
I've been through
it feels like I can
finally relax.
That's a good thing.
What if it's too good
to be true?
Don't overthink this,
Einstein.
Just let yourself be happy
for once.
You deserve it.
Hi, Alex.
Hi.
Mr. Feldman told me you
were here, is everything okay?
We stopped by because we
wanted to tell you in person,
I'm being transferred
to a base in New York.
We leave in two months.
Oh.
But we want you to come
with us.
You'd take me with you?
Of course.
You have a home with us
as long as you need it.
I don't know what to say.
Say yes.
I'm really grateful
but moving away would
defeat my whole purpose
and it's the reason
I wrote the letter.
I want... I need to stay here
and graduate from Eagle Creek,
and I can't leave my mom.
At least when I'm here,
I know she's nearby.
We understand.
Is there another family
you can stay with?
Oh, sure, definitely.
I am so sorry, Alex.
We really wanted this
to work out.
Good luck, son.
Bills, bill and bill,
there you go.
Do either of you know someone
by the name of Alex Chivescu?
Nope.
Who is he?
I don't know, let's find out.
Oh, goes to Eagle Creek High,
and he lives in an orphanage.
How sad.
He's looking for a foster
family to live with
during his senior year.
He's going to college
after that,
his father
is out of the picture
and his mother has
psychiatric issues
and lost custody of him?
We need to meet him, Mom.
- Jen.
- Mom.
Look, this isn't like
your stray dogs or cats
or wounded birds...
Or turtles.
Exactly, that you brought
home since you would walk.
I mean, this... we don't
even know this kid.
It's probably a scam.
Dad, can you imagine that the
guts that it took for him
to write this letter?
He's turning to total strangers
because he has nobody else.
You don't even
know him, Jen.
Well, I know that he's got to
feel scared and desperate.
I have you guys, this kid
doesn't have anyone.
We need to help him.
Bringing a stranger into
our home is serious business.
We need to learn
more about him
and then we can talk
about it.
All right.
I'm going to go check
if he's on Facebook
and add him as a friend.
Okay.
Our daughter has a very
big heart.
Yeah, well, I know where
she gets that from.
But, Suzanne, this has to be
a thoughtful discussion.
There's too much at stake
for our family
and for this young man.
I know.
He's on Facebook!
Let me see.
He's kind of a nerd in a nice
way but a total brain.
He looks friendly, Mom.
He does, Jim.
Oh.
So when can we meet him?
Now hold on, you two,
come on.
Dad, I'm going to be going
to college in the fall.
You and Mom are going
to be here all alone.
The empty-nest thing is going
to be really hard on you.
Or liberating.
No more loud music, no more
giggling girls at sleepovers.
Very funny.
I suppose we could just meet
the boy, Jim.
Yeah, I suppose we could.
Yay!
That's all I'm promising.
- Sure.
Thanks.
I didn't realize I'd be
so nervous.
Me neither.
Mr. And Mrs. Bante?
Yes.
Alex, nice to meet you.
It's nice to
meet you, too.
You want to grab a seat?
Sure.
Okay.
Don't forget your coffee.
Well, Alex, we spoke
to your school counselor
and obviously you're
an excellent student
and that's just great.
But Suzanne and I want to know
some more things about you.
Of course, sir, um, here.
Here's some of my awards,
my high school transcript,
and these are letters
of recommendation
from some of my teachers
and my social worker.
Alex, you're not applying
for a job.
If we do this,
we're not asking for you to
live with us for a year or so,
we're inviting you
into our home
to be part of our family,
permanently.
Permanently?
- That's right.
- Yeah.
So you really need
to think about that,
and so do we.
Okay?
Yeah.
Hello?
Yes, Mr. Bante.
Thank you, sir,
thank you very much.
I can be ready then.
Okay, okay, bye.
Hey, Alex, you almost
ready?
We're parked out front.
I'm all packed.
Where are the rest
of your things?
I thought you said
you had a lot of stuff.
Well, this is it,
everything I own.
Okay.
Great, we'll
give you a hand.
Here I'll take that,
Alex.
We'll meet you in the car.
I don't know what to say,
Henry.
I wouldn't have made it
without you.
No need, my man,
this isn't goodbye.
You'll come and see me?
Of course!
Still gotta finish teaching you
how to drive.
Your parallel parking needs
a lot of work, you know.
I know.
Here we go.
Hey, Alex, it's nice
to finally meet you.
I'm Jen.
It's nice to
meet you too, Jen.
Come on, I'll show
you to your room...
actually it was my old room.
Well, I don't want to take
your room.
Oh, no, it's okay.
I moved into
the smaller guest room.
I leave for college
in a couple of weeks
so I won't be home
that much.
It will be your job to look
after my parents,
make sure they don't party
too hard.
Two years ago I was
diagnosed with Lupus.
I have flare-ups sometimes.
Last spring, I had this
really bad attack.
I had chest pains and
I couldn't breath,
and I collapsed on
the bathroom floor.
Must have been scared.
Oh, I was terrified.
Fortunately, my parents
found me right away
and I had to go to the hospital
for like a "kazillion" tests
and my mom and my dad,
they never left my side.
I can't imagine what
it's been like for you,
not having your parents around.
I mean, it's just
the way it is.
I don't even remember
my dad,
but my mom was incredible.
Before she got sick
she was on her own,
raising a kid, somehow still
managed to get her PhD.
Well, now we know who you got
your brains from.
Yeah.
Disturbed?
The Black Keys?
Sierra?
Okay, no way!
What?
When it comes to music, we were
definitely separated at birth.
Oh, I wish I wasn't going
to college so soon;
you are going to be
a cool little brother.
Just don't be bratty.
Deal, as long as you're
not bossy.
Hey!
Welcome to the family!
So don't worry about me,
'cause I found a really nice
foster family
and they have a daughter who
already feels like a sister.
I'm still working hard towards
getting into Harvard.
My counselor thinks
I can do it.
Remember when I made that
promise to you?
I'm going to keep it.
I miss you, Mom.
Love Alex.
Hey, there he is.
Good morning, Alex.
Morning.
Eggs and toast okay?
Thanks, Mrs. Bante.
You know, Alex, you don't have
to call us Mr. And Mrs. Bante.
What would you like me
to call you?
I don't know,
Jim and Suzanne?
Whatever you're
comfortable with.
Yeah.
Well, I'm comfortable
with Mr. And Mrs. Bante.
Okay.
Grab a seat, Alex.
We never had a chance
to talk about your chores.
Chores?
Yeah, everyone pitches in here,
so when Jen leaves for school,
you'll take over her jobs.
Well, what kind of jobs?
Well, for example, today's
trash pick up day,
so when you leave the house,
you'll put the cans out.
When you come home
from school,
you'll put them back
in the garage.
We'll talk about the rest
later, I gotta run.
Bye, honey.
Bye.
I will see you guys tonight.
Scrambled?
Ah, yes, please.
Great.
I can't take it,
it's too much.
And a bunch of chores, too.
And Mrs. Bante came
into my room,
tried to get me to talk
to her.
Well, imagine that.
Okay.
Remember to check
your side mirrors.
She wants me to talk
about my feelings.
So what's the problem?
I don't know, they're not
my parents, you know?
I wish they'd stop
acting like they are.
Why?
Because I don't need that.
You don't need it,
or you don't know
how to handle it?
I wish they'd just let me
pay rent and leave me alone.
Really, Alex?
I mean, is that what
you really want?
Hey, Alex,
how was school?
Fine.
Learn anything
interesting today?
Not really.
Can I have an apple?
Alex, this is your home,
you don't have to ask.
Y'know, when Jen was in senior
year all she wanted to do
was bring her friends over
and...
Mrs. Bante, I got lots
of homework to do.
Yeah, sure, go ahead.
Come in.
Hey, Alex, I just wanted
to say good night.
Good night, Mrs. Bante.
Alex, I want you to know that
you're part of our family now
and the thing about
families is
that we can talk
to each other.
So if there's anything
you want to say...
I'm fine, Mrs. Bante.
Good.
But if you ever do want
to talk,
Jim and I are ready
to listen.
Okay, um, all right,
good night.
Night.
It's a miracle he turned out
as well as he did.
He doesn't know how to do
the most basic things
and his social skills
definitely need some work.
I think his upbringing
was a lot more difficult
than we realized.
Well, at least he
talks to you, Jim.
He barely says a word
to me.
Don't take it personally,
honey.
It's not about my feelings,
it's about his.
I can only imagine what
it must be like for him.
I just wish that he felt
safe enough with us
to open up and share
what he's going through.
Suzanne, he barely knows us
and he definitely
doesn't trust us, not yet.
Well, what if he never can?
Well, that's up to him.
He'll let us past his defenses
or he won't.
There has got to be something
we can do to help him.
All we can do is treat
him like what he is,
a member of this family.
Jim, are we crazy to have
gotten into this?
Probably, but no matter
how it turns out
I'm not going to be
sorry that we tried.
You?
No.
Good.
Call us as soon as you
get there, okay?
I will, Mom.
And I know you're going to be
busy, but please stay in touch.
Okay.
Go.
Keep an eye on them;
don't let them get
into too much trouble.
It will be okay.
They're not the coolest parents
in the world
but they'll be there
for you
just like they've
always been for me.
Wouldn't ya know it.
I finally get a brother
and I have to leave.
Are you gonna miss me?
Nah.
Ha, very funny.
See you at Christmas.
See ya.
But, Mr. Bante, I don't need
you to give me money
to buy Christmas gifts.
I don't want to be
a charity case.
Don't give me that, Alex,
you're not a charity case.
Don't assume what people
feel for you is pity.
It might actually be
something else.
Alex, come here.
Listen to me.
I want to be clear here.
You've had a rough time,
life hasn't been fair,
but it wasn't your fault.
Now it's natural to feel
sorry for yourself,
but that's not going
to get you anywhere.
Look, we respect everything
you've accomplished,
but more so we respect
who you've become.
Now, I know it's been
hard all this time
with your dad not
being around,
maybe I can help you
with that.
Now what do you say we get
this tree in the house, huh?
It's a beauty, isn't it?
Hey, remember
this little guy?
Oh, yeah.
Hey, Alex, come on in,
decorating
the tree is the best part.
Oh, look, this is Jen's
Christmas ornament
she made in second grade.
Look at that.
Everything okay, Alex?
I, um, I got my report card.
I don't know if you guys
want to see it or not.
Absolutely!
Yeah, of course, we do!
Will you look at that...
straight "A"s.
Alex, that's great!
We're so proud of you.
Nice work, this calls
for a celebration.
Do you have an extra card
I could have for my mother,
Mrs. Bante?
Yeah, of course, Alex.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Would you help me
with the tree?
Yeah.
You know, Alex, if you wanted to
get a present for your mother
I could take you shopping,
pick out something nice.
No thanks, Mrs. Bante.
Well, if you wanted to visit
her, I could take you there.
I don't think so.
Alex, it must be hard spending
Christmas without her.
No, I've spent a lot of
Christmas's without her.
College girl's home!
- Hey!
- Mom!
Oh, welcome home, sweetheart!
Did Dad tell you how much
we missed you?
Only for the last 300 miles.
Good, good, well, let's
get you settled.
There's tons of food
in the kitchen.
It is so good to be home with
my folks and my little bro.
College is great
but the food sucks.
I'm so excited for mom's
Christmas Eve dinner tonight.
The turkey smells so good!
Believe me, you're going
to want seconds.
Jen...
how come you don't mind
sharing your parents with me?
It doesn't take anything away
from how they feel about me.
They have plenty of love
to go around.
It's just who they are.
But they hardly know me.
I mean, how could
they love me?
Because they do.
You're worth being loved,
Alex.
You know that, right?
Are you going to go see
your mom on Christmas?
No.
Or at least call her?
Do you ever talk to her?
I, um, I write to her.
Well, that's good.
What's this?
I don't send the letters.
Why not?
You don't know how angry
she was, Jen.
Especially when I went to court
to terminate her rights.
I abandoned her,
just like she did to me
only she couldn't help it.
Neither could you.
Well, I don't think
she'll ever forgive me.
Of course she will,
she's your mom.
She loves you
no matter what.
Come on, let's go.
Where to?
Let's go give your mom
the best Christmas present
that she has ever had.
Jen, I can't.
Come on!
- Come on!
- Jen!
Nistor, apartment 103.
Wait, wait, wait, Jen!
What if she freaks out?
Come on, Alex, we're here now,
you can do this.
No, no, no, I can't, Jen,
please, I can't,
I'm not ready to see her,
please!
Jen, please!
I'm sorry, Alex,
I didn't realize.
Do you want to leave
the letters?
No, this was a mistake
coming here.
All right, let's go.
- Merry Christmas, everyone!
- Presents
Come here quick!
All right, which one's mine,
which one's mine?
Well, well, it looks like Santa
was generous this year, huh?
Okay, I want you both
to open these first.
That's for you and...
Slow down.
What is it, what is it?
That's for you.
- Mom.
- Do you like it?
This is awesome!
I cannot believe that you
saved all my old t-shirts!
I did, I did.
There's one from your tennis
team, your debate club
when you ran for
student counsel
and a whole bunch of music
groups I've never heard of.
Me neither.
I cannot wait to put this on
my bed in my dorm room!
Oh, I'm glad you like it,
Merry Christmas, sweetheart!
Thank you.
Well, how about me?
- I made it.
- Yeah, right, thank you.
I hope you like it, think
of it as a family heirloom.
Something you can keep
forever if you want.
It's amazing.
The letters spell out
Harvard.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Jen, just give him
a minute.
This is a good thing,
he should be happy.
I think he is.
He probably never had much of
a real Christmas growing up.
I'm sure it's just a little bit
overwhelming for him.
Yeah.
Dear Mom,
I heard you're out
of the hospital.
I hope you're
feeling better.
Even though I haven't
seen you in a long time
I want you to know I think
about you a lot and I miss you.
Here's my number in case
you want to call sometime.
I hope you have a great
holiday, Mom.
Love Alex.
- Hello?
- Alex?
Mom?
How are you?
I'm all right, much better
being in my own place.
Is it nice?
Yes, yes, it is very nice.
Maybe you can come
visit me sometime?
Sure.
And, um, is it all right
where you are?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Are they good to you?
Very good.
Thank you for the card,
it's beautiful,
and it means so much
to me.
I wish you were here, Mom,
I miss you.
Merry Christmas.
Well, it all looks great.
Alex, we have a family
tradition.
Before we enjoy dinner,
we all like to share
what we're thankful for.
If you feel like it,
I hope you join in.
I'll go first.
I'm thankful for sharing
this special time of year
with the three of you.
I'll go next.
I am thankful
for my beautiful family,
especially its newest
member, Alex.
I'm grateful for my parents
who help me through
all the difficult times.
And my new iPad.
Umm, I'm thankful for...
having a normal Christmas.
Well, okay, I like that.
Let's raise
our glasses.
To a normal Christmas.
- To a normal Christmas.
- Normal Christmas.
Okay, let's eat.
I'm starved.
All right,
sweet potatoes, Mom?
Yeah.
Alex, pass the buns
around, please.
But, Mr. Bante, you didn't
need to buy me a suit.
Alex, you're not going to wear
a t-shirt and jeans
to your high school graduation.
And what about your
college interviews?
It's too expensive.
Hey, you let me worry
about that.
Hey!
You wanna go to prom
with us?
Are you kidding?
No, people go in
groups all the time...
Well, not everybody but...
Yeah, come on, dude,
it'll be a blast.
- What's the theme again?
- "It's a jungle out there."
Yeah, me Tarzan,
she Jane, you Cheetah.
Very funny.
No, seriously, will you go?
- Sure.
- All right.
Well, how are you feeling
about your Harvard interview?
It's coming up,
isn't it?
31 hours and 14 minutes.
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
Just remember,
be yourself,
look 'em in the eye, give
them a firm handshake, okay?
Okay.
Excuse me, I gotta
take this.
There you go.
Mom, calm down.
I can't
understand you, okay?
Okay, don't worry about it;
I'll take care of it.
Thanks for coming.
I didn't know who else
to call.
Not a problem,
what happened?
I don't know exactly.
I thought she was doing okay.
Now she's been evicted and
she's back in the hospital.
Okay.
This is why I'm always afraid
to let her back into my life.
Do the Bantes know
about this?
I didn't want
to tell them.
Well, I'm pretty sure
they'd want to help.
You okay, Alex?
I should have been
there for her.
I should have taken
care of her.
You're just a kid.
You couldn't take care
of her.
You need help.
You need to tell the Bantes.
Get them involved.
No, this is none
of their concern.
Yes, it is because
you're their concern.
That's the problem, Henry.
They want to
help too much.
Because they care about you.
That's just the way moms
and dads are, man.
I already have a mother.
Oh, Alex, it's not
the Bantes fault
that your mom couldn't
take care of you.
You gotta stop blaming them.
Everybody needs somebody.
Stop trying to act like
you're different.
Alex, where have you been?
We've been worried
sick about you!
Are you all right?
It's my mom.
I need your help.
It's going to be okay.
She's in room 304.
We can go up anytime.
Do you want us to go in
with you?
Well, if you don't mind,
I'd like to go in alone.
Of course,
we'll wait here.
Just take
as long as you want, okay?
Dr. Reynoldson, you have
a call at Nurse's station 2.
Dr. Reynoldson, phone call
at Nurse's station 2.
Mom?
I'm sorry I never came
to see you.
I wrote to you.
I don't know why
I didn't send them
but I want you to have
them now.
I'm sorry about
everything, Mom.
Alex.
Should we go talk to him?
Not right now.
He needs a little time
to deal
with whatever
happened back there.
His Harvard interview
is tomorrow.
Come on.
Come in.
I brought you some
hot chocolate,
put little marshmallows
in it.
Jen likes it that way.
I thought maybe
you would too.
Thanks.
Here you go.
Anything else you
need, Alex?
Anything at all?
No.
Okay.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Bante.
Sorry for what?
You tried to do all
this nice stuff for me
and I couldn't handle it.
I wasn't used to it.
I know.
You thought I was trying
to take your mother's place.
You do all the things
that I needed her to do.
I felt guilty about thinking
you were better at it
than she was.
Alex, your mother couldn't
give you what you needed
but I know she tried
as hard as she could.
How can you be so sure?
Because I know how much
a mother loves a child,
how much we want
to protect them.
And if we're unable
to do that
it's because it's out
of our control.
It's the worst feeling
in the world.
I know your mother loves
you, Alex, I know it.
And so do I.
Rise and shine, buddy,
today's the big day.
Suzanne pressed your suit,
picked out a tie,
and we're having
French toast for breakfast.
Alex, why aren't you dressed?
Yeah, your interview
is at 11:00.
It's all the way
across town.
I'm not going.
What?
I mean, what's the point?
I've just been
kidding myself.
Why would Harvard
take a kid like me?
I've been in and out of
seven foster homes
and nothing ever works out
so why would
this be any different?
I'll tell you why,
Alex,
because you have a gift.
One that you inherited
from your mom,
and her of all people
would hate to see you
throw that gift away.
Did something happen
at the hospital?
If you talk about it
maybe we can help.
Please.
When I was 10 and I saw
her in the hospital
for the first time,
you know what really got
to me?
It was her hands.
At the time, I called
them her alligator hands
because she had them
curled up tight
against her chest
like this.
I saw those same hands again
last night.
After all these years,
nothing's changed.
She's never going
to get better
and it's always going
to be the same.
You can't give into that.
But what if I end up
like my mother?
Alex, that is not going
to happen.
I just wanted her to tell me
I could do it.
She knows you can do it.
And so do we.
You know what, Alex,
we haven't asked a lot of you
but we're asking now.
Go upstairs,
put that suit on
and let's get you
to that interview.
A firm handshake, right?
That's right.
Alex Chivescu?
How do you do?
Please come on up,
we've got lots to talk about.
Well, how'd it go?
I gave it my best shot.
That's my boy.
Come on.
Jim, it's here!
It's here?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Now, before I open this,
there's a couple things
I want to say.
Okay.
First, I respect you both,
Mr. And Mrs. Bante,
more than anyone else
I've ever known.
Second, I used to think
that this was everything.
Now, I still hope I get in
but if I don't,
I'll go somewhere else
because the thing is I already
have what matters most...
...a family.
Alex, open it.
I made it.
What?
I made it!
- Yeah!
- He's going to Harvard!
I gotta call Jen and Lucy
and Danny!
Go, go, go!
He did it, Jim!
No, we did it.
That's good,
right, I got this.
Okay, squeeze in, you guys,
squeeze in.
All right, Eagle Creek grads,
say, "2009."
- 2009!
- Whoo!
That's good, that's good,
one more,
one more, 2009.
2009!
Oh, man!
I don't believe it,
I'll be right back.
I can't believe you
guys came!
My man, of course
we came!
We couldn't miss
this party!
Listen, you need any help
with that college algebra,
you know who to call.
Yeah, how've you been,
Carlos?
I'm good.
I'm working, I'm going
to community college.
Yeah?
Taking classes in welding.
You ought to see this guy
with a blowtorch.
I'm awesome.
Yeah, I bet you are.
Um, excuse me.
I am so proud of you.
Thank you.
Thanks for coming, Mom.
I wouldn't miss
this for the world.
I read your letters.
It really means a lot to me
that you wrote them.
I'm sorry I never
mailed them.
No, Alex, I'm sorry.
I'm so...
I'm so very sorry
you had to go through
everything you went through.
It wasn't
your fault, Mom.
Thanks for that.
Okay, anyway...
I got you something.
This is on loan until you get
one of your own from Harvard,
and I know you will.
I... I just
want you to know
that whatever I become,
whatever I achieve
is because of you.
I love you, Mom.
I love you, too.
Congratulations.