Give these corpses a
little respect, Uncle.
Oh, God.
Go.
- Oh, God.
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, God.
By the Grace of God. God..
Sakina.
No, it's someone else.
Uncle.
Uncle, come here.
What do we do about her?
We can't bury a Hindu corpse.
Uncle. Hey, Uncle. What
are you doing, Uncle?
Have you gone mad? Leave it. Leave it.
- Let me.
Leave it.
- Let this snake die.
Finished everything.
Uncle. She has died.
- Don't stop me. Let me go.
How will you kill the dead?
I've gone mad.
It would be better if
they don't leave tomorrow.
How long would we have
stayed hidden in their hovel?
Sameer sir sheltered you for
the entire month in such times.
If you could, you would
have left for Delhi with him.
Yes, I would have. You too.
He has kept with so much difficulty.
He stays in such a big house. Pool park.
What danger does he face?
Don't forget that he had given
you money to buy the rickshaw.
Yes, but I had paid him back the money.
What have they done? Oh, God.
Everything is lost.
I had told you to fix
another lock in the house.
So, it's my fault.
Idiot.
- Oh, God.
You filthy idiots. I'll deal with you.
What will we do now?
They had burnt everything.
Where did this come from?
Henna.
What? - Of my
henna. - Don't lie.
Since Nazo has been born, you
haven't gone to apply henna.
I didn't give Sameer sir his money.
What? Why did you do that?
You think you are very clever.
You're not worried about the house.
Were you going to mend the broken sofa?
You wanted to sit on the sofa. Sit now.
Sit, you idiot.
I told you so many times.
I told you so many
times that we will go..
..and see the house once. But no.
What if they had killed you?
- That was better than this.
She forgot to add salt again.
Get the salt.
Once the riots stop, the
vegetable vendor will come.
Otherwise, we would have to
make do with onions and potatoes.
What are you thinking
about these days? Give me.
No one was knocking.
I think she has gone crazy.
'But anyone can actually..'
I'm going to Ritesh's house.
Dear, learn a little, though
you are not going to school.
Am I taking this bag for nothing then?
This is an astounding statement
on the security situation..
..in Gujarat, especially
the remote areas..
..which are away from the media gaze.
These English newsreaders. Filthy liars.
'The police officers we met at the..'
These rogues were silent
when Hindus were killed.
Keep watching. The entire world will hit them.
- Yes.
Brother Sanjeev, what will happen now?
I had told you to give one
Black Label (brand of liquor)..
..bottle to that officer.
You didn't listen to me.
And now, you say, ''Brother
Sanjeev, what will happen now?''
''What will happen now?''
If they come here with the warrant..
There is no F.I.R. How
will they get a warrant?
If you waste time in eating,
that fellow will go away. Get up.
It's 8 o'clock. Make something good.
Are you going out?
- No.
I have a habit of standing
in the middle of the door..
..and twirling the scooter keys.
Come on now.
Today, a truck with vegetables
is standing at the square.
Buy some good vegetables.
What happened? Again
you are lost somewhere?
Sister. Sister. Door. They
will kill me. Open. Open.
Open the door. Open the
door. Open. They will kill me.
They will kill me. They will cut me.
He will keep repairing the
entire world's instruments.
But this dead TV won't
be repaired till I die.
Everything can be heard.
The TV is meant for watching.
You will know more about the world..
..if you develop the habit of listening.
I keep listening to the hazy
sound of the TV and your snores.
If you listen carefully, then
you would find rhythm there too.
But you don't have such intellect.
Yes, you are right.
I'm serving you since 40
years for my little brains.
Stop meddling with this
box. Prepare for the morning.
Where is sugar candy for tomorrow?
- It is full.
This is full?
It is full according to
the people who will come.
You'll see that more
people will come tomorrow.
Every Thursday night, you
never stop from ordering..
..for worldly things, moving
furniture and spreading carpets.
And I too obey like a fool.
And who comes on
Saturday? Only your doctor.
Wake up, Mr. Khan. Open your eyes.
It's not enough to keep
listening in such times.
Now, why are you worried?
I will break the three into
six if more people come.
I don't know how I will
sing without Mr. Khan.
I'm really feeling very guilty.
- Forget it.
Now, we've decided, right?
I just wish we didn't had
to watch that CD today.
Really? I feel finally
there will be some closure.
We are leaving this city.
What more closure do you want?
What's the use of watching
the store getting robbed?
Listen, what time did
you call the movers?
They said they will
come at 8am tomorrow.
But while talking to
me, it finally hit me.
We are actually moving.
You always have a delayed
response to everything, right?
Watch out.
Are you blind? - Hey. - Get
out. - Hey. - Will you kill me?
I had just serviced and brought it.
Please. Please. Please.
If you come at such speed..
ls it okay, Sameer?
First, you hit and then you say 'okay'.
Brother Sameer, forget about our speed.
This is bound to happen
when ladies drive the car.
It happened for the first time.
First time or last, but I have
to bear the expenses. Oh, you..
Look here, everything is bashed up.
Just look at this.- Oh, God.
This will not solve my problem.
Go eat snacks at Mehta's with this.
Okay. Okay.
Come on, now, who is
going to argue with him?
It wasn't my fault. I swear.
It wasn't my fault. Just..
I know, darling. It's okay. Sit.
Did you see this? It was our
mistake, but he paid for it.
This is what I call smartness.
She was very beautiful.
Let's go.
Kavita, hurry up.
- Give the receiver to the inspector.
Hi.
- Hi.
Did you meet your aunt? Come on now.
Hi, Sameer. - Hi. -
The CD has not come yet.
Raman has been waiting
since the last two hours.
Typical.
- Sit, sit.
Who has my CD?
- No fun. Go back to your room.
Come on. Okay.
- Mummy.
I had talked about the
payment. What's new?
I too want to watch see.
- No, its not children. I'm sorry.
Please. - No. - I should remind you
that you are returning what's mine.
You can't imagine these children
recounting those horrors.
The activists here are saying that
the options may be just as bad.
What did you hear?
They beat everyone, unrobed
them, raped and killed them.
Burnt them. - Your daughter
was in it too. - Yes, she was.
ls Kesar going to come or not?
What was her name?
- Afsana.
I don't know.
My brother and I were sitting outside.
The poor man was lame in one leg..
..but when he broke the net
and went out, he was stabbed.
She was standing behind,
so, the girl was stabbed too.
Whether you kill or cut..
Kill or cut. Here and there..
Swords stabbing. Petrol fumes.
What are you doing?
Slowly.
'When they burnt our houses, they..'
Weapons. Even children
were carrying weapons.
The elders carried rifles.
We wear saris and speak
Gujarati, that's why we escaped.
Everywhere here..
- And turn off the TV and close the curtains.
Look at the walls. The
walls are spoiled too.
There are iron marks on the walls too.
What did they do? They pulled
us out from inside and..
Sister. Sister. Open the door.
They'll kill me. They'll kill me.
Open.
These rogues have finished everything.
They did not leave anything.
Do you think Mehul's gang has done this?
They hate you since the
affair and the Toll gate.
He'll do so much.
What is that?
Nothing. It's a pendant.
Your friend's. Jyoti. Ask
her. She will surely know.
Why? Mehul is one of her
relatives, that's why.
Where are you going?
To Munna. I'll come at 10.
Hey.
Listen.
Be careful.
Greetings to God.
Oh, my God.
Come on, wake up.
What kind of medicine am I having?
Listen, call Subhash.
He will be at the hospital
right now. Talk to him at night.
If you want, shall I arrange
for Mr. Shafiq to talk to you?
I want medicine, not an amulet.
- Then bear it.
I'll bear it better if you prepare
some poppy seed juice for me.
''He led my hand with
his own selfish reasons.''
''My hand. The evening
plays hide and seek.''
''He led my hand with
his own selfish reasons.''
Have this.
All right. My God.
The Muslims are being killed ruthlessly.
Aren't you grieved about that?
Mr. Karim, I'm sad because
a man is killing a man.
Listen, get me the
'Surmandal' from above.
I've to give it to little Maya.
Mr. Khan.
None of your disciples are Muslim.
Have you every thought?
- It's God's will.
Maybe the Muslims don't respect music.
It's not respect.
No Muslim has escaped here
in a radius of ten miles.
You have your medicine
and sleep peacefully.
And I stay awake the entire night.
Why? What are you scared of?
- Yes, why will I?
Everyone is God's child here.
Here Hindu and Muslim
stay happily together.
Go. See who is it?
Come. You will live long.
- I was going to Mr. Joshi.
I thought I should meet him. How is he?
He feels very sleepy.
- That's good. Delicacies for you.
Greetings, Mr. Khan.
- Live long. Live long.
How are you? - Absolutely
fine. - Show me.
Brother Karim was telling that..
..you get very sleepy
with these medicines.
He is jealous.
- Yes.
He stays awake the entire night
worrying about his welfare.
Yes.
- And mine too.
And listen, this..
- One minute.
This is for your daughter. Maya.
Mr. Khan, how can I take this?
This is your childhood souvenir.
So what? It has not become old like me.
- Oh, no.
I will bring Maya and you
can give it to her yourself.
She will be very happy.
- That's fine too.
I'll leave.
- Live long.
His blood pressure is high.
- ls he worried about something?
Doctor, you know that
no one except you came..
..in the Saturday gathering
in the last three weeks.
How can I tell him why
other people don't come?
Come.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
You know, I just can't
get over it, friend.
How did they come to know that
Sameer was a dormant partner?
Because big brother's watching.
What?
- Did you read?
They have got databases of
all Muslim-owned businesses.
Yes, but..
Apart from some bank
papers and legal documents..
..Sameer's name shows nowhere, friend.
Ketki, leave it. Now, I
don't want to ask all this.
Yes, leave it.
I had promised Sameer
that I will learn this.
And now see. Now, it's the last day.
He is really fond of tea.
ln his family, all are fond of it.
ln fact, father says that
Muslims are allowed more tea..
..because they are not allowed alcohol.
But Sameer drinks.
And I have never seen
him pray or anything.
Really, he is so not a Muslim.
- But he is, Ketki.
He is.
Somewhere on the list in
big bold letters is written..
..Sameer Arshad Sheikh.
I was not joking when I said
that big brother is watching.
Tell me honestly, Anu.
Do you ever regret marrying a Muslim?
No.
When we got married, I knew
it was not going to be easy.
But this last month has taken that
to a completely different level.
What do you think?
Delhi is going to be
much different from here.
Your brother is also
there. ln U.S. of A.
His life is hardly a picnic, friend.
So what you are saying is that
no matter where I go I'm done for.
What I'm saying is, this is
your home. Just leave the rest.
It is easy for you to say.
You don't have to hide if some
Hindu fundamentalist kills someone.
If some lslamic extremist
bombs someplace in the world..
..we've to hang our heads in shame.
What?
We?
I don't know 'me' became 'we'.
- Tea is ready.
Coming.
Sister, take some more.
You can never say what
happens at such times.
No, it's very expensive.
Mother!
- Hey, can't you see? You are running blindly.
Did you hurt yourself?
Are you hungry?
Come, come with me.
Come.
Are you a Muslim? What is your name?
- Mohsin.
Take this. Eat it.
Aarti.
- Coming, Father.
'Did Kesar return?'
Later, okay.
Come.
No, he has sent a child.
Where is he?
Come. Come.
Go to father. There is
no need to be scared.
He can't even stand.
- Come here. - Go.
What is your name?
Mohan.
He is so small. What work can he do?
Come here.
Go and wash it.
Amen.
- Amen.
Come. Let's go.
Father did so much for our neighbours.
But so few people came at such a moment.
Yes, dear.
More people would have come
if it was an ordinary priest.
Well, I'm pleased
that you came at least.
He doesn't go anywhere. But
he insisted to come here.
It was my duty to
come. Don't worry, dear.
God is the giver.
Father was exactly like
you. Hardly any earnings.
A house which may
topple over at anytime.
And he would say that God is the giver.
If you need anything, ask
me unhesitatingly. Okay?
I should leave now.
- Have some lentil pilaf at least.
No, I will eat something after
I'm done with my medicines.
Live long.
The idiot saw us and left.
Who will take two oldies?
- You have decided not to see.
Will you go to Hirabaug society?
- No.
What happened?
- What will happen? Shook his head.
Maybe he doesn't want
to go to that side.
Why will a Muslim go to that area?
lsn't his life dear to him?
- You are too much.
Do one thing, wait here. I'll
go and look at the corner.
How much is this sugar candy for?
- Rs.20 per kilo.
Rs.20 a kilo.
- Leave it, Brother.
It's enough if you get
sugar candy at such times.
Mr. Khan.
Mr. Khan, come. Come. I
told you to wait there. You.
Come. Sit. Let's go.
Rs.20 a kilo. -
What? - Sugar candy.
Have you found the prices these days?
And you wanted to help Sakina.
What would you give
her if she really asked?
Your old sitar or the broken TV.
Stop him. Stop him.
Hey. - Stop him.
- Hey. Stop him.
Why are you stopping him?
Look. Where are you going?
Mr. Khan. Listen. Hey.
Where is the mosque?
- Where are you going?
The Wali mosque was here.
Hey. You would have been
hurt. What are you doing?
The Wali mosque was here.
- They broke it in the riots.
Shut up. You have lost your mind.
No, I may forget. The mosque was here.
It wasn't here.
- How can it disappear like that?
It was on the other road.
It wasn't here. Come. Yes.
Sit. Sit.
Let's go.
Munira.
Jyoti.
- I can't believe it.
It was worse. I'm cleaning
it since yesterday.
Do you know who has done it?
- No, I was at my aunt's.
It's good that you were not here.
When did this happen?
Don't think about it
now. What's the use?
Take this.
I brought hiding it from mummy.
You knew that the kitchen will be in this condition.
- No.
I didn't think that it
would have been so burnt.
Give it to me.
- Go, keep it outside.
We've to go to apply
henna in the evening today.
Are you coming?
Have you lost it?
Munira, look. You need money
now. They are very rich.
Just the bride and a few more. That's it.
- No.
5000 each for both of us.
5.
Truly?
- Yes, so.
They have to pay if they
get married in such times.
Oh, God. I'll place it outside.
But I don't have henna. -
What? - I don't have henna.
Don't worry. I have got lots of henna.
You've even thought of this.
Then? I'm your best friend, right?
Then tell me who did all this?
I told you I don't know. I
was at my aunt's. Leave it.
Okay, when will we return
if we go to apply henna?
Hanif is coming at 10.
- We are sure to come by 9.
Oh, come.
People have been raped, killed,
burnt alive for no fault of theirs.
Anu, there are always
two sides to a coin.
If those people hadn't
started this violence..
..things wouldn't have been
this bad. No offence, Sameer.
I can't believe you're
justifying this madness.
Tell me. You tell me.
When your maid eloped
with your jewellery..
You didn't go torch the whole
Chara community, did you?
Hey guys. Please. Come on.
You're leaving tomorrow, right?
And can we change the topic please?
And in any case, we too
have our own share of loss.
A loss that's covered by insurance.
Let's go. We've got tons to do.
- Sit.
Hold there. That must be Rahul.
Hail the Goddess.
We've come to take donation
for the Goddess Lakshmi temple.
It's okay.
That's it. Such a big
bungalow but you are so stingy.
Goddess Lakshmi won't be
satisfied with this much.
My dear, whether Mother Goddess is
appeased or not, but you should be.
You are right.
Name?
- Sameer.
Sameer what?
Desai.
Mother Lakshmi will
shower you with wealth.
You too.
Look, madam, you didn't turn
into a Muslim after marriage..
..but this gentleman has turned Hindu.
And that too with your surname.
You don't know how many times..
..I've silently thanked his
parents for naming him Sameer.
Actually, I didn't even know that..
..Sameer was a Muslim
name until I met you.
It's in Arabic.
It means the companion who
talks to you in the evening.
These days.. quite the whole day.
Too scared to open his mouth.
There were many. Everyone was shouting.
They burnt my mother and brother too.
They even killed my younger
sister, aunt and uncle.
You saw all that?
Some even brought swords.
They killed aunt after unclothing her.
But they didn't disrobe the men.
And where were you?
I was hiding in the dustbin.
Then?
Then uncle Yusuf took
me to the survival camp.
But I want to go to father.
Where is your father?
I don't know.
Father had gone to the
shop when they had come.
Maybe your mother escaped.
Had she worn a black stole?
No, my mother only wears saris.
Come here.
Come.
Let me see.
My name is not Mohan, but Mohsin.
Mohsin in the kitchen
and Mohan outside. Okay?
I don't want to return to the camp.
Will you stay here as Mohan?
Will you go to look for my father first?
They had burnt you too.
'Brother, say something.'
What are you telling me to
speak? What is left now to speak?
Brother I really never knew.
You fool, you should have checked.
If we would have known that
the report is already filed..
..at the police station, we wouldn't
have looked like fools there.
But Barot had told me..
To hell with your Barot.
That DCP wants some scapegoat.
He will catch two-three
like you and put behind bars.
And the rest will go scot-free.
Brother, I know all the names.
- Oh, my God!
You fool, you must never be
a witness in this. Understood?
It is a rape case. You
will be in for seven years.
Because of you, even
I am trapped in this.
Get some water.
You are asking how did this happen?
There was lot of beating.
All women are safe here.
They are safe at the
society in the back.
The police came at 12 at night..
You enjoyed doing that?
Tell me. Tell me. You
can always tell me.
I was not the only one.
Are you bringing water
or are you digging a well?
I am scared.
I'm scared.
- Don't get scared. No one comes to the kitchen.
Sit here quietly. Sit here.
Okay? Nothing will happen.
I promise.
They did not think twice when
they saw these young girls.
They dishonoured them.
Those who don't have any honour,
how can they get dishonoured?
And do you have any honour?
'She is Shabana.'
- I mean..
Come inside.
I don't like to beat like this.
'Deven, are you coming now or
are you going to stay here?'
'Come on.'
Mohsin.
Oh, God.
Who is it? - Me,
Munna. - Who? - Munna.
Brother Hanif.
- Come.
Sit.
I was told about your uncle from Munna.
God will manage him.
I couldn't save my own.
I didn't know that such
a big riot will occur..
..when they came to burn our house.
But I somehow took
out uncle from inside.
And then he ran straight
towards the circle.
But the police asked us to
go towards the Patipara road.
But a bigger mob than that
was as if waiting for us..
..with tridents and
swords there. The rogues.
I didn't know what happened.
I had held uncle's hand
firmly. But I don't know..
Stop it, Lala.
I've seen more dead people
than you've seen live people.
Make the child sleep inside.
Look at her, she is so scared.
Look at her.
She doesn't let go of the
child even while preparing food.
She takes him along even
when she goes to the toilet.
What's the use of living like the dead?
I'll kill them.
You can think like that
since you were away.
But don't we feel like
finishing off the rogues?
Then let's go and kill
them. Let's go now.
Who will you kill? -
What? - Who will you kill?
I will kill Mehul first.
Mehul?
- I will tell him what a pile of ashes is.
The idiot. Fie on him.
Wait. - The rogues
have come here. - Open.
Hey! Hey! Wait!
Flow the water. Sir,
what are you doing? This.
Who is in uniform?
Sir, you.
- Then why are you asking questions?
And if you are really
interested in asking questions..
..then come to the police station,
you will get all your answers.
Drop this, why are you just standing?
Did you see?
Did you see how nicely
they are looking after us?
We store water in drums
to extinguish fire.
And these people.
And these people come and empty them.
Not anymore. I'll go mad.
- Listen.
Do you still have Suleiman's pistol?
Tell him. Who will he tell?
I would have saved uncle if I had it.
Suleiman had taken it long back.
- Henpecked.
The rogue has fled to Surat.
I just want a weapon
for today. That's it.
Have you ever seen a pistol?
I don't know if the
pistol is in the shop.
But uncle Altaf has the
key to Suleiman's shop.
Are you thinking the same as me?
Bring the pistol. Bring it.
And shoot me on the head.
Have you gone mad?
- Yes, I've gone mad.
I prepared bread in the
bakery my entire life.
What wrong did I do? What wrong did I do?
- The pistol..
Where is Halim?
Go home. There are riots going on ahead.
Go home. Run.
One day we must go..
Hey you small fellow. Hey you.
Come here.
- Come here.
Why are you in a hurry
and where are you going?
He had stolen those berries,
that's why he was running away.
Ask him his name. His name.
- What is your name?
Mohan.
And this Mohan?
- Mohan?
Bring him here.
- Bring him here.
Dear, do you know what punishment..
..they give to a thief in Saudi Arabia?
They cut off the hands.
They hang you upside-down and whip you.
Look, he got scared. He got scared.
Where is your house?
He is pointing there.
- Why are you standing here?
Run away before the police arrive here.
Go! He has been
standing here since long.
This is sick.
Look, she has got a Honda
waiting for her, friend.
Fatso, show me your face.
lf she had shown her face,
then these policemen..
..would have taken millions from her.
Stop. Stop. Stop. Rewind. Rewind.
Pause. Pause.
The person who ran into your car.
- What?
You didn't note down the idiot's number.
No. I was even smarter.
I gave them Rs.800
for damaging our car..
..and looting our store.
Great, Sameer Sheikh. Brilliant.
Hey. Enough.
It's not your fault.
- Of course, it is.
Can't you see it?
To begin with, your store was
looted because I'm your partner.
Well, yes. But I wouldn't have
had that store without you.
Yes, right. You wouldn't have
had that store without me.
Now, you don't have
that store because of me.
Look, friend. Think it this way.
You had to pay because Anu was with you.
This is the system here.
We live in such a country.
Didn't I give Rs.10,000 or
this CD which is mine. Tell me.
And that also just for five minutes.
I didn't pay because Anu was with me.
I paid because I was scared.
Hey Sameer. Come on.
I'm not going to let you
play the victim. Okay? Please.
Stop.
- Do you know what's being a victim?
Did you ever change
your name for any work?
Do you have to think twice before
praising a Pakistani player?
Do you ever have to
worry about someone..
..stripping down your pants to check your..
- Hey. Hey.
Come on. Come on. Don't
over react, friend.
Don't overdo this.
Didn't anyone strip-search
you? - But I could be.
And that terrifies me.
Sameer, we all have been
scared at some point of time.
Who are you?
Sameer.
You can thank my parents a
thousand times for naming me Sameer.
But I can feel the burden of that name.
Really?
And what happened when the person..
..who came to ask for
donation asked Sameer?
Then you should have said Sameer Sheikh.
Why didn't you say Sameer Sheikh?
Because I've no courage,
okay. I'm terrified.
What a way to live.
They got my store and I decided to run.
You know what?
We don't need to go to Delhi. Yes.
We shouldn't go to Delhi.
Seriously, Anu. Can we reconsider this?
Don't do this to me.
Please, don't do this.
15 days ago, you gave
me a million reasons..
..why this move is a good thing for us.
I hated the idea. Absolutely hated it.
And then I started convincing myself.
Now. Just now, you told
me how scared you are.
Do you think that after hearing
this I will want to stay here?
You are Sameer Arshad Sheikh.
And this isn't going to change anywhere.
We have our life packed in boxes.
And the movers are coming at 8.
I want to go home.
When did you come
from your aunt's house?
ln the morning today.
- When had you gone?
I don't remember. I
told you I don't know.
Shut up. Wear it silently,
otherwise you'll catch cold.
I won't spare the
rogues once I catch them.
Munira, feel happy. There
is a wedding in this house.
Your mood is okay. That's enough.
They know me. Come.
What was after that? I got lost.
I was lost myself.
I suddenly remembered the first
time I went to Wali mosque.
October..
1960.
It was a full moon night.
And it was surprising that
it rained the entire day.
And priest and I had sung
the Raga Malhar on the radio.
Then he told me that he will
drop me home. So, I went.
Then suddenly, he stopped his
scooter in the way at Wali mosque.
And started singing Wali's song.
The music echoes because
this heart stays there.
The mosque washed by rain and
glittering with moonlight..
I suddenly saw something moving there.
Do you know what was it? A mouse.
We three were lost in Wali's
poetry in the darkness of the night.
No one moved. Not me, not the priest.
And not even Lord Ganesha's mouse.
How will you think? They
were distributing letters.
That eradicate this mini-Pakistan.
People would come here
from Lahore in trucks.
My sister-in-law
and cousin had come..
Wali was from the South.
But he loved Gujarat so much
that he became one of here.
Whenever I would pass by his mosque..
..I would stop to read the prayers.
When I read in the newspaper
that his mosque was broken..
..then I found out
who Wali Gujarati was.
I knew.
I knew we were on the right spot.
The thumb like this.. One
minute. Lift your thumb.
What were you doing so late at night?
I was cutting gourds for
dessert for you and doctor.
All this is because of
this idiot television.
How do we turn it off?
- We've to go to the hospital.
The wound is not deep but
have to be sewn. Let's go.
Yes, let's go. Don't waste time.
Let's go.
- Mr. Khan, wait. We two will just come.
Come.
Come. Come. -
Careful. - Yes.
That's nice. Now, it looks
like a real henna ceremony.
Hardly, friend.
Do you remember Sonia's wedding?
Just for the henna ceremony,
there were 50 people.
I don't think so.
- So..
Aunt, Vineet and his friends had
given such a lovely performance.
ls it?
Just like Shah Rukh.
- Then you too do it.
Oh, God, I've so many plans.
These riots have ruined everything.
But where are we involved in that?
- It is one and the same thing.
Aunt, let's not take this too lightly.
- Yes, that's true.
Yesterday I received an
e-mail from my friend.
That had all the Muslim
rickshaw numbers to be involved.
Oh, my God. I am so scared.
What if they kill them?
Anyways, forget it, please.
Let's just have some fun, friend.
What are you doing?
- Oh!
She does not see properly.
No. - Come on. - I am
just getting done. Please.
Come on.
- Sister, come on. Come on, dance. Come on.
''What has happened
to me? Why am I lost?''
You are sure that you haven't
seen anyone entering my house.
lf you ask me repeatedly will
I say that I've seen someone?
''Your eyes are intoxicating
and your tresses are tousled.''
''What have you done to yourself?''
Hanif said that you'll know everything.
''I have met someone.''
Whatever happened, Munira?
We know that Mehul brother and
Hanif brother were never friends.
But this thing never bothered us.
''I met someone.''
Why do you start now?
You started it.
''I met someone.''
- ''You have met her.''
I think Mehul's gang has done this.
I don't know. People can
do anything at such times.
Come on, all of you take a
break and have some snacks. Come.
Go and get tea. Go.
Give to me. - No,
it's okay. - Munira.
Stop it.
Papa, why isn't mummy
serving food today?
My dear, your Mother has gone crazy.
Have you gone mad?
What are you doing?
ln the morning. you opened your
mouth and now you have become deaf?
I will beat you up again.
You wretched female.
Uncle Altaf will meet
you at Suleiman's shop.
I can't go leaving Zahira alone.
Hey. - Who is
it? - It's Goga.
Goga, what are you doing
here? Come, let's go home.
Goga.
- What? What yours?
He says that he likes
Preity Zinta a lot.
He is the son of the uncle who was killed.
- Come home. Come on.
Let him come with us.
How can he go alone without me?
Then you too come.
- Yes, you come too. Come.
Okay, if the neighbour comes and
sits with Zahira, I will come too.
It'll be good for me to leave home too.
Okay, come fast.
He is like this.
- Yes, since childhood.
He became like this after he
was wounded in the head once.
Does he know? - What? -
That his father has died.
How could I know if he knows or not?
Give me.
Hanif, when did you start?
Friend, I started this
since I was tensed.
Hurry up, sit. We've to return
soon. - Be careful. - Let's go.
Lucky, prepare four omelettes.
I will come in some time.
Some people carry on
like nothing happened.
Because they can.
- And we can't.
That's why we must leave.
Come, Mr. Sameer. After a long time.
Lucky's night has become double lucky.
Two delicious bun omelettes. -
One without chilli. - Correct.
Very good. Very good.
- Shall we pack it? It's getting late.
No, madam. Sit. Please sit.
Come, let's eat it piping hot here. Sit.
Lucky, how are you?
- Yes. Nothing, sir.
These riots have ruined our business.
I can't even ask the
shopkeeper for riot discount..
..when things are so expensive.
Don't worry. Your omelette is a
hit, forget about other things.
What can I say, sir? I've to
feed the entire army for free.
Just to stay here and that too alone.
But where is Chhotya?
He hasn't come since
the riots have started.
May God keep him safe.
Listen. We'll be fine in Delhi.
A fresh start is always a good thing.
- Yes.
Whatever doesn't kill
you makes you stronger.
Sir, if these people
had not started this..
..then the city wouldn't
have been like this.
It's in their blood to
riot. ln their blood.
We are being taught to tolerate.
And they are taught
to be fundamentalists.
Then Chhotya should be a fundamentalist too.
- Yes?
Chhotya, a fundamentalist.
That poor boy cannot even kill an ant.
But Chhotya is not like him.
I have seen many Muslims.
They are very strict.
I'm a Muslim.
- Stop it.
You crack good jokes.
I'm not joking. I'm truly a Muslim.
Will you stop it, Sameer?
Sir, such jokes are
dangerous at such times.
You can't say anything.
You don't know when.. Sir.
Come. Come. What will you have?
Omelette, scrambled egg or boiled egg?
Come on, wind up.
There is going to be commotion today.
And you two also move on.
One minute, sir, I am
just finishing this.
At such times, you must
not fulfil your wishes.
Come on. You had enough.
No, sir. We are going. ln
fact, we are leaving the city.
He likes Lucky's omelette, that's why..
For the last time.
Come.
What is your name you said?
My name is Anuradha Desai
and this is my husband Sameer.
Make Mr. Desai understand.
Don't try to act smart.
- Yes.
Go now.
Give this to Chhotya when you meet him.
Sir, I will tell you one thing.
I am not Mr. Desai.
I am Mr. Sheikh.
Sheikh? Then why did you lie?
I did not lie. My name is Sameer Sheikh.
And she is my wife Anuradha Desai.
Now, I know why you act so smart.
Come on, go now.
Yes, we are going.
Go straight to Pakistan
Come on, now wind up.
Why did you do that?
It just feels good. Very good.
Uncle Yusuf.
Mohsin. What are you doing here?
Come. Careful.
You said that father will
come to the camp to fetch me.
But he didn't come.
- How did you come here?
I ran away from the camp alone.
- Mad boy.
You shouldn't roam alone
at night. Come. Sit.
I'll go and drop you. Sit.
Uncle. Give me Suleiman's keys.
I know who broke Suleiman's
shop. They won't escape now.
Don't you understand?
Why do you act so smart?
Will the dead return?
Give me the key.
Wait. Wait. Drop him at
Sabur camp before leaving.
I can't go to the camp now.
Fear God a little. These things..
The poor boy is an orphan.
- Hurry up, then.
Come, Mohsin, he will
drop you at the camp. Okay?
I'll come tomorrow morning to meet.
- With father?
Come. Come dear. Come.
Drop him at the campo first.
I'm very scared.
- Don't worry. We have reached.
Wait. - Come, come.
- Open the boot.
Stop. Stop. Park here.
Don't be scared. Do you have
the spot on your forehead?
It's so late. Hanif will kill me.
- Wait, I'll see.. - Hey, come.
Hey, come here. Come this way.
At this time?
Sir.. sir, we are returning
home after applying henna.
License. Show me.
I have. I have my license.
We both had gone.
Okay. Okay. Come on
go. Don't waste time.
Thank you.
Mohsin, come here. Come.
Be careful of the broken glass.
Sit. Silence. Don't do anything here.
Who is it? Who is it?
It's us. Open.
- Munna? - Open.
We have come.
- We've left the rickshaw at the Red Door..
Careful..
Oh, God.
Who is he?
- What can I do?
Uncle Yusuf gave his
responsibility to me.
I have to drop him at the Sabur.
Hey. What is your name?
Where is that pistol? Where is it?
First, remove this garbage, after
that I'll find the secret cabinet.
The rogue Suleiman was very rich.
What's the use of riches?
He fled as soon as the storm started.
He did the right thing. It's
better than living scared here.
That's right.
- You'll say so.
You had run too.
I don't know how you got
comfort among the Hindus.
And you must have got good
comfort among the Muslims.
Look, the idiot named
his shop 'Parimal'.
What's the use of a Hindu name?
Friend, you can't do anything.
lf we don't get anything,
then I take up a weapon..
The place from where
weapons were procured..
..was in curfew the whole time.
And anyway, when you are
scared even to breathe..
..you don't think about weapons.
I thought a lot about
guns, pistols, bombs.
But I was reminded
of my mother the most.
But I couldn't do anything.
My body still reeks of burnt corpses.
I dream of blood. Their
burnt pieces of flesh..
I killed the rogue.
It's so late. Where
is your secret cabinet?
There is no secret cabinet.
He is fooling us. ldiot.
Got it?
Show me.
ls it real?
Yes.
It seems small, but it's real.
Be careful. It may contain bullets.
- Open and see.
See.
It doesn't contain anything.
They stabbed the boy and they
pulled the girl by her hair.
And I came running here.
Children are dying of hunger.
How will we satisfy our hunger?
Everything is over.
Everything is finished.
They sewed it and it's done.
Leave it. There is no need.
- Oh, no.
Nothing has happened to me. I'll do it.
- There is no need.
There will be meeting tomorrow.
What do you mean?
You were right. I was wrong.
Oh, God. It's of no use. It's of no use.
Mr. Khan.
What will happen to us if you lose hope?
The seven melodies don't
have strength enough..
..to face such hatred.
Where were you running to?
Wait here. I'll go and see.
'What are you doing?'
Come on from here.
Come on sit inside.
Go. Go. Go from here. Go.
Munira.
- What happened?
Don't say anything. Come
quietly with me. Come.
Tell me.
What happened?
The police are saying that
there are weapons in your house.
What?
- Come. Come. Come.
Weapons in our house..
Speak softly. Everyone
will find out at home.
Look, stay here till those
people are there. Sit here.
Make Nazo sleep here.
- Do you want anything?
Why don't they find those
rogues who had burnt our house..
..instead of finding weapons there?
- Softly.
Nazo will wake up.
You still won't tell me.
That's enough. Stop it.
Here are clothes. Change.
Whom are you saving by
remaining silent? Me or you?
God, leave it.
- It's easy for you.
Your house was not burnt.
But you're still
burning. What about that?
Look, Jyoti, tell the
truth. You were there.
I won't tell Hanif anything. I swear.
- My pendant?
My pendant..
What? What did you say?
My pendant. Mother has given me.
I've dropped it somewhere.
- You had come to my house.
What?
Hanif found your pendant.
You saw everything.
Why did you do this?
Mehul told you to.
What?
Tell me. Did you take
kerosene from my kitchen?
Or had you brought yours?
We just found one bullet.
And that one is big.
I'm telling you, it'll fit.
Done?
Friend, you were right.
Now, what will you do with this pistol?
The same I wanted to do the entire day.
I'll tell that idiot Mehul what fear is.
And what then?
- What then? I will go home.
Or whatever that's left of a home.
And if some mob comes home
and takes away your daughter..
What will you do then?
- I'll kill all. - How?
You will waste this one bullet on Mehul.
Look, I'm the one who
requires this pistol.
You've seen how the
police behave with us.
But your house was not burnt.
You know that my wife is pregnant.
One minute. I brought the shop key.
I cut the bullet to fit.
That's why I've the first
right to this pistol.
I told you in the beginning
that I need weapons.
What have you done for so many days?
- And what did you do?
You were hiding and
enjoying for one month.
Enjoying. I was hiding in
that hovel. I was scared..
Ask me what it is to live in fear.
Only I've right over the pistol here.
Yes. Everything is about you.
You have always been concerned
about yourself since I know you.
Shut up. How do you know
what he has gone through?
And how do you know
what I've gone through?
I do not smell of corpses
but that doesn't mean..
..that I haven't gone through anything.
- Leave it.
Anyway, Suleiman had given the
key to uncle Yusuf and not you.
He would have given
me, if I had been here.
The rogue has changed
his colour so fast.
You called him henpecked at first.
Yes, I said. So? - Hey.
You are no less. - Meaning?
Leave it. Everyone knows
who rules your house.
Yes, you take the pistol. As it
is, Munira is equal to 50 bullets.
You. ldiot.
- Leave it.
There was only one bullet.
Father.
- Don't be scared. Nothing has happened.
Come. Come here.
Shut up. Shut up..
- Police..
What is he saying?
- He says he will manage the police.
Then let him go.
- Have you gone mad?
They won't be able to make
him say anything. Let him go.
Okay, go. Distract
the police. Be careful.
Come, let's move from here. Come.
Come, let's go. Come fast.
Hanif, I can't leave Goga behind.
Come. He will look after himself. Come.
- No, you go.
I. Run. Run.
Come here. Come here. Yes
Where did the sound of firing come from?
He is dumb, but he can hear.
Sir, leave it. I will
ask him. I will ask him.
Where did the sound of firing come from?
From there?
No, I can't go leaving him.
From here?
- No, he is a child.
What? Yes! Yes, that is it.
Not a bomb explosion, but
the firing of the bullet.
Why are you looking down? Look up. Fool.
Hanif, run away with the child. Go.
Sir! Sir!
- There is someone.
Sir, let him go. He is my brother.
He hasn't done anything.
- He is your brother.
Both of you together are..
Wait, idiots.
Hey you, wait.
I say, just stop.
Hide here. I'll come to fetch you.
Who was he?
He was a Muslim.
Which side did he go?
- This way.
There is still time. Why
did you wake up so soon?
What happened? What happened?
I just realised something.
- What?
Every single box in this
house is packed with my fears.
So, what's the point of moving?
What do you mean?
When you said that I'm
Sameer Arshad Sheikh..
And this isn't going to
change anywhere. Anywhere.
But what if we are
scared again tomorrow?
Maybe. But this is our house.
So, just forget the rest.
Sorry for the delayed response.
Aarti.
Where did she disappear?
Will you play?