Four
(sending message - Mom)
(sending message - Sis)
(sending message - Ingrid)
(sending message - Lone)
There is your best line.
(New messages from the Falk.
Read them now?)
(From: the Falk.
I can't take it anymore. Feel like blowing my head off.
Does that make me a coward?)
Ok. That's fine.
Bye.
(Calling Mom)
(New message - Sis)
(From: Sis
I want to go home.)
I want to go home.
Come.
Bathroom?
(Turn off sound.)
She probably has company.
Doubt she will let me in tonight.
What will you do?
I'll be alright.
Don't have time to sit here now.
Don't you need them yourself?
You don't have to leave.
I've told you not to come here.
I miss you.
Can I come in?
Are you seeing someone?
No, I am not.
Please leave.
Mom and dad can't find you here.
Can I borrow some money?
It's important.
Please.
Hello.
Do you have a light?
Are you ok?
Hi! Silver!
Look!
My God, she has puppies!
-Did you know?
-Yes, they are six weeks old now.
That one is Sis. And that is the Falk.
I don't know if they are girls or boys, but....
Hey! This is private property!
We're sorry, we'll leave now.
Bye, Silver.
-Do you know the dog?
-Yes, she used to be ours.
Our father gave her away
just before he died.
He died?
I thought he was
only moving.
He was full of cancer.
Did he say where he was moving?
I didn't know he even had a family.
Just stay here and visit the dog if you like.
Why did you say he died?
What did you want to say?
The truth. That he left, because he
couldn't stand mom anymore.
(From Ingrid
You can sleep here. I miss you.
Home alone until Wednesday.)
-Little one.
-Sweetheart.
How are you?
Dance for me.
Remember to lock when you leave.
(I love you, mommy.)
(New Messages from Mom.
Read now?)
(From Mom.
Love you, too, Falk)
Flatmates
I'm going to find me a sexy girl tonight.
So get off then.
Are you horny or what?
What are you talking about?
You're rubbing yourself against me.
You're the one who wanted to lie here.
Yeah, but you're the one rubbing.
Okay Hampus, I'm damn horny.
Especially on your tight little ass.
You are.
You really are. Let me touch it.
Okay, be gentle.
Fucking hell, that's disgusting!
I'll have to screw you a little then.
Fuck you.
Yes, I fucked you.
Hey Bjorn, have a look...do I look good?
No.
What do you mean "no"?
You can't look good.
I'm going out. Want to join?
No I'll stay here.
Come on! You can fix this any time.
No, I want to finish up today.
We can go to a gay club
... and you could get laid. It's been a while.
That's probably why you are so
grumpy all the time.
Yeah, that's probably why Hampus.
So stay home then, and keep on sulking.
Give me a ring if you change your mind.
Bye.
Hi this is Hampus. Say something if it's important
....if not don't. Bye.
Hi.
Bye bye.
So what do you think?
She's cute.
Yeah...
In love?
Don't know.... I don't know.
You're so cute. Little baby bear.
Give me a hug so I can feel.
Nice and clean.
Now?
No.
Now! No it turned fuzzy again.
There you've got it.
How many channels do we have? Look...
Come in.
Hi Bjorn.
Hi.
Uhm... do you have my...
where is my mobile charger Hampus?
It's in here somewhere...
Where?
I don't know.
Can you help me look for it?
Take mine then. It's in the socket.
You'll get it back when you've found mine.
Yes, that sounds good.
Bye bye.
Stop it!
Yes?
Hi.
I'm leaving now, so I thought I'd say goodbye.
Okay, bye bye. Going home?
Yes, well no... I'm off to work actually.
Shall we go? I'll follow you to the tram.
You don't have to, I can go...
Of course I am, come on.
Okay, well...bye, bye.
Bye.
Hi this is Hampus. Say something if it's important
... if not don't. Bye.
What are you up to?
I'm looking for the ISS.
What "the ISS"? What's that?
The International Space Station.
Really. Show me then, Where is it?
You can't see it now
So what have you been up to all night?
I've been painting.
Paint...? What?
Have you been painting all night?
Yeah.
Have some water Hampus.
"Have some water Hampus".
My little sweetheart.
I'll get you some water.
Wow, that's great. What a job!
I've bought you a space shuttle
It stands at the parking lot.
Good. Come on.
I really have!
But I bought a space shuttle!
Come.
No, no, no!
No stop it, I want to sleep... I want to sleep here.
There's not enough space for both of us.
Come on, be a little generous for once.
Hampus...
...shall I sleep in your bed instead?
Have you cleaned up in here?
No.
It looks as if you've cleaned up.
This is not working Bjorn.
To the moon
Ouch! Cunt!
Cloth.
Elvis? How long are we staying here?
I don't know.
Bingo.
How much does a hotdog cost?
-What?
-How much does a hotdog cost?
-It depends.
-On what?
-What type.
-A regular sausage in bread.
-With onion?
-Yes.
-Hot or cold?
-Cold.
20 kroner.
I am starving!
No!
What are you doing?
Get back here right now!
If you could wish for one thing
what would you wish for?
What would you wish for?
What? If you could choose one thing,
what would you wish for?
I don't bloody know.
Choose one thing! Answer me!
If you could choose! What?
-If you could choose one thing?
-For you to shut up a little while!
I'd choose a hotdog stand.
I'd eat as many hotdogs as I felt like eating.
Where are you going?
-To the bathroom.
-I am going with you.
I am only going to the bathroom.
Do you need to go?
Do you have to go?
-Aren't you going to pee?
-Don't have to, after all.
-What's that?
-A razor.
I am going to shave. Ok?
I'll wait.
When I get my hotdog stand
I won't let anyone buy anything.
I'm keeping them all to myself.
Watch out.
Look at what I found!
Elvis?
Did mom have black hair?
No.
Yellow?
Let's go.
Where?
To the moon.
-Is it far?
-What?
To the moon.
As far as it is from the moon to here.
That's all?
I can't wait to go.
I can't wait until summer.
Maybe we'll still be here?
Maybe.
Where do you think they are going?
Home.
SPARK
Can you believe it?
They actually made a mistake with the cake!
It's a good thing that I stopped by
and checked up on them.
It would have been a disaster if Anders didn't get
his favourite cake for his birthday.
By the way, we need to know if they are coming.
Who?
-Nice to meet you.
-Nice to see you again.
This is Marie. You remember her?
The artist.
Oh.Yes.That's right.
-Could I have a word?
-Yes, of course. I'll walk you out.
Just a minute, Mother.
I got the job in Copenhagen!
Congratulations! How wonderful for you!
For the both of us! It's fantastic!
I am so excited.
Everything is fine. Right?
Yes.... yes.... But let's not talk about it now.
I'll call you later, ok?
Ok...
I'll talk to you tonight?
Yes.
Happy Birthday, Anders.
Congratulations on your promotion.
So you've heard?
Looks like I will be following in your footsteps.
Cheers!
What? Who can that be now?
I'll go see.
-What are you doing here?
-You're not answering your phone.
-Who is it?
-It's Marie.
-Marie! Come in!
We've just started eating....
Are you having a party?
-No, I don't want to...
-The more the merrier! Come on!
Is there room for one more?
Oh? Another guest?
I guess we can manage.
For he's a jolly good fellow...
Welcome. Cheers.
Cheers!
And who are you?
I'm Marie.... Just a friend of Caroline's.
Caroline. Caroline?
It's time to bring out the cake.
-Everything is ready in the kitchen.
-Yes, of course...
I can't understand how you can stand this charade.
It will be a relief to go to Copenhagen.
Stop it.
-Everything is so easy for you.
-What do you mean?
We can't just leave, just like that.
Of course we can.
We have talked about so many times.
This is what we want.
Let's not talk about it now.
I have already accepted the job in Copenhagen.
Kiss me.
Come over to my place afterwards.
-Are you coming? Everyone is waiting.
-We're coming now.
I'm leaving.
I can't stand being here any longer.
I'll talk to you later. Right?
I'll do my best.
-What a cake!
-Happy birthday.
Dear guests, friends and family.
And not least, my dear Caroline.
This day is not just about me.
It is also about us.
Caroline...
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Congratulations.
-Welcome into the family.
-Thank you.
I am so excited!
Will you marry me?
-It's time for us to have a serious talk.
-I don't want to talk about it.
You are so beautiful.
I have already accepted the job in Copenhagen.
This is what we want.
Caroline, will you marry me?
Caroline, do it for my sake.
I can't see how you can stand this charade.
/text by CMP
DVD production
by Cicknave Media Productions