Michael ?
Look at me when I'm talking to you,
Michael.
What did I tell you
about touching the glass ?
Let's start from the beginning.
When's the last time you remember wearing them ?
I want you to try to remember.
That's not too much to ask, is it ?
- Charlie.
- What?
- I know you've been under a lot of pressure lately.
- How Lisa?
How could you possibly know
how much pressure I've been under lately ?
You have no idea,
not a clue.
Your book is brilliant.
Yes ?
What's so funny ? Do you know how expensive
they were ? Do you realize ?
How expensive those glasses were, do you
Mr. smarty pants ?
Stop calling him that.
Michael feels bad enough already.
Then why is he laughing ? Maybe he knows
something I don't know, he's so goddamn smart.
- Charlie.
- But if Mr. smarty pants
- Stop. Stop calling him that.
- Could remember where he put his glasses
- Charlie!
- Maybe it would be more slightly comfortable.
Once the reviews are out,
you'll be granted tender.
- I earned that tender.
- I know you have.
They can go fuck themselves.
What did I tell you
about touching the glass ?
That's it.
What are you doing?
- You remember how to get home, don't you ?
- Don't be ridiculous.
We wouldn't be late,
picking up your sister from the airport
- if your son could remember where he put his glasses.
- Stop acting like a child.
You're calling me a child, me ?
Do you know what I do ?
- Have you even begin to conceive
the sacrifices I make for this family ? - You ?
Nobody forced you to quit this.
Take responsibility. It was your choice.
- One of us had to be an adult, raise our son.
- Find job you did in that.
If you'd stop babying him, he wouldn't be such a fuck up.
Have you ever think of that ?
Michael!
Mr. Taylor ? Sorry to bother you, do you mind ?
Yeah ... No.
LOVE LETTERS
FOR KELLY
Do you have a pen ?
Thank you Mr. Taylor, I'm such a big fan.
I've read all of your books.
Mr. Taylor is my father's name.
Call me Michael.
Thank you.
#baseball vocabulary#
Back off the plate then.
- It's not my fault you're such a shrimp.
- I'm not a shrimp.
- Mom says I have big feet for a girl my age.
- What's that suppose to mean ?
Leslie, Christopher, Aunt Lisa and Uncle
Charlie will be here any minute now to pick us up.
Okay, be there in a second.
Pitch it for real this time.
- Just put your seatblet on.
- It will wrinkle my dress.
I am proud of you, honey.
Is that so hard to believe?
Thank you, Charlie.
And you look beautiful.
I'm sure Michael's landed by now.
Ryne's probably just about there.
Sorry, it's such a big deal to take
3 cars instead of two ?
- You're not sorry. Not at all.
- I mean, nobody drives this car but me.
You've made that perfectly clear.
The white zone is for loading and
unloading, passengers only.
all unintended luggage will be confiscated
by security personal...
- *
- Yeah .. yes.
- Where is the rest of your luggage ?
- You're looking at it.
What ?
- I thought you would be staying longer.
- How long are you staying ?
I live here, remember ?
Yes, you live in a dorm. Look at you.
- Yes ?
- You've grown into a fine young man.
Shut up, asshole.
- How was the flight? - Incredible.
- Awesome.
How is New York?
- Cold.
- You guys still living in the same place ?
- Yes.
You think that it'd be okay to come out
and stay with you guys for a little bit ?
***
- Nice. - I don't want to impose.
Only if you have time.
- Of course we have time.
- Yeah ? -Yeah.
- Okay, cool.
- Cool.
Game over.
- Oh, come one, one last pitch, please !
Nice throw, Mom.
- Okay? - Fine.
- Lisa, do you have to do that now?
You rushed me out the door.
I don't want to be late.
Yes ! I did it.
In your face !
Leslie, Christopher, I said now !
Yes, I did it !
Charlie !
Mom ?
Mom !
- How's Kelly ?
- Fine.
Kelly ...
- I wish she was here.
- Yeah.
Stop at the omega.
I can't, we're gonna be late.
We'll get some pie, like old times.
I was six, that was no old times.
Shoot.
Hi, Aunt Jane.
Yes, yes. Michael's right here.
What's wrong ?
No ! No ...
No let me, I want to see it.
***
Are you okay ? Jesus.
- I didn't have a key.
- You should have gone to the porch.
Let get you inside, it'll get you warm.
Come on.
Why is she here?
Aunt Jane's spending the summer with us.
Why ?
Because she's my sister.
See how lucky I am
to have a son like you.
Well, I know.
I hate him.
Your father loves you very much.
He's a good man ...
- He's been under a lot of pressure lately.
- Why do you do that ?
- What?
- That.
What is it that I do ?
Never mind.
Have you read his book?
- Yes.
- Is it any good?
I think now that it's finished,
things will be...
better.
I love you big.
I love you bigger.
Where did you get this from ?
I made it myself,
thank you very much.
Is there something wrong with the food ?
Meat is murder.
Sorry Jane, I've forgotten, Mom did tell me
you've become a vegetarian, what a healthy choice.
- Jesus, thanks.
- In this house we eat what's put on the table.
- What's your damage, Charlie?
- Excuse me what did you just say?
She said she doesn't eat meat, dad.
I see that you finally found your glasses.
Where were they?
- You don't know, where you found them ?
How's that possible. - The important thing is that he found them.
Since you're staying here this summer ...
- follow our rules.
- Like what, eat meat ?
Michael can explain them to you.
Or better...
he can make a list.
Write them up, tonight after dinner
You'll do that for us, right ?
You can look them over in the morning
before you go to the hospital.
Who's going to the hospital?
- Just ...
Tell me when you're done.
Hello ?
- Is anyone in there ?
- I heard you.
Why didn't you answer me ?
Because, Charlie, did not ask a question.
Tell me when you're done.
If you were half as thorough with your schoolwork
as you were writing up these rules
maybe you'd get better grades.
Well, maybe I'd get better grades,
if I did not have to ...
to spend all my time
writing up those rules.
Give them to your aunt Jane.
Michael.
You have a beautiful penmanship.
Yes ?
Cousin Michael.
I'm not your cousin.
I am your aunt.
What ?
What do you want ?
Are you okay ?
Does he really expect me
to memorize all this ?
Yes.
This place totally sucks.
Where are the kids ?
They are with Uncle Jimmy.
Christopher ? Jane ?
Yes, Jane is fine.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Daddy, Daddy, stop, please.
Where is Michael?
- He's out making the arrangements.
- Michael's making the arrangements ?
Don't !
- He's  ...
- Just don't.
Everything needs to be perfect.
- Perfect.
- It will be Daddy.
- Hello, Michael.
- Jimmy.
I'm so sorry, man.
I don't not know what I'd do
if I was Charlie.
How is he ?
Come on, let me get it for you.
Welcome home.
- Yes, I haven't read that yet, but I will.
- You're going somewhere ?
- A couple days in Cincinnati, I try to push
it off with this new job you know. - Right, right.
It looks good, Jimmy.
***
- Hey, sweet.
I got to tell you, my kids love it here.
Christophe's in your old room,
and Leslie's here in Ryne's.
Say hello to your cousin.
- Go on.
- You're short.
The guest room is upstairs. 2nd door on the right
But I guess you know that, cause it's your home.
Uncle Charlie says this is our home now.
You're right, honey.
It is our home now.
-But, Michael grew up here,
so this his is home too. - But is is our home.
Let's go catch some more of that ball game, right ?
If you need anything, let me know.
- This is great, to see you again.
- Yeah, you too Jimmy.
That's some good looking weather.
I like what you've done with the room.
I used to come here all the time
when I was grounded.
Mom told me you were always
getting her in trouble.
They talk.
What's that supposed to mean?
Before your mother was a mom,
she was my best friend.
You guys had tea parties together ?
Occasionally.
Your mother taught me anything I shouldn't know.
Smart ass.
How to write like a chick.
Funny.
Glad to see your balls finally dropped.
No, your mother taught me
the art of fishing.
Fishing ?
Fishing is boring.
Not the way we use to do it, it wasn't.
Yeah, right.
Want me to show you ?
- That story's gonna stop ?
- You're right, it is gonna stop, just not tonight.
- Have we got any cheese, Dad ?
- What for ?
- Butterfly net ?
- Yes.
- Cheese ?
- Yep.
Buckle up.
- What's in the box ?
- Patience, Christopher.
Patience.
- Now ?
- Patience.
- I'll just go to my dorm.
- No, you won't.
- Well, Aunty Jane.
- Don't call me Aunty Jane.
You're not a little girl anymore.
And I'm not that old.
You look so much like your mother.
Perfect.
Both of you.
Come, it's okay, let's go.
These things are totally ancient.
They're never gonna work.
Can I see ? Can I see ? Cool !
Get out of here, lesbo.
I'm not a lesbo.
What's a lesbo ?
- A girl and girl.
- Get out of here !
- What the hell is wrong with you ?
- She's always screwing stuff up.
- Look who's talking. - Screw you !
- I'm telling Mom he swore.
Come here. You too.
Nobody's telling Mom anything.
Not me, not you, nobody. Got it ?
Well. You okay ?
Let me look at you.
- So, we're not gonna tell Mom ?
- No, Jesus Christ, no.
What's wrong ?
You hear that ?
What ?
Leslie, Christopher ?
Honey ... Honey ?
Where are the kids ?
- With Michael.
- Where did they go?
Christopher said he wanted some cheese.
And a butterfly net.
You know how to do it?
Throw it. Away, away, away.
- Nice pitch.
- I told you they wouldn't work.
Can I try ?
No, you're strictly a spectator. Back. Back.
Come on guys, back, all the way.
Damn.
Wow ! I wanna try, can I try please ?
We need to do that again !
How did you get hurt ?
You know, Christopher?
You took them fishing, didn't you ?
Fishing with firecrackers.
That blond didn't throw a single fish,
not one.
Michael said you can skip a fish
all the way across the ...
You took them to a large body of water
during a lightning storm.
Let's not rush to judgment just yet.
We got home well before the storm.
We did, didn't we ?
- Get upstairs, wash out, you stink.
Washing them the all time,
I had proper adult supervision.
Do you know who still got their kicks
blowing out fish ?
You use to.
Get upstairs immediately.
You're right. We did do a lot of dumb things
back when we were kids.
- But that is not the point.
- What is the point, Jane ?
My children lied to me,
because you told them to.
Sorry.
I messed up.
I promise you that I will never ever
take them fishing with firecrackers again.
Further more, they will never ever
lie to their mother again.
Probably because they are the worst liars.
What are you doing ?
Promising, like we were doing when we were kids.
Come on.
- You suck, you know that ?
- I really do.
But you love me.
Shit!
The thing that is written will come true.
Death has been swallowed up in victory.
Where death is your victory.
Where death is your sting.
The sting of death is sin.
And the power of sin is the Law.
But thanks be to god,
that gives us the victory
through our Lord Jesus Christ.
We bow our heads and pray.
God of peace.
You brought again from the dead,
our Lord Jesus Christ.
The Great Shepherd of the sheep.
Through the blood of the everlasting covenant ...
Where's your jacket?
Christopher's wearing it.
Why's Christopher wearing your jacket ?
Because I gave it to him.
- Amen
- Amen.
- Christ is risen.
- He's risen indeed.
Just go forth in peace,
in the name of our risen Lord.
Stupid.
Stupid, stupid.
Stupid. Stupid.
Why ? Fucking stupid.
Why ?
Congratulations on your retirement.
Thank you, thank you
I am sure that I
leave university in good hands.
- It's gonna be ok.
- ok.
Your father told me
that you were graduating next month.
I am proud of my girl.
- Is this seat taken ?
- It's all yours.
Addison Wesley.
After reading his memoir,
masqueraded as a novel ...
I wanted to jump in the shower
and scrub the slime away with the brillo pad.
Did you ?
Manage to scrub the slime away ?
You always memorize
all of your reviews ?
No, only the good.
Michael Taylor.
Always nice to meet a fan.
- Your mother was a wonderful person.
- Yes, she was.
How did you know her ? - Your father and I
teach in the English department together and...
She was my best student.
- Yeah ?
- Yeah.
Kelly.
I'm so sorry.
- Would you excuse me?
- Of course.
- Jane, hi. How are you?
- Kelly.
- I'm glad you could make it.
- Thank you.
Come on, come here.
You need anything right now ?
It's good to see you.
Yes, I'm glad you're here.
Mind if I join you ?
How did Jane call ?
How do you know it was Jane ?
She's the only one I told.
It is not what you think. Show up here ...
It's just easier.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah ?
What are you sorry for ?
I've been sober for two months and fifteen days.
- I am proud of you. - Thank you.
- Your welcome.
It sucks that it broke up our marriage
but hey, you're sober now, that's all that really matters.
Stop it. Stop it.
- This was a mistake coming here.
I shouldn't be here. - Wait.
You did not answer my question.
What are you sorry for ?
Fuck it, I ...
I just wanted to help.
Help you.
I know.
Are you happy ?
Yes, I'm happy.
Good.
I am happy for you.
I am.
Michael, time up, time up.
Everybody's downstairs.
Fuck it.
My father used to say,
that if you don't take care of something ...
You don't deserve to have it.
Lisa was so good,
so beautiful ...
She gave herself to me ...
and she loved me.
Sometimes I wonder why ...
but she did.
Lisa was perfect.
- Where is your brother?
- I don't know.
Lisa was graduating ...
So we're here not only in remembrance,
but also to celebrate her accomplishments.
I know this gathering
would have made Lisa very grateful and happy,
so in her honor,
let's share a moment of silence.
I am sorry Daddy.
Excuse me.
Michael, I heard you took the kids fishing,
the night before your mom's funeral.
- Yes, we had tons of ...
- And then we threw them all back.
Yes, and then we threw them all back.
- He took you out fishing ...
- What's the big deal ?
- The big deal ...
- It's okay.
Let sit.
It does not feel right. At a certain
way shows no respect.
In what's fishing disrespectful ?
It's not about fishing,
but when you go fishing,
it's about being properly dressed
for your mother's funeral,
it's about demonstrating some self-control
and consideration for others, you understand ?
- No.
- You don't understand ?
Not really.
- I'm confused ...
You don't understand or you do understand ?
Which is it ?
We understand, Charles.
Don't we, Michael?
I understand that Mom wouldn't have care
over something as silly as fishing.
Your behavior is embarrassing.
- For who ? You ?
- For this family!
Well...
I'm sorry, Jane.
Sorry isn't gonna get the stain out, is it ?
After all that happened,
don't you think you two could just ...
stop.
I'm sorry.
It's ruined.
Maybe you and Ryan could box
some of your mother's stuff for good will.
I know it's what she would have wanted.
Will you do that ?
Yeah.
- Okay, all right.
- Thanks Jimmy.
I'll get the car.
Leslie ...
Say good night to your Uncle Charlie.
Have I scared you at dinner ?
Sorry, I didn't mean to.
Sometimes your Uncle Charlie
acts a bit stupid.
That's OK.
Thanks Jane.
Dinner was good.
I'm sorry.
- Good night, Daddy.
- Good night, honey.
- Ready Charlie ?
- Yeah.
Good night, Christopher.
I'll be right there. Okay.
I so wish you didn't have to go.
Me too, me too.
- Don't go.
- You're gonna be ok.
You are.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- Call me as soon as you land.
- You know I will.
Go on, get outta here.
Thank you.
For calling Kelly.
- Why did you do it ?
- Because I knew you wouldn't.
If she makes you happy,
that's what's important.
You know, I think I read that somewhere.
How is Christopher doing ?
Doesn't sleep, keeps running on fumes.
You look like you could use
a little rest yourself.
I'd love to Michael, but with Jimmie gone,
it's not really an option.
Yes, yes ...
Jimmie's got a lot huh ?
- Jimmy has never once said a word about you.
- What ? What did I say ?
- Oh, shut up. - Let's go fishing.
- This is not funny. - Come on.
No.
- I got it.
- No, I'm gonna wash and you dry. Here.
Thanks.
- Think you can manage ?
- Yeah, I think I can manage.
It's fine.
This was always your mother's job.
She wore gloves to protect her hands.
She had the most beautiful hands.
"You don't want dishman hands" she warned me.
"You should always wear gloves,
always. "
But they never did fit me quite right.
Always a little too tight.
Did you read my book?
I don't need to, Michael.
- Why not?
- Because I lived it.
- It is fiction, Jane.
- No one is gonna read that book and not think it's about ...
- This book is gonna kill your dad.
- Am I suppose to spend the rest of my life writing romance novels ?
What's that all about ?
Proving yourself ?
No, this is not about proving myself at all.
Because of that book, everyone is going to know.
Why ?
The kids ... Jimmy ...
Everyone's gonna know.
What ?
Jane, what's everyone gonna know ?
Oh my God, oh God.
I'm sorry.
How can you be sorry,
when you have no idea ...
what your apologizing for.
Come on cousin Michael. Let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
- Okay, okay.
- Come on.
Fireflies in the garden,
by Michael Taylor.
Here come real stars
to fill the upper skies,
and here on earth,
come emulating flies
That, though they never equal stars in size
(and they were never really stars at heart),
Achieve at time a very starlike start
Only, of course, they can't sustain the part.
If you don't know how to take care
care of something ...
you don't deserve to have it.
In the car.
Get in the car, now!
Am I a bad father ?
- No.
- I couldn't here you, what did you say?
I said no.
Go ahead, pick them up.
Michael.
Look at me, Michael.
Why did you do that ?
Why ?
Did you think you were gonna get away
with it ?
Or is it because you don't respect yourself ?
I told my colleagues in the English Department,
the English Department ...
that my son was going to recite
from an original poem.
- That means a poem written by you.
- I know.
Then, Mr. smarty pants,
Tell me...
exactly when did you become a buddhist ?
I am not.
You must be if you claim to be
the reincarnation of the late Robert Frost.
Otherwise why would you be
so stupid to say
that you had written one of his poems.
Why ?
More tea ?
Excuse me please.
Charlie.
Charlie, open the door.
Charlie, open the goddamn door.
Charlie !
Do you understand me ?
Yes.
Charlie, Open the door!
That's enough.
Charlie !
Will you open this door ?!
Sweetheart, are you okay ?
What happened ?
What happened sweetheart ?
It's okay, it's okay.
Mom is here.
It's okay, sweety.
Michael ?
Honey.
I brought you some dinner.
I'm not hungry.
Just try to eat something.
Are you okay mom ?
That baby brother sure can kick.
Can you feel that ?
How does it feel like ?
Let's see if he does it again.
Give me your hand.
- Did you feel that ?
- No.
Press right there.
That was weird.
That's him.
How do you know it's not a girl?
Just a feeling, I guess.
What about names ?
What do you think we should name him ?
I don't know.
What names dad want ?
We haven't talked about it actually.
I was thinking... Max.
Max is a strong name,
what do you think?
Max, like Maxi pad ?
Do you have any ideas ?
Ryne.
- Ryan ...
- No, not Ryan.
Ryne, like a ryony.
How did you think
of a name like that ?
I like it.
Ryne Taylor.
Sounds good. - Yeah ?
Yeah.
Eat your dinner
whenever you're ready, okay ?.
I love you honey.
I love you big.
You're okay ?
Aren't you gonna eat ?
Go away, Jane.
Take a bite.
Take just one bite
and then I'll leave you alone.
What happened in the garage,
Michael ?
What did Charlie do to you ?
I'm not leaving until you take a bite.
- Just take one more bite...
- I can't, okay?
I can't take a bite.
I can't move my arms.
- Why can't you ?
- Because it hurts too much.
I can't.
- What are you doing?
- Eat.
Eat.
You wanna go fishing sometimes ?
I thought you were a vegetarian.
We're going to Jane's house,
to pick up the rest of the family, so we can all go to...
Lisa's graduation together.
As always ...
we were late.
Lisa was ...
putting on make up in the car ...
I told her to wear a seatbelt.
We ...
started arguing ...
I got angry ...
I was driving fast, too fast.
As we got near the house,
Christopher ran out, I swerved ...
We hit the pole.
It's my fault.
It's my fault Lisa's dead.
Daddy ?
Yeah, honey.
- Everything okay ?
- Fine.
Everything's fine.
I'm gonna take a nap.
This is a keeper.
This is more than a simple sale, Kelly.
Good will said that they'd be here on Monday and ...
since the 2 of you are leaving tomorrow,
it doesn't leave us much time.
- What are you doing?
- I'm just checking.
I already pull out the pockets on everything,
like you told me to.
- I know you did.
- What are you doing ? -  What does it look like Micheal ?
What's wrong with you?
Dad made the money,
Mom paid the bills.
She had to hide everything,
because he would have blown all the cash and then we'd be broke.
The problem is, we do not know
where she hid anything.
You get it Michael ?
You get it now why I'm being so fucking anal ?
Calm down, Ryne.
It's just ...
I just never thought that ...
That we'd be ...
Fuck.
It really fucking sucks.
What am I suppose to do
with all mom's shit ?
I'm gonna start with mom's closet.
This is a great idea, just ...
Be quiet about it, please.
Your mother kept everything.
Better safe than sorry.
Found anything interesting?
Not really.
Jane told me
that you just finished you're new book.
I did, yeah.
I heard this one's different.
You can say that.
When does it come out ?
Soon.
It's good.
What's it about ?
- You did write it, did you ?
- Yes, I did.
Just read it, okay?
Whatever you want.
- Hey, Dad ...
- Yes, Michael.
What happened to us ?
What do you mean?
It hasn't always been like this.
The way it is now, between us.
Has it ?
I can't remember, Michael.
Hello ?
Michael.
Everything looks different.
Yes.
There's been a lot of building.
New student center, new residence halls.
It used to be my dorm room over there,
it doesn't exist anymore.
We need to talk, Addison.
- What about?
- About why you were fucking my mom.
Sit.
Come on, sit.
Where do you wanna talk about ?
Do you like pie ?
- Yes.
- Me too.
It's good.
Where did you take her ?
Your place, her place ?
A hotel.
Just trying to make sense of this arrangement.
How can you look my father in the eye,
every day ?
Was she happy ?
- Was my mother happy ? With you ?
- Yes.
- Did you love her?
- Very much so.
- How long were you two together? - Michael ...
- How long ? How long ...
were you two together, Addison ...
- Two, maybe three years.
Three years.
What do you remember most
about my mother?
Her eyes.
When she smiles she ...
she had the happiest eyes ...
Open it.
She wanted him to leave,
after she graduated.
I would not know why, leaving
with him is like Christmas every day ...
but she was gonna leave him.
For you.
- Michael, I'm so sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
Don't.
You made here happy,
that's all that matters.
Thanks.
- Daddy !
- Hey, sweet.
I missed you.
And I have something for you.
- You like that ?
- Thanks.
There's no reason to be nervous.
I'm just gonna ask you a couple of questions and that's it.
What about your aunt's funeral ?
Can we talk about that ?
- Did you go to your aunt's funeral ?
- Yes, I was there.
- We know you were there. - Then what's she doing here ?
- I'm just here to help you Christopher. - Leave me alone!
I don't need your help.
- Christopher ...
These are so cool.
You've got Sweetness ...
Ernie ...
McMahon, Fisk ...
Santo ...
Fergie ...
Oh God, you've got a Ryne
Sandberg rookie card, he's totally my favorite.
Seriously ?
- Me too.
- He's so hot.
You want 'em?
Really ?
He's yours.
- Don't you dare turning this around on me.
- Lisa ...
- it's not what you think.
- Why don't you tell me, Charlie ...
What am I thinking ? Tell me !
- Listen to me.
- All I've ever done is listen to you, Charlie.
Listen and apologize
on the half of all my ...
fellow idiots in the world,
who couldn't give too shit in what you have to say.
I'm sorry you didn't get tender.
I'm sorry no one is buying your book.
I'm sorry being a husband
and a father isn't enough for you.
I never said that, never... never.
You sleep with her ?
Did you sleep with her ?
Did she tell you everything
you so badly need to here  ?
How witty you are, how charmingly handsome ...
"Oh, Professor Taylor, you're such a genius ..."
She giggles at your stupid fucking jokes ...
- Is that it ? - Yes. And then I took her to my office
and then I fucked here.
Is that what you want to hear?
- Michael ? Michael, Jane, we're leaving.
- Lisa
I'm sorry, nothing happened.
- Lisa.
- Get away from my car.
- Your car ?
- Who paid for your car? You?
You don't even have a fucking job.
- So look at me when I'm talking to you.
- Get away from her.
Get back in the house.
Get away from her, or I'll kill you.
I swear I'll do it,
damn it, I swear.
Are you threatening me?
I am your father.
Put that down, and come here.
Come here right now !
I swear to god,
I swear to god, I'll kill you.
Who are you?
The knight in shining armor ?
Mommy's little protector?
You ain't gonna do anything.
Michael !
Michael, don't !
Michael, Michae l!
I hate you.
You hear me ? I hate you !
I wish you were dead.
Michael !
Christopher !
- Stop !
- What do you want ? - Nothing.
Leave me alone.
- Just... talk to me.
What for ?
Just to go tell how fucked up I am ?
You don't need to tell me it's all fucking fine.
Aunt Lisa is dead.
It's not your fault.
- Get out of the way.
- You did not have time ...
I had time.
I had time enough to think "Move your feet !"
Move your fucking feet.
No matter how loud I yelled in my head.
I just couldn't move.
I tried to run, but ...
I did not even go
to Aunt Lisa's funeral.
You were there.
- No.
- Yes, you were - I was in the car.
- I saw you Christopher.
I saw you. Look at me.
Come on look at me, please.
I want you to think, okay?
Think about this ...
If your mom didn't let you throw
that last pitch ...
If your sister didn't hit
that last home run ...
If my dad wasn't driving too fast ...
If my mother was wearing a seatbelt,
she might be alive.
Maybe. But that's a whole lot of things
that has nothing to do with you.
Understand ?
It's not your fault.
- Okay ?
- Yeah.
Let's go home, okay ?
No, I'll get a walk back.
Are you sure?
It's along way.
I'm sure.
- Call me if you change your mind. - I don't need that.
- Take it, just in case.
See you home, okay?
Okay?
- Yes.
Later.
Have I done something wrong ? Jane!
No, Michael,
You did everything just right.
You left Christopher alone in a wheat field.
- He wanted to walk home.
- And you let him ?
- Yes. Yes I did, he's not an infant Jane.
You left him 4 hours ago,
and he's not home, is he ?
He'll be fine.
You're like a human shit trail.
Everything you do, everything you touch,
turns to crap.
Why don't you put that
in your precious little book.
Red Socks or White Socks,
when is gonna be the cubs turn ?
***.
I'm gonna be the pitcher.
Your mother was a pretty good pitcher,
when she was a girl.
- Yes ?
- Your cousin was pretty good too.
- Ryne ?
- No, Michael.
He could hit.
The kind of swing you just can't teach.
Nice and easy and natural.
One day ...
he's getting to his head...
to swing for the fence
every time he stepped up to the point...
slap and sings was never good enough
for your uncle Charlie...
- Where are you going ?
- To the bathroom.
Here.
- In case someone calls.
- Got it.
- Who's in charge ? - I am.
- Right.
Michael ?
Are you awake ?
Yes.
You put a real beat on your old man
you know that ?
Please look at me, Michael.
I really need you to look at me now.
Your mother and I had a talk.
There's gonna be some big changes around here.
Big changes.
I'm gonna change.
Yes ?
I'm gonna try.
You believe me?
Yes.
Good night Michael.
Good night, Dad.
You're not the boss of me.
- You wanna know why ?
- Why?
Because I could like totally
kick your ass in a fight ...
like you can't ever imagine.
Do you think they will find Christopher ?
I hope not.
Of course they're gonna find Christopher.
But what if he's dead?
Look at me ...
Nobody's gonna die.
I promise you.
We're all gonna die someday.
Yes, we are.
But, you know ... Nobody's really dead
as long as you always remember them.
Want to know how I always remember my mom ?
I look at my watch ...
When all the numbers line up ...
Like 11:11, 2:22, 3:33 ...
When those numbers line up,
it is a reminder.
It reminds me to tell my mom I love her.
- You check your watch pretty much.
- Yes.
Yes.
We were barely able to use the video camera,
and you know how much ...
your aunt Lisa hated to have a picture taken ?
- She hated it.
So, the clock game, that's all I got.
Leslie?
- Yes, Uncle Charlie ?
Will you help me up the stairs ?
- I can.
No, you stay down here
in case Christopher comes back.
Come on, baby.
Where are you?
Don't worry Jane,
I'm sure Christopher will be fine.
Kelly, don't tell me not to worry.
You don't have a kid,
you don't know the fuck what you're talking about, so just don't...
Do not tell me not to worry.
What are we doing in the attic, Uncle Charlie ?
I just remembered something.
- What ?
- Just hold on.
Patience.
Patience is a virtue.
Catch it if you can.
Rarely found in women,
never found in men.
Charles ?
Michael ?
Oh my God.
Oh God. Is he all okay ?
Is there firecrackers in there ?
Why would they be firecrackers ?
This is what I was looking for.
What's that ?
Something beautiful.
You're right.
I don't imagine what it would be
to be responsible for something.
Someone ...
entirely depending on me.
On me.
I am such a fuck up.
What are you talking about, Kelly?
I just hope she's healthy.
She will be healthy.
- How is Michael ... doing with this?
- He doesn't know yet.
Kelly ...
don't hurt him.
Don't you dare hurt him.
Michael has been hurt enough already.
I know.
Well, we are in the right place.
Your mother's gonna kill me.
- Christopher, are you okay?
- I'm fine, Mom.
Who is that ?
- That is your pappy.
That's nana.
That's me.
Let me get that.
Come on, honey,
You shouldn't...
These should fit.
Hey, you know?
Seems like you've grown a foot since I got here, Blondie.
- It's impossible.
- Yeah, whatever.
Wish we had spend more time together.
That will change.
- I'd like that Michael.
- Me too.
We have something to tell you.
You tell them.
No, you.
Please don't.
- I'm pregnant.
- I knew it!
Oh my God, Kelly.
- Thank you.
Awesome !
Well ?
What do you think,
you're gonna be grandfather ?
I think ...
I think your mother
would have been very happy.
She was happy. Dad.
Send me a copy of your new book.
- That's not gonna be published.
- Why not?
When will you be coming back ?
- Soon. Very soon.
Wait a second. Give me a hug.
Come on.
What do you say ?
See you soon.
- Yes.
- Come on girl.
If it's a girl,
Michael and I love the name Sadie.
- Sadie ? No.
- What's wrong with Sadie?
- Like the Beatles song ?
- Sexy Sadie?
This is a scar for life.
- She knows the Beatles!
- Yes I know the Beatles.
And if it is a boy ?
We haven't really thought of a name for a boy,
have we honey ?
Max.
I like Max.
Why Max?
Mom would have loved that.
Max.
I like that. It's nice.
Corrected by TofHetfield
khammet5@hotmail.com
www.u-sub.net