Previously on The Firm
What I gave you
incriminated the firm.
You said it would
motion a chain of events
that could cripple
the mob, Mitch.
They deal in revenge.
This is Marshal Coleman
with the witness
protection program.
It's been ten years.
We're done running.
The firm--
it's called Kinross & Clark.
They offered me the job.
- You joined a firm?
- I'm not kissing any asses.
Fair enough.
You report to me
on all our cases.
I'm your boss
from this day forward.
- I'm your defense lawyer,
Sarah--I'm Mitch McDeere.
I have questions, questions like
why would a 27-year-old
kill a 71-year-old woman
in her sleep?
I didn't.
Does he know why
we made him an offer?
No.
Of course, our real interest
here--Sarah Holt.
We were just
discussing your case.
I'm telling you,
I'm onto something.
He should be
under surveillance.
We should
be listening everywhere.
Our priority here
is control.
I have to see somebody.
Somebody knows the truth.
If Mitch McDeere ever finds
the truth in this case,
everyone in this room
is going to prison.
Mr. Markson,
thank you for coming.
Five minutes.
That's what you said...
Then I'm gone.
This is my client.
You know who this is?
No.
A woman is dead.
Bottom line is the trail leads
me to you and your company.
They'll kill me.
Hell, I'm already dead.
(Knocking on door)
Mr. McDeere,
hotel security.
open the door please!
I can't help you.
And you can't help me.
Mr. Moxon.
Martin!
What are y--!
Mr. McDeere,
hotel security!
McDeere!
Open the door!
♪
(Cell phone ringing)
I don't have him.
Then you might not
have a job.
The boss won't be happy.
Well, at least Moxon's dead.
McDeere just lost
his only witness.
True.
That's not all he lost.
♪
sync and corrected by Bellows
www.addic7ed.com
Boundaries?
That's not a word you use
in a law firm, buddy.
That's a word you use in
couple's therapy.
I'm serious.
I'm not your employee,
Andrew.
My firm is associated
with your firm.
Meaning?
Meaning I get a say in which
cases I choose.
You can't just summon.
You went to
couple's therapy?
Yeah, twice.
I mean I'd tell ya,
but we're settin' boundaries.
Well that's number 1.
I get to approve my cases.
Done.
2...
I prefer to
do criminal work.
Also done.
Are we good,
'cause we're here.
One more thing: I don't
take meeting with guys
who wear suits that cost
more than 5 grand.
Is that a problem?
Not anymore.
Sorry we're late.
Russell Strickland,
this is Mitch McDeere.
Hello.
Thanks for coming.
This is my son, Brian.
Hello.
Hi.
Well, I know the 3 of you
have a lot to talk about,
so I'll leave you to it.
So, is this
a criminal matter?
We don't know.
My girlfriend,
Amy Sackheim,
she's been missing
for 3 days.
The police have asked Brian
to come in for questioning.
Well, that sounds routine,
I'm sure they just want to know
the last time you saw her.
Well, that's the problem.
I was with Amy
the night she disappeared.
We had a fight.
We'd been together
almost 3 years.
And we were
graduating in may...
And I didn't
want to lose her.
So, I got it into my head
that we should get married.
I got this ring.
I made a reservation
at Sophia,
a little French place
near where I live.
And I asked her.
And she said no.
She didn't just say no.
She got upset.
She told me that
we were too young,
that I should have
discussed it with her first.
They got into an argument.
Maître d' asked us
to leave.
Everybody was staring.
What happened outside?
Well, we walked to the car,
but Amy...
Amy wouldn't get in.
She wanted to be alone.
So, she took my keys and
she said she was going home.
She left you there.
I was only live a few blocks
away, she knew I could walk.
Brian's car has
never been found
and nobody has seen
the girl for 3 days.
That's all we know.
And when do the police
want to meet with you?
11 o'clock tomorrow.
You think we should go?
Yes, I do.
By now, the police will already
know about the fight.
If you're telling the truth,
then I would prefer to
get out in front of this.
I am.
I loved her,
Mr. McDeere.
So, you're bringing
in the son voluntarily?
If we don't, the police won't
focus on anything but him.
Well, they're probably
already doing that, honey.
Maybe, but the kid did have a
plausible explanation.
So it is our job
to provide a new theory.
I think he killed her.
That's just my opinion.
You don't know anything
about this girl.
Maybe she left town.
Or maybe she's seeing
somebody else.
Suddenly Brian proposes,
she doesn't want
to tell him yet,
so she skips town
with the new guy.
There you go.
And they go to Vegas.
Sleeping in motels
along the way,
but never long enough
for anyone to notice.
Eating in truck stops
and existing solely
on their secret love.
That's a disturbing
amount of detail, babe.
Okay.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Well, for now,
I want this case
to be your top priority.
What about your
murder case? The woman?
Sarah Holt?
I'm seeing her
later this afternoon.
You two, find me Amy Sackheim.
Mr. McDeere...
Brian?
What I told you
wasn't all true.
Have a seat.
It was an accident.
We left the
restaurant together.
Amy forced me to stop the car,
I didn't want to,
but she insisted.
I left her there.
(Tires screeching)
I couldn't do it.
I loved her.
So, I turned the car around.
I wanted to apologize,
I wanted to cry,
I wanted to see her,
I didn't even know
why we were fighting.
(Screaming)
I put her in the car
to take her to the hospital.
She was gone.
What happened then?
There's a lake...
About 2 hours north.
My family used to go there
when I was a kid.
I drove there.
I left Amy
in one of the boat houses.
I sank the car in the lake.
You have to
go to the police.
Listen to me.
If this was an accident,
we have to
tell them that now.
They will find the body
and they will find the car.
And when they do, they will
never believe you.
I can't go to prison.
You can't tell my father.
Brian, you have to
tell your father.
You have to
tell Amy's family.
They deserve to know
what happened.
No.
Brian?
Brian!
I've been over the case
a hundred times.
By law,
everything Brian said
is protected by privilege.
He has a right
to confide in his lawyer.
Okay, so we
can't tell the cops.
At least we can tell
Amy's parents
where they can
find her body.
No, we can't.
Why not?
'Cause he's our client.
We cannot incriminate him.
He's not our client, bro.
You're the one
who took the case.
You work for my office.
The privilege applies
to all of us.
Okay...
The body is in a location that
can be connected to Brian.
The body itself could have trace
evidence proving he killed her,
which would lead to his car.
So we just sit here?
Forget that.
I'll go get the body myself
and I'll take it
to a hospital.
And in the process
get arrested
for tampering with evidence
and obstructing justice.
We're obstructing justice
if we sit and do nothing.
Okay, Ray, see if you can
find the boathouse.
Don't touch anything, but see
if you can verify Brian's story.
And what are you going
to get him to do?
I'm going to get him
to tell the truth.
We have to be at the precinct
tomorrow at 11.
We will make the right
thing happen here.
♪
Remember to explain
your answers.
Don't just give me
names and dates.
♪
Relax, Martin, everything
is under control.
No, Alex, things
are not under control.
There are loose ends.
McDeere works
with us now.
He knows nothing
about why we hired him.
He thinks it's because
of some tort case he found.
How did he get our case
in the first place?
A mistake.
It was assigned by the court
before we knew about it.
The better question is how did
the girl get arrested?
We don't know yet.
Her name is Sarah Holt.
McDeere is
meeting with her now.
Well, I'm his boss.
Whatever he learns,
I learn.
Now, is that all?
No.
We have another problem.
Do you need
to be somewhere?
No, no, not until um...
Until 11.
Tell me about the woman they say
you killed, Margaret Whittaker.
I hardly knew her.
I have a new doctor here,
in D.C.
I went for an appointment
about a week ago.
We met in the waiting room.
And you spoke
to her first?
Yes.
She was very sick,
I could see that.
I didn't know she was
terminal at that point.
It was just
the two of you?
Yes.
And we started talking.
She said she
was all alone,
that her only son
is a deputy sheriff
who lived 2 hours away.
She was very unhappy.
She wasn't allowed
to be alone at night.
And she said the woman
from the hospice
who stayed with her
was abusive.
That's the word she used?
Yes.
It sounds crazy, but she...
Asked me if I would maybe stay
with her at night.
She said it wasn't much work.
She'd pay well.
I said, "yes,
I'm a Christian woman."
I got there at 8.
We watched tv for an hour,
I did some work on my laptop and
then I took her to the bedroom.
I waited until she fell asleep.
And that's when I saw it.
It was so beautiful.
And I know it was wrong but...
I put it on.
I heard the door opening.
Who are you?
Where's my mother?
You must be Eugene,
Margaret's son.
I got a call from the hospice,
she fired her nurse.
You wait right there.
And he told you to stay
while he checked on her?
I got scared.
I-I just didn't want to be there
to explain, so I left.
And when I got outside,
I remembered the pendant.
It was a mistake.
I started to go back
and he came running outside
with his gun drawn.
He said he found
his mother dead.
I don't know how.
They can't honestly believe that
I killed her for a necklace.
(School bell ringing)
Hey, Claire.
Hey.
You going to ally's party
on Saturday?
Yeah.
Great.
So am I.
And if you want anyone to talk
to you there or ever again...
You didn't see anything.
It's not just any necklace,
Mitch, it's worth over 50 grand.
Come on, Diane, she's an
auto insurance adjuster
with no record.
She's a good samaritan,
she's not a murderer.
She was stealing
that necklace
and she would
have taken more
if the son
hadn't come home.
You're wrong.
And you know this how?
Because I just
talked to her.
I'm pretty good
at reading people.
I don't see a case here.
Sorry, Mitch, you're not
the only one who can read.
The me's report
just came in.
Cause of death
was asphyxiation.
Margaret Whittaker
was smothered to death.
Guess word's out.
Why?
What's going on?
I just heard, you know
the girl who is missing,
the college student?
Amy Sackheim?
Apparently, she's dead.
The guy who killed her
just walked into a precinct
and confessed.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I gotta go.
That's my client.
(Tires screeching)
Detective...
Detective!
Uh, my name is Mitch McDeere,
I'm an attorney.
I understand you're uh,
you're questioning my client
in connection to the Amy
Sackheim disappearance.
He's represented.
You cannot interrogate
him without--
hey, we didn't
interrogate anyone.
Guy just walked in here
spilling his guts.
Well, then I am invoking
his rights to council.
You cannot question him
'till I can see him.
You're too late anyway.
He told us everything.
I was supposed to meet him
here this morning.
You got 10 minutes.
Who are you?
I'm Mitch McDeere,
I'm a defence attorney.
Good.
Looks like I'm going
to be needing one.
♪
- What is you name and age?
- Calvin Parker, 43.
And you live in Washington?
Your elbows
are on the table
and your posture
is terrible.
I'm sorry.
You know what else
is terrible, Calvin?
Lying.
Saying you
murdered Amy Sackheim
when we both know
you didn't.
I did.
No, you didn't.
Wh-- why would you say that?
I think I know what I did.
Certainly better than
some person I just met.
A person with the table manners
of a chimpanzee.
Did you know Amy Sackheim?
Of course not.
I mean,
only for a few minutes.
I picked he up in my car near
some French restaurant.
She was hitchhiking
in the rain.
Very dangerous.
Go on.
She wanted to
go back to her dorm.
She had a fight with her
boyfriend, something.
To be honest, I tuned her out.
I found it very impolite
to talking about
another man in my car.
And so, you killed her.
Her voice was upsetting.
I pulled the car
onto a side street.
Which one?
I really don't remember.
And I strangled her.
And her body?
It was thin, athletic.
What did you do
with her body?
No shouting.
We don't need
to shout to be heard.
Now you're upsetting me.
I need to know, Calvin.
If you truly did this.
Then where can I
find Amy's body?
I don't know!
The red room.
I put her in the red room
the red room?
What does that mean?
I don't like this.
I don't like talking to you.
So you just decided
to confess?
Killers go to prison.
Is that what you want?
You want to go to prison?
I think it's time.
I think I need to be stopped,
otherwise I might do it again.
Does that mean that
you've done this before?
Yes.
Many times.
You're not s--
it's not acceptable
to sit like that.
You'll get a hump
when you get older.
Is that what you want,
a terrible hump?
Hey mom, I'm going to Gillian's
house after school.
Really?
Thanks for letting me know.
I am.
I mean...
Can I go?
I graded your test.
Don't you want
to know how you did?
Already?
92. A-.
Second highest
in the class.
Uh-huh.
Who beat me?
Heather gamble.
Ugh!
What does that mean?
Nothing.
Look, I know she hasn't done
as well as you in the past,
but she is a smart girl.
Yeah, great.
Thanks mom,
see you later.
Why do you do that?
Another student improves,
you should be
happy for that.
Happy for me as their teacher.
Whatever.
No!
Not whatever!
Why whatever?
It's one test.
If you're jealous,
maybe you should--
I'm not!
Okay, I'm not jealous!
Well obviously--
I think it's great!
She cheated!
She cheated, okay?
She had the answers
written all over her arm.
How do you know that?
I saw her.
Okay, but mom, mom,
you cannot say anything.
Claire...
Mom, please!
She cannot know
that I told you.
Well, I have to
do something.
So, he just walked in
and confessed.
Yeah,
to multiple murders.
He can't even
keep track of how many.
I've seen this before, bro.
I did time with a guy
at Brushy Mountain,
he killed his
entire family and then,
some innocent dude
took the credit.
You think he's a crazy?
Well, he wants the attention.
He knew details.
He knew Amy was out
walking in the rain,
that she'd gone to college,
that she had a fight
with her boyfriend.
So, he reads the papers, I mean,
all that stuff was reported.
Yeah, that's true.
He didn't seem to know where the
body was.
We already know
where the body is.
That's assuming Brian
is telling the truth.
Maybe he's lying.
Mitch, Brian wasn't lying.
You found the boathouse?
Echo lake, 2 hours north.
And don't worry,
I didn't touch anything.
Amy's here.
If she's there, that means
Calvin Parker is innocent.
And crazy.
But the police don't know that.
We need to find Brian.
If he tells the truth,
then we can get Calvin out.
Mitch, you already have one
client in this case,
you can't have 2.
But we have to do something.
I'm not just sitting
by while they charge
the wrong guy with murder.
Look, you want it, you take it.
I don't give a damn
about the rules.
But what's Russell Strickland
going to say?
Absolutely not.
He is disturbed, Russ.
I don't know
why he confessed,
but I am satisfied that
Calvin did not kill Amy.
You don't know that.
Yes...
I do.
But...
Brian told you that he did it?
I can't answer that,
but we did have a conversation.
I am so sorry, Russ.
I uh...
I can't find him.
I haven't seen Brian
since our meeting.
- He's not at home?
- No.
And he won't call me back.
- If you're hiding him--
- I'm not!
But even if I were,
you'd have to protect him.
You're his lawyer.
Listen to me.
I promise you,
nothing I do will
incriminate your son.
But I feel obligated
to help the police realize
that Calvin
is not responsible.
No!
To represent him, you are
pointing the finger at Brian.
I won't.
You have my word.
Now, if it comes
down to that,
I will withdraw and let
another lawyer step in.
I said no.
End of discussion.
I'm doing it, Russell.
I am not letting some jaded
public defender screw this up
and plead him guilty.
You want to fight me
on that,
you put in a complaint
at the bar
and we will air this out
in a hearing.
I understand, Martin and I told
you we'd take care of it.
Why do you think
he sniffs like that?
Does he have a cold or
is he snorting half the coke
on the eastern seaboard?
Well, if it's a cold, he's had
it for the last 3 years.
Could be a nervous tick.
I suppose.
He does have reason
to be nervous.
McDeere met with Sarah Holt
this morning.
You get an update?
Not yet, I called,
but he's knee-deep in the
Strickland situation.
He asked if it could wait.
The update can,
but this can't.
When Sarah Holt was arrested,
she had a laptop with her.
Her own?
No, it was provided
by her employer
and let's just say it had
sensitive information.
Do you know what it is?
Material we care
about is hidden.
Routine examination by the
police won't reveal it,
but our client
wants it secured.
Then how am I supposed
to get access to it?
It's in evidence lock-up.
Then you steal it or you pay
someone to hand it to you
or you burn down the building.
I don't give a damn if you have
to join the police academy.
Whatever you need, boss.
Andrew...
You may not know
what's on that computer,
but what you do know
is more than enough
to take you down
with the rest of us.
It's not just what I need.
It's what you need,
what your wife and son need.
Are we clear?
Yeah.
(Elevator dings)
Calvin Parker, 43, in a
flaming ball of excitement.
Works as a tax evaluator
for the IRS.
Ah, no wonder he wants
the attention,
it's a nameless,
thankless job.
There's a thousand of him
out there.
Where'd he grow up?
Right here in DC.
Father was killed in Vietnam,
raised by his mother.
She taught music over at a
private school, very posh.
So, she spends her day with kids
who are rich and well-mannered.
That explains the whole
"elbows on the table" thing.
She wants her kid
to act like them...
Probably made him
crazy about it.
Literally.
Anything else?
Everything else is routine.
On the day Amy was killed,
he went to the bank, got his car
serviced at the dealership.
No red flags
on his credit card.
He's clean.
♪
It's kind of creepy, huh?
15 women.
Girls, really.
So this is how he knew
about the cases.
He memorizes the details
from the papers.
Ah, the truth is
it doesn't make perfect sense.
Some of these girls went
missing for a while,
but returned later,
unharmed.
Why does he put their
pictures up here?
'Cause he's innocent
and a fruit loop?
No way.
Half a dozen of these girls
was murdered
and I'll bet my badge
your boy did it.
Unless you know something
I don't.
Cops still think it's Calvin,
they're not giving up.
They will.
Look, we know Calvin
didn't do this,
we just have to find Brian.
Yeah, I'm trying, my sources
are all over it.
Meanwhile, Amy's body is still
sittin' in a boathouse
and her parents think she
still might be alive.
Which horrifies me
as much as it does you,
but my hands are bound.
There's nothing we can do;
We're out of options.
No, we're not
out of options!
Look, Ray,
you're a convicted felon.
Do I need to explain to you
why criminals need
to trust their attorneys?
Hey-hey, I took responsibility
for what I did.
I didn't hide behind any
technicality.
It's not a technicality, Ray,
it's the law!
Oh, you and your
precious rules, Mitch.
How do you live
with yourself?
What am I supposed to do,
let my emotions run me?
Yeah, because we both
know how well
that philosophy
worked out for you.
Meaning?
Meaning your way got you 15
years in a federal prison.
And yours got
your entire family
10 years
of Witness Protection!
At least when I went down
I got to keep
my own last name.
I mean, in a way,
I feel responsible.
I've been pushing this student
to do better and I...
You didn't
drive her to cheat
if that's what
you're saying.
Well, even if I did, I-I can't
just look the other way.
I mean, I have
to confront her, right?
Mitch?
I agree.
Or maybe you can
let this one go.
Are you serious?
I'm just thinking about Claire.
I mean, she's spent her whole
life moving around
and she's been
home schooled.
So?
So, she's just
trying to fit in.
The last thing she needs
is to rat out
the popular girl to her mom.
That's interesting.
What?
You're all about the rules when
it comes to your job, by mine...
Stakes are a little different,
Abby.
Hey, are you okay?
When I was a kid, my dad,
he drove this old truck.
Red pick-up.
Thing had to be 30 years old.
Breaks were shot,
no air bags, no suspension.
Half the time he drove it,
it broke down.
And my mom, my mom,
she had this rule.
Ray and I were not allowed
to ride in that truck.
Ever.
That sounds like her.
The thing was a death-trap.
One day, Ray and I were playing
in the driveway, my dad,
he comes out, says he
doesn't have to go to work
for a couple hours
and to get in the truck.
We'd go for breakfast.
But the rule.
It didn't stop Ray.
He yelled "shotgun"
and he jumped in.
Me, I wouldn't go.
What happened?
Nothing.
Nothing, two hours later,
they came back,
dropped Ray off
and he went to work.
My dad...
He was killed that day.
Killed in an explosion
in the mine.
It was his last day.
And Ray got to spend it
with him.
That's the thing
about rules, Abby.
It's more than what you do,
it's who you are.
Some people are wired to follow
them, others aren't
baby, that could have been
Ray who died that day.
Or you.
In an old truck with a
half a million miles on it.
What did you say?
I just don't think your
dad should have--
no, no...
About the mileage?
Abby, that's it.
That's it.
Where are you going?
I gotta call Ray.
I think you just got Calvin
Parker off the hook.
Your honor, the defendant is
charged with a single homicide,
the murder of Amy Sackheim.
But we ask you to note
that he has confessed
to several other
killings as well.
Which you cannot prove.
And I object to you
trying to sway the court
with speculation.
Speculation,
is that a joke?
Your client told us
about the crimes.
We just haven't had
time to investigate.
Your honor, my client confessed
to killing a dozen young girls,
half of which the da knows full
well are very much alive.
Is that your defense,
council?
He thinks he killed 12,
but he only killed 6?
He didn't kill anyone,
your honor.
These are false confessions.
And why, pray tell would
an everyday tax evaluator
want us to think
he's a serial killer?
Because he is unstable.
Because he wants the attention.
Your honor...
Amy's parents
are in the court, today.
It's hard enough
to face this tragedy,
but now to be told
it was all a sham?
I'm sorry.
But Calvin
did not do this.
He can't even tell the police
where to find their daughter.
A sidebar, your honor?
Quickly!
Your honor, the day before
Amy Sackheim disappeared,
my client had
his car serviced.
What's the relevance?
Just listen.
Calvin says he picked up
Amy in his car
near a restaurant
called Sophia.
That road is 29 miles one way
from the dealership
that serviced his car.
So?
So, the dealer registered his
mileage on the odometer
when they serviced it and the
police also registered his
mileage when they seized it.
The car had only gone
21 miles in total.
It's not possible.
He could not have been there,
not in that car.
Okay, look, I admit,
that's a discrepancy.
This is a lie.
His entire confession is a lie.
Mr. Hobermann, aside from the
confession of the defendant,
do you have any real evidence
connecting him to the crime?
I feel confident--
answer the question,
council.
Not directly, no.
Are there
any other suspects?
We intended to question
the victim's boyfriend,
but that wasn't necessary.
Well, it is now.
You don't have enough
to hold this defendant.
And so until
you can find more,
this charge is dismissed.
Bailiff, take charge.
Mr. Parker, you will be
released from inside.
What did she say?
I strongly suggest you
seek counseling, sir.
No, wait, listen to me,
you're making a mistake!
I'm the killer!
No!
Don't do this!
Now, you will be sorry.
I need to be in prison.
I'm a killer!
Don't do this!
Why won't you stop me?
I need to be stopped!
♪
So what are you gonna do, honey?
I don't know yet.
I mean, we've enough
for the last 10 years
to guarantee Claire
a lifetime of therapy.
I don't want to do anything to
make things worse.
I get that.
But you also don't want
to give her the impression
that she's running things,
you know?
Claire!
I need your help
setting the table!
And this girl, Heather,
she just gets
away with it?
Maybe not.
When I was 19, I was in love
with Jimmy Martucci.
Gorgeous!
And he used to hang out
at this place
where I was working
and waiting tables.
And he was older, you know,
like 21 and wouldn't give me
the time of day.
I find that hard to believe.
Well, he was a tough guy,
you know, not a real one.
But he thought he was.
And anyway, so one day,
I show up at work
with my new Firebird.
I had saved my money for
2 years and all of a sudden,
Jimmy wants to know me.
He asks where did I get it?
What's up, ladies?
Take those bowls to the table.
Please.
And I don't know why,
but I told him that I stole it.
The words just came out!
You did not.
From that moment on,
Jimmy loved me.
I was the bad girl
of his dreams and we started
hanging out almost every night.
Was it amazing?
Actually,
it was the worst.
He turned out to
be a total moron
and his friends
were petty criminals.
And I was just stuck, like
driving around with these jerks,
trying to figure out how
I'm going to break it off.
And that's the problem with
pretending to be
someone you aren't,
you have to then be that someone
even when you don't
want to anymore.
So, that was Strickland.
Detective Doyle just called.
The police want to
talk to Brian again.
Join the club.
If he went underground,
my people'll find him
before the cops do.
Maybe he's at the boathouse.
Why would he go back?
You don't think he'd move
the body, do you?
Maybe it's psychological.
They took Amy's body there
for a reason, right?
He feels safe at the boathouse.
Sometimes when people do
horrible things, they regress,
they go back to the place where
they felt secure as a child.
Okay, I keep thinking this,
so I'm just going to say it.
But what if Strickland
found Calvin Parker.
What if he hired this
crazy guy to confess.
Do you think that's
even possible?
I don't know, but something's
wrong and I keep thinking
that thing has to
do with Calvin.
Where'd he grow up?
Dc, single mom.
Uh, went to a fancy private
school, uh, Wardell...
Something.
The Wardell Fieldhouse?
Got it.
His mom used to teach there.
You know it?
I've heard of it...
It shut down a
couple of years ago.
I worked with some people who
used to teach there.
A lot of really good schools
lost their funding
when the economy
went bad.
Wait, wait.
Calvin said he put his victims
in a red room.
"Mrs. Joanna Parker in the
middle school music room."
That was his mother.
Could be a coincidence.
Or...
Maybe not everything Calvin
told us is a lie.
We appreciate the help.
I appreciate
the hundred bucks.
I don't know what you boys
are looking for.
No one's been around
this place for years, now.
This is research for a case.
Well, this is it.
This here,
is the music room.
Look, you'll need this.
I'll be outside
if you need me.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Vivaldi.
(Groaning)
(Laughing)
I don't know.
I don't see anything here.
Maybe up here.
Bring-bring that trunk over.
I need something to stand on.
Slide it over.
Ray?
Yeah,
put your back into it.
♪
(Coughing)
I count 6 bodies.
All women.
Well,
he isn't lying.
Calvin Parker's a serial killer
and I just set him free.
I don't understand.
How is that possible?
Calvin Parker kills women.
He uh, he warned me.
He's so far gone,
he can't even keep track.
That's why he confessed.
He read about Amy Sackheim
disappearing,
just assumed it was him,
like all the others.
So what now?
You heard him.
Calvin said we'd be sorry.
It's only a matter of time
before he does it again.
Mitch.
It could be a young girl
like Claire.
It's time, bro.
They want to disbar you,
let 'em.
They can't.
Lawyers are allowed
to disclose to save a life.
That's the rule, isn't it?
Do it.
Yes, 9-1-1, I'd like to report
a multiple homicide.
Dc police are reporting
the discovery of 6 bodies,
all of them women in an
abandoned school,
here in the city.
Police are confirming they
received an anonymous tip.
The bodies are believed to be
connected to Calvin Parker,
the man recently
released by a court
due to insufficient evidence.
(School bell ringing)
Uh, Heather, could you stay
behind for just a minute?
Heather, you did
so well on the test.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
I mean, I always knew
that you had great potential,
but this...
I was really impressed.
How did you do it?
Studying, I guess.
Well, I teach some of the other
students who need help,
every Tuesday
and Thursday after school
and since you did so well,
I decided to make you
my very own assistant.
I think you could
really help them.
Um, I'm not sure I can
stay after school.
It's okay.
I called your mom
and she said it's fine.
She's also really
proud of you.
Great.
So today's Tuesday,
so I guess I'll see you later.
Where'd you find Brian?
He was hiding at
a youth hostel downtown.
Gracias.
So what's the plan, Brian,
you gonna run forever?
'Cause let me tell ya,
that is harder than you think.
I don't want to run.
I know.
Because if you did,
you'd be long-gone by now.
Look at me.
Was this an accident?
Okay.
Then I will be with you
every step of the way.
This will not be okay until you
face it, until Amy's home.
You know that.
♪
I love you.
(Cell phone ringing)
Andrew Palmer.
Andrew, listen to me.
I found something.
I'm not sure what, but someone
just tried to kill me.
Mitchell, what are you
talking about?
I don't know who they were,
but I can't talk on this phone.
Hold on a sec.
It's McDeere.
He said someone
tried to kill him.
Keep him talking.
We agreed he
wouldn't get hurt!
Find out where he is.
Now!
Mitch, buddy, where are you?
♪
sync and corrected by Bellows
www.addic7ed.com