It's alright.
He's just for show.
What are you looking for?
A Volvo 940.
- What's it look like?
- Like a Volvo 940.
Alright clever dick.
Yes! Look, a Volvo 940.
Looks like any other car to me.
Well you don't see them often.
They don't buckle easily in a smash.
You want some of this?
Right, you keep a lookout yeah?
- I don't like this place.
- I'll be one minute.
Come on. I know somewhere where we
can get some money for some drink.
What?
I know somewhere where we can
get some money for some drink.
Alright.
I got it.
You brought me luck today you did.
Come on then, let's get wasted.
Hold on.
That's it, stand up.
Fucking hell.
- Getcha!
- Get down.
Get off me! Get off me!
Get down!
- You're no fun.
- I'm supposed to be at work.
What you after?
- We need some money.
- Oh yeah?
- You drunk?
- No.
Can I have a fiver?
It's my job to throw
drunks out you know?
- Oh come off it.
- Look, i've got no money on me.
Look how skinny this boy is.
We're starving, we need food.
I'll pay you back.
- I'm not a bloody kid you know!
- I know that.
- Is there any dinner?
- It's a bit late for that now?
What do you think this is, a café?
Thailand, anger?
I don't think so.
Japan, anger? No!
Russia...
- You still got my camera?
- You want it?
As long as it's safe.
It's safe.
You going out with that boy then?
Why?
- He looked a bit old for you.
- He's 19.
She's never had a boyfriend.
Just fucked him upstairs actually.
That's nice.
You can talk.
- Shall we go to bed?
- Yeah.
Come on to bed Sleeping Beauty.
It's about your new school,
you get to stay there.
You can fuck as many ASBO
boys as you like now.
That was clever.
I ain't going.
That place might
teach you some manners.
It's nothing to do with you, is it?.
- You need sorting out you do.
- So you keep saying.
But you're nothing to me
so why should I listen?
I can't believe it.
Oh my God, he's
just so easy going.
I knew it when I
saw him, I just knew.
Oh fuck off, as if I am.
No i'm not.
You know they're only
good for one thing,
and he is fucking excellent at that!
I know.
I know, I know, don't worry
babe, you'll meet someone.
Yeah, of course.
Are you going to
Anne-Marie's thing tonight?
9, right?
Alright then babes, see you later!
You have one new message.
This is a message for Mia
Williams, you sent us your video.
We wondered if you'd like to
come in for an audition next week?
Give us a call back
on 01708 665 001.
Oh, it's Val by the way.
Put your arm round me.
Hang on, the other arm.
- Up the stairs, that's it.
- My baby...
- I bloody love you.
- I know.
I'm going to sleep. You'll
be around in the morning?
Be a big girl, i'll be around in the morning.
- You promise me yeah?
- I promise you.
- You're up late?
- I've been busy.
- Are you my friend now?
- What?
You seemed a bit funny with
me the last few days.
You've been funny with me.
Have I?
Maybe.
- Your mum's passed out.
- She does that.
You all love your booze
in this family don't you?
Your hair looks nice down.
Better than the
ponytail you usually have.
- I've got myself an audition.
- Good girl.
No surprise in that one.
I borrowed one of your CDs.
- What sound did you pick?
- "California Dreamin'".
The one you put on in the car.
That's my favourite song ever.
- Do you want to show me?
- No way!
Come on, if you can't do
it in front of me now,
how are you gonna do it in
front of all those people?
Anyway, I think you're great already.
You know that?
I only worked it out tonight.
- It ain't ready really.
- Alright.
Just thought I could help.
It's your call.
That's all i've got so far.
Come here.
That was really good.
- You're just saying that.
- No, i'm serious.
If it was up to me
i'd give you the job.
I bet it doesn't feel liek this
with that boy of yours does it?
No.
Is his cock this big?
I'm pissed.
That was all avoidable.
No it weren't.
We have to keep this
between you and me.
Yeah, I know.
I'd better get off to bed.
I'm wasted.
We'll talk tomorrow, yeah?
Connor's gone.
Connor!
Did I tell you I nearly had you aborted?
I even made an appointment.
Are you gonna phone him?
- He won't come back.
- You don't know nothing.
I know what you did,
i'm telling mum.
I don't care what you do.
This is Connor, leave us a
message and i'll get back to you.
This is Connor, leave us a message...
118118, how can I help you?
- Hello, Wickes in Barking please.
- One moment please.
- Shall I put you through?
- Yeah.
Mia!
- I was just coming to look for you.
- Wickes, Barking, how may I help you?
Hello, can I speak to Connor
please, he works on security.
- Where you going?
- Connor O'Varner? he's nnot in this week.
- When will he be back?
- Not until next Friday.
- When?
- Next Friday.
- D'you know how I can get to Tilbury?
- Yeah A13, that way.
I'll come with you.
No, i've got some personal shit
to deal with, i'll see you later.
Excuse me, Danton Road?
- Straight there, down there on the new
estate, it's on the right. - Thanks.
Jesus Christ!
Come on!
Look, I don't know how you found
me here but this isn't a good idea.
- You're not answering your phone.
- My battery's dead.
- I was gonna call you.
- You ain't even got my number.
- You know I like you Mia.
- Well why did you leave then?
You know why.
Mia, you're 15 years old!
What does it matter
if you like someone?
Look, im gonna get the car,
i'll drive you to the station.
We'll talk some more then.
Wait here.
Stay there.
- When's the audition?
- Tomorrow.
I hope you're great.
I've got no money.
That should be enough to get you back.
Come here a minute.
Safe trip home.
We'll talk some more tomorrow.
No, don't shoot me!
Alright sweetheart.
Come on, up you go.
Keira, go on!
Sing a song for daddy.
That's great!
Smile for daddy.
- Come on!
- Smile for daddy.
- Keira, stay off the road, yeah?
- I will.
Keira! Keira!
Keira!
You mum said i've gotta take you
to the van to get some ice-cream.
Come on! Do you wanna come.
Let's see who can go faster, quick!
Come through here, come on.
Give me this.
- My scooter! - Well you can't
ride it through here can you?
We'll get it on the way back.
- Keira!
- Mummy!
She's playing a game,
come on, quick.
- Keira!
- Mum!
- Walk!
- I don't want to!
If you don't walk i'll
make you walk, now move.
Where are we going?
I wanna go home.
Come on!
Keira, walk!
Stop it, Keira! Walk!
You're starting to scare me now!
Move!
Stop it! Climb over this.
- Lift you fucking leg over.
- Shut up!
Get over.
Fuck!
Keira!
Keira! Wait for me!
Stop!
Stop running off!
That was silly weren't it?!
You stupid little girl!
Anyone can do that!
Keira!
Stop running off from me! Now!
- Let me go!
- Stop it!
You're just as bad
as your fucking father!
Stop it! Stop kicking me!
Stop it!
You alright? Yeah?
- I'm cold!
- Cold? Come on.
Off you go then.
That was beautiful darling, really
beautiful. We'll give you a call.
- And thanks for coming.
- Thank you.
- Lovely legs.
- Who's next?
Mia... have we got a Mia here?
Mia Williams?
Mia? Please.
- What track would you like?
- Number 17.
Can you just put your
hair down for us please?
That looks alot more
feminine, that's lovely.
- Any hot pants? Shorts?
- No.
Don't worry about that just... carry on.
What was that all about?
- Alright.
- That your car?
- Yeah.
It still needs a coupld of bits.
You left your cap.
Where's your horse?
She was sick.
We had to shoot her.
She was 16.
It was her time.
Alright.
I was thinking of trying
out the motor on a long run.
- Yeah?
- I know some people in Cardiff.
You know, in Wales.
Why d'you need so much stuff?
Just in case.
What about the referrals unit?
- You can have my place.
- I don't want it.
It's full of spastics
and idiots those places.
I'm going then.
It's one of your CDs.
Yeah.
It's alright.
Yeah it's nice.
He's good, you can keep it.
Go on then.
Fuck off.
What you waiting for?
Where you going again?
I'm going to Wales.
I thought you'd changed
your mind or something.
- This is my sister, Tyler.
- Hello, Tyler.
- Are you a pikey?
- Shut up you!
Ow bitch!
I hate you!
I hate you too.
Tennents!
See you later boy.
Later.
Alright?
Yeah.
Laters. Don't forget to text me.
Say hello to the Welsh for me!