Okay, my idea is, we find someone
like a Jo Wilf, or an Arthur Taub
and we get them to buy about
$300 million of debt
and then pay 80-90 cents on the dollar.
And let's say it's Jo Wilf,
he walks away with $30-40 million.
This is good.
I've thought it through, I know.
I just got to find someone
who can actually do this.
I take my seven percent.
You set it up, you get a finder's fee...
It's a lot of money.
And everybody wins.
Isn't this the scale?
The kind of deal that
Jo Wilf is looking for right now?
Yeah...
Yes, but I don't have direct contact
with Wilf. You know that, right?
Yeah, but you have friends there. Don't you?
I mean, this is your circle, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Bill Kavish. You know him?
He works for Wilf. He is a friend.
- Yeah.
- Do you know his name?
- Maybe.
- You know his family.
His father was Henry Kavish.
You remember him?
He got into some kind of trouble.
Yeah.
He was caught taking some money.
I don't know exactly
what happened there, but...
He was fired.
His wife left him.
Kids turned their backs on him.
He died alone and penniless.
- Bill is his youngest son.
- Introduce me to Bill.
I can give you his e-mail,
but I prefer not to send
a formal introduction, you know?
We represent clients
that do business with them...
I don't want to look like
I'm asking him for a favor.
Can I say that we're related?
- Can I say that I'm your uncle?
- No.
No. No. Don't make it a family thing.
It doesn't sound good.
It might not be a good idea
to mention my name.
Okay, you can say you know me.
Yeah, but please don't tell him
you got his address from me.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry I can't be more helpful.
It's tough.
You're like a drowning man
trying to wave at an ocean liner.
Jo Wilf is an ocean liner.
He doesn't see any of us.
But I'm a good swimmer.
- Yeah.
- Don't forget that.
As long as my head is above water...
Good morning, Bill.
Norman Oppenheimer.
What the fuck? Are you stalking me now?
No, I just need
a couple of minutes of your time.
I know you're busy.
Philip Cohen might have mentioned me.
No. This is my private time.
Please respect that. Call the office.
Does Philip know you're here?
- How did you even find me?
- It's just a business opportunity.
Look, I wouldn't be here
if it wasn't time-sensitive. Let me explain.
- Give me one minute.
- No.
A very high official...
I can't mention his name right now.
Made me an offer
to sell his country's tax receivables
to a third party for 80 cents
on the dollar...
Excuse me. I have to leave.
This is unacceptable, please.
Bill. Bill, no, I wouldn't be doing this
if I didn't think it was worth Jo's time.
Don't trust me, trust Philip.
Good things come in surprising ways.
You never know.
You never know, right?
I mean, what, worse comes to worse,
he kicks me out the door.
No! Worse comes to worse,
It is my job to keep people like you away.
Don't you get that?
- Yes.
- So please, respect my position.
Stop.
Please.
I'm sorry. I don't know what else to say.
So I'll tell my partners
that we had a good conversation.
And we'll see what happens. Okay?
Thank you, Bill.
It's not just about this one deal.
It's about connecting to people
at the level of Wilf or Taub.
If only it were that easy.
Look, I'm meeting a very high Israeli
official at a conference later today.
All I need is to get my Israeli
in a room with one of these guys.
I don't know if he would get involved
in a political situation.
Trust me, something good will happen.
...of chemical warfare on a first name basis.
Some of them are married to Russian women.
But it should be a real contact
without a drop of arrogance.
Well, suppose someone says
you can't trust them.
You would say it is not a matter of trust
but one of national interest?
There is clearly a problem.
Is America pushing Russia
away from the West
and into the arms of China?
Some natural gas experts
in this room will say
that's exactly what they are doing
by encouraging a pipeline
between Israel and Turkey.
But as I always say,
when dealing with global interests,
we shouldn't be playing backgammon,
Shesh Besh, you know.
Where you roll your dice
and hope for the best.
We should be playing chess.
The distinguished minister
speaking before me,
for whom I have a great deal of respect,
seems to know a lot about everything,
and it is hard to argue with him.
China, Russia, America...
He must know what he is talking about.
He's my boss, after all.
And a very good chess player.
But, you know, George Bernard Shaw once said,
"Some people see the way things are
and ask, 'Why?'
"I see how things should be
and ask, 'Why not?"'
Thank you, my friend.
- Okay. Hope to see you soon.
- Bye.
...people were there today.
You know, I'd be happy
to introduce you to him.
Shall I tell him that you are in town?
I could do that.
You know, I'm going to a dinner
at his house tonight. You can join me.
How do you know Arthur Taub?
My wife used to babysit him.
And then she ended up working for him,
years later.
They were very close. Very close.
Why don't I just call Arthur right now
because I'm sure he would be happy...
- Hold on, please, put the phone back.
- Happy to have his...
Welcome to Lanvin. How can I help you today?
Mr. Eshel is speaking in a series of meetings
with businessmen and diplomats.
He is interested in trying out those shoes
in the window.
Sure, may I ask
what line of business you're in?
Well, I don't want to ruin my first
impression, but I'm a politician.
Well, not any politician.
Mr. Micha Eshel is
the Minister of Trade and Labor in Israel,
and Deputy to the Prime Minister.
No, no, no.
I'm the Deputy Minister of Trade and Labor.
My boss, the Minister,
is Deputy to the Prime Minister.
But there are three other deputies,
just to put things in context.
It's an honor to meet you, sir.
I'm sorry, but you look too young
to be so important.
Well, thank you for the very flattering lie.
He has a future in politics.
Which is more than I can say for myself.
I might be young, but I'm already washed-up.
- You don't look washed-up.
- Yeah.
That's because I'm in New York now.
New York makes me feel good.
Back home, I look tired.
No. No, you don't.
I've seen your appearances on TV.
You look great.
Yeah, well, that's because
I'm very photogenic.
No, no. It's because
you are one of the few Israeli politicians
who radiates optimism.
Optimism... Yeah.
Well, the shoes I buy today will last longer
than the government I serve in.
Change is good. That's what they tell me.
The fashion world relies on change.
And the Middle East relies on...
How do you say stagnatzia?
- Stagnation.
- Stagnation, yeah.
Once you're in power,
you don't want anything to change.
You can ask my boss about this.
The young Minister shouldn't feel washed-up.
Excuse me for saying, please.
I can help with this.
Let me try something.
So, you said your wife works for Arthur Taub?
She used to, yes. She passed away.
I'm sorry.
It was years ago.
But she was very close to Arthur.
And I would be beyond happy
if you were to join me tonight.
He is someone you should meet.
Yeah, I know. I've been hearing his name
from a few different people recently.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
What's he like?
There are two kinds of moguls.
First kind is like a big ocean liner ship.
Makes a lot of waves, a lot of noise,
everybody sees it coming from miles away.
Like Jo Wilf.
I think your boss,
Minister Maor, is actually...
- In his close circle of friends, of course.
- Yeah.
And then, there is Arthur.
Well, Arthur is more
like a nuclear submarine.
He's quiet. He's fast. He's young.
Extremely sophisticated.
- Interesting.
- Yeah, he's a very interesting fellow.
He likes to surround himself with consultants
who are in influential
political positions, you know.
And he's very good at compensating
his consultants. He's...
Yeah, well, maybe I'll have
my office contact him.
We'll see. I'm not a private person,
you know. Not yet, anyway. So...
Yeah, if you have any trouble reaching him,
please, I'd be happy to help you.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
So where are you staying while you are here?
How can I reach you?
Just a second. Can I look at myself yet?
Please do.
Well, take this away from me
before I get used to it.
There is one rule
every Israeli politician learns
in the beginning of his career.
You cannot wear a suit that costs
more than an ordinary man's car.
But what if you didn't know what it costs?
I do. It's too late.
Israelis don't like to see
their representatives enjoying themselves.
I'm sorry for wasting your time.
- At least take the shoes.
- No, enough. I don't want them.
Let me buy you the shoes.
It would be my privilege
to buy you these shoes.
- Please...
- If it makes an Israeli leader feel good,
it's the least that I can do.
- I can't...
- No. No. Come on.
Just put them on one more time.
Would you do that?
Put your feet in.
Before you say no, just...
Please.
We'll take them.
I don't want you
walking out of here empty-handed.
- Here.
- No, no, no. I can't let you pay.
- If I take the shoes, I have to pay for it.
- You don't have to. It's done.
It's done. Okay?
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure. Yes. Positive.
Mr. Oppenheimer?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
- Please.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. Yes, everything is terrific.
- Enjoy.
- Thank you.
Jesus. I just realized I'm terribly late.
I have to run.
But I'm glad I bumped into you.
- My pleasure.
- Yeah.
Here, take some chocolates.
They're really delicious.
No, no. I have a severe nut allergy.
One bite, I could drop dead. So...
- Specifically cashews?
- Peanuts, actually. Peanuts.
But this is the one area I don't take
any risks. But thanks for offering.
- Wait a minute. This could really kill you?
- Yeah, yeah.
What happens to you if you take a bite?
Look, if there's even
a smallest trace of a peanut,
my throat closes up, so I can't breathe.
If I don't inject myself with one of these,
I could die in 15 minutes.
Your receipt, Mr. Oppenheimer.
Okay. Thanks.
Mr. Eshel...
Thank you.
- Okay. All right.
- Yeah.
Please, take some chocolates.
Hey, what about Arthur?
Can I tell him that I'm bringing you tonight?
Yeah. Sure. Sure, why not.
- Good.
- I'm staying at the Warwick.
You can leave a message for me there
with the details.
Okay. Will do.
- Thank you. Thank you, Norman...
- Oppenheimer.
- Norman Oppenheimer. Yeah.
Here. Take this.
It has my private number in back.
No matter what,
whenever you are in Israel,
Norman Oppenheimer,
if you ever need anything, feel free to call.
This is me.
Micha Eshel. E-S-H-E-L.
Just tell him he is the guy that is in charge
of regulating the energy industry.
Can you do that for me?
My name?
My... My name is Norman Oppenheimer.
Yeah. No, Mr. Eshel is
a very, very close friend of mine.
Well, just get back to me, okay?
Could you do that?
Thank you. Thank you.
I got a meeting!
What? With Jo Wilf?
No, no, no. Better. Better. With Arthur Taub.
Yeah, him and my Israeli guy.
At Taub's house, tonight.
How did you manage that?
I told you. I'm a good swimmer.
Yeah, hey.
Could you connect me
to Mr. Eshel's room, please?
Well, could I leave a message?
Norman Oppenheimer.
Did he say what he does?
He's a businessman...
some kind of investment fund.
I'm not sure exactly. A warm Jew...
Micha...
You can't walk in there
with someone you just met.
What do you know about him?
These things are important.
You want to meet Arthur Taub?
Let me set up a proper meeting.
Are you sure? It seems harmless.
I'm sure. One hundred percent sure.
I hear Taub is like a nuclear submarine.
We don't even know
what this event is all about...
I don't want you walking into
an uncomfortable situation.
Go see a movie. Go have good meal.
I'll book a table...
No, no, it's okay...
Any press about my trip so far?
No, nothing special.
It's better this way.
All right, I'll get something to eat.
Don't worry about me.
OK, but put it on your hotel bill...
the gas company is paying for it.
And do me a favor...
stay away from the Normans, please...
Sure.
Okay, okay...
Wonderful.
Hey. Ronnie, great to see you.
Thanks for coming, I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Mr. Taub would like to speak with you.
Would you mind joining me?
You can wait for him in here.
All right. Thank you.
Mr. Oppenheimer?
Norman. Norman.
We met, actually, at the Stern auction.
My wife is very friendly with Lili.
By the way, I can't thank you enough
for this last minute invitation for Eshel.
- It was very important...
- And where is he? Mr. Eshel.
He's on his way.
I just spoke to him. I'm sorry.
He apologizes.
He just got held up in a meeting at the UN.
- But he is on this way...
- You just spoke to him now?
Yes. I just spoke to him.
Yeah, he's on his way.
And how do you know Mr. Eshel?
Well, actually I'm helping him out
with some of his American alliances.
He... He's got very interesting ideas
that he's trying to promote right now.
For instance, the tax money
that Israel is withholding.
Well, he has this genius idea
for a third party
- to buy the tax receivables...
- And just so I understand,
Mr. Eshel asked you to ask me
if he can come tonight?
Well, no, I... I told him
about the amazing work
that you have been doing,
you know, especially with the...
The cancer research fund in Israel.
And he was so appreciative.
You do realize that this is
an intimate dinner?
Absolutely. Yes.
And that this is my house.
This is my private home.
- It is a beautiful home...
- Thank you very much.
Now, you can't just walk in it
and sit at my table.
Now I was happy to include Mr. Eshel,
even though I did find it a bit odd
that he would invite himself to a dinner
through someone I don't actually know...
- No. No. We met.
- But,
if he isn't here,
the invitation is not up for grabs.
- I... He's actually going to be here though.
- You understand that, right?
He... He's... I promise you,
he's going to be here very soon.
Okay, well, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you wait for him outside
and when he arrives, I promise you
we will make him feel very comfortable.
You want me to wait outside?
That would be great. Thanks.
Okay. That's fine. That's fine.
I know he's going to be here very, very soon.
Thank you, Arthur.
- Thank you. Good night.
- Good night.
Mr. Oppenheimer.
This way, please.
Norman Oppenheimer. If you came
to hear my class, you're a little late.
If I had the time. If I only had the time.
You're busy. That's good.
Someone has to keep
the world out there spinning.
So, what's new? Who's winning? Who's losing?
Tell me something exciting.
Well, I came from
a very special evening tonight.
Very fascinating people
at Arthur Taub's house.
You were in Arthur Taub's house?
Yeah. I took Micha Eshel with me.
Can I introduce you to him sometime?
You know who he is, right?
He's in the Israeli parliament.
He's young and charismatic. He's...
He's... He's sharp. Very sharp. Very sharp.
I'm helping him out a little bit,
showing him the ropes.
I'm helping him raise some money.
Well, he is a lucky man
to have you on his side.
No, actually, I'm the lucky man,
'cause this guy I'm telling you...
This... He's... This guy's the real thing.
He is just an incredible human being.
Well, maybe bring him to us
as a guest lecturer.
- If you say he's good...
- Next time he's in town.
And we should make an evening out of it.
- Sounds like a plan, Norman.
- Good. Good. Done.
I'm heading home. Are you staying?
Yeah, I want to listen a bit.
It relaxes me.
Enjoy.
Hello, sir.
Is it too late to call?
No. No, no. Not at all. No.
I just got back from Arthur's dinner.
Really wonderful.
I'm sorry I couldn't make it.
It was a crazy day.
I'm... I'm... I'm really sorry.
No, no. Don't worry about it. It's okay.
It's okay.
No apologies necessary.
We'll find another opportunity.
I told Arthur all about you.
I feel terrible.
- No.
- Do you forgive me, Norman?
Please, don't give it...
Don't give it another thought.
- It's fine.
- Are you sure?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm positive.
I... I want you to know
how much I appreciate
what you did for me today.
I really do. It was...
Nice.
I'm glad.
- Me, too.
- Yeah.
Thank you, Norman.
No, thank you. Thank you.
- Mr. Eshel?
- How do you say galgal anak in English?
You know, the big wheel
in the amusement park, like in London...
A Ferris wheel? It's a Ferris wheel.
Ferris. Ferris, yes. Ferris wheel.
Yeah.
Sometimes you are up
and sometimes you are down.
I just wanted to say that to you, Norman.
I've tasted it on my tongue.
Being on top of everything.
Once you taste it,
you can't settle for anything less.
Do you understand what I am saying?
I do.
I do, too.
Mr. Eshel?
It is my great honor to welcome
the Prime Minister of the State of Israel.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
For once I bet on the right horse.
It is a miracle.
So, from now on, how does it work?
Are you friends? How close are you?
Do you visit him in his office?
To tell you the truth, I don't know.
I don't know.
I just want him to know
that I'm here for him.
If he needs me.
So have you spoken to him yet?
We've been exchanging messages.
It's not that simple to reach him nowadays.
He's got a lot on his plate.
Well, if you don't go up to him,
he won't know you're here.
Look at him. He is sealed off.
For all you know, he won't return your calls,
even worse, he might not even
receive your messages.
Look, I mean, you need to get on that line.
Jo Wilf, needs no introduction.
- Mr. Wilf.
- Prime Minister.
It is good to finally meet you.
- Great pleasure for me.
- Another picture.
I was very close to your predecessor
as you know.
- Very glad to have you here.
- Thank you very much.
- You doing okay?
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
I might be reacting to something in the room.
I don't know...
Pastor Kermit Little.
Pastor. I'm so honored you are here.
Norman Oppenheimer, from New York.
Norman.
Norman. My friend. Where have you been?
I've been trying to reach you.
- Hanna. Hanna, do you know Norman?
- Nice to meet you.
This is my wife Naomi. Norman Oppenheimer.
Norman is going to be
my special honorary ambassador
to New York Jewry.
My personal, special advisor.
- I am?
- Yes. Of course.
Look around you, Norman.
There are over 500 organizations
represented in this room.
It is a tremendous force of nature.
Unprecedented in our history.
We need to understand
how this incredible force
unites around the issues
that are important to the Jewish people.
And the world.
- Thank you very much.
- No, no, no. Stay with us.
- Congressman Bob Easterly.
- Hello, Bob. How are you?
Do you know Norman Oppenheimer?
No, I don't. Nice to meet you, Norman.
This is my wife, Joyce.
- Nice to meet you.
- Very nice meeting you, too.
This is my nephew, Philip Cohen.
I think he is the youngest partner
at Frankle, Zell, Gould and Rudoff
in New York. Right?
- Well, one of the youngest.
- I'm sorry, sorry.
Nice to meet you, Philip.
- We represented Toby Tabatchnik, I think.
- Yeah, yeah, Toby, Toby. Yes.
Yeah, Toby. Toby. He married a Solomon.
Beth. Charlie Solomon's daughter.
Good to see you, this is my nephew.
My job is basically
to help Israeli businesses
communicate with the World Bank
here in Washington.
- My wife, Rita...
- Nice to meet you, Norman.
I'm with the JDC,
Joint Distribution Committee.
Her brother is the chief rabbi of Rome...
- Rabbi Ariel De La Pelgula.
- Nice to meet you, Mr. Oppenheimer.
- Please, meet Luis Pascual.
- Very pleased to meet you, Mr. Oppenheimer.
Luis is a Spanish Parliament member.
You know my friend, and lawyer, Philip...
They all come together through Jo Wilf
who is very close to
Rabbi De La Pelgula's family
and of course through him to the Pope...
Amos Chertoff.
Messianic Jewish Alliance of America.
Very pleased to meet you.
I want you to meet a relative of mine,
Norman Oppenheimer.
Norman, this is Jo Wilf.
- Norman is close with Eshel.
- Close?
How close is close?
"Close" close...
- God personally touched me.
- Listen, how come I don't know you?
I know every Oppenheimer in the world.
There's a lot of ideas out there
that are not biblical.
Do you know Steve Goldfarb?
For us at the NJF,
it's all pretty simple and straightforward.
The rule of law. Free and fair elections.
- Meet Sister Agnes.
- Nice to meet you, Norman.
This is Norman Oppenheimer,
a very close friend of Prime Minister Eshel.
- We're the only organization that's doing...
- Gay rights.
...what James, the Lord's brother,
said to do...
The goal is to encourage
positive views of Israel.
Have you met Barbara Klein?
I work with Peter Black
at a hedge fund called Sand...
Our mission is to make sure that
New York doesn't turn into New Havana.
Introduce me to Ariel-what's-his-name.
I saw you talking to him.
- We get you what you want...
- ...and we get what we need.
But everything has to be public.
Next time the Pope is in New York,
there's no reason the only rabbi he sees
is Alan Schweitzer!
Maybe there's something
we have to talk about.
Bill? Bill.
- Be sure we get in touch with Norm...
- Is this a cell?
- Do you have an office?
- ...with Mr. Oppenheimer.
No, but if I want to come visit you,
where would I go?
Startup State doesn't have an address.
That's the point.
- It's abstract.
- We're losing the building,
- that's what's going on.
- That rabbi you spoke with. Blumenthal.
Is he friendly?
Do you think he could help
with Nicole's conversion?
Something physical has to hold us together...
Evidently, there hasn't been a feature film
that's been seductive about Israel
since Exodus, so we're working on
a romantic comedy set in Israel...
Please, don't speak to anyone
on behalf of the Prime Minister.
If he asks you for something,
it is very important that you speak to me
or with Hanna first.
I'm so happy to finally meet you in person.
Feel free to call me.
That's what I'm here for.
My son, Davidy, he wants to go to
Harvard Business School.
He doesn't have the grades,
but he has good instincts,
- believe me, like his mother.
- His grades are good.
But he missed some of his exams
because he had to go to miluim.
You know what miluim is?
It's an Army service.
- ...a few tips.
- What can we do?
- We live in a tough neighborhood.
- To understand
- what they are looking for...
- But he's an excellent student.
Don't worry, all his calls go through me.
So don't use any of the old numbers.
- Thank you, Norman.
- Thank you.
- Any time.
Here, take my card.
Call me.
Norman Oppenheimer.
Nice to meet you.
Alex Green.
- Nice to meet you, too.
- Yeah.
So what brought you to the convention?
I work in the legal department of the
Israeli consulate in New York.
Really? No kidding.
You're Israeli?
That's funny, you don't sound Israeli.
I'm not.
Where is your family from?
Excuse me?
Where are you from? Where were you born?
How did you end up here? You know.
I'm from Geneva. Originally.
Really? Geneva.
Any connection to Julian Green? From Basel?
No.
No? Well, he's a big supporter
of the Israel Museum.
Could I introduce you to him some time?
You want to sit here?
If you want to? I mean, you got work to do,
I'm not gonna bother you. I promise.
It's all right.
Can I ask you something?
What is it you actually deal with?
Like commerce agreements or...
That's a different department.
We're an arm of the Israeli Justice Ministry
in the United States.
Okay, so if an Israeli criminal
flees to the U.S.,
it's your job to bring him back?
- We would be involved in that, yeah.
- Yeah.
The same if an American criminal
tries to hide out in Israel.
Yeah, that, too.
You must have some
really interesting stories.
Like, you know, those Russian oligarchs.
They're wanted all over the world,
but they're looking for asylum in Israel.
Can you give me the inside story
on how that whole thing works?
Sorry.
Do you know Carol Raskin?
You know, I may be wrong about this,
but I think she's actually the one who wrote
a lot of those international treaties
they're talking about.
She's a very close friend of mine.
I'd be very happy to introduce you to her.
No, no, no. That's not necessary.
I wouldn't want to bother her.
You have a family? Kids?
- Family?
- I'm sorry. What?
Do you have a family? Kids?
A partner.
You're a lesbian?
- Yeah?
- Yes. I am.
That's great! Good for you. That's terrific.
- What is?
- No, it's just wonderful.
I love that, when people know what they want.
You know, and they just...
No, it's a good thing.
I have a very close friend, a rabbi,
professor Nathaniel Lewis,
he teaches at JTS.
His daughter started a
Jewish lesbian organization.
Abigail Lewis. Do you know her?
No.
No? No? She's a... You would love her.
She's a wonderful, wonderful person.
I'd be happy to put the two of you together.
Look, it's the third time in five minutes
that you've tried to introduce me to someone.
Why are you trying to get me to meet people?
Do I look lonely?
Look, I'm sorry.
I didn't want to embarrass you.
If I did that, I apologize.
I appreciate you trying to help connect me.
It's just that I don't need connections now.
Okay. So what do you need?
- What do I need?
- Yeah.
I'm offering my services.
What do you need? I'll help you get it.
I need many things, but not
necessarily things you can help me with.
Try me.
I need the satisfaction of knowing
that I'm doing good in the world.
That's a big one.
You win.
What about you?
Do you have family? Kids?
Yeah, I have a daughter.
She just finished graduate school.
Yeah. Yeah, thank you.
Yeah.
Her mother died when she was three.
Sorry to hear that.
So you raised your daughter alone?
I did the best I could, yeah.
And why were you at the convention?
I noticed you were speaking
with the Prime Minister.
You know him well?
Yes. Yes. I do.
Micha is a close friend.
How did you meet him?
I bought him a pair of shoes.
- What? You bought him a pair of shoes?
- You never know.
You never know, you never know.
What do you mean
you bought him a pair of shoes?
You never know.
A pair of shoes.
The most expensive shoes in all of New York,
but the best investment I made my whole life.
May I ask what you do for a living?
Sure. I'm a businessman.
What sort of business?
Consulting. Mostly.
Who do you consult?
Well, businesses, organizations, individuals.
It varies, you know.
Sometimes I consult other consultants.
But do you have a specific area of expertise?
Can you explain to me
how your business works?
If it is not too complicated. I'm curious.
Hello?
Hi. It's Alex. From the train just now.
Alex. I was just getting into a cab.
Should I give you a ride? Where are you?
I'm still at Penn Station.
Are you on the street?
No. I'm still inside.
I just realized
you didn't have my telephone number.
So I just wanted you to have it.
Norman, are you okay?
Yes, of course I am.
No. Everything is perfect.
Couldn't be better. No.
This whole evening has been like...
Been like floating on a cloud.
May I have your attention, please,
Amtrak passengers?
All ticketed passengers
are required to have valid identification
at all times.
Randomly selected passengers,
their baggage, handbags...
Everybody, go home. Go to sleep.
The historical bond between
the United States and Israel
has never been stronger, you can all relax.
At least till tomorrow morning. Right, Duby?
If I have to shake one more hand tonight,
my fingers will fall off.
One more hand to shake, I'm afraid.
Bruce Schwartz.
Special Middle East Coordinator.
It's good to finally meet in person,
Prime Minister.
We don't have to shake hands.
You're not going to make me
put on my shoes, are you?
No. No. No. This is as informal as could be.
Good. The formal me needs a rest.
Bruce would like to go over some points
before tomorrow's meeting with the President.
Well, it's less about
your meeting with the President
and more about the statements
you will be delivering
elsewhere around town.
Now, as someone who occupies
a fairly tough job himself...
Excuse me, let me stop you. Please.
Tell the President that
I am here to say "yes" to peace.
I'm sorry "state of peace",
as we agreed to call it.
I fully accept his vision.
I understand it and I believe in it.
No internal politics will change
my commitment to the Wye document.
This evening I had to...
How do you say mas sefataim?
- To pay lip service.
- Yeah, I had to pay lip service
to a few organizations on a few minor issues,
but I promise you, it has no substance.
Well, I'm sure the President will be very...
You know what I've found out
in the last couple of weeks
since I was elected?
Maybe the President can identify with me.
For the first time,
I don't have political worries.
Somehow, God put me in this job.
It's not that I didn't work very hard
to get here, I did,
but hundreds of other potential leaders
worked and campaigned just as hard as I did,
and for some reason,
I'm the one sitting in this chair today.
The top spot.
I've reached the top of the ladder.
Why me and not someone else?
Who knows?
Believe me, I'm as surprised as anyone else.
But this is the interesting thing,
instead of feeling the burden
of that great responsibility,
I'm feeling...
How do you say goral?
- Fate.
- Fate. I feel fate.
If God put me here,
he must have had a good reason.
Now, I'm not free to run away from this job,
but to be honest,
no single human being can really claim
to be big enough for this job either.
I would be very happy
to go over our itinerary...
What is it that really worries the President?
Tell me.
What doesn't he want me to say?
Well, you have been saying
different things in different forums.
And I think we're just trying
to get a better understanding
of what is the singular message
you wish to deliver.
The "singular message"?
You were there tonight, right?
Hanna? Hanna, how many
completely opposing organization leaders
came up to me and said, "We're behind you"?
Fifty? 100?
Each with a completely different agenda.
There is no such thing as a singular message.
And anyone who tells you
he's got a singular message
is probably teaching at a university
or writing a blog.
- Okay, I didn't mean it that way, I'm sorry...
- I'll tell you what my singular message is.
I'm going to end this conflict.
How? I'm going to say "yes" to compromise.
To everybody!
Because the opposite of compromise
is not idealism.
The opposite of compromise is not integrity.
The opposite of compromise
is fanaticism and death.
Life is compromise.
I not only believe in that, that is who I am.
That is why I'm here, in this position.
If it works,
I will go down in history
as the leader who ended this epic conflict.
If I'm wrong, and my compromise
leads to another catastrophic bloody war,
I will blame God for giving me a role
I was clearly incapable of performing.
Look who showed up.
Our savior has finally arrived.
Sorry I'm late.
No reason to kill me.
Can you get rid of the nuts, please?
The situation is very simple.
The National Council
has decided to sell the building.
To be practical, we need to raise
approximately $14 million
to save us from the wrecking ball
and ensure our future here.
Or we start wandering
from one temporary arrangement to another
which, in my humble opinion,
would mean the end of this community.
Exactly what we talked about before...
Okay. Well, all right, let's not despair.
This is where our friend
Norman Oppenheimer comes in.
Norman?
Norman, Philip tells me you can help me.
You will have my best effort, yes.
Here, talk to Bill.
- Norman, this is Bill.
- Is Jo still there? Can he hear me?
Jo had to step out.
- Let me tell you what we need.
- Okay.
Colleague of ours needs a friendly
introduction at the State Department.
- State Department?
- Yes.
And if Eshel can help us with that,
we'll see what we can do
about your synagogue situation.
All right, I got it.
Hanna, Hanna, please,
just give me a minute with him on the phone.
One minute.
I'm sorry, Norman. The Prime Minister
is not available to speak right now.
Look, Hanna, this is a special request.
The Prime Minister asked me
to look into it, okay?
These are just very busy days for us.
Unfortunately, I can't be more specific,
but I'm sure you understand.
I understand, of course I understand.
All right. All right, all right, all right.
Please tell the Prime Minister
it would be great
if we had a short conversation
about a certain individual
who's on the board of the dean's advisory
at Harvard Business School.
Okay, Norman. Thank you.
No, no. Thank you, Hanna.
Thank you very much.
You can go back to your
very important work right now.
I know, I'm sorry for interrupting you.
And you're doing a great job.
I mean that, a really great job.
- Thanks.
- The prime minister appreciates it.
Just don't forget me.
What do I do with him?
Norman does not get past you. No matter what.
If he gets obsessive...
...take his call once every few days
so he doesn't get paranoid.
Do you think the PM asked him for something?
Isn't Davidy applying to Harvard?
I don't care.
Don't worry about Norman.
In his head, he just had a conversation
with the Prime Minister of Israel.
Yeah, I got a call
with Eshel this evening, but,
you know, I brought it up with his main man,
Duby already.
I think it's going to be okay. He's...
He's being very practical about things.
He says he can fix it,
but he wants the exact information,
so if you can send me an email
with your colleague's name please...
No. No e-mails, Norman.
His name is Matthias Kone.
He is an official in the treasury department
in the Ivory Coast.
Eshel's office will need to reach out to him.
We are not involved.
Rabbi! It's Norman.
I know, I've been calling you all morning.
Why don't you answer your phone?
I'm answering now.
Do you want to hear what I have to say?
Yeah. You spoke to him? What did he say?
Let's just say, get ready for a big surprise.
How many zeros
are at the end of this surprise?
- Can you tell me that at least?
- Come on.
A considerable surprise. That's it.
I gotta go, Rabbi.
No, no, Norman, you realize
how important this is, right?
We are going to get kicked out of here.
You need to give us a firm answer.
No games, Norman.
- Hold on. Hold...
- No time for...
I can't hear a word you're saying.
Norman? Norman?
God damn it!
How is the rabbi
connected to this again, Norman?
Remind me. Why am I doing this?
Do you want Rabbi Blumenthal
to marry you or not?
All you have to do is you pick up the phone,
call one of your buddies at Harvard
on behalf of the Prime Minister of Israel.
Is that really so difficult for you?
Don't belittle what I'm doing, okay?
In the world of Harvard admissions,
this is the biggest no-no in the book.
It's like incest. It's taboo.
That's funny, because Rabbi Blumenthal
is going to think exactly the same thing
when he finds out I'm asking him
to marry a Cohen and a convert,
who hasn't even officially converted.
Fuck.
Jo, something very, very big is going on.
I can't be more specific than that,
but if you saw the papers this morning,
you're gonna have some idea
what I'm talking about...
I'm not following you, Norman.
Did you speak to him or not?
No, but I'm going to read
the latest message I got from Hanna.
Who is Hanna?
Hanna is Duby's assistant.
- Who's Duby?
- Well, that's what I'm trying to explain.
Look, Eshel and Duby
are now at the national security committee
as we speak,
but there's no way
that I'm going to be able to get to them.
Hanna, on the other hand,
is just outside that closed door.
- She's gonna help us...
- Norman, cut the bullshit!
When you get Eshel on the phone
then call me back when he says yes to you!
Until then don't waste my time!
Yeah, Jo, but this is time-sensitive.
Look, I've got to tell Rabbi Blumenthal
that you're gonna give the money
because someone else
is gonna buy that building...
Rabbi Blumenthal is not my fucking problem!
They're going to launch a war in Syria
that's gonna turn into World War III!
I don't give a shit who started
World War III.
He's got a country to run. He's busy!
Yeah, well, so am I. Goodbye, Norman!
Fucking windbag.
Philip, it's a call, it's a call.
Norman, why haven't you
returned my phone calls?
Deliver that rabbi, Norman.
Why do I get the feeling
that nothing you tell me is real?
It's done. Eshel's son is on the list.
You don't want to know what this cost me,
but he is on the list.
Now please, if I decide to marry a camel
with three humps,
this rabbi still better be there
with his tallis.
Thank you, Philip.
You'll have your rabbi tomorrow.
5:00 p.m. I'll call you, okay?
I might have a donor who will match
your pledges up to seven million.
In other words,
if you come up with seven million,
half of the amount, the building's yours.
I mean, ours.
Who's the donor?
I'm sorry, I can't say.
He will remain anonymous.
Who donates $7 million
and wants to stay anonymous?
- That doesn't make sense.
- What do you care?
He's a modest man.
As long as he's good for it.
That's a legitimate question.
It's a lot of money,
we should know who the donor is.
Do we know who this person is?
Is he sitting here right now in this room?
What? Maybe this is
a money laundering scheme.
I have a feeling I know
who we are talking about.
Does his last name start with an R?
Are we playing guessing games now?
If he can say goodbye to $7 million,
why won't he just buy the whole thing?
I mean, it's just a number to these people.
- It's not real money.
- Seven million is real.
When you get to hundreds of millions,
that's another story.
Let's not get greedy.
This is a very generous gift.
And it should motivate our entire community
to become involved.
Thanks to Norman here,
we are only $7 million away
from finally owning our home.
But we need some kind of letter.
I mean, how do we even know
- this guy exists?
- A letter of intent.
- With all due respect, okay?
- We do need a letter.
Some kind of written commitment...
You can get us a letter, right?
- A formal letter...
- It should be notarized. Should be notarized.
And the money should be in escrow.
Okay. Escrow.
You sure you can't tell me who it is?
I probably should know.
I'd like to thank him.
Just between you and me. Is it Arthur Taub?
He was very clear about remaining anonymous.
But, can you tell me why he is doing this?
He can afford it. He knows me.
I told him... I told him about the community,
you know,
the history of the building, everything.
And why does he insist
on remaining anonymous?
If people knew he did this kind of thing,
there would be hundreds of other requests.
You know, this is not the usual
type of charity that he gives to. This...
This is something he did especially for me.
He did it as a favor to me.
Well. It is a good thing.
So please thank him on behalf of all of us.
Yeah. Yeah.
Not that raising the other half
is going to be so easy.
But the challenge, it's good.
- We should all open up our hearts.
- Yeah.
And our wallets.
God knows there are some
big wallets in this community.
And if there's any way
that you think it's appropriate
to honor this mysterious man, or woman,
a dedication of some kind...
Or if there is something
you would like me to do.
Yeah, well, now that you mention it,
you know, the person
who introduced me to Mr. Anonymous
is actually my nephew.
You know, he's a very,
very successful young lawyer.
Maybe I mentioned him to you. Philip Cohen.
Yeah, he's getting...
He's engaged to a very, very sweet girl.
Mazel tov.
From a Korean background.
He might need
a little help with her conversion and
officiating the wedding.
Philip Cohen?
If it were simple,
he wouldn't need your help.
Have him give me a call.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you, Rabbi.
Norman.
Norman called.
I should call him back.
He always helps
that lump in my chest disappear.
And I never understood why.
If anything, he should make it feel worse.
Why do you say that? He's a good friend.
...the most generous person I know.
It's naïve to call him "generous."
He is! He has a tremendous heart.
...always eager to help.
Not to say anything negative,
he's not your "friend."
He's someone you take advantage of
when it's convenient.
I doubt he feels that way.
That's actually pretty insulting.
No. It's just the reality.
When you needed him in New York,
you let him in.
Now that you don't, you ignore him.
Now you're making that lump feel worse.
You think I took advantage of him
consciously?
Maybe not consciously.
I believe that you consider him a friend.
But the right thing to do now
...is not to take any more favors from him
...or from any of the other Normans
in your life.
You know...
you didn't protest when Norman offered
to connect us to that Harvard guy for Davidy.
Right.
But I was uncomfortable with it...
But you went along even though
you were "uncomfortable."
Honestly, I thought it was another
of his empty promises
...and if that's the case, why make a fuss?
Plus, you wanted Davidy to get into Harvard.
...so you figured, it can't hurt.
And you let it slide.
- Right?
- No. Absolutely not.
I thought it definitely would hurt.
But I didn't want to hurt Norman's feelings.
I'm glad you didn't hurt his feelings.
That was very nice of you.
ACT FOUR
THE PRICE OF PEACE
"SOMETHING STINKS"
"ESHEL FACES POLITICAL RUIN
OVER BRIBES INQUIRY"
"The speculation about Eshel's future
has weakened him politically
"even as he undertakes delicate negotiations
with Israel's neighbors."
Well, now...
Is this serious? Do we need to
worry about our peace talks next week?
- I hope not.
- Well, can we help?
Maybe. Look, I don't know
who this businessman is yet,
but if he's an American citizen,
he can't testify
without your justice department
being part of the procedure.
At the moment,
this is just the press spreading rumors
but let's make sure
it doesn't spin out of control.
All right. Let me look into this.
Thank you. Thank you very much, Bruce.
The Knesset has seen politicians
with no backbone.
That is not new.
We've seen opportunists
distort the will of the voters.
This is also not new.
But never have we seen
...a man so morally bankrupt
...so spiritually empty
...so hedonistic
...selfish
...in a position to do so much damage
...as the man I'm pointing to right now.
Do you know who he is,
the New York businessman?
No. If I did,
is there any way we could help Eshel?
Careful, Norman. Don't put your nose
into this if you don't have to.
This kind of investigation
brings out the worst in everyone.
So, what do you think? How bad is this?
Is this serious?
It's serious.
Bribery is tricky, especially in Israel.
We have the Mid-eastern mentality
of giving baksheesh
and cutting corners and a legal system
run by tight-assed German yekkes.
If they can prove he accepted a gift,
he's done. He could end up in jail.
Look, I gotta go.
Bye.
No. He's the last thing I need today.
Hello?
Alex. Alex Green?
It's Norman, from the train.
Norman Oppenheimer.
I've been meaning to call you.
How are you? How've you been?
Sorry. Sorry.
I can't... I can't talk to you right now.
Yes, you can. Come on down.
I'm just around the corner from you.
Did you find out who it is?
Better. I'm meeting the investigator
who is in charge of the whole thing.
Just come on down, right now.
Give me five minutes...
- Norman, I can't...
- Bye.
Thanks for coming down, really.
I appreciate it.
You're acting like a maniac.
Look at you. Why are you getting involved?
This thing is bad for Israel, bad for America,
bad for Jews, bad for everybody. Step away...
You're right, this is bad for everybody.
That's why I want to help.
How can you... How can you help?
This is a political war
going on 7000 miles from here.
Look, Eshel's rivals
have found this cockamamie story
and they're going to use it to take him down.
There is nothing you can do about it.
Don't get involved. It is too big.
Just one thing, though. One thing.
Just hypothetically, look...
If this guy, this businessman,
he comes to you for advice,
he wants you to represent him,
what are you going to tell him?
You want to approach him? That's a bad idea.
No! No, I'm just thinking maybe
we can come up with an option for him
that's not so harmful to Eshel.
I'd throw him out of my office.
That's what I'd do.
I wouldn't want anything to do with him.
He is a threat to a sitting prime minister.
But even if it doesn't end up
having any criminal implication...
Okay? Apparently his dealings with Eshel
are embarrassing enough
so that his political rivals
think they can use him to hurt Eshel.
Eshel's people can't ignore that.
They have too much to lose.
They're going to strike back.
Dig up everything they can find on this guy.
The FBI will get involved...
I mean, no matter how you look at it,
this guy is fucked.
And you want to avoid him like the plague.
Look, I'm just asking if there's
some legal way to defuse this whole thing?
Okay, all right.
Norman. Now you listen to me.
Whoever this unnamed businessman is,
he is in very serious trouble.
And he needs to be very careful
what he says now.
And who he speaks to.
Yeah, I just was asking, you know, if I'm
meeting with the investigator of this suit
and I find out who this guy is,
I want to be able to offer him something.
So, think creatively with me...
I'm not sure I can offer him anything.
This man needs a very good criminal lawyer.
Don't be creative.
And do not meet this investigator.
Can you do that?
A man who isn't strong enough
to say no to gifts
...too weak to resist
the temptations of power
...has taken us hostage
...in his megalomaniacal peace adventure.
He'll drive me crazy.
He'll call every 3 minutes.
Easier to just answer.
Alright, but keep it short.
Don't let him get involved.
Before you say "no",
just listen to what I have to say,
because they're really
going to want to hear this.
I have a meeting with the woman
who is in charge of
this investigation that's going on right now.
Her name is Alex Green.
She agreed to have a meeting with me today.
At 4 o'clock.
And I'm going to try to get
all the information I can out of her,
but I was thinking maybe
Duby would want to give me
a briefing before the meeting...
Norman, I don't think it's such a good idea
for you to meet this woman.
Please, they can use me any way they want.
I'm... I'm like a puppet in their hands.
I'm just here to help.
And... Look, this is off the record,
a friendly conversation,
I have known Alex Green for years.
- She is a wonderful person.
- Norman...
My wife used to babysit her.
Hold on, just wait on the line.
We must vote against this dangerous agreement
...masquerading as a peace treaty.
- Norman...
- Duby!
Shut up, Norman.
Shut up and listen to what I'm saying to you.
I don't want you
meeting anybody on our behalf.
Creating the impression that in some way
you are connected to our office
is a severe, punishable crime.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Stop using the Prime Minister's name.
Don't do it anymore. He's not your friend.
And you don't have any relationship with him.
I forbid you to meet with this woman.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Answer me!
- Yes.
- Good.
I'm not sure if it was a good idea
to insult Norman.
That's the problem with these Normans.
They're a double-edged sword.
If you keep them in the loop,
you're more and more dependent on them
until they own you.
If you cut them off,
they blackmail you forever.
He's just trying to help.
No more Norman.
Find out who this businessman is.
I need a name!
In a day, every newspaper will want to know
who this man is.
We must be ready.
"WHO IS HE?"
I don't know.
Giving in to our enemy's every demand
is not peace.
It's DEFEAT.
- Norman.
- Hanna.
I'm calling for Duby.
He shouldn't have spoken to you like that
and he asked me to apologize.
- He did?
- Yes.
He specifically asked me
to call you and apologize.
Okay.
And don't worry. The whole thing
with this unnamed businessman
is going to disappear
as soon as people find out who this guy is.
Thank God we're strong.
Nothing like this can really affect us.
Well, do you know who he is,
this businessman?
All I can say is
it is someone the Prime Minister
doesn't even know personally,
and someone he would never get close to.
The man's a clown,
someone who makes up stories
'cause he's got nothing better to do.
Just between you and me,
this man is a known crook.
I can't tell you how relieved I am
to hear you say this, Hanna.
Thank you.
And please tell Duby that
I understand his situation completely.
And if there's
anything that he needs me to do,
I'm there for him and for the Prime Minister.
- I will, Norman.
- Yeah. Thank you.
You're assuming he'll repeat it all
to the investigator?
He'll want to prove
he's got the inside scoop.
And not only to her.
He'll spread it all over.
...exaggerating so that it sounds even worse.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hey. Hey, you. You. Wait a minute.
Hey. You.
- Who, me?
- Yeah, you. What are you doing?
Why are you following me?
First of all, it's a pleasure to meet you.
I'm Srul Katz.
No, don't do that.
Excuse me, don't give it to me.
I don't want it. Just stop following me.
Why are you angry? I'm not following you.
It's sheer coincidence
I'm going the same way you're going.
You want me to apologize? I'm very sorry.
I'm truly sorry. I apologize.
But since...
Since we're already talking together,
if I could take
one more minute of your valuable time,
it's such a pleasure to meet you in person.
You're the Eshel guy, right? Oppenheimer.
Yeah? Maybe Zvi Fink, he mentioned me to you.
How do you know Zvi?
We're very close, me and Zvi.
My wife, she practically
grew up in his parents' house.
I'm gonna see him tonight, actually.
You know, you should come by and say hello.
He'd be...
Oi, he would be delighted to see you.
Are you all right?
You look a little shaken up.
How can I help you? Let me help you.
What do you need?
Tell me what you need.
- What do I need?
- Yes, please.
Could you give me the honor of helping you?
You're a choshuve' man.
Please, a very important guy.
Which... We're going to walk together.
Which way... Are you okay?
- I...
- Which way are you going?
- The Israeli consulate on Second Ave.
- I'm going that way. Come on.
- What, you just get bad news?
- Yeah, I ate something.
- You ate something?
- I have to have a Benadryl.
Sometimes, I get a little thing in my body...
You get allergies?
You know who it is, this...
The New York businessman?
If I knew, would I tell you?
Well, no. 'Cause I heard a rumor but,
you know, they swore me to secrecy.
Yeah, yeah, don't believe the rumors.
Well, look, obviously you know
more than I do,
but whoever this guy is,
one thing is for certain,
it's a conspiracy. Yeah?
They found a way to assassinate Eshel,
without actually killing him.
Don't bury Eshel yet. Trust me.
He's not going anywhere.
Why? What do you know?
You know something.
I can't go into details,
but let's just say
that this unnamed businessman...
He's a nobody. He's a parasite.
He's trying to
extort money from the Prime Minister.
He is the lowest of the low, this guy.
He made up a story, you know.
The whole thing is just a made-up thing.
You know? It's... It's...
Eshel doesn't even know the man.
I think I'm okay from here on.
So, thank you. I... I appreciate it.
Are you sure?
Because I'm happy to go in with you.
No. I'm okay. I'm okay.
You want I should wait out here?
No, I... I'm good from here, I...
But, thank you very much, I really...
I appreciate it.
Norman, are you going to do me a favor?
You're gonna call me
if you need anything at all.
You don't understand,
it's going to be my pleasure to help you.
My name is Norman Oppenheimer.
I have an appointment with Alex Green.
Hey, you know what?
I... I forgot something. I...
I'm gonna be canceling this meeting, so...
Look, I don't see my phone in there.
Can you give me my phone?
Can you give me my phone? Hello?
Hello?
Hello! Could you give me...
I don't see my phone!
Could you... I'm not going in!
So you might as well
give me my phone back right now, please!
It's okay. Come.
They told me not to meet with you.
Who?
The Prime Minister's office. Duby.
I don't want to upset them.
He'll know I was here. I don't...
It was a mistake.
No, please. I respect you very much.
I'm sorry. I apologize.
I shouldn't have called you.
No. It's good that you called.
I'm glad you're here.
Norman, I want this conversation
to be as straightforward
and honest as possible.
Do you think you can do that?
I spent the past few months
trying to know more about you.
Where you come from, what you do,
who your friends are, your family.
Your financial situation.
And what I've discovered is very strange.
Everybody seems to know who you are.
But nobody knows anything about you.
Even people
who say they have known you for years.
For instance, nobody knows where you live.
I was able to confirm that
you inherited a small amount of money
from your mother,
and that she left you
her rent-controlled apartment after she died.
But I wasn't able to
verify that you have a daughter
or that you were ever married.
Were you?
Do you have a daughter?
Why are you
gathering this information about me?
Because you've been unusually generous
toward the Prime Minister of Israel
and have created
an intricate network of people
who benefit from the access you provide.
The relationship you've established
with the Prime Minister of Israel
is illegal.
I think it is corrupt.
The unnamed New York businessman...
You are that man, Norman.
You are our witness.
No, I'm not.
We can subpoena you. You have no choice.
I'm going to go now. I'm sorry, but, I'm...
Wait. You need to hear what I have to say.
We're arranging
for an early deposition for you tomorrow.
I can't force you to stay here now.
But here is your official notice.
If you testify and speak truthfully
about everything that you've experienced,
we can protect you from self-incrimination.
It will be about him. Not about you.
But what is Eshel going to do?
What will he do to me?
They will try to
persuade the court and the public
that you are an unreliable witness.
That will most likely be their defense.
I'm sorry.
Right now...
...few people know who Norman Oppenheimer is.
We have an opportunity to brand him.
...to disqualify him as a witness
...portray him as a crook
...and paint the Prime Minister
as an innocent victim.
How am I a victim?
We have all the power, Duby.
Never say that. It is not true.
You are Mr. Peace right now.
The press will be on your side.
Nobody wants to see our peace efforts
go down the drain...
...because of some shady Jewish macher.
We need to portray him
as a delusional name-dropper...
...who has been sucking your blood for years.
You need to say this clearly.
It's necessary. And it's true.
There must be another way.
Norman is a friend. A very generous friend.
I won't hurt him.
It is not personal.
It's bigger than
the pain felt by one individual.
He's a threat to our national interests.
Our personal feelings aside...
...we must treat him like
any other strategic threat.
I took your advice.
I didn't go to the meeting.
I'm stepping back, like you said.
I'm proud of you. Good move.
Are you there, Norman?
I'm here.
You okay?
I'm a good swimmer, Philip.
Don't worry.
As long as my head's above water...
You are a good swimmer. That's for sure.
Look, I wish I could've
been more helpful but...
- You know, I...
- You've been a very big help, Philip.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
I love you.
Excuse me. Can I help you?
Rabbi!
You!
What are you doing?
I need to talk to you.
No, you need to sign those escrow papers,
that's what you need.
Do you realize
we're going to lose all our pledges?
Not to mention this building, and my job!
Norman, why haven't you
returned my phone calls?
Fuck!
- I'm working on it.
- Fuck!
I should've known not to trust you!
What am I going to do now?
Was there ever a donor? At any point?
Yeah, but I thought I had someone.
I still might have them, I just...
It's not a sure thing.
Then why would you tell us you had a donor?
Why? Why would you do that?
Is that you, Norman?
Norman, are you there?
Is it safe for us to talk?
It probably isn't.
But there's something I need to tell you
before the lawyers
and the PR people take over.
And I'm speaking to you now as Micha Eshel,
not as the Prime Minister of Israel.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for what is about to happen to you.
In the next couple of days,
you're going to hear me say things
that I don't really believe.
Things about you.
And it will hurt. It will hurt both of us.
But the only reason
I will be saying these things
is because there are
hundreds of thousands of lives at stake.
The enemies of peace
have decided to step all over you
on their way to behead me.
It is a terrible price to pay.
But, Norman,
I can't let them win.
We can't let them win.
History is full of anonymous heroes, Norman.
The day I walk up to that podium
to sign the peace treaty,
you will see
a very specific expression on my face.
Know that I will be thinking of you...
Norman Oppenheimer.
Do you accept my apology, Norman?
Do you forgive me?
I will never betray you.
I love you, Norman.
Thank you.
Good morning, Bill.
Why do you do this?
Why can't anything ever be simple with you?
Who says simple is good?
I have a business opportunity for Jo.
He's going to like this.
No. No, you don't.
Whatever it is, it's too small.
Norman.
Wait.
I'm listening out of respect to my father.
You knew him, didn't you?
All right. What have you got?
If you knew with 100 percent certainty
that the witness who is
trying to topple down Prime Minister Eshel
will never testify,
would you know
how to make money with that information?
Well, it depends on
where and how I got that information
and if I can verify it.
You realize
you're not a very reliable source, right?
You put me in a room with Jo Wilf.
I'll give him all the certainty he needs.
Think about it. Go ahead. Think about it.
Run the numbers, do the whole thing.
You have until 8:00 a.m. to call me back.
After that, I'm going to Arthur Taub.
What's your fee?
Philip. Nicole.
At times like this,
when we're aware of our blessings,
we also know that the world
is in desperate need of repair.
Tradition explains
the act of breaking the glass
reminds us to turn our hearts
towards the city of Jerusalem.
In which the ultimate peace
shall be granted to the world.
Mazel tov!
- Hi.
Thank you.
Welcome to Harvard, David Eshel.
Thank you. Happy to be here.
As we turn to the economic implications
of this peace treaty this morning,
one investor, Jo Wilf,
is looking like a big winner.
And when I say big winner, I mean, like,
a-billion-dollars-overnight big winner.
Wilf, at a series of what now
seem like pretty prescient bets that...
All the way back to the conversation
we've been having
about the possible impeachment
of Israel's Prime Minister.
Now, just when everyone thought
the Prime Minister would get the boot,
Wilf bets the opposite.
He shorts natural gas
and then he magically buys shares
in both Sampton Energy
and the Tel Aviv-based Barkin Group.
Those are the companies
building the Israel-Turkey pipeline.
This deal is starting to look like
the trade of the decade.
Genius.