... light the night, and every tune
seems to sound just right,
It's absolutely the place to be, making
Wikki Wakki down in Waikiki
Come with me, all you whoopee-makers,
all you wide-awakers, join me.
Oh boy, I just found a spot.
You're gonna like it a lot!
And it's far away, off in Honolulu,
where the hula hula greets you....
Hawaii is the place, get a smile on
your face!
And I want to go where they swing
their hips,
that's where the sailors all shake their
ships,
you wouldn't blame me, if you could be,
making Wikki Wakki down in Waikiki!
You get a feeling of pure delight, your
head is reeling, your heart is light!
Your eyes are dancing with revelry,
making Wikki Wakki down in Waikiki!
You never saw, dresses of straw, like
they're wearing there...
And all those dances they do, there's
nothing you can compare!
What a revelation!
Hawaiian cuties, with goo-goo eyes!
And they are beauties,you'd be surprised
You're never lonesome for company,
Making Wikki Wakki down in Waikiki!
Say, you never saw, dresses of straw
like they're wearing there!
And all those dances they do, there's
nothing you can compare,what a revelation!
Hawaiian beauties with goo-goo eyes, oh
they are beauties, you'd be surprised!
You're never lonesome for company,
making Wikki Wakki down in Waikiki!
Son of a bitch!
Get up!
Up now!
I'll put this foot down here!
You're insane, you really are insane!
You're the one that's a fucking nut!
- Just leave me alone
- Now get up and go to work!
There's nothing to do now, there's
nothing to do, just leave me alone!
Oh really?
OK, I'll get up, I'll get up!
Now!
Get up now!
You've been sleeping in that damn bed
all day, and you've been out with those
dumb cunts, all night,
And then you waste your time watching
television....
- Yeah
- Get up!
I'm up!
Alright, get in the shower!
Come here! C'mere, talk to me...
- Aren't you getting up?
- Not yet....
My girlfriend's coming over, c'mon
you have to get dressed now.
- Don't you want to get up and see my
girlfriend? - I don't...
C'mon darling, get up...
But what am I going to do if I get up
now?
There's that pig on the phone!
- Who?
That filthy filthy pig that you know!
Who's that? I don't know any pigs!
- Yes you do!
- You know the pigs, I don't know any
pigs - A million pigs!
- You're the only one that knows pigs,
I don't.  - Where's my matches?
Get them, I'm, I'm going to ...
What are you going to do today,
what do I have to do?
You have to, uh....
do something with me!
Beautiful!
Why do you do that?
What are you doing? Clothes on...
Get it!
See you do that?
What do you do that for?\
Cause I like it!
Love to...
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
Why do I...?
always have to tell you when to do
my laundry?
To iron my shirt, to ask you if you did
it?
How can I....?
I can't yell at you, even, because...
You are really...
Will you please?
Will you please stop, please, stop!
Please!
They're dirty...
Do my laundry will you?
Without me asking just once?
I make you happy don't I? No?
What do I have to do to make
you happy?
Look it, if you want to make me, you
want to make me happy?
You really want to make me happy?
Do my laundry?
Oh yeah?
You know the kid?
She's got, you'll have to take her to
the doctor, you, you should be able to
take her, I'm sick of going to the
doctors and looking at all
those fucking old ladies, crazy old
ladies... - No, you go!
- I'm sick of...
- Sitting there looking at me...
- Well, it isn't my job
- No, it isn't my job!
- It's your job! No!
- Yes it is!
- You never do anything else!
- No!
My job is to make sure that I protect
the family, you know, that's all.
Make sure nothing happens to you
- You never protect any... - Sure, I
would never let anything happen to you
- Oh, you're so full of shit, yes
you are! - No, no,no...
- You are full of shit!
- I'm not full of shit!
- You are!
- Oh!
Don't you...
- any places to go, yeah
- Oh yeah....
- Go out and get some fucking money,
for Chrissakes! - I get enough money...
I not only need money for the house, I
need money... $200
For what?
For my girlfriend's abortion...
- $200?
- Yeah
Why do I have to give you $200 for
your girlfriend's abortion?
Because you have the money and I don't!
- Why do you have to give it to her?
- She really has to...
Because she has no-one else to
give it her!
So like you know, I'm not in the mood to
go down to 42nd street, you know.
Like, you know, I call up two or three
people and I make the money,
and I hand it over, and like I can't see
these people no more!
- All family... - So why would I want
to do that, you know?
- What happens if the baby gets sick?
- Go somewhere else and get it!
There's other places besides 42nd St.
You're just too spoiled, you know that?
- Yeah I know...
- Your mother teach you to...
I know I can't so.. when I'm out, you
watch, right?
When you're out. I'll watch.
- I can't hustle 25 calls a day...
- No let's do it the same time
We'll make the neighbour watch the baby
Or your mother can watch, she
doesn't do anything else!
She'd better just be sitting...
- Ain't ya a dumb cunt!
.. her number
- Oh yeah? What did you do with her?
-Yeah!
- I know all about your mother
-Oh yeah? My mother knows all about you!
So like you know, you get the money,
but like...
- So what are you gonna get, $200 and
that's it. - No, I need some more money!
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah!
It's very painful, I like, you know...
don't like that kind of work!
- Are you going to do it?
- Yeah
When?
- Tonight
- Tonight?
- Are you sure?
- After your girlfriend leaves
- After my girlfriend leaves? Why not
before? - Yes.
Because, I wanna see her.
Oh, what'd you marry me for anyway?
- Cause you're a good fuck!
- Awww, thank you!
- I think I'm going to wrap it up,
honey... - You getting
- getting pretty embarrassed now...
Yes I think i'm gonna wrap it right up
- Guess she'll like that. Won't she?
- OK? She'll love it!
- See I got a package for you!
- Good things come in small packages!
- Right?
- Right.
Wrap it nice and pretty
Okay!
Oh, it looks so great wrapped up. Oh,
so scrumptious!
- All you have to... yeah it does
- Does it look good?
-Does it look pretty? - Oh it looks
so beautiful, a little bow on it!
- A little bow?
- Gee it does wonders!
- Don't you like it? You don't?
- Mmm Hmm
- Do you like it honey, isn't it
beautiful? Yeah, beautiful.
Oh, wait until my girlfriend sees it,
she's gonna go wild!
She's gonna go insane!
Oh, isn't it the cutest little thing, oh
it's marvellous!
- Really?
- Just look at that!
It's the only way for it to be!
- Don't you like it?
- Now you're not going to get any!
Isn't this fantastic? Did we do this
before?
- No, I've never had...
- No?
- You're kidding!
- I was...
So, I'm going to get ready now,
get dressed.
- No!
- Yes!
I wanna sit and watch this pretty
package!
- No!
- Yeah!
- No, because I... I'm not getting...
- Oh, but it looks so good!
Since you are a...
- Oh, a harlot!
Go on...
- Do you have that underwear?
- No, I...
Well how am I supposed to make any
money without clean underwear, the johns
- You can wear that, you know that's
better... - The johns won't see dirty...
You do, just get up and look at yourself
- It's marvellous! - No it
doesn't, it looks terrible...
Where's my underwear?
Oh, so marvellous, come out let
me see it!
No, that's terrible, I don't like
that...
- Oh, I love it!
- I don't like that!
- It's marvellous, come out!
- Where's my... no!
- Oh, don't take it off it looks really
great! - No, I need clean underwear!
- No, go watch Mitt today and then run
down to.. - No, you can wear anything..
- the dryer for...
- I wanna see it!
No, see it!
- Ain't it fabulous, but now go get
me, I need - I wanna see it!
I don't like you to have any underwear,
you'll have to wear that! - I need...
So much prettier wrapped up!
You have the underwear? I'll wash it
for you! - Go wash it!
- You... I know!
- You'll get looked at!
I waited, I let you wrap it up, I let you...
- No!
- Is that washed?
- No, come...
- Please don't grope it!
- Give it!
- Let's put it on your head!
- On the head!
Hey listen you, I'm gonna drop you
a line.
- Yeah
- Yeah.
I'd like to see you again.
Yeah well, you know, that can be
arranged!
You seem...
- really busy, so....
Well, so...
- Occupying the other room is....
Like to see you again, we're
really good together
Always walking around on....
- Ninth, and...
- Yeah, yeah...
- Okay
- Okay?
Hey listen I owe you some money!
- Alright
- Thank you
You're very welcome.
- And, uh.. I'll see you again!
-Alright!
-Yeah, see you later..
- Yeah
- But, uh, why don't you check out,
you know, see if...
- Yeah, yeah
- Awake and that, ok?
- And this way I can leave.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah, it's cool, it's ok
Alright, so...
- I'll be seeing you soon, alright!
- Alright.
- Thank you very much, really
- OK
- Bye
Well, uh...
- Nothing actually
- You're not doing anything now?
Would you like a small job, two dollars?
Yeah.
Do you know anything about art?
- I did a little modelling, and, um..
- You did a little modelling?
- Haven't done much
- Now isn't that strange!
That's what I had in mind
when I walked past you, I just saw you
standing there...
Well, maybe we can do something about
this.
Now, how much...money did you think
you... were worth?
Now I'd like to... make a hundred bucks
like, you know, I really need it for...
I have to make it anyway today somehow
A hundred bucks?
Um, you'll have to take all your
clothes off for that, you know!
Oh, there's gotta be a cab somewhere!
Shall we walk out?
Here we are.
Well now.
I expect you'd like something to drink,
would you? - Yeah.
Go on then, stick them  there
Thank you
All these things are just strange,
aren't they? Do you like them?
A world of the imagination...
You've um, you were saying you have done
some of it before?
- I mean, I can see that because you're
not self-conscious. - Mmm hmm
You take your clothes off, and that's
all, you're quite used to that.
That's a big barrier with some people,
takes hours to get the clothes off!
But here in the art world, what the hell,
it's got nothing to do with the outside
world, nothing whatever! It's in the
world of imagination.
And some of the biggest people are
athletes...
Oh boy they're athletes who got there by
running faster than anyone else in the
world, by vaulting, by high pole. by
crossing over the bar, all those things
And the greatest of them were the Greeks
But they are people you see! Now...
I don't care who you think of, whether
it's Michelangelo or...
a collage or the Cistine Chapel, it looks
as if he's taken all his boys and
stuck them up there, and then, you know,
painting some of...
or whether you go to the Greeks.. which
reminds me of a , ummm...
- Hermes the name?
- Yeah.
Well, he's a... he's a god, holding a
little kid...
in his arm, and he's dangling a bunch
of grapes...
the most wonderful face,
And previously the statues were made, to
look like your muscle boy covers you know
Marvellous figures and all this sort of
business.
This, this statue suddenly appeared,
and it was a person.
In fact the Greeks invented a word
entirely for that,
'synphatica' sympathy
empathy, all these words, they come from
Greek statues
I think he won about five things, for
his little town, he come from
you see, and the town was given a
tremendous honour
and he's a very beautiful young man,
And somebody who had some money there
had a wife in Athens
And the night before the last games,
she made a date with him in one of the
temples and she gave him some dope,
the love philtre, cause she saw his
naked...
He fell for him, hook line and sinker,
and he wrote some of the world's most
marvellous odes just like, like
Shakespeare did too, about this guy.
Yeah, Praxiteles
who was the best sculptor, was...
But I'm talking about, you want to work
for someone like Michelangelo, like
these are the sort of people he goes for
- You know, I...
- We are right...
I never really thought of it like that..
- Well, let's get started anyway, it's
getting late - Yeah, yeah...
It's good to know that, really
Take it easy, don't worry, it's not
all done in a day
Now you've got the idea of what picture,
the image...
-you can fill it in
- right
That's to give you some pride in your
job, and in your location.
So, let's start with a Greek statue.
I don't know what...
A greek statue.
And um... the shot, the discobolus. the
discus
thrower, the fellow who throws the disc,
you might do very well with that,
You've got that sort of torso, taut body
so we'll start with that.
Well we'll try this, this... discobolus
thing
and I'll show you what you have to do,
why... stand on the bed!
You have to be above my level, that's why
you're standing at my eye level, you see
Now, you're going to throw this thing
like a plate, you know, a plate.
in that direction.
So first of all... You're going
to take that off...
But now this back line, try and get all
the back muscles into this...
Right there, down here, cause that's
what I want, close to my form, body...
Now take your shirt and things off
I think you'd better take everything off
in one flash
You should have done that before really
Give them to me
That's right, that's only right.
How the hell do you get out of those
things?
So I have to change it all...
- You do that?
- Yeah
Right...
That's right, that's fine... you don't
have to move that.
That's the lucky charm.
You've got to work on the muscles there
and there.
What you can do by, that's the very thing
we're doing, by discus-throwing.
If you practice discus-throwing, walk,
throwing anything like that,
You will produce these, these side
muscles that come out and look very good
So...
Alright, throw it... throw it in either
direction, I don't mind which direction.
Picture.. in the middle, although doing
that, so forget all about it, just...
Back up for another one
That's fine, that's one... that's one
thing
So, what are you going to do with
those pictures you've been taking?
I make large drawings from the pictures
And the negatives, I'll give them to you
if you like, in the darkroom
That's fine.
- Tired? It's the same with the....
- Why don't I sit down...
Put that aside, you can sit down...
There it's got...
Of, of movement.
Here you're standing, now...
Here's another famous statue like that.
Put your foot across there, bend forward
get forward a little bit more,
And pick some.... Those famous statues
people will recognise...
OK, now turn around sideways, put both
feet up,
And bring, bring your heels in as close
to underneath you as you can.
And, keep your balance, lean forward.
And rocks, see, that's another one.
Good. Another one - you may have
seen them, put your arms around...
No, you gotta put out that, right...
Now kneel...kneel down on one knee and
throw the other leg up right behind you
Like um... hang on.
Now that... that is like a starting,
start of a race.
You begin like that don't you, and then
the thing comes, and you, and you...
You, what do you do when you're in a
race, you, put your hands down first!
And you've got to hold that, is that a
strain on you?
- Little bit - Cause I might say you've
got to hold that ten minutes.
You're a runner...
And you're going to take off!
When I say relax you can go down on...
go down on your knees and take it off
Now good, alright relax, go down
on your knees.
Now...
One sec.
Well if you could only stay like that for
thirty-five minutes that'd be splendid!
- I'll just use this for a while
- OK.
OK, you got that one?
Right so we'll move onto another one,
that's alright?
- Yeah, alright.
- Alright.
Just relax, yes but now I'm too close
So um, what shall we do now, another
pose?
Well, we'll do that other one I was
doing, the runner, alright?
You've sat all the time, can you lie
diagonally....
No, we'll do the runner one, OK?
- The runner?
- Yeah, we'll do that one.
- And we'll get it out of..
- Alright, turn round again.
You can hold that... if you want
to give in,
and then drop it, and then go back
to it, you see because,
the whole picture, if I do a picture of
this thing will take quite...
quite a while, so...
Lie flat on...
Alright, pick this thing up in the
morning...
Well, that's good, now that's going
better.
For general development, swimming is
the best.
I think, from my... it's the best, eh...
Nobody's ever, in my opinion, beaten
Johnny Weismuller.
who was an Olympic swimmer.
In a liberated person, a person makes
himself whole
Body worship
is the whole, I think the whole thing
behind all art, all music,
and all sex, and all love.
If you cut it out, for any reason,
you've deprived yourself of one
great chunk of life.
just as the people who say they don't
dig rock and roll.
But it's all, all vitally important
That... whether you just look at it with
the rotten view of making money
in other words popularity and success,
if you want the millions
to take an interest in you, it's done in
the same way as making one person
take an interest in you, that body
worship
is in... is in the makeup of the human
animal.
All human beings, whether they are
puritanticals or whatever they are!
They love it!They all come to the theatre
come to the films, they all dig it!
and they all get what they call the sex
kick
which is bullshit, there's no sex in it,
it's body worship which becomes sex.
It's like if I pick up a violin, and
I can't play the damn thing,
what hell use is it, might even be a
Stradivarius, wouldn't be any good.
- You've got to have the music!
- What are we having for dinner?
- Yes. Food!
- Alright.
That's the other thing, food and sex go
together, body again.
It's a worship, it's..
The door...
After all some deities and...
they became rituals you
worship
Now if this question bothers you...
Say you've got a lovely body and
somebody else hasn't got a lovely body
You can't worship yourself, you see
what...
..receive there often.
Let's say one doesn't know what to do
about it,
If there's... are some friends around,
boys and girls,
and they're all madly in love, and they
all have frightful problems,
and it's always the same kind of problem.
They can't get anywhere.
They don't seem to get any satisfaction.
And when they do have a good time.
it's always the sort of promise of
something that never comes off.
and so it's always the same, the great
question is what are you going to do
about it?. Adoration...
He literally, to himself in the mirror..
Am I talking to an empty bed? Oh fuck.
Hey what are you doing?
Oh Christ, he hasn't locked himself out
in the street without any clothes has he?
- Joe?
- Coming!
That's pretty good.
That's good.
You know what I can't stand about it,
the bloody age we live in,
They give expensive educations,
and don't give a hell if they give birth
to no more craftsmen, no more...
Nice day isn't it? How long you guys
been out here?
Half an hour, somewhere around there...
- Half hour?
- Yeah
- That's not, it's... what you meet
anybody, make anything? - No...
No it's a bad part, there's not many
people around, you know...
Well that's all that, you know, I got
home, I said that's all I wanna do
Like I don't wanna make another scene so
I had to, make up work
keep that mind work...
- No, I work. Yeah
- Yeah, you bum. Work, work.
Shit. Nobody works.
..there, a scene.
- You straight?
- Eh, nobody's straight
- What's straight, It's not a thing...
- Yes there is, shit...
to be straight, or, or, or being
not-straight,
It's just, you just do whatever you
have to do!
- Yeah, but it's tough - Yeah, it's hard
it's hard to learn how to do that
But once you got that down pat, like,
don't even worry about it no more because
Well, well look do you, what do you
consider yourself, do you consider
yourself abnormal?
What other people think doesn't matter,
you know, if you have to care about what
the straight people, what they're going
to think man, then you're not in your bag
- Do you care? Do you really care?
- Yeah, I care, I mean...
I guess it's because I'm just starting
out.
Well it takes, time, yeah, well
how long you been...
- you know, really into it?
- I, just a couple weeks like I said
Did you ever have that...
You get into it because, why did you
get into it, first of all,
- Why did you even start?
- To make bread, I came to this city,
but like, you can make...
Wow, it's for bread, man.
- How much money do you make a week?
If I wanted to go out every day and do it
I can make close to... 150, 175, 185,
you know
If you want to do it every day, four times
a day you can make an awful lot of bread
I don't do it, I do, you know, I go
home and the wife says, 'Hey'
You know, like, I went out today and met
this artist, man, and like,
He wants me to stand there and do some
photos, so I got a free dinner out of it
I got my wife to come over, get a free
dinner get some food and stuff like that
But doesn't your wife get uptight about
it?
- Why should she get uptight man, it's
feeding her, isn't it? - Yeah...
Why should she care, like, she knows
where I'm at, man.
She knows where I'm at, like, we have
a kid already man, and, like...
You know, so, uh...
I mean it's just being small, and not
knowing, where it's...
What people are doing, you know.. you
have to do, don't follow everybody...
do more or less what you want to do, and
what you like to do is make bread, right?
-Make cash, right?
- Yeah, right.
So the easiest way to do it is, you know
what you're doing here,
looking for those dirty old men as
they walk by, right?
- How much do you get on one job?
- Well I got this, well, it's one job..
Most of your jobs are from $20 to $30,
you know, most of them.
But like, you can get one like I got
today, right, get one like that...
Well, you make yourself a hundred bucks,
right?
- That's crazy!
- Oh well everybody's a little crazy!
What about that guy over there, do
you think I should get a job with him?
- See now look, he's, he's got...
- Dressed like a pig.
- Like people dress sporty, right, they
wear sports clothes - Yeah, right.
- You don't wear a dirty t-shirt!
- Oh, well...
Well how much did you make today,
maybe, did you make...
- Oh what, what was the last...
- I show it to you sometime
Like you know that thing... wasn't
that thing ugly?
Look at this one over here man, wow...
- Won't that get you bread?
- Stop it...
I know see but you don't worry, it's
only going to suck your peter, man
- A lot of men, like, fuck that scene
- But...
- How do you know he's got any bread,
I mean real bread? - Aww, shit
- I mean he really doesn't look very
rich to me - Yeah.
Well you just got to play it right...
Oh yeah, you think about...
- You go to, you went to school down
there? - Yeah.
- And you just got, couldn't take it, eh?
- No, no it was...
- Well I took it till I graduated, did
you graduate? - No.
- Didn't you? - I got up to the
eighth grade, that's about it...
- Then they sent me off to reform school
- Reform school, for what?
Ah, used to steal cars...
Fuck that shit, can't follow it no more
Yeah, but uh, did you spend all your
time in one school or what?
- No, I was in high school in two schools
- Oh, you in high school in two schools?
- Yeah, in Wisconsin
- Wisconsin, and Alabama?
- Beautiful, beautiful.  - Yeah, not so
beautiful, I hated high school.
And uh, maybe split home for a while
And you say whatever you want to say to
them, and like you want to meet them,
I heard a lot about you mister, that
whole bag, you do that whole scene
But, like, it's bad standing around like
all three of us, it's no good
We'll never make no money that way,
really.
- Wow - But you couldn't just take
me along some day?
Oh yeah, I'll do that.. how beautiful
you are, like...
How much do you seriously...?
Find a good street corner's a good
idea, you know
- You know, you find a good street
corner... - But where?
- Well.. - I didn't really know where
to look, you know...
-Well actually, down by the '50s...
- This is new to me...
That news stand down there man, 'bout
Third avenue?
- That's a good area, it's a good area
to stand.  - 50 what?
Uh, think around 56th Street, 55th
Street.
- Right?
- Yeah.
But, how will I know the news stand?
- Well you see it's the only one there
on the corner. - I know, but...
- There's an outlet stand like that...
- Isn't there another news stand?
- fairly near?
- Yeah, pretty close.
Isn't there a drugstore nearby, or
something like that?
- Oh there must be
- Or a telephone booth?
- That you could tell me about, that
I know. - Yeah.
Gibbys, or something like that.
- You'll see it. I'll show it to you
sometime.  - Yeah.
- You know, your best bet is standing
where you were, because like somebody
No, like, I was standing there several
hours and nothing happened...
- 58th street
- I mean this is really a bad park.
Yeah well they have these pictures down
there, the four big poster pop pictures
Yeah down there's good, good idea.
- Catch you around there, ok?
- Yeah, I'll see ya. Right.
Hello David? Hi. Joe.
Look, uh, you gonna be home for
a while?
Yeah?
What you say I stop over later on?
Okay?
Right, yeah.
So I'll see you in about, maybe,
twenty minutes.
If everything's alright. Right.
Yeah. Alright. Right.
Right. Yeah. Ok then, right, bye bye.
Right bye.
You're so right. She's going to be a
big star.
Veronica was inspired by... the orient.
Here she's showing a chiffon negligee
embroidered in silver.
I love to kiss your satin-smooth face.
Too bad a dry skin causes you lines and
wrinkles too soon.
Are you referring to me?
Durgan's face cream.
Big stuff, he's big stuff alright!
Eugene Palant. I work in a Bulmers
factory.
I can't afford to slow up a single
minute.
No matter what day of the month it is,
so believe me, I need more comfort
now than I ever did
That 3 out of 4 women voted 'Modest'
softer. I got a box quick!
Does exercise make women muscular,
Geri?
Don't you believe it!
When is a tampon right for you?
Battle of the bulge!
You know they try and tell you that it's
all exercise, these beauties are
- starved to death!
- Oh, I don't know.
They have diets!
Personality demands its daily duty
You know this magazine is falling apart.
I'm proud of my figure now.
Loses 17lbs in six weeks!
She's, she's trash!
That's a good idea!
I like it when...
We should act natural the way Jane
Frazee does!
She's an up and coming girl about town
these days, now Geri listen!
No wonder, as witness
the figure she cuts in a chiffon
negligee
And Jane's winning cheers for her acting
in 'Moonlight Masquerade'.
- She looks like a masquerade!
- I'm telling you, look!
The lowdown, on high...
She knows how, Anne Jeffreys, she knows!
- She knows how to lose weight!
- I'll look at it later if I'm bothering
We're trying to educate you, here!
-Don't you want to learn to be glamorous?
- Ah, Candy...
Geri, that's a very petty trick, you
know.
Trying to make the likes of me
jealous!
I'm not trying to get you jealous!
I'm trying to make your friendlier, or
you can ignore me!
Isn't she wretched?
- She's told us
- She'll come to a bad end!
It's a hot box in here, how would
Lucille..?
She's a prestige star.
I don't know.
I mean, she was a band leader, and the
girl most likely to succeed, in 1942.
She looks like Olga San Juan.
I think it was, Olga San Juan, she...
Did you see her when she played Amber
La Vonne?
- Calling Amber La Vonne? Did you
see that? - No!
Oh look at this, it's falling
everywhere...
Soaping...
You know you can get so hung up with
these magazines.
- Oh she loves Anne Sheridan
- Mmm.
Juke Girl, starring Ronald Reagan, Anne
Sheridan, and Richard Whorf
- Do you know, she made me stay up all
night - The tale of two hitchhikers
Who wander into the Florida tomato
country, and get mixed up
There's nothing like being dull, by
Jackie Curtis
Where's that?
Only kidding...
All these pages have 'Buy War Bonds' on
them.
Aren't you going to pay any attention
to us?
Do you know any poems? I'm
starving for culture.
- Joe?
- What?
- ... a nice handkerchief?
- Oh, it's a beautiful handkerchief!
- Would you like a cigarette, Joe?
- Yeah. Oh stop.
Open your mouth.
How could you? Right in front of
all of us!
How could you not watch and sit still
reading magazines,
-that's the most disgusting of all!-Don't
you know the angels are watching you?
They're doing it too!
- Well, they're used to watch...
- She didn't mind!
You know Joe...
You'll never get to heaven if you...
I don't want to go to heaven anyway.
- I have a frog in my throat
- No, it can't be Joan watching you.
- It was Joan!
- Joan Crawford!
Oh, she's done it too.
What did you just say? Joan Crawford?
- have a habit... - I said I don't
mind her watching, she understands.
- You better go and call... - Why Joan
Crawford is one of my favourite stars.
She'd only be good enough to pick up
her glove!
- I wish the phone would ring, I need
some money!  -Can't you make some
phone calls?
I wish you, I tell you something Geri,
it's so frustrating...
I want to be a vampire! That's why I
have this outfit on, notice this smooth
I love horror things!
- Splendid!
Don't you feel guilty, Joe?
You do feel guilty?
Why do you feel guilty?
Joe, we had so much fun...
We were stuck in this hotel in Chicago,
what was the name of it....
The Carling hotel, right Joe?
The Carling. How much did we owe there?
About $50 or $60 and we didn't have the
money so
he threw the luggage out the window!
And it was in that snowstorm!
The cat, and all.
Then I had to run and climb a six foot
fence. Remember Joe?
Remember what you said before about what
you did for Joe?
At the door, and I just slammed the door
in your face and said I'll be back?
Well, I never told you, but that night
I got raped,
and you wanted me to make love to you
right after I got raped,
and you almost broke up with me cause I
wouldn't... and...
his name was Mikey, and he said that he
would ruin my face unless I went with him
or he'd bang on the door and get you out
and he was much bigger than you,
So I said OK, I'd go cause I didn't want
anything to happen to you,
and he dragged me to this filthy hotel
and he made me do everything, and then
he called up some other guy and
made me do something to him, and the
other guy was like really nice
and I said 'Please let me go!' and he
wouldn't!
And they both like made me do everything
to them! And he said if I just did it
to them once, he'd let me go and he lied
and later he made me do it again
and then I was just crying, and then he
finally drove me home,
and I said I don't want him to drive me
home, just let me go.
and so he let me go, and now when
I dance,
up the club, up at the lake, you know
where I dance topless, he was there!
Do you know what it's like to dance
topless in front of someone who raped you?
And that, that was how I got him back!
Cause, like he didn't think I'd have the
guts to dance in front of him,
I just danced the best I could to say,
this is what you didn't get,
cause like when he raped me I was real
stiff, and I danced fantastic,
so that he knew, if he would have, you
know, got me to dig him,
he would have had it out of sight, but
because he took it, I was awful.
And that's how much I love you, I
wouldn't let them hurt you.
- But it was fun!
- What was fun? Getting raped?
Yeah. At the time it wasn't but now that
I think about it, it was weird.
Oh, look at my hair.
- I like it!
- It's terrible!
- I like it!  - Do you believe
this hair colour cost $10?
- Ten dollars!
- But you can do it yourself!
Andre did it, Andre of Paris on
5th Avenue.
- Why don't you do it yourself, it's so
easy! - I'll kill that queen Andre!
Well I don't like a set look, you know.
I don't like anything that looks too
set, I like things a little...
and things that move, I think things
that move are beautiful.
- Like your, your bust, it moves.
- It does!
- Cause you don't wear a bra. Do you
have a bra? - Yes!
It still moves.
Pretty soon it won't move because I
want to get a silicone shot.
Like I want to be really big
- Oh don't, you shouldn't.
No, like now I'm proportionate, and
I want to be, you know a little extra
Oh don't... Statues in Greece.
- Yeah
- When they, when they...
All those beautiful statues, they don't
have... big...
tits like a cow!
- They won't... willowy
- Yes but if one of those
-  statues did it would stand out!
- Let me see what your bust looks like
Okay.
Oh I want to get silicone shots, cause I
know they're too little, especially
for dancing topless...
Oh don't be a fool, you already die your
hair and now you want
- See, they're too... - I think
they're fabulous, I love them!
But wouldn't you want them bigger?
I like the bigger, the better!
Why, everything's gone bigger?
- See!
I'm definitely doing it. I called into
this one doctor,
and he's on vacation, and when he comes
back he has this stuff that isn't silicone
It's some kind of juice from a plant,
cause he said that silicone lumps up,
so that sounds pretty...
And I called up this other doctor and
he's all out of silicone!
So it shows that everybody's getting it!
Because then I'll get all our customers.
- Except for the... - Why don't you
develop your brain instead of your bust?
My brain can't be developed any more
than it is. And I think I'm cute!
I don't want to change. If I learn too
much, I won't always be happy!
Cause the more you learn, I think the
more depressed you are!
- You get silicone shots, so I'm goin
to, that's all - Joe doesn't ever...
Yeah!
They should really be much harder because
it doesn't, shouldn't hang like that.
- I know
They should be up, should be
- That's why I'm getting the shots!
- Like that...
Joe, you never seem like you like them
like you used to.
- Are you turning gay or something?
-No I still like them, just not as much
- Why?
- I'm used to them now, and...
I guess that's why I want you to have
the silicone treatments done.
- Well if you want it, you got it!
- Changed a little bit.
- and my topless dancing!
- that's beautiful, man!
I'd like to see that! Yeah, good...
- Okay
- Good.
- You know you're sweet, you really are
- I try hard.
You got that tattoo, that says...
That says little Joe...
On 42 street
- Oh yeah, I saw that - He was still in
it so I walked out, in the middle.
I couldn't believe it!
I understand I can't, you know, when you
don't listen to the sound, you don't
listen to the words, you can't
understand nothing...
It wasn't good sets to watch, I like
watching the sets.
Not only that but there was nothing to,
I mean there was no,there was a story but
Joe would you please read this letter?
I can't see anything without my glasses
Alright.
Dear Audrey, I'm blind from several
things, number one my weekend in
San Francisco, uhh....
and...
was in Hawaii, so I figured, no..
no scenes in LA, fully...
yes clearer night flight to Frisco,
arrived after two shows and four hours
sleep, be it...
Got some 8 by 10s of my face, and
11 by 14s too,
Not the one I wanted, there were 2 or 3,
203 alike, and when I'm...
When I meet, when I met it...
When I sent it.. to be... blown up to
11 by 14 I picked accidentally the one
with my hands on my cock.
There are so...
There are so.. nearby, there
are... whatever.
nearby, think it the best of 72 shots
You'll see them, on the first.
It's now the 21st, 11 days...
For appointments, parties...
I can't see!
Gee, it's awfully quiet in here.
Don't think about it!
- I love him
- I don't either!
- You don't like em?
- No, I don't!
They're my brains.
Listen Geri, can I feel your, umm,
hoojiggers?
- Sure!
- Your Ittytuggers!
Yeah, haha, ittytuggers!
- That's another quaint expression
- Bring them up there!
- I never heard of that, cat!
- Oh, well I know this girl...
Oh, you don't need silicone!
- I do, that's my little one, this is my
bigger one! -Oh i see they come in sizes
I thought these plants were real when I
bought them!
- Are you sure you're right?
- I don't know...
- This one feels really wrong! - I know
lots of things feel real that aren't real
No, I could tell a fake plant from a
real plant, I think!
Listen, would you mind getting me some
water?
I have to leave!
- Alone.
- Alone!
- Now what did you say this meant?
- I mean, it's awful pretty.
- Yeah, but it..
- Do you get this, almost satin!
Joe I'm glad you could make it, let me
just put the blinds down!
Two doors down...
Some of these, physique, horseshit
Oh yeah? These dudes, do they pay
anything?
- I got $100 for doing it...
- A hundred dollars!
Hey man I haven't seen you at the gym
lately. You haven't been around at all!
- Actually, I've been just, you know
- You not working out any more?
No, just, more or less working for
money man, I have to.
Keep making that money, I've no
time for relaxing.
Because, the gym really, you know,
like, is very important
you know, if you're going to stay in your
line of duty because you got to keep
yourself together, I mean, you get to
a certain point in life, and
the body completely collapses, there's
no getting it back, I mean
this gut that I got it's getting, it's
embarrassing.
You?
Now, you know now I have all this flab
on the hips, and, lot of fat..
I just notice it, it's just all of a
sudden coming along that's why I want
to get back to the gym and, just
relaxing
cause remember when I met you at that
gym I was, real tight and swollen
Yeah I know, you were so tight, that's
what, you know that was...
the most glamorous thing really, the fact
that you needed so much help, and
and everybody was, like willing to
help you.
Yeah you were really popular at the gym,
I must say.
The problem you know, like, you remember,
I had this.. this..
- enormous scar, you saw that? That
scar? - Yeah, yeah
... off that muscle because that muscle
was all destroyed there.
That was from Korea too. I got
burned by a flamethrower.
The flames were licking out and, right
up my arm...
and the hair all came back,everything
came back, it was nice.
feels good, except that I can't, I can't
really reach for anything, you know.
I've been having a difficult time like
that.
I can't get a hard-on any more.
I mean we can, we can talk about a lot
of things. I mean I'm not like all the
johns that you usually deal with, right?
- Am I? - I don't actually put you
in that bag, man
- I don't classify you as that, you
know, I just - I hope not.
- Cause I like you a little more
- You're really beautiful
I thought you feel like, don't I
enlighten you a lot? I mean - I just...
I mean, with all these art objects you
have, do you find that wherever you go?
No, I just find it here, you know,
I mean...
It's just, the whole thing is always
very beautiful you know...
But you know, I mean I don't ask you
for anything, you know.
Unless you know, I'm not asking you what
I ask you for,
for anything at all, it's as a friend
you know, because,
I need money today because, I have a
couple of things I have to...
Money, cause...
You know, a john or anything like that,
I think of you as a friend and...
- Well, it's.. - I mean the money I ask
for is just, you know, like a loan or
anything like that, right?
I mean I don't just want.. I just
want you to...
To like me, you know? I mean...
you're not all...
- pieces of shit? - Yeah right! How
could you say that?
They are! They really are, I don't
like them!
They're terrible, they're disgusting,
they're...
I mean, I really can't take them, the...
asking for money you know is like a
punishment to them you know or a
- to myself or something
- Hold still. Let me get that.
That's a nice one!
- Just be good
- Because...
It was fun, it was always fun, it was
a lot of fun. I don't know.
Could you lend me some bread? In other
words, you know...
nothing to do with, what, whatever we
may do, you know...
How much do you need?
Well actually, you know, $30, because...
I mean I don't really desperately
need it, you know, it's just that...
right now I need some bread, you know,
I'm in a little financial difficulty.
You're all, you son of a bitch, the last
time you were over here you took me for
fifty bucks!
- I know but it's not because - And you
didn't even pay it back, you said you
were going to pay it back, I wish you
would just say to me, just say
- I'm not going to pay it back - I'm
not, no I'm not even going to say I'm
going to pay you, because I'm really, I
know what I'm going to do, I'm going to
- really pay this back
- Yeah!
No, I really mean it dude, I really do,
I'm going to pay this back,
and I'm gonna you know, I'm done
but if I say it, and I don't do it, or
something like that, or
or sometimes I don't do it if I make a
date, you know, next week I'll pay you
back, then you don't believe me.
Well it really doesn't matter, you know
that!
It really doesn't!
- Oh wow!
- Can you feel it?
Not too much, that's all dead!
- Is it?
- Mmm hmm. It's all dead.
It's all grafted skin, and when they
grow back, it just didn't...
- It just didn't have any feeling in it
- Wow!
You! Terrible!
But I have a feeling that...
No, I really think if you don't..
Why don't you come and live with me,
I mean you fuck around too much!
You're not going to be able to do this
forever! - I'd love to do it, you know
I just, I don't know if I'm ready for
that kind of...
But Geri wouldn't like that too much,
actually, she, it would upset her.
You know that.
- I mean who else does she have besides
me? - Well, she can afford it, man
I, I hate to say it to you but she's so
ugly, man.
She can afford to be upset.
Really, you're crazy dude, I mean...
- We're not queers
- I know.
But, lot of people, lot of people don't
understand that, you know.
They really can't see it as that...
- Well, can you help me out?
- Sure, I'll help you out of your...
No, I don't mean my pants, I mean, you
know, with money!
- Oh man, that's all you ever think
about is money!- No it's not,cause, it's
just, you know, I have to save it if I,
I may need it for later.
- You mean you got another, you got
somebody in trouble? -I'll have to find
-some, I'll have to stand out on corners
- You're not taking dope are you?
- Let me see!
- No!
- You know, it's just that I need the
bread, not dope. - You are!
- You were shooting up for a while
- No I wasn't!
That's propaganda, you idiot!
- Well that's what they sell
- See don't believe what you hear!
- That's what they sell in the Meat
Rack - What, in the Meat Rack?
That's not true!
Okay, okay.
- I'll give you money
- Alright!
Wait a minute before we do anything I
want you to listen to this
It says 'After a few moments he pulled
me up from where I had been kneeling
and placed my cock in front of his mouth.
He then licked..You know they always say
that a picture's worth a thousand words
This book is so fantastic,I mean some of
the things that they have in here I mean
- What is it...?
- They do inches, huh?
- What is it about?
- It's about, it's about
It's about images that, you know that
people get involved in, I mean things
that you do, but the way they...
Before I make a mistake.. everything
that
they put down here, it is so sexy I
can't believe it, it's fabulous, it's
all these things in here that, you
know, that...
You can't, well, look at that!
Wow! wow!
- Does it get any groovy pictures in..?
- And, yeah, this one.
- An ass picture!
- You ought to try that!
- Right now. Yeah do it!
- Just do that?
- Take your clothes off and do it!
- No!
Could you get your legs back like
that and spread them?
So that your buttocks are pressed
against the, that's like crushed velvet!
And just smash down, so that there's
this,
great fantastic line running up.
Go on, try it Joe, I mean, you can
do it!
I could do it, I could do it before I
got wounded,
I really could, and, I'd like to see
it, wouldn't you?
Like to do it?
Well do it man! I mean I'd like to do it
I like to do anything!
Right about now. Go ahead, take your
clothes off man. Hurry up!
I have about seven and a half...
steady head movement, and it didn't
take long...
for me to reach the point of no return.
As I did he took all of my
tingling, and I filled his hot mouth...
...before I fell asleep!
I awake to find... throbbing at my... I
knew I couldn't handle it!
So I tried... He began to run his tongue
between my firm cheeks
He spread my cheeks and... and I begin
to wiggle.
And it was fast responding to his wild
caresses
It didn't take long for him to moisten
it enough to suit his next...
The pain was so bad that I thought I
must be ripped open completely
There he held me fast until my body got
accustomed to its visit. Drag his black
nap, out, and then he threw, he threw my
legs over his shoulders...
and he went again
Slowly but surely he worked our two
bodies to the edge of the mattress
It was wonderful, I was now in such a
state
that I didn't notice we were being
watched, I had forgotten
about the phone and gas company
He was twenty-four, twenty...
waited for the sub.. and he decided.. I
still didn't know where, and, he took...
went open, only to find it was filled to
the very fat...
I opened my eyes and start to behold two
well-developed
There had been a lot of weights lifted,
the chest was free of hair,
And I was completely spent and fell
asleep again, how do you like that story?
Okay?
- Do you think it was too dirty?
- No!
I don't think I'll ever be the same!
Fuck!
- C'mere!
- I have to go, I have to go!
You big beautiful piece of shit get over
here I want to get a hold of you!
- I have to go man! - Where you gonna
go, not now!
- Yes
- You tease me, c'mon now!
You don't have to go, you stay all
night with me!
- You can't treat me like this!
- David!
Listen you keep slipping out all the
time, you're not, you haven't been
doing anything, are you still going with
that chick?
- I'm married to.. - You didn't marry
her, you can't lie to me!
I did marry her!
- As gay as you are?
- As gay as I am, maybe, whatever.
- You're not really going to marry her,
are you? - I married her!
I'm sorry, it's just what I had to do.
At the time, you know, one of those
things, but uh...
- You know
- Well I'm gonna blow ya!
It's pretty convenient!
Oh no!
- Look at this. One!
- I want... Look!
- Look at this. Hey!
- Two!
- Hey!
- Three!
Oh my goodness, Patty!
I mean, I fell down, then I fell down
How about the time when we hitched
with that maniac?
- We were sitting inside...
- Oh yes he had peyote!
He brought it and he brought
a pretzel too?
And he says 'Would you like some
peyote?'
- He said he has a pretzel, he said
'Look, honey'... - This is really...
Then he starts jerking off! And says,
well this is peyote!
- Remember when he said I want to smell
your bloomers! No, he said... - Yes!
- What do you have under those mini-...
- A real psycho!
They really, they're all over.
I run into them all the time, every time
I go into a train station
somebody's jerking off!
I said, 'What are you doing?' I said I
know some games too...
I got the blame!
And the time Andrea went in his apartment
took this big piece of hash, this big...
And the guy said,'Well, you, both of you
are not leaving until I get my hash back!'
And I said, 'Look I didn't take it!'
How about the time when the guy
gave us $500?
.care of you,have somebody to look after
you, give you money when you need it
- Like an allowance, someone gives me a
quarter a week!  - Are you kidding?
It's worse to be married!
-Is out of her mind!
- Oh, that's because of crying...
She's really sick, yeah!
She's real psychotic!
- But, you know, we're all a little
touched! - Yeah!
Allo.. people!
- What did you do today?
- Nothing!
What did you do?
- Who's this?
- I don't know!
- Tell her who I am
- What?
- Tell her who I am!
- Why? I don't know you!
Well, this is my new girlfriend
So you can go fuck off!
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah!
What's your name?
- Patty
- Mmm? Mines is Joe
Joe?
-This the one you talking about?
- Yeah
And you have to show her your
body!
Peek a peek peek!
- One time he washed, his, uh, seat!
- Seat?
- Take his panties off!
- Does that have a scab on it?
- No it has a hole in it!
- I have one in my little...
There it is! There it is!
- C'mon look!
- Looks better, now its sleeping...
Let's see it now! C'mon!
Do you like it? Patty?
- Can't complain!
-You are! What were you doing today?
Don't you think you should take this
off?
-I wouldn't feel comfortable with it off
- Take if off!
- Shoes...
- Take it all off!
- Everything has to come off!
- Don't break it off!
-... to go into your purse!
- It has to go off!
- Just here, blue...
- Man,you don't have to dress me up!
You don't need...
Now C'mon let's have some fun!
- No, no fun, not when I'm tired!
- Yes!
What did you do that you're so
tired?
Yeah
Oh but look at this, the cutest little
buns you ever seen!
Is this the one you wanted the night
before?
Yeah!
No, you can tell, want to stroke
all...
See, look?
I'm not going to have it
removed...
So it doesn't cost me anything? You
were too fast to jump in...
Where'd you find him?
Him? In the street!
But where?
I mean, how did, did you do...
I don't understand
why you got married?
- I know but...
- We all make our little old mistakes
- With him every day,you know,you mgiht
as well have a little - little change
- What? The bore...
- Same thing every day!
It is, besides, if
you're together every day it's tiring,
it's, you know
the magic isn't there any more, if it
was there in the beginning!
Well I think the best kind of marriage
is when
the two people don't live together!
- Don't live together? Well what's the
point of getting married? - Yeah
Yeah, that's true.
Well I think it should be like that where
they just see each other every
- once in a while. Don't you?
- Well why not...
just not see each other when you don't
want to, instead of...
instead of that. You can always leave!
- Get out of there!
- Just pack up your bags and go!
Well, Jeez, I gotta tuck him in!
- But seriously why's he so tired?
- Because he's so lazy!
There's nothing in, nothing in his body
works properly!
The blood doesn't flow...
- Nothing
- Girls have energy!
- Vitality
- Right. They think it is...?
The birth control pills!
- Give you so much energy! - It all
leads back to that, that's all it is!
First of all gives you confidence!
Protects you...
I don't know why you'd get married!
- Hello?
- Mmm?
- Why did you get married?
- To get out of school!
- I hated school so much, didn't you?
- And why?
I learned more out of school than I
did in school!
I think they should have school up till
the 8th grade, just so
you can learn the basics!
And then let you decide whether or not
you want to go to high school or college
- Exactly!
- You know?
- And if it wasn't forced on you, you
wouldn't, you know - You would enjoy it!
A
I was absent, and I was always...
Yes the same thing like me, I was
always...
instigate, I'd make the whole class
get up in a uproar
Teacher would say, 'Miss Smith!'
I got expelled from Catholic school
in the first grade!
Nun choked me...
- Cause they'd rather do something else
- They're all frustrated old maids!
- Well I don't know..
- Why did....
- What? - I said why did they
have to be all that?
Because they just are!
They're so miserable after all those
years, doing the same thing
How miserable?
What makes you think they're
miserable?
Well, I don't know, they don't...
I couldn't do it, that's all I know
I wouldn't be able to live that
kind of a life.
I'm bored now! Imagine me in
a convent!
I don't think he's so bad, Geri!
- Did you make any money today?
- No
No? Why not?
- Cause you don't need it!
- I need plenty of money!
I say you just told me you didn't
need it!
- Everything you can get!
- OK
- As much as possible
- Alright
- Okay?
- Okay.
- I'll get some tomorrow
- Okay
- Okay? Right
- Right
- Well...
- Well why don't you get up and...?
What do you want, why are you
bothering me?
You entertain!
You entertain me!
- Oh I do enough entertaining!
- I want to see something!
Because I said so
- Why?
- Cause I...
I'm tired now and I want to go to sleep
but I don't want to sleep over here
- With something separating, I want to
sleep on this side! - I know!
Climb over.