THREE COLORS
RED
Come here.
This is 320 04 86.
Leave your name and number
and I'll get back to you.
Valentine?
Are you home?
Are you there?
I'll call back later.
Michel...
I was having breakfast.
First it was busy, and now
the machine. Are you alone?
Yes.
- All alone?
- All alone.
The agency was on the line
about a photo shoot,
setting up a time.
When did you get back?
Yesterday.
I called, but you weren't home.
Our car was stolen in Poland.
They got everything:
passports, money, clothes.
So what happened?
A nice guy put us up.
The embassy gave us money
and passports, and we got home.
Michel?
I felt lonely last night.
What did you do?
I slept with your jacket
the whole night.
I wanted to be with you.
I can't right now, Valentine.
I know.
What's the weather like there?
Typical English weather:
It's pouring.
It rained here yesterday too.
The sun's out now.
It's spring.
Where were you
when I called last night?
I took your advice and saw
Dead Poets Society.
- Great movie.
- I liked it a lot.
I'll call you tonight.
I'll be back at 7:00,
and I'll stay in.
Talk to you later.
- I miss you.
- Me too.
A big hug.
Personalized weather reports.
Hello.
Lose?
Take that out.
Take your sweater.
Put it around your neck.
Sleeves too.
- Like this?
Give me a profile.
No, don't smile.
Look sad.
Sadder.
Think of something awful.
That's it.
Sad.
Now it's coming! That's it!
Turn and six
and seven on the barre.
And one and two
and three and four.
Stretch and six
and seven and eight.
And one, plié,
and three and four.
Back and six
and seven and stretch.
Keep stretching.
Stretch your chin, your arm,
out to your fingertips.
Stretch your hand, your neck.
Relax through your toes.
Stretch.
I almost fell.
Excuse me. The door was open.
I'm sorry.
I think I ran over your dog.
Rita. A German shepherd.
That's possible.
She disappeared yesterday.
She's in my car. Alive.
I don't know what to do.
Would you like me
to take her to a vet?
As you wish.
If I ran over your daughter,
would you react the same way?
I don't have a daughter, miss.
Go away.
Don't close the door!
Everything's fine.
We stitched her up.
Otherwise just a few bruises.
She'll need some rest.
She's pregnant.
Will you take her or leave her here?
I'll take her.
We'll help you carry her.
Marc.
Are you alone?
Say something.
You hear that? I have a dog.
A dog.
I ran over her yesterday.
Michel, I'm sorry.
That wasn't funny.
No, it wasn't.
I knew it was a joke.
I could see you laughing.
You remember how we met?
I remember.
If I hadn't stepped out during
the break, we'd never have met.
That's true.
Valentine, return the dog.
I tried.
The owner doesn't want it.
Who is it?
I hear an alarm.
It might be my car.
It's my car.
Wait while I turn it off.
- I'm in a hurry.
- I understand.
Move.
Move!
They prefer these.
They'll be using the slogan
"A breath of life."
Which do you prefer?
I like this one.
Me too.
It'll be 65 by 25 feet.
Will people recognize you?
Like who?
Who are you thinking of?
Not you.
Bad sign, eh?
I think I know why I won.
Good-bye.
So long.
Back already?
The mailman delivered
some money for you.
- Who could have sent it?
- No idea.
Isn't that your brother?
Or someone who looks like him.
What a shame.
Does your family read this paper?
I don't know. Thank you.
Good-bye.
May I speak to Marie, please?
It's Valentine.
Will you see Marc soon?
Tonight, probably.
Tell him to call me.
As late as he wants.
I'll let you run around.
But don't run away, okay?
Promise?
There.
Excuse me. My dog ran away.
Call her. She's yours.
- Did you send this?
- For the vet.
- How'd you get my address?
- It wasn't hard.
You don't know what it cost.
It was 130 francs.
You sent 600.
Wait here. I'll get the rest.
What about Rita?
She's a very intelligent dog.
Take her.
- You don't want her?
- I want nothing.
Then just stop breathing.
Good idea.
Did you stop breathing?
If you don't come over,
you'll never see me again.
But today is Sunday.
Yesterday was Saturday
and we were together.
I can't talk right now, my friend.
We're about to have lunch.
I just ask one thing:
Don't call me "my friend."
Talk to me like yesterday.
Call me Pierre... or Pierrot...
or "my love."
Say "my love."
Let me go to another room.
- Pierre, I'm alone now.
- So am I.
Far from you.
I want you to come over.
I can't be alone!
Pierre, we agreed to meet tomorrow.
I miss you too.
You have to understand —
- I don't want to!
I'm thinking of you.
You're naked in front of the mirror.
But for someone else, not for me.
I want to kiss you.
I lean forward...
and with my lips I touch...
What are you doing?
- I'm eavesdropping.
- What?
Listening in
on my neighbors' phone calls.
You shouldn't have turned it off.
It was getting interesting.
You don't seem amused.
- That's disgusting.
- Yes...
and illegal too.
Your 30 francs.
One minute, miss.
You feel certain you're right,
don't you?
Yes.
Then why don't you do
something about it?
Like what?
Can't I touch your scar
like I did —
Go see that man.
Tell him someone's listening
to his conversations.
While you're at it,
tell him it's me.
I will.
It's that house there.
Hello.
- I'd like to see Mr. —
- My husband?
He's upstairs on the phone.
Let me turn off the stove.
Go on in, please.
Have a seat.
He'll be right down.
Caroline, don't play around.
Daddy's talking.
I'm sorry.
I have the wrong address.
This is number 22.
Yes. I'm very sorry.
Don't mention it.
Have a nice day.
- Good-bye.
- I'll call you later.
You dropped this.
Well?
Did you tell him?
Would you like something to drink?
No, I wouldn't.
I only came back —
I came back to ask something of you.
Stop doing this.
I've done it all my life.
What were you?
A cop?
Worse. A judge.
A judge?
Never seen a judge in person?
Would you like to try?
It makes a very nice sound.
I don't know if I was
on the side of right or wrong.
Here at least...
I know more or less
where the truth lies.
You have a much better
vantage point than in a courtroom.
People have a right
to their secrets.
Of course.
You didn't tell him.
What stopped you?
The fact that he has a nice wife
who's devoted to him,
and a sweet little daughter
who loves him?
Is that why you couldn't do it?
Were you seized by remorse
or just afraid to cause harm?
Maybe both.
Let me tell you.
I can eavesdrop on them or not.
You can tell him or not.
But sooner or later,
he'll jump out the window,
or she'll find out everything.
Someone will tell their daughter,
and their lives will be a living hell.
And what can we do about it?
You have nothing to say?
Does this remind you of something?
- Yes.
- What?
Say it.
A boy I know.
A boy you know who...
what?
Found out his mother was a whore?
Who found out...
he wasn't his father's son.
He was 15.
That man's daughter...
she knows too.
Stay a minute.
Why?
The light is beautiful.
Personalized weather reports.
I'm the one driving
to Turin tomorrow.
Ah, yes. The weather
will be fine to Chamonix.
From Chamonix to the tunnel,
it may snow.
And after the tunnel —
just a minute —
This way I know
the weather all over Europe.
Up to Turin, the weather will be fine.
Leave early to avoid snow.
Thanks.
This is a wonderful service.
Thank you. Good-bye.
Personalized weather reports.
It's me.
Did you get any sleep?
- A little.
I didn't tell you this —
it may be easier on the phone —
but it was really wonderful.
We've never made love
so intensely, for so long.
We each learned something.
Me from you, you from me.
When I woke up, you were
still sleeping. Like a child.
- I'm older than you!
- By a year.
- Two.
- Okay, two.
But as I watched you, I got scared.
Where is this leading?
You're not in great spirits.
Nervous about your exams?
No, about what I'm going to do.
Will it be enough for you?
How about going bowling?
I just got all my books out.
But maybe you're right.
You got a coin?
Toss it.
Tails is bowling.
Heads is criminal law.
Tails. Bowling.
I'll study for an hour
and then call you.
- Or I'll call you.
- Okay, I'll wait.
If I go out,
it's just for cigarettes. Bye.
You didn't listen?
Too bad. It was romantic.
I heard the beginning.
They're in love.
Yes.
He hasn't met the right woman yet.
How do you know?
I watch them sometimes
from my window.
You think I'm a bastard?
- Yes.
Come look.
That guy bought a telephone in Japan
that uses a different wavelength.
My radio can't pick it up.
Too bad.
I suspect he controls most
of the heroin trade in Geneva.
No one can touch him.
He never takes any risks.
You like him?
- Very much.
I'll call him.
You have his phone number?
You deserve to die.
What did I do?
Here's his phone number.
If you get the urge to assault him
verbally again, don't be shy.
I turned out the lights at 10:00,
but I couldn't sleep.
Next program.
Not very interesting.
I kept tossing and turning,
and it kept hurting.
It still does.
I haven't shopped for groceries.
- I'm sorry, Mother.
- I have no milk or bread.
I bought you some.
I put it in the freezer.
I ate it all.
Stop it.
You didn't eat seven loaves
in four days.
I'm sick of this.
You should go do her shopping.
You'd feel better.
Maybe she's the one
who'd feel better.
Why did you stop and pick up Rita?
Because I'd hit her.
She was bleeding.
Otherwise you'd have felt guilty.
You'd have had dreams
about a dog with its skull crushed.
Yes.
So who did you do it for?
There's no point doing
that old lady's shopping.
She has everything she needs.
She wants to see her daughter,
but her daughter won't come by.
She came by five times
when her mother faked a heart attack.
When she dies,
I'll have to notify the daughter,
because she won't believe
her mother now.
She doesn't believe her anymore.
You're wrong.
About what?
Everything.
You're wrong about everything.
People aren't bad.
It's not true.
Yes, it is.
They may be weak sometimes, but —
That boy who found out
his father wasn't his father —
was that your boyfriend
or your brother?
My brother.
How old is he?
Sixteen.
Has he been shooting up
a long time?
How did you know?
It wasn't hard to guess.
One can only feel pity for you.
Maybe you didn't know.
Your dog is going to have puppies.
- It's Valentine.
- Hello, darling.
Hi, Mom. Did Marc arrive?
Two days ago, with his lovely girlfriend.
Do you know her?
Yes. Marie.
We're all together.
They're watching TV.
I'm sorry I can't be there.
Yes, too bad. It's like old times.
Your brother's a good boy.
Can I talk to him?
Marc! Here he comes.
Call me, Mom. I love you.
- Hi, Valentine.
- Thanks for going there.
At your service.
We're leaving tomorrow. I can't take it.
Mom didn't see the paper?
I don't think so.
She'd never believe it anyway.
- You're right. You should go home.
- Bye.
Call me, Michel.
Please call.
Did you see the picture?
The picture?
Jacques?
Isn't it great? You didn't see it?
I forgot. I've had a hard day.
- Come join us. It'll relax you.
- Where?
Not bad.
Sorry to bother you,
but someone's played
a stupid prank and I can't get in.
Those Turkish kids.
Always causing trouble.
I don't know.
Someone stuck gum in the lock.
Tweezers.
- It's me.
- Michel...
I just called.
There was no answer.
Someone stuck gum in the lock.
I couldn't get in.
I heard the phone.
Gum?
I did an ad for chewing gum.
That must be why.
You shouldn't do that work.
They're taking advantage of you!
Forget it.
Didn't you turn the machine on?
I just want some peace.
A life of peace and quiet.
Then I'm not your guy.
You won't have peace with me.
Did you meet someone?
No, I'm waiting for you.
Why didn't you pick up before?
I told you. I couldn't get in.
I understand.
How are you?
I'm going to Hungary next week.
What are you going to do?
- I'm going to bed.
- Then go ahead.
Go on!
Are you there?
Michel, are you there?
It's starting again...
Are you asleep?
No, I'm not.
Well, get in bed!
Are you in bed?
I'm taking a shower.
I was getting undressed.
No one's helping you?
Valentine, are you there?
No. Good night.
I knew you could do it.
Congratulations.
Did they ask the question?
The one in the book
you dropped in the street.
Don't you like it?
Very much.
What will be
the first judgment I sign with it?
Civil hearing in the case of...
the residents of Pinchat
versus Joseph Kern.
Please come inside.
I'd like number 432.
Van den Budenmayer.
Did I pronounce it right?
- Yes.
This one?
I just sold the last one.
I'll have more this afternoon.
I'll set one aside if you like.
Whose newspaper is that?
Yours.
RETIRED JUDGE
IN INVASION-OF-PRIVACY CASE
Hello. I've come —
I saw the newspaper.
I want you to know I didn't tell a soul.
I know.
Not a soul.
Not the police or anyone.
I know.
I know who it was.
Who?
Me.
You asked me to.
Won't you come in?
There's something
I'd like to show you.
One, two, three, four,
five, six... seven?
Seven.
Would you like some pear brandy?
I've had it for ages
but never had the occasion.
To my health.
Why did you do it?
Why did I turn myself in?
Yes.
To see what you'd do
when you saw it in the paper.
Did you think I'd come by?
After our last conversation,
I thought so.
Why?
Do you expect something from me?
Yes.
Before leaving the other day,
you spoke of pity.
I realized later it was disgust.
Would you sit down for a moment?
Would you smile for me?
You cried when you left here
the other day.
Yes, I did.
And I turned off my radio.
I sat down at my desk.
The fountain pen I'd used
all my life was out of ink,
so I took a pencil
and wrote letters
to my neighbors and to the police.
I mailed them that same night
while you were sound asleep.
I wasn't asleep.
I'd gone bowling.
- Bowling?
Do you remember
that couple's conversation?
The boy and the girl?
I remember.
They were going bowling
that evening too.
You might have been
right next to them.
Perhaps.
You didn't like her.
I was right. It's almost over.
You seem pleased.
Did you do something to end it?
Yes or no?
Because of my eavesdropping
and my trial,
the girl met another man.
Ladies and gentlemen...
She's been all alone since then.
I asked my brother to go see her.
He stayed three days.
I'm going to England in a week
for I don't know how long.
I'm abandoning my mother
and my brother.
He's a little worse every day.
I shouldn't go.
Go. It's your destiny.
You can't live your brother's life
for him.
I love him.
If only I could do something.
You can: Be.
What do you mean?
Just that: Be.
Do you like flying?
Then take the ferry.
I've never taken one.
It's less expensive and healthier.
It's a good idea.
Do you like it?
Today's my birthday.
- I didn't know.
Thirty-five years ago today,
at about this time — 5:00 p.m. —
I acquitted a man. A sailor.
One of my first big cases,
and I was going through a tough time.
I've since realized I made a mistake.
He was guilty.
I don't think I have any more bulbs.
What became of him?
I did my own investigation.
He got married
and had three children,
and a grandson not long ago.
He's living a peaceful life.
So you did the right thing.
And you did it well.
Don't you understand?
You saved him.
Perhaps.
But how many others
could I have acquitted?
Even if they were guilty?
Deciding what's true and what isn't
now seems to me...
to show a lack of humility.
Pride?
Yes, pride.
May I have another drop?
Here's to you.
If I were ever taken to court...
you think there are still
judges like you around?
You'll never be taken to court.
The courts don't deal
with the innocent.
See that?
That's the sixth window
they've broken,
even though
the wavelength's been changed
and it's impossible
to eavesdrop anymore.
Where's the broom?
In the kitchen closet.
Put the stone on the piano.
Aren't you afraid?
I ask myself
what I'd do in their place.
I'd do the same.
You'd throw stones?
In their place? Of course.
And that goes for everyone
I passed judgment on.
Given their lives, their circumstances,
I'd steal and kill and lie.
Of course I would.
It's only because
I was in my shoes, not theirs.
Is there anyone you love?
Have you ever loved?
Yesterday I had a dream —
I had a dream about you.
You were 40 or 50 years old...
and you were happy.
Do your dreams come true?
It's been years since I've had
a really pleasant dream.
Stay there!
I bought a ticket for the ferry.
I arrive in England next Wednesday...
at 7:30 a.m.
Why the ferry?
That way I can visit
my mother near Calais.
I'll be there by 8:30 at the latest.
I'm happy you're coming.
Michel, tell me...
do you love me?
I think so.
You love me, or you think you do?
Same thing.
The battery...
Auguste!
Personalized weather reports.
I've tried calling for a few days.
I was sick. I'm sorry.
What will the weather be
on the English Channel next week?
Wonderful. Sunny, a slight breeze,
chilly in the morning.
Why do you laugh?
I'm heading there myself.
And beyond.
For your work?
No, for pleasure. On a yacht.
- It's nice sailing.
- Yes, very.
- Will you be closing?
- I'll have to.
Too bad.
It was a good idea. Good-bye.
We said not to smile!
Be serious!
Could you send
an invitation to this address?
Just one person?
Everything okay?
Have a good time.
- Anyone got makeup remover?
- Here.
Everyone noticed that guy.
I kept staring at him
during the whole show.
You came.
Did you know
the invitation was from me?
I hoped it was.
Did you look for me?
During the entire show.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
I wanted to say good-bye.
Good-bye.
I'd like you to tell me in detail
about that dream you had.
You were 50 years old,
and you were happy.
In this dream...
was there anyone else?
There was.
Who?
You woke up...
and smiled at someone next to you.
I don't know who.
And that's what will happen...
in 20 or 25 years?
Yes.
What else do you know?
Who are you?
A retired judge.
It feels like something important
is happening around me...
and it scares me.
Is that better?
I used to come here often.
Where did you usually sit?
Where I sat today.
That's why you couldn't see me.
One day, during intermission,
the strap around my books broke.
One large book fell
all the way down...
somewhere around there.
It was just before my exams.
I ran down immediately.
The book had opened to a random page.
I read a few sentences.
It was the question
they asked during my exam.
Getting out of the house
did you good.
It recharged my battery.
It was dead.
The storm.
Pretty lousy coffee.
I was wondering
why you told me about that sailor.
You know why?
Yes.
Because...
there was something much more
important you couldn't tell me about.
About the woman you loved.
She betrayed you.
She betrayed you...
and you never understood why.
And you went on loving her
for a long time.
How do you know all this?
It wasn't hard to guess.
What was she like?
She was two years
ahead of me at the university.
She was blond...
delicate...
radiant...
with a long neck.
Her clothes were light-colored,
and all her furniture was too.
In the foyer there was
a mirror in a white frame.
It was in that mirror one night...
that I saw her white legs
spread wide...
with a man between them.
Why...
did that happen?
Do you know?
That man...
whose name was Hugo Holbling...
could give her what she wanted.
They left.
I followed them.
I crossed France
and the English Channel.
I felt humiliated.
Until the day
she died in an accident.
I've never been involved
with another woman since.
Yes...
I stopped believing.
Or maybe I never met the woman —
Perhaps I just never met you.
The story doesn't end there.
A while ago,
I was assigned a difficult case.
On the file was the name
of the defendant:
Hugo Holbling.
The same man.
He'd come back here.
I'm closing up.
Have you seen a woman
with some buckets?
The storm flooded
the wardrobe department.
If you see her,
tell her I'm upstairs.
You should have declined the case.
I didn't want to.
Back then I'd wanted to kill him.
And I would have,
if it would have changed anything.
But now...
he awaited my verdict.
He'd been building
a covered market that caved in.
Several people died.
I found him guilty.
It was a perfectly legal sentence.
After that I asked for early retirement.
Did you see her?
I'm always running after her.
Milana!
There you are!
Give me those buckets.
They're too heavy for you.
You seemed to like my pear brandy.
Thank you.
I have another favor to ask.
I'll be gone two or three weeks.
I'll come see you when I'm back.
I'd like one of Rita's puppies.
Will the fashion show be on TV?
Probably.
I'll have to get one.
I have one I never use.
My brother could bring it by.
His name is Marc.
I'd like to meet him.
Until next time.
Good-bye.
Do you have your ticket with you?
Where do I go?
This deck. That corridor.
- I'm a bit lost. F38?
- The deck above.
TRAGEDY ON THE ENGLISH CHANNEL
SEVEN SURVIVE
Very bad weather
on the English Channel
is making the rescuers' task
more difficult.
Several fishing boats
are reported missing ,
as is a yacht
with two people aboard.
The cause of the disaster is unknown.
According to sources,
the ferry was carrying
1,435 passengers.
Rescue operations
are still under way.
Hundreds of bodies
have been recovered.
Many passengers are still missing.
A police boat,
first to respond to the SOS,
retrieved seven passengers.
All are reported unharmed.
The widow of a French composer
who died last year, Julie Vignon.
Steven Killian, English citizen,
bartender on the ferry.
Polish businessman Karol Karol.
Dominique Vidal, French citizen.
Frenchman Olivier Benoît.
There are also two Swiss citizens
among the survivors:
Auguste Bruner, a judge...
and a young model,
a student at the University of Geneva,
Valentine Dussaut.