Give me your hands.
It's okay.
Is it your marriage ring?
Your wife must be happy
to have an attentive husband.
I read an article that you met her
in America and married there.
And you let her continue her study
for the love of her, right?
Why are you still single?
I know.
Guess I was busy living my life.
Oh, I'm bleeding.
Seems the hen pecked at you.
Let me see?
I'm okay.
Let me see.
Are you daring or reckless?
You didn't know
you were being pecked?
That was close.
Time is the bigger deal
than my scratch.
Hurry, let's go.
I have to try the new menu.
Alright, ma'am.
What shall I tell you first?
Yes.
With this, I can finish
both Minjoon and Lena Jeong.
Such a weakling.
When Minjoon and I were at your age,
we could drink gallons of liquor.
You can't succeed
with that mettle.
You need to start over
at the bottom.
With whose permission?
I didn't give birth to him
to see him suffer.
Mr. Taesoo Park,
you will have no choice
but to do this.
Oh, there you are!
Why didn't you answer?
I looked for you.
Hi. I was
going over something.
What are these?
Remember I told you about
the hospital site in Qingdao?
I know you don't want to
put too many irons in the fire...
but Dr. Choi already signed the paper.
So why don't you...
Honey.
I made it clear that Jaejoon is
too soft-hearted to run a hospital.
Spending money on the hospital
will be a waste of money.
Break the contract and just wait.
Are you going to
discriminate your kids like this?
What?
You encouraged and supported Minjoon
when he started business,
but you put Jaejoon down
before he even starts.
Your favoritism
might break his spirit.
Are you serious?
Yes, I am.
Have I ever asked you
a favor for Jaejoon?
I've endured a lot for the peace
in the family but this is too much.
Tell me.
What's so wrong with him?
Well, listen.
He became a doctor because
you wanted to have a doctor son.
He also flew to Taiwan to date a girl
because you told him to.
He does whatever you tell him.
So why do you hate him so much?
That's the problem!
He is a man but he's so sissy
and dependent to his parents!
With that soft mettle,
what can he achieve in this tough world?
Then should he be like
defiant Minjoon...
who started business at will,
who married and divorced
of his own accord?
Wasn't it enough for you
to invest in his business?
Must you always put him
before Jaejoon?
Are you done?
How could you
draw the line between them?
Both Minjoon and Jaejoon
are precious to me.
Every child is dear to his parents!
You are really disappointing me!
Disappointing?
YOU are disappointing.
For our 30 years of married life,
how have I treated you and Minjoon?
He still doesn't
regard me as his mother...
and keeps his distance from me.
But I've always smiled at him
and put him before my own son!
Honey, listen.
Don't tell me to let it pass.
If you really
regard them equally,
prove it to me
before you support Minjoon.
Otherwise, I will never believe you!
Do you understand?
Honey.
- Heera.
My daughter, Heera.
What's the matter?
Where are you
going to go at this hour?
Right, it's late at night.
You really want to
take it this far?
Don't raise your voice!
It's your fault!
You should humbly beg for
her forgiveness instead of yelling at her.
Stop her.
Oh, Heera! Heera!
Let her go!
She is not in her right mind.
Do as you like!
Let's have it our ways!
How cold-hearted!
I cast pearl before swine.
Can't believe I gave
my daughter to him. You're a devil!
Margherita is ready!
Taste it.
Margherita will add
rich flavor to this.
Let's taste the upgraded taste
of our top-selling pizza.
The cheese tastes really good
with spicy chicken.
Yes.
This is the very taste.
I'm sure it'll
receive a great response.
Oh, yes.
It'll go very well
with a drink, too.
It's good.
We can do more sales in the evening
if we release this.
Wait.
How about moving up
the release date?
Meeting on 15th...
Oh, we're on a tight schedule.
Can I ask you a quiz?
Quiz?
Guess you're poor at Korean history
since you lived abroad.
What are you talking about?
I lived in Korea until I turned 20.
Then you can guess the answer.
Of all kings in Korean history,
guess who held the lowest position.
The lowest position?
Let me think.
Yeonsangoon?
Kwanghaegoon?
Uijawang?
Beep!
Your guesses are wrong.
The answer is...
the minimum wage.
Sorry for the lame joke.
I think you need
a little balance.
I look like a workaholic, huh?
But I really feel rushed.
I worked frantically hard
to achieve something in life.
But I always ended up
empty-handed.
If I fail this time,
my life will end up in failure.
I push ahead hard
not to miss the chance.
I know how you think of me.
I'm frantic and
reckless to your eyes.
That's fine.
Just understand that I have a reason.
My service to you.
I'm so bitter and resentful!
This is ridiculous!
How dare he preach
a homily to my daughter!
He's completely uneducated but
she is an Ewha grad.
It's him who should
listen to her!
I don't think so.
Taesoo is right.
It's true Jaejoon is a bit too
weak-hearted, isn't it?
How can you say that?
When we should close ranks
and attack Taesoo, you're saying what?
Cut the crap and just pack up!
The person you have dialed
is not available.
Dang it.
Where on earth did she go?
I'm so resentful!
Changsoo, get the car ready!
Okay.
Where are you going
this late at night?
You really don't know?
Hope you enjoy your
solitary life in this big house.
I will go to my daughter...
and make a living by ourselves.
We are history now.
Wait!
Are you adding oil to the fire?
What?
Okay, leave.
But keep this in mind.
You are free to go but
you can't come back at your will.
What?
Is that a threat?
Yes, it's a threat.
Go ahead, leave.
Leave my house.
What?
You think I'm afraid?
What's wrong with this?
Is it broken?
It won't move.
Changsoo, I think the
wheels are broken.
Let's go back in.
They're turning well.
Listen, Taesoo.
I'm going back to my room
when you told me to leave,
but don't think
I got scared by your threat.
Once I fix the wheels,
I'll leave right away. Changsoo.
Go get a screwdriver
and come in with this.
The wheels are fine.
Just shut up and come in!
We can leave. Mom!
By the way,
where on earth has she gone?
It's dangerous at night.
Well, I've endured for 30 years.
I can't give up now.
I will roust Minjoon and
let Jaejoon have the hospital.
I worked frantically hard
to achieve something in life.
But I always
ended up empty-handed.
I dozed off again.
I always put my
worst foot forward.
Thank you so much
for today. Good night.
Lena.
You said your life might end up
in failure if you fail this time.
That'll never happen.
This time,
you have me by your side.
Thank you.
Drive safely.
What's wrong with me?
Why is my heart racing?
Get a grip.
You still didn't learn a lesson?
Men eat the orange
and throw the peel away.
He's only a ladder
for my success.
Is it your marriage ring?
I read an article
about your love for your wife.
Excuse us.
We came to see
if we can work here.
I don't hire inexperienced people.
I'm not inexperienced.
I made stuffed animals
in Taiwan for 3 years.
And I picked bananas
and pineapples there for 4 years.
Really?
So you have
international experience.
Yes. If you give us a chance,
we'll do anything.
Come on,
don't say like an amateur.
Everybody in this
Whiz Sideline is a pro.
Take a look around.
They seem to be whizzes.
Can we do it like they do?
Enough.
You may leave.
Bastard.
I wonder if he is alright.
I almost scorched it!
It's done.
Where's my recipe notebook?
Esol, hurry.
You might be late for job interviews.
Can't you knock?
You scared me.
Oh, sorry.
Hurry up. I'll go out.
Wait. Have you seen
my recipe notebook?
I can't find it anywhere.
Hey.
Don't you think
you're going too far?
Why?
Oh, because I lost it?
No, it's not that.
I'm a man.
How can you crawl around
in your underwear in my presence?
You're not a man to me.
We used to swim in our skin
and go to a bathhouse when little.
Hey!
I'm not who I used to be.
I'm a grown up, mature man!
What's wrong with him?
Is he at the awkward age?
By the way,
where on earth has it gone?
Jaejoon, give me 30,
or at least 10 minutes.
I need to explain
what happened. Please.
Jaejoon,
your mom and dad had a
big fight last night over your hospital.
I spoke with Mom.
She needs some time alone.
Huh?
Why don't you act charming
and pester your dad?
"Dad, can you set up
a hospital for me? Please." Like this.
- Uncle Changsoo.
- Yes?
Don't worry.
They'll stop fighting over that matter.
What does he mean?
There's a bite in his words.
Why is it still on YouTube?
Didn't you ask the police
to delete video clips?
I did.
Then why are some
still on the Internet?
They keep spreading them.
Yura became famous overnight,
"Water Bombed Club Girl!"
Be quiet.
Did you tie Jaejoon's tongue?
Who knows?
Yura constantly called him
but he didn't answer.
I'm going nuts.
No.
I'm not Hyejin
if I back off here.
Heera is quiet, which means
she doesn't know about it yet.
I must persuade Jaejoon
once he comes to work.
Will he come to work?
He saw everything?
Shut the mouth.
But from a
common-sense point of view...
One, two!
Yes. Did Dr. Park
come to work?
Yes, he just went up.
Okay. The game is on.
Jaejoon.
I have to work.
Please get out.
No. I came since you
didn't answer the phone.
I know you're upset
but please listen to me.
I'm not upset.
I'll tell Dr. Choi everything.
Like what?
You mean you'll break up with me?
Yura.
No! Please don't do that.
Don't be so petty.
Girls at my age go out
on the razzle at a club.
I learned all sorts of dances
since I was little.
Korean dance,
ballet, jazz dance...
So when I hear music,
my body moves in spite of myself.
I have to work.
No. You can't go!
You can't move an inch
before you change your mind.
Yura.
Jaejoon, cut me some slack.
I will quit drinking and clubbing
if you tell me not to.
If you break up with me,
I'll be dead in my mom's hands.
Do you love me?
I'm sorry?
Do you love me enough
to marry me?
Well...
I'm not mad at you.
On the contrary, I thank you.
We both were
pushed to marry but...
you being honest with yourself
encouraged me.
Let's break up for both of us.
Jaejoon.
Don't worry.
I won't cause you damage.
Jaejoon, wait.
Break up?
With whose permission?
You think it's possible?
Didn't you hear what she said?
She only danced at a club.
She was highlighted
since she was outstanding.
She didn't have a fling with a man
or have a dirty past.
Her dance at the club
can't be a ground for breakup.
Right.
You're mutually at fault.
You too had fun at the club.
Please accept my resignation.
Were you this foolish?
Can't you see what
your breakup means?
Your marriage is not just
about you and Yura...
but more about business
beyond the two families.
Yet, will you break up with her
and neuter the great synergy...
from your marriage just because
you think she's ill-behaved?
Yes, I will break up with her.
I'd rather listen to my heart than hope
to get a rake-off from the synergy.
What? Dr. Park!
I don't want to ruin
your friendship with my mother.
I'll bear all the responsibility.
Thank you for everything.
Boy. He's manly.
What?
Well, you want me
to bring him back?
One, two, three!
Don't. It won't work.
What's in your mind?
Can I break up with him?
Are you crazy?
Now I have no choice
but to use the last card.
The last card?
Like what?
You don't need to know.
So you lived in Taiwan.
Yes, I lived there for 6 years.
I got certificates for
Chinese and Korean cuisines there.
Really.
Seems you're industrious.
Why didn't you
go to college then?
Excuse me?
I dropped out of college
for family reasons.
I think field experience is as important
as the school education.
I learned a lot from experience.
Her mother is half-educated.
You can tell her backgrounds.
Really?
Well, you're dressed up today.
Can you dance before us?
Yes. It's written here your hobby
is singing and dancing.
Show us.
Come on.
A good staff these days
can liven up the mood.
Do you know
'Poison' by J.H. Uhm?
Poison.
Yes. I'll do my best.
Keep going.
You're making a fool out of me.
I really need a job
so I came here in desperation.
Even though you're interviewers,
how could you...
You know what?
You can't have the
upper hand over me forever.
I might be back
as your customer someday.
The person you have dialed
is not available.
Mom, I have
something to tell you.
Give me a call
when you get this message.
Chef Esol Kang?
Esol Kang...
Esol Kang?
So you are Esol Kang.
Now I learned your real name.
Monthly Plan of Esol Kang.
Go, Esol! You can do it!
There are so many things I want to do
but I can't because of my family.
Do you have to do this job?
Doesn't it hurt your pride
to sing before drunken men?
Sometimes, there are things
to come before my pride.
It's good!
Paprika tastes
different per color.
Mom, try it.
Paprika is good for your stress.
How indifferent!
How can you possibly eat
when we haven't heard from Heera?
Yes, we have.
She needs some time alone to think.
So what does she
have to think about so long?
Perhaps, something bad
happened to her.
She's pretty, she looks rich.
Someone might have
kidnapped her.
Who would have kidnapped
a middle-aged woman?
And she's so heavy
you might break your back.
Sample menu fair?
Already?
Yes, we'll release new menus
next week with publicity.
You look full of confidence.
Seems Lena acts her part well.
I feel reassured.
If this new menus make a hit,
we can push into
Shanghai right away.
Maybe next month...
Minjoon.
Actually, I called you in
regarding that matter.
How about putting it off?
Things are messed up.
Your business expansion...
and Jaejoon's marriage
came up all at once...
and it's beyond my limit.
Though I have money to burn,
it's too much for me
to support you both.
So...
I see your point.
Support Jaejoon first.
I think Stepmother
wishes it too,
though she didn't show it.
Well, it's not
because she wishes it...
As long as
you are happy, I'm fine.
Well, I'm really sorry.
I'll get back to work.
That's my boy.
Very thoughtful.
That's why I trust him.
This is Spicy Chicken
Margherita Pizza.
Have a taste.
It's great!
It has a grilled chicken taste.
Yes. It's spicy yet sweet,
very inviting.
I think it'll make a big hit.
Ha. It's not different
from the pizza I made.
Yes, it is.
Chicken meat is
as chewy as cheese.
Did you use different chicken?
Yes.
The secret of this pizza
lies in the meat.
See?
Shut up.
I know that much.
I think it'll bring us success
with a good marketing.
Thank you for your
hard work so far.
Thank you!
Guess the response was good.
Why yes.
I beat the bush and
Ms. Jeong caught the birds.
This new menu
will be successful.
Good job, everyone.
Ms. Jeong,
you need to come with me.
Sorry? To where?
What the.
They always go in couples.
Are they
seeing each other or what?
What is it?
Mrs. Park,
we got a problem.
Lena Jeong twists
Mr. Park around her finger.
If her new menu is released,
she'll be on a roll.
What should we do?
Where are you calling?
In the restroom.
I clearly told you to
keep this matter between us.
Don't worry, Mrs. Park.
My mouth is tight.
I initiate contact with you.
So don't make a call to me.
Understood?
Okay. I'm sorry.
Lena Jeong will be on a roll?
Don't make me laugh.
With this,
I can finish her today.
How are you, sir?
Is it ready?
Yes.
Come this way please.
- Here's the car key.
- Thanks.
How do you like it?
I'm busy.
Why did you bring me here?
Can't you tell?
I bought a new car.
Take the wheel.
Excuse me?
Why should I drive your car?
What do you mean why?
Did you forget
I drove you home several times?
You can at least
do me this favor. Take it.
Mr. Park.
You said you're busy.
The person you have dialed
is not available.
Dang it.
Where on earth is she?
She's worrying me too much.
Sir, your wife is here to see you.
What?
My wife?
What tea would you like to...
Just leave us alone.
Get out.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry no matter what.
Just don't leave home again.
Without you,
I couldn't focus on work,
I couldn't sleep,
and I couldn't even eat.
Honey, forgive me.
Are you still mad at me?
What should I do
to have your forgiveness?
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry, so don't cry.
It's not that.
I'm not crying because of you.
I'm just disappointed in myself.
I...
made a resolution to love Minjoon
as my own when I married you.
Surely, the skin
is nearer than the shirt.
I've come to favor
Jaejoon before I realized it.
No, it's not your fault.
That's human nature.
No.
I don't deserve
to be his mother.
You were right,
so feel free to support Minjoon first.
No.
I will build the hospital
for Jaejoon first and then...
No, no.
Like you said,
Jaejoon can't gear
his ability to the job now.
Minjoon is your successor
so please support him first.
Okay.
If you insist,
I'll support him first and
look after Jaejoon's needs right away.
But if any problem
comes up with Minjoon,
I'll build the Qingdao hospital
for Jaejoon first, okay?
Okay.
That'll never happen
but thank you for saying that.
Oh, that's my wife.
Honey, life is short.
Let's not fight.
You are my sunshine.
So please smile
like a bright sunshine.
Please smile.
You're so...
Please.
Oh, that's my beautiful wife!
My beautiful wife!
Oh, my beautiful wife!
Mr. Park!
Here you are.
Keep it.
It's your car.
I'm sorry?
You returned the rental car.
Use this car.
Wait.
Why are you
giving this car to me?
If it's out of a personal favor,
I want to refuse it.
Why?
You really don't know?
You're a married man and...
Don't trust the article you read.
You don't tell the truth
when interviewed.
I bought you this car
for one reason.
I want to give my partner
the best working environment.
You've done well so far,
so it's a kind of reward.
That's all.
So feel free to take it.
A reward?
Yes, now my
ability is recognized.
Sure, Mr. Park.
I'll drive to the top.
Who is it?
Yes.
Ms. Lena Jeong?
Can we meet?
Who's calling please?
You'll see when we meet.
I'll text the place to you.
Wait.
Why would I...
You know Mr. Sungsoo Kim,
don't you?
It's about him.
Wonderful!
That is it!
It'll make us look great
on the mountain.
Absolutely!
We want that outfit each.
What freehanded ladies!
Let me size you with my eye.
Well, well.
Guess you wear size 4.
And guess you wear size 5.
Right?
You're a handsome,
excellent sales clerk.
He's cute.
So are you Dongoo's friend?
Yes, sir.
You look like a
model in that outfit.
Why don't you
work full-time here?
Really?
As a sales clerk?
Yes. Salaries and incentives,
health insurance,
and paid vacation.
How does that sound?
- I'm okay with...
- No!
She can't.
She's a culinarian.
She came to help me
just for today.
Really?
I'm sorry.
You can come here often though.
Why did you cut him off?
It wasn't a bad offer.
Don't give up just because
you failed job interviews.
You're a born cook.
No. Maybe I'd better give up.
It's hard competing with
all the elite college graduates.
And I swallowed an insult today.
Then how about
going back to college?
I'll support you.
If I work hard
and receive incentives,
I can pay your tuitions.
What?
Why would you do that?
Huh?
Well, it's kind of
an investment.
Later when you succeed,
I can eat free meals
at your restaurant.
Get real. Forget it.
It's not in our lot to attend college
when we have to earn our bread.
I'm serious.
Give it a thought.
Forget it.
Let's work hard and make money.
Fool.
I meant our marital home
by the free meals.
Yes.
Yes, this is she.
Really?
Oh, thank you!
Yes.
Sure, I'll be right there.
Bye.
Dongoo!
Why, something good
happened to you?
I found my recipe notebook.
I'll be back soon.
Excuse me.
Did you call me
to return my recipe notebook?
Have a seat.
This is my treasure.
I was upset after I lost it.
Thank you for turning it in.
Wait.
I can't give it to you
for nothing.
I made time to come here.
Then how much
do you want as a reward?
You're going too far.
You think money is everything?
I feel pathetic
for having worried about...
your losing this notebook forever.
Wait.
'What if he never wakes up?'
'What if he has
a serious disease?
Something happened to him?'
I feel pathetic for
having worried about you.
I helped you not for money,
but out of concern for you.
But out of concern for you.
How are you?
What happened?
How did you get this?
I think you left it in my car
the day you took me to the hospital.
Oh, I can relate.
Fool, I never thought that.
I want my reward.
Okay.
What is this?
Fortune cookie.
It's a reward from my heart.
Hope it'll bring you luck.
By the way, it's filled with recipes.
Are you a would-be chef?
It's my dream.
I have licenses and work experiences
but it's hard to get a job.
How about dinner with me?
You owe me.
Sorry, I have to
get back to work.
Oh, really?
Okay.
Don't forget you owe me dinner.
Goodbye.
We're back.
- We're back!
- Hi!
You sound happy.
You have good news?
Yes.
Did you pass the interview?
I'm proud of you!
See? I told you
she's good enough to get a job!
Wait.
I want to celebrate it.
One, two, three, four!
You are the best
You are the best to me
It's not that.
She failed job interviews.
Sorry, I failed.
I was happy to find this.
Oh, is that so?
We're acting silly.
Sorry, Esol.
No, don't be sorry.
Family's meant to comfort
and support each other.
A job?
Yes.
I think she has great potential.
She's a good cook,
her Chinese is excellent,
and she's pretty.
If you hire her,
your business in China
will be smooth and easy.
Who is she that
you ask me for a job for her?
Just a friend.
You like her, don't you?
Nice aroma.
What brand is this?
Okay, I won't ask anymore.
I'll meet her.
If she's really competent,
I will give her a job.
You mean it.
Stick to your word.
Sure. I can do
the favor for my only brother.
Don't worry.
I love you, Minjoon.
I give you my heart. Bye!
Esol Kang?
It's a reward from my heart.
Hope it'll bring you luck.
Okay.
"Your dream
will come true soon."
Hospital coordinator?
Yes.
It's a plastic surgery hospital
in Chongdam.
They need a coordinator
good at Chinese.
You're the right person.
Do you think they'll hire you?
I have a last interview
with the director.
Sending you my luck.
You will get a job soon.
Wish your mom is always upset.
Why yes.
Otherwise we can't
eat these foods.
She always says,
"You'll get fat.
Just throw them away!
One, two!"
Look at me.
I just move as a
reflex action at one, two.
Oh, right.
I got a call from a
TV network to appear on TV.
Really?
Guess they saw your dancing video
and really liked it.
On what program?
I Am a Singer?
Super Star Korea?
No.
It's a morning show,
'How Is Your Daughter?'
I was offered to appear as a bad girl
with my face blotted out.
Those bastards!
Tell them to mind
their own daughters.
Don't worry.
I will wipe out those
who give you a hard time.
Even Mom?
Yes, of course!
Be quiet!
Yes, honey.
Let's just eat.
I will break up with her.
I'd rather listen to my heart...
than hope to get
a rake-off from the synergy.
How impudent.
I can't help but
reveal the truth after 28 years.
Heera will be shocked but
she'll understand after all...
since our common cause
is the Qingdao Hospital.
But if any problem
comes up with Minjoon,
I'll build the
Qingdao hospital for Jaejoon first.
Alright?
Keep the promise, Taesoo.
A problem will come up soon.
Hi, Ms. Lena Jeong.
Mrs. Park.
Why?
Are you surprised
because it was me?
I don't want to be interrupted
so I'll order later.
Was it you who called me?
What's your business with me?
I told you it's about Sungsoo Kim.
I don't get it.
Who is Sungsoo Kim?
I don't know who that person is.
You don't know him?
Sungsoo Kim of Youngdengpo
Private Detective Agency.
Should I continue?
Alright, ma'am.
What shall I tell you first?
It was a put-up job.
She asked me to pretend to faint
at the restaurant that day.
She said she'd save me if I
fainted from mango allergy...
I'm sorry, Mrs. Park.
I did great wrong.
Please forgive me.
I was so desperate to get a job.
I mean it.
I didn't have
any bad intentions.
I wanted a job
to prove my ability.
I've worked really hard
and I still will.
If new menus are released,
sales will increase and
we'll make success in Shanghai.
I will work hard with my best
so please forgive me.
I thought you were smart
but seems you are not.
That's not what I want.
Excuse me?
What do you mean?
Didn't you eavesdrop me
at the restaurant the other day?
I'm not interested
in management.
What if Minjoon succeeds
your father in the mean time?
If he succeeds Father,
that's good for both
the company and the family.
What if you're left out forever?
There cannot be
two suns in the sky!
If you're shouldered off now,
you'll live as a loser
for the rest of your life.
You want to be
a loser all your life?
You mean...
Right.
What I want
is the fall of Minjoon Park.
To prevent his
success in Shanghai.
You'll release
new menus soon, right?
Instead of what you prepared...
use this.
You're wily enough so I think
you don't need further instructions.
I'll leave the matter to you.
What if I say no?
Why should I do that?
I have no reason to do that.
What?
I can't do that.
No, I won't.
[Subtitles provided by MBC]
[Preview]
I didn't know
there's a place like this.
Did you throw yourself
to Mr. Park?
So sexy.
Don't drool.
It might hit the floor.
You're my lovely wife, Chef Kang.
You think marriage is a joke?
Forget about it!
Honey!
Can you make me a star?
You're a mere consumable of TNC.
It's natural to
switch to a higher ladder.
Now it's your turn to trust me.
To the first success
we'll make together!