[Solemn Oriental instrumental music]
'HOUSE OF FLYING DAGGERS'
CHINA 859 A.D.
- The once-mighty Tang Dynasty is in decline.
The Emperor is weak and incompetent.
His corrupt government
no longer controls the land.
Unrest sweeps the country.
Village by village,
an underground alliance forms...
'The House of Flying Daggers'.
Based near the Imperial Capital,
The House Of Flying Daggers
moves in the shadows.
Stealing from the rich to give to the poor,
they earn the support and
admiration of the people.
At the same time,
they are feared and hated
by their bitter rivals...
the local deputies.
Police Headquarters - Feng Tian County
Capt. Leo, Capt. Jin.
We're heading out on patrol.
We're going to be busy again.
The Provincial Office has given us 10 days...
to catch the new leader of the Flying Daggers.
What?
It took us three months
to assassinate their old leader.
Ten days? Impossible.
Have you heard of the new Peony Pavilion?
Yes.
Does anyone know you there?
No, I haven't been there yet.
Good, now's your chance.
Any information?
We suspect one of the showgirls
is a member of the Flying Daggers.
Okay, I'll check it out.
Entertainment House - Peony Pavilion
[Women giggling]
JIN: Pull. Pull harder.
Pull harder.
[All laughing]
GIRL: Come on.
[Light Oriental instrumental music]
[Jin exclaiming]
That's it. I'm done.
- Madam!
- I'm coming.
JIN: Madam.
MADAM: Here I am.
What can I do for you, sir?
I heard you have a new girl.
You're well informed.
Is she pretty?
She's quite a beauty.
Bring her to me.
[Clearing throat]
There is one thing you need to know.
What's that?
The girl is blind.
Blind?
Then she must be special.
I'm curious.
[Light Oriental instrumental music resumes]
[Women chattering and laughing
in the distance]
[Grunting questioningly]
How did you lose your sight?
I was born blind.
Why would a blind girl work here?
Why can't a blind girl work here?
[Chuckles]
You're right.
- What's your name?
- Mei.
Mei?
Every girl in this pavilion
has taken the name of a flower.
Why is yours so plain?
I don't want to compete
with those ordinary girls.
What do you mean?
MEI: The flowers displayed here
can hardly be called flowers.
Real flowers bloom
in the wilderness.
[Grunting affirmatively]
well said.
If you impress me...
I'll take you
to where the real flowers grow.
What's your talent
as the top showgirl?
Dancing.
Come closer.
[Mei gasps]
[Jin chucking]
Don't you know the rules?
[bell ringing]
[Jingling]
[Melodious Oriental music playing]
[Singing] A rare beauty in the North
She's the finest lady on earth
A glance from her,
the whole city goes down
A second glance
leaves the whole nation in ruins
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty like this
A rare beauty in the North
She's the finest lady on earth
A glance from her,
the whole city goes down
A second glance
leaves the whole nation in ruins
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty
like this
[Mei screams]
[Women exclaiming in shock]
[Mei screaming]
SERVANT: Please calm down, sir.
JIN: Go away.
MADAM: What's the matter?
Please let me explain.
MADAM: She is young and inexperienced.
Please forgive her.
Take her away.
JIN: Go away.
MADAM: Take her away.
LEO: Stop!
MADAM: Captain.
This is the Captain of the County.
JIN: To hell with the Captain!
Outrageous! Arrest him.
JIN: Let me go.
Who are you?
[Mei grunting]
How dare you! I'm the Captain.
You're drunk and indecently dressed.
Arrest both of them.
JIN: Get your hands off me.
JIN: Let me go.
Please spare the girl, Captain.
That man was drunk.
It was not her fault.
Please don't arrest her.
Our business is new.
I rely on her to bring in guests.
How can a blind girl
be a top showgirl? Move!
She's a dancer with rare skills.
Please see for yourself.
Do you know the Echo Game?
I played it once.
All right.
Perform well and I'll let you go.
Thank you, Captain.
Go and change quickly.
[All clamouring]
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
ALL: Fantastic.
[Spectators cheering]
[Chuckling]
[Spectators applauding]
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
ALL: Excellent!
[Drums rattling in succession]
[Clattering]
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
[Drumbeats increase in tempo]
[Drumbeats swell to a climax]
[Women screaming]
[Leo grunting]
[Exclaiming]
[Gasps]
[All clamouring]
[All screaming]
Who are you, really?
Why do you want to kill me?
Government running dogs...
I wish to kill all of you!
[Both grunting]
[Laughing softly]
[Gripping Oriental instrumental music]
[Drum pounding]
I do enjoy fighting a blind girl.
[Gripping Oriental instrumental music
heightens]
[Beads tinkling softly]
[Water gurgling]
[Leo grunting angrily]
[Mei choking]
POLICEMAN: We found this in her room.
You're a member
of the Flying Daggers.
Who's the new leader?
LEO: Where's the new leader?
I'll show you what We'll do to you
if you refuse to answer.
Show her!
In front of you is a torture device.
[Mei grunting]
Your head will be put here.
Your shoulder, here.
Your back, here.
Your legs, here.
[Machine creaking]
you'll never dance again after this.
Do you understand?
You have one day to think it over.
This girl reminds me of someone.
Who?
Rumour has it...
the old leader's blind daughter
disappeared after his death.
It was a heavy blow
to the Flying Daggers.
They vowed revenge for their loss,
while searching for the girl.
Why would the old leader's daughter
end up in a brothel?
Who owns the Peony Pavilion?
Perhaps the Flying Daggers
have realised...
we were responsible
for their old leader's death.
Forget it.
Let's turn her over to the
Provincial Office for a reward...
and then go out for a drink.
I have a better idea.
Since we have some clues...
let's follow them through
for a bigger reward.
Do you want me to do it?
Of course, who else?
All right.
This girl is a rare beauty.
You know I love flirting with girls.
Don't let beauty
blind your judgment.
If I die under a skirt,
I still can flirt as a ghost.
[Both laughing]
[Guards grunting]
[All grunting]
MEI: Who are you?
I undressed you only yesterday.
Have you forgotten me already?
Why did you rescue me?
Why do you think?
You're an exquisite flower.
I'll do anything to help you.
Control yourself.
Don't worry.
I'm no longer a guest
of the Peony Pavilion.
JIN: You're not a showgirl anymore.
You're the daughter
of the old leader.
What did you say?
How many blind girls
know martial arts...
and carry daggers like these?
JIN: I've rescued you...
and your daggers, as well.
Why did you take such a risk?
I hate the corrupt government
and admire the Flying Daggers.
Much obliged.
MEI: Why did we abandon the horses?
JIN: Hoofprints can be easily tracked.
I have two new horses hidden ahead.
MEI: You've planned well.
What's your name, Master?
JIN: Just call me Wind.
Wind?
I wander around all alone,
come and go without a trace.
Like a carefree wind?
No, a playful wind.
[Jin chuckling]
You like to tease.
I wonder what you look like.
That's easy to find out.
Here.
Please let go.
This isn't the Peony Pavilion.
There are no rules here.
you'll know what I look like
if you touch my face.
Come on.
It's not respectful
to touch your face first.
I asked you to start from the top.
You prefer to start at the bottom.
That's fine with me.
You've mastered
the flying technique.
Your right hand
is skilled with a machete.
Your left hand is powerful
with a bow and arrow.
Your heart beats steadily,
you seem sincere.
You can read me like a book.
You're a brave man.
I'm never shy around women.
You're young, indeed.
You know how to hold your drink.
The soldiers are approaching.
[Tense instrumental music]
I've lost my dagger pouch.
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Horse snuffling]
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Soldier screaming]
[Mei grunting]
[Horse neighing]
[Mei gasping]
[Horse neighing in pain]
[Dramatic instrumental music continues]
[Mei screaming]
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music]
I'm sorry I was late.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music
continues]
JIN: The Flying Daggers
are always moving.
Where should we go?
We just keep heading north.
Just head north?
They will come to us.
The Flying Daggers
have many masters.
Why did they send you
as an assassin?
No one sent me. I came alone.
JIN: As the old leader's daughter,
you should be more cautious.
Have you considered
the consequences?
I'll do anything
to avenge my father.
Come here.
These are men's clothes.
Put them on for now.
[Clanking]
I won't take advantage of you.
[Clanking continues in the distance]
MEI: Have you seen enough?
Please hand me the clothes.
JIN: You knew I was here?
MEI: Master Wind wanders like the wind.
MEI: I'd expect you to be anywhere.
You look different in men's clothes.
Do I look awful?
I will tell all the girls
to wear men's clothes...
the next time
I visit the Peony Pavilion.
Now I know...
you're not shy around women.
You're not shy, either.
How do you know?
You knew I was watching you bathe,
yet you said nothing.
You saved my life.
You can look all you please.
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music]
JIN: I thought you were hot as fire.
JIN: In fact, you're cool as water.
MEI: I don't know you well enough.
JIN: I really care for you.
MEI: A playboy like you,
are you ever for real?
JIN: What if I am this time?
Are our men close by?
LEO: I'm sure today's fighting
has fooled Mei.
Our men will ease off from now on.
Good. That'll save me some arrows.
Any clues?
Not yet.
Don't let her see through you.
Don't worry.
I never fail at seducing a woman.
She trusts me.
I warn you, don't fall for her.
What do you mean, fall?
Fall into bed.
Like her father,
she must be very cunning.
Don't let her fool you.
Don't be absurd.
I'm in control.
I have to get back now.
Don't turn a game into
reality and ruin our plan.
JIN: Who cares,
as long as the plan works.
Shall we rest for a while?
[Soft Oriental instrumental music]
[Inhaling deeply]
I smell flowers.
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music]
You told me you'd bring me
to where real flowers grow.
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music
continues]
Which is the most beautiful?
How do I look?
Pretty as a flower.
Soldiers are approaching.
[All grunting]
- [Whispering] I'm on your side.
- You?
JIN: I am a captain of the County.
SOLDIER: A captain?
Nonsense.
You are the bastard who broke the jail.
[Tense instrumental music]
[Soldier screaming]
[Tense instrumental music continues]
[Mei screaming]
You're wounded. Is it serious?
No.
[Music intensifies]
[Soldier screaming in pain]
Was it someone
from the Flying Daggers?
It's not likely.
Then who?
I don't know.
He's gone.
I guess he doesn't want
to reveal himself.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music]
This time,
I believe that you're for real.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music
continues]
[Jin grunting]
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music
continues]
You've done enough for me.
Please leave.
Don't worry about me.
We've come this far.
I can't leave you now.
[Mei crying softly]
I hope you're not seriously wounded.
We agreed
there would be no more fights.
Why did government soldiers turn up?
The General sent them.
They don't know you.
The General?
How did the General get involved?
This case is important.
I had to report it.
The General is taking over.
The soldiers
didn't have to be that aggressive.
The General ordered it.
He said we need real blood
to draw the Flying Daggers out.
Even if the blood is mine?
Jin...
the soldiers' lives and our lives
are worth nothing to him.
You don't know how I felt
as I killed our own men.
I feel worse. I am tortured.
You?
I truly regret...
taking on this mission.
I've followed you all the way.
Endured many sleepless nights.
LEO: My heart grows heavy
when I think about what lies ahead.
Is there no other way to do this?
The General said...
it's the only way
to expose the Flying Daggers.
Jin, you should know
there are more soldiers ahead.
- What?
- The General sent them.
They don't know you, either.
You must stop them.
There is nothing I can do.
The order given to these soldiers...
is ''fight to kill.''
If you don't kill them...
they will kill you.
Take care.
I quit.
Where have you been?
I have a question for you.
- What question?
- Are you for real?
What do you mean?
Do you feel anything for me?
Don't take this so seriously.
I want to know.
I'm a free spirit...
like the wind, airways moving.
The wind never thinks too much.
I want the wind to stop and think.
The wind cannot stop.
Not even for me?
The wind breezes through
without a trace.
Now you understand...
why I'm called Wind.
Fine, go and be the wind.
I don't need you anymore!
[Wood clattering]
I don't care if you're true or not.
I have to leave.
I want to end this.
Are you going alone?
I'd like to be the wind for once.
Where will you go?
Who knows.
Whichever way the wind blows.
Aren't you going back
to the Flying Daggers?
Do you want me to go back?
I've left them. Why would I return?
Thank you
for all you've done for me.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music]
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music
continues]
[Soft clanking]
[Mei grunting]
[Mei screaming]
[Soldiers panting]
[Soldier screaming]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
- It's you.
- Go.
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music]
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music
continues]
[Mei exclaims]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
You said the wind could not stop.
A playful wind stops at will.
You shouldn't have come back.
I came back...
for you.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music]
[Daggers whooshing]
[Soldiers exclaiming in pain]
Nia!
Mei, you're back.
Who will believe
the madam of Peony Pavilion...
is the leader of the Flying Daggers?
I behaved badly that day.
Please forgive me.
Did I look like a real madam?
Very much so.
What do you think of Mei?
What do you mean?
[Chuckling]
I mean her personality, of course.
She's passionate.
Go on.
She may be blind,
but she's very bright.
Hardly anyone can match her.
Not even I.
Do you care for her?
You are asking....
A man and a girl travelling all alone.
What else could I be talking about?
Mei is a rare beauty.
I care for her a lot.
Then I shall act as the matchmaker
for you two to marry.
Marriage is a big deal.
This is too sudden.
She's not a good match for you?
On the contrary.
Mei is from a respectable family.
I'm just a humble swordsman.
MADAM: Our old leader
loved his daughter dearly.
Now I've become the new leader.
MADAM: It's my duty
to find her a good husband.
I haven't been able to find anyone
within the Flying Daggers...
who would be a better choice
than you.
What do you say?
I accept your offer.
Our House is much obliged to you.
You've done us a great favour.
Please accept my gratitude.
With much pleasure.
[Jin grunting]
What is going on?
Where are our soldiers?
They were ambushed.
You were both plotting to catch me
by following Mei.
[Dramatic Oriental instrumental music]
You're not blind?
Are you the old leader's daughter?
He has a blind daughter.
She doesn't know martial arts,
so I pretended to be her.
MADAM: If you had known the truth...
would you have followed her here?
[Soft instrumental music]
It's all been an act.
Who are you really?
My name is Mei.
I'm just one of many girls in
the House of Flying Daggers.
That's enough. Take him out.
MADAM: You wait here.
MADAM: I want to finish him off myself.
Move.
MADAM: Stop.
MADAM: Do you have anything to say?
You're not Nia, the new leader.
[Madam scoffing]
You're right.
Of course I'm not Nia.
Nia wouldn't show herself so easily.
Who are you, then?
That is not important.
Nia sent me to finish this matter.
You've done a good job, Leo.
[Soft instrumental music]
We've never met before,
but I know you by reputation.
Three years ago...
our old leader planted you as a mole
within the government.
You've accomplished much
in that role.
I failed to protect him...
from being assassinated.
MADAM: Nia knew
that you were away on duty.
There was nothing you could do.
I'm grateful for her understanding.
MADAM: We need to win this battle
against the government troops.
You and Mei have successfully
set up a trap for the General.
Well done.
I'll report to Nia
and have you rewarded.
It's my duty.
Please tell Nia...
the General has led all his
best soldiers towards us.
Be careful.
Don't worry. Nia has a good plan.
There is one thing
I don't understand.
What's that?
Who sent Mei on this mission?
Nia did.
Has Nia ever considered my feelings?
What do you mean?
I haven't seen Mei for three years.
Now I have to watch her flirt
with another man.
It's not the first time...
Mei's been asked to use her beauty
to seduce a man.
MADAM: I've heard about
your feelings for her.
Do you still love her?
We're facing a battle...
that will decide
the fate of the Flying Daggers.
The troops are closing in.
This is not the time for love.
All right.
I will let you see Mei.
[Soft instrumental music continues]
[Dramatic Oriental instrumental music]
[Dramatic Oriental instrumental music
resumes]
You haven't changed.
I'm still Mei.
It's been three years.
Finally, we're alone together.
I know.
You saved me
during the battle with the soldiers.
Thank you.
You don't need to thank me.
I would do anything for you.
I know.
You've risked everything
going undercover...
to win honour...
and to impress me.
You're the only one...
who understands me.
I was all alone for three years.
You were in my mind
every single moment.
LEO: My love for you was all
I had to keep me going.
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music]
[Mei sobbing softly]
[Romantic Oriental instrumental music
continues]
Do you love him?
You knew the plan.
It was only an act
between you and him.
There is no future for you two.
Do you understand?
[Mei grunting in protest]
[Leo grunting angrily]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
LEO: Nia!
You can't force a woman
against her will.
Do not pull this dagger out.
I'm sending you back
to keep spying for us.
You will be more convincing
with a dagger in your back.
You must leave immediately.
LEO: Yes, ma'am.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music]
I have sacrificed three years
for you.
LEO: How could you love Jin
after just three days?
NIA: Mei, I also have a task for you.
Jin is of no use to us anymore.
Take him out and kill him.
Leo plays a crucial role for us.
We can't let Jin ruin our plan.
You must kill him...
to prevent any future trouble.
You know our rules.
MEI: Yes, ma'am.
[Solemn Oriental instrumental music
continues]
I left you...
in order to save your life.
But you still followed me.
Please don't blame me.
MEI: If your plan succeeded...
many in the Flying Daggers
would die.
You wouldn't let me go, either.
It would be me on my knees...
waiting to die.
You're right.
If I won...
I wouldn't let you go.
[Romantic instrumental music]
[Romantic instrumental music continues]
[Romantic instrumental music intensifies]
[Solemn instrumental music]
Go.
How will you explain this to Nia?
That's my business.
Why don't you come with me?
Deep in your heart,
you have a secret.
I guess...
there is a man
you find hard to leave behind.
Yes, a man who's saved my life
many times.
Was it he who helped us
in the last battle?
Yes.
Then he has saved my life, too.
Do you still love him?
[Solemn instrumental music continues]
When can we see each other again?
We cannot.
We belong to two opposing sides.
If we meet again...
one of us will have to die.
[Solemn instrumental music swells]
JIN: A decisive battle is imminent.
JIN: You and I are just pawns
on a chessboard.
Nobody cares if we live or die.
Let's go away together
and roam the world...
as free as the wind.
We'll wander around alone.
MEI: Come and go without a trace,
like a playful wind.
No, a carefree wind.
Just you and me.
Come with me, please.
[Melancholic Oriental instrumental music]
[Melancholic Oriental instrumental music
continues]
intensifies]
[Groans]
[Whimpering in pain]
Are you going with him?
[Sentimental instrumental music]
Why?
You're the love of my life.
You don't have to love me...
but you can never go with him.
Otherwise you'll die.
Mei...
you've forced me to kill you.
I knew...
you would do this.
You knew and you went anyway. Why?
Why did you go?
Why did you go? Why?
To be free...
Like the wind.
[Screaming hysterically]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
Mei.
JIN: Mei!
[Whispering] Turn....
What?
MEI: Turn....
Turn around?
MEI: Look behind you.
[Leo screaming]
You're a member of the Flying Daggers.
You're right.
You're the one who loves Mei?
Yes, I love her truly...
while you are only playing a game.
If you love her, why kill her?
It's all your fault.
My fault?
I warned you, but you wouldn't listen.
She has betrayed me because of you.
You must die.
Fine.
You kill Mei, you must die, too.
[Both screaming]
[Sombre music]
[Thunder rumbling]
[Jin and Leo grunting in the distance]
[Both screaming]
[Screaming hysterically]
[Sombre music continues]
[Sombre music intensifies]
[Both screaming]
[Groaning]
[Melancholic Oriental instrumental music]
Mei.
Let him go.
If you kill him...
I'll kill you with this dagger.
Mei! Don't pull the dagger out!
JIN: If you do, your blood will drain
and you will die.
You must not do it!
[Melancholic Oriental instrumental music
continues]
Mei...
I'm closer to him.
He will hit me first.
You cannot save me...
with your dagger.
[Melancholic Oriental instrumental music
continues]
[Groaning]
Mei!
[Sobbing]
You shouldn't have come back.
I came back...
for you, my love.
[Jin sobbing]
[Thunder rumbling]
[Wind howling]
JIN: [Singing] A rare beauty in the North
She's the finest lady on earth
A glance from her
the whole city goes down
A second glance
leaves the whole nation in ruins
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty like this
[Melancholic music]
[Melancholic music continues]