All right, come on back.
Come on back.
Okay, whoa.
Yeah, it's good.
-What do I owe you?
-Forty's fine.
Here you go. Appreciate it.
-No problem.
-Thank you.
What is this?
1958 Triumph TR3,
two-door coupe.
Four in the floor, twin carburetor...
...electric overdrive.
How does it run?
It don't. At least, not yet.
That's what this man is for.
Gonna fix it up for me.
Jay, I知 your tune-up man.
I don't restore classic cars.
No, Max, you've worked miracles.
I know you can do it.
And he says that every time
he wants something he can't have.
It's a good car.
Clean interior, good stereo.
Low mileage for an '88 Honda.
What about the back end here?
Has it ever been wrecked?
No, I don't think so.
I think that was repainted
from scratches in the bumper.
I see that done pretty often.
You said you like the way it drives.
Yeah.
Tell you what.
You want the car,
I値l give you a tune-up and oil change...
...and a free car wash from my porter
any time you want it.
-All right, I値l take it.
-That's my man.
We can do the paperwork...
...you can show it off to your girlfriend
inside half an hour.
I don't have a girlfriend.
-Bernie.
-Jay.
Finally got a buyer for that Accord.
Hey, congratulations.
Didn't think that would stay
as long as it did.
Bernie, this is Scott.
Scott, Bernie Meyers,
one of our sales associates.
-Well, that's a great car.
-Thanks.
If I could get you to have a seat...
...and I need to see
your driver's license.
If you'll fill this form out,
just sign there, fill that out...
-...initial there and there.
-Driver's license.
Thank you. I値l be right back
while you do that.
I don't mean to be rude,
but what is this?
Oh, that's a retail-installment
contract...
...which says what you purchased
the car for.
Also a warranty disclaimer
and mileage statement.
Most people don't ask, they just sign.
You're smart to check before you sign.
Thanks.
This is really the first big purchase
I've ever made.
It痴 a good one.
You'll love it
and your friends will love you in it.
There's your driver's license.
Thank you, Scott. Congratulations.
-Thanks.
-You're the owner of a beautiful car.
-Take that girl for a ride.
-I don't--
Oh, right, no girlfriend.
At least not yet.
But a handsome guy like you,
a hot car like this...
...it's not gonna be long.
I know that's what my woman
always wanted.
A 1988 wrecked Honda.
Jay just sold the Accord.
-The wrecked one?
-Yup.
-Just cleared three on it.
-He did not.
Yeah, he did.
No way.
How does he do that?
Man, you are the king of cheese.
What does that mean?
-You just made $3000 off that car?
-That's why the sign says...
...Jay Austin Motors,
not Vince Berkley Motors.
Man, I didn't think we'd make
a thousand off that Honda.
Tell him it was wrecked?
No.
Man, you are slicker than snot
on an ice rink.
You're jealous.
You wouldn't have cleared two.
You amaze me.
Remind me to tell my friends
to never buy a car from this place.
All right, shut up and go sell a car.
Hey, Judy. Hey, Todd.
How y'all doing?
Hey, Bernie, Vince.
We're doing good, how are you?
Jay Austin Motors.
-What are y'all up to today?
-We're just out running errands.
We thought we'd see
if Jay needed something.
Have y'all eaten yet?
I just ate and Bernie,
he's always eating.
-If you want us to pick up something--
-No, no, no. Don't do that.
Thanks for the offer,
but Jay's the one who hadn't eaten.
Actually, me and Vince
were about to go outside.
-Dad?
-No, you--
You just do what you did last time.
See you, Judy. See you, Todd.
It's good to see you, guys.
Have a good day.
I致e already spent too much.
-Jay, what do you want for lunch?
-I don't care, just grab something.
No, do not do that.
I知 not spending any more
than my average.
How about a burger?
I don't care.
All right.
No. Don't let them do that to you.
You tell them you've already
gotten permission.
Doesn't matter. Make up something.
If he gives you a hard time,
you tell him to call me.
He can't deny you access to the lot,
he did it last year.
It doesn't matter.
How many you bringing back?
What year?
Yeah.
It is in good condition?
Fine. Look, when you come, just don't
get pulled over this time, all right?
Yes.
Good. Bye.
Vince, you gotta go get them.
That's why Bernie outsells you
every month.
I知 just honing my craft.
I値l be the main man soon.
Not by just standing around.
I知 not just standing here.
I知 watching the customer.
That way, I learn how to make
my best approach.
Every move I make is calculated.
Well, don't calculate too much,
all right?
All right.
Here's your lunch, Dad.
-Did you get me a burger?
-We got you a chicken sandwich.
I thought you were getting a burger.
Just put it on the desk.
Tell your mom I値l be home at 5.
I thought you were
coming home at 5.
I guess I知 late.
Does it not bother you
that you don't keep your word?
Don't start, Judy.
Guess not.
Why aren't you helping
set the table?
She asked me to do my homework.
Do your homework later.
Help your mother.
But Jeff's coming over.
He's spending the night.
Did you sell any cars today?
One.
Which one?
Black '88 Honda.
-The one that was wrecked?
-Yup.
How much?
-Does it matter?
-I知 just asking.
You don't wanna tell me.
-Six.
-Six thousand?
-You said that car wasn't worth three.
-Why do you care?
-It was worth 6000 to the buyer.
-The buyer know it was wrecked?
I致e had my mind on work all day,
I don't wanna talk now.
-No, you didn't tell him, did you?
-Why are you interrogating me?
-I知 a used-car salesman. I sell cars.
-At dishonest prices.
That's enough.
Shouldn't bother you.
I make more when I sell more.
You benefit from it.
Are we going to church tomorrow?
Did we go last week?
No.
We'll go tomorrow.
-E-5,
-Nope,
-C-3.
-Don't miss it,
Got one.
It's crazy,
'99 Chevy Blazer, 11,995,
Look, your dad's on TV again.
Yeah, I致e seen it.
'99 Ford F-150 T-cab, 14,995,
'02 Avalanche C-7 1, 25,995,
We're out of our minds,
Pick wheels,
I'll give you a deal,
Jay Austin Motors,
Is it weird seeing him on TV?
Not anymore. It used to be cool.
-So do you wanna sell cars too?
-I don't know.
It seems like it's hard...
...and I don't really wanna be
like my dad.
Why not?
Well, sometimes he lies to people.
What do you mean?
Well, sometimes
he doesn't tell them...
...if something's wrong
with the car and stuff.
-Like if the engine doesn't work?
-No, the engine works.
But it might have been wrecked
or have bad parts.
-And he sells them anyway?
-Yeah.
But they're used cars.
I know, but he makes people
pay too much.
I wanna do something different.
Yeah, I guess I would too.
Good morning.
Jeff, tell your mom I値l pick you up
after soccer on Thursday, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
-Jay Austin, it's good to see you.
-Morning, Reverend, how are you?
-Well. Judy, it's good to see you too.
-You too.
Todd, you're growing up.
Gonna be as tall as your dad.
-It痴 good to have all of you here.
-Thank you.
Jay, I知 getting ready to try to look
for a car for my daughter.
She's going to college.
Wonder if I could come by.
I got some sharp cars now.
Come any time you want.
-Thank you.
-Glad to.
Thank you.
Praise him, praise him
Jesus our blessed redeemer
-Todd, have you got your Bible?
-Yes, ma'am.
-What are we doing for lunch?
-Pizza at home...
...or we can grab something
on the way.
I'd rather do something else.
I wanna come back tonight
for the evening service.
I知 not coming back,
I致e got things to do.
On a Sunday? Jay.
I致e already tithed my time
to church this week.
Dad, what's a tithe?
It痴 when you give money
to help the church.
Or in our case, an empty envelope so
people think we give money to help.
Is that supposed to be funny?
You know,
I致e never thought it was funny.
We've given money before.
Oh, then I guess we're okay.
Your dad called tonight.
What did he say?
He wanted to know how we were.
What did you tell him?
I didn't know what to tell him,
to be honest, Jay.
Why didn't you just tell him
we're fine?
Are we?
Jay, your dad cares about you
very much.
He's never wanted anything
but the best for you.
You just need to talk to him.
My dad is still disappointed in me...
...and has been
since I was 18 years old.
That's because you were stubborn,
rebellious and never listened to him.
If he gave me the encouragement he
gives Joey, things would be different.
But your brother honored your father.
He at least showed him
enough respect to listen to him.
Okay, we're gonna talk about
something else.
Okay. When's the last time
you did something with Todd?
What do you mean?
Spending quality father-son time
with him.
I spend time with him.
I知 not talking about
when you're at the table.
I知 talking about investing time
with him, doing something worthwhile.
-Okay, why do you do that?
-Why do I do what?
Put me down
and try to embarrass me?
-I知 just asking a question.
-Well, I have a question.
You enjoy trying to embarrass me.
Is that a question or a statement?
It痴 a-- It痴--
Do you enjoy trying to embarrass me?
-See, that was a question.
-Okay, just forget it.
-No, I値l answer the question.
-I don't want you to answer.
-Then how about the statement?
-Forget it, Judy.
I知 just saying
you should make time for your son.
He looks up to you.
No, he doesn't.
Why would you say that?
-He said he doesn't.
-When?
Don't worry about it.
-Jay.
-What?
You're acting like you don't even care
about your own son.
He told Jeff that he did not want
to be like me...
...he did not wanna sell cars
and he did not think I was truthful.
Should he think you're truthful?
I知 not answering that question.
-Morning, Max.
-Jay.
You seen Bernie and Vince?
They went to test drive the Miata,
they'll be back in a few minutes.
Still working on this thing, huh?
You gave me quite a challenge
on this one.
Well, I知 wondering
if I made a mistake.
It just looked so good.
Price was right.
I was just hoping
we could get it going.
Give me a little longer.
Let me see what I can find.
We may have it running yet.
All right.
Just-- Move.
Man, I知 gonna
have to pry them out.
I got it.
You look like two marshmallows
trying to get out of a Hot Wheel.
That's not funny, Sam.
Yes, it is too.
Well, the good reverend
came after all.
-Jay, how's the car business today?
-We're making ends meet.
It痴 good to see you.
Tell me what I can do for you.
I知 looking for a car for my daughter.
She's our last one.
I wish she were here, but she's
out shopping with her mother.
I知 trying to find a good buy for her.
Well, let me commit
to giving you a good deal.
Hey, Bowers is having another sale.
So?
So I知 just saying.
Give me that last chip.
You fat, lazy, last-chip-eating punk.
Oh, like I gotta get on the ball.
You need to get on a treadmill.
What?
Hey, who's this guy?
I致e seen him before.
He's a minister, isn't he?
Oh, that's right.
He did Keith and Cindy's wedding.
Hey.
That would be my bag.
No, that's your bag.
Jay will probably give him a deal.
Twenty bucks says he doesn't.
You really think he's gonna stiff
a minister?
Twenty bucks says he will.
You're on.
-These are pretty cars right here.
-You got a lot of nice cars today.
Jay, tell me about this Camry.
Camrys are good cars,
one of the most reliable on the road.
Lindsay has a friend that has one.
I know she's even driven it.
-Maybe we ought to take a look at it.
-It痴 open, let's look at it.
They're looking at the Camry.
I say he sells it to him.
Hey, what we get it for?
Sixty-five hundred.
It痴 got 89,000 miles on it.
He'll sell it for eight.
Seven.
I致e always liked the storage space,
dual airbags.
It痴 done real well in safety tests.
I know it's a really good car.
I知 just wondering if I should try
to find one with lower miles.
Camrys do real well.
Their early-'90 models
were doing a quarter million.
-Is that right?
-Yeah. Great retail value too.
I致e got $8500 in this car.
If you want it,
I値l give it to you for nine.
Would you let me take it out
for a drive?
Reverend, you can drive it all day
if you want to.
He's taking it for a drive.
This is where Jay
gets the papers ready.
Give me the forms
for the gold Camry.
Is he buying it?
He might.
You think he will.
I do.
How do you know?
I sell cars for a living.
At what price?
We'll see.
Reverend, you bought a good car.
Thank you, I知 sure I did.
I know Lindsay will enjoy driving it.
I know she will.
I appreciate you coming to see me.
-Thank you.
-Let me walk out with you.
Thank you.
-Gentlemen.
-Good Reverend.
Good night.
-No way.
-Pay up, baby, I won.
You didn't say nine. You said eight.
-Closer than you were.
-We didn't say whoever's closest.
-You said he'd sell it for eight.
-I said he would stiff him, he did.
I知 not paying you a dime.
Well, then you're buying
me lunch tomorrow.
I知 not buying lunch either.
We both lost.
Well, I appreciate
all your help today.
I知 gonna go pick up Lindsay now,
she's gonna be excited to see this.
-She'll drop me off and I値l get my car.
-That's fine. Fine.
Jay, I thank you so much,
you've treated me so well today.
-I would like to do something for you.
-What's that?
I壇 like to pray and ask God
to bless you in your business.
-I壇 appreciate that.
-Let's pray.
Lord, today I come before you
and thank you for this day.
I thank you for Jay
and his business.
I thank you for this car for Lindsay
and I ask that you'll protect her...
...and give her grace
as she drives this car...
...and traveling mercies.
And, Lord, I ask that you treat Jay...
...just like he treated me today
in this deal.
-It痴 in your name I pray, Lord. Amen.
-Amen.
Thank you, Jay, for your help.
Appreciate it, Reverend.
Glad you came by.
Take care.
Maximus.
Bernie.
Max the Marvelous.
The Magnificent.
Max-a-roni.
You get it? Max-a-roni.
That was stupid.
What?
Now, there's the man.
Why are you always eating?
When was the last time you sold?
I sold two last week.
I got a guy coming in today
on the Jeep.
Looking or buying?
He might buy.
I didn't think you had it in you, Jay.
-What's that?
-The ability to stiff a minister.
You think I知 interested in making
the least amount of money we can?
Hey, I知 for making money.
I just thought you'd cut a deal.
-And you would have?
-I壇 try to.
Bull.
Would you trust Bernie
to sell a car to your mother?
-To my mother?
-To your mother.
-No way.
-Oh, come on.
What's worse, overcharging
the reverend for a Camry, a good car...
...or squeezing that old lady
for the Marquis?
She wasn't that old.
-She was in her 70s.
-Late 50s.
Oh, please.
Maybe early 60s.
Don't wag your tongue
over the Camry.
You've ripped off more naive ladies
than anyone in Albany.
And stop judging me for something
you do yourself.
That old lady is probably
an honorable woman.
Husband probably served
in the military.
Or the ministry.
Jay Austin Motors.
This is Jay.
Mr. Austin, this is George MacDonald
from Franklin Bank and Trust.
I need to talk to you. Got a minute?
Yes, sir, what can I do for you?
I知 showing you're a month behind
on your payment for your lot...
...as well as your credit line.
And if I remember correctly, this is not
the first time this has happened.
Sir, we've had a pretty slow month.
Had extra expenses
we don't normally.
But I think we'll back
in a week or two.
I hope so.
It痴 not my intention to be cruel...
...but if you don't catch up
by the end of next month...
...we'll come get your cars
and close you down.
I understand, sir.
We're looking at a payment
of $32,400.
Yes, sir.
Thank you for your call.
Have a good day.
Todd, come to the table, please.
What is he doing?
He's building a volcano.
-A what?
-It痴 for his science project.
-He has to build--
-Todd, come to the table.
Jay, he's coming.
He's probably washing his hands.
We've got glue and paint
all over the place.
Glue and paint?
Yeah, you know,
you add baking soda...
...pour a little vinegar,
you get an eruption.
-You're not getting any on the carpet?
-No, sir.
Jay, we've got newspapers
and towels down.
He's being very careful.
We just finished paying for that carpet.
I wanna keep it clean.
Jay, will you stop worrying about
your precious carpet?
-Nothing's going to happen.
-What's with the attitude?
-I don't have attitude.
-You do have an attitude.
Should I not be concerned
about a $4000 investment?
Jay, just say the blessing.
Why don't you say the blessing?
Okay.
Dear God, thank you for this food,
your blessings...
...and the carpet
we're allowed to walk on.
May it serve us years to come
and be a beacon of hope...
...to all those who live in the house
after we're gone.
Amen.
That was lame.
You're welcome to pray any time
you like.
Thank you for reminding me.
Dad, would you help me
with my project?
I知 getting tired of this
holier-than-thou attitude.
Mom, can I have cereal instead?
Cereal?
Todd, honey,
I thought you liked pizza.
You want cereal over pizza?
Yes, sir.
I don't care.
Okay.
Did Reverend Michaels come by
to see you today?
He did.
And?
-And he bought a car.
-He did?
He did.
And you gave him a good deal,
right?
It痴 a good deal.
A good deal for him?
I see it's time
for my nightly interrogation.
Come on, you've never kept
this stuff from me before.
What did you charge him?
Nine thousand dollars.
And what did you get it for?
Sixty-five hundred.
-That doesn't sound like a deal.
-It was a deal for me.
Oh, great.
So now you're ripping off ministers.
I want you to shut up now.
The next time, you only open it to eat.
Do you understand me?
The best for your baby--
Listen, folks, Listen,
You're in the shape you're in today
because of the choices you've made,
Your marriage
is in the shape it is in today,,,
,,,because of the choices
you've made,
Your relationship with your wife
and with your children,,,
,,,is in the shape it's in
because of the choices you've made,
You're in financial bondage today
God's word would set you free
if you would read it,,,
,,,but you're in bondage
and you're trapped,,,
,,,and you're under all the dirt
and the stuff,,,
,,,and you feel like you're a slave
to your debt and to a relationship,,,
,,,because you've not listened
to the word of God,
And until you listen
to the word of God,,,
,,,you will make
the wrong choices,,,
,,,go down the wrong road,
lose your family, lose your home,,,
,,,lose your security,
your investments,,,
,,,because God has a way
to live life,
And you and I cannot live life on
our terms and ask God to bless that,
And the reason that many people
that I'm talking to today,,,
,,,are in bondage
and in frustration and in defeat,,,
,,,is because you don't really
wanna know what God says,
And you don't wanna live it
God's way,
If any man is in Christ,
he is a new creation,
All things have passed away,
All things, not some things,
All things have become new,
When these came out,
no one could keep them.
I知 just telling you
they're great cars.
Well, you know that
or you wouldn't be interested in it.
Oh, I just love them.
They're so cute.
When we graduated two years ago,
my friend got one and she loves it.
I致e been amazed it has stayed
out here as long as it has.
Someone's gonna realize
what we've got...
-...and take it out of here.
-Really?
If I were able to get it,
you wouldn't have had a shot.
You're getting a corner
on an amazing vehicle.
I壇 like to get it, I just don't know
about the monthly payments.
You tell me you want this car...
...I will bend over to make it happen.
Oh, you're so sweet.
Hey, I just wanna see you get
the best car you can.
If I told you I could get the payments
under 250 a month...
-...would you be able to do that?
-Oh, well, actually...
...I was thinking
more like 150 a month.
I know it seems a lot, but I don't wanna
see you miss out on a deal like this.
It痴 rare to find one
in this good of condition.
I don't know.
Hey, let me see if I can get it
under 230 a month...
...throw in a free detail, fill it up.
We could be done the paperwork...
...and you can be showing it off
to your boyfriend inside half an hour.
Okay. I mean, I guess I should take
advantage of this great sale.
Hey, that's right.
You've made a good decision.
I would have hated to see you
walk away from such a good deal.
I can't believe you sold her that car.
She told me she was just looking.
You're too nice to them, Vince.
I知 too nice?
Yeah, you gotta be
more aggressive.
Flatter the snot out of them
and just reel them in.
Hey, what did you clear?
-You wouldn't believe me.
-Bernie.
Five.
No, you didn't.
Bernie, tell me you didn't do that.
You made $5000 off that car?
I did. I知 bringing it in today, baby.
It痴 time for you to treat me
to a round of golf.
You need to start selling some cars
like a big dog and buy your own round.
What's different about
that wall up there?
There was a clock there
or something.
Hey, Jay, did you take anything
off that wall?
You shouldn't have done that,
Bernie.
Shouldn't have done what?
Someone's gonna figure out
she got overcharged $4000...
-...and make an issue out of it.
-What?
Would you not kick the guy in the teeth
that overcharged your wife on a car?
-She's not married.
-That's not the point.
She's got a boyfriend, parents
or friends...
...that are gonna figure out
she got sloshed.
Who you talking to? I just made a
profit and I知 getting slammed for it?
Bernie, it's not the profit,
it's the way you got it.
Since when did you become
a Boy Scout?
You don't think you did
anything wrong?
When Jay Austin pulls in a few
thousand, it's good business...
...but when Bernie Meyers does it,
it's ripping people off?
You grossly manipulated her.
s
You taught me how.
I don't know what game this is,
but you've got different rules.
All right, that's it.
We're not gonna talk about this now.
What the heck was that?
I don't know.
No, I知 not doing this.
If he starts unloading trash on me,
I知 out of here.
He's no saint.
You look like you just got out of a fight
where everybody had a stick but you.
-How's it going, Max?
-I don't know yet.
I keep thinking I got it figured out...
...but I keep being wrong.
That's true for both of us.
You got something
you can't fix either?
Several things.
At least I think I know how to fix them,
but I keep being wrong.
We both sound pretty pathetic.
Is that worth the time
you're putting in?
Well, I think the flywheel
may be stripped.
Don't tell me you don't know
what a flywheel is.
I don't.
How long you been selling cars?
Tell me what a flywheel is.
When you put the key in the ignition,
that sends power to the starter.
The starter engages your flywheel,
your flywheel turns your crankshaft...
...and your crankshaft starts
your engine.
Without your flywheel,
you're not going anywhere.
So can we get a new one?
Well, we may need to.
I hoped it was
something easier to get to.
Flywheel is sandwiched in between
the engine and the transmission.
I値l have to drop the transmission
to get to it.
Well, if there's anybody that can do it,
it's you, Max.
Then at least one of us
will have our problems fixed.
You seem to be carrying
a heavy load lately.
You okay?
Not really, to be honest.
I cannot remember the last time
I felt like my life was going right.
So I should pray for you.
Maybe you should pray for you.
I don't know about that.
Why not?
I don't think God will listen
right now.
What do you mean?
I mean, he knows
I知 not an honest man.
He knows I知 a lousy husband
and father.
He knows how selfish
and prideful I am.
I don't even like myself, Max.
I致e got friction with almost
every person in my life.
I owe money to the bank
that I don't have.
I知 an old man, Jay.
There's some things I wish
I壇 have gotten right decades ago.
But my pride got in the way.
But when I learned
to let the Lord run my life...
...my life got a whole lot better.
I don't mean to preach at you...
...but I just know I needed him.
Frankly, I壇 say
that we all need him.
You know, this is a beautiful car.
Still got a good engine.
But until we get that piece
that fixes the engine...
...it's not going anywhere.
O Lord...
...I don't want your face
against me.
I need you.
I知 sorry.
Help me, Lord.
Help me get back in your will.
I want to be a good man.
Help me, Jesus.
You're in charge now.
You're the boss.
I didn't expect to see you home
so early.
Can we talk?
Sure.
Would you come sit with me?
I know I hurt you terribly last night.
I was wrong to do that and I'm sorry.
You're apologizing to me?
I am.
Is something wrong with you?
There is.
Jay, are you--? Are you dying?
No. No.
What's wrong with me is that
I have been living for myself.
I have not been the husband
I need to be.
I have not been the father
I need to be...
...the spiritual leader I need to be.
Today, I asked God to forgive me.
I have gotten myself in a mess
in almost every area of my life...
...and I can't fix it.
I admit that I have not been worthy
of honor...
...or respect,
or the love of my family.
But I want to be.
Jay....
Judy, I知 asking you to pray for me.
I need you.
I need you terribly.
I am resolving to let Jesus be
lord of my life.
Every day.
-You're serious.
-I am serious.
I will be honest in my business.
I will take responsibility
as the spiritual leader of my home.
I will love you, I will love Todd,
and I will love our baby.
So help me God, I will.
''Blessed is the man who does not
walk in the counsel of the wicked,,,
,,,or stand in the way of sinners
or sit in the seat of mockers,
But his delight
is in the law of the Lord,
And on his law,
he meditates day and night,
He is like a tree planted
by streams of water,,,
,,,which yields its fruit in season
and whose leaf does not wither,
Whatever he does prospers,
Not so the wicked,
They are like chaff
that the wind blows away,
Therefore, the wicked will not stand
in the judgment,,,
,,,nor sinners in the assembly
of the righteous,
For the Lord watches
over the way of the righteous,,,
,,,but the way of the wicked
will perish, ''
All right, Lord,,,
,,,this is your lot,
I will honor you with it,
Max. I知 a little low
on transmission fluid.
How about hooking me up, man?
Where were you?
What are you talking about?
You said the Corner Cafe at 9:00.
No, I said be at the Biscuit Barn at 9.
-The Biscuit Barn?
-Yeah.
So where are the biscuits?
I didn't feel like a biscuit,
so I went to Pearly's.
What did you get at Pearly's?
A biscuit.
You're a goober.
I know.
But at least I got a biscuit.
But I was there at 9 and you weren't.
I was at the Corner Cafe at 9.
And you better be there tomorrow at 9.
How about being at work
at 9 tomorrow?
Jay's cracking the whip again.
We better stop being lazy.
-You admitting that you're lazy?
-Well, no.
I know it may look like it sometimes,
but I like to think of myself...
...as a hardworking man
trapped in a lazy man's body.
I致e always thought of myself
as tan body builder...
...trapped in a chubby man's body.
Sam, anything we should know?
I知 just a black man
in a black man's body...
...working with a bunch
of strange white boys.
Would you mind getting Max?
I壇 like for us to have a talk.
Sure.
-With all of us?
-Yep.
What is this about?
Are we in trouble?
-I値l tell you when Max gets here.
-I知 planning to be here at 9 tomorrow.
I could get a biscuit earlier.
-Or I don't have to get a biscuit at all.
-It痴 not about the biscuits, Vince.
If this is about Bernie scraping
the side of the Tahoe...
...that was an accident. I was there.
-He was only trying to park it--
-Vince, shut up.
-You gonna tell me about that?
-Of course I was.
Morning, Max.
Thanks for coming in,
this shouldn't take but a minute.
I壇 like to start by apologizing
to each of you.
Apologizing? For what?
This is my business.
For two years, I have not been
running it honestly or respectfully.
I wanna say I'm sorry
to each of you...
...for being a bad example.
You've got to be kidding me.
I壇 also like to say that from now on,
we'll be selling cars at honest prices.
What does that mean?
It means you get a fair commission
off a fair sale.
Well, who determines
what fair means?
Well, if you bought the car that you're
trying to sell from another salesman...
...what would you feel okay
with him making?
That stinks.
What are you doing, Jay?
I知 changing the way we operate.
-By stripping our commissions away?
-Not necessarily.
So we're supposed to accept
your apology...
...while cutting our salaries in half?
Work hard, you can make
the same you're making now...
-...and with a clear conscience.
-Who cares?
I have to make a living for my family
and you're taking food off my table.
I知 not out to hurt your family.
But I have every intention of running
an honest business from now on.
Jay, I sell cars for you,
I organize all your promotions.
I make you look good
in this community.
The last thing you should be doing
is cutting my salary.
I can make twice this right down
the road at any of your competitors.
-I don't disagree.
-Why are you shooting us in the foot?
Don't change anything.
We're doing fine.
I want a clean conscience
before God.
Oh, come on. This isn't a church.
Bernie, I don't think this
is a bad move.
Of course you don't.
You two aren't salesmen.
Your income stays the same.
Yours could too, Bernie.
Only if I work my tail off.
So we're changing prices
on the cars?
We'll be doing that today.
No. I don't like this.
Either you're gonna keep the same
commission on every car we sell...
...or you're gonna raise our salaries
to make up the difference.
No.
Well, you just got one
less salesman.
-You're quitting?
-I知 quitting.
I知 not playing this game anymore.
If you're smart, you'll quit too.
-You don't have to leave, Vince.
-Vince, don't be a fool.
You will never make a living here.
He's gonna make it impossible.
You could still be successful here.
You've got opportunity
when Bernie walks.
Why waste time? We can make twice
what we're making here at Bowers.
Vince, you can stay.
Come on, Vince.
Vince.
I知 sorry, Jay.
I can't do this.
You've wasted two years
of my life, Jay.
Sam?
I told you those were strange
white boys.
I値l tell you, Vince, Bowers is hiring.
I知 about to ride down there right now
and you better go with me.
-You think we did the right thing?
-Yeah, we did the right thing.
Unless you wanna stay here
and work harder for less money.
This ship is sinking, man.
Hey, did you hook me up?
Yeah, I hooked you up.
Where did you go?
Come to the window
if you wanna see the big show.
What?
What did you do?
-I left Bernie with a little parting gift.
-What's that?
I hooked his brake pedal
to his horn.
No, you didn't.
You guys are something else.
That's not funny, Max.
Sam, I need your help.
I知 gonna make you a car salesman.
I知 not a car salesman.
I値l give you a raise.
Then again,
I might be a pretty good car salesman.
I知 not kidding.
Both of them quit and walked out.
So, what are you gonna do?
Sell cars by myself.
Sam will be able to help some.
-Are you nervous about all this?
-Yes.
But if I go under,
it's because God allowed it.
I told him it was his lot now.
Then don't worry about it.
I知 trying not to.
I need to stay until 7 today.
I gotta do some of Bernie's work.
Okay. I値l see you tonight.
I love you. Bye.
Hello, Papa? It痴 Judy.
Do you have a minute?
-That's a flywheel for a TR3?
-Yep. That's the real thing.
-Same model?
-Same model.
Where did you get it?
A friend of mine had it in his shop.
No charge.
All I had to do was ask.
Dad?
Hello, Jay.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to talk to you,
if you have a minute.
You drove down from Atlanta
to talk to me?
I did.
-You wanna sit down?
-Yes, thank you.
Is Mom okay?
She's fine, son.
I wanted to come down
to see you today.
I got a call from Judy this morning.
She told me about
some decisions you've made.
She said you've made
quite a change in direction.
And you've even decided
to make Jesus lord of your life.
Yes, sir.
Jay, did you really mean that?
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
I have to admit I was thrilled
when I got that call.
Your mom and I have prayed
about this for a long time.
Dad...
...I know I've been difficult...
...and I know I have been stubborn.
You have been a good father to me.
I知 sorry I was that difficult.
Jay, I didn't come for an apology.
I came to encourage you...
...and to tell you
how proud I am of you.
Lord, I thank you for my son, Jay...
...and I thank you
that he's turned his heart to you.
Thank you for receiving him
and cleansing him...
...and directing his path.
I praise you, Lord,
for what you've done in him.
Now, Lord, in your name,
I bless him with courage...
...with faith and with integrity.
Lord, I call him a man of strength,
of love and grace.
I ask as his earthly father...
...that you would rain down favor
on him.
That he would know
that he is loved and treasured.
That you would bless
whatever he touches.
This is my son, Lord,
and I give him back to you.
Lord, I love him.
Keep him and bless him.
in Jesus' name. Amen.
I love you, son.
What are you reading?
A book on Vesuvius.
Vesuvius? What's that?
It痴 a volcano
that destroyed a whole village in ltaly.
I didn't know you were interested
in that. Why are you reading that?
It痴 for my science project.
When did you do this?
I致e been working on it for a few days.
Mom helped me.
It痴 incredible.
Todd...
...I don't think that
I have been a very good dad to you.
And...
...well, I wanna be.
So I have asked God
to help me do better.
And if it's okay with you...
...I壇 like to hang out with you
a little bit more.
Okay.
I知 impressed with your volcano.
Good night, buddy.
I am really out of touch with my son.
That can change.
It will change.
Will you be able to handle the lot
without more help?
I can't afford more help.
I致e already given Sam a small raise
to help me sell.
Unless there's some
hardworking guy out there...
...who'll wanna work for peanuts,
we're on our own.
Why don't you ask God
for someone like that?
Well, I can...
...but who would do that?
-Good morning.
-Hi, I知 looking for Jay Austin.
-You found him.
-Oh, hi, I知 Kevin Cantrell.
Hello, Kevin Cantrell.
What can I do for you?
Well, you can give me a job
if you have an opening.
-Looking for a job?
-If you're hiring.
Why don't you have a seat?
I知 between semesters
and I got about six weeks.
I致e always wanted
to see how I壇 do at sales.
-You're looking for a job for six weeks?
-Right.
Kevin, I could use some help
around here...
...but I need it
for more than six weeks.
I understand,
but I知 a really fast learner...
...and I wanna have my own lot one
day, so I壇 work really hard for you.
-But six weeks.
-You could pay me minimum wage.
Come on. I wanna sell a car so badly,
I can taste it.
-Minimum wage?
-That's right.
Here's my resume and references.
I知 available
any time you can schedule me.
-Six weeks.
-Minimum wage.
Come on.
That's good. All right, we're gonna
do the same thing with the Taurus.
-We're gonna put it right here.
-Okay.
I値l be right back.
So how long you been here?
-I致e been here about two years.
-You like it here?
I do.
Albany's a good-sized city
that still has the feel of a small town.
I like the pace.
Just wish I could sell more cars.
Speaking of selling cars,
I wanted to ask you.
You don't seem to be getting
as much as you could.
If I sold one for a little more,
could I keep the rest as commission?
Kevin, we're not gonna go that route.
We're gonna charge what
we'd feel good about being charged.
I知 gonna stick
to the fair market value.
You can get away
with pushing a little bit.
I mean, don't you need money?
I do, but I've gotta live
with how I run this place.
I just don't want any more regrets.
I知 sticking
to the highest standard I can.
You treat people right,
it'll come back to you.
You're dying to drive that car,
aren't you?
I am.
Why don't you take off?
I can lock up.
You remember
how to do the paperwork?
I sold the Bronco yesterday
and I didn't have a problem.
Okay, but if you have any questions,
you ask Sam, all right?
I値l be fine.
Just lock both doors
and don't forget the alarm.
Check out this '02 Yukon
for just 25,995.
It痴 phenomenal.
Or this '99 Mustang GT,
sliced down to 10,950.
How about this '02 F-250 diesel
for just 28,995?
And if you act now, we'll throw in a
free chassis-treatment undercoating...
...guaranteed not to rot, rust, bump...
...chip, pop, stain, crack or peel,
unless it comes in contact with water.
That's a Butch Bowers
factory guarantee,
You won't find a better deal,
I'm Butch Bowers,
and you can bet on it,
Well, I致e said so long
to Max and Sam.
Well, Kevin, I hate to lose you.
Well, I知 just sorry
I couldn't sell more cars for you.
I didn't sell many either.
But you kept your word.
-Worked hard for me. I appreciate it.
-Well, thanks for the opportunity.
You know, I have to admit,
working here has been a little bit...
...different than what I expected.
-Well, what'd you expect?
-I don't know.
I guess I halfway expected
you'd be a little bit more strategic...
...with the way you sell cars.
-Strategic?
-Okay, devious.
I understand.
Well, you're not a bad guy
and I知 glad I met you.
Well, I知 grateful for your approval.
-Drop us a line sometime.
-I will.
Take care of yourself.
Jay Austin Motors.
Hello, Mr. MacDonald, how are you?
Yes. I realize that.
That'd be fine.
You can come
whenever it's convenient.
Very good.
Twelve thousand dollars
is a good start, Mr. Austin.
That's about a third of what you owe.
You're behind with your floor plan,
your mortgage...
...your checking account's overdrawn
and your insurance is fixing to lapse.
Well, we didn't sell cars
like we normally do this time of year.
That's why I知 behind.
I don't suppose I can
talk you into a few more weeks?
Mr. Austin, the bank's been gracious
in giving you some extra time.
But unless
you have the money by Friday...
...I値l have to come get your cars.
I understand.
I知 sorry it's come to this.
I wish you luck.
And I appreciate you
meeting with me today.
So, what's the plan?
Max, I never thought
I壇 be saying this.
We might not have a lot next week.
We'd have to sell almost every car on
the lot to pay all our debts and bills.
I知 not sure what I知 gonna do.
Well, I知 going fishing.
Well, I gave this lot to the Lord.
I guess he can do
whatever he wants to with it.
Don't you quit yet.
Let's see what the Lord does.
I wish I had more faith.
''Trust in the Lord
with all your heart...
...and lean not
on your own understanding.
in all your ways, acknowledge him
and he will make your paths straight.''
See? It says to trust in the Lord
with all your heart.
That's not the part
that hits me so hard.
It痴 the ''lean not
on your own understanding'' part.
You're not thinking about getting
another emergency loan, are you?
No.
It痴 crossed my mind,
but I know that's not the answer.
It痴 his lot, Jay.
It痴 his lot.
I知 tired of worrying about money,
anyway.
That's because
it's always been our money.
What, instead of God's money
that he allows us to use?
Now, there's a thought.
That's the right mindset.
It just feels so backwards
to think that way.
Or maybe it's the normal way...
...and we've just been
doing it backwards this whole time.
I致e been going backwards so long,
it's a rush to go forwards.
This is from Psalms 3 7.
''Delight yourself in the Lord...
...and he will give you
the desires of your heart.
Commit your way to the Lord,
trust in him, and he will do this.
He will make your righteousness
shine like the dawn...
...the justice of your cause
like the noonday sun.
Be still before the Lord
and wait patiently for him.''
The desire of my heart
would be to finish well.
If I have to change jobs, I壇 wanna
do it in a more honorable way.
instead of getting kicked out
because I couldn't pay my debts.
All you have to do is be still.
My car has rockets
coming out the back.
Oh, yeah?
Well, my car's got a missile on the top.
Yeah, so? Mine goes faster.
Let me see that.
Hey, that's not bad.
-Where'd you learn to draw?
-I don't know.
That's pretty good.
I知 gonna have to put that on the wall
when you're done.
You stay right here, okay?
Hey, Mary, how are you?
-Fine.
-All right, Mary.
I知 not here to make a payment.
I知--
I知 here to give the car back.
Can you tell me what's going on?
I知 so far behind on payments.
-I can't get caught up.
-Mary, you only owe $1265.
I know.
I just can't afford it...
...because my husband's been out
of work for a couple of months, and--
It just seems like every week,
there's a new bill.
One on top of another,
and we just can't get caught up.
My son, he's sick...
...and we're going back and forth
to the doctor in Atlanta...
...and I don't know what else to do.
I don't know what we're gonna do.
The car's been great.
I just--
I don't know what to say,
I知 so sorry.
I mean, I just feel like I'm making
the right decision here. I really--
Mary...
...I believe you.
I know you're behind...
...but you have been
one of my best customers.
And I just pray that God helps you
through what you're going through.
The title?
The car is yours.
You're paid in full.
Excuse me.
Your daddy's a really good man.
Hey, honey.
If we took credit card offers
and put them end to end...
...they'd go to the moon and back.
Or you could take the cards
and buy me the moon.
Would you want it?
Well, I don't know where I'd put it.
Probably just have to leave it
where it's at.
Yeah, and we'd never pay it off.
-Yeah.
Hello?
Yes.
No, actually we don't need
another credit card.
Yes.
Oh, it's a mind-blowing rate.
Unbelievable.
I知 still not gonna take it.
Thank you.
We don't need any more calls
tonight.
So tomorrow's the day.
It is.
How you doing?
I知 not sure.
I致e got some anxiety.
But it's a peaceful sort of anxiety.
A peaceful anxiety?
Can you have peaceful anxiety?
Well....
What do you call it when you feel like
your life's turning upside down...
...but you still think God's in control?
It痴 like a....
A serene chaos.
A serene--?
What's the difference between
peaceful anxiety and serene chaos?
Serene chaos is better.
Well, there you have it.
Look at the latest craze
in weight loss,
With a growing number of new
energy-giving weight-loss drugs,,,
,,,is the health risk going up
to trim down?
For those stories and more
on the NBS Nightly News Watch.
And now from our studios
in New York, here's Tom Jennings,
Good evening, Our top story tonight
is about the car business,,,
,,,or specifically,
the sale of used cars,
Each year in America, over
half a million cars are sold,
The number of used-car lots
in this country,,,
,,,has risen dramatically
over the last year,
But how much do we really know
about buying a used car?
Most Americans take for granted,,,
,,,that any markdown in price at all
is a deal,
And although there are many deals
to be found,,,
,,,experts say that most Americans
are unaware,,,
,,,of just how easy it is
to be deceived,
For the last six weeks,
NBS Nightly News has conducted,,,
,,,an undercover investigation
into the used-car business,
We have to begin with a warning,
you won't like what we found,
We decided to do an investigation
of six used-car lots,,,
,,,picked at random
across the United States,,,
,,,and we begin tonight by taking you
to a lot in North Arkansas,
Bud Morris Auto Sales has been
around for almost 30 years,,,
,,,with a seemingly solid reputation,
After an undercover reporter spoke
with a sales associate,,,
,,,behind the scenes,
what we found was a different story,
I mean, how do you do it?
Is 8000 the most
you've ever cleared?
No, Bud got this lady
to pay 16,000,,,
,,,for a Cadillac
that we'd just got for five,
Sixteen?
Oh, yeah, we made 11,000
off of her,
She left here
thinking she got a great deal,
Does that happen very often?
We just end up making
about two or three grand,,,
,,,more than we ought to,
On every car?
You can tell pretty quick
who's done their homework,
And if they don't know how much
a car should cost, we'll get them,
And get them, they did,
After obtaining information
on a dozen cars,,,
,,,sold to unsuspecting customers,,,
...NBS Nightly News found that
on average...
,,,each car is sold for $3500
above the acceptable range,
Next, we go to the state of Utah,,,
,,,where we had an undercover
reporter pose as a customer,,,
,,,with seemingly no idea,,,
,,,as to what her car of choice
would cost,
Experts say
this 1988 Chevrolet Blazer,,,
,,,should run
between $1200 and $1500,
But listen to what the salesman tries
to sell it for,
This is a very, very popular car,
Great riding,
You drive it,
I promise, it's a great ride,
Great stereo system,
It will hold its value,
It's American made,
We've got 7 000 on this one,
but I can give it to you for about six,
Six thousand dollars,
Even in great condition,
our experts say, ''That's a rip-off, ''
As a matter of fact,
of the six lots we investigated,,,
,,,only one proved to deal honestly
all the time,
We now take you to South Georgia,
to the city of Albany,
Our undercover reporter
actually was hired and trained,,,
,,,to sell cars at Jay Austin Motors,,,
,,,a small car lot
with at most 35 cars,
Except this time,,,
,,,what he found
was a different story,
Speaking of cars,
I wanted to ask you,
You don't seem to be getting
all that you could out of these,
If I sold one for a little more,,,
,,,do you think I could keep the rest
as commission?
Kevin, I don't wanna go
that route,
I'd rather charge what we'd feel good
about being charged,
I'm gonna stick
to fair market value,
But you'd get away
with pushing it a little bit,
Don't you need the money?
I do,
But I gotta live
with how I run this place,
I just don't want any regrets,
I'm gonna stick
to the highest standard I can,
If you treat people right,
it'll come back to you,
That's a good philosophy
and one that he apparently lives by,
In six weeks, the profit averaged out
at $1500 per car,,,
,,,an amount considered
completely acceptable,
In fact, Jay Austin Motors
even paid for repairs to cars,,,
,,,that had problems
soon after being sold,
A gesture not often seen
in the used-car business,
And whereas he may not be rolling
in the dough,,,
,,,his honesty comes
as a refreshing reminder,,,
,,,to treat others
as you want to be treated,
When we return, we'll--
''Delight yourself in the Lord and he
will give you the desires of your heart.
Commit your way to the Lord,
trust in him, and he will do this.
He will make your righteousness shine
like the dawn.
The justice of your cause
like the noonday sun.
Be still before the Lord
and wait patiently for him.''
I am so proud of you.
Did you hear me?
I just wanted to finish well.
You may not be finished yet.
I saw you on the news last night
and I was gonna buy a car.
-What about this Tracker over here?
-Excuse me.
You were not the first one here.
I致e been here since 7:30.
Okay.
Are you all here to buy cars?
-Yes.
-I am.
Okay.
Let me run in quick and open.
I need to make a call.
Would you mind staying
for a minute?
Yeah, I ain't buying a car
nowhere else.
Okay. Don't go anywhere.
-Hello?
-Judy. I need a favor.
I need you to get Max and Sam,
get them up here as fast as possible.
Well, what's going on?
I致e got 30 people outside waiting
to buy a car right now.
-Did you say 30?
-Thirty.
-Thirty?
Call them, get them up here
as soon as you can.
And I need your help, too, okay?
-What? I知 not a car salesman.
-Well, you are today.
I like this Oldsmobile.
How much for it?
About $7000.
You take 6500?
-All right.
-You will?
I guess so.
If that's what you wanna pay.
Hang on now.
How about 6000?
You done said 6500.
I know you got it,
or you wouldn't have offered it.
I値l get the paperwork.
Oh, man.
-Miles?
-One-twenty.
-Highway?
-Some.
-Wrecked?
-No.
-Smoker?
-Cruise?
-Yes.
-Price.
-Eight.
-Seven.
-Seven-five.
Done.
I like the way you deal.
Thirty-eight thousand,
four hundred and fifteen dollars.
And that's after covering the cost
of the cars.
-Mr. MacDonald?
-Yes.
-How are you doing?
-Hi, how are you?
I知 doing fine.
That's for you.
I think that should about
cover what we owe.
Where's the cars?
-Well, we sold them.
-What do you mean you sold them?
We had a real, real good day today.
Do you trust used-car salesmen?
They don't always have
great reputations,
But one here in Albany
is earning respect,
A national news organization,,,
,,,recently investigated
Jay Austin Motors,,,
,,,and found his prices and business
practices are always fair,
After an undercover investigation
that lasted six weeks--
There's a new record for cars sold
in one day here in Albany,
Jay Austin Motors sold 32 vehicles
inside of eight hours,
The rush to buy cars came
after a story ran,,,
,,,which highlighted the honest
business performed by Jay Austin,,,
,,,who says it was an answer
to prayer,
So, what did your dad say?
He said we shouldn't be surprised
when God is faithful.
He's right.
Hey, I tried taping
those news stories.
And I keep getting the last half
of each interview.
I致e got the last half of four stories.
Do you know anyone
who can copy these tapes...
...to give to your parents?
Just take it to the church.
Don't the church media guys...
...just sit around
and copy tapes anyway?
I don't know what they do.
This has been the craziest week
of my life.
Jay, I wanna ask you something.
God's blessed you...
...because of your faithfulness
and obedience in the last months...
...but what about all the customers
before that?
I know.
I致e been thinking about them.
I was reading about Zacchaeus
this morning.
He returned money to all those
people he took advantage of...
...when he did his tax collecting.
That's a painful thought.
I mean, not only would that take
a lot of money...
...I壇 have to eat more humble pie
than any man alive.
It痴 not about you
escaping discomfort, Jay.
It痴 about you honoring God
with what he's blessed you with.
That's two years of customers.
It痴 probably half of them I cheated.
Well, I知 done with the books.
Are you done with your project?
This will take a lot longer
than you think to pay these people.
-Why?
-We gotta have enough money...
...for the mortgage and light bill.
If we skip a check for me...
...I think we ought
to pay Sam and Max.
But you're selling cars
as fast as you're getting them in.
You only have 12 cars
on the lot right now.
But our current profits
aren't gonna cover the $39,123.50...
...that I owe previous customers.
-I think we need to do it in steps.
-How much did you say?
I致e made 39,000 more than
I should have over the past 2 years.
No, no, no.
What was the exact amount you said?
$39,123.50.
-No way.
-I don't think it's a coincidence, Jay.
This is after all our bills
and salaries?
Yep. And I checked it twice.
-No way.
-What do you need?
A big neon sign above your head
that reads ''This is a sign from God''?
I知 supposed to give our profit away
while admitting that I知 a skunk?
If God keeps blessing you, that money
will be replaced in a matter of days.
-What if we stop selling cars like this?
-Jay Austin, you gave this lot to God.
And he's gonna run it the right way.
And it looks like it means
repaying all the people you ripped off.
I can't believe what I'm about to do.
-Yes, may I help you?
-Miss Wright?
Yes.
I知 Jay Austin.
I sold a car to you about a year ago.
-Yeah, I remember.
-And....
Well, I overcharged you for that car.
What?
And I came to give you
a portion of that back.
And I wanted to say
I知 sorry for doing that...
...and to ask you to forgive me.
This is $1500.
Right. I believe that's what
I would have owed you...
...had I been honest about the sale.
I知 sorry about that.
This is an answer to my prayer.
I got laid off my job today.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, God.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome. Thank you.
Oh, I won $1000! I won $1000!
No, it's--
I致e never won anything before.
-It痴 not a contest.
-I won $1000!
I won $1000!
-You're giving me $1000?
-I am.
Why? I agreed to buy it at that price.
But the information I gave you
on the truck wasn't entirely accurate.
You bought the truck
on what you thought it was worth.
I apologize for that.
But it don't make sense that you just
give $1000 back.
Why would you do that?
The best way to explain it is that I want
my life to be pleasing to the Lord.
So you're just giving us $1000 back,
no strings attached?
-Well, if you'll take it.
-Oh, we'll take it.
That ain't your money.
I bought the truck.
You better take it.
The man's trying to give it to us.
You watch your mouth.
This is business.
This ain't business.
He's trying to give us free money.
He's giving me free money.
You go finish the bean dip.
If you don't share, you're gonna
be making your own bean dip.
Woman, I could buy
$1000 worth of bean dip.
Well, I probably need
to go ahead and go.
Man, I appreciate it. And I知 sorry for
calling you a scum-sucking maggot...
...when I bought my truck.
I don't remember that.
Well, I知 sorry anyway.
Well, I appreciate that.
-You guys have a great night.
-Yeah. You do the same, Jay.
Judy. You would not believe
how easy this has been.
Yes.
People have been blown away
when I come to see them.
It痴 been incredible. One girl--
One girl thinks
she still won a contest.
I thought I'd have to eat crow,
but this is cake.
I知 not being prideful.
You what? You cheated me?
I wasn't very honest about it.
So you think you can waltz right in
with a $1200 check...
...and expect me to accept
what you've done?
-Well, I知 sorry for what I did.
-You better be sorry.
Do you know how hard it is
to make it in this world today?
The last thing we need
is a dishonest person...
...taking advantage of old ladies.
-Ma'am, all--
-Don't you interrupt me.
I致e been working 40 long years
for every penny I got.
That's right.
Then a scam artist like you
tries to take it away.
-Tell him.
-You better give me an apology.
-Well, that's why I知--
-Don't you talk back to me.
I知 tired of the lies, the deceit,
the confections and everything else.
-The confections?
-Don't you sass me.
Keep your mouth shut
till I tell you to open it.
Amen.
-Now say you're sorry.
-I知 sorry.
Get out of here
and go get right with God...
...before I get you right with him.
Bye.
Oh, sweet Jesus, $1200.
So she threw you out?
So you're getting kind of cocky,
aren't you, Jay?
Hi there. How are you?
-Hi, Mr. Austin?
-Yeah.
-Hi. Hillary Vale, WALB News.
-I致e seen you on TV a few times.
Yes, well, we caught your story
on the national news...
...and we're wondering
if you'd give us an interview as well.
I don't know what I can say
that hasn't been said.
You just leave that to us.
What we would like to do
is a live remote from here tomorrow...
...for our 5:00 newscast.
-Okay, that'd be fine.
-All right.
We'll send the crew over
around 4:00 to set up.
-I look forward to talking to you.
-Thank you.
-All right.
Well, who needs to advertise
when you got all this free publicity?
So we'll stay on the two-shot
until we cut to the video.
Mr. Austin,
we need to get a sound check on you.
Could you count to five for us,
please?
-One, two, three, four, five.
-Are we good? All right.
So are you ready to do this?
-I guess so.
-Okay.
You're on in five, four....
Ben, we are live
at Jay Austin Motors in Albany...
...where things have been very busy
ever since that story broke...
...on national news
about their honesty policy.
Joining us now is the owner,
Jay Austin,
So, Mr. Austin, have things
really been that different,,,
,,,since this all happened?
That'd be an understatement,
One day we're just trying
to survive,,,
,,,and the next day,
they're lined up to buy cars,
I know about
the power of the press...
...but it would seem like you already
had a good customer base.
Have you changed the way
you've been doing business at all?
Well....
Well, you've been in business
for over two years now?
Right,
And you've always
run your business honestly?
What is she doing?
Well, Mr. Austin,
we had the opportunity...
...to speak with a gentleman
who claims that he worked with you...
...during your first two years.
And his view of the operation
is quite different.
Let's take a look.
Honest dealer?
That's not how I'd describe
Jay Austin,
I've seen him rip off tons of people,
Teenagers, young couples,,,
,,,old ladies, even a minister,
He even tried to teach us
how to rip people off,
And that's why I left,
Because of his lack of integrity,
What? You snake!
Mr. Austin, did this man, in fact,
work for you?
-Yes, he did.
-And is he telling the truth?
Did you, in fact, teach him
how to cheat your customers?
I知 ashamed to say this,
but, yes, I did.
So you're admitting
that you were dishonest in your sales?
I admit I used to be dishonest,,,
,,,but I have had a dramatic change
in my life,
Yes, sir. But why should the public
believe you now?
I知 not sure how to answer
that question.
Well, Ben, last week Jay Austin
was being praised for his honesty...
,,,but now a former employee says
that isn't the whole story,
I guess our viewers will just
have to decide for themselves,
This is Hillary Vale reporting live
from Jay Austin Motors in Albany,
Back to you, Ben,
We're clear.
I知 sorry if I caught you off guard...
...but it is my job
to report all the facts.
I understand,
but that is not who I am now.
Yeah.
All right, let's pack up and go.
We gotta get back to the studio.
Thank you.
Todd, let's pray for Daddy.
Lord, I知 angry.
I know I deserve this.
Would you help me, please?
I cannot defend myself.
Yes, we'll be there in 30 minutes.
Yep, not a problem.
I'll have it packaged for the 11:00.
Okay, what's the address?
All right, we'll be there.
Yes. Thanks.
Excuse me, Miss Vale?
I saw your report,
and I know you're just doing your job...
...but you need to know
that ain't the whole story.
What do you mean?
Jay Austin came to my house...
...and apologized
for the way he misled me.
And paid me back $1200.
-He what?
-He did the same for us.
He gave us $1000 back.
-You've got to be kidding.
-No, ma'am.
This story ain't over
until you report that.
What are you doing in here, bud?
Complaining to God.
Well, while you're in here yapping,
he's out here working.
No, no, no. You stay right here.
You let the Lord fight for you.
Hey.
I'm Ben Roberts,
Our top story tonight is a follow-up
to a story we told you about at 5:30,
There's another side to the story
about used-car dealer Jay Austin,
We go live now to Hillary Vale
with the details,
Thanks, Ben, After our report
on Jay Austin just a half-hour ago,,,
,,,these customers
showed up at the lot,,,
,,,with yet another side of the story,
Miss Harris,
you say that Jay Austin,,,
,,,came to your house
and returned money to you?
That's right,
He said he overcharged me
and he gave me back $1200,
He apologized,
and for that, I commend him,
-Lord, thank you.
-Reverend, you say,,,
,,,he returned money to you
as well?
He gave me back $2000
and apologized too,
-And what about you, Miss Carter?
-He gave me $1500 back,
-I'm so grateful for that,
-Thank you. Thank you, Lord.
-He gave us back $1000,
-Thank you, Lord.
He said he wanted his life
to be pleasing to the Lord,
And I believe him,
What you need to be doing
is talking to Bernie Meyers,,,
,,,that used to work here,
the one accusing him,
Jay met us on the lot,
but Bernie sold us that truck,
That's right! Yes!
Now, I have rebuked you.
I have defended you.
Now it's time for you to stand up
and be a godly man worth defending.
Do you understand me?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
All right, then.
May God bless you.
Oh, yes, Lord. Yes.
Oh, yes, Lord.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
-What is it, Mama?
-Todd, get me the phone.
Oh, no.
Hey.
What?
Where are you?
No, I知 on my way.
Judy's in labor.
Get out of here. I値l take care of this.
Well, Ben, we've had
quite a turn of events here today,
According to these customers
behind me,,,
,,,Jay Austin is a changed man,
And to top it all off,
his wife just called,
She's in labor
and they are now on their way,,,
,,,to have their baby at the hospital,
I'm Hillary Vale, reporting live
from Jay Austin Motors in Albany,
Back to you, Ben,
Hey.
How you doing, Faith?
Yeah.
You look just like your mother.
You know why we called you Faith?
That's what Daddy was learning
when you were being born.
Hey, if you're gonna go get Todd,
you better leave now.
Shouldn't you be sleeping?
No, I知 fine. You need to go.
Hey.
-Okay.
-Hey.
Hey, sweetheart. Hey.
Thank you for watching her
so I could rest.
Well, I loved it.
Did you have fun with your daddy?
Did you have fun with your daddy,
sweet girl?
Okay.
Now, you know
we're gonna be gone until tonight.
Mom's coming over.
Faith and I値l be just fine, Jay.
This will make Todd's day.
You need to go.
Okay.
Hey.
-Hey.
-Okay.
Say, ''Bye-bye, Daddy.''
Go to the left....
You know me.
You know when I sit and when I rise.
You perceive my thoughts from afar.
You discern my going out
and my lying down.
You are familiar with all my ways.
But before a word is on my tongue...
...you know it completely, O Lord.
''She's also bulletproof.
I壇 be able to help the police
fight criminals and robbers.
The only thing she can't do is fly,
but that's okay...
...she's still my favorite hero.
That's why
I would like to be like her.''
Thank you, Rachel.
You may be seated.
Okay, who's next?
Todd Austin, you're up.
''Well, I have many
favorite superheroes...
...that I would like to be.
But since they're not real...
...I thought about somebody
I could be like.
My real-life hero is my dad.
He's not perfect
and sometimes he makes mistakes...
...but he says he's sorry.
He is spending more time with me...
...and sometimes takes me to work
with him on Saturdays...
...just so we can talk.
He's pretty smart too.
He knows a lot about cars...
...and he even has one
that looks like a superhero car.
He prays with our family now
and even helps my mom.
I like spending time with him.
Even though he doesn't have
special powers or anything...
...he is still my favorite hero,
so that's who I want to be like.''
Very good, Todd. Thank you.
You may sit down.
Okay, next we'll have Joshua...
...then Anna, then Catherine...
...and if time permits,
we'll end with Caleb.
You can get me out of school
like this?
Well, I got permission.
-From my teacher?
-No, from your principal.
You went all the way to the top?
Well, if your principal's the top,
then, yes.
All right. Do we get to ride
in this car?
Sure do.
Yes.
Here you go.
-My hat.
-Oh, yeah.
You ready?
Is it the flywheel?
No, we got that fixed.