And like that,
Eva walks stone-faced,
down the unfamiliar
streets of New York.
With the black-and-white landscape
of the city behind her shoulder
An unforgettable opening scene.
From "Stranger than Paradise"
In a few days, I'll be walking
those streets myself.
Tomorrow will be my last show
before I leave for New York.
I'm sad to leave but tomorrow.
I'll wait for you here at Midnight FM.
With the soundtrack
from "Stranger than Paradise"
"I put a spell on you,"
I'll conclude tonight's broadcast
Oh, and for the tickets to
the "Breaking News" premiere.
Keep your calls coming in,
all you thriller-lovers!
Talking about the movie reminds
me of the killer's chilling glare
There is a serial killer at large
going after criminals.
I don't want to see psychos
even in the movies.
...reminds me of the killer's
chilling glare from the movie.
There is a serial killer at large
going after criminals.
I don't want to see psychos
even in the movies.
I hope you enjoy
the rest of the night.
And that tomorrow will be
another movie-like day.
This is Ko Sun-young
saying goodbye.
MIDNIGHT FM
She's here!
Clap, everyone!
Charismatic announcer turned
radio DJ
How fresh she looked!
Those were her good days.
You're right
What's with sudden interest
in studying abroad?
So that I can take your job
when I come back.
I don't think she's kidding.
As if she ever does!
Studying is just an excuse
I need some time off.
Plus, there is
my daughter's operation.
Being a single mom is
definitely not easy.
She'll be fine.
Declared innocent by lack of evidence
Leaves us all puzzled as to
where there is any justice
Obviously, Judicature has lost it.
Judicature has lost it!
Still makes my hair stand
to think about that time.
Resigns as a news reporter
Come back after 2 years.
I'll put you back in the newsroom.
What's the point when she'll
get kicked out right away?
Somebody is upset about
Sun-young's departure.
Where is Se-yeon?
The new girl can't be
bothered to show her face?
She's been out of reach
since last night.
Old one or the new one alike,
they have no respect for the producer.
I should get going.
Producer Oh.
What are you doing?
I don't feel so generous as to
wish you good luck.
Can we get over this?
You want to make up?
So, you wrote up your own
little playlist and faxed it over?
What fax?
- What's he talking about?
- Forget it!
Don't get your hopes up about
getting your TV job back.
It's not happening.
Where are you going, sir?
What about the show?
Don't you know how busy I am?
I'm not a family babysitter.
Even Jun-young had me pick up
Hye-ji from the airport.
What a handful!
Eun-soo, what are you doing up?
She's still up?!
Your mom is angry
because you're still up.
Share your bed
with your cousin tonight.
What you doing up, honey?
You could miss the flight tomorrow
So go to bed now.
If you agree, tap tap tap.
Once more.
Good girl
From tomorrow, mommy will
spend more time with you
Put your auntie on.
I have to stay up for work.
What the hell?
Can I send in my request by text?
I'm really not in the mood
So, please stop talking nonsense?
Hey, I'm a listener, too!
We started together,
we end it together
I can be an annoying listener
Don't fool around.
Get Eun-soo into bed for me?
I'll check in later.
All right! Don't be a pathetic
crybaby for the last show
Go get it, sis!
Sun-young!
All right. Gotta go.
Come on.
A single tap for no and
3 for yes, is it?
Isn't it better
to just text each other?
I don't want her
to forget how to talk
She's putting up with so much...
So many operations.
Will she get a better result
in the States?
She will
I know she will.
Difficulties following the homicide
at the red light district,
the police...
Red light district!
Difficulties!
Concentrate on the crackdown
Red light... Red-light District
Are you serious about
going back into TV?
Makes me look like an ass, right?
You actually know that?
And, you're still doing that?
What the heck?
Jesus Christ!
Are you all right?
Is he out of his mind?
Come back here!
Oh, my god!
What's he doing?
- What the! Let me...
- Stay in the car
He's going to kill her!
Out in plain sight...
It scares me to raise a daughter
with a scum like that around.
It's obvious he's stone drunk.
Shall I call the cops?
Forget it. No good can come
out of getting involved.
What the fuck are
you looking at?
We'll get off here.
What a creep!
Pick up the damn phone...
The person you're calling...
You'll be a pain in the ass, too?
Lost your mind?
Call me right away!
Eun-soo, I made this for you.
Promise me you'll
wear it every night?
Good. Now, go to sleep.
I can't. I've got work to do
Go to sleep! Now!
As 7th victim from the recent
serial murder has emerged,
the police have announced
reinforcement of the task force team
This is Jang Seok-hyun from HCN News.
Anything you want to add?
Looks like they're having fun.
Guess what? Our show could
go down the same road.
Mr. Oh is eager to rebuild
the program from the inside out.
I think he'll get on well
with the new girl
I don't think so...
With you gone,
the ratings will drop.
And by next fall,
we'll get the axe.
You know Deok-tae?
He's tonight's guest.
But, I thought it was someone else.
The 'Travis' guy didn't
answer my calls
Thank god we found
a replacement in time.
Are you crazy?
That man is a stalker!
I think you're overreacting.
He is an avid listener and
the biggest fan of our show.
We still have time.
Find someone else!
You can't be serious.
Hey, where are you going?
That was very bad.
Come and have a seat
Give me your phone
What have you got here?
2424? What are you, a mover?
Is that why you have
those broad shoulders?
She won't be using this
number from tomorrow.
Saved
What do you see in her?
She a mom, you know?
She has... a divine voice.
Real soft up in your ears.
Like a soft tongue?
You're dirty.
I'll give you a shout later.
Go to the bathroom.
Switch off the cell...
Do it now
He is a just fan.
We can't change him now.
Did you see this?
Look at those muscles!
There is only a fine line between
a fan and a stalker.
Let your guard down and
they'll walk all over you
It's your fans that keep
you on your job.
Make sure you get that
to the new girl as well.
The minute you let them
take control, it's over.
Whatever you say!
Totally oblivious of this.
How about coming in
on time for once?
- What a beautiful night!
- Hi!
It's the last show.
You could have come early
Coffee?
...and doughnuts! Oops!
Go on.
They're fattening
You said I should
put on some weight
Did you check the CDs?
Am I your maid?
- My sweetheart
- Cut it out!
Thank you for this!
It's nothing
Let me see
I'm impressed!
It is quite hard to take in but
it's our dear friend's last show.
In 5 minutes.
What's gotten into him?
Sam?
Sam!
Where are you?
You scared me.
You'll wake Eun-soo up
if you scream like that.
I said stop screaming.
Stop!
What do you want?
Shhh...
Eun-soo!
Have you ever had
coffee with an angel?
This program is brought to you
by angels' choice of coffee,
Angel-in-us
3... 2... 1!
Did you have another
movie-like day?
Hi, this is Ko Sun-young
from Midnight FM.
Tonight will be the precious
last time that I share with you.
I hope the next two hours will
be an unforgettable experience.
Our last...
I never thought I would
ever say these words.
Tonight we're going to
talk about farewells.
There she goes again!
Why bother writing up the script?
If I were to pick the most
beautiful farewells in the movie.
What's wrong with you today?
I would choose last scene
from Casablanca.
I'm a bit of a romantic.
At the foggy Moroccan airport.
Two people stand facing each other
unable to speak their mind.
Ilsa boarding the plane and
Rick watching on.
A farewell scene that was
as beautiful as it was heartbreaking.
What would our farewell be like?
It's a text from a listener.
It says
Love that lasts the longest is
love that never returns.
I suppose that parting
could be...
a way to preserve your love forever.
The queen of improvisation!
What is this?
The reason why so many fans
still remember James Dean.
Somerset Maugham
could be because of
his unexpected early farewell
A listener who sent in
the Somerset Maugham quote.
You forgot to give us your name
but thank you.
You could call this the love
theme song of "Casablanca"
'As time goes by'
They won't notice that
this was an accident?
How could they?
When she's that smooth.
Take it easy, relax!
You nervous? Forgetting to
switch off your cell.
It's officially the final show.
Even Ms. Perfect is making mistakes.
I've never seen her make
a mistake since her first broadcast.
It's your fault.
She's low on caffeine.
I could use a cup of coffee.
You heard her! Get some
doughnuts and cheesecake, too.
People will remember
this show forever
Shall we go together then?
Consider it a date.
Go on. It's still quite early.
I can manage by myself.
I don't like where this is going...
- You said my pot belly...
- I know you want it, too
Hey, sis! Are you trying
to pull tricks on me?
I know you're trying
to loosen me up.
But tonight's show is
really important for me.
Ko Sun-young?
Did you get my fax?
Who is this?
You'll play the songs
as it appears on the list.
Because I'm holding
your family hostage.
What?
Or your sister will die.
A-young, who was that just now?
Listen carefully.
You try to tell anyone about
this situation and I kill them
Hello?
Hello? Police?
I can't reach home.
Could you send someone
to look around?
Detective Cho, check this out.
Something is wrong.
Face covered up and bow-like knot
looks like our serial killer's
But he's only been going after
pimps and drug dealers.
Is she one of them?
Who reported this in?
The killer called in to say
he left her body here.
Detectives!
The suspect called himself?
It's the producer from
the radio show.
- I'm Detective Cho.
- Oh Jung-moo.
I'm sorry to have called
you so late.
But the victim's cell phone had
multiple calls from you
Hang in there.
It won't take long.
Who is that kid?
Where is Sun-young's daughter?
She's... in the hospital.
Because... she hurt... her neck.
Those of you still up at this hour
and listening to this show
send in texts to #2112.
'Sun-young,
is this really the end?'
'You already kept me company
through the night'
Hi, Ms. Bridget Jones,
it's you guys who kept me company
Tomorrow morning,
tell me the sky is white...
then, I'll reply that
the clouds are black'
It's black.
'Travis'! You quoted from...
- "Les amants du Pont-Neuf"
This quote reminds of the
scene where the heroine leaves
And my heart starts to ache.
I feel that I've broken
a promise I made with you
because of personal reasons.
Mr. Ko Joon-young...
- So, you're her brother.
- That's right.
But in the movie, the lovers
are eventually.
But, it's a protocol.
We still have to take a look around.
Well...
If you must.
Pont Neuf is the oldest bridge
in Paris
But its name actually
means a 'new bridge'
Thank you and sorry to be a bother.
What a nice place.
You have upstairs, too?
The radio is a little too loud
I'm already jealous that
she'll get more love.
I missed 3 minutes of the show.
I hope you'll give her just as much
love and attention.
I'm going back up.
The next song is from
Michael Haneke's "Pianist"
another film about obsessive love.
Hey, Sun-young.
I told you not to tell anyone.
Why did you call the police?
Why won't you listen to me?!
Now I'll show you what
the consequences are.
Listen very carefully.
You cannot tell anyone
about this situation
Who are you?
Are you a friend of A-young's?
Stop this sick joke!
Does this look like a joke to you?
Does it?
Look!
I am holding your family hostage.
Where is your daughter anyway?
I only see this kid.
She's in the hospital.
She hurt her neck.
Please...
Why are you doing this?
Hey! I'm telling the truth!
From this moment,
you'll be running the show
according to my instructions
You got my fax, right?
So, you faxed over
your own little playlist?
I put a lot of thoughts into that,
you know
I don't have it with me.
Somebody took it away.
I hope you won't
disappoint me any more.
Shouldn't we try for
a beautiful ending?
I'll tell you what you
should play next.
July 18, 2005...
Was the first week after you
started the show.
I want the first song
you played that day.
Trouble recalling?
Let me give you a clue.
It's a bit like our relationship.
The main character was a DJ.
Quite a bit actually.
"Play Misty for Me",
"Good Morning Vietnam"
"Fisher King", "Talk to Me"
The list goes on.
You're going to find that song
and play it.
Right after this one.
What are you doing here?
Woo-han, when this song
ends play the ads.
What?
Don't play any songs!
Just the ads!
Ko A-young
Look at this
Now, it's all up to your sister.
Are you... okay?
Sun-young!
What's the matter with you?
Hey, stop it!
What's the matter?
What's this about?
From when?
July 18, 2005!
I must find the first song
I played that day
What the...
It was 'Everybody knows'
from "Pump up the volume"
You know that? From memory?!
It's right...
'Everybody knows'/"Pump up the volume"
Holy shit! He's right.
This is all you need?
You really are a stalker!
That's creepy.
Find "Pump up the volume"
OST from the database.
Pump up the volume!
P! U! M! P!
It's not on the database.
Try the shelf.
What kind of database is that?
Pathetic!
Found it! Hang on...
Shit! The case is empty
Can you download an MP3
or something?
Are you for real?
We are a radio station
Is it the sound quality?
Listeners won't notice.
Why on earth do we need it anyway?
I don't know, either.
Look up Leonard Cohen discography.
You're right!
It's a Leonard Cohen song.
I'll be right over.
- Excuse me, Mr. Oh.
- Yes.
We haven't notified the family, yet.
Please keep it discreet.
It's track 3
I had to play six public
service ads in a row.
What the matter with her?
She has completely lost it.
What a sure way to screw up.
I'll have to write
a thousand report on this.
Talk about something after this ad
while I get the song ready.
While I get the song ready.
Maybe because it's my last show.
I'm getting really nervous.
I hope you'll understand
Even if I seem to be
acting a little strange.
Wake up! Wake up!
It's just... really hard
for me today
because I don't want it
to be the end.
Originally, I wanted to
talk about farewell
as the subject of the last show.
But, let me just play the songs
you want like always.
Wake up! Wake up!
My apologies. I must
have been too sentimental.
Up next is 'Everybody knows'
from "Pump up the volume"
Where the hero was a DJ.
A shy teenager, Mark
becomes a DJ at night
and enthrals fellow teenagers.
Through broadcasting
he discovers himself changing.
Here is the song.
We need to talk
What is it?
Is it Mr. Oh?
He won't get off your case?
Excuse me
Well, I...
It ain't...
What do you mean?
I dug up the old cue sheet...
I specifically requested the song
you played on July 18, 2005.
And the version you played
wasn't Leonard Cohen's.
It was the Concrete Blonde.
You even said yourself.
That Cohen version
was in the movie
but not on the OST!
You don't even remember
what you said.
I am really disappointed.
Who are you talking to?
Sun-young!
Open the door!
Look! Ko Sun-young!
If you hang up on me again,
I'll fucking kill them all!
I'll give you one more
chance to make up...
With the next song.
Oh, my god! A-young...
Please... what is it that you want?
Is it money?
I'll give you it to you.
It's not money that I want.
Let's meet up
I'll come over to you.
You'll come here?
How can you be so irresponsible?
This is your last broadcast!
Wasn't it your idea to make
a memorable time with your fans?
And, now... you'll abandon
the show and come here?
Hey... please!
What is this about?
You will not stop the broadcast!
Because, If you do...
It'll be your sister's ankle
not just a toe.
Next is the theme song
from "Taxi Driver"
You must say the exact thing
you said when you.
Played that song on Dec 5, 2006.
Come on, Sun-young
You can do this!
You poor little thing.
Do you remember what I said
when we played 'Taxi Driver'?
You're driving me nuts!
Tell me what's going on
so I can help
I'll explain everything later
But now...
You've got to help me out
Please, okay?
Give us at least
some kind of explanation.
Well, the main character Travis
is a taxi driver...
so every night...
No... no!
You said you remember
all my shows.
That's right...
December 5, 2006.
What did I say when I
played the song from "Taxi driver"?
This song is finishing
Shall I play another advert?
Quickly! Think!
Travis, a hero grows...
through suffering
A hero grows through suffering.
I have never heard before
They could no longer put up
with the corrupt world...
So, they had to stand up.
Taxi driver
"HBC Radio"
That was 'Everybody knows'
from "Pump up the volume"
You have to tell me
what the situation is
Stop making prank calls to 911.
By killing the pimps and
rescuing the prostitute, Iris,
Travis earns the title of hero.
Was he really a hero?
At time, I said a hero grows
through suffering'
In the movie, Travis is
portrayed as a maladjusted man.
But if you think about it,
all heroes are like that
to a certain extent.
Because they cannot endure
the corruption of society,
so they must act.
Right answer! Clap Clap
Are you out of your mind?
What do you think you're doing!
I said unless the world changes,
we can only wait for heroes to rise
Are you all trying
to finish the show?
Don't shout at me
I'm fed up too
I suddenly remember this
Let's fuck it up and
hand in our resignations!
Someday a real rain will come and
wash all the scum off the streets.
She's already introduced
the next song.
If you have any bitter feelings
you wish to get rid of.
Hope you can wash them away
with this song...
You want to fuck up?
Let's finish it off.
- The music! Change the song!
- Screw you! All of you!
Sun-young... Don't cry.
Do you know where
I've just been?
You were doing so well.
Why are you screwing up now?
It wasn't me.
Your sister is dead because of you.
Shouldn't we work together
for a beautiful ending?
No, then he'll kill her daughter
But we gotta call the cops.
That psycho killed a cop
He's capable of anything.
Exactly! We don't know
if he'll keep his word.
Are you okay?
Who the hell is he?
We saw your phone
He threatened us, too.
Sun-young, check this out.
My sister got killed because of you!
If I only played the right song...
You killed her!
Calm down and check this out.
I don't want to listen to you.
Se-yeon is dead, too.
I just went to identify her body.
What's up?
Hey...
This came in for you.
No name?
What is this?
The police thinks it's connected
to the serial killer.
Maybe he has something
to do with us.
Can you think of anything?
Baby... is that you?
Baby, are you okay?
Eun-soo!
The playroom, you know.
Get inside the closet
and stay quiet.
Inside the closet
and stay there, okay?
mommy will come for you
Hang in there, okay?
What are you doing?
I gotta go.
You should calm down.
Pull yourself together!
Can you get a broadcast van ready?
Leave one phone line open
Put others on hold.
Stay focused!
- You've got the ads?
- Yes, sir!
- Can you give us a hand?
- Relay channel... 3!
Let me take it.
Once you get home,
what will you do?
She's hiding from him in that house.
I can't just wait around.
This is like asking him
to kill you, too.
I can't just sit here
and do nothing.
Have the van meet me
at the front.
Hey! Sun-young!
This is too dangerous.
Are you up now?
You've only done
40 minutes of the show.
Doesn't look like you're
in the studio.
- Where are you?
- The restroom
The restroom?
Why are you doing this to me?
What did I ever do to you?
How uncommitted you must've
been all this time?
Just get to the point.
What is it that you want?
I gave you many chances.
What the fuck do you want,
you psychopath!
Shut up!
Of all people, you cannot
insult me like that.
We've still got so much work
to do together.
And you're bailing out?
That's all fine but you gotta
put things right before you go.
Put what right?
Don't worry.
We still have time.
Part 3, when you take calls
that caller will be me.
I hate it when I get
beat off for that.
Whatever you want.
But, don't touch the kids
Kid...s?
Maybe the kids are tired
of playing hide-and-seek.
Maybe she wants to play ball.
Lay a finger on my daughter,
and, I'll kill you myself!
You're a big fat liar.
Eun-soo! Come out, come out
wherever you are!
Hide!
Don't let him find you!
You can get the call sign
through this.
Do you know where
we're going anyway?
Turn left here.
Damn traffic!
Let's get started.
It's not the time yet...
Signal!
You're listening to Midnight Soundtrack
We're back with part 3 of the show.
In part 3, we'll be connecting
to one of the listeners
and have a live chat.
We already have a caller
I'll put him through.
Hello?
Hi
Can you tell us who you are?
About me?
I'm someone who believes
this program is all about you.
Your partner, Han Dong-soo.
What do you mean by that?
I'm saying that.
I don't think anyone else
can replace you on this program.
An unqualified DJ like Lim Se-yeon?
Simply unacceptable!
Although she won't be able to now,
even if she wants.
Son of a bitch!
What do you for a living?
Look! Hurry!
Can you tell us more...
Hurry!
Hello? Hello?
Hang on a second.
Hurry!
He hung up.
We have a bad connection.
Let's listen to a song first.
Eun-soo!
Hurry, Eun-soo!
Try not to breathe heavily.
And, be careful!
Sun-young, wait a little bit.
There is no time
I think he found my daughter.
Wait till the cops arrive.
Did you call the police?
- Is this it?
- Yes, sir.
Are you crazy?
He killed a cop already.
You're only provoking him!
He's a nutcase!
It's too dangerous.
You can't reason with him.
If anything happens to the kids,
I swear I'll kill you.
Don't do this.
Don't go in there!
Ex... excuse me...
I'll come with you.
Just stop it!
I don't need this.
I think I can help.
You're a god-damn stalker, too.
We're back on.
We'll try again.
- Dong-soo?
- Hello
Shall we continue
where we left off?
What you do for a living?
I... I raise rabbits.
Because I just adore rabbits.
Did you say... rabbits?
They love to hide from me
when I as much as blink.
I see.
They are such sweet little creature
but they cause trouble time to time.
And, one of them has
a injury on the neck.
I see.
As an avid listener...
What's your most...?
Wait!
You said earlier.
Parting could be a way
to preserve love eternally.
That's not what I meant...
If my rabbits vanish one day.
Then, I'll be able to keep
their loving memories.
No, actually...
So, I...
Found the two rabbits
that got away.
And killed them.
You son of a bitch!
Music!
All force dispatch immediately.
What the fuck did you do
with the kids?
What did you do with them?
Hey! What are you doing here?
- Anything?
- There's no one here.
Nobody upstairs either.
Sun-young! He got away.
Eun-soo!
Seon-young
Was it so hard to follow
my instructions?
I asked you not to leave
the studio no matter what!
He knows everything.
It's too bad but you won't be
able to see the kids again.
No... Don't do that
Hello? Is this the TV station?
I have information about the murder.
It's difficult to confirm without
an official police announcement.
But, Ms. Ko Sun-young is
staying at her house
while the police is trying to locate
the perpetrator on the run.
As Han turns out to be the one
responsible for the recent serial murders.
Relationship with Ms. Ko seems to be
the key to understanding this case
What about the show?
Play the songs on the list.
I'll call you back.
It's ready.
I want to be like mommy.
- This is the fax he sent you?
- Yeah.
I pulled up his record.
He was arrested for
attempted murder 4 years ago.
Attempted murder?
He was diagnosed with schizophrenia
during investigation.
I'm Ko Sun-young's partner.
He was sent to a mental institution
for 3 years
and got released last year.
This type of serial killer is
known as mission-oriented
They believe they're doing
good for the society
by ridding the world of criminals.
What about an innocent family member
or a DJ? A contribution?
A contribution?
I'm saying that he's a mental case
who believes his cause.
Look at the date the fax.
I think he was motivated
by Sun-young's program.
The dates of the murders
coincide with the program schedule.
Travis from "Taxi Driver",
drives his taxi every night
through the decadent streets
of New York.
'Someday a real rain will come and
wash all the scum off the streets'
Why do get such satisfaction
from watching our heroes in the movie
Because in reality,
no-one takes care
of the wrongs we come
across everyday
Where is my hero right now?
Are you listening to me?
Heroes sometimes suffer
at the weight of their fate.
But, it's that suffering
makes them stronger.
Where is my hero right now?
Are you listening to me?
He's using the term partner
he probably wants recognition
from his object of obsession.
I don't want to see these
psycho killers even in the movies
Sun-young is a victim, too.
Stop connecting her to the case.
I don't want to see these
psycho killers even in the movies.
What!
You'd better turn on the television.
The suspect just sent us
a video clip of himself
Reporter Jang Seok-hyun
has the exclusive.
Every Saturday, this is the
quiz corner where you participate.
We have a caller on hold...
Hello, 'Travis'?
Hello...?
Are you ready?
In front of me, there is a girl
that needs my help.
The poor girl is living in hell
because of her scumbag pimp.
And, I have her pimp who is
lower than a scumbag.
Do you know Iris?
I don't know.
I've never heard that name before.
Is it from Taxi driver?
The final shootout scene, right?
Travis kills the pimp
and saves Iris.
Where is everybody?
And is hailed as a hero
in the press.
Do you agree with that?
Travis put his beliefs into action.
He might be the man we need
in this time of rampant immorality
Well, I...
couldn't agree more.
What is this?
How was that?
You scared me.
Is this being aired?
It's from our show
When did you get that?
You can't just show that
on a public channel!
We were blackmailed, too.
The suspect sent us the message
that if we don't release this clip
there will be another murder
The murder victim in the video
was identified as Kim Tae-soo
He threatened to kill the kids
who made the news in 2006 for
his involvement in human-trafficking.
He was released on the grounds
of insufficient evidence
Sentenced innocent
by lack of evidence
whether there is any justice
in our society.
Ko Sun-young who was
the newscaster at the time...
Ms. Ko, how do you feel right now?
Please, just one word!
Was the voice on the tape yours?
It was.
How do you feel about
Han Dong-soo?
He...
He killed criminals.
I think...
It was a heroic act.
Are you listening to me, Han?
Come on out and talk to me!
Tell me what you want!
What do you think you're doing?
He's a psycho threatening
to kill your kids!
This is what he wants.
He's a psycho who
believes he is a hero.
He'll call me again.
Eun-soo?
One more time, baby.
Can I consider
that as your recognition?
Yes. Isn't that what you want?
But, you're too late.
I've already killed them.
Liar!
You're a hero.
A hero would never do
such a thing
Officers, have you finished
tracking the location?
Come and collect the bodies.
Han Dong-soo!
I'm turning myself in.
Do we have his location?
Get everybody over there now!
And, request for a backup!
My kids... they're alive,
aren't they?
Ms. Ko, the sky is white
and clouds are black today.
Come meet me. Hurry.
Go! Go!
All hell broke loose here.
Where the hell are you?
Get your ass over here, now!
Yes, sir!
I gotta go back to the station.
Will you be okay?
I'm okay.
Come with us, ma'am.
I'll take my car.
- Keep closely behind her.
- Yes, sir.
Let's go!
Her car just started off.
You should've sent out
a substitute program
I don't believe we should do
that in this situation.
What situation?
Get your ass in the studio. Now!
Yes, sir.
We have exclusive breaking news?
I have the fax that Han Dong-soo
sent to Ko sun-young tonight.
Son of a bitch!
In the fax, there is a playlist
of songs that Han put together
All these movie soundtracks
have one thing in common
that the main character kills
villains and becomes a hero himself
We're heading to the place where
Han says he's turning himself in
Block off the press!
Don't let anyone near.
Are you on your way?
Can't wait to see the kids?
Then, let's get started with part 4.
Tap tap tap, if the answer is yes.
Can you help me?
We'd like to apologize
for earlier problems...
Hey!
Have you lost your mind?
Get out of here! Now! Out!
I'll be expecting your resignation
Until 4 am, this time slot
belongs to Ko Sun-young.
And I'm the producer in charge.
Is that the car?
I think it's a recording
of Ko's program
Coming up in a few minutes in part 4,
We'll reconnect with Han Dong
Detective Cho!
Who is that?!
I did exactly as you told me.
Now, where are the kids?
Don't worry about them.
They're safe in my hands.
Take the right.
What the...?!
She gave us the slip.
Were following her to the west.
Find out who she is.
And, get an aerial backup.
Yes, sir!
Hello! This is Han Dong-soo.
I'm currently moving in a car
with my partner, Ko Sun-young.
Ms. Park? Are you there?
Can we play a song first?
Is that... Is that her car?
Where are you going?
Where are the kids?
Stop right there.
You want me to stop?
The kids are in the trunk.
Just drive through.
No!
That's more like it, partner!
Stop the car!
Get out of the way!
This city fills up with trash
like them at night.
Out of the way!
But, with your voice even things
like that turn into a scene from a movie.
No!
- Sun-young!
- Keep going
No... no!
You said that I was a hero.
Did you mean that?
I did everything you
wanted me to do.
People change their words
all the time.
I can't feel the sincerity
in your words any more.
But, it doesn't matter.
All they care about is
what you say.
We're almost there.
You'll like what I've done.
You're right, Han Dong-soo.
I've been spitting pretentious
words out of my mouth.
But, you...
You're just a dumb killer who
can't tell a broadcast from reality.
Eun-soo!
Eun-soo! My baby.
Sun-young! It's me!
What are you doing here?
The clouds are black
and the sky is white.
Pont Neuf is
the oldest bridge on Seine.
And this is the oldest bridge
in Seoul.
Why do you keep avoiding me?
I really want to help.
Stop following!
Ko Sun-young!
Eun-soo!
Kids!
Eun-soo! Eun-soo!
Detective Eom!
Sir!
What about the woman?
Any leads?
She's still unconscious.
She had no identification on her.
Man, it's a hard day to forget.
Let the kids go.
You can tell me what you want.
I'll do anything you want.
Ms. Park, listen to me carefully.
The moment this show gets
interrupted,
I'm scared...
It's so cold here.
The kids will die.
Is that clear?
We'll continue with the show.
I'm at the place where
Han Dong-soo lives.
Let's hear from him directly
why he committed these crimes.
Dear Midnight FM listeners
a special corner.
It's your turn, Sun-young.
Do you recognize him?
He's a trash!
A piece of trash that
needs to be swept away.
You said
I'm scared to raise my daughter
in this world.
That's right, everyone!
Sun-young will shoot
the guys with this gun.
And become a hero herself.
Leave me alone!
Sir!
What the hell?
What the fuck are they doing?
You think this your show?
Who is this?
Psychos!
Hey... Hey!
You wanna see them all die?
Back off, Han Dong-soo.
This is my show.
I'll host it to the end.
Are you all right?
We've got to get the show going.
Stay with us till the end.
Damn!
Park!
Get your ass over to
the control room.
What are you doing?
Tick-tock! 4 minutes passed...
Eun-soo, hurry!
- Tell me if anyone comes this way.
- Got it
Shall we get started again?
Look,
This man is a filthy low life
human-trafficking scum.
That needs to be swept off.
What do you mean
human-trafficker?
She is my sister!
She ran away from home!
He's lying.
What did you do with my sister?
Where is she?
We don't have much time.
Fuck you!
You're delusional.
Find him! Now!
Even a criminal deserves the law.
Law?
They'll sneak out with a fine.
Who are you calling a criminal?!
Is that train sound
in the background?
Train runs at this hour?
From all the listeners out there
only you...!
How did you feel when
Kim Tae-soo was found dead?
You were happy
that I did it for you.
Then you should be thankful
Leaves us all puzzled as to
where there is any justice.
Now, it's your turn.
Ms. Ko...
Shoot that scumbag and be my partner.
Fuck yourself!
You crazy psycho!
Search around the train tracks
where trains are still running.
In about 5 minutes,
blood will start to freeze.
It's your call.
Listen, lady! Just calm down.
Is it going to be your kids
or that piece of trash?
Go on, do it!
Like you said on the radio!
No...
Promise me.
That you'll let my kids go
if I shoot that scumbag.
I'm not a liar like you.
Hey, wait! No...!
No! Don't shoot!
Eun-soo, I'm scared...
Please, don't shoot me!
No... please! You can't do this!
3...
- Why...? What did I do?
- 2...
Please... No! Don't kill me.
1!
I'm not a scum.
My brother...
I'll get you out.
Han Dong-soo!
Tell the listeners!
That you'll.
Let my kids go if I kill this scum.
- No... no... no...
- You lied to me again!
Help us!
Go! Hurry!
Run! As fast as you can!
We haven't got much time.
Come on! Hurry!
Sun-young! Sun-young!
What the fuck?!
You ruined everything!
You...
Get moving!
Sun-young that talked to me
always said the right thing.
Drop the knife!
Put your hands up where I can see 'em.
It's over, Han Dong-soo.
Wait!
People should never hear
your voice again
Han Dong-soo
Go to hell.
Did you get that shot?
We'll get a direct interview
with Ko Sun-young
You'll be reunited
with the children soon.
How do you feel now?
I'm reporter Jang from GCN.
Any comment, please.
Step back, please!
Hey, can you stop for a second?
Be gentle!
I got shot.
Are you okay?
Don't worry about the reporters.
They'll forget all about it soon.
I'm sorry, sir.
We'll get moving.
You must have felt the need to escape
from this suffocating daily routine
How about you go
crazy today for once?
Turn it off
Are you willing to go wild?
Excuse me?
Then follow my instructions.
Turn the god-damn radio off!