Tarek.
Tarek, dear, you wanted me
to wake you up early.
Tarek, get up. It's late.
Okay.
Mother.
Yes, my dear.
Nothing.
Get up, Tarek. Get up.
Good morning.
Good morning, Katz.
Well, we'll see. Forgot me?
How could I?
- Thanks, dear.
- You're welcome.
Tarek, move over.
- Careful, slowly.
- Okay.
Take off your shirt.
It's my daughter.
What? Not now. Later.
Okay, go with mother.
Okay, that's it. Bye.
It's Salma.
She's getting married.
Salma's getting married?
Yes, at Abu Ala's restaurant.
- When is the wedding?
- Next week.
The groom is Walid,
owner of the roasting place.
It'll be a great wedding.
At precisely 8:00
you push the button.
...for several months,
will probably be announced today.
Last night's heavy rains
caused flooding in various places.
The level of the Sea of Galilee
rose by two feet.
- Shit.
- There were traffic jams this morning.
A TERRORIST PENETRATED
FROM THE WEST BANK.
In Tel Aviv the security forces
ended their patrols.
Rehavia, come.
Rehavia, go down. It's Katz.
- Who?
- Katz.
I can't take this anymore.
- Pull over a minute.
- Not now.
I need to take a leak.
Wait, we'll be in Tel Aviv soon.
Where will I piss there?
You'll manage. Hold it in.
It's not healthy. I want to piss here.
Come on, Abed. Pull over.
Let him feel comfortable
before the operation.
I don't trust him.
I know him. Trust him.
I'm not sure about him.
He's like his father.
Shaul, are you listening?
Control, H1, over.
Shaul, the old man is
opening the hydrants again.
Roger, direct me.
Shaul, are you kidding me?
It's 20 meters from you.
Shit. I'll kill him.
Oh, great water.
Katz, turn off the hydrants.
Look what you've done
to the street.
The street looks fine to me.
A few repairs.
- I'm working on it.
- I'll call the police.
Shaul, leave him alone.
I'll take care of it. We'll clean up.
- Dad, this is my job.
- Shaul, you know him, really.
- Dad, don't interfere.
- I'm telling you, leave him alone.
Don't tell me not to interfere.
Okay, why yell?
Enough, what's with the water?
There's too much water
in the country.
Okay, you're right.
Let's play dominoes.
Come on.
Girls, turn off the water.
Turn it off, come on.
- Who prepared you for this?
- Ibrahim.
- What did he tell you?
- He didn't have to tell me anything.
What did he tell you?
I watched videos and heard stories.
What stories?
I saw children murdered.
I saw roadblocks, beatings.
What else?
Shut up. I know what they did
and how they'll pay.
That's why I'm here, not you.
No wisecracks. Let's repeat it.
When do you push the button?
When I'm in a crowded place.
What if the police suspect you?
I go near them and push.
What if they're searching
people in the market?
I come near and push.
No.
First you try to get in,
then you push it.
What if something goes wrong?
I call you.
What number?
050-5411400.
Last question, no wisecracks.
All this is for the future.
What drives you to do this?
Since I was born
I couldn't even dream.
And that won't change
unless they are hurt.
Trust him. He's ready.
- Is that her?
- Yeah, that's her.
- How do you know her?
- She grew up next door.
Look at her,
how tight her clothes are.
Shame on her.
You can see everything.
What do you want to do?
We'll take care of the whore.
But not now. Too many people around.
We'll come back later.
Does it sit properly?
- Salim, the money.
- Wait. First things first.
Shall I connect him?
I have a mobile phone.
If something goes wrong
we'll set you off.
- How?
- We call this phone.
From now on you can't take it off.
The circuit passes through the buckle.
If you open it...
But don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
What were you saying?
Give all the money to my father.
We'll give a part of it
to your uncles.
No, give it to my father.
He'll take care of them.
- You sure? Your father could...
- Give it all to my father.
Salim, give it
to whoever he wants.
Enough. We don't have time.
Okay,
they'll have it in two weeks' time.
Tarek, listen.
We have no air force.
If we had an air force
we wouldn't need all this.
You're doing
something important.
You're our air force.
Cool him so he doesn't sweat.
What's wrong with you?
I feel sick.
Drink. Calm down.
Everything will be fine.
Want something from the market?
No, thanks. I'll go later.
- Keep an eye on my kiosk.
- Sure sure.
We're in the market,
by Amram's lovely stall.
Hello, Amram.
How's it going?
Hi, Aharoni, hi.
I love shopping in the market.
There's wonderful fruit,
lots of great vegetables,
the best and freshest
you can get.
But most of all I love
the people in the market...
warm, simple people
who have much more to offer.
Now it is artichoke season.
Where are these from, Amram?
The Negev desert, Aharoni.
Great artichokes. You can do
lots of things with their hearts.
They go well with olive oil, herbs.
- Hello.
- Tarek?
I love cooking artichoke hearts.
Yes, my dear. Are you in Tel Aviv?
Yes.
- You started working?
- Soon.
Where are you, son?
I hear lots of noise around you.
I'm at the market, buying food.
I'll talk to you later, okay?
The market? May Allah keep you safe.
Take care of yourself.
They say a terrorist
got to Tel Aviv.
Don't worry, Mother.
Don't hang around.
Don't worry. I'm leaving now.
Tarek, come back to me soon, son.
I'll be back in two weeks.
Allah help us.
Allah be with you, son.
Goodbye. Mother?
Onions, garlic and herbs,
and even lemons.
Please give me
two kilos of artichokes.
- Do you cook artichokes?
- Sure.
- A lot? You like them?
- Yes.
- Do you cook with artichokes?
- Every week.
Give me big ones, Amram.
Do you happen to have
celery heads?
Give me two, but also big ones,
and remove the leaves.
It's Tarek. Shall I take it?
No, activate him.
What if he's alone?
It would be a pity, no?
Answer him, quickly.
Hello, Tarek.
Hello.
What happened?
Anything happen? Trouble?
Did something go wrong?
KATZ ELECTRICIAN, REPAIRS
No, everything's fine.
I'm going now.
Okay, buddy. Allah help you.
Goodbye.
What happened?
Nothing. A mistake.
Don't worry.
Are you threatening me?
No, he doesn't know I'm here.
So why did you come?
I wanted to tell you
Avinoam's coming tonight.
You know him, so maybe
you won't be here.
- First, I don't know him.
- You do.
He's from our neighborhood too...
Avinoam.
Oh, Avinoam...
black pants and a yarmulke.
Sure sure, Shlomi. Okay,
I don't have time for your bullshit.
I'm not afraid of you.
Let him come. I'm here.
I'm sorry.
We'll have to come tonight.
You'll have to?
Are you coming too, Shlomi?
Go away.
Get out of here.
What are you staring at?
May I use the toilet?
What do I look like,
Social Services?
All day you come here
for the toilet.
Don't you have toilets
at the building site?
Building site?
No, the lawyers' office.
Yes, the building site.
You work there,
so go do your business there.
They don't have toilets.
Okay okay, but be quick about it.
Quick.
And clean up after yourself.
Will you finally bring
someone to fix your roof?
I can fix it myself.
I don't need some
thieving Jew to do it.
Come on, you can't fix it yourself.
You need a pro.
I don't need anything.
Zipora doesn't care?
Since when does Zipora care?
What? What do you want?
It's broken.
What?
It's no good.
Can you repair it?
It can't be repaired.
It's burnt out.
But I have a new one.
I can get you one.
Want it?
Yes, I do.
You want it? So come with me.
What do you need it for?
I'm from the building site.
I need it for the generator.
Okay, where is it? Here it is.
Here, take it.
No, I need the same thing.
It is the same.
Exactly the same.
Okay, this I don't have.
But I can order it.
Tomorrow's Shabbat.
Everything's closed.
Come back on Sunday.
Is that okay?
Okay.
Sunday at 8:00.
At 8:00.
Fine.
Listen.
Leave me alone.
Rehavia, leave it.
- You don't know anything about it.
- What don't I know?
Great.
Maradona.
Come here, come here.
Where did you learn this?
In Nazareth.
Tell me, Maradona, you're Arab?
Muslim?
So me and Katz...
we have an argument:
Which religion was first,
Christianity or Islam?
Islam started
in the seventh century.
We know that, but who was first?
Christianity.
- You just guessed. Shabbat shalom
- Shabbat shalom.
That's all you know...
"Shabbat shalom, Shabbat shalom."
- Read a book.
- I have.
Primitives. He doesn't even
know when he was born.
He just guesses by the size
of his fingernail.
I'm stuck with these primitives.
You need help with this?
No, I just don't have the time.
Why? Do you know how?
It's my job.
You just have to make
a hole in the ceiling,
clean and fill it... a few hours.
I know, I know.
It's just a matter of time.
I have time.
How much to fix that ceiling?
For the switch, okay?
Okay,
but don't tell Rehavia...
the guy who was here.
Don't tell him you work for me.
It is just between us.
No problem.
Okay, come with me to the storeroom
to get some cement.
Okay? Come.
Wait. Wait here. Wait here.
Okay, take that
back to the shop.
I'm off to the market.
I'll be right back.
L... I work for Mr. Katz.
He asked me...
It smells of...
I must have forgotten it.
I'm here to fix
the hole in the ceiling.
What's your name?
I'm Tarek.
Thank you, Tarek.
Katz left.
I should fix it while he's gone.
Okay.
Take off your jacket.
Aren't you hot?
No, I'm a little sick
in my nose and throat.
Would you like some tea?
Thanks, just water.
Better?
Better.
- Hello.
- Keren.
Mother?
I called to wish you
a happy birthday.
Sweetheart, happy birthday.
- It's tomorrow.
- I know.
- Is Father home?
- He's at the synagogue.
Why didn't you go with him?
I'll pray at home.
What about you?
Do you pray?
Come for the Sabbath eve meal.
I'll talk to Father, please God.
Come, my sweet. It'll be all right.
How can I come?
You know he won't agree.
I'll talk to him. He'll agree.
I can't come anymore.
Keren, Father is back.
I have to hang up.
Who are you talking to?
I'm ordering groceries.
We need coffee.
Bye, my darling.
Katz wants some coffee,
if you have some.
I'm working for him now.
Everyone wants coffee today.
Sorry about earlier... the toilet.
I'm not usually like this.
It's just...
I don't know, they all
got on my nerves today.
Do you want coffee too?
I make it really well, like we do.
What do you mean,
"like we do"?
On the Kibbutz.
We make it best.
Do you have a coffee pot?
Yes.
What's your name?
- Tarek.
- Tarek?
- And yours?
- Keren.
- Where are you from?
- Tulkarem.
And what are you doing here?
What can someone
from Tulkarem do?
- Renovations.
- What do you do?
I'm from a Kibbutz,
I just make coffee.
Where did you learn
the word "kibbutz"?
In Nazareth.
There's lots of kibbutzes there.
I thought you were from Tulkarem.
I am from Tulkarem,
but I played soccer
in Nazareth for many years.
Really?
You must have been good.
I don't know.
I was pretty good.
What are you doing for Katz?
Fixing the leak in his ceiling.
Really? I was sure
he was doing it himself.
Right, he really...
Don't tell anyone, will you?
I forgot he said not to tell.
Don't worry.
He's a little crazy, isn't he?
He's mad at the world.
Why?
Did you see the photo on his wall?
Of the soldier?
That's his son Yakir.
He died many years ago
in the army.
Katz always says he died
because everyone here is stupid.
Are you alone?
Yes.
Where is he?
Who?
The boy.
I'm having a party tomorrow night
on the beach. Want to come?
I don't know, l...
I leave on Sunday.
So tomorrow is your
last day here?
So you have to come.
I have to go.
Come, it'll be fun.
DEATH TO THE ARABS
Tarek?
Zipora invited you to dinner.
Tonight?
Of course tonight. When else?
Thank you.
Hello.
- Where are you?
- In Tel Aviv.
Listen, you traitor,
I'll kill your parents, get it?
The button didn't work.
I'm fixing it, I swear.
- What do you mean, didn't work?
- I don't know. You gave it to me.
- Where will you fix it?
- At a repair shop... a Jew.
If you say a word
I'll kill your father.
I won't say a word.
I'll have it fixed.
It'll be ready on Sunday.
Not Sunday.
Tomorrow morning.
Go to a crowded place
and we'll activate you.
- Tomorrow's Saturday.
- I don't care.
Tomorrow go to a crowded place...
a restaurant or cafe.
Everything's closed on Saturday.
Abed, don't you dare do anything.
There's no one near me.
Sunday morning I'll blow myself up.
People like you should
blow themselves up 10 times
to clear their father's name.
Got it?
Oh, mamaliga.
Want some?
- No, thanks.
- You should.
Zipora makes it to die for.
Here.
There's nothing like
Zipora's Romanian kebabs.
Eat, eat.
The search continues
for the terrorist
who penetrated into Israel.
The police ask the public to be alert.
I'm going to take a shower.
- Dad.
- What?
What's that Arab doing at Katz's?
He's helping him to fix the leak.
- Are you sure, Dad?
- Sure I'm sure.
Did you think Katz
could fix it himself?
Katz couldn't do
anything by himself.
If not for me, he'd have
gone under long time ago.
He can't do anything
by himself, come on.
- There's a warning out.
- So what?
You think this Maradona...?
Come on.
If someone sets off a bomb
it'll be Katz.
If so, Katz for me
is an Arab, Dad.
Dad.
Dad, I'm no racist,
but I don't like it
that this Arab is hanging around here
on Saturday when there's a warning out.
I'm a realist.
It's dangerous.
It's in their genes.
Not in their race, in their genes.
Do you hear me?
Do you?
You should have known Zipora
when she was young.
Everyone was after her...
notes on her door
in Bucharest.
Her father would go nuts.
How she danced.
Right, Ziporale?
Ziporale, how you danced, eh?
Everyone was crazy about her.
- Darling, darling.
- He's drunk.
I'm not drunk.
No, I'm not drunk.
This was a famous singer
in Bucharest.
The girls were crazy about him.
He had a velvet voice.
Do you know "Romeo and Juliet"?
He used to sing that.
The guy opposite
didn't talk to him.
They fought over a girl.
The entire town knew.
But when they sang
we all cried...
tears.
That was culture.
And what have we here?
Nothing.
Just sweat and more sweat.
No culture,
no romance, no nothing.
They took everything.
Once in the army
they wouldn't let
soldiers drink water.
In the Romanian army?
No, not that far back.
In the Israeli army
they wouldn't let soldiers drink.
Stop it.
They called it "water discipline."
They didn't let you drink,
did they, Yakir?
did they?
How come?
A soldier.
Boot camp, four months in.
They didn't let him drink water.
Stop it.
- Water.
- Come to bed.
Didn't let him drink water.
Hush. Come on.
- Avinoam, don't be...
- Don't worry.
Everything's fine.
Don't be afraid,
nothing by force.
Keren, this is Avinoam.
Throw away your cigarette.
It's Shabbat.
Do you love your family, Keren?
Joseph Shoshani worked
and studied all his life
to give you a good education,
so you could marry
and have a family.
I know who my father is,
but thanks anyway.
Your father loves you.
You're breaking his heart.
And how exactly
is that your affair?
I didn't come here to fight.
I just came to tell you
that your family is suffering
from your behavior.
I also wanted to see if your new
and despicable lifestyle
is making you so happy
that you're willing...
I didn't ask you that,
only how it is your business.
I know what happened,
but that's forgivable.
Mistakes are permitted.
We'll help you get over it...
we, the family, the community.
I don't think you'll get
such an offer here.
Here no one will help with anything,
and you know it.
Is this how you want to live...
alone, with nothing
beyond money or beauty,
no family?
Are you happy like this?
Are you happy?
Well, we'll come back
in about three hours.
Pack up your things
and dress properly.
Wait for us here.
So what do your parents do?
My mother was a nurse.
And your father?
He stopped working
a long time ago.
He used to be a violin player.
He'd play for us every day at home
and the whole town knew him
from the band, the radio...
the mayor.
Violin... I just love it.
It can open the heavens.
So your father retired?
A year ago there was...
a thing with my father.
He hasn't played since.
He won't get out of bed.
He used to take me
to Nazareth every day...
for me, for soccer.
He'll be okay.
Sometimes when difficult things happen
you have to rest.
In Bucharest there was a story
about a Madame Popescu
who didn't leave her bed
for 66 years...
66 years.
Even the wedding was
in the bedroom.
Until one day when she was
already a grandmother
she got out of bed,
went out to the town square
and started trying on
new dresses.
And everyone was surprised.
Children who'd heard the story
from their mothers asked her,
"Madame Popescu,
why aren't you in bed?"
What did she answer?
"Enough. I'm tired of it."
What?
It's okay, Avinoam.
She can wear my jacket.
I'm not going anywhere.
- Now you've decided you like it here?
- No.
- So what's the problem?
- No problem.
Shlomi, where does she live?
Shlomi.
Micha St., number 6.
You see, this may end
well or badly,
but I won't let you
stain the community
hanging around
with those types.
You're coming home
with us now.
We'll compensate
anyone needed...
your boss, your landlord,
- so you won't have trouble.
- I'm not going anywhere.
Shlomi, get some water.
There's a limit to being nice.
Hold her, Shlomi.
You'll go home clean.
We'll make sure of that.
It's closed.
Get out and close
the gate behind you.
Didn't you hear what I said?
Beat it.
Hey, I told you to go.
Don't you understand Hebrew?
No, I don't understand.
So now you're a whore
for Arabs?
- Want another baby?
- Bitch!
Just you wait.
It's not over yet.
Are you okay?
They know where I live.
WATER DISCIPLINE
ABOLISHED IN IDF
YAKIR KATZ'S SUPERIORS
CLEARED
COMMITTEE FORMED TO INVESTIGATE
PRIVATE YAKIR KATZ' DEATH
All parents stay alive.
What, you're leaving?
Yes, I'll go to Katz's.
Stay with me until I fall asleep.
Why do they...?
They don't like girls
walking around like I do.
Walking around?
Dressed like me...
with earrings and hair.
And they go to all the girls
who do that?
No, not all.
It's a long story.
Maybe they'll come back.
On Sunday I'll talk
to my cousins.
They'll take care of it.
Are they strong?
Very strong.
They're the only ones
I still talk to.
So you'll sleep here
until Sunday?
Until Sunday I'm with you.
Tell me a story
to make me sleep.
I don't have many stories.
Anything, about your home,
your family, about Tulkarem.
Those aren't bedtime stories.
Just any story.
Any story?
Okay.
Today I had dinner
with Katz and Zipora
and Zipora made
special Romanian food...
Mamaliga, kebabs.
And Katz told us about
the singers in Romania.
But...
Zipora is a bit sad.
She... maybe she doesn't
want to go on.
This afternoon
she didn't want to go on.
Sometimes I don't
want to either.
Good morning, sleepyhead.
Where are you going so early?
To the dining hall.
Then I'll take you to the fields.
Why? Because I'm Arab?
Well... come on.
Ahmed.
Don't worry, it's Shaul.
Ahmed, come here.
He's just a parking warden.
I'm not a parking warden.
I'm a municipal inspector,
and you're in my jurisdiction.
- Your jurisdiction?
- Yes, my jurisdiction, Ahmed.
- His name isn't Ahmed.
- Don't interfere.
Ahmed, go to the wall over there
and put your hands on it.
- Shaul, what are you doing?
- I'm going to search him.
- Come on.
- Rehavia, calm your son down.
Katz, don't interfere.
Arabs come here on Shabbat,
hang around as if
in their mother's home.
Listen, he's with me,
so don't cause trouble.
What's he doing with you?
Ahmed, what are you
doing with him?
Nothing.
Tell me, you 're fixing
the leak, aren't you?
No.
- So he's fixing my leak.
- I knew it.
Good for you.
Now take him and get out of here.
- Shaul, enough.
- Why?
I have nothing
against this Arab,
but as far as I know,
only Arabs commit bombings here.
If Indians were committing bombings,
I'd search them.
Listen, if you don't get lost
within one minute
I'll call the police and say
you're impersonating a police officer
and I'll tell God you're impersonating
a human being.
Now shut the hell up
and get out of here.
Get him away, Rehavia.
Okay, Shaul, come on home.
Come home, let's go.
Enough. Enough.
Come on!
That's enough.
Asshole.
Don't listen to him. Let's go.
Where?
To the synagogue.
The synagogue?
To meet my family.
Wait a minute, okay?
Sweetheart.
- Is Father inside?
- Yes.
Do you want me
to get him?
- No.
- Why not?
It won't change anything.
Keren, he's your father.
How are you managing?
Do you have any money?
Honey, no money at all?
No, it's Shabbat.
Take it.
No time for Shabbat now.
Sweetie, come home,
I beg you.
Right, I have to go in.
Take care of her.
I feel like I'm exploding.
It's just everything's
such a mess.
You're not religious anymore?
Not for a year.
Why?
I did something
that God doesn't forgive.
Something bad?
Something good.
I had a little baby in my belly.
He died three months
before I was due.
Everyone said it was
God's punishment.
I wasn't married.
And God won't forgive you?
I don't want Him to anymore.
Do you think there is a God?
I don't know.
Maybe not.
If I knew there was life after death
I'd kill myself.
Maybe that's why you don't know.
So I won't die?
So you live.
Hello.
Did you find a place?
There aren't any people.
It's Sabbath. Tomorrow.
No, today.
Trust me, I'll fix
the button tomorrow.
Trust you?
Where are you?
I'm in Tel Aviv.
But there's no one around.
Tarek.
Are there people around you?
Salim, activate him.
Tarek.
I have to go.
- Tarek.
- Go away.
- What are you doing?
- What did I do?
- Nothing.
I'll explain later.
Please go.
Tarek.
- Activate him, Salim.
- No, let him do it.
Tarek.
What did I do?
Tarek, wait.
Tarek.
Go away.
They'll find out by tomorrow.
They've said it on the radio.
- Activate him.
- But it's Saturday.
- Go away.
- What did I do?
- Why? What did I do?
Nothing. I'll explain later.
Please go.
What, you're doing yoga now?
Everyone's screwed up here.
No people around,
and the restaurants have guards.
Trust me, tomorrow morning
he'll go to the market
and blow up 50 Jews
instead of a couple of old ladies.
It's a waste.
Trust me, let him do it himself.
Besides, if Command knew
we activated him without his consent
we'd have trouble.
You know that, don't you?
Tomorrow 8:00 in the morning,
or we'll be in trouble.
No problem.
Hello.
We won't activate you.
I convinced him.
- But tomorrow for sure, right?
- Sure.
Okay, buddy.
Go to the beach.
The sun is shining, no?
Almost.
How's Tel Aviv?
Great.
Okay, I gotta go.
We'll talk later.
Have you calmed down?
- What?
- What's the matter with you?
I don't know.
What planet are you from,
you nutcase?
What do I know?
From Tulkarem.
Were you really a soccer player,
a builder, a Kibbutznik and all that?
More or less.
Except a Kibbutznik.
- And what are you doing here?
- That's a long story.
So tell me.
I started playing
in the neighborhood team
in Tulkarem.
One day a sports announcer,
Arab, very famous, saw me.
In that game I scored
and we won.
And Salah, the radio announcer,
talked to my dad after the game.
He suggested I should
play in Nazareth,
and that's how I got there.
Every day my dad drove me
an hour and a half each way.
The trouble started
with the Intifada,
so it was difficult to get
through... roadblocks.
But it didn't always work,
so we would run.
That's how it went on
for months.
My father realized we'd have to go back
to the roadblocks.
Then it was more difficult
to get through.
I didn't want to go
to the training anymore.
I couldn't bear the humiliation,
couldn't see the soldiers,
so happy that we were
ready to do anything
just to cross the roadblock.
But my father wouldn't give up.
Soccer's above everything, see?
He was crazy for soccer.
I liked to play,
but I also liked other things.
But he loved it
more than his violin.
He'd watch my games
wearing earphones...
you know, "Songs and Goals,"
the sports program...
so as not to miss any goal
in any game.
After a while
the bombings
and the operations started.
You couldn't cross
without special passes.
So he got these passes.
Ali, Ali, Ali,
you're not a kid anymore.
You know that if I don't
get something real
you won't get your passes
until the year 2050!
Ali, you're forcing me here.
So we got through
another year.
After a year rumors began.
Everyone gave us the eye,
but my dad said,
"Never mind, it'll pass."
I knew it wouldn't pass.
The rumors about my father
reached the Tanzim,
and then it was all over...
no more Nazareth.
And now?
Where?
- In Tulkarem.
- It's shit.
Because of the situation?
Because of everything.
Also in my family.
We're like a ruined family.
Our reputation is ruined.
And for us
a bad reputation is bad.
Can't you clear him?
I can.
But not with a rag.
Are you angry at them...
the Tanzim?
What?
For what they did
to your father, and the soccer.
They?
You're a little girl.
You don't understand anything.
I'm not angry at people
who barely have anything to eat.
I'm angry at...
whomever I'm angry at.
Tarek, wait.
Tarek, wait a minute.
- I didn't mean it.
- Go away.
Go back to your kiosk
and your nonsense.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were angry
at whoever you were.
Do you know who I'm angry at?
At me?
I'm angry at everyone except you.
We're enjoying the great
atmosphere of the stadium,
but first the lineup:
Ayash, Mussa, Keinan
and Lockman in defense.
Our reporter Salah in a short interview
with Nazareth's trainer.
Over to you, Salah.
Salah?
Salah, can you hear me?
We seem to have a technical problem.
We'll try to solve it
in a short while. Meanwhile,
back to the studio for songs.
Hello, Katz.
We have a problem with the recorder.
Could you take a look?
Again? When will you guys buy new ones?
This is older than me.
If we replace them we won't see you.
Be a shame, no?
- Okay. Show me.
- Here.
I'll check it inside.
I'm going to pack.
You're not going
back home now.
No, don't worry.
I'm just taking a few things
for the campfire.
Tarek?
Tarek Rana?
Where did you disappear to?
Where are you?
I'm here.
Goal!
I don't believe it!
Maccabi Nazareth: 1.
Maccabi Tel Aviv: 0.
Where did you disappear to?
I went back to Tulkarem.
Things didn't work out after my injury.
Well, when are you coming back?
I'm not.
What do you mean?
What does your father say?
- About what?
- About soccer.
My father's out of it.
What do you mean?
He's out of it since the injury.
Wait wait, I'll talk to Samir
and tell him you're here.
- Don't bother, Salah.
- What do you mean? Wait.
Hello, Samir?
I'm here with Tarek Rana
from Nazareth.
Remember him?
Sure I remember.
Wait, I'll put you on the air.
I just learned that
our reporter Salah Huri
is talking to someone
who till a year ago
was one of the most promising
junior talents at Nazareth,
and who even played with the club.
Over to you, Salah.
Yes, I'm here with Tarek Rana,
who's been away for a year.
Together we're hearing your
wonderful crowd. Over to you.
Tell Tarek to get well soon.
We haven't forgotten.
Tarek's on the radio.
If he were here with us today
it could have been 2-0
and we could take a breath.
We hope we'll see him on the field
in Nazareth as soon as possible.
What do you say to that, Tarek?
I... was injured.
Thank you, Tarek.
Thank you, Samir.
Back to you.
Thank you.
And thank you, Tarek Rana.
And now back to Bloomfield.
What about your injury?
Did you go to a good doctor?
I know a doctor...
Salah, I wasn't injured.
I know.
My father got into trouble.
We couldn't go to Nazareth.
Who stopped you?
Forget it.
This is too big even for you.
Okay, I'll forget it.
But what now?
Now nothing.
Nothing.
Tarek, I can help you.
Salah, don't you get it?
Of course not.
You're not telling me.
- I got into trouble.
- What trouble?
With the Tanzim.
You know the situation.
Are you working for them?
Terrorist stuff?
- No, are you crazy?
- So what do you do?
I just check.
Sometimes I go in.
How did you get
through the roadblocks?
They got me a pass.
Till when?
Work permit for three months.
Are they watching you?
Yes.
Okay, come to me tomorrow.
We'll see what we can do.
It's hard. I was in trouble.
Come tomorrow. We'll see.
- I'm going away tomorrow.
- You're not going anywhere.
You're a soccer player and
you need to start training gradually.
Promise me you'll come tomorrow.
It's too late. Even if I wanted to,
it's no longer in my hands.
Do you want to?
Maybe I do.
Promise me you'll come.
You'll lose nothing.
Trust me.
I know a lot of people here,
not just soccer people.
Let's see what we can do.
Just come tomorrow.
Promise?
I'll come.
Okay, say hi to your father.
Tell him to invite me to a concert.
I love good music.
He stopped playing,
even stopped watching soccer.
Your father was never
a great soccer fan.
What?
He'd come to the games
with earphones.
"Goals and Songs."
Songs. Songs.
Goals were yours.
He's a violin player.
What is soccer to him?
Thank you very much, Katz.
See you, 'bye.
Messiah, Messiah, Messiah.
Here. Her bike is here.
Keren.
- Keren, come out.
- Keren.
Maybe they can't find us.
They won't come.
Why not? Sure they'll come.
No one will come.
Okay, they're not here. Let's go.
- Yeah, he's right. Let's go.
- Cowards.
There's an Arab with a knife
hanging around, and you want to go?
Okay, you go. I'll stay
and take care of him alone.
- What are you going to do?
- I don't know,
I won't let an Arab
attack me in my own country.
Everything all right?
Are you waiting for someone?
We're waiting for a friend.
I brought lots of food.
What a waste.
Why a waste?
I'm hungry.
I eat like 20 of your friends.
They're not my friends.
I don't have any friends.
I see. I'll take it from here.
Go home. This is no joke.
You'll just be in the way.
We'll deal with this.
I too don't want an Arab
with a knife hanging around,
and whatever else he has.
Go on, go home.
Go home, go home.
Let's go in.
What?
Now?
Let's go in.
You go in.
I'll go in later.
Come on, go in with me.
Okay, so turn around.
Don't peep.
Are you coming?
Not today.
Come on, Tarek.
You only live once. Come on.
Hello.
Mother.
Tarek.
Where are you, son?
We heard you on the radio.
Let me talk to Father.
Your father is a little tired.
He's asleep.
Mother, let me talk to Father.
Father.
Yes?
I saw Salah today.
I know.
Nazareth beat Maccabi Tel Aviv,
made it to the semifinals.
Didn't you hear?
Of course I did.
I heard you, son.
How will this end, Father?
Come back home.
God bless you, son.
Don't worry.
I'll be back soon, God willing.
Everything will be okay.
Father,
take care of yourself.
It's cold.
Who was that?
My father.
Everything okay?
He'll be okay.
I think he'll be okay.
So why are you sad?
I don't know.
I'm not sad.
I'm okay.
You're my friend, aren't you?
I'm your friend.
Hello.
It's Abed. You ready?
What?
In an hour at precisely 8:00,
the entrance to the market.
8:00?
No screw-ups.
You remember last year?
This time it won't pass.
Tarek, don't change your mind.
Remember our talk two days ago...
what you are for us.
I'm not for you or anyone.
8:00, the entrance to the market.
Good morning, Maradona.
Shalom.
Have a good time, Maradona.
He's on his way to the market.
I'm following.
Tarek, I've been waiting
a long time.
Mr. Katz,
please go away.
Want me to go away?
I've been shopping here
for 40 years. You go away.
- I can't.
- You can.
The suspect is wearing a brown jacket...
the third stall on the right.
Mr. Katz, please leave.
Why are you doing this?
- Go away.
- I'm not going anywhere.
I'm with you now wherever you go.
Katz...
What are you going to do?
Kill me?
- You're not going to kill me, I know.
- No.
So you want to kill all these people?
No.
So who do you want to kill?
What are you doing this for?
For my father.
It won't help him.
It will kill him too.
Look at me. Look at me.
You're getting by.
You're okay. You're alive.
I'm not alive.
I'm dead.
Yakir would do
the same for you.
Tarek, when good people die
they kill a lot of people
around them.
The suspect has something under
his shirt. Permission to open fire?
I repeat, permission to open fire?
Why are you doing this?
It won't help him. It'll just kill him.
Look, we'll get out of this.
Your father will too. Trust me.
You know, I had a neighbor
in Romania... Mrs. Popescu.
They said she never
got out of bed in 60 years.
- 66.
- What?
- 66 years.
- Yes yes.
Nothing happened.
He has something
under his shirt.
He's moving his hand
to his sleeve.
Asking again,
permission to fire?
- Come on, kid. Let's go home.
- Permission to fire.
What's this?
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Don't shoot.
A suicide bomber at the entrance
to the Carmel market.
With us is Chief Inspector Shmulik
Dotan, Central District commissioner.
Chief Inspector Dotan,
we were very lucky today,
if one may call it luck.
We're still investigating
the incident.
We'll have answers later.
Meanwhile,
what we do know...
this morning at 8:00
a suicide bomber was shot
before he managed
to detonate his charge.
Apparently one of the bullets
blew up the belt he was wearing.
For reasons we don't know yet,
there were no shrapnel injuries,
as we usually see,
but only victims
of shock and trauma.