(Trey) Look, look, I'm on the
other line right now, so, so...
(Katherine) Just call me
when you get home, all right?
(Trey) Yeah, I'm gonna
call you, all right?
I'm gonna call you.
Yeah, you too.
(Keily) I really wish I could,
but I can't right now, Trey.
It wouldn't be right.
You know
I'm in a relationship.
[phone beeping]
[phone beeps]
[line ringing]
(Trey) Look, I want to
get to know you, all right?
The only thing
I know about you,
that you beautiful
on the outside.
I want to get to know you
on the inside.
Yeah.
[smooth R&B music]
(Keily) Can you believe
how long we've been talking?
I know.
It's been a minute, right?
[phone beeps]
Oh, gosh,
hold on.
It's Sida
on the other line again.
She keeps calling.
I'm going to see
what she wants.
Hello?
(Sida)
Hello!
I've been trying to hit you up
for, like, two hours, girl.
Where-
(Keily)
Sida, come on.
You know what?
Just hold on
for a minute.
Give me a second.
Hold on.
- Hold on.
- Okay.
[phone beeps]
(Keily)
Hello?
Trey, I'd better go.
But can I tell you how much
I've enjoyed our conversation?
(Trey)
Me too.
Look, hope we get to talk
to each other again soon.
(Keily)
We will.
Take care.
(Trey)
All right.
[phone beeps]
(Keily)
Yeah.
(Sida) Uh-huh, so what's
going on with Carlton?
(Keily)
Same old same old.
Yeah, I heard about him
jacking up Trey.
Personally, I hope he beat
his ignorant behind down.
(Keily) Oh, my gosh, Sida,
that was embarrassing.
Is that why you've been
blowing up my phone?
No, I was calling to see if you
wanted to go to the movies,
but since you and Carlton been
tying up the line for two hours,
it's now too late.
(Keily)
Look, I'm tired.
I'm going to just
call it a night.
(Sida) Okay, well, I'll talk
to you in the morning, then.
Bye.
(Keily)
(Sida)
She hung up.
(Carlton)
You sure?
(Sida)
Yes.
(Carlton) Man, why didn't you
ask her who she was talking to?
(Sida) Because then it would
be obvious something's up.
I'm a woman,
remember?
(Carlton)
I'm calling.
(Sida) Carlton,
please don't call her.
Just wait until tomorrow.
She's going to know
I told you.
(Carlton)
All right.
I'm gonna
wait till tomorrow.
But I'm getting tired
of this dude.
(woman)
Ooh, Daddy. Yes, Daddy.
(Vince)
I'm ready to join now.
(woman)
Ooh, Daddy. Yes, Daddy.
Join now.
Take the tour.
(Vince)
Ooh.
(woman)
Join now
or take the tour.
Ooh, Daddy.
Yes, Daddy.
Join now.
(Trey)
What you doing, man?
(Vince)
Uh, nothing.
I'm, um...
I'm online doing research.
What-what-
what do you want, baby?
What's going on?
What's happening?
(woman)
Ooh, Daddy.
(Vince)
Damn.
(woman)
Ooh, Daddy. Ooh, Daddy.
(Vince)
Damn.
(woman)
Yes, Daddy.
(Vince)
Oh, damn it.
(woman)
Join-
(Vince)
I-I-
(Trey)
What's up with the sock, man?
(Vince)
Uh...
Man, I was...
I was doing some research, and-
It's my private time, man.
I...
[Mr. Vickers crying]
(Trey)
Mr. Vickers.
What did Cinque say to you?
(Mr. Vickers) He just told me
about the Tuskegee experiment.
To inject somebody
with a disease
and then use them
as a human guinea pig is monstrous.
I don't understand
why white people are so evil.
I don't understand it.
And it's just not right.
And I just
can't explain it.
I'll be in my room!
(Trey)
Hey, guys.
(K-3)
Yo, it's Trey, dog.
(No Doubt)
Yo, what up, Trey?
My man.
Hey, boy, you heard our stuff
on the radio?
(Trey) Yeah, man, congrats on that.
(K-3) I told you. I told you, man.
I told you.
(Trey)
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yo, didn't get my message?
(K-3)
What message?
(Trey)
To call me.
You didn't
check your voicemail?
(K-3) Hey, Trey, I want you
to meet our new manager, man.
This is Real Rex.
Hey, Rex, this is Trey.
Real Rex.
Are you serious?
(K-3)
Yeah, hey,
did I get a message
from the boy?
(Rex)
Russell, what's up, baby?
All right.
Huh?
Nah, I'm going to need you
to trust me on this one, baby.
Listen, man, come-
Wasn't I right
with Phat Farm?
I told you the Russell way
wouldn't work, right?
Trust me on this, baby.
I got you.
All right?
Tell Run
I like the show too.
All right, baby.
(K-3)
Yo, was that Russell Simmons?
You know Russell Simmons?
I can't believe-
(Rex) What's-what's-
what's this dude name?
(K-3) Oh, okay,
okay. Trey, with a T.
(Rex)
Yeah. Yeah, I got it.
Look, I usually return
the personal calls,
you know, like on Tuesdays
and Thursdays and whatnot.
And, you know-
what's today?
(K-3) It's not
Tuesday or Thursday.
(Rex) I got you,
though, man. I got you.
(Trey)
What is this, K?
(Rex)
It's simple.
I return their personal calls.
I'm their manager.
Now, if you'd like
to email me,
you can hit me on my website,
which is on my business card.
(Vince)
Hold up. Hold up.
What y'all
need a manger for?
(K-3) I mean, you know, for
bookings and press, etcetera,
all that type of...
(Vince)
Dude, you only got one song.
(Trey) You mean I got to talk to
this clown in order to talk to you?
(Rex)
Clown?
Look, I came here
to get some ribs, pork not bull.
You ready?
(Trey)
I was talking to K-3.
(Rex)
Well, carry on.
(Trey) So what,
you about to go too?
(No Doubt)
No, Trey, man. What did you want?
(Trey) I wanted to know
why y'all didn't mention
my uncle name
on the radio.
(No Doubt)
Man, I am so sorry.
We shouldn't
have done that.
We just got caught up
in the hype.
(Rex)
Doubt, come on, man.
(Trey)
Man, talk to K.
(No Doubt) All right,
man, I'm gonna talk to him.
I'm gonna talk to him,
'cause he trippin'.
(Dedra)
You're whipped.
(Katherine)
You think?
(Dedra)
Yeah.
(Katherine) I just-I didn't expect
to care for this young man so deeply.
(Candace)
I think you should've stayed with Roger.
(Katherine)
Really, Candace?
Okay, so what
was I going to do?
Was I going to move to L.A.
with him and his girlfriend?
(Candace) You could've
split the rent three ways.
[laughing]
All right, my bad.
(Dedra) Kat, you let the
window of opportunity close.
I mean, you could've salvaged
that relationship.
But now you're talking about
getting into a relationship
with someone
you can't even relate to.
(Katherine) Okay, my relationship
with my husband was unsalvageable.
I think I have something special
with this young man.
(Dedra)
No, you don't.
It's just physical,
pure and simple.
And you know it is,
'cause that's why you ain't ever
taken him nowhere in public.
(Katherine)
I think I'm in love with him.
(Dedra)
You love the wiener.
(Katherine)
Okay, why are you here?
'Cause you're not helping.
(Dedra)
Oh, but I am.
I'm helping you to see
that you need to take
your emotions out fo this.
(Katherine)
God, I'm trying.
I just can't stop
thinking about him.
(Dedra) I swear I need to be paid
for all these therapy sessions.
Between you and my niece,
I don't know whose situation
is more jacked up.
(Candace)
Kat's.
Definitely Kat's.
All right, I ain't gonna
say nothing else.
[crunching]
(Katherine) Would you
stop chewing so loud?
I can't hear myself think.
(Vince)
What the hell is this?
Hey, man,
that doesn't change anything.
(Trey)
Hey, what's up, man?
You get some
personal satisfaction
out of harassing my uncle?
(man)
I'm just doing my job.
I was just telling your uncle,
only an idiot
walks away from this deal
that's on the table.
(Vince)
You know what?
Don't even trip,
'cause we gonna get the money.
Come on, Trey.
How did you even
get this job anyway?
You don't even speak English.
[man speaking native language]
(Vince) Hey, hey, hey,
I don't understand none of that.
I think you just said
something racist to me.
Don't make me
beat your ass out here.
You know we in the hood,
right?
Hey, hey,
we in America, buddy.
(Trey)
Hey, Unc!
Unc, what is you doing?
(Mack)
Hey, hey, hey.
(Trey)
Get up, man.
(Mack) Hey, man, let me sleep.
What the hell's
wrong with you?
(Trey)
What are you doing, man?
(Trey) Hey, come back
during office hours, man.
(Trey)
What is he-
Hey, Vince, go to the kitchen
and get him some coffee, man.
(Mack)
$30 an hour.
(Trey) Look, Unc, this is a
God dang eviction notice, man.
We got 30 days
to vacate the premises.
Man, I thought
you handled this.
(Mack)
Oh, hey, Trey.
(Trey)
Come on, man.
(Mack)
Hey, man.
They trying to tear
this place down, man,
turn it into a strip mall.
You can't fight the bankers
and the corporate lawyers
and stuff.
(Trey) Yeah, Unc,
look, I understand.
Look, Unc, we got to have 75K
before the 27th.
(Vince) Wait a minute. I got it.
Man, this studio's produced
dozens of stars, right?
I'm pretty sure if we call, uh,
what, the Name Rapper,
Sloth, and the rest of them,
let them know what's going down,
they'd help us out.
We'd charge $25 at the door,
3,000 people.
That's $75,000 right there.
(Trey) You know what? That's it.
That's a good idea.
Hey, yo, Unc,
where your Rolodex at?
(Mack) Oh, it's, uh
- it's in the drawer in the office.
(Trey) All right, hey, let's go
ahead and get started right now.
(Vince)
Wait a minute. Hold on, hold on.
Let's see
if we can get a venue first.
(Trey) Okay, what about
the Rocks by the university?
(Vince)
You know what?
My dad sits on the board.
I know we can swing that.
How much, though?
(Vince)
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
(Trey) All right, let's do that.
(Mack)
Hey, what can I do?
(Vince)
Drink that damn coffee.
(Trey) Look, man,
let me speak to K-3.
Man, no way in hell he'd charge
my uncle anything,
let alone $10,000.
Man, it's only
a benefit concert.
Man, let me speak
to K-3.
Let me speak
to K-3, man.
Can you believe this dude
just hung up on me?
(Mack) Well, hey,
at least we tried.
(Trey) We can just go ahead
and get a DJ to throw the party.
(Vince) Man, we can't pull
3,000 people doing that.
Ain't nobody going to play $25
to see no damn DJ.
I just talked to my dad too.
We got the venue
on the 23rd or the 23th.
(Mack) Hey, maybe we can
have a talent contest,
and the winner gets
free studio time.
(Trey) Unc, they have step shows
and talent shows all the time.
Nobody never show up.
Why would you-
(Carlton)
Hey, baby.
(Keily)
Hi.
I'm guessing you still
a little mad at me.
No, just annoyed.
You're annoyed with me?
Are you serious?
You kidding, right?
(Keily)
No, I'm not kidding.
(Carlton)
All right.
Who were you talking
to last night
on the phone for two hours?
(Keily)
What are you talking about?
(Carlton)
You know what I'm talking about.
(Keily) Did you come over
here to argue with me?
(Carlton) No, I didn't come
over here to argue with you.
(Carlton)
Hi, Miss Dedra.
(Dedra)
Keily, is everything okay?
(Keily)
Yeah, everything's fine.
(Carlton)
Hi, Miss Dedra.
(Dedra)
I heard you.
(Carlton) Why she always
got an attitude with me?
(Keily)
Hm, I don't know.
Maybe you should ask her.
(Carlton)
You know what?
I'm really not feeling
your tone right now.
(Keily)
Okay, I really don't care.
(Carlton) Wait, who do you
think you're talking to?
(Keily)
What do you want, Carlton?
Why'd you come here?
(Carlton) 'Cause I want to
know who you were talking to
from the 6237 number.
(Keily) I really cannot
remember everyone I talk to.
(Carlton) You would if you talked
to him for more than two hours.
(Keily)
I don't know.
It was
probably Sida, then.
You know how we do.
(Carlton)
No, it wasn't.
(Keily) Well, then I was
probably talking to my aunt.
(Carlton)
For two hours?
You lying.
(Keily) I don't have to
answer your questions.
(Carlton)
I'm your man.
You have an obligation to answer
any question I have for you.
(Keily)
How would you possibly know
how long I was talking
on the phone anyway?
(Carlton) Because I
called the phone company.
And between the hours
of 9:37 and 11:16,
you were on the phone
for two hours.
Who were you talking to?
(Keily)
Oh, you want to play FBI now?
Well, it's none
of your damn business.
(Carlton) Girl, everything
with you is my business.
(Keily)
Carlton, you're hurting me.
Stop.
(Carlton) Well, answer
my damn question, then.
(Dedra) Get your sorry-ass
hands off of my niece.
(Carlton) What, you
going to hit me with a-
Oh!
(Dedra) Yeah, get your ass in
your car and get off my street.
(Carlton)
You lucky you a woman.
(Dedra)
Mm-hmm.
(Carlton)
Keily, let's go.
(Dedra)
Keily, what are you doing?
Keily.
[engine turns]
Look, we can't do free shows,
all right?
We don't have a deal yet, man.
I thought we had a deal
with Stick With It Records.
(Rex)
I mean, you know-
Got attorneys to take care-
(No Doubt)
Hold on.
I just don't see
why we can't do the show.
(Rex) Look, we have to be
selective to what gigs that we take.
And doing a free show
is not my idea
of a gig that we need to take
at this time.
(No Doubt) Yeah, but
this is Uncle Mack, man.
(K-3) I mean, dog
does have a point, man.
Mack has helped us.
(Rex) Look, if you want
to live in the past,
then you do you.
I'm trying to get your record
high on the charts,
high as giraffe titties,
but-
[phone playing music]
Hello?
Jigga, what's up, baby?
I mean, Vince Carter
got me a skybox,
but if you want me on the floor
with the team, I mean, hey.
All right, cool.
Hey, did B get the chocolates?
That's what's up.
All right, baby,
I'm gonna hit you later.
All right.
(K-3)
Yo, was that Jay-Z?
(Rex)
Listen.
Listen, listen.
Forget that.
Let's get back to business.
(K-3) All right.
I mean, okay, man.
I'm with you.
You our manager.
It's whatever.
(No Doubt)
We owe Unc.
(Rex) No, you don't
owe Unc nothing.
(No Doubt) K, how many
times we been in the studio,
we didn't have a dime,
and Unc didn't say nothing?
(Rex)
Well, you know what?
When you stack your paper up,
you can pay him back
for all that plus interest.
Until then, there's no room
in this business for emotion.
(No Doubt)
Yeah, but right is right.
(Rex)
No, money is money.
Next subject.
(K-3) Okay, that's
what I'm talking about.
When we gonna get in the studio
and work on the album?
(No Doubt)
Hold on.
I'm doing the show.
(Rex)
You better talk to him.
(No Doubt) Talk to me? Talk to me?
What do you need
to talk to me for, partner?
I make my own decisions.
He don't need
to talk to me.
(K-3)
Chill, man.
Dang, he our manager, man.
We got to start
listening to him.
He was just on the phone
with Jay-Z, man.
(No Doubt) I don't
give a damn about Jay-Z.
I don't give a damn
about Real Rex.
I'm gonna keep it real.
(Rex)
Well, guess what.
You gonna be doing the show
by yourself.
(No Doubt)
Is that right, K?
(K-3) Doubt, man, you got
to be more flexible, baby.
(No Doubt) Oh, you mean
like Uncle Mack was with us?
Is that the kind of flexibility
you talking about?
(Rex)
We not doing the show!
End of story.
(No Doubt)
You know what?
I'm out.
(Rex)
No.
Without K-3,
you nothing.
(No Doubt) Well, I guess
we'll see about that, partner.
Appreciate the love, partner.
(Trey) Hey, so look, I just
got off the phone with No Doubt.
He say he in.
(Vince)
Man, they have one-
all right, not two, not three,
but one marginal record
that plays on the radio
a few times.
Don't nobody even know
who the hell that is.
(Trey)
Look, it's a start.
(Mr. Vickers) I'm willing to let
you use some of my advertising budget
to promote it on the radio.
(Mack) Oh, no, Vick, look, I
don't know if I can pay that back.
(Mr. Vickers) You don't
have to worry about that.
(Cinque)
Payback?
Payback is what
the white infrastructure
really fears, Vick.
(Mrs. Vickers)
Believe that.
(Mack)
Okay.
(Vince) Look, let's
just get to work, okay?
I'll print out the flyers
on my computer.
(Trey)
That's cool.
So I'll start posting them up
around town.
(Vince)
Hey, but check it out.
We only got one artist.
What you want me
to put on the flyer?
(Trey)
Know what?
I'll think of something,
all right?
I'll see you in a minute.
[woman singing]
I have never been stronger.
(Keily)
I'm ready to go home.
(Carlton) Could we please
finish a conversation for once?
(Keily) I knew I shouldn't
have left with you.
(Carlton)
Girl, I'm your man.
You are always supposed to stand
by my side, no matter what.
(Keily)
Oh, beside you.
Yeah, what you mean
is behind you.
I'm ready to go home now,
Carlton.
(Carlton) Sweetheart,
just answer one question.
(Keily)
What is it?
(Carlton)
Be honest.
Who were you talking to
on the phone for almost two hours?
Sweetheart, if you answer that,
I'll take you home.
(Keily)
You know what?
I'll walk.
(Carlton)
What do you think you...
Just answer my question!
(Keily)
You are hurting my arm.
(Carlton)
You cheating on me.
Look, Keily,
I'm sorry, okay?
But, baby, I just can't
bear the thought
of somebody else
being with you.
(Keily)
You are suffocating me.
Can't you see that?
I've had enough,
and I need a break.
Can you understand that?
(Carlton)
Are you serious?
You need a break from me?
Look, I don't know
who this guy is,
but you're getting ready
to lose the best thing
that ever happened to you.
(Keily)
The best thing?
I pray to God that this
is not the best that I can do.
(Carlton) I tried to give
you a chance to tell me,
but I already know
who you were talking to.
Give me this scarf I bought.
Walk, whore.
[woman singing] I done
never been strong as I am.
(Carlton) And tell Trey I said hi.
[woman singing] Could've never
written this song that I can.
'Cause of you,
now I'm labeled a stand away...
(Katherine)
Keily?
Is that you?
(Keily)
Oh, hey.
(Katherine)
Are you crying?
Get in the car.
Come on,
get in the car.
What's wrong?
(Keily) I really don't want
to talk about it right now.
Well, you know-
you know about Carlton and I.
We've been together since I was
a freshman in high school,
and that's basically the only guy
I've ever been with.
It's just that things have been
changing recently,
and he's so manipulative
and possessive.
(Katherine)
Yeah, well, like every man.
Welcome to the real world.
Go on.
(Keily)
Recently, I met a guy.
(Katherine)
Okay.
This is getting good.
(Keily)
He's just a friend.
(Katherine)
Mm-hmm, yeah, right.
A friend.
They all are.
(Keily) I really have
feelings for him, and...
you know, I...
Carlton somehow found out
that we talked, all right?
How he knows,
I have no clue.
But it's like he's a stalker.
He put a bug
on my phone or something.
This boy, tell me
how you feel about him.
(Keily) Well, I fantasize
about him all the time.
Well, you know, I'm kind of
going through the same thing.
[laughs]
You know, I mean,
I think I really love this guy,
but we just don't have
anything in common.
(Keily)
Oh, really?
(Katherine)
Yeah.
I mean,
the sex is outrageous.
[both laugh]
(Katherine) But, you know,
I'm old enough to realize
that sex doesn't define
a relationship.
(Keily)
Very true.
You know,
Carlton and I,
we stopped having sex about,
what, a month ago,
because we just
don't have a connection anymore.
It sucks.
(Katherine)
Trey.
Hey.
(Trey)
Hello, Miss Katherine.
(Katherine)
Miss Katherine?
(Trey)
Hi, Keily.
(Keily)
What are those?
(Trey) These are flyers for the
big party/fundraise on the 23th
that we're having.
(Vince)
Watch this.
Featuring No Doubt.
(Keily)
Who?
(Vince) I told you they didn't
know who the hell that was.
I told your ass.
(Trey)
Later, man.
Y'all don't know
who No Doubt is?
(Keily) That's the one that
goes "Hot water, corn bread,
I said I just got popped
by the feds."
(Trey)
Yeah, yeah.
(Keily)
Good song.
(Trey)
That's them.
(Vince)
Oh, well, in that case,
then you can help us out by passing
these around the campus,
'cause all the proceeds
are going to Trey's uncle's
recording studio.
They trying to shut it down.
Oh, God, they're trying to shut
down Uncle Mack's studio?
(Trey) Yeah, they
trying to shut it down.
But it's all good.
Well, you know what?
Listen, I've got some friends.
I can pass those out.
(Vince)
Please do.
Take all of these.
We need as much help
as we can get, ladies.
(Trey) We really
appreciate this, ladies.
Well, we got to get going.
- Come on, Vin.
- Cool.
(Katherine)
Hey, um, Trey.
Why don't you
let Mr. Vickers know
that I want my usual tonight.
(Trey)
Will do.
Bye, Keily.
(Vince)
She like them damn ribs.
(Keily)
Can I tell you something?
(Katherine) I was just about
to say the same thing to you.
(Keily) All right, well, go first.
(Katherine)
No, you go first.
(Keily) You know the guy
that I was talking up,
about the fantasies
I was having and stuff?
(Katherine)
Yeah?
(Keily)
It's Trey.
(Katherine)
Trey that, um...
that just left here,
Trey?
(Keily)
Yeah.
[Katherine laughs uncomfortably]
Well, he's-
he's gorgeous, girl.
(Keily)
Oh, tell me about it.
I can't
stop thinking about him.
You know, I really...
I really, really want
to get to know him better.
(Katherine) Wow, well, you
know, I think you should
(Keily)
Well, it's your turn.
(Katherine)
My turn what?
(Keily) You remember, you wanted
to tell me something earlier.
(Katherine)
I forgot.
Don't worry about me.
Let's eat.
(Katherine) So Keily's
the unavailable girl?
(Trey)
Yes.
(Katherine)
Wow.
(Trey)
So did you tell her?
(Katherine)
Tell her what?
(Trey)
About us.
(Katherine)
What about us?
(Trey)
That we were-
(Katherine)
That we were or are?
(Trey)
We were lovers.
(Katherine) Okay, so
I never got the memo.
When did we stop
being lovers, Trey?
(Trey)
You know what?
This little attitude,
all this angry-
(Katherine) Trey, you
can't come into my house
and treat me
like a piece of meat.
You can't walk
into my life,
make love to me
a couple of times a week,
and then expect me
not to be emotional.
(Trey) Katherine, just
listen to yourself.
Let me tell you something.
Look, she has a boyfriend.
She's unavailable.
So what difference
does it make?
(Katherine) Keily and Carlton
are no longer attached, all right?
(Trey) What you mean,
they no longer attached?
(Katherine)
They broke up.
(Trey)
Okay, they broke up.
(Katherine) Trey, I'm not
prepared to give you up, okay?
(Trey)
Did you tell her?
(Katherine) No, I didn't
tell her, but that seems to be
the only thing
that you're concerned about.
What about me?
(Trey) Katherine, for
real, you need to calm down.
You got neighbors next door,
all right?
(Katherine)
I don't care!
(Trey)
You already-
Look, look,
why are you playing?
You know
how I feel about-
(Katherine)
No, Trey, I don't.
How do you feel about me?
(Trey) Look, Katherine, I
care deeply for you, all right?
You scaring me right now,
for real.
You really scaring me.
(Katherine) How deeply
do you feel for me?
(Trey) Look, Katherine,
look, look, look.
This is just, like-
honestly,
all I'm saying is-
(Katherine)
How do you feel for Keily?
(Trey)
Listen.
Oh, do you want to know?
For real,
you really want to know?
So you want to act all crazy
and yelling and been-
(Katherine)
Yes!
(Trey)
Listen, listen.
I care for the girl.
I love the girl.
I like the girl.
I want to be
with the girl.
You crying,
and I got to go.
I got to go.
I can't deal with this.
(Katherine)
If you love her so much,
then why are you here
with me?
(Trey) You want to
know why I'm here?
This is why.
These right here,
this little stupid bag that you
always wanted me to deliver,
this damn bag of ribs.
That's what you always
called me for, ribs.
That's why I'm here.
(Katherine) I don't
want the stupid ribs.
I want you.
(Trey)
Why you acting like this?
Why you crying?
[camera clicks]
[camera clicking]
(Trey)
I'm just surprised you called.
(Keily) Well, actually,
I'm outside right now.
(Trey)
You are?
Right now?
For real?
I see you.
(Keily)
I see you too.
Can we go somewhere and talk?
(Trey) Yeah, hold
on one second, okay?
Mr. Vickers,
I got to go, brother.
I'll be back.
I'm coming out.
(Keily)
All right.
(Trey)
How you doing, Keily?
Hi, Sida.
(Sida) Call me if
you have any problems.
Okay?
(Trey)
There won't be no problems, okay?
[woman singing] Lately I feel
like I'm doing this on my own,
like I'm so alone.
Even my shadow
is gone.
I'm trying hard
to focus on what I know.
Hustle and the bustle
on which way
I should go.
I'm tired of watching
my enemies grow strong.
Adversaries get on.
I'm saying
this is hard for me.
I need a word,
a noun, adjective, and verbs.
(Keily)
All right.
Thank you.
[woman singing]
How much longer till the sun comes up?
I'm saying how long?
Till i break free.
How much longer till you rescue me?
Tell me, how long...
Till I get you.
How much longer till I hear from you?
(Trey)
Is it really over?
(Keily)
Yes, it's really over.
(Trey)
I want you, Keily.
I'm just a bit overwhelmed
right now.
You want me
in what way?
(Trey)
I want to be with you.
In what way, Trey?
In every way.
I thought you meant
something else.
(Trey)
Nah, not in that way at all.
I want your smile.
I want to have
your embraces.
I want your kisses.
I want to share your air.
(Keily)
That's so sweet.
That's the most romantic thing
anybody's ever said to me.
I wasn't trying
to be romantic.
I was speaking
from the heart.
Well, I'm gonna
get out of here.
I have a fire to put out on the bridge
I burned with my aunt.
Um...
would it scare you
if I told you that...
that I just-
Don't say it.
(Trey) Let me get the
door for you, though.
Don't worry about that.
Always let a man
open the door.
I got you.
Hey, I think we should do some
old-school reverb on this, man.
That'd be real cool.
(No Doubt)
Yeah.
Yo, I heard the commercial
on the radio.
(Mack) Yeah, man, I heard
it three times yesterday.
Say, dig, man, I really
appreciate what you doing, man.
It's a beautiful thing.
You know, all the time
you been coming here,
I don't even know
your real name.
(No Doubt) You know, I usually
don't tell people my real name.
But you know what I'm saying,
if you can keep a secret,
it's all good.
(Mack) Hey, you
know, man. I'm good.
(No Doubt)
Corky Douglas.
(Mack)
What?
(No Doubt)
Corky Douglas.
(Mack)
Corky Douglas?
[laughing]
Okay, Corky.
I'm going
to call you No Doubt.
(Rex)
Yeah, yeah.
Come on, Weezy.
Weezy, it's just a chorus.
Man, don't worry
about Baby.
I'll take care of that.
All right?
All right, all right,
all right.
(K-3)
Hey, yo, yo.
That as Lil' Wayne
and them?
And Baby?
Yo, you know them?
Damn.
That's cool.
Yo, heard
you was in here.
Hey, listen, man.
You've got to reconsider
doing the show.
(Rex) There's absolutely no
buzz on the streets on this.
You gonna damage
your career.
(No Doubt)
I don't care about that.
I'm a loyalist.
I don't leave my partners
out there when they need me.
(Rex) Man, that spot
gonna be empty, man.
K, you know what?
You need to make a decision
right now,
'cause I'm detecting a problem,
a virus,
in this here
whole program.
I say that we delete
and download another rapper.
(K-3) Yo, I grew up with this man.
(Rex)
Then you can grow apart from him.
We can always find
another No Doubt,
one with "real" skills.
It's either him or me.
(K-3)
Doubt...
man, we need
to start rehearsing.
(Rex)
Brilliant.
You gonna blow a golden
opportunity for this clown.
(Mack) Hey, it's
time for you to leave.
(Rex)
No problem.
I could've done wonders
with y'all limited talent,
but if that's what you want,
then fine.
(K-3)
Man, nah, nah, nah, nah.
It ain't even worth it.
Man, be up out of here.
(Rex) Yeah, all right, tough guy.
But I give you three months,
three months before
you working in a movie theater
tearing up tickets.
Theater 8,
to your right.
Fake-ass Kenan & Kel- looking bastards.
(K-3) Man, you come in here
dressing like chocolate and butter.
(No Doubt)
Shit, let's do it, man.
(Mack) Say, man, let's get to work.
We need to cut
a couple of more hits.
What you got
in your notebook?
(K-3)
Hey, show him the stuff.
(No Doubt)
Oh, man, oh, man.
I got some new stuff, dog.
Look, look, look.
Here goes one.
It's called
Streaks in My Drawers.
[laughing]
Then I got another one
talking about,
I'm Calling In Sick.
[laughing]
(K-3) Yo, Mack, I love these, man.
You got to see where you're
going with them, though.
You got to see
where you're going with them.
Mm.
(Trey)
So look, man.
She going
to the concert with me.
(Vince)
Oh.
So you not at all
worried about Carlton?
(Trey)
Nope.
Not at all, man.
Not at all.
(Vince) Oh, then you must
be in love, then, man.
(Trey) Yeah, I'm gonna
give you that right there.
I love you like a brother
and everything, man.
(Vince)
Oh.
Oh, that's what
I forgot to tell you.
You know I had to break it up
with Bunni, right?
(Trey)
Why?
(Vince)
Man, come to find out,
the broad been squeezing me
for cash the whole time.
(Trey)
Just been squeezing you, huh?
(Vince)
Huh? What?
(Trey)
Nothing, man.
Just nothing at all, man.
You know how it-
Uh, so how'd
she take it, man?
(Vince)
Aw, man, pretty damn hard.
You know, once you get
a dose of this pimping,
hard for them
to go back.
[knock at door]
(Mrs. Vickers)
Excuse me.
Hi.
Honey,
can you watch the front?
Cinque has a customer,
and, well,
your father's a little upset,
and he went to bed.
(Vince)
What's wrong now?
(Mrs. Vickers) Cinque told
him how the Voting Rights Act
has to be renewed
every so often
so blacks can get the vote,
you know?
And your father took it-
took it pretty hard.
(Vince) All right, I'll be
downstairs soon as I put my sock on.
(Mrs. Vickers)
Thank you, baby.
(Trey) Look, man, I'm
gonna go watch the front.
That may
take you a while.
[crackling]
Damn.
You don't even know anything
about this Trey dude.
(Keily)
I know enough.
(Sida)
Hmm.
Well, did you
know about these?
Did he mention that?
(Trey)
Hi, Keily.
Damn.
Keily, just give me
a minute, okay?
Please, please.
(Keily)
There's nothing to say, Trey.
(Trey) Keily, this doesn't
mean nothing, nothing at all.
(Keily) I thought
you were different.
(Trey)
Come on, Keily.
(Katherine)
Hey.
(Keily)
Pick one.
(Katherine)
What-
What are these?
(Keily)
I trusted you.
Why don't you
say something to me?
(Katherine) Keily, how
are you going to leave
before you get the answer
to your question?
(Keily)
No, you betrayed me.
(Katherine) Look, how was I supposed
to know that you had a thing for Trey?
And don't go
blaming this on Trey.
Besides, it doesn't even matter
anymore, 'cause it's over.
(Keily) So he was the guy
you were talking about?
(Katherine)
Yes.
(Keily)
Do you love him?
(Katherine)
I thought I did.
But it's exactly
what I told you.
I mean, we have nothing
in common, nothing.
(Keily) Well, why
would you just sit there
and not say anything to me?
(Katherine) Because, Keily,
I was caught off guard.
I didn't know
what to do.
I had a million things
going through my head.
Look, it doesn't even matter,
because it's not me
that he wants.
It's you.
[man on radio]
Tickets are still available...
(Vince) Boy, tickets
are still available.
(Cinque)
Hey, don't worry about it, fellas.
You'll probably get
a bunch of walk-ups.
You know how people are
at the last minute.
(Vince)
Well, at least we tried.
What's wrong with you?
(Trey)
Nothing.
(Cinque) Look, big fella, I
don't want no problems, all right?
(Carlton) Nah, man we just
here to get some ribs, man.
(Vince)
Just, uh...
Why don't you get over here
to the counter,
and I'll take y'all's order.
What y'all-
What y'all want?
(Carlton) Ain't
nobody going to this.
Trey, what's up, playboy.
All right, look,
I just came to apologize
for my behavior the other day.
I was out of line.
(Trey)
Whatever, man.
(Carlton)
I understand that.
Oh, by the way,
how's my girl?
(Trey)
What girl?
(Carlton)
Oh, come on, man.
Did you get the pictures?
(Vince)
Ooh, get him, Trey!
Hey, get him, man.
All you got to do
is hit him.
(Cinque)
You know what?
(Carlton)
What?
(Cinque) You officially
banned from these premises.
You understand me?
(Vince)
Get his ass up out of here.
Get him up out of here.
Yeah.
(Carlton)
Keily will be back.
These are for you.
(Keily)
I don't want them.
(Carlton) Look, I just want to take
you to the concert tomorrow night.
(Keily) I wouldn't go to
the city dump with you.
(Carlton) You just
trying to make me angry,
and it's not going to work.
Keily, I've changed.
And I want
to prove it to you.
All I need
is one chance.
(Keily) You have run
out of chances, Carlton.
(Carlton) Come on, you cannot be
this serious about this guy Trey.
(Keily) That is none
of your business.
(Carlton) Please don't
talk to me like that.
Like what?
Like I'm some
little child to you, okay?
I'm a man.
I'm a man
that loves you.
And I know
you still love me.
(Keily) That assessment
would be so incorrect.
It's over, Carlton.
No, it's not over, okay?
This guy is sleeping
with your sorer.
You going to lower yourself
to share some trash?
(Keily) What I do should
no longer concern you.
(Carlton)
Keily, open this door, baby.
Keily, I wasn't done talking.
See you just-
Open this door, Keily!
Open this damn door now!
Open the door!
I'm not standing out here!
Get out here now!
Open this damn door!
Oh, come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
[hip-hop music playing]
[dogs barking]
(Cinque) I know they
made some orders.
(Mr. Vickers)
So how's it going out there?
(Vince)
Not too good, pops.
(Mr. Vickers) At least we
don't have any overhead.
(Vince) Yeah, it's a good
thing we didn't put up the money
for the facility;
otherwise, we'd be seriously screwed
right now.
(Trey) Well, look, hey, I
just want to let you guys know,
we grateful
for you guys helping us.
(Cinque)
Oh, wow.
So how's Mack taking it?
(Trey) The way I see it, if God going
to take his business away from him,
He must have
a better plan for him.
(No Doubt)
Yeah, I don't know about y'all,
but I'm starting to get
a little nervous.
You know what I'm saying?
I ain't never performed
in front of no big crowd before.
(Keily) Hi, this is Keily.
I'm not in right now.
Leave a message,
and I'll hit you back.
(Vince)
Hey, you.
Will you get yourself together,
brother?
You already done left
ten messages, man.
When she ready to call you,
she will.
(Trey)
Yeah, you right.
(Vince)
Look, I need you to focus, okay?
The sound people
just called.
They just got there
at The Rocks.
Sound check
is in another hour.
(Trey)
Okay.
(K-3)
We'll be there, man.
(Mack)
Um, listen.
I really want to thank everybody
for their efforts.
I'm truly blessed to have
all of you people in my life.
(Trey)
Oh, my God.
(Vince)
Wow.
(Trey)
Yo, roll the window down.
Open the door.
Hey, what's the line for?
(man) Yo, this is for
No Doubt and them, man.
[all cheering]
(Vince)
That's crazy.
Man, I see where
y'all going with this.
We going to the bank.
[crowd cheering]
[man rapping]
I gotta have.
You the type that could get
all of my cash, my cash,
my bread, my bread,
my cheese, my cheese.
And tonight
you'll be leavin' with me.
So, shorty, come on,
come on.
Let's go,
let's go.
(Vince) Man, I told you I
know how to throw a joint, man.
Diddy don't got nothing
on me.
He learned everything
from me.
I told you, man.
(Trey)
You did, man. You did.
(Vince)
Check it. Check that.
[slow R&B music]
[woman singing]
I think it's safe to say
I don't care anymore.
All the things
that made me crazy
don't affect me
no more.
Oh, listen to me now.
(Trey)
How you doing, Keily?
[Trey mumbles]
[woman singing] It's the I
realize I'm nothing without you,
but with you,
I'm everything good,
everything pure.
If you live in me-
(Carlton)
Hey, stop all that, man.
You embarrassing yourself
with this chump.
(Keily) Wow, Sida, it
was you the whole time?
(Sida) Yeah, well,
your loss is my gain.
(Keily)
No, my loss is your loss...
traitor.
(Sida)
Whatever.
(Trey)
Look, Carlton,
from now on, I'd like you
to cease contact with my woman.
And if you don't,
I'm going to have to-
(Carlton)
You'll do what, bitch?
Get your face ripped off?
(Sida)
Carlton, come on.
Let's go dance, okay?
(Keily) Come on, Trey,
let's get out of here.
(Trey)
That's a wrap, man.
[thud]
(Vince) I told you I was going
to knock his big ass out one day.
I told you,
big man!
Oh, no, no, no.
Get him, get him, him,
and her ass too.
Get her.
Grab her by the back
of the weave.
You can come back
if you give me your number.
Oh, well,
forget you then.
Yeah, take her ass out, then.
What I think about you.
(Mrs. Vickers)
Oh, my gosh.
Honey, are you okay?
Let me see.
Let me see that.
Oh.
(Trey)
I know.
We need to talk.
(Keily)
No, we don't.
I just want to move forward,
not backward, okay?
[DJ over PA]
Now, hold up, hold up, hold up.
I need your attention,
ladies and gentlemen.
It's show time.
It's your man, DJ,
from 97.3.
And I need y'all
to help me out.
Now, when I say "K,"
y'all say "3."
- K.
- 3.
When I say "No,"
y'all say "Doubt."
- No.
- Doubt.
What I want y'all to do
is put your hands in the air
and give it up
for No Doubt and K-3!
[cheers and applause]
[cheers and applause stop]
(Vince)
Oh, snap, they froze up.
[crickets chirping]
[bass drum beating]
[No Doubt rapping]
Hot water, corn bread, I said.
Got popped by the feds.
Now I'm seeing red.
I peed in my bed.
I must be dead.
Yeah, flip-a-tick,
talk the talk
like a clock
with a hole in my sock.
I could kiss a gnat
strapped with my gat.
I hit you with the word,
y'all...
(K-3)
Yeah.
(No Doubt)
Like a ninja turtle,
I talks with the po-po.
But I flow
on the low-low.
And I will get yo-yo.
(K-3)
Yeah.
(No Doubt)
Yo, yo.
(K-3) Do you know where
we going with this?
Do you know
where we going with this?
[hip-hop beat pounding]
[hip-hop music playing]
(Carlton) Where were you
between 7:00 and 7:15?
(Sida) I told you, I
was at my cousin's house.
(Cinque) Listen, so the
No Child Left Behind Act
did the exact opposite of what
it was supposed to do, Vick.
They never funded it,
you know what I'm saying?
It just looked pretty
on paper.
(Mr. Vickers)
He's not finished.
(Cinque)
That's what I'm saying.
It looked pretty on paper.
So young black children
all over America, Vick,
were and are
left behind, man.
You got
to open your eyes, Vick.
You got to see
what's going on in America.
[talking softly]
Hoo.
Oh, yeah.
Oh.
Yeah.
(K-3) We going to the top
with this one baby, yeah.
(No Doubt)
Hot water, corn bread, I said.
Got popped by the feds.
Now I'm seeing red.
I peed in my bed.
I must be dead.
Yeah, flip-a-tick,
talk the talk
like a clock
with a hole in my sock.
I could kiss a gnat
strapped with my gat.
I hit you with the word,
y'all.
(K-3)
Yeah.
(No Doubt)
Like a ninja turtle,
I talks with the po-po.
But I flow
on the low-low.
And I will get yo-yo.
(K-3)
Yeah.
(No Doubt)
Yo, yo.
(K-3) Do you know where
we going with this?
Do you know
where we going with this?
Yeah.
[slow R&B music]
[woman singing]
Yeah.
Uh-huh, yeah.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
Baby, I see you
when you're tired.
Yeah, I know
you're working so hard.
But sometimes
I look in your eyes,
and it's so sad,
it just breaks my heart.
And, baby,
I know that we're struggling.
But that's why
our love's the best part.
Together,
you know we're gonna make it.
We're riding this out
to the top.
Love should be much more
than just a four-letter word.
Yeah, it's the reason
I keep believin'
even when
sometimes it hurts.
It might catch you off guard
and change your breathing
before you know
it has occurred.
But I wonder
if they can't shake the feeling.
So right now,
for what's it's worth,
seeing all that you see me,
the love that's in your eyes
is telling me that you need me.
Before you came along,
all that I had was lonely.
And now
that's all gone away.
You and I together
even when it ain't easy.
The way that it should be.
Baby, you got to believe me.
And when you're down and out,
you know
that you can count on me,
'cause you know
that I see you.
Baby, I see you
when you're trying.
Yeah, I know
you're working so hard.
But sometimes that
look in your eyes
is so sad,
it just breaks my heart.
And, baby,
I know that we're struggling,
but that's why
our love's the best part.
Together,
you know we're gonna make it
We're riding this out
to the top.
Subtitles by LeapinLar