Can we see them?
Overseas Geneva Bank Ltd.
It's time to work.
I'll be right back.
- I lose.
- Stand there.
Yes, sir.
Honor to Kasparov.
Lower your eyes.
Why are you laughing?
What did you say?
I said you look like Danton.
I told you so.
History professor?
No, philosophy.
Same thing.
Have you read Michelet?
Yes, sir.
Do you remember his description
of the Committee of Public Safety?
I don't remember that.
They were third-rate writers
and failed actors.
No one had slept for 3 weeks.
Everyone was crying.
Danton wasn't part of the Committee.
Articulate!
Danton wasn't in it.
He was Minister of Justice.
Turn around.
Bend over.
Lift up your shirts.
You too, Miss.
Oh, what we take up the ass!
Your grandfather?
He's your brother?
They're your sisters?
How about them?
What will it be?
Philosophy will be our girlfriend.
Forever.
Day and night.
Even if she loses her name.
Even in her absence.
A clandestine friend.
We respect what prevents us
from getting close to her...
As we sense
that we're not awake...
And that which is wakeful in us,
even in our sleep,
is due to her difficult friendship.
Farewell, Perdican.
I said to wear a skirt!
Yes, Dad.
Cinema replaces our gaze
with a world
in harmony with our desires.
Water! Only water!
No, it's no good.
Since I'm in the movies,
all I do is wait!
I'm half an f-stop off.
He's the new runner, sir.
I'm asking what this is!
The location, sir.
What are you eyeing, asshole?
Nothing, ma'am.
A pack of Marlboros.
Yes, ma'am.
Stay here!
I'm studying cinema in high school.
Give him a script.
Go have a seat.
The poster.
It'll cost a fortune.
There's money in the sea.
The Hakim brothers taught me that.
What we need is a casino nearby
and a school for Solange.
No problem.
Give me the figures.
- What is this?
- The location.
It's not natural.
Get something else.
Seriously... what's the problem?
Everything. There's not enough water.
It's all wrong.
I was told to keep expenses down.
Let's go.
I'll call the production office.
Don't forget the paychecks.
Who will the actress be?
We'll tell you later.
Here are the pictures.
They're all cows.
What do you think?
Why do cows always look
so grumpy?
lf your breasts were yanked on
four times a day
and you only got fucked once a year,
you'd look grumpy too.
Have you read it?
Yes. In my opinion...
We don't want it!
I don't care about the story!
The title should be "Fatal Bolero"
and the girl should die
in a twister!
Yes, sir.
This must be why I've always felt
a profound sadness in the cinema.
Both a possibility of expression
and the trace of something
essential, renounced.
Butt-fuck me, bastard.
Shove your cock
up the bitch's ass.
Slide your dick up her butt.
Stick your prick...
Place your bets.
-So what's the news?
-Some good, some bad.
I'll be right back.
I found cheap actors.
He's here. He wants money.
Who are these people asking for money?
What have they done?
None of them
has ever sent me a nice letter.
I'll sign two more, then it's over!
We still need... some cash, sir!
Show me that.
Place your bets.
Go sit down.
Did I spell it right?
No!
Place your bets.
Number 36, Baron...
You think so?
Like the Popular Front?
Exactly. Paid vacations.
Long live vacations!
Do your homework!
Number 36.
36, red, even, passe.
Godammit, piss up my crack,
piss up my bung hole!
Give me a raise, Baron.
Butt-fuck me to death !
We found cheap actors.
Go away!
I need cash, sir!
See if they're still breathing.
You're crazy.
How horrible!
Not at all. Didn't Cocteau say:
"The cinema..."
That's right.
There's a woman in here.
A man in here.
We'll meet at the hotel.
Knowledge of the possibility
of representation consoles us
for being enslaved to life.
Knowledge of life
consoles us
for the fact that representation
is but shadow.
No film stock.
- Since when?
- 3 weeks.
I'm half an f-stop off.
I'll take care of it.
We're not tourists.
Why "Fatal"?
There's no use. I can't.
Let's start over, Miss.
It's too hard.
It's because you're acting.
Acting weakens the text.
Acting removes its presence.
It sucks the blood out of it.
You've received money.
It's time to work.
When will you shoot the battle?
There is no battle.
The script!
How about page 121?
Ah yes... you're right.
There... It's done.
Lesson 32.
John Ford. Henry Fonda.
"She Wore a Yellow Ribbon".
I have an idea.
He has an idea!
Don't you care that I love you?
See you tomorrow.
- Can I come in?
- What for?
So I can teach you the rest.
- You're harsh.
- That's how I feel.
Because you've never suffered.
I've made mistakes...
but I've loved.
I don't understand the "Fatal".
Can I ask him?
He won't answer you.
In a novel,
a house or a person
gets all its signification
its very existence,
from the writer.
Here, a house or a person
gets a small amount
of its meaning from me.
It's true signification
is much larger. It's gigantic.
It is to exist here and now,
like you and me,
like no imagined character can exist.
Its immense weight,
its mystery and its dignity
arise from this fact.
The fact that I exist,
me too,
not like in a work of fiction,
but as a human being.
Yes, Dad.
I knew it'd end like this.
Not knowing
where to put the camera.
What do we do?
Put the camera
in front of the actors.
Rolling!
"Bolero Fatal", 52.
Yes, there's more.
Now that I'm unemployed,
during these slow, empty hours
there rises
from the depths of my soul
and... into my mind,
a sadness.
2.8 minus 1/4.
Yes, Dad!
We'll make it easier.
Just say the "Yes" at the beginning.
Yes... sir.
Perfect. That will do.
We weren't rolling.
We're reloading.
We have time.
What's the problem now?
I prefer to die.
Whenever you're ready, Miss.
I'm going to lunch.
I'm staying.
How horrible.
It's what I like in cinema.
A saturation of glorious signs,
bathing in the light
of their absent explanation.
I'm cold!
Fight, Miss.
I am fighting.
Let's go.
Okay.
You're better already.
Yes.
Okay, cut!
The sound's okay!
The camera too!
My master once said:
"I conceive of nothing as infinite.
"How can I conceive
of anything as infinite?"
"Listen," I said.
"Imagine a space,
"and that beyond this space
is more space,
"and farther on,
there's more and more.
"It's never-ending."
"Why," asked my master?
I was stupefied.
"lf it ends," I shouted,
"what's beyond it?"
"lf it ends, beyond it is nothing,"
he answered.
My master was the only philosopher
who was truly sincere.
What's going on?
We're ruined, honey.
They ran off with the money.
Where to?
Now I'll have to work.
No, we have the negative.
What's that for?
We'll make prints
and open the movie fast.
It's in black and white!
No, it's in color.
Dumb bitch,
it's black and white!
lf it's poetry, I'll walk out.
We pay enough taxes as it is.
Look, we'll be able to buy
your Omega.
Not an Omega.
I'm not in the Olympics.
Whatever you want!
Judging by that...
I'll end up with a Swatch.
Is your husband here?
It's Mr Felix!
Quiet. Keep working.
Does it start soon?
lf it doesn't, I'm leaving.
It's in black and white.
I hope it's not poetry.
It looks like a winner!
Why "Fatal"?
It's the name of a war.
We lost many friends.
Your fucking movie
is full of corpses?
- Not exactly.
- The cinema is all about waiting!
Shut up!
Sorry, kid. There are no tits!
Miss, you'll see.
What's the movie about?
The photography is gorgeous,
you'll see, Miss.
Are there any boobs?
- No, no boobs.
- Any knockers?
Your grandmother used that word.
No knockers!
Get lost, dickwad!
Get that asshole out of here!
Beat it, little prick!
Let's go see "Terminator 4".
Come back, friends! Come back!
We'll change the movie!
Where's the mistake?
Mother and I told you,
you have to turn the page.
Justice prevails.
I knew it.
Try it as a farewell to the tutti
and an invitation to the solo.
It's another world.
Built up from nothing,
then come back to nothing.
Let's begin.
Yes, Governor.
I prefer Wagner.
Not Wagner!
You'd hear him at the bottom of the sea!
Whereas Mozart...
It's gentle and light.
That's what people think.
Let's begin.
Yes, Governor.
Too many notes in Mozart.
That's what people think.