- You like it?
- All right.
I need to go. My dad's here.
- I'll see you tonight.
- Yeah.
This is the dress. Do you like it?
We've got to hurry. Everyone's going.
There's only two left in my size.
Come on, Dad, let's go.
When do I meet him?
His name's Chappy.
On the football team and very...
- Chubby?
- Chappy.
You'll meet when he picks me up
for the dance.
Not before?
Dad, you really need to go faster.
Will he drive you to the dance?
He's rented a limo.
So he won't drive you?
Limos come with drivers. So stop worrying.
It's a nice dress. You'll be very pretty.
I want you to like it.
- I'm getting out.
- No, no, no. Wait until I park.
Everyone's already inside.
Fan, careful crossing the street!
You stupid...
Metro desk, Ian Wood.
Listen carefully.
An action wing of the Authentic IRA
has just exploded a bomb
at the OBT Bank in Knightsbridge.
The code word is "Phoenix."
Britain's banks are now targets
for the Authentic IRA.
The bombings will continue as long as
Britain's financial criminal institutions
persist in their support of the illegal
occupation of Northern Ireland.
A bomb just went off,
an OBT Bank in Knightsbridge.
A group called the Authentic IRA just
phoned it in. They're claiming credit.
Who's the Authentic IRA?
No idea. Never heard of them.
Christ. There goes the Peace Accord
right back in the shit.
Listen up. A bank has just
been bombed in Knightsbridge.
A group calling itself
the Authentic IRA just phoned it in.
I want to know who they are,
who's behind them.
Call the Met, Sinn Fein,
monitor the blogs.
Is it the IRA or is it something else?
ISIS? Al-Qaeda?
What are you waiting for? Get over there.
...have asked
a number of police officials
for current estimates
on the dead and wounded...
This is a major incident
that they're treating
as a possible terrorist attack.
The bomb went off at exactly...
...4:15 GMT in Knightsbridge.
One theory on the cause of the blast
was that it may have been
a gasoline explosion underground.
How many? How many I get?
Twelve dead so far,
three times as many injured.
The explosion was centered
at the OBT Bank Branch in Knightsbridge.
There was no warning and police
were taken completely by surprise.
Fuck warnings. That'll teach 'em.
Any problems?
- No.
- We should be moving.
That's normal procedure.
Every cop, hotel, and landlady in London
is now looking for the Irishman.
This place is safe,
so long as we stay put.
Could I go to jail
if I murdered your phone?
Destruction of government property?
Absolutely.
Too bad. What's the time?
Almost 10:00. Ten more minutes.
Um, I'll miss my flight.
Let's stay here,
door locked, blinds down...
Room service for a week.
Sound good?
And your work, Deputy Minister?
An acute case of food poisoning.
You need to work on your excuses, darling.
Jesus Christ.
There's been an IRA bombing in London.
Scores dead and injured.
- Yes?
- Jesus, Liam.
Half the world's trying to find you.
Do you even know what's happened?
Yes, yes, yes, I heard.
I've been trying you for hours.
Where've you been?
Meetings.
- Meetings?
- Aye.
And last night?
You didn't come home. I was worried.
Came in late, left early.
Lot of work to catch up on.
But the guest room wasn't slept in.
Who said I slept?
Oh, cut the crap, Liam.
You didn't come home, plain and simple.
And what if I didn't!
Look, I've got a lot to deal with, OK?
So, don't wait up, and don't be worried.
Sunday is the 20th anniversary
of my brother's death.
Saint Mary's is dedicating
a mass to him, so...
I'll have Beth put it in the calendar, OK?
We'll talk later.
Oh, Jesus.
Yes, I understand
the need for swift action.
But until we can identify the threat,
there's not much we can do.
Well, you have your finger
on the pulse over there, Liam.
We're depending on you.
Anything you can provide, anything at all,
would be a tremendous help.
I'm meeting the Council now.
I'll shake the trees as hard
as I can and see what falls.
But, Kate, this is crucial.
We've managed to keep the lid on this
for 19 years now.
But there are new upstarts in the ranks
pressing for the way things were.
I could use something now.
And you know what I'm referring to.
The Royal Pardons.
I remember your list, the 40 "On-the-Runs."
Are we really back to that?
My cousin's on that list.
He hasn't even been convicted
of any paramilitary offenses.
These people are suspects
in many things, including murder.
These people are critical
to holding the peace together now.
A few letters of pardon
would be a small gesture.
We keep it quiet.
But knowing it's been considered,
gives me leeway
to press certain men
for something in return.
As Irish Deputy Minister,
you have served the British
government honorably,
which hasn't always been easy.
But appeasement is a dangerous thing.
These are longstanding issues.
That if addressed now
would smack of appeasement.
I need something, Kate.
The newer members haven't
lived the bloodshed and are easily swayed.
I'm trying to hold this together.
A gesture is all.
It would make a difference.
I'll consider it.
But I want something first,
something real.
Understood.
Hello?
We're closed. We open at 12:00.
Uh, we're looking for the owner,
a Mr. Quin Minh?
Quan.
Upstairs.
They were found on site,
not far from your daughter's body.
Can you positively identify them as hers?
Who did this?
As of now, sir, we don't know,
but we're going to find out.
Why my daughter?
Is there someone we can call
to come and be with you, Mr. Quan?
I have no more family.
These bombers, will you catch them?
Yes.
Will they get punished?
Yes, they certainly will.
We'll let ourselves out.
Ah, good morning, Hugh. Thanks for coming.
Been a long time, Liam.
It's been a long time, indeed.
Go on, take a chair, there.
All right, Hugh?
Now that we're all here,
does anyone know
who this Authentic IRA is?
Are they even part of the IRA?
Some new upstarts
or something else entirely? Hmm?
They're trying to undermine everything
we've achieved over the last 19 years.
Well, I won't have it.
They don't have the support of the people
who said no to the violence.
Our mandate's to uphold that choice
and maintain the Peace Accord
no matter what.
Are we in agreement?
There's a lot of support for their actions
amongst the younger ranks.
Hotheads.
Hotheads who don't remember
or know any better.
You were once one of those hotheads, Liam.
Aye.
Long ago, when it was the only way.
And what did it give us?
More graves than I care to remember.
This bombing rivals Omagh
with its civilian deaths.
It's unacceptable, anytime, anywhere!
And do you think the bombers
come from our ranks?
The Brits ID'd the explosive.
Czech-made Semtex from our dumps.
They also used our code word.
Which means they have
a contact in our command.
Maybe someone in this room.
They're trying to divide us,
put the Brits back on the streets again,
stir up the troubles all over again.
Well, I won't have it!
I want a complete check
of all the arms dumps here and abroad,
everything verified,
guns, Semtex, the whole fuckin' lot.
- Jesus, you can't be serious.
- Never been more so, Patty.
We check 'em, and if something's missing,
we trace it back
to those who knew the location.
And then we deal with this internally.
Unless someone here's got a better idea.
What do we get in return?
Peace.
Is that so bad, Brennan?
Haven't you paid enough in family blood?
So, unless you all
want to trash what we have,
I need your full support and respect.
I want a complete list
of all the stocks within the week,
along with their locations,
and everyone who knows where they are.
And no fuckin' exceptions!
Show me.
We backtracked 47 minutes.
Clearly anticipated the CCTV.
He circled London for quite some time
prior to the bombing.
Now, this is the first
CC feed we have on him.
Heading southbound on the A413
near Wendover at 10:53 a.m.
We retrieved the serial number
from the bike's frame.
It was reported stolen
in Reading the night before.
The license plates were also stolen
from another bike in Reading.
What about phone calls?
Assuming that the bomb
was phone-activated,
we've dumped the five closest towers
to the blast zone
trying to ID any call terminating
at the time of the incident.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Yup.
For you.
- Bromley.
- He's here again, sir.
- The Chinese man.
- What?
The Chinaman.
It's five days in a row, now.
Christ. Tell him I'm busy.
I did, and he said he'd wait, again.
I assure you, this investigation
is our top priority, Mr. Quan.
And we're doing all we can
and pursuing every possible lead
to find those who killed your daughter.
But they're a difficult people to catch.
And it may take some time.
I need you to understand that.
You must catch these men,
Commander Bromley.
Again, it's our top priority.
Twenty thousand pound.
All I have for the names of the bombers.
- I'm sorry, but we can't take this.
- Then please tell me...
Just give me the name
of someone in the IRA.
To be clear, these are vicious men
who take pride in their atrocities.
Any attempt by you to contact them
is likely to end very badly.
This is our work, not yours.
You need to be patient.
How long have you been
in this country, Mr. Quan?
Since 1984. I'm a British citizen.
You were born in Guangxi, China.
Yes. I'm Chinese Nung.
I work in Saigon after the war.
We escaped to Singapore.
Then we immigrate here.
You had two daughters
before Fan.
Both killed during the escape.
And your wife?
Where is she now?
She died, giving birth to Fan.
I'm truly sorry for your loss.
But you mustn't keep coming here
on a daily basis.
It doesn't help, and diverts time
and resources from our investigation.
Do you understand?
Yes. I understand.
Thank you for seeing me,
Commander Bromley.
After three weeks
of investigations,
there's little in the way
of solid leads that I'm aware of.
The public is looking for reassurance.
One leading politician
who somberly may have answers,
lies uncomfortably
at the center of this storm.
We go now to an interview
I recorded earlier in Belfast
with Deputy Minister Liam Hennessy.
Deputy Minister Hennessy,
you've publicly condemned the bombings.
Yet, as a former leader of Sinn Fein
and a member of the IRA,
you took part in similar events years ago.
What's the essential difference between
those acts you were involved in then
and what's happened in London recently?
Hope. We had none,
just years of vengeance.
We needed to break the cycle,
so we committed
to a political path which lead to...
So, if you say "hope,"
why are these IRA men,
who come from your own ranks,
returning to the bombings?
I can say with reasonable certainty
that the IRA are not behind this.
They stand firmly behind
the agreement and the promises...
So, you're saying
possibly it's a financial problem
rather than a political one.
People look for scapegoats, for a way out.
And for some, they are more than happy
to resort to violence,
to upset the status quo.
Prepared for your signature.
They absolutely must be signed now.
What's the latest reaction
on social media?
Same as before. Fear and anger.
Anger directed at whom?
From the Prime Minister on down.
CNN and The Irish Times
want interviews with you.
You can do tonight
or tomorrow morning at 8:00.
Tomorrow morning by phone. What else?
You've a call waitin' on Line Two.
- Waiting?
- For 30 minutes now.
A Mr. Quan from London, very insistent.
- What does he want?
- His daughter was killed in the bombing.
I tried my best to console him,
but he really just wants to speak to you.
- He saw ya on TV.
- Oh, Christ, Beth.
Civic duty. Take it and be done.
This is Liam Hennessy. How may I help you?
Mr. Hennessy,
tell me who killed my daughter?
What on Earth makes you think
I know who killed your daughter?
Because, you are the First Deputy Minister
and advisor to Sinn Fein,
and a former IRA member.
I am truly sad for your loss, Mr. Quan.
I have a daughter myself.
And I condemn these acts of violence,
but I can't help you.
Then please tell me someone
who might know the names of the bombers,
someone I can talk to.
I don't have any connections
to those sorts of people. I'm sorry.
I don't believe you, Mr. Hennessy.
You are very powerful man.
Well, I work for the government
and our elected officials.
I do not work for terrorists.
IRA politics and terrorism
are different ends of the same snake.
Whichever end you grab,
you still grab a snake.
It makes a great deal
of difference which end you grab,
because one end will bite.
Again, I'm sorry for your loss, Mr. Quan.
Good day.
You have a room?
These are important documents
that we must have today.
Yes, I will keep trying
the sender because,
apparently there's nothing else I can do,
which I find strange
and certainly not the service
I've come to expect.
Yes, 329174-N for November.
You tell your supervisor
I'll be calling back.
Good day.
Yes? May I help you?
Please, I would like to
speak to Mr. Hennessy.
- And your name?
- Ngoc Minh Quan.
You're the one who's been phoning.
Yes. I phoned many times.
I'm afraid the Deputy Minister is busy
and won't be able to see you.
- I will wait.
- No, you must leave.
Best do as the lady says.
He's been phoning up
at all hours asking for Liam.
He won't take no for an answer.
Just groceries.
Go now, before we make ya.
- No. I'm wait.
- Right.
It's the man who's been
phoning you from London.
He's got a knife on him.
One of those Swiss Army types.
Well, take it off him.
Jesus, how much damage
can he do with you two around?
Let him be.
As I explained before...
...I don't know who the bombers are.
I realize you're angry,
but there's not much I can do.
It's also very dangerous
for you to be here.
People in Belfast
won't take kindly to your accusations.
If you do not know who they are,
I would like you to please find out.
I haven't been affiliated
with the IRA for 30 years.
When I was,
I fought hard against the violence.
I went to prison
for what I did and paid my debt.
Now I serve the politics of both sides,
trying to heal the wounds
and bridge the divide.
Again, my sincere condolences,
but there's nothing I can do.
What if your wife and daughter
were killed by bomb?
I'd do everything in my power
to get justice.
So, I've chosen you, Mr. Hennessy.
You will tell me who killed my child.
Again, I don't know.
You will change your mind.
Thank you for seeing me,
First Minister Hennessy.
I'm sorry, Liam. He took me by surprise.
You're OK, Beth. OK, you're OK.
Take her, take her.
- Murphy, have the boys check the building.
- Right.
Jesus.
Would you like a whiskey, Inspector?
No, thank you.
I suppose it would be a waste of time
asking who might've done this.
No one comes to mind.
Well, it appears to have been
nothing more than a warning.
Fortunately, it wasn't a serious bomb.
If it had been, we wouldn't
be here talking, would we?
Feel free to reach out,
should you have the unexpected urge.
I'll feed the press a gas leak story
in the meantime.
Fair enough. Thanks very much, Inspector.
Hello?
It's him.
You come to my office
and plant a fucking bomb?
- Have you changed your mind?
- Changed my mind?
Are you out of your fuckin' tree?
You have no idea who you're dealing with.
But you'll soon find out.
Give me the names.
I'll tell you what.
Let's meet face-to-face.
We'll settle...
The fuckin' wanker
threatened me and hung up.
Right. Let's check all the hotels
and guest houses.
He won't be hard to find.
Fuckin' Chinaman.
Uncle Liam? What's up?
I'll be there.
Stop! Hold it, hold it,
hold it! Don't move!
Don't move! She's wired to blow!
Two sets of wires
ten-foot long,
soldered to that light bulb
and covered with ground-up match heads.
Gives an extra kick.
Not needed, but a nice touch.
Crude, effective, and easy to spot.
So, he wanted us to see it.
Well, it wasn't in the tank,
so it wouldn't have worked.
He just wants you to know
he can get to ya.
Micky.
We found him.
A B&B in Wellington Park.
- They found him.
- Grab him.
Drag him out of Belfast.
Discourage him from returning.
Wait for me. I'm on my way.
Hello.
I hear your office was bombed.
Hardly.
It was the toilet in the hall.
An Asian man in his 60s with a grudge.
It's all being taken care of.
Why'd he do it?
His child died in the bank bombing.
He thinks I know who did it.
He's not the only one of that mind.
- So, where are we with the pardons?
- Lots of resistance.
But, if you give us something useful,
things might turn in your favor.
I may have a lead. I'm pursuing it.
Well, let's hope it bears fruit.
People here want heads.
The dogs won't stay leashed much longer.
Top floor on the right.
Fuckin' get him!
Christ Almighty,
are you dumb and blind?
An old man making fools
out of the lot of you
and he's still running around
out there, for God's sake.
You are four men. Four.
We had him cornered,
then he jumped off the roof
and slid down like some fuckin' monkey.
What is goin' on?
Pack your bag. You're going to the farm.
Go on.
Get your things.
- You all right, Sean?
- Hi, Christy.
Go on through, he's expecting ya.
Beat ya up. Come on in
and have a drink, for God's sake.
Well, look at ya.
- Jesus, the place looks well.
- It's not bad, is it?
- No.
- You're a sight for sore eyes.
So, how is New York treatin' ya?
- Ah, it's cold.
- Uh-huh.
Look, Murphy filled me in, there.
That bloody Chinaman.
He set off a bomb in my office,
put one in my Jag, and beat the bejesus
out of Mick and Jimmy.
- Do you want me to handle him?
- No. That's Kavanagh's problem.
I need your help with the London bombing.
Any idea who's behind it yet?
Not at all.
- Well, the Yanks aren't happy, Liam.
- Mm...
Dead women and kids
all over the news.
Any fundraising now is impossible.
Yeah, this is not about fundraising, Sean.
I need you to go to London
and meet someone...
A Richard Bromley in SO15.
SO15?
He needs to know the bombings aren't ours,
and that we're working the problem hard,
but we need his help.
Why me?
You're a decorated Ranger
in the Royal Irish Regiment.
Bromley will respect you as much
as he's capable of respecting any of us.
Should anyone find out
that we're talking to the Brits,
to go after one of our own, rogue or not,
there'll be the devil to pay.
So, can I count on you, Sean...
to be discreet?
Of course.
Right this way, sir.
Thank you very much.
You took your time.
I just had to put out
the odd fire here and there.
I'll be back in a minute.
I'll be right here.
Jesus.
Mr. Morrison.
Commander Bromley.
- We're not responsible.
- Really?
Forensic evidence and the use
of your code word suggests otherwise.
It's a renegade unit.
We don't know who they are yet.
You're telling me
there's an active IRA unit
on the loose you know nothing about?
Yes, I am.
And the Semtex?
They're raiding our dumps.
Dumps that were
all given up for the Accord?
And your code word?
They're being helped by someone
in our command, Belfast or Dublin.
So, what do you want, Mr. Morrison?
We've a plan.
Different codes will be given
to each member of command.
When the bombers claim credit
for the next attack,
you'll tell us which word they use.
Then we'll know who gave
the orders and then we end it.
Who else is involved in this plan?
Liam Hennessy.
So, you can appreciate
the need for discretion.
Only Liam knows
who will be given which word.
So, Hennessy will personally work with us
to take out an IRA cell?
- A rogue cell.
- Your people, nonetheless.
I've one condition.
When Hennessy finds the bombers,
he tells me directly.
Then we take them down. Not you.
This is non-negotiable.
We found some plastic bags in his room.
Based on what I saw,
he's brewed up some nitroglycerin,
mixed it with weed killer, packed it
into some plastic plumbing pipes.
How much damage can he do?
I'm guessing he's made four bombs,
each enough to blow up a lorry.
Jesus.
Knows what he's doing.
I've half the city looking for him.
When he surfaces in Belfast,
we'll find him.
You'll be safe here.
Aye. I wouldn't count on it.
Benny!
Jesus Christ!
Move it! Move it!
Jesus. He roughed up Benny and Sean.
They'll be fine.
Get more men from Belfast.
I've underestimated him.
It won't happen again.
It's another warning, Liam?
Aye. Nothing I can't handle.
First Belfast, now here.
How in God's name
are you handling anything?
The problem's being dealt with.
He is destroying our farmhouse,
intent on God knows what,
and you're calling it a problem?
God, you can be so pompous sometimes.
I'm leaving for London.
Gonna stay at Keri's.
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
Well, I wasn't asking for your permission.
He's hardly likely to know
about our daughter's flat, and besides,
it's you he's after, not me.
Well, the point is,
if he knows about the farmhouse,
I assume he knows about Keri's flat.
It's not worth the risk.
Well then, you're just gonna
have to handle it, like you said.
I remember a time when you would've
dealt with this, properly,
and other things, too.
But those days are gone.
Weighs a bit more,
but shouldn't be noticeable.
All I'm adding is the Semtex,
a micro-chip and a few inches of wire.
It looks good.
Tricky part will be getting it through
the scanner, but, we'll find a way.
And if it's turned on?
Shorter battery life,
but it'll work, no problem.
Any idea which plane yet?
No. We don't want to hit a flight
with any Irish on board.
One in the queen's fleet'd be best.
We just need the right mule.
Code word has changed...
As of tonight.
My news editor's a complete twat.
Spends as much on a pair of shoes as I get
for eight hours writing crap like this.
Makes perfect sense.
Who doesn't like a new pair of sexy shoes?
You should try a real whiskey.
Two Jamesons, single malt.
"Wife Attacks
Husband's Transgender Lover."
Some serious news you're writing there.
Well, if it pays, I'll write it.
Beats being knee-deep
in a bloody bomb site.
- So, what do you do?
- Wealth management.
I'm Maggie.
Ian.
All right.
I'll call if we need more.
- Thanks, Mary.
- All right, thanks. Bye.
Six more men
are on their way from Belfast.
When they get here, they'll relieve
the fellas who've been up all night.
Is it enough to secure the farm?
Secure as it can be.
It's 20 total working two shifts.
All right. You're flying
to London today with Mary.
- Right, yeah.
- That's completely unnecessary.
Get her into Keri's flat,
then move them into a hotel.
I can manage this, all right?
I'll not be debating this!
Nick's gonna fill up the Jag.
You're leaving...
Take him to the hospital.
- Get Mary to the airport. Go.
- Right.
Buried nitro bomb, detonated by remote.
He needed a line of sight.
Those woods, that's where I'd be.
- Go.
- Sean! Mick! Get in the car.
Go, go, go!
Come on. Go, go, go!
You guys spread out.
I'll take the high ground.
Names!
Jesus Christ!
One ol' man running circles
around the lot of us.
Why is it so hard?
He's ahead of us every step of the way.
We need more men.
We need 100 more men, at least.
And if we did that,
we'd have the whole of Belfast against us.
Bring in a tracker,
someone who knows the woods,
and beat him at his own game.
My nephew?
Aye. If you can spare him.
Come on.
How's Keri? Where is she?
Out.
You're a wee bit early,
but I'm nearly ready.
Have you a restaurant in mind?
Haven't given it much thought.
So, what urgencies
bring my nephew all the way to London?
A few personal matters.
I'm glad I made the list.
Mm. I think that works.
What do you think?
You've gotta be kiddin'.
- Liam?
- Tell Bromley I'll accept his terms.
I'll pass it on.
I've given out the code words.
Now we wait.
Quan hit us again.
Blew up the Jag,
put Billy in the hospital.
Kavanagh and the boys went after him.
The wee shitey injured three more men.
Punji sticks, if you can believe that.
Liam, it sounds like he's trained.
Maybe Special Forces.
Which brings me to the point.
I need a tracker, Sean.
Can you give us a hand?
- I'll take a morning flight.
- Good man.
Hey. How'd he sound?
Worried.
He's got a lot going on.
Well, if he doesn't
find the bombers, the Accord's dead.
And politically, so's he.
Do you think he'll find them?
Yeah, if there's another blast.
The code word will lead us to
who's running them.
He's finished.
The code word won't save him.
What the Council needs is new blood...
someone stronger, like you.
He's afraid to use his power.
He's just a washed-up old man
trying to hold onto whatever he can.
I've never forgiven him
for my brother Patrick.
Liam found out who killed him.
A UVF death squad. Four men.
I told Liam to kill them
before they got to court.
But he said no.
That the time for revenge is past.
So, my Patrick is dead and buried,
and they're sitting in jail now,
all four of them,
taking classes at the open university.
It's not right. It's not.
Hugh McGrath's here.
I heard you're checking my dumps.
We're checking everyone's. No exceptions.
Four came up short. Two were yours.
Ten kilos of Semtex missing.
What in God's name are you doing?
My dumps were off-limits.
We were clear in that. Remember?
You were at the meeting.
If you knew they were short,
you should've handled it.
They were in perfect order.
I checked 'em myself, and that's a fact.
Christ, Liam, so the committee
knows it's my Semtex?
Don't know who we can
trust anymore. Do we?
Trust, or fear?
In your case, mostly fear.
Simple and brutal, like my da taught me.
Look, we have an opportunity here, Liam,
if you take the lead.
This Chinaman isn't helping matters,
but let me get some locals
to hunt him down.
- How much do you know?
- Plenty.
Bomb in your office. Your farm. Your car.
Mary and your daughter hiding out
in a London hotel, a bloody mess, it is.
And the men sense weakness, as do the UVF.
You should be back in Belfast,
out in front, taking charge.
- Look, I'm no politician...
- What're you trying to say?
The bombing.
A few quiet words of encouragement
would soothe the ranks.
"Encouragement"?
They kill civilians by the buckets.
They went a bit far, I know,
but they have given us real momentum.
The Brits are on the ropes.
Jesus Christ, I said hit a few
financial targets. That's it.
No one gets hurt.
That's what we agreed to.
- You gave me your word.
- And by God, I kept it.
I don't know who they are,
don't even know who's controlling 'em.
And that's the way it has to be.
Because, if something goes wrong,
they could trace 'em straight back to us.
Go wrong? This wasn't the fuckin' plan.
I needed this to get our people back.
- You and I have spent our whole lifetime...
- You don't give a shit about those men.
You needed the bombing
to shore up the election,
to prop up your weakness in the ranks.
Well, guess what?
In the fog o' war, plans fuckin' change.
Now, I stood by you
when you put fire into the lads.
M62, Aldershot, Mountbatten.
You were calling for an escalation then,
right enough.
Those days are long gone!
That's not what I heard a few months ago.
I heard the old Liam,
a man back on track with a plan.
You haven't forgotten
what we're fighting for, have ya?
You question my loyalty?
I buried my brother-in-law,
before that my da and my two cousins.
We spilt our fair share of blood
struggling for united Ireland,
not profiting off a divided one.
So, don't fucking go asking me again
if I've forgotten what we're fighting for.
If there's anyone profiteering
around here, it's you,
sitting in your fancy houses,
cozying up to the Brits.
You're not the Liam I once knew.
You want the old me, huh?
The Butcher of the Bogside,
is that what you want?
Well then, hear this.
You reel in those fuckin' cunts
and end it,
or by God, I'll bury the lot of yas.
Right. I'm going now.
I'll be at my farm if you need me.
And take care of that Committee issue.
We don't want them jumping to the wrong
conclusion about that Semtex. Do we?
Yeah.
Do you or any of the men know
where Mary's staying in London?
No. No one, but Murphy.
Hmm. McGrath knows where she's hiding.
I wanna know how.
What a day, Charlie.
What a day. Come on now, let's go.
Come on, Charlie, up you get.
Charlie.
You killed my dog?
Dog's fine. Just sleeping.
Sit.
I'm wearing a bomb.
Anyone comes in,
I touch it one, then we die.
Now, give me the names.
They claim they're the IRA,
but I don't know who they really are.
I'm doing everything I can
to find out who's responsible.
You're lying! Who killed my daughter?
I'm sorry. I truly don't know yet.
The explosives the bombers use,
it's Semtex-H?
Yes. Yes. You know about Semtex?
I know Semtex-H.
During the war,
Czechs make for the Viet Cong.
Good for bombs and traps.
- In Vietnam?
- Yes.
Many American people died by Semtex-H.
Now, IRA use to kill my daughter.
That's ironic.
I've read your history.
We both know about war.
We've both tried to put it behind us.
You and me, we're alike.
We are nothing alike. You're nothing!
You kill women and children! Names!
To Almighty God, I don't know!
Wait! Wait. I've set a trap for them
when they use the next bomb.
When they claim responsibility
for the next bombing,
they'll use a code word,
telling the police they're IRA.
I've changed that code word.
So, when they use it, I'll know.
You have one day.
What if they don't set off a bomb by then?
Twenty-four hours.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, Jesus. Sweet Jesus.
We missed it the first time...
But ran a reconfiguration through RAPTOR,
and the image's anomalies
and architecture became more apparent.
Now there, look, the back of his hand.
- Hmm.
- Looks like a burn or a birthmark.
We're running comparatives now.
So, it's a bit more time,
but we'll get it.
Come on. Come on.
OK.
There you go.
- Good morning, Sean. Thanks for coming.
- Are you all right?
Well, I've been better.
There's been another bombing.
- Yeah, I just heard.
- Aye, a London bus.
- Has Bromley phoned?
- No. Not yet.
McGrath's on his way with some locals.
They'll give ya a hand.
No, I don't need them. I'll handle it.
Good man.
Hennessy.
They called, but didn't give a code word.
What the hell's going on?
Maybe it wasn't them.
Press Association took the call.
A man with an Irish accent said
there'd be no more fuckin' cooperation
with the Brits and no more code words.
He knew exactly which bus
and how much explosive was used.
And it's been ID'd as your Semtex again.
Either someone talked,
warned them off, or you're playing me.
Only two people knew what was happening...
Myself and Morrison.
Like I said, one of you can't be trusted.
Send me a number where
I can reach you day or night.
I'll call the moment I have something.
It better be soon,
or you'll feel a backlash the likes
of which you've never felt before.
A bus now.
For God's sake,
16 dead, twice that injured.
I'm sorry.
I had a plan to nail the bastards.
Didn't work.
I've just come
from Downing Street.
The PM will consider the pardons,
but only if you give up
the bombers immediately.
And how in God's name do I do that?
Find a way.
Plans are afoot to put the paratroops
back on your streets in 48 hours.
Belfast will erupt.
You'll give the bombers
exactly what they want.
Well, it's out of my hands now.
Call when you have something.
I'm heading for a conference
in Rome tomorrow.
I'll have my cell at all times.
How was London? Is Mary OK?
You said to keep an eye on her,
and make sure she and Keri were kept safe.
I spent some time in her hotel lobby
watching the comings and goings, you know?
She had no idea I was there.
And your nephew turns up.
He spent two hours in her room.
- He spent two hours in Mary's room?
- Aye.
And after he goes,
Mary comes down,
and calls Hugh McGrath on the lobby phone.
It's done.
Unless they take it apart,
there's no way to know it's been modified.
Fuckin' brilliant. What'll set it off?
The internal clock.
I'll input the time
once we know the flight.
There's a security conference
in Rome tomorrow.
All the top MPs and security people are
flying there on three lunchtime flights.
Perfect. What about our mule?
Sara just confirmed he's going.
We then ran the burn-mark
through the database.
We got a positive hit
on a Patrick O'Reilly,
age 29, from Belfast.
O'Reilly had one prior for a domestic
abuse incident three years back.
Did two months in Hydebank.
We entered O'Reilly
into the facial rec bank for matches.
We got a hit.
That's him in a Dublin pub
with an IRA member four weeks ago.
It's a known IRA meeting place
we've had under surveillance for years.
And the other two with him?
I was about to get to them,
Minister.
That and a woman we've just ID'd
at the bus explosion.
Yes.
Your mole's Hugh McGrath.
Did you hear me, Hennessy?
Are you sure now?
Quite.
We've ID'd the Knightsbridge bomber
as Patrick O'Reilly of Belfast.
Three weeks ago, Mr. O'Reilly was observed
meeting Hugh McGrath in a Dublin pub.
Where's McGrath and O'Reilly now?
I don't know O'Reilly.
I haven't seen McGrath.
Let me help you with McGrath.
His phone's GPS puts him
52 meters south of you.
I'm watching him coming up your drive.
So, let's cut the shit.
There's a Chinook airborne
right now with a 12-man team.
They'll land on your farm in 30 minutes
to take McGrath into custody.
I needn't tell you how that'll go,
nor how your cozy relationship with him
will sink your career...
This time for good.
Or?
Question McGrath your way
and get what I need.
Names and locations of everyone.
You can't save him,
but maybe you can save yourself.
Thirty minutes, get what I need,
I'll turn them around.
Jim.
Send McGrath's men to the trailhead,
see if Sean needs any help.
Give me your phone.
- What the hell?
- Give me your phone.
Get your ass in that chair there,
you motherfucker.
- A London bus, for Christ sake!
- Now hold on.
Not even fuckin' warnings!
Sixteen dead.
You stabbed me in the back
and sanctioned this bloodbath
to get your war back on.
The plan had no balls.
This wasn't a Bombing Light campaign.
You said hurt 'em, and hurt 'em we did.
By killing women and children?
You can't restrain yourself.
You never could. Well, it's over.
Their names, aliases, and location.
You know I can't do that.
That's me being nice.
Now write. And it better match
what I already know.
By God, I'll take you apart
joint by joint!
You used me.
You wanted the pardons
for your own political gain.
You're a disgrace to the cause.
Four men and a woman.
Maggie Dunn?
Aye. You call her that.
Sara Mackay's her real name.
She works for you?
Bloody right.
Checks and balances.
An insurance policy,
in case you lose your nerve,
which you have.
So now, if they take the lads,
she will lead them straight back to you.
Not so easy anymore now, is it?
SO15 will be here
in 20 minutes to take you in.
We both know that can't happen.
You gave me up to the Brits?
You tout bastard!
You gave yourself up.
They've got surveillance of you
in an IRA pub with a Pat O'Reilly,
who they ID'd as the Knightsbridge bomber.
And thanks to your GPS phone,
they tracked you here.
You broke every rule, Hughie.
And now I'm left to clean up your mess
as I have for the past 30 years.
A final thing.
My wife?
What about her?
She hates you because of her brother.
And so she reached out to me.
So, yes, I helped her...
And she helped me.
- Yes.
- Bromley.
I got your names.
Oh, shit, I'm late. I've got to go.
Did you cum?
No.
I'm not a three-second wonder like you.
Well, keep wearing that shirt,
I'll be a two-second wonder.
You're gonna have to get used to it.
Practice, practice, practice.
I'm close.
McGrath confessed.
It was his op all along.
I've got the bombers' names and location.
I'll text you the info. You may need it.
The one that killed Quan's daughter
is Pat O'Reilly.
He's got a burn-mark on his right hand.
Either way, Sean, you end this, now.
- You hear me?
- Understood.
You know why you're still alive?
You want the names?
They're in the phone.
The last text, code 7741.
Five names and their location in London.
O'Reilly set the bomb
that killed your daughter.
He's got a burn-mark on his right hand.
You fought in the army.
Iraq. Royal Irish Regiment.
Two tours, Special Forces.
You're Catholic,
but you fought for British. Why?
I fought for the regiment.
Out there, religion didn't matter.
We were all the same. That's it.
Family?
A brother.
The rest have passed away.
Come in.
Take a seat, Sean.
Aye. You look like
you've been through the wars.
Aye. Quan got the drop on me.
I gave him the names,
he took my things and let me go.
When the bombers called in about the bus,
they didn't use a code word,
because someone tipped them off.
Only two people knew
the reason for the code change.
You and me.
Liam, I didn't tell anyone. I swear.
I spoke to Bromley, and that was it.
What if I told you I had Murphy stay
and watch Mary in London?
My own flesh and blood.
Liam, I'm so sorry.
I don't wanna know
what happened in that room.
All I wanna know is, what was discussed
when your sweet Aunt Mary was with you?
Did she say she was involved
with McGrath and the bombers?
No. Never.
She was upset about her brother
and kept on about that.
When you and I were talking
about the code word, she asked about 'em,
but she never let on about McGrath.
Oh, so, she could hear us on the phone?
No, it was only after our call
she mentioned the code word.
- She thought they wouldn't be of use.
- So, she steered the conversation?
Well, yes, I guess she did.
Ah. A good manipulator, she is.
So, she told the bombers?
She told McGrath, McGrath told them.
Thick as thieves, they were.
She tricked the information
out of ya, Sean.
She used you.
- Liam, I...
- Shut up!
Bury that pig in the sow-pen.
And after that,
I have one final task for you.
And when that's done...
go back to New York, son.
Thank you.
Zero, this is Alpha Two.
Echo One toward target house.
Zero. Echo One's
toward the target house. Copy.
Echo One has entered
the target house and unsighted to me.
Zero. Echo One is in target house
and unsighted to you. Copy.
Thank Christ for that.
Sierra call signs. Confirm when Echo One
is complete in target house.
Sierra Two, roger that.
Sierra Three, roger that.
X-Ray One on balcony.
Echo One approaching front door.
How'd it go?
It's done.
I have visual. X-Ray One
and Echo One have left the room.
All other X-Rays remain.
Zero, this is Alpha Two.
One unknown Echo and two children
entering the target house.
Roger that.
He's a slobbering oaf.
It had to be done.
I had to shag him.
It was fuckin' disgusting.
Look, I know what you
went through. All right?
Do ya, Denis? Do ya really?
Well, maybe for the next bomb,
you can set up a gay Magistrate.
How would that be?
Taking a shower.
Next.
X-Ray One entering living room.
All X-Rays now complete in living room.
All call signs
move to your final rendezvous.
X-Rays and Echo complete in living room.
We've lost visual.
Echo One has closed the blinds.
Fox One, you have control.
Roger that. I have control.
Standby. Standby.
Stop, stop, stop!
Wait!
Sierra call signs, report what's going on.
I've two unknowns
at the front door. Wait.
Sorry for the bother,
but there's a gas leak in the building,
and the gas man
needs entry for an inspection.
Our gas works fine. There's no problem.
He needs to inspect
all the flats, regardless.
He won't take a moment,
and it is an emergency.
It's quite important, Mr. Upton.
By law, I'm allowed to use my own key.
All right. Just a second.
Come down when you're done,
and I'll take you to the next flat.
Thank you. I will be very fast.
This way.
Can I see the boiler, please?
Would you mind
putting your bag on the table?
Open it up.
All right.
All call signs, standby, standby.
All call signs, go!
Get down! Get down!
Get down! Get down! Get down!
Room clear!
X-Rays down.
What about Echo?
She's alive, under control.
Who planned this?
Go fuck yourself.
What's this, eh? Your next bomb?
Talk, you rotten slag!
It's too late.
Nine minutes it blows. No time to land.
What's that? A plane? Which plane?
Which plane?
Open her shirt.
This is how it works.
I ask questions. You answer.
That's right. Flight 136 to Rome.
Passenger name Ian Wood.
Bomb's in his laptop.
Set to go off at 3:00 p.m. exactly.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please be advised.
Flight 136 to Rome
has been further delayed.
We apologize for the inconvenience.
Again, Flight 136 to Rome...
Ian Wood!
Is there an Ian Wood here?
Ian Wood! Ian Wood?
Is there an Ian Wood here? Ian Wood?
Ian Wood? Ian Wood? Ian Wood?
What's going on? What's going on?
They're looking for someone
named Ian Wood.
That's me. I'm Ian Wood.
Ian Wood!
I'm Ian Wood.
- Is that your laptop?
- Yeah.
Move! Move! Move!
Get down! Get down! Get down! Get down!
Get down! Get down!
Move! Move!
Get down! Get down! Move!
Get outta the way! Get out!
Move here! Get out!
Move!
She said a gas man turned up
with an assault gun, a Chinaman.
Started shooting, killed everyone but her,
and then walked out the door.
She said he was a Chinaman?
Affirmative. About 60 years old.
Just got word
the device is neutralized.
Good work. Fox Hunt is now terminated.
No loose ends.
Understood.
It's Bromley. I need an AP
out to all city-district units
from Wapping High Street to the A1203.
Suspect's an Asian male, 61 years of age,
five feet, eight inches, 11 stone.
His name's Ngoc Minh Quan.
He's armed
and has U.S. Special Forces training.
Use extreme caution.
Yes.
I was on the flight
they targeted to blow up.
Because of your timely information,
we stopped it.
I wanted to thank you personally.
Thank God you're OK.
The bombers were neutralized,
even Sara McKay,
whom you called "Maggie."
She gave a reporter the bomb
that was to have been put on my flight.
She also carried out the bus carnage,
and is directly connected to you,
and McGrath.
We have call-pens going
to and from her off the cell tower
by your farm and town homes.
That's 250 precision locations
and activations
- consistent with your mutual activities.
- Katherine...
I've spoken to the PM.
He's agreed to keep you in office for now.
I'm issuing pardons
for five On-the-Runs, one is your cousin.
But, make no mistake,
Deputy First Minister, you are ours now.
I say jump, you say where.
You're on the next flight back to London.
Tomorrow you'll brief
SO15 and myself on everything you know.
All of it.
Good evening, sir.
How did you find me?
I gave you the names, like I said.
This woman, she's a bomber.
You lie. You plan everything.
For whatever it's worth...
I never intended to hurt your daughter
or any of those people.
Send.
Do it!
It's now on the Internet,
you and your mistress.
The whole world will know
you are a terrorist.
Good-bye, Mr. Hennessy.
Yes?
It's Landesman, sir, in S-11.
I've got him.
Where?
The Happy Peacock Takeaway.
He's returned.
Do I send in a team?
No.
I believe we owe this chap something.
Keep back for now.
Observe and report only.
Yes, sir.