I have a faith.
I believe that there are two types
of people in this building.
Guardians and criminals.
Barrister's robes and prison uniforms.
No matter what the situation may be,
I believe that we're different
from those whom we need to punish.
Mr. Hwang!
The man, Byung-jun Woo,
did leave the country yesterday.
He went to Taipei, Taiwan.
Contact Interpol and ask them
to issue a red notice.
And inform
the Korean Mission in Taipei as well.
- We'll send investigators there.
- Okay, got it.
You moved Yeon-jae's money
after making her leave the country,
then you dared to summon Mr. Song
and tried to steal my profit.
Did you think I wouldn't know?
Of course you'd know.
What on earth are you up to?
Killing Eun-soo...
It was your doing, wasn't it?
Stop spewing such nonsense.
You're being ridiculous.
You told Mr. Woo to do the job
and sent him abroad after, didn't you?
You're much sneakier
than I thought you could be, Chang-jun.
Was this your plan?
Will you say that I instigated murder
to threaten me
so that you can take
a hefty amount from me?
The killer has already been caught.
I've never even met that guy.
He didn't kill Eun-soo.
Is there evidence?
I'm the evidence.
What do you mean?
Moo-sung Park and Ga-young Kim.
It was me.
The guy who got arrested is just a blade.
I'm the one who held the handle
of the knife.
Why?
You'll find out soon.
All right, I've told you everything.
Now, it's time for you to be honest,
Father.
I don't know anything about it.
Chang-jun.
We've been a family
for a pretty long time.
Why have we become like this?
PROSECUTOR SI-MOK HWANG
I have to go.
Take care.
END THE CALL WITH FATHER
THE CALL HAS BEEN SUCCESSFULLY RECORDED.
Freeze all bank accounts
under Chang-jun's name,
and tell them to stop all withdrawals
immediately.
Speak of the devil.
Were you talking about me?
I was thinking about you.
You can stop thinking. Let's meet up, sir.
Hold on. Mr. Hwang, which investigators
would you like to send to Taiwan?
- Lieutenant Han and Detective Jang.
- Got it.
Byung-jun Woo left for Taiwan yesterday.
We've asked their government
for cooperation,
so you should go there with Detective Jang
and arrest him.
And Chang-jun Lee was
the accomplice behind Mr. Yoon.
I'm on my way to meet him now.
I'll send you the address.
Hongje-dong.
Please track the location
of Chief Secretary Chang-jun Lee.
If people from Hanjo Group come,
do not let any of them into my office.
Yes, sir.
I sincerely apologize.
I ran into her right in front
of Mr. Hwang's place.
I didn't expect to see
Mr. Young's daughter...
You moron. Leave the country right away!
Don't come back until I tell you to do so.
- Thank you, sir.
- Take this too!
Get rid of it. Don't leave any traces.
Come in.
I found out that Mr. Lee has
a personal safe deposit box at Hanil Bank.
What should we do?
Tell the CEO of the bank
that I want to meet.
And bring Chang-jun here immediately.
It shows that Chang-jun Lee is
on the move toward Muakjae now.
Then he is going to Hongje-dong.
Where are you now?
I'm... Hang up first.
I'll send you my location.
Send the current location
to Detective Jang.
SEND CURRENT LOCATION TO DETECTIVE JANG.
DETECTIVE JANG, NEW MESSAGE,
TRACKING MY LOCATION
ADDRESS: HONGJE-DONG, SEODAEMUN-GU, SEOUL
We've figured out that
he's the accomplice.
Why is he letting us track his location?
What is he thinking?
What happened?
We're at the Blue House,
but we can't get in.
We told them your name, but...
Track his car. I don't care what you do!
Bring him to me immediately.
You got here faster than I thought.
You still have a long way to go, though.
You must have a lot of questions.
Did you instigate Mr. Yoon
into killing Moo-sung Park?
Yes, I did.
Did you cause bodily harm
to Ga-young Kim as well?
Yes.
What about Eun-soo Young?
Aren't you here
because you know who did it?
Why did you do it?
You said
that I must've been threatened by Mr. Park
and that I tried to shut that girl up.
I now know that's not what happened.
I should've said no.
Mr. Park begged me
to help him get a contract,
but I should've refused it.
Did you introduce him
to those in Hanjo Distribution
yourself?
He was trying hard to revive
his dying business,
and I had no reason to be cold to him.
Hanjo Distribution was
getting the least amount
of attention out of all the subsidiaries.
I didn't think putting him in touch
with them would affect anything.
You didn't know that it was soon
to be used for illegal transfer of assets.
I had no idea.
It wasn't in the limelight because they
wanted it to stay out of public attention.
I regret it.
That's the only thing I regret.
The one misjudgment I made.
Is that why...
Would you have
done something you'd regret later?
Why did you want to meet here?
It's such a beautiful day, isn't it?
I'll be cuffed.
Then with my prisoner number on my chest,
I'll be dragged around.
I'll be interrogated by prosecutors
below my seniority level.
I've seen it many times.
Isn't it strange?
All those men who were interrogated
in front of me
had lost a lot of hair
at the crown of their heads.
Why is this popping up
in my mind right now?
Please come with me.
Should I become the defeated
and get dragged around as a captive?
Or shall I choose to vanish
on the battleground?
Chang-jun.
Chang-jun?
I like being called that way.
Slow down.
Did Si-mok really say
that Mr. Lee is the culprit?
Pull yourself together.
Someone is up there.
I'll go check. Please stay with him here.
You can do it, right?
The redevelopment area in Hongje-dong.
It's behind Inwang Elementary School.
Send an ambulance immediately.
Someone fell.
Sir, Mr. Chief Secretary.
Sir, sir!
Mr. Hwang?
Sir!
Sir... Mr. Chief Secretary.
Please keep yourself together. Sir!
You still
have a chance.
Dong-jae.
Do not
follow my path.
Sir...
Mr. Chief Secretary...
Put both of your hands up.
Turn around slowly.
Did you push him?
Reporters will swarm all over here soon.
Tidy things up before that.
- Yes, sir.
- Let's go.
I heard he jumped off
before Mr. Hwang could even stop him.
Before that, he admitted
being the accomplice.
Are you sure it's suicide?
What if there was a tussle up there?
Lieutenant Han saw him jumping.
She must've seen it from down here.
Weren't they the only ones up there?
I'm not saying that Prosecutor Hwang
pushed him intentionally.
He could've done it by mistake
while trying to stop him.
Prosecutor Seo said he saw it too.
It looks like he took his own life.
Who's here now?
The protocol team has started
preparing for the funeral.
The planning team and the PR team
are both on standby.
Shall I call the executives?
Control the media first.
Chang-jun has committed many corrupt deeds
since he was a prosecutor.
He kept his henchman in the prosecution
in order to bury all of his wrong deeds.
And using that guy,
he killed Moo-sung Park who bribed
prosecutors at the western office.
- Pardon me?
- The guilt made him take his own life.
Distribute a press release
before reporters come up
with imaginative stories.
Understood, sir.
What a moron.
They say that a live dog
is better than a dead lion.
I guess that's just his fate.
What can I do?
As a prosecutor, I want to do it. But...
Si-mok.
I don't want to lose this position.
Is it true? Our chief prosecutor...
I mean, the news
about Chief Secretary Chang-jun Lee.
He passed away.
Then the other things too?
How he was the mastermind behind Mr. Yoon
and that he took his own life?
Yes.
It's all true.
Are we going to start?
We should.
Let's do it.
Now, I'll distribute documents that list
all illegal deeds Hanjo has committed.
They're organized by date,
and they go back to about two years ago.
The enclosed memory sticks contain
voice files, which are recordings
of secret meetings held for the schemes.
Where did you get this?
Mine isn't about Hanjo Group.
They pressured our offices
to hire specific people.
There are things related
to the Public Prosecutor General as well.
Who else has been informed about this?
Those of you here
are the only ones who know.
They've never been disclosed before.
Intellectual property infringement,
illegal sales of real estate,
unlawful transfer of assets, tax evasion
and violating Foreign Exchange Act.
You'll see what each team from Division
One to Five will be in charge of.
Some public officials helped Hanjo
evade law enforcement.
There are politicians too.
We're so dead, aren't we?
Why should we die?
These guys are in trouble, not us.
All right. It's all or nothing.
If we want to crush them,
we must strike them with full force.
If we approach them rashly,
we'll be crushed.
Please help us out.
Your accomplice, Chang-jun Lee,
confessed everything
and jumped to his death.
You don't seem that surprised.
I guess the two of you
had talked about it.
Did he tell you that Byung-jun Woo
is the one who killed Ms. Young?
Is that why you kept your mouth shut?
Because we'd find out about your source
if you told us Byung-jun Woo killed her?
Did he tell you anything else
about Byung-jun Woo?
Where in Taiwan he may be, for example.
All I know is he went there.
I don't know anything else.
While you were working with us,
all of us must've looked
like complete idiots.
While wandering around to catch
the killer, we addressed you so politely.
We must've looked really pathetic,
especially me and Detective Jang.
During the special investigation...
It was the first time.
For the very first time in two years,
I felt like I could actually breathe.
Shall I go tell Mr. Park's mother that
the prick who slashed her son to death
said he felt like he could
finally breathe?
Or shall I go tell Ga-young's mom?
In this country,
there are so many parents
who lost their children
unfairly.
Do all of them brandish knives?
You basically stabbed them too.
They've done everything in their power
to overcome their losses,
and you made all of their effort
go to waste.
You feel like you can breathe now?
While many of us are still shocked
by the late Chief Secretary Chang-jun Lee
committing suicide right before getting
arrested for murder,
the recordings he left got leaked,
which has been causing a big stir.
The secret documents, which were made
to prevent betrayal of those
who were involved in the secret deals,
were taken into custody by the prosecution
after Chief Secretary Lee, who was
on the run from the police
and prosecution, took his own life.
Using these documents as evidence,
the prosecution have
commenced a search and seizure at Hanjo
and The Bahn Group early this morning.
Moreover, a list of high-ranking officials
who were involved in illegal acts
has also been disclosed,
which is expected to cause
an immense stir.
Detective Seo, join Team Two
and hit the savings bank.
Geon and Yeo-jin, go to the bus company.
Sun-chang, you and I will go
to Financial Supervisory Service.
The media beat us. Time isn't on our side,
so get moving quickly.
- Yes, sir.
Hello? The Ministry of Foreign Affairs?
Official documents have been issued?
Thank you.
Detective Jang,
let's go catch that killer.
I told you that I don't know anything.
I'm calling from Mr. Chief Prosecutor's
office. Please play it now.
You've never given the Incheon office
any orders related
to Sepoong Transportation's trial?
Hey, Won-chul.
Do you want to leave the prosecution
right after your promotion or what?
Go bring that man, Mr. Yoon.
Let me talk to him face-to-face.
There's something you should hear
before that.
Hello, Congressman Bae.
It's been a long time.
- I heard the killer has been caught.
- Yes.
I didn't expect that you'd be
affected by the Huam-dong case.
What are you talking about?
I don't have anything to do with it.
I don't think you're in a situation
where you can worry about saving face.
The killer must've told them
everything by now.
It's only a matter of time
before your name comes up.
So? You must've called me
because you have a plan.
I'm sure there will be something
I can do for you.
Do you have some time now?
CHIEF PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE
I just got a call
from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
We'll be sure to bring that prick,
Byung-jun Woo, back to his home soil,
so just trust us and wait for us.
Best of luck to you too.
Please catch him.
LIEUTENANT HAN
I've been
responsible for 30 percent
of this country's GDP.
That's right, 30 percent.
For my whole life, I've devoted myself
to sustaining the nation's economy.
And as you're probably aware,
I have given jobs
to millions of young people
in this country.
The anti-corporate attitude
that calls my effort a crime
and uses it as a reason
to criticize all the work I've done
makes businessmen like me lose our ground.
Wondering what kind of outcome
this may bring
truly terrifies me.
The thought of my beloved country
getting dropped from the list
of highly developed countries
due to such collective unreasonable rage
scares me.
I, Yun-beom Lee, would like
to make this one thing clear.
Prosecutors may be able to strap me down
jurisprudentially,
but I can
confidently face the honorable history
of this country and say
that I am innocent.
Even toddlers know shame.
You haven't become a decent human being
even after killing a person.
Well, I can understand
why the former minister
is not in his right state of mind
at the moment,
but I have nothing to do
with the death of his daughter...
Your son-in-law!
I'm talking about Chang-jun.
You killed him.
Did you ask the late Mr. Lee
to record those conversations secretly?
The suspect of Ms. Young's murder is
your employee. What's your thought on it?
- Please say a few words.
- Sir, please tell us.
- Sir!
- Sir, please say a few words.
- Sir, what is the truth?
- Please say a few words!
The intensive investigation on Chairman
Yun-beom Lee of Hanjo has been extended,
which has resulted in a prospect
that an arrest warrant might be requested.
And about Chairman Lee's daughter
and the late chief secretary's wife,
Ms. Yeon-jae Lee,
donating her illegally transferred assets
to a scholarship foundation,
the prosecution stated that they are
investigating it to find out
whether it was done to escape
being convicted of tax evasion.
Next breaking news.
The prime suspect
of Prosecutor Eun-soo Young's murder
who killed her two weeks ago
and fled to Taiwan
has been caught by Korean police officers
who were sent to Taiwan
and is being transferred at the moment.
I sat right beside him
and kept asking him,
but he strongly denied
Chairman Lee's involvement.
He kept insisting
that he did everything alone.
Damn it.
It'll become harder for us to prove it
if he keeps denying it.
He's certainly not an easy one.
He hasn't said a word about his boss.
You guys must be exhausted.
You should go home get some rest.
Gosh, I wish I could be home
when I open my eyes.
Oh, boy. I miss my son so much,
but he'll ask me to play with him
when I get home, which will exhaust me.
Then tomorrow...
Gosh, kids don't even get tired.
Hey, get up.
Hey, both of you.
Go home, wash up and go to bed.
That won't make my fatigue go away.
I'll say this one last time.
Do you think that
a sane person would get his subordinate
to kill someone?
Why are you guys making all this fuss
over what a crazy man said?
My apologies. So you're saying
that your son-in-law fabricated everything
and that none of it is true.
Of course, none of it.
My wife likes watching dramas.
This is what characters in those dramas
say when their parents don't approve
of the one they want to marry.
"We don't need your approval.
We wanted your blessing."
Right, then they ask their parents to buy
them a house and pay for their wedding.
They say that they don't need
their parents' approval, but in the end...
"Yes."
That one word is what they really need.
This isn't any different.
You're pretending that
you don't need me to admit the charges
because you have firm evidence,
but the fact that you're keeping me here
for this long
must mean that
you guys can only do things
if I admit that I've done wrong.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
No matter how hard I rack my brain,
I can only think
of the good deeds I've done.
I think I've done enough to help
the prosecution save face.
No one will criticize your investigation
or say that you gave me special treatment.
You've worked hard enough.
Please come with us.
Has it been issued?
- We just got the arrest warrant.
- Good.
Don't you dare touch me.
Si-mok.
If those of us collapse,
this country will collapse as well.
It won't collapse.
Let go!
Good work.
LIEUTENANT HAN
Hello?
Who?
Send her up, please.
Do you think you won this game?
I will destroy you with everything I have.
You'll regret it
for the rest of your life.
You'll beat your chest,
wishing you hadn't bothered us at all.
Who is "us"?
You and Chairman Lee?
Or you and your husband?
You killed him.
It was in the bag he gave me.
Chang-jun
gave it to you?
The Republic of Korea is collapsing.
Even the senses of security and belief
that most ordinary people would be safe
have collapsed,
and that's where we're at now.
Our society will break down soon.
For 19 long years...
For the last 19 years as a prosecutor,
I watched that hole of destruction growing
at a frightening speed
right before my eyes.
Mr. Prosecutor. Please.
I'm so sorry.
Please let it slide just this once.
Mr. Prosecutor!
- I'm so sorry. Please help me, sir.
- Once, an elderly woman who had been
living on sugar water was dragged to me.
One day, I had to arrest someone
for theft when all he had was nothing
but 3,000 won,
which he made from selling junk.
I arrested people like them during the day
and went to a secret lounge at night.
There, I met people who make hundreds
of billions of won with just a few words,
and I observed them so that they could
escape the net of justice.
CHIEF PROSECUTOR SANG-WOOK BAE
Yes, I completely understand how you feel,
but I have no choice.
It's an order from higher-ups.
Just let him go.
When I wasn't observing them,
I faithfully jotted down and executed
each administration's guideline.
Had our society been moderately corrupt,
I would've ignored it.
I would've enjoyed what I have if that
had been the degree of its rottenness.
But at some point, my body started telling
me that it couldn't take it anymore.
I can't keep collecting dust
like an old book sitting on a shelf.
Everything in this bag
must be known as what was taken from me
when I got caught while on the run,
not as belongings of a traitor who stabbed
his father-in-law in the back.
It must be known as what the prosecution
confiscated from me,
a rich tycoon's loyal dog who enjoyed
a comfortable life
until his final moments.
Only then, they will gain irrefutable
efficacy and credibility as evidence.
VOICE RECORDING 001
FATHER, CONGRESSMAN SANG-WOOK BAE
RECORD
The corruption in our society
is no longer just a malaise.
It's killing people.
We're talking at least
dozens or hundreds of lives.
CHAIRMAN OF HANJO GROUP
YUN-BEOM LEE
I should've unsheathed the knife
from the get-go, from the very beginning.
If I don't pull out the knife
even at the last gasp,
the system itself will collapse.
What can restore
the crashed system is neither time
nor money.
Even if something unexpected happens...
Blood is what can reinstate
the destroyed system.
Blood of many people.
I want to say that history proves it all,
but blood sacrifices are still ongoing.
We must change it.
I must find whatever it is that I can do
and turn the tables.
CHIEF SECRETARY OF BLUE HOUSE
CHANG-JUN LEE
We've already missed the time
it could've been healed by normal means.
I must not forbear any longer.
I should not wait for someone else
to clean up the filth in my place.
If I wait and stay silent,
this entire country will be
covered in filth in no time.
Now, I ought to open my mouth,
point at those who have done wrong
and reveal the secret behind the curtains
that had been kept closed.
I hope that this is the beginning.
Defendant, you stated
that you admit all of the charges
and that you do not wish to say anything
to defend yourself. Is it true?
Yes, Your Honor.
What is the reason?
I would like to apologize.
To whom?
"Under the name of justice,
we pursue truth"
and never compromise
with injustice or any illegal pursuits
"as righteous police officers."
I'd like to apologize
to everyone in the police force
who'd be working very hard even
at this moment with the Police Charter
engraved in their hearts.
I sincerely apologize.
I plead guilty to all of the charges
and deeply regret what I did.
I earnestly hope that those of you
in the force don't forget why you joined
the police and turn out like me.
I will now announce the verdict.
Even though the defendant, Woo-gyun Kim,
was a public official whose duty
was to be a model citizen,
he accepted bribes and bought
sex services from a minor.
His offences deserve a heavy punishment,
but he is repenting
and deeply regretting what he did.
Ergo, the court sentences him
to 42 months in prison.
Chief.
Thanks, Sergeant Kim.
Su-chan.
Shouldn't that idiot know better by now?
Why is he not letting go
of the rotten rope?
I'll ask you once again.
Who are the other men you met
besides Chief Woo-gyun Kim?
Are you not going to answer?
Ms. Kim, you're here
as a perpetrator, not a victim.
You're being investigated
for prostitution.
If you keep this up, you may end up
with more than a fine.
I'm not well yet.
I don't remember anything.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello.
You should've told them
that I still don't remember anything.
Are you a bonehead?
Stop following me around.
You're embarrassing me. Leave me alone!
Why do you keep taking everything
out on me? Goodness.
Hey.
My gosh, Detective.
- Why are you being like this?
- Look.
See what her arms are doing.
Look at what she's doing
even after hearing such rude remarks!
Do you know what your mom went
through while you were at the hospital?
Do you know how much effort the culprit
made to let you live?
- Sorry?
- Had it been someone else,
you would've died in someone's bathroom.
That's how you got your life back.
Do you want to waste it like this?
Do you know how many women
in prostitution end up dead?
There are so many of them
they don't cover the story on the news.
It was God's will
that your life was spared.
Don't you ever forget that.
You should really listen to her.
Why can't you pull yourself together?
And what are you wearing?
For goodness' sake.
That almost made me jump.
Shall I smash your desk for you?
You're back, sir. What happened to Chief?
What do you think? He's been
sentenced to 42 months in prison.
What's the matter though?
Gosh, don't even get me started.
He didn't have an attorney,
and he refused to defend himself.
Watching him admitting everything
and apologizing... Gosh.
At least Chief is repenting what he did.
"At least"? What do you mean by that?
I wonder what Sergeant Kim is up to.
What are you trying to say?
Don't be so cryptic.
Ask yourself what it may mean.
I'm done for the day.
Gosh.
That little...
I got a job.
- My comrades, please congratulate me.
- Why is she being like that to me?
I'll get going too.
You should ask yourself for the answer.
Lieutenant Han, wait up.
Good grief.
Oh, boy.
SERGEANT KIM
Hey, Sergeant Kim.
How have you been?
Well, I was just wondering.
Hey, let's meet up and have some soju.
- Cheers.
It's not even a small law firm.
It's a big company.
They recruited me.
My experience in the special investigation
team was certainly very helpful.
Congratulations.
Your trip to Taiwan must've been intense.
You'll have to stay up for four nights
to hear about everything that happened.
You got promoted because of it though.
It's great.
You too, Detective Jang.
We really should celebrate.
Gosh, stop. I shouldn't drink anymore.
Are you still taking herbal medicine?
Does it even work?
You look even more fatigued than before.
I should start taking care of myself.
I'll have to wear the uniform
for the ceremony.
I should go get some coffee.
Ceremony, my foot.
- Does anyone want coffee?
- I'd love a latte.
- Me too.
- Same here.
What's going on with Mr. Hwang by the way?
- I couldn't get a hold of him.
- Oh, you're right.
He left work right on time today,
which never happens.
That jerk. He just sent me
a one-word text to congratulate me
- and didn't even answer my call.
- Stop calling him like that, will you?
- We're friends.
- And stop saying that as an excuse.
- Oh, coffee.
- He's just in a good mood.
This coffee is delicious.
Oh, I have to watch the baseball game.
Here.
For the last few months...
- Wait, wasn't that Mr. Hwang?
- What?
Switch the channel. Go back.
Today, we'll be speaking with Prosecutor
Si-mok Hwang from the western office
who's been on the frontline
of the investigation committed
to eradicating corruption,
which started with the Huam-dong murder.
- Hello.
- This is my second time meeting you.
- That's correct.
How are the trials of the politicians
and financial authorities going?
From what I know,
a number of trials have been held so far.
I mainly oversee investigations,
so I'm not directly taking part
in the trials.
You haven't changed at all
from what I remember.
There's something else I remember.
The last time you were here,
you said that you'd catch
the culprit within two months.
- Yes, I did.
- From the killer, Se-won Yoon,
to the mastermind behind him,
the late Chang-jun Lee,
you brought the truth to light
a few days before the promised deadline.
- That's right.
- You kept your promise.
That day, I asked you
to come back on the show
if you ever catch the culprit.
- You kept that promise too. Thank you.
- No problem.
I'm actually here because there is
something I'd like to say.
Sure, please go ahead.
The late Mr. Chang-jun Lee
didn't record the conversations
to threaten those who were involved
in the corrupt deeds with him
in case they might end up betraying him.
Isn't that what was released
by Western Seoul Prosecutors' Office?
Yes, that is correct.
And you're refuting it now?
This is an old case, but I'm wondering
if you remember what happened
at the genetic research lab in Pohang.
One of the employees
disclosed a confidential internal document
after he left the lab.
Even though the document
was very detailed,
none of the executives
whose names were on the document
was punished in any way.
From what I remember, people only
criticized the employee,
calling him a traitor and swindler.
It was because those at the lab
insisted that he embezzled research funds
and that he was lying
in order to conceal it.
They kept brainwashing people like that.
Are you bringing this up
because you think that Mr. Lee's case
is like his?
This was his final wish.
"I must be remembered as corporate riches'
spy who was loyal to them until the end."
He said that it will give
more power to what he was leaving behind.
Then, are you saying
that he voluntarily disgraced himself
in order to prove
the corrupt deeds that he had
witnessed and heard about?
That's correct.
When faced with death, all of us hope
that our true intentions would be
understood after we die,
yet he even gave up on that.
Yes.
I knew it.
Mr. Lee was such a righteous person.
I had no idea.
Those of us at the police
spoke ill of him like crazy too.
What you said is making me think
that he could either be viewed
as a criminal or as a righteous man
who sacrificed himself depending
on which aspects are emphasized.
Such dichotomous opinions
may be brought up.
What's your take on it?
He was a monster.
He killed a person.
He probably thought of it
as a small sacrifice for a big cause,
but I personally have never thought
that certain people's lives could be
considered less valuable than others'.
He deluded himself into thinking
that he had the right to punish sinners.
He was a monster created by our time.
A police officer once said to me
that people do things because
they can get away with them.
Because they can get away with it
and people will turn a blind eye.
She said people do corrupt things
because we turn a blind eye to them
and that we can change it if just
one person keeps his or her eyes open
and barks at them.
That is actually the prosecution's job.
How do you think
the prosecution have done?
We failed.
As an organization whose duty
is to correct injustice,
the prosecution has failed.
We, at the prosecution, applied
the presumption of innocence in a way
that was catered to those
with wealth and power. Moreover,
we protected a criminal,
instead of our citizens.
We failed in carrying out
our most essential duty.
The late Mr. Chang-jun Lee was the outcome
of accumulation of such failure,
and everyone in the prosecution
was his accomplice.
I cannot speak on behalf
of all of my colleagues, of course.
However, I thought I should apologize
to all citizens through this opportunity.
Those of us in the prosecution
disappointed you.
Nevertheless, I think
that we still have a chance.
"The most powerful weapon
law enforcers can have
is the constitutional law."
Someone once told me that.
We can continue to fight
as long as the constitution exists.
The prosecution will no longer
be swayed by those with power.
We'll rise again to fight.
We'll exercise our rights on indictment
accurately.
We'll remember that the people are
essentially
the ones who hold the power to appoint us.
We'll devote ourselves to you.
We'll take responsibility.
We'll strive to become fairer
and more honest.
We'll make sure that none of us
will become another monster like him
by doing our very best.
I've been feeling very bad
because my show has been filled
with nothing but disturbing news lately.
I think that
you should be able to relax a little bit
this evening after watching this.
Thank you for watching News 60.
Thank you.
I can understand Mr. Yoon though.
What are you talking about?
Anyone who kills a person is a murderer.
But his son... He lost his child
who wasn't even 10 years old.
And those pricks were living great lives
as if nothing had happened.
Even so, he can't punish them like that.
Why does the law even exist, then?
Even though prosecution
and police are both rotten,
there are still people like
Prosecutor Hwang, Lieutenant Han and me.
Yes, you're absolutely right.
It's all over now anyway.
Don't fight, guys.
By the way, Mr. Hwang
made another appearance on network
television, looking all handsome.
He's definitely going to be promoted
to the division head role this time.
I heard he'll go to the States.
Is Si-mok going to the States?
He was supposed to leave a while ago,
but he couldn't because of what happened.
We've arrested most of the people
who should stand trial,
so I guess he'll leave soon.
I heard the chairman of The Bahn Group
is already preparing for an appeal.
Of course. People like them
won't get locked up easily.
He's going to the States.
I wonder how Mr. Yoon is doing.
Why do you care? I'm sure
he's paying for what he did.
Gosh.
You said you don't want to drink more.
Gosh, seriously.
I watched the show.
What brings you here?
Si-mok.
Trust me and just give me one chance.
Mr. Lee's last wishes
and what he said to me
in his final moments.
I really want to keep the promise.
You
still
have a chance.
I'll never do anything stupid again.
I swear on my name.
I beg you.
Give me one last chance.
- He's coming!
- Oh, there he is!
Please say a few words.
- How do you feel, sir?
- How do you feel to stand trial?
- Is there anything you'd like to say?
- How do you feel now?
Gosh, don't push me.
- How do you feel?
- Please say a few words.
I'm
not well. I'm ill.
- What's your condition?
- How do you feel?
- Do you have to be hospitalized?
- Is that all you'd like to say?
Is that all you want to say?
- Please say something else.
- Please say a few words.
- Will you go to a hospital?
- Please tell us.
I told you to stop!
Is there anything else you'd like to say?
I'm
really ill.
What exactly is your condition?
What are you waiting for?
- What is your condition, sir?
- Please say a few words.
- Step aside!
- Are you going to a hospital?
Mr. Yoon, the firm I work at
will handle your trial.
He said
he has to meet you.
Did killing my dad
make you feel better?
I heard that you lost your son
due to an accident.
I lost my dad in your hands.
Are you satisfied?
Did you really achieve
everything you wanted?
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I'm fine.
Well, thank you so much
for everything you've done for me.
- I'll work hard and take care of Grandma.
- Good.
- Oh, right. I got a job at a golf course.
- Really?
It looks like good things are happening
to both of us.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I'm glad that things are going well
for all of us.
Byung-jun Woo keeps insisting
that he did everything alone,
so we'll need more time to prove
that Chairman Lee instigated the murder.
Yun-beom Lee denied instigating
the killing even in the recordings.
Let's deal with the scandal
involving Hanjo's corrupt deeds first.
Got it.
Anyway, I can see
that the end is drawing near.
We've investigated most things
in the documents, right?
Yes, sir.
The plan of sending you to the States
has been canceled.
Will I be transferred elsewhere?
Yes, Namhae.
I see. Okay.
Mr. Lee was the one who brought us here.
The Public Prosecutor General told me.
Those at the Cheongju office wanted to
re-evaluate you as you irked them,
and I had been pushed out
of Criminal Division.
Chang-jun Lee was the one who brought
both of us here.
I think he wanted you to take care
of things after he died from the get-go.
"Who would take on this burden?"
I thought about it for a very long time.
I thought he gave me this position
of chief prosecutor to appease me,
but he was actually looking for someone
who would support you.
But... They should be awarding you
for all of your work if anything.
Damn it.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You have given me support.
Thank you for everything.
I think he wanted you to take care
of things after he died from the get-go.
Would you have
done something you'd regret later?
You can do it.
I know that you won't get swayed.
You'll chase them until the end
in an unflinching manner.
"Who would take on this burden?"
I thought about it for a very long time.
Prosecutor Si-mok Hwang.
You were the only answer.
- Si-mok.
- It's Si-mok Hwang.
For a better future.
You can't make me stand here.
Absolutely not. I will never
stand before you as a defendant.
Chang-jun?
I like being called that way.
Slow down.
What's the matter?
What is it?
- Did you get a boyfriend or what?
- Sorry?
Congratulations.
Bring him here. We should meet him
to make sure that he's a nice guy.
What are you guys talking about?
Ta-da!
Who sent it? Who is it?
Congratulations. Jung-bon.
I didn't know Jung-bon would
hit on you like this.
Don't be ridiculous.
He must've sent it as an ex-colleague.
We're just friends, okay?
I'm getting promoted too. Where's mine
then? He's obviously making a move.
You should open the present first.
- Wow.
Why is this so red?
- Is this food or lipstick?
- Gosh, stop it.
Why did he buy this for me?
I don't even wear lipstick.
Hey, get back to work.
- You'll put it on like this.
- Go. Get your work done.
It's only morning,
yet you guys are already so distracting.
What's wrong with them?
They're being so silly.
God.
It's so pretty. I like it.
Mr. Hwang will be transferred
to Namhae County.
What?
Enjoy.
Wow.
You know how to enjoy a drink alone now.
Look at you all grown up.
Why are you late?
Keep being inflexible like that,
and you'll be all alone in Namhae.
Anyway, it's so sudden.
What are you going to do with your house?
I'm going to lease it out.
Ten million won.
Rent it to me, okay?
I listed it for 350 million won.
You don't come across like that,
but I guess you're greedy for money.
Oh, well.
Come to my place if you have nowhere
to sleep when you come back.
I'll let you sleep on my porch.
All right.
The cold wind might freeze
your face though.
Okay.
Here. Congratulations on your promotion.
Gosh, it's not that big of a deal.
By the way, the promotion ceremony
will be held tomorrow morning.
So what?
You said you'll leave tomorrow morning.
What about it?
Forget it.
How's work going?
Did you get everything done?
Yes. There's Dong-jae, but I'll leave that
up to Mr. Kang's discretion.
Why aren't you arresting him?
He's done enough to be arrested.
She kept begging me to trust her,
but I chose not to trust her
until the end.
I'm talking about Eun-soo.
So you want to trust him?
Him out of all people?
I'll observe him.
Ta-da.
Gosh, it's...
What on earth is this?
This looks nothing like me.
You should look at it
and practice smiling.
It's a gift.
By the way,
why are they sending you to Namhae?
The high-ranking officials
and Chairman Lee have been arrested,
but things won't stay like this for long.
I bet they'll be released soon
by special pardons.
I guess it's a preparatory measure.
Goodbye.
I won't be able to see you off.
Good luck in your new position.
Sorry I can't attend the ceremony.
Wait, did you just order one?
How could you?
Gosh, you haven't changed one bit.
We had to water it down last time
because it was too salty.
You told me to get ramen instead.
It's under a new owner now.
Is that why you ordered it?
So how does it taste?
Is it not salty?
What happened to your lips?
Oh, this.
Why? Do I look pretty?
- It looks weird.
- What?
Lieutenant Yeo-jin Han
and Sergeant Geon Jang.
SPECIAL PROMOTION CEREMONY
YONGSAN POLICE STATION
"Lieutenant Yeo-jin Han made
great contributions"
to solving the Huam-dong murder case
as well as to arresting
and transferring the culprit
of a serious crime.
"Along with this recognition, she will
also be promoted one rank up."
Sergeant Geon Jang. The same as above.
Attention. Salute!
We'll see you soon, right?
It's a small world, you know.
Take good care of yourself.
Please don't skip meals.
- Thank you both for everything.
- We should thank you.
Thank you.
- You should go in.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Drive safely.
Please drive carefully.
Who do you think will come?
Who knows?
Come in.
- Where's Si-mok?
- Mr. Hwang just left.
Already? I guess I came too late.
- Well...
- I told you. He's not in his office.
Oh, this is my office now.
- What?
- Sorry?
Let's be a good team.
- Pardon?
- Hold on.
Wait, are you saying... Well...
This is Prosecutor Dong-jae Seo
of Division Three.
Prosecutor Dong-jae Seo?
I beg your pardon? Me?
Hold on a second, please.
Yes, sir.
I didn't expect
to receive a call from you.
Yes, I know. Of course.
The problem? Everything has been resolved.
Have you forgotten who I am?
I'm the prosecutor, Dong-jae Seo.
Of course. Totally.
When? I'd love that.
CHANG-JUN LEE RESTS HERE.
When I had soju at a tent bar
for the very first time,
you were there with me.
Why didn't you tell me?
You should've told me.
You made me feel so safe. What are you
doing there now, buried underground?
Are you
in peace there?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, honey.
CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER OF HANJO GROUP
YEON-JAE LEE
Please let Mr. Chairman know that we're
working on getting his arrest suspended.
10 MONTHS LATER
Rain is expected to start
from the southern regions on Saturday
and to spread into the most parts of
the country. Have a great day, everyone.
Next song is "Camellia Lady" by Mi-ja Lee.
Prosecution, what is this about?
What a toxic, crude melody,
don't you think?
That's probably why the song got banned.
This song, "Camellia Lady,"
was banned in 1968
for Japanese influence
shown throughout the song.
You may not believe it,
but that was before I was born.
My deceased father used to like
the song a lot when he was alive.
Hence, I always had this question.
Which parts show the Japanese influence?
What about this song is toxic?
"Is this land still a good place to live?"
Is this land still beautiful?
No, it's a lie.
Every day, we have to pretend
that we don't know,
quietly listen to lies
and endure whipping that sends
pulsating pain down to the bones
because we're servants, slaves
and puppets.
"How humiliating and mortifying."
Had this been 31 years ago,
what I just did would've been seen
as insulting the nation
and causing public harm.
Now that 31 years have passed,
I don't have to hesitate to deliver
what the poet really wanted to convey,
and it makes me happy.
However,
the old poet had to give up
his humble wish of wanting to go back
to teaching Korean at the school.
I would like to ask you all what you think
a true reinstatement means.
Last but not least,
to the poet who was told
he's not allowed to return to the school
even though he could be reinstated,
I'd like to apologize as his contemporary
who has a lot to learn
from his experiences,
and I'd also like to thank him.
I'd love to assist him.
Isn't he so cool?
Today's noon news.
While the opposition party has been
strongly criticizing.
Prime Minister Chang-sik Kim
for abusing his power,
Prime Minister Kim has been
denying all the allegations
saying that he is being targeted,
which is becoming a heated debate.
Yes, this is Prosecutor Si-mok Hwang
of Criminal Division Two...
PROSECUTOR SI-MOK HWANG
Mr. Kang.
Have you already made yourself
at home there?
That won't be good.
What are you calling about?
There will be a special investigation
on Prime Minster Kim's power abuse case.
Members of Congress chose you unanimously
for the special investigation team.
I see.
You're not even surprised.
You have to be here in two days.
And when you're here,
you have to do something about Dong-jae.
What did he do?
He's still the same.
He hasn't changed one bit.
Okay. I won't be late.
Sure.
ALL EVENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS.
STRANGER
One, two, three.
Subtitle translation by Liya Choi